Good morning.
Hey, Cutter.
Your lawyer is here.
There is literally nothing left for
me to do, your appeal was denied.
- Look, you got a little shy of eleven months...
- Ten months!
Ten months. Whatever...
That's better, right? Just ride it out.
You gotta do your the time right.
Call Keegan.
- No.
- Call him.
No.
OK, as your attorney, I advise you
just to ride out the eleven months.
Ten months! Martin, call him. Today!
SUV huh?
You know Daphne.
What are you gonna do?
So, what the fuck, Ray?
Nine months to go and-and what. You call Keegan?
Why would you do that?
That's such a wicked price to pay, you know.
Fuck.
You're still gonna tell me what's going on, right?
Oh, yeah. I'll tell you.
Jesus Christ!
What the hell are you doing here?
You're not on the lam, are you?
Yeah, pop, I tunnel out.
Oh, that's funny.
Where is he?
Upstairs.
How the fuck did you get out, Raymond?
Yeah?
Hey.
Dad?
Right.
How did you get out?
I know it's hard to believe
but, judge granted my appeal.
I didn't know you're into all this.
What are you working on? That's-that's good.
It's just plastic pieces.
Yeah, but you got to put them
together and paint all the details...
Dad.
Let's not do this, OK?
Yeah...
OK.
So? How did it go?
Well...
he has some tests...
tomorrow.
I'd like to think you didn't
do something foolish...
just to be here.
Oh, fuck it.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Guys, gotta get through. Excuse me.
Excuse me. Miss.
Tommy.
I was just now standing there, with my dick in my
hand, I'm shaking it off and thinking to myself.
Wonder when the forger's
gonna walk through my door?
- Tommy.
- What?
Right there.
Jesus.
Can't tell from the camera
angle of this guy right here.
He's got huge fucking balls.
Dealing product from behind my bar.
I got him.
Got to deal with this.
Fucking Chuck town junkie.
So, Ray.
You calling me with ten months to go.
'Cause what, you're-you're-you're bored?
I really appreciate what you did for me but...
- I need a little time.
- 50K, Ray.
It's the going rate for judges.
And time?
No. It's something you don't got.
Don't... Don't look like that, already.
Since you went away. I've been in
business with these guys. It's...
These chainsaws, Ray.
Compared to them, I'm a fucking humanitarian.
You know this painting?
Yeah.
Do it.
Do it? What do you mean, do it?
You mean-you mean forge it?
It's a Monet. What the fuck for?
So you can steal the real one.
Steal? What are you talking about?
Steal the real one?
In three weeks...
It's gonna be on display, right here.
And the guy who wants it.
He's gonna be in Boston, too.
For one night only.
That's impossible.
Three weeks. I can't do that.
Look, it's either yes...
or I make a phone call.
And you go back to prison.
Yes or no. You have 48 hours to make a decision.
Welcome home, Ray.
- Jesus!
- I'm so sorry.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Where you going? Haven't seen you
around here before. I'm Catherine.
- I'm Ray.
- Ray. Nice to meet you, Ray.
Hey, you know Tommy?
Tommy?
Yeah.
- Alright, I gotta go...
- Hey-hey-hey!
Wanna go somewhere?
Oh, thank you.
Wow, is this your car?
So cool.
Can I drop you off somewhere?
- Drop me?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I got things to do and
you don't wanna be in there.
Stay out of there. And stay away from Tommy Keegan.
OK. There's better people
and there's better places.
Hey!
Are you serious?
Hey.
You hungry?
Not for those.
OK.
Well, eggs it is.
Where's gramps?
He's out. But I'm gonaa take you today.
Because of it's location in the
midsection of the brain stem.
It makes it very difficult to remove surgically.
I'm sorry, Mr. Cutter.
I know this is difficult.
- Do you have any questions?
- Yeah, I do. What do you do now?
I mean... you know. What-what-what is the plan?
- The plan?
- Yeah!
Is he gonna be in pain? I mean,
what-what-what's gonna happen?
What we should focus on is...
keeping William as comfortable
as possible during the process.
Then what?
Well, you know, it's... it's impossible to say.
Each patient is very different.
- So?
So what?
What'd they say?
Gramps took it out.
He took it out?
Why'd he take it out?
He hit it too many times. Sprained his wrist.
So, the chemo... will it cure me?
- The fuck did he take the horn out for?
- Dad.
Fuck.
Will-will the chemo cure me?
Oh, Will.
Dad, for once in your fucking life.
Could you just tell me the truth?
I don't know.
Can I help you?
I like to see the man in charge.
In here.
Hey, gramps.
Can I have one of those?
I want to report a murder.
Sit down.
The name's Bigelow,
Frank Bigelow.?
Where was this murder committed?
San Francisco. . Last night.
Who was murdered?
I was.
Sean Mcgill. Lived in Cambridge.
- 28 years old today.
- I knew him.
Bartender at the Palace.
Talked to him the night before last.
Watched him get fired.
Finn Gerrity... told him to walk,
right when he came on shift.
Like they caught him in something.
He looked scared.
- Any way we can this to Keegan?
- Love to.
Alright, guys, Come on in here and do your jobs.
Get that new trace heroin to the
lab, see if we can match it.
Do me a favor. Why don't you fingerprint
the fuck out of this place, huh?
Know what's hard? Relying on local
law enforcement to connect the dots.
Well, it's tough all over. Do you
want me to get you a tissue? Huh?
What do you wanna know?
There's a guy. Ray.
Met with Keegan that night.
Buick Skylark, license plate 'J433K6'.
OK. What's so special about this guy?
I don't know. Something.
- I think he made me.
- Made you?
Like... DEA made you?
- Just a cop.
- Oh, just a cop.
Did you talk to Keegan?
What did he want?
One answer. Tomorrow.
About what? About a job?
Yeah.
What do you want?
What I want...
What I've always wanted, Carl.
Go to Tahiti and live like Gauguin.
In Tahiti?
What's Will want?
I don't know.
Hey, Will. Check it out.
Don't even think about it.
What?
You're not gonna sign me up
for something like that.
- What? You don't want to meet nobody?
- No. I don't want to meet at all.
Or go to Disneyland, or meet Tom Brady.
Why not?
Because dad, it's embarrassing. What's the point?
What? Y-you don't want to do anything?
Yeah, I'd like to stop talking about it.
Hi, handsome. You been waiting long?
No, not long.
What if I did that?
Dad, just dropped it.
No, I mean it.
What if you... you made a wish. You could
even make like three wishes. Like a genie.
Dad, a genie?
You are not a genie. Jesus Christ.
No, I'm serious, Will.
You make what... make any... anything.
Anything you want.
Like you'd follow through with it.
How do you know? I-I might surprise you.
Give me a chance.
Alright then.
You know what I wish for? I
wished I didn't have cancer.
Is that fair?
I don't know, dad, you tell me.
You're the genie, right?
Look at you. I think those
girls were checking you out.
Dad, stop.
They're like 20-something.
I was joking.
So, you had a girlfriend, right? Like...
Tracy, or Trixie, or something like that.
How'd you know about her?
Gramps.
I asked about you all the time when I was away.
You talking about Tricia?
Yeah, Tricia... you, uh... How
long did you go out with her?
Dad...
Can we drop it, huh?
Yeah, I gotta go to the bathroom.
I'll be right back.
I got my son sitting over there.
If you could, give him anything he wants.
And I'll have a cheese burger and a coffee.
- Guess what today is, Cutter?
- I know what day it is.
Now look, I'm having lunch with my son.
So, why don't you just tell Tommy
that I'll see him later, OK?
I haven't forgotten.
Fuck you, Cutter.
So who's the guy you followed into the bathroom?
What guy?
Dad, I saw you follow the guy in there.
Burger, no onions and a grilled cheese.
Anything else you need?
No, that's it. Thanks.
Grilled cheese, that's all?
- Yeah.
- Why?
Dad, I don't know.
My stomach hurts.
Why're you worried about it?
So you're really not gonna
tell me who the guy was?
I owe his boss money and he
came to remind me. That's it.
How much you owe him?
You know, I really don't want
to burden you with this stuff.
Dad, I don't care. You can tell me.
I don't see why you're so
scared to tell me things.
Fifty grand, OK?
- Holy shit, fifty thousand dollars?
- Yeah.
How do you owe him 50 thousands dollars? For what?
Because we had to pay the judge to bribe him.
In order to get out early, so...
So I could-I could spend some time with you.
I want to meet my mother.
What?
- Your mother?
- Yeah, dad.
Yeah, I want to meet her.
- Oh, gee, Will...
- Am I talking to a genie, or what?
But I don't know where she is.
I thought you said she moved
away, to that fancy condo.
Yeah, exactly. You know... the condo, right.
OK then.
That's my first wish.
Agent Paisley.
I got your guy, Raymond Cutter.
Five years forgery.
Fresh out of Northport. Ten
months early for good behavior.
Forgery? You don't hear that every day.
No, you do not. Busted back in '87
for art fraud and then nothing,
until someone dropped a dime on him.
Who?
Tommy Keegan.
That's right. Your bad guy.
They say that Cutter took the fall.
The Buick...
Is registered to his dad, Joseph Cutter.
Old school conman, pickpocket, petty thief.
It stretches up and down the east coast.
Buy me a drink and I'll read you his rap sheet.
And Keegan is a felon, so Cutter violated
his parole when he went and visited him.
You wanna do, bring him in?
Nope, wanna watch him.
Who's the buyer?
Buyer? There's no buyer.
He's just a guy...
and he wants it.
I gotta pay for a fucking... what is it?
Appraiser?
Do you believe in that shit?
Making me pay.
I don't know...
You know any?
For stolen art?
Yeah.
Legit?
I don't know. Maybe...
Maybe Owensby, from Minnesota.
Something like that.
Minnesota...
So, how much?
Nothing, Ray.
I'm getting you out of a jam,
and you getting me out of one.
Do you want to go back to prison?
Or do you want to just do this thing?
What do you want?
I'll need, um... a painting of the same year.
Same size.
And, uh... when I find it...
whatever it costs, you gotta
be ready to pay for it.
Yeah, yeah. This is Ronald Chambers.
Chambers.
Yeah, I'm looking for something specific.
I'm looking for something French.
Circa 1875.
40 inches by 32 inches.
Let's go, boy.
No, that doesn't matter, it doesn't matter.
Just it-it's period and-and-and size.
Hey, gramp.
What was grandma like?
Your grandmother was a saint.
She never lied, she never... gossipped.
And she'd give you the last... dime in her pocket.
I don't know... She didn't deserved to
suffer her life with me, I tell you.
Jesus Christ!
- How old was dad when she died?
- Four.
So, it's just you two, then.
You guys get along?
What kind of a question is that?
I was just... just wondering.
Wondering... wondering why?
Well, I don't know, I guess I
never see you guys hug or...
or say you love each other.
Yeah, well, I don't do that.
But he knows.
You sure?
I didn't tell your grandmother
either, but she knew.
Why? Because words don't mean
a shit in this world, Will.
It's what a person does feel that counts.
Well, what about my mother?
You ever meet her?
Oh, that's what this is all about, is it?
Yeah.
Dad asked me what I wanted and I, I told him...
I want to meet my mother.
Yeah? Well, fuck that.
Get in the car.
All I know is, one of Keegans' guys got busted.
Lost an entire load of H.
Now Tommy owes someone.
Who?
I don't know.
But it's a lot of dough.
Any fucking idea what you're doing?
Nope.
Oh.
Good.
- Hey.
Uncle Carl.
Hey, Will.
How you doing, buddy?
- Alright.
- Good to see you.
Alright, alright.
You, upstairs.
You, get in the wind.
You, out back.
Call me tomorrow?
- Why?
- Out back!
So.
What are you doing?
Promising that he can see his mother, huh?
Well, how do you think he's going
to feel if you don't deliver?
And God forbid if you do. Bullshit!
Whatever you're going to say is bullshit!
Four years we've been here, Ray.
Me and Will.
And we are doing fine.
And you come catapulting out of prison.
Jesus!
You tell me the truth.
How did you get out?
Keegan.
Oh, fuck me.
Tell me you're lying.
Tell me you're not in it for Tommy fucking Keegan!
Jesus, Mary and me!
How much?
How much are you in it for him?
Oh, no, don't...
don't tell me. I-d, I... I don't want to hear it.
Go.
Take Will and...
get the fuck out of town.
I need your help, pop.
You know something?
You should have stayed inside.
Closed, now.
Rodney, remember me?
Ray.
No.
Kim's ex.
What the fuck do you want?
I need to know where she is.
No.
I haven't seen her.
Oh, come on, you know where she is.
Told you, Ray.
I haven't see that fucking bitch in years.
Look, Rodney, I'm not here to cause any trouble.
- Are you here to cause any trouble?
- I just wanna know where she is.
- Come on, this ain't that kind of visit.
- Hey!
- Go check it out.
- Get this guy out of my fucking shop!
- Oh, give me a fucking break, will you?
- Get the fuck out, Ray.
Let's go buddy.
Never liked you, Ray!
Never liked you!
Come on! I'm gonna get you!
Fuck!
Fucking fucker.
Where? Fuck you!
- Last time. Where?
- Fuck you!
That's it. I'm not asking again.
You want "Ray" in your fucking forehead?
Fuck off!
- I'm going to ask you again.
- Fuck you!
- Fuck!
- Where?
Prescott Road!
It's in Braintree.
That's where she is, I swear.
I do...
How'd you find me?
Rodney.
Fuck.
That was easy.
Not really.
What do you want?
Your son, Will. He wants to see you.
What is he now? 12?
Try 15.
- Does he remember me?
- Hmm-mmm.
I mean what? All of a sudden he wants to see me?
This isn't you...
- Trying to hook me back into you and your dad...
- Your son is sick.
He's got cancer.
He's got a stage 4 tumor in his head.
OK?
So I need you to clean yourself up...
put your best face on...
- and have lunch with us on Wednesday.
- No.
I can't do that.
- Oh, yes, you can.
- No, I can't.
W-wait a minute, I just told
you that your son was dying.
And you can't do this? Wh-wh-who are you?
You're gonna do this.
Or I'm going to make your fucking life
more miserable than it already is.
I'll be back at noon. You be ready.
Hold-hold... hold still now.
Oh, did it hurt, Ray?
- Just get on with it, will you?
- Heh, heh.
Will you be needing a tissue?
Are you done?
Yeah, done.
So.
It was Keegan.
Rodney.
Oh... Christ, Ray.
I'm sorry, dad.
You were right.
Alright.
What can I do?
Is Will good?
He's sleeping.
It was a tough night for the Cutter boys.
What do you need?
Ivan.
He still in business?
Ivan?
Of course, he is.
That russky is like a cockroach.
- Heh, heh...
- Heh...
And here he comes...
Sha-wing... a hit!
Oh, man.
- Who's the victim?
- Rodney Hunter. Three time loser.
Spousal abuse, identity fraud and
possession of methamphetamines.
And what's he got to say about this?
Nothing.
According to Mr. Hunter, your Raymond Cutter was
looking for somebody that they had in common.
Who?
His ex-wife, Kim o'Halloran.
I'm running her down now. But so far...
your boy has violated his parole
like one, two... five counts now.
What do you want to do?
I want to know why.
Here.
Yeah, that's her.
So why has she got such a hardon for you, anyway?
No, it's Keegan she wants.
She just saw me come out of his
office and probably thought I was...
you know. Hanging with another felon and shit.
If Rodney dropped a dime on me...
fuck!
I don't got time for this.
Yeah.
Come on. I want to show you something.
You know a lot of these old buildings have
hidden rooms left over from the prohibition.
You can't even get to them from the inside.
Wicked cool, huh?
It's good.
It's a stupid plan.
Which part?
No, I'm serious.
What makes you think you can pull it off?
I mean, you haven't painted
anything for fucking years.
You're right, I haven't. But it
doesn't mean I never wanted to.
In fact, up till now, it's the
only thing I ever thought about.
Are you good?
Let's go.
Look, could you tell Ivan that, uh...
Joseph Cutter's here to see him, please?
Ivan's not here.
Oh, yeah, he is.
I watched him come back from the deli.
He's back there right now.
Feeding his fat face, with a
fucking corn beef sandwich.
- Take a walk old man.
- Tell you what.
If I win...
take me to Ivan.
If, uh... you win...
you got this.
- Alright.
- On the count of three.
One.
Two.
Three.
Son of a bitch.
I told you never to come in here again, Cutter.
Well, I just happen to have, in my
possession, a little shopping list.
You see, I'm not selling. I'm buying...
your services as a procurement specialist.
You know, scrounger, as in king fucking rat.
Copper acetate.
Cadmium.
Arsenic sulfide.
Cinnabar...
What the fuck? These are chemicals.
And minerals.
And a lot of them fucking poisonous.
Read it carefully.
We're gonna need it all, and we need it quick.
- Hey.
Ronald Chambers.
- Oh, dude! Awesome.
- Yeah.
Great to meet you.
Yeah, wow.
Yeah, I'm gutting the place.
It was my grandparents'.
Oh. And now it's yours?
Now, it's mine.
It's epic.
This... this guy... was-was an inventor.
He was a philosopher.
He was, um... he was a patron of the arts...
Not a good painter.
But he was friends with Degas.
- No shit!
- No shit.
So, how much for the bad one?
This one?
That one.
Would you look at this?
What am I looking at? Paint by fucking numbers?
Evidence. From Cutter's 1987 conviction.
Most of the stuff was auctioned off as lesser
known pieces by Paul Gauguin, except for this one.
Which is in a museum in Paris.
So, so why would he forged it?
I mean, like... why would someone
steal a famous painting?
You can't... sell it. You can't
exactly show it to people.
Status.
Look at this.
Raul Carlos, head of the Arroyo cartel,
is reported to have the largest private
art collection in Latin America.
You think that Keegan and Cutter are
trying to run a scam on your boy?
Scam?
Carlos is a bad guy.
I sure as hell wouldn't.
Kim?
You up?
Mother fucker!
So?
You look nice.
You coming in?
No.
I think you should.
Well, Kim.
Just look at you.
- Look at you.
- Pops.
Hi.
OK, we should go.
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
So, uh... where in New York do you live?
Um...
Right near Times Square.
I hope you're not a Yankees fan.
Ha! Not really.
Good. 'Cause I don't know if I could
be your son any more if you were.
So...
Do you have a girlfriend?
No.
Excuse me a minute.
You OK?
- What?
- You OK?
Yeah.
You like her?
She's nice.
I'm starving.
What's good here?
The grilled salmon's good.
Is that what you're getting?
I think so.
Then that's what I'll have, too.
OK.
So...
What's New York like?
Like Boston, only bigger.
No one, drives.
Everyone takes a taxi or the subway.
So do you live in a nice building?
I like it.
- We have a game room.
- Nice.
- A hot tub on the roof.
- Oh, wow.
I'd love to see that.
When you get better, you should come visit.
Yeah. Yeah.
I will.
These are really hot.
Thank you, sir.
Pretzel.
Here you go.
Dip in.
Wish you weren't going so soon.
Wish you could stay longer.
So, why-why aren't you flying?
Ha-ha.
You don't have wings, you got to get in a plane.
Goodbye, William.
I had a really great day.
Yeah. Me, too.
Wait here.
Thanks.
OK.
- Yeah.
She is nice.
- She was nice, dad...
- Yeah.
Yeah, I told you.
Thanks. Thanks for pretending.
What do you mean pretending? Pretending what?
Yeah, you know.
About her... living in New York and...
and not being a drug addict.
Glad I got to meet her.
You OK?
Yeah.
Feeling sick?
No, I'm fine. Just... you know.
Gramp's breakfast.
- We ready to go?
- Yeah.
- What does it feel like?
- What?
The chemo.
I don't know. It feels like shit.
You OK?
What's going on?
Alright.
Promise you're not gonna laugh.
I'm not gonna laugh.
I want to have sex.
That's my second wish.
So the bad news is they got a gallery mast on.
They got wireless sensors on
all the doors and windows...
and each painting's equipped with a battery
operated magnetic sensor behind the frame.
If it's moved, the detector sets off an alarm and
we're looking at like a six minute response time.
And they send their alarm
signal directly to the cops.
The whole thing's keypad controlled.
Oh, keypads, just call pops.
Yeah, roger that.
How good are security guards? How about that?
Five at night.
Top of the hour.
They do rounds on foot after they lock up.
OK, so what's the good news?
Oh.
Here. Call in advance.
Ask for Melanie. She will take good care of Will.
- Where'd you get this?
- You know, it's online.
It's a site like Yelp, but for hookers.
No, no, no... forget it.
There's got to be a better way than that.
Well, if there is, you be sure to let me know, OK?
I mean though, what do you want him to do, Ray?
Meet some girl, and take her out on a date.
Maybe fall in love, meet the family, and...
some day have sex.
In the back seat of the Buick,
on the banks of the Charles?
Yeah, Carl. I do.
Alright. Thanks.
Six parole violations and now he's
taking a minor to a whore house.
You know at this point, if...
we don't fucking arrest him,
then we aren't doing our jobs.
So, uh... this Melanie, she
she's a friend of Carl's?
Yeah.
You OK?
You got any questions?
I don't think so.
No?
Just remember what I said, you know.
Wear your raincoat. No fancy stuff.
2C, 2D...
2B. Here we go.
Melissa?
- Melanie.
Yeah. Come on in.
Carl explained everything.
So, you must be William. Hi.
Hi.
We're fine. We'll see you in an hour.
OK.
- OK... good.
- OK.
Alright.
Will, open up!
- Hey, what... everythings fine.
- Look, I'm sorry, we got to go.
The cops are here.
Look. Here's your money.
They're gonna ask me questions, I cannot answer.
I got this. Go, go, go.
Left. Left.
Go up. Up, up, up.
Oh, fuck.
Dad-dad let's jump over.
No, we can't jump. We're not jumping.
Dad, what-what are you, scared?
You can't... you can't...
- You don't think I can make it?
- Let me-let me find a fire-a fire escape.
Come on.
- Shit.
- Oh!
A whore house.
Why are you laughing?
Gramps. It's the coolest thing I've ever seen.
Well, I bet it wasn't supposed to be.
Heh, heh, heh...
No, no, Gramps.
We jumped to a whole 'nother building.
On the top of the roof. And
then he picks the lock, and
and I'm so nervous, my stomach's
just doing somersaults. But him...
He's just so calm.
No, I wasn't calm on the inside.
So, you never got... you never got to finish...
Hey, pop, pop!
Why don't you go call Carl and
have him pick up the Buick.
Alright. And then, then, then what?
Go walk the imaginary dog or
some other fucking thing.
- If you want the time to be alone together.
- You're too much.
Fucking take it.
No need to patronize me, you... fucker.
Oh, you're too much.
Hey, Will.
I'm sorry about Melanie.
You kidding me?
Dad...
today was awesome.
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
How come you broke up with that girl?
- Tricia?
- Yeah.
She would smile at every guy that walked past her.
And it...
it just, you know, it drove me nuts.
But that-that's it? She-she just smiled?
She was trying to make me jealous or something.
But... but...
what if she... is just friendly?
Why don't you just call her?
The kid. It's his son.
William.
Cutter took him out of school, the day
after he got out of prison. Ask me why.
OK, why?
Medical.
William Cutter's got cancer.
Jesus.
Lab test results on the trace heroin found
in the dead bartender's hotel room.
Spoiler alert. Matches the shit you're after.
OK. Um...
Find out who granted Cutter's parole, and uh...
give me Keegan's rap sheet.
Please.
Wow.
What's the occasion?
Here, sit down.
Can't believe it.
I figured out my third wish.
- But you didn't get your second wish yet.
- It's alright. We can come back to it.
OK.
Lay it on me.
Well.
I know you're planning something...
something to get the money to pay that guy back.
- Gramps tell you that?
- No.
Look, Will. You know...
Dad. I want to help you.
Getting you laid.
And having you meet your mother... is one thing.
- But this is ain't your problem.
- Dad...
you have this problem because of me.
That is not true.
I was in the hole way before you came along.
But, dad, I...
I-I've never done anything so
exciting as I did yesterday.
And you and gramps...
You guys have really lived, and...
I want to experience that, you know?
Oh no. No, no, no...
Trust me.
I don't... I...
I knew you weren't gonna follow
through with the fucking wishes.
A-all you are... is a liar a-and a fake.
Will?
Will, open up!
Hey.
Hi, pal.
What happened?
The doctor said that y-you had a seizure.
I guess that's kind of normal for this thing.
Hello, boyo.
Dad, please.
Please, please, please.
What is it you want, William?
Please.
So this is Claude Monet, he's an Impressionist.
The word came from the name of-of one of his
paintings, called the Impression Sunrise.
He-he-he's not trying to be
exact like a photograph.
A picture. He-he's trying to...
Well, he's...
he's trying to paint the feeling.
Like Paul Gauguin?
Yeah.
Like Gauguin.
It's a sunny day.
It's, um... Spring time.
Camille is looking at Monet.
And Jean...
Wait.
Who-who are they?
Camille is Monet's... Monet's wife.
And Jean, is his eight year old son.
So, is it gonna be hard to fake?
Oh, no, you don't fake this.
I mean, you don't-you can't copy it.
You-you have to...
you have to get inside it... you know, it's...
it's hard to explain.
But if I could...
if I could...
feel what he was feeling...
you know, maybe... well, maybe I could do it.
It's beautiful.
It is.
You ever gonna go to Tahiti, like Paul Gauguin?
I don't know.
OK, you just keep grinding.
See all these minerals are pure.
Like back in the day 1875, There
was no pollution, you know.
Then, you know, factories came along and cars...
They put little... like black
specks in the-the minerals, so...
well, you can't use that. That's
why I can't use my paints.
Let's see how you're doing there.
Good.
Now uh, OK.
Some oil.
Hold still.
OK.
Now, use this...
Stir it up.
- You want me to do it?
- Yeah. Go ahead, do it.
- See that?
- Yeah.
Yeah. And watch it become paint,
right in front of your eyes.
Hey.
You take your meds?
- Yup.
- Good.
Hey, dad.
What you did today...
it's pretty crazy.
Thanks.
Yeah, you know, I could've done it my whole life.
Should've.
Why don't you?
Let's get through all this.
Tomorrow we start fresh.
Alright.
- Night.
Yeah.
Cutter's grant of parole was
signed by Judge Jacob Brooks.
That's the same judge who acquitted Keegan
of his second felony charge back in 03.
So Keegan puts Cutter in prison...
and four years later, gets him out.
Why? 'Cause he feels bad?
Tommy Keegan doesn't know how to feel bad.
Yeah, Ray.
She's coming right at you.
Catherine.
You want to talk?
It's OK.
We're alone.
I mean it's OK for both of us.
How'd you make me at Keegan's?
I don't know.
You know, you were asking a lot of questions.
So...
this is really about Tommy Keegan, right?
Maybe.
Well, I can't tell you nothing about him.
I mean, not that I care about him, because I don't.
But, I'm not a snitch.
- Never have been, never will be.
- Tommy Keegan was.
Put you away for five years, huh.
Keegan is in serious debt to the Arroyo cartel.
Do you know what that means?
- Have you seen this man before?
- No.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
His name is Raul Carlos and
he's a real patron of the arts.
Painting again, Ray?
I need time.
I need privacy.
Because of your son?
- Yeah.
- Look, whatever you think you owe Keegan...
it's just gonna destroy the time
that you have left with Will.
Help me to help you.
You OK?
I just had a dream and...
I'm here.
Come here.
Dad, I'm scared.
I know.
Hey, Ray.
How we doing? Hmm?
What the fuck are you doing here?
I told you I'd get you the painting.
My goodness.
Is that little William?
Hey, you know what? You got
a phone call young man.
Who's Tricia?
- OK, go upstairs. Go, go, go.
- Come on bro,
are you getting some?
He turned into a good looking young man.
But he's uh...
I don't know. Looking a little peaked.
I told Finn I'll break his fucking
neck, if he came near my son.
And that goes for the three of you.
And stab him to death with a fucking
paintbrush, right? Why-why-why the hostility?
Hostility?
- Don't fucking move.
- Jesus Christ!
OK, pop, it ain't that kind of night. OK?
- Joe, come on, we're partners.
- Not with me, you're not.
And this is my house...
and I didn't invite you.
Tommy, Tommy. Why don't you take Colin and Finn...
tell them to wait in the
car, and-and we'll talk, OK?
- Tomorrow's D day.
- Yeah, I know it.
You ready?
- Yeah, no, it's not ready.
- Is it done?
But it will be done.
The museum closes at 9:45. I'll
get it to you by midnight.
You can back that up, because I need
to have it at Copley by midnight.
- You have it to me by eleven.
- F-for the-for the buyer?
Mmm-hmm.
In person.
And the appraiser. Fuck.
The appraiser. You got the
contact number for that guy?
How much is this gonna cost me?
How the fuck should I know.
I haven't done this in years.
Fucking Minnesota.
Jesus!
You're really in trouble
with this guy, aren't you?
Shit.
Yeah.
- Tomorrow night. 11 PM.
- Yeah.
You should be so proud of Ray.
I-I, I know they're saying that...
he's a better dad than me.
I ain't saying anything.
But... but there it is.
And-and your grandson...
Well...
He's just as tough as you were.
So...
When you meet him...
take good care of him, will you?
I love you, that's a fact.
Yes.
Yeah, it's me.
Whose calling?
OK. Three 15 minutes bakes, five minutes apart...
and 375.
Think we're OK. The restaurant opens in an hour.
Well, you ready for this, boyo?
I'm just studying.
Yeah, good. Good, good.
Alright, you guys got any questions?
- Nope.
- No...
Well...
I want to smoke these, uh... now...
by a way of...
celebrating our coming success.
It's a sort of toast.
Life is short...
and things go wrong.
May we always have enough.
He's here.
Just got pinged by ICE.
Raul Carlos and two of his
captains just flown into Logan.
Start with the top 3 hotels. Let me know
when you find out where he's headed.
I'm on Cutter.
Get someone on Keegan.
Yeah.
OK, so. Carlos and two captains
just checked into the Conway.
Shit!
Whoa. Lady, watch out. This a
neighborhood, there's children here.
Sir, I need you to move your car. Right now.
Really, you're gonna pull a badge?
Like what, are you gonna arrest me
- for pulling out of my driveway?
- Sir, move your car.
Sir. You can't have drinks in here.
Damn. What's that?
You can't... you-you can't have drinks in here.
Oh, I don't know.
- Sir, give me that sir. Give me the soda please.
- I'm thirsty, boyo.
- Give me that. Give me that.
- The corridors are so long and such a long walk.
- No, give me that. Give me that.
- Alright, let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
Let's go.
Thank you. Thank you. Yeah,
I was-I was leaving anyway.
Hey.
Sir, it's 9:30.
We're closing in fifteen minutes.
Alright.
You have to leave now.
Can I help you?
Federal police.
- We need to take a look around.
- Yeah.
Anything unusual?
No.
Just some old guy who spilled
a soda in the European wing.
I gotta call Will.
- Hey.
- Will.
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm OK.
We're moving. You got three minutes.
Alright.
Hey. What's the score, guys?
Let me take that.
- In the European wing.
- Show us.
Sure.
Right here.
We already mopped it up.
What did he look like?
Just an old man.
A little demented.
Sad.
Let's do a ride around.
Thanks, guys. Let's go.
Now.
Still on.
Fuck.
What the fuck?
Shit.
The door is stuck.
Get the fucking flashlight.
Hit it. Hit it.
Calling all units in the vicinity
of the Museum of Fine Arts.
Come on!
Hey! Hey!
Stop!
Come on!
Go, go, go...!
Holy shit!
The police are on the scene here at
the MFA, after an apparent break in.
A small group of suspects were
able to disable the alarm.
However, nothing was taken.
Claude Monet.
1875.
Woman with Parasol.
So what now?
Now?
Now, Finn is gonna take this to the guy...
along with this.
And I am off... the hook.
OK. What about me?
When I leave here.
I don't see you anymore, right?
Not exactly.
Fuck you!
I know you, Ray.
So.
After my man...
gets out of town with that stupid fucking picture,
I'm gonna make a call.
They're gonna take one look at whatever
the fuck it was, you put on that wall,
and they're gonna put you away.
Again.
So now, why don't you get up...
and get out the fuck out of here.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
I got eyes on Finn Gerrity
walking into the Copley Plaza.
Jesus.
- You need backup?
- No. I got DEA in the lobby.
Here you go.
Senor Owensby...
I'll call you back.
Catherine.
Let this play out.
If you wanna bust this guy Carlos.
Just let it play out.
Do you have the payment for Mr.Owensby?
Yeah, I got the payment.
One hundred thousand dollars.
Yeah, it's all there.
So...
this guy comes all the way from, uh...
Minneapolis, Minnesota...
to tell me that Tommy Keegan is a fool.
What the fuck's that supposed to mean?
I always thought Mr. Keegan was stupid.
But I didn't know that he was this stupid.
Bullshit! Wait a minute.
Oh, what the fuck?
Let's go visit Tommy Keegan.
Fuck that!
Mr.Owensby?
- Uh, Mr... uh... Carlos.
- Carlos.
I'm-I'm... sorry.
Not only is this a... forgery.
It's a bad one, at that.
S-so it's worth nothing?
It's for you.
- Here they are.
- Oh shit!
No. Don't, don't, don't!
He's coming back.
OK, he's just gonna pay someone a visit.
He'll be back.
You don't have anything on him, anyway.
Can't wait.
Pop!
Geronimo.
- What did you do?
- OK. There's a painting upstairs.
It's a Monet. It's the real thing.
When they come back, you arrest them.
Read them their rights...
- Whatever you guys do.
- That's right.
Wait a minute. Nothing was taken.
Trust me.
You just be very careful with the painting.
Bring it back to the museum.
They'll know exactly what to do.
Yeah.
I thought you didn't snitch.
I don't.
It's just this guy Carlos ain't from here.
We gotta go. OK.
Jesus!
Any sign of Finn Gerrity and Colin Corley?
No, not a trace.
It's been over an hour. Why is he taking so long?
When I was his age, two minutes, tops.
This is fucking ridiculous.
Goodbye, Tricia.
Hey, pop.
Thanks for taking care of him when I was gone.
- Oh, stop it.
- Yeah, you know.
- Well?
- Hey!
How did it go?
Gramps, that's none of your business.
Alright, sergeant.
- Carl.
- Goodbye.
Bet he wishes he was going.
OK, here we are.
Dad.
You sure, huh?
Yeah, this is the real thing.
Here we go!
Thank you.
- Have a nice flight.
- Yeah, thanks.
Thanks.
I've never seen him this happy.
Hey, dad.
If you had one wish.
What would you wish for?
Come on in, you two pantsies.
Join me. The water's fine, for Christ's sake.
Hey, Will.
What do you say we explore Polynesia, huh?
We go to... we go to Fiji,
We go to Tonga.
We go to Marquesas. That's where Gauguin lived.
We got time.
What do you think?
Jump in and join me.