No more dictatorship!
The people united
will never fall.
One giant leap for all mankind!
They’ve never been known
for their modesty.
He’s got the Hollywood thing down.
Stop the jealousy.
The man’s walking on the moon.
If he were a Soviet,
you’d be drooling over him.
I got drunk when they launched Sputnik,
then drunk again for Laika.
Laika?
The dog the Soviets’
sent into space.
Then I got drunk again for Gagarin
and for that guy ….
—Titoy.
This is too much!
The U.S. cavalry
conquers the moon ….
and there’s not even natives
to kill.
I would like to ask Mr Ambassador,
Charles Elbrick …
and his distinguished wife …
to accept congratulations
from our Samba Club …
on this glorious night
for the United States of America.
The Ambassador can Samba very well.
Let’s leave the moon
and come back to Earth.
The press is under total censorship.
Hundreds of political prisoners
are being tortured …
including some friends.
What are you going to do about it?
Me?
Yes, you.
We’re joining an armed movement.
Are you with us?
—You’re kidding!
—No. We’re serious.
How many bullets have you fired
in your life, César?
Have you ever even killed a bird?
I can learn.
You’re a seminary student.
Killing is a sin.
You’re going up against the military
with a weapon in your hand?
If you want to commit suicide,
just throw yourself out a window.
The pretty-boy actor is afraid,
Fernando.
Yes, I am an actor and I am afraid.
Vanity, you know, I like to show off.
You want to show off too, don’t you?
You’re legitimizing this dictatorship.
They’ve already legitimized
themselves.
What do you propose?
That we sit and do nothing?
You’re getting into
a pointless adventure.
For God’s sake, Fernando,
this is crazy.
The press is censored,
Congress is running scared.
A strong congress could defeat—
Your thinking is bourgeois.
The time is ripe for revolution.
Your decision, is it definite?
Yeah, it’s definite.
You won’t have a home or a name.
Nothing.
I know.
Try not to get killed.
I’ll try.
See you.
No, we’re not going
to see each other.
Ready?
Yes.
Put these glasses on.
Let’s go.
Can you get the key?
Yes. I’ll guide you.
This way.
Wait a second.
Put your hand on my shoulder.
We’re gonna go down some stairs.
Smile.
—Another step.
—Is the car far?
No, it’s close.
Another step.
—Ray Charles must have a tough life.
—Yeah. Step.
Let’s get in the car.
Watch your head.
You can take off your glasses.
Let’s sit here in a circle.
The first issue is security.
Does anyone know anybody else?
Everyone here has participated
in student marches and rallies.
I’m asking you, does anyone know
the name of anyone else in this room?
Good. Because now you are about
to be re-baptised—born again.
Your name is Paulo.
Yours is Júlio.
Yours is Renée.
And yours is Oswaldo.
—Oswaldo.
—Yeah. Oswaldo.
I’m Marcão.
I don’t like it either.
Lenin’s real name wasn’t Lenin
and Trotsky’s wasn’t Trotsky.
But that’s how they made history.
Comrades Paulo, Júlio, Renée
and Oswaldo, you now will stand ….
Not now. Let me finish.
You’re going to stand
and face the wall.
Our leader, Comrade Maria,
is going to talk to you.
Until you’ve been approved
to join the group …
you can’t see her face.
Understand?
Face that wall.
—Stalin’s name wasn’t Stalin either.
—Shut up, Oswaldo.
I’m Comrade Maria …
one of the leaders of the 8th October
Revolutionary Movement:
the MR-8.
Our purpose is to fight
the dictatorship in Brazil.
Many of our comrades
have already fallen. Some are dead …
others are in prison being tortured
by the military.
The fate of our dead
and tortured comrades …
could be our fate.
Let me make a comment.
What’s the name of the first one
in the corner?
Paulo.
This is a revolutionary organization.
We have rules of discipline.
These rules are to be obeyed.
Understood, Comrade Paulo?
Understood.
Don’t put your thumb on the hammer.
Change your grip.
Relax. Fire!
That’s looking better.
Reload.
Go.
Excellent.
Have you had prior training?
Yes. A little.
Good going.
Relax.
Fire!
You’ve improved since yesterday.
It’s easier than I thought.
It’s easy to shoot a target.
It takes courage to shoot a man.
Lower your thumb.
Watch your grip.
Aim.
Pull the trigger.
No. Relax when you pull the trigger.
Are you afraid of the noise?
What a drag! All we need
is reveille or “fall in”.
Only soldiers can fight soldiers.
Now, I think the little sergeant
is into you.
She either wants to fuck me
or fuck me over.
—She’s kind of pretty, Fernando.
—Paulo. My name is Paulo.
Comrade Maria, would you permit
a criticism?
Of course. I think we should all
accept criticism.
You are good with weapons,
but eating your cooking …
is a true test
of revolutionary courage.
Attention!
This is not a robbery.
It’s a revolutionary expropriation …
of a bank that is a supporter …
of this bloody dictatorship.
Many of our comrades …
are being tortured in the prisons
of this military government.
You know nothing about it
because the press is censored.
Tell your friends what is going on!
We are the 8th October Revolutionary
Movement: the MR-8.
Hurry!
A new safe house!
What a waste!
Oswaldo went down
because he hesitated …
and didn’t shoot the guard.
What a disaster!
Lower your voice!
He’ll talk in less than 15 minutes.
You recruited idiots.
César’s not an idiot.
César?
Who is César?
I know his name.
What?
We’re friends.
Calm down!
Your normal life has ended.
You don’t have friends anymore,
nor a home nor a family.
You have nothing! The military
probably already knows your name.
Going to Victor’s party tonight?
Probably. After the game.
—Are you going with Lilian?
—If she’s not too tired.
Is there another today?
No. Only this one.
Great. We’ll get out earlier.
He’s going to talk soon.
—Let him breathe.
—Not even 20 seconds.
He’s wounded.
I don’t want an accident.
He may faint, but he won’t die.
No fainting. He has to talk.
Repeat the names.
Paulo.
Maria.
Marcão.
Renée.
Júlio.
220 Portugal Avenue.
Apartment 204.
Describe them.
Maria …
thin …
brunette, twenty-something.
This isn’t going anywhere.
We’re going to go down one by one.
I disagree.
We’ve just pulled off the biggest
bank expropriation …
in Brazilian history.
We want money.
We can rent a safe house, buy guns,
do whatever we want.
You’re right.
I don’t think so.
We’ve got money.
The operation was a success,
in spite of César’s loss.
But there is no victory when you’re
playing to an empty stadium.
No one’s going to know what we did.
What we really need is an operation
to break-up censorship of the press.
What if we kidnap a general?
They’d let him die
and he’d become a hero.
Yesterday I saw the U.S.
Ambassador’s limousine go by.
What if we kidnap him?
—Easier said than done.
—Maybe not.
Nobody’s ever kidnapped
an ambassador.
They are not expecting that.
If we get the U.S. Ambassador …
the wall of silence would come down.
Newspapers, radios, television—
everyone would hear our voice.
The military would be forced
to free our friends …
that are suffering in prison.
Can I help you, Miss?
My name is María das Dores.
I’ve just arrived from Varainha.
—From Minas Gerais.
—You’ve been there, sir?
Don’t call me “sir”.
No. I’ve never been there.
I came to work as a housekeeper.
Is this the right address?
This address is correct.
But we don’t need a maid right now.
Oh, my God!
What am I going to do?
Don’t panic. You probably
got the numbers mixed up.
Thank you.
Wait.
I get off in half an hour.
I’ll help you find
Mrs Paulo Alancastro.
—God bless you.
—Amen. In half an hour then.
I’ll figure this thing out. We didn’t
find it today, tomorrow we will.
Maybe your boss
could give me a job?
He lives in such a big house.
That house belongs
to the U.S. Ambassador.
Ambassador!
Really?
You need to get references
to work there.
And besides that,
they investigate your whole life.
Why?
Security purposes.
The Ambassador’s a very important man.
He’s one of those guys we see on television.
Lots of armed guards around.
No. He’s a simple guy.
He doesn’t like armed guards.
See this lighter?
He gave it to me.
He’s a good man.
Make yourself at home.
You can sleep on the sofa.
I will get you some sheets.
Do you have any beer?
I’ll get you one.
You dance very well.
I speak English.
It’s required at the embassy.
I didn’t know you were so important.
I’m the head of security, honey.
I told them to take
the U.S. flag …
off the Ambassador’s car.
That little flag was like bait
to attract terrorists.
Sometimes gringos are a little thick.
—What’s a terrorist?
—Forget it.
You are very pretty.
You probably say that
to every girl.
No. You are very special.
I’d do anything for you.
Yeah. Right.
Go ahead.Just ask me.
—Comrade Paulo?
—Yes.
I’m Toledo and this is Comrade Jonas.
It’s an honour to meet you,
Comrade Toledo. You too, Jonas.
Should we stand out in the street
so everyone can see us?
Come in, please. Don’t worry,
I’ll take care of it.
It’s a great honour to introduce
Mr Toledo and Mr Jonas …
from the National Liberation Group.
They bring their experience
from struggles in Sao Paulo …
to help us in our current operation.
Comrade Toledo is a veteran
of the Spanish Civil War.
He has an extensive background
in defending …
liberal causes in our country.
Comrade Jonas has shown
outstanding courage …
in risky operations in Sao Paolo.
Welcome to Rio de Janeiro, Comrades,
and may our mission be successful.
I’ll be brief.
I did not ask to command
this operation. It was offered to me.
So from now on,
I’ll give the orders …
and they are to be obeyed blindly—
without question.
We will be a united
and disciplined group.
Our job is difficult and does not
permit any hesitation.
I will kill the first one
who disagrees or vacillates.
And if there’s a second one,
I’ll kill him too.
Understood?
Júlio and Marcão shoot very well.
We need two cars to cover us.
—Comrade Paulo.
—Maria?
—Comrade Maria.
—Yes. Comrade Maria?
It’s been decided that you won’t
participate in the operation.
It was my idea!
You’ll stay and wait.
What happened?
My idea.
Those are Jonas’s orders. He is
in command of this operation now.
Is anybody going to question
the orders of Comrade Jonas?
They’re a bunch of middle class kids,
out for an adventure.
They’re not prepared
for an armed operation.
I know, but we need to recognize
that they had a great idea …
got the money to carry it out.
and wrote a great communiqué
to the newspapers.
We shouldn’t underestimate them.
We came to help them
and we are going to help.
President Nixon authorized
the withdrawal of …
25,000 troops from Vietnam.
Today’s weather will be sunny
and clear …
with the temperature rising.
He’s fifteen minutes late.
He’s the Ambassador. He doesn’t have
to leave at the same time every day.
I hope he uses the same route
every day!
Good morning, Ambassador.
Military police. Good morning.
Good morning.
There’s something strange …
happening at the corner
of Abrau and Marques street.
One moment, please.
This is Sergeant Eiras.
How can I help you?
There are three men and a woman
in a car on the corner …
of Abreu and Marques.
They look suspicious.
What do you mean by suspicious?
They’ve been there
for half an hour.
As if they’re waiting for someone
and they’re very nervous.
Can you see the license plate?
Hold on, please.
Guanabara 1-28-34.
—Did she give the signal?
—She started then stopped.
That’s the Portuguese
Ambassador’s car.
That moron.
Take it easy. That limo looks
just like the U.S.’s.
The U.S. doesn’t have
a little flag.
Thank God you called!
They’re still there
and their behaviour is getting weird.
No need to worry …
the car is clean,
there’s no problem with it.
Maybe there’s no problem with the car,
but there’s a problem with those people.
Take my advice, Madam. Stay away from
the window and give yourself a rest.
Do you think I’m an idiot?
I don’t need to rest.
I slept very well last night.
Mr Ambassador,
Security hasn’t arrived yet.
There were problems
with their trains.
No problem.
Let’s go anyway.
Open the door!
Open the fuckin’ door!
Put your head down!
Don’t look at me.
I knew it!
Don’t be so impatient, Paulo.
That’s the fifth time you’ve gone out.
The neighbours are gonna
get suspicious.
They’re half an hour late.
These things don’t go by the clock.
How can you be so calm?
One day, you’ll be calm too.
If I live that long—
maybe I’ll die young and nervous.
Maybe.
Don’t move,
or I’ll blow your head off!.
They’re here.
We did it! We kidnapped
the Ambassador of the United States!
We interrupt this program
for a news bulletin.
Good evening.
Today, in Rio de Janeiro,
terrorists kidnapped …
the U.S. Ambassador,
Charles Burke Elbrick.
Here is the communiqué
that was left in the embassy car.
“To the Brazilian people: revolutionary
group detained Mr Elbrick …
taking him to a place in the country,
where he will remain a prisoner.
The life or death of the Ambassador
is in the hands …
of the military dictatorship.
If they meet our demands,
the Ambassador will be freed.
If they don’t …
he will be executed.
The demands are as follows:
A) The release of 15 political
prisoners and their …
extradition to Mexico.
These are 15 revolutionaries
being tortured by the military police.
as well as humiliated
and imprisoned.
B) The publication and broadcast
of this communiqué …
in all major newspapers, radio
and television stations …
throughout the country.
The 15 prisoners must be freed …
whether or not
they have been convicted.
We realize that this is
an extraordinary request …
but we are confident …
that the Attorney General
will concede to our demands.
The dictatorship has 48 hours
to respond …
and accept our proposal.
This deadline will not
be extended …
and we won’t hesitate
in carrying out …
our promises.
Whoever wants to keep on torturing
and killing our comrades …
should be prepared.
From now on, it’s an eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth.
Signed: National Liberation Group …
and MR-8. “
I have to go now.
We’ll talk later.
You’re on vacation.
Where do you have to go?
Not now.
If you leave without talking
to me, don’t come back.
Oh, God!
Brandao? I’m going to be late.
I can’t talk now.
All right.
What do you want to know?
Where are you going?
My vacation’s over.
You saw the news on television.
So what?
You serve on a submarine.
Now I work for the Secret Service.
Since when?
Why didn’t you tell me?
It’s a secret service.
I can’t tell anyone.
You’re not doing those things
they’re talking about on television.
That’s exactly what I’m doing.
Not torturing those kids.
That too.
Why, Henrique?
It’s my job.
I was assigned to it
and I do it.
That’s all?
Why do you think I do it?
Because I want this glory
on my resume?
Try to understand.
These terrorists …
act like a group of blind people.
Nobody knows anyone
in their group.
And the few that we do know …
all use phoney names.
Either you torture them right away …
and they confess where they last met,
or there is no progress …
in your investigation.
If you don’t torture them, they win.
And if you do, they still win.
They accuse you of being barbaric.
It’s total hypocrisy, but it works.
It really works.
Then, why the insomnia?
Most of them are innocent kids
with big dreams.
God.
Kids being used by dangerous scum.
And if they get into power …
there won’t be torture,
but many executions.
You can’t shoot,
you can’t drive or follow orders …
but you write very well.
I’m very proud of you.
This is a list of things to buy.
What is this, Comrade?
A kiss, Maria.
You have a mission to carry out.
We forgot about dinner …
and you’ve been chosen
to go buy some pizzas.
—Now?
—Now.
Just water.
Fernando.
Artur!
What kind of costume is that?
It’s dress rehearsal
for Ibsen’s play.
—Are you that hungry?
—It’s for a party.
For an Ambassador?
If I were involved in that,
would I be buying pizzas?
“We realize that this is an
extraordinary request …
but we are confident—”
I recognize your style.
You overestimate me.
Do I?
How does it feel
being in the 19th century?
Closer to reality than being
in your horror show.
Kidnapping the Ambassador is like
shooting the soldier …
carrying the white flag.
Don’t be so dramatic.
You and the military seem distant
like two ends of a horseshoe, but …
actually you’re very close.
One day, everyone will know, a group
of kids picked up weapons …
to fight against the dictatorship.
That’s very important.
Not everyone’s hiding out in
A Doll’s House.
—Did you see it on television?
—What?
They kidnapped the U.S. Ambassador
right under the nose of the military.
I heard.
You heard!
What world are you living in, pal?
I’m not into politics.
Well, the guys that kidnapped
the Ambassador are very brave.
These guys and the astronauts
are my heroes.
What’s he doing here?
He’s not one of the leaders.
My English is lousy.
We need an interpreter.
The prisoner speaks Portuguese
very well.
Shut up!
You only speak
when you are questioned, understand?
Very good, Mr Elbrick.
I’ll speak slowly and don’t pretend
not to understand.
Who are the C.I.A. men in Brazil?
Do you think you’re talking
to a moron?
Aren’t you aware that
U.S. military aides …
are teaching torture
to the Brazilian military?
We are wasting our time
with this liar.
Once he feels the same pain
that the U.S. military …
is causing in Latin America …
he will talk.
What did he say?
He asks if he’ll be tortured.
No. You will be executed
with a bullet in your head …
if the dictatorship
doesn’t meet our demands.
Do you agree
with the dictatorship’s policy?
I cannot understand that kind
of behaviour.
Why threaten to torture
the Ambassador?
Does anyone intend
to carry out the threat?
Why threaten him?
So he will be frightened and talk.
He was not kidnapped to talk.
He was kidnapped to save
15 comrades in prison.
Let’s deal with the list now.
It is important that the names
chosen, represent …
all segments of the fight
against dictatorship.
This kidnapping has to be
the pinnacle in this fight.
Any suggestions?
Oswaldo.
Who’s Oswald?
Oswaldo was wounded in the bank robbery
that financed this operation.
But still, who is Oswaldo?
Oswaldo is a member of the MR-8 …
the group that thought of,
financed and—
Comrade Jonas is trying to—
I know what he’s trying to say.
Oswaldo has my vote.
And Marcão’s vote.
Does he have yours?
Yes.
Mine too.
Oswaldo’s in.
—How many, son?
—Eight.
—Eight?
—Yeah, eight.
Do you have enough money?
I could buy eighteen,
twenty, fifty!
But I only want eight.
The Globo, please.
A new group is using the name MR-8,
because we eliminated the old one.
A police report has just come in.
A young boy bought eight
roasted chickens …
and paid with a lot of cash.
The grocer thinks the boy
is involved with robbers.
Eight chickens?
Yeah. We asked the police
to report anything unusual.
Let’s investigate.
If the police had listened to
that complaint on Marques St … .
we wouldn’t be in this mess.
Five kidnappers were seen,
one of them was really young.
Get the address of the grocer.
Any news about the demands?
Nothing yet.
There will be a rash of kidnappings
if we concede.
So, should we let the Ambassador die?
Journal of Brazil. Good morning.
—Editorial room, please.
—One moment, please.
A list with the names of the
15 prisoners to be exchanged …
for the U.S. Ambassador and a letter
from him to his wife …
are in the collection box inside
the church in downtown Rio. Repeat.
I voted for Oswaldo
because he was a friend.
You voted wrong.
He didn’t have the courage
to shoot the guard.
That’s what they told me.
—Yeah, he did hesitate—
—That’s what I’m saying.
More courageous Comrades
were left behind …
because of bourgeois sentimentality.
But he was already in.
That doesn’t matter.
You shouldn’t vote
to please other people.
You’re right. I made a mistake.
You’re brave, Júlio.
I’m proud of you.
Thank you.
Your opinion means a lot to me.
What if the military doesn’t agree
to our demands?
We’ll kill the gringo, of course.
Can I carry that out?
I know you’d do it without hesitation,
but I have someone else in mind.
Who?
Comrade Paulo.
He’s a good talker.
But he has to prove something else.
It’s just between you and I.
Did you find a good apartment?
—Two.
—Where?
I don’t want to know the address.
The newspaper has the list
and the Ambassador’s letter.
—Everything’s okay?
—Yes.
Toledo, what’s that?
Spanish rice.
You’re all so lazy and
I’m tired of eating junk food.
—I did one stupid thing.
—What?
The church is only two blocks away
from my old job.
No problem.
“Prison Diaries of Ho Chi Minh”
The only clue I can give you
is that …
my delivery man thinks that the kid
lives in a house on Petropolis Street.
Can we talk to him?
Not until tomorrow morning,
when he makes the deliveries.
Do you know where he lives?
I think I have his address.
Excuse me.
—Who was it?
—Nobody was at the door.
What’s the matter?
The two men from the phone company.
—They could be from the phone company.
—No way.
Look at their faces.
They’re both clean-shaven!
You’re right.
How did they find us so fast?
Those guys are pros.
Ours is an amateur group.
If that’s the place, they must have
taken the tunnel to get up here.
The garage probably connects
to the house.
Yes. The house is perfect.
Lots of rooms, a quiet street.
If this is the house,
where would the Ambassador be?
Second floor …  in the back?
Renée, answer it.
I would like to speak to Desiree,
please …
There is no one here by that name.
—Is this 225-8716?
—That’s right.
But she gave me this number.
Is this 105 Petropolis Street?
It’s the right address,
but there’s nobody by that name here.
Leave it off the hook.
—What did you see?
—What’s going on?
Speak to us.
We have visitors. Tell Paulo to come
and you watch the gringo.
If you hear a gunshot, shoot the man.
No mercy.
Maria, you and Renée stay here
for backup.
Marcão, you come outside with me.
—May I help you?
—Please, can I speak to Eduardo?
—There’s no Eduardo living here.
—No? Really?
But isn’t this 105 Petropolis Street?
Yes, but there’s no Eduardo.
We were invited for lunch.
Could I use your phone?
I don’t have a phone.
Sorry to bother you …
—Good luck with your lunch.
—Thanks.
Follow them.
Now?
Now. Find out where they go
and who they are.
—It’s them. I recognize that guy.
—Me, too.
We have pictures of him speaking
at student meetings.
They screwed up, buying take-out food.
If they only knew how to cook.
A bunch of lazy middle class—
The son of a bitch is following us.
Let him come.
We’re going to let them know
they’re surrounded.
It’s time to make them sweat.
—I don’t know. The Commander—
—Fuck the Commander.
If the Military Junta accepts the
demands, we’ll go to plan B.
Commander, we found the house.
We recognized the guy
who answered the door.
Do you know the name
of the owner of the house?
The stakeout is almost finished.
I think they’re suspicious.
They didn’t let us in and
they denied having a phone.
I’ll wait for your orders.
Open the door.
They already know we are here.
That’s not important.
They’re not going to invade the house …
because they don’t want
the Ambassador to die.
But they still haven’t
given us an answer.
What if they don’t agree
to our demands?
The deadline expires—
Tonight at 10 p.m.
I’m going to read to you
a segment of our document.
“This deadline will not be extended
and we will …
not hesitate in carrying out
our promise.”
We have to decide who’s going
to carry out the execution.
Comrade Jonas is the commander.
I’m not going to choose.
The Ambassador will be executed …
by whoever is with him
at ten o’clock tonight.
He’ll be killed by whoever is on duty.
In other words, by all of us.
That’s Paulo’s shift.
Congratulations.
If necessary, I know you will
carry out what you wrote.
Thank you.
Two bullets in the head at ten sharp.
I won’t stand for any delays.
The sentence will be carried out or
there will be two dead instead of one.
Understood?
He changed the shifts.
Why did he do that?
It’s not important. Either the military
accepts our demands by 10 p.m. or …
they’ll storm the house.
No one will get out alive.
Did you think we’d go this far?
ARMY HUNTING DOWN KIDNAPPERS
Yeah, sure …  no, I didn’t.
Maria, do you think they’re gonna
let the Ambassador die ?
No.
I’m not sure.
I’m afraid of dying.
I don’t want to die.
I would rather go to jail.
Sometimes I dream that I’m in jail
and I feel so relieved.
I know your name …
Fernando, isn’t it?
I heard you speak at a student rally.
You spoke so well!
I admired you.
Comrade, you’re completely
irresponsible.
My name is Andrea.
—Did you hear about Pecanha?
—Who?
—Sergeant Pecanha.
—No. What?
—He married Marta.
—Marta who?
That skinny redhead.
The terrorist?
That’s the one. They got married
and are moving to the suburbs.
Pecanha really got into
torturing people.
He found a passion he never had
when he was a bureaucrat.
And Marta was always his favourite.
We opened up Pandora’s box.
We shouldn’t have done it.
Things got out of control.
Do you sleep okay?
I sleep fine.
I don’t.
I’ve been dreaming about things
hanging upside down.
He put on the glasses.
—Give me the hood.
—You’re gonna wear it?
I won’t kill a blind man. He has the
right to know that he’s going to die.
They accepted our demands.
They are releasing the prisoners.
We won.
We interrupt this program
for a news bulletin.
The Reuters Agency just released
this wire photo …
of the arrival in Mexico City …
of the 15 prisoners freed in exchange
for the kidnapped U.S. Ambassador …
Charles Burke Elbrick.
—We did it?
—We did it.
Be careful, son.
Be careful.
It’s a great game!
Maracana Stadium is sold out!
They’re following us.
Oh, my God! Get the machine gun.
Fifteen made it to Mexico,
but these seven aren’t going anywhere.
We’re being followed!
Oh, shit!
Marcão, there’s a police car behind us.
What are you trying to do …
kill the Ambassador?
The coast is clear.
Put that back in the bag.
I hear a helicopter.
If they think they can follow us
from up there, they’re crazy.
Go to the soccer stadium.
The game’s just ended.
Get lost, gringo.
—I have the Ambassador here.
—The Ambassador! Open the gate!
The Sergeant told me to call you,
if I found something unusual.
Maria, one month without seeing you …
hidden, hunted and wanted.
I need to see you.
I don’t care about the rules
of being safe.
I need to see you.
I heard that in Gil’s latest record …
he shouts the name “Marighella”
in the middle of a song.
So what?
It’s important.
The name of a revolutionary leader
in the middle of a pop song.
That’s important.
Do you think that’s true?
I heard that if you listen
to it backwards …
he says “Marighella” quite clearly.
No one listens to a record backwards.
It was a dream that failed.
We’re shouting into the wind.
Your name is not Maria. It’s Andrea.
You should’ve invited me
to lunch, Fernando.
Only my friends eat in my house.
The world has turned
upside down, Fernando.
Fernando, the kidnapping of
the German Ambassador gives me hope.
I wonder if you are also on the list
of prisoners to be exchanged.
Maybe I will see you
when we’re sent to Algeria.
Jonas and Toledo are dead.
As for me, don’t be concerned
about what you’re going to see.