Just a few minutes past
7:00 in the morning.
Hi, I'm Jeff Gonzer.
It's time to wake up.
- I know that you feel that it's completely...
- Wrong.
No, but you're ready
to wake up, aren't you?
- Yes, Jeffrey.
- That's good,
'cause it's going to be
a beautiful day today,
temperatures in the mid-70s in the city,
a little cooler near the beaches and
warmer in the valleys, as always...
Look it, you gotta wake up. No arguing.
It's time to stick your finger in your
third eye at least to wake yourself up.
You even have to get your dog awake.
It's just time to wake up.
Everybody, get up!
Hey. Shake your booty.
Jeanie, don't stay in there.
I'm not even in there yet.
Oh, Christ. We gotta wake up Annie.
Annie? Annie, wake up.
- Is Annie awake?
- Not yet.
I didn't even hear her come in.
I was totally vegged.
Yeah, she was sick all
over some guy's car.
Yeah? From what?
Quaaludes. Beer. Wine.
Some real heavy kind of pills.
Poor thing.
Teenage dopers. What a waste.
Don't do that.
The Three Stooges,
they always just sort of throw it.
She can't do that. She'll drown.
I'm only saying that's what
the Three Stooges always do.
I'm not saying she should do it, okay?
Yeah, well, you know,
she ditches one more time, that's it.
They're just gonna flunk her
and throw her out in the street.
Forget it.
- What's that mean?
- I mean, what the shit?
- Please.
- She doesn't care if she never wakes up.
- Hi.
- Hey.
What are you guys looking at?
Oh, my gosh.
- You're not gonna eat that, are you?
- I am really hungry.
It's really disgusting. Yeah.
And then tomorrow you're gonna complain.
You just take that and
rub it in your thighs.
You're such a dummy.
You're hilarious.
Get your hands off of there.
I'm gonna eat it.
But I want it.
You guys are really pissed at me.
How's your head?
A whole bunch of people just moved in.
I think I'm gonna barf.
- You don't look sick.
- Well, I am.
I just got a case of the munchies.
Anybody want to ditch sixth
period and go to the beach?
I got a hair appointment at Saks.
Thought you said I couldn't ditch.
That's just Phys. Ed.
You can ditch that.
What're you gonna do with your hair?
Mom's after me to have it chopped
so I can look like Dorothy Hammill.
What?
Like, she doesn't dig me
wearing her clothes, you know,
and having all the guys
think I'm mature, okay.
Like they'd be coming on to me
and not looking at her.
Get 'em to chop your
head instead, Deirdre.
That's pretty retarded,
considering who it was sick all
over that guy's car last night.
- Who cares?
- He cares. Don't you care?
I don't even know him.
Besides, it was this
really gross Trans Am
with some jerkoff dragon blowing
smoke all over the hood.
- Was he cute?
- Who?
The geek in the car, geekaloid.
The only geek I know
is Randy Teratunian.
- So?
- You're the one thinks he's hot.
- I do not.
- You said you wanted to go with him.
I never said I want to go with him.
I said I want to ball him.
Excuse me.
Did you tell your Dad that you were
staying over my house last night?
I gotta call him.
Guess what? For an elaborate change,
we are late again.
- I don't believe this.
- God.
- I do not believe this.
- Come on.
I'm always getting tardies.
- Anybody seen my keys?
- No, not again!
- Have you seen the keys?
- I don't know.
My keys!
Where'd you leave 'em?
Who knows? It's not my house.
Can I listen to Abbey Road?
Whenever I need to mellow out,
I always listen to my Mom's Abbey Road.
We're going to school, retardo.
When I'm 18, I'm gonna shine that place.
Well, you're 16 now.
Ain't that a bitch?
- Where are you going?
- To school.
Leave the keys.
- Why?
- Because you can't take the truck.
- We'll talk about it later.
- How come?
We'll talk when you
come home from school.
That's unfair.
Come right back.
Can't we talk about it now?
No, please. I don't
want to start anything.
Well, I don't want to have
to worry all day that
you're just gonna pull
some big number later.
The school called.
Oh, God, I don't want to
talk about this now.
I know, Child Development.
You've been cutting.
It's just Child Development, Mom.
It's so stupid. You wouldn't believe it.
- Jeanie.
- Can I just have the keys?
- Please?
- Jeanie, I don't want to have a bad day.
Well, it's my truck, you know.
Dad gave it to me.
This is Sam.
My daughter, Jeanie.
Hello.
Hi.
Jesus, Deirdre, this is gross.
I don't know what I'm going
to do about this shit.
- We're walking.
- No!
God, you know what
I hate about this place?
When some place is too small,
you can never find anything.
I should go to New York and live
in a loft, become a painter.
I need space,
like 20 foot ceilings, you know?
Really, let's all go to New York
and open a boutique.
Yeah.
Dad!
Dad, please!
That guy is sick.
What are we gonna do?
Call the cops?
You're lifting the child by the leg.
You are not savages!
Take the child gently, ever so gently!
We show our babies love
and our babies grow up in love.
That's a rubber doll, Mrs. Steiner.
Excuse me.
You want a hit?
I'm a mother.
All right!
Creep.
- Don't you want to say hello?
- Hello, Scott.
- Wait a minute. Did you miss me?
- How's Susan?
Susan Halpern?
You know any other Susans?
Come on, I mean, so her folks invited us
to the beach for the weekend.
They were there the whole time.
And they never took
their eyes off of you.
Well, yeah. Sort of.
Hey, Jeanie, like your new hairdo.
It's not new, Mr. Symonds.
- Will you come to the office?
- Yeah, sure.
Wait a minute.
Don't I even get a kiss?
You think I want Susan
Halpern's bacteria?
- They were fighting.
- Something racial?
- No. A girl.
- Thank God.
- Do you know where Annie is?
- Nope.
- No idea?
- No.
Her dad's looking for her, you know.
No. I mean, I don't.
You see, I'd like to talk to her first,
find out what's going on in her head.
Then maybe I could smooth things
out with her dad. He's...
Crazy.
Angry.
He thinks she should go to a hospital.
- Where?
- A private hospital.
Someplace out in Sun Valley.
You mean, a mental hospital.
They work with lots of runaway girls.
She doesn't run away anymore.
She's been gone for a week.
But she's been at my house. Ask my mom.
I know, honey. But the guy's
her dad. He's worried.
You know why her sister ran off?
Really, Mr. Symonds, do you know?
He put handcuffs on her because
she got pregnant by some guy
and he acts like she's some sort
of fallen woman or something.
All she wanted to do was
go out and get an abortion.
No shit, Mr. Symonds.
Yeah, I know. The guy gets really angry.
Yeah.
Really, man.
I mean, how's Annie supposed to
become your well-adjusted teenager?
If she got right with her dad,
then she'd really be fucked.
For sure.
If she got so he thought that
she was like really A-Okay,
she'd have to become a policewoman.
She should have someplace
to go, you know.
Where?
Well, I don't know.
Sometimes I think it's
like 1:00 in the morning
and you just had a fight with your
mom and there's no place to go.
Someplace with like pillows around,
a little music,
some people to talk to.
That sort of thing, you know?
Someplace of our own, you know?
- Hey, Brad!
- Hey, hi.
- Where you been?
- I've been working.
Yeah? Aren't you going to school?
No, I got a job filling
up fire extinguishers.
- Have you seen Annie?
- Yeah.
- Where?
- On the bus.
- That bus?
- Yeah.
- Hey!
- Hey, bus! Dumb bus! Dumb fucker bus!
Hey, you sure you saw her?
Yeah. She wanted me to hang
with her, but I got to go to work.
Well, did she say where she was going?
Hollyweird.
You're lying. She's on probation.
Hollywood Boulevard is a bozo no-no.
That's what her parole officer said.
If you're lying,
you're really a low character.
Excuse me.
A major injury accident,
a collision on the Golden State Freeway
northbound on the Glendale Freeway
and San Diego Freeway
northbound north of Avalon.
Bruce Wayne, KFI in...
You're Dragon, aren't you?
Have you seen Annie?
Annie Mallick? You used to know her.
God, Jeanie, I don't know how
you can even talk to that guy.
I mean, like, he looks like,
he could hypnotize you like a
cobra or something, you know.
And the next thing,
you're out on the Boulevard
and you're dressed like
the Pointer Sisters.
I knew Annie wouldn't be here.
She's not that bananas.
I don't know.
- Hey, there's Mary!
- Who's she?
She's in my floral arrangement class.
Jeez, what a weirdo.
- Mary Weirdo.
- The Merry Weirdo.
Hey! Annie! Annie! There's Annie!
- Annie!
- Jeanie!
Jeanie! It's Jeanie!
Come on! Get in the car!
I'm walking my dog!
What, on Hollywood Boulevard?
I just found him! This is Loser's belt.
Just get in the car, okay?
Hey, baby, move it, will you?
You talking to me?
No, creep, you ain't my baby.
You don't talk to my woman like that.
Come on, just move it, will you, friend?
I ain't your friend.
You're busting my asshole, asshole.
Come on! Get in!
Jeanie!
You're on probation, you dumb shit.
You're supposed to stay out of Hollywood.
Loser was taking me home.
Well, just stay away from Loser.
He's in a street club.
I just wanted to get home and see
my mom before my dad gets there.
Yeah, he wants to put you in a hospital!
- A hospital?
- For severe maniacs.
He can't do that.
He can't?
I'm totally freaked.
You see your dad's car?
- Nope.
- And what about your mom's?
No, she doesn't have a car.
Okay.
Oh, man.
We were going to call, Mrs. Mallick.
I mean, my mom was gonna call.
Mom wants to know if
Annie could stay over our
house for a couple of days.
If that's okay with you.
Just so long as her dad doesn't come
along with a straitjacket or something.
If you wouldn't tell him where she is,
I'd really appreciate it.
I don't tell the man nothing.
I can't feel sorry for my mom.
Not while she takes shit from my dad.
Is this what you call barbeque flavor?
All right, let's check this out.
Here.
Gross!
You know, he's not really my dad.
Since when?
- It's true.
- No kidding?
Remember the flower children
that all the time used to do acid?
I was like 11.
I dropped acid and it all came out.
You know that guy, that cop?
He ain't my dad.
I saw my real dad. No shit.
- What'd he look like?
- Really cool.
A cross between Cary Grant
and the mighty Thor.
He was a motocross biker.
I don't see Cary Grant on a bike.
He was.
He was so beautiful.
You're crazy.
Hot breath.
Okay, now just cool it.
You know, just shine him.
Is that all you're eating?
Would you girls kindly
talk to each other?
What's wrong with her?
What's always wrong with her?
Please.
Forty-one cents, please.
- She's paying for it.
- All of this?
This okay?
That'll be fine. Thank you.
Thank you, Greg.
Greg.
Yeah. Greg.
Hey. Stick the goodies
in the goodie bag.
I want to get out alive!
Just as long as it's not someplace
in the Valley, you know?
I've been thinking someplace
in the hills, you know?
With, like, avocado trees everywhere,
and a really great sound system.
- As long as the neighbors don't complain.
- Yeah.
Well, I don't know what I'd tell my mom.
Well, just tell her with all the
money she's getting for alimony...
She doesn't get alimony anymore
since she married Franklin.
- She gets child support.
- Yeah, I guess.
Well, you're the child, dummy.
It belongs to you.
Well, what about me?
My folks are still together.
Maybe they're about to break up.
God, Annie, don't say that!
Just tell her you need
a family unit, you know?
Because you haven't especially
got a family unit right now.
No, Franklin isn't
exactly a family unit.
Hey, I don't want you guys going through
this big number just 'cause of me.
What number?
Moving out. Finding a place of our own.
Well, you know, it's not just for you.
My mother would love it.
She's all the time talking about how
she's such a young woman and all.
God, my folks,
I don't know what they'd say.
They never think that
I should do anything.
Well, why don't you just tell them that
you're spending all your time at my house?
At least in the beginning.
Sometimes they make me feel
so incredibly juvenile. I hate it.
Hello, may I speak with Greg, please?
It's an emergency.
I'm calling from the hospital.
No, no, but pretty serious.
Not really. But pretty.
God, I look like shit!
I know you don't remember me,
but I was in your store today.
Deirdre Thompkins. I just bought
this little container of yogurt.
You know, I was thinking of some place,
like, with two windows on either side.
- That was Mexican lace.
- One in the morning where I could write.
And one in the afternoon
where I could paint.
I'm surprised you remember.
Jeanie, do you think we could do that?
I don't know. I gotta ask my dad, 'cause
if I tell my mother about the child support,
she's just gonna freak.
You see, I have well, that is,
I had these two tickets to the
Angel concert for tonight.
But I lost them and I thought,
maybe I might have dropped them
near your cashier stand.
You haven't.
Drats.
I mean, I looked through my purse
and everything. I mean, like...
Let me just look again, okay?
Oh, my God! Am I embarrassed!
I don't know how to tell you this,
but I feel so stupid.
I mean, I just found them in my purse.
I mean, I already told my date he's not
my boyfriend or anything, you know.
He's just my date.
But I already told him we couldn't go
and he's already gone down to
Newport Beach or something.
- Oh, God!
- What? What?
Oh, God, Greg. Well...
I don't know, I mean,
if you'd like, but,
you hardly know whether
you would like me.
No, no, no. I'm getting there in a
car with some of my dear friends.
But I could meet you in the lobby.
The Shrine Auditorium.
About 8:00?
Wonderful!
What're you gonna tell Bobby?
You broke your leg?
Hello Mrs. Koch? Hi, it's Deirdre.
Can I talk to Bobby, please?
He left already?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I went to Elaine's
and then I saw Princess
Lee Radziwell, right?
And I said, "Hey..."
Hey, Princess Lee, what're you trying
to do, make me sick or something.
- Look!
- Right on.
Hey, you fine thing!
Hey, you got any tickets you wanna sell?
Wanna buy some ludes?
Anything you want, baby.
Not from you, slime.
- Dykes!
Dykes!
Baby!
Kissy, kissy!
- Yes, yes, yes!
- Come on, girls!
- Why don't you stop, please?
- Why?
To check your purse.
Pull it down, please.
Come on. Where you guys been?
The first group's already on. Let's go.
Good evening.
Look, we're missing Heavy Waters.
Skip says they're dynamite.
I see you got your tickets okay.
Yeah. Thanks.
You don't have to thank me.
I mean, my dad gets these
tickets for free, right?
- Hi, Scott. How's tricks?
- Hi.
Hey, who's Skip?
- A surfer.
- What's wrong with that?
Let's shoot the curl, man.
She okay?
Maybe you better go on in
and check out the seats.
I already did.
They're dynamite. Come on.
Dynamite...
You got an attitude, you know?
Why don't you just try
and be sweet, okay?
I'm not going in by myself.
Why not?
'Cause you're with me.
- I mean, you're...
- What?
You used to be my girl.
Hey, Jeanie! There's your main man!
Here's your guy!
- Hey, there's Bobby.
- Where?
Okay, Dee. Do your stuff.
- Hi.
- Hi, Deirdre. Am I late?
Who are you?
Who is he?
Bobby, Bobby.
I got to talk to you, okay?
Come on. Come here.
I've got to talk to you.
Are you sick or something?
Here. Why don't you sit down?
Have you ever known me to shit you?
Yeah, all the time.
Well, this is the one time that
I'm not going to, all right?
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah. It's Annie.
She's really sick.
She doesn't look sick.
Well, that's 'cause she's not talking
to the blonde guy over there.
- I'm going in.
- No, no! Look, see...
We tried to distract her mind, right?
So we line her up with this guy
and she takes one look at him, right?
She totally freaks.
She thinks he looks like her dad.
- And she almost pulled...
- He doesn't look anything like her dad.
Well sure he does. I mean, he's got like
the whole cop thing going for him.
She almost pulled a whole self-destruct
thing right on the spot!
Bullshit!
And, well, you know that she's
always had this thing for you and...
Since when?
Since she was 12 years old!
Don't you remember?
She always thought that you
were like all four Beach Boys
rolled into one pair
of flippers, you know?
- You're a lying bitch.
- Yeah, and you're Annie's date.
Well, what about Deirdre?
She's being kind.
- Yeah?
- She agreed to sit with Greg.
For Annie.
You gotta keep it low, keep it low.
Two bucks.
Do you want a lude?
Hey, what's going on?
Hi.
- Where are you sitting?
- With Annie.
I'm her date.
Well, fuck you guys.
What's wrong with him?
I don't know.
Watch 'em move
Watch 'em shake it down
All right!
Strolling to the beat
To the beat of the song
They're looking good
Like foxes should
Dancing to the music
All night long!
No one can do it
Better than they can
Twentieth Century Foxes!
Hanging tough through thick and thin
They're stepping out
Stepping out of...
You get your tickets, all right?
Yeah, thanks.
My friends say thanks, too.
- All right. How's your mom?
- She's okay. I was hoping...
- Dad, can I ask you something?
- Yeah, of course.
- He's on the bass.
- Good. Okay.
Oh, God, we gotta go
to Seattle tomorrow.
Three nights in a football field.
Dad...
I'm sorry. Go on, ask.
Maybe after the concert.
Come on. We'll go in here.
Oh, Christ.
Here.
Are you that unhappy?
It's not that, Dad. It's just...
We want some place where we can
help each other, you know?
Look, why won't it wait until
I come back into town, eh?
I'm gonna be here all through Christmas.
We'll see a lot of each other.
Anyway, I want you to meet Sandra.
Did you meet Sandra?
- No.
- Good God, what a cook!
Her Japanese is superb. You'll like her.
Just a minute. Give us a minute. Please.
Getting any rest?
What you ought to do?
You ought to go out and get a
nice little place for you and Mom
in the Valley with some trees around it.
I'll pay for it.
Mom likes where she is.
I'm talking about me, Dad.
What a bummer.
Living in a place like that
with all those dead plants.
Look, it's not gonna take much.
It just means the child
support bit, that's all.
Look, I can't mess with that!
Those lawyers would roast me,
wouldn't they?
You need any money or
anything for clothes?
No, I'm okay.
Look. Stick with Mom.
Christ, it's bad enough
having an absentee dad.
- I don't mind.
- I do.
Look, I'll tell you what.
At Christmas,
let's go back up on to the ranch.
Come on.
One of these days I'm gonna
buy out Zak and the other guys.
You and me can own the ranch.
We'll get rid of all
those crazies up there.
Just you and I
and lots of your friends.
And well get some horses in.
Plenty of horses.
It'd be great, wouldn't it?
Yeah.
Waste the night away!
Can I stay with you tonight, Annie?
I'm staying at Jeanie's.
Well, can I stay with you?
What do you mean?
Can I sleep with you?
God, Brad. What if I meet someone slick?
You know, you really
are shitty sometimes.
'Cause I won't sleep with you?
We've known each other
practically forever.
- Can I stay with you?
- Me?
I told my dad I wasn't coming home.
You want to... Jesus, Brad.
It wouldn't be bad.
Jeanie?
- Duke! Duke! There's Duke!
- Hey, don't! Will you let go?
- Honk the horn! Honk the horn.
- Would you quit it?
- Hey, Annie, what about my party?
- Duke!
Hey! How you been?
- Oh, crap.
- Shit.
It's all over with Scott, huh?
Guess so.
You know, you've been together
with him for three years.
- It's too much.
- Yeah.
You know, when I first met him
I was so much in love with him
that every time I saw him, I'd cry.
He couldn't figure it out.
"Hi," he'd say, and I'd just blubber.
It was really weird.
I bought this necklace,
this bracelet for him in Laguna.
I never had the guts to give it to him.
Then finally, when we got together,
I never gave it to him, because it
reminded me so much of him that
I just didn't want to
let it go, you know?
He sure has changed
since he got the van.
Changed since he got the hair blower.
Guess you don't feel
much like my party, huh?
Yeah, why not?
Jeanie, there's a lot of other guys.
Yeah? Like who, for instance?
Lots.
- Lots of egos.
- No.
Out of control egos.
You know about guys.
What's that supposed to mean?
I mean you've slept with guys.
A lot.
I slept with a couple of guys in
ninth grade, 'cause it was new.
But I'm not some total
dingbat like Deirdre.
Okay.
- I'm no Suzy Slut, you know what I mean?
- Yeah.
- I slept with a guy once.
- What?
We didn't do anything or anything.
We just slept.
I mean, he held me so tight my
nose was pushed against his neck.
I thought I was going to suffocate.
Who was this guy? The Boston Strangler?
You don't know him.
He's a much older guy.
You been sticking your nose in
somebody's neck, and I don't know him?
- God! We used to be friends.
- Come on!
Hey, sis.
What are you guys doing here?
Mother!
What are these guys doing here?
God, what a cry baby.
I'm gonna get furious at you.
- "I'm gonna get furious at you!"
- Sissie!
Put 'em up.
Okay, kids! In the kitchen, quick!
Scoot!
- Hi, Jeanie.
- Hi, Mrs. Axman.
What's the fuss?
Mom, you know I don't want
a bunch of kids at my party.
Okay, okay. Your friends
aren't kids anymore, huh?
Mom! I don't expect you to understand.
Come on. You know and I know that
that's malarkey, Miss Smart.
- Jeanie, turn that off, will you?
- Sure.
We'd just as well sit down and talk out
the ground rules of a few things
before your friends get here.
- I don't want a lecture now.
- I didn't say lecture.
In front of Jeanie and everything?
Jeanie, you want a beer?
There's a keg in the kitchen.
No thanks.
Let's all sit down.
Mom, I'm trying to get my head
into having a good time, okay?
If you're gonna go and spoil it...
Come on and laugh a little,
for damn sake!
Dad and I got the keg of beer, which I still
can't believe, but damned if we didn't.
When the party gets started,
we're gonna go on to bed.
You'll have the house.
What if I told you some of
the people don't drink beer?
They drink other stuff.
What people? You mean
your high school friends?
Well, they drink Scotch and
tequila and stuff like that.
You drink Scotch, Madge?
No. But I could if I wanted.
I could drink it for breakfast.
You drink Scotch, Jeanie?
No. I don't like Scotch.
They're bringing Scotch tonight?
Maybe. I don't tell them what to bring.
I'm not their mother.
Well, well, it's gonna be some party.
Maybe Dad and I should
go out of town tonight.
That way everybody wouldn't
have a mother around.
You're just going to make it impossible!
Everybody could get real drunk
on Scotch and have a free time.
A real sexual time, maybe.
- Did you call me?
- No!
Go to the kitchen, Sissie!
- I want to hear!
- Go!
It's so unreal. Why do they
always have to talk about sex?
It's not me, it's you. Your friends,
they're all talking about it.
They're having affairs in
junior high school. Oh, my God.
You don't think that we can
have any serious emotion, huh?
That any of us can experience
something really deep?
Jeanie, she's been in love since she was 12.
And I'll bet you don't even believe it!
I don't want you to think
I was born on another planet.
When Dad and I were going together,
we experimented.
Yes, we did. More than once.
I can't lie to you.
Mom, you don't have
to get into this, okay?
But I always wished that we hadn't.
That we waited.
You don't understand. I have.
- I've waited.
- What do you mean?
I mean I'm a virgin.
What's wrong with that?
- I hate it.
- Thank God!
Sissie, bring your mother a beer!
Come on, Mom.
What're we gonna do with her?
We're not gonna have a party.
We sure as shooting are!
Madge says were not.
If you don't come out and say hi to
your friends, I'm sending them away.
If I send them all away,
you are going to have to
call everyone and apologize.
And until you do...
You are making me furious, Madge!
Until you make an apology on the
phone to everyone of your friends
who comes by here tonight,
you are grounded!
You can bank on it!
Yeah. I think Angel's
real cute, you know?
That punk movement, they're a bunch of
retards with safety pins in their faces...
- But Angel's good.
- Yeah.
Gotta go home. The party's off!
Where's Madge?
- She's grounded.
- How come?
She's a virgin.
Hi.
How was the concert?
Fine.
I saw Dad.
How was he?
Fine.
What's wrong, Mom?
I just read this frigging
page five times.
How come you're not asleep?
Because I have a test tomorrow.
And I study for my tests.
Your dad thinks that if I get a degree that
I'll be smart enough to leave him alone.
Did you do your homework?
I don't have any. It's the weekend.
I got this crazy idea that
you'll go to college,
you'll read a lot of books.
You'll become this brainy person.
You'll know how to talk to
neurotics like your mother.
How's your friend?
- Sam?
- He seems nice.
He's with his wife.
- Ex-wife. He's divorced.
- That's cool.
He's taking me to lunch tomorrow.
Did he take you to dinner last night?
What does that mean?
Nothing. Forget it.
I'm a 40-year-old woman and I'm
sitting here reading Plato again.
It's insane!
No, he didn't take me
to dinner last night.
And he didn't take me to dinner
tonight like he said he would
because his ex-wife called
and he wasn't free to go.
So he apologized.
What for?
Sure, I should have had dinner with him
first and found what his intentions were.
If they were honorable or not.
I was too busy throwing
myself at some guy.
Like all the other divorced,
desperate UCLA undergraduates.
But I did it 'cause it felt good,
'cause I wanted to. Okay?
Okay.
Shit. I'm sorry.
I can't focus again.
You gotta get your prescription checked.
I know. I keep meaning to.
Right there.
I would've loved Plato.
He and his friends,
none of them liked to wear shoes.
"Thus far I have been speaking of
the fourth and last kind of madness
"which is imputed to him who,
when he sees the beauty of the earth
"is transported with
the recollection..."
...the manager of the Shoe Stop shoe store
on Hacienda Boulevard in La Puente.
Good morning, Shoe Stop. May I help you?
I have a hobby. I like to chew on shoes.
- It's something usually I do at home, but...
- You like to what?
Chew on shoes.
Today is my day off
and I wondered whether I
could come down to Shoe Stop
and just chew on some of the
shoes down there for a while.
Get out of here or I'll
personally kill you.
I don't take them home.
I mean, I'm not gonna wear them.
Is it going to be noticeable?
If another customer comes in
and wants that shoe to wear,
is it gonna be noticeable
that somebody nibbled on it?
Are your shoes that quality shoes that
somebody's gonna care that much?
- Don't.
- Yes, they are.
I mean, we don't carry junk here.
You do have terrific prices down
there because it is self-service.
Yes.
The shoes would sell
elsewhere for $20 or $16.90?
- Yeah, that's correct.
- I'm at a pay phone right around the corner.
Why don't you let me come over...
All right. Why don't you come over now?
I have some shoes at the back.
We'll talk about it.
I mean, if somebody's gonna eat shoes,
they might as well eat the best. Right?
That's right.
Jay? Are you leaving?
Just to New York. For a week.
I've been calling your place for weeks.
I couldn't call back.
Well, why? I mean, I was like dying.
Mom thinks I'm going with Terry.
She likes him 'cause he smiles a lot.
It's obnoxious.
What's wrong with me?
You know.
The age thing.
- For a change.
- I'm 16.
Doesn't matter. I mean,
my grandmother was having babies at 16.
Well, Sheila had a baby at 16.
Yeah, my grandmother was married.
Well, she didn't want to marry the guy.
Okay, okay. Don't get mad.
I want to ask you a question.
Do you really love me?
- That's the question?
- No, I'm getting to that.
But I want to know that first.
I'm in love with you.
You know what that means?
Yeah, it means you throw up a lot.
No, seriously.
Every time I listen to the radio,
every song I hear is about you.
I've been sick a lot.
What's the question?
Well, I know how we didn't
actually do anything that night
because you have this tremendous
amount of respect for me.
I appreciate it.
Like you say, you don't
want to rush into anything,
not when you feel so deeply about
somebody and everything, but...
Yeah?
What would have been so wrong with it?
What?
If we made love.
Would it have been so terrible?
Well, no.
What time does your plane leave?
They got planes going
all day to New York.
Hello?
Jeanie? Hi.
I've been a terrible friend to you.
I've been keeping a secret from you.
It's just about the most
important secret in my life.
I feel terrible. I'm in love.
A guy named Jay. You don't know him.
He's much older.
Yeah, guess what?
I'm in his bed now. Yeah.
Madge?
Did you cry?
What the hell, maybe I will.
He says if I want why don't
I spend all my time here?
Except when he's out of town,
and then he says everybody can stay here.
Yeah, Annie, too. Annie's cool.
Well, he wants to meet you, too.
But I'll talk to you later, okay?
Okay. Yeah, okay. Bye.
- That was Madge.
- I heard.
Things like that can really
make you sad, you know?
Yeah. The day your best
friend gets de-virginized.
No, it's not that.
She's the type of girl that...
She goes to bed with a guy once
and that's it, she's gonna marry him.
Come on. A girl gets married at 16,
she'd have to be real ugly.
We'll probably never see her again.
You know, I'm not gonna
get married until I'm 26.
Maybe I'll have a baby and then
decide if I really need the guy.
But not before I'm 26.
What are you gonna do up until then?
Just what I'm doing now.
Have a good time.
Good time.
This is making me sick.
I hope Jay doesn't mind us
using all his logs.
Nah, he won't mind.
- Wait a minute.
- Shit.
We gonna have a fire again?
- We're trying.
- Isn't it awful hot?
Didn't you like the
fire we had last night?
Yeah, it was like Camp Fire Girls.
A lot of the old songs.
When you got a home,
you gotta have a hearth.
Okay. Here we go.
God, look at this!
Look what you did to my floor.
It's Jay's floor.
We better get a vacuum
and clean this shit up.
Hi.
- Yellow Zonkers. Fiddle Faddle.
- Caramel.
- Twinkies!
- LAY'S!
- Look at this!
- Wheat Thins?
I'm on a diet.
- What's this?
- Malt liquor.
This is supposed to be a dinner,
not a football game.
- Go yourself next time!
- You're the only one with an ID.
- Where's the cream cheese?
- I ran out of money.
No dip? Thirteen bucks and no dip?
I don't believe you, Deirdre.
God, what a gimp.
No dip?
Fuck you all, okay?
I'm the only one who has to go to the
store all the time and buy that stuff.
And my mom doesn't even
know where I am for sure.
She sounded really worried on the phone.
Come on, Dee.
I don't even know what we're doing here.
This is a place of our own, you know?
A family sort of.
Wait right here.
Maybe I should go
home for a little while.
Look, Dee, forget your mom, you know?
When you go out in the world,
it gets scary sometimes.
Learn to laugh a little.
Yeah. Why don't we ever have a party?
A party without Jay?
Forget it.
I'm sorry. I'll be right back.
Hey! This is dumb.
Jeanie?
How about a little something
for those glasses?
- Shit!
- Annie!
Terry?
Carter? Here you go. Greg?
Thanks.
Greg?
Need anything from the kitchen?
Yeah, just you, Deirdre.
I think this occasion calls for a toast.
Great. Carter has this
tremendous speaking voice.
Shit!
- I'll get it.
- I got it!
I'll get it! I'll get it!
Are you gonna be gross at our party?
I told you we shouldn't invite him.
I wanted a real date.
- I'm a real date.
- You're a nerd.
You know, you piss me off sometimes.
Well, why don't you just grow up?
Get taller or something.
Brad, you're tall enough to eat dinner.
Now why don't you dry up?
Go get some coffee.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
Hey! Rejection.
- Hey, hey, is this stoked?
- Yeah, really stoked.
Why don't you sit over there, okay?
- All right.
- Nice!
Everyone, start.
I'll be back.
- Is Laurie here?
- No, Debbie, this is a private party.
Well, Laurie told me to meet her here.
Look, Debby,
I'm really gonna get pissed.
I don't know how Laurie
knows about this party, okay?
Well, excuse me!
Can I at least come in and wait for her?
- No.
- God!
Good night.
This party is, like, wow!
I looked over at the other table.
- Yeah?
- And it was her!
Joni Mitchell, man.
I could not believe it
and she looked terrific.
Anyway I put my hand on Corky's hand
and I go, "Hey, that's Joni Mitchell."
And he goes, "Yeah," you know,
just like it was his mother or something.
Joni Mitchell. Wow! It was
like freaking out. I mean...
I could not believe it.
Joni Mitchell. Wow, man.
Anybody hear the new
album by Weather Report?
I smiled at her. She smiled
back at me. No shit, man.
I thought that was so hip.
I mean, Joni Mitchell smiled at me.
Okay, Annie, okay.
- I mean, no shit.
- Okay. Calm down, all right?
My turn.
At least she wasn't some stuck-up twat.
- Scarlett!
- Jason.
Scarlett, it's Rhett. Let me in.
Very funny.
On good looks alone,
I deserve more than that.
Look, why don't you take your good
looks back down the hill, all right?
- Jason! Jason!
- Hey, hey, Princess.
You still go to Hollywood High?
No, Christ. I go to Pierce College now.
I'm a Psych major.
Come on in and have some champagne.
Look, this is a private party, okay?
What? You guys know Buddy, don't you?
Hey Buddy, you want some champagne?
- Come on in, Buddy.
- Banzai, all right.
No, you don't. No, you don't.
Come on, Jeanie. Dinner's over.
Look, this isn't even our place.
Well, let's ask Madge. Come on.
- Stay there.
- I'm with Buddy.
Oh, Christ.
There's a lot of guys out there.
Hey, come on outside.
I'd like to show you something.
No, thanks. I've seen it.
Now, listen.
- If you're going with a guy...
- Yeah?
You can use a diaphragm.
'Cause you got an idea
when you're doing it.
But, on your own,
you better stick to the pill,
'cause you never know what
you don't know, you know?
No! They can't stay!
You can't stay. I'm sorry.
It's okay. Don't be sorry.
Look, this is a private party, okay?
I'm just leaving.
Hey! You ready to go, darling?
Yeah, he's ready to go.
Dang you!
What's going on?
Get off the line!
You bastard!
Get off the line! I'm trying to
call the police! Get off the line!
You fucker!
Any injuries?
Some items are harmed.
Stereo equipment mostly,
but nobody wants to remember who
stole them or where they went.
Yes, they're right here,
the responsible party.
No, we wanted to hold them
until we told you.
No, no, no, sir.
It's your place.
In that case, we'll hold
them for their parents,
and give them a counsel and release.
Again?
Mad, Mad Axman?
Give me a spelling on that.
Madge.
Axman.
Thank you.
He wanted a Madge Axman to know he'd
be returning to the city in the morning.
Hello, Frank.
- Working hard?
- No.
What've we got here?
Drunkenness, narcotics,
destruction of property.
Some stolen goods, but the owner
doesn't want to press charges.
I'm giving them all a
counsel and release.
Is that your daughter?
Bye, Ann.
Stay there.
Drunkenness, narcotics,
destruction of property. What else?
They're cops, Mom.
I don't like your friends, Jeanie.
I know that.
You'll have to tell me. Are there
any nice people left in the world?
You never like my friends.
Are there some nice boys,
nice girls, either one?
- Yeah.
- What?
Yeah. I said, yeah.
Whatever happened to the word "yes"?
For Christ's sake, Mom,
they're putting Annie in the hospital.
You don't even care.
I do care, and I'm sorry, darling.
I know Annie's basically a nice kid.
You don't even know her.
I know you're upset.
She could die in that hospital.
She could end up committing suicide.
Did she say something about suicide?
She can't stand small spaces.
Did she actually say the word suicide?
No, but I know what she feels.
Well, I'll call the hospital.
Oh, God, that's not
going to do any good.
We'll ask the doctors,
what their opinion is.
They're the ones that are
saying Annie's sick.
Their opinions are just sick.
They're doctors.
At least we can ask their opinion.
- Forget it! Just forget it.
- What?
Why, stop keep telling me
to say things over again.
It really bothers me.
"Forget it" is a very rude
thing to say to somebody.
Oh, God, you keep telling me to cry!
I don't want to cry anymore!
Maybe Annie is sick.
Did you ever think of that?
Maybe the whole bunch of you is sick.
You booze. You dope.
You sleep with whoever.
I don't even know who you are.
You look like kids,
but you don't act like 'em.
You're short 40-year-olds
and you're tough ones.
You just hate everybody since Dad left.
Everyone except some guy
you can just meet and...
What? Meet and what?
You throw yourself on the
line all the time, Mom.
You jump on some guy and when he tells
you he doesn't want to see you anymore,
you just cry on the phone.
I don't care if you are my daughter.
You're not talking about me
or my friends like...
Well, you talk about
my friends that way!
And you don't like Sam?
I don't know him! Do you?
Do you know him, Mom?
Did you know him before you just
jumped into bed with him like that?
That's nasty. That's cruel and
nasty and ugly and unloving,
and I wish I could punch you.
I wish to God I knew how to punch you.
What's the matter with Sam?
He wears white shoes.
White shoes? You apologize!
You apologize!
I haven't finished. I'm not finished!
Just because they fit you for a
diaphragm doesn't make you a woman.
Sam is a good man, and you
make no mistake about that.
He's a decent human being
and he cares for me.
He says he even loves me.
I'm going to spend some time with him.
A week, a few days. Who knows?
You want a place of your own?
Fine. Take this one, 'cause I'm
not gonna bring him here anymore.
All you girls are laughing at him.
There's too much music here
and too many boys, girls,
laying all over the furniture,
half out of your clothes, on the floor!
You're too beautiful, all of you.
You make me hate my hips.
I hate my hips!
- I thought it was Jay.
- It's just me.
Jeanie.
- Where's Deirdre?
- Her mom won't let her come.
Stay away from trouble.
Something like that.
Well, shit on her.
She's not going to go
with us to see Annie?
No one is.
I talked to her mom.
You talked to Gladys?
Yeah. She says no one can
visit her unless they're family.
Her dad doesn't want
her to see us anyway.
He's such a total drag.
I could scream, you know.
Well, it's not her fault.
Gladys is a nice lady,
once you get past her depressions.
What are we gonna do?
It's awful, huh?
It's not good.
We're gonna get jobs
and pay for the stereo.
I'm taking the proficiency exam
so I don't have to go to classes,
and I can work full-time.
They're gonna give me a certificate
so that I can show it...
Will you excuse us, please?
I can get into some colleges.
Some colleges, I can get into.
We're paying for everything.
Doing what?
Do you have any idea
what it's going to cost to put
this place back together again?
Yes.
Yeah? How much?
Jay, you think
we're children, don't you?
I know you're children!
Living off your parents,
for Christ's sake.
I thought you loved me.
I thought age didn't matter.
I do love you! I fucking worship you!
I must be nuts.
God! I must be nuts.
- I'll leave.
- Terrific.
You can stop wrecking things.
It's just gonna cost us more.
- What are you gonna do?
- Jay.
What are you gonna do?
Be a waitress at Denny's?
Maybe!
Well, at that rate, it would take
you all about 80 years apiece!
I'll tell you one thing,
Mr. Jay Thompson.
The next time you see any of us
children coming through that door,
well, I'm gonna have
the money in my hand!
- Damn!
- What door?
This door!
I'm really pissed at you and all
your flaky teenage friends.
I'm not through talking to you.
I am!
- Come back here.
- Why? So you can beat me up?
- You're goddamn right!
- Forget it.
Please.
- What?
- What do you mean, what?
Please, what?
Please come back here
so I can beat you up.
Hey!
I thought they had you
filling fire extinguishers.
Christmas is coming.
- Are you breaking for lunch sometime?
- No way.
I thought maybe you'd want to
come with me and have some lunch.
All right.
Well, would they let you do that?
Are you kidding me?
This guy is paying shit.
You've got some white stuff
in your hair. Come here.
I thought you might be sad about Annie,
need someone to talk to.
I remember how incredibly sad you can
get about things and I thought that,
you know, you shouldn't have
to go through all that alone.
Thanks.
Smell something?
It's my boots.
Well, what you been walking in?
I ran out of socks and that
makes my feet sweat a lot.
God, that's awful. I mean, I'm sorry,
but you should get some socks.
Those boots are awful.
You didn't have to do that.
The trouble with LA is that everybody's
trying to act so supercool
and into their own space.
Like they'd be ruined if
they had to feel anything.
I know, I used to be in yoga class.
God, this stuff is poison.
You don't know what they put in here.
Yeah. What are you gonna do, right?
You know, nobody wants to feel
the pain in things anymore.
For instance, I can feel the
pain in things sometimes.
There's this one-eyed rooster I know.
Like some dog got to him
and bit a hole in his head.
Back in this place my dad used to take me,
when he was into the outdoors.
Some ranch, really, in the Sierras.
Bunch of stoner types, real spiritual heads,
always in some full lotus
squatting their way to a
new head or something.
And this is really bullshit 'cause
there are all these rock-n-rollers
making lots of real heavy money
and they're om-ing up in the hills.
And I said, there's pain
in this rooster's head.
And they go, "Too much maya, man.
Too much maya."
Like pain's an illusion.
Like it isn't even real.
Christ. Illusion, right?
I wanted to laugh. It was...
It was like some church for these guys
sitting under these trees, you know?
I did something really gross.
My dad got so pissed.
I let this guy's tea...
Accidentally, right, this whole hot cup
of hot tea fall down this guy's leg.
He's sitting there
screaming and yelling.
He said he wasn't mad at me,
but it was a really stupid bitch thing to do.
Boy. He stopped talking
about pain being an illusion.
What are you thinking about?
About Annie.
What about Annie?
Just about Annie.
I guess it's too late
to go back to work.
It's no problem.
Sorry.
Was there angel dust in those joints?
No.
Sure you're not lying?
- Would I lie to you?
- Yeah.
I just, I can't handle it.
Angel dust, I mean.
Is that your phone ringing?
Nah, forget it.
Yeah.
Hello?
Annie. How are you?
Well, they let you phone from there?
Brad's here, I'll let you
talk to him in a minute.
What? Wait a minute! Where are you?
You're where?
Annie! Annie!
- Let's go. That's Annie.
- How is she?
She's loaded.
Jesus.
Come on, baby. You ready to leave?
- We're having a party.
- Doctor says no more parties, okay?
- Get me home.
- Okay.
- Excuse me.
- What did he say?
- "Excuse me."
- Why? What did he do?
Jimmy, what is this pile of shit?
Shootout.
- Your neck's bleeding.
- My neck!
I was so pissed I just walked out.
Right in the middle of visitors' hour.
With this girl's parents,
like I was the sister.
They gave me all this prescription
dope at the hospital.
What a trip, man.
Remember that? Jack Nicholson.
Can we sit down?
No. Look, would you
just walk off these pills?
'Cause otherwise you're gonna
end up going into a coma.
Was I happy to see you!
You were beautiful.
- You lie.
- You were my hero!
I saw you coming and I said,
"Hero, take me home."
You did not.
I was thinking it.
Yeah? You should've called, you know?
I did. I called forever!
I thought you'd be happy to see me.
- You got a lude?
- No, he doesn't.
You gonna be a total drag?
I just shined one mother,
I don't need another.
Okay, so you got a couple of
low characters for parents
and you think they can just fuck all.
Well, I can understand that.
But if you're just gonna get loaded
all the time and shine everybody,
well, shine you!
'Cause it's not working anymore!
Shine you, if that's how you feel!
I'm going to Oregon.
- Oregon?
- Bert's up there.
Another dirthead.
He's measuring trees.
Look, I'm living alone right now.
My mom moved out.
I don't know what the hell she's doing with
her life, but that's her business, okay?
I'm willing to take you on
for a couple of weeks
but not if you're just gonna go out and
get loaded all the time! You understand?
I'm going to Oregon.
You can't even walk with one
foot in front of the other!
Come on now, Annie.
Annie! Annie!
Annie!
Listen to me!
I'm getting real pissed! Stop!
Listen to me, god damn it! Listen to me!
If you're gonna stay with me,
you gotta go by the rules!
And the rules are we're gonna get
through this fucking high school!
We're gonna pay back Jay and get
jobs and a bunch of shit like that!
And if you don't like that,
that's just tough shit!
'Cause that's the way life is and
you better learn to eat a little!
And I'm not coming back for you
every time you goddamn blow it!
You know, no one can
take a joke anymore.
- It's my dad!
- No, it's a patrol car, Annie.
Annie! Annie, stay there.
Don't go far, okay?
- I want some ID.
- What for?
You're after curfew, this is a private
road and because I want it. You, too.
You're going home. We don't
want to see you up here again.
We've got your names.
Annie! Annie, where are you?
Was that my dad?
They're gone, Annie! They're all gone!
Where are you?
Here.
Where the fuck is she?
Hey, turkey! Here!
Come on!
Did you see that?
Oh, shit!
Get the guy! Try and get him!
Let him drive!
She thinks I'm putting her
in a spot if I just call her.
Like it's really stupid if I love her.
She keeps on saying, "You must be high."
Isn't that the rat's ass?
High? Just because I love her?
"That's the rules," she said.
I can't come over or see her
or anything if I'm high.
Oh, man. I just love her.
That's not high, huh?
No.
I've been in my car for three days now.
For real?
Well, you know, I stop to eat.
God, you're really bent up.
You girls think it's a joke
or something, being in love.
Are you sure we're going
to North Hollywood?
Well, actually, I was
going to Santa Monica.
But I thought you might
want to go with me.
Thanks, man. But I really
gotta get to North Hollywood.
You know, I'm not like the rest of those
guys that are disrespectful to girls.
You better let me out.
Okay.
Thanks a lot, really.
Here, you want a pill?
Jeanie, be there!
Annie! Annie!
Annie!
Disappointed?
I know you wanted a place of your own.
It's okay, Mom. We sort of had one.
Sam wants me, it's not that.
He'd like me to stay.
What happened?
I couldn't move my robe in there.
The place was too nice for my robe.
Annie's left the hospital and
we don't know where she is.
She'll be back.
I don't know.
You want a ride?
Are you going to North Hollywood?
Are we going to North Hollywood?
Yeah. Let's go to North Hollywood.
- Sure you're going that way?
- Sure.
Hi.
I'm Daryl.
This is my wife, Bert.
Yeah?
You think that's a strange name?
It's strange.
Here. Hold this.
Hey, watch your driving.
Grab onto that.
Here, grab the wheel.
You guys are weird.
Did you hear that?
Come on. Why are you so uptight?
We like you.
Why don't you relax?
- I gotta get to Jeanie's.
- Who's Jeanie?
Come on, relax.
The beast with five fingers.
- Wanna turn up the IV's?
- Don't.
Those are Jeanie's pants.
- Now, it's okay.
- Pressures dropped.
Pressure's dropping.
She's going out of it here.
- Turn up the IV.
- All right.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
It'll be okay.
Slow that down, good.
That's good. That's good.
She's spitting up blood.
We've lost her.
We gotta wake up Annie.
You sure piss me off sometimes, Annie.
I can't go on without you all!
- How does it feel, married woman?
- I'm terrified!
- You hear that?
- Good-bye!
Goodbye! Dad!
Here you go!
I'll come out later, okay?
Where're you going?
We've got to go over to Stan's.
It's some real heavy family stuff.
Otherwise I'd go with you now, you know?
- Really.
- Okay.
- Bye, Mary.
- Bye.
You want me to drive up there with you?
If you want.
I don't want to tell you that you can't.
Well, tell me the truth. My God,
you're on your way to college.
You're gonna be on your own.
The least we can do is be
honest at this point, can't we?
I don't know. Things get so complicated.
I think we'd be better off if we didn't
call each other mother and daughter.
I'd rather go alone.
I mean, that's the truth.
I like calling you mom. Okay?
- Okay.
I know that the subject
doesn't come up too often.
We never really get the chance
to talk about it, but...
I really love you.
I love you, too, honey.
Back in the heavy stoned days when
we used to stay up and talk a lot,
Annie and me,
we were talking about dying.
How it feels and all.
I said I'd never get buried.
I couldn't stand them
shoveling dirt in my face.
Like I'd know I'd be dead,
but I still might have this strong
compulsion to breathe, okay?
But Annie,
she said she wanted to be buried
right in the ground under a pear tree.
Really. Not in a box or anything.
She said she wanted the roots
going right through her.
And each year, we'd come along
and take a pear and go,
"Hey, Annie's tasting
good this year, huh?"