Miss?
Miss, can you hear me? Miss?
All right,
everybody, let's get it on.
Come here.
Hey, Frankie!
Here you go, sweetheart.
Wall Street.
Oh, yeah,
princess! Yeah!
- Here you go.
- No holding out.
Wall Street!
Try reading a newspaper, Hal.
Wall Street's going down!
Yeah, and dicks are going up.
Keep 'em coming, Frankie!
Let's go, chickies.
Now come on, let's move it.
Shut up!
- Frankie.
- That's pretty sad...
Can you believe that sleazy son-of-a-bitch
humping out my leg like a dog?
- It's gonna take forever to get this shit off.
- Girl, I'm trying to eat.
He tipped me $4.
Can you believe that shit?
Four...
Oh, I was just waiting for him
to start counting quarters!
I told you working
on the floor is for chumps.
Now if you was a Leo like me,
you'd have figured it out already.
I can take one look at their face and
tell who ain't getting no sugar at home.
And that's the one got
the most money for Frankie.
I'm a Pisces,
so what does that mean?
Charlie,
get down those stairs now.
Shit, blame your mama.
I don't know!
You through with
the newspaper, sweetie?
- Go ahead.
- Thank you.
Hey, Frankie?
You want some of this?
I don't mess with that.
Okay, just tell me something.
It gets easier, right?
When I went out there tonight,
I thought I was gonna barf.
Here's what I do, baby.
I close my eyes and
let the music take me.
Like I'm on the outside,
just watching.
Like I ain't even there.
Like I'm watching myself
from the outside.
- Works for me.
- Thanks.
Thanks, Frankie.
You did the crossword?
No, I didn't.
Well, yeah, sweetheart.
Sure looks like you did.
No, I didn't.
That ain't even my handwriting.
Genius has
done the crossword again.
I'll take that.
What you trying to do, Frankie?
Make us look bad?
Got something to prove?
So, are we going or what?
♪ I don't want you
to be no slave
♪ I don't want
you to work all day
♪ But I want you to be true
♪ And I just want
to make love to you
♪ Love to you
♪ I can tell by the way
you walk that walk
♪ And I can tell by the way
you talk that talk
♪ I can know by the way
you treat your girl
♪ That I could give you all the
loving In the whole wide world
♪ Oh! ♪
See what we got here!
Girl, you're on fire.
What did you think of that?
Eight in the corner.
No way. Not happening.
She's gonna fold like a table.
Frankie doesn't have it in her.
Did you see that?
Line 'em up!
Frankie, that's some sharp shooting, baby.
Real sharp.
Polyester Molester...
Marry me!
Honey, that ain't for real.
Hey, how do you know that?
Number one, he's white.
Number two...
He's white!
I know one guy who don't need
no sock in his pants.
Who, Cliff?
He's so fine,
I'd fuck him for free.
Me too.
Yeah?
Make you feel good? Yeah?
What?
- Touch me.
- Yeah, baby.
Give it to me.
Frankie?
What's the problem?
Frankie! Hey!
It's all right.
Took the kid to her mama's
on Crenshaw, so...
Frankie, we good, baby.
Mama, what's wrong?
Come on, baby, you can't leave me hanging
like this. I been really nice to you.
Take your filthy
nigger hands off me.
"Mortify, therefore your
members which are on earth.
"Fornication, uncleanness,
inordinate affection,
"evil concupiscence,
and covetousness, which is idolatry,
"for which things' sake
the wrath of God
"comes on the children
of disobedience."
Frankie.
Frankie come on, baby.
Frankie is not here.
What are you talking about?
Come here.
Frankie, come on!
You are hurting me!
- No, I'm not.
- You're hurting me.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Frankie, it's me. Okay? It's okay.
I ain't gonna hurt you.
Shit!
- Damn it!
- Okay.
Frankie!
Get your ass back here, Frankie!
I'm going to kill you, girl!
I swear to God
I'm going to kill you dead!
Shit! Frankie,
get back here!
Get off the road!
Watch it!
Frankie! Bitch!
You're crazy!
You know that?
You're a crazy goddamn bitch!
Get out of the intersection,
are you drunk?
- Jesus!
- You crazy freak!
Man, you're gonna get hit, girl.
What's wrong with you?
How could you do this to me?
Hey, Miss?
Miss, do you hear me?
Hey, get up!
Come on! Get up!
You think she's on drugs?
Hey!
You listening to me?
Come on! Get up! Get up!
Let's get this junkie
off the road.
Watch your head, Miss.
Dr. Sawyer to admitting.
Sorry.
Dr. Oswald?
You're here early.
Nurse Shaw.
Do you listen to jazz?
A colleague from the faculty
of arts once told me
that he'd had the most amazing
results from listening to jazz.
He claimed it allowed him full
access to the subconscious state
without any need for
hallucinogens or stimulants.
I don't experience
anything at all.
Well, maybe you're not
listening properly.
Yes, I am.
This equipment...
It's absolutely state-of-the-art.
Dr. Oswald...
Are you free to
handle an admission?
A patient?
I looked everywhere
for Dr. Michaelson
but I think he is
somewhere over in trauma.
No.
That's not my department and
I have to teach a class in...
Well, several hours.
Well, I'm sure you'll
be through by then.
Can't it wait
for Dr. Michaelson?
He's much more
efficient than I am
and I don't want to step
on anybody's toes, so...
These tapes will be
here when you get back.
Doctor?
Miles Davis!
Maybe I'll have better
results with Miles Davis.
- Or even Dave Brubeck and...
- Oh!
She is somewhat disoriented,
but she doesn't appear drunk.
Her name is...
Murdoch.
Miss Murdoch?
- Dr. Martinez to treatment room four.
- Oh!
Dr. Martinez to
treatment room four.
Doctor, her file.
Oh.
So...
Miss F.R. Murdoch.
Nope.
- You're not Murdoch?
- No, that's me.
It's just my middle name
ain't R. It's Lucinda.
Lucinda?
Lucinda... From the Latin,
lucidus via lucere, meaning "to shine".
An origin it shares
with the word "lucid"
meaning "to think
or see clearly."
It's a beautiful name.
Do I know you?
No, we've never met.
I'm Dr. Oswald.
Shit.
This one's pretty
bad on my leg...
No...
Oh, wait...
You don't even know
what you're doing.
Oh, yes, I do.
I'm a doctor.
Can you hold that?
Why do you think we've met?
I don't know.
Maybe you came to see
me dance or something.
Oh, you're a dancer?
Yup.
Ballet?
Exotic.
Exotic?
I'm a stripper.
Well...
How many times have
you been admitted?
To Pearce or some place like it?
You knew your way
to the examination rooms.
You thought we'd met,
but you couldn't remember.
What else can't you remember?
What happens?
I get a little mixed up,
that's all. Come on.
Let's get this
show on the road, Doc.
66.
You're in good shape.
Well, thank you.
What do you mean
"mixed up"? Drugs?
Are you currently
taking any medication?
Any recreational drug use?
That depends what
you talking 'bout, Doc.
Benzodiazepine?
Methaqualone?
That's Valium and Quaaludes.
None of that shit.
Frankie got rules.
No smack, no blow, no speed.
LSD?
Did you hear what I said?
No!
I smoke a little reefer...
That's it.
Look at my nose.
What were you doing
running in traffic?
Were you being attacked?
You don't recall, do you?
I think we should keep
you here for a while.
On what grounds?
Blood pressure, normal.
Indications of memory loss.
No sign of nystagmus.
Exactly, she was
absolutely reeking
of alcohol, and yet,
there was no oscillation at all.
Completely smooth pursuit
at every deviation.
So she can hold her liquor...
Well, that certainly is interesting, Joe.
- Discharge her, please.
- No!
Does she pose a significant
threat to others?
- No.
- Is she gravely disabled?
- No. So she's out.
I'm sorry, Joe.
I don't have the beds.
They found her in
the middle of the street!
She has no recollection
of how she ended up there.
Come on, Joe.
She's a stripper from Watts.
She was probably
coked out of her mind.
Then keep her for three days.
Wait for the toxicology report.
- Joe.
- Don't you have a class?
Now, I thought you cut right
back on the clinical work.
- Yes.
- Doctor.
Look, we will patch her up
and we will send her home.
Let the cops handle it, please?
Zuca abra. Se que esta ahí,
déjeme entrar. Vamos abra.
What?
Shit!
Oh, hey, Hector.
¿Qué pasa, jefe?
Your check bounced.
Cheque rechazado!
What?
- No, no, no. I got money in the bank.
- No, you don't.
Yes, I do.
You pay now.
You pay now,
or you go find a new place to play crazy.
Okay.
Okay, just hold on a minute.
See what I got.
Okay.
Here you go,
$20 it's what I got for now.
Give me a couple days.
I'll get the rest. Come on...
You know I'm good for it,
Daddy. Come on, you know...
You know Frankie good for it.
This is the last time.
- Okay.
- Last time.
Te quiero, papi.
What?
Oh, Jesus!
Again?
What?
- What?
- Stop!
- What's going on?
- Get off!
You got something to say,
you ought to just say it.
You need help!
- Come on now, honey. Let's go.
- What's going on, Wanda?
- They say you attacked him, Frankie.
- Who?
Cliff! They say you
cut his head wide open!
What got into you?
He try something on you?
He try to hurt you?
Frankie! Talk to me!
Frankie!
I can't have it, Frankie.
I can't.
You're out of here.
Fuck you then, Hal.
- Hey, Frankie.
- Hey, Bobby.
Smell good!
When do we eat?
Wha...
I just said,
"When do we eat?"
I heard what you said.
We gonna eat when she gets here,
not before.
Mama,
this is just like back home.
- No, Mama, I can't.
- Oh...
I'm fitting to bust!
Look at you girl,
there's nothing to you.
Would you stop that.
Why don't you open your present?
I'll take
a little more cornbread.
I hope you saved room
for blueberry pie.
Now, you know I did!
Oh, Frankie.
That's a ruby.
That's my birthstone.
And that's amethyst for Maxine.
So you think of us.
You shouldn't have.
You think I don't already?
Frankie, you didn't have to go
wasting your money on me like this.
- All right then, I'll take it back.
- No, you won't!
I'm gonna put this on right now.
I am never gonna take it off.
Must be going pretty good
at the telephone company?
They're going real good.
Guess what, Mama?
I'm going to night school
to get my degree.
Night school.
You love it, Mama?
Oh, Frankie, it's beautiful.
It's beautiful!
Seen the paper today, Frankie?
Maxine!
Go fetch that pie in here.
Why?
That girl, Paige your dearest friend?
She's getting married.
Maxine!
Oh, yeah? To who?
Some rich guy here in the city.
Right here in LA?
Yeah, that's why they
put it in the newspaper.
Works with Governor Reagan some shit.
Should be quite a party.
Maxine Murdoch, where'd you get such
spite in you only the Devil knows.
I'm okay, Mama.
Happy birthday.
I'm glad you like your present.
I love it.
Y'all got a Paige
Prescott staying there?
One moment, please.
Hello? Paige Prescott.
Hello?
Who is this?
Oh.
Hey.
Hey, Bobby.
I was gonna get some coffee.
Do you want... I should get two?
Yeah. Coffee'd be good.
Paige, wait!
Wait for me, Paige!
You can't catch me.
Come on, Frankie!
Frankie? Frankie!
Let's play!
Frankie.
- Frankie!
- Frankie?
Frankie?
Come on, Frankie!
I'm gonna catch you!
Frankie?
No. Don't you touch me.
Don't touch me!
- Come back here!
- Frankie...
Come on, Frankie!
It's not your place!
- I'm gonna catch you!
- It's not your place!
Frankie?
Come on, let's play!
Francine Murdoch!
Get out!
You and me,
Frankie, friends forever.
Frankie?
Frankie's not here.
Hello, Paige.
You look beautiful.
I'm sorry, have we met?
I'm so angry
I missed the ceremony.
Now, I won't bore
you with my reasons.
Not too sure there's
a difference between
a reason and a plain
old excuse anyhow.
Well, how are you?
I'm well.
Remember, we always said we'd be there
for each other on our wedding day.
I'm here, Paige...
And I wish you every happiness.
Frankie?
Now is that your
husband back there?
I would like to see him...
How could you?
Why would you come here?
Paige...
Excuse me?
- There seems to be a misunderstanding.
- Well, there certainly does!
She seems to think
I'm somebody I'm not.
I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave.
I will not leave here.
I was invited.
Just walk with
me this way, Miss.
Take your hands off me, boy!
I will have you fired before either
one of us reach that doorway.
You're acting crazy.
Take your hands off of me!
Have you lost your natural mind?
Easy, there.
I will call the police in here!
Just give it to me.
Give it to me.
Stop her!
Get off of me!
Get off!
- Dr. Oswald?
- Yes?
It's me, Frankie.
Yes?
Francine Murdoch?
Oh, Lucinda, yes, okay.
Yeah. Look, Doc...
I'm locked up.
They fittin' to put me in jail.
Yes?
They're telling me that,
you know...
Because of my history,
I could get myself out of here if
I check myself into the nuthouse.
Under a 4011, maybe, yes...
Sure, but it depends on an assessment.
Well, is that
something you can do?
What has happened?
Did you have another blackout?
I don't know, Doc.
I don't know what happened.
'Cause I think what I will do is
I will refer you
to Dr. Warren Backman.
He's the Chief Attendant Psychiatrist here,
and he's a clinician.
No. It's gonna
have to be you, Doc.
But I don't have the time.
I'm a research man.
I have students.
Please?
There has to be
certain conditions.
Okay. Shoot.
You'll be signing yourself in voluntarily,
under my care.
Okay.
For how long?
Let's say,
to begin with, 30 days.
30 days!
Yeah, to begin with.
Okay. I guess it beats
being in jail, don't it?
I'm not that familiar with jails,
but, I suppose it does, yes.
I believe there is something
wrong with you, Miss Murdoch,
but we don't have any
idea what it could be.
Okay, Doc, but look,
you gonna have to be honest.
What do you think
is wrong with me?
Come over here
and we'll find out.
This doesn't make sense.
Are you ambidextrous?
That's kind of personal for the first date.
Don't you think?
So look, if I'm gonna
be here for 30 days,
you gonna have to help me
out with something, Doc.
Because I'm about to go cold
turkey something fierce.
Oh, I ain't talking about dope.
I'm talking about Ding Dongs.
- Ding Dongs?
- Yeah.
You know, them little chocolate
cakes with the cream on the inside?
Do you know your IQ?
They tell me it's pretty good.
Up around 130.
132.
Last year in March, when you checked
into Kedren Community Health,
you tested 156.
That's pretty high, ain't it?
Technically, it's genius.
What can I say,
my mama ain't raised no suckers.
No. You don't understand.
It's not possible to have such
wildly divergent results.
Or if it is,
it's highly irregular.
And then a third time,
at Gateways,
you scored a little
better than average.
Guess they took one
look at a black stripper
and decided
she wasn't no Einstein.
Left-handed,
right-handed.
Nearsighted, 20/20 vision.
Blood-pressure,
120 over 80.
Hold on, Doc.
Enough about me.
How about we talk
about you for a second.
When did she leave?
What?
Your wife.
When did she leave you?
I noticed you got you a tan line on
your ring finger but it's faint.
So that tells me you didn't just
take that off before work today.
It's been off.
That's very observant.
I grew up in Georgia
in the '50s.
You learn to pay
attention to skin color.
So how's that
going for you, Doc?
On the way home...
Stop by the grocery,
pick you up a tuna on rye,
a fifth of whiskey?
It's kind of lonely, ain't it?
You really don't have
to do this, you know.
There's no stigma attached to mental illness.
At least, not here.
So you don't have to be afraid.
Tell me what do you remember
about your arrest?
You were picked up
at the Ambassador Hotel.
You got into a fight.
Why were you at the Ambassador?
Checked into
the Presidential Suite.
Heard it was real nice.
Before you went,
did you have any auditory hallucinations?
Any what?
Voices telling you
what to do? Delusions?
- You mean voices in my head?
- Yes.
Like talking to me?
Hell, no!
What do you think, I'm crazy?
Any feelings of paranoia
- or visual hallucinations?
- No.
How long have you
had these blackouts?
Waking up in unfamiliar places?
I don't know.
Since your late teens,
early 20s?
I don't know.
Try to remember...
Do you remember what you felt
before you decided to go?
Do you know why you wanted to go to
the Ambassador in the first place?
I don't remember!
Could you sit
over there, please.
I'll check your
ocular responses.
Look at me, please.
Look at my eyes...
Look at my eyes.
Very good.
Look at me.
Miss? Hello, miss,
can you hear me? Miss?
Look at me.
Do you have feelings
of dissociation?
Miss?
You all right?
Nurse Freeman will
take you to your room.
I need some time alone
with your file.
Shut your face!
Shut it!
You never answered my question.
Do you ever have a
feeling of dissociation
of being outside yourself?
Watching yourself perform actions
from an objective remove?
Honey,
I picked out clothes for you.
These oughta be
just about your size.
Don't you ever dare touch me!
And I choose what I wear.
Miss Murdoch?
You left your cigarettes.
I don't ever smoke, Doctor.
Tuna, right?
I got tuna for Dr. Oz.
What else is good?
Ham salad, very good.
Chicken salad, very good.
Cheese salad, very good.
- Tuna?
- Tuna, yes.
If you were to
go to sleep one night
and awake to find,
that by some unknown agency
you had been transported
to a cold, dark cave,
the rational mind provides for one
of only five possible explanations.
One, "I'm dead."
Two, "I'm dreaming."
Three, "Somebody
played a trick on me."
Four, "I'm crazy."
Or?
Or, five...
"I am in a cave."
Oh, I get it, Doc.
You're trying to say I'm crazy.
Or somebody
played a trick on you.
Who?
You.
If you trust me,
there's something I'd like to try.
Actually,
I spent most of the 1950s,
1954 to 1962 to
be exact, on acid.
Say what?
LSD.
It's a synthetic hallucinogen.
I know what LSD is.
You just don't seem
like that kind of dude.
"Turn on, tune in, drop out."
It was nothing like that.
I was investigating
the phenomenological effects
of LSD-25 on consciousness.
We were among the first
in the world to try it.
It was a rigorous study.
We tested over 900 patients.
Yeah, by getting folks high?
Well, it was
a scientific experiment.
So basically, what you're saying is you
was responsible for the Grateful Dead?
I guess I was.
Doc, you got them Ding Dongs?
This is just a mild sedative...
To aid with hypnotic suggestion.
I want you to follow
the light with your eyes.
And, as you do so,
focus solely on the light.
You're drifting away.
There's nothing but the light.
Nothing but the light.
Hey, Frankie.
Frankie?
Nod your head
if you can hear me?
Good.
There's someone else
I'd like to meet.
Is that possible?
Hello.
Hi.
You're like that wizard from Oz
where Dorothy
fell upon that witch?
You like that film?
I read the book.
I read books.
That's good.
How long you going
to keep her here?
Who? Lucinda or Frankie?
From the Latin, lucidus via lucere,
meaning, "To shine."
An origin it shares
with the word "lucid"
meaning "to think
or see clearly."
I'm not keeping her here.
She's here of her own accord.
I'm just trying to help her.
Nobody ever care about Frankie.
Except for Mama.
And Mr. Pete.
But you try to
help her, don't you?
When I can.
What stops you?
It's getting dark in here.
Want me to open the blinds?
Here. Have some water.
Good Lord.
Thank you.
May I ask who I'm speaking with?
Well, you never end a sentence
with a preposition, Doctor.
Isn't that what
we were taught in school?
You know who I am.
That puts me at a slight
disadvantage, doesn't it?
Yes, it surely does.
Maybe Miss Murdoch would be kind enough
to make our introduction next time.
That's quite slippery
of you, Doctor.
That is a trait that's
common to your race.
You don't deny
that you are Hebrew?
No.
Well, at any rate,
she won't be able to make an introduction,
because she won't remember
a word of our encounter.
Oh? How's that?
She's weak.
She's frightened.
She's incapable.
Is there anything
she has trouble accepting?
Something that happened
a long time ago?
In my experience,
doctors are almost
always tiresome bores
and frequently drunks.
Oh?
Which one are you, Dr. Oswald?
Are you gonna be working late?
Well, good night.
Good night.
Don't you all
wanna watch something good?
Every species...
Oh!
♪ Jungle boogie
- Don't you want some jungle boogie?
- No.
- Yes, you do.
- Come on. Get up.
- No.
Me too. Yeah!
"Murdoch.
Francine L.
"History of substance abuse,
amnesiac episodes, outbursts of rage."
Come on, Celeste. Up.
♪ Jungle boogie
♪ Jungle boogie ♪
Schizophrenia?
Or manic depression, possibly.
We might start her on lithium.
I know what it is.
That's not the problem at all.
She has a dissociative identity disorder.
It's really quite extreme.
MPD?
Under hypnosis
and pentobarbital sedation...
she presented two quite
distinct and consistent alters.
Really? Quite a girl.
Yeah.
How can you be sure that it wasn't
a transient ego-state phenomenon?
A mood swing?
The girl is a pothead.
I was there.
Might she be responding
to your own suggestion?
You know I'm wary of hypnosis.
I haven't told her yet.
Multiple personality?
Who are they?
They're you,
they're aspects of you,
your subconscious.
Okay, but why?
Well, that's what
we have to find out.
Okay, so what you're saying is
I got all these different people livin'
inside me, right?
But I don't know who they are?
Well, we all have different
personalities and different selves
"Do I contradict myself?
Very well, then, I contradict myself.
"I am large.
I contain multitudes."
It's Whitman.
Oh, I know who it is.
He was a racist fag.
Well, I don't think
that covers him entirely.
Well...
At least you ain't been
wasting your time, Doc.
'Cause I'm crazy
as a shithouse rat.
- Yeah?
- Hey, Maxine, it's me.
Frankie?
Hey, Mama.
You still wearing
that necklace I gave you?
Oh, of course I am!
Where have you been?
I needed to take
a little break, Mama,
so I went down to Florida.
Oh.
That sounds real nice.
Take care of yourself,
baby, all right?
Okay, Mama.
I will.
Well, Doctor?
Again, I find myself unable
to properly address you.
No names.
A little mystery adds spice,
don't you think?
Now, Doctor,
I sincerely hope
I didn't offend you
when I made that
reference to your religion
but I was bewildered by whatever that
was you'd administered that girl.
You feel the effects
of the sedative?
Of course!
I suffer every abuse
she inflicts on this body.
Frankie likes to drink,
doesn't she?
She certainly does.
At least her taste
runs to bourbon.
It's that vile marijuana
I can't stand.
Do you think it's got
something to do with,
something she's trying to cover up,
some bad feelings about the past, or...
Doctor, do we have
to talk about her?
Let's talk about your wife.
Or don't you want
to talk about that?
No, it's fine.
We weren't compatible.
Did you learn this from Frankie?
Well, that girl does know how to read a man,
I have to give her that.
And she ought to,
considering her occupation.
You find her promiscuous?
Well, now that's a fancy
word for an ugly tendency.
But you're different
from her in that respect?
Why, Dr. Oswald,
whatever do you hope to imply?
I have nothing in common
with that girl...
Except the unfortunate situation
of having to share this body.
And we'll see
how long that lasts
because I'm getting tired
of having to step in for her.
Suffer her hangovers.
The smell of her encounters
still on the sheets.
They actually smell different
from you and me.
Don't you find that?
You mean black people?
Negroes... Yes.
Did you know that one of them claimed
in a book that Beethoven was a colored?
Beethoven!
I'd like you to tell me
a little about Paige Prescott.
I tried calling her family,
but they weren't prepared to talk to me.
Well that family has an inflated
sense of its own importance.
But you attended her wedding,
didn't you?
At the Ambassador Hotel?
Looks like rain.
All right.
Tell me about Mr. Pete.
Did you know him
back in Georgia?
Did he do something to Frankie?
She wasn't fit
to lick his boots.
So they knew each other?
How sad.
I was right.
You're just a bore.
She thinks she's white?
Well, one of her multiples does.
It's the child I want
to try to reach.
She's a helper.
She's very smart.
The woman, on the other hand,
who thinks she's white,
she's far too strong.
She's a problem.
I thought the county
sent her to us under 4011.6.
It says here, the charges
against her have been dropped?
I'm working on having her sign
a 6000 voluntary admission,
but I don't want to rush it.
I don't want any of the alters
to walk out on me.
And you're certain she's
not just making this up?
Well...
You said it yourself.
She's intelligent, imaginative...
No.
Girl, your head looks
just like a feather bed.
Come on.
Pretty girl like you oughta
make something of herself.
Come on now, when's the last time
you combed through this hair?
What medication
do you have her on?
Nothing. Just the sedative
when I induce hypnosis.
I don't want anything
to interfere with her therapy.
The wrong medication could
cause an alter to predominate.
Then what happens to Murdoch?
- If an alter predominates?
- Yeah.
She'd no longer be Murdoch.
Sit down.
Hi!
You ever had a flip?
My friend.
Just bring it down...
I'll get my iron, we'll straighten
this out and just flip it back.
That's my friend, Frankie.
That's gonna
look so nice on you.
This one goes way back to 1957.
It'll make you
feel better, to do your hair.
You know you got a pretty face.
If I had a face like yours,
you know my hair would be straight.
It's gonna look
a whole lot better.
Afterwards,
it gets tight like this.
I'm gonna get my iron. You're gonna look
real nice. You're gonna feel better.
Shh!
What are you doing?
This is my brother!
Get out my house,
you filthy degenerate!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Make you feel good?
Bonnie! Eva!
Peter!
Code green!
Eva, get some help!
Get your filthy...
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
Miss Murdoch!
You're gonna have to control yourself!
Subdue her! Subdue her!
"No man could bind him, no,
not with chains..."
Keep the area around her clear!
Miss Murdoch,
I need you to calm down.
"Bound with
fetters and chains..."
Come on, give it to me now!
"The chains
were plucked asunder by..."
Hold her still.
There you go. Okay.
"The fetters torn
him to pieces..."
"Neither could
any man tame him."
Is everyone okay?
Let's get her back to her room.
Everybody, now.
Nurse, please?
It was like she was
a whole other person.
She just went off on me.
- What triggered the switch?
- I don't know.
- What made her attack?
Think!
We had the radio playing.
What was it?
It was some old song.
I can't remember.
What?
What is it?
Frankie?
Mr. Oz?
Hello, Genius!
I hope you don't
mind if I call you that?
That's a mighty big name.
You're a very smart kid.
Now, there's a game
I'd like you to play.
I did notice that you have a squint,
so I got you these.
It's a writing game.
You like words, don't you?
I want you to think of words
that mean something to Frankie.
I want you to write them down for me.
Can you do that?
Think of words and names,
like Mr. Pete.
What?
Did he hurt Frankie?
He hurt her real bad.
Ain't nobody ever hurt Frankie
like Mr. Pete did.
What about the woman I've been talking to?
The Southern one?
You know her name?
- Sorry!
- I ain't done with that!
Thank you!
Here. Write her name.
"Alice."
"This contract is
an agreement between you,
"the patient,
Francine L. Murdoch
"and alternate personalities Alice
and Genius, and Dr. Joseph Oswald.
"All concerned are
expected to respect."
"Please do not sign the contract
until you are satisfied
"with the terms
and conditions of it.
"If you are not satisfied,
"you are strongly advised
to discuss the matters
"with me, Dr. Joseph Oswald."
She's her usual
charming self this morning.
Coffee?
Why, thank you, Doctor.
Just set it right over there.
What's the matter?
You don't quite seem
yourself this morning.
I want you to
tell me about Pete.
I think he hurt Frankie
and I think you know about it.
And I want to know how and why.
How sweet.
You've been talking
to that child, I see.
Well, I'm sure
I'll take care of that.
You look tired.
Were you up all night,
thinking about your wife?
Or is it somebody new?
Well, now, I don't mean
to be ungrateful, Doctor,
but why would I waste a second
of my time to help her?
What do you mean "ungrateful"?
Well, for all the help
you've given me.
I think it's this place.
Poor thing's gettin' tired.
She's findin' it harder
and harder to cope.
I don't know how much longer
she can go on fightin' with me.
Alice...
You gotta see who you are.
You're black, you're not white.
You're her, and she's you.
Well, then who am I looking at?
You don't mean to tell me you're
taking the side of a common donkey?
Nobody's taking anybody's sides.
This is not a fight.
It's not a battle you can win.
Well, I promise you, Doctor,
it's not a battle I will ever let her win.
I have a contract here,
I want you to sign.
It sets out some provisions...
Doc?
Frankie?
I can hear her in my head.
You can?
That's good.
That's fantastic, Frankie.
That's fantastic.
We're getting there, Frankie.
- We're getting there.
- Yeah.
"I, the patient,
"agree to take part in the
treatment proposed, as follows...
"I understand
the objectives of treatment
"the techniques to be used...
"Francine L. Murdoch...
"Alice, Genius...
"...and Dr. Joseph Oswald."
Hello, Martha?
Is this a message machine?
I know it's late,
but I was thinking of something you said...
No, I wasn't thinking,
I was feeling.
But then, on the one level,
cognitively,
there's very little
to distinguish
between the processes of
thinking and feeling, and...
It's Oz.
No, I'll start all over again.
What I wanted to say is that...
Whoever it is that
you wanted me to be...
I think I'm prepared
to be him now.
For you.
What?
Thank you.
Francine. Good morning.
I am Warren Backman and I am
here to make my evaluation.
Evaluation?
Yes, I was hoping
that we might start off
with a few simple tests,
if you don't mind?
Okay, but who the fuck are you?
I'm the Chief Psychiatrist
here. Okay?
Just tell me what you see.
I see a honky
in a piss-ugly suit.
Now would you please
go get my doctor.
'Cause he wants me
to sign this shit
and I don't even know
what the hell this is.
Look, Francine.
I'm not obliged to keep you in here.
Now, I don't want you out
on the streets causing havoc.
And I don't wanna release you if
you're gonna be a danger to yourself,
but how am I supposed to judge
the level of care you need
if you won't cooperate with me?
I got a court order, don't I?
I'm supposed to be up in here.
Well, no, that's not true.
Those charges were dropped.
Dr. Oswald should have
explained that to you.
You lied to me!
Nurse Shaw!
Love can hurt, can't it?
He didn't abuse her.
She loved him!
I've been an idiot.
Too literal.
Far too literal again!
What?
See how that goes.
You discharged a patient
under my care.
You had no right to do that.
Dr. Oswald, maybe this could
wait until later in my office...
She was a patient at this hospital.
She was deep in therapy!
She was an outpatient at this hospital,
Joe, and you knew that.
Now, why didn't you tell your
patient that she was free to go?
Because it had to
be handled carefully!
I'd drawn up a contract
I wanted them each to sign.
You were waiting for her
multiples to give you the okay?
Well, of course! How else was I
going to get them to cooperate?
Well, did you plan on having
their lawyers look it over first?
That's an incredibly unimaginative
way of looking at it.
Her address is on file.
And her next of kin.
Probably too many previous
employments to be any use, but...
Some white guy here.
Has something happened?
Is it the police?
I doubt it.
I didn't know
she was seeing a psychiatrist.
How could she afford it?
Well, technically the State was paying for
her treatment while she was under my care.
- What's wrong with her?
- There ain't nothing wrong with her.
She just has these spells and the
child gets agitated sometimes.
She's been like that, though,
ever since she was a girl.
I really have to find her.
We ain't seen her in a while.
Last I heard,
she was some place down in Florida...
She was just here.
She flew in here this morning.
She had one of
her crazy moods on.
She was asking for money
and saying that we owed her,
and then she went for Mama.
Show the man what she did!
She just wanted the necklace,
that's all.
She wanted the necklace
and I told her
she couldn't afford it
when she gave it to me.
Mama, she had her hands around your
throat and she wouldn't let go!
- Stop it!
- Why do you keep defending her?
She's my daughter!
Actually, in a sense, the one who
attacked you is not your daughter.
Frankie has a very
particular condition.
It's brought on
by repressed trauma.
I believe it has something
to do with a man she knew.
A Pete, a Mr. Pete.
Do you know him?
He died, Dr. Oswald.
He died a long time ago.
That was God's will.
They was trying to live
between two worlds.
Wouldn't have fitted
in neither one.
Are you saying he was white?
It's over now.
And now it's time
for you to leave.
With all respect, it's not over.
It's not over for Frankie
and I'm trying to help her.
And I'm not?
I've always tried to do
what was best for Frankie.
I've only done what was right.
Whatever happened, this,
her illness, it's not your fault.
If she tries to
contact you again...
Or if you could tell me
where she last held a job,
I would appreciate it.
She works at the phone
company over in Inglewood.
Thank you.
No, she don't.
Better get you a pencil
and draw you a map.
You don't look like the kind of man
who would know where this place is.
Yeah!
You feeling groovy out there?
I never touched the guy!
What do I look like?
Do I look retarded?
You were on your knees with
a nice dick in your mouth!
Well I never
touched him with my hand.
Come on, Hal.
Give her a break.
- Go on.
- We're outta here.
Ooh!
Hello, handsome.
I need a smoke.
- You Vice?
- No.
I'm looking for
Francine Murdoch.
- Who?
- Francine Murdoch.
She works here, or used to.
I'm her psychiatrist.
Oh, you mean Frankie.
She was definitely a whack job.
Good moves, great tits,
but pure psycho.
Do you know where she might be?
Can you tell me?
It's important.
She might be over in Lakewood.
She might be in Venice Beach.
She might be in Philly,
taking cookies to her sick grandmother.
Now, would you mind getting out of my
place of work. I got things to do...
You looking for Frankie?
You're a doctor?
A head doctor?
Do you know where
she liked to go?
Maybe some place unusual?
Someplace she normally
wouldn't be found dead in?
She's sick?
I mean, mentally?
You're gonna fix her, right?
You better!
Try to think of a place she might go
when she wasn't acting like herself.
We like to call
our servants "staff."
Quite often, we would
treat them like family.
Wait, Alice. Maybe I knew your aunt.
Why, sure I did.
Jemima?
Or perhaps it was your uncle.
Did you have an uncle named Tom?
Thank you for my drinks,
gentlemen, but I...
Hey hey, Alice, wait.
I was only fooling.
- Excuse me.
- You haven't finished your drink.
Sit down.
Alice!
I'm sorry I'm so late.
Let's go.
Hey. Hey!
Who's gonna pay for her drinks?
It's a curious thing,
but the thought of
breaking your nose
is almost as satisfying
as actually doing it.
You came for me?
Of course I did.
Thank you.
You came for me.
Give that necklace
back to me! It's mine.
It's mine! Give it back to me!
Mama!
No! Mama!
I know he died.
It's something you have to face.
We was in love,
then a car killed him.
What else you want to know?
I don't remember
that much about it really.
Well, maybe she does.
That's her?
Does that name
mean anything to you?
But I want to see her.
Is that something
you can help me do?
Yeah.
How?
Oh, shit.
You don't have no idea, do you?
You're not alone.
Well, no shit!
You lied to me, Doc.
- No, I didn't.
- Yeah. You did.
You ain't tell me that I
didn't have to be here by law.
Well, I withheld
some information.
Yeah, well...
That's okay.
If we're gonna keep workin' on this thing,
there's somethin' I'm gonna need.
Dr. Oz,
is that all?
Yes. Thank you.
What's this?
Where'd you get that from, Doc?
You steal that shit?
Can you put those away?
Oh.
Sorry.
You should try this though.
Really good!
I want you to
concentrate on the light.
Focus solely on the light.
There's nothing but the light.
And you're no longer here.
It's no longer now.
We're going back
to your youth...
Going back to Georgia.
What are you doing?
This is my brother!
Get out of my house,
you filthy degenerate!
Get out!
We had to leave.
Because of what
happened with Pete?
He was gonna take me to a
place where nothing mattered.
Not money...
Not family...
Not the skin color.
He loved you?
You came for me.
He loved me so much.
But he died?
Miss?
Miss, can you hear me?
His hand,
I want to touch it,
but I can't touch it.
What happened
after the accident?
After he died, what happened?
Mama.
Your mother? Edna?
Oh, it hurts, Mama. It hurts!
Frankie?
She lied to me.
She made me a promise
and she broke it.
What kind of promise?
Why the only promise
that really matters!
Alice, what promise?
What's happening, Frankie?
Where are you?
Can you tell me where you are?
"With skin and flesh
you clothed me,
"with bones and sinew,
you knit me together.
"Your hands have
formed and furnished me.
"Will you then
turn and destroy me?"
Who wants to destroy you, Alice?
Mama!
Is it coming, Mama?
What is it?
What's coming?
Oh!
Frankie, what's coming?
Mr. Oz?
Is that you, Mr. Oz?
Yes, Genius. It's me.
She's hurting.
I know.
I know she's hurting.
She's hurting!
- And she's crying!
- Yeah.
She's crying.
The pain will go away, Genius.
Frankie will be okay.
It's not Frankie.
It's not Frankie!
Then who is it?
- No, Frankie!
- Who is it, Frankie?
Mama, is it coming?
Yes, baby, it's coming.
Just breathe, Frankie.
Just keep breathing.
Push...
It hurts, Mama. It hurts.
I know. Push, baby.
Push. Push.
Mama... Is it coming, Mama?
Mama! Please, make it stop!
All right, baby.
Just come on, now.
Can you see it?
Tell me what it is!
Come on. Come on.
Me and Pete,
we got names picked out.
Emmett if it's a boy,
and if it's a girl...
Frankie...
Okay, baby.
Okay. Thank God.
- Mama, is it out?
- Yes, baby.
Tell me what it is.
Is it a girl?
What? Mama, what's wrong?
Mama? What's wrong?
Mama, why isn't he crying?
Let me see my baby.
Wait, Mama!
Where are you going?
No, Mama!
Mama!
No!
"With skin and flesh
you clothed me.
"With bones and sinew,
you knit me together.
"Your hands have
formed and furnished me.
"Will you then
turn and destroy me?"
Who wants to destroy you?
Mr. Oz?
Is that you, Mr. Oz?
It's me.
She's hurting.
I know she's hurting.
And she's crying!
Frankie...
I saw a hand move.
My mama killed it.
Our memories are not
always trustworthy.
Maybe the child wouldn't
have survived anyway.
Perhaps your mother just tried
to protect you from that.
Protect me?
Every dream I had
was in that baby.
It's the only thing
I had left of Pete.
Me and Pete,
we got names.
If it's a boy,
we gonna name it Emmett...
And if it's a girl...
Alice.
We were going to call her Alice.
Do you think my mama killed her?
I think all of us have to face
something we've done,
mistakes we've made,
things we've allowed to happen.
The things that
would've happened anyway.
But I don't think it's
the blame that's important.
I think it's the facing of it.
If we don't, there's no chance
ever for us to become whole.
Are they gone?
No.
But so long as you continue to
experience simultaneous co-presence,
you have a chance of achieving
successful integration.
In English, Doc?
You'll have to
learn to live together.
Wall Street, Tina baby.
Wall Street.
I will be
putting it on your mid-term.
Like a fresh start.
Well, I can work with that.
Is Alice going to let me be me?
That's between the two of you.
You have to understand,
treatment is indefinite.
And integration is
only the beginning.
The ultimate goal is acceptance.
How long will that take?
Honestly?
I don't know.
Guess we'd better get started.