Ru료, this is my niece Vera.
She's a hard-working girl.
She could replace Lidia.
I decide who we hire here, Mila.
Hurry up, we've got a lot to do.
There's one too many.
It's a gift.
I don't need any gifts.
Thank you.
8.30, please.
Bon app俸it.
Is the butcher sick again?
15.50.
Too much meat is bad for you anyway.
Thank you.
Slovenia played badly last night.
That's not true.
You've never understood
anything about football.
They played terribly
and that's that!
That was offside.
You're blind.
Weren't you at the eye doctor's last week?
There we go!
They're going to score.
Goal!
Time to go, gentlemen.
Out of the 7 inhabitants...
who were all asleep...
only the little girl survived.
Here is the traffic news on Radio 24...
Okay.
You'll easily make your way from here.
Thanks.
Can you spare any change?
Spare any change?
Spare any change, please?
Cool, thanks a lot.
Excuse me, you got a cigarette?
Turkish?
Bosnian.
Thank you very much.
What are you up to tonight?
Were you in Sarajevo
during the siege?
Yes.
It was shit.
I was young at the time.
My grandma says...
I always stopped...
to look at the dead bodies.
It's really tough, a war like that!
Damn!
What were you looking at?
I'll be fine in a minute.
It doesn't look good.
14.50.
Mila!
Just a minute.
I'll take care of it.
Here you are.
Wait.
Here.
For your work.
I just wanted to help.
I could use...
someone like you.
No thanks,
I'm not from here.
And then I finished...
my studies in New York.
- In New York?
- Yes.
My brother and I
always wanted to go there.
So?
Why didn't you go?
He killed himself after the war.
Cheers.
룔vjeli means "to life!"
To life!
Do you live alone?
I think...
I'd better get home.
When can we meet again?
I'm sorry, really, sorry.
Good girl!
Heel.
Damn.
What do you want?
Get lost.
Leave me alone.
I can't tell you anything new
about your condition.
You're better
but the symptoms will come back.
- Ms. Hanovic.
- Tanovic!
You have to get yourself
to a hospital.
In Sarajevo they gave me pills.
Yes, but that's not enough
to treat your condition.
Is there anyone who could be a...
bone marrow donor for you?
Do you have any siblings?
I'm alive!
How long
have you been working here?
From the very beginning.
We've been through a lot together,
me and Ru료.
But I'm not staying much longer.
We're going back home
to Croatia next year.
Look, it's on the coast.
It'll be lovely... one day.
My Ante is building it.
But he's hurt his foot and can't work.
Don't bother.
She won't appreciate it.
It looks prettier this way.
Watch out Fredi!
Where did you learn German?
In Sarajevo.
At school.
During the war?
So?
I don't understand you.
What are you doing in this canteen?
Making money...
and anyway, I won't stay long.
That's what we all said!
And you young people
travel for fun these days.
We left home to earn money.
You're spoiled.
Finished?
Are you new here?
Looks like it.
Where are you from?
Bosnia.
Ana! Come here.
You're here to work not chat.
That goes for everyone.
OK.
Why do you speak German to me, Ru료?
You're from Belgrade, aren't you?
Number two, please.
18, here you are.
Hey you, come over here!
Does this belong to one of you?
Thank you.
Where do you come from?
Sarajevo.
How long have you been here?
A few days.
See, she's only just arrived and speaks...
better German than you do after 40 years.
What's life there like these days?
Go and see for yourselves!
Where shall I put it?
You don't need to bring me my food.
Leave it in the kitchen in future.
See you tomorrow then.
Have a good night.
Are you going to sort out your papers?
I have to register you.
I'm not sure...
how long I'll stay.
I met Pero today.
The workers have been booked
to do the roof.
When for?
When we're there.
I need to keep an eye on things...
I thought we wouldn't...
be able to go this year because of your leg.
Do you think I can just leave it
to the workers?
So once again Mila has to cook...
and clean up after everybody.
When will I get a chance to relax?
Calm down dear,
we need to get our house finished.
Where can we go back to otherwise?
The younger one's thinking
about coming with us.
But Miro will have
a family of his own soon.
You can't just get up and go
once there's a family.
Ru료 doesn't want us
to throw those away.
Rinse them and chop them up with the rest.
I didn't forget.
Hey, you're bleeding!
She's got a nosebleed.
Go and wash your hands!
I've seen it all before,
birthdays.
What do you mean?
- Is it her birthday?
- Yeah.
Aren't we going to celebrate?
Fr屢lein and celebrate!?
What if we throw a party for Ru료?
Now you've completely lost it!
She might like it.
Forget it!
She'll fire us.
You first.
What the hell's going on?
Get out.
Now, out.
Happy Birthday, Ru료.
Today we're celebrating Ru료.
Ru료!
Do you want to dance, Ru료?
Look at her, the little Bosnian.
She isn't afraid of anything.
Come on, let's dance!
Come on.
- Franz, I'm too old.
- Don't be silly!
Stay with me.
Morning, beautiful.
I overslept.
It certainly took a lot of wine and music...
to finally let me stay over.
Don't you have to go to work?
We can go together.
I'll hurry up.
I have to leave now.
Make sure you lock the door properly.
You're late.
Here, we work the same after parties.
Tired after all the dancing?
And 10.
How are you?
7.30.
What are you doing here?
I missed you.
I can't just sell you...
a prescription drug.
It's not allowed in this country.
I've taken it before,
it's nothing special.
You've come to the wrong place.
Go and see a doctor.
8.30, please.
Thanks. Bye.
What are you still doing here?
I'm working.
Finish, I'm locking up.
Do you have a brother or a sister?
A brother.
Where does he live?
In Belgrade.
Do you see each other often?
He still plays the piano every day.
His repertoire covers everything
from jazz to Chopin.
Question:
What was Chopin's first name?
He doesn't even know!
Come on, say something!
- So?
- Henry Chopin.
- Wolfgang, Sebastian.
This question goes
to you too, Mr. Remund.
His name was Frederic Chopin.
Did you find the towels?
Is everything okay?
You remind me of my brother Adis!
These are his milk teeth.
Are you falling sick?
If you need anything,
I've got everything:
Vitamin C,
Aspirin, throat lozenges.
Help yourself.
I'm a hypochondriac.
Where do you work?
Can I have your phone number?
Thanks for looking after me.
I'd like to look after you again.
No sugar.
240.
200, 300.
Come in.
Time flies, doesn't it?
Thank you.
I'm off then.
Don't you want to count it?
I'm sure it's fine.
If there's one thing you're good at,
it's counting.
You're doing a great job.
You've adjusted quickly.
Well. Adjusted.
I want to go to the mountains.
What are you scared of?
Are you afraid
I'll push you or I'll jump?
I don't like that emptiness down there.
Don't you want to know
what the war was like?
Everybody asks me about it.
Well, only if...
you want to tell me something about it?
Not really.
Are you afraid of dying Ru료?
What kind of a question is that?
It's the only thing I'm scared of!
How silly!
At your age!
It's beautiful up here.
I wonder what it looks like in summer.
There's no snow.
Ana, Ana, no.
A hot punch, please.
And for your daughter?
- The same.
- Two punches.
I ordered you a punch.
Thank you.
- How old are you?
- Guess.
Twenty...
...two.
Not bad.
- Cheers.
- Thank you.
I was 22, too...
when I came from Yugoslavia.
Nobody calls it Yugoslavia anymore.
Do you miss it?
No.
Do you miss Bosnia?
When were you there last?
When my mother died.
You know...
I've been here...
for almost 25 years.
A lot of people left the country back then...
Even though we didn't have a bad life.
But I wanted to live better...
to be more independent.
I was ambitious,
had plans...
and I was in love.
And?
He was supposed to come, too.
But...
...he didn't.
- Cheers.
Didn't you ever want to go back?
No.
But sometimes...
I wake up in the middle of the night...
and I'm scared.
I don't know where I want to be buried.
What difference does it make
when you're dead!
Let's go for a drink!
I have to go home.
OK.
See you tomorrow then.
Where do you live?
With friends.
The key to the canteen.
Make sure you lock up!
Thank you.
Maybe I...
could come along...
fishing after all.
But I've already booked!
I was down in Croatia recently Ante.
Life has gotten expensive there.
Don't worry,
Ante has it all worked out.
He'll go on
"Who wants to be a millionaire?"
Ante's a genius.
He's sure to get through to the first round.
In one year you'll get your pension...
Then you'll be off home, right?
You'll definitely miss the boys!
It's not like I get to see them often here.
Anyhow, we have each other!
And we can do...
some work on the house if we get bored.
Help yourselves!
Did you think I wouldn't notice?
I'm going to tell Ru료 everything.
Making yourself at home like that!
You should be ashamed of yourself.
You're very ungrateful.
Ru료 took you in...
even though nobody knew you.
Nobody actually knows
what you're doing here.
And what are you doing here, Mila?
Your house is waiting.
It might suit you.
Come with me!
I want to show you a place!
- I can't.
- Do you have plans?
- No, but...
- Come on!
No, wait, I can't.
15 black.
16 yellow chips for you, sir.
For you, madam.
- Let's go.
- Thank you.
People gamble in casinos.
What did you expect?
- Come on, try.
- No way.
Come on!
Go put your money on a row!
Six black.
You've won.
And 13... for you.
Let's go.
Let's go. Stop it!
35.
Ru료!
You forgot your winnings.
And you?
You just threw your money away.
Just like that.
I don't give a damn about money.
I was like you once.
So carefree,
full of joie de vivre,
an optimist.
You've got no idea how difficult...
it was here at the beginning!
It was lonely, damn lonely.
Every day I wanted to pack my bags...
and disappear,
go back home.
But I didn't,
I stayed.
And I created something.
Something for myself.
Now, I don't need anybody anymore.
I've made it.
Do you understand?
Who are you to tell me about life?
What is it you want to tell me?
That I should live your life?
I'm not like you,
you don't know me!
How dare you talk to me like that?
Ru료,
I'm scared, really scared.
I have leukemia.
I wasn't expecting you...
What a nice surprise.
Don't you want to get undressed?
I started the inventory lists.
Put them on the table.
What's the matter with Ana?
What do you mean,
what's the matter with Ana?
It was hard work today without her.
I'm getting used to her.
Where's my money?
No idea.
You took my money, just like that.
I had to put down...
a deposit for the roof.
Our roof, Mila.
I was saving up for a new coat.
Calm down love.
We must get that house finished.
Where can we go back to otherwise?
I'm not spending
any more money on that house.
What good is that house to me?
But Mila, it's our dream!
It's no longer my dream.
Our children are here,
my life is here.
Do you know the feeling,
when you think...
you're thirsty and then you realize...
what you're feeling is longing?
Your blood count isn't very good,
but statistically...
people respond well to this treatment,
especially at your age.
You've been treated in Sarajevo before!
Yes.
We'll start chemotherapy tomorrow.
You could of course continue...
the treatment in Sarajevo.
What matters most
is that you start immediately.
You know what Ru료?
All hospitals smell the same.
But the view is different!
The best view is the one...
you choose for yourself.
Lie down and sleep a little.
Don't worry,
I'm counting it for the third time.
Just to be sure!
What are you doing here?
I'm only doing your job...
because you weren't there.
You could be grateful!
Good night Ru료.
See you tomorrow.
Mila.
Thank you!
Good night.