Hey, there he is,
at one o'clock!
Let's get behind him!
Yeah.
We'll cut him off!
Get him!
About 200 yards!
Clear!
I got it!
Full throttle!
Let it go!
Whoo-hoo!
Hey!
More throttle!
Keep it up!
That's it!
That's it.
[crying]
Lay it down! Keep it coming!
Lay it down!
Yeah, fish!
Yeah!
Come on, boy!
Yeah, baby!
Yeah!
Yeah, fish!
Go on in there!
Pin it! Pin it!
Closing in!
Close it up!
Yeah!
They got him!
Yeah! Go!
He's not getting away!
Keep the others
away from him!
We got him!
[crying]
Close it up!
That's it!
[crying]
- Here goes!
- Got it!
- Whoo!
[crying]
Get him
in the middle!
- Go, go, go!
- Yeah!
Keep closin' it up!
Come on!
[crying]
Yeah!
Back up a bit!
All right!
Tighten it up!
Yeah!
FREE WILLY
Excuse me. My mom dropped me off
on the way to work,
And she forgot
to give me bus fare.
Could I borrow
some money?
Oh, thanks, lady!
You have a good day.
Thanks a lot!
I really gotta get home, man.
If you could lend me
a just, like, a buck--
Get outta here.
Excuse me, lady.
Excuse me.
My friends and I
are having a problem.
You see, we spent all our money
at the natural history museum,
And we have to take
the ferry home.
Think you could
help me out?
I suppose.
A few bucks.
Shoot!
I'm hungry.
God, man.
I need some food.
Let's go.
Let's go, Jess!
Hey! Hey, you kids!
Come back here!
Ha ha ha!
Oh, cool!
Yeah!
Come on, guys.
Wha ha!
Whoo!
You know, the first time
I ever went there,
oh!  It was so bad.
My mom dropped me off when
she went to work in Houston.
I never saw her again.
I Don't care.
I hate her anyway.
You know, I could eat
one of these every day.
Yeah,
well, I bolted.
- Oh!  You bolted from Cooperton?
- I did, bonehead.
Yeah, right.
Shut up! Bull shit!
What do you know?
I know they watch like you're gonna stick
a knife in their back.
I had to wait till some stupid foster home
losers took me, and then I slipped.
- Maybe you ain't
as smart as us.
- Oh, eat it.
- I am.
I just want
my own place.
Like an apartment
or something.
Yeah, right.
You and me, man,
We'll hook up
with someone.
With my brains and your
wonderful personality, we'll be rich.
Get outta here!
Go, go, go!
Let's split up!
- See you, guys!
- All right. Bye!
This way!
Come on!
Go, go, go, man!
Go, man! This way.
Come on, come on!
Come on! Go!
Quick! Go!
Quick, quick, quick!
Move!
- Uhh!
- Down here.
Right here.
Shut it.
Quick, quick, quick!
Check it out, man.
Perry?
Aah!
What is that?
Wow!
Jesse, cops!
Run!
There he is!
Hold it, kid!
Heading up the stairs, Jim!
Hey, kid!
- All right.
- Hold on.
Let go of me!
Relax.
Calm down.
Unhh! Uhh! No!
Breakin' and enterin', malicious mischief,
Vandalism, resisting arrest.
Anything else happen
I should know about?
Yeah, I robbed a few banks.
Is that a problem?
Yeah, I'm glad you were
only out there 3 days, son.
Sit down.
Aw, did you miss me,
Dwight?
So was Perry with you
on this number?
Perry who?
Look, don't play.
Don't come in here
being a bonehead.
Now, I hate telephones,
and I spent 45 minutes
on a conference call...
with the police department
and that Adventure Park...
trying to keep you clean, son.
You know what?
We were lucky this time.
I kept you a little
behind out of court.
You have to clean up the mess you made
at Northwestern Adventure Park.
Ah, ah,..., ah!  That is your probation.
You got a problem with that?
- Yeah. Why should I have to clean it up?
- You know, I don't know why...
I fool around with
you kids in the first place.
You know, I don't know why
I'm working so much overtime with you.
But you split out again here,
and I am out of the picture.  Gone!
You'll be with Youth Authority,
court supervised and controlled.
They'll put you in baby jail. That means
a lockup in juvenile hall, son.
Ok, look...
Your placement is still on.
The greenwoods are OK.
They don't even care
about this...incident.
What's wrong with  them?
Oh, I see.
Because they want you in their home, there's
got to be something wrong with them, right?
What do you think?
I think that on paper you're still real
young, so you get some chances.
Not an infinite number of chances,
but a few.
A few, son.
You get it?
Ok, you got any questions
about, uh, any of this?
You hear from my mom?
You still want me
to hear from you mom?
I just want to know if she's okay.
Nobody's heard from your mom
in six years, Jesse.
Anytime you're ready, big guy.
Hi, Jesse.
Hi, Dwight.
- Hey, how are you doing, Annie?
- Good.  How you doing?
Well, It's kinda been a long day
for the both of us.
- Hello, Dwight.
- Hey.
Hey.
There he is.
- Can I carry your stuff for you?
- No.
Well, why don't we go inside and
wash up, and we'll have dinner?
Well, Glen, got a little
paperwork here for you.
Always got to have
the paperwork.
You know, I bought a new car recently.
Man, with the contracts and all, it came to 37 pages.
Well, this is a lease.
I ain't buying yet.
- You interested in computers, Jesse?
- No.
- Well, I could teach you.
I just learned last summer myself.
- I'm not into it.
That makes two of us.
Well, I wasn't, either,...
but then I decided that I wanted
a second career as a journalist.
I'm a teacher,
and so I'm taking
the Summer off to write.
A couple of weeklies have, uh,
taken a couple of my stories.
- I haven't earned anything yet.
- Go ahead!  Just dig right in.
In fact, that's how I know Dwight.
I did a story on Cooperton.
Dwight's a jerk.
So, what exactly
are you into, Jesse?
I'm not into talking
while I'm eating.
Here's your room, Jesse.
Our bedroom's downstairs,
buut, uh...
You've got the best view
in the house.
Go ahead. Open it.
It's, uh, kind
of a welcome gift.
You can open it
later, if you like.
Uh, I--I bought you
some things, some clothes.
Some socks, and, uh,
there's lots of blue.
Dwight said you like blue.
Anyway, uh,
try them on,
And... And if you don't like them,
we can exchange them.
Well, I guess we'll get outta here now.
If you need us for anything,
we'll be downstairs.
Good night, Jesse.
It's great to have you here, Jesse.
Good night.
Hey, Jess.  You remember that turn
right before the bridge?  That's 88th Street.
My garage is
straight up from there.
If you go 6 more blocks,
you'll be right at the house.
Think you can find it?
When you go inside, you're looking for
the Aquatic Theater. Ask for Randolph.
Yeah. Great.
Hey, mister.
Do you know where
I can find Randolph?
Yeah, he lives in the cottage
right by the water.
Thanks.
Hello?
Randolph?
What's this?
Well...
The artist returns.
Well come back.
We've all become great admirers
of your work around here...
...but all good things
must come to an end.
Time to let your
creativity flow backwards.
You know what to do
with all this?
- Yes, I do.
- Good.  See you later.
Wow!
Hey!
Uhh!
What are you doing up here?
Nothing.
7,000 pounds, that one.
Jaws powerful enough
to crush bones to oatmeal.
Willy gets into moods.
You gotta give him his space.
You know what I mean?
Don't bother him, he won't bother you.
You understand?
Sure.
[band music plays]
Ladies and gentlemen,
girls and boys,...
...just a reminder that our sea lion show
plays 4 times daily,
...and your Northwest Adventure Pass
will admit you to all sessions.
Show times are at 10:00,
12:00, 2:00, and 4:00.
[crowd applauds]
As you can see, Olivia and Belinda
flip out at lunchtime.
Belinda. Belinda, we have a nice-looking
audience.  What do you think?
[barking]
Yes.
You are looking so beautiful.
How about a kiss?
You should be ashamed
of yourselves.
Wave goodbye to everybody.
Wave goodbye.
Let's give a big round of applause
to Olivia and Belinda,
...and their trainer, Rae Lindley.
[applause]
In a couple of minutes, ladies and gentlemen,
you'll be able to have a look at Willy,
...our prize orca whale,
right here in the main tank.
- You're the graffiti kid, aren't you?
- I guess.
You really messed up
our observation area.
Sorry.
- You like whales?
- I like him.
Well, he doesn't like anybody,
so you be careful around him.
See, Willy's a case.
A very special case.
So?
Who isn't?
Wanna play catch?
Catch?
Yeah.
I like to throw the ball
around once in a while.
Had this mitt ever since
I was in eighth grade.
We used to sit around and...
Spit in it, Smack it.
Get a nice pocket there.
Look at that.  Pretty nice, huh?
Let's play.
How much they paying
you to be my jailer?
Your jailer, huh?
Yeah, boy, I'm making such a great deal
on you, you wouldn't believe it.
You're
a regular cash cow, kid.
That, plus a million dollars, I could
probably retire by the time I'm 300 years old.
Look, you're gonna have to help
me out a little bit here.
Ok?
Dwight says that I'm supposed
to make some rules for you, and....
Problem is, I've always been a better rule-breaker
than a rule-maker myself, and, uh....
So you're gonna have to tell me
what you think you need.
You're askin' me?
Yeah! Well, you're
the big expert, right?
I Don't know any rules.
Aw, come on!  Kid like you?
Been around, been in trouble.
What's it gonna be?
Ok.
Let's see. Uh...
I got it.
First rule is...
You have to give me an allowance
every week.
Fiive bucks.
What's next?
I don't know.
I haven't thought about it yet.
Well, while you're thinking about it,
I need you in bed every night by 10:00 o'clock.
And up every morning
in time for breakfast.
And I want you in the house
every night by 7:00.
And don't go running
around the neighborhood
...and disappearing without
telling somebody.
'cause we need to know
where you are.
Ok!
Kid.
[sighs]
Almost finished with this place.
[music]
Ohh!
Come on. Come on.
Aah!
Ha ha!
Well, you have a nice
day, too, grouch.
He likes messing around with
people's heads, doesn't he?
Yes, he does.
If I can't get him to perform,
no one can.
Orcas are usually
nice and smart.
Willy's smart and nasty.
- You really like him, huh?
- Yeah.
Good.
You can help me out.
Broken belly.  Toss it.
Look. This is a good fish.
That's a bad fish.
Good fish, bad fish.
Every day we gotta sort out what Willy can eat
from the cheap crap they buy him.
Willy's a killer whale, right?
So would he kill us?
No!  Orcas are just hunters.
Mostly they eat fish.
Well, sometimes they'll eat
porpoises, squid... birds...
...sharks...
What Willy really
likes is salmon.
That's his chocolate.
Kiss me. Kiss me. Kiss me.
Rrr...Rrr...
Ready to get back
to your painting?
[music]
Aah!
[cough]
You saved my life.
You must have something special, kid.
That's why Willy didn't eat you up.
- What do you mean?
- Oh, I don't know.
High blood, medicine roots.
- No way.
- Then you're one lucky white boy.
Like the sound
of that better?
Willy doesn't have a problem with me.
We appreciate each other.
Appreciate? Ha.
Willy saved your butt.
I don't know why everybody around
here has a big problem with him just because...
Willy does not like visitors
in his tank.
What the heck
were you doing there?
I came to say good-bye.
Job was almost up.
Didn't want to say good-bye.
Well, just maybe...
- What?
- Ahh!
Old Indian stuff.
Orcas.
Ever look into Willy’s eyes?
Those eyes discovered the stars
...long before man was even
a whisper on mother earth.
Could look into a man's soul
if they want.
Willy...
He won't look at Rae...or me.
Maybe he sees you.
Looks like your parents
are still up.
They're not my parents.
Jesse, where have you been?
You're soaked!
I was at work.
You snuck out of the house in the
middle of the night to clean up graffiti?
- That's an amazing story.
- I fell in the tank.
The whale tank?
Will somebody please tell me
what the heck is going on around here?
I slipped and fell in the tank.
It's my fault.
- Oh, right.
- Folks, my name is Randolph.
Randolph, how are you?
I'm Glen. This is my wife Annie.
Hi.
I've been supervising Jesse down at
the park.  He's been doing a really good job.
Did his cleanup, helped out in some
other areas, and made some friends.
The thing is, we could use him for the rest
of the summer, if that's all right with you.
Make a job of it.
Pay him a little something, too.
What do you say
to that?
Yeah! Yeah!
I want to, please!
Finally found something
that you're into, huh, Jess?
Well, it sounds OK, but days.
No more of this sneaking out at night.
All right.
I promise I won't.
Just be straight with us
from now on, all right?
If there's something
that you need, just ask us.
Think you can do that?
All right.
It's past your bedtime.
I think you should get in
the house, son.
I'm not your son.
Yeah, I know that.
[Willy crying out]
- Ok, easy!
- Watch it!  Watch it!
Watch those lines!
[Willy cries out]
Why don't you just
get out of the way?
I'm not in the way.
Look, this examination area
is completely inadequate.
But it's all we've got.
Holding him in this net is dangerous.  We've
told you that I don't know how many times.
- Could you finish the exam now?
- No. He's acting up too much.
You and Dial bought Willy
from some slimeball whale catcher.
He was too big and too old to be caught
in the first place.
Then you put him
in a dolphin tank, alone.
He's not a natural performer,
and you expect me to work miracles?
You're paid to train him,
not analyze him.
These are not the circumstances
described when I signed on.
You're a professional, right?
So make it work.
Dial give me a line,
and I am not gonna cross it.
This is not about crossing lines.
Which words don't you understand?
Look, if the whale was
to bring in customers...
[crying out]
Then we could spend
some money on him.
But since he's not, you're just gonna
have to make do with what you've got.
Easy, Willy!  Easy, son!
Untie those back lines!
What's going on?
Randolph, what happened?
I don't know.
The net came loose.
I saw what you did.
- So?
- So nothing.
I'm sure Willy’s grateful.
The whale's still not performing.
We're getting deeper into this,...
...and Rae keeps saying we have
to expand that tank.
Very nice.
This is what I get...
...for bringing the animal in
to boost business.
Why don't we just move him into the
Ritz-Carlton?  I can tack it onto the 5,000...
I just dumped into his
latest insurance premium.
Yeah. The whale's worth
more dead than alive.
It will cost at least 100,000...
...to expand that psychotic
malcontent's playpen.
Oh, God,
I hate that whale.
You got any leftover
scraps or anything...
...I could take your hands off?
Might have.
Well, I've got a really
special friend named Willy.
Why would he
want scraps?
- Well... He's a whale.
- A whale?
Jess, man.
I'll meet you all up there.
- What's up, man?
- Perry.
New clothes.  New gig?
- Staying with some people.
- It's cool.
What happened to you that night, man?
I saw you get popped.
Not much.
Had to clean up all my mess.
I'm working there now.
They looking for me?
- Nah.
- Cool.
Yeah, it's a total drag, man.
Sorry.
No sweat.
Where you been staying?
Dayton set me up.
Working for him now, looking out
for cops and stuff. You know?
I mentioned you to him.
I can hook you up if you want.
I gotta think about that.
Snooze, you lose.
Stop by sometime, huh?
See you around.
I gotta bail.
All right, man.
- See ya.
- Later.
[music]
What's the matter, Willy?
Thought you liked these things.
You know?
Well, you know.  You're supposed
to eat it like this.
See?
No?
Oh...You want me to put it
in your mouth.
I'll make a deal
with you.
Don't bite my hand off, and I'll
give you the fish. Ok?
You like these.
Wow.
You're like... rubbery.
Skin peels off.
Still a beautiful animal, though.
Well, buddy, I gotta go.
We'll save these scraps
and fishes for later.
What, you want
to go with me?
Oh, I can do that, too.
You do it with the other arm?
Yeah?
Hey!
Hey, can you wave?
Can you dance for me?
Can you groove?
Dance?
Rae.
What?
Can you go in circles?
Hey, look.
Hey. You're really doing it.
Yeah, look at you.
Makes me dizzy.
Looks like Willy’s
got himself a soul mate.
Jess.
Can you feed him?
Sure, I can feed him.
It's easy.
Want a try?
Come on.
Willy and I didn't get off
to a very good start.
He thinks I'm the wicked witch or something
'cause of the medical tests I had to do on him.
You know, out in the ocean, killer whales
like Willy live in families. pods.
Some of them spend their whole lives with
their moms, and they never leave them.
Never?
Nope. Their social structure is
really important to them.
Over 50 orcas have been
seen traveling together.
Some of them stay together forever,
for their whole lives.
You've seen them out there?
Yeah. My dad was in the Navy.
He did sonar research
on whales.
I went out there all the time.
Well, do you do research here?
No. Here, I'm just a trainer, but
I want to work out on the ocean.
I'm going back to school
to get my PhD. in marine biology.
But if you do that, Willy will be alone.
And there'll be no one here to take care of him.
Well, Charlie's in school, so...
Who's Charlie?
My boyfriend, Charlie.
Do you have
a girlfriend?
- What makes you think I want one?
- Just guessing.
- This isn't him.
- What?
Willy. Right here.
- Sure, it is.
- Willy's fin is flopped over.
That's what happens in captivity.
Why?
Nobody knows.  Maybe they need
more room to really swim.
Then how come Mr. Dial
won't build Willy a bigger tank?
Because Dial thinks he can treat
a wild animals like a commodity.
What's that?
Just a big word Dial likes to use.
Actually, It means that Dial  won't
build Willy a bigger pool...
...unless he thinks he can make
more money off of him.
How'd you like
to help me with that?
Yeah, sure!
Most orcas love to play
around and do tricks.
They like the stimulation.
[snorts]
Can he see me underwater?
Sure, he can.  He can hear you, too,
from anywhere in this whole tank.
Now, this, young man,
is a target.
Willy's supposed
to respond to it, follow it.
And when we work on tricks or behaviors,
we reward him with fish.
Now, what we’re
gonna try to do is...
See if we can get Willy’s nose
to touch the end of this target.
Ok?
Ok.
Move out there.
You're doing pretty great.
Thanks.
Thank he with a fish!
There you go, Willy.
He likes that fish, doesn't he?
Roll on over.
Orcas love to be touched, petted,
hugged, anything like that.
Oh, they love to have
their tongue stroked.
Wait a minute...
You want me to take my hand,
stick it in his mouth, and rub his tongue?
Yeah, eventually.
I don't think so.
You'll learn to read him.
You'll be able to do it.
What's this?
Thought you might want to know
what we're dealing with here.
My father
gave it to me.
Thanks.
It's Haida.
What?
"Haida" is the name of my people.
300 years ago, there were so many
fish in the water,
...my people only had to spend
one day a week gathering food.
And everybody ate like kings.
- What did they do the rest of the time?
- Carved and painted totems,
...made music, told stories, made babies.
Sounds good to me.
Skaana.
It's the Haida word
for "whale".
Natsaclane was a Haida who lived a long
time ago, before there were orca whales.
Hunting fish with the other warriors,
young Natsaclane lost his way
...and found himself all alone.
While he was searching,
a fierce storm began.
Natsaclane couldn't find
shelter anywhere.
The otters came and took him
way down deep under the water...
...where he was safe
for the night.
After the storm, Natsaclane again
searched for the braves.
But all he found was a huge log.
He began carving
a great beast on the log...
...and tried carrying it to the ocean.
Finally, he found some water,
but it wasn't the ocean.
The great carving sank to the bottom
of this pool and disappeared.
Natsaclane sat
and watched and waited...
...and said a prayer
he never heard before.
Sa-la-na a-yoong I-asis.
He kept saying this prayer.
It's so weird!
He'd never heard it before.
Then it really got crazy, because
the water started flying out,
...and all this commotion
started happening.
And out of the water
came the carving.
And it wasn't a carving.
It was a whale, like Willy.
He flew all the way down
to the ocean, like a bird,
...and Natsaclane, he went after him,
down to the beach.
And he got on his back,
and rode him all the way home.
- Isn't that cool?
- That's very cool.
- What is this?
- It's an orca, like Willy.
Randolph gave it to me.
It's from his tribe.
It's beautiful.
Well. You get some rest.
Here.
Sweet dreams.
Night.
Sa-la-na a-yoong I-asis.
Hi, boy.
What's up?
Hi, buddy.
You like that?
Toot-toot-toot-toot-toot
Boo.
Gotcha.
Ho!
Hey! Hey, kid,
you took my fish!
Yeah!
Whoo!
All right!
I get your chocolate, buddy.
What's the matter?
What are you making
that awful noise for?
[crying]
Whoo!
- What you got there?
- It's a toy I made for Willy.
Big slap!
One more!
Big slap, Willie!
One more, buddy.
Come on, Willy!
Big circle, buddy, big circle!
Big circle!
Big circles, buddy.
Big circles!
Come here, boy!
Come on!
Come on, boy.
Here we go.
Whoo! Yeah!
All right!
There you go.
Double "a" 675434.
Hey, Jesse, what's up?
Annie.  Dinner.
Oh, terrific.
Hold on
one second.
I need 2 sets of gaskets for that, too.
So, don't forget.
Bring them in first thing
in the morning?
All right. Thanks.
Oh, neat car!
Check it out!
- You like that car?
- Oh, yeah.
That's a classic.
It was the love
of my life.
I spent 1 1/2 years putting that baby
together, getting it in primo condition.
And then I had to sell it.
Why?
Well, simple reason that you can't have
more than one love in your life.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
You and Annie...
Ever fight?
Yeah. We, uh...schedule one
every other month or so.
Why?
Just asking.
- Oh.  What's this?
- That's a picture of me and my mother.
Long time ago.
About your age there.
So where is she now?
Well...She died about 2 years ago.
Yeah, well, my mom's coming
to get me one of these days.
She is?
Not too long from now.
Well, that's funny.  That's, uh....
That's not what they said.
You don't believe me, do you?
It's not that.  I just...was
under the impression that--
I don't care what those people said.
Those people don't know anything!
Ok.
My mom has some things to take care of,
when she's done, she's coming back for me!
Jesse?
- Hi!
- Hi.
What happened?
He wasn't at the park.
He wasn't? Well, maybe
we should call Dwight.
It's after 11:00.
I know what time it is!
I'm sorry.
Jesse?
Where have you been?
What do you think you're doing?
You weren't at the park.
You're supposed to let us know
where you are! Remember?
It doesn't matter.
You want to dump me?
Go ahead. I Don't care.
I'm not living here.
I'm just staying here for a while.
[door slams]
How do you like that?
Just when you think you're starting
to get through,
...starting to make some sense,
starting to make a connection...
Whammo!
Well, he's scared.
He's pushing us away.
I'd like to give him a
push right out the door.
Hey, don't say things
like that!
What's the matter?
Does that make you angry?
Yes, it makes me angry!  It didn't help...
...if you use that tone of voice
the minute he came in the door.
- He's driving me crazy!
- You know why you're really angry?
No. Why?
You want to know why?
Because you have feelings for him,
...and that scares you because
he reminds you of yourself.
- Ok. You're right.
- I know I'm right.
I don't like it.  We don't
owe anybody anything, OK?
We tried.  We did the best we could do.
It doesn't have to be any more than that.
What is this, another
one of your crusades?
This is not a crusade, Glen.
We're talking about a human being!
Annie, I'm happy,
just you and me.
Jesse?
Are you OK?
I just got scared.
What are you scared about?
I dn't know.
I heard you guys fighting.
It scared me.
Jesse, adults
argue sometimes.
But that doesn't mean that
anybody's gonna get hurt.
I would never hurt Annie
...or you.
You should know that.
I know.
I see you opened
your present.
Yeah. Thanks.
Let's go outside and find the baseball.
What do you say?
Ok.
Not gonna steal this one, kid.
I should charge you double.
There you go.
See you, kid.
This is from me to you.
There you go, bud.
Got that with all
my pocket money. Enjoy.
- Aw, Perry, man!
- What's up, man?
What is that?
It's an orca.
- Awesome!
- Definitely awesome, man.
So...I'm going.
First Sacramento, then L.A.
Dayton and I are like...
business partners, you know.
You can get in on it.
Perry, I can't do
that right now.
Aw, come on, man!
This is major stuff.
We're gonna be rich.
All right, fool,
be that way.
Here.
This is where we're going.
Look, if you ever get
the guts to go, look me up.
Sure.
See you, Perry.
Hey, Willy.
You miss your family?
Yeah, well,
my mom's a pain.
Couldn't take
care of me.
Couldn't even take
care of herself.
I haven't seen her
since I was a little kid.
But, you know, I still miss her.
Greenwoods, they're OK.
They're OK.
You know, it's rough.
I'm nervous with them.
That's just the way it is.
It could be a lot worse.
Really. You understand?
I'm sure you miss
your family, too.
And I Hope you
find them one day.
I love you, Willy.
They're ready inside.
Would you like to do
some tricks today?
Ok.
Ohhh!
Don't squirt me!  Go squirt everyone else.
Go squirt them, buddy,
go squirt them.
Swimming tail slap!
Hey, all right!
Why don't we thank the nice people
for their applause?
Aw, excuse yourself.
Thank them.
Good boy!
Thank you.
Want to play ball?
Yeah?
Yeah, good boy!
Big barrel roll.
Good boy!
All right, boy!  Come on, Willy!
Go, Willy!
Go on back down!
Yeah!
Now come to me!
Willy!
And that, gentlemen,
is our show!
[blows whistle]
Yeah!
- You did it!  You did it!
- Did you see him?
So you can do all that again?
What you and Rae want
costs a lot of money.  I have to be sure.
Do dogs pee on brick walls?
Um, I mean, yes, sir.
Sure, we can do it again, anytime.
- You set it up.
- Yes.
- We may be able to turn this around after all.
- It'll cost us to set up a show.
So what?
We let the kid work up a presentation.
It catches on, and we're back
on track, just like we planned.
"the Willy show."
It'll make money.
And that, my friend,
is what we are all about.
You'll have a whale of a time
when you see me at the Willy Show!
Wow!
Aah!
See "Willy the whale show"!
Programs for "Willy the whale."
Ladies and gentlemen, girls and boys,
please take your seats.
The Willy show will commence
in 5 minutes.
And just a reminder,
...we ask you to please remain seated
at all times during the Willy show.
Remember, if you wish to  purchase
Willy souvenirs,
...our gift shop has a great selection.
It's open all day, and it's located
right outside the Aquatic theater.
[thump thump thump]
Lots of people out there.
You're nervous?
- No.
- Here.
- What's this?
- A little present from Randolph and me.
Oh, hey, cool!
Thanks, Rae.
You're welcome.
» Ladies and gentlemen,
See you.
» girls and boys,
...please take your seats immediately.
The Willy show is about to commence.
Hey, Dwight, how you been?
Jesse, now, this is exciting, huh?
I'm really proud of you.
Thanks.
And now...
...the Northwest Adventure Park...
...proudly presents the Willy show!
Go get them, Champ.
[applause]
Ladies and gentlemen!
Presenting the superstar orca
of Northwest Adventure Park...
...let's hear it for Willy!
[applause]
This could be big.
And this is Willy’s friend, Jesse,
ladies and gentlemen.
Jesse and Willy have
a very special show for you.
Go get them.
[crying]
He's not into this.
Something's wrong.
Try something simple.
I'll talk.
Willy is a 12-year-old adolescent orca.
He is 22 feet long and weighs in
at over 3 1/2 tons.
Come here, buddy.
What's up, guy?
Come on, Willy, you know the signals.
[chattering]
Willy, this is important to us.
Please, Willy, please!
Don't blow it.
[crying]
- Come on, Willy.
- You can do it, Willy.  I know you can.
All right?
Now, let's go, bud.
[clapping]
All right!
» Boo! Boo!
» Get him off the stage!
Hey, shut up.
» Get the fish out of the water!
Hey! Stop! Stop!
Like every great performer,
ladies and gentlemen,
...sometimes Willy gets
a little stage fright.
[shouting and banging]
[shouting]
[crying]
Jesse!
Aah!
[crash]
He just wasn't ready.
No.
Jesse, that wasn't your fault.
You didn't do anything.
Uhh!
Jesse!
I'll hold it and you kick it.
Uhh!
Jesse, it takes
a lot of courage
to do what you did,...
...to work with an animal
that's so big and strong.
Maybe that whale just doesn't want
to be a performer.
Yeah.
Look, you gave it your best shot.
You worked real hard, and...
...you did everything you could do.
And we're very proud of you.
You know, I'd get a little nervous, too,
if I had to do tricks in front of all those people.
Jesse.
So what's up?
- The show wasn't--
- Screw the show, and screw the Greenwoods.
- Oh, now they're against you, too, huh?
- Just like everything else.
You know, I don't think you have such
a bad thing with the Greenwoods's schedule.
Then you go live there!
I'm sick of this place!
I'm going to find my mom.
You mean you're gonna go
hit the streets again.
- No! I'm gonna find my mom.
- Yeah, right!
The state can't find your mom.  The federal
government can't find your mom, either.
Yeah, well, I'll find her.
When are you gonna get it, huh?
When are you gonna get it...
...and your mom isn't coming back?
Forgot the day she dropped you
on our doorstep?
Forgot about that?
Well, I remember.
Turned around and drove away.
Didn't look around, didn't slow down,
didn't even look in the rearview mirror.
That sound like
somebody's mama to you?
You got 2 people over here
Who want to be your friend.
That's more than your mother ever was.
And you could use a friend right now, son.
Because if you go off on your own,...
...you are gonna end up losing big time.
You got that?
Dwight, shut up and leave me alone!
[knock on door]
[door opens]
I feel sorry for Willy.
Me, too.
You know...
Animals can be unpredictable,...
...and they can misbehave sometimes,...
...just like people.
But that doesn't mean
you have to lose faith in them.
Right?
Well...
Good night.
[Willy snorts]
Yeah, what do you want?
Go on.
Get outta here.
Just go.
Yeah, now you want to mess around.
So, what happened today?
You choked, didn't you?
Quit it.
Better stop that.
Quit it!
Willy.
See this?
See this, Willy?  It's going bye-bye,
and it's never coming back!
[crying]
Don't you start that now?
I'm out of here.
I'm going to California.
Have a good life.
[crying]
[whales singing]
Wow.
[whales calling out]
It's your family.
[crying]
Randolph!
Randolph, wake up!
Wake up, Randolph!
There's a hole
in Willy’s tank.
- They're going to kill Willy!
- Wade was with them?
Yeah, and they drop this.
It's part of the tank.
Dial's trying to collect the insurance money.
Willy's worth a million dollars.
A million dollars?
- Randolph!  Let's free him!
- What?
Let's free Willy!  We could take him down
to the bay and put himback in the water.
I never liked this job, anyway.
This is no accident.
Dial's trying to kill Willy.
So we're putting him
back in the ocean.
- You two?
- And you!
- And me?
- That's right, lady.
Just wait a minute.
All I know is Willy’s gonna die if he's dry-docked
too long.  This tank's way beyond repair.
He's got a family out there.
I heard them.
Don't you get it?
He's homesick. That's why he acts so weird.
- Jesse--
- Rae, they tried to kill him!
Hand me that, Jesse.
Randolph, did you call the police?
What good would that do?
If we Don't get Willy
into water soon, he's gonna die.
Rae, either get the heck out of here,
or go turn on the number-2 pump.
Come on, boy.
Come on!  Come on, Willy.
Yes. That's it.
Come on.
Come on, boy.
Jesse!
Jesse, get out of there!
Willy!
Come on, Willy!
Come on now!
Please, Willy!  We're gonna get you
out of here.  Now, help us a little bit.
Attaboy, Jess.
Please, Willy, please!
Just cooperate!
Come forward.
Into the net,
boy.
Good boy!
Good boy, Willy.
Good boy.
It's gonna be OK, Willy.
[Willy snorts]
It's gonna be
all right.
[moans]
Ok, that's good enough.
Come on up here.
Bring him on a little bit more.
All right, come on.
Nice and slow,
Randolph.
Watch his pecs.
Come on, boy.
You're gonna be OK, buddy.
You're gonna be OK.
How do you think he's doing?
He's all right.
He's been moved before. As long as
we keep him wet, he's gonna be fine.
How are we gonna to pull him?
Go! Hurry! Hurry!
I'm hurrying,  I'm hurrying!
No, go! Go! Go!
I'm going,  I'm going!
License plate number 5-2-zebra,...
34 Baker. That's right.
Hold on one second.
- Just now.
- Jesse's not here.  His things are gone.
Go take care
of Willy.
What do you think?
We go straight out to Dawson's Marina?
Yeah. It's the only
ocean access for miles.
Better stick to the back roads, though.
Jesse, this is Glen.
If you're there, answer me.
Are you in the truck?
» If you're there, answer me.
» Jesse, please, answer us.
» Jesse, are you there?  Jesse!
OK. Let's go.
You're gonna be OK, boy.
Jess. We won't let anything
happen to him, I promise.
What do you think?
The Old Forest Road?
Yeah, that might be
the least conspicuous.
Nobody steals a whale.
But I'm telling you,
the whale is gone.
The trailer's out of there,
The forklift's been moved.
That big-mouthed trainer and
the Indian must've done it.
- This is a disaster.
- Why?
Because we don't have theft insurance
on the whale.  That's why.
Call Wilson. Tell him
to bring his crew down.
You see that?
Oh, no. What are we gonna do?
We'll have to
back it up.
OK.
Keep going.
It's OK.
Watch it, Randolph.
Stop! Randolph, stop!
[Willy cries]
- Jess, you're OK?
- Yes.
It's OK, boy.
It's OK.
How's he doing?
I don't know.
He's pretty scared.
Maybe we should try
taking it forward again.
If the trailer tilts any further,
we'll lose him, Randolph.
It's OK.
You're gonna be
all right.
- Hey, Brody.
- Hey, Glen.
- You heard anything about a stolen pickup?
- It's your?
Yup.
The whale yours, too?
- The what?
- The whale?
Back!
Down!
[Randolph grunts]
[grunting]
Stop!
We've--  We've definitely
hit some kind of low here.
No question about it.
We need help.
» Glen? Annie?
» You guys there?
» Glen?
Yeah. Jesse.
Jesse.  Are you all right?
I'm OK.
So what's going on?
What the heck are you
doing with my truck?
And this whale?
- They tried to kill Willy.
- Kill the whale?
So we're putting him back in the ocean.
Glen...
Help us!
Help us, and I'll do anything.
Anything!
What is it that you think
I want from you, Jesse?
I don't know.
I don't know what
you want from me.
Look. I gotta look out for Willy,
and I gotta do what's best for him.
You understand?
[Willy cries out]
Please, Glen, please.
I'm asking for your help.
He's gonna die.
There's a 10-foot length of chain
and a winch control...
...behind the seat of the truck.
Go and get it.
Thanks, Glen.
Behind the seat.
That's the only place I didn't look.
Come on.
Don't worry, boy.
You're gonna be OK.
Glen's working on it.  We're gonna
get you out of here.
Keep going!
Jesse, help me with the other board!
- Annie, keep him wet.
- OK!
- Coming up!
Keep going!
OK.... Keep going!
- Annie!
- Yeah?
Move your car and lock it up.
Hang a right!
You're good.
Good!
OK! Jesse, sit down.
[Willy crying]
Look, we gotta wet Willy down completely.
He's getting too dry.
The sun's gonna come up.
We Don't have much time.
Ok. I know a place
we can go.
Don't worry, bud.
You're gonna be OK.
We're just gonna give you a nice rinse.
Jess, open his mouth.
All right.
Ok, buddy, open up!
Good boy.
Thanks.
Sorry I Haven't got
a fish for you, though.
All right.
Let's go.
- Nice whale.
- Thanks.
You'll be OK.
Hang in there, bud.
We're almost there.
[crying]
We gotta hurry!
He's not doing so good.
Please, Glen, hurry!
You're gonna be OK.
Hurry, Glen!
Annie: Go for it.
Stop them immediately!
[tires squeal]
Hurry!
Come on!
Come on, boy, come on!
We got you to the water.
Now you gotta do your part.
Stop them! Don't let
that whale get away!
Randolph, why isn't he moving?
You said if we got him
to the water, he'd be OK.
I don't know, Jesse.
He's been out of the water...
...a lot longer than we thought.
Come on, Willy!
Go, Willy, go!
Get outta here!
- Come here, kid!
- No, wait!
Go, Willy!  Go, Willy!
No! Let me go!
Go, Willy!
Let go of my boy!
Please, go.
Go!
Go, Willy. Move!
Good boy.
I love you, Willy.
Go, Willy!
Go!
Go, Willy! Go!
Yeah!
Yeah! Ha ha.
He's never gonna make it.
That whale's not going anywhere.
Water's 20 feet deep. Those nets
will touch bottom, close him in.
Come on!
[cries]
Jesse!
- Jesse, get back here!
- Jessie!
Hey! Get out of here!
Go!
Come on, Willy!
Come on, boy!
Follow me to the breakwater!
Go, Willy!
Get away from those boats!
They're dangerous! Swim!
Come on!
Come to me, Willy!
Get away from those nets!
Over here, boy!  Hurry!
Over here!
Hurry, Willy, hurry!
Come here, boy!
Come on.
Come here, boy.
Come here.
I'll miss you.
[cries]
Don't forget me, OK?
I won't forget you.
Say hello to your mom for me, OK?
I really love you, boy.
And I believe in you.
You can do it.
You can be free.
Now, do it. Do it.
Come on, Willy! I know
you can do it, boy!
I know you can jump this wall.
Come on!  I believe in you, Willy.
You can do it.
You can be free!  Come on!
You can jump it!
Come on, Willy!
You only have to do it once.
Just once, boy!
Randolph, you ever
see him jump that high?
Things can happen.
Sa-la-na a-yoong I-asis.
Yeah!
[laughing]
I hate that whale.
Bye, Willy.
I'm gonna miss you.
Hope we get to see each other sometime.
I love you.
Hey, Jess.
Thanks, guys.
Thanks a lot.
[Willy calling]
So long, Willy.
Hey...
Let's go home.
Ok.
♪  Hold me, like the River Jordan
♪  And I will then say to thee
♪  You are my friend
♪  Carry me, like you are my brother
♪  Love me like a mother
♪  Will you be there?
Mother!
♪  Weary, tell me will you hold me?
♪  When wrong, will you scold me?
♪  When lost, will you find me?
♪  But they told me
♪  A man should be faithful
♪  And walk when not able
♪  And fight till the end but I'm only human.
[Hmmm]
♪  Oh, love
♪  Everyone's taking control of me
♪  Seems that the world's got a role for me
♪  I'm so confused, will you show it to me?
♪  You'll be there for me
♪  And care enough to bear me
♪  Hold me
♪  And show me
♪  Show me
♪ Lay your head slowly
♪  Care
♪ Carry me there
♪  Lead me
♪  Hold me
♪  Love me and feed me
♪  Care
♪  Kiss and free me
♪  I will feel blessed
♪  Carry
♪  Carry me boldly
♪  Lift me up slowly
♪  Carry
♪  Carry me there
♪  Save me
♪  Heal me and bathe me
♪  Kiss me
♪  Softly you say to me
♪  I'll be there
♪  Lift me
♪  Slowly
♪  Lift me up slowly
♪  Carry me boldly
♪  Care
♪  Show me you care
♪  Hold me
♪  Lay you head slowly
♪  Softly then boldly
♪  Carry me there
♪  Lead me
♪  Love me and free me
♪  I will feel blessed
♪  [Hmm]
Michael Jackson:
In my darkest hour,
In my deepest despair...
Will you still care?
Will you be there?
In my trials...
And my tribulations...
Through all doubts...
And frustrations...
In my violence...
In my turbulence...
Through my fear...
And my confessions...
In my anguish...
And my pain...
Through my Joy...
And my sorrow...
And the promise
of another tomorrow...
I'll never let you part...
For you're always...
In my heart.
}}