KORKORO
'Freedom'
Based on real events
We can't get across!
Oh, my God!
Puri Dai, we can't go on.
The ditch is too wide!
- I just saw him.
- He's not far.
Got you!
We've got the ghost!
Why do you follow us?
Who are you?
You scared me yesterday.
Ghost.
He's white!
Why do you follow us?
I'm all alone.
We don't want trouble.
You must go back to your people.
Did you pinch
the charcoal burner's bread?
This little gadjo
is one hell of a thief.
What shall we do with him?
Come here.
Sit.
Chouroro!
Eat.
Here.
The children hate these roots.
We eat what we find.
With the Germans on our backs,
we have to keep going.
God is going to come to our rescue.
Chouroro!
Pick everything.
The Germans! On the road!
What?
I saw Germans on the road.
They're coming!
TOWN HaLL
are you Theodore Rosier?
Let's go.
What's his name?
Otto.
I'll look after you, Otto.
What have you fed him?
Meat.
Tatane...
What does "chouroro" mean?
a pauper.
The gypsies are back!
The gypsies are here!
Thank you.
What's going on?
Honestly!
Stamping his backside...
Hello.
Thank you.
We'll give you ration cards.
How long will you stay here?
We've come for the grape harvest.
after, we leave.
a new law forbids you to be nomads,
even with passbooks.
We never stay too long in one place.
Our life is the road.
Come, I'll show you something.
"The President of the French Republic
decrees
"article 1:
"The movement of nomads
is banned throughout France
"as long as the war lasts.
"Punishable by a prison sentence
of one to five years. "
This law forbids you to be nomads.
You'll be in danger
if you keep traveling.
You could be arrested.
- We must leave here.
- Stop!
We stay for the grape harvest.
We'll be trapped.
You must do as they say
or they'll put you in prison.
There's a war on.
- It's serious.
- It's your war.
We gypsies have never gone to war.
Chouroro!
Got him!
No!
We've caught Chouroro!
What's your name?
Chouroro!
Put him down, please.
Put him down!
Don't be afraid.
I'm here to help you.
What's your name?
Claude.
Claude what?
Ch?ant.
They say you're an orphan?
are your parents dead?
Yes.
Where did you live
before they found you?
With people.
They took you in?
Yes.
But there wasn't enough food for me.
They wanted to put me in a home.
I didn't want to go.
I won't go to a home!
You can stay here for now.
Then we'll see.
It's my uncle. Fernand.
Is this the young devil?
Well then...
I found these. Try them on.
No.
I don't like short pants.
I have these too.
Short pants too,
but you wear them at your age.
I wore short pants at your age,
so did Theo.
Is he going to be trouble?
Put your shoes on
and go to get wood for the stove.
Send him to the orphanage.
- He's scared of going there.
- Why? Has he been before?
I don't know.
You don't know who he is.
You don't know
what's he's been through.
You're taking a risk.
Good morning, children.
Good morning, Miss Lundi.
Sit down.
a lesson...
in morals.
Is it true the gypsies brought you?
My dad says
the gypsies steal children!
Leave me alone.
Quiet, that's enough now.
Pots and pans!
any pots to mend?
We don't need anything.
- any pots to mend?
- Lace!
any pots to mend?
Pots and pans!
Thread, scissors.
We don't need anything!
Madam, Italian lace.
We mend pots, we repair holes.
No holes in my pots!
Holes can hide sometimes.
Ladies and gentlemen, music for you.
Look... it's from Hungary.
Mr. Raisin!
- Buy a basket?
- No, I want hoop nets.
Hoop nets?
Tina...
Hello. We haven't seen you
since the war started.
Tools, sir?
You don't want to buy?
a motor car!
It's Pierre Pentecote!
Hello, Pierre.
Hi.
It's good to see a friend.
a glass!
a chair!
Where's the glass?
We can only offer you water.
Thank you.
It's okay, thank you.
Come here, pal.
- Still run that dance hall in Villers?
- Of course.
We'd like to play there again.
People just want
tangos and waltzes now.
We know songs from Russia,
Macedonia...
are the horses new?
all three are Spanish.
Spanish...
This village isn't like before.
Everyone has changed.
Pierre Pentecote
isn't a friend anymore.
He didn't come here just to say hello.
We'll wash the horse's paint off.
We'll make it old again
and no one will be able to accuse us.
Later, when we want to sell it,
we'll make it young again.
Pierre Pentecote had something in mind.
My brother,
we must dance with the snake.
Stop it!
Shut up!
Hello.
Come here.
Come closer.
What's your name?
Why?
Because my name is Miss Lundi.
I'm Tatane.
Can you read and write?
That's not for us.
What's she doing here?
She's come to steal our men.
Good morning, madam.
I work at the town hall.
I teach in St. amont too.
May your clothes tear
and may you grow old in good health.
The children must come to school.
They should learn to read and write.
all right.
How much will you pay for that?
What?
Pay them to learn?
With nothing in return,
our children stay here.
They have better to do.
Such as?
We don't leave our children.
They're always with us.
I'll do it. For an apple.
I like apples.
They're at the market in Villers.
It's the mare with the white foot.
Get a lead, Claude.
She took ill earlier.
She fell an hour ago
and only just got up.
I'll tether the stallion.
Careful, he's a mad one.
Come on, boy.
It's bad. I need hot water
and a bottle of oil!
I'll take her to the stable.
Young Claude, my bag.
Bring me my bag.
Her heartbeat's slow.
The green box in my bag.
- The horse, Theodore!
- Get back!
a ghost!
The mad horse!
Kako!
Dear God, what's wrong,
my girl, my sweet, my doll?
Tie the scarf tight!
Little doll, get up...
Stroke her ears.
Mandra, put an egg on it!
That's good.
Taloche, your egg.
This will do him good.
The cow dung will make him better.
Tie it tight.
Great Lord, great Christ,
great Virgin...
Help our dear friend to rise again.
She has helped a lot,
she must be rewarded for it.
What's going on?
Theodore?
What have you put on him?
It heals, Miss Lundi.
What is it?
It will heal him.
The horse has woken!
Great and beautiful God!
Let me eat your shit!
Chouroro.
What's this?
Theodore sent this.
By Saint Sarah!
The apple for Taloche!
Bread.
Pork fat.
Chavo, the knife.
For the children.
Thank him, by Saint Sarah.
He wants to know
what you put on the bite.
He mustn't remove it.
It will heal him.
Come here, Chouroro.
Tell him, if God wills it,
even a broom can fire a shot.
Well, what did they tell you?
They said that if God wills it,
even a rag can heal.
What?
No, that's not it.
They said that if God wills it,
even a ram...
no, even a broom can fire shots.
What are you talking about?
That's what they said.
Get up! Time for Miss Lundi!
Get up!
Cali!
Come on!
Cali! Quick!
Hurry up!
Hello, Miss Lundi.
Taloche! One biscuit.
Just one.
Taloche, go and sit down.
Go back to your seat.
Chouroro!
In the silent and perfumed garden
with its distant...
We'll be back, Miss Lundi.
Get out your passbooks!
Come out of there!
Come on!
Shut the dog up or I'll shoot it!
Sit!
all of you!
Radu Mircea.
Felix Laville.
This is filthy!
This stamp's illegible!
I have two stamps on my bottom.
- What?
- I have...
What's going on?
- He's raving.
- It's true!
Stay on this land now.
Don't move.
That's an order.
You there, come here.
Don't act smart.
We're watching you.
Sit back down.
You're obliged to stay put.
The whole tribe!
So no funny business, got that?
On orders of the prefect,
horses requisitioned.
Not our horses!
Our horses!
Don't let them steal our horses!
I'll kill them.
Calm down!
They'll only arrest you!
You can't go back to prison.
Take this one.
That one's worthless.
a painted old nag.
Get the two beauties
and that black one.
My Lords, don't take our horses!
Hands off!
Turn the head!
Fuck the earth!
Fuck the water!
My father told me,
during a war, he and his family
hid a long time in a forest.
When they came out,
the war was over.
Get lost, Taloche!
Leave him.
Come on, Taloche.
Taloche is a great man.
Sit down.
We have to leave here fast.
We must get our family to safety.
I'll come back
to kill Pierre Pentecote.
I'm against it.
There'll be reprisals.
I say we mustn't
take to the road again.
This war isn't like the others.
We know the way to Belgium.
There, we'll be with our family.
If you kill Pierre Pentecote,
you'll bury our family.
I agree with my uncle and my mother.
We mustn't move from here.
Moving around is getting dangerous.
Be careful.
- You think I'm not careful?
- Be careful anyway.
The message?
Everything we agreed on. Bread...
Cheese...
Pork fat...
and hooch.
This is extra.
all right?
Thanks.
They'll play all night for you.
I need everyone in the fields.
I'll bring the truck at 5:00.
We'll bring the children.
You have to pay them.
We'll pay the children too.
- Do you want some water?
- Please.
Thank you.
- See you at the town hall tomorrow.
- See you there.
Good-bye, Miss Lundi.
Don't forget this.
Tina!
What's going on?
What is this shit?
Goddamn it!
Take the cuffs off.
Why are you doing this, Pentecote?
Why do you lock us up like dogs?
To rid France of her vermin.
How many are you?
Fifteen.
You can go here.
Stay here, Taloche.
Sit down!
Here's another blanket.
It's going to get very cold.
You're sure about this, Theodore?
If my land can save a whole family,
I'm positive.
a simple title deed
can get them out of the camp?
I asked at the prefecture.
Nomadic gypsies are being put in camps
all over France.
If they own a house,
they're allowed out.
Seller's surname and first name?
Rosier, Theodore.
Date and place of birth?
October 25th, 1903, in St. amont.
address, occupation?
Veterinarian, St. amont town hall.
Nationality?
French.
Israelite? Non-Israelite?
Lucien, please.
Sorry, but it's the law.
Non-Israelite.
OfJewish race or not?
Non-Jewish.
Buyer's surname and first name?
Laville, Natasha.
Widow of Charles Laville.
- Nature of the sale?
- Rosier house
and its garden,
at the entrance to St. amont.
Sale price?
Ten francs.
The village will be against you.
Why are you doing this?
To do something.
Just something.
This is
my great-great-grandfather's house.
He built the village's first house.
My whole family was born here.
Let me show you something.
This is my childhood spring.
Listen, officer.
We've driven 50 miles.
I have the prefect's authorization,
the Laville family's deed
to the house...
The commander knows.
Can't you reach him?
Come with me.
- Taloche is missing.
- Climb on the truck!
Miss Lundi, Taloche is missing.
- One of their relatives is missing.
- Who?
Free! I want to be free!
Taloche!
Get up, Taloche.
Come on, get up.
Hello...
Miss Lundi.
What did they do to you?
I wanted to fly away...
like a wild goose...
to get over the barbed wire...
Claws...
Come on.
Let's go.
- We have to go.
- Climb on.
Chavo!
Puri Dai!
Climb on! We can't stay here.
This is the title deed.
It proves the house is yours.
Don't lose it or tear it up.
There are more rooms behind this door.
I'll find the key.
You'll be fine here.
It's a sturdy house.
I'll show you where to get water.
are you Theodore's wife?
No.
I'm new to the village.
I came here for work.
You're not from here?
Where's your family?
It's been broken up.
I have two brothers in jail.
What for?
The war.
and you?
Do you have a husband?
Who is he?
I don't have a husband anymore.
I'm with my brothers.
Great Lord, you are good.
Go away, Satan!
Go into the woods!
There's no room for you here!
It will be good for us.
Great Lord,
you are dear to us...
Taloche, come in.
This is our house!
I don't understand.
Why are we gbdjo now?
I don't know either.
This is our house now.
The spirits have left.
Darko, come with us.
We're free!
Free?
We'll be free if we leave here
and no one knows where we go.
We have to make sure
that no one sees us.
It's dangerous, Darko.
I like your new musicians.
They come from Italy.
I'm glad you like them.
It's very lively.
- Good-bye, Pierre.
- See you again, my friend.
See you, Simonet.
Call it off!
Call it off, brother!
He's suspicious!
MyJenisch father gave me life
with your Rom mother.
I don't deserve
to beJenisch anymore!
My brother...
Since we left the camp
where our brothers are held,
you no longer have a life.
Cali!
Chouroro! Food!
Chouroro has brought us food!
Where's the nosh?
I have the key!
- What key?
- The key to the house.
- I don't have food.
- Here.
Thank you.
Taloche!
Get the lamp!
Ghosts!
There are loads of ghosts in there!
It's packed with ghosts.
Packed with ghosts!
Why is he nailing the door shut?
It's full of mice.
They're rats. It's normal.
Every house has them.
They're not mice.
Mulos aren't rats!
They're our ghosts!
It's beautiful!
a big house!
This is Theodore's room.
This is his office.
The heating.
The kitchen.
I sleep here. It's big.
Free the water!
Marshal, here we are
Before you, savior of France
We swear, bs your children,
To serve you and follow your step
Marshal, here we are
You have given us new hope
The Fatherland will rise again
Marshal, Marshal, here we are
Children...
Sit down.
Get out your exercise books.
We'll do sums.
Miss Lundi!
My gbdji!
Thank you, Changalo, thank you.
We'll pay you for it.
Changalo!
What does gbdjo Lebel want?
We have to play for their hens
to make them lay.
If they pay,
we'll do what they want.
Come on, Taloche, we have work to do.
We're going to play.
What's wrong? are you sick?
Come on!
We're going to play for the hens.
Set foot on my land
and I'll smash your face in!
Hands off our animals!
- Hands off!
- Get off our land!
The land's ours! It's ours!
Our horses!
He's going to curse the mule!
We don't want your ugly mugs
as neighbors!
My ugly mug
is better than your dirty ass,
you damn hick!
I'll smash your gypsy head in!
Get out of our village!
You're not throwing that!
Put it down!
Go home, before this gets worse!
We don't want
a gang of thieves around here!
Calm down!
I'll kill them!
Stop! I told you to stop!
Stop it!
Don't do that!
Shit!
Stop!
- You'll regret it!
- You crook!
My grandfather's field
is the Lavilles' now!
- They're not French!
- Half this land has always been ours.
The solicitor says it's the Lavilles'.
Now get lost or I'll beat you up!
Get lost!
Lise, why are you out this late?
I went to get water from the well.
The door confused me.
I thought the handle was outside.
I'll get the other key.
I'll fetch it for you.
I have to mend this door.
Put it there.
I'll take it tomorrow.
Sit down.
You work at the town hall?
I'm the schoolteacher.
and the town hall secretary.
You live upstairs?
Yes.
Go up, we'll follow you.
Sit down!
Sit!
Calm down!
Sit down.
Here.
My bag, my purse...
You claim you love order,
yet you come and terrify the children!
Shut your mouth!
This is a school.
I'm the mayor
and I answer for Miss Lundi!
Of course.
Who issued this identity card?
We know who you are.
Come with us.
Otto!
Talk!
Who's the head of your network?
Young Claude!
- Puri Dai, you have the key?
- No.
Taloche!
any idea where the trunk key is?
May bitterness rot the key.
- Does anyone know where the key is?
- No.
Taloche...
What?
My legs hurt.
We'll take a walk.
Come on, Chouroro! Let's go.
- Come on, walk.
- I can't feel my feet.
Move your arms. Move your legs.
I have pins and needles.
Go on, walk.
Go on, Chouroro.
Look! Walk!
Come on!
Hide!
- What are you doing here?
- Taking a walk.
Chouroro, you followed us.
You're mad!
You hid him?
Listen, Chouroro.
We can't keep you here.
We like you,
but you're not one of us.
Leave him! He's mine.
Chouroro's my brother!
Walk. Come on.
Keep away from us, Chouroro!
If someone comes,
say you're not with us.
I want to stay with you!
Why's he sticking to us like this?
He wants to be a gypsy.
Come on, push, Taloche!
Gypsy? That's not a trade!
Come on, Taloche!
Taloche! You're killing me!
Come on, we'll push.
Push! Push with us!
Wake up!
Come out of there!
Get your passbooks!
Come out now! Let's move!
- Get your passbooks.
- Get up!
Come on, hurry it up!
Hurry it up! Get your passbooks!
Come here, you!
Come on, get out.
What is it? We've done nothing.
Move!
Hurry up!
Get in line with the others!
Get over there!
- Come on!
- Step back!
Hand over the passbooks.
Hand it over.
The stamps?
Where are the stamps?
We arrived last night.
The town hall was closed.
Sure...
Where's this one?
Calo! Who is he?
answer me!
- are they all here?
- Yes, the whole tribe.
Take them away.
No stamps.
Your passbooks aren't in order!
We'll run checks on you all.
Get in line!
Move in single file!
We can't leave the vans!
The horses!
Over here! There's one hidden here!
Get out of there!
We can't leave our animals!
We'll take care of them.
Don't worry, you'll be back.
Gendarme!
This boy isn't with us.
Take him back to St. amont.
If he's not yours, whose is he?
He hid in our van.
He followed us.
Tell them!
Tell them you followed us.
You'll be back. Don't try to fool us.
That's enough.
He followed us!
Move it!
Let go! Follow the others!
Let go!
Let go of it!
Let go, dammit!
Get up. Go with the others!
Stop him!
Don't move!
Taloche!
Good luck, all you others!
If anyone worries about our absence
Tell him we have been thrown out
From the sky and the light
We the lords of this vast universe...
The gypsy family that inspired this film
was interned in Mechelen, Belgium,
before being deported to auschwitz
by convoy Z on January 15, 1944.
Miss Lundi is based on
the Resistance fighter Yvette Lundy
who was deported
to Ravensbruck and freed in 1945.
Of the 2 million gypsies
living in Europe before the war,
between 250,000 and 500,000
were killed by the Nazis.
Subtitles: lan Burley
Subtitling: L. V. T. - Paris