I have left  many Ages ...
as salmon,
deer,
and wolf.
I have seen the dark man invading Ireland
destroying homes, In search gold.
I saw the Samurai in the dark.
yet ... I have seen the beauty
emerge from the most fragile.
I have seen the book ... the book
turn darkness into light.
The Secret of Kells
Brendan? Do not let it get away!
Come here! gosling, gosling, gosling ...
Become back, I'm gonna get!
Where was it?
Brendan! The scaffold is not safe!
Do not worry, brother Assou, I will be careful.
Sorry.
Brendan!
Coming!
Are you hurt?
Mantel quiet, Brendan!
We are in an abbey.
Sorry, but we have to do this.
End in a minute.
That was not so difficult, is it?
Aver lucky.
Your feathers will become the tools
create pages with that immortal
sacred texts.
Father! Let me explain ...
We tried to catch this
goose ... but he ran too fast.
And I fell in the mud ...
Forgive us, father.
Brendan! Where are the
plans, I asked?
The plans ... I left them in the
Hall writes.
- Bring them to the castle!
- Yeah, man.
Tomorrow, going to work on the wall.
From sunrise to sunset.
Brother Leonardo ...
... wipe, for God's sake.
I do not know why it bothers you so much
when all he wants is to build that wall.
Yes, it's the only concern
yet you keep defending, Brendan!
The guy just wants to protect us from outside.
The Vikings will not make a distinction
between young and old. So ...
Preparenme me too!
You do not understand ...
But Brendan, they have never been outside these walls.
However, I know how dangerous it is.
- Where were they?
- Bringing it to you.
You must be his brother Sergio,
its wings outstretched,
as a beautiful swan.
This is not funny.
The father saw us very angry.
Why do not we work on the wall.
Enough of that! And the book
What are not valuable?
Without any knowledge books
will be lost ... forever.
You can not build walls forever!
People who need books,
which expect to get.
A master illuminator
would be necessary.
Pray that
God will bring us!
Yes! Pray!
But I need a teacher
your work is so perfect ...
Thanks Brendan, but
we are merely scribes
- Close to a true master.
- A teacher? One as ...
Brother Aidan from Iona.
Aidan is the largest.
Who is the brother Aidan?
A sage.
The wisest of all.
Illuminator perfect.
And where is it?
He lives in the small island of Iona.
There is an abbey on the island, where he works
in a wonderful book: The book of Iona.
The book 200 years ago, began to be written
of the Orders of Columbanus.
Iona's book to epclipsa
all others.
For the miraculous third eye
Columbanus
Not for the third eye, but by their
three hand with 12 fingers each.
Not true! There were three eyes
not three hands!
Never heard of the third eye
Columbanus
Yes, yes, but the third eye was
to make prophecies
while the third hand
was to write the book.
Enough! Just tell us about
Brother Aidan.
Light of his writings out of the pages.
Evil beings have been blinded
with only perch on them.
These pages were conceived
in the same sky.
The Book of Iona.
But where is Iona?
Far away at sea, too far away. Each
island should be.
A beautiful place
where the illuminators
should not build a wall.
But the father said that the
islands are easier to attack.
Brendan! Are you still here?
Bring plans to Abbot,
or you'll be in trouble!
Uncle!
Hurry up, boy!
I came, man.
Brendan! How can I trust you
if you still disappointed?
One day you run the monastery.
But it takes you hours to complete
a simple task.
Sorry.
The monks told me about Iona.
I had a dream that was destroyed.
Ta was real, man!
Brendan is real.
One day, look at us.
So we must be prepared.
This section is supported by
three pillars: here, here and here.
Man, someone has arrived!
It has a white cat with him!
No doubt, another victim of the Vikings.
Let's see.
Why? Beyond Africa
No, no, no ... not so far.
But due to the expiration of the foot.
But from where How far?
No, but if you live only once
the road seems half as long.
Not true Pangur Ban?
Welcome to Kells, brother.
- Abad Cellach
- Peace be with you!
Brothers and sisters, give welcome
one of the greatest illuminators of our time.
You're sure there must be a mistake.
Brother Aidan of Iona.
One question at a time.
As St. Columba, "The questions will not burn
your tongue if you wait for them "
Welcome to Keller, brother Aidan!
Over here, brother.
Hello! Welcome to Kells!
Hey, wait!
just talking about you and the code.
Good spacious room!
Fresh air, bright light
through the windows ...
Brother!
Is that where you save the workbook?
Here ... that ... a. ..
And you see they have younger siblings?
Although short stature never falls short
Question.
Why do you care about the Book?
Well ... brothers, said they
St. Columba who began ...
Brothers and sisters, the brother of Aidan
must take part
strengthening work Kells.
They have work to do.
Plans are in my office.
- I thought, I could stay here
and ... - Over here, brother.
Boy! Search for something to eat ...
You know, I plan to finish the job
within two years.
So you're Pangur
Ban. My name is Bre ...
Hey! Wait! I'm supposed to feed you
Wait!
Pangur Ban!
You should not have come here.
The Vikings will follow.
"I would have stayed to die?
I ran away from the Vikings and left far behind.
brother Cellach
I mean ... Father Cellach.
The book is savlo, and can be completed.
Yes, well ... we have more pressure to complete
other things here.
- You mean your wall?
- Not my wall!
A wall to save civilization.
A wall to save your book!
Heathens ...
Worshipers of Crom ...
The strength of the village
shows how strong our faith.
I've always drawn well, Cellach.
Yes, sorry, but
I have many things to attend to.
There is no wall that can
stop the Vikings.
When they come here, we can only run
and hope that
are fast enough.
Come Pangur.
Pangur!
I did not want to hurt the work.
I've never been on the outside wall.
I wanted to see
at least one page.
Please.
Good!
Is not it the little brother
the big questions?
- I did not want ...
- I understand.
You tired of spying on the conversation of the father
and decided to come here.
No, no, that's it!
Quiet boy, do not tell anyone.
Maybe not ...
The brothers said that sinners are
remain blind to look at the book.
So maybe I should not
Do you really think
of that happening?
Life is full of doubts, do not you boy?
This is your decision.
It does not cover the real treasure. Open up!
The work of angels.
"The work of the angels"
Did you hear that? Pangur
I did not know that angels painted
as funny as me.
Maybe it's the boy has gone blind.
I also thought the same,
when I first saw it.
However, it is the work of
Mere mortals like you and me.
The book is light in these dark times.
Would you like to see the most beautiful pages?
Where darkness becomes light.
This is the website "Chi Ro".
But not even have anything!
No, but it is the most glorious page
the entire book.
Brendan, would you like help?
Yes, please! I help brothers
all the time.
Calm down, brother.
First, you bring me some of this,
of a very old tree.
But what is that?
It's a little soft, but makes the ink
darker emerald green you've ever seen.
If I get a dozen in the woods
I'll show you how to make it, come on!
What?
I can not go beyond the wall.
It's too dangerous.
It's dangerous.
Iona
I lost my brothers
by the invaders.
Now only is the book to remember.
But if they were here now
I would say that you can learn more in the forest
with trees and stones
that on any other place.
You can see miracles.
That was a long time ago, the father knew.
I've never seen anything like it, Pangur.
I would love
help his brother, Aidan.
I think I can get
berries alone.
I enter the woods.
Brother Aidan will be surprised ...
But the father ...
I'll be back before noticing.
But .. What if I get lost ...
... in the dark?
No! I can not leave!
But if I keep thinking
in the book
Do not be afraid to darkness.
On the contrary, can not wait
to go.
Well, Pangur Ban.
Tomorrow go into the woods!
Pangur!
It would be easier if he knew as
is an oak.
It might be better to go home ...
Was it here? Do not you remember?
Do not worry, Pangur. We only have
get back before it gets dark earlier.
Is not that enough? ...
Is this your cat?
Well?
I heard of creatures like you
You're a fairy, right?
What are you doing in my forest?
They have come to ruin it right?.
Are you orguilloso because your family sends
for food? right?
Well, you can go where you came.
If not, the wolves will catch you!
No!
I did not want ... Hey, sorry.
I'm not here to put food
my family. I am here for ink.
There is no family, and there
enough food in Kells.
I only lost in the shuffle.
Do not have a family?
None.
No mother?
I'm single too.
If this is your forest, no doubt
know everything about him.
Well, of course.
Wait!
Hello!
Not so hard! Go!
Hold on! Please! Do you know where
you can find this?
Yes
But you can not eat.
I do not want to eat, are for ink.
What is that?
It is for the book ...
To make drawings.
Color liquid that is put on paper.
As the leaves ... hard to explain,
I guess you'd have to see it.
I do not know what you're talking about,
but I do not know ...
But the brother Aidan ...
I'll help, on one condition ...
You have to promise that you and your
pet will never return here.
Okay. I promise.
Come then, to forests.
What ...?
Hey, wait!
My name is Brendan. What is yours?
It's a miracle, as Aidan said.
Aidan is my friend.
Assists in the preparation of
world's most beautiful book.
Change of darkness into light You'll see!
You wait until you see
the rest of the woods!
Wow, you're quick.
Yes, I'm the fastest.
So ...
Where are the berries?
They climbed a tree, right?
Yes, of course. Easy.
So come on!
Second time in the day I saved your life.
You said you could climb trees.
I know. Only small.
Of course ... shrubs.
Do not look down. Come on!
Look!
Insects recognize each other.
Come on!
If you open your eyes
I'll tell you my name.
Aisling.
This is my forest.
I asked them to not bite you.
This is what you want ...
... parachute but not all berries.
Rather, as a waste of wild boar.
And it smells bad too.
If you've done?, It's time to lose.
Download ...
A little to the left.
Do not wait! Do not go to the ...
... branch.
I regret that it took so long to download.
With the exception of the last stage ...
You better go. I know a secret way
to get home
Come on!
Look!
Brendan?
What are you doing? Come on!
This is the place of suffering.
Suffering? What do you mean?
Just stay away! It's too dangerous.
It can be dangerous
like climbing an oak.
This is the cave of darkness.
Crom Cruach cave?
But it's just a story for children.
The Abbot of Kells, says you should not
fear of imaginary things.
This is not imaginary.
He's waiting in the dark.
Aisling, you only scare yourself.
The father said that this
only a pagan.
Crom Cruach there.
Prnuncies not that name!
Do you really have fear?
Aisling!
Are you hurt?
What was that?
I told you ...
Crom!
- Brendan?
- Huh?
You can visit the forest again, if you wish.
Pangur can come too.
- Iona But we always do ...
- This is not Iona.
The room will be arranged according to scripture
my instructions.
But this is not good ...
It will be as I said.
Brother Aidan! I found them!
Brendan. It was time.
Where were you?
I'm listening. Where were you?
Yes ..
I went to the woods.
But only for a while, not much.
It was by Brother Aidan ...
Brendan. Have I not warned enough
about what lies beyond these walls?
Do not listen.
I know, but the book ...
Brendan. You can not leave
the monastery without permission.
But, man, you should have seen the book ...
Understand?
Yes, uncle.
That's good.
Now come with me, there are things to fix in the room.
- Look!
- What, what happened?
- I found them.
Really. You found.
I did it with a little help.
A friend of forests.
There is nothing you can do
with friends at your side, right?
Let's see.
Yes, yes ... seems
This corresponds very well ...
Small berries to large images.
Come on!
It is a lot of smoke ... a good sign.
- Yes?
- Sure.
- It's beautiful.
- From a soft foul.
Make ink is fine, but it's useless ...
... without any of this.
I am not allowed to do that.
Nobody here but us.
Only you
and ta imagination.
Are you afraid?
Me? No. I'm not afraid of
imaginary things.
Go! Finish what you started.
Gold!
Not bad.
I could say that you are doing
well enough.
What?
I must confess something, my son.
I have not been honest with you tally.
I can not draw the Chi-ro page.
My eyes are old.
My hands are trembling.
But .. said ...
You must be the one who does that page!
Me? No! I'm just a ...
Must be someone else
You should.
I would ruin it.
No, no, no. You can do it.
You found the berries
Your hands are firm.
Before I arrived they had already learned a lot
the work of the other brothers.
Only your imagination loose.
I gotta go.
Where have you been so early?
Come on, there is much work to do.
Pangur do not know ...
I can not see something stops him.
If ever he illumination in the Chi-ro
will face whatever it takes.
Brendan!
So we are moving the scaffolding
the west wall. Hurry!
I think it's time to discover the secret of Columban.
The fascinating details ...
Of course, you need another eye.
Well ...
- Once I found a crystal.
- Brother ...
Small miracles are brand new
Columbano, said crystal is not
should never be used.
Nobody has used.
What is a ... glass?
This is not a crystal, glass.
Colombano eyes.
Columbano, wrote over 300 books in his life.
With your hands!
The deathbed, prayed
so clear that the wizard
had wonderful visions
to be like him.
And as your last breath ...
dropped from his hand ...
... Colombia's eyes!
Colombano want it to be yours.
Where is it?
Forgive me, Pangur.
Have not you seen?
Is lost.
Lost!
When was the last time you saw her?
I do not understand.
If I could show the crystal
everything will be cleared.
... all understand.
- But ...
- But I can still continue training, can I?
Have you ever studied the small employer
of the wings of a fly?
- No.
- And you never will without the glass
How about if we pray for a miracle?
As Colombano made
Some people say that before the glass
was known as the eye of Columbanus
had an ancient name.
A name like the creature from which
Colombano was awarded the crystal.
Deep inside your home.
Cruach Crom!
It was called the eye of "Crom Cruach"
Do not know which part of the story
is true and what part ...
... is covered by darkness.
Ah, life is full of darkness ...
And only a short time
while we're on this earth.
Do not worry, Pangur.
I will not be alone.
Rohibido you leave the abbey.
Now you have forbidden to enter the
room scriptures.
Please, Uncle, do not understand.
I understand perfectly!
No more trips.
No more room and no more scripts brother Aidan.
No.
What?
I can not do that.
I can not give in to the book.
If you see only one page
understand why.
Have you forgotten how important it is?
Only cares about the wall.
Aidan's brother told me you
Lit once was.
- He said ...
- Stop!
If I can not trust you
'll stay here until they regained consciousness.
Cellach, do not blame
the boy. I'll talk to him ...
- You will not.
- You can ...
Tang's brother brought him food once
there is nothing here to distract ...
Let me save the workbook
I have been entrusted to me.
Okay.
On one condition: You will leave with the first Kelles
outbreak of spring.
Brendan
Aisling!
How can I get you?
Do not know.
The tower is closed.
And my door is locked from outside.
The key is in the room of the abbot.
Maybe ... can carry a message
brother Aidan.
You have to go where I can not go ...
Pangur in ...
Why the father has locked you in there?
Because I was naughty.
Why?
Look!
- The Eye of Crom!
- No, this is a crystal.
I think he's in the dark cave.
I have to go.
No Brendan, you are cheating.
You were safe in the tower.
Crom Cruach take my people, my mother took.
Take everything. Going to die!
Aisling, if not try the book
will never be completed.
The book ...
Well, I'll help.
Aisling! This place is hurting you,
you must go back.
Find another way.
I need help ...
Now retgresa please!
Turn the darkness into light.
Aisling!
Fool!
The old fool had to maintain
mouth shut ...
But the young fool would listen ...
There you are! How ... How ...?
How did you leave the tower?
You must come back before the father finds out.
This is no place for you,
there is nothing for you here.
But you're here, the book is here ...
and here is the eye.
How is this possible?!
There are more than a story about the eye.
More than a dwelling for the dead ...
and over one eye.
Did you go to dark cave?
You can not learn everything from books.
I think I read that somewhere ...
Well ... is time to start.
His breakfast, father.
Take it to Brendan.
See if ...
See if you are gaining a better understanding.
It's like heaven.
Heaven on Earth.
Please ... was my fault, father.
Little fool.
The Vikings are upon us
and you ... drawing
We have a day before the Vikings
Vikings attack Kells
- We stand at the door.
- We must flee!
Aguantaremos
Will guide the refugees to the chapel.
We must prepare ourselves for when the attackers
move.
Tang! Tell people
stay at home.
Cellach!
You'll be safe here with your beautiful book.
No, not yet!
Stay inside!
Tang! Open the door!
The tower!
One at a time!
The staircase is not strong enough!.
Tango, there are many!
Too late.
Close the door!
Brendan!
Ink! we have to ink!
- Brendan! you can not ...
- Fast!
Uncle!
No!
No! We must save him!
Brendan, where is the
secret passage into the woods?
We must save him!
I can not help it.
Brendan!
We can not stop.
I have to go back.
The Vikings did not let anyone in Iona
not let anyone in Kells
- He is my uncle.
- He did it to protect you.
The only way I could ...
Now I have to protect
by Cellach and for the book.
Gold!
Brendan!
Aisling!
We gotta go, Brendan,
hopefully be fast enough.
He's alive!
I'm so tired.
Tang, leave me be.
Please ...
Let me be.
You are the abbot of Kells!
Ue has lifted.
The book should be kept beyond any reason
within the walls ...
... journeys through the world with your inspiring creation.
Brendan,
You should take people
To give hope ...
to light the way in these dark times.
"Aisling?
I'm so tired.
Please, father, rest.
Rest?, How our most important
treasure destroyed?!.
But how would know?
How could he know he was going to die?
Please, Father.
It was only a child ...
Angel of Darkness! Not yet!
I need time!
Uncle!
Brenda?
Am I dreaming? ...
This is not a dream.
I'm so glad to find you here.
I thought I'd lost long ago.
Brendan!
Only a small child ...
A lot of innocent people ... lost.
- It was all my fault.
- Please, baby ...
... Do not blame yourself
You do not understand.
No time, Brendan.
You were right ...
About Kells ...
About Aidan ...
About the book ...
There should ...
This is all that remained.
This is the only consolation I have in this world.
Aidan's brother was right ...
And I tried to stop him.
Aidan never heard you, man.
Probably not ...
Aidan's brother alive to see
his work through ... and be completed.
Iona's book!
Is the Book of Kells?
Book of Kells.