- All right, Weinkoop, where is she?
- In this car, sir.
- Has she recovered consciousness?
- Not sir, not yet.
This is the company doctor.
- Follow me, doctor
- Come on, Doc.
Five minutes out of Port Johnson
she went into the ladies' room.
- Must've finished off a pint.
- The telegram said she fell.
Rolled off the seat
like a sack of flour.
- Well?
- She's dead drunk.
I'll say something else in my report
if you want, but that's what it is.
Should be in a hospital.
Anything to get her
off company property. Come on, Doc.
Have her taken to the Jefferson
Hospital. You go with her.
Be sure you make it straight with the people
there that we're not taking any responsibility.
We're doing this only as a courtesy
to her husband, and that's all.
Put her in a private room
under another name.
Keep her there until I get
Sam Eaton to come take her home.
Very well, Mr Jones.
There's more to running a railroad than
just laying down some tracks, doctor.
- Ah, looking for quail, Frolick, as usual?
- As usual, DD.
You won't find any around here.
They're all down on Market Street by now.
- Nobody left on that train?
- No, no, just the crew.
I wonder if...
Oh, no. Not Martha Eaton.
See you later.
This is DD Jones.
I want you to put in a long-distance
call to Port Johnson.
To Mr Samuel Eaton.
That's right, Eaton Iron and Steel.
Will you be home for dinner,
Mr Eaton, if anyone should ask?
If you mean by "anyone" Mrs Eaton...
Say so, Nellie, or
forever hold your peace.
Well, I was only thinking what with
Mr Alfred coming home from the war today.
Oh, you're sure it's today, are you?
Maybe you even know what time
he's coming.
Or how he's coming.
No reason why a servant shouldn't know
more than his own family.
Those eggs were too hard
again today, Nellie.
When I say soft-boiled,
I mean soft-boiled. - Yes, Mr Eaton.
The answer is: I may be home,
and then again, I may not.
- And now I'm off. Goodbye, Nellie.
- Goodbye, sir.
Hello. Eaton residence.
Oh, I'm sorry. He just left.
You should be able to reach him
at the mill in about 10 minutes.
You're welcome. Goodbye.
Mrs Eaton got out of the house
mighty early this morning, George.
Yes, sir.
Philadelphia again?
I didn't wait to see
which train she took, sir.
Didn't she say anything?
We were too busy
talking about your boy...
Coming out of the Navy alive and well to be
concerning ourselves with unimportant matters.
In other words, Mrs Eaton's
whereabouts are too unimportant...
For me to have any interest in them.
There's nothing about Mrs Eaton
that's unimportant.
At least, not to me, sir.
Are you trying to say something
to me, George?
Well, sir...
I made me a promise
the day your son went away.
"George Fry", I said,
'The day Alfred comes
home from this war,
you'll say some things
that's been wanting to be said."
Took a lot for granted, didn't you?
I knew he was coming back.
I prayed for him.
You prayed?
You're no more
of a praying man than I am.
If it was Billy gone to war
instead of Alfred...
Maybe you'd have learned
to pray, Mr Eaton.
Is that what you promised
yourself to say?
A father can feel badly
over a son dead 13 years...
Without ignoring the other one.
Don't preach to me, George.
No, sir.
Maybe you'd better be taking the day off.
I'll accept the day's holiday, sir,
But after that, I don't want to work
for you anymore, Mr Eaton.
No, I shouldn't think you would.
I'll have your check ready
for you tomorrow morning.
Yes, sir.
You might as well stop
in front of the saloon...
When we get there and get out.
That's where you'll be going anyway,
I'm sure.
Here's to Samuel Eaton...
President of Eaton Iron and Steel...
Who, after 20-some odd years
of being...
Dirty, rotten mean to his boy Alfred...
Has just been fired.
I said fired, Noony...
By his own chauffeur.
I'll drink to that.
And here's to Alfred Eaton...
Who never did anything wrong
in his whole life,
Except be the son who didn't die
of spinal meningitis...
When he was a kid.
And now...
I hope he'll be forgiven
for living through the war.
You know where North Hill Road is?
Hey, Jake. Got a passenger
for out of town.
Good!
Don't you want to
help me with my bags?
Who says so?
How much do I owe you?
3 dollars.
- Oh, yeah? Who says so?
- I said so. 3 dollars.
Wait here for a minute while
I go and telephone.
Telephone who?
The taxi company, I want to find out
when they raised their prices.
2 dollars.
Here's one dollar.
Go ahead, beat it before
I pull you out of that cab...
And bust your nose for you.
Well, big man.
Oh, Mr Alfred!
- Oh, Mr Alfred!
- Hello, Josephine. Hello, Nellie.
Stop, Nellie, for
the Lord's sake.
I can't help it.
Well, you all look fine.
Come on, now.
Turn around, Josephine.
I will not.
You don't have to.
I can see it's getting bigger.
- It is not.
- She don't have her corset on.
Shut your mouth, for the Lord's sake.
I brought you two old crows
some presents from London.
You didn't have to spend
your money on us.
We're just thankful
you're home.
And I'll bet you are, too.
You didn't tell a soul
what time you were coming.
I didn't want to give anybody
a chance not to meet me.
We aren't really ready for you,
Mr Alfred...
What with the mister
and missis away.
Away?
Tonight I don't have only
some lamb chops...
But I did make a nice
apple pie, though.
Where did they go?
The missis went away this morning.
I don't know where.
The mister he called
this afternoon.
It sounded like long distance.
And he said, "Don't wait with dinner."
So we fixed for Miss Trimingham early.
Miss Trimingham?
Yes. Come on, Josephine.
Help me with these bags.
You'll find your old room, just exactly
the way you left it, Mr Alfred.
Nellie, who's Miss Trimingham?
She's your mother's
trained nurse.
Trained nurse?
For the drinking, Mr Alfred.
Alfred!
Oh, my Alfred!
Mother, you all right?
Oh, forgive me. How horrible.
I'm so excited and awkward.
- Oh, but you're home.
- Yes, Mother.
Oh, darling, don't. Don't look at me.
I didn't want you to see me
like this.
I'm so tired,
and I'm not feeling well.
Couldn't we save everything for
tomorrow, when I'll be at my best?
We'll make believe
there was no tonight...
And that you came home tomorrow and...
We'll say all our hellos
just as they should be.
Sure, Mother.
Here comes your father.
Now make allowances.
He's not at his... best.
Here we are, Sam,
and look who's with me.
- My boy. Home at last.
- Hello, Father.
Hello, Father?
Is that all after all this time?
No. There's a lot more.
Yes, I should think
there would be.
Now what've you
done to yourself?
She just tripped and fell.
Doesn't he look wonderful?
Yes. Let's get in the house.
Now, Sam, what we've decided is...
We're not going to
say our hellos tonight.
We're all much too tired
and tomorrow
we'll all be fresh as a daisy.
How was the war?
OK, I guess. We won it.
Oh, have you met my son?
Alfred, this is Miss Trimingham.
- How do you do?
- Welcome home.
Up we go.
Cool sheets and heavenly rest.
Good night, Alfred.
Sleep as late as you like...
And remember...
You're coming home tomorrow.
Tonight never even happened.
The house looks good.
Yeah.
Your mother touched it up
a bit here and there.
You've put on a
couple of pounds.
Soft living in the Navy.
I suppose you're sleepy.
I was up at quarter to 6:oo
this morning.
Not a very good time to talk now
anyway, is it?
No, I guess it isn't.
I guess I'll go upstairs, too.
If it's all right with you.
Father?
Yeah?
Nothing. Good night.
Good night.
She doesn't need you now.
Well, Mr Alfred, how does it feel
to be home again and...
Seeing your mother and father?
Things don't change, Nellie.
They just get more so.
We got ginger ale, seltzer, glasses
and no liquor. Where's the liquor?
Your father keeps it
under lock and key.
- Good night, Mr Alfred.
- Good night.
Even the servants in your own house,
know about you.
I'm tired. I'm sick. Leave me alone.
I'll leave you alone when you tell
me everything I want to know.
- Who else saw you together?
- Nobody else. Not a soul.
- You were in restaurants together.
- Never.
Wallowing in filth together!
And I want to know where
every damn place! - No.
Well, you're going to tell me.
Oh no, Sam, not tonight.
Please!
Where else did you meet him?
Nowhere else. Only his house.
You're lying to me.
You were with him in a hotel room.
All right!
But only once.
You could stay with him
and me the same night?
Yes!
Did you think you're any better...
Than one of those sluts
on River Street?
I'm not proud of myself.
Not proud of herself, she says.
How can you look
at your own son?
I can't.
If that egotistical little
father of yours
Was alive to know about this...
Your son.
Your father.
Your heroes.
I have no heroes,
only some people I love.
- You were my hero.
- Shut up!
And you drove me to it.
You turned your back on me
just like you did on Alfred.
I needed love...
Wherever I could find it.
Love!
You're a pig.
I can't stand the sight of you.
Mr Eaton.
His name is Charles Frolick.
He's a terrible, evil man.
How long has it been going on?
About a year.
She's been trying not to see him,
but he won't let her.
She can't help herself.
Frolick?
Number 22 Walnut Street,
Philadelphia.
- Yes, what is it?
- Are you Charles Frolick?
I am. What kind
of an hour of the night...
- Who the devil are you?
- Charlie.
What do you think
you're doing here anyway?
Charlie!
My name is Alfred Eaton.
Alfred Eaton. You got that?
Now, you go near my mother
again, I'll kill you.
Charlie? What's the big idea
of keeping me...
Charlie!
Mr Alfred down yet?
He's having breakfast, sir.
There you are, boy.
Watch those eggs, Nellie.
Yes, Mr Eaton.
Well, how did it feel
sleeping in your own bed?
You mother wanted to buy
a new mattress...
But I said no, that wouldn't be
like coming home.
I slept very well.
Thank you.
Well, I didn't.
It's not as easy
as it used to be.
Still, I guess I'm all right
for a man of 57...
Considering the way I worked
my tail off during the war.
Way things work I'm going
to get a chance to rest.
We all are, in our business.
Big contracts canceled months ago...
And now those darn fool workers
are going to strike.
Well let them.
There'll be nothing,
but gas in their kids' bellies...
By the time they come back.
Pay them exactly what you want.
So what do you care?
I care because I'm against
anybody going on strike against me.
You'll know what I feel, when
you come into the business with me.
Well, I suppose you're thinking
of taking it easy for a while.
Not exactly.
Maybe traveling a bit, seeing
something of the country...
Before settling down here.
You know, we got to start thinking
of a club in Philadelphia...
For a young fellow like you.
I doubt very much that
I'll be joining a club...
But even if I do,
it'll probably be in New York.
New York?
What for?
Because I expect to be spending
some time there.
I thought you were going to travel.
No, you said I was going to travel.
I didn't say it, you said it.
My home base will be in New York.
The hell it will.
The hell it won't!
I guess I don't feel
like having any breakfast.
Tell them in the kitchen
I'm not staying.
Don't you want to hear
what my plans are?
I'm in no hurry to.
I can see you are not going to do what
I'd hoped you'd do...
And you thought it all out without
discussing it it with me.
I'd be glad to discuss it
with you.
You don't want to discuss anything...
You want to tell me to go to
the devil and take the mill with me.
That's probably the only reason
you came home...
You've been wanting
to do that all your life.
All my life, all I wanted to do
is to be friends with you.
That's what you want,
to be friend with me.
Listen to me young fellow...
I haven't got a friend for every 10
years of my life.
I was hoping for that, too.
But first, you'll gonna have
to show me...
You're the kind of a man I'd want
to be friends with.
The job at the mill was gonna be yours
because the mill would be yours....
And I hoped the friendship
would come out of that.
Would come out of what?
Being your errand boy,
the boss's son, your lackey?
You never asked me
what I wanted to do.
What I wanted to be!
Now I'm supposed to go
into the mill with you, what for?
To please you, that's all!
You'd cripple me for life.
You would like that wouldn’t you?
You don't think I can make it on my own.
You're not big enough
to even walk in my shadow...
And you never will be.
Alfred.
So much shouting...
So early in the day...
With the servants around, too.
I guess we're not a very dignified,
respectable family, are we mother?
You must give him time.
For what? He'll never change.
He might get used to your ways.
I don't think I have that much time.
Neither has he.
There's a lot of sadness
and a lot of sweetness in you, Alfred,
But you can be very cruel
and cold sometimes.
Nice, kind Alfred.
Did I just say something awful?
I'm sorry.
Nothing for you
to be sorry about.
Yes, I did.
What's happened to me?
I used to be nice...
And I don't even remember
what made me change.
Don't be hard on yourself.
I know a lot more
than you think I do.
You're still my mother.
What do you know?
Everything.
Oh, God.
Put your arms around me, Alfred.
Do you still like me a little?
I love you, Mother.
Even when I'm like this?
You're leaving us,
aren't you, Alfred?
Yes.
Where are you going?
I may stay with Lex Porter
in New York for a while.
I suppose you'll see the Thorntons.
Fritz Thornton is throwing a party
for Lex tonight in Southampton.
The Porters and the Thorntons
are like a second family to you...
But just remember, they're not.
Don't get too independent.
Don't cut off
your own flesh and blood.
Anybody can disappoint you,
if you catch them
at the wrong time
and that includes
you, too, Alfred.
I know I'm not what you think
your mother ought to be.
I'm sorry if it embarrasses you...
And I'm not going to make
any excuses.
Don't worry.
That's not why I'm leaving.
I could feel it last night...
Your very first look at me
down in the driveway.
What am I?
A hopeless drunkard?
They'd rather have me that
than the other thing...
An unfaithful wife.
A pig, he called me.
Well...
The drinking makes a good
cover-up for a lot of things.
Goodbye now, Mother.
"It wouldn't have happened
if she hadn't been a drinker."
"Martha Eaton wouldn't do such things...
If she didn't like gin
and whiskey so much."
Well...
Little do they know.
Little does anybody know.
May I have this dance?
Oh, why, certainly.
Will you pardon
me just a moment?
Sure.
Thank you.
Are you looking for me?
I am if your name
is Lex Porter.
Well, my name is Clemmie Shreve...
But I'll change it
if you'll stop looking further.
Just how far am I allowed to look?
You're fresh.
I like you. Sam?
No, Alfred.
Are you going to make
a pass at me, Alfred?
You believe
in long courtships, don't you?
Who's got time?
I'm crowding 19.
What, years or guys?
Nasty.
Come on. Let's dance
and crowd each other.
Look I got a wooden leg,
I better go fill first.
Oh, you mean it's all over between us?
Well,
these things don't last forever.
Waiter, where I can find Mr Porter.
He went into the den
a few minutes ago, sir.
Excuse me.
Hey, wait a minute.
Alfred, when did you get here?
Couple of minutes ago.
Come in, come in!
Join us!
Alfred Eaton...
Sage Rimmington.
Sorry.
So am I.
Sage, this is the rover boy,
that I went through...
Princeton and the Navy with...
And, who knows what lies ahead?
Darling, if you'll excuse me...
I think I'll put on
something more comfortable.
Like my husband.
Bye, sweetie.
I like that.
Oh, she's very inventive.
- How was it, boy?
- How was what?
Getting home.
Great.
Yeah, me, too.
I snapped out of it, though.
Good booze, bad women.
It never fails to work.
How did things go
in the money department?
Our project.
Did you raise the dough?
Oh, your old man, uh?
Well, I'll have another little talk
with Uncle Fritz.
I'll just charm him
into putting up the whole 500,000.
I don't want that.
I know you don't, sport,
but have we got any choice?
I don't mean to sound ungrateful,
But we'll just have to wait
till I can swing my own end.
I'm not going into any
business venture...
Where I carry as much weight
as a poor relative.
Well, I understand pal.
It just doesn't mean that much to me.
It does to me.
Boy, you did have a rough time
at home, didn't you?
You know, the first thing we got to do
is get you out of there.
I've already taken
care of that.
Really?
What are your plans?
I don't know.
I was sort of...
Thinking about that
bachelor apartment...
You were going to set up
in Gramercy Park.
Hey, now you're talking.
Play it by ear for a while.
Well, you can use your ear.
I got better ideas.
C'mon, let's start right now.
Now, would you look at this?
200 beautiful Long Island virgins.
Markel's dance music,
buckets of champagne...
And I'm the guest of honor.
Now, how can I lose?
Unless I start getting drunk...
And taking those little girls
upstairs.
I met something called Clemmie.
Oh, Clemmie Shreve.
Now, I'm saving that
for a rainy night.
Uh, there he is, Uncle Fritz.
Look who's here.
- Alfred, I'm so glad to see you.
- Mr Thornton, how are you?
This party wouldn't be complete
without you, young man.
Champagne for three.
Have they been treating
you properly here?
No complaints.
Well, I hope you're going to stay
with us for a good long visit.
I may take you up on that.
Well, I...
I hoped for this moment.
The three of us together like this...
As I hoped for victory.
God bless you.
Thought I might as
well start at the top.
Did you?
Pretty close to it.
Thanks for the compliment.
And who are you?
Alfred Eaton, but that wouldn't
mean anything to you.
What's your name?
Mary St. John.
A nice, respectable name.
Well, of course
it's respectable.
That's a silly thing to say.
Am I the first
to call it respectable?
You're the first
who ever raised the question.
In that case I'm glad I called it
respectable instead of the opposite.
If you're trying to annoy me, Mr Eaton,
you're succeeding.
No, my manners are just a little rusty.
You're the first girl I've danced
with for a long time.
Why didn't you bestow that
honor on someone inside...
Instead of here on the terrace?
Oh, I don't know, I...
Rather like the view
from the terrace.
And then I saw you
and I liked the view even more.
You touch me deeply.
But not in the right places?
Well,
that was reasonably disagreeable.
Yes, and it was so easy.
Would you like to go upstairs
and cry or something?
No, but I wouldn't mind,
if you faded away into the sunset.
Here comes the bird dog,
to retrieve you.
What's his name?
- Jim Roper.
- Oh, grim Jim Roper?
No. Dr Roper.
He's a psychiatrist.
Oh, sorry.
I hope you get well very soon.
Good night, Mr Eaton.
Good night, Miss St. John.
All yours, Doctor.
I know that.
Oh, I don't know about these girls.
I heard they were like minks
during the war.
How are you doing?
You tell me.
Who's Mary St. John?
Her old man's with the DuPont
Corporation down in Wilmington.
Fancy pedigree.
Papers on both sides.
Hey, waiter.
You can forget about her.
Why?
- You want one?
- No.
She's secretly engaged
to the guy she's with.
The doctor, Jim Roper.
I really don't think
he's rich enough for her...
But if it isn't him it'll be
somebody else who is.
If you're not thinking
about marrying her...
You can forget about
anything else.
She's really saving it.
Do you want to make a little bet?
Oh, wake up, sport.
You haven't got
the necessary qualifications.
Well, there are all kinds
of qualifications.
And straight ahead you'll notice
the famous Whitney estate.
Oh, and there to the right...
Is the estate of James
Duncan MacHardie.
You notice the smoke
rising from the chimney?
In all probability
Mr MacHardie is burning money.
Stop hiding behind the glasses.
I'm not hiding.
You always manage to put
something between us...
Like Jim Roper, or your friend
Sage Rimmington...
Or the net of a tennis court.
What are you afraid of?
- Let's go back to shore shall we?
- See what I mean?
You know, I don't even know
why you bother talking to me...
Because every time you do, you get
sarcastic and we end up in a fight.
Now, if you don't approve of me,
why don't you just leave me alone...
I'm sure I won't perish
from unhappiness.
This is the first time
we've been alone.
How long are you going to be here?
A month or so.
Then back to Wilmington?
I used to live very close to there,
Port Johnson, Pennsylvania.
I thought you lived in New York,
in Gramercy Park...
With Lex and all the stray girls
you could lay your hands on
Or so they tell me.
I think we'd better go back.
- You don't mean that.
- Yes, I do mean that.
I knew you were going to kiss me today,
but I didn't know I'd kiss you back...
And it isn't going to happen again,
so don't try to get me up alone somewhere.
- You'd like that.
- Stop it.
- Why?
- 'Cause I'm engaged to Jim Roper.
- You going to marry him?
- Well, I'm engaged to him.
But you didn't say
you were going to marry him.
Look, are you going to row me back to shore
or am I going to have to swim back?
Swim.
Hello, Alfred.
Who is it, Mary?
It's just a friend, Mother.
Well, who is it, Mary?
I think you better come in.
Mother, this is Alfred Eaton.
My mother.
- How do you do?
- How do you do, Mr Eaton.
And my father.
Daddy, Alfred Eaton.
Pleased to meet you, sir.
I don't believe
we've seen you before.
Are you from these parts?
Not very far from here, sir.
Port Johnson, Pennsylvania.
Oh, yes. The steel mill.
So, you're that Eaton.
What do you think of the strike?
I'm not in the mill, sir,
but my father doesn't like it.
Yeah, I shouldn't think he would.
Well Mr. Eaton, what brings you to
Wilmington at this awkward hour?
I was just duck hunting
on my way to New York...
I thought I'd stop and say hello to Mary.
How was the shooting?
I got a few tail feathers.
How is Jim?
- Jim?
- Yes.
You mean Jim Roper?
Yes. I assume you're close
friends, aren't you?
Not exactly.
Oh, well, now...
Not a friend of Jim's.
Isn't that a bit strange?
No, Mother, Jim and I met Alfred
at the same time.
Then he's really a friend of yours,
more than Jim's.
That's right.
Tell me, Mr Eaton...
You're not in the mill.
What do you do?
I mean, besides duck hunting
in the middle of the week.
Actually, I've got some very
exciting business plans...
I'm not allowed to
disclose them right now.
I see.
Well...
I guess I better be going.
My husband will see you to the door.
No, mother, I will.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
- Good night, Mrs St. John.
- Goodbye, Mr Eaton.
Your mother and father...
Are sort of distant.
Now, what do you mean by that?
You know what I mean.
You never did believe
I was going to marry Jim, did you?
I wrote him a letter
and I broke up with him.
Why didn't you tell me?
I don't know.
I didn't tell anybody.
Alfred?
Are you going to do something...
And be somebody?
For you?
Yes.
Settle down?
With you?
Do you love me?
Oh, I want you.
More than anything
in the whole world.
Mary?
You're never going to want anybody
else as long as you live.
You better go in now.
I should think he'd know better.
- He wanted to see me.
- And you should, too.
I happen to like Alfred, Mother.
The Eatons are nothing and nobody.
The mother is a drunkard.
The father is a noisy nouveau riche
war profiteer.
Now how do you
happen to know that?
You haven't met
either one of them.
I have my sources of information.
And if he were a gentleman, he'd stay
away from you before people start talking.
I don't want him, your father doesn't
want him. That's all there is to it.
That isn't all there is to it.
I've broken my
engagement to Jim.
I can't believe it.
Mary...
I forbid you to see this man again.
I don't like that word forbid, father.
It makes me want to disobey you.
In that case,
I shall have a talk with Mr Eaton.
Alfred or his father?
I meant the young man...
But you've given me an idea.
Don't do that, father!
It's my life!
I don't have to take
that kind of talk...
From Eugene St. John
or any of that DuPont crowd!
So you didn't.
You hung up on him.
If you'd stayed
where you belong...
Maybe I don't like
where I belong.
That's what is souring
your insides, isn't it?
That my blood and your mother's
is running through your veins.
That's why you want to get mixed up
with a family who doesn't even want you.
I'm not interested
in her family!
Well, let me tell you something...
That you can't buy respectability...
By slipping a wedding ring on it.
Sometimes you end up with just what
you're trying to run away from.
And remember, I am
the one who told you.
If you're through with me,
I'd better get going.
Where, back to that apartment
your friend Porter...
And all those questionable
goings-on I hear about?
You haven't done an honest day's
work since you came from the Navy!
For your information father, I'm going into
business with Lex Porter.
Business?
What kind of business?
Aircraft, private planes.
Airplanes.
That's right. We're going to design,
them, build them and sell them.
What are you going
to use for money?
It's already been taken care of.
Your friend Lex's family financing you?
That's right.
- 100%?
- Yes, 100%.
That's one way of putting
your head in a noose.
I was going to ask you for my share,
but I changed my mind.
How much were you
going to ask me to give you?
Not give, lend.
What difference does it make?
Well, here's what I think
of your airplane business.
You can put me down for 500 dollars.
Well, that's exactly 500 dollars
more than I expected...
If I had asked you for it.
Wait a minute!
It's too late, I've
already signed the papers.
It's something else.
There's something
I have to know.
I've been wanting to ask you.
Come to the office.
I don't know how to start this.
I mean, where's the beginning?
Did you ever hear
of a man named Frolick?
- Did you?
- Yes.
In what connection?
I'd rather you put the question
some other way.
All right.
- Did you ever meet this man?
- I saw him once.
- Did you beat him up?
- Yes, I did.
Thank God.
Thank God it was you.
Maybe you're a lot of things
I never gave you credit for...
But a man my age
can't change so quickly.
I can admit I've been wrong
all these years...
But that wouldn't
make anything right.
It won't take away
what I felt about you...
What I still feel, regardless
of what I know in my brain.
Some time
when you have children, you'll know.
One of them is in here.
He shines. His voice is music.
You love him as though
he never lived in his mother's body.
That's the way Billy was to me...
Long before he died.
And when he died...
There was nobody
who understood what happened to me.
You were living...
You were alive...
A deliberate thing God did to me.
I didn't want another son
or anyone in my life.
Not you, not even your mother.
Just Billy.
That's why your mother took Frolick,
Not because she's immoral...
Because I didn't even tell her
I didn't love her anymore.
She had to find that out for herself.
I guess she knew it before I did.
And yet, even knowing,
How badly it turned out
for everybody...
Including myself...
I would do the same thing over again.
It was so wonderful
loving Billy that much.
Always in your thoughts.
I can feel his arms
around my neck this minute.
Don't go.
Don't go?
What do you think I am?
Alfred, I didn't mean it!
Alfred, my son...
Alfred?
- Hello, Mary.
- Get in.
Good evening.
How's your father?
It's hard to tell.
He's always the same man, sick or well.
Yes.
Old men may seem unchangeable
to you, Alfred...
But life itself now,
there's a different thing.
Consider this.
A week ago, I was firmly opposed
to any thought of you two marrying.
Tonight, I'm not only reconciled
to it I'm secretly in favor of it.
Yes. Life's full
of unpredictable ironies.
Now, you wouldn't have thought
it was going to be your own father...
Who would be responsible
for this change in my attitude?
My father? How?
By having this unfortunate
heart attack...
Which automatically
transforms your life.
You suddenly change from
irresponsible young man...
To the active head of a family
and Eaton Iron and Steel.
And this removes the lot of
the objections we had to you...
As a prospective son-in-law.
I know you haven't had experience
running a mill, Alfred, but...
But you can be sure I'll help you
in any way I can.
Thank you very much, Mr Saint John, but
I haven't got the slightest intention...
Of running my father's mill.
I plan to be active head
of my own family...
Which means Mary and me.
Good night, sir.
Good night, Mary.
Do you give up?
Yes, I give up.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
Eugene, lovely day for a wedding.
Hello, Mary.
I wouldn't miss this for the world.
- Don't go, Sage.
- I think I'd better.
I read all your letters.
I know exactly how you feel.
Does he know you the way I do?
Does he know that wild
and wonderful nature of yours?
I think you'd better leave.
It won't work.
Please go.
You don't have to marry him
to get what you want of him.
Good luck, Mary.
Yeah?
Hi. What's the matter
you change your mind?
Alfred, do you love me?
Do I love you?
Of course I love you.
Is that why you called?
All right.
I love you. I love you. I love you.
And incidentally
we have a date tonight.
Careful, now.
Somebody might be listening.
Yeah.
Goodbye.
Hi. Come on in.
I've got a great idea.
Porter-Eaton Flying Machine Company.
Tailspins, Incorporated.
Bottoms Up Corporation?
If your Uncle Fritz ever heard me
talking like this...
He'd probably take back the money.
Alfred, you trust me, don't you?
Why, sure, I do. You're my best man.
I have to tell you something, then.
I can't.
Your mother
just phoned from the hospital.
She told me not to say anything
to anybody, especially to you.
What is it?
Your father died a few minutes ago.
I'm sorry.
Shall I tell them to
call off the wedding?
No.
Well, I guess he hated me so much...
He couldn't even...
Stand to be alive
on the day I got married.
Oh, I like this little baby.
She's like my ideal woman...
Handles easily...
Levels off without too much work.
Hey, buddy, you're not with me.
Oh, I'm with you.
Come on, what is it?
Alright.
I saw those new two cradled engines
in the hangar today.
The Navy ordered
100 from Continental.
We heard about it and got two.
Who's we?
- Von Elm and myself.
- Why wasn't I consulted?
- We need engines, don't we?
- Yeah, we need engines.
I just don't like the idea you're
going over my head again.
How do you like it?
We're about to buzz
your happy little home...
And your happy little wife.
I think the least you can do out of the occasion
is put a smile, on that sour pan of yours.
What did you marry,
a man or a mosquito?
Very much a man, Sage.
A delicious man and all man
from the top of his head...
To the tip of his toes.
Ah-ah!
What was that "ah-ah" for?
You've been married over a year, honey.
If you're about to say,
"Why no children?" don't.
That's my doing, not his.
Sweety, I ain't talking
about children...
I hate the little stinkers,
and you know it.
You absolutely shock me, Sage.
Why?
Because I say what you...
Secretly feel?
Oh, stop it.
It's unfair, you know...
The way I tell you everything
about Steve and me...
What it's like when
we're alone together...
And you not only
don't let me in on a thing...
That goes on between you
and that gorgeous fellow of yours...
But you even try to pull
the wool over my eyes.
The trouble with you Sage is you're
nothing but a frustrated Peeping Tom.
Oh, this is the wrong gender, darling.
Come on now, woman-to-woman...
What's he like?
He's fine.
But you do wish he'd come home
into your waiting arms of yours...
A little more often, huh?
Precisely what can a group
of red-blooded American males...
Do to an airplane propeller
until 4:oo in the morning?
Well, I don't think I'd want a man...
Who wasn't interested
in being successful.
Oh, I'm curious.
What does success look like
when you turn out the lights?
Oh, you're impossible, Sage,
you know that?
Well, I say if work is a man's mistress...
Then there's only one answer
for the wife...
Another man.
And how is Jim Roper these days?
Ever hear from him?
Of course not.
Now, don't let faint heart...
Spoil life's golden
opportunities, darling.
You know, I don't want to seem like a bore,
Sage, but I'm really not interested in this.
- What gives?
- I don't know.
- Pull it up.
- I'm trying.
What happened?
Fortunately, he woke up in time.
Looked like the new stabilizer to me.
What new stabilizer?
We're trying out
a modified version of the old one.
What's wrong with the unmodified
version of the old one?
Well, nothing, really, but
there's always room for refinement.
Wait a minute.
I'm not going to make a point
out of the fact...
That nobody told me what
was happening around here...
Because I got a
bigger point to make.
Lex, you and Von Elm must think we're running
an aeronautical laboratory around here.
We're designing planes,
refining planes,
We're modifying planes,
we're redesigning planes...
We're doing everything
but selling planes.
Either we're in business
or we are not in business.
Now, I think we got
a good plane there.
Let's freeze the design, let's start
manufacturing, and let's start selling.
And if you don't see it that way...
I think we ought to sit down
right now and have a serious talk.
In your office or mine?
Every time Sage start stalking
like that, I get a little crazy.
I don't want to win out anymore.
I just want to get out.
I feel like I'm blushing all over.
I'd hate to have
her think I'm a...
What do you call me?
A hot number.
Lex is rich he doesn't give a hang
about business.
I went into this business with the idea
of making make money...
Not in five year, not next year,
tomorrow.
All I could think
of was one thing.
How much I wanted you.
Well...
If he and Von Elm are going to play
Tiddlywinks at the drawing board...
With Fritz Thornton's money
they are gonna have to do it without me.
When we go there on Sunday, I'll tell them
either I get some control, or I want out.
Darling?
You talk too much.
- So long, Mary, Jim.
- See you back at the house.
Can we go inside for
a few minutes Mr Thornton?
You cold?
No, I'd just like to have
a few words with you.
Sure you don't want to
keep an eye on Mary?
Why? She's a good skater.
Well, that's not exactly
what I meant.
You were my girl, right?
Obviously I wasn't your girl.
You wouldn't say awful things, about
somebody you really cared about.
Honey, you made a
fool out of me.
Did you think I'd be a
little gentleman about it?
Jim, If you wanted to make me
feel terrible, you've succeeded.
Jim, don't.
Now when I hold a girl,
I pretend it's you.
That's a filthy thing to say.
I've had a dozen girls
since you left me...
But they've all been you, Mary.
That's the way
it's going to be with you.
Some night in bed,
he'll turn into me.
Are you angry, Alfred,
or just thinking?
What?
Oh, no, I'm not angry.
I expected you
to support Lex and Von Elm.
Well, I admit it would be easier
to make money now, Alfred...
But it would be nothing compared
to what might come in 5 or 10 years...
If the itch for quick profits could
remain unscratched for a while.
Well...
I guess I have to make a decision
then don't I, Mr Thornton?
Yes, I guess you do.
But not today.
On the seventh day
the businessman should rest.
If it was so much nothing
why were you running away from him?
I was not running away.
My fingers were freezing.
Now, do you want a wife
with frozen fingers?
What did you two talk about?
He still loves me.
Thanks.
You wouldn't have believed me if I said
we talked about the weather, would you?
Did he kiss you?
- I bet he tried to kiss you.
- Not only that.
He picked me up in his arms...
And carried me off across the
desert on a white charger.
You're just trying
to make a joke out of it.
Darling, you're being silly.
I like him.
And I always have liked him.
Now you can't expect me
to stop liking my men friends...
Any more than I can expect you
to stop liking your women friends.
And I said liking!
So let's not talk
about it anymore.
That suits me fine.
Sandy! Sandy!
Alfred, stop the car. Look!
Sandy fell in!
Oh, sir! Mr MacHardie!
Sandy fell in.
He wouldn't... Listen to me.
Here, give him to me.
Get away from here.
- Who are you?
- I'm his grandfather.
Call a doctor,
the fire department, hurry!
Yes!
It's all right.
Well, you can't begrudge them
for wanting to thank you.
I wish he'd let it go
at sending flowers.
Darling, you rescued the grandson
of James Duncan MacHardie,
Who is only the most famous
financier in America.
- Yes!
- I know.
We'll get a lot more
than a houseful of flowers...
And an evening of gratitude,
you can be sure.
I'll bet we are.
First he is going to look us over
To find out whether we're
sufficiently respectable.
- You're going with that word again.
- And then, he's going to look me over...
To find out whether
my halo's bright enough...
To qualify me for one of those...
desks of his at number25 Wall Street.
An aging fortress
of banking integrity.
You must admit
the timing's perfect...
For what with you planning to leave Lex
and no job in sight.
How do you know I'll take
his job if he offers me?
Because I know you, darling,
and you're very shrewd, darling...
You're not at all the kind of man...
To turn down the opportunity
of a lifetime, darling.
No matter how much
you protest, darling.
Besides, doesn't Wall Street close
up shop early in the afternoon?
I love the idea of your being
available to me more often.
Is that all it
would mean to you?
What's wrong with a girl...
Worrying about her own
needs now and then?
How nice of you to come.
I'm Jean Duffy,
Mr MacHardie's daughter,
- And Sandy's very grateful mother.
- How do you do.
- And this is my husband Creighton.
- Hello!
- We wanted to thank you alone...
- And we do.
But we also wanted Sandy to meet
the gentleman who saved his life.
Oh Sandy, dear.
- This is Mrs Eaton.
- Hello, Sandy.
- And Mr Eaton you have met before.
- Glad you dried off.
Thank you very much for fishing
me out of the pond.
My pleasure.
- And?
- And...
Oh, yes. And it's a good thing
I wasn't any smaller...
Or...
Or you'd have had to throw me back.
Oh, very good.
- Good. Now, son, skedaddle.
- Good night, Sandy.
Now you're ready
for your cocktail.
Creighton, dear, will you and
Mrs Eaton lead the way?
You were very sweet to him, Mr Eaton.
I'd like you to meet
the other guests.
Here Mrs Ripley...
Lady Sevringham...
Mrs Pearson...
Lord Sevringham.
My father you know, of course.
Glad to see you again, sir.
And Mr Thornton.
Mr and Mrs Eaton.
I think that does it.
I didn't expect to see you here.
It might turn out
to be something of an occasion.
Watch out for Creighton Duffy.
He's a member
of MacHardie and Company...
But only because he's a son-in-law.
Resents competition.
You have a Portland, Oregon
and a Portland, Maine.
Why, when you have a new country
like this and a splendid opportunity...
To start from scratch
with all-new names...
Why must you have two Portlands?
Well, we have a lot worse
than that Lady Sevringham....
- You've heard of California.
- Of course, I have a friend there.
- And you've heard of Indiana.
- Yes, I think so, yes, Indiana.
- And Pennsylvania.
- Philadelphia is in Pennsylvania.
Yes, but you see, we have
a California in Pennsylvania...
And an Indiana in Pennsylvania.
I'm not at all surprised.
You have a place in New York
called the Polo Grounds...
And all they do there
is play baseball, and football.
I never saw an elephant
in Piccadilly Circus. Did you?
Well, gentlemen, I think
brandy and cigars are in order.
Creighton,
will you play host in the lounge...
While I have a few words
with Mr Eaton?
I like the way you handle yourself,
young man.
It was a lucky shot.
I was not referring
to your manipulation of a cue stick.
I've made inquiries
about you, Mr Eaton...
And the results
have been most satisfying.
I'm very flattered.
I'm not in the habit...
Of offering positions
with MacHardie and Company...
To men who qualify...
As lifeguards and nothing more.
That seems to make good sense,
Just as a sensible man...
Ought never to accept anything
that life has to offer...
Unless he's absolutely sure
that that's what he wants.
Can a man be that sure of his goals?
I think so.
Tell me yours.
I want to live in a big world...
And compete with big people,
and make big money.
How big is big?
As big as you are, sir.
Certainly far bigger
than my father.
I always wanted
to top my father, too.
It helped me to achieve what I did...
Even if I fell short
by almost 30 million.
I don't intend to fall short.
And preferably not with your present
business associates?
There is such a thing
as information, Mr Eaton.
And you've got it.
How long will it take you
to clean up your affairs?
Two months.
Shall we join the ladies?
At your pleasure.
Yeah.
What?
You're right, Mary. I'm sorry.
I said I'm sorry.
Well, why don't you go on ahead,
then and I'll meet you there.
Yeah. What?
Yeah. Right now. Absolutely.
When will he get
back, does he say?
In time for
Christmas, he hopes.
What's he doing in California?
He's not in California.
That was last year. It's Colorado.
Alright! What's he doing in Colorado?
Buying a copper mine
for Mr MacHardie.
Well, make sure he buys you one, too.
I said how is every little thing
in Baton Rouge, Louisiana?
It is Louisiana, isn't it?
Alfred, you'll have to speak up.
I can't hear you.
Look, why don't you come a little
closer like... New York City?
That's in New York state, remember?
I am not.
I've only had one teeny
little glass of champagne.
Oh, just the usual crowd.
You know, Sage and Steve,
Nancy and Parker Wells and...
Nobody else you know, I don't think.
Yes, dear, I will.
You, too.
Bye-bye.
Tell him we can meet
whenever it's convenient.
- Mr Eaton...
- Yes?
Mr MacHardie wishes
to have lunch with you at 12:00.
Alas I've another engagement.
It is now 3 minutes to 12:00, sir.
All right.
Thank you, sir.
See if you can catch
Mrs Eaton at home...
And if it's too late, just
call the restaurant.
Yes.
You will be there posing
as one of our bond salesmen...
Opening up new territory...
Eyes open, ear to the ground.
Find out all you can about a man
named Ralph W. Benziger.
Benziger.
If we ever make sizable
commitments in that area...
This is the man
we might want to take charge...
Provided his hands are clean.
That's for you to find out.
The color of his hands,
what kind of man he is.
I would like to ask you
a question, sir.
Was it Mr Duffy that suggested me
for this expedition to Mountain City?
In the past, you might have felt...
That Mr Duffy recommended you
for other surveys...
Merely in order to keep you away
from home base for a month a the time.
Perhaps that may have been
in his mind.
Perhaps not, it's of no interest to me.
I am interested only in result.
And I may tell you, young man,
they have been enormously profitable
And largely owing to the shrewdness
of your reports.
Thank you, sir.
Not to go beyond
the walls of this room...
The only gold stars on my son-in-law's
record during that time...
Have been his recommendation
of you for these assignments.
How long will I be gone?
You'll be there
about two months.
- Can I take my wife?
- I prefer not.
I suggest you plan to leave
not later than Friday night.
Friday night?
We just moved into
our New York apartment.
We've got 35 people
coming over on Sunday.
I've never made
any sacrifice for this firm...
That I didn't feel amply repaid.
No dessert for me.
Good luck and good day to you.
Well, good night, Mary.
Thank you, Steve.
Good morning.
So why didn't you meet us?
Didn't you see the note I left?
I got home too late.
I had to finish that Dunham Report.
I suppose I'm supposed to know
what the Dunham Report is.
Oh, just one of the trivial little things
that helps pay to keep you...
Neck and neck with Harper's Bazaar.
Thank you.
Incidentally, just where
did you wear that little number...
Until 2:00 this morning?
I wore this little number
to the Mona Lisa.
Would you unzip me
in the back, please?
I thought Sage
didn't like that place anymore.
Oh, Sage wasn't along.
She stayed home
with a bad tooth or something.
What do you mean, just you
and her husband?
Just little old us.
Can't you do any better than that?
As a matter of fact,
I could have...
But unfortunately he had another date
with the Dingham Report.
Dunham.
Oh, so sorry. Dunham.
Suppose you tell me
what was so important...
That you left me
sitting alone today...
Over a chicken salad sandwich
while you had lunch with MacHardie.
He's giving me a new assignment.
The coal regions of Pennsylvania.
I'd give you the details,
but you're obviously not interested.
I have to leave Friday night.
And what about the
party on Sunday?
I know. I'm sorry.
And just how long do you suppose
you'll be gone this time?
About two months.
And of course I am forbidden to go
with you or to visit you because...
It's not exactly forbidden, but...
The trouble with this company
is it's...
Run by one old man.
I hope you know what
they're doing to us.
What do you want me to do, resign?
Let me tell you one thing.
I'm not going to sit around
and stare at four walls.
You don't have to sit here.
Well, if somebody invites me
to go to the theater...
- I'm going to the theater.
- Go to the theater!
What if it's somebody
you don't know?
A man.
Now look, I don't want you having dates
with guys that I don't know.
Suppose it's somebody
you know and don't like?
For instance?
Jim Roper.
What made you think of him?
Because he's coming to the
party on Sunday.
How did that happen?
I ran into him on Fifth Avenue
and invited him.
In that case,
I'm glad I'm not going to be here.
It's probably just as well you're not
if that's your attitude.
Yeah, it is my attitude.
I'll tell you another thing
that's my attitude...
You're not going out with Jim Roper
and that's final!
- Final?
- Yes! That's final.
Well, I wouldn't be too sure.
You go just right along to Pennsylvania...
And you play with your grimy coal
miners, but don't be too sure.
Anything on that call to New York?
Come in.
Here you are, sir.
Keep trying, will you?
They're celebrating the football game.
No kidding.
They play on Sunday?
Sure. Mountain City
beat the Steamrollers 28 to nothing.
Thanks.
Hey, you're that Providence left end.
I know you.
Nope. Sorry.
You played awful dirty.
You should have been thrown
out of the game.
I was.
No, you weren't, but
you should have been.
You're cute.
Come on in and join us.
I've got a couple of quarts.
I'm in training.
For what?
I'll bet you're married.
You're absolutely right.
- My wife gave a party today.
- She did?
- You know who was there?
- Who?
Not me.
Why don't we stay in here, then?
I bet you won't be sorry...
'Cause when I like a fella...
- I hate to say no to a lady.
- Well, don't say it then.
But you got to beat it.
What do you mean beat it?
I just got in here.
Right, and you just went out.
Well, luck to you, Buckley!
- Hello. Hello, Mary?
- Hello!
I've been calling all evening.
Well, nobody was here.
We all went to dinner
at Michel's after the party.
Who's "we"?
Peg and Bill, Sage and Steve
and Jim Roper and I.
Who brought you home?
Jim.
- How long did he stay?
- About half an hour.
Are you going to see him again?
I don't know... Oh, yes. He'll be
at Peg and Bill's on Friday for dinner.
Then he'll undoubtedly
bring you home.
Possibly. I don't know.
You know what you're doing,
don't you?
Yes. I'm showing you I won't stay
cooped up in this apartment...
While you run off free as a bird
all in the holy name of career.
Now, you listen to me, I don't want
that guy in our apartment anymore.
Either you tell him, or I'll come back
and tell him myself.
Burt he'll have a...
Tough time explaining a busted head
to his patients.
Very well. I'll tell him.
Is that all?
Yeah, that's all.
You're not to come up here anymore.
People don't think this part
of the country as being cold.
We have readings
of 15, 18, 20 degrees below.
You know, I'm glad you came in
to see me today, Mr Eaton.
I'm not always as talkative as this....
But maybe that's because I don't
run across many man like you...
Who are so willing to listen to me...
It's my pleasure, Mr Benziger.
I mean it.
That's mighty nice of you.
Makes me feel kind of poorly...
About not being in the market
for any bonds right now.
I know how it is for a young fellow
like you breaking in a new territory.
We've got our good days
and our bad days.
This happens to be
one of my good ones.
Local folks tell me you've been
making a few inquiries about me.
Yes, sir. A little.
If you heard anything disgraceful,
it's probably true.
You down here all by yourself?
Pretty lonesome town.
My wife's back in New York.
Oh... Taking care of
the kiddies, eh?
No. No kiddies.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Well, put her on.
Hello, Natalie.
Oh, let's see.
In about... 15 minutes.
Yeah, I will.
Oh, hold on a second.
You're all alone.
Why don't you join us for dinner?
We are having steak tonight...
You won't get as good a steak
down at the hotel, I guarantee.
- If that's an invitation, you sold me.
- Good.
Nat?
Tell Mother I'm bringing
a guest for dinner.
I will.
Bye.
Quiet, Rocco, it's all right, yes.
He can be pretty loud at times.
My wife and daughter are here
alone a good deal at night.
- Hello, Dad.
- Hi, Nat.
Natalie, this is Mr Eaton.
How do you do?
Won't you come in?
Oh, Dad.
Like the side of a matchbox.
I can't think why.
I shaved at 5:00 this morning.
I'll take care of those, Mr Eaton.
They usually have a place for them under the
stairs but we're getting new shelves built.
Did you hear that, Dad?
I heard it. I know.
I haven't finished them yet.
This is intended as
the start of a den...
But as you see, it's
as much office as den.
I'll go up and get Mother.
Be down in a minute.
Alright
I'd never seen a mine
before last Monday.
Is this one of yours?
Yes. That's number four.
Dad wanted to call it the Natalie, after me
of course, but he was overruled.
This one's number one.
It's the oldest, but
number four is our pride and joy.
When it was built, it was the most
electrified colliery in the world.
This is my favorite room
in the whole house.
I used to come here
and do my homework.
Especially your arithmetic.
Why do you say that?
So your father could help you.
No. I was very good in arithmetic...
But he did help me
with everything else.
And he'll be here in a second
and help you with a drink.
I'm in no hurry for one.
- Tell me something.
- Yes?
How does it feel
to be someone like you...
Blooming in a coal
town like this?
Do you really want to know?
Well, I love it here.
When the mountains are
covered with laurel or snow...
There's something
so beautiful about them.
And the people, too.
The miners.
The old ones, not the young.
I've been in so many of their homes.
Not much time left to them.
Not much to show
for working hard all their lives...
Yet they have such
dignity and wisdom...
Sorrow and pride.
Oh, Mother, this is Mr Eaton.
Good evening, Mr Eaton.
It's very nice of you to come.
Very kind of you to have me.
What is everyone standing around for?
Let's have a drink.
- Nothing for me, dear.
- Nor me, Dad.
What's the matter with you people?
Mr Eaton?
- Straight scotch is fine.
- That's my boy.
Only one drink now.
We don't want our steak ruined.
Welcome to our city.
Welcome to our home.
And all that's beautiful in it.
I guess we live closer
to basic instincts here...
Than some other regions
I could name.
These miners
are a pretty hard-bitten lot.
Sometimes they start home
a little drunk...
Fall down an air shaft,
get bitten by a rattlesnake,
Drown in a dam.
Yet I have to say
I can't blame the men...
Goodness, I had no idea.
Well, I can finish this tomorrow.
- Coming to bed?
- Maybe I'm a softie...
Baby the men too much, but...
- Good night, Mr Eaton.
- Good night. Thank you very much.
We enjoyed having you.
I guess I might as well
say good night, too.
Nat, would you keep
Mr Eaton company for a minute?
Mother has a heart condition.
She never stays up later than 10:00.
What do you do with your time?
Or do you... Have
a heart condition, too?
No, I have no particular
heart condition...
Of either kind.
I do some welfare work, digging the garden,
go to the movies...
The usual.
Would you go to the movies
with me sometime?
No.
'Cause I'm married?
That's a pretty good reason, isn't it?
At least in Mountain City.
And how about going to the movies
with me in Philadelphia?
Mr Eaton,
you probably have a very nice wife.
I suppose you're angry
because I asked you.
- No. I consider it a compliment.
- I hope you do.
You're the first person I've asked
out since I've been married.
- Thank you.
- There's some other things...
I really don't want to encourage
this conversation.
- Mother all right, Dad?
- Oh, yes.
I had some things to tell her.
I won't be seeing her in the morning.
I guess I'll be wandering along.
Natalie's having some people
for dinner Saturday.
It'd be nice if you came, too.
Dad, I don't think Mr Eaton
would really enjoy himself.
It's just our bridge club.
I'll take a rain check.
Some other time.
I think that would be better.
All right, but we do hope you'll
come back for dinner some time.
- Good night.
- Good night, sir.
Hello.
Natalie?
I was just thinking about you.
What were you thinking?
I'm glad you did the right thing.
You said no and...
Turned me out into the cold
and lonely night.
Don't.
You saved me
from making a big mistake.
Maybe it was...
I who made the mistake.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
I'm not sure. Are you?
No.
There's a drive-in movie
just outside of town.
The last show starts at 9:30.
Yes?
Tomorrow night?
Tomorrow night.
The last row of cars.
A yellow Plymouth convertible...
Slightly covered with coal dust.
We're probably making a big mistake.
You know that, don't you?
Yes.
I know.
Good night.
- Hello.
I guess we're the only two people
watching the movie.
- You know something?
- What?
I don't even know your first name.
Actually, it's David.
David Alfred Eaton.
See, I liked David,
and my father liked Alfred...
So it was Alfred.
May I call you David?
If you like.
Do you believe in love
at first sight?
No.
Neither do I.
I believe in confusion.
Yes.
A man walks around in a desert...
All his life looking for water.
All he ever finds is sand.
I didn't know you were
lost in the desert.
I didn't know it either
until last night.
I walked into a house
where there was warmth...
That didn't come from radiators.
I saw your mother and father,
and I saw you.
You're lonely.
You're away from home, that's all.
No. In one evening...
My whole life seemed to change.
I know it sounds ridiculous...
But you made me feel so I'd been
cheated out of something all my life.
It's funny...
That movie out there doesn't seem
so bad with the sound turned off.
In other words,
you'd like me to shut up.
No. I'd like you to do
much more than that.
Now you've got me
lost in the desert.
I guess we're all out here...
Searching.
Even your wife?
I didn't sleep very well
last night after I left you...
And now many things
seem clearer to me.
I don't know if you're
still in love with your wife...
But I do know that you haven't
given up on your marriage.
I know if we stop now,
we'll never do injury to anyone...
Except possibly ourselves.
I want to say goodbye...
But not in a letter.
So I'll have to see you...
One last time.
- Sure it's all right?
- What?
Oh, I don't know. Our cars
being parked so close together?
Nobody uses this road.
In fact, nobody knows this place
except wild rabbits and squirrels...
Chipmunks and field mice...
And birds and butterflies and...
- Falling leaves.
- Which one of those are you?
I don't know.
A squirrel, perhaps, or...
Maybe just a coward.
I saved your letter.
You know, I realize
something now, David.
What?
It was the proper way
to say goodbye.
- The only way.
- Natalie.
- Yes?
- Look at me.
You know something?
Even if we never
see each other again...
Something very good
has happened...
'Cause you'll know
for the rest of your life...
Just the sight of you...
Just the...
Just the sound of your voice...
Created a...
Feeling in me that was
so strong that I...
That I couldn't treat it
as polite conversation...
Or with silence.
And I...
I'll always remember...
A sad...
Lonely...
Searching young man...
Who passed through my life
for a brief moment.
And I loved his sadness...
His loneliness...
His searching.
Please don't.
Well, I'll make it easier.
I'm leaving here. I'm going back
to New York tonight.
In three weeks up here I...
Accomplished all I set out to...
More than I intended.
Will we be writing to each other?
What do you think?
No.
Of course not.
Welcome back.
- I ordered for both of us.
- Fine.
I haven't studied your report,
but I did glance through it briefly.
And its thoroughness convinced me...
That I've no reason to be displeased
with you for coming back so soon.
You did all that was expected of you.
I'm glad you agreed about Benziger.
Fine man.
However, that's not
what I wanted to talk about.
We don't want to be disturbed.
I'll get right to the point.
Have you seen your wife yet?
Or did you come here directly
from Mountain City?
Mary? No.
I got home last night.
She was still out on Long Island...
And she hadn't returned when
I left this morning. Why?
May I assume you're aware
of trouble in your home?
Would you care to be more specific?
Well, now, you see...
Our Mr Hasbrouck...
Who, as you know, has nothing
but the highest regard for you
Happens to live in Westport,
Connecticut.
And so it was inevitable...
He should hear about your wife's
presence at the home of a neighbor...
A certain Mr and Mrs Joseph Cash.
- Cash? I don't know them.
- No, you don't.
But Dr. James Roper does...
And it was there that he spent last
weekend, with your wife...
After the Princeton-Yale
football game.
You have my word for it,
or Mr Hasbrouck's word...
That that particular
host and hostess...
Make a practice of having
a houseful of guests every weekend...
The attraction being
that there'll be no checking...
On who sleeps in which room.
Aren't you jumping to conclusions?
I can assure you that
Mr Hasbrouck made quite certain...
That your wife's affair
was an open secret...
Before he invited
Eugene St. John to lunch.
Eugene St. John?
Their talk was most informal.
St. John agreed
to take no action right now...
But he promised to speak
to his daughter
If and when you decided it was
either necessary or advisable...
And that is where the matter stands.
That's not where the matter stands
where I'm concerned.
I don't think it's any of this firm's
damn business what my wife does.
And I'm surprised that Mr St. John didn't
tell Percy Hasbrouck to go to the devil.
He probably realized that what's
good for your promising future...
Is also good for his daughter's.
If there's anything that he,
or I, or anyone else can do...
To save your marriage
he's for it.
What if I don't want
to save my marriage?
Then we've failed.
Then you have failed, Eaton.
Divorce is a damnable thing.
It violates good order.
It's a threat to good order.
Isn't it just possible that infidelity
might be ground for a divorce?
There are no grounds
for divorce.
And if you want my personal theology...
Infidelity is the lesser sin.
I'd do anything in my power
to prevent a divorce.
Including condoning infidelity?
I consider your word
"condone" disrespectful.
I condone none of it.
The problem of infidelity...
Is between husband,
and wife, and God.
The problem of divorce
concerns the whole of civilization.
What is marriage?
An exchange of vows, a contract.
It is my duty to myself
and to any man working for me...
To demand that he honor
all his contracts.
When you came here you found out
we always honor our word...
Even if it means taking a loss.
This is the first
opportunity you've had...
Of putting yourself to our test.
And if I don't choose
to meet your test?
You've worked
hard and well, Eaton.
You have a fine,
hard-earned record with us.
You can't afford
to throw that away.
With all due respect, sir,
I can afford to do as I please.
And I say with all due respect...
That you can afford
nothing of the kind.
I wasn't going to tell you this.
I didn't want it to form
part of your decision...
But I like you, Eaton,
and I don't want to lose you.
And only you and I will know that
I mentioned it to you at this early date.
Mentioned what?
The roll-top desk.
The partnership.
I've had discussions
with the board...
And it's only a question of time...
And much less now
than you might suppose.
Stay where you are, son.
You've a lot of thinking to do.
But don't do it all now.
You've had a bad time.
Well, you're back.
- Was the trip successful?
- Yeah.
Are you back for good
or is this just a visit?
For good.
Finished up sooner
than you expected?
Sooner than you expected, too.
Now that I'm back you'll have to
start behaving yourself.
Did you say start?
I know all about you
and Roper at the Cashes'.
I could subpoena everybody
that was up there...
And divorce you in New York State,
right now if I wanted to.
But you won't because Mr MacHardie
wouldn't like that.
You think you're pretty
clever, don't you?
But you're not as clever
as you think you are.
Flaunting your affair publicly.
And I don't like a wife thumbing her nose at
me and thinking she can get away with it.
And I don't like having a husband
who isn't a husband.
And what do you
think you're doing?
What does it look like I'm doing?
What do you expect me to do,
enter a convent?
And what about you?
I'm sure you'll find yourself
a woman, if you haven't already.
You just better be careful.
You'd better be able to explain
every minute of your time, day and night.
Or you'll do what?
I'll put you where you're
so afraid of landing...
In the tabloids, page one, two,
or three. Take your choice!
I know why you're
doing this to me!
It's not our marriage
you're trying to hold together.
It's your own sick dream
of 5 million before you're 40!
Be the big man,
bigger than your father!
Mr Eaton, will you go directly into
the partners' room, please?
Mr Duffy, please go directly
into the partners' room.
Creighton, come in.
Alfred, come in and sit down.
Now, we've been having a go at the Nassau
Aeronautical Corporation's proposal...
And we've been taking
under consideration...
Nassau's request that we underwrite
a common-stock issue...
To finance a plant expansion.
Nassau obviously wants to expand...
Because they expect
to land a sizable contract...
To manufacture their new
E1-FX plane for the Navy...
And it behooves us
to look into this E1-FX...
To see how good an aircraft it is...
Before we commit MacHardie
and Company to getting involved.
Sir, isn't the United States Navy's
interest in the planes...
Sufficient endorsement for us?
Ordinarily it should be,
but in this case...
My sixth sense tells me
that we ought at least to conduct...
A routine investigation of the E1-FX
before under writing the venture...
Particularly as we have on our team
a man so well qualified to do it.
Alfred, you're not only a personal
friend of Alexander Porter...
But you were yourself associated
with NAC...
In the days before it
rose to prominence...
In the aircraft
manufacturing field.
Some people seem to think that
my departure from Nassau...
Marked the beginning of its rise.
Wouldn't we be placing Mr Eaton
in a rather embarrassing position...
By asking him to attempt
to exercise impartial judgment...
Where his close friend
Mr Porter is concerned?
And who would you recommend
for the job, Creighton?
Well, sir, in as much as
I brought this venture...
To the firm's attention
and in as much as I'm familiar...
With all of its ramifications...
I have every confidence
in Mr Eaton's judgment and loyalty.
Alfred, how long will it take you
to get this underway?
By a fortunate coincidence,
Mrs Eaton and I...
Will be at Mr Porter's table
at a charity ball this Saturday night.
There's no rule that says that a man can't
take advantage of his host...
Is there?
I'd like to be able to say I'm close
to everything that goes on at Nassau,
But why give it all away?
I'm just the titular head,
if you'll pardon the expression.
Thanks to Uncle Fritz' money...
I reap the dividends,
the profits, and the credit.
Yes, thanks.
Von Elm's the real brains. He'll give
you all the facts you need.
You set it up with him?
I'll see you get the run of the place.
Thanks.
Can I ask you a corny question?
If you don't mind me giving
a corny answer.
Are you getting anything out
of your success besides more success?
Why don't you say what you mean?
- All right. Let's talk about Mary.
- Nothing to talk about.
Things any better?
They're not any worse.
They'll never get any better.
- I'm not interested.
- Am I not good enough for you?
That's one way of putting it.
You won't be the first dissatisfied
wife I've made happy.
I'd like to go back to the table,
if you don't....
He doesn't even know
you're alive...
What kind of perfume
you're wearing, or...
How gorgeous you are.
This is not a secret,
Everyone knows it. So do you.
Wont you let go of me, please.
Don't throw an act on me.
I know all about you.
Do you?
Alfred, would you take me home,
please?
Why, I thought you were
having a merry old time.
- Good night Lex. It was delightful.
- Good night, princess.
- You were a charming host.
- But corny?
- Get my car, please.
- Yes, sir.
- Hello, Natalie.
- Hello.
It's nice to see you again.
Do you know my wife Mary?
Natalie Benziger.
- How do you do, Mrs Eaton?
- Hello, Miss Benziger.
What brings you to New York?
A little shopping expedition.
Are you here at the hotel
with your mother?
No. With a friend, Mrs English.
Caroline English.
- How's your father?
- He's fine, thank you.
Where did you two know each other
in Philadelphia?
Oh no, I tried to sell
Natalie's father some bonds...
That time when I was
down in Mountain City.
In Pennsylvania, remember?
Yes, I remember.
Well, good night, Mrs Eaton.
It's very nice meeting you.
- Good night, Natalie.
- Good night.
Well...
And what does she call you?
Miss... Benziger.
She calls me Mrs Eaton...
You call her Natalie...
But she doesn't
call you anything.
Aren't you Mr Eaton or Alfred?
As a matter of fact,
I'm Calvin Coolidge...
But she doesn't know that.
She's really quite lovely, you know.
And you know me. I like men.
So I'm told.
When she's that lovely,
I find it hard to hate her.
- I think you were lucky.
- I was?
Yes.
She has something I haven't got...
Niceness.
But then I have something
she hasn't got.
Me?
No.
Honesty and guts.
She has no guts.
What are you doing?
Don't worry. I'm not calling
your girl friend. I don't have to.
Dr Roper, please.
Hello, Jim?
Remember me?
Exactly.
Look,
why don't we have dinner sometime?
Tomorrow night?
Aren't I, though?
Fine. I'll meet you at your place.
Marvelous.
Any objections?
I have no facts and no evidence...
So this is what I'm going to do.
It's all I can do for now.
Just like that?
Yes, just like that.
I let you talk to foremen, designers,
mechanics, public relations men.
Everybody but the test pilot.
I'm sure
they told you everything they know.
They were instructed
to be cooperative.
I'll bet they were.
Everybody's been very helpful.
E1-FX is the greatest plane
to ever sprout wings.
I don't know, maybe it can fly, too.
What am I supposed
to say to that?
I don't want you
to say anything, Van Helm.
But before I go back to Wall Street
and report the failure of a mission...
I'll give you exactly one hour
to produce this test pilot...
That's been so mysteriously busy,
alas, this last three days.
Suppose I can't find him.
Then you're in the wrong business.
And don't think that won't
be in my report, too.
Wait a minute.
- Get Kelly In here.
- Yes, sir.
You know, if somebody like me
didn't know you as well as I do...
They might jump to conclusions
and figure you to walk in here...
with a whole set of prejudices
against us.
After all you left this company
when it was nothing...
Because you thought
it would always be nothing.
I'm glad I'm known so well
by somebody like you.
Come in.
- You sent for me, sir?
- Yes.
This is Jerry Kelly, our test pilot.
Mr Eaton.
- Glad to know you.
- Sit down Kelly!
No, I think Mr Kelly and I
can go for a little walk.
- What do you mean, a walk?
- You know!
That's when you put one foot
in front of the other.
All the time we've wasted.
I'll make it up to you.
I intend to make you do that.
Every time I'm with you this way
I get the strangest feeling.
Well, I'm a strange man.
Are you?
And you're a strange woman.
How am I strange?
- Haven't you discovered that yet?
- No.
Well, I'll let you find out.
Jim.
Do you love me?
Love you?
Honey, I adore you...
But I don't believe in love
any more than you do.
I believe in you wanting me
and me wanting you.
That's what brings you here...
And that's what will keep
us together.
Then I don't suppose
there's any...
Sense...
In us talking about marriage...
Or even thinking about it.
Look, let's have no more talk about
love or eternal devotion...
Shall we?
Jim!
Want me.
Please want me.
Oh, David...
The first real thing
in a whole long year.
I had to see you again.
This is really why
I came to New York.
Well, I'm glad you did.
I've been wondering...
Wondering about so many things.
- You have?
- Yes.
Your wife, she's...
Lovelier than I thought she'd be.
And you're still with her,
aren't you?
We live under the same roof.
That's all.
David...
Is there someplace we can go?
So there it is.
Or there it was.
I could have
divorced her for it.
I could have, but I didn't...
Because it would have meant
damaging my career.
God help me.
My career seems
to be more important...
Than I ever thought it could be.
I put you out of my mind...
And buried myself in my work...
Even deeper than before.
But... I guess it never
really worked...
Because whenever
I thought of you, it was...
It was always with love.
Then the other night...
The moment I saw you...
It was like seeing you
that very first time.
But I felt real danger
for both of us.
You see, that's why...
I wish I'd had the courage
not to phone you.
So be careful, Natalie,
I have nothing to offer you...
Except pain, deep, tender,
loving pain...
And I don't want to hurt you.
You understand what
I'm trying to say?
Yes, I do.
If you had any sense
you'd get up from the table...
And never see me again.
Do you want me to?
Oh, David.
I can't bear being with you
any longer...
Just talking.
- Is there someplace we can go?
- No, Natalie.
A hotel?
You wouldn't like that.
No.
Neither would you.
But arrange it, darling, please.
Busy, busy, busy.
How's the Nassau Investigation going?
Don't you want to wait
for my report?
Only if I have to.
Don't worry. You'll get
the whole story tomorrow.
I hear you had a talk with their
test pilot, a fellow named Kelly?
That's right.
You know, you saved
my son's life once.
Who knows, you might want to do the same
for the boy's old man some day.
Creighton, you skate on thin ice,
you're going to get your feet wet.
Weren't you skating
on thin ice last night...
Making love in public
to a young lady...
Who bears no resemblance
to your wife?
You should be more careful, Alfred.
Now, wait a minute.
Let's be a little realistic.
You and I may want to do
each other a big favor.
You can do me a favor right now,
just by getting out of the way.
Now, you know as well as I do...
That Mr MacHardie
has some hidebound notions...
About improper behavior
around here... Scandal!
You mean like the
improper way...
You tried to turn the Nassau deal
into your own private gain?
I got proof...
And I plan to put it in front of
the board at tomorrows meeting.
Oh, you wouldn't do that...
Because if you do,
you go with me.
You and your plaything.
Why don't you go
jump in the lake?
Oh no, that's your specialty!
That's how you got
into this company in the first place.
Sir...
Could I interest you in a set
of the Encyclopedia Britannica?
Step right this way, young lady
and we will discuss the matter.
Thank you.
Oh, darling, hold on to me.
Don't let me run away.
I almost didn't come.
I turned back twice.
You know, we don't have to stay here.
We could go for a walk
or out for dinner, go to the mov...
Champagne?
Come here.
Look.
It's lovely.
You know, I think I'm going
to remember this night for all time.
And someday, when we finally part...
I'll go to Spain
and live with my memories.
As soon as I see you
getting tired of me.
You'll be too old to travel
when that happens.
I love you.
More than I ever thought
I could love anybody.
And I love you, David.
- Message from Mr Duffy.
- Get out!
- Get more of the girl.
- I got plenty of her.
Let's get out of here.
Come on, let's go!
Why do I feel this...
This kind of death?
Of what?
I don't know.
You were just thinking of what
your mother and father would feel...
If they saw one of those
photographs of us.
I wasn't thinking that,
and I won't let you.
Can't keep it out
of your mind forever.
Unless I play ball
with Duffy tomorrow...
You're going to be undressed
in public...
Smeared all over the newspapers.
I don't care.
You got to believe that.
I knew what I was doing....
And I've got to accept the consequences,
whatever they are.
Well, I won't let them
do it to you.
Not to me.
If you're going to let that man
blackmail you...
it's to protect your career.
Everything you've worked for,
not me.
You see?
That's the death I feel.
There will always be that uncertainty
for you, won't there?
Why you did it, for whom.
I don't think
I could live with that.
Is there somewhere we
can end this kind of talk?
You're very close to saying
final things, Natalie.
Maybe they have to be said.
Maybe there never really
was any future for us...
And it took your friend Mr Duffy
to wake us up from the dream.
You know what you're doing,
don't you?
Sending me back to Mary
and yourself back to Mountain City.
Is that what you want?
Well, if it is, why don't you say so?
Because the moment I do...
I'll feel that my life is over.
You're trying to force me
to say it, then.
I guess maybe I am.
All right, then...
If that's the way you want it.
Goodbye, Natalie.
Goodbye.
Is something wrong?
Anything you want to unload?
The least I can do is listen.
You know something, Alfred?
You and I could have
such a pleasant relationship...
If you'd just unbend a little.
What kind of relation ship?
Whatever we like,
whenever we like it, silly.
Of course I know there's...
No love lost between us, but...
If you'd just stop playing
the role of the aggrieved husband...
We might have the same
enjoyable relationship...
That a lot of our
married friends have.
Well, I've seen you look at me when
I knew you wanted me...
And I certainly wanted you.
And you just turned around
and walked back in your own bedroom.
I always thought, He's such a fool...
Such a waste.
Now, wouldn't it be nicer if
we were friends this way?
Shut up.
You look like an old man
tonight, Alfred.
What's the matter, your girl friend
giving you trouble?
I don't want to talk about it.
I hope you haven't been
stringing her along...
And telling her you
were going to get a divorce.
Knowing women, I'm sure
she kept hoping you would.
And now she's angry
because you won't.
I always knew she had no guts.
Well, am I wrong?
Is your girlfriend holding out
on you and demanding marriage?
Mary, please.
Well, if it'll do you any good
you can tell her...
It's not just your boss-man Mr MacHardie
who's standing in your way.
You can tell her that
you also have a wife...
Who happens to like
her marital arrangement...
And doesn't intend to change it.
Why not?
It gives me status, security
and a wonderful kind of freedom.
Well, why are you staring at me?
When I think...
Of the misery that we've
brought each other...
The wasted years,
betrayals, humiliations...
I'm not blaming you for it.
I guess I did as much
as you did...
To destroy whatever we had
between us, but it's gone now.
It's beyond recovery, dead.
That's all right.
We don't need it.
As a matter of fact...
Maybe it would be more
interesting without it.
I'm going to bed now, Alfred.
I'm really not that bad, remember?
- Mr Eaton?
- Yeah.
Sign here, please.
Thank you.
"All I ask is your friendship
at the meeting tomorrow. Creighton"
Before we hear Mr Eaton's report...
On the Nassau Aeronautical
Corporation situation...
I have a few words to say...
Of a very happy nature.
All right, Henry.
I know you'll forgive me for breaking
one of our more tire some traditions...
If I decorate this stale
but profitable room today...
With the presence
of an attractive young lady.
Gentlemen...
Mrs Alfred Eaton.
How do you do?
Right over there, Mary.
Mrs Eaton was let into our little
secret, several days ago...
And if I may judge by the look
of surprise on her husband's face...
She's kept her secret
better than most women...
Are considered capable of doing.
And now, Alfred, I come to something
which is no secret...
And that is the high esteem
in which you are held by this firm.
I speak not only for myself,
but for all my partners.
You have dedicated yourself
to your work...
With a devotion that might serve
as an example to all young men...
Who aspire to success.
You have sacrificed your own
pleasures and pastimes for us.
You have traveled all over
the country for us.
You've sat at your desk until 3:00
and 4:00 in the morning for us.
And time and again you have executed
difficult assignments...
With more boldness and courage
than we had any right to expect.
Not only that.
And this is especially important.
You have made us proud
of your performance...
In the private walks
of your life as well.
I think you know
what I mean now.
There you have
conducted yourself...
With a wisdom, maturity, good taste...
And a fine sense of responsibility
to your business position.
And in a few moments I think
you'll see why it was worth it.
It's now time to be specific.
As long we were all going
to be assembled here today...
I thought this would be
the proper occasion...
To tell you before you read about
it in the Wall Street Journal...
That you have just become
the first man...
On the sunny side of 40...
Ever to be made a full partner
of MacHardie and Company.
Congratulations, Alfred.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations, Alfred.
- Congratulations.
Congratulations, Mrs Eaton.
Congratulations.
Now, then...
Mr MacHardie...
Gentlemen, I...
I am deeply honored.
I'm flattered by...
Your generous bestowal
of a partnership...
'Cause this is a day...
That I have been working toward...
With every fiber of my being.
For like all...
Well-brought-up American males
I have always been aware of the fact...
That nothing
is more important in life...
Than the attaining of wealth...
And high position.
And I can honestly say that I never
allowed anything to sway me...
From my goal of achieving it.
When business called...
I never let personal responsibilities
stand in the way.
If anything ever threatened
to interfere...
With the affairs
of MacHardie and Company...
I always knew...
That there would only be one choice...
And I invariably made it.
Because I have truly learned, gentlemen...
As Mr MacHardie
so gracefully put it...
That it does take wisdom...
Maturity...
Good taste...
And a fine sense of responsibility
to one's business position...
If one is to get ahead
in this world.
Some men think
in very small terms, gentlemen.
If they find themselves
married to a woman...
Who has been unfaithful to them...
They dissolve the marriage just as
if they owed no responsibility...
To the... Business firm
for which they worked.
And if they find genuine happiness
with another woman...
They embrace it...
As if they had...
No consideration...
Of their business colleagues.
These men do not become
successful, gentlemen.
They do not become full partners
at MacHardie and Company.
They become abject failures.
They take their place alongside
the millions of...
Mediocrities who value...
A houseful of kids...
A host of friends...
Photograph albums filled
with trivial memories...
Above all the truly
important considerations...
Of this world.
With all due modesty, gentlemen...
I feel that I have earned
the position you have given me today.
No one here deserves it
more truly than I.
- Just one second...
- I'm not through yet.
My first act as a partner
will be... To deliver my report...
On the Nassau
Aeronautical situation.
And after you've read about it...
I'm sure that...
My friend Mr Duffy there...
Will want to issue another
report on another subject...
Namely, the newest partner
of MacHardie and Company...
The newest and possibly
the shortest-lived.
And now gentlemen,
if you will excuse me...
I have other less important
business to attend to.
Sorry.
- What is the meaning of this?
- What's the matter with him?
Alfred!
I know you've come to congratulate me.
Thank you very much my dear.
- You're making a fool of yourself.
- That was terribly...
Considerate of you last night
when you were telling me...
About the
"beautiful relationship we could have"...
But you never mentioned
the partnership.
Because maybe I would've thought...
That the partnership had something
to do with your new-found...
If somewhat unwholesome
interest in our marriage.
Alfred.
Alfred, I want to talk to you.
Any further communication
between you and me...
Will be through legal channels.
Alfred!
Alright go ahead and go to her,
but it won't do you any good.
If she's foolish enough
to still have me...
Nothing will stop me from spending
the rest of my life with her.
- I'll never give you a divorce.
- No you won't, ah?
Wait till you see the photographs...
That our friend Creighton Duffy is gonna
let loose for public consumption.
What photographs?
You won't be able to show
your face in this entire city...
If you don't give me a divorce.
How do you like them apples?
Alfred!