(wind howling)
(rumbling)
(screeching)
(rock music playing)
I don't see her.
The shift changes.
Just give it a couple of minutes.
You guys sure about this?
Yeah yeah, works all the time.
Besides, this lady loves Lynch.
- Loves him.
- I'm cute.
(chuckles)
(sighs)
Is that...
is that her?
Shit.
Parker, what you could do
is go down there and look beautiful
and smile.
- What? Me?
- Yeah.
Uh, no.
No no, this is your thing.
All you have to do is go
over there and say, like,
"Hey, me and my friends..."
Girlfriends.
Say girlfriends.
"Me and my girlfriends totally
forgot our credit cards"
so we can't get our lift tickets
from over there.
- So can you, like, help us out?"
- That is so lame.
- Give me my money back.
- Your money.
- It's not gonna work.
- Take this. Start at 50.
That's what the other
lady usually takes.
And just, you know,
work your way up if you need to.
- Dan...
- Hey, look at me. Look at me.
You're gonna be fine.
You'll be great.
Parker, you've so got this.
Yeah, and what's the worst
that can happen?
The guy says no.
And he's not gonna say no.
No one's ever said no.
Dan, you do it.
I feel stupid.
Relax, okay?
I promise, you're gonna be great.
- Why me?
- That's 'cause you're a girl.
A beautiful...
hey, you're a beautiful girl.
And you have a charming smile.
Just...
There we go.
That's great.
Go get him.
- Get in the game.
- Okay.
Come on.
Woman on P. A: Attention all skiers.
The Black Dog Trail is now open.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Hey.
Can I bum a smoke?
(clanging)
- I'm Parker.
- Jason.
Oh cool.
My brother's name is Jason.
That's awesome.
Yeah, so I don't want to waste
your time or anything
because you seem like
a wicked busy guy and everything.
This is gonna sound really stupid.
It's just that my girlfriends and I
came all the way up
from Salem State.
I was kind of the dumbass
who said that I could pay
for all three of the tickets
on my mom's credit card.
And then I left her credit card
at the gas station.
- Right.
- No, I mean...
I totally have money.
Just not enough for all three,
you know?
- How much?
- 50?
I could lose my job.
No no, he's not going for it.
Yes he will.
Just shut up, please.
I mean he's either gonna do that job for...
What do you call it, minimal?
- Minimum.
- Minimum wage,
or he's gonna do it for minimum wage
plus a little bit.
I mean, I know what I'd do.
She just had to come
skiing today, huh?
You said you wouldn't mind.
I don't. I don't mind.
I don't mind at all.
I'm just saying we haven't seen you
at Fezzywigs for a $1 pitcher
since last semester and you don't
show up for Monday Night Football.
I watched football
at your house last week.
Dan, 10 minutes. Football games
are more than 10 minutes.
They're like lots of 10 minuteses,
you know?
I have a girlfriend now.
I don't know what you want
me to do about it.
- I'm sorry.
- You know what? It's fine.
I'm... I'm just just saying that
Mt. Holliston was kind of our thing.
And she can't even ride
so it's a little weird.
- She's getting better.
- Yeah yeah.
(laughs)
Now I feel like a dick.
I mean, if you had a problem with this,
you've got to say something.
No no, it's not a problem.
Just forget I said anything.
I'm sorry.
Woman on P. A:
Attention all skiers.
Mt. Holliston will be open
next Friday through Sunday.
Get your tickets now
to avoid waiting in line.
(laughs)
Okay.
I think you did great.
I'm proud of you, Parker.
- I did good, right?
- You did well.
So where's my change?
Um, there isn't any.
You just gave him the full 100?
Well, yeah.
He wasn't gonna do it for 50.
Okay, so what happened to
the numbers between 50 and 100?
Like, say, 51
or 75 even?
Dan, you gave me two 50s.
Was I supposed to ask for change?
I would have asked for change.
I mean, it's still way cheaper
than paying for tickets, right?
I definitely would have
asked for change.
Hey.
Girlfriends?
What's up?
Look at these chumps paying
top dollar for their lift tickets.
- Whoo-hoo!
- Not us, though.
Thanks to you, babe.
Oh, now I'm babe.
You never call me pet names.
- I'm not a pet name guy.
- Hmm.
He calls me Parker.
- That's your name.
- I know.
But you're supposed to
call me something affectionate
like honey or sweetie.
You know, I hooked up
with a girl last semester
that called me my last name in bed.
It was weird.
She was all like, "Oh, Lynch,
your hair's so soft.
Do me harder, Lynch."
It was like throwing it to Dan over here.
Yeah, I could call you O'Neil.
(laughs)
You don't touch
my face enough either.
Third wheel.
- Watch it, Lynch.
- Hey, I'm not dating you.
You don't get to make my life suck.
- Whoa! No no no.
- Whoa.
No one ever said anything
about you making my life suck.
- Uh-huh.
- Sweetie.
Aw.
So Dan tells me you're getting
a little better on that board.
Well, I don't know about that.
Last time I did pretty good, didn't I?
Yeah.
Yeah, you're getting better.
You fall on your ass snowboarding.
The first few times
you fall on your ass.
After that it's easy.
It's like riding a bike.
Just tell me, when are you gonna
get rid of those goddamn skis?
- Come on.
- What?
I mean, snowboards are just
too emo for me.
Those things are a fad.
In 10 years they'll be gone.
Yeah, that's what they said about rap.
That's true.
(inhales)
Can you guys smell
that fresh mountain air?
It smells a bit like...
Cancer.
You know what?
I am so sick of potheads
giving me shit about smoking butts.
- At least pot does something for you.
- Oh.
Yes, cigarettes are just gross,
especially in the cold.
They stick to you.
You smell like
an ashtray,
an old man's used floss.
Old man's... where the hell do you
come up with this stuff?
Okay, have you ever
smelled your floss?
No, I have never
smelled my own floss.
- Never. Not once.
- Well, it's nasty. It is nasty.
- Why am I friends with you?
- I don't know.
Here, give me a drag.
Do you guys know
when we're gonna get back?
'Cause I've got like two weeks
worth of chapters to read.
Oh come on.
She broke the first rule.
- Parker, you broke the first rule.
- What?
You can't talk about real life shit
while we're up here.
The whole point of being here
is to forget about all that shit,
- relax, enjoy ourselves.
- Okay.
Deal with that shit
when you get home.
- Okay, but I've got...
- (Cables creaking)
(skiers shouting, groaning)
Okay, what asshole couldn't
get on the chair right?
- What the hell, right?
- Dude.
Oh, that's good.
Yell more.
- Hello!
- Man: Having fun up there?
Parker, it's okay.
(laughs)
Is someone afraid of heights?
- No.
- No?
So it doesn't bother you
when I do this?
- Quit it!
- Don't be an asshole.
- (laughs)
- Stop.
Sorry.
Honey, crazy thing.
Only one of these things
has ever fallen off
a chairlift thing before.
Okay,
points for calling me honey.
But you just made that statistic up.
Yeah, and statistics don't work
on smokers.
Come on, man.
We paid good money to ride.
Let's go!
Actually, I paid good money.
Actually, I'm gonna pay you back,
so it's like the same thing.
- Okay.
- What, do you want it now?
- (Lift clangs)
All right, that's what I'm talking about.
Whoo!
You guys ready?
- Why do I have to wear a helmet?
- Safety first.
But you guys aren't wearing helmets.
Only kids wear helmets.
That's 'cause they're still learning,
like you.
Here, I'm not arguing about this.
Just put it on. Here.
No, Dan, I don't want...
Look, even the pro guys wear helmets.
Nobody makes fun of them.
Aw.
You guys are just doing this
to make fun of me.
Dan:
No, huh-uh.
Parker:
Oh yeah, sure.
No, I think chicks in helmets are hot.
- Right?
- Yeah.
- Need a little help?
- You think?
Yeah, looks like your bindings
are a little loose.
Come on, I'll get you up.
Come on.
There you go.
I'll just tighten these up for you.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Aw.
Look at Lynch.
Yeah, look at him.
He's a chick magnet.
- These all right?
- Yeah, that's a lot better.
- What the hell are you doing, man?
- Lynch: What's your problem?
- I'm trying to help her.
- Ryan!
- He had his hands all over you.
- No he didn't. I can take care of myself.
Just go, okay?
I'll be there in a second.
I am so sorry about that.
He can be such an asshole sometimes.
I was seriously just trying to help.
I mean, I don't know if I can compete
with a catch like that.
(laughs)
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Well, thank you for your help.
I'm really sorry about that.
- I'm Shannon, by the way.
- Joe.
Shannon, come on.
(sighs)
Well, it was really nice to meet you.
- Yeah, you too.
- I've got to go.
- Good luck with that.
- Yeah.
I was like a second away
from kicking that guy's ass.
Yeah, I know you were, Lynch.
Don't worry about it.
He's a douchebag.
Seriously, that guy was such a dick.
Why don't we talk about how tough
you guys are at the bottom?
I'm tough.
I know you are, baby.
Come here.
Whoo!
♫ How can you say there are no answers
to my questions? ♫
♫ You just called once
to let it go ♫
♫ How can you say that none
of this is really worth it ♫
♫ When we've already won? ♫
♫ When we've already won. ♫
What?
(sighs)
Oh, she told you that?
Yeah, we'll go to Okemo, Killington.
We'll just go up north.
- We'll get away for a while.
- Let's do it.
- Christmas, you and me.
- Deal.
Listen, it's not like out West where,
you know, it's like a commercial.
You've got to ride three lifts to get to
the top, it's like perfect powder.
Let's be honest,
it's not gonna be like that.
Yeah, well, speaking of good skiing,
riding the bunny hill
has been fun all day,
but, you know, I think I'd like to do
an actual run before we leave tonight.
Look, if you want to go off on your own,
you don't have to hang out with us all day.
No no, it's fine. I'm just saying
I'd like to step it up at some point.
You know, it's been amazing watching
Parker fall on her ass all day,
but, you know, it'd be cool to...
- do some real skiing.
- (Laughs)
I think I've had enough
skiing for today anyway.
So I can just stay here at the lodge
if you guys want to do more.
I didn't mean that.
I didn't mean it like that.
That's not what I meant.
I don't know what I meant.
I told you I didn't...
I didn't have to come.
No no no, Parker,
I didn't not want you to come.
No, he was the one who suggested
you come in the first place.
Okay okay.
The last thing I want
to do is intrude on guy time.
I will not be offended.
I have a lot of things I can do here.
Actually, why don't you give me the key
and I'll go check my messages?
Not to the locker, no.
You're gonna...
Come sit down for a second.
Come here.
All you're gonna get is a bunch
of messages from your mom
complaining about this,
complaining about that.
No, I'm not gonna give you the key.
I'm sorry if I ruined
skiing for you today.
You didn't.
Honestly, you didn't at all.
You missed the whole part of
the conversation before you walked up
where I was saying, like, um...
what was I saying?
I was saying, like,
"Dude, this has been really cool.
I'm glad that we sort of had
this chance
"to bond as a threesome."
- (laughs)
- What?
No, I mean, I've seen you
fall a couple times today.
But Dan, I mean, I think
it took him maybe three months
before he could even stand on that
thing without looking like a total idiot.
No offense, buddy.
Just the truth.
Joe.
I will catch up with you guys.
- Hey. Hey.
- Hey.
I just... I wanted to apologize again.
Yeah, it's no big deal.
He's just lucky
he didn't make me mad.
I only look half your boyfriend's size.
Ex. He's my ex-boyfriend.
We're, you know, trying to
still be friends and everything.
But as you can see,
it's not really gonna work out.
No way.
A group of us all agreed
to go skiing this weekend.
Well, whatever. It's this whole story
and I don't want to hold you up.
But that was just
really embarrassing
and I just wanted to say sorry.
That's no problem.
Um, are you gonna be here
next weekend?
Yeah yeah, probably.
My roommate and I come up like every
Sunday, so maybe I'll see you around.
That would be a nice time.
- Okay.
- I guess I'll see you then.
- Great. Good night.
- Good night.
Come on.
You know what?
Can I just get your number so I know
how to catch up with you?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
Shit, I don't ski with a phone.
You have a pen?
I don't ski with a pen.
Sorry.
All right, you know what?
Just shoot.
I've got a pretty good memory.
I've only smoked pot like 500 times
so I'm good.
Dan:
How can they afford to close early?
You're only open three days
out of the week, man.
Why don't you write a letter?
Why don't you give me
my money back?
(laughs) What money?
We're only had, like, four runs.
- Can you give us a break, please?
- 830.
- What?
- Just remember 830.
- Just one more time, please?
- Sorry.
I'd give you more money
but I gave it all to you.
Hey, you got a pen?
It's not about the money.
We got weather coming in.
We're trying to clear the mountain.
There's nothing I can do.
Okay, what if we run straight down?
Like the quickest run ever?
We'll be, like, wicked fast.
We gave you 100 bucks.
Come on.
Please?
- Hurry.
- Like I said, wicked fast.
- Like the wind.
- 7860.
Seriously, for 100 bucks you'd figure
the guy would cut us some slack.
No shit.
I thought they were open
till 10:00 on Sundays.
What ever happened
to night skiing?
Wachusett's got night skiing.
Should have gone there.
It's kind of like Quash Hill,
just not as lame.
Do you remember
the numbers I told you?
830.
Look at you, Lynch.
You got her number.
What did He-Man
have to say about that?
That guy? Who cares?
Steroids shrink your dick.
- (laughs)
- Oh shit, what are my numbers?
7860.
Parker, will you
remember that, 7860?
Nope.
- Early night, huh?
- Yeah.
Pendergraph wants to see you
in his office.
Something about the schedule
next weekend.
- I'm not working next weekend.
- Well, that's what you thought.
Come on, Rifkin,
it's my brother's bachelor party.
I put in for it two months ago.
Go talk to the boss.
He's packing up.
I'm the best man.
Ready to shut down?
There's three more on the way down.
Wait for them and it's all set.
I am not waiting till we get back
to campus to eat.
I am starving.
Why didn't you just eat
some of that pizza?
Oh, you mean the cardboard
with tomato sauce you guys ate?
That's not pizza.
That's like roller-skating-rink-
birthday-party pizza. No.
There's a Papa Gino's in the way back.
It's like 15 minutes down the mountain.
Sweet.
I may eat a whole real pizza
myself, thank you.
Dan:
Whoa, look at those guys.
We are definitely hitting
that jump this time.
Last run, got to make it count.
- Hey, Sullivan, hey.
- (Groans)
Hey, man, do me a solid.
I've got to take a piss so bad I can taste it.
- What? What?
- I'll just be gone for two minutes.
Asshole.
- (wind blowing)
- (Chairs creaking)
(metal groans)
- Jesus.
- It's just the wind, Parker.
Don't you mean baby?
Man on radio:
Last chair is through.
All set down here.
Man on radio:
Let's go home.
(metal groans)
Oh, come on.
It's freakin' cold up here!
We don't have time for this.
Thank you.
Anyone know any good jokes?
Uh...
What did the 14-year-old girl
from New Hampshire
say to her dad
when she lost her virginity?
Get off me,
you're crushing my Marlboros.
Yup.
Dan: What do you think the worst
way to die would be?
Parker:
That's not morbid.
Lynch: Yeah, seriously,
that's kind of spooky, Dan.
See, I think being eaten by a shark,
that would be the worst way to go.
Not like one of those surfers
who gets attacked from below.
You know, never sees it coming.
Like the poster for "Jaws."
The chick on the "Jaws"
poster was hot.
She was?
I don't know. She was naked
and naked chicks are hot.
What if you actually saw
the fin coming towards you?
That'd be worse than being eaten,
I think.
I mean, knowing this giant animal
is coming at you
and it's gonna eat you alive.
Did you ever see the video,
by the way,
of that great white that's jumping out
of the water and eating the seal?
Yeah, that's why I only swim in pools.
I think burning would be
the worst way to go.
Well, yes and no.
I mean, most people die of smoke
inhalation before fire even touches them.
It's a fact.
I remember watching TV
for three days straight
after 9/11.
The footage they showed of those
people leaping off the Trade Center.
Can you imagine how bad
it must have been inside
to know that jumping would have
been the better way out?
Yeah, but they say that when you jump
from that height your heart stops.
You don't feel it
when you hit the ground.
Okay then, Lynch,
what is the worst way to die?
- What?
- Oh no no no.
You have an answer for everything.
What is your biggest fear?
That's easy.
The sarlacc pit.
I'm sorry, the what?
The sarlacc pit
from "Return of the Jedi."
Uh, hello. Being slowly digested
over 1000 years...
Worst death ever.
"Dan, why don't I ever
have a girlfriend?
Why?"
Hey, shut up.
Why hasn't the chair started again?
Just give it a minute.
This is nothing, man.
At Stowe last year,
me and Sullet
were stranded for like 25 minutes.
This big chick fell at the top
and twisted her leg, you know?
And I was like, fine, people.
Just hoist her off to the side.
Keep the line moving.
But no, they had to stop,
celebrate it right there.
We all had to stay on the lift
and freeze our asses off.
Honestly, by the end of it I couldn't
feel my fingers.
Dan:
What? Come on.
Lynch:
Oh, come on now.
Man, this is so messed up.
(laughs)
- Are you kidding me?
- Dan.
I kind of just shat my pants a little bit.
I'm not gonna lie.
Hey!
Turn the goddamn lights on!
They forgot that we're up here.
No one knows we're up here.
They didn't forget
that we're up here, okay?
There's cameras all over the place.
- Hello!
- Hey!
Assholes, start the chair!
We're freezing!
Parker: Oh my God.
What if they can't get the chair moving?
What if... what if everyone went home?
Hey hey, you know what you need to do?
You need to stop, okay?
You're just scaring the shit out of me.
By the way, remind me to knock
the shit out of that chairlift guy.
What exactly did you say to him?
What? Nothing.
I didn't say anything to him.
Well, you clearly pissed him off
enough to do this.
Look, he knows we're up here.
Then why are the lights off, Dan?
Is that part of their policy?
Turn off the lights
and scare the customers?
I don't know.
Maybe it's a power outage
or something, okay?
That stuff happens all the time.
They didn't go home.
That's retarded.
This is so messed up.
I mean, worst-case scenario
they send up a ladder
or something, right?
Worst case I could just jump.
I've done that before.
It's not so bad.
We have to get off these chairs.
We can't stay up in this chair.
Why isn't the goddamn chair
moving, Dan?
You acting all psycho is not gonna
make the chair move along, okay?
All right?
(Parker sobbing)
Please don't yell at me.
I didn't mean to yell.
This shit happens
all the time though, okay?
I mean, they can't just leave
people up on chairs.
You know the kind of lawsuit
that they would have?
What other people?
There wasn't anybody
in front of us.
They're not gonna leave us
up here all night.
That's all I'm saying.
It's Sunday.
It's fucking Sunday
and they're not open again till Friday.
We're gonna be stuck
here all week.
Oh God.
We're not gonna
be stuck up here.
Parker.
Parker, look at me.
Come on, there is no way a ski resort
would let that happen,
no matter how shitty
they are, okay?
(sobbing)
Hello!
Somebody help us, please!
- Somebody! Hello!
- Hey hey hey.
- Come on, it's all right.
- Somebody!
Shh.
Come on, it's okay.
They're gonna turn
the power on in a minute.
We're all gonna be
laughing about this. Seriously.
(thunder rumbling)
I have to pee.
(laughs)
I have to pee wicked bad.
Yeah, that makes two of us.
Ew, Lynch.
If you pull your junk out
in front of me, I might puke.
Well, what do you want me to do?
I've got to go.
How am I supposed to go?
I don't know. Just, you know,
lift this up and bend down.
Are you crazy?
Put the bar down.
It's just a safety bar, okay?
It doesn't really do anything.
Well, I like the safety bar and I like it
down where it's supposed to be.
Well, how are you gonna piss?
- I can hold it.
- For a week?
What? She's the one saying
we're gonna be here for a week.
I can hold it.
Well, I can't.
I'm pissing.
Ew, that is so gross, Lynch.
Well, too bad, okay?
Make me wait up here
in this below freezing weather...
While I wait for this Fisher-Price
lift to work.
Ah.
Oh shit.
(thunder rumbles)
(ice clanking)
(wind howling)
Hey!
We're up here!
Hello!
- Somebody help us!
- Somebody!
- Put the bar down, Joe.
- Help!
Put the goddamn bar down, Joe!
Parker:
God, it feels like a needle.
(panting)
(engine humming)
Hey!
What did I tell you guys?
Parker:
Hello!
- Hey!
- Hey, we're over here!
Whoo-hoo!
Up here!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Help us!
Help us!
Man on radio:
Cody, this is base.
Parker:
Why is he stopping?
Dan: He's gonna help us.
He sees us.
Go for Cody.
Hey man, where you at?
I'm cutting over to Pinewood
to pick up Barnes.
No, man, Barnes just landed.
The mountain is clear.
Come back to base so we can
get the hell out of here.
- Copy that.
- (Truck beeping)
Parker:
Hey, where are you going?
- Hey! Hey!
- Where's he going?
- What is he doing?
- Where is he going?
- Up here!
- We're up here!
(clangs)
- Hey!
- Come on.
Up here.
Hey!
- Hey!
- Please don't leave us!
- Look up!
- No!
- Come back! Stop!
- Hey!
Stop! Stop!
Hey, come back!
Parker:
Come back. We're here.
(sobbing)
No. No.
Parker:
My face is burning.
Dan:
Power's coming back on.
- Parker: No it isn't.
- It has to.
Parker:
Does anybody know what time it is?
Dan: Hold on. Let me just
run back to the locker.
I'll check my phone real quick.
Okay,
top three breakfast cereals
of all time.
Go.
Okay, I'll go first.
Uh, Crunch Berries.
- Parker: Stop.
- Cinnamon Toast Crunch.
Please stop.
And I'm gonna go out
on a limb and say
Lucky Charms
pre purple horseshoes.
Is it just me or is it really weird
eating purple horseshoes?
Everybody went home.
They left us up here.
Top three celebrities you'd do.
Go.
Somebody needs to jump.
If we're up here all week
we're gonna die.
(sobbing)
Hey. Shh.
Hey.
Shh shh.
- It's okay.
- I don't want to die up here, Dan.
No no no.
Hey, you're not gonna die.
I promise I won't let you die.
Okay?
I'm so...
I'm so scared.
Dan:
Yeah, me too.
Oh my God.
Hey, guys.
What was the best Christmas
present you guys ever got?
Shaina my puppy.
Hey, Dan?
No? Okay.
I guess it's my turn.
My skis.
You get it?
- Oh shit.
- Oh! Shit.
Hey. Hey.
Look at me.
Look at me. Look at me.
Your face is...
It's really red.
I think you got frostbite.
Lynch:
No, you can't get frostbite that fast.
We've only been up here, what?
I mean, it's only been
a few hours tops.
- Parker: What are you doing?
- I'm jumping.
- Lynch: No you're not.
- Yes I am.
Even if I hurt myself
I can get myself down
and I can get us some help.
It's too far, man.
You can't jump.
- Do you have a better idea?
- Than jumping?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I got a better idea.
We can wait till the morning.
I mean, someone's gonna come.
A groomer or some shit.
They're gonna groom the mountain
when it's closed, huh?
When it's not gonna be open
for another five days.
- Dan, don't leave me.
- I can do this.
All right, Joe's gonna
be here with you, okay?
All right?
He'll take care of you.
No, man, don't do this.
Walker, don't.
Dan, don't leave me.
Please.
Look at me.
You're gonna be okay, baby.
You're gonna be okay.
- Dan, no.
- Don't do this, man.
Remember that thing I said
about having done this before?
I totally lied.
I'm scared shitless.
- (cracks)
- (Groans)
(groans echoing)
(Parker muffled)
Dan! Danny!
(Lynch muffled)
Dan, are you okay? Say something!
Oh my God.
Oh my God!
Parker: Danny!
Talk to me, Danny!
- (heart beating)
- Oh my God.
- Oh my God, my legs.
- Lynch: Dan!
Oh my God!
My legs are broken!
Can you move, Dan?
No, I can't.
I can't move.
Okay, hold on.
Hold on, baby.
- What are you doing?
- I've got to get down to him.
Stop, you're gonna get hurt.
Calm down.
No no no, stay there.
Don't get off the chair.
Stay on the chair.
- How bad is it?
- It's bad.
It's really bad.
The bone is sticking out of my leg.
Help!
Please help!
Hey, Dan, buddy.
Dan, can you move at all?
No, man, it's bad.
You can't slide down the hill
or anything?
No, I can't slide down the fucking hill!
I'm bleeding to death, man!
Okay okay.
Can you stop the bleeding?
- With what?
- Hold on.
Here.
Shit!
Hey, Dan, hold on, man.
Hold on.
I'm gonna throw mine down to you.
Here it comes.
Ready?
Can you get to it?
Just feel for it, buddy.
(grunting)
- (screaming)
- (Cracks)
(screaming)
(panting)
(grunting)
(sobbing)
I got it.
Okay, Dan, you're gonna have to
tie that to your legs.
Tie it onto your legs
above where it's bleeding.
Okay?
Like a tourniquet thing.
(groaning)
Okay, hold on. Wait.
Here, take my coat.
No, leave your coat on.
Don't take your coat off.
It's okay.
I can huddle next to Lynch.
- Please.
- Leave your coat on!
(screaming)
Dan: Fuck!
- Hey. Hey, Dan.
- What?
Maybe I can climb up to the cable
and get to a chair
that's closer to the ground.
You've got to be careful, man.
Those cables are razor sharp.
You think you can pull yourself
across on these chairs?
I can't even do a pull-up.
You never even tried
to do a fucking pull-up.
Your mom had to write you a letter
so you could get out of gym class.
- Hey, Joe.
- Yeah?
Remember Jenny Bluth?
Huh?
Remember her?
She could do a fucking pull-up.
I know, but...
Even if I get to that chair,
how many more chairs is it gonna take
before I get to one
that's closer to the ground?
(groans)
The poles.
The poles, they all have
ladders on them, okay?
The lift poles.
You just have to find
your way to one of those.
Okay.
Okay, how far is that chair
away from the pole?
- I don't know.
- Just give me a second.
Give me a second, all right?
Wait, what if you fall too?
Parker, if we stay up here we're gonna
freeze to death and he's gonna die.
(groaning)
Okay, Dan.
Dan, I'm gonna try and scale back
to the next chair.
(growling)
Baby.
Baby, was that you?
- What?
- Hey, shut up, Dan. Shut up.
(wolf howling)
Oh my God.
That was a wolf.
Dan, that's not a wolf, man.
That's a coyote or something.
Dan:
I know the sound of a fucking wolf!
- Help!
- Lynch: They're scared of people.
- Help me!
- Come on, relax.
When was the last time you heard
of a wolf attack in New England?
Never.
They're pussies, man.
The wolves around here,
they're not even that big.
(sobbing)
Hey. Hey, listen.
It could be worse, right?
How could it be worse?
It could be the sarlacc pit.
Lynch: Hey, Parker came through
with the tension breaker, bud.
Your girl's all right, Walker.
- Hey, she's all right.
- Dan: Just climb.
Please, please just climb.
Okay, hold on.
Hold on, I'm coming.
Hold on.
It'll be okay, Dan.
You know it's funny, I was never
afraid of heights until right now.
- Okay, what can I do to help?
- I don't know.
Just hold on to my legs.
I mean, you can't stop me
from falling but it's...
It's like psychological or something.
- Okay.
Oh shit, it's high.
It's really fucking high.
- What can I do to help?
- Nothing. Just stop talking, okay?
- Okay.
Come on.
(grunts)
Dan:
Please hurry!
Dan, just be quiet, okay?
- (gasps)
- Oh God.
Shit, it's all ice.
Hey, Dan.
Dan, buddy, it's all ice.
But I think if we knock it off
I can get to the top.
Hold on.
Shit.
(groans)
(growling, barking)
Oh shit.
What am I supposed to do?
(barking, growling)
You guys!
What the fuck
am I supposed to do?
Get the hell away from him!
(panting)
(wolf howling)
Hey.
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm alive.
See, I told you, man.
They're more afraid of you
than you are of them. Huh?
I don't know, man.
I'm pretty afraid.
I know, man.
I know.
I can't feel my legs anymore.
That's not good, right?
I mean, they don't hurt as bad,
but that's not good.
No no, it's fine.
You're gonna be all right.
Okay, it's probably
really really bad.
We're got to move and get...
Hey hey hey.
Go like this.
Ow.
Ow, it's like a sunburn.
- No no, I think it's frostbite.
- What?
Is my face changing color anywhere?
I don't know.
I can't see anything.
Don't... don't touch it.
Stop.
- Stop.
- But it itches now.
I know, but if you rub your face
it's gonna come off.
Will you just hurry up up there?!
Okay, I'm trying.
Hold on.
Shit.
Be careful.
Okay, just don't talk.
I can do this.
Oh, I got you.
Shit, it's slippery.
Parker:
Don't look down.
My boots are so heavy.
(grunting)
The cable is cutting
through my gloves.
Do you got it?
(groaning)
Oh, my hands.
(branches rustling)
Oh my God.
What?
What's wrong?
Oh my God.
Okay.
Parker:
What is it? What?
I got you.
I got you, you're okay.
You're okay.
What's wrong?
- What's wrong?
- Don't look down.
- What?
- Don't look. Don't look.
- Lynch.
- Yeah, man?
- (barking)
- Don't you let her look.
- Don't you fucking let her look.
- Dan!
- Shh.
- No, I won't, man.
- (Growling)
- (both sobbing)
- Don't.
Don't you let her look!
- (screaming)
- Dan!
Let me look.
I need to look.
I need to look!
No!
(crunching)
No! Dan!
Let me look!
(Dan screaming)
(Dan gurgling)
- No!
- Oh my God. Oh my God.
Oh my God.
(crying)
Oh God.
Think about Dan.
(wolves growling)
(Dan gurgling)
- (shrieking)
- Shh shh.
Don't listen to it.
Just don't listen to it.
(wolves howling)
(wailing)
Okay. Okay.
- (sobbing)
- Okay.
(screaming hysterically)
Dan!
No, Dan.
(echoing) No!
(chair creaking)
Cables cut through my gloves.
My hands are wasted.
Why'd you let him jump?
You can't be serious.
It was too far.
No, he said he could do it.
You didn't try to stop him.
I can't believe this.
Are you trying to blame me?
No.
No, I'm not blaming you.
I mean, you're his girlfriend.
I didn't see you trying to throw
yourself in front of him.
He wasn't going to listen to me.
But he would have listened to me?
No, I said it was a bad idea.
I said it was too far a drop.
I didn't hear any ideas from you
except for crying about it.
Don't you fucking blame me.
You've been his girlfriend for what,
a year?
Maybe?
I've known him
my entire fucking life.
You should've...
- you should've...
- What?
Say it!
It should've been me.
- No.
- That's what you want to say.
No, that's...
that's not what I said.
It's okay. I get it.
I get it.
It should have been me
down there, right?
'Cause who gives a fuck about me?
No.
You know what?
If we hadn't spent the entire day
on the fucking bunny hill
watching you fall on your ass
we would have done some runs
and we could have gone home.
I'm sorry.
Or maybe if you hadn't
fucked with our thing.
Maybe if you had just stayed home
and not tried to force yourself
into every little aspect of his life
my best friend
wouldn't be dead right now.
(sobbing) That's...
Not fair.
That's not fair.
It's not fair
that my best friend is dead.
(crying)
He's not coming back.
He's gone.
- I'm sorry.
- Fuck you!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Lynch.
Please.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
I didn't mean it, okay?
Parker: 830.
Lynch:
Oh shit.
What were my numbers?
- 786...
- Parker: 7860.
830-7860.
Yeah.
I'm so gonna call that girl
when I get back.
You know what?
I'm gonna ask her to marry me.
No messing around.
I'm just gonna call her and I'm gonna
be like, "Hey, Shannon.
It's Joe from the chairlift.
Will you marry me?"
We'll get a house,
have two kids
and a dog named Steve.
- Who's gonna pay for the house?
- She will.
She's got a great job.
Parker:
What does she do?
Lynch:
Orthodontist.
Parker:
Orthodontists make a lot of money.
Lynch: Yeah.
Parker: Well, I'm sure the two of you
will be really happy.
Lynch:
830-7860.
Who names their dog Steve?
I will.
Steve's a people name.
Says who?
You don't, like,
go to someone's house
and have them say,
"Here, meet my dog Steve."
Why not?
I think Steve's a good name for a dog.
Here, meet my cat Chris.
No cat.
Just a dog...
Steve.
Shaina must be so hungry.
What kind of pizza should we get?
The poor thing.
She's just a puppy.
She's not gonna understand
that I died.
She's gonna think that I left,
that I forgot about her.
She's probably waiting
by the front door right now.
At every little noise
that she hears
in the hallway,
she's probably
cocking her little head
to the side
wondering when
I'm gonna come in.
But I won't.
I won't come in.
And she's gonna...
she's gonna starve to death.
She's gonna starve to death
waiting for me to come in.
It's all my fault.
She's not gonna starve to death.
You're not gonna die, Parker.
I'm the only one with a key
to my apartment, though.
Yeah, I know, but the neighbors
will kick the door down
if she doesn't stop barking.
Someone will figure it out.
She'll be just fine.
So will you.
So will we.
(groans)
I just want to see my mom.
And my dad.
(birds chirping)
(wind howling)
(squeaking)
(birds chirping)
(grunting)
(wincing)
- Ah!
- (Bar clangs)
I thought I was dreaming.
I thought I was dreaming this.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
Your frostbite is getting worse.
- Really? How bad...
- Don't touch it. It's bad.
It doesn't itch as much anymore.
Okay, don't touch your face though.
When we get out of here
I'm gonna get you to a doctor.
- They'll fix it right away.
- You have...
You have red marks on your face too.
They'll fix me up too.
Don't. Don't.
Don't touch it. It's bad.
Lynch:
Well, it's the morning.
Maybe someone will come up now.
Parker:
For what?
Lynch: Mountain maintenance.
I don't know.
Besides, if we don't show up for class
people will start looking for us.
No one knows we're here.
I didn't tell anyone
I was coming.
Help!
We need help!
If I can get to that pole
I can climb down the ladder.
How are you gonna climb
with your hands like that?
We won't make it another night.
Are you sure you don't want to...
Wait a few hours?
I mean, maybe you're right.
Maybe someone's coming in today.
(sighs)
(sobbing)
(exhales)
Parker:
The sun feels good.
Lynch: First we're freezing,
now we're gonna get sunburned.
Be careful what you wish for, right?
Parker: How come you
never have a girlfriend?
Lynch:
How am I supposed to answer that?
Parker:
I just mean you're a decent guy.
And chicks dig you.
But you never
have a relationship.
Lynch:
I had a serious girlfriend once.
- High school doesn't count.
- No.
No, post high school.
Freshman year.
Who?
This girl Annie.
We met at freshman orientation.
We emailed each other
during the summer.
When we got back to school
it was like we were dating.
Oh.
I just really felt it
with her, you know?
We were into the same stuff,
which was cool.
She was way into Aerosmith.
I'd seen 'em five times.
She'd seem 'em eight.
What happened?
She, uh...
Had the same favorite
movie as me... ET.
It was like soulmates,
that shit you read about.
So what happened?
Same old shit.
No.
You know what happened?
She...
She liked another guy.
This fraternity douchebag
named Dean.
She dumped you for a frat guy?
No.
No, I dumped her.
We were in the cafeteria, right?
You know, we were having lunch,
facing each other.
I was facing the wall and she was
facing everybody behind me.
And I kept seeing her, like,
you know, looking at somebody.
You know, like kind of laughing.
And I was just like, you know,
"What's so funny?"
You know?
And, you know, like,
"What the hell is going on?"
And she said...
She said,
"Dean's making fun of you."
So I turn around and I'm ready to
just beat the shit out of this guy.
But all I can see are these
random fucking people.
All these faces.
This guy was making eyes
at my girl and could see me
but I couldn't see him.
That's messed up.
I never felt so stupid.
I just walked out.
You just walked out?
Yeah, I told her to laugh it up
with Dean the frat guy.
I was out.
That sucks.
Maybe I shouldn't have been
so quick to walk away.
You know, maybe I should
have had a thicker skin
and not been
such a sensitive bitch.
Sometimes I feel like
I was just insecure.
Maybe I screwed up.
You should tell her that.
When you get home
you should call her.
I can't.
(chuckles)
She's dating Dean.
(laughs)
I should have done something.
There was nothing
you could have done.
I just sat here
and I let him die.
No, you didn't.
We didn't let him die, okay?
There was nothing
we could have done.
He jumped down there
to save us, okay?
He was the one.
He was the boy
I was gonna marry.
Hey.
First grade
and we get left there
by our moms
for the day.
It's like the first
real day of school,
you know,
without your folks around.
And Dan was this chubby little kid.
(laughs) No, fuck it.
- He was a fat ass.
- (Parker laughs)
And so our moms all leave
but Dan wouldn't let go
of his mom's hand.
And even after she left he just stood
at the front of the class
crying like a total pussy.
- That sounds like Dan.
- Yeah, you have no idea.
Anyway, so the teacher...
Oh, what's her name?
Mrs. Schifrin.
So Mrs. Schifrin is trying everything
to get the fat kid to stop crying.
And she says,
"You know,
maybe there's somebody..."
somebody else
you know in the class.
"Maybe you have a friend
you want to sit with."
And this little fucker points
right at me and says, "Him."
Now I've never seen
this kid in my life.
But for some reason
he pointed at me.
- So you had to sit with him?
- Yeah, for a whole week.
Whole first week of school I had to share
my little cubby with his fat ass.
(laughs) Oh, gosh.
He was a douchebag.
I never let him forget it.
(sighs)
Dan didn't die up here just for you
and I to give up and die too.
Help me up.
(breathing heavily)
Are you okay?
(groaning)
(screams) Oh God!
Lynch: Oh shit.
- Shit, just hold on.
- Oh my God.
- The chair is gonna fall.
- No it's not. No it's not.
(groaning) Oh, God.
My hands.
Oh God, my hands.
(groaning)
Joe!
Fuck you, Jenny Bluth.
(groaning) Oh fuck.
(growling)
Oh shit.
Shit.
- Hey, Parker.
- What?
I need you to throw my extra pole
as far as you can this way.
What?
I said I want you
to throw my ski pole
as far down the hill as you can.
I'm gonna need some defense
when I get on the ground.
Okay.
(cable groaning)
(rattling)
(chair creaking)
Okay.
(shrieks) Oh my God.
- Shit.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- (Wolf barking)
Shit.
Oh shit.
Okay.
Parker:
You can do it.
Please do it.
(grunting)
Please don't break.
(growling)
Shit.
(groaning)
I just want to go.
Please let me go.
You did it!
- Oh shit.
- Joe!
Lynch!
- Lynch!
- I'm okay.
(wolves barking)
No! No!
(screaming)
Lynch: No!
(yelps)
Stay the fuck back!
Try and stay still.
I'll be back as fast as I can.
Please please hurry.
Please.
- (barking)
- Joe, look out!
Joe!
(sniffling)
(birds chirping)
Aw, Joe...
(whimpering)
(rattling)
(grunts)
(screams)
(whimpering)
(cables snapping)
Ow!
(crying)
(grunting)
(panting)
(groans)
(growling)
(wolves bark)
(groaning)
(winces)
Hello!
Help, please!
Wait!
(groans)
(panting)
(wind howling)
(tires squeal)
Hey, you okay?
Hello?
Hey, you all right?
Hold on.
I'm gonna get you help.
No, there were no other cars.
I found her laying in the road
right outside of Mt. Holliston.
I'm taking her to you now.
Hold on.
The hospital
is only 10 minutes away.
You're gonna be okay.
Dan's voice:
You're gonna be okay, baby.
You're gonna be okay.
(orchestral music playing)