Solar Films presents
A Markus Selin Production
An Aku Louhimies Film
Born pure into the future's hands
in these cold and northern lands
Eppu Normaali
"A Land of Mournful Songs“
I never wanted this to happen.
Do you remember the questions
we asked each other as kids?
How big is space?
Where does the sky end?
Where does the sea begin?
Why can't I scream
when I feel bad?
What's the point of living
if this life is merely he"?
But we have to believe
that in the end -
things work out for the best.
Otherwise, nothing
makes any sense.
FROZEN LAND
Commencement, conflict,
transformation, and so on.
What's relevant is what is
said, not how it's said.
Tell me about Tolstoy's world.
He discusses one -
where people peddle
their own private hells.
Person A shoves it onto B -
who cannot help but pass
it onto C. And so on
Essays back next week please.
And don't download
them from the net.
This is our new EDP teacher.
- Antti Arhama, physics and EDP.
Pertti Smolander. Literature
studies I' though not very literate.
I'll be back shortly. Pertti,
can I see you for a moment?
You're talked of
as our most popular, -
possibly our best teacher.
I wouldn't know about that.
But we have
a problem which means -
we are going
to have to let you go.
Our main focus
on EDP and math -
means we don't need
so many Lit. teachers.
It's beyond my control I'm
afraid. I'm really sorry.
UNEMPLOYMENT
Hell. Cold
Was there this much snow last
winter when I got the boot.
Where are we going?
Niko! Niko!
Turn it down.
You're like Oblomov.
You only bloody lie there.
Pull yourself together.
I promised to
lend this to these guys.
Just temporarily.
The CD player?
I gotta disk in it.
It'll stay there.
Keep it. Have fun!
We didn't like it anyway!
Get out of here. Go on.
You know where the door is.
I saved a long
time for that player.
Leave me alone.
Just like your mom did.
Take the whole shelf.
Give that to me.
Are you trying to teach ME?
Are you raising ME,
you punk?
Move on out!
Niko, please.
Lend me a twenty.
If I had it, I would.
I don't have any.
"I don't have any"-
Where did you get it before?
- None of your business
Beat it!
And don't come back!
Not without a job!
Were you sleeping? - No
Oh, yes you were.
Sleeping this late.
Hi. Happy New Year.
What am I doing with these?
Is this a bad time to call?
How come you're
not opening the door?
What's the plan for
tonight? Fireworks?
My cousin's throwing
a party. - I'll join you.
We can do the fireworks.
Can I take a nap here? I'm
fucked. - Be my guest.
I have to take
my parents to the airport.
We're off. - My old
man threw me out.
What? - Nothing.
See you tonight.
Chill out. Lock the door.
What's this place we're
going? - It's my cousin's.
What's in there? - What are you
up to? Where are you going?
Let's take him with us.
- Are you coming with us?
Heavy duty.
Going downhill is much
less hassle than going up.
Mankind is
coming to the end...
Yeah. The end is near.
I mean really close.
Can you
upgrade my computer?
Six, five, four, -
three, two, one!
Ten, nine, eight
What's up? Pass it this way.
Pass it on to Tuomas.
- He won't have any.
What's that?
Print it out! - No way.
Go on. Let's take a look..
Can I have a line?
Just one.
I'll have your line, too.
Coming, coming!
Tuomas. Why not give it a try?
- Don't touch anything!
Come back to the party!
- You know you can trust me.
Niko, come over here!
- No sweat. I'm not stupid.
How much for the player?
- Let's say about forty.
Come on. Twenty is more
like it. - Don't make me laugh.
Twenty-five. - Thirty.
Let's make it twenty-five.
- Thirty's as low as I go.
OK. Thirty it is.
Don't you have anything
smaller? - Not right now
But hey! That's money,
too. Money! Money!
Two, three, four...
There you go! - Were
you trying to screw me?
Happy New Year!
- Same to you.
You fucking stupid bitch!
Are you blind?
You'd let them pay
you in toilet paper!
How can you tell? It looks
real! - No hologram!
What-gram? - Holo! Hologram!
They all have one these days!
How should I know?
These euros all look
like funny money to me.
All you do round here is
read the tabloids and booze.
Good morning.
Do you have any old
coins? - Old coins...
Fucking old coins!
BOOZE
It's been looked after.
Barely used.
Just need a bit of cash.
It was an engagement
present, just six months old.
Wide-screen, 28".
Five hundred.
A thousand.
It's as good as new, y'know.
Still six payments to go.
Five-ten. - OK.
If that's your final offer
These don't keep their value.
Always a newer model.
There's a big note in there.
Money is money.
What shampoo do you
use? - Why is that?
Your hair's a bit limp.
It happens I have some state
of the art shampoo in the car.
I don't need it.
- You could stock it here.
We don't sell shampoo.
- Hell of a profit margin.
Buy cheap, sell dear.
Fat profits. - No deal.
You've got a new routine.
- Yeah.
Why are you
still hanging about?
Just thought I'd return the
keys. - I'll pass them on.
How about dinner tonight?
Somewhere rich.
Your choice. - Why?
Why not?
Where's the money from?
I have a new job.
Good for you.
What restaurant you working
in? - Not in a restaurant.
A household appliance store.
TVs and stuff.
Hey, wait. How about
a drink? - It's no use.
Or maybe a drive?
Isto, you're
a really nice guy.
But it just doesn't
work for me any more.
Please. I love you.
A couple of drinks...
Can I buy you dolls some
hot shots? - No thanks.
Isto pays for everything.
Let's go to a hotel.
You're gorgeous,
you know that?
Fuck off!
Don't mess with me, asshole!
Do I look like I'm broke?
This guy's not with us.
What do you think this is?
What's this? What's this?
It's money!
I'm not a forger.
I sold my TV.
I have a Ford Mercury.
American.
A great fucking car.
Let me outta here!
Morning, Virtanen. Another
day, another hearing.
You haven't been messing
with drugs, have you?
Don't feel like talking?
Can I go home?
- That's not up to us.
Drop your pants
and spread your legs.
Just relax.
OK. Put your clothes on.
The only sure thing is death!
Fuck!
Jerk! Jerk! Faggot!
Straight through
- and no alarm.
Smart ass security
systems - complete waste.
When are the police coming?
- In the afternoon.
Matikainen! Someone to
see you! - Fucking hell!
Sit down.
What do you want?
Looks like
business is good.
Is that what
you're here to tell me?
I would like to -
to make a new deal, -
if that's OK.
I'll cover the interest
with a vacuum cleaner.
That's for you.
Plus a year's supply
of hair shampoo.
It's good shampoo.
Dandruff...
Do you take me
for an utter moron?
I'm temporarily short of cash.
- When do you have it?
When the snow melts...
When? - Let's say in May.
By Mother's Day.
- Mother's Day?
Where's this money coming from?
Selling vacuum cleaners?
I've told you that selling
Hoovers is bullshit.
How many have you sold?
How many? Tell me.
How many exactly?
Quite a few.
And a lot of hair shampoo.
Where is the money?
If you don't pay up, you lose
your car. Fucking simple.
Can you cut me some slack.
For old times' sake.
Jartsa...
Goodbye.
Hi there.
Allow me to demonstrate
this vacuum cleaner.
What brand do you use?
- An ordinary one.
Have you ever
seen one of these?
Do you speak Finnish?
- No, no.
What sort of
shampoo do the kids...
What shampoo do you
use? - Me or the dog?
Latest model.
- A bit expensive.
There's a payment plan...
- No, no...
Metal casing.
- Not interested.
A black dress
shows all the dust...
Made in Sweden.
The land of honest labor.
We don't buy anything.
My bathroom's
full of shampoo...
How old is the dog?
Didn't you see the sign?
- I am not vending...
I'm a sales representative...
- Really? Bye!
When you're
dealing with alcohol, -
you're dealing with
a cunning adversary.
By ourselves, we're
not strong enough.
We need
God's assistance.
We'll take it in turn
starting with Teuvo.
My name is Teuvo.
I'm an alcoholic.
Where should I start today?
Today wasn't exactly
a major success.
My mind is blurry.
I haven't been close -
to anyone -
for a long time.
For reasons of my own.
I guess my car has
been my best buddy.
Sounds funny.
But now I've lost it.
But spring is on its way.
A time of hope.
And I thank God
for a sober day today.
Thank you... Mauri.
I'm Mauri.
And I'm an alcoholic.
It's tough making
it here but I'm happy -
to know I'm not alone.
Would you like
vacuuming to be easier?
It's time to make
your life easier.
Open the door!
Bastard! You wanna die?
This is for the five hundred.
With some interest!
THE AXE
Fuck!
The light's red, you jerk!
You looking for
a knuckle sandwich?
Homo! Faggot!
Hi. Any vacancies?
Just for the night.
Alcohol goes into circulation
when it hits your lips.
That first slug
of an ice-cold beer.
It just hits your fucking brain!
And let's talk about the profit!
What's the purchase price?
Maybe 80 cents?
The keg costs you 50 euros.
But after that -
when you've once payed
for the keg, it's kinda free.
You following me?
Some places have the nerve -
to ask for eight euros a pint.
Or seven... six. Of course,
it's more often five.
But starting from nine.
A coffee, please.
And another one.
Another coffee, please.
Was it good? - Sorry?
How did it taste?
The coffee?
Fine.
You look familiar.
Where you from?
- Hollola.
How about you?
I live in Nummela these days.
I have a major
car dealership there.
Cars?
- Yes, big, fancy cars.
How about
the financing options?
Depends on the down
payment. Isto. Virtanen.
Hurskainen.
Teuvo. Teukka.
"What shampoo do you use?"
We're selling the same brand.
Like they say in the US,
the world's one big network.
Any good bonuses lately?
- Quite a bit.
I have a vacuum cleaner
business on the side.
I owe money
to the shampoo supplier.
Are you going
to stick to coffee all night?
Let me get you a round.
We'll put the drinks
on my room bill.
A glass of milk.
- A glass of milk!
You're drinking milk!
Milk.
A man who drinks milk.
A double whiskey!
A double whiskey.
Now we're talking.
Milk, followed
by a double whiskey.
Way to go!
Milk lines your stomach.
"Our company is doing a-okay..."
With all the accessories.
Isn't she a beauty?
One click and everything opens.
Let's party!
We'll round up some girls.
I release my aggressions.
Fuck! I'm going
the beat the car up!
Tonight we're going for a spin.
Go on, check out that box!
It's a fucking TV!
Sky channels and all.
14 channels and MTV!
- I'd like to have a go.
No jerk is driving my
car drunk! No one!
No drunk is driving my car.
Look, Teukka
Hey! Let's wank!
All emissions
go through 8 filters.
Hose attachment
is in the rear.
One click and
everything opens.
Fire at will! Take cover!
You're so beautiful.
Can I kiss you?
No, don't! Stop it.
If I'm not interested
then I don't want it.
Help! - Hey, Teukka.
He's trying to rape me.
That's no way to treat a
woman. Gently does it.
You gotta to
be gentle with them.
Like this.
A few kisses.
Look. This is the way.
Gently, Teukka. Look.
Smile. Smile.
This is the way.
Smile.
Get the fuck out of here. Go
screw your vacuum cleaner.
Help! Help!
Don't kill me! Don't!
A guy with a mustache and
a mullet. A pilot's flight jacket.
Is he still here? - Yes.
Will this be on the
same bill? - Yes.
Anything from the
mini bar? - No.
I'd like to see his records.
- Just a moment.
237.
FAMILY
How about
another two weeks?
Have you
been depressed lately?
What if I just go home.
I don't want any more leave.
How've you been handling
your job lately? Overall?
What do your partners think?
Everything's fine.
You're sleeping okay?
You're not taking
unnecessary risks?
For depression:
1 tablet as required.
Hi. - Hi.
Don't you have your key?
I left it at home.
Any homework? - None
today. I did it all at school.
We were
learning about colors.
There's a new color.
Oh, come on.
Cut it out!
Are you sure you're OK?
- Yes. I must go.
Personnel shortages.
Give me a kiss.
Have you lived in
Helsinki a long time?
Almost four years now.
Where? - Downtown.
Smack in the center.
Close to the Bank of Finland.
At Ritarikatu.
- That's a nice place.
The guys at the precinct say
that you're doing a good job.
Yeah? Maybe I am.
You know these
streets pretty well...
Shit. No reflector!
- I thought he had one.
That was a close call.
I've got some hot coffee.
Want some? - Not for me.
You haven't taken
detective course yet?
I've been sort of tied up.
Hey, when
was Karl Marx born?
Sometime in the
last millennium.
In the 19th century.
You should know.
Hell!
This is 237, in pursuit
of a red Ford Sierra.
We're driving
on Sahaajankatu.
Moving at high speed, -
turning left
Take my car and go
straight to the precinct...
To all cars: suspected burglar
broke loose from a patrol, -
running towards -
the rail yard.
Probably armed.
Male, normally built, -
6 ft tall.
237 has a visual.
Suspect is running
for the rail yard.
Police! Freeze!
Stop! Police!
The chaos theory. A frightening
phrase. What does it mean?
We are all
familiar with chaos.
One look in the mirror
after the weekend.
My hair's a "chaos".
A leaking tap: the regular
rhythm of the falling drops -
suddenly going haywire...
Antti, have
you got a second?
Antti Arhama?
I'm afraid you must be prepared
for some very sad news.
Your wife was killed in
the line of duty last night.
She was crushed by a train
while in pursuit of a suspect.
The suspect is in custody.
We are not yet certain
that he was involved -
in your wife's death -
or even whether she was
pushed under the train.
Investigations
are in progress.
This is all I can tell.
My deepest sympathy.
Hi. You're early.
Tomorrow the class is going to
the zoo. Three euros each and...
Are we going shopping?
- Not right now.
Maybe later. - Why not?
We'll see.
Why don't
you take your coat off?
Why don't you
take your coat off.
You promised we would
buy some bubble-gum.
Can I play?
May I play? - Go ahead.
Kill!
Let's go and see granny!
- Kill, kill, kill.
Did you hear what I said?
To granny's! - Off we go.
If daddy says
we're going, we're going.
Big sisters are such a drag.
Go on. Go now.
Daddy. You're speeding.
Did you hear me?
You're speeding!
Daddy. You're going too
fast. Can you hear?
Why did we stop here?
Daddy.
You can't stop here.
Do you hear?
Daddy, do you hear?
- You can't stop here.
Hey, kids.
I want to take Niko in on this.
Can we trust him?
- Of course.
He's my childhood friend.
And he's only the driver.
- OK then.
You're cold?
Do you want to marry me?
- What?
Be my wife.
SNOWPILE
People talk
about Eco-catastrophes.
The population explosion.
The end is near.
Do you love her? - Yes.
That's good.
The kid coming and all.
Is it a boy or a girl?
- Too early to tell.
The main thing
is the baby's health.
Does it make any sense -
to bring babies
into a world like this?
Nice cake. - A special offer.
German. Paid for it in euros.
The end is near. - I guess.
Don't worry so much. - No.
I'm trying to talk to you.
But you look worried.
- If you would only listen to me.
It's about your family.
- You don't know my parents.
The way things are going, I
never will. - This is my call.
If something goes wrong, -
I don't want you to
know anything. - OK.
I'm not going to hurt anyone.
I get the feeling
you're trying to back off.
Things are different now.
You're pregnant.
Come right in.
Here's my dad's access
card and the keys.
Did you find what we need?
Yes. More than I expected.
Control camera angles
and all kinds of stuff.
I think it's a girl.
How can you tell?
- It's just how I feel
We need your help.
For something we've
been planning for a while.
Talk to me.
You have to get into a building.
- And you're the driver.
Who lives there?
It's an information
security company.
I need to get to their server.
- And what does that mean?
A lot of cash
passes through every day.
My old man is the MD.
- And?
We take from the rich and give
to the poor. - I'm pretty poor.
Are you in? - Am I?
What's in it for me?
What's my share?
Do I get something?
You get to be
a part of something big.
Very funny. Very funny.
Do you copy? Do you copy?
I CODY-
Fuck, what's with this?
Tuomas.
Do you copy?
Fuck.
I'm done.
Do you read me?
I can't hear you.
I have to come out soon.
I'm coming out now.
Wait!
Police! Freeze!
Hola! Como estas?
You waiting for someone?
How's your beer?
Is it good?
So, you like beer?
Can I get you something?
What do you want?
Do you like poetry?
Do you want to go to my place?
Mankind is
the crown of creation.
Niko. I want to introduce
you to a friend of mine...
Let's just be friends
Put your clothes on.
First give me a kiss!
After the war 129 police officers
have been killed in the line of duty
The chase ended with a
tragic death in the rail yard.
She was a
respected police officer
Elina Oravisto? - Yes.
Criminal investigations.
How long have your
parents been in Thailand?
A few weeks.
- Where exactly?
Have you been there?
- Yes. In Phuket.
They're in Pattaya.
Your father doesn't know
this Tuomas? - No.
How is that?
They've never met. - Do your
parents know you're dating him?
No. - Why do
you want to hide it?
My parents are so
different from him.
Why did he raid your father's
company? - I don't know.
Did you help him? - No.
Tuomas is in the EDP business.
- He has his own company.
There must be other parties
involved. Any ideas? - No.
Does he belong to any
organizations? - No
Does he have any
enemies? - No.
Did you give him
the access codes?
No. I don't even
know them myself.
You might be an accomplice.
- On what grounds?
Tuomas may have
murdered a police officer.
Do you understand how
serious this is for you?
I need to get high.
He's fine.
- How do you know?
Tuomas can handle anything.
It can't be my fault.
They can't accuse me.
Patrols and German shepherds
all over the fucking place.
What are those?
They're a bit like...
They're downers.
Good for depression.
Have one.
She's not breathing too well.
Saturation 87. And decreasing.
What's the blood pressure?
80 over 40. She needs
a drip. In both arms.
Prepare to pump her stomach.
The patient is in her twenties.
She's not dying?
POLICE
Why can't we go over there?
- You just can't. Cut it out!
Kids aren't allowed in there.
We cannot comprehend
the power of evil, -
the power of death.
Why is our society
not free of evil?
Why are there victims -
who must suffer for
the actions of others?
Yet the riddle of
evil is not outside us.
The line between
right and wrong -
divides us but it is
also within ourselves.
Who can we depend upon?
We seem to be powerless
in the face of death.
Yet even sorrow
can bring us strength.
Through it, we
can search for a reality -
which is
greater than any of us.
Darling Hannele.
Why did you leave
us alone so soon?
What made you do it?
What could you possibly
have thought to gain from it?
Let's start again
from the beginning.
How did you get into Certum -
if you didn't get
any help from anyone?
Why did you go there? What
were you looking for there?
I wanted to... - What?
What makes the world go round?
- What? Why did you go there?
We are going to keep going
through this until we get answers.
Who was there with you?
Answer!
The accused, Tuomas Saraste,
was breaking and entering.
And while evading capture -
he attacked a police officer -
and pushed
her under a moving train.
Furthermore the
engine driver states: -
they fought and then -
he violently pushed
the officer onto the tracks.
There is very
little one can do...
My client pleads
"not guilty" to murder -
but "guilty" to
breaking and entering -
and involuntary
manslaughter.
The verdict of this court
states that the accused, -
Tuomas Mikael Saraste -
is guilty of
breaking and entering.
The court does not
find him guilty of murder, -
rather, the accused
is convicted of -
manslaughter.
This is based on the affidavits
and police investigations.
The sentence is eight
years and six months -
in the penitentiary.
From this sentence he has
already served 185 days.
Furthermore, he must
pay the victim's children -
2600 euros as compensation
for their mental suffering.
Arhamo's claim
has been rejected.
The court is adjourned.
Is that all! A few years.
- We must appeal.
He only got few years.
Did he say eight?
Was that it? - I'm sorry.
Was that all? Is that
the best you can do?
He murdered my wife!
I'm sorry. - He should
get the electric chair.
The termination
of your employment, -
who was the initiator?
- The employer.
The house is your own?
- Yes.
Well, 50% belongs to the bank.
We don't do
loan repayments.
Calculations indicate -
a monthly deficit of
41 euros. - Right.
Cash or credit?
- I have this document.
I'm not sure we take these.
Do we accept
social security vouchers?
No. - They should be
OK in all supermarkets.
Not in this one.
Maybe somewhere else.
Have you opened that already?
- The kids are eating the candy.
You don't have any cash?
- Not on me at the moment.
How about
a trip to the ATM?
I'll pay you later for
the candy. - Well, OK.
Maybe you should
use the other counter.
Some for me too.
- Move the spoon.
This is yummy.
How long ago did your
wife die? - About a year.
You got some crisis help
then? - Yes.
And the kids too?
We all went
together a few times.
Good.
How have you been lately?
Not so well.
What sort of symptoms?
Sort of... outbursts.
Outbursts?
What do you mean?
Quite... violent
Violent outbursts?
What are they?
I seem to lose it.
Can you be
more specific, please?
They're quite violent.
And you have 3 kids. - Yes.
How about a prescription?
Tranquilizers?
Maybe something
to help me sleep.
You have trouble getting
sleep? - Yes.
What is troubling you most?
I simply can't...
I can't get over my
wife's death... not yet.
How is that?
I keep thinking
about her death.
Getting over a loss of a loved
one could take a long time.
That's what they say.
Kill! Kill!
Daddy, why are we born?
Why was I born?
- You want to know?
Some people believe
that God created us.
What the hell is this again?
Jaakko started it.
- Shut up!
Do you want me
to take you outside?
Let go of my hair! - You
disgust me. God damn it.
It was an accident.
Now the teachers know that
my son beats up his friends.
It was an accident!
- Shut up!!
Daddy, don't hit! - Fuck!
Welfare office?
Put me through to someone
who deals with family violence.
Hello? Antti Arhamo here.
I would like to ask...
I have three kids -
and I hit
one of them quite hard.
Yes, at home
Say good-bye to your father.
Bye, daddy. Bye.
- Konsta?
Give your dad a hug.
I'm sorry, Konsta.
- Forget it.
I love you.
- I love you too.
THE LAST MISTAKE
- five years later -
Business closed.
Why don't they
stop doing that stuff?
That's a good question.
Are humans born innocent?
And if we are,
how is ill feeling born?
Next I want everyone to think back
to a situation in your own lives, -
where you have passed your
ill feeling to someone else
A friend of mine...
My best friend
is getting out soon.
I'm a little nervous
ans scared about it.
He hasn't...
He hasn't been in touch -
with his ex-girlfriend.
I've been seeing her, Elina.
We're friends.
I've a clear
conscience about it.
We have just spend -
a lot of time together.
I'd like my father here.
He's in poor shape.
The best dad,
but now in bad way.
I'm very happy to be
here. Thank you.
My name is Anna.
And I'm an addict.
Prison area.
No trespassing.
Good mash, isn't it?
- Pretty good.
Real potatoes
What's your plan?
- No idea.
You should
get in touch with them.
After all, he's your son.
And he needs a father.
- Drop it.
If you run now, you have
to face it later. - So?
What's your next step?
This is for you.
Give me a break.
- Just take it.
Besides it's real.
I'm doing okay.
This is a start.
A new beginning.
To everything.
- If you say so.
Mommy?
What's up, sweetie?
- I had a bad dream.
Let's go back to bed.
I'll tuck you in.
I heard voices.
I thought you'd
meet him a bit later.
Who is that?
- Let's go and see.
Hi. - Hi.
Are you my daddy? - Yes.
Good.
I need to do pee-pee.
Say "good night" to daddy.
- Good night.
Let's put you
under the blankets.
I suppose you'd better go.
Hey young fella!
Gotta spare coin?
For a phone call?
Thanks.
Happy Midsummer!
Come inside.
You'll have to
excuse the mess in here.
Coffee? - Yes please.
I'm out of milk.
- Black is fine.
I can tell that you believe
that I did it. But I didn't.
You have beautiful kids.
Yeah.
What's the little one called?
- That's Jonttu.
Joonatan.
Where are they now?
What? - The kids.
At school?
Where else?
Marja is just about to
graduate. A smart girl.
Wanna visit Hannele's grave?
It was what she wanted.
- Now it's frozen?
Just like then.
Don't do it. Don't do it.
I never wanted this to happen.
Do you remember the questions
we asked each other as kids?
Why am I who I am?
Why was I born here?
Why can't I scream
when I feel bad?
What's the point of living if
this life is merely hell?
But we have to believe, -
that in the end things
work out for the best
Otherwise, nothing
makes any sense