What's your resolution?
I'm gonna cut carbs.
But, you're Mexican. You can't
eat nothing yo grandma makes.
It only takes 30 days
to form a habit.
And then, it becomes
second nature.
- Who said that?
- Oprah.
Okay, you and Oprah cool now?
- What's yours?
- I'm gonna quit selling trees.
Hold on, hold up.
What's up? I been
home hella long...
I don't know...
Every time you touch me,
all I can think about is how
you was touching that Bitch.
I'll never hear
end of that shit.
You know what?
You right,
go.
What did do?
I fucked up that one time.
No, you got caught, one time.
And you gonna sit here
and tell me, that was
the first time you kicked
it with that Bitch.
You ain't never seen
her before that.
That shit is over.
All I want is you... and T,
forever.
What you mean, forever?
Let me show you.
Daddy.
What?
She's asking for you.
What's up?
I can't sleep...
Can't sleep.
You want to sleep in here
with Mummy and Daddy?
T..You know better than that.
What time is it?
Damn, it's after midnight.
Mummy, can I have two of
the fruit snacks today?
No, You can take an extra
apple, if you want.
But mummy I-
Don't argue T. It's too early.
- We gotta stop and get gas.
- We got enough to get us there.
- Good morning, Tatiana!
- Good morning, Mrs. Stacy.
- How you doing today, Osc?
- Doing good, you?
See? Told you we'd make it.
You gonna go home and sleep, right?
Naw...
I'ma go up to the job.
Get some stuff for tonight.
I'd rather die than
come here on my day off.
We gonna go to Frisco, right?
To see the fireworks?
Yeah.
We'll do that.
Alright, Let me get in here.
- Aren't you gonna say, 'Bye'?
- Bye.
Love you too!
- Hello?
- Last shot right here,
you sure you want to
work on your birthday?
Come on, I'm gonna come and get you
right now. Let's go celebrate.
As tempting as that sounds... this place
would be a mess without me today.
Okay... You still want me to
get a couple crabs, right?
Yes, and can you
pick a couple of...
- are you driving?
- Yeah.
- You wearing your earpiece?
Don't lie to me.
Alright, alright. Hold on.
- Hello?
- It's on now?
Yeah.
Yeah, get me a couple of
packets of dried shrimp.
Stop by on your home for the money.
Don't worry about that.
Alright, I'll pay
you back tonight.
Come on Ma, don't trip. You ain't
paying for nothing' on your birthday.
Okay, I need to run on in here,
babe. I'll see you later tonight?
Yeah. I Love you.
Love you too.
- Sup Osc, bruh?
- Shit. What's good?
Same shit, Bruh. You
looking for Emi?
Yeah, he here?
Yeah, seen him earlier today...
Bruh..I came to
get some crabs too.
Shit. That's right.
It's Ma's birthday.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, forgot to hit her.
Tell her, I said, Happy Birthday.
Why don't you come and tell her yourself.
I can't be doing it tonight. You
know I've gotta bust some moves...
You ain't bustin' shit bruh.
It's good for the
countdown though.
Frisco. Fireworks
and the whole shit.
You ready?
Yeah... I want to
get a pound of..
Can you show me what
your sole looks like?
Sole?
Okay,
What about your catfish?
Can I see that?
Okay..I wanna do like... fish
fry; Are these ones good for fry?
It's fish. You can
fry all of 'em.
Right.
Give me a second.
What you need for mum's, bruh?
Let me get three
Dungeness crabs.
From the back, bruh.
Fat ones too...
So, you're having a fish fry
for New Years or something?
Yeah. Something like that.
I work here. I can help
you figure it out.
It's my day off.
Well, I'm cooking for a friend, tonight.
Before we go into the city..and..
He loves fried fish.
Like, Southern style...
Southern? He sounds
like, he's black?
He's white. But he knows a
lot of black people I guess.
I don't know, what
I've got myself into.
- Hello?
- Grandma...
Oscar? How're you doin' Baby?
I'm at my work, and this girl here...
You at booth? Yeah, grandma.
Bye. - No, no. Grandma,
it's my day off.
Alright? I'm shopping
for the party tonight.
I'm sorry baby. I thought
you were playing on the phone.
No, no. Grandma.
But, I do have a customer here. She wants
to have a fish fry but she don't know how.
You think, you can tell her
everythin' she needs to know?
No problem, baby.
What kinda fish
does she wanna fry?
Grandma, She don't know.
She don't now what kinda
fish she wants to fry?
No, grandma. No.
Put her on the phone.
- What's her name?
- Grandma Bonnie.
- Hi, Grandma Bonnie..
- Emi right there, bruh.
It's Katie..nice to meet you.
Hey, Good morning, Emi.
Oscar, what's going on?
Grab some stuff for
my mum's birthday.
I hope you found
everything that you need.
Yeah, I just wanna
talk to you for a sec.
It's a little nuts right
now, holiday and all.
Look, I wanna talk 'bout my job.
- The Position's been filled.
- Look, look Emi..
Look, I really need this job.
Alright.
Look, I was going through some shit, trying
to get back on my feet. You feel me?
But, I need this.
You can start me back off with one shift
a week or whatever. I'll be here.
You can work me 40 hours a
week and pay me for 20.
Dude. I hired somebody else.
For me to bring you back, that means
I have to let someone else go.
Someone... Who's never
showed up late, once.
I'm sorry,
I like you man, but
I can't do that.
You want me selling dope, bruh?
Oscar,
You need me outside,
to get it done, bruh?
Take care of yourself.
Hey!
I'm an expert now.
Sure you got
everything you need?
I've got everything, thank you.
No problem.
Here you go.
I am Katie, by the way.
Oscar.
Happy new year.
What's up bruh?
- Emi was good.
- Putting you back on?
Starting next week.
Take it easy man. We'll celebrate tonight.
Can you not be late?
Don't worry about that, man.
Keep your nasty phone.
- Be safe, bruh.
- Yup.
- Hello?
- Hey, chump! What's up?
- What you doing?
- Just got back from the job.
I thought you were off today.
I am.
- You call Mum yet?
- Yeah, did you?
Yeah.
I got good news and bad news.
Give me the bad news first.
I'm gonna need help with
the rent for this month.
How much?
Like $300. But, I can get you
back in a couple of weeks.
Okay. So, What's the good news.
I'm doing overtime tonight.
Come on Chantay.
I gotta do it.
Plus, Mums understands.
But I need you to get her a card
for me and sign it alright.
All right.
And Osc, don't get me a fake ass
card with white people on it.
I want a black card.
All right. I got you.
All right.
I love you, alright.
Love you too, scrub.
Whatever, bye.
What's up wit it, Osc?
What's up bruh? My bad
about last night.
You still trying to get that?
Yeah, but I ain't out that way though.
I'ma be in the Town all day.
It's cool, I'm
coming to you, bruh.
All right.. Meet me over
there by the water.
Right off of 80. Give
me like an hour.
- All right, bet that.
- Bet.
Hey, hey. Slow down.
Hey, slow down. You
beched motherfucker.
Somebody help!
Alright, give me your hand.
Ear.
Hair..
And your mouth.
Alright, turn around.
Bend over... squat.
It's alright, you're good.
Happy Birthday.
What happened to your face?
You look nice today.
My girls come over last night?
We played board games.
I bet, Y'all let her win too.
Of course.
Y'all hella weak for that. She
gets no easy wins around me.
What?
Remember that microwave
popcorn you bought a while back?
Hella good.
Yeah. While I was
putting it into a bowl.
Tatiana's just standing there..
Staring up at me;
Looking like she
wants something.
Okay, what? Come on Mum.
She says..
"Grandma, do we have
any dark butter?"
What's Dark butter?
I'm thinking, maybe she watch
"Food Network" or something.
So I say, "what's dark
butter sweetheart?"
She says, "When Daddy took me to see
WALL.E he asked for light butter",
so I want to try some
dark butter this time."
She too smart.
This mums right here?
She a snitch to?
What the Fuck you say about my Mum bruh?
Fuck you and that bitch.
Yeah, You tough in here with these guards.
I'm gonna see ya bitch ass outside bruh.
Is there a problem here?
Naw, we good.
Yeah, we good for now.
Calm down.
Calm... down!
Oscar...
What happened to your face?
Dark butter.
She always listening? Too
damn smart for her own good.
The preschool said we should think
about starting her in school early.
Phina tell you that?
Yeah, we're gonna put
her in private school.
Uniforms...
I was looking at St. Bede
the other day. It's this
other school that starts
them off learning Spanish,
and they back going on English - -
I'm not coming to see you anymore.
What?
I'm not coming here, to these visits
anymore. This is the last time.
I know I know I know. This is my
last time too. I told you that.
I ain't going down no more. You want to
keep putting SOPHINA through this...
you go on right ahead. Okay?
But Tatiana,
that baby doesn't
deserve this, Oscar.
She don't know what's going on.
So, I guess that's why she
asked me why you love
taking your vacations
more than being with her.
She ain't say that.
So I'm the liar now.
Ma you gotta tell her
that I love her.
Tell her, I ain't gonna leave her.
Tell her yourself!
The Next time you call home
you tell her yourself.
Or better yet, let her
come visit you here.
- She don't need to be exposed.
- You've already exposed...!
You've already exposed her to this.
So, you gonna leave me?
You gonna leave me again,
What kinda Mum is you?
You wanna fuck around
and leave me in here?
You ain't never have my
fuckin' back anyway.
I'm being here by myself.
I love you Oscar.. I do.
And, I'm praying for you.
I'll see you when you get home.
Ma, hold up. Let
me get a hug, Ma.
- Grant.
- I can't get a hug?
Ma, let me get a hug..Ma!
Hey Ma, I'm sorry!
Ma, I'm sorry!
Bruh I didn't think we
was ever gonna link up.
- What's good?
- Just new..
I got good news and
bad news my nigg.
Don't tell me you ain't got it.
- Sold it to a white boy.
- For real..For how much?
- Gave me a rack for it.
- I wasn't gonna pay that high.
But, I still needed that
though... What's the good?
- For you driving out.
- Right on Osc.
- It's good bruh.
- You sure?
Take it.
Right on.
Burn one with ya boy
right quick though.
That's all you bruh.
Alright, bruh. Peace...
I'm movin'.
What kinda cake is it?
Carrot cake.
Why you didn't get ice cream?
'Cause it ain't your birthday.
You know it would be hella easier if you
just had your stuff at my spot right.
When you gonna move in.
Maybe, when you stop having trees
in the car before we pick up T.
Can you roll down
the window, please?
Hey T. T, come here.
- We played "Freeze Tag" today.
- Really?
- Did you win?
- They couldn't catch me.
You think you're fast.
Faster than Daddy?
Really?
What's that?
- What are you doing?
- What you mean?
Can watch T tonight?
We gonna go to Frisco.
Ask your sister.
But Rose got hella kids to watch.
But what's the difference between
watching six kids or watching seven kids?
Quieres pasar la noche con sus primos?
Si, Si.
Daddy, what's that
on your shirt?
Daddy had an accident at work.
How's work? By the way.
Work is... work.
I'll be back.
What you think?
It's cool.
There a shirt on the bed
for you, if you want.
Are you alright?
Osc. What's up?
Fuck it.
I lost my job.
For what?
Being late.
Missed a couple days when
I had to get some money.
They told you today?
On your day off?
Keep it real, they
told me two weeks ago.
My bad Phina.
I though I was gonna
get my job back.
- I thought I could talk to Emi...
- You think life a fucking joke...
You think you're gonna get fired and then
somebody is gonna give you their job back?
What?
You ain't shit, you know that?
You lie to me, you lie to
your fucking daughter.
I didn't have to
tell you nothing!
I could have kept gettin' it.
I don't wanna know shit.
So you would have
just kept faking..
You been out busting nocks?
And doing whatever
else, or WHOEVER else you
do while I'm at work?
You ain't even listening to me.
Not after you lie for two weeks get
cornered, and don't have a choice.
That's some pussy act shit.
What did you today.
I bet you sold that fucking zip.
I dumped that shit, Phina.
That's what I'm
trying to tell you.
I'm tired.
Thought I could start fresh. But
that shit ain't working like that.
You threw a whole zip of weed.
And you don't got a job.
I could slap you right now.
What are you gonna do?
Something legal.
Maybe if I can just not
fuck up, for 30 days..
That's how long Oprah said
to form a habit, right?
Look at me.
Don't make me have to do
this shit alone, again.
You guys are just in time.
My God, you guys got a cake too?
Thank you baby.
Baby, You know all I needed was two, you
didn't have to spend so much money.
You Ain' gotta worry about that.
A Raiders fan, cheering
for the Steelers.
Yes, A Raiders fan,
cheering for the Steelers.
Black uniforms,
black players, black coach.
Coach even has a black wife.
I'm going with the Steelers.
You're insane, you know that?
Thanks for your help tonight.
Come on Ma, You
ain't gotta thank me.
You shouldn't even
be doing this.
Relax.
If you say so.
I say so.
You guys got plans for tonight?
Yeah, nothing major though.
I'll meet up with the fellas.
Head out to the city.
You guys gonna go OUT OUT? Or..
Its gonna be low key.
Catch the fireworks Probably
roll around a bit after that.
Roll around?
Yeah, it's gonna be
cool though, Chill.
Plus, Sophina's got work
in the morning anyway.
You guys gonna be drinking?
Mum, there ain't gonna be drinking.
I haven't had drinks in since..
I can't even remember.
Why don't you take
the train out there?
That way you guys can drink and hang out,
and not have to worry about anything.
No traffic either.
You know its gonna be crazy.
Going and coming back.
Yeah, we might take it.
Don't make me follow
you guys to make sure.
Remember Prom.
I'm tryin' to forget.
We gotta go. We're
gonna go, okay.
I love you.
Love you too.
Happy Birthday.
Happy new year.
Happy new year!
You don't want to
just call it a night?
I'm going out.
I don't know what
you're doing, but..
I'm going to Frisco.
You're too drunk.
Alright.
Happy New Year!
Come on Osc, I just got
them ready for bed...
You ready to brush those teeth.
No.
No?
Cos if you don't,
your teeth gonna rot and your
breath to smell like gumbo?
- You want that?
- Yes.
No you don't. Because then-THE.
You had gumbo, too.
Me and Mum are gonna
take off, okay?
You guys aren't gonna
sleep over too?
We already promised our friends
we are gonna kick with 'em tonight.
But, We'll be back before
you wake up though, okay?
No! Don't go.
I'm scared.
Scared of what?
I hear guns outside.
You know what, baby?
Those are just firecrackers.
You'll be safe inside,
with your cousin.
But what about you Daddy?
Me?
Baby, I'll be fine.
I'll tell you what, though.
When we wake up in the morning,
we'll play "Candyland".
And then guess what
we can do after that?
- Go to the park?
- Better.
"Toys'R'Us?"
Way, Better than that.
What?
I don't know, maybe...
Chuck e Cheese's.
Really?
I promise.
Daddy's gonna give you heck of tokens
and we'll play all the games.
Maybe, we'll get you
ya favourite pizza.
I want you to eat it all up.
Even Mummy, cos she
can't have carbs.
What's a carb?
You ain't gotta worry
about that right now.
I love you.
Love you too Daddy.
Osc, Osc! Take a shot
for the New Year nigga.
Happy new years, motherfuckers.
Happy new year, you too.
You know it's illegal to smoke
"Blacks" on Bart right?
Is that right officer?
We'll let you slide 'cause
its holiday and all.
I like your dreads.
I like your everything.
We need to put it together.
We gay.
Shit, we gay too.
Y'all not gay.
Hey Osc, bruh...
- Ain't we gay?
- They Gay as Fuck!
TRAIN OPERATOR Now approaching...
West Oakland Station.
Sorry folks, there's gonna be a slight
delay while we sort out an issue.
We Gon Miss the countdown.
We ain't gonna Miss shit, we can
get it cracking right.. here.
- Hey, you got a watch?
- Yeah.
Hey bruh, Turn the
music off bruh!
Seven..six, five..four..three...
What's up bruh? You got a
bathroom that we can use?
I'm all closed up, man, I don't
even have a bathroom for customers.
But I'm sure, you got a bathroom
for your employees though, right?
Tell you bruh, I ain't
rich at all; You feel me?
This my last ten dollars.
Now you can take this $10,
let them use the bathroom.
Or you could go home,
Come back tomorrow, there's gonna
be a hell of piss right here,
'Cause they ain't gonna piss
on themselves. You feel me?
Look at her.
- Just these two girls?
- Just these two girls.
Okay, Come on in. Just
watch your step.
Thank you.
Don't worry about it, man.
Happy New Year.
Please tell me this
place has a bathroom.
She pregnant...
Okay, come on.
Thank you.
- No more.
- That's it.
Promise, the last one.
Thanks a lot, man.
- No problem.
- Appreciate that.
Thought she was gonna
have to go in the street.
Nah, we had the same problem.
How long y'all been married?
Eight years.
You thinking about it?
What's stopping you?
No Money.
Shitty reason.
We had nothing, When
we got married.
No shit.
I wasn't working at all..
And she's a teacher, which is practically
the same thing as far as money.
How'd you get the ring?
I stole it.
I told you, I had no money. Nothing.
I used to be good with credit cards.
I wouldn't go that route
if I were you though man.
Nah, I'm cool on that.
Then, I got my business started.
Got her a ring that she wears now.
What you do?
I own a web design company.
Hit me up, if you
ever need anything.
Peter?
- Oscar.
- Alright, Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too, bruh.
Here they come.
- You good?
- Yeah.
It was nice meeting you guys.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks again.
- No problem.
- You take care.
Happy new year, bruh.
Announcer Next stop,
FRUITVALE Station.
Hey, Oscar!
Katie, from the store.
Hey.
How are you?
I'm good... I'm good.
Happy new year.
Oscar from fucking Palma Ceia.
What the fuck shit
you hollering.
Fuck all that shit, Alright!
This ain't the time bruh.
Osc, what's up?
Hey Phina, Get Cato and them niggas!
Fuck ass, South side niggas.
We gotta get off
this train bruh.
Just please, get back on
the train, get back on
- the train...
- Alright, meet me at the Hayward.
Hey, boys div up.
Split up, alright.
Get your hands off your pocket.
You too, let's go.
Get over there!
That ain't even real police man.
Get down.
If you're involved in the fight,
get off the fucking train now!
Don't make me come in
there and pull you off!
You. Get off the train.
I ain't do shit.
Alright, bruh. I hear you.
What you doing man?
You arresting us? Cos we ain't do shit.
What the fuck you's gonna hold us.
That's what I've been
saying, this whole time.
She don't want to
listen to me, cute ass.
Hey, shut up!
Where are your friends at?
We ain't got no friends.
I see one of those
punks right now.
On the platform,
in need of backup.
Four suspects apprehended.
Sit down! Sit down!
You gonna sucker
punch me like that?
All right, okay. What's up?
I said, shut the fuck up.
And put that phone away.
You keep these assholes secured, I'm
gonna check the train for witnesses.
I got you.
Put the fuckin' phone away.
I'm good, I'm good.
Phina, what's up? Osc, where you at?
Are you still on the train?
Hell Naw, we still up
here at FRUITVALE.
They holding us here and
beating on us for shit.
Who the fuck is beating on you?
The fucking police.
I'm about to get us up out of here
though. I'ma hit you back, okay?
It's cool bruh, I'm gonna
get us out of here, bruh.
- Stay down.. stay down!
- Let me talk to..let me...
We good bruh. We good bruh.
They can hold us here as
long as they want but
they can't arrest us
bruh, we ain't do shit.
I said, we ain't do shit. You
can't fucking arrest us.
Cuff these two assholes.
They're going to jail.
We just trying to get home.
Maybe, you should have
thought about that before
you started acting
like a punk ass bitch.
Man you a bitch ass
nigga, for real.
Are you calling me
a bitch ass nigga?
Bitch ass nigga.
You shot me... bruh.
You shot me. I got a daughter...
Get up, bruh!
Shot fired. Code 3.
What the fuck happened?
You shot me.
You stay right here.
I have a daughter.
Get your eyes up.
The police, they got Oscar and them...
I heard something I don't know if
it was a beanbag or a taser...
Is Oscar there with you?
Naw, he upstairs, with the Police.
Did Oscar get arrested?
I don't know, but I
think so, Wanda.
Okay, I'ma call you back.
Who's that for?
Why can't you tell
me what's going on?
What is the problem? Tell
me, what's going on?
Jason! Jason! What happened?
- What happened?
- They fucking shot him, Phina!
They shot him in the fucking
back for no reason man!
Where is Oscar?
Where is he?
What is going on?
Oscar can you hear me?
Please... Please.
My boyfriend is...
My boyfriend is up there, okay.
You don't understand.
You need to let me up there.
Wanda. I'm trying to get up, but
they are not letting me up.
My God!
What did you do to him? Did
you fucking killed him?
What did you do to him?
I need to check he's okay.
Where are they taking him?
- Where are they taking him?
- He's going to Highland.
Get off me!
Wanda, They shot Oscar!
They say he alive, but
his eyes was closed.
They taking him to Highland, you
gotta come and get us right now.
I'm on my way.
Fuck.
- What you got for me?
- 22 years old male,
scapula GSW. He was lying
face down when he was shot.
On three. One..two... three.
- What's blood pressure?
- 72 solid.
- Was he moving his limbs?
- Yes, moving arms and legs.
I'm gonna need a chest tube.
We gotta get him
upstairs, right away.
Excuse me.
My son is Oscar Julius Grant III. He's
been shot, and they told me to come here.
N-T. Yes.
Okay, he's in surgery. Go to the
ICU and someone will be out soon.
- And then, where?
- Right there.
Is that blood in?
Scissors.
Suction.
Hey, listen. None of that.
None of that.
It's not the time or the place.
Hey, we gotta keep him positive.
We gotta. We gotta let these
people do their job.
He's gonna be fine.
Let's put all our energy
toward Oscar right now.
I know y'all are upset.
We gotta lift him up.
Let's keep him lifted up.
- Mrs. Johnson?
- Yes.
How is he? How is he?
Mrs. Johnson, as you know..
Your son has been shot.
We've stabilized him,
but he's critical.
Critical. What is that?
Well, he has massive internal bleeding
and we had to remove the right lung.
His lung? How is he... How is
he going to be able to breathe?
He's on a breathing
machine, right now.
His breathing is stable.
The main problem is the
internal bleeding.
We've had some difficulty
stopping the bleeding..
That's getting his
blood to clot.
He hasn't fully responded
to the transfusions, yet.
But he's going to make it right?
But he's going to make it.
I promise you, we're gonna
do everything we can okay?
Please do whatever
you can, please.
We gotta lift him up, you all.
We gotta lift Oscar up.
You all, let's pray.
Heavenly father...
We kneel before you..
And ask you..
To put your healing hands
around your child.
We ask you dear Lord...
to operate through
these doctors;
Breathe strength into their hands
Lord, as they work on him.
We are asking you right
now, to heal him.
Heal him Lord, so we can hold
him and see his smile again.
In your name, we pray. Amen.
He didn't make it.
I need to see him.
Okay, you can see him.
But they don't want you go
into the room and detach him.
Cos they ruled it a homicide.
I need to see him.
- I can take her.
- Okay.
I told him to catch the train.
I told him to catch Bart!
I didn't know they
were gonna hurt him.
I should have just
let him drive.
I should have let him drive.
I wanted him to be safe.
You gotta let me hug him.
Please, let me hug him. Please.
He didn't like to be alone!
Come on, T.
Where's Daddy?