We're almost there.
Is that supposed
to make me stop?
You're gonna make me crazy.
I'm gonna have to pull over.
So pull over.
Lauduree!
Trying to sleep.
Did gigi call?
Yeah.
What'd you tell her?
The truth.
Shit! Ree!
Just kidding.
You're not gonna believe what
happened... my phone died.
It jumped right out of the canoe
into the lake, and Tommy tried...
Okay.
Good night, my little boobaloo.
Good night,
my little sugar booger.
Thanks, Ree.
Did you have fun?
Yeah.
Then what's wrong?
He's here now, and I just want
to cuddle up.
Well, can't you tell him
to go home?
Yes.
Y'all having a slumber
party in here!
Tommy, I am tucking
my daughter in.
Can I watch?
That is so wrong!
Tommy, this is Lauduree.
She's gonna save
the world someday.
Hi.
Oh, you're waiting for me,
Aren't you, sweetie?
Okay, I'll just be one minute.
Okay, rooster.
Did you water your plants?
Did you water your trees?
Uh-huh.
Do you forgive me?
Okay, guys.
Here is your extra
credit question,
and you have 15 minutes
to answer.
Why...
Does science matter?
For makin' babies!
Actually, Alex,
that's an excellent answer.
And if you guys can
answer that using science,
you will get 25 extra points,
which you guys need, 'cause
your test scores are dismal.
So, not a great way to start
the year, guys, okay?
See you guys writing...
already. Good.
"Science says that
everything around us
"has an invisible reason
for existing:
"The sky...
"Electricity..."
"Chlorophyll..."
"The color of someone's irises."
"Science brings me
closer to the world."
"Science is also the only way
we're going to figure out"
"how to make our planet
safe for future generations."
"Solutions for global warming
"must be researched now.
We're at the tipping point."
"Dear Lauduree...
"I went to California
to follow my dream
"of becoming a makeup artist
for the stars."
"I left you $50
for food and other things."
"I want you to call grandma."
"This is not goodbye forever."
"Love, Mom."
Hey, hon. Just stopping by
to say hi.
Hi.
Your mom wanted me to check
on you on my way to work.
Wait a minute, my phone.
Hey.
I-I can't hear you, the reception's
bad out here. Hang on.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I have a test tomorrow.
Well, if your mom forgets to come
home tonight, you call me.
She's doing 'mary kay.'
I know what she's doing, hon.
Have her call me.
Consider that my
rain dance for the day.
As the heat wave continues,
we'll try to keep you cool
here at WUXI.
Mom.
Pretty pro, huh?
Boo!
La la la la! Stupid asshole
piece of shit!
Screw you! Fuck you!
Oh. Hi.
I didn't see you sitting there.
My name is Neel.
I just moved here.
Lauduree's very pretty.
Where'd it come from?
My mom made it up.
She was obsessed
with french things.
Is she not alive anymore?
No.
What are you reading?
An article that says
that the buildup
of carbon dioxide
is killing off coral.
It's poisoning
their food source,
so they're spitting out
their own tissue
and starving to death.
It's why they're turning white.
Are you going to the Science
Club meeting tomorrow?
I'm trying to read.
Ms. Markovi's really cool.
I think she's Macedonian.
I'll save you a seat.
Hey, it's Tanya and Ree.
Leave us a message
after the beep.
Hey, girls, it's Gigi.
I'm inviting y'all
for dinner tomorrow.
Ed, his daughters,
and the grandkids
are making a special trip
down from Owensboro.
I got really good news.
Okay, call me. Bye.
Hey.
Yeah, I just gotta go get
something from my locker.
Hey, how's it goin', buddy?
How's my little science
nerd doing today?
Huh? Huh? You like my
armpits, creep?
- They stinky? They stinky?
- Oh, nice! From gym class!
Look me in the eye! Look
me in the eye, butt wad!
- It's trash girl!
- Trash girl!
It's trash girl.
Is she gonna save us?
- She can't do it...!
- Leave him alone.
Gettin' your girlfriend
to fight your battles.
I'll kick your balls, piss ant.
Did she just say piss ant?
Let's go. Let's leave this loser
for someone else
to take care of, huh?
Do you need me
to call a teacher?
So... welcome to Science Club.
We have two brave souls.
You like raisins?
You?
Good.
And we will get started.
Biodiversity.
You know what that is,
right, guys?
The number of plant and animal
species in the ecosystem.
Right. What's the plainest language
we can put that in?
Life.
Yeah. Biodiversity.
What else do we know
about biodiversity?
It's being threatened by global warming.
Yep. Mmhmm.
What are some other threats? Neel?
Polution.
Deforestation.
Mmhmm. And the list could go on.
So most scientists agree
that the rate of species
loss is greater
than it's ever been
in human history.
I mean, this is a big deal.
This is something that scientists should
be talking about more, right?
And we're not.
So my challenge to you
as young scientists is,
how do you guys propose
we get the data
out of the laboratory
and into the community?
By telling people?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
We need to tell people.
But more than that,
we need to involve people,
'cause that's where stuff
starts to happen.
So what I thought we would do
is something called
community interventions,
where we take these field trips...
I... I started...
a science project
in the spring already.
I didn't know we were
gonna do a group one.
Oh! Well... tell us about it.
Well, my hypothesis is
that in our region,
the loblolly pine affixes more
carbon dioxide yearly
than the red oak.
Great.
So you're trying to use
photosynthesis.
To pull CO2 out of
the atmosphere.
- It's a great premise.
- Yeah.
Whichever species
uses the most CO2
could be planted as
forests in our region
to reverse the effects
of global warming.
This is something scientists are
talking a lot about right now.
However, from what I've
read about carbon sinks,
which is what you're
trying to create,
more forests can
actually raise temps.
I haven't been looking
at temperature change
because the trees are too small.
What you're proposing is
extremely complicated.
I mean, there is
a lot of variables.
It's very tricky to model,
even for scientists,
especially with climate patterns
becoming so unpredictable.
Lauduree.
I-I thought your mom
was picking you up.
I forgot, she has
to work on thursdays.
Well, get into the car.
I'll take you home. Come on.
We can change the meeting night.
I can call your mom.
I decided I'm not doing science
club this year. - Why?
I've spent too much time
with my tree data.
I'm not giving up now.
I mean, we're gonna learn a
lot about conservation issues.
I know you're interested in
that from your extra credit.
Neel's really smart.
I think you guys would
make a great team.
I don't work with partners.
Who wants a burger? Huh?
Greta, honey? You coming back?
Hey, you've reached
my voicemail.
I'm waiting for your
secret message.
Well, here's my secret message:
Ed and I are moving.
I'll send you a postcard.
Same time next week?
You like it in the ground.
I'd sleep out here
with you tonight,
but I can't risk a tick bite.
Can you believe
how good she looks?
Do you sell light bulbs?
Right there.
You want one?
Nah, it's okay.
Total is $19.72.
I think these have expired, hon.
Hold on. Let me talk to
the manager a second.
Will you give me a ride?
Sure.
Hey! Ernesto! Hey!
Did you get any I.D.?
- Whoo!
- Hot damn!
That was like fate
that I was there!
Yeah, that was awesome.
Thanks for the ride.
Sure. I won't tell
your mom, but...
Is she here?
No.
Listen, honey,
they're not gonna
press charges, okay?
But the deal is, I need to speak
to a guardian.
What about your dad?
I don't have one.
All right, I guess you'd better get
started on your homework, then.
If your mom's not
back in an hour,
I'm gonna have to take you
down to the jail.
I need to file a report.
You got somebody you wanna call?
No.
So why are these things so
expensive? They last longer?
Looks like you're in luck.
What happened?
- You Mrs. Cready?
- Yes.
Well, we picked up your
daughter for shoplifting.
Tanya!
There's not gonna be any charges...
but, you know, you may
wanna keep an eye on her.
And next time I see you, you'd better
be giving your valedictorian speech.
Valedictorian?!
She's a terrible thief.
What's going on?
I shoplifted.
I can see that.
Why were you shoplifting,
and more importantly,
where is your mother?
Do you know that Roy called me,
and the goddamn rent check
is late again.
The district manager requested
her for a bachelorette party.
They... they liked her best.
- How'd you get to the store?
- I walked.
You walked two goddamn miles
to shoplift a light bulb?
I like walking.
Where's your vanity?
Huh? Where is it?
Mom loaned it to Juanita
for the miss apple pageant.
Where... where's the TV?
It broke. No, you shouldn't
go back there.
Why? - Something really
bad happened.
- Roy was supposed to...
- Oh, really?
- What happened, huh? What?
- It was really bad.
You better tell me what's going on,
Lauduree,
or I'm gonna find it
out for myself!
She moved.
She what?
She moved to California!
I'll see you in hell, Tanya.
I haven't seen
Mr. banana in years.
Want me to lay with you
till you fall asleep?
You must be feeling
pretty crummy.
I'm here if you want
to talk about it.
Right.
What were you planning doing
out here all by yourself?
Living.
Aren't you afraid
it'd get lonesome?
You live alone.
I have, for a long time.
I don't want to leave my home.
I don't blame you, hon.
Let's not talk about it tonight.
We're wiped out.
Let's get some rest.
We'll talk about it
in the morning, okay?
No, it's not.
It's based on evidence.
Hey, Ree, you up?
Yeah, I'm just working
on a report.
- Well, what time's your bus?
- No, there's no more debate.
Just follow the hot spots.
Listen to me. Spring is happening...
Ree!
Hon, you're talkin'
in your sleep.
What time is it?
It's 6:45. Let's go.
I don't like to lollygag,
so I'm gonna spend the day
doing stuff around here.
Like what?
Well, I gotta pack up everything
to move it to my house.
- Now, I talked to Roy, and he said...
- When did you talk to Roy?
Well, earlier this morning.
- Did he call?
- I called him.
Thought you said we would
talk about it in the morning.
Lauduree, there is
nothing to talk about.
You are 13 years old.
You cannot live here on
your own. That is it.
Why?
Well, for one thing,
the criminal life
doesn't seem to be working
out so well for you.
I told you, I'm working
as a tutor to pay the rent.
- What is it? You don't like me?
- I like you.
Then what is so bad about
coming to live with me?
I can't leave my research.
Lauduree, you are
not a scientist.
You are a minor
without a mother.
I am in the middle
of finding out.
That fix a greater
proportion of CO2
in the atmosphere than oaks.
If you make me leave now,
I'll have to abandon
six months' of data.
Lauduree, look,
I know that you are an extremely
self-sufficient girl,
but even if I could abide you
living out here on your own,
the state would come in,
and they would take you away
and place you in a foster home.
Now, is that what you want? Huh?
And anyway, I am not gonna be
around here to bail you out.
Ed and I are movin'.
- What?
- Yeah.
To Florida, just as soon
as the house sells.
I'm not going.
Well, you can take
those trees with you.
No, I can't, because pinus taeda
will not survive in
a tropical climate.
And guess what?
We're running out of time!
Well, you really don't have any
choice in the matter, do you?
Do you realize the situation
your mother's placed us in?
You had a piece of
hair sticking up.
It looked cool.
How do you know they'll survive?
I think they'll do just fine.
Can't promise, though, can you?
No, Ree, I can't,
because there are all sorts
of things in this world
that are beyond my control.
Like what?
Like a fungus.
Or you could mow them over
like you did mom's stargazers.
That was a mistake
for christ's sake.
Just tie a ribbon around them,
they'll be just fine.
Not if you've tied 'em on.
I'm gonna get ya!
Hey, you want me
to make you a scar?
- Nah.
- Yeah? Come on!
Don't be such a fuddy-duddy.
I'm not. I just don't
like looking weird.
Well, I'll make you
look pretty, then.
I don't want to look
pretty, either.
What do you want to look like, then?
Mom.
- Mom.
- Hmm-hmm?
Mom, look what I found.
Pretty.
Will you take my picture?
Sure.
Where'd you get this?
Tommy.
I gotta get my
portfolio together.
Tout de suite, cherie.
This is the big time.
Mew. Another. I wasn't ready.
Okay. Okay.
Cheese!
Hey. I'm gonna
smoke a cigarette.
Why don't you go on in
and say goodbye?
I'm just saying,
don't bug me about that.
Don't...
I'm sorry. I'm not mad. No...
I'll call in to work.
No, what are they gonna say?
Yeah. I know.
I'll call you back. Bye.
Thanks, Ed. It's, um...
It's really big.
You're welcome.
So what's this I hear about your
mom driving to California?
She wants to be a makeup artist.
Well, I just want to say,
Ree, how sorry I am.
She's not dead.
What'd she say?
She didn't die, Ed.
That's awful, Ree. I would
never say something like that.
Hon, you want to
start up the grill?
Sure.
Oh... I got you this too.
Thought you might like it.
Everybody's doing the
best that they can,
and you'd better rise
to the occasion, hon.
Real page-turner, huh?
What's happening now, Ree?
They're lost.
Everyone back at base camp
thinks they've either
died of hypothermia
or eaten each other.
Ooh.
Now, you want to do
something like that?
Work at a weather station
under perilous conditions?
It's just a story.
Well, sure, but...
I mean, people really do
do stuff like that, you know?
You could definitely get that
kind of training in Florida.
And it's a lot warmer
than the Himalayas.
Anyplace is warmer
than the Himalayas, Ed.
The Himalayan glaciers
are actually melting faster than
any glacier in the world,
and over a billion people
depend on them for water.
- A billion.
- Hmm.
Your grandma hates
the cold, don't you, hon?
I live through it.
Every year, Ed.
Ree, did you know
that the Kennedy Space Center
is in Florida, and they have got
every kind of research facility
that you can think of.
As a matter of fact,
right next door to my condo
is the school for meteorology,
Which is global warming, Right?
Weather patterns.
I'm more interested in
wilderness preservation.
Florida is a wilderness paradise.
Ree...
One of the sharpest kids
that I have ever met.
- What do you want to do?
- You just asked her that, Ed.
Well, no, Greta, I did not.
Whatever it is that
you are after,
you need to promise yourself,
make a promise to yourself
that you will try to get there.
In case you haven't noticed, Ed,
we are not in the mood for one
of your motivational speeches
because we are sucking lemons.
'Course, if we were Himalayan,
we'd be making lemonade,
and we'd be grateful.
What do you think, Ree?
I think Florida's gonna be
underwater in 30 years, Ed.
Yeah, that book?!
That book now?!
Yeah, well, I thought the book
would be a good idea.
Just lookit. She's interested.
- Death and Mayhem.
- I know, I know!
What do you wanna do?
There's so much
tension in this house.
I know. You're smoking again!
I don't even want to know
what kind of a wreck
you would be
if you had to look after
little Caleb and Courtney
all by yourself.
I suppose I would have
called the police.
Right! Because if Mandy
or Tina disappeared,
that would mean that
they had been kidnaped.
Mine, on the other,
disappeared her own goddamn self!
She ran away, Greta!
Ed, she's a 30-year-old
woman, she's not a runaway.
So I guess looking for her
is out of the question.
I didn't say that.
Well, Lauduree certainly
wasn't warm
to the idea of
moving to Florida.
Well... maybe it's better
if she just stays put.
What, so she can get
knocked up her junior year?
Ed, I'm just talking till
the end of the school year.
You could move in here.
My mom's coming back.
Whatever floats your boat.
Weather will spell
economic disaster
for many local farmers,
as extreme draught continues to
plague the tri-state area.
Mustard or mayo?
Dry.
Temperatures in the upper 90s.
That the prices of corn
and soy could soar.
How 'bout plants?
Very good.
Local plant or flower?
I'm ready to help.
Awesome.
We're just getting ready
to do interviews.
Let's go. Grab your backpack.
Okay.
Hi, I'm a member of the Central
School Science Club.
Would you have a minute
to tell us about
your favorite local
animal or insect?
I always loved butterflies,
the yellow kind
that look like tissue.
Oh, and of course, cicadas.
There's someone,
Lauduree. Go for it.
We're talking to people
in the community
about how environmental disruption...
Sorry.
I love horses. I love horses.
It's a passion of mine.
I love to ride,
and, you know,
I used to ride, like,
english, western, you know,
and then I went into bareback.
I like snapping turtles.
I remember him showing me
this beautiful,
snowy-white egret,
and... but, you know,
you don't see them
around here anymore.
You know, I haven't
seen any in... 14 years.
They used to come around
every summer.
I used to be able to
catch lake sturgeon
this big across't.
I haven't caught any
like that in 20 years.
What are you laughing at?
Pigtoes!
All right, so...
a pigtoe looks like, um...
looks like the...
Pleurobema Serlus.
Let me see.
"Habitats include
streams and creeks
in and around Jackson County
Nature Preserve."
That's right by my house.
"They ingest algae, bacteria,
and other detritus
in the water."
They're natural filters.
They keep the water clean.
It says here that
they're in danger.
Maybe we've found the hero
to our food web, guys.
They're primary consumers.
Their ecosystem is fragile.
Their habitat is endangered.
Endangered doesn't mean they're
past the point of no return, right?
No. Some mussels species have
lived over a hundred years.
If you find one in this draught,
you have a chance
at restoration.
Save the pigtoe!
Why not?
Hey, where did you buy
this lovely...?
They were on sale
at J.C. Penney!
Oh, he's taking advice
from strangers!
I can't believe you
bought this for me!
You should have seen the girl!
What did you say?
I said, "Oh, she's
about this big, and..."
"and she's..."
well... just...
I think they thought
it was for me!
Wait a minute. I am going to go over
to meet the boys at the VFW.
Would you like to buy a vowel?
- Oh. Hi, hon!
- What?
Hey! Hey...
She's a beauty, ain't she?
Darling, would you like to
join us on the veranda?
Come on, Ree, come on!
Come on out!
Smells like a skunk.
Honey, stay out here
and celebrate with us.
I got an offer on
the house today.
I have homework.
Lauduree?
Hi.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm...
it's just allergies.
Global warming's increasing
pollen count.
- What have you got there?
- It's my oak.
I'm staying with my grandma
'cause my mom's out of town,
so I had to move it.
The experiment's dead.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Do you need someplace
to plant it?
I guess we were thirsty.
Yeah, I guess so.
The mint's from my garden.
I can give you a bunch
to take home.
Also, I thought
you could use this.
Sometimes it helps to have
a camera in the field.
It's just a point-and-shoot.
Hey, if there's anything you want
from your mom's room,
take it, 'cause the rest,
goin' to Goodwill.
Ms. Markovi...
says that if Science Club goes
well next year,
she's taking a group
of us to Guatemala
to do a community
outreach program there.
Is Miss Markovi paying for this?
Miz. I don't know.
Well, why don't you ask
Miz Markovi about that
before she goes booking
trips to other countries.
Why don't you have a carwash?
I'd pay a buck for
a good carwash.
Carwashes poison rivers and
everything that inhabits them.
Well, lucky for you,
you're gonna be in Florida.
Aren't you going to
eat your broccoli?
- You're a crank.
- Hmm?
Nothing.
I-I thought you said that you
wanted to be a vegetarian!
No. I said...
that confined animal
feeding operations
are the largest cause
of greenhouse gases,
and that we should only buy
from small local farms.
I swear, you have
selective hearing.
Do not talk to me
that way, Lauduree!
I'm really tired of this
"miss know-it-all attitude."
Now, if you're gonna be
living in this house...
I didn't ask to live here!
You're right.
Where are you going?
It's none of your business.
Shot of maker's.
Hey, you seen a girl named
Tanya in here lately?
She's about this tall,
blonde hair, blue eyes,
real cute figure.
Crystal's friend.
That's the one.
Nah, I ain't seen
here in a while.
Crystal was in here
the other night, though.
She was showing me pictures
of her chihuahua.
Lucky you.
Them things are freaky.
Hello?
Hi, is Neel home?
This is Neel.
Is this Lauduree?
- Yes.
- Hi.
Do you want to find
some pigtoes tomorrow?
Let's get started, baby!
- Hey, Crystal!
- Whoo!
Hey!
I need to talk to you.
Oh, hey, Greta, I'm workin'.
You wanna come in for a drink?
No, not really.
Are you still working
nights at the V.A.?
Like a rat in a can.
So you got a number
where she's at.
- Who?
- Cut the crap, Crystal...
'Cause you know what
I'm picturing right now?
I'm picturing her real high on crank.
Good lord!
In a horse barn turned
into a meth lab
with the lowlife that
you turned her on to.
I'm gonna go back inside, baby.
Cruiser!
Look, Greta,
I'm in the same boat you are.
I haven't heard from her in two weeks,
and I'm worried to death.
I can tell when you're
lying, Crystal,
'cause you are the one that
taught Tanya how to do it.
Oh, little ol' me, huh?
I just wanna know
if she's alive.
Okay, I'm gonna level with you.
Ree thinks she's dead.
She won't eat. She won't sleep.
She won't bathe.
She quit goin' to school.
I been thinkin' about
goin' to a psychiatrist.
Now, where am I gonna get
that kind of money?
Shit!
Told her she should have
just let me take her.
She wrote me some
dumb-ass letter.
It broke her heart, Greta,
honest to god, but you gotta
try and be proud of her.
She thinks she's doing
something right in her life.
You know how old I was
when I had my first beer?
12.
You know where I was?
Your basement.
Hey, I know your daddy.
There wasn't any shortage
at your place.
No pigtoes.
No pigtoes here, either.
Gotta find a spot
with deeper water.
Did you read that somewhere?
No.
But pigtoes need fish
to reproduce.
It was too shallow over
there for fish to swim.
You gotta get in.
It's just water.
- I found one.
- Where?
- Just kidding!
- Hey!
All right, stop, stop, stop.
You're gonna make
the water cloudy.
Look! I found one!
Really?
Don't touch it!
You need a permit.
Oh.
He's dug in there.
That's it.
I think I got it.
There's no way you're
catching up with me.
Do you want to go in?
No.
Should we wait here
till your mom gets back?
My mom ran away.
What do you mean?
I mean she packed up her
stuff and drove away.
I thought you said your mo...
I lied.
I didn't want you to make a big
deal about the whole thing.
We moved here when I was 5.
This was our first
house together.
Before that, we lived
at my grandma's.
Is that where you live now?
What about your dad?
He was a business
student at Rend Lake.
He was killed in a motorcycle
crash when I was 2.
I never met him.
Will you take my picture?
Jesus!
Ree!
You scared me.
Lauduree.
Honey.
Come on, you gotta wake up.
You fell asleep in the kitchen.
For Pete's sake.
Fine. I don't care.
What you drinkin'?
A beer.
How come?
Well, 'cause I like it.
What are you doing up
past your bedtime?
You said I could.
I don't recall that.
You said it was a new
first date rule.
Lauduree, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Mom.
Remember that guy you
dated when I was 9?
He was bald and had a ponytail?
Good french inhale.
Jim Polecock.
Yeah, that's right.
He called Crystal Betty Grable,
- and you Gene Tierney.
- I didn't know that.
Yeah, 'cause you were
both beautiful.
But Crystal was an airhead,
and you were tragic.
God, if he only knew.
And he called Gigi Bette.
Bette for...
- Bette Davis?
- Yeah.
Huh.
Hey, do you remember
the nursing home?
Yeah.
They kicked you out, though,
'cause you made all the old
ladies look like movie stars.
God, they loved her there.
That was a great job,
and you know,
I got her that job.
She was at her best then.
Think you'll ever get married?
No.
Why?
'Cause I stay up late,
and they get up early.
Well, that's sorta dumb.
Yeah, well...
I don't trust men.
Why not?
I met a bad one once.
He kind of ruined the rest.
All right, come on.
Gotta get you up to bed.
It's okay.
It's grandma. It's Gigi.
- Gigi?
- Yeah.
Is mom here?
No, honey.
I... I was just talking to her.
Where'd she go?
It's just me.
It's all right. Come on.
We came down here
in the kitchen,
we had a nice little talk.
Your momma used to sleepwalk.
I used to find her
all around this house.
It's all right, honey.
You know, it's gonna be okay.
We just gotta tough it out.
What if we never see her again?
I want her to come back.
Hello?
Hey hey! What's
the banana, Popsicle?
I can't do it, Ed.
Darling, I'm on the green here
with lamb and the doc.
Can I call you back
this evenin'?
I can't uproot her again...
and I am through with
this long-distance stuff,
- so we're breaking up.
- Can I call you tonight?
- No, I'm working tonight.
- Call me when you get off.
- You'll be sleeping.
- I'll wake up!
You always say that, Ed,
and you never do it.
I will this time!
Listen, I am trying to find a time
when I can give you my...
I am breaking up with you!
- Made coffee.
- Wonderful.
Want some eggs?
Hon, I don't have
my stomach yet.
I called the realtor,
turned down the offer
on the house.
We're not moving to Florida.
Is Ed moving in with us?
I'm sick of Ed.
Thought everything
was going good.
Same as it's always been.
Do you know that we had to go
in front of the 'Queens
of Owensboro'
to get a blessing for this move?
Who are the Queens of Owensboro?
Ed's daughters.
They practically disowned him
when he even thought of buying
me an engagement ring.
He is spineless.
That sucks.
Yeah, it does. It sucks.
But it was my own goddamn fault
for thinking that this
was gonna work out.
There's a reason we've been
long-distance for 10 years.
But you know what?
You make your bed.
Your mom, when she was pregnant,
she begged me to
have an abortion,
and I said over my dead body
because I thought a child
would teach her
how to take care of herself.
What a joke!
She blows town,
leaves you with me.
Poetic justice.
Isn't that what they call it?
Isn't that what you get?
Where are you going?
Okay, I think it might be...
I think I left it on...
Lauduree.
What are you doing here?
How... how did you get in here?
Neel and I found
the crescent pigtoe.
Laudur, how did you
get into my house?
What's wrong?
This is my student, Lauduree.
Lauduree, this is
my husband, Paul.
Hi. Maybe you could
get us some water.
Sure.
You in trouble?
We found the pigtoe in a
stream near little grassy.
Okay. That's great.
It's not extinct,
so we could breed it
and reintroduce it
to a bigger river.
Lauduree.
Florida was a lie.
What do you mean?
I mean my mom's not taking
me there on vacation.
She moved to California.
Oh.
You know?
Your grandmother came to school.
She's very worried about you.
I can't stay with her.
Did something happen?
I thought I could
live here for a while.
You're the only one who gets
what's going on in the world.
I am not equipped
to deal with this.
Let me get you someone
to talk to, okay?
I don't need someone to talk to.
I need a place to stay.
You don't have any kids.
No, actually, we're
expecting a baby.
You trying to get
yourself killed?
Your car's already
doing the job, asshole!
And your selfish,
ignorant oil addiction!
What are you lookin' at, huh?
Are you ready for
23 feet of water
flooding the eastern seaboard?
You ready for refugees camping
out in your backyard?
What do you think the
future's gonna look like?
Tropical paradise?
Think it's gonna be
nice and warm?
Hell, there's not
gonna be any food.
Welcome to my future.
This is part of our problem!
Do you really need to buy
a new plastic water bottle
every day of your life?
It's made from oil,
the same stuff that gushed
into the Gulf of Mexico,
while we all just stood around.
Lauduree.
You are a hypocrite!
Why would you want to bring
a child into this world?
It's cruel, and you know it.
I was born with
a mother and a father,
and I don't know
where they went.
And that's how your kids
are gonna feel
when the shit hits the fan.
Lauduree!
It's time to come home.
I'm not getting in that car.
It's poison.
You're poison.
Hello?
Hey. Is Greta there?
One second.
Um... she's in the bathtub.
Can I take a message?
She hasn't picked up
for three days.
You, uh... you okay?
Yeah.
Not going to do that anymore.
I'm tired of being half here.
I'm tired of putting
my life on hold!
♪ Time heals
♪ Two thousand stomachaches
♪ If I get bored
♪ Every other day
♪ Are we to have
♪ Another century of guitar
♪ When the best instrument
♪ In the world
♪ Is still... ♪
Why are you wearing makeup?
It's an experiment.
What kind of experiment?
To see whether people
will treat me differently.
Are they?
You're the first
person I've seen.
Do you want people to
treat you differently?
That would be bias.
I can't introduce bias
into my experiment.
Do you think I'm attractive?
Yeah.
Do you think you could
like me forever?
Probably.
Then for the experiment,
I need you to kiss me.
Okay.
I still have that feeling.
Where is it?
In my chest.
What does it feel like?
Tight and panicky.
It's like I have no future.
Everything's your future.
Right this second is.
Can I kiss you,
to see if that has a result?
Oh, my god!
My baby! Come here!
Ohh...!
I came back for you, Ree!
I came back for you!
Shh. Shh.
Let me look at you.
You're a real lady now,
aren't you?
Feels like you've been
gone for a year.
Well, time moves
slowly when you're little.
I had to give up my project.
We'll just...
we'll start a new one
just as soon as you
get home, okay?
It's too late.
Ree, you're gonna be
so proud of me.
I've found us a place
by the beach,
in San Diego.
With a patio for your plants.
And it's real close to school,
so you can walk
without having to take the bus,
just like you're
always talking about.
And there is nature
everywhere in California.
Sound good?
Yeah?
Okay.
All right, will you just
help me up now?
Okay. Okay.
Okay, we gotta hustle,
though, okay?
Will you... will you just close
up that back right there?
Just give it a real good shove.
I was puttin' that TV
in the back,
and just as I was jumping out,
I thought I shouldn't
leave it loose like that.
It'll roll all around,
and I landed right on my ankle.
Ohh!
I just gotta think for a second.
Maybe you should take a nap.
A nap?
Oh, god.
We have to go, Ree!
What am I gonna do?
I killed it.
Just until Missouri.
Rooster! Rooster! Rooster!
Are you ready for
a whole new life, Ree?
- Let's do it.
- Okay.
All right, you've got it in park.
Now, let's turn that key.
That's it!
Now... put it in reverse.
Yeah, just take your
foot off the brake.
- You got it, Ree!
- Whoo-hoo!
See ya, suckers!
Wouldn't wanna be you!
Au revoir!
♪ I woke up
♪ I was already me
♪ I was somewhat afraid
♪ I was something
♪ Peace signs
♪ I told you I could
no longer see
♪ I was right in the fire
♪ I was on my knees
♪ peace signs ♪
Okay, I'll be just a minute.
You be good.
What was that? - Oh, yeah, you
know, it just started doing that,
So I thought we could
take it to, um,
this friend of mine,
just on the way out of town...
- who fixes cars.
- Mm-hmm.
It probably just needs some oil.
You know I'm an idiot when it
comes to that kind of stuff.
Oh, my god!
So guess who's gonna help
me pay for beauty school?
Mom, I don't know if
we should keep going.
My dad! I met my dad!
Thought no one knew
where he was.
He's got a whole new family.
- Forgot his daughter, Ree!
- Mom.
Mom, I need you to focus. I need
you to tell me what to do. Mom!
You need to cut her, Ree. Brake.
- I'm trying.
- Well, turn off, turn off.
Right here. Easy!
Goddamn it! What am I
supposed to do now?
Call a tow truck.
I can't afford a tow truck.
What was the $300 for, then?
To get back to California!
Give me your phone.
No, let's just wait
for somebody to stop.
Give me your phone. I know
someone who can help us.
I'm at the juncture
of 29 and 70.
Who was that?
It's fine.
You should stay off your foot.
California is beautiful, Ree.
You're gonna love it.
There's palm trees everywhere.
The beach is real close by.
I'm gonna get a convertible.
Custom-painted to match the sky.
Why didn't you tell me
about the truck?
Because I wanted everything
to be perfect
when I came to get you.
Let's go.
Did you call her, Lauduree?
Look, do not put this on her!
Get in the car!
Just stop ordering me around!
I would love to leave you by
the side of the road, Tanya.
It's up to you.
Just let me make a phone call.
- I am not waiting.
- Just wait!
Jesus Christ!
I swear to god, Tanya.
There is something
wrong with you.
I don't know whether I should call
the police department...
or the psych unit! Well, there's
no need to call anybody...
'cause I came to get
my daughter!
Well, what happened to you
out there, anyway, huh?
Did you lose all your cash?
You down to your
last plug nickel?
Get outta the car, Lauduree.
Give these to your Ma.
Lauduree, maybe you can tell me
why you were a half a mile away
from the gold post pawn shop.
Just tell her, mom.
She's gonna find out, anyways.
I found a diamond ring in an ashtray
in the bathroom, and I sold it.
Lauduree, go upstairs.
Go upstairs!
Ree, I love you.
Jesus Christ, mom.
Did you just think that was just,
like, some bauble?
From my bathroom?
- What is...?
- Stay out of my life!
I did not ask you to come
back here, did I?
I did not ask to come back here!
Well, then, why are you here?
Because she called you!
I told her not to.
I said I didn't need you!
I didn't want to be here!
Somebody in the family
has a brain.
Do you know that every
barfly in Jackson County
wants to be a makeup artist,
don't they?
But they have something
you don't, Tanya.
See, you're just saying that
because you hate me.
I don't hate you!
Tanya, you're just...
missing something.
I have tried for years
to give it to you.
I just don't know what
to do anymore.
The more you tell her that,
the more she believes it.
Okay, Ree, um, why don't you
go up and pack up your stuff,
'cause we're gonna sleep
at Crystal's tonight.
I'm not going with you.
What?
Okay. Now, look, baby.
It was a mistake to leave, okay?
I know that you're mad at me.
It was so, so, so selfish.
But now I'm back,
and we're gonna
have a great time
and be really,
really happy together.
I can't make you happy,
'cause it makes me a nothing,
it makes me a blank.
I'm your mom.
Why would I make
you a... a blank?
What is a blank?
I have no idea.
Can I go to the library?
Sure.
We're gonna be at the pawn shop.
I'm not giving up.
I'm gonna be right here
when you get back, Ree.
Okay.
- Now give me a kiss.
- Okay.
- I love you.
- Love you too.
I was about two minutes
away from calling the cops.
I'm sorry.
Your mom went out with Crystal.
She said she'd be back
to tuck you in.
Believe it when you see it.
What happened?
I stood by you.
What'd she say?
I told her I would take her to court,
if need be.
You know, I had a feeling
that she was gonna look up
that goddamn,
no-good son of a bitch.
Well...
Maybe it'll do her some good.
Who knows?
Why are you laughing?
I would have paid cash money
to have seen her dad's face.
When he opened up the door,
there she was.
That man was so stingy
that if he'd give you
a cigarette
and you didn't smoke it
right down to the filter,
he'd go pick it out of the
ashtray and suck on it,
and suck it like he
was suckin' lemons!
Well, maybe he's learned
a little bit since then.
Gigi...
Mmm?
I want to move to Florida.
You can't expect things
from people, Lauduree.
Ed loves you.
Okay, we're walking in a line.
Good, keep holding hands.
Oh, we have to share
the sidewalk.
Let's let this lady through.
Good job.
♪ Oh, where did you go
♪ When the snow
fell that year? ♪
Those from the camera
I gave you?
♪ These wooden walls
like a bear ♪
These look really great.
- Thanks.
- Great map.
This... this is the pigtoe
that Neel and I found,
right around here.
What are you having?
A girl.
What are you gonna name her?
June.
Do you have any other photos?
Yeah. I have...
- This one's a cicada shell...
- Yeah.
That I found right by my house.
- That's a great one.
- Oh, thanks.
And that was near it?
- Pine needles?
- Mm-hmm.
I like science
because it helps you
measure changes.
Changes so small...
they're barely visible
to the naked eye.
Ree!
All right, all right, I'm coming,
I'm coming. Hold on.
Whoo! Let's go!
Holdin' up the show, girl!
♪ Good night, darling
♪ Good night
♪ I hope
♪ You sleep well
♪ Good night, darling
♪ Good night
♪ I wish
♪ I could be there
♪ Hear you breathing
♪ And watch
♪ Your chest
♪ Rise and fall
♪ Wrap around you
♪ You are
♪ The same length
♪ As me
♪ I was young when
♪ I first
♪ Heard about
♪ Something called love
♪ Someone told me
♪ It was
♪ Like finally waking up
♪ 'course I laughed then
♪ But now
♪ You could say
♪ I believe
♪ If I were smarter
♪ I'm sure
♪ I'd write you
♪ A symphony
♪ I barely know you
♪ But I feel I've
♪ Loved you before
♪ And I want to show you
♪ This loose board
♪ In the floor
♪ This is where I
♪ Keep my heart
♪ Yes, this is
♪ Where I
♪ Keep my heart
♪ Not on my sleeve
♪ Nothing's certain
♪ I know
♪ But I like
♪ To believe
♪ Something out there
♪ Somewhere
♪ Intends us
♪ To be
♪ I'll keep standing
♪ Right here
♪ Just as proud
♪ As april pie
♪ Your eyes are colored
♪ In shades
♪ Of copper and malachite
♪ This song
♪ Is simple
♪ But it's the best
♪ I can do
♪ 'cause it ain't so simple
♪ To capture
♪ The way I feel
♪ But I thought I'd try
♪ Yes, I thought I'd try
♪ Good night, darling
♪ Good
♪ Night
♪ Sleep well ♪
www.moviesubtitles.org