Episode 23
Baek Dae Gil.
Long time no see. Yi In Jwa.
Is it your doing?
Enough. Give up now.
Here. Hurry up.
You lost most of the supplies
and food for the soldiers.
Half of your soldiers are held
back with upset stomachs.
It's almost impossible for you
and your soldiers to advance.
No, it's too early to give up. (Yi In Jwa)
Prince Milpung (Yi Tan, Crown
Prince Sohyeon's great-grandson)
This is His Highness, Prince Milpung.
Are you Baek Dae Gil?
The royal court will commit all
military forces to block the treason.
They say the army general will
really lead 50,000 soldiers, right?
The central soldiers from the five
military departments will join forces
and gather at Anseong. Isn't that right?
You must be feeling anxiously urgent,
because you even planted a spy.
The justification of the Great
Cause is still thriving,
and there are still more
than 10,000 soldiers left.
Also, 100,000 rising solders from Gyeongsang
Province and Jeolla Province will join us.
So block us to the death.
I'll look forward to it.
Please give up.
Are you going to send all
these people to their deaths?
They are the comrades of the Great Cause who stood
up on their own and volunteered for service.
How dare such a bastard like you...
Soon, all of them will come to know
your true colors, Yi In Jwa, who would
exhaust every means to sit on the throne,
and who would sacrifice the
people for his ambition.
I'll block you.
Without fail, I'll send you
to join your ancestors.
Leaving the wounded, women, and
children here, we are advancing.
Instead of horses, let the
strong men pull the wagons.
Keep sending the pigeon posts to ascertain the situation
and movements in Gyeongsang and Jeolla Province.
Dae Gil, I was really worried.
Let's organize quickly.
Well... Since others'
eyes are watching me...
I'm thinking of carrying a sword...
Gramps, don't think useless
thoughts, help over there.
Is it enough for you alone to wear a sword?
Well! Let's gather here.
I'll give you food now.
All of you! Grab it and go home!
Don't uselessly break your leg or bleed.
Hurry to come here. You people who sink down
on the ground, get up quickly and come here!
All of you! Let's gather here! Come here!
Boil down these medicinal
herbs and take them.
Hurry and take it before
you become dehydrated.
Come here!
Here, some.
Boil them down well and take them.
Here.
Are you going to give
some to your wife too?
Was your part cut off?
Where did you come from?
Dae Gil!
The stomach upsets have subsided.
Even though we gave out a lot of food,
we still have a lot of food left.
It's a relief.
Go outside. Everybody is waiting for you.
What will happen to us now?
We joined in the treason.
I heard the people who joined in
the treason will be beheaded.
Since all of you dropped your spears and
swords like this, that won't happen at all.
Is it true?
The King promised
to forgive whoever drops
their weapons at any time.
He said it clearly.
Therefore, everybody, all of you
have to do is to take the food
and go to your hometowns.
Is it true? Did the King really say that?
The Army General, his 50,000 soldiers and
5,000 central solders joined together,
and passed the Gwacheon area just now.
However, to block Jeong Hee Ryang, Park Pil
Hyeon, and their 100,000 rebel soldiers,
our numbers are far from
sufficient, aren't they?
If we are not able to block Anseong,
it's a matter of time
before the capital falls.
Your Majesty!
It's a message from Mokcheon.
Baek Dae Gil broke down
half of the rebel army.
Of 30,000 Yi In Jwa's soldiers, he reorganized
barely half of them and advanced to Anseong.
Although his army has been cut in half,
if we miss the chance, in the
end we will cede Anseong.
Since the central army
also arrives in two days,
we can't waste a moment.
I'll go myself.
But, Your Majesty. If you go there
yourself, it's too dangerous...
When the bastards are close at hand,
do you mean that after everything, I should
just watch and give them the palace in the end?
Each moment is urgent, so
everybody hurry to get ready.
Yes. Your Majesty.
We need to send a message to Dae Gil.
You don't need to.
What do you mean we don't need to?
Regardless the movements in the capital,
Dae Gil will move as planned.
Planned?
Right now, the rebel army
is probably passing here.
But the rebel solders who
didn't eat are getting tired.
So they will stop by this
town before going to Anseong.
My Liege, the soldiers
are getting very tired.
It's hard to advance the date by two
days for a four-day march.(Hwang Jin Gi)
Without food and horses,
if we force ourselves to keep going like this,
all of us will collapse before we reach Anseong.
Let's unpack at the nearby town.
It is possible that they
might pillage this village.
The rest of you should take the remaining
provisions and head to this village.
It's a letter sent by your master.
I found Jeong Hee Ryang's station.
I will keep my promise to you.
I will make sure that no one gets hurt.
(Kim Che Geon)
In terms of the South, there's nothing
we can do but trust in Master.
- Then, now what?
- We have to move on to the next part of the plan.
Three-step strategy?
First, smuggling the military
horses and provisions,
to slow down the attack
of the rebel forces.
Eh, do you think that's an easy matter?
There rebel forces have a weakness.
Coming across the eight provinces, they haven't been
together long, so they do not know each other's faces.
I just received notice. It
seems they were successful.
Are you serious?
Let's have just a bit more strength.
We are almost there.
It seems around half the
soldiers have fallen away.
Then what's the second part of the plan?
It's trampling on the boosted confidence the rebel
forces acquired after winning Cheongju City.
"Yi In Jwa's rebellion has failed."
We will spread this rumor.
Wow, that's spectacularly good.
Since the truth of rumors
cannot be verified,
those who sought to join the rebel forces,
can't help but be very careful.
How is it that there are
no soldiers in sight?
Hmmm.
A rumor is circulating at the marketplace
that Great Commander Yi In Jwa
has been defeated at Anseong.
How could you be so dense? (Park Pil Hyeon)
You wouldn't...
believe that baseless rumor?
It's unbelievable, but I
can't dismiss it either.
I am sorry that I cannot be of help to you.
How about we say that our promise never...
What are you doing?
If you decide to withdraw from the situation in
this manner, it looks like you'll betray me,
so I can't send you away.
You bastard...
Is a traitor in the end a traitor?
Arrest these bastards this instant!
Yes!
Stop them!
Did you have them concealed?
On general principle, I
tend not to trust those
who receive their pay from the government.
Let's observe for a bit longer.
Dae Gil.
It appears the forces of five military
departments have left the palace.
I'll give you five days.
If there is no news even
after five days have passed,
the central army will be mobilized.
Grandfather, the situation
has become urgent.
I'll move first, so you take
care of the remaining people.
Where are you going alone?
To Anseong. Before something happens,
I must meet the King.
My Liege, we've already gone
half a day without food.
At this rate, we'll...
Everyone gather up the
last bit of your strength.
According to our news from the Yeongnam (current Gyeongsang
Province) and Honam (current Jeolla Province) regions,
two days from now. In two days' time,
the 100,000 troops who are marching
for us will join us at Anseong.
We will complete the Cause
we have been working for.
I'm feeling hungry
and I don't have any strength.
Look, My Liege.
Two days? I don't think we'll
last more than half a day.
Look! Isn't that something edible?
What is that?
Let go.
Let's share it.
Oh, radish stems? Give it here. Oh my,
oh my. None of us have been able to eat.
Give it here. Give it up!
It's mine! Let go!
Pick 20 good soldiers.
What are you guys doing?
Why aren't you hurrying?
My Liege.
Don't you think it's wrong of us to
pillage the people's provisions?
It is only the bare minimum that
is needed on our march to Anseong.
Are you suggesting we give up the
Great Cause over a few sacks of rice?
Have them moved.
Look here.
Who did it?
You bastards! You can't!
Do you know what this rice means to us?
Aigoo, aigoo, Elder, are you okay?
Elder...
You bastards, deserving of death!
You have nothing to take so you
take from lowborn tenant farmers?
This a**. Hey, you piece of...
If you're going to take the provisions
here, take our heads first!
I'm telling you, kill
us first then take it!
Because even if we must die, we will never
give it up! Try to have it your way then!
That's right!
Then, I have no other choice.
You lock them up inside there,
and the others move the rice.
What are you doing now?!
From now on, whoever blocks or
prevents me from getting to Anseong,
I will mercilessly cut their hand off.
What... What did you say?!
Whoever that may be.
What?! Then are you saying you want a go?!
Are you saying you want to fight?
What is your reason for
imprisoning all these people!?
It is a sacrifice for the Great Cause.
Just know it as that.
Are you crazy?!
I will surely make a prosperous
country and raise a strong army
that will befit their holy sacrifice.
Watching innocent people
die, I can't do that!
Are you planning on
ruining the Great Cause?
Do you really not know it is all
sacrifice required for salvation?
Jukju Mountain Fortress
How many soldiers have gathered in all?
Though they number 35,000 as of now,
20,000 more from Suwon and
Yongin will soon join us.
Approximately where are the rebel forces?
They have not yet reached Anseong.
According to the recon troops, a
fellow by the name of Baek Dae Gil
has stolen Yi In Jwa's war
horses and provisions.
We hear that rumors are circulating in Jeolla Province
that Yi In Jwa failed to incite the soldiers.
It must be the doing of this
fellow called, Baek Dae Gil.
Is there a reason that you are so
confident that you will block Yi In Jwa?
I am asking if you have a plan.
Going after his weaknesses,
I will slow down his march
and cut his numbers in half.
Second,
what is scarier than a sword is
a rumor.
Rumor?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Using rumors, we will cut off
Yi In Jwa's arms and legs.
Then what's the plan after that?
The third plan is...
There will be 100,000 rebel solders coming up
from Gyeongsang Province and Jeolla Province.
If we fail, we are done for.
- Aigoo.
- Have some strength.
Hwang Jin Gi
You all must be exhausted,
but just have a bit more strength.
(Yi In Jwa)
They look terrible.
How about (Prince Milpung, Yi Tan,
Crown Prince Sohyeon's great-grandson)
quitting around this time?
Why are you saying such weak words?
Commander-in-Chief,
This is not the kind of
world that I imagined.
I heard you looted.
It was a choice that could not be avoided.
That choice...
Do you think that it was right?
Follow me.
Nobody touched the food.
They are commoners before
they are soldiers.
To make the country prosperous and
create a country for the people,
they threw themselves into
this matter with enthusiasm.
How could they eat this looted food?
It's not looted, it's sacrificed.
If the people are sacrificed
for me to sit on the throne,
what meaning would it have?
Anseong is just in front
of us, Your Highness.
In half a day, the throne
will fall into your hands.
Saying those things, you hurriedly ushered
all those commoners here, didn't you?
In the end, didn't you plunder a
village and even kill people, too?
Why did you do that?
If I happen to starve, I'll starve.
But did we say we should take
it away from innocent people?
I told you repeatedly not to talk glibly.
I
Followed His Highness Prince Milpung,
not you, Sir.
What?
If you value your own life,
be careful with what you say!
You... You! How could you, without
even batting an eye, dare to kill...
Your Highness,
I beg of you to please
believe in me, Yi In Jwa.
This lowly subject will deliver the
throne, Your Highness, without fail,
into your hands.
You did not need to KILL!
Bury them in a sunny place.
I want to be alone.
I am sorry.
Your Majesty, why didn't
you keep your promise?
Didn't you say you would give your
lowly servant five days' time?
Today would be the fifth day.
As for you,
have you brought Yi In Jwa's head to me?
Of course your achievement is great.
You cut the number of the
rebel forces in half,
and smuggled the war horses and
provisions, slowing down the march.
However,
your role will only go that far.
From now on,
I will suppress the rebellion myself.
Are you planning on drawing
your sword against the people?
These are your subjects, Your Majesty.
They are your children!
Since they have given up
on being my subjects,
I will punish their
wrongdoings with the sword.
Your Majesty, how do you think that
I, without even once using the sword,
was able to cut Yi In
Jwa's supporters in half?
It's faith.
Here, take one.
It is having faith in the common people.
Thank you very much.
Take it and live well!
They number as many as 15,000.
That many soldiers have
thrown away their swords.
What do you think that signifies?
I can do it.
Without raising a sword or shedding blood,
we can stifle this uprising.
Soon that bastard will arrive here.
If this place falls, then they can reach the Four
Gates of the Capital without shedding any blood.
No matter how many government
troops there may be,
it will be hard to block them. So I
definitely plan on beating an iron
bludgeon right into this place,
on the rebellion,
to put it into complete disarray.
Your Majesty!
The rebel forces have arrived.
In the end, you came here.
To Anseong.
Is there no news from
Yeongnam and Honam regions?
As for Yeongnam, they have
just taken off from Jincheon.
We received notice that Honam
just passed Pyeongtaek.
A quarter of a day must
pass for them to arrive.
If the government troops
should attack in the meantime,
it will be over.
Don't worry.
Inside there,
I have hidden a card.
Look.
Those soldiers...
Do they look like my subjects to you?
Slaughter the rebel forces.
Your Majesty.
Yi In Jwa, Prince Milpung, and all others
who have taken part in the act of treason
Do not leave a single one out—!
Step aside!
No, Your Majesty, you mustn't!
Do you dare? Go against me?
They are your subjects.
They are the enemy.
Please bestow your mercy upon them.
They are people who do
not know about kindness,
so I will pass judgment through the sword.
As for me.
Will you throw me away too?
If you are going to ally with the enemy,
I will gladly cut your neck.
Your Majesty.
I have promised His Majesty, the former King,
that I will surely protect Your Majesty.
However, that oath! From
this moment forward,
I cannot keep it.
What are you doing?
You, bastard, really!
King!
Now, die!
What did you say? Still left there?
Since the royal court has become rotten as possible,
wouldn't it be even stranger if no one left there?
Right after the Dowager Queen joined me,
the commanders from Su Eo Defense Department and Fireworks
Military Department turned their backs on the King.
Since the foolish King came this far,
after all, it looks like he is
rushing to end his life soon.
Finally, the King is dead!
Soon, the fortress gate will open! Our
great dream we have held will come true!
Now, we are going to advance
on the capital this way!
- Everybody! Are you ready?
- Yes!
Your Highness! You go in first.
Advance!
Baek Dae Gil.
Retreat!
You! From now on, you are not
the insurgents any more.
That fellow Yi In Jwa doesn't
have the Great Cause!
He only has his ugly self-interest.
Your Highness. We're waiting for you.
Were you looking for me?
I asked what your last, third strategy is.
If the rebel army from Honam region and
Yeongnam region are Yi In Jwa's two arms,
the sword in Yi In Jwa's
hand is Prince Milpung.
The dagger that he holds to his chest
is the spies that hide in the palace.
Prince Milpung and the remnants from
the military officials faction...
How do you plan to cut off those two?
I'll let the rebel army led by
Prince Milpung march in here.
You're going to set a trap by
using Prince Milpung as a bait?
How can you reveal the remnants from
the military officials faction?
I... will... point the knife
at Your Majesty's neck.
I never thought it possible!
As many as two of them!
I can't believe this even with my two eyes!
Throw away your weapons!
His Majesty promised to let all
of those who surrender live!
Before my mind changes,
lay down your swords!
Don't be afraid!
Soon the rebellion will be over and all of you
will be able to go back to your hometowns.
You saved 7,000 people again.
However, your role only goes this far.
I'll punish the rest.
Your Majesty.
Prince Milpung, I'll punish you
after suppressing the rebellion.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, please put your sword down.
Soon, 100,000 insurgents will gather here.
If we miss this chance, from here to the capital it's
an ownerless (deserted) mountain, so we'll be finished.
If we don't attack first, the capital,
following Anseong, will fall as well.
I'll make sure to succeed
with the second strategy.
Did you receive a message?
Did you confirm that they blocked Park
Pil Hyeon and killed Jeong Hee Ryang?
Tonight is the last night.
We set up a rough camp.
Prince Milpung rejected the
throne so simply offered to him.
My Liege, it's hard this way.
Already not enough when the number was cut in
half, our number has been cut in half again.
Gather the leader-level soldiers.
I have something to say.
Your Majesty, please reconsider it again.
What can you gain with any sacrifice?
How can you force the people
to sacrifice themselves?
After subduing the rebellion,
I'll ask for forgiveness.
I will arrange their funerals and continue
to care for them generation upon generation.
Did you say I'm forcing their sacrifice?
I also
have made up my mind to suffer the
disgrace of being called a tyrant.
Your Majesty!
- Why are they doing this to us?
- We just stand here for a moment?
- Here!
- Do we all stand here?
- What do we do with this?
- Do we stand here?
Do you mean they all die?
We still have more than 8,000 soldiers.
If we resist and endure, Park Pil Hyeon and
Jeong Hee Ryang's big army will join us.
The Central Army is five
times bigger than ours.
Are you saying that because you don't know?
My Liege, this is not it.
I'm telling you it's not.
This far!
Do you know how we came this far?
The victory is in front of our noses.
Did you forget the thousands or tens of
thousand of comrades who were sacrificed?
Tonight,
there will be a surprise attack.
I'll conduct a surprise attack myself.
The royal troops attacked us.
Finally...
Are you ready?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Attack!
Please halt!
Your Majesty, please halt!
It's already too late.
Those standing over there
are only a shield.
They are traitors here
with traitorous minds.
Wipe them out, to the last man!
Fire!
Aigoo! My son!
Wake up! Open your eyes!
Come to your senses!
Stop!
Please stop!
Look at it clearly with those eyes.
Is this really... Is this truly
the Great Cause you wanted?
Where is the Great Cause
without a sacrifice?
Regroup
and block the royal army!
Aim!
Your Majesty!
Halt! Halt! Halt!
Don't shoot! Don't do this!
Please save them!
Cease fire!
Seol Im!
Your Majesty, please trust me.
Though your intention is admirable,
I don't intend to watch the insurgents
who joined the rebels at all.
Then I'll show you
whether they are traitors
or innocent people.
What?
Please watch them.
This humble subject will show you.
Whole army!
Halt the attack!
Baek Dae Gil, it's still not over.
You are finished now.
However... you still choose.
The people's lives
all depend on your choice.
If I held my life dear, I
wouldn't have even started.
I, Yi In Jwa, with those around me,
will bury my bones in this place.
I will... ally myself with you.
Having come now, you will ally with me,
you Baek Dae Gil, will do so?
All the commoners who followed
you have fallen away,
and even Prince Milpung has
turned his back on you.
Now you don't even have a
reason to take over the throne.
So?
I will pledge against my own life
that if you prove that
you're right, I'll do it.
Proof? How do we go about proving it?
Leave it to the heavens.
What did you say?
Your Majesty. It's not a situation
where we can just wait and see.
Your Majesty.
Wait.
Do you remember? This coin?
For this mere coin, I wagered my life
and I was able to protect it too.
This brass coin changed my life.
So I'm saying your fate and mine—this country
Joseon's fate—I'll wager on this round.
Sure.
I will.
Let's make this one thing clear.
Promise in front of all
the people standing here
that if I win,
you'll cleanly give up.
If by chance you win,
I'll give up the Great Cause.
Choose.
I choose heads.
Then I'll choose tails.
I'm curious.
Whether heaven will select
you or me, Yi In Jwa.
You know what? If it's not
certain I don't place a bet.
As you promised, give up everything
and docilely accept being tied up.
I'm sorry, but I don't think I'm
going to be able to keep my promise.
Yi In Jwa.
After this night passes, the troops
from Yeongnam and Honam will join us.
Would 100,000 troops be unable to cross
that measly Jukju Mountain Fortress?
I knew it would be this way.
Jeong Hee Ryang and Park Pil
Hyeon are already finished.
What are you talking about?
It's already over, I said.
Honam's Park Pil Hyeon's
hands are already bound.
From the looks of it, you're not men
who've only held hoes in your hands.
Same with Yeongnam's Jeong Hee Ryang.
I received word from them that
they will surely be arriving soon.
Did you by chance...
Do you think I only stood in their way?
When you enter the afterworld,
sincerely repent your wrongdoings.
Then... Even Park Pil Hyeon?
That bastard Yi In Jwa, sprays
blood everywhere he goes.
A Great Cause that kills the people.
I guess that's the Great Cause
that you keep bringing up.
It's not a name that any
dog like you can bring up.
I'll be sure to see whether your mouth will
still be that lively after you lose your head.
Then I leave the aftermath to you.
There are no reinforcements.
So why don't you give up now?
Yi In Jwa, your selfish ambition is over.
What did you say?
What are you doing, not
tying this rascal up?
Warrior Hwang.
What are you doing?
You said it yourself:
"A country for the people,"
and that you would establish a King
who would look after his people.
But not only were you unable to even
fill the stomachs of the hungry people,
you made the flesh of the
people into cannon fodder!
I contemplated it a lot.
Shall I let you live, or
shall I die with you?
Still, since you were a
nobleman I served as my master,
shouldn't I be the one to send you off?
Let's not be shameful towards each other.
You can't!
This fellow's life is the people's.
The time is not now.
Throw down your hoes and kneel.
All of you, lay down your weapons.
- Arrest him.
- Yes, Sir!
Yi In Jwa. It's over now.
You bastard, Baek Dae Gil.
♪ Longing for you even
if the tears well up ♪
♪ I will withstand you. Even
if my heart fills up more ♪
♪ Because the words which have
not yet been said remain ♪
♪ Because I cannot live
in a time without you ♪
Preview
Don't think of dying easily. Repent your
wrongdoing before the people, then die.
You will come to know that I,
Yi In Jwa, am a needed human!
Who took part in the poisoning
of the Crown Prince?
Their acquaintances, in-laws, even their third
cousins. Have them all arrested and brought in.
People from all across the eight provinces are
lauding this fellow named Bae Dae Gil as their King.
Wouldn't it be possible to go back
to His Highness, like before?
I heard there was someone who was acting as the
people's king, so I decided to pay a visit.
Today I have come to kill you.