[♪]
GOOD MORNING,
BEAUTIFUL.
GOOD MORNING.
SO, WHEN'S
YOUR FIRST?
8:00 A.M.
EARLY BIRDS WILL BE
HOVERING OUTSIDE ALREADY.
AT LEAST
YOU'RE NOT THAT CRAZY.
I ASKED HANNAH
TO GO WITH ME,
BUT SHE WANTED
TO SLEEP IN.
I DON'T BLAME HER.
YOU THINK SHE'S OKAY?
SHE'LL COME AROUND.
IF THEY'RE
GOING TO BREAK UP,
BETTER NOW THAN LATER.
YEAH, I GUESS YOU'RE RIGHT.
WOW, ANOTHER BURGLARY.
WHERE?
GLENWOOD,
SAME AS THE OTHER ONE.
HMM. REALLY?
I WAS THERE FOR A GARAGE SALE
LAST WEEKEND.
SURPRISING. NICE PLACE.
WELL, I'M GLAD ALL OUR MONEY
IS IN OUR HOUSE.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT FACE.
OOH!
[LAUGHING]
NO JUNK!
LOVE YOU!
[TO HIMSELF]
WE HAVE ENOUGH...
[ANSWERING MACHINE PLAYS]
HI, THIS IS DANIELLE.
I'M PROBABLY HOME,
I'M JUST AVOIDING SOMEONE.
LEAVE ME A MESSAGE.
IF I DON'T CALL YOU BACK,
IT'S YOU.
[BEEP]
GET YOUR BUTT UP, PARTNER!
IT'S ALMOST 8:00,
AND I'M ABOUT TO DO SOME DAMAGE.
EXPECT TREASURE.
[♪]
THAT'S VERY PRETTY.
KINDA.
SEEMS A LITTLE OLD FASHIONED.
IT WAS MY GRANDMOTHER'S
FAVORITE.
IT'S AN ENGLISH DESIGN.
I'LL GIVE YOU $75.
125, AND I'LL
THROWN IN THE CHAIR.
EXCUSE ME,
THIS IS A LOVELY SALE
YOU'RE HAVING.
I HAVE A FRIEND
THAT MIGHT BE INTERESTED
IN THE ROYAL ALBERT.
HOW MUCH
FOR ALL OF IT?
I MIGHT BE INTERESTED.
YOU DID THIS LAST WEEK.
I JUST MADE AN OFFER.
AND I MIGHT MAKE A BETTER ONE.
ANYTHING'S POSSIBLE.
HOW MUCH FOR ALL OF IT?
I'LL GIVE YOU
$150, CASH.
GARAGE SALES ARE ALWAYS CASH.
$200.
DON'T YOU USUALLY
BUY FURNITURE?
YEAH, BUT IF YOU'VE GOT
A DINING ROOM TABLE,
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE
CHINA TO PUT ON IT.
I WILL GIVE YOU
$250 FOR ALL OF IT.
COUNTER?
THANK YOU.
I THOUGHT I'D GET 200, TOPS.
OH, WELL, THEN, I GUESS
WE BOTH DID ALL RIGHT.
IT WAS A WIN-WIN.
YOU KNOW, THERE WAS A SET
I WAS GOING TO KEEP,
BUT SINCE YOU BOUGHT
ALL OF THIS, AND WERE SO NICE...
WHAT IS IT?
MATCHING TEAPOT
WITH SERVICE.
MAY I SEE IT?
IT'S INSIDE.
[♪]
KATE!
OH, HEY! EXCUSE ME.
I THOUGHT THIS ADDRESS
WAS FAMILIAR!
OH, I SHOULD HAVE
CALLED YOU.
YOU COULD HAVE HELPED ME
PRICE ALL THIS STUFF.
WHY ARE YOU HAVING
A GARAGE SALE?
FOR FUN. AND I WANT
TO REDECORATE.
OH...
HI, JEN.
HEY, BEN!
NEW RULE.
KATE CAN'T BUY ANY NEW STUFF
TILL SHE GETS RID OF
THE OLD STUFF.
I SEE SHE'S
GOT YOU WORKING.
OH, YOU KNOW ME,
ALWAYS WORKING.
OH, THIS IS NICE.
OH. RE-PRO.
AH, I LIVE FOR THE DAY
WHEN I FIND A REAL TIFFANY
AT A GARAGE SALE.
OH, I'LL BET.
COME INSIDE.
I HAVE SOMETHING
TO SHOW YOU.
OH, GREAT.
I'VE GOT A FEW PIECES
THAT MIGHT BE REALLY
GOOD FOR YOUR SHOP.
[QUIETLY] YOU KNOW,
IT'S NOT SUCH A GOOD IDEA
TO HAVE PEOPLE
IN YOUR HOUSE
AT A GARAGE SALE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO CARRY
THIS OUT ONTO THE DRIVEWAY--
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
HOLD IT, YOU DON'T
WANT TO SELL THIS.
I DO. I DON'T EVEN
REMEMBER WHERE WE GOT IT.
I'LL CONSIGN IT
AT THE SHOP IF YOU WANT,
AND I'LL GIVE YOU A FAIR PRICE.
THIS IS REALLY OLD JADE.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
IF I DIDN'T HAVE A CONSCIENCE,
I WOULD BUY IT.
YOU HAVE IT MARKED FOR $40.
TOO LOW?
ADD ANOTHER ZERO.
OOH.
HERE, YOU KEEP THIS.
BUDDHA WILL BRING YOU
GOOD LUCK AND LONG LIFE.
FINE, I'LL PUT IT
WITH THE "NOT FOR SALE" ITEMS.
OH, I WANT TO
SHOW YOU THE DINING ROOM.
OH, GREAT.
SO, THIS WHOLE SET
IS GOING TO GO
BECAUSE I FOUND A DUNCAN
PHYFE DOUBLE PEDESTAL
WITH LYRE-BACK CHAIRS.
OH, MY, WHERE
DID YOU FIND THAT?
OVER IN DAVIS.
IT'S ON HOLD.
EXCUSE ME,
I WAS WONDERING
ABOUT THIS COFFEE TABLE.
OH, SURE. SURE.
SEE YOU OUTSIDE.
OKAY, GREAT.
WELL, THEY WERE SEEING
EACH OTHER FOR TWO YEARS,
SO SHE'S TAKING IT PRETTY HARD.
AW... WELL,
HANNAH WILL BE FINE.
I MEAN, IT JUST
TAKES TIME, RIGHT?
AND WHO DIDN'T HAVE
A COLLEGE BREAK-UP?
HEY, UH, CAN WE HAVE LUNCH?
SOON?
SURE. HOW'S TUESDAY?
UH... THAT'S GREAT, YEAH.
MONDAY I'M HAVING A MASSAGE,
A FACIAL,
GETTING MY NAILS DONE,
AND BEN'LL BE OUT OF TOWN
ON A CONFERENCE,
SO, YEAH, BY TUESDAY,
I'LL BE ALL RELAXED
AND READY FOR A LONG LUNCH.
ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH. YEAH, OF COURSE.
YOU'RE SURE?
WE'LL TALK...
IT'LL BE GREAT
TO CATCH UP.
IT'S BEEN SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
GOOD TO SEE YOU, TOO.
I'LL SEE YOU TUESDAY.
OKAY.
[♪]
[KIDS LAUGH]
EXCUSE ME,
DO YOU HAVE
ANY MORE OF THESE?
I THINK SO.
DOWN IN THE BASEMENT.
THERE'S A COUPLE
OF MYSTERY BOXES.
IF YOU WANT
TO DRAG 'EM UP,
THEY'RE YOURS.
ANY IDEA WHAT'S INSIDE?
MAYBE SOME MORE TRACK.
SOME OTHER JUNK.
20 BUCKS, YOU CAN HAVE THE LOT.
DEAL.
[UNZIPPING PURSE]
[CLICKS ON FLASHLIGHT]
[MUTTERING]
OH, I HATE BASEMENTS.
BINGO.
[♪]
HEY!
HEY, DANIELLE.
I THOUGHT WE MADE A RULE
YEARS AGO, NO MYSTERY BOXES.
AND I HAVE A RULE
"NO BASEMENTS," BUT I WENT.
SUCH A MARTYR.
AT THE FIRST SALE,
SOME CHINA.
DOULTON?
ROYAL ALBERT.
NICE!
IT GETS BETTER.
SHE LET ME INSIDE
TO SEE ONE MORE ITEM,
IT COST A HUNDRED BUCKS...
A HUNDRED BUCKS?
MM-HM, TEAPOT...
[POURING WATER]
AND SERVICE.
[GASPS] NICE!
WELL...
YOU DESERVE
A GREEN DRINK FOR THAT.
-WHAT?
-UH-HUH.
-OH, NO.
NO, NO,NO.
YEAH, KALE, APPLE, SPINACH,
CARROT, BEET, AND GINGER--
[STAMMERING
IN PROTEST]
ORGANIC.
I WAS THINKING
MORE LIKE A COFFEE.
MOCHA JAVA WOULD BE NICE--
DRINK IT.
IT'S LIVE FOOD.
I GUARANTEE IT'S BETTER
THAN MY DATE LAST NIGHT.
MMM...
IT TASTES LIKE
I'M DRINKING A LAWN.
A BITTER LAWN.
IT'S SO GOOD
FOR YOU.
OH, THERE'S NO WAY
YOUR DATE COULD HAVE BEEN
WORSE THAN THIS.
OH, REALLY?
HE SELLS CANINE
HEALTH CARE PRODUCTS.
WHAT?
UH-HUH,
TOOTH WHITENERS FOR DOGS.
I WANTED TO TELL HIM
HE COULD USE A FEW HIMSELF.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN A...
"RUFF" NIGHT.
[GROANS]
THAT WAS FUNNY.
[GIGGLING]
IT WAS VERY FUNNY!
DRINK YOUR JUICE.
I'M GOING TO GET THE BOXES.
SO I FIGURED,
WHERE THERE'S TRACK,
THERE'S TRAIN.
YEAH. YEAH,
AND WE'VE GOT A...
HEADLESS BARBIE...
OH, NICE.
AND A DOG-CHEWED
LINCOLN LOG...
OH, NO.
A STUNNING ASHTRAY...
LET'S SEE WHAT WE HAVE
IN HERE.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
[GASPS]
THIS IS NICE.
OH... OKAY.
ONE THING
TO PUT ON EBAY.
HOW MUCH?
50 BUCKS?
HEY, DID HANNAH MAKE
AN APPEARANCE TODAY?
FOR A WHILE.
FORAGED FOR CHIPS,
THEN RETREATED UPSTAIRS.
HMM.
LOGAN...
WHAT AM I DOING?
COOKING DINNER?
THEN DON'T EAT ANYTHING.
APPETIZER.
[SIGHS]
YOU FIND ANY ATARI
TODAY, MOM?
NOPE.
ATLANTIS II.
LOOK FOR IT, OKAY?
ALREADY ON MY "BUY" LIST.
WE'LL BANK, BIG TIME.
SUPER SIDEKICK 4, ALSO.
GOT IT.
JASON!
APPETIZER!
[SIGHS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[KNOCKING] HANNAH?
HEY.
-HEY.
-HOT CHOCOLATE?
WE MISSED YOU AT DINNER.
I JUST COULDN'T EAT ANYTHING.
CAN I SEE WHAT
YOU'RE WORKING ON?
OH, THAT IS SO GOOD.
YOU ARE SO
TALENTED, HANNAH.
[SCOFFS]
YOU WANNA TALK ABOUT IT?
WHAT'S TO TALK ABOUT?
WE BROKE UP.
IT HAPPENS.
SWEETHEART, THIS WILL PASS.
[CHUCKLES]
[GROANS]
IT'S NOT LIKE
IT'S SOMETHING I ATE, MOM...
LOOK AT THAT,
YOU'RE LAUGHING ALREADY.
BECAUSE YOU'RE
SUCH A GOOFBALL.
YOU'RE LAUGHING.
SMILE.
NO, DON'T MAKE ME LAUGH...
I'M MISERABLE.
[CHUCKLING]
ARE YOU LISTENING
TO BREAKUP SONGS TOO?
IS THAT WHAT THIS IS?
I'M, LIKE,
THE BIGGEST CLICHE EVER.
YOU ARE KIND OF
A CLICHE, HANNAH-BANANA.
[LAUGHS]
LET ME HEAR WHAT
YOU'RE LISTENING TO.
OOH, THAT'S SAD.
MMM.
GIVE ME A HUG.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
AND I LOVE YOU.
YOU LIKED HIM, RIGHT?
SEEMED LIKE A GOOD KID.
YEAH, I LIKED HIM TOO.
ANY CHANCE THEY MIGHT...
GET BACK TOGETHER?
NO, SHE CAUGHT HIM
IN A LIE.
THAT'LL DO IT.
[SIGHS]
I HOPE SHE'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
I'M GLAD SHE CAME HOME
FOR A FEW DAYS.
HEY, THIS MORNING
DID YOU SAY
ONE OF THOSE BURGLARIES
WAS IN GLENWOOD?
BOTH OF THEM.
HMM.
I WAS THINKING...
ISN'T IT ODD
THAT I WENT TO TWO
GARAGE SALES RECENTLY
IN GLENWOOD
AND NOW THERE ARE TWO
BURGLARIES IN GLENWOOD?
OH, NO.
I'M GOING TO GET
SOME CHAMOMILE TEA.
YOU WANT SOME?
NO, THANK YOU.
PAPER'S IN THE KITCHEN.
LOCAL SECTION.
ONE COULD BE A COINCIDENCE...
TWO IS VERY INTERESTING...
AND THREE IS ONE TOO MANY.
WHAT HAPPENED,
DID SOMEBODY SEE YOU?
GO! DRIVE!
JUST START THE VAN AND
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE, GO!
[STARTS ENGINE]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
I THOUGHT IT WAS
A LITTLE FARFETCHED,
BUT THEN I WENT
TO WHERE WE KEEP THE OLD
PAPERS FOR RE-CYCLING,
AND I FOUND A THIRD.
SO YOU THINK THIEVES
ARE GOING TO GARAGE SALES
TO CASE HOUSES,
LATER RETURNING
TO STEAL THINGS?
EXACTLY!
AND THE THING IS,
THERE ARE SOME REGULARS,
PEOPLE THAT I SEE
AT DIFFERENT GARAGE SALES.
I MEAN, ISN'T IT POSSIBLE
THAT ONE OF THEM
COULD BE A THIEF?
HOW DO YOU LIKE
YOUR NEW OFFICE?
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THIS IS A NEW OFFICE?
OUTLINE OF OLD FRAMES
ON THE WALL.
SOMETHING'S BEEN
TAKEN DOWN RECENTLY,
LIKE SOMEONE'S MOVED OUT.
CARDBOARD BOXES OVER THERE,
LIKE SOMEONE'S
MOVING IN...
YOUR NAME,
IT'S NOT ON THE DOOR.
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF MY THEORY?
THE GARAGE SALE... MYSTERY?
GRANTED, YOUR POWERS OF
OBSERVATION ARE EXCEPTIONAL...
BUT EVERY TOWN HAS BURGLARIES,
AND EVERY TOWN
HAS GARAGE SALES--
YES, BUT YOU'VE HAD
A RASH OF BURGLARIES,
AND I'LL BET, I'LL BET
THAT THE THIEVES KNEW
EXACTLY WHAT THEY WANTED,
LIKE THEY HAD BEEN
IN THE HOUSE BEFORE,
OR AT LEAST
BEEN TO THE HOUSE BEFORE,
LIKE AT A GARAGE SALE,
WHERE THEY COULD SEE
WHERE THE WINDOWS WERE,
IF THEY WAS SECURITY,
IF THE FAMILY HAD A DOG--
OKAY, LISTEN--
DON'T YOU THINK
IT'S A STRANGE COINCIDENCE
THAT THE SAME THREE HOUSES
THAT HAD GARAGE SALES
ARE THE SAME THREE HOUSES
THAT WERE BURGLARIZED?
[CHUCKLING]
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
WHAT?
YOU'RE TALKING ME INTO IT.
SORRY.
IT'S MY NATURE.
SATURDAY.
8:00 A.M.
MY HOUSE.
HEY, SWEETHEART,
I'M GOING TO GET GOING.
WOW, THIS BENCH
LOOKS AMAZING.
YEAH, I MADE IT FROM
THAT BUSTED-UP BED
YOU DRAGGED HOME
A FEW WEEKS AGO.
WELL, DANIELLE AND I
ARE GOING TO HAVE
A BIDDING WAR OVER THIS
AT THE STORE.
GIVE ME A KISS.
OH, HOLD ON, YOUNG LADY.
DID THEY LAUGH YOU
OUT OF THE STATION
THIS MORNING?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THEY DID NOT LAUGH ME
OUT OF THE STATION.
DETECTIVE IVERSON
WANTS TO GO GARAGE-SALING
WITH ME ON SATURDAY.
OH, GOOD TO SEE
OUR TAX DOLLARS AT WORK...
MM-HM.
BY THE WAY,
HANNAH WENT OUT JOGGING
THIS MORNING.
WELL, MAYBE THERE IS LIFE
AFTER BOYFRIEND AFTER ALL.
[CHUCKLES] YEAH.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
YOU TOO. BYE-BYE.
HEY, KATE, ARE YOU HOME?
I'M PARKED IN YOUR DRIVEWAY
NEXT TO YOUR CAR.
I THOUGHT I WAS SUPPOSED
TO PICK YOU UP AT NOON.
IT'S NOW 12:15.
I RANG YOUR DOORBELL,
YOU DIDN'T ANSWER.
I CALLED YOU ON YOUR PHONE,
YOU DIDN'T PICK UP.
WHERE ARE YOU?
[DIALING]
OH, HEY, DANI, IT'S ME.
DID KATE CALL THE SHOP,
BY ANY CHANCE?
HUH.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S WEIRD.
WELL, I GUESS
I'LL JUST HANG OUT HERE
FOR A FEW MORE MINUTES,
AND THEN I'LL TAKE OFF.
OKAY, I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
KATE?
KATE, IT'S JENNIFER!
ANYBODY HOME?
[GASPS IN SHOCK]
YOU OKAY?
YEAH, I GUESS.
WE REACHED THE HOTEL
IN INDIANAPOLIS.
MR. DOUGLASS IS
GETTING ON A PLANE
AND HEADING BACK.
HOW IS HE?
NOT GOOD.
DO YOU THINK YOU COULD
WALK ME THROUGH
EVERYTHING YOU DID
BEFORE YOU CALLED 911?
WHEN I COULDN'T GET HER
ON THE PHONE
AND SHE DIDN'T
ANSWER THE DOOR,
I...I WALKED AROUND
TO THE BACK OF THE HOUSE.
COULD YOU SHOW ME?
MEDICAL EXAMINER ESTIMATES
SHE HAD BEEN THERE
ABOUT TEN HOURS
WHEN YOU FOUND HER.
SO, YOU CAME IN HERE,
THEN WHAT?
RIGHT, UM, I CALLED OUT,
NO ONE ANSWERED.
I CALLED OUT AGAIN,
AND THEN I WALKED THIS WAY,
AND I FOUND HER THERE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
HAPPENED?
WELL... IT APPEARS
SOMETIME
AROUND 2:00 A.M.,
SHE WENT TO GO DOWNSTAIRS,
AND TRIPPED
OR LOST HER BALANCE SOMEHOW
AND FELL.
YOU'RE SAYING ACCIDENT.
PRETTY SURE.
NO SIGN OF A STRUGGLE,
THE HOUSE
HASN'T BEEN ROBBED...
WAIT A SECOND.
I WAS HERE JUST LAST WEEK
FOR A GARAGE SALE.
IS IT POSSIBLE THAT THERE WAS
A BREAK-IN, JUST LIKE--
HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
I'D LIKE TO SHOW YOU
SOMETHING UPSTAIRS.
YOU OKAY WITH THAT?
YEAH.
YOU SEE ANYTHING
UNUSUAL?
NO, IT ALL LOOKS
PERFECTLY NORMAL.
NOW, IF THERE
WAS A BURGLARY,
THIS PLACE WOULD
LOOK LIKE A TORNADO.
NOT IF SHE SURPRISED
THEM IN THE ACT.
OKAY, LOOK AT THIS.
IF THIS WAS A HOME INVASION,
THESE WOULD BE GONE,
AT THE VERY LEAST.
THERE'S NO BURGLARY HERE,
AND THE FACT THAT SHE HAD
A GARAGE SALE LAST WEEKEND
IS A COINCIDENCE.
I SEE YOUR POINT.
SHE DIDN'T HAVE A JOB.
SHE DIDN'T NEED TO WORK.
I MEAN, BEN'S
A FINANCIAL ADVISOR.
HE DOES VERY WELL.
SO WHY WOULD THEY HAVE
A GARAGE SALE?
IT'S FUNNY,
I ASKED THE SAME QUESTION.
KATE SAID
SHE WANTED TO REDECORATE.
BEN SAID SHE HAD TO
MOVE OLD STUFF OUT
BEFORE SHE MOVED
NEW STUFF IN.
CAN YOU COME IN
TO MY OFFICE TOMORROW?
I'D LIKE TO TAKE
A MORE FORMAL STATEMENT.
SURE.
GREAT.
AS MUCH AS I LIKE
A GOOD MYSTERY,
I THINK HE'S RIGHT.
[SHUTTER SNAPS]
I KNOW.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WALKING IN
AND FINDING HER LIKE THAT.
IT'S JUST SO WEIRD.
PEOPLE HAVE GARAGE SALES,
AND DAYS LATER, THEY GET ROBBED.
KATE HAS A GARAGE SALE
AND SHE TURNS UP DEAD.
I DIDN'T REALLY KNOW HER.
WERE YOU CLOSE?
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
USED TO BE CLOSER.
I HADN'T SEEN
MUCH OF HER LATELY.
[SIGHS]
BUT I HAD A FEELING THAT
SOMETHING WAS BOTHERING HER,
THE WAY SHE WANTED TO
GET TOGETHER OUT OF THE BLUE.
NO IDEA WHAT?
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
NOPE.
NOW THE VASE.
YOU KNOW, THIS LOOKS
AUTHENTIC TO ME.
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S A REPRODUCTION?
YEAH, I LOOKED IT UP...
THIS TIME.
[CLEARS THROAT]
IT'S QING DYNASTY,
WHICH IS
RIGHT AFTER MING,
SO IF IT WERE REAL,
IT WOULD BE
ALMOST 400 YEARS OLD.
-HMM.
-HUH.
-THINK FAST!
-[GASPS] OH!
[LAUGHING]
LIKE I SAID, 50 BUCKS.
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
LOOK HOW LITTLE THE KIDS ARE
IN THIS PICTURE.
OH, THERE'S KATE.
THAT'S
A NICE PICTURE.
YEAH...
SHE HAD A BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
[SIGHS]
THE MINUTE I ENTERED THE FOYER,
I SAW HER LYING THERE.
SHE WAS MOTIONLESS.
I WENT OVER TO FEEL
FOR A PULSE, AND...
SHE WAS COLD.
I IMMEDIATELY WALKED
OUT THE FRONT DOOR,
I CALLED 911,
AND I WAITED IN MY CAR.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO.
IT'S JUST SO ODD.
SHE SLIPS ON THE STAIRS
AND DIES?
IT'S MORE COMMON
THAN YOU'D THINK.
I HATE TO THINK
THAT SHE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
LYING THERE IN PAIN.
NO, PRELIMINARY
CAUSE OF DEATH
WAS TRAUMA TO THE HEAD.
SHE WOULD HAVE TO BE
UNCONSCIOUS.
SHE'S BEEN DOWN THOSE STAIRS
A THOUSAND TIMES.
IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
THERE ARE A LOT
OF POSSIBILITIES.
WE'LL KNOW MORE
WHEN TOXICOLOGY COMES BACK.
DO YOU STILL FEEL LIKE
TAKING ME TO GARAGE SALES
ON SATURDAY?
ACTUALLY, I DO.
I THINK IT'LL HELP ME
GET MY MIND OFF ALL OF THIS.
GREAT. WELL,
I'LL SEE YOU THEN.
SEE YOU SATURDAY.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE
TO DO THAT.
OH, IT'S MY PLEASURE.
IF YOU GET HUNGRY, JUST
POP IT IN THE OVEN,
AND IT'S ALL
READY TO GO.
THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
HEY, WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME COFFEE?
I DON'T THINK THAT
IT'S FULLY SUNK IN YET.
PART OF ME EXPECTS HER
TO WALK THROUGH THAT DOOR,
YOU KNOW?
I UNDERSTAND.
I HAVE TO GO DOWN
TO MOUNT VERNON TODAY.
HER MOTHER IS
IN A HOME DOWN THERE.
I THINK I SHOULD
DO THIS IN PERSON.
WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO GO WITH YOU?
I'M OKAY, REALLY.
I'M JUST NOT SURE
HOW TO TELL AN 80-YEAR-OLD
THAT HER DAUGHTER IS DEAD.
THERE'S NO EASY WAY.
YOU JUST TELL HER,
AND THEN YOU BE THERE FOR HER.
IT'S TOUGH.
[SIGHS]
I'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
UM...
THIS MAY SEEM WEIRD,
BUT THERE WAS A JADE BUDDHA
OVER HERE ON THIS SHELF
THE OTHER DAY.
YEAH, I REMEMBER THAT.
KATE DIDN'T SELL IT, DID SHE?
NO, UH, SOMEBODY
ASKED ABOUT IT,
AND KATE SAID THAT
IT WAS NO LONGER FOR SALE.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO IT?
I DON'T KNOW,
MAYBE SHE TOOK IT UPSTAIRS?
IT'S KIND OF THE LEAST
OF MY WORRIES NOW.
OF COURSE, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
LET ME KNOW IF THERE'S
ANYTHING ELSE I CAN DO.
THANKS.
WELL, I THOUGHT
YOU COULD COME UP
WITH SOMETHING CHEAP.
HONEY, I'M AN ENGINEER,
NOT A ROOFER.
OH, YOU CAN FIX
ANYTHING, JASON.
YES, ANYTHING!
FIRST OF ALL,
THERE'S SUPPOSED TO BE
GRAVEL UP HERE
TO PROTECT THE TAR FROM THE UV,
WHEN THE UV DRIES IT OUT,
IT MAKES IT CRACK.
[BOARDS SQUEAKING]
LOOK, THERE ARE CRACKS
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
SO WHEN IT RAINS,
YOU GET LEAKS, RIGHT?
EVERYWHERE THERE'S
A PLASTIC BUCKET.
LOOK, HONEY,
WHEN IT'S GONE THIS FAR,
YOU'RE BOUND TO HAVE
ROT UNDERNEATH.
THAT'S WHAT
THE ROOFER SAID.
THE ROOFER SAID THE WHOLE
THING NEEDS TO COME OFF,
AND EVERYTHING NEEDS
TO BE REPLACED.
THAT SOUNDS
ABOUT RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
WHY DON'T WE CAREFULLY
GET DOWN OFF THE ROOF?
WHY, IS IT GOING TO
COLLAPSE ON OUR HEADS?
NO, THERE'S
NO CHANCE OF THAT.
JUST PROMISE ME
THAT YOU WON'T THROW
ANY PARTIES UP HERE, OKAY?
OH! THERE GOES
OUR RAGER ON THE ROOF.
GO.
[CHATTING QUIETLY]
HI.
HI!
WELCOME TO
RAGS TO RICHES.
UM, THANKS.
I WAS TRYING
TO HELP MY MOM OUT...
HERE...
OOH.
THAT'S NICE.
MM-HM.
IT'S OLD.
WELL, THAT'S
WHAT I SAID TO HER.
SHE WANTED TO SELL IT,
BUT I TOLD HER NOT TO.
HOW CAN YOU TELL IT'S OLD?
WELL, THE COLOR,
AND THE WEIGHT.
THE WAY IT'S CUT.
YEAH, I'D SAY
40, 50 YEARS OLD.
WELL, IF SHE WERE TO SELL IT,
HOW MUCH SHOULD SHE ASK?
WE DON'T DO APPRAISALS HERE.
DO... YOU WANT TO BUY IT?
YOU SAID IT WAS YOUR MOM'S?
I'D NEED TO SPEAK TO HER.
NO PROBLEM.
I'LL HAVE HER COME BACK DOWN.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
SHOULD WE GET ANOTHER
BID ON THE ROOF?
IT WON'T GET
LESS EXPENSIVE.
YEAH...
WHERE AM I GOING
TO GET $20,000?
YOU KNOW
THE DEAL, JEN.
YES, I AGREED I WOULD GO
INTO BUSINESS WITH DANIELLE
AS LONG AS
IT WAS SELF-SUPPORTING.
WHICH MEANS
THE BUSINESS PAYS FOR
CAPITAL IMPROVEMENTS.
MEANWHILE, STAY OFF THAT ROOF,
AND I'LL PERSONALLY FUND
ALL THE PLASTIC BUCKETS
YOU NEED.
FINE. CAN I PICK
MY OWN COLORS?
ANY COLOR YOU WANT.
OKAY.
-HAVE A GOOD DAY.
-YOU TOO.
OH, THANK YOU.
[SIGHS] SO WHAT
DO YOU WANT TO DO?
I WANT TO
DO WHAT WE DO BEST.
SATURDAY WE'RE
BACK TO IT?
YUP.
YOU BETTER JUST
KEEP YOUR BROTHER
FROM WIMPING OUT.
HE'S COOL.
HE IS NOT COOL.
[REVVING ENGINE]
AND JUST REMEMBER,
IF IT WASN'T FOR ME,
WE WOULD HAVE GOTTEN
NOTHING FROM THAT HOUSE.
[WINCING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
HANNAH!
LET'S GO IF YOU'RE GOING!
I BROUGHT SOME MOCHA JAVA.
I KNEW I LIKED YOU.
MOCHA JAVA.
HANNAH, COME ON!
OH, I HAVE A LIST
OF ADDRESSES FOR YOU
OF ALL THE GOOD GARAGE SALES
WHERE I THINK WE MIGHT SEE
SOME REGULARS.
I HOPE
YOU DON'T MIND.
I ASKED MY DAUGHTER
TO JOIN US.
NO.
THIS IS GREAT.
I FIGURED
WE'D TAKE TWO CARS
JUST SO IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
WE'RE TOGETHER.
OKAY, GOOD IDEA.
AND IF YOU SEE
ONE OF YOUR REGULARS,
JUST LET ME KNOW DISCREETLY,
I'LL FOLLOW THEM OUT,
I'LL RUN THEIR LICENSE PLATE,
SEE IF THEY HAVE
A CRIMINAL RECORD.
OH, HANNAH,
THIS IS
DETECTIVE IVERSON.
DETECTIVE IVERSON,
THIS IS MY
DAUGHTER, HANNAH.
HI.
ADAM.
HANNAH, WHY DON'T YOU
RIDE WITH ADAM?
HE WON'T STAND OUT
IF HE'S WITH SOMEONE.
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
OKAY, I'LL SEE YOU GUYS
AT THE FIRST SALE.
OKAY.
COME ON.
WHOA, SWEET.
THANK YOU.
[HANNAH]:
WHAT'S ITS NAME?
[HE LAUGHS]
THANK YOU.
I SHOULD APOLOGIZE
FOR MY MOM.
I'M EMBARRASSED
SHE FOISTED ME OFF ON YOU.
I DON'T MIND.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO HAVE
THE WRONG IMPRESSION.
-I DON'T.
-GOOD.
I JUST BROKE UP
WITH MY BOYFRIEND.
HE WAS A REAL JERK.
DO YOU WANT ME TO ARREST HIM?
YES.
[CHUCKLING] YEAH, I DO.
THANKS.
AHEM.
[STARTS ENGINE]
...POLITICAL SCIENCE.
I GRADUATE JUNE THIS YEAR.
THEN?
I'M INTERNING AT THE CAPITOL,
AND THEN LAW SCHOOL
IN SEPTEMBER.
WHAT?
IT'S JUST,
YOU LOOK PRETTY YOUNG
TO BE GOING TO LAW SCHOOL.
OH, OKAY.
WHAT, AND YOU LOOK OLD ENOUGH
TO BE A DETECTIVE?
DO THEY CALL YOU DOOGIE
AT THE STATION?
OH, OUCH...
DO THEY GIVE YOU A GUN
WITH AN ORANGE PLASTIC TIP?
OKAY, EASY.
I'M SORRY.
I APOLOGIZE.
"DETECTIVE DOOGIE."
THAT'S WHAT THEY CALL ME.
OH...
WE'LL STAY PUT ON THIS ONE.
YOU RECOGNIZE ANYONE?
YEAH.
YOU SEE THE GUY
WITH THE DARK HAIR,
SUNGLASSES,
ABOUT 30 YEARS OLD?
UH, YEP. GOT HIM.
I'VE SEEN HIM A FEW TIMES
IN THE LAST MONTH.
IN FACT, I NICKNAMED HIM
"THE STRANGER"
BECAUSE HE NEVER
SEEMS TO BE SHOPPING.
OKAY.
HOPEFULLY HE DOESN'T STAY LONG,
AND WE CAN GET HIS PLATE.
[HANNAH CHUCKLES]:
STAKE-OUT. COOL.
[ADAM]: HOLD ON.
YOU SEE THAT GUY WITH
THE GREEN ARMY JACKET?
YEAH?
HAVE YOU
SEEN HIM BEFORE?
NO.
I HAVE.
THAT GUY'S A KNOWN THIEF.
HIS NAME'S SAM.
GREAT JOB, JENNIFER.
HEY, I NEED YOU TO JUMP OUT.
I'VE GOT TO HAVE A CHAT
WITH THIS GUY.
OH, YEAH, OKAY.
[OTHER CAR ENGINE STARTS]
OH. HEY.
THANKS FOR THE JACKET.
NO PROBLEM.
[STARTS ENGINE]
SURE, I'LL GET OUT.
NO PROBLEM.
OH. YEAH.
HEY, YOU'RE VIOLATING
MY RIGHTS!
YOUR RIGHTS, SAM?
I'M VIOLATING YOUR RIGHTS?
YOU CAN'T JUST HASSLE ME
FOR NO REASON.
YOU'RE ON
PROBATION, SAM.
THAT MEANS
THAT I CAN.
SO WHAT ARE YOU NEEDING
AT A GARAGE SALE?
TOASTER.
I NEEDED A NEW TOASTER.
I HATE IT WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK IN YOUR TRUNK.
HERE OR AT THE STATION.
[KEYS JINGLE]
STEP BACK.
GOING SKIING, SAM?
ALL RIGHT,
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
MAYBE THEY'LL GIVE YOU
A COMMENDATION
AT THE NEXT
CITY COUNCIL MEETING.
OOH, MAYBE THEY WILL.
I WOULD TAKE IT, TOO.
I WAS KIDDING.
BESIDES, THE THIEF WASN'T
EVEN ONE OF YOUR REGULARS.
HEY, I MADE
THE CONNECTION, THOUGH.
HEY, I HAD A LITTLE THIEF
COME IN HERE THE OTHER DAY.
SERIOUS?
HE TAKE ANYTHING?
SHE.
NO, TRIED TO SELL ME SOME JADE,
SAID IT WAS HER MOM'S,
BUT I DOUBT IT.
WHAT WAS IT?
IT WAS A LITTLE BUDDHA.
OLD JADE?
ABOUT SIX INCHES TALL?
YEAH, HAVE YOU SEEN IT?
AT KATE'S HOUSE.
IT WAS STOLEN FROM KATE'S HOUSE.
WHEN?
MY GUESS,
THE NIGHT SHE DIED.
WHAT ARE YOU
SAYING, MOM?
I DON'T THINK KATE'S DEATH
WAS AN ACCIDENT.
AS FAR AS WE KNOW,
THIS ISN'T THE ONE
THAT KATE SHOWED YOU.
OR IS.
IF IT WAS,
SHE SOLD IT AND
DIDN'T TELL HER HUSBAND,
OR MAYBE IT WAS STOLEN
AT THE GARAGE SALE.
DIDN'T YOU SAY
THAT PEOPLE WANDER
AROUND THE HOUSE
LOOKING AT STUFF?
OH, IT'S OKAY.
HE CAN'T SEE US IN HERE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I WATCH COP SHOWS.
[CHUCKLES]
OKAY.
SAM BURGESS.
CURRENTLY ON PAROLE FOR
BREAKING AND ENTERING, BURGLARY,
SELLING AND POSSESSING
STOLEN GOODS,
AND ASSAULT.
HIS TRUNK WAS PACKED WITH
ALL THE TOOLS OF THE TRADE.
WELL, LIKE I SAID,
I'VE NEVER SEEN HIM BEFORE.
WELL, I WANTED YOU
TO GET A CLOSER LOOK.
YOU'RE SURE?
OH, I WOULD'VE
REMEMBERED HIM.
WHERE WAS HE
THE NIGHT KATE DIED?
JAIL.
DRUNK AND DISORDERLY
OVER IN WRENTON.
A PERFECT ALIBI.
ARE YOU SURE
HE CAN'T SEE ME?
YUP.
I THINK THAT YOU SHOULD
BE VERY SATISFIED.
YOUR THEORY WAS SPOT ON.
A THIEF IS OFF THE STREETS
BECAUSE OF YOU.
I SUPPOSE.
WHAT?
WELL, CALL IT
WOMAN'S INTUITION OR WHATEVER,
BUT WHEN KATE ASKED ME TO LUNCH,
I GOT THE FEELING
THAT SOMETHING WAS WRONG.
LIKE?
I DON'T KNOW, I JUST THINK
SHE NEEDED
TO CONFIDE IN SOMEONE.
AND THEN SHE TURNS UP DEAD
JUST DAYS AFTER.
AND THEN,
A VALUABLE ITEM IS
MISSING FROM HER HOME,
AND THAT SAME ITEM,
A JADE BUDDHA,
OR ONE JUST LIKE IT,
TURNS UP AT MY SECONDHAND STORE
WITH SOMEONE WANTING TO SELL IT
AND LYING ABOUT HOW THEY GOT IT.
MM-HM, AND THAT'S
ALL CONJECTURE,
GOOD CONJECTURE,
BUT HERE ARE
ALL THE FACTS, OKAY?
TOXICOLOGY IS BACK.
KATE HAD SOME ALCOHOL
IN HER SYSTEM,
NOT A LOT,
AND SOME ZOLPIDEM,
A SLEEPING PILL.
NOW, THOSE TWO,
IN COMBINATION,
COULD HAVE COMPROMISED
HER BALANCE.
HER INJURIES ARE
CONSISTENT WITH A FALL,
AND THE CAUSE OF DEATH,
A FRACTURED SKULL.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT, JENNIFER.
SHE WAS HOME ALONE.
THE HOUSE WASN'T ROBBED,
THE MISSING BUDDHA
NOTWITHSTANDING.
OKAY, I HEAR YOU.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW THAT YOU'RE STUBBORN.
HEY, WITH SAM OFF THE STREETS,
I THINK WE'LL BE SEEING
A LOT LESS BURGLARIES.
HEY.
THIS IS REAL,
AND IT'S OLD.
YOU LOOKING TO SELL IT
OR PAWN IT?
MAYBE SELL IT.
[SIGHS] IT'S REAL.
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING
TO GET FOR IT?
I THINK IT'S WORTH
A THOUSAND DOLLARS.
[SIGHS] NOT TO ME.
I COULD GIVE YOU A HUNDRED.
300.
125.
-200.
-THAT'S IT!
FINE.
HEY, SEE THOSE LITTLE STATUES?
HOW MUCH DO YOU WANT FOR THEM?
SEVEN LUCKY GODS?
20 BUCKS.
IS THAT ALL?
THEY'RE IMITATIONS.
PLASTIC REPLICAS.
REAL ANTIQUE JAPANESE IVORY,
THEY'D BE WORTH $5,000.
LOGAN, GO HELP
YOUR MOTHER.
I'M IN THE MIDDLE
OF A GAME.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY,
SKY IS BLUE,
SMELL OF MESQUITE SMOKE,
AND YOU'RE STARING
AT A SCREEN.
DANIELLE SAID
THOSE VEGGIE KABOBS
AREN'T ORGANIC,
AND THE CORN HAS BEEN
GENETICALLY MODIFIED
TO KILL ANY BUG
THAT EATS IT,
SO WHAT'S BETTER,
ME DOING THIS,
OR YOU DOING THAT?
LOGAN, TURN THAT OFF
AND GO HELP YOUR MOM
BRING OUT THE FOOD.
AIRFORCE FIGHTER PILOTS
IN THE FUTURE
WILL NEED THIS SKILL SET.
OH, SO IT'S A NATIONAL
DEFENSE THING YOU'RE DOING?
[SIGHS]
IF WE LOSE THE NEXT WAR,
IT'S YOUR FAULT.
ALL THIS?
ALL OF IT.
-HELLO!
-HEY, DANIELLE.
NO, NO.
OH, NO, NO.
MAKE MORE TRIPS.
LOGAN, I CAME SPECIFICALLY
FOR THOSE BEANS.
BE CAREFUL.
WHAT TIME DID YOU TELL
DETECTIVE IVERSON TO ARRIVE?
THANKS FOR
THE INFO, MOM.
YOU THINK I WANT
TO LOOK LIKE THIS?
[ALL CHATTING HAPPILY]
NO, NO, IT'S OBVIOUS.
I BLAME MYSELF
FOR NOT THINKING OF IT.
GARAGE SALES ARE
A NATURAL WAY
FOR A BURGLAR
TO CASE A HOUSE.
I WAS SURPRISED AT HOW OFTEN
PEOPLE ARE ACTUALLY
LET INTO THE HOUSE.
MOST PEOPLE ARE NICE.
IF YOU ASK THEM
TO USE THEIR RESTROOM,
THEY'LL TELL YOU
TO GO INSIDE.
YEAH, THERE'S ABOUT 6,000
HOME BURGLARIES A DAY.
WHAT, REALLY?
EVERY DAY?
YEAH.
LESS THAN 15% ARE EVER CAUGHT.
WELL, THAT'S IT,
NEW CAREER CHOICE.
NO, YOU NEED
TO GO TO COLLEGE.
COLLEGE FOR BURGLARS.
[LAUGHING]
HEY, CAN I GET YOU
ANOTHER LEMONADE?
THAT BE GREAT.
THANKS, HANNAH.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
PERHAPS YOUR FATHER
WOULD LIKE A LEMONADE?
YEAH, I... WAS ALREADY
GETTING YOU ONE.
[LAUGHING]
SO, UM...
I HAVE A HOME ALARM,
AND IT GOES RIGHT TO
A PRIVATE
SECURITY COMPANY.
AM I SAFE?
YOU'RE NEVER SAFE.
[LAUGHTER]
ZIP IT.
TRUTH IS,
MOST PROS DON'T EVEN WORRY
ABOUT ALARMS.
THEY'RE USUALLY IN AND OUT
IN LESS THAN EIGHT MINUTES.
THAT FAST?
YEAH, THAT'S
ALL IT TAKES.
LESS THAN THAT
IF THEY'VE ALREADY BEEN INSIDE.
[LAUGHING]
YOU KNOW, I JOG
WHEN I'M STRESSED.
CLEARS MY HEAD.
OH YEAH?
I'M A RUNNER TOO.
WHAT, I DON'T LOOK LIKE
I KEEP IN SHAPE?
HMM...
[LAUGHS]
NO, YOU LOOK FINE.
I JUST DIDN'T THINK
YOU WERE A RUNNER.
YOU KNOW, I DO
THE SCHOOL TRACK
IN THE MORNINGS
WHEN I'M HERE.
IF YOU WANT TO RUN,
I GO AROUND 7:00.
GOOD TO KNOW.
OKAY, READY?
WE'RE GOING TO BE
IN AND OUT
IN LESS THAN FIVE MINUTES.
OKAY.
HEY, YOU BE READY.
ALL RIGHT!
[LIGHTS SNAP ON]
DON'T MOVE.
BUT WHAT DOES
THAT MEAN?
IT MEANS THAT SOMEONE
WAS IN THE HOUSE.
AND IF SOMEONE
WAS IN THE HOUSE
THE NIGHT KATE DIED--
THAT'S A PRETTY
BIG "IF".
JUST LET ME PLAY DEVIL'S
ADVOCATE FOR A SEC.
ALL OF THE OTHER BURGLARIES
THAT YOU TIED TO GARAGE SALES,
WAS ANYBODY HURT?
[DOOR OPENS]
NO.
NO, BURGLARS
WANT TO GRAB AND GO.
I'M THINKING.
HEY, WHAT'S UP?
I FOUND THE SHOP.
LET ME GET MY PURSE.
WHAT, YOU...?
OH. OKAY.
BYE, DANI.
BYE. HAVE FUN.
YOU GUYS, AND YOUR...
LITTLE ADVENTURE.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I'M LOOKING FOR
A SMALL GREEN JADE BUDDHA.
A GIRL SOLD IT TO YOU
A COUPLE DAYS AGO?
HMM, I DON'T THINK SO.
SHE HAVE A RECEIPT?
DO YOU GIVE OUT RECEIPTS
FOR STOLEN ITEMS?
WHOA, WHOA,
WE CHECK ID ON EVERYTHING,
WE DO A TWO-WEEK POLICE HOLD
ON EVERYTHING WE TAKE IN--
LISTEN, I NEED
THAT BUDDHA NOW.
IF I DON'T SEE IT
IN THE NEXT 60 SECONDS,
I'M GOING TO
HAVE A CREW DOWN HERE
CHECKING EVERY ITEM
IN YOUR STORE,
THE BACK ROOM, THE OFFICE,
EVERYTHING.
-I'LL GET IT.
-GREAT.
HEY...
THOSE ARE LIKE THE ONES
ON THE SHELF
THAT WERE NEXT TO THE JADE.
YEAH.
CELESTE SAID THE CLERK TOLD HER
THEY WERE WORTH
ABOUT FIVE GRAND.
IS THAT IT?
THAT'S IT.
KATE HAD A PRICE TAG RIGHT HERE.
YOU CAN FEEL THE ADHESIVE.
ORDINARILY, IT WOULD BE
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
I HAVE BEEN
VERY HELPFUL SO FAR,
YOU HAVE TO ADMIT.
NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
AND YOU HAVE COMPLIMENTED ME
ON MY POWERS OF OBSERVATION.
NEVER SEEN ANYTHING LIKE IT.
SO, DETECTIVE, WHAT DO YOU SAY?
FINE. YOU CAN WATCH.
I GOT NO IDEA.
I WAS NEVER IN THE HOUSE
BEFORE IN MY LIFE!
THAT'S FUNNY, BECAUSE
I'VE GOT A WITNESS
WHO SAW YOU THERE
DURING A GARAGE SALE.
[SCOFFING]
WHAT, I CAN'T GO
TO A GARAGE SALE?
THE STUFF THAT I SAW
WAS ON THE DRIVEWAY.
I WAS NEVER IN THE HOUSE!
BUT SOMEHOW, JUST SOMEHOW,
YOU KNEW RIGHT WHERE A VALUABLE
SET OF ANTIQUE IVORIES
WAS LOCATED?
I HAD NO IDEA.
I DIDN'T
BREAK INTO THE HOUSE, OKAY?
CELESTE DID.
SHE OPENED THE GLASS DOOR,
AND I WALKED IN.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'RE DUMB
OR JUST STUPID.
I'VE GOT YOU
IN THREE DIFFERENT STATES,
ALL BURGLARIES.
IT WASN'T ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THEY WERE DOING IN THERE.
THEY JUST ASKED ME
TO GIVE THEM A RIDE.
RIGHT NOW COPS ARE GOING
THROUGH THAT SHACK
YOU CALL A HOME.
A LOT OF STOLEN GOODS
ARE TURNING UP.
WHATEVER.
I DIDN'T STEAL THEM.
YOU DO KNOW
THAT DRIVING A CAR
INVOLVED IN A CRIME
IS THE SAME THING AS
COMMITTING THE CRIME, RIGHT?
WE WERE IN A VAN.
[SHUDDERING AND WHIMPERING]
I WAS AFRAID OF HIM--
[CRYING]
I WANTED TO LEAVE, BUT...
HE WAS ABUSIVE,
PHYSICALLY.
[ADAM]: I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
MAYBE A JUDGE WILL,
MAYBE NOT.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN TO ME?
NOT GOOD THINGS.
STATE PENITENTIARY.
YOU KNOW, THE DEAD BODY
COULD COMPLICATE STUFF--
SHE WAS ALREADY DEAD, I SWEAR!
IF RIGHT NOW,
YOU TELL ME THE TRUTH,
YOU ARE STATE'S EVIDENCE.
YOUR FRIENDS WILL TAKE THE FALL.
YOU MAY WALK, PROBATION.
BUT, CELESTE, ONE LIE,
AND THIS CONVERSATION IS OVER.
OKAY.
DID RALPH
PHYSICALLY ABUSE YOU?
[SCOFFS TERSELY]
NO.
GOOD START.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED
THE NIGHT YOU TOOK
THE JADE BUDDHA.
WE CHECKED OUT THE HOUSE
AT THE GARAGE SALE.
PEOPLE HAD NICE THINGS,
NICE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I JIMMIED THE WINDOW
AND CLIMBED IN.
I CAN DO IT SO THERE'S NO MARKS.
I OPENED THE BACK DOOR...
AND THERE WAS THIS STUFF
ON THE SHELF,
THE JADE BUDDHA,
SOME OTHER THINGS.
BUT WE WERE AFTER MONEY
AND JEWELRY,
AND THAT'S ALWAYS
KEPT UPSTAIRS,
SO WE WERE ABOUT TO GO UP,
AND THAT'S WHEN
WE JUST SAW HER LYING THERE.
SHE WAS DEAD, MAN.
WE TURNED AND RAN BACK.
I GRABBED THE BUDDHA
ON THE WAY OUT.
IT WAS SOMETHING, AT LEAST.
I THOUGHT IT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BRING GOOD LUCK.
GUESS NOT.
IT'S SO SIMPLE,
IT MAKES SENSE.
SLIP IN THE BACK DOOR,
SEE A DEAD BODY,
PANIC AND FLEE,
STOP JUST LONG ENOUGH
TO GRAB ONE THING.
IF SHE'S A LIAR,
SHE'S A GOOD ONE.
I BELIEVE HER.
YEAH, ME TOO.
UNLESS SOMEONE
CHANGES THEIR STORY,
I THINK WE'VE GOT THIS
ALL WRAPPED UP.
WILL SHE GO
TO PRISON?
DOUBT IT.
NO PRIORS.
THE OTHER TWO, ABSOLUTELY.
HEY, CAN I, UH...
[CLEARS THROAT]
CAN I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
SURE.
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLING NERVOUSLY]
THIS IS AWKWARD
AS HECK...
WHAT?
AND IF YOU TELL ME
TO TAKE A LEAP,
I WILL DROP IT.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WELL, UH...
I ENJOYED MEETING
YOUR DAUGHTER.
I LIKE HER TOO.
GOOD, UM, OKAY.
WELL--
SHE'S AN ADULT.
YOU ASK HER, NOT ME.
BUT... SINCE
I AM HER MOM,
IF YOU TREAT HER BADLY,
I WILL TAKE YOUR BADGE
AND PIN IT SOMEPLACE SENSITIVE.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
HEY, BEN, WHAT'S UP?
SURE.
SURE, I CAN DO THAT.
I APPRECIATE
THIS SO MUCH.
IT'S JUST,
IT'S SOMETHING
THAT I'D REALLY
RATHER NOT DO.
OH, I UNDERSTAND.
THE CEREMONY TOMORROW
WILL BE FOR
IMMEDIATE FAMILY ONLY.
OF COURSE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO MAKE
OF THE FACT
THAT THE HOUSE WAS
BROKEN INTO.
I THINK IT WAS JUST
BAD TIMING ON THEIR PART,
THAT'S ALL.
YEAH, THE DETECTIVE
SEEMED PRETTY SURE,
AND IT MAKES SENSE.
WHY BREAK IN, ATTACK SOMEONE,
AND THEN NOT
CLEAN THE PLACE OUT?
I AGREE.
I'VE GOT TO GET
OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
ARE YOU OKAY INSIDE?
OH, YES, I'LL BE FINE.
MR. DONALDSON
FROM THE CHAPEL
SAID THAT YOU COULD JUST
DROP IT BY
ANY TIME THIS AFTERNOON.
OKAY, BEN, UM...
FOR THE DRESS, DID YOU HAVE
SOMETHING IN MIND?
OH.
I DON'T KNOW, UM...
[VOICE BREAKING]
THERE WAS A NAVY BLUE DRESS
THAT SHE LIKED.
IT WAS SILK.
AND ANYTHING ELSE
THAT YOU THINK
MIGHT BE APPROPRIATE.
YOU KNOW, I CAN
STAY IF YOU WANT.
NO. NO, YOU GO ON.
I'LL BE OKAY.
JUST CLOSE THE DOOR
WHEN YOU LEAVE, IT'S LOCKED.
YEAH.
OH, AND...
I THINK IT WOULD MAKE HER HAPPY
TO KNOW THAT THOSE PURSES
WERE GOING TO BENEFIT
HER CHARITY.
THEY'RE IN THE WALK-IN CLOSET
ON THE RIGHT-HAND SIDE.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
THANKS AGAIN.
[SIGHS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[♪]
SLIP,
AND STOCKINGS?
OH, YES,
I HAVE STOCKINGS
RIGHT HERE.
AND, UM,
A PEARL NECKLACE
AND EARRINGS.
OH.
YOU KNOW THESE ARE IMITATION.
REALLY?
WELL, I JUST GRABBED
WHAT WAS THERE.
DOES IT MAKE A DIFFERENCE?
OH, NO.
WE JUST NOTE THAT,
IN CASE SOMEONE
MAKES A LATER CLAIM.
THANK YOU.
UM, I WON'T BE ATTENDING
THE SERVICE TOMORROW.
COULD I POSSIBLY SAY GOODBYE
TO HER JUST FOR A MOMENT?
OH. WELL...
IT WOULD MEAN A LOT TO ME.
AFTER THE ACCIDENT,
I WAS THE ONE
THAT DISCOVERED HER.
IT'S BEEN VERY UPSETTING.
I COULD USE THE CLOSURE.
AND... THIS KINDNESS
WOULD BE KEPT
BETWEEN US, OF COURSE.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND
THAT SHE WILL LOOK
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT TOMORROW.
HAIR, MAKEUP, NAILS...
I UNDERSTAND.
WILL FIVE MINUTES
BE SUFFICIENT?
YES, THANK YOU.
HEY.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
I HAD THE WEIRDEST
DAY TODAY.
FIRST I WENT
TO A PAWN SHOP
WITH DETECTIVE IVERSON,
WHO, BY THE WAY,
WANTS TO ASK HANNAH OUT.
I WISH HIM LUCK.
AND THEN WE WENT TO
INTERROGATE THE THIEVES.
YOU INTERROGATED THE THIEVES?
I WATCHED.
THE GUYS LIED.
THE GIRL ADMITTED
TO BREAKING IN,
BUT SAID KATE
WAS ALREADY DEAD.
I NEED YOUR HELP
TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
[SIGHS]
RIGHT, LEFT, OR BOTH?
BOTH. PLEASE?
I DROPPED ONE OF HER EARRINGS,
AND I KNEELED DOWN
TO PICK IT UP,
AND I SEE, UNDER THE BED,
AN ACRYLIC NAIL TIP.
I'M NO EXPERT
ON NAILS,
BUT THEY DO
BREAK OFF, RIGHT?
YEAH, THEY DO,
BUT KATE TOLD ME
SHE WAS HAVING HER NAILS DONE
THE DAY BEFORE WE WERE
SUPPOSED TO HAVE LUNCH,
AND WHEN I SAW HER
AT THE FUNERAL HOME,
HER NAIL WAS BROKEN.
I'M NOT GETTING
THE SIGNIFICANCE OF THIS.
IT'S JUST...
IT'S JUST LITTLE THINGS
ADDING UP TO SOMETHING.
OKAY.
I WENT TO HER
JEWELRY BOX
TO GET A STRING
OF PEARLS.
I SEE ONE OF HER BRACELETS,
DIAMONDS, BEAUTIFUL.
BUT IT DOESN'T FEEL RIGHT.
SO I HOLD IT UP TO THE WINDOW.
IT'S NOT REAL.
HONEY, I'M STILL LOST.
SO SHE HAD A FAKE BRACELET.
WELL, THE PEARLS
WERE A FAKE, TOO.
BUT THE THING THAT
HAS ME FREAKED OUT...
IT LOOKED LIKE THERE WAS
A LITTLE DRIED BLOOD
ON THE BED FRAME.
WHAT DOES
DETECTIVE IVERSON THINK?
OH, SWITCH. [GROANING]
WELL, I HAVEN'T
TALKED TO HIM YET,
NOT ABOUT
THIS NEW INFO.
HE SAYS ACCIDENT, RIGHT?
YES, BUT WE NOW KNOW
THAT THERE WAS A BREAK-IN
THE NIGHT THAT SHE DIED.
ALL RIGHT,
AND WHAT DO YOU THINK?
[SIGHS] I DON'T KNOW.
JUST THAT KATE WOULDN'T HAVE
FAKE ANYTHING.
SHE WAS PROUD OF HER HOME,
THEIR CARS,
HER LIFESTYLE.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
HEY, A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO,
WE WERE THINKING ABOUT USING BEN
AS OUR FINANCIAL GUY--
I WISH WE HAD.
EVERYONE WHO USES HIM
IS DOING QUITE WELL.
WHY DIDN'T WE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK I JUST WANTED
TO KEEP OUR INVESTMENTS
WHERE WE ALWAYS HAD THEM.
IN THIS HOUSE?
EXACTLY.
[LAUGHING]
OH, THANK YOU.
OH, TWO FOR ONE,
TWO FOR ONE...
[LAUGHING]
[♪]
[KNOCKS GENTLY]
LOGAN?
[KNOCKS]
[FLICKS LIGHT SWITCH]
HI, MOM.
IS IT SAFE TO COME IN?
YOU SHOULD BE IN BED.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
I'VE MADE LEVEL SIX.
OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
I THINK.
DAD SAYS YOU'RE ALL WORKED UP
OVER YOUR FRIEND DYING AND ALL.
OH. WELL, I DON'T KNOW
IF I WOULD PUT IT THAT WAY,
BUT I'M DEFINITELY TRYING
TO FIGURE A FEW THINGS OUT.
YOU'LL DO IT.
I HAVE FAITH.
YOU'VE GOT THE BEST
PROBLEM-SOLVING MIND I'VE MET.
THANK YOU.
I'M SERIOUS.
YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN
A GREAT GAMER
IF YOU WEREN'T
A GARAGE SALE DIVA.
HOW COME I NEVER KNOW
IF I'M BEING COMPLIMENTED
OR INSULTED BY YOU?
[CHUCKLES] ALWAYS
COMPLIMENTS, MOMS.
BUT, FOR REAL,
DID YOU KNOW
THAT RESEARCH
SHOWED GAMERS
TO HAVE REMARKABLE
LOGICAL THINKING,
PROBLEM SOLVING,
OBSERVATIONAL
AND VISUAL SKILLS?
NO.
NOT ONLY THAT,
BUT PARENTS AND CHILDREN
WHO PLAY TOGETHER
HAVE BETTER RELATIONSHIPS.
JUST FORGET ABOUT WHAT
YOU'RE TRYING TO SOLVE,
FOCUS ON THE GAME,
AND WHEN YOU'RE DONE,
YOU MIGHT HAVE
YOUR ANSWER.
MY SON, YODA.
[CHUCKLES]
OKAY, DO I KNOW THIS GAME?
YUP. MINECRAFT.
IT'LL HOOVER THE CORNERS
OF YOUR BRAIN.
RIGHT, MINECRAFT.
I THINK I REMEMBER THIS.
FRONT, BACK,
LEFT, RIGHT...
YEAH.
OKAY...
[HANNAH]:
YOU DOING OKAY?
[ADAM, BREATHLESSLY]:
I'M FINE. FINE...
WE'VE GONE A COUPLE
MILES NOW, RIGHT?
ALMOST.
GREAT.
YEAH, NO SWEAT.
SO MY MOM JUST
NEVER GIVES UP.
AND IT'S AMAZING
WHAT TURNS UP
AT THESE GARAGE SALES.
I LOVE GOING WITH HER
AND WATCHING HER
DO HER THING.
YEAH, I WAS GOING TO GO
TO A FEW NOW MYSELF.
IF YOU WANTED TO COME,
THAT MIGHT BE FUN.
ARE YOU ASKING ME
ON A DATE
TO A GARAGE SALE?
WELL... I THOUGHT,
IT MIGHT BE FUN--
I MIGHT CONSIDER
DINNER AND A MOVIE,
BUT ONLY
IF YOU CAN KEEP UP.
I CAN KEEP UP.
THAT'S GOOD, DOOGIE.
'CAUSE, AT SCHOOL,
I'M ON
THE CROSS-COUNTRY TEAM.
[SIGHS AND CHUCKLES]
...WE'VE GOT MORE
DESKS OVER THERE,
AND I'M AROUND IF YOU
NEED ANY MORE HELP.
OKAY, HAVE FUN.
OH, HI!
HELLO.
I'M RICHARD MILLER
FROM THE ASIAN ARTS GALLERY.
YOU SENT ME AN E-MAIL
CONCERNING
A REPRODUCTION QING VASE.
YEAH, I'M SORRY.
YOU DIDN'T NEED TO COME
ALL THE WAY DOWN HERE.
I WAS JUST LOOKING FOR
A LITTLE MORE INFORMATION
BEFORE I PUT IT UP ON E-BAY.
MAY I SEE IT?
SURE.
CAREFUL!
WHY? YOU DON'T THINK
IT'S WORTH ANYTHING, DO YOU?
IF SOMEONE IS GOING TO MAKE
A HIGH-QUALITY FAKE,
IT'S USUALLY MING DYNASTY.
THIS IS LATER, QING.
NO ONE REALLY BOTHERS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN A GOOD FAKE,
BUT THIS, THIS IS GOOD.
THIS IS VERY GOOD.
YES, WHAT, UM,
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE FOR IT?
$75?
75... IT'S--
OH!
WELL, YOU MUST HAVE
MIS-MARKED IT.
THE TAG SAYS 50.
[SNAPS FINGERS]
WELL, THERE YOU ARE.
OUR LOSS.
VERY GOOD.
OH, GREAT!
OKAY...
I'LL GET A BOX.
YOU'RE AN EXPERT.
I'VE ALWAYS WONDERED,
IS IT "VAH-SE" OR "VAY-SE"?
WHEN SOMETHING IS THIS NICE,
IT DESERVES TO BE CALLED
"VAH-SE." HMM?
UH-HUH.
AND HOW DID YOU
FIGURE THIS OUT?
VIDEO GAMES.
MY SON'S IDEA.
SO YOU SAW THE BODY?
AND KATE WAS MISSING
AN ACRYLIC NAIL.
I FOUND IT UNDER THE BED.
OKAY.
SO WHAT'S YOUR THEORY?
I THINK RALPH SURPRISED KATE
IN THE BEDROOM.
HE KNOCKED HER DOWN,
HE PANICKED,
AND THEN HE THREW HER
DOWN THE STAIRS.
THEY RAN OUT,
BUT CELESTE HAD TO TAKE
JUST ONE THING.
THE BUDDHA,
FOR GOOD LUCK.
YES.
WHEN KATE FELL,
SHE CUT HER HAND
ON THE BED FRAME,
AND SHE TORE OFF
HER FINGERNAIL.
I THINK THAT THERE'S DRIED BLOOD
ON THE BED FRAME.
DETECTIVE?
MR. DOUGLASS.
THIS WILL ONLY
TAKE A MINUTE.
JUST TRYING TO TIE UP
SOME LOOSE ENDS.
SURE. NO PROBLEM.
COME ON IN.
THIS TEST CAN TELL US
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY
IF A DRIED SUBSTANCE
IS HUMAN BLOOD.
WHERE DID THIS
SUDDENLY COME UP?
WHY HERE?
WHO SAW BLOOD ON THE SIDE
OF THE BED, FOR GOD'S SAKE?
IN THE QUESTIONING
OF OUR SUSPECTS,
THERE WERE SOME INCONSISTENCIES.
PLEASE DON'T TELL ME THAT
YOU THINK KATE WAS ASSAULTED.
PLEASE DON'T
TELL ME THAT,
NOT NOW.
[CLEARS THROAT] MR. DOUGLASS,
WHEN NEW INFORMATION
COMES FORWARD,
WE ACT UPON IT.
ARE YOU PEOPLE
COMPLETELY INCOMPETENT?
MY WIFE MAY HAVE BEEN MURDERED,
AND YOU DIDN'T INVESTIGATE
THE CRIME SCENE
PROPERLY?
[DOORBELL BEEPS]
HELLO.
THESE PURSES OF KATE'S
ARE UNBELIEVABLE.
I FEEL KIND OF WEIRD
JUST TOUCHING THEM.
KATE WAS A BIG SUPPORTER
OF THE ANIMAL RESCUE.
BEN THOUGHT IT WOULD BE
A NICE MEMORIAL.
SO... I HAVE BIG NEWS.
I HAVE BIG NEWS!
OKAY.
-OKAY, ADAM CALLED.
-MM-HM?
THE TEST SHOWED POSITIVE
FOR BLOOD ON THE BED FRAME.
OH, MY GOD.
YOU ALMOST SINGLE-HANDEDLY
SOLVED THIS.
OH, WELL, HARDLY,
BUT ADAM IS
VERY APPRECIATIVE OF MY HELP,
AND HE SAID HE WOULD
KEEP ME INFORMED.
YOU'RE A NATURAL!
THIS IS, LIKE,
YOUR DESTINY.
NO, BECAUSE
YOU SEE ALL THE LITTLE THINGS,
AND THEN
YOU PUT THEM ALL TOGETHER,
AND YOU SOLVE THE QUESTION.
YOU WERE BORN TO DO THIS.
WELL...
I'M SERIOUS.
THE POLICE SHOULD HIRE YOU.
OH, COME ON.
HEY...
WHAT'S THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
SOMETHING.
[STAMMERING] NO,
NO, DON'T TOUCH IT!
WHY?
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT
TREATED IT LIKE A FOOTBALL.
I THOUGHT YOU SOLD THIS.
I DID.
THAT'S MY BIG NEWS. SIT.
OH, THIS SHOULD BE GOOD.
[LAUGHING]
WELL, MR. MILLER
FROM THE GALLERY
RETURNED IT.
HE THINKS THE FAKE'S
A FAKE?
NO.
HE THINKS THE FAKE IS...
[WHISPERING] REAL!
SERIOUS?
HE SAID HIS ETHICAL STANDARDS
WOULDN'T ALLOW HIM TO KEEP IT,
SO HE OFFERED TO BUY IT FROM US,
OR WE COULD CONSIGN IT
WITH THEM FOR AUCTION.
HOW MUCH?
HE WOULD GIVE US $110,000.
TODAY.
[CHUCKLING IN DISBELIEF]
AND THE ESTIMATE FOR THE ROOF
IS ONLY 20.
LEGALLY, IT'S OURS.
[LAUGHS BREATHLESSLY]
JEN?
[SIGHS] THIS HURTS.
HI.
WELL... HERE IT IS.
[GASPING]
I HAD NO IDEA.
COME IN, PLEASE.
OH, THANK YOU, BUT WE CAN'T.
WE JUST WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THIS GOT BACK TO YOU SAFELY.
OH, THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
[CHUCKLES]
WE USED TO PUT FLOWERS IN IT
WHEN I WAS A CHILD.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
WELL, JUST DON'T SELL IT
AT YOUR NEXT GARAGE SALE.
[LAUGHING] I WON'T.
MR. MILLER IS ON HIS WAY OVER.
DO YOU THINK I SHOULD
ACCEPT HIS OFFER?
I THINK MR. MILLER
IS AN HONEST MAN.
AND YOU ARE HONEST WOMEN.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT THIS MEANS TO ME.
WELL, WE'RE GLAD
IT ALL WORKED OUT.
REALLY,
YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
MY HOUSE IS ABOUT TO GO
INTO FORECLOSURE.
THANKS TO THIS,
I'LL BE ABLE TO
PAY OFF MY MORTGAGE...
YOU ARE MY ANGELS.
THANK YOU.
DETECTIVE BY DAY,
HOUSEWIFE BY NIGHT.
WELL, I'VE BEEN RETIRED.
I KNOW.
ADAM STOPPED BY
MY OFFICE.
GREAT.
I WAS JUST TRYING TO HELP.
AND YOU DID.
YOU ARE AMAZING.
HE GIVES YOU FULL CREDIT.
I KNOW, BUT I'VE BEEN
TOO INVOLVED ALREADY.
YOU KNOW HOW MUCH
I LOVE YOU, RIGHT?
AND WHEN YOU GET IT
IN YOUR MIND TO DO SOMETHING,
THERE'S NO
STOPPING YOU.
OKAY, DON'T WORRY.
I'M GOING TO LEAVE IT
TO THE PROS.
IT'S A MURDER
INVESTIGATION NOW.
MAYBE MURDER.
ADAM SAYS BLOOD JUST MEANS
THAT AT SOME POINT,
SOMEONE MAY HAVE CUT THEMSELVES
IN THE BEDROOM.
RIGHT, WHAT DO I KNOW?
I'M JUST A GARAGE-SALE DIVA.
WHERE DID
THAT COME FROM?
[LAUGHS] OUR SON.
AW, AND A GREAT COOK.
A PHILANTHROPIST, TOO.
I GAVE AWAY $110,000 TODAY.
[LOGAN]: MORNING, MOM.
HEY, SWEETHEART.
ARE YOU GOING
TO A GARAGE SALE?
I KNOW, ATLANTIS II
AND SUPER SIDEKICK.
ANY OLD ATARI.
GOT IT.
[KEYS JINGLING]
THANKS, MOM!
LOVE YOU.
[♪]
JUST THIS.
THANKS.
OH, UH, IT PAYS
TO CHECK THESE OUT.
I ONCE FOUND A $20 BILL
IN AN INSIDE POCKET.
I ALMOST SOLD
A PAIR OF PANTS
WITH A CREDIT CARD.
I ALWAYS GO THROUGH
EVERYTHING INSIDE AND OUT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M KATHERINE.
HOW MAY I HELP YOU?
OH, HI, I'M JENNIFER.
-PLEASE.
-OH, THANK YOU.
AS "FAMILY LAW," YOU
HANDLE DIVORCE, RIGHT?
WE SPECIALIZE IN DIFFICULT
AND CONTESTED DIVORCE CASES.
ARE YOU SEEKING
REPRESENTATION?
UH, NO.
I'M A FRIEND OF KATE DOUGLASS.
WAS... A FRIEND.
I READ ABOUT THAT.
I'M SO SORRY.
I FOUND YOUR CARD
IN ONE OF HER PURSES.
WELL, THAT'S INTERESTING.
DID YOU REPRESENT HER?
WAS SHE SEEKING A DIVORCE?
I COULDN'T ANSWER THAT
IF I WAS REPRESENTING HER.
WE CHARGE A LOT OF MONEY
FOR DISCRETION.
BUT SINCE
SHE IS DECEASED,
I WILL TELL YOU
THAT I HAVE NEVER SPOKEN
TO KATE DOUGLASS,
ABOUT ANYTHING.
HOW ARE YOU
CONCERNED?
UM, I'M HELPING HER HUSBAND WITH
SOME OF HER BELONGINGS.
I FOUND YOUR CARD,
AND I WAS CURIOUS.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
[MUTTERING QUIETLY]
INDIANAPOLIS TO HERE,
CAN YOU DRIVE IT?
OH, BEN, PLEASE BE TOO FAR.
OH, MAN.
WOULD'VE BEEN A LONG DRIVE,
BUT YOU COULD HAVE DONE IT.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
HEY, SWEETHEART.
NO, I'M JUST
CLEANING UP SOME PAPERWORK.
PIZZA? YEAH, THAT'S FINE.
JUST SAVE ME A SLICE.
OH, HONEY, WILL YOU
HAVE LOGAN CALL ME?
IT'S A COMPUTER THING.
THANKS.
[SIGHS]
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
HEY, LOGAN.
I'M GETTING
A "DEVICE NOT RECOGNIZED" THING
WHEN I TRY TO OPEN
A FLASH DRIVE.
YOU CAN DO THAT?
OKAY, WELL, NO,
I'M ALREADY ON-LINE.
OKAY.
"REQUEST FOR REMOTE ACCESS,"
SO I HIT "ALLOW."
PERFECT.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL GO TO THAT.
OH, MY GOODNESS, LOGAN,
YOU ARE A GENIUS. THANK YOU.
OH, AND DON'T TELL YOUR DAD
WHAT I'M UP TO, OKAY?
THANKS.
OH, WOW.
"BEN, IF YOU DON'T ADMIT
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE,
THEN YOU LEAVE ME NO CHOICE.
I WILL NOT STAND BY SOMEONE
WHO HAS DEVASTATED FRIENDS,
FAMILY, CLIENTS.
IF YOU DO THE RIGHT THING,
THEN YOU HAVE MY FULL SUPPORT.
WE CAN START OVER..."
"KATE."
OH, MY...
BEN, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHY ARE YOU INVESTIGATING ME?
WHY ARE YOU GOING TO MY LAWYER
AND ASKING ABOUT MY MARRIAGE?
YOU FOUND A BUSINESS CARD
IN ONE OF KATE'S PURSES?
WHAT ELSE DID YOU FIND?
BEN, YOU'RE SCARING ME.
PUT IT DOWN, JEN.
MOVE AWAY FROM THE COMPUTER.
MOVE!
I'VE ALREADY CALLED
DETECTIVE IVERSON
AND TOLD HIM EVERYTHING.
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOU'RE LIKE MADOFF, RIGHT?
ON A SMALLER SCALE.
ONLY KATE WOULDN'T STAND BY
AND LET YOU GET AWAY WITH IT.
SHE INSISTED THAT YOU ADMIT
THAT YOU LOST
YOUR CLIENTS' MONEY.
I HAVE ENOUGH,
MORE THAN ENOUGH,
TO LIVE NICELY IN BRUNEI.
I COULDN'T FIGURE OUT
HOW YOU GOT
FROM INDIANAPOLIS TO HERE,
BUT THEN I REALIZED, YOU DROVE.
IT'S ONLY EIGHT HOURS.
SO KATE HAD NO IDEA
THAT YOU WERE COMING HOME
THAT NIGHT...
[FLOORBOARD CREAKS]
[JENNIFER]: I KNEW IT HAPPENED
IN THE BEDROOM.
BUT YOU DIDN'T REALIZE
THAT SHE CUT HER HAND
AND TORE OFF HER FINGERNAIL
WHEN SHE HIT THE BED FRAME.
[BLUNT THUD]
BECAUSE I FOUND THE NAIL
UNDERNEATH THE BED.
YOU WANTED IT TO LOOK
LIKE AN ACCIDENT.
SO YOU CARRIED YOUR WIFE
TO THE TOP OF THE STAIRS...
AND YOU TOSSED HER
LIKE YOU WERE
THROWING OUT THE TRASH.
[SIGHS]
THIS IS WHAT HAD ME WORRIED.
IT WAS MISSING
FROM MY OFFICE,
AND I HAD NO IDEA
WHERE IT WAS.
AND NOW I THINK IT'S TIME
I TOOK A VACATION.
[GUNSHOTS CRACK]
[SHOTS BLAST AND SMASH]
[SHOTS RICOCHET, JEN YELPS]
[BOARDS CREAKING]
[FOOT CRUNCHES]
[WOOD SPLINTERING]
[HE SCREAMS]
[POLICE RADIOS CRACKLE]
HEY, HOW WAS
YOUR DATE?
OH, MY GOD,
ARE YOU OKAY?
-YES, I'M FINE.
-ARE YOU SURE?
YEAH, I'M FINE.
I'M FINE.
WELL, IF THERE IS
SUCH THING AS KARMA,
WE JUST SAW IT.
LOTS OF BROKEN BONES,
LOTS OF PAIN.
HE'LL BE GOOD TO STAND TRIAL
IN A FEW MONTHS.
YOU REALLY ARE SOMETHING.
WHAT SET HIM OFF?
I MEAN, WHY GO AFTER
JEN SO SUDDENLY?
THE VISIT TO BEN'S LAWYER.
THE SECOND JENNIFER
LEFT HER OFFICE,
SHE CALLED BEN.
HE FLIPPED OUT,
NOT KNOWING EXACTLY
WHAT SHE KNEW,
AND WONDERING IF SHE
HAD THE FLASH DRIVE
THAT HE WAS MISSING
FROM HIS OFFICE.
HE HAD LOST A LOT OF
HIS CLIENTS' MONEY.
KATE FOUND OUT,
AND SHE THREATENED TO EXPOSE HIM
IF HE DIDN'T COME CLEAN.
[SIGHS]
CAN I GET HER HOME NOW?
PLEASE.
[CELL PHONE RINGS] SORRY.
GREAT, NOW YOUR DAUGHTER
WANTS TO KNOW
HOW I COULD HAVE PUT YOU
IN HARM'S WAY.
OKAY, YOU GUYS GO.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF EVERYTHING.
THANK YOU.
-OKAY.
I'LL CALL YOU TOMORROW.
OKAY.
I THOUGHT
YOU WERE GOING TO
LEAVE THIS ALONE.
I TRIED.
I REALLY TRIED.
I EVEN WENT TO
A GARAGE SALE THIS MORNING
TO TRY TO GET MY GROOVE BACK...
AND THEN I HAD AN IDEA.
AND I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
BECAUSE I PROMISED YOU
I WAS DONE.
WELL, THE BAD GUY WOULD HAVE
GOTTEN AWAY WITH IT
IF NOT FOR YOU.
BUT FROM HERE ON OUT,
CAN YOU PLEASE
JUST STICK TO GARAGE SALES?
I'LL TRY.
[CHUCKLING]
I WONDER IF INSURANCE
WOULD PAY FOR THE ROOF?
I THINK YOU'VE DONE
ENOUGH WONDERING
FOR ONE DAY.
[♪]
ALL RIGHT, 40 BUCKS.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU.
WELL, THIS WAS
A GENIUS IDEA.
ALL THE STUFF WE BOUGHT
AT A THOUSAND GARAGE SALES,
WE TURN AROUND, SELL IT,
AND THEN GIVE AWAY
THE MONEY.
DANI, IT'S FOR
A GOOD CAUSE.
THINK ABOUT ALL THE
ANIMALS WE'LL BE HELPING.
AND BESIDES,
ISN'T THIS ALL THE STUFF
WE TRIED TO SELL ALREADY
BUT COULDN'T?
YEAH.
IT'LL MAKE ROOM FOR MORE--
-STUFF.
-THERE YOU GO.
WHY DIDN'T I
THINK OF THAT?
-HEY, ADAM.
-MM-HM?
COME HERE. I WANT
TO SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
OKAY.
IT'S AN ANTIQUE BADGE.
NICE.
VERY NICE.
THAT'S FOR
WATCHING OUT FOR MY MOM.
I DIDN'T DO
A VERY GOOD JOB.
WELL, WITH HER,
ALL WE CAN DO IS TRY.
HEY, MOM!
I FOUND SOMETHING INTERESTING
INSIDE THIS WOODEN BOX
FILLED WITH THESE OLD
METAL TOY SOLDIERS.
IS THIS TO
A SAFE DEPOSIT BOX?
MAYBE WITH CASH INSIDE?
OH, NO.
THIS KEY HAS
A NUMBER ON IT.
THIS COULD BE VERY INTERESTING.
[SIGHS]
[♪]