The marsh ended
in a broad plain where
the light twinkled.
It was a long time since Mowgli had
concerned himself with
the doings of men.
I will look, he said, and I will see
how far the man pack has changed.
The door of the hut opened, and a woman
stood peering into the darkness.
Who calls, said the woman,
a quiver in her voice.
Have you forgotten, said Mowgli.
His throat was dry as he spoke.
Have you ever stayed
in a shelter before?
Just walk-ins.
Never for the night.
And both your parents are dead, right?
Leslie?
Yes.
And how were you when they died?
I'm sorry.
That must have been very difficult.
How old were you?
I was seven.
It was eight.
Eight.
And did you go and live with a relative,
then, who looked after you?
It... uh, an uncle.
We stayed with an uncle.
We?
Who is we?
You and who else?
My brother.
Trixie, come on, girl.
Come on, Trixie.
Trixie, we gotta go now.
Where are you, girl?
Come on, Trixie.
Where are you?
Hey, sweetheart.
You live around here?
Have you seen my dog?
It's a little white terrier.
It's got black spots around its eyes.
No.
Oh, boy.
Well, we were up here
working, and this big Labrador
came along, and they ran off together.
And I've looked everywhere.
I have a Labrador.
A light brown Labrador?
Mm-hmm.
Did you see it play with
a little white terrier?
No.
No?
Are you sure?
What's your dog's name?
Elvis.
Elvis?
That's a good name.
My dog's name's Trixie.
Do you think they could be
playing in your backyard?
I don't know.
Is your Mommy home?
She's at work.
Yeah?
Well, I bet they're up there right now
tearing up your Dad's flower bed.
Could we go take a look? Real quick?
Come on.
Come on, honey.
Hello, Elvis.
Hey, Elvis.
Have you seen Trixie?
Trixie?
Come here, Trixie.
Come here, girl.
Thanks a lot for helping look for her.
I'm gonna check the pound.
She's probably there.
She can be a bad dog
sometimes, you know?
Are you on your way to school?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, great.
Now I'm making you late.
I'm sorry.
What school do you go to?
St. Andrews.
St. Andrews?
I went to St. Andrews.
Over on Hoover?
Well, come on, I'll give you a ride.
Come on in.
We'll get there lickety-split.
Come on.
Why didn't you say so?
What'd you say your name was again?
Leslie.
Leslie, I'm Alex.
This is Frank.
Hey.
Oh, St. Andrews.
I'll tell you.
Does Mrs. Williams
still teach music there?
Bright red hair... she's
probably pretty old now.
She used to play the tuba really bad.
Yeah.
It's your lucky day, Leslie,
because I'm showing you
a shortcut I used to take
when I was late for school.
What'd you say your last name was?
Whitehead.
Whitehead?
Is Mr. Whitehead your Daddy?
Oh, my gosh.
You're kidding me.
We work for Mr. Whitehead.
He's our boss.
At the Water Company.
Yes, at the Water Company.
You know what, I've worked
there almost as long as he has.
I run errands for him sometimes.
I... I might have got your
birthday present for you.
Did you get a big doll
for your birthday?
No.
Oh.
Well, it's still
something, isn't it, Frank?
Huh?
Well, I'm gonna tell him I gave
his daughter a ride to school,
but I'm not gonna say anything
about making her late.
Here we go.
All right.
Have a good one.
Of course I'm gonna do my homework.
I'm almost done.
I'm on the very last chapter.
Bye.
Hey Leslie, quick.
We're gonna give you a lift.
What?
Your Daddy asked us to take you.
There's been a problem
at the Water Company.
I'm going home.
They ain't there, honey.
Where are they?
Get in, and I'll explain.
Come on, Leslie.
Get in the car.
Your Daddy's in some trouble, and he
had to leave Wilmington right away.
Where's my Mom?
She went with him.
She went straight from work.
Why didn't they take me?
Because they asked us
to because it was urgent.
We're going to take you to them.
So come on, let's go.
Ok, we're going to take you to them.
Don't worry.
Why didn't they wait for me?
I don't understand.
Well, it all happened so quickly.
Your Dad called me at the office.
He said to pick you up.
He's in a little bit
of trouble, but it's
nothing serious, so
don't worry about it.
Just eat your hamburger
and drink your drink,
and we'll get you back
to him in no time.
Come on.
Drink it.
Do you have a phone call to make, Alex?
Oh, that's right.
Anyone sees a pay phone, holler.
Yes, she's with us now,
and everything is fine.
Is... Ok.
Ok, that's not a problem.
We'll hear from you
then, Mr. Whitehead.
Ok, thank you.
Bye, now.
Well, that was your Daddy.
And he said everything is a-OK.
He's gonna call us later.
When am I going home?
Soon.
Now drink up your drink, honey.
It's warm.
I'll tell you what.
You drink all of that one, and I'll
get you an ice cold one next.
Go on.
Drink it up.
Help.
Where are we?
All right, folks.
It's bath time.
Ok, let's get undressed and jump in.
Come on.
It's just a bath.
It's not going to bite.
I'm shy too.
Hey, you gotta rub it harder
if you want to get it clean.
Right?
Nobody likes little
boys with dirty hair.
Did Leslie tell you that
she has a dog named Elvis?
Yeah, he's a yellow Labrador.
Right, honey?
Where's Trixie?
Where's who?
Your dog, Trixie.
Oh.
Trixie, well, Frank went
back there to look for her.
And he looked at all the pounds.
And he couldn't find her.
So I guess she's lost.
Poor Trixie.
She shouldn't have run off like that.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Mr. Whitehead.
It's Alex.
Yeah, she's fine.
So how long?
Are you sure?
Ok.
Ok, but hold on a second.
Let me right in down.
All right.
Ok, I guess I'll hear from you then.
Ok.
They don't want her back yet.
Hey, how's your hair?
You want a wash?
I don't believe you.
What have I done wrong?
Nothing.
I want to call them.
I want to speak to them.
They wouldn't leave me.
You can.
I have your Dad's cell phone number.
Hey, it's ok, honey.
We're here.
And we'll take care of you.
Me and Frank, and so will Donnie.
Won't you, Donnie?
We're gonna look out for you.
So don't worry.
It's all going to work out.
I want to speak to them.
Well, of course you do.
So why don't you keep
their phone number,
and you can call them
back anytime you want?
Ok?
Now, Frank's gonna be back
in a couple of minutes
with some new clothes for you.
Let's say our prayers.
Lord, bless this food for
which we are about to receive.
We are ever so grateful.
And bless this house
and all of us in it.
And look out for Donnie's Mom.
We hope she gets well soon.
And bless Leslie's parents, and help
them get through this troubling
time so they may return to her.
Amen.
Ok, enjoy.
Ignition.
Lift off.
30 seconds after the hour.
Development flight
instrumentation recorders
are on.
Power clear.
The next event is lander separation.
The heat shields will separate in about
three, two, one, zero seconds.
Did you go to school?
What does this say?
Action Truck. Can't you read?
No.
Hey!
Did I say eat your fucking cookie, huh?
Is that what I said?
No, I didn't tell you to eat it.
Neither of you... you fucking
don't listen, neither of you.
You want me to let you
in on a little secret?
Your Mama and Dada, they
don't want you anymore.
They haven't called.
They haven't written.
So it seems like they're pretty
happy without the both of you.
Sometimes, you know,
things are very strange.
But no matter how hard you try,
you can never understand them
for why they've done this to you.
Maybe Frank was right.
For whatever reason,
maybe for your Mommy
and Daddy, life was hard.
Things go wrong for them,
and suddenly you're gone.
And who knows why, but their
life gets a little bit easier.
Now, your Daddy, he used to
leave you for a few days,
right?
And your Mom said it was for business.
But he didn't even have time to buy
your birthday presents
for you, remember?
Remember?
I got them for you.
Right?
Well, my Daddy was like that too.
I remember this one time,
he'd been away on a long trip.
And he came home, and that night we
stayed up all night, playing games.
And he read to me.
And I remember thinking, this is
the greatest night of my life.
And then he said, I have to
go buy a pack of cigarettes,
but don't worry, because
I'll be right back.
And he never came back.
And I never saw my Daddy again.
So I know how you feel, honey.
I know that I could never be your Daddy
or be anything like
him or take his place.
But I can be like an uncle.
Uncle Alex.
Get some rest.
Were you crying?
No.
Good.
You can't cry.
Nobody likes little girls who cry.
It makes you look like shit.
So your Alex's little girl now, huh?
Alex's favorite little girl.
And you are my favorite little boy.
Just drive the car.
Puts it up off the glass, and it's
in for two.
Leslie, this is Orlando.
He's a good friend of ours.
He's going to look after
you for a while, ok?
I want you to do whatever he asks.
Ok?
She understands.
Don't worry about it.
She's fine.
All right.
We'll see you in a bit.
All we want to do is have
a little fun, Leslie.
It could be fun for you too.
Hey, you ever cleaned your
Daddy's shoes, each one
you get a dollar?
Did you do nothing like that?
Mow the lawn, clean the car?
I guess that's what little
boys do... mow the lawn
and clean the car.
You see, if you work at
something, it pays off.
If you work like you're
supposed to... you
know, like you would at school.
Only instead of good
grades, you get money.
You pull in enough money, you ain't
got to live on the streets.
And you don't want to do
that, because the streets
is where the devils live.
The streets, you'll get lost forever.
Hey, baby.
What's the matter?
Are you scared?
You know, what we're gonna do is OK.
It's beautiful.
Is it me?
Is it the color of my skin?
That ain't nothing to be frightened of.
It feels just the same as yours.
You want to touch it?
Nothing wrong with that either.
Did you know that?
I bet that's been kept
a secret from you.
I bet you everybody
knows except for you.
Nothing wrong with touching.
Everybody does it.
Teacher does it.
Doctors do it.
The police officers do it.
Everybody does it.
Even your Daddy does it.
Your Daddy touches people.
And if you had stayed home, pretty soon,
he'd have been touching you.
No.
What?
Hey, get over here.
Stop!
Sit down there!
Shut up!
Do you hear me talking to you?
I'm trying to be nice to you, bitch.
What the fuck are you doing to her?
Just stay out of it.
It's OK.
It's ok, baby.
Alex, what the fuck happened?
Get in.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
Go, go, go!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Christ, Alex.
For fuck's sake.
Now, didn't I tell you I'd
always be there to protect you?
Huh?
Nothing's ever going to happen
to you, because I won't let it.
Hey, this is murder, man.
This is fucking murder.
We're all involved in
this, all three of us.
It's ok, Frank, because no one saw us.
All we gotta do is stick together
and support each other.
Shit.
Fucking cops.
Fuck.
Just fuck.
Fuck!
You know, Leslie, we all are
a part of something really terrible now.
But if we help each other
and we stand by each other,
then everything's going to be OK.
Do you understand?
Because I'm not going to tell anybody,
and you're not going to
tell anybody, are you?
No.
Don't worry.
Why did they leave me here?
I hate them.
Leslie?
Shhh.
It's ok, honey.
No, shhh.
That's the old you, honey.
You're just leaving it behind.
That's all,
honey.
Shhh.
It's just like the caterpillar.
He has to shed his skin to
become the beautiful butterfly.
And you don't think that
hurts the caterpillar?
Of course it does, honey.
But it's the only way he can
become a beautiful butterfly.
And that's what you're
becoming... something really,
really beautiful, honey.
Honestly, I think you're beautiful.
Honestly, I would never hurt you.
I would never hurt you, honey.
Shhh.
It's ok, honey.
It's okay now.
It's OK. Shhh.
You've got me.
You've got me, honey.
It's all right.
I'm so proud of you.
Something is coming uphill, said...
Mother Wolf, twitching one ear.
Get ready.
The bushes rustled a
little in the thicket,
and Father Wolf dropped,
ready for his leap.
Man, he snapped.
A man's cub.
Look!
Directly in front of
him, holding a low branch
sit a naked brown baby
who could just walk.
As soft and as dimpled
a little Adam as ever
came to a wolf's cave at night.
He looked up into Father
Wolf's face and laughed.
Is that a man's cub, said Mother Wolf?
I've never seen one before.
Bring it here.
How little, how naked, and how
bold, said Mother Wolf softly.
The baby was pushing
his way between the cubs
to get closer to the warm hide.
He is taking his meal with the others.
He looks like a frog, said Father Wolf.
Then that's what we'll call
him... Mowgli, the Frog.
We should make secret
names for each other.
I could be Mowgli,
and you could be Wolf.
And who are they?
They are the monkey people.
And Mowgli's lost in
the jungle, and Wolf
has to find me and protect me
from the evil, crazy monkeys.
And this is our jungle, and
nobody can come into it.
I had a birthday party once.
It was at the old woman's.
She made me a cake...
A chocolate cake.
It had five candles on it.
Why'd you run away from home?
My Mom went crazy.
She said she wanted to
stuff dogs in a library.
What about your Dad?
He lives in a van somewhere.
Where's your Mom?
They put her in a hospital.
Is that why she sold you?
Do you have any pictures like that?
Uh... I don't.
It's OK.
I could take some.
Then they go in the book.
The book gets sent all over the country.
I send it by Fed Ex.
If they get picked, they're
gonna be flown to the client,
or sometimes the client flies to you.
If the kids fly, I go with them.
I arrange the ID.
And the split is an even 50-50.
It's profitable and safe.
Safe?
That's good.
It's important.
Yeah.
We give partner discounts,
so if there's any...
Oh, no.
I don't... I don't...
No, I don't...
Hm?
I'm not like that.
No, me neither.
Ok, good.
So... cute kids, by the way.
Yeah.
Adorable.
They are.
Really.
Uh, see, I don't want my kids flying.
Ok.
Maybe later.
Yeah, maybe.
Yeah.
Ok, so take a bath.
Take the bath first.
They like that.
Remember, that's a free tip.
Everything's going to be fine.
You know where you're going?
You're going to a judge's house.
You know what that is?
That's a good man.
Judges are fair.
They always do the right thing.
So whatever he wants, you do.
If a judge says it's okay, it's OK.
Hey, I'm only going to let
you see the good people,
the nice people, people
just like your parents.
Ok?
Listen, Mowgli, said Wolf.
I have to tell you all the
laws of the jungle for all
the peoples of the
jungle, except the monkey
people who live in the trees.
They have no laws.
They are outcasts.
They have no speech of their own
but use the stolen words they
overhear when they listen and peer
and wait up above in the branches.
You got dressed again.
Um, why don't you, uh,
put this on instead, hm?
Their way is not our way.
They have no leaders.
They have no memories.
They boast and chatter and pretend
they are great people about to
do great things in the jungle.
Who's this?
Oh, a friend of mine, Jimmy,
dropped by to say hello.
He ran off to do an errand for me,
so I said it was fine
to leave his niece here.
Is he coming back soon?
Yes, he is.
What's your name?
Leslie.
Would you like to
come upstairs and play?
Girls, I want you to look after Leslie
till she's picked up, ok?
Daddy and I will come and
kiss you good night later.
Your blood shall run on the floor
with that of the governor's pigeon.
And him.
I can't see right.
Everything's gone all funny.
You tripping over there, Donnie?
Everything seems so slow.
Mm, yeah.
Yeah, that's about right.
Be right back.
Shit!
Shit, shit...
What?
Ice cream is gone.
Ice cream, ice cream,
ice cream... always gone.
So what if the ice cream's gone?
That's shit.
Hey, don't bust your britches.
You just don't have a sweet
tooth like I do, that's all.
I just don't let it
get to me like you do.
That's all.
Honey?
Would you like some ice cream?
Yeah?
What about you, Donnie?
You want some ice cream?
Well, then, let's go to the
store and get some ice cream.
Alex.
Who wants a piggyback ride?
You know, they have
300 kinds of ice cream,
one for every night of the year.
How many can you name, Leslie?
Strawberry, chocolate, vanilla...
We got butter pecan.
You like that?
Ooh, butter pecan.
We got vanilla bean.
We got all kinds of
chocolate... dark chocolate,
light chocolate, mint
chocolate, strawberry,
raspberry, blueberry.
We got Neapolitan, which
is all three together.
That's one of my favorites.
And then we got Rocky Road,
Crunchy Crunch, Butter Ripple...
It's 7.95.
Seven-nine... keep the change.
There you go.
Thank you.
Let's go!
Now, I'll share, but I
got dibs on the Rocky Road.
Let's go.
Come on, get up.
Shhh.
Come on.
Shut the fuck up.
Keep your mouth shut.
Alex!
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up.
Shit.
What?
Alex, they're at the fucking door.
Let's go.
He's got our fucking faces all over.
Get in, get in, get in.
Let's go.
Make a left.
Make a left!
I can't.
There's a truck.
Start singing a song.
What?
Well, start singing a
fucking song, please.
Uh, The red, red, Robin keeps a...
Bump, bump, bumping along.
Red, red robin keeps
bump, bump, bumping along.
The red, red, robin keeps
I fucking told you, Alex.
Stop.
Get down, you little shit.
What the fuck were
they doing back there?
Where you going?
I gotta get us off the fucking road.
Every fucking thing was in there.
Everything.
They have exactly nothing.
Bullshit!
Those were the same fucking slopes
from the ice cream store.
I mean, what the fuck
were they doing there?
Well, how should I know?
It was you.
It was you, you fucking...
Hey!
Fucking... fuck you!
Don't blame Leslie!
- Why?
- Because think about it.
She's the one who
fucking said something.
Think about it.
It's not her fault.
Leslie would never say
anything, would you, honey?
Because we have our little
secret, don't we, honey?
We have our secret.
Frank, outside.
Outside.
Shit.
Just stay the fuck away from me.
Calm down, son.
Don't you touch me, Alex.
Calm down.
Don't you touch me.
I'm gonna take care of it, ok?
What are you gonna do?
I'll figure out something.
Now, just calm down.
You gotta give me more that 20.
Yeah, yeah.
I get it.
I appreciate it.
I've got everything I have, ok?
Well, you got all the good stuff.
I've given you every
single thing I have.
You all nervous here today.
Well.
Let me see what you got.
This is all the good stuff?
Yeah, everything.
You got a little of this?
Well, you know what, you got a bonus.
All right?
Oh, shit.
Now, give me the money.
Ok.
Right.
You ever hit that
place right over there?
Yeah.
That place with
the big Coca-Cola sign?
The next thing...
Mowgli remembered was feeling
hands on his arms and legs
and then a swatch of
branches in his face.
And then he was staring down
through the strange tree limbs
as the monkey people howled with triumph
and scuffled him away
to the other branches.
Then they began their long flight.
And a flight of the monkey
people through tree land
is one of the things
nobody can describe.
Let's make a promise, Donnie.
What promise.
We'll always be together.
Always.
And if something
happens and we can't be,
we'll meet up someplace.
Ok.
Where?
And for the big kid in all of us,
twirl upside down then back
again in the thrilling zipper.
There.
We'll meet up there at Wonderland, ok?
Ok.
Remember, the family
that plays together stays together.
Located in the heart of Miami Beach.
Wonderland USA is bringing
back wonder to the USA.
Get up.
We slept late.
Hey, you want to party?
What you looking for?
Yeah?
How much you looking to spend?
Ok, let's go.
Got a place.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, excuse me, sir, but
that's my sister right there.
Donnie, what the hell are you doing?
Now, I don't know what
she's been saying to you,
but she's a bit of a romantic.
You know, flowers,
margaritas, soft music.
You know...
Donnie, get the fuck out of here.
This '80s shit you've got going on,
man, it just ain't the ticket.
She don't like that stuff.
So maybe you, uh... maybe you
should try something else.
Come on, let's go.
Hey!
Go home to your wife, pervert.
Give me back my fucking phone!
Hey, what does that say?
Armaments.
What does that mean?
Guns.
You know, guns, bombs, stuff like that.
Guns?
Why didn't they just say that, then?
Guns.
I mean, I bet you a bunch
of... a bunch of people
are gonna get fucking
caught up on that shit.
Arm... armaments.
Armaments.
Ar... ar... armaments.
We cannot enter into
this war unprepared.
It is vital that we
know both the strength
and size of their armaments.
Guns.
But brother, any such action...
Oh, what's up, dude!
Hey, man, what are
you... you're crazy, dude.
Yeah, it's fucking nuts, man.
I'm okay now.
You know, I've been having
this fucking hospital,
right, laying in bed, tubes
out of my arms and shit.
It's fucking crazy.
And there was this other guy.
He was all shrunk up.
He was covered...
Excuse me, sir.
Hey, can I interest you in a bar?
We got cheap drinks.
We got straight business.
We got the best live sex acts in town.
Lesbians... we got
fucking everything.
You know what the best part is?
You don't have to pay.
You can just sit there,
and you can watch.
I mean, come on.
Think about it.
We got young girls.
We got little chickens.
Come on.
Can you spare some change?
All right.
Man, look, how much do
you want for that phone?
I don't even know.
Like, 100, 120.
In your dreams, boy.
You fucking serious?
Come on, man.
That's a nice phone.
Hey, mister.
I'll catch you at the boardwalk.
I know it scares you, fool.
You're afraid that that girl's going
to get in one of those cars,
and she's not gonna come back.
Yeah.
Is that good, baby?
Oh, yeah.
It feels good.
Do you want it like this?
Everything all right?
It's fine.
I'm almost done.
Hey.
Hey, Leslie.
Holy fucking shit, girl.
Come here.
Hey, Angel.
I'll talk to you afterwards, all right?
Stay close.
What's up?
How's it going?
Good, Cooper.
It's going okay.
Hey, I got that date for
you on Night Airline Highway,
if you still want it.
Yeah, right.
Hey, are you still with that kid?
Yeah.
Why the fuck do you
hang out with him, huh?
Does he got the guide map to your life?
I don't think so.
Yeah, but you do.
Listen, baby.
Friends are just people who
haven't fucked you over yet.
Look, you sure you're OK?
You don't look so good.
I'm fine.
Here.
Take this.
A gift.
Thanks.
Look at those fucking niggers, man.
Remember Donna?
Yeah?
She's hanging out right over there.
She was a lot like you too.
She wanted to be independent.
You know?
Anyway, one day there was
this gang of nigger pimps
from Oceanside driving by.
Saw her.
They liked her, so they
fucking grabbed her right off
the fucking street, man.
You ever think why they like
working the white girls?
It gets them the white money.
It's a real fuck you.
Hey Leslie, I want to
show you something.
Come with me?
You know that shelter on India Street?
How would you feel about going
there and bringing her out?
Too you?
Yeah.
But first I want you to turn her.
And then you bring her.
I'm not a fucking booster.
I know that, but it doesn't
take any special skills, right?
I mean, you tell her
how I'm gonna help her,
and then you break her in.
Let her watch you do
it a couple of times.
You know how it goes.
Hey, I'm offering you
something pretty great here.
I know you.
I know that when you close your
eyes, you see something better.
I can set you up with
some people I know.
You won't have to scrounge
around for a tiny bit of money
anymore.
Ok?
Think about it.
- Hey.
What's up?
Hey, I got you this.
Oh, my God.
Hey.
Thank you.
No problem.
So what did Cooper want?
Nothing.
So he just gave you this?
He likes me.
Yeah, well, he's an asshole.
How's that?
He's OK.
He just gets uptight sometimes.
Hey, guys.
How you doing?
I got something for you.
I'll take them if I can use them, ok?
We're here every night.
Kinda hot for one of those ladies, huh?
Select music.
This is a great song!
Ready?
Hey, I'm gonna stay up.
So if you want to sleep,
you know, it's cool.
You want me, don't you?
You want me now so bad,
you don't know what to do?
Well, feel this.
It's so wet.
Oh.
I can feel it.
Oh, I can feel it.
It's so big, rubbing up and down.
It's so big.
It's almost too big.
Oh, come on, baby.
Fuck me.
Come on.
Come on, spit it into me.
Come on, spit.
Spit.
Come on.
Let it explode.
Oh my God.
Let it explode so hard, it's
gonna shoot out my throat.
Oh my God.
I'm gonna come.
And then they do.
32 seconds.
Shoot out my throat?
I gotta use that.
You really have to say all that?
I remember this one time,
I had this Chinese guy,
and he had a small one.
You know, very small.
We're talking teensy-weensy here, ok?
And he goes, oh, oh,
you like my big dick?
Big dick?
He paid me, like, an extra
100 just to keep saying that.
I did like his big dick.
Why are guys so into
the size of their dicks?
Well, because we are.
No, they're not.
Not all of them anyway.
All they want to hear
about is how big it is
and how smooth it is and
how good it feels going in.
No, they don't.
I do the same stuff you guys
do, and I don't say that shit
to them, and they don't
say that shit to me.
Well, maybe you're not, like,
a great conversationalist,
Donnie.
What the fuck is that?
Just some big-ass word?
It just means that
you're not into talking.
No, we talk.
We just don't talk that stuff.
Well, what do you talk about?
Fuck you.
Football, man.
Football and politics.
That's what we talk about.
Leave all that dirty
shit up to you girls.
Ahh!
I got it.
You know, Rat Boy's thinking about going
over to Fort Lauderdale.
You know, maybe we... maybe
we should go along with him.
Why?
Well, there's that carny
that starts up in March.
And it travels up and down all year.
Maybe we could... maybe we
could get a job working
the rides or the hot
dog stand or the popcorn
or something like that.
I, uh... I met some
friends up there last time.
And they seemed like
they really liked it.
You know.
I don't know.
I thought it'd be kinda cool.
I'm tired of moving.
Well, do you want to just settle down,
get a house and a pool and
a dog and the whole thing?
A dog would be OK.
Yeah.
A dog would be nice.
Did you sell that phone yet?
No.
Rat Boy's got it.
Donnie, how long does it
take to sell a fucking phone?
I told you, Rat Boy's
gonna take care of it.
I mean, I'm just waiting on him.
You don't care, do you, if we sleep out
on the beach and the park, do you?
Thanks.
Thank you.
Do you ever think about Alex
and Frank and that whole thing?
No.
Never?
I don't think about it.
I do.
Like, I mean, I know that
sounds weird, but you know,
without them, we would
have never met, you know?
You don't have to do anything to me,
and I'm not gonna do anything to you.
Anybody can have that part.
How old are you, Leslie?
18.
I'm nearly 17.
And both your parents are dead?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
That must be very hard for you.
How old were you when they died?
Seven.
Eight.
And did you go to live with relatives?
Who looked after you?
An uncle.
We stayed with an uncle.
We?
Who is we?
My brother.
And where is the uncle now?
I don't know.
And your brother now?
Have you ever stayed in a shelter?
Just walk-ins.
Never for the night.
All right, Leslie.
Well, here it is.
No drugs or alcohol in this building
or in the recreational yard.
If you're caught with them in
your possession, you're out.
And no amount of tears
or pleading or excuses
will change that.
If you have to smoke, you do it
outside, not in this building.
Ok?
You're free to come
and go during the day.
But those doors are looked
at 9 o'clock at night,
and they are not reopened
till 8.00 in the morning.
The shelter is here to help you.
It's here to help you stop taking drugs,
to help you stop prostituting yourself,
and to help you stop killing yourself.
You understand that?
You came in here to get
away from something.
But you leave that something
outside, all right?
Understand?
Yes.
Don't bring it in here.
Ok.
Good.
Hey.
They were gonna send
me to a foster home.
Soda home.
Everything's got another name.
Sweet Mac, player, gorilla, meat dealer.
Just another name for somebody
who wants to make money off
of you.
A strawberry is somebody who lets them.
What you got to do is make your
own family, somebody who'll
keep an eye open when
you want to close yours.
These places are no better,
selling dope in the kitchen.
They let the johns in at night,
keep the money for themselves.
You may as well keep
the money for yourself.
The whole world's doing it,
and you might as well know it.
How old are you?
12.
What's up, man?
You wanna party?
How you doing?
Not bad, man.
You know.
Nice sea breeze, pleasant night.
How much?
My man, you couldn't afford me.
I'm just too expensive for you.
All right.
Fuck you, punk.
Hey, wait, man.
Man, fuck you.
You can't take a fucking joke?
Laugh about it, motherfucker.
Fuck you.
So, this is Cooper, who
I was telling you about.
You're a beautiful girl.
You know that, right?
Yeah.
Lady's gonna take care of you, ok?
I've been waiting for you
for a long time, you know.
Did you know that?
Leslie wouldn't care unless you no good,
but we're gonna work something out,
all right?
My parents got this place
in the country.
They're away, and I think we should go.
You sure that this is
the right thing to do?
Yeah, why?
I just feel scared.
Hey, it's gonna be OK.
You know what this is like?
It's like when a caterpillar
becomes a butterfly.
You think that doesn't hurt?
But it's the only way
to become a butterfly.
And that's you.
You're gonna become something beautiful.
Hey, don't worry.
I'm gonna look out for you, ok?
Hey, man.
Where's Leslie?
- What?
- Where the fuck is she?
You know what I'm talking about.
Where's Leslie?
Man, get the fuck away from me.
Fuck you.
Listen, asshole.
Man, I didn't do anything
with her, all right?
She went.
And she wanted to go.
What?
Fuck you.
You're fucking lying, man.
What, you thought she
was going to hang around
with you the rest of her fucking life?
You're a fucking liar.
Her own fucking words, man.
She had a chance to move up, and
you're a fucking dead weight.
You're a fuck up.
Fuck you.
Come on, Cooper.
Let's go.
What?
I'm your host, Rod Baker.
Now, on today's show, let's welcome back
our champion, Bunny.
Oh, hi!
Hello, Bunny.
Come on in.
Hiya, Rod.
And how are you today?
Oh, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Feeling lucky?
Oh, yeah!
Oh, that's great, Bunny.
As you know, Bunny
has won $17.380!
Oh, thank you!
Bunny, are you ready to meet
that new challenger?
Oh, yeah.
I really am.
Ok.
Oh, yeah.
I can feel it.
It's so big.
It's so big, rubbing up and down.
That's my little girl.
Baby, fuck me.
Come on.
Talk to me, little girl.
Come on, spit it into me.
Come on.
Spit it.
- Come on.
- Tell me, little girl.
Come on, it's gonna
shoot out in my throat.
Oh, baby.
Yeah.
Come on.
I'm gonna come.
Tell me.
Tell me, little girl.
Just come.
Why can't you come?
Come on.
Come.
Hey.
Come on, just fucking come.
Why can't you come?
Hey, get the fuck off me, then!
I don't need this shit.
I don't need this.
Fucking crazy bitch.
Hey, fuck you, then.
Fuck you.
Fuck!
Shhh.
It's okay.
That's the old you.
You're just leaving it behind.
You're my girl now,
and that's our secret.
You don't love me.
I'm just something you caught.
You think I'm some kind of animal...
Come on, honey.
You gotta wake up.
You gotta listen to me.
I lied to you.
These people, they're
not gonna protect you.
They're gonna make you
do terrible things.
They gonna make you do the
worst things in the world,
so we've got to get out of here.
Come on.
That fucking bitch is dead.
Oh, fuck.
Hey, you guys know where
the fucking jump is, right?
Get to that shit right fucking now.
Get there.
Fuck.
Hey, Christian, you fucking faggot.
Where's Leslie?
Where is that bitch?
Man, I swear to fucking God,
where is that bitch?
You must be out of your fucking mind.
You remember Surf?
You want to end up
dead in the toilet too?
I just want to get Donnie.
Donnie?
Donnie's long gone, honey.
He left town with Rat Boy.
He left town?
When did he go?
I don't know.
But they're long gone.
Just get the fuck out
of here yourself, ok?
Wait.
Did he say where he was going?
Yeah.
To find America.
Leslie, let me ask you, do you
really think both your parents
are dead, your Mom and your Dad?
Do you really believe that?
Were you still living
at home when they died?
No.
Then how do you know they're dead?
I heard it.
You heard it?
Where did you hear it?
Hm?
All right.
And where's home to you?
Leslie, where is that?
I don't remember.
I think we all remember home.
You know what I think?
I think you left, maybe
because you wanted to,
maybe you didn't, maybe you had to.
And I think you left
so long ago that now
you have no idea how to go back.
It's like you don't know how to tell
your parents that you're not dead.
It's like you can't
even admit to yourself
that your parents aren't dead.
Right?
Why can't you admit that, Leslie?
Because they fucking didn't want me.
They left me, and they
never came back to get me.
And I fucking... I heard
them on the phone.
And they kept saying, soon.
And then they never came.
Well, I would imagine you heard
one side of a conversation.
You know how many kids I've
had in here over the years who
heard one end of a
telephone conversation... one
side of a call, where the
other side is only a dial tone?
You know how many?
A lot.
What's wrong?
It looks to me like
they... they want you.
I... I... I couldn't go back.
They don't want me.
They wouldn't want me now.
I'm...
And I've done too many things.
They don't want me.
Oh, you could go back.
Of course they would want you.
No, they wouldn't.
You don't understand.
They wouldn't want me now.
Leslie, it's time for you to go home.
I can't believe you're actually here.
So Leslie, um, there's
something that you have to know.
We, um... your
mother and I wanted
to be the ones to tell you.
You have a brother and a sister.
What do you mean?
Well, after you... we
had two more children.
Where are they?
They're, um...
They're at a friend's.
We wanted to see you first.
Do they know about me?
Of course.
Of course they do.
Well, what did you tell them?
We told them that, um,
they had a beautiful older
sister who we love very much.
And who had gone to heaven.
Is that what you thought?
You thought I died?
No.
No, no.
No, we never stopped hoping.
Never, never.
Leslie.
I want you to come home.
Hey.
So this is... this is Dylan.
This is Gracie.
This is your sister.
Hi.
Did you come back from heaven?
No.
Where did you come back from?
I was in a forest.
What forest?
It was far away.
What were you doing there?
I was lost.
Were you scared?
Sometimes.
Why?
Because there were
monsters in the forest.
Hey, you know, tell you what, why
don't we all go in the dining room.
And then you guys can show
Leslie the really great cake...
Mommy made especially for her, ok?
Hey!
It's yummy.
And Mama says it's your favorite.
Ow!
Did you get it in your hand?
Did you catch it?
Excellent.
It's glittery.
Look at that.
You ever get scared,
doing stuff like this?
You just have to have
somebody to look out for you.
That's all.
And this is our jungle,
and nobody can come into it.
Come back, she whispered.
Come back, for I love you.
Come back again by night or by day.
This door is never shut to you.
Mowgli's throat worked
as though the cords in it
were being pulled and his voice
seemed to be dragged from it,
as he answered, I will surely come back.
Manual corrected, synchronized,
and spell checked by H@w-to-kiLL.