(Episode 3)
Hello, sir! I brought the samples!
You're always just on time.
Kim Mi-poong, you're the best!
You should check the samples.
You never made a mistake before.
It's obviously just right.
You should still check.
Mi-poong, out of the clothes here, which one of them do you think will sell the best?
You have good sense! Pick it again this time.
That one.
The length is just right, and the quality of the
material is good, so it would be flexible to wear.
You think so?
Then I should hang up this dress in the front.
By the way, did you move yet?
I'm moving tomorrow.
I'll finally be able to leave the semi-basement!
Is that so?
You worked so hard to make money. You've succeed!
Congratulations!
Thank you! Have a good day!
Bye!
I ate so well. I think I overate. I'm so full.
I'm glad the food was to your liking.
The food was delicious, but why did you make
so much? It must have been tiring for you.
We could just have simply ate some noodles.
It wasn't tiring at all.
The maid did everything.
If I was struck by money like you were, I wouldn't do the household chores either.
But is the Elder not home?
He went out to attend a meeting today.
Maid!
Aren't you going to prepare the fruits and tea?
-Hold on a minute. -Sure.
Money really is good!
Chung-ja looks so nice!
But isn't the Elder's family in North Korea?
I heard you can give your inheritance to your family in North Korea nowadays.
He has no family in North Korea. They're all dead.
Really?
-Honey, I'm home- -Honey, you're home!
These are my friends. Say hello.
This is my husband Jo Dal-ho.
Oh, hello.
Hello.
Enjoy yourselves comfortably.
Excuse me.
Go ahead and talk amongst yourselves. I'll be back!
Is he really Chung-ja's husband?
Doesn't he look ten years younger than her?
Not ten years. He's only two years younger than her.
Chung-ja must have saved a country in her past life.
When she was little, she was shabby and had a difficult life.
Now she has a young, handsome husband and a 100 million dollar inheritance.
She must have saved the country ten times in her past life.
Your friends are here, so why did you ask me to come home early?
Just...You can meet my friends.
What's the point of me meeting your friends?
It's not like we're going to play patty cake.
I wanted to show off my handsome husband.
It's too wasteful for me to see you alone.
Come on. Don't say that anywhere else.
I'm not a young man anymore.
To other people, I'm just an old man.
How can you be just an old man?
You're still a handsome and firm young man!
Seriously.
You're like a little kid.
We ate a lot.
Why are you already leaving? You don't have to mind my husband.
Since we know where you live, we can visit again next time.
You're right. Visit often.
But your husband isn't acting like a bachelor outside, is he?
You should keep an eye on him.
If he does, I'll kill him. I'll kill him slowly and painfully.
Oh my goodness! He would be too scared to cheat on you!
-We're leaving. Don't come out. -Bye!
I'll take you guys home.
-Oh, really? Okay! -No, go ahead.
I have somewhere to go.
-Okay then. Bye, Geum-sil. -See you again!
-Come out to our gatherings! -Bye!
Hello, Nam-yi.
Jang-go bought a lot of meat to celebrate his
winning today. So hurry up and come home.
All right. I'm on my way home right now.
That's right.
I have Jang-go and Jang-soo, so why should I feel pathetic or be envious?
Mister!
-Cheers! -Cheers!
It feels so refreshing!
Grandma, eat a lot of meat.
All right.
Mom, you eat, too.
Aunt, you eat a lot, too.
You should eat a lot since you worked hard.
Mom, you should eat a lot. I'll eat, too.
Okay.
The meat is tastier since Jang-go bought it.
So you bought this meat today because you won the case?
Yes, grandma.
I see. Then you don't have to worry about the office rent anymore?
That's right!
The money hasn't come in yet, but it will.
Mom, eat a lot!
Okay!
But what about Jang-soo?
Aunt, did you call Jang-soo?
He said he'll be here soon.
Oh, Jang-soo is here! Hurry up and come sit here!
We have the pork belly you like so much.
We have a guest.
Who?
Hold on.
Come in.
Hello.
What are you doing here, Ms. Song?
Oh, are you the owner of the beauty parlor on the side of the street?
That's right! It's her!
But what are you doing here?
Jang-soo.
Everyone, don't be surprised.
Joo-ri is my girlfriend.
I'm going to marry her.
Please have a seat first.
You can't sit down!
What?
What? You're going to get married? To who?
With Ms. Song?
Yes.
-Jang-soo, you crazy fool! -Geum-sil!
Hold on.
Ms. Song, aren't you over forty years old?
Aunt!
She's not over forty! She's exactly forty years old! She's only forty years old!
She's only forty years old?
Do you think that makes any sense?
Do you not know how old Jang-soo is?
She knows I'm twenty-nine years old.
But what does age gap have to do with anything?
Our hearts are important.
And I'll be thirty soon!
How dare you, you crazy fool!
-Mom! -Geum-sil!
This is ridiculous!
Oh my goodness.
Look here, Ms. Song.
You must really have no conscience.
How dare you come after our pure baby Jang-soo?
We have nothing else to say to you. Get out of this house at once. Get out!
Grandma, why are you doing this to my Joo-ri?
-What? -And grandma, I'm not a baby! I'm twenty-nine years old!
Oh my goodness, you crazy idiot!
-You idiot! -Gosh, seriously!
All this time, you cut my hair for free and were really friendly to me.
Was that all because you wanted to seduce Jang-soo?
Get out of my house at once!
Get out! Get out at once!
It's not like that!
Joo-ri! Song Joo-ri!
Joo-ri!
-Oh my gosh. -This is ridiculous!
-Oh my goodness. -Mom!
Joo-ri! Song Joo-ri!
Joo-ri!
Wasn't Ms. Song married once?
That's not all. She has two kids, too. A son and a daughter.
What?
She has kids?
Are you serious?
Yes!
My goodness.
She has kids.
Is Jang-soo out of his mind?
Jang-soo is out of his mind. He's crazy!
Oh, no.
-Get out! How dare you come inside! -Mom!
Am I kid? Use your words! Your words!
Yes, yes. Just use your words.
Jang-soo, Ms. Song has kids.
That's not right, Jang-soo!
People marry people from different countries, so age gap doesn't really matter.
But what are you going to do about her kids?
Will you raise them?
Why? Can't I?
I can raise them!
Oh my goodness!
Hey, Lee Jang-soo!
Why? If they're the kids of the woman I love, they're my kids, too.
And once I get married to Joo-ri, I'm going to tie it up!
I'm not going to have kids!
-Oh my goodness! -What? Tie what up?
That thing! He's going to have that surgery where you can't have kids anymore!
Oh my goodness!
Jang-soo, you've gone completely mad!
What on earth did that old fox do to him to bewitch him like this? Jang-soo!
Grandma, don't talk about her like that!
Joo-ri is the woman I like.
She's the woman I love!
She's the only person who understands my dreams and talents of becoming an actor.
She said she would make money and feed me until I succeed.
And grandma, Joo-ri didn't bewitch me. I was the one who begged her to date me!
I was the first one to tell her that I like her and
I was the first one to tell her that I love her!
Joo-ri's parents were against us, but I finally
got permission after I knelt before them!
What did you just say?
Die. You should just die instead!
Mom!
Use your words!
Is it a crime to love someone?
-What did I do so wrong? -Grandma!
Lee Jang-soo, be quiet, will you?
Joo-ri is such a kind woman!
Is it a crime to love someone?
You don't deserve to talk back to me! What are you, a little kid?
Jang-go, do you know about love?
Do you know about love?
You don't know anything.
There's no solution for you.
If you're going to curse someone, you should curse me! Why curse my nice Joo-ri?
How can he become so crazy?
Shouldn't we take him to the hospital?
This is all your fault!
Pardon?
Ever since Jang-soo was little, you would only take
care of Jang-go and leave Jang-soo out in the dust.
Because of the lack of affection, he fell for an old woman!
Mom, stop it. Geum-sil is upset enough already.
Aren't I telling the truth?
Because you stopped Jang-soo from becoming an actor,
he fell for that old woman who encouraged him on!
Mother, you can't say that just because he isn't your son.
If he was your son, would you have allowed him to become a stage actor?
He doesn't make proper money from that, and
all he does is stick posters on street lamps!
What? Jang-soo is your son?
Jang-soo is my son. My son.
He's my son who I raised in my arms while you left him behind to do business!
What are you talking about?
Fine.
Jang-soo is not my son anymore. He's your son,
so you can take him out of this house and let him do whatever he wants.
He can become a stage actor or get married to that divorcee with children.
What did you say? Are you telling me to leave this house?
-Mom! That's not what she means! Go to your room!-You!
My son bought this house with money he worked hard to make!
Who are you to tell me to leave this house!
-How dare you tell me to leave! -What's wrong with you?
Mommy, hurry up!
Okay!
It's hot, so be careful.
Here you go.
There you go! Here.
This is okay, right?
Yes, it's perfect!
Yoo-sung, starting from tomorrow, we're going
to live in a house that has a lot of warm water.
Really?
Close your eyes, or they'll sting.
The new house that we're moving into isn't a semi-basement
like this one, so there will be plenty of sunshine and wind.
Sounds great, right?
Yes!
You're so cute, Yoo-sung!
Why aren't you sleeping?
I knew you would be like this.
After losing your dad in a car accident,
I thought I had lived pretty well.
Today he's on my mind a lot.
If your dad had been alive,
I wonder what he would have said about what happened tonight.
You still have me by your side.
I know.
Mom.
Don't worry about Jang-soo too much.
After a few days pass, I'll talk to him about it.
No matter what we tell him right now, he won't listen.
So just let it go.
Okay?
All right.
Mom.
I can't fall asleep thinking about moving tomorrow.
Me, too.
Yoo-sung, you need to hurry up and sleep so that we can
move tomorrow. If you don't sleep, tomorrow won't come.
You're right.
Mom.
You worked so hard all this time.
I didn't do anything.
Seung-hee, you were the one who worked hard.
Grandma, why do you keep calling aunt "Seung-hee?"
Aunt's name is Mi-poong. Kim Mi-poong.
Oh, you're right.
I forgot.
But why do you, my smarty-pants, call your aunt "mommy?"
That's because...
Because I fed you milk, carried you on my back, and bathed you.
I am your mommy, right?
You can call me whatever you want.
What will you do if you never get married because of that?
What else will I do?
I'll keep living with you and Yoo-sung.
You really can't fall asleep? Huh?
One.
Two.
Exhale.
Elder, when you're exercising, breathing is very important.
When you lower your arm, you should exhale like this.
Yes, just like that.
When I pull up my arm, I need to inhale?
Okay. Inhale.
Exhale.
I really hate that song.
Who on earth made that kind of song?
Why is everyone trying to live until they're a hundred years old?
Goodness.
I'm so frustrated.
"Ask him when I'll naturally be able to go."
Is the green vegetable juice not done yet? Elder is thirsty.
For how much longer are you going to call him "Elder?"
If we decided to serve him as a father, then you should call him father.
Is it so hard to call him father?
Why are you getting mad at me over nothing so early in the morning?
This is "nothing?"
You need to call him father so that he'll think of you as his child!
Stop talking nonsense and hurry up!
Stop turning on that song.
I'm getting sick of it.
Do you really want father to live until he's a hundred years old?
Then?
You don't?
Well...
I just heard it's not good if you live for so long.
They say longevity is a disaster.
Don't you read the newspaper?
You need to live moderately. That's order.
Stop talking crap!
Crap?
Did he just say that I'm talking crap?
Elder, you're thirsty, aren't you?
Drink this.
Today, I mixed enough carrots and apples together, so it won't taste bitter.
Is that so?
Thank you.
Let me try.
It's good.
Father, how's your condition today?
Are you uncomfortable anywhere?
I feel great. Thanks to you, I'll be living for a long time.
Yes!
Of course!
You need to live a long life until you're two hundred years old!
Two hundred?
It's an insult to tell old people to live for a long time.
But as for me,
I won't ask for more or less.
I'm going to live until we're unified and I can step onto my home country.
Of course!
You need to be healthy until then, so drink up.
All right.
I'll drink it.
Oh, my. So is he saying he'll live over a hundred
years old if the countries aren't unified?
When on earth will that unification happen?
Mom!
Did you talk to grandfather about it?
Talk to him about what?
About buying me a fashion shop in Cheongdam-dong.
Cheongdam-dong fashion shop, my foot.
I sent you to study abroad, but you didn't even graduate. Shop, my foot!
Why do I need to graduate to own a shop? All I need is money!
Oh my goodness! Where did you get your stubbornness from?
Mom, I'm really confident about it!
Although I didn't graduate,
but I lived in New York! I have those senses!
What's more important for my career than the fact that I was once a New Yorker?
You didn't even study. You shopped and played around
while spending money. Is that part of your career?
I had such a hard time gathering money for your expenses when you were living abroad!
Grandfather paid for the tuition.
Tuition wasn't the only thing wasted on you!
I borrowed money without your dad or grandfather knowing in
order to cover up for your costs of living as a New Yorker!
That's why I'll pay you back once I make money.
Don't even lie.
Mom! Shop! Shop! Mom! Shop!
What if grandfather finds out you didn't even graduate?
If you get on grandfather's bad side, it will be the end of you!
If you don't have any brains, the least you should have is some tact!
Goodness. Who would know how I feel?
No one else will know that I didn't graduate as long as you and Hee-dong stay silent.
The two of you are the only ones who know.
My gosh!
Go and wake up your brother for breakfast!
If it hadn't been for Hee-dong, mom wouldn't have found out I hadn't graduated either.
Shit!
Jo Hee-dong.
Jo Hee-dong, you better wake up.
How can you act so rudely to your big brother?
Brother, my foot.
You rag-like blabbermouth!
Oh, really?
Rag-like?
You went to go study abroad after begging and
begging the adults that you wanted to study design.
Grandfather and father have no clue yet that you didn't graduate, do they?
Grandfather! Father! She-
Don't do it! Don't do it!
Watch what happens if you tell them!
Please don't do that.
If grandfather and dad finds out, they'll be so disappointed.
Please!
Big brother.
Okay. Go get me some water.
I'm very thirsty.
Got it.
Watch.
I'll get you back.
(Fasting)
Jang-soo said he's not going to eat.
Why not? If he doesn't feel like eating, he should
have some of this beansprout soup at least.
The thing is...
he's not just saying he won't eat.
He said he would rather die of starvation if we don't allow him to marry Ms. Song.
He said he would go on a hunger strike until we give them permission.
What? A hunger strike?
He can starve to death if he wants. He can get married to Ms. Song if he wants.
He's not my son anymore, so tell him to do whatever he wants.
Are you saying that towards me?
Fine.
Go ahead and pig out by yourself.
If Jang-soo starves to death, so will I.
Mom.
Why is she acting like this now?
Don't mind him. Jang-soo will stop soon enough.
It just doesn't make sense!
What about Jang-go?
He went out early to the police station for work.
Oh, it must be because of that grandmother yesterday.
Every day he only works on such small cases.
Jang-go needs to do something that will make money.
Hi, Young-soon.
Why are you calling me so early in the morning?
What?
Really?
Of course he can take that case!
Okay, then bring him so my son's office later today.
I'll send you the address through a text message.
Okay. See you later!
Who is it? Did Jang-go get a new case?
My friend's brother-in-law runs some kind of business,
but the product he has been creating for over ten years
has been copied and released by another company.
Oh my goodness! So he's going to leave such a big case in Jang-go's hands?
It's a big case?
Of course! Not everyone can handle such a big case!
Those are only cases that can be gotten through lobbying by skillful office managers.
Oh my goodness!
I shouldn't just sit around like this.
Wait for me! Oh my goodness! It was such a big case? Oh my.
(Seoul Law Office)
Thank you for introducing such a big case to Jang-go.
If this works out well, make sure to buy a big meal for your friend.
That's not all.
I'll buy two or three meals.
Thank you so much, Young-soon.
It has to work out well.
Jang-go is very competent. It'll definitely work out well.
Maybe he can't find this place.
Why don't you call him?
I got a call.
Hello.
Okay, I understand.
What do we do?
He decided to leave his lawsuit up to Jangaenggo Law Firm.
It's such an important matter for the company.
I'm so sorry.
No, it's fine.
I hope it gets solved nicely.
I'm sorry, Geum-sil.
I'll call you next time.
"Daddy bear, mommy bear, baby bear!
Daddy bear is fat!
Mommy bear is skinny!
Baby bear is so pretty!
Shrug, shrug. You are growing tall!"
I wasted your time. I'm sorry.
Mom, it's fine.
Aunt, I'm going to the court.
-Bye. -Bye.
So what if he has skills? He has no connections.
Everyone looks down on him because this office is so small.
He needs to either get married to a wealthy woman or hire a skillful office manager.
Jang-go's skills are too wasteful to be stuck in here.
In order to try something, he needs an opportunity!
The truth is, a matchmaker introduced him to a wealthy business
family, but Jang-go said no, so we quit the whole thing.
Geum-sil, you should have still pushed him to do it!
Jang-go would become big if someone just supported him!
Try this just once.
-(Fasting) -Just take one bite.
This is the chicken you like the most. Have some.
Grandma, don't test my love.
I'm not going to eat it even if I die.
You can just pretend you didn't eat.
I'll take this secret to my grave. So just take one bite.
Good. That's it.
Really, grandma?
-You really have to take this secret to the grave. Okay? -Yes.
Don't ever say that you're going to tie it up again.
The day you tie that up will be my death day. Got it?
Eat slowly.
What is it?
Oh, my.
I'm the one who's eating this.
Jang-soo didn't even take a bite.
Darn it! Grandma, I said I wouldn't eat it!
Gosh, seriously!
Miss, hold on.
Come on, miss!
Starting from today, this is our house! Why aren't you
letting us go inside? Hurry up and open the door for us!
How many times do I have to tell you that this house is put up for auction?
This is our house, so how can it be put up for auction?
Look!
-(New House Contract) -It says Kim Mi-poong right here.
This is our house under my name Kim Mi-poong!
Oh, dear. You were conned.
Conned?
This house has been put up for auction ever since the owners were
indebted to the bank. You were conned into signing a fake contract.
That can't be.
My close friend introduced me to this house! This can't be!
Then your close friend must have teamed up with the con-artists.
Ma'am, go inside.
Teamed up?
That's impossible.
The phone number you have just dialed is a non-existent number.
What's wrong with her phone? What's going on?
-The phone number you have just dialed is a non-existent number. -This can't happen!
What on earth happened?
Did we really get conned?
No, mom.
Let me go meet my friend. Wait right here.
It's nearby, so I'll be back soon.
Open the door! Come out!
Open up!
No one lives there. She moved yesterday.
Where did she go?
I wouldn't know that.
Anyways, no one lives there, so stop making a ruckus.
We were both from North Korea, and she sympathized with me about living a hard life.
She said we should try our best together.
How can she do this to a fellow countrywoman?
I'm out.
I got it!
Three hundred more.
I'll see that and raise you a thousand.
A thousand? Deal.
Jangddaeng.
Hold on.
38 gwangddaeng.
Police! Don't move!
Damn it!
Ma'am. Ma'am, hurry up and come out.
Hurry up and come out, ma'am.
I didn't do anything. All I did was watch.
Hurry up and get up.
Let's go.
Oh, no.
-My money. -Seriously.
-Hurry up and come with me. -My money!
-Hurry. -Forget it!
Let go of my arm!
Who is it?
Hello?
Yes, I'm Ma Chung-ja. Who is this?
Pardon? The police station?
Why are you calling me?
Are you Chun Gwi-ok's daughter?
Chun Gwi-ok?
No. I don't know such a person.
I'm not her daughter! I don't know who she is!
Chung-ja.
It's me, your mom.
Who is my mom? I told you not to call me again!
I don't think of you as my mom, so you shouldn't think of me as your daughter either.
Chung-ja, just once.
Help me out just this once.
I really think I'm going to be stuck eating bean rice this time, Chung-ja.
Go ahead and pig out on bean rice.
Long time ago, we starved because of you.
-You should be grateful they're at least giving you bean rice! -What?
Are you really done talking, you wench?
That way you'll learn your lesson. How else will you fix that bad habit of yours? Huh?
Fine. Forget it.
Forget it, you little wench!
If you come out like this, I'll call that Elder of yours.
You're going to call who?
What right do you have to contact him?
You serve him so well. I deserve to get this much help from him.
You better not. You better not call Elder!
Why are you getting angry?
Are you getting angry because I'll tell him
the reason why you're being so good to him?
You serve that Elder who is just a distant relative so
well, but you ignore your own mother who calls you for help! You terrible wench!
You think I don't know your ulterior motives?
All right! All right! I got it! I'm coming!
She's my enemy, not my mom!
It would've been better if I had been born as an orphan.
That's right.
Geum-sil said her son is a lawyer.
He needs to either get married to a wealthy woman or hire a skillful office manager.
Jang-go's skills are too wasteful to be stuck in here.
In order to try something, he needs an opportunity!
(Blue Thread Red Thread. Name: Lee Ji-hee)
Hi, Chung-ja.
She said there were no problems with the house.
My friend was from North Korea, too.
That's why I trusted her.
In South Korea, you can't just sign a contract
for a house just because you know the person.
When you want to buy a house, you need to get a certified
copy of register and check for collateral security.
You need to get proper help from a real estate agent.
Many people become conned because they try to save money like you.
Mr. Detective, please help me out.
That money was all I had.
Gosh. People should help each other out, not con each other like this.
Then sue your friend first.
Sue?
You need to sue her so that we can catch her.
First, hire a lawyer, and go through the lawsuit process.
Sir...
Chung-ja! My daughter! This time, it is really unfair for me!
Hello.
Who are you?
I'm Chung-ja's friend, Hwang Geum-sil.
Long time ago when I visited your home, you used to make pancakes for me.
I did?
Oh, dear. I'm getting old now. I can't remember very well.
That happens when you get old.
You can't remember people because you're getting old,
but how can you remember those flower cards so well?
What did you say?
She's so mean like this.
She doesn't treat me very well.
I was dragged to the police station when I didn't do anything wrong, and
she doesn't pity me when I'm suffering. All she does is act like this!
Do you think our country's policemen have nothing better to
do than to catch innocent people and lock them up in jail?
Ms. Chun, my son will take care of everything, so just wait a little bit.
Hello. I'm Lee Jang-go.
You're very handsome!
Jang-go, what does she need to do now?
Just wait here for a moment. Let me go meet the detective-in-charge.
Don't worry too much.
My son is a lawyer.
A lawyer?
Yes!
He looks like a lawyer! No wonder!
Hi, mom.
Seung-hee, where are you right now?
The moving truck dumped all our things here and left.
Hurry up and come here! I'm so scared!
What did you say?
Mom, I'll be there soon, so just hang on for a little bit.
Thank you.
-Are you all right? -Yes, I'm fine.
I'm sorry.
Wait.
Detective!
Thank you so much!
Make sure you get re-compensation from my daughter.
Yes, ma'am.
But I have work to do, so I have to leave first.
Yes, go on!
Thank you so much.
You must be busy, but you helped us out.
I'll call you.
Okay.
See you at home.
-Bye, mom. -Bye.
Let me make myself clear. This is definitely the end!
Even if you use Elder to threaten me, it won't work!
This is so embarrassing!
How can you humiliate me in front of my friend and her son?
From now on, don't contact me even if you die.
Geum-sil, I'm sorry.
I'll call you later.
Okay.
Fine! I don't need a daughter like you either!
If I look for you again, I'll become your daughter, you brat.
It's been a while since we met again, but all I did
was trouble you. I'll pay you back later, okay?
-Okay. -Bye.
Good-bye.
Seung-hee!
Mommy!
Yoo-sung, it's okay. There, there. It's all right.
Mom, what happened?
Where did the moving center man go?
He had other things to move, so he just left us.
He's too much.
What are we supposed to do if he just leaves our things here?
It's raining, too.
What do we do now?
Did the center deposit their money?
Yes, sir. They deposited two hundred thousand dollars today.
That's why they wanted to call the reporters,
take photos, and release an article, too.
Tell them no.
Yes, sir.
Hello!
Who is he?
He's the lawyer of the law firm in room 305.
Oh, you're a young one.
Work hard and pay your rent on time.
Yes, sir!
I'll work hard!
Good.
Why is it raining again?
I'm so sick and tired of it.
Mom, this won't do.
If it keeps raining, Yoo-sung might catch a cold.
You and Yoo-sung should go to a motel.
I have money for a motel.
I...
hate your father so much.
I can't forgive him.
How can he make us like this...
and die by himself?
Is death all there is to it?
Mom.
Why would you say that?
Fine.
There's nothing to it.
Seung-hee.
The three of us should end it here.
Mom.
What are you saying?
What's the point of living a worthless life that's lower than dirt?
Mom, what's wrong with you?
Don't be like this. Please!
I can't handle this any longer!
The three of us should just die together.
We can go meet your brother and your father.
What's wrong with you?
No matter how hard life is,
you shouldn't say that to me.
We worked so hard to come this far!
We survived when that wench Kang Mi-Jung fled with our money.
We survived when we had to beg on the streets in China.
We even survived...
when we saw father and brother being shot to death in front of our eyes.
But now you want to give up?
Seung-hee, I...
feel like this is all just a dream.
A nightmare that I won't be able to wake up from unless I die.
Mom, this isn't a dream.
This isn't a dream.
This is reality that we must overcome!
Seung-hee...
Mom, what did dad say?
He told us that we had to live no matter what!
We can do this.
We can survive through this.
Seung-hee.
Mom.
Soon-ok!
Soon-ok.
I don't have much time left.
Wait a little bit longer.
Just a little longer.
Well, the thing is...
I wanted to check if you and I were meant to be.
I don't want to!
I can't go! I'll never go until I hear that song!
Stay here by yourself.
Don't ask me for help even when a ghost appears.
-It's a ghost! -It's a ghost!
Help!
Come on now. How can you do this in a park?
I'm sorry. We have nowhere else to go.
We'll go as soon as we get a place.
-Please let it slide. -If we could, we would.
We're getting complaints that someone set up a home underneath the bridge.
Excuse me! Hold on!
Mr. Jung?
Oh, hi mister!
Hi!
I'll take care of this matter.
-(Home of Free Immigrants. Name: Jung Woo-Jin.) Don't worry.
Then we'll leave it up to you.
Ms. Kim Mi-poong,
why didn't you contact me when things have become so terrible for you?
I felt so bad that you always had to help us.
My goodness. Why would you feel bad about this?
It's my job to make sure you and your family live well in this country.
Anyways, I found a temporary place for you to live in, so let's go there first.
You'll do as I say, right?
-Hello. -Hello.
Sorry for troubling you.
It's no trouble at all.
It's an empty storage room anyways.
Is Mr. Kim in today?
I would like to say hi.
He's not here today.
I'll tell him you said hi.
Yes, thank you.
I heard your story from Mr. Jung.
How did something so terrible happen to you?
You can stay here comfortably until you find a new home.
I don't know how we can pay you back.
Thank you so much.
Hi.
Go on in.
Hello.
She did seem a bit immature, but she was bright and pretty.
Speaking of the devil...
Hi, Chung-ja.
I'm so grateful about yesterday that I think I should pay you back.
Come on. You don't need to pay me back when we're friends.
It's because I'm grateful and sorry to you.
Then buy my son dinner.
Tomorrow? Sure, that's fine.
My son won't have any fun eating with just you and me.
Your daughter seems to have a bright personality. Bring her out with you.
Okay. See you tomorrow.
Yes.
I did well.
I'm going to make Hee-Ra into Jang-go's wife.
If Jang-go gets support from wealthy in-laws, he'll be able to thrive in his work.
It'll be good for Chung-ja since they'll have a lawyer as a son-in-law.
I'm going to create a sturdy support system for Jang-go.
Mom, lie down.
Yes. This is a much better place than under that bridge.
But Yoo-sung, what's wrong?
Aunt, does this mean I can't go to kindergarten anymore?
Why not? You can go.
It's too far from here.
It's not far at all.
If you ride a bus, you'll be there in no time.
Grandma and I will take you to kindergarten every day.
Really?
Of course!
Yoo-sung, stay here with grandma.
Where are you going?
Well, I saw a law office on the third floor of this building.
I want to ask if there's a way I can get my money back.
We need to get our money back, mom.
Ms. Lawyer, that security deposit is money that we
saved over the year while not eating and not shopping.
Please.
Please help me get that money back.
That's so pitiful.
All right. We'll be able to come up with a way together.
Thank you! Thank you, Ms. Lawyer!
But I'm not a lawyer.
Excuse me?
You're not a lawyer?
Isn't this a law firm?
This is a law firm, but the lawyer is away for the moment. I'm the office manager.
If you wait here for a moment-
Speaking of the devil. He came right on time.
You have a client.
Hello.
What brings you here?
She lost her entire security deposit.
(Lawyer Lee Jang-go)
Lawyer Lee Jang-go?
Jang-go?
(Blow Breeze)
No! Where the heck did she go?
Your daughter is coming, too, right?
Why is she so interested in Hee-Ra?
There was this crazy psycho in the parking lot.
Crazy psycho?
He blocked me so that I couldn't even move!
I have no choice but to get the money from your husband.
I'll pay you back this week along with the interest.
-Let go! -What are you doing to my friend?
Jang-go. Fish boy, it's me.
Get on. I'll give you a ride.
If you don't eat, you'll become a fish.
Kim Seung-hee. You're Seung-hee, aren't you?