No offense, but...
your hair's messed up.
You must have been in a hurry
falling down from heaven,
you didn't have time to fix it.
Do you want to have a drink?
Let's do it in order of importance.
How old are you?
20 years old.
How about all of you, Ajussis?
(Ajussi - Older man, Uncle)
There are no ajussis here.
There's only a 10-year difference.  Call us oppa.
(Oppa - Older brother, boyfriend)
We're 30 years old this year.  Born in 1983.
Don't believe them.
They're sneaky.
Isn't this straight out lying?
It's the new year, so we're 31.  Born in 1982.
But doesn't she look like Jeong Pal?
That guy who got married in 1st year college
or was it 2nd year college?
Jeong Suk?
I heard that punk is an animation director.
Were you referring to Na Jeong Suk?
How did you know? Is he that famous?
Ajussis, how do you know my father?
Nobody said the name earlier.
Yesterday was... February 14.
Today is... February 15.  Wednesday.
=The gallery site... me and Director Choe will go...=
=The man I want to confess to is Gim Do Jin.=
You will accept it, right?
Of course. You will surely feel
it's very absurd and unimaginable.
That there's such a woman saying this
after only meeting for a few times--
Are you okay with that?
Excuse me?
If I were to accept this,
who knows you might live happily ever after with me.
Of course, it's enough.
If I hope for more, that would
make me a bad woman.
T-Then...
How?
Why, exactly?
When did it start?
Really?
Teacher Seo really confessed to him?
That's right.
You don't know what kind of spectacle that was.
But it happened before my eyes,
so I have to believe it.
And why did she have to do it so sincerely?
Why are you angry?
Isn't it good that they can be together?
I wanted I Su to be with you.
Not with Do Pal.
You wanted Yun and I to be together?
I heard Teacher Seo confessed to you.
A straight ball strike.
What kind of big news is it?
How come everyone knows?
Give me the same.
Yes.
The country is generally having a fine weather,
so what's the difference?
Such a know it all...
So... are you going to formally date Teacher Seo?
I want to but I think she's embarrassed.
She keeps avoiding me.
She said you're embarrassing?
Leave, if you're done.
Aren't you busy?
I Su is a good woman.  Very kind.
Is that so?
She's an honest woman.
The fact that I never introduced her to you,
doesn't it say it all?
Maybe you just forgot about it.
If you're not sincere,
better reject her.
She's not the type to satisfy your curiosity.
Curiosity can eventually become sincerity.
Who knows, it might be changing now.
But while you're in the midst of changing,
models, stewardess, doctors, graduate student and the likes,
Find one amongst them.
Exclude I Su from that list.
Maintain your playboy character.
Do it properly!
Because of you, I'm going out of my mind.  Really!
Until you talked about that unrequited love or whatever,
I was living in peace.
But suddenly, I told him,
"The guy I like was actually you".
I even sent a big basket of chocolates.
This is the biggest reversal since Sixth Sense?
What do I do?
I know that too.
But please consider it from my perspective as well.
I did that because I really wanted you
and my brother to be together.
Otherwise, will you get another
chance to confess to him ever?
Who told you to stop?
Teacher, I don't get you.
Since I've already laid the path for you,
you should have at least tried.
How could you have changed
the direction of your confession?
What did Do Jin oppa say?
What else can he say?
He probably thinks I'm this crazy woman!
In this kind of situation,
you have to be positive.
That was what you taught us, Teacher.
What else can he say?
He probably thinks I'm this crazy woman!
Just like that.
Come here.
Teacher, phone.
What do I do?
This is already the 5th call.
I'm not answering it.
I'm not going to...
Do you want to be like an ostrich all your life?
Now more than ever, I can't take his call.
I have an idea.  Give it to me.
Hello.  I happened to pick this phone off the streets.
=Is it you, Mi A Ri?=
He recognized me.
I'm really dead!  Let's die together.
Avoiding me like this, can't help
dig you out of your grave.
Tae San.
I love you so much,
it gives me the chills.
So excruciatingly handsome.
My Tae San.
But, you're really awful.
How can you steal my heart
without my permission?
Therefore, I've become
a person without a heart.
So, can you take me?
A person without a heart?
Is she in her right mind at all?
We meet again.  I'm sure
you're not here to see me.
Yes.  I'm here to see Seo I Su.
She had done enough wrong to me.
Now, she's even avoiding my calls.
She's not home.
There are 2 reasons why a woman rejects a call.
Either she likes him very much
or she hates him to bits.
Is it because she hates herself too much
for liking him too much?
That's only possible in Romeo and Juliet.
See you.
Teacher Seo.
Well... God loves us, doesn't He?
Enjoy your drink.
Hello, Madam.
Hello.
Organic Earl Grey.
Jae Sik, 1 cup of Earl Grey.
Is that all?
I just ordered, didn't I?
What are you doing?
How can I take my wife's money?
Take it.
Yes.
Please sign.
Sign your name, please.
I slept at Do Jin's place, Customer.
Do you want me to call him, Customer?
Hello.
Oh... Hong pro.
I need some caffeine.
Omo.  Eonni, long time no see.
You look younger.
(Omo - Oh my)
(Eonni - Older sister)
I spent money, that's why.
You don't look bad.
Is that so?  I just used a bit of BB cream.
If a woman my age takes special care,
her age won't show.
Then you have to take special care, too.
I said you don't look bad.
I never said you look good.
Aren't you supposed to exert
extra effort in golf, instead?
Everytime I see you,
I envy you to death.
You've no ability whatsoever.
Living in luxury because your family is rich.
It seems like you spend your idle time
in useless endeavors.
Pro?  What are you ordering?
Latte?  Cappuccino?
Americano cafe with lots of ice.
I want a large size.
I'm leaving.
Why did you butt in?
I was about to answer, didn't you see?
Are you leaving?  Go, then.
You've already confessed,
why just this reaction?
Please don't get caught.
Oh, no.  Oh, no.
I'm dead meat.
I told you not to get caught.
You have a one-sided love with Tae San,
yet you confessed to me, Seo I Su.
How's... it going?
Not so good.
Not as bad as I feel.
Because you were so embarrassed,
you didn't even answer your phone.
Can't sleep and can't eat either.
Yes, right.
Because you used me.
There are only 3 types of situations
that a man can't tolerate.
Stolen pen.
Seeing the curses against him on the post it notes.
And also receiving the chocolates
from the woman who cursed him.
I didn't steal it.
Why do you keep saying I stole it?
You're really such a rascal.
Do you want to talk somewhere else?
Fine.
There's a coffee shop nearby.
You want to walk?
I want a private place with
soft sofa and expensive wine.
Where we can have 4 walls to isolate us from
the prying eyes of the people and the noise outside.
And then use the living room
or the bedroom afterwards.
You want to go to a hotel?
You don't have roof and walls in your house?
Are you living on the hills
of the outer suburbs?
You don't want to?
Should we go to a hotel?
Please sit.
I drank too much yesterday,
if I drink more, I might vomit.
Did I caught you off guard yesterday?
Actually, it's--
Since when did you start liking me?
What do you like about me?
I am sorry.
You really wanted to confess to me that badly.
You even bought a chocolate basket this big.
Something so heavy, even the sick
and the old can't carry it.
It's too dangerous.
I'm... really sorry.
It's not that I can't understand it.
I really don't want to say this but really...
"I love you so much,
it gives me the chills."
So excruciatingly handsome, am I?
From the way you're glaring at me,
looks like you don't agree.
Such a coward.
Actually ""I love you so much, it gives me the chills."
is really far out.  So I didn't hear the rest.
Excruciatingly... bad, is that it?
Is that how you understand it?
Sorry.
Excruciatingly... busy?
Swamped with work.
There are only 4 types of
situations a man can't tolerate.
You just said 3 types earlier.
You just added another one yourself.
Omo!  Look at me.
President Gim, you actually
look like a "flowering" man.
No wonder, everytime I see you, I feel that
you're so excruciatingly handsome indeed.
What?  Don't tell me you
don't feel like a "flowering" man?
Omo!  I totally agree with it after I heard that.
This is upsetting.
Aren't you a bit too modest?
Are you suffering from multiple personality disorder?
Is Teacher Seo I Su inside?
What I saw is a thief
who specializes in unrequited love.
A woman who denies when backed into a corner.
You're flattering me too much.
Why did you come here today?
I was thinking about you.
Tae San was looking, wasn't he?
Yesterday's confession.
I've also thought about this.
Just say, "I hate that woman,
I rejected her".
Those kinds of words.
I don't hate you.
What did you say?
I said, I don't plan on doing that.
Why?  What's so difficult about this?
I can't go and tell him I've been rejected?
I already gave you the reason.
What's the reason?
Are you planning to keep
ignoring my calls?
Are you going to keep calling me?
You don't plan on taking my calls?
Whether I like it or not, that's not the issue.
Then just answer it.
I came to get my clothes.
Those women who sleep with you,
aren't they willing to do your laundry?
That's one aspect and I also left
some of my nice clothes here.
My nice clothes are all in here.
Why do you come at a time
when I'm not around?
I saw that the lights were off from outside.
Then all this time,
you never came in because the lights were on?
Are you hurt?  Where?
I'm not hurt.
It's my punishment.
But my punishment has nothing to do with you.
Have coffee before you leave.
Since there were only Tae San and I here,
we kept things up there.
We have to move them
so that you can reach them.
Otherwise, you might get hurt.
Pretending to care.
I'm not moving them.
Leave it there so that I'd get hurt.
After I get hurt, I'll file a lawsuit.
That way, I can see you.
I'm leaving.
I'll break all the dishes.
Why are you going to Gangneung?
To watch a baseball match.
You want to come?
No way...
To see men in their baseball uniforms?
I'm warning you.  Don't use
this baseball match as an excuse
to set up your getaway plans.
At most, you'd only lose your pretty wife
but we will lose our landlord.
Do you know what her strong point is?
She only considers a man's physical appearance.
Do a good job.
You punks... don't you know
how well behaved I am these days?
We're more well behaved.
Isn't that for my happiness, anyway?
When is the competition?
I Su will come with me.
You go and pick up our office staff.
Fine.
You should come and hit some balls, too.
Our Do Pal values his passion
more than his friendship.
Friendship was invented by single men.
I'll go ahead.
So rude.  Your hyeongnims are still talking.
(Hyeongnim - Respected older brother)
Don't give refills, otherwise their nagging won't end.
Most of it revolves around you anyway.  Go.
That is why don't give them refills.
Welcome.
Hello, Chairman Seong.
I am President Gim.
Yes, Tae San's doing very well.
Yes, Tae San has eaten.
It's nothing.  I was just wondering
if you have time this weekend.
I'm going crazy.
Why? Did something happen?
Chairman Seong...
Of all days, she has to pick the morning
of that baseball match to inspect the properties.
I'm going crazy, really.
Man. Why must it be that day?
Exactly.  What can I do?
Can you go instead?
- Of course I can.
- Really?
That is, if you want to sever
our relationship with Chairman Seong.
I really want to beat you up.
Why couldn't you be as charming as me?
I'm sorry.
I can go to Gangneung for you.
I'll pick Teacher Seo up.
Forget it. I'll ask Yun, instead.
It's me.
I have a client meeting this weekend.
I can't pick I Su up.
Can you pick her up instead?
The office staff?
We're one family.
Do Pal will take care of it.
And best of all, he said he will.
Why is it too much trouble
to give this woman a ride?
Mi A Ri.  It's Do Jin oppa.
I'm also very happy to meet you.
I'm not avoiding you.
I left something at home.
That's right. No woman avoids me.
Why are you here?
I have a baseball match today.
I need to leave as soon as Yun arrives.
I know. But, you have to come with me.
There's no room in Yun's car.  No room...
So... you're all here because
Do Jin asked you to come over?
He said you cannot have
an empty seat in your car.
He said not to worry about Teacher
since he's picking her up.
That son of a bitch.
It'll be tight. Will it be all right?
- Yes! No problem!
- Me too.
Rather than get stuck in the car for 3 hours
with President Gim, it's much better to take a bus.
Let's go. Get in.
President Gim asked us to get our uniforms.
He wants us to do that, too?
Are we putting this in the car?
Go ahead.
Oppa, how do I look?
Pretty, isn't it?
Now, you look a lot prettier.
Go. Let's go.
What position are you going to hold?
Last time, I saw--
Last time, Tae San threatened me.
I don't like baseball.
Except for golf.  All ball games feel like a gang war.
Don't you like fights?
But why are you going to this match?
Blue Cat needs a handsome muse.
Do you have something
to eat in your bag?
I brought some Kimbap and hard boiled eggs.
(Kimbap - Dried seaweed roles with rice)
So this strange smell is coming from the Kimbap?
It's a long ride, we might get hungry.
Who?
Unrequited love with Tae San
but confessing to me.
Did you make that Kimbap for Yun?
- You want to have some?
- Forget it.
Then eat the eggs.
- What are you doing right now?
- What?
I hate chicken.  I don't even meet
people born in the year of the chicken.
And you dare peel an egg
laid by a chicken in my car?
Haven't you noticed the condition of my car?
My car has a germ free environment where even
a medical experiment can be conducted at any time.
My car is in this condition 365 days of the year.
Do you know what it means?
Does your friend own a car wash?
Not that.  I love my car.
Eating in the car. Sticking things in the car.
Throwing things in the car.  Car--
In this situation, might as well give the car a name.
It can't be...
You want to go to the toilet?
Oh no, you did name it.
What's the name?
Is it a male or a female?
Get off.  Bring your bag.
You're not thinking of leaving me--
You can't have that bag with those food in my car.
Ingest it first before getting back in.
Do you usually eat that much?
I like eating these sorts of stuff
at freeway rest stops.
Does your comprehension deteriorate
when you're eating?
I was asking how a woman can eat so much.
That's why I wanted you to eat this with me.
Forget it.  I don't eat with a thief.
Seriously.
But, you don't really remember me?
Red yarn.  Contentious behind.
You really don't remember?
Since you've regurgitated all the food in your mouth,
you must have forgotten it.
I don't know!  I don't know!
I have told you so many times already!
Even if you ask me a million times,
I still don't know!
Oh, that's how much you've forgotten.
I got it.  Hurry, let's go.
There's still a lot left.
You've already eaten enough.
Come on.
What did you do again?
Yeah. Why?
We're here?
We're in Yangyang.  Get off the car.
Yangyang?
Why are we in Yangyang?
It's an emergency.
It's a very important problem that has something
to do with Tae San, Yun and my life.
Then, you should have dropped me off at Gangneung.
The match will start at 2.
It's already 12:30.
Then what are you standing there for?
Hurry take a taxi to the bus stand.
Please don't do this.
Although I don't look like it, but I am someone
who acts irrationally when backed into a corner.
Since I'm an Ethics teacher,
I have great curiosity in unethical matters.
Then, we're about the same.
Here.
Hey! Hey!
From the minute we set off,
how can you mess up someone's schedule like this?
What do you expect me to do?
What exactly is it?
Hold your horses.
Go to the toilet and listen to this first.
When did you get here?
- Last night.
- In what?
I caught a plane.
What if she tries to confirm the passenger list?
Looks like I took my car.
- Why are you here?
- To play golf, of course.
- When are you leaving?
- Tomorrow.
Yes, Ji Su.  I'm President Gim.
Yes, Jeong Rok is with me.
Of course, don't worry.
You know I'll always be on your side.
No, we'll be going to Gangneung.
Jeong Rok is going home now.
We wanted him to finish his Sashimi
before he heads back,
but he said his plane is leaving soon
so he couldn't stay.
Okay then.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
And furthermore, I brought my car,
why'd you say airplane?
Then step on the accelerator and fly faster than a plane.
I've never met someone as nice as you.
Actually, I met Hae Ju.
She was in my shop and
you even bumped into her.
Who's Hae Ju? Was she the one who
dumped you and married a doctor?
No, that was Jeong Mi.
The one who dumped me and
married an accountant, Baek Hae Ju.
Your first love--
She's not my first love.
My first love was Yun Hui.
So, what happened afterwards?
She gave me a call yesterday saying
she wanted to go for a ride.
So I drove all the way to the East China Sea.
Did you sleep together?
What are you saying?
After her divorce, she's been living with her daughter.
She must have suffered a lot.
That beautiful face had all but disappeared.
Although she's without a doubt an ajumma,
(Ajumma - Older lady, Aunt)
but my heart still ached for her.
So we watched the sea together,
drank a bit of wine,
booked a hotel room for her.
It's true.  That's the whole truth!
Perhaps... it's your child?
Hey!
Excuse me. Madam asked me to pass this to you.
The car was driven away by Madam.
Madam!
Did you get married secretly?
You looked very busy. So I went ahead.
But I didn't have enough time
to ask for your permission.
Then, see you in Gangneung.
Take the plane, I'm taking your car.
Who took your car?
Was it a girl?
Is she pretty?
Are you a high school student?
A runaway?
Holiday.
Where are you going?
Tell me. I'm a high school teacher.
I just stole this car.  Is that all right?
I'll be your best accomplice.
But, you don't have a gun, do you?
So... they were all in your car?
Yes.
Since he did all this, maybe Do Jin
is serious with Teacher Seo.
But still...
I don't know why but I don't feel comfortable with this.
It's Se Ra.
Yes, it's me.  Where else can I be?
Of course, at the baseball field.
Where's my Hong pro?
I'm at the driving range.
I Su said she went to Gangneung
for the baseball match.
Tae San, are you there?
I Su said she's joining the match?
She went to Gangneung?
If I Su went to the match, then I just got caught.
I am currently holding the phone with both my hands,
with great reverence.
Im Tae San?
Are you a baseball player?
I'm an architect, of course.
Do you have to do this every weekend?
Of course, I won't be doing this next week.
If I do this for 2 weeks straight, is that still
an architect?  That's a baseball player already.
What shall we do next week?
Kiss?  Skinship?
He-hello?
Se-Se-Se Ra?
Miss Hong.
Why did I bring up kissing?
Was I too self-centered?
Yes.  Generally, after skinship comes the kiss.
Oh, so that's how it is.
How do I look?
What's that again?
She's also one of Do Jin's creations.
Oppas!...  Fighting!
(Oppa - Older brother, Boyfriend)
Victory! Victory!
V. I. C. T. O. R. Y.
Fighting!
Where's my car?
Do you want to know?
Then listen carefully.
I only want one thing.
Never bring up my shortcomings with you again.
Including the incident that
I've forgotten about.  Okay?
Then that's a bit too infuriating, isn't it?
Teacher Seo.
It's a deal then.
If you're all done, please head to the field.
I love you, President.
This lapse is work related,
go ahead and punish me.
Everytime I make eye contact,
they express their admiration for me.
Like this.
You're really handsome, President.
But when will you ever do
something to receive such punishment?
Where's my car?
Betty!
Kinetic energy of a gaseous substance EK.
It will only change with the absolute temperature, T.
Kinetic energy is directly proportional
to the absolute temperature.
The higher the temperature,
the more prone it is to molecular diffusion.
Right here.
Play!
Out!
Good ball.
Good shot!
Oppa!  My Oppa!
Do your best.
Oppa! Fighting!
Mi A Ri is here!
Win.
Oppa...!
Im Mi A Ri!
Mi-Mi A Ri.
Are you all right?
Im Mi A Ri, are you all right?
Mi A Ri.
It looks bad.
Mi A Ri. Eyes. Open your eyes.
Are you all right?
Where were you hit?  Where?
Are you all right?  Can you see me?
I'm not all right.
Looks like you have to use your sincerity
and love to slowly help me get better.
It was a direct hit on the head, really.
Can you see this?  How many?
I can't see... Yun oppa...
Hurry, get in.
I'll bring her home. Take care of the things here.
Don't worry, just go.
Pass by the hospital first.
You want me to leave with you?
No way... I want to go with Attorney.
Atty. Choe, I want to file a case.
Let's talk about it on the way home.
Right, let Yun take her.
You stay and take care of things here.
If you're worried, I can go with them.
What are you doing, Teacher?
Nothing was really going to happen.
But good thing, I got hurt.
Looks like you'll be all right going alone.
Go.
Then, we'll go ahead.
Teacher, take care of my bag.
Sorry to bother you.
I'll give you a call.
Is your sister all right?
She won't die.  She's fine.
We're heading back to the pension house now.
Those who need to wash, wash up.
Those who need to eat, eat.
Was that from I Su's room?
She's calling me.
It's a secret code between us.
Hey.  What the hell did you do to her?
Right now, are you officially provoking me?
You provoked me first.
How's the squid?
I hacked it to pieces.
This squid's life...
What kind of a man are you?
When I gave you the car keys,
didn't we just agree to
never raise the past again?
What made you think I agreed to it?
That is...
Because you're a man.  A gentleman.
Do I look like a gentleman to you?
I'm very sorry.  I'm not a gentleman.
Why?
Aren't you being a bit too critical on yourself?
You will... keep your end of the deal?
You're really stupid.
You're also lacking in foresight
when it comes to men.
What?
The man standing before you now,
do you reckon he's no better
than your average man on the streets?
Especially with regard to concealing
an unrequited love after the confession.
Let alone settle this properly,
but instead this woman actually made
the situation more complicated.
How can you directly go from stealing a pen
to stealing a car?
Burglar Miss Seo I Su.
Because the competition was at 2--
Therefore... what do you want?
What my staff did earlier, you saw it, right?
Staff?
Don't tell me... you want me to...
That's right.
Next time, as soon as yell "Seo I Su",
Regardless of when, where, what and why...
you have to praise me.
You must use flattering words.
I'm speechless.
What if I don't do it?
What?  Will you spill everything to Tae San?
Don't try me.
Wow. Look at this bruise.
Will this take weeks to heal?
So what if it does?
It has to take a long time so I can
get some settlement money.
From now on, I am a client.
You're my lawyer.
Are we lost?
This is heading to Seoul.
Seoul.  220 kilometers.
No bleeding, great vision.
I think you don't need a lawyer but an egg.
Oh... what do I do?
My eyes are swollen and painful.
It's turning black.
It feels like my eyes are about to fall off.
I'll lie down for a while.
It's a bit cold, thank you.
This is Mi A Ri's bag.
Those clothes are Mi A Ri's, too?
There was an accident so...
I Su, I didn't know you have this side.
I Su, it's best if you hitch
a ride back with him, is that okay?
I have to meet Se Ra.
Is that so? Then, bring me with you.
What's wrong with you?
Didn't you say you're not going home?
You said we're going to stay here.
When did I say that?
Don't be shy about it.
Tae San, you'll understand. Will you?
She said since we came all the way here,
she must try the Sashimi before heading back.
That's why I said that.
I'd like to, Miss Seo I Su.
Then, are you coming back again?
Answer him. Seo I Su.
I think she's still very shy.
In fact, I can hear it.
I'll buy you chicken.  Did she say that?
No, it's not like--
If it's like that, I'll just say it out loud.
But she's still shy about it.
She even praised me.
Then go back.
Let's go.
Teacher Seo has totally become a different person.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
Too cool. Too cool.
Guys!
She's prettier from the front.
It caught me by surprise, too.
How can they look so good together?
Be careful of that punk! I Su!
Come! Cheers!
You're not eating?
Is it really because of this Sashimi?
The reason for making me stay behind.
How is that possible?
Then, what is it?
You've never been in love before?
I was considered a prodigy.
A love prodigy.
Then, you should know.
The reason why a man would hold a woman
at such a distant and unfamiliar beach side.
That's why I'm asking.
What exactly is your reason?
It sure is embarrassing
if you don't know at that age.
I want you to drive... to Seoul.
You look disappointed.
Looks like you want something else.
Put it down...
Do you really want to sleep with me?
I'm ready for it.
Oh, gross...
As a woman, why can't you set
your sight for the long run?
That's right.
Me?
This woman's problem is always
the bottom part of her clothes.
Thank you.  You're very kind.
You're quite persistent.
Although I still feel that we're both to blame,
but anyway...
Thank you.
That's quite an impressive confession.
Why be a baseball umpire?
Teaching children is already tiring enough as it is.
Aside from teaching the children,
I love baseball the most.
And I also like...
Im Tae San, the baseball player.
For putting you in an awkward situation
because of my confession,
I'm really sorry.
Please understand.
Now, I...
have even lost my chance... to confess.
We'll schedule the construction work next week.
Sure.
But President... how old are you this year?
41 years old.
As a 41 year old, this answer...
is when you won't allow yourself
to feel wronged and dejected again.
It's already March where spring flowers bloom.
It's a season most suitable to a "flowering" man like me.
Although some women might laugh at this.
Hello, everyone.
I presume everybody knows me.
The Ethics Goddess, Seo I Su.
Not 20, maybe roundabouts 15 people
tossed coins to enter.
I told you so.  Should not be more than 20 people.
I'm sure of it.  I know it.
No problems, for sure.
They are kings when it comes
to throwing.
How many times do I have to say the same thing?
My throat is aching.
How many times do I have to say it?
What did I do wrong in my previous life?
What the heck?
What goddess?
It's such a waste of time.
It's not even Chinese, English or Math.
She's merely an Ethics teacher.
Ethics is not even included in the college exams.
What's the use of attending her class?
Just try and stop me from doing
my other assignments in her class...
I will punish her immediately
and then lay her off.
Hello, Friend.
I'm sorry but can you repeat
what you just said earlier?
Wh-wh-what did I say?
No?
You can't even do this for a friend. So disappointing.
You jerk! #@%&
This is the most common violent attack
in school campuses of the Korean peninsula.
Next time, it'll be the Chinese version.
So...
Don't look down on her.
You're here.
Everything's going smoothly?
There are no problems with the store,
but it feels like something
is going to happen to you.
Me? Why?
Earlier, Madam came and took away the credit card bills.
What? You jerk.
This kind of thing, why tell me only now?
Do you think that I pay you just to sell coffee?
How long ago since she left?
Where did she go?
I can handle it.
Really...
Hey!
What are you doing?
Stay far away from my wife.
Say hello.
He's a man who shares the
same family registry with me.
Nuna, you're married?
(Nuna - Older sister)
Don't worry.
I think we'll be having separate
family registers soon.
Honey, how can you make such a scary joke?
In front of a strange man.
If you came because of the credit card bills...
then tell me your prepared excuses.
Credit card bills?
So it's with you.
Your naughty curiosity.
Kimbap Heaven, 2 million Won.
What is that?
Don't tell me, you're operating a Kimbap business.
What are you saying?
What is that?
Tae San and his baseball team.  Blue Cat.
I treated them to lunch.
So it's like this.
Wow.  They can sure eat.
They can sure eat...
1 000 Won a piece of Kimbap,
each of them can actually eat
166 000 Won a piece.
Nowadays, night clubs, these types of places,
will use other shop's name in their receipts.
What are you doing?
Butting into our business.
Do you want to go to heaven?
Should I send you there now?
No.
You like flowers, right?
For you...
Should I bring this home?
Where shall I put it?
Bring it to heaven.
Give it to the angels.
Aren't angels females?
Wife.
Honey.
Darling!
Min Suk nuna...
What is the reason for
deciding to be an architect?
Gim Do Jin:
"Because during the 90's, the age of capitalism,
my parents wanted me
to become a professional.
An architect is also a professional.
So carrying the spirit of the X generation,
I chose to be an architect."
"Those were my prepared answers."
The truth is I scored high enough to get in.
Are there any buildings you
want to see in your lifetime?
Why should I go see a building before I die?
That time is very valuable.
Then, what do you want to see?
Your beloved wife's face?
I am a lone wolf.
That's unexpected.
Is there a particular reason for it?
I don't think I can spend
a lifetime with one woman.
I also don't think that I can love
1 woman for the rest of my life.
I don't want to share the money I earn
with my wife or my children.
That's about it.
Really...
President Gim Do Jin left us a few words
prior to the end of his interview.
Please embellish that for me.
Such a straight shooter.
But, what's up with this man?
It seems like I am hearing his voice over
while reading this article.
Poor you.
No man sent you home.
That I can understand.
Why don't you even have a man
who can have coffee with you?
Did you end it with Do Jin?
I already told you we don't have
that kind of relationship.
If that's the case, then go out with Yun.
Although he was married but...
He has high market value, handsome.
To be honest, he is too good for you.
He is even a lawyer.
Otherwise, just go on a blind date.
I know of a good seonbae in our pitching team.
(Seonbae - Senior, Mentor)
Forget it.
Don't tell me it's because of that
20-second man you told me before?
No.  It's not because of him.
Who is it?
Is he someone I know?
All right, set me up on a date.
Really?
But, at our age, we call it date.
But in reality, it's a marriage introduction.
You understand?
I know.
When are you setting it?
You're alone?
They're in the car park.
What do you want to eat?
With my teacher?
Do you like I Su that much?
If I were a man, I would make her my wife.
I really hope I can have
a sister-in-law like her.
Se Ra's also good. She's cool.
What's so good about her?
It's only you who thinks so.
This girl, really.
For a girl who lived in the U.S.,
how can you have a Joseon mentality?
Is this how you treat your future sister-in-law?
Why?  Mi A Ri is back biting me again?
I'm starving.
Where is my teacher?
I Su went on a blind date.
Blind date?
Why must she go on a blind date?
She already has someone she likes.
Who? Do Jin?
From the way she's behaving,
looks like she'd been dumped.
Dumped?  By Do Jin?
Where is the place?
So what if you know?
We have to drag her out.
Just like in the movies.
Who? The three of us?
Go ahead and order first.
What slander did you tell him?
It's just random talk between brother and sister.
Why do you hate me so much?
Do you really want to know?
I couldn't care less in the beginning,
but now I'm a bit curious.
When you went to New York with Oppa to see me,
do you still remember?
You just started dating.
So,
Oppa went to see the major league baseball that day.
I saw you kissing a guy you
had just met at a club.
You... me...
are not the type who'd
stay in a library, am I right?
I never told my brother.
That's why I hate you so much.
I hope you can understand.
Oh, I see.
The reason is very clear.
Of course, you'd hate me.
I admit it.
Admit?
What can I do?  I already kissed him.
Do I continue to sit here or do I leave?
Do as you wish.
She said I got dumped?
I'll call you again.
Because of the Sokchodong leaking incident,
I'm at Yun's office.
Was that Tae San?  Why?
Some girl went on a blind date.
Who is she?
Why?  Are you worried it was Mi A Ri?
You, brat...
What did the owner say?
He said no one ever told him about
changing the drainage pipe size to 120 mm.
But because he said that,
it makes it a lot easier for us.
Why?
Your recorder.
There must be a record of it.
Did you keep the file?
This thing is useful.
Then, there's nothing to worry about.
Want to have coffee?
Is it Teacher Seo?
The woman on a blind date.
Do I ask you to stay put?
Or do I push you to go?
Iced Americano with 3 shots.
Do you wear something like this
when you meet other men?
It's not that pretty.
It's been quite a while.
Long enough that the seasons have changed.
Actually, I am meeting someone right now.
There's 10 minutes before the set time.
You're so early.
Why must I save a girl who's so eager
to go on a blind date?
Tae San asked me to bail you out.  Seo I Su, you.
Tae San asked you to save me?
Was that all you heard?
I don't have to come but I still came.
You don't feel anything at all?
You didn't have to come.
But why are you here?
I've decided to embark on a one-sided love.
With whom?
You.
Which 'you'?
M-me?
You're not allowed to refuse.
-=Next Episode Preview=-
Don't you remember meeting me in Busan?
What is your father doing?
This person...
Your first blind date isn't over yet.
For male number 2, meet him next time.
You don't have appetite?
How can I?
Even if it's cast iron, I would still gobble it down.
You really make me witness a lot of things.
I don't have the confidence to make Mi A Ri like me.
The bar was 5 hours and 10 minutes ago.
This is the hotel.
Yun Pal moved from our house
to live with his mother-in-law.
Your friend came over and took it away.
Is this how a person with one-sided love
supposed to behave?
Can't a man with one-sided love
sleep with another woman?
Why? You want to sleep with me?
-=XX.  The same bastard.=-
-=Why did you switch off your phone?=-
-=Where did you sleep last night?=-
-=Gim Do Jin's little intelligence is
recognized without exception.=-
-=20 000 Won.=-
-=Seo I Su=-
-=Architect Gim Do Jin's view
on Korea's modern architecture.=-