♪♪♪♪
[ Otis Redding ]
♪♪ BAH BAH-BAH BAH-BAH
BAH-BAH-BAH-BAH ♪♪
BAH-BAH-BAH ♪♪
♪♪ I KEEP SINGIN'
THEM SAD, SAD SONGS, Y'ALL ♪♪
- ♪♪ SAD SONGS IS ALL I KNOW ♪♪
- YOU WANT TO TAKE THE WHEEL,
SADE ?
- SADE.
-♪♪ I KEEP SINGIN'
THEM SAD, SAD SONGS ♪♪
[ Indistinct ]
♪♪ SAD SONGS ♪♪
♪♪ IS ALL I KNOW ♪♪
♪♪ THERE'S A SWEET MELODY
TONIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ ANYBODY CAN SING IT
ANY OLD TIME ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S GOT TO YOUR HEART
PUT YOU IN A GROOVE ♪♪
♪♪ AND WHEN YOU
SING THIS SONG IT'LL MAKE
YOUR WHOLE BODY MOVE ♪♪
♪♪ IT GOES BAH BAH-BAH BAH-BAH
BAH-BAH-BAH-BAH ♪♪
♪♪ YOUR TURN ♪♪
♪♪ OUR TURN ♪♪
♪♪ BAH BAH-BAH BAH-BAH
BAH-BAH-BAH-BAH ♪♪
♪♪ YOUR TURN NOW ♪♪♪♪
[ Knocking ]
HOUSEKEEPING.
IT'S A LITTLE EARLY.
YOU'RE LUCKY
IT'S JUST ME.
COULD BE MY ASS.
DO YOU KNOW WHO I AM ?
YEAH.
YOU'RE THE T-MAN.
"I'M GONNA MAKE YOU MINE."
YOU'RE TRUCKER.
YOUR TURN.
I'M SADIE FLOOD.
I SING.
THIS IS GREAT.
THIS IS MY HAPPY HOME.
MY RETREAT FROM CARE.
THERE'S A PLACE
FOR EVERYTHING, AND
EVERYTHING'S IN ITS PLACE.
IT'S HOW I KEEP TRACK.
YOU UNDERSTAND ?
WHO ARE YOU EXPECTING ?
♪♪ IF ME AND MY BABY
FUSS AND FIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE NEXT
MINUTE ♪♪
♪♪ WE ALL RIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ OOH-OOH-OOH ♪♪
- ♪♪ AIN'T NOBODY'S BUSINESS ♪♪
- ♪♪ IF WE DO ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I'M THREE TIMES SEVEN ♪♪
♪♪ UH-UH-UH
THAT MAKES 21 ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OOH-OOH-OOH
AIN'T NOBODY'S BUSINESS ♪♪
♪♪ AIN'T NOBODY'S BUSINESS ♪
♪♪ IF WE DO ♪♪
♪♪ WELL, IT AIN'T
AIN'T NOBODY'S BUSINESS ♪♪
♪♪ IF WE DO ♪♪♪♪
♪♪♪♪ [ Drumroll,
Cymbals Crash ]
WHAT YOU THINK
YOU WERE DOIN' ?
YOU NEED TO DO
WHAT I TELL YA.
WHAT ?
IF WE GONNA GO
THIS JOURNEY,
I DON'T MEAN FOR YOU
TO LOOK AT, TALK TO...
OR FRATERNIZE.
MY SIDEMEN GOT FRIENDS.
THEY DON'T NEED FRIENDS.
YOU WITH ME.
RESPECT IT.
HELLO, CHASMAN.
HOW YA DOIN' ?
GREAT.  I'M GREAT.
THIS IS GREAT.  HOW ARE YOU ?
THAT'S SO GREAT.
I GUESS I'M GONNA
HAVE TO KILL YOU.
JOKE, SADIE.
BLANKS.
♪♪ I CAN'T STAND IT ♪♪
♪♪ YOU'RE FOOLIN' AROUND
I CAN'T STAND IT ♪♪
♪♪ YOU'RE RUNNIN' AROUND
I WON'T STAND IT ♪♪
♪♪ YOU'RE FOOLIN' AROUND
WITH MY HEART ♪♪
♪♪ I'LL EXPLAIN-- ♪♪♪♪
[ Newscaster ]
TOMORROW, ONCE THE FOG CLEARS,
WITH HIGHS NEAR 70.
CURRENTLY 68 ACROSS.
AND THAT'S THE LOWDOWN.
MIKE JONES REPORTING.
MORE PURE ROCK.
NO-REPEAT WORKDAYS,
WITH NO USELESS TALK.
99.9 FM, KISW.
[ Echoing ]
SEATTLE'S BEST
ROCK, ROCK, ROCK.
WE'RE HERE.
WHERE'S THE CAT ?
BUMMER.
[ Screaming, Cheering ]
[ Crowd Chanting ]
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ LET US PAUSE ON
LIFE'S PLEASURES ♪♪
♪♪ AND COUNT
ITS MANY TEARS ♪♪
♪♪ WHILE WE ALL SHARE SORROW
WITH THE POOR ♪♪
♪♪ THERE'S A SONG
THAT WILL LINGER ♪♪
♪♪ FOREVER IN OUR EARS ♪♪
♪♪ OH, HARD TIMES
COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S A SONG, A SIGH ♪♪
♪♪ OF THE WEARY ♪♪
♪♪ HARD TIMES
HARD TIMES ♪♪
[ Crowd Whistling, Cheering ]
♪♪ COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ MANY DAYS
HAVE YOU LINGERED ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AROUND MY CABIN DOOR
♪♪ OH, HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ COME AGAI
N   NO MORE ♪♪
[ Cheering, Whistling ]
♪♪ WHILE WE SEEK MIRTH
AND BEAUTY ♪♪
♪♪ AND MUSIC
BRIGHT AND GAY ♪♪
♪♪ THERE ARE FRAIL FORMS ♪♪
♪♪ FAINTING AT THE DOOR ♪♪
♪♪ AND THOUGH THEIR VOICES
ARE SILENT ♪♪
♪♪ THEIR FLEETING LOOKS
WILL SAY ♪♪
♪♪ OH, HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S A SONG ♪♪
♪♪ A SIGH OF THE WEARY ♪♪
♪♪ HARD TIMES
HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ MANY DAYS
HAVE YOU LINGERED ♪♪
♪♪ AROUND MY CABIN DOOR ♪♪
♪♪ OH, OH, HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ NO MORE HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ NO MORE HARD ♪♪
♪♪ TIMES ♪♪♪♪
[ Crowd Cheering ]
STEPHEN FOSTER,
1859.
WHOO !  WHOO !
THANK YOU.
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
WE'VE BEEN TRYING OUT
SOME NEW SONGS.
I KNEW YOU'D BE HERE.
I DIDN'T KNOW
I'D BE HERE.
WELL, I FELT YOU
OUT THERE.
HEY, MISH IS HERE.
DID YOU SEE MISH ?
ANDREW'S ASLEEP
IN THE DRESSING ROOM.
HE'LL WANDER OUT IN A MINUTE.
GOD, YOU LOOK AMAZING.
WELL, YOU ALWAYS
LOOK AMAZING.
I LOOK LIKE SHIT, JAKE.
NO, NOT TO ME.
NEVER.
THIS IS CHASMAN.
HIYA.
THIS IS JAKE.
BEST MAN IN THE WORLD.
HIYA.
UH, COULD I GET YOU
SOMETHIN' TO EAT ?
HOW YOU DOIN',
SADIE ?
NO, THANKS, JAKE.
INCREDIBLE OUT THERE
TONIGHT, HUH ?
PRETTY INTENSE.
SO HOW YOU DOIN' ?
GREAT.
HEARD YOU WERE
WITH THE TRUCKER.
THAT TRUE ?
FOR ABOUT HALF A SECOND.
YOU HEARD THAT ?
HE'S MY MAN,
YOU KNOW.
YOU HEARD THAT, HUH ?
OH, GOD.  GOD.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
YOU WERE GREAT
OUT THERE, MAN.
SO IN-FUCKING-CREDIBLY GREAT.
YOU TEAR ME UP,
YOU KNOW ?
WHAT DID DAD USED TO SAY ?
GOD KISSED HER.
GOD KISSED THAT GIRL.
GOD, I'M GLAD
YOU'RE HERE.
WELL.
HEY, MISH. HEY.
I GET A HUG ?
SURE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
NO, SURE.
THAT WAS GREAT.
SO, ARE YOU DRINKING ?
YOU KNOW ME.
WHATEVER'S CHEAP OR FREE.
SO YOU'RE HERE
IN SEATTLE ?
LOOKS LIKE IT.
HELLO.
- THIS IS CHASMAN.
- HI.
HE'S WITH ME.
OH ?
CAME UP FROM SAN FRANCISCO.
SAVED MY LIFE.
OH.
HELLO.
I'M A FAN.
SO SADIE SAID
YOU WERE HER SISTER.
CHASMAN'S
A PROMOTER.
OH.
- WHAT DO YOU PROMOTE ?
- ME.
SADIE'S AMONG MY CLIENTS.
YEAH, MY STAR CLIENT.
I MET SADIE
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
I'M FROM LONDON
ORIGINALLY.
OH ?
BALAND.
YOU CAN HEAR
THE ACCENT.
WHERE YOU STAYING ?
WELL, I THOUGHT, YOU KNOW, I'D
COME HOME FOR A LITTLE MAYBE.
OH, THAT'D BE GREAT.
FERGUSON HEARD
YOU WERE WITH TRUCKER.
EMMETT TRUCKER ?
I'M-GONNA-MAKE-YOU-MINE TRUCKER.
YEAH.  FOR ABOUT HALF A MINUTE.
YEAH.
YOU WERE GREAT.
YOU WERE GREAT TONIGHT.
WHAT YOU DO
UP THERE.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW YOU THINK
THAT SOUNDS LIKE BULLSHIT.
NO.
WE'RE STAYING
IN TOWN TONIGHT.
LET US GET YOU A ROOM
AT THE HOTEL.
UNLESS YOU--
THAT'D BE GREAT.
SO YOU WERE THINKING OF
STAYING WITH US A LITTLE.
UNTIL I GOT SETTLED.
UH, THAT'S FANTASTIC.
I COULD HELP
WITH THE HOUSE.
WELL, MAYBE NOT.
HAS SOMEONE GOT
AN EYE ON ANDREW ?
ANDREW'S FINE.
MISH, YOU WANNA
GO SEE TO ANDREW ?
SURE.
SEE YOU, SADIE.
YOU BET !
WHAT ARE YOUR PLANS ?
CHASMAN.
HE'S GOTTA GO BACK.
NOT TONIGHT.
NO, NOT TONIGHT.
NOT TOMORROW MAYBE
NEITHER.
IT'S A LONG RIDE.
WELL, WE'LL SEE,
WON'T WE ?
THERE'S TONS OF FOOD
OVER THERE.
CAN I FIX YOU A PLATE ?
WELL, I WAS THINKING
OF YOU GUYS, ACTUALLY.
[ Sadie Singing Quietly ]
♪♪ WHOSE HONEY ARE YOU ♪♪
♪♪ WHOSE TEA
DO YOU SWEETEN ♪♪
♪♪ WHOSE SUGAR AND SPICE
AND EVERYTHING NICE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ DEPEND UPON YOU ♪
♪♪ YOU'VE GOT
A TINY LITTLE TOUCH ♪♪
♪♪ OF HEAVEN ♪♪
[ Bottle Gurgling ]
♪♪ IN HER FINGERTIPS ♪♪
♪♪♪♪
♪♪♪♪ [ Music Blaring ]
I MEAN, IT FIRED LOUD.
BUT I DIDN'T GET HIT
BY ANYTHING.
HE HAD GUNS EVERYWHERE.
HE JUST ALWAYS THINKS
PEOPLE ARE DOIN' HIM IN.
SO HE'S ALWAYS
EXPECTING, LIKE,
A SIEGE.
MISH ?
SO EVERYBODY'S
OUT TO GET YOU.
AND ALSO... GERMS.
HE HAS A THING ABOUT GERMS.
AND THE FAUCET HAD TO BE
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE SINK...
OR HIS LIFE WAS RUINED.
-COME ON, YOU GUYS.
- YOU WANT ME TO TAKE 'EM ?
NO, I'LL TAKE 'EM.
WELL, SADIE'S HERE.
- I'LL TAKE 'EM.  ANDREW !
- IS THERE BROWN SUGAR ?
AND HE WOULD DO
THESE MIDNIGHT RAIDS...
WHERE HE WOULD LOOK
THROUGH THE CUPBOARDS TO SEE
IF I'D EATEN ANYTHING.
MISH.
ARE THERE
ANY GRAPES ?
HE'S DEFINITELY
MULTIPLE PERSONALITIES.
I MEAN, THERE WERE
THREE MAIN ONES,
AND TWO WERE VERY MEAN.
AND THEN THERE WERE,
LIKE, SUBGROUPS.
THERE YOU GO,
DRUID.
HE'D ROLL A JOINT
BIG AS CIGARS.
HE WAS REAL NICE
WHEN HE SMOKED.
HE'D BECOME REALLY MELLOW.
HE COULD SMOKE TWO HUGE SPLIFFS
AND STILL SING GREAT.
AND YOU KNOW,
HE CAN BE SO WONDERFUL.
HE CAN BE
SUCH A FABULOUS SINGER.
HE HAS GREAT VOCAL RANGE,
GREAT BREATH CONTROL.
YOU GUYS HAVE ABOUT 20 MINUTES
BEFORE YOU HAVE TO BE
OUT THAT DOOR.
[ Sadie ]
THAT WOMAN CAN
SURE AS HELL SING.
AS OPPOSED
TO WHAT, SADIE ?
DID I SAY SOMETHING ?
I DIDN'T MEAN ANYTHING
BY IT, JAKE.
EVERYTHING'S JAKE,
JAKE.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
IS SHE GONNA STAY ?
DON'T KNOW.
MISH, YOU'RE GONNA
RUIN YOUR EYES.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' ?
IT'S 8:00 IN THE MORNING.
YOU NEED NOT TO DO THAT
AROUND THE KIDS, OKAY ?
WOULDN'T.
I DON'T NEED TO SAY
I'M GRATEFUL I'M HERE.
NO, SADIE.
HOW WAS THE TOUR ?
IT WAS GREAT.
I WASN'T ON THE TOUR.
OH ?
I DON'T MANAGE
THE BAND ANYMORE.
NO ?
NOT FOR SIX YEARS,
SADIE.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE HELL I DO,
DO YOU ?
I DO.
SURE I DO.
YOU ARE SO FUCKED.
I DO.
I TEACH AND I WRITE.
- I KNEW THAT.
- I WANNA START
WORKIN' THE FARM.
I LIKE DOIN' STUFF
WITH MY HANDS.
THEY THINK
THEY OWN HER.
I'D BE WALKIN' AROUND,
MAKIN' SURE THE SOUND WAS GOOD
AND EVERYTHING'S FINE,
AND I'VE HAD GUYS GO,
"HEY, YOU WITH THE BAND ?
GOD, I'D LIKE TO FUCK HER."
YOU KNOW YOU GOTTA
BLAND IT OFF.
YOU KNOW ?
SEE, WE'VE BEEN THROUGH IT.
SHE SLEPT WITH SOMEBODY
SO I SLEPT WITH SOMEBODY...
OR WE THOUGHT WE WERE
GONNA SLEEP WITH SOMEBODY.
THE FIGHTS ARE ONE THING,
BUT THE SEX--
[ Laughs ]
WE HURT EACH OTHER.
WE'VE DONE JUST ABOUT
EVERY LIE THERE IS.
SOMETIMES I AM AMAZED
THAT SOMEHOW WE'RE
STILL HERE.
AND ALL I CAN
THINK ABOUT IS THAT
I FELL IN LOVE WITH HER...
THE MOMENT I LAID EYES
ON HER.
SHE'S GEORGIA,
YOU KNOW ?
AND WE'RE GONNA
GROW OLD TOGETHER.
- I STRIPPED THE BEDS.
- YOU DIDN'T NEED TO DO THAT.
YEAH, WELL,
SURE, I DID.
IT'S POURING, SADIE.
AND YOU HANG THEM OUT.
HOW DUMB TO FORGET.
WELL, NO HARM DONE.
I BORROWED THIS, OKAY ?
WHATEVER.  IT'S FINE.
YOU DON'T NEED TO
CLEAN THE HOUSE, SADIE.
I WAS CLEANING
MOTEL ROOMS.
REALLY.
NO,REALLY.
OH, GOD.
SADIE REDUCED TO THAT.
OR IS THERE ANYTHING SADIE
CAN'T BE REDUCED TO ?
YOU WANNA GIVE ME
A BREAK, SADIE ?
YOU WANNA GIVE ME ONE ?
I CAN FEEL
WHAT YOU'RE FEELING.
NO.  NO, YOU CAN'T.
YOU CAN'T FEEL
WHAT I'M FEELING.
YOU AREN'T ME.
I THINK WE SHOULD NOT
GET INTO THIS.
FINE.  BETTER FOR ME.
SHIT.
DAD'S COMING
TO STAY A WEEK, FRIDAY.
I'LL BE HERE.
GETS REALLY
TENSE, SADIE.
I'LL BE HERE, OKAY ?
HOW'S HE DOIN' ?
FINE.
I THINK FINE.
I THINK ALL RIGHT.
YOU NEED SOME MONEY ?
YEAH.  YEAH.
SOMETHIN' TO
GET STARTED ON.
I'M GOOD FOR IT.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE GOOD FOR IT.
IT PLEASES ME TO BE ABLE
TO GIVE IT TO YOU.  I LOVE
BEING ABLE TO GIVE IT TO YOU.
OKAY.
THINGS ARE GONNA BREAK FOR ME.
THERE IS NOT A DOUBT IN MY MIND.
THIS HAS ALL GOTTA BE
ABOUT SOMETHING.
THIS WHOLE... ADVENTURE.
EVERYTHING IS STORED
FOR LATER USE.
THERE MUST BE A PONY.
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ THERE SHE GOES AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ THERE SHE GOES ♪♪
♪♪ SHE'S KNOCKED OUT
ON HER FEET AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ THERE SHE GOES ♪♪
♪♪ SHE'S DOWN ON HER KNEES
MY FRIEND ♪♪
♪♪ THERE SHE GOES ♪♪
♪♪ SHE'LL NEVER ASK YOU
PLEASE AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ THERE SHE GOES ♪♪
♪♪ NOW TAKE A LOOK
THERE'S NO TEARS
IN HER EYES ♪♪
♪♪ LIKE A BIRD
YOU KNOW SHE WILL FLY
FLY, FLY AWAY ♪♪
♪♪ FLY, FLY
FLY, FLY, FLY
FLY, FLY ♪♪
♪♪ JUST SEE HER WALKIN'
DOWN THE STREET ♪♪
♪♪ FLY, FLY, FLY, FLY ♪♪
♪
♪♪ LOOK AT ALL YOUR FRIENDS
SHE'S GONNA MEET ♪♪
♪♪ FLY, FLY, FLY, FLY, FLY ♪
♪
♪♪ SHE'S GONNA GO DOWNTOWN
GONNA GO DOWNTOWN ♪♪
♪♪ FLY, FLY, FLY, FLY, FLY ♪
♪♪ GO DOWNTOWN ♪♪
♪♪ GONNA SHOOT IT UP, BABY
SHOOT IT UP, BABY ♪♪
♪♪♪♪
THANK YOU.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A LITTLE BREAK.
EVERYBODY, BUY A PITCHER
OF BEER.  WE LIKE THE GIG.
♪♪♪♪ [ Jukebox ]
WHATEVER
HE'S DRINKIN',
I'M BUYIN'.
YOU WANT
ANOTHER ROUND ?
NO.
NICE DRESS.
IT'S GEORGIA'S.
I HEAR YOU'RE LOOKIN'
FOR A BACKUP SINGER.
AND WHERE'D
YOU HEAR THAT ?
I MADE IT UP.
COME ON, BOBBY.
I WANT TWO SOLOS.
[ Laughs ]
COME ON, BOBBY.
WE WERE GOOD TOGETHER.
LELAND'S STILL WITH YOU.
AND PAUL.
YOU WANNA SIT IN ?
YEAH.
HOW WAS SAN FRANCISCO ?
HAD A FEW GIGS.
GOT MYSELF A MANAGER.
YEAH ?
YOU HAD A GIG
WITH TRUCKER.
YEAH.  UNREAL.
WANNA WELCOME
A GOOD FRIEND,
GEORGIA'S BABY SISTER.
SADIE FLOOD !
COME ON, Y'ALL !
GIVE IT UP !
[ Scattered Applause ]
"ALMOST BLUE."
♪♪♪♪
HI.
[ Man ]
COMRADE.
♪♪ ALMOST BLUE ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST DOING THINGS WE ♪♪
♪♪ USED TO DO ♪♪
♪♪ THERE'S A BOY HER
E   AND HE'S ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST YOU ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST ♪♪
♪♪ ALL THE THINGS ♪♪
♪♪ THAT YOU PROMISED
WITH YOUR EYES ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ I SEE IN HIS TOO
♪♪ NOW YOUR EYES ARE RED ♪♪
♪♪ FROM CRYIN' ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST BLUE ♪♪
♪♪ FLIRTING WITH THIS DISASTER
BECAME ME ♪♪
♪♪ IT NAMED ME AS A FOOL ♪♪
♪
♪♪ WHO ONLY AIMED TO LEAVE ♪
♪♪ ALMOST BLUE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ ALMOST TOUCHING IT WILL ♪
♪♪ ALMOST DO ♪♪
♪
♪♪ THERE'S A PART OF ME THAT'S ♪
♪♪ ALWAYS TRUE ♪♪
♪♪ ALWAYS ♪♪
♪♪ ALL THE THINGS ♪♪
♪♪ THAT YOU PROMISED
WITH YOUR EYES ♪♪
♪♪ I SEE IN HIS TOO ♪♪
♪♪ NOW YOUR EYES ARE RED ♪♪
♪♪ FROM CRYIN' ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST YOU ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST ME ♪♪
♪♪ ALMOST ♪♪
♪♪ BLUE ♪♪♪♪
OKAY.
THANK YOU.
[ Scattered Applause ]
I FORGOT HOW MUCH
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
ONLY A COUPLE OF DAYS,
SADIE.  THAT'S IT.
SCOUT'S HONOR.
IF WE TAKE YOU ON,
THE FIRST TIME
YOU FUCK US OVER--
I'M NOT GONNA
FUCK YOU OVER.
'CAUSE THE BAND'S DOIN' OKAY.
I'M NOT GOING
TO FUCK YOU OVER, BOBBY.
YOU SHOW UP STANDING UP.
BOTH.
YOU'VE BEEN
OUTTA MY LIFE, SADIE.
I DON'T WANT YOU BACK IN,
NOT LIKE BEFORE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
IT'S OKAY.
DON'T SHIT WHERE YOU EAT.
IT'S TOP OF THE LIST.
SADIE, WITH THE MAKEUP ?
A HAIR LESS OF EVERYTHING.
YOU'RE THE BOSS.
DID YOU FUCK HIM ?
WHO ?
- TRUCKER.
- NO.
♪♪♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ SALLY IS LOSIN' HER FACE
♪♪ SHE LIVES ON
ST. MARK'S PLACE ♪♪
♪♪ IN A RENT-CONTROLLED APARTMEN
EIGHTY DOLLARS A MONTH ♪♪
♪♪ SHE HAS LOTS OF FUN
SHE HAS LOTS OF FUN ♪♪
♪♪ SALLY CAN'T DANCE NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, SALLY CAN'T DANCE
NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ SHE WENT AND CARRIED ON AND
CAN'T GET OFF OF THE FLOOR ♪♪
♪♪ NOW SALLY ♪♪
♪♪ SHE CAN'T DANCE NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ SALLY CAN'T DANCE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, MEAN SALLY, WHAT YOU MEAN
YOU CAN'T DANCE ♪♪
♪♪ SALLY CAN'T DANCE ♪♪
♪♪ HEY, SALLY
I KNOW YOU CAN DO IT ♪♪
♪♪ SALLY CAN'T DANCE ♪♪
♪♪ COME ON, SALLY
COME ON, COME ON ♪♪
♪♪ SALLY CAN'T DANCE ♪♪
♪♪ COME ON, COME ON
HEY, COME ON, COME ON ♪♪
♪♪ COME ON
COME ON, COME ON ♪♪
♪♪ SALLY CAN'T DANCE ♪♪
-♪♪ HEY, HEY, HEY, SALLY ♪♪
- ♪♪ SALLY CAN'T ♪♪
♪♪ HEY, HEY, HEY, SALLY, YEAH ♪♪
♪♪ HEY, HEY, HEY, SALLY ♪♪♪♪
SUPPOSED TO RAIN
TOMORROW.
[ All ]
NOBODY ANSWER
THE PHONE !
SEE YOU GUYS.
WHICH ONE'S MELLON ?
ME.
WHAT, NOBODY ANSWERS
THEIR PHONE ANYMORE ?
DO YOU THINK YOU'RE
GONNA PLAY IN THIS ?
HEY, WE GOT A GIG, WE SHOW UP.
YEAH, RIGHT.
-[ Cheering ]
- WE LOVE YOU, SEATTLE !
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ KEEP STRAIGHT AHEAD FOR
THE MOST GLORIOUS PLACE ♪♪
♪♪ ON THE FACE OF THE EARTH ♪♪
♪♪ OR THE SKY ♪♪
♪♪ HOLD ONTO YOUR HEART
HOLD ONTO YOUR HAT ♪♪
♪♪ HOLD ONTO YOUR DREAMS ♪♪
♪♪ THIS MAGICAL PLACE
IS MORE THAN IT SEEMS ♪♪♪♪
WE'LL BE BACK IN 15.
GREAT SONG.  YOU'RE GREAT !
OKAY, PAL, YOU TOO.
WHAT'D YOU HAVE,
SADIE ?
IT WAS BLOW.
I WOULD'VE TOOK IT.
I OFFERED, HERMAN.
WAS I THERE ?
YEAH, HERMAN.
WOW.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
WITH BLOW, HERMAN ?
WHAT'D YOU DO
WITH IT ?
I FLUSHED IT.
I WISH
YOU'D HAVE ASKED.
YOU KNOW WHERE
YOU ARE, HERMAN ?
WE'RE IN A FUCKING
BOWLING ALLEY.
YOU GOT A WAY HOME ?
YEAH.  LELAND.
DELIVERY.
YEAH !
THANKS.
UH, MR. BRUNO HAD ME STOP
AT THE LIQUOR STORE ON THE WAY.
[ Coughing ]
MR. BRUNO'S
A GREAT MAN.
HOW MUCH DO
I OWE YOU ?
UM, GROCERIES
ARE $4.53,
AND THE LIQUOR IS...
$36.60.
COME IN.
GOTTA TAKE THOSE DOWN.
WHEW.
NEVER GET A CHANCE
TO PICK UP, YOU KNOW ?
DAYS JUST... PHEW.
GET AWAY FROM ME.
THAT'S $41.13.
- ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
- WHAT ?  YEAH, I'M OKAY.
I MEAN, I'M NOT
A MANIAC OR ANYTHING.
AND THERE'S
A LITTLE SOMETHING
FOR YOU.
HEY, YOU KNOW, I DON'T--
I DON'T FEEL RIGHT ABOUT THAT.
WELL, IT'S NOT A LOT.
I'D LIKE YOU TO HAVE IT.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
YEAH ?
WELL, I TRY TO CATCH YOU.
WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU'RE OUT THERE.
NO, I DO,
WHENEVER YOU--
I THINK YOU'RE GREAT.
"ONLY BLUE" ?
"ALMOST BLUE."
YEAH.
THAT'S A GREAT SONG.
WELL, THAT'S MR. COSTELLO.
I DON'T KNOW.
EVERYTHING YOU DO--
GUESS I'M MAKIN'
A PERFECT ASS OF MYSELF.
YEAH, I GUESS SO.
WHAT WOULD YOU THINK
IF I SORT OF HUNG OUT ?
YOU KNOW, LIKE
HUNG OUT WITH YOU.
MADE MYSELF USEFUL.
I COULD DO THAT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WOULDN'T HAVE TO BE--
YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
THAT'S NOT WHY.
THEN WHY ?
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO OFFEND YOU.
I HAVE THE HIGHEST
RESPECT FOR YOU.
I HAVE BEEN BROUGHT UP
TO HAVE THE HIGHEST RESPECT
FOR WOMEN.  VERY MUCH SO.
HOW OLD ARE YOU ?
TWENTY-THREE.
- WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
- AXEL.
WELL, I'M GONNA HAVE
A DRINK, AXEL.
WOULD YOU LIKE ONE ?
DON'T DRINK.
YOU'RE A VERY NICE
PERSON, AXEL.
THANK YOU.
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ HAVA NAGILAH ♪♪
♪♪ VENISHMEHA ♪♪
♪♪ HAVA NERANNENA ♪♪
♪♪ HAVA HAVA NERANNENA ♪♪
♪♪ URU URU AHIM ♪♪
♪♪ URU AHIM
BELEV SAMEAH ♪♪
♪♪ URU AHIM BELEV SAMEAH
URU AHIM BELEV SAMEAH ♪♪
URU AHIM, URU AHIM ♪♪
♪♪ BELEV SAMEAH ♪♪♪♪
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
♪♪ YOSSEL, YOSSEL, YOSSEL ♪♪
♪♪ MAIN CHEI-ES GAIT ♪♪
♪♪ MIR ASH OUS NOCH DIR ♪♪
♪♪ OI, OI, OI, YOSSEL
YOSSEL, YOSSEL, YOSSEL ♪♪
♪♪ DEIN MAL-KE SITZT NOCH ♪♪
♪♪ ALTZ UN VART AUF DIR ♪♪
♪♪ OI, OI, OI, YOSSEL
YOSSEL, YOSSEL, YOSSEL ♪♪
♪♪ ICH CHUL-EM YED-ER
NACHT FON DIR ♪♪
♪♪ UN GIT DER YAI-TZE HOR-RE ♪♪
♪♪ NOCH A MUL A TOR-RE ♪♪
♪♪ YOSSEL
ICH KRA-NOCH DIR ♪♪♪♪
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ I'LL BE YOUR MIRROR
REFLECT WHAT YOU ARE ♪♪
♪♪ IN CASE YOU DON'T KNOW ♪♪
♪♪ I'LL BE THE WIND
THE RAIN AND THE SUNSET ♪♪
♪♪ THE LIGHT ON YOUR DOOR
TO SHOW THAT YOU ARE HOME ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN YOU THINK THE NIGHT
HAS SEEN YOUR MIND ♪♪
♪♪ THAT INSIDE YOU'RE
TWISTED AND UNKIND ♪♪
♪♪ LET ME STAND TO SHOW
THAT YOU ARE BLIND ♪♪
♪♪ PLEASE PUT DOWN YOUR HANDS ♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE I SEE YOU ♪♪
♪♪ I'LL BE YOUR MIRROR ♪♪
♪♪ REFLECT WHAT YOU ARE ♪♪
♪♪ I'LL BE YOUR MIRROR ♪
♪
♪♪ REFLECT
WHAT YOU ARE ♪♪
[ Voice Indistinct ]
♪♪ I FIND IT HARD
TO BELIEVE YOU DON'T... ♪♪
♪♪ A LIGHT IN THE DARKNESS ♪♪
♪♪ SO YOU WON'T BE AFRAID ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN YOU THINK THE NIGHT
HAS SEEN YOUR MIND ♪♪
♪♪ THAT INSIDE
YOU'RE TWISTED ♪♪
♪♪ AND UNKIND ♪♪
♪♪ LET ME STAND TO SHOW
THAT YOU ARE BLIND ♪♪
♪♪ PLEASE PUT DOWN
YOUR HANDS ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE I SEE YOU
♪♪ I'LL BE
YOUR MIRROR ♪♪
♪♪ REFLECT WHAT YOU ARE ♪♪
♪♪ I'LL BE
YOUR MIRROR ♪♪
♪♪ REFLECT WHAT YOU ARE ♪♪
SORRY, HON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, BOBBY.
[ Sadie ]
WHY'D YOU LEAVE ME, BOBBY ?
SHE'S NOT GONNA GET SICK
IN THE RABBIT, IS SHE ?
IT'S THE FUCKIN'
NYQUIL, MAN.
DON'T GET PISSED AT ME.
DON'T GET SICK
IN THE RABBIT,
OKAY, SADIE ?
SHE JUST SLID DOWN THE WALL,
YOU KNOW ?  PASSED OUT.
NOTHIN' MAJOR.
TO YOUR RIGHT.
I'M WITH HER.
[ Water Running ]
YOU KNOW I LOVE YOU, BOBBY.
'CAUSE YOU TAUGHT ME
TO LISTEN TO THE BOTTOM.
BASS AND DRUMS, MAN.
SHUT UP, SADIE.
DON'T PLAY IT.
DON'T LIE IT.
IF YOU'RE GONNA DO IT,
BE IT.  TRY IT.
DON'T YOU WISH
YOU'D SAID IT, SADIE ?
DON'T CUT ME LOOSE, BOBBY.
I'LL DISAPPEAR.
DO YOURSELF A FAVOR.
[ Axel ]  WHAT KIND OF A THING
IS THAT TO SAY ?
YOU USED TO BE ABLE
TO GET MY CLOTHES OFF.
SHUT UP, SADIE.
SHIT.
YOU KNOW WHAT, SADIE ?
GOT THE FLU, BOBBY.
IT'S TRUE, MAN.
SHE'S BURNIN' UP.
I TOLD HER, YOU KNOW,
SHE SHOULDN'T MESS AROUND, BUT
SHE HAD THE GIG AND EVERYTHING.
SO I THINK IT'S OKAY
TO DELIVER GROCERIES.
YOU KNOW.  I'VE DONE
A LOT OF THINGS.
I'VE DONE A LOT WORSE.
BUT I HAVE
MY WHOLE LIFE
AHEAD OF ME.
MY LOVE IS CARS.
I FIX VINTAGE CARS.
I THINK THERE'S
WHERE MY FUTURE IS.
VERY MUCH SO.
YOU TAKE ME
SERIOUSLY ?
YEAH.
I DO, AXEL.
I'M YOUNG, BUT
I KNOW WHAT LOVE IS.
I MISS LOVE.
I MISS IT.
I HAD A REALLY GREAT LADY.
SHE GAVE UP
EVERYTHING FOR ME.
SHE FOLLOWED ME
TO CHICAGO.
WE LIVED THERE
TOGETHER TWO YEARS.
TWENTY-FOUR HOURS A DAY.
THEN ONE DAY,
SHE SAID, "THAT'S IT.
WE AREN'T ANYMORE."
SHE WENT BACK TO MINNESOTA.
I NEVER HEARD FROM HER AGAIN.
I'M SORRY, AXEL.
SEE, I KNOW IF
IT'S REALLY LOVE THAT...
YOU TRY TO WORK IT OUT
IF IT'S GOIN' WRONG.
SO MAYBE IT WASN'T LOVE.
I HAD THESE GOALS ABOUT
GETTIN' TO KNOW MYSELF BETTER
SO I'M NOT SO DEPENDENT ON LOVE.
THERE'S A LOT
OF UNKINDNESS
IN THE WORLD.
YOU KNOW YOUR--
YOUR LIFE, YOUR DAY ?
THEY COULD BE THE MOST IMPORTANT
PART.  ONE DAY COULD BE THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING IN YOUR LIFE.
YOU'D NEVER KNOW IT.
I THINK, YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE GOOD FOR ME.
I WALK INTO A CLUB, AND
THERE'S THIS BEAUTIFUL GIRL
SMILIN' AT ME.
SINGIN' TO ME.
AND THESE SHININ'
EYES... AT ME.
SHE MAKES ME REAL.
SHE GIVES ME
REALITY, SO...
I'M IN LOVE.
♪♪ I'LL TELL
THE ARIZONA MOON ♪♪
THE ARIZONA ♪♪
♪♪ MOON ♪♪♪♪
WHOO !
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU MADE IT.
I HAD TO SEE YOU.
THIS IS AXEL.
HEY, AXEL.
HI.  THAT WAS GREAT.
YEAH, THE BAND
WAS HOT TONIGHT.
I WANT YOU
TO GIVE MY BEST TO BOBBY.
YOU GUYS ARE WORKIN'.
DOIN' GOOD, YEAH.
HEY, YOU KNOW WHO CAME BY
THE BACKSTAGE ?  GEORGIA.
REALLY ?  WHEN ?
IT WAS WEDNESDAY.
WE WERE WORKIN'
WEDNESDAY AND THURSDAY.
YEAH, IT WAS
WEDNESDAY.
DID I JUST SCREW AROUND
WITH A CAN OF WORMS HERE ?
NO.
'CAUSE IF IT'S OPEN,
YOU KNOW, I'LL STEP IN IT.
YOU KNOW WE OPENED
FOR GEORGIA.
I HEARD.
YEAH.  IN AUSTIN
AND EUGENE...
AND WINNIPEG.
SO SHE CAME BY,
AND THEY WERE JUST
COMIN' OFF THE CEILING.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T THINK
SHE'D FEEL TOO GOOD
STEPPIN' IN YOUR LIGHT.
FUCK YOU VERY MUCH, JO.
[ Door Opening ]
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE IN HERE.
NO, COME IN, MISH.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I WAS JUST--
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I WAS JUST.
EVERYBODY'S
LOOKING FOR YOU.
THANK YOU
FOR FINDING ME.
YOU ARE SO
LIKE YOUR MOTHER.
TWO PEAS IN A POD.
AND YOUR GRANDFATHER.
THREE PEAS IN A POD.
I'M LIKE MY DAD,
I THINK.
THE TABLE LOOKS
GREAT, MISH.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S SO GOOD
ABOUT US, GEORGIA ?
WE'RE SO CLOSE.
GROWING UP, I CAN'T REMEMBER
NOT DOING EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
ARE YOU OKAY ?
I'M FINE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH AXEL, SADIE ?
HOW DO YOU AND DAD FIND
SO MUCH TO TALK ABOUT ?
WE DON'T.
WE DON'T TALK MUCH.
I'M GOING TO MARRY HIM.
HIS GRANDMOTHER'S RING.
AND THERE'S
ONLY ONE JAKE.
HOW OLD IS HE, SADIE ?
HE LOVES ME.
I'M GONNA STAY
OUT OF THIS.
SO WHAT IS IT THAT
HAPPENS BETWEEN YOU
WHEN YOU DON'T TALK ?
LEAVE DAD ALONE.
I DO.
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
WILL YOU COME
TO THE WEDDING ?
SURE.  OKAY.
I'M GOING TO DO IT.
FINE.
YOU KNOW I WATCH YOU,
AND I LISTEN TO YOU.
THIS GIFT FROM GOD.
AND I SWELL UP WITH
ADMIRATION AND PRIDE...
AND LOVE.
AND I SWEAR
ON MISH AND ANDREW...
THERE'S NO ENVY.
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T.
AND HERE I AM, NOT
THREE FEET AWAY FROM YOU,
AND I TALK TO YOU...
AND I SWEAR, GEORGIA,
IT FEELS LIKE NO ONE'S HOME.
YOU DISAPPEAR ON ME.
YOU KNOW WHAT I TRULY
WANT FOR YOU, SADIE ?
I WANT YOU TO BE HAPPY.
YOU WANNA BE
TROUBLE-FREE, GEORGIA.
OKAY.  ALL RIGHT.
HOW YOU COMIN' WITH
THE TABLE, MISH ?
FINISHED.
WHY DON'T YOU SEE IF
ANYONE NEEDS ANYTHING ?
THINGS ARE GOIN'
GOOD FOR ME.
I'M GLAD.
YOU KNOW
HIS LAST NAME ?
AXEL ?
YEAH.
OF COURSE.
YEAH ?
YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
YOU WRITING ?
EVERY DAY.
WORKIN' ON
AN ALBUM ?
YES.
I SHOULD DO SOME BACKUP.
IF YOU WANT.
GOOD IDEA.
YOU HAVEN'T COME
TO HEAR ME.
WHY IS THAT ?
I WILL IF YOU WANT.
IT'D BE GREAT
IF YOU DID.
WELL, I WILL THEN.
OKAY, GREAT.
I'M INTERESTING,
YOU KNOW ?
YOU WERE THE ONE
WITH AMBITION, SADIE.
I NEVER GAVE A DAMN.
YOU SAY.
YOU KNOW IT'S THE TRUTH.
FUNNY HOW THINGS WORK OUT.
NOT WHAT I MEANT.
YOU KNOW, I LET YOU TALK TO ME
THIS WAY, AND I MANAGE TO MAKE
MYSELF THINK IT'S OKAY.
AND I'M ALWAYS GLAD
YOU'VE BEEN HERE.
AND I CAN'T STAND IT
WHEN YOU'RE HURTING.
AND I'VE MADE PEACE WITH--
THAT NOTHING'S
ENOUGH FOR YOU.
I DON'T WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOU DO
LOCKED AWAY IN THAT BATHROOM
FOR HALF AN HOUR.
I DON'T WANT
MY KIDS TO KNOW.
I WOULDN'T DO THAT
IN YOUR HOUSE, GEORGIA.
OKAY.
THIS IS A WONDERFUL HOME.
IT'S VERY WARM.
YOU MUST BE
VERY HAPPY HERE.
SADIE AND GEORGIA
GREW UP IN THIS HOUSE.
GEORGIA BOUGHT IT
WHEN IT CAME ON
THE MARKET.
HOW YOU DOIN', DAD ?
I'M DOIN' ALL RIGHT.
IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
YOU OUGHTA
GET OUT MORE, DAD.
WELL, I GET OUT ALMOST MORE
THAN I LIKE ANYMORE.
HOW YOU DOIN', SADIE ?
I COULDN'T BE BETTER.
THIS IS
YOUR YOUNG MAN ?
YES.
GOOD FOR YOU.
AXEL DELIVERS GROCERIES.
I SPECIALIZE
IN VINTAGE CARS.
SO YOU'VE GIVEN US
TO UNDERSTAND.
IS THAT YOUR, UH,
VEHICLE OUT THERE ?
THAT'S MY TREASURE.
VERY MUCH SO.
WELL, I WISH YOU BOTH
EVERY HAPPINESS, AXEL.
YOU'RE A PEACH, DAD.
I MEANT TO DO THAT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GET MARRIED, AXEL ?
YEAH.  SEE, I THOUGHT
THAT'S WHAT WE WERE DOIN'.
I'VE BEEN WITH
A LOT OF MEN, AXEL.
IS THERE ANYONE
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE
APPROVED BY ?
- "APPROVED BY" ?
- TO MEET.  FAMILY.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I MEAN, IT'S NOT LIKE YOU
HAVE TO MEET 'EM RIGHT AWAY.
AXEL GOLDMAN, RIGHT ?
YEAH.
SEE.  I KNOW IT.
[ Horns Honking,
Whistle Blowing ]
HELLO.  MY NAME
IS SADIE FLOOD.
[ Scattered Applause ]
THAT'S ALL,
MY FAN.
I GOT MARRIED TODAY.
[ Applause ]
THANK YOU.
MY HUSBAND, AXEL.
THANK YOU, AXEL.
SO EVERYBODY BUY
ANOTHER PITCHER OF BEER
BECAUSE WE NEED THE GIG.
MY SISTER'S HERE
TONIGHT, EVERYBODY.
[ Enthusiastic Applause ]
AND WE'RE GONNA DO
ONE OF HER SONGS !
[ Cheering, Applause ]
YOU WANNA COME UP AND
DO IT WITH US, GEORGIA ?
[ Applause, Cheering ]
[ Man ]  GEORGIA !
[ Woman ]
GEORGIA !
MY SISTER !
THE SINGLE PERSON I'LL MISS
WHEN I LEAVE THIS EARTH.
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ WHAT AM I SUPPOSED
TO DO WITH ♪♪
♪♪ HAPPY TIMES I HAVE
IN MY HAND ♪♪
♪♪ SEND THEM OFF
TO PURGATORY ♪♪
♪♪ THOROUGHLY CONFUSED ♪♪
DO THIS.
♪♪ MAYBE THEY COULD MEET ♪♪
♪♪ SOME OLD ACQUAINTANCE
S   OF THEIRS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ AND WE COULD HAVE
A DRINK TOGETHER ♪
♪♪ REMINISCING
MISSING YOU ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED ♪♪
♪♪ I COULD SCRAP YOU ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED
TO GET BACK AT YOU ♪♪
♪♪ TO GET BACK AT YOU ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MAKES ME MORE MAD ♪♪
♪♪ THAN LOSIN' YOU ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED ♪♪
♪♪ I COULD
FEEL GOOD ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED
LIKE I SHOULD ♪♪
♪♪ LIKE I SHOULD ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T KNOW
WHAT MAKES ME MORE MAD ♪♪
♪
♪♪ THAN LOSIN' YOU ♪
♪♪ WHAT AM I SUPPOSE
D   TO FEEL WHEN ♪♪
♪
♪♪ EVERY TIME
I HEAR YOUR NAME ♪
♪♪
♪♪ I FALL FOUR STEPS BEHIND
♪♪ WHEN I HAVE ONLY
CLIMBED UP TWO ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T WANNA
GIVE AWAY MY FEARS ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T WANT ANYONE
TO TASTE MY TEARS ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T WANT HELP ♪♪
♪♪ FROM ANYONE BUT YOU ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED ♪♪
♪♪ I COULD KILL YOU
♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED
I WOULD DIE TOO ♪♪
♪♪ I WOULD DIE TOO ♪
♪♪ I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MAKES ME MORE MAD ♪♪
♪♪ THAN LOSIN' YOU ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED
I COULD NEVER ♪♪
♪♪ FIND ANOTHER FRIEND
FOREVER ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MAKES ME MORE MAD ♪♪
♪♪ THAN LOSIN' YOU ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED ♪♪
♪♪ IF I WANTED ♪♪♪♪
[ Applause ]
[ Cheering, Whistling ]
SO DO YOU
WRITE, TOO, SADIE ?
YOU DO YOUR OWN SONGS ?
I DON'T WRITE SONGS.
THAT WHOLE CONCEPT'S
FOREIGN TO ME.
I MAKE 'EM UP.
I PUT DOWN THE WORDS SOMETIMES
TO REMEMBER 'EM, BUT...
YOU KNOW.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO GO.
AND DON'T GET UP.
[ Jake ]
CONGRATULATIONS.
SEE YA.
[ Jake ]  THAT WAS
A NICE THING YOU DID.
DIDN'T KNOW I HAD A CHOICE.
I THOUGHT IT WAS
PRETTY TERRIFIC.
AND THERE'S
A REPORTER THERE.
I MEAN, WHAT'S THAT
ALL ABOUT ?
WHAT'S RUNNIN'
THROUGH HER HEAD ?
IT WAS A GOOD THING
YOU DID, GEORGIA.
I FEEL BAD FOR AXEL.
"I DON'T WRITE.
I MAKE THEM UP."
SHE DIDN'T EVEN SAY IT.
IT'S NOT EVEN HERS.  I MEAN,
IT BELONGS TO SOMEONE ELSE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU ?
NOTHING.
I'M TIRED, THAT'S ALL.
SHE SWALLOWS PEOPLE UP.
- HOW DO YOU NOT SEE IT ?
- I THINK SHE'S AN ORIGINAL...
AND BRAVE
AND WITHOUT MALICE.
FINE.
SHE SHOULDN'T SING.
WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU ?
YET ANOTHER
CASUALTY.
ANOTHER CASUALTY !
PAYS THE RENT.
[ Doorbell Ringing ]
ARE YOU FUCKED UP ?
HELL, NO.
HI.
HI.  HELLO.
YOU WANNA BRING YOUR GEAR
AROUND BACK, SOMEONE'LL
MEET YOU BACK THERE.
HELLO.
MY NAME IS SADIE.
HI.
OKAY.  THANKS.
DON'T FUCK AROUND.
WE GOTTA CUT YOU LOOSE.
YEAH, UH, THAT'S
WHAT YOU SAID.
THAT'S WHAT YOU SAID.
YOU'RE FUCKED UP
ALL THE TIME, HERMAN.
I HAD THURSDAY DOWN
FOR THE GIG, AND I DON'T KNOW
HOW I GOT THURSDAY--
IT'S NOT THURSDAY
ANYMORE, HERMAN.
THURSDAY CAME AND WENT.
THIS STUFF IS
MAKING YOU STUPID.
YEAH.  YOU THINK SO ?
SO YOU ALL DECIDED
THIS TOGETHER ?
YEAH.
NOT ME.
LELAND AND PAUL AND CLAY,
WE'RE TRYIN' TO BE
IN A BUSINESS HERE.
WE'RE NOT 23 ANYMORE.
WE AT LEAST GOTTA SHOW UP.
I MEAN, OUR DRUMMER'S
GOTTA SHOW UP, HERMAN.
I DON'T HAVE A CLUE
HOW I MISSED IT, BOBBY.
IT'S NOT THE FIRST TIME, H.
IT'S NOT
THE TENTH TIME.
SO... OKAY.
YEAH.
DON'T BE A STRANGER, OKAY ?
I LOVE YOU GUYS.
ALL RIGHT, SEE YOU
AROUND, THEN.
TAKE IT EASY, HERMAN.
WELL, THAT SUCKED
PRETTY GOOD.
YOU GUYS WOULD TELL ME
IF YOU WERE LOOKIN' FOR
A NEW BACKUP SINGER.
- COME ON, SADIE.
-YOU WOULDN'T, YOU FUCKERS.
YOU WOULDN'T,
WOULD YOU ?
COME ON, SADIE.
GIVE IT UP.
WHAT'S YOUR FUCKING PROBLEM ?
WHY DO WE HAVE TO
TURN THIS INTO
YOUR LOSS, HUH ?
GODDAMN IT, DON'T ANSWER ME.
DON'T SAY ANYTHING.
I WANNA RUN THROUGH THE SET.
IT'S NICE.
IT'S NEAT.
IT'S--  YOU KNOW, IT'S
WHAT BOBBY HAD TO DO,
YOU KNOW.  I UNDERSTAND.
I'D HAVE DONE
THE SAME THING.
DONE THE SAME THING,
YEAH.
THIS STUFF'LL KILL YA
A LOT QUICKER THAN SMACK.
YOU CAN GO A LOT OF YEARS
DOIN' SMACK, BARRING ACCIDENT.
CHETY WAS 58.
ART WAS
60 OR SOMETHIN'.
LADY DAY MADE IT
TO HER FORTIES.
IT'S NOT GONNA BE
A LOVE AFFAIR WITH ME...
'CAUSE I KNOW IT'S
A REAL HARD KICK.
ALCOHOL'S
BAD SHIT, MAN.
IT'S A REAL BRING-DOWN.
THOSE GUYS DID
EVERYTHING, THOUGH.
DID YOU EVER TRY
MORNING GLORY SEEDS ?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO, H ?
DIDN'T YOU THINK BOBBY
WAS GONNA GO THE DISTANCE ?
I THOUGHT HE WAS GONNA GO
THE WHOLE NINE YARDS.
YOU KNOW, BOBBY'S A POET.
HE'S AN ARTIST.
WHEN YOU SEE DESPERATION
IN THE EYES, IT'S A BAD SIGN.
IT GETS TO
ABOUT PAYIN' THE RENT.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO, H ?
I CAN ALWAYS GET A GIG.
DON'T YOU THINK SO ?
I-I BEEN LOOKIN'
TO GET OUT OF SEATTLE.
BUT I'M AFRAID TO LEAVE
MY CONNECTION, YOU KNOW ?
EVERY TIME I GO OUT OF TOWN,
IT'S A DISASTER.
IN CHICAGO, I WENT DOWNTOWN
TO SEE WHERE TO SCORE,
AND I SEE THESE THREE
BIG, HUGE BLACK GUYS...
WITH GUNS IN THEIR PANTS.
AND I KNEW ALL
THAT WAS GONNA HAPPEN WAS
I WAS GONNA GET ROBBED.
I MOVED TO NEW ORLEANS.
TRIED TO DO IT THERE.
GOT ROBBED.
I KNEW I WAS GONNA GET ROBBED,
AND I GOT ROBBED.
THEN I--
YOU KNOW, I USED A DETOX
TO GET OFF THE STREET.
MY SISTER'S ALWAYS GOOD
FOR A FEW BUCKS.
MMM, SHE'S NOT GONNA
PUT ME UP FOREVER.
I-I DON'T WANNA BE
ON THE STREET, MAN.
IT'S NOT MY BAG.
I TH-- I THOUGHT,
YOU KNOW,
I COULD TEACH.
YEAH ?
SO YOU AND AXEL
DOIN' OKAY ?
YOU MAKIN' OUT ?
HE HAS A CAR TO WORK ON
EVERY SO OFTEN.
HE'S IN PARADISE.
AND HIS MOM SENDS HIM
A LITTLE SOMETHIN', REGULAR.
HE'S A NEAT GUY, AXEL.
YEAH.
AXEL'S A PRINCE.
AXEL'S A SAINT.
[ Sadie Singing Quietly ]
♪♪ LOTS OF TIME JUST
TO DREAM THERE ♪♪
♪♪ GOLDEN SUN IN THE VALLEY ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME TO ARUANDA ♪♪
♪♪ EASY LIFE WAITING
YOUR WELCOME ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME THERE ♪♪
♪♪ LEAVE MY SADNESS
BEHIND ME ♪♪
♪♪ LET SWEET PARADISE FIND ME ♪♪
♪♪ HEAVEN WAITS
OVER YONDER ♪♪♪♪
EVERYBODY NOW.
AXEL.  I TOLD THEM
TO BRING YOU IN THE STUDIO.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I DON'T LIKE TO DISTURB.
IT'S NOT MY NATURE.
HOW YOU DOIN', JAKE ?
ALL RIGHT.
HEY, YOU.
HELLO, AXEL.
HEY, YOU, AXEL.
WHAT'S UP, AXEL ?
EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
OH.
GEORGIA, YOU THINK
I COULD HAVE A MINUTE ?
COULD I HAVE A FEW MINUTES
WITH GEORGIA, JAKE ?
NO OFFENSE.
NO OFFENSE, AXEL.
I MEAN, IF YOU'RE TAKIN'
A BREAK, YOU KNOW.
I KNOW.
SURE.
YOU WANNA TAKE A WALK ?
SO YOU THINK
SPRING'LL GET HERE ?
I THINK YOU CAN
COUNT ON IT.
I THINK IT'S BEEN DELAYED.
MECHANICAL DIFFICULTIES.
SO YOU GUYS DON'T CALL A LOT.
YOU COME INTO TOWN.  YOU KNOW,
LIKE, YOU DON'T ALWAYS CALL.
WELL, THERE'S NOT
ALWAYS TIME, YOU KNOW.
YOU'RE NOT ALWAYS HOME, AND
WE HAVE TO GET BACK, AND--
WELL, I UNDERSTAND.
VERY MUCH SO.
SHE SORT OF KNOWS
WHEN YOU'RE IN TOWN,
THAT'S ALL.  IT COMES UP.
SHE DOESN'T CALL ME
EITHER, AXEL.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU CAME OUT TO THE HOUSE ?
SHE'S NOT WITH BOBBY ANYMORE.
IT WAS LIKE A SELF-FULFILLING
PROPHECY.
YOU KNOW, THEY HAD
THIS HISTORY AND EVERYTHING.
IT KEPT GETTIN' IN THE WAY.
SADIE GETS
IN THE WAY, AXEL.
SO, SHE'S BEEN SITTIN' IN
AROUND TOWN, AND SHE JAMS
WHEN SHE CAN.
YOU COULD HELP HER.
LIKE HOW, AXEL ?
YOU COULD DO
SOMETHIN' FOR HER.
LIKE WHAT, AXEL ?
HONESTLY.
IT'S JUST BREAKIN' MY HEART,
THAT'S ALL.  SHE'S FULL OF HOPE.
SHE'S FULL OF HOPE.
YOU KNOW WHAT SHE'S LIKE.
SOMETIMES IT GETS
TOO HARSH, YOU KNOW ?
YOU KNOW, NO OFFENSE.
YOU'RE HER SISTER.
YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU
OFFER HER MONEY,
SHE TAKES THE MONEY--
AND GOD KNOWS,
WE COULD USE IT--
BUT SHE TAKES IT REALLY
NOT TO OFFEND YOU.
I THINK
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
MAYBE YOU DO KNOW THAT.
MAYBE I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
I HATE THIS, DON'T YOU ?
IT'S FREEZING.
WANNA GET SOME COFFEE
OR SOMETHING ?
[ Crowd Screaming ]
STEVEN SOLES.
THE BAND IS STRINGFELLOW.
[ Cheering Continues ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
ALL RIGHT, GEORGIA !
[ Man ]
GEORGIA !
YOU WANNA
SHOOT SOME POOL ?
YOU GOT HOURS,
WHOLE HOURS.
I GOTCHA.
IT'S GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT.
[ Georgia ]
ONE, TWO, THREE.
♪♪♪♪
♪♪ I GOT A FIELD ♪♪
♪♪ OF UNRIGHTEOUSNESS ♪♪
♪♪ SOW A SEED ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OF SCORN AND BITTERNESS ♪
NICE SHOT.
YOUR LADY'S GOT
A TOUCH, AXEL.
YEAH.
OH, MY GOD !
I THINK WE SHOULD
START BACK.
IT'S GONNA BE GREAT.
IT'S GONNA BE
SENSATIONAL.
WHO DID THIS ?
DID YOU DO THIS ?
GEORGIA DID THIS.
WHY DON'T YOU
NOT HAVE THAT ?
THIS IS TO YOU.
FOR ALWAYS BEING JAKE.
THE ONLY THING I EVER
ENVIED MY SISTER.
THIS IS TO YOU
AND TONIGHT.
YEAH.
GEORGIA'S PREGNANT.
OH ?
GOD !
WELL, THAT'S
SO GREAT !
IT'S PRETTY GREAT.
IT'S A KNOCKOUT.
[ Crowd Whistling,
Cheering ]
IT'S A VERY SPECIAL PRIVILEGE
FOR ME TO BRING SADIE FLOOD
OUT HERE TONIGHT.
SEATTLE'S HOME.
[ Cheering ]
WE'RE GONNA KICK THE SHIT
OUT OF THIS THING !
PUT IT TO BED, BABY.
IT'S INCREDIBLE
FOR ME TO BE HERE,
ON THIS STAGE
WITH MY SISTER.
THE SINGLE PERSON I'LL MISS
WHEN I LEAVE THIS EARTH.
YEAH.
HOW SWEET THIS IS.
♪♪♪♪
THE ONLY THING
THAT HAS ANY MEANING
IS WHAT'S REAL, RIGHT ?
WHAT WE GET ?
WHAT WE GIVE EACH OTHER ?
IN THE DARK,
WE'RE ALL SCARED.
AND THERE'S MORE OF US
OUT THERE ALL THE TIME, MAN.
AND THE SONG IS FROM
VAN MORRISON.
♪♪ I'VE BEEN WALKIN'
BY THE RIVER ♪♪
♪♪ I'VE BEEN WALKIN' DOW
N   BY THE WATER ♪♪
♪♪ I BEEN WALKIN' DOWN
BY THE RIVER ♪♪
♪♪ MM-MM-MM ♪♪
♪♪ I BEEN FEELIN'
SO SAD AND BLUE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ I BEEN THINKIN'
I BEEN THINKIN' ♪
I BEEN THINKIN'
I BEEN THINKIN' ♪♪
♪♪ I'VE BEEN THINKIN' ♪♪
♪♪ OH, THERE'S
SO MUCH SUFFERIN' ♪♪
♪♪ AND IT'S
TOO MUCH CONFUSION ♪♪
♪♪ TOO MUCH, TOO MUCH
CONFUSION IN THE WORLD ♪♪
♪
♪♪ TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK ♪
♪
♪♪ TAKE ME WAY BACK
TAKE ME WAY BACK
TAKE ME WAY BACK ♪
♪♪ TAKE ME WAY BACK
TAKE ME WAY BACK
TAKE ME WAY BACK ♪
♪
♪♪ TAKE ME WAY BACK
TAKE ME WAY BACK, OH ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME WAY, WAY, WAY
WAY, WAY, WAY, WAY BACK ♪♪
♪♪ HELP ME UN-- ♪♪
♪♪ HELP ME UNDERSTAND ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME
DO YOU REMEMBER
THE TIME, DARLIN' ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN EVERYTHING MADE
MORE SENSE IN THE WORLD ♪♪
♪♪ YEAH, OH, I REMEMBER ♪♪
♪
♪♪ I REMEMBER WHEN
LIFE MADE MORE SENSE ♪
♪♪ OH, I
TAKE ME BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME BACK, TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK, TAKE ME BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME BACK, TAKE ME BAC
K   TAKE ME BACK, TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK ♪♪
♪♪ WHOA, WHOA TO WHEN ♪♪
♪♪ THE WORLD MADE ♪♪
♪♪ MORE SENSE ♪♪
♪♪ WELL, THERE'S
TOO MUCH SUFFERIN'
AND CONFUSION ♪♪
♪♪ AND I'M WALKIN' DOWN
BY THE RIVER ♪♪
♪♪ OH, LET ME UNDERSTAND
RELIGION ♪♪
♪♪ ALL THE WAY BACK ♪♪
♪♪ WAY BACK ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN YOU WALKED
IN A GREEN FIELD ♪♪
♪♪ IN A GREEN MEADOW ♪♪
♪♪ DOWN AN AVENUE OF TREES ♪♪
♪♪ OH, ON A ♪♪
♪♪ ON A GOLDEN SUMMER ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE SKY WAS BLUE ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU DIDN'T HAVE
NO WORRIES ♪♪
♪♪ YOU DIDN'T HAVE NO CARE ♪♪
♪♪ YOU WERE WALKIN'
IN A GREEN FIELD ♪♪
♪♪ IN A MEADOW
THROUGH THE BUTTERCUPS ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE SUMMERTIME ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU LOOKED WAY OUT OVER
WAY OUT, WAY OUT OVER
THE CITY AND THE WATER ♪♪
♪♪ AND IT FELT SO GOOD
AND IT FELT SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪ AND YA KEEP ON WALKIN' ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE MUSIC ON THE RADIO
AND THE MUSIC ON THE RADIO ♪♪
♪♪ HAS SO MUCH SOUL ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU LISTEN
IN THE NIGHTTIME ♪♪
♪
♪♪ WHILE WE'RE STILL AND QUIET ♪
♪♪ AND YOU LOOK OUT ON THE WATER
ON THE BIG SHIPS ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE BIG BOATS
CAME ON SAILIN' BY ♪♪
♪♪ BYE-BYE, BYE-BYE ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU FELT SO GOOD NOW ♪♪
♪♪ AND I FELT SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪ I FELT I WANNA HEAR CLAY
BLOW HIS HARMONICA ♪♪
♪♪♪♪ [ Harmonica ]
♪♪ TAKE ME BACK THERE
TAKE ME WAY BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME WAY, WAY, WAY
BACK, BACK TO WHEN ♪♪
♪♪ TO WHEN I UNDERSTOOD ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN I UNDERSTOOD
THE LIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN I UNDERSTOOD THE LIGHT
IN THE GOLDEN AFTERNOON ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE GOLDEN AFTERNOON
IN THE GOLDEN AFTERNOON
IN THE GOLDEN AFTERNOON ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE GOLDEN AFTERNOON
WELL, WE SAT AND LISTENED
TO SONNY BOY BLOW ♪♪
♪♪♪♪ [ Harmonica ]
♪
♪♪ IN THE GOLDEN AFTERNOON ♪
♪♪ WELL, WE SAT AND LET
SONNY BOY BLOW ♪♪
♪♪ BLOW HIS HARP ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK
TAKE ME BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE ME WAY, WAY, WAY, WAY
WAY, WAY, WAY, WAY, WAY, WAY
WAY, WAY, WAY, WAY BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TO WHEN I UNDERSTOOD ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN I UNDERSTOOD ♪♪
♪♪ YEAH ♪♪
♪♪ OH, AH, TAKE ME BACK ♪♪
♪♪ TO WHEN, WHEN, WHEN, WHEN
WHEN, WHEN, WHEN, WHEN
WHEN, WHEN, WHEN, WHEN ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN I WAS WALKIN' ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ WALKIN' DOWN THE STREETS
♪♪ AND IT DIDN'T MATTER ♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT ♪♪
♪♪ EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT ♪♪
♪♪ EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT ♪♪
♪♪ EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT
EVERYTHING FELT SO RIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ AND SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪♪♪ [ Humming ]
♪♪ EVERYTHING FELT
SO RIGHT AND SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪ EVERYTHING FELT ♪♪
♪♪ SO RIGHT AND SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪♪♪ [ Humming ]
♪♪ EVERYTHING FELT ♪♪
♪♪ SO RIGHT AND SO GOOD
SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE ETERNAL NOW ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE ETERNAL MOMENT ♪♪
♪♪ OH ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE ETERNAL NOW
EVERYTHING FELT ♪♪
♪♪ SO GOOD
SO GOOD ♪♪
♪♪ SO GOOD, SO GOOD
SO GOOD AND SO RIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ AND SO RIGHT
JUST SO GOOD
AND SO RIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE ETERNAL
IN THE ETERNAL MOMENT ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE ETERNAL MOMENT
♪♪ IN THE ETERNAL
MOMENT ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN YOU LIVED
WHEN YOU LIVED ♪♪
IN THE LIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN YOU LIVED ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE GRACE ♪♪
♪♪ IN GRACE
WHEN YOU LIVED ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE LIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE GRACE ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE BLESSING ♪♪♪♪
[ Light Applause ]
[ Applause ]
THANK YOU !
GOD BLESS.
YOU WERE REAL GOOD.
KEEP DRINKIN'.
ROUND THE EDGES.
I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, GEORGIA.
[ Applause, Cheering ]
WANT ME TO DRIVE ?
NO, I DON'T WANT
YOU TO DRIVE.
I TAKE IT THAT
YOU'RE ANGRY WITH ME.
YOU TOOK HER TO A BAR,
GOT HER JUICED UP,
GOT YOU JUICED UP.
WHY WOULD THAT
BOTHER ME ?
SHE WAS WOUND UP TIGHT.
SHE WAS GONNA COME
BOPPIN' OFF THE WALLS.
WELL, YOU FIXED THAT.
DID YOU SERIOUSLY THINK
THAT SHE HAD NO OTHER ACCESS
TO A BOTTLE...
OR WHATEVER ELSE SHE WANTED
BEFORE SHE GOT THERE ?
I DON'T NEED
TO BE RIGHT, GEORGIA.
I DON'T THINK
I COULD EVER GRASP--
I MEAN, NOT A CLUE--
WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE YOUR SISTER.
EVER SO SORRY ABOUT THAT.
VERY MUCH SO.
THANK YOU, JAKE.
I WHIPPED YOUR ASS
AT POOL.
YUP.
I WHIPPED
HIS ASS.
WHERE ARE WE GOING ?
TO THE HOUSE.
AH.  RIGHT.
FAMILY WEEKEND.
SO, WAS I GREAT
OR WAS I GREAT ?
I WISH I'D BEEN THERE.
[ Snickering ]
YOU WERE THERE.
OR WAS I JUST OKAY ?
YOU COULD HEAR
A PIN DROP.
YOU WERE GREAT.
I THOUGHT THAT
YOU WERE SOMETHIN'.
HA !
WHAT DID SISSY THINK ?
[ Panting ]
OOH.  STERN SILENCE.
GEORGIA WAS
EMBARRASSED OF ME.
FOR ME.
WHICH ?
GEORGIA NEEDED
TO HELP ME OUT UP THERE.
DIDN'T YOU, GEORGIA ?
SEE, I THOUGHT
I WAS DOIN' FINE,
BUT MY SISTER...
COULDN'T
LEAVE IT ALONE.
FOR FEAR OF WHAT ?
FOR FEAR OF
FUCKING WHAT, GEORGIA ?
DID I NEED SAVING,
GEORGIA ?
HOW GOOD DID IT FEEL
TO BE ABLE TO PULL ME OUT ?
IT FELT LIKE
A THOUSAND POUNDS
OF DEAD WEIGHT, SADIE.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU WANNA HEAR ?
I DON'T WANT THIS
ANYMORE, SADIE.
I WANT YOU
TO LET GO OF ME.
LET GO OF ME !
PLEASE !
PLEASE, SADIE !
DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO DO,
BUT I DON'T WANT TO BE
A PART OF IT ANYMORE.
I CAN'T DO IT.
- I DON'T WANNA DO IT.
- GEORGIA.
RIGHT.
SADIE !
SADE.
GOOD, SADIE.
- YOU WANNA GET OUT ?
DO YOU WANNA GET OUT, SADIE ?
-[ Jake ]  GEORGIA.
GEORGIA !
WHAT DO YOU
WANNA DO ?
THIS IS ENTIRELY
UP TO YOU, SADIE.
THIS RIG'S NOT BIG ENOUGH
FOR THE BOTH OF US.
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO SPEND THE NIGHT,
YOU AND AXEL.
WHAT DO YOU
WANNA DO, SADIE ?
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF NOWHERE.
HOW LONG WERE YOU
PREPARED TO SIT HERE ?
♪♪ BUT HE SURE FOUND OUT
THE HARD WAY ♪♪
♪♪ THAT DREAMS DON'T
ALWAYS COME TRUE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, NO
UH-UH ♪♪
♪♪ SO HE PAWNED
ALL HIS HOPES ♪♪
♪♪ WHOO-HOO, HOO-HOO ♪♪
♪♪ AND EVEN SOLD
HIS OLD CAR ♪♪
♪♪ WHOO-HOO, HOO-HOO ♪♪
♪♪ BOUGHT A ONE-WAY
TICKET BACK ♪♪
♪
♪♪ TO THE LIFE
HE ONCE KNEW ♪
♪
♪♪ OH, YES, HE DID
HE SAID HE WOULD ♪
♪♪ OH, HE'S LEAVIN'
♪♪
♪♪ LEAVIN' ♪♪
♪♪ ON THAT MIDNIGHT TRAIN
TO GEORGIA ♪♪
♪♪ ON THE MIDNIGHT TRAIN ♪♪
♪♪ I'D RATHER LIVE
IN HIS WORLD ♪♪
♪♪ THAN BE WITHOUT HIM
IN MINE ♪♪
♪♪ COME ON
TAKE A LOAD ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE A LOAD ♪♪
♪♪ THE MIDNIGHT TRAI
N   TO RIDE ♪♪♪♪
THANKS, GUYS.
NIGHT.
NIGHT, SADIE.
GOOD NIGHT.
WELL.
CAN I FIX YOU
SOMETHIN' ?
NO, SWEETIE.
IT'S NO TROUBLE.
NO, BABY.
- YOU SCARED OF ME, AXEL ?
- NO.
GOTTA GO HOME
FOR A WHILE.
CHICAGO ?
YEAH.
FOR A WHILE.
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
MAYBE YOU COULD
COME LATER, YOU KNOW ?
YOU TAKIN' A HIKE, AXEL ?
NO.
'CAUSE IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T THINK
MY MOM'S OKAY.
I'M SORRY.
I'LL BE BACK.
HARD TO KNOW
HOW LONG, RIGHT ?
[ Striking Match ]
I CAN SEND FOR YA.
THIS MUST'VE TAKEN YOU
DAYS, AXEL.
I CAN.
I CAN SEND FOR YA.
I'M 23, SADIE.
TRY TO CUT ME SOME SLACK.
HOW 'BOUT
A BLOW JOB INSTEAD ?
FUCK YOU, SADIE.
DIDN'T MEAN IT.
I SWEAR.
I DO EVERYTHING
I KNOW HOW FOR YOU.
I KNOW, AXEL.
YOU GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT ?
YES.
I'M NOT LEAVING YOU.
NO.
NO SUCH LUCK,
ALL RIGHT ?
SEND FOR ME, AXEL.
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Door Opening ]
- I GOT BACK.
- DID YOU MEET BRIAN ?
YES.
D'YOU KNOW
GEORGIA FLOOD, BRIAN ?
THIS IS HER SISTER.
OH.  UH, WELL,
IT'S GOOD TO MEET YA.
I'M A BIG FAN.
[ Chasman ]  SHE SANG WITH
TRUCKER TOO.  DIDN'T YOU ?
HOW'S THE WORLD
TREATIN' YOU, SADE ?
WELL, WE'RE TRYIN'
TO COME TO TERMS.
YOU AND THE WORLD ?
THAT WOULD BE A SHAME.
I'M A MARRIED WOMAN.
WHAT, YOU ?
YES, ME.
WELL, CONGRATULATIONS.
SO HOW YOU DOIN' ?
THE SAME.
THINGS ARE ABOUT TO BREAK.
I'M NOT A HOMOSEXUAL, BRIAN.
DID SHE TELL YOU
I WAS A HOMOSEXUAL ?
NO.
SADIE'S
LITTLE JOKE.
DID YOU GET ANOTHER CAT ?
NO.
YEAH.  WELL,
I TRIED A DOG.
YOU CAN RELY ON A DOG,
BUT I COULDN'T TRAIN HIM.
MESSED ALL OVER
THE APARTMENT.
HE SHIT.  HE PISSED.
SO DAMNED DEPENDENT, DOGS.
I NEED A GIG,
PLACE TO STAY.
LET ME LOOK INTO IT, OKAY ?
YEAH, WELL,
A PLACE TO STAY.
YEAH, I'LL LOOK INTO IT.
WHAT KIND OF ANSWER IS THAT ?
YOU'RE MY MANAGER, RIGHT ?
WHATEVER THE HELL THAT MEANS.
WHERE WERE YOU FOR ME
TO MANAGE ?
I DON'T REMEMBER SEEING
TEN PERCENT FOR THE MONTHS
AT A TIME YOU WERE GONE.
IT'S NOT THE MONEY, SADIE.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
YOU HAD THE GOODS.
I APPRECIATE TALENT.
I PUT MYSELF ON THE LINE.
YOU WANT WORK
AND TIME TO PAY OFF.
I'M NOT ABOVE GETTING HURT.
SO IF I'M NOT
IN TOTAL RAPTURE
AT SEEING YOU,
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
YOU ARE SO
FULL OF SHIT, CHASMAN.
THE OTHER DAY, MAN,
I COULDN'T FIND THE DOOR.
SHIT.
I SWEAR.
I COULDN'T FIND
THE GODDAMN DOOR.
NO FUCKING SHIT.
YOU KNOW WHERE IS THE DOOR
TO THIS APARTMENT...
LIKE THE BACK OF MY HAND.
AND I CAN'T
FIND THE DOOR.
DID YOU LOSE BRIAN ?
BRIAN FOUND THE DOOR.
GUESS SO.
WELL, I'M GAME.
FUCK IT.
WE'LL CHECK OURSELVES IN.
DETOX.
WE'LL GO TO L.A.
YOU'VE GOTTA MAKE IT IN L.A.
TO MEAN ANYTHING.
YEAH.
WE'LL CLEAN UP.
DON'T TOUCH MY WAKE-UP.
WANT TO FIND IT RIGHT THERE
IN THE MORNING.
[ Coughing, Sniffing ]
DO YOU HAVE
A PREPAID TICKET HERE
FOR SADIE FLOOD ?
FOR SEATTLE.
THE 11:30 ?
I'M NOT SHOWING ANYTHING.
FLIGHT 484 ?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M IN MEDFORD, RIGHT ?
THE 11:30.
I'M NOT SHOWING
ANYTHING.
YEAH, WELL, MAYBE
YOU COULD CALL.
AS SOON AS IT WAS PREPAID,
THEY'D HAVE PUT IT
IN THE COMPUTER.
IT WOULD SHOW UP
ON THE COMPUTER.
I'M SICK, SEE ?
THERE WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE A WHEELCHAIR.
SO, UH, MAYBE YOU
COULD CALL SOMEONE.
WHY DON'T YOU HAVE A SEAT ?
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
YEAH, WELL--
THERE'S ANOTHER FLIGHT
AT 2:35.
I'M NOT ON THIS PLANE,
I'M OUTTA HERE.
IT'S A MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
I'M SICK, AND--
HOW LONG AGO WAS
THE TICKET PURCHASED ?
I DON'T KNOW.
HOUR.  HALF-HOUR.
LOOK, DO YOU
HAVE A SUPERVISOR ?
I GOTTA BE ON THE PLANE.
I'M SICK, SEE ?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
WHY DON'T YOU SIT DOWN
AND LET ME SEE WHAT I CAN DO ?
I REALLY NEED TO TAKE CARE OF
THE REST OF THESE PEOPLE.
OKAY, HELEN.
[ Flight Announcement
Over P.A., Indistinct ]
WHO DO YOU HAVE TO FUCK
TO GET SOME HELP AROUND HERE ?
[ P.A. Announcer ]
ROLLINGER, MUNSON,
OKESON AND RICE,
TO THE BOARDING DOORWAY,
GATE C-2 FOR DEPARTURE.
YOU CAN'T GET ON THE PLANE
WITHOUT SHOES, MISS.
YOU HAVE SHOES ?
ARE YOU KIDDING ME ?
IT'S AN AIRLINE
REGULATION, MISS.
IT'S A MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
I HAVE TO GET TO A HOSPITAL.
I'M SORRY, MA'AM.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
LET ME BOARD ?
WE CAN'T LET ANYBODY BOARD
WITHOUT SHOES, MA'AM.
SHIT.  FUCKING
HORSESHIT, MAN !
ANYBODY GOT
A PAIR OF SHOES ?
THIS IS A MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
ANYBODY GOT A PAIR OF SHOES SO
I CAN GET ON A GODDAMN PLANE ?
PLEASE ?
ANYBODY WANNA GIVE ME
A PAIR OF SHOES TO GET ON
THIS FUCKING PLANE,PLEASE ?
THANK YOU.
[ P.A. Announcer ]
THE ARRIVAL OF FLIGHT 484
AT 12:37 FROM MEDFORD, OREGON.
ALL THOSE ARRIVING PASSENGERS
CAN BE MET MOMENTARILY
AT GATE R-54.
[ Toilet Flushing ]
HI.
I'M SORRY.
YOUR FLIGHT
WAS EARLY.
TWENTY MINUTES, YEAH.
I THOUGHT
JAKE WOULD COME.
NO, I WANTED
TO COME GET YOU.
SO HOW'D YOU FIND ME
IN HERE ?
I LEFT MY BAG OUTSIDE.
I'M REALLY SICK,
GEORGIA.
LET'S GET YOUR STUFF.
LOOK AT YOU.  YOU TOLD 'EM
NOT TO LET ME DIE, RIGHT ?
YEAH.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN ?
YES.
THANK YOU.
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHO ELSE TO CALL.
[ Crying ]
I'M SO SORRY, GEORGIA.
THEY WEREN'T GONNA
LET ME ON THE PLANE.
THIS KID WAS GREAT.
WELL, I'M THIN, HUH ?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE ABLE
TO FIND A VEIN.  WHY DON'T
YOU LET ME DO THAT ?
I THINK I'VE GOT THIS
UNDER CONTROL.
SHE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA BE GIVING HER
HIGH DOSES OF VALIUM
SO SHE DOESN'T SEIZE.
AND HE'LL GIVE HER
CLONIDINE PATCHES
FOR THE HEROIN.
YOU GO HOME AND REST.
SHE'LL PRETTY MUCH SLEEP
THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
THIS IS PROBABLY
INAPPROPRIATE, BUT...
I'M A REALLY BIG FAN.
[ Bell Dings ]
WHAT ARE YOU
DOIN' HERE, DAD ?
I DON'T WANT YOU HERE, DAD.
REALLY NOT.
THIS IS MY PARTY.
WHERE'S MY SWEETHEART ?
WHO ?
THIS GUY I WAS
SLEEPING WITH.
HE LEFT ME.
- SHE AWAKE ?
- SHE WANTS A CIGARETTE.
[ Groans ]
I'M SORRY ABOUT THE ROBE.
I REALLY LOVE THIS ROBE.
I DON'T CARE
ABOUT THE ROBE.
IT'S YOURS.
MAKE SURE SHE'S SITTING UP
WHILE SHE'S SMOKING.
DON'T NOD OUT ON US, SADIE.
WE'RE VERY PROUD OF THIS GIRL.
SHE'S COME A REALLY LONG WAY.
SHE'S THE BEST NURSE
ON THE WARD.  YOU ARE, HUH ?
THEY HATE ME HERE.
[ Laughs ]
THEY DO.
SO THIS MUST BE
A REAL EMBARRASSMENT TO YOU.
NO.  WHY ?
CRY ALL THE TIME.
THE PATCHES MAKE ME
A LITTLE--
YOU KNOW.
- WELL, YOU SEE.
- HOW'S IT GOIN' ?
[ Snorting ]
LOTS OF PAPERWORK.
IT'S ALL PAPERWORK.
AND MEETINGS.
MEETINGS.
I'M HAVING SOME TROUBLE WITH THE
GOD-AS-I-UNDERSTAND-HIM PART.
[ Laughs ]
WHAT WAS DAD
DOING HERE ?
DAD ?
REALLY.
I DON'T THINK SO.
RIGHT THERE
IN THAT CHAIR.
[ Sighs ]
I LIKE MY COUNSELOR.
DAVID.
DONALD.
WHICH ?
DAVID.
DONALD.
DAVID DONALD.
[ Laughs ]
I THINK THAT'S HIS NAME.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO CALL AXEL ?
OH, GOD.  AXEL.
SWEET AXEL.
AXEL NEEDS TO GET A LIFE.
SO WHEN DO YOU THINK YOU'RE
GONNA HAVE THIS BABY ?
I DON'T KNOW.
CAN I ?
IT'S SO AMAZING.
DID I TELL YOU
ABOUT STEWART ?
THE ONE WHO
DESIGNED SPEAKERS.
FOR CONCERTS.
- HE WAS IN LOVE WITH YOU.
- YEAH.
YOU MEAN SAM.
SAM ?
YEAH.
DID I TELL YOU
ABOUT SAM ?
[ Laughing ]
OW.
YOU LOOK GOOD.
YOU TOO.
THEY HAD TO SEE
IF I WAS APPROVED.
YEAH.
I MAKE A LIST.
LIKE I'M IN CONTROL HERE.
[ Chuckling ]
SO HOW IS IT ?
IT'S GREAT.
YEAH.
REAL PEOPLE.
SO HOW YOU DOIN' ?
YOU KNOW.
SURVIVAL.
AND BOBBY ?
SEATTLE'S OWN, HUH ?
SAY HELLO.
SURE.
I DID IT MYSELF.
IT WAS DRIVING ME CRAZY.
THEY LET YOU
HAVE SCISSORS ?
YEAH.  SCISSORS.
SO YOU THINK
I LOOK OKAY ?
YOU LOOK GREAT.
I MISS YOU GUYS.
YEAH, ME TOO.
I MISS HERMAN.
I COULD'VE CALLED THAT.
WHAT ?
UH, SHIT.
I'M SORRY.
A MONTH, MONTH AND A HALF AGO.
FUCKIN' HERMAN.
♪♪ LOOKIN' FOR SOUL FOOD
AND A PLACE TO EAT ♪♪
♪♪ WENT TO THE APOLLO ♪♪
♪♪ APOLLO ♪♪
♪♪ SHOULD HAVE SEEN HIM
GO, GO, GO ♪♪
♪♪ THEY SAID
HEY, SUGAR ♪♪
♪♪ HEY, SUGAR ♪♪
♪♪ TAKE A WALK ON
THE WILD SIDE ♪♪
♪♪ I SAID
HEY, BABE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ TAKE A WALK ON THE WILD SIDE
♪♪
♪♪ TAKE A WALK
ON THE WILD SIDE ♪
♪♪ ALL RIGHT, HA
AND THE COLORED GIRLS GO ♪♪
♪♪ DO DO-DO, DO-DO
DO-DO-DO-DO DO ♪♪
♪♪ DO-DO, DO-DO
DO-DO-DO, DO-DO ♪♪
♪♪ DO DO-DO, DO-DO
DO-DO-DO-DO DO ♪♪
♪♪ DO-DO, DO-DO
♪♪♪♪ [ Continues ]
[ Baby Gurgling ]
GOOD JOB, DRUID.
♪♪♪♪ [ Woman Singing,
Indistinct ]
♪♪ I CAN'T AFFORD TO GO
TO MARDI GRAS THIS YEAR ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T EVEN CARE ABOUT
PAYIN' MY PHONE BILL
KNOW WHAT I MEAN ♪♪
♪♪ AND PRIVATE PROPERTY IS
REALLY AN OUTMODED CONCEPT ♪♪
-♪♪♪♪ [ Continues, Indistinct ]
- MY MIND GETS UP FIVE MINUTES
BEFORE I DO.
AND THEN IT'S SITTING
ON THE BED.
SAYING, "I'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR YOU.
"I HAVE SOMETHING
TO SAY TO YOU.
I'VE BEEN WANTING
TO TALK TO YOU."
♪♪ IF I WANNA SLEEP
ON THE FLOOR ♪♪
IN MY BREAKFAST-- ♪♪♪♪
MY MIND SAYS,
"I'VE BEEN AWAKE
ALL NIGHT.
"I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
YOU HAVE CANCER.
"YOU'RE ON THE VERGE
OF BANKRUPTCY.
NOBODY LIKES YOU."
OVERRIDING DOOM.
IT'S A MIND FUCK.
ANDREW.
HE'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GOIN' ALL
TOUCHY-FEELY, ANDREW.
I DON'T MIND.
[ Laughing ]
I'M SURE NOT.
BRAY HAMMOND KILEY.
THAT'S A LOT OF WEIGHT.
MY MOTHER'S FATHER'S NAME.
IT'LL KEEP HIM
GROUNDED.
ONE WOULD HOPE.
- YOU DIDN'T COME VISIT.
- NO, I DIDN'T, BUT
I LOVE YOU JUST THE SAME.
I HOLD A VERY SPECIAL
PLACE FOR YOU, SADIE.
DO YOU, JAKE ?
YEAH.  A SACRED PLACE.
WELL,
YOU'VE ONLY EVER BEEN
THE ONLY MAN IN THE WORLD
FOR ME, JAKE.
YES.
YES ?  YOU SURE ?
YES.  MM-HMM.
I DON'T WANNA TAKE IT
UNLESS IT WAS GOIN'
TO GOODWILL ANYWAY.
YOU'RE IN MY CLOSET, SADIE.
YOU CAN HAVE ANYTHING
YOU LIKE, REALLY.
YOURS.
DON'T DO THAT.
DON'T DO WHAT ?
TAKE WHAT
YOU NEED.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' ?
NOTHING.
MY FAVORITE THING.
MISH HAS GOT
THE TICKET.
SHE CAN BECOME
WEIGHTLESS.
THIN AIR.  IT'S SOMETHING
I'M APT TO ENCOURAGE.
ARE YOU GONNA NEED MONEY ?
NOT A LOT.
IT'S NOT A BOTTOMLESS
PIT, SADIE.
WELL, SIS,
I KNOW THAT, SIS.
I'M KEEPIN' ACCOUNTS.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
[ Laughs ]
YOU'RE SO FUNNY, SADIE.
YOU HAVEN'T ASKED
MY PLANS.
NO, I HAVEN'T.
DO YOU CARE ?
I KNEW
YOU'D TELL ME.
UNCERTAIN.
I THINK L.A.
I THINK IN STAGES.
OH, GOOD.
- GOOD WHAT ?
- I DON'T KNOW, SADIE.
AS LONG AS YOU'RE OKAY.
I WAS JUST THINKIN',
YOU KNOW ?
YOU NEVER LEFT HOME, GEORGIA.
I GUESS SO.
I MUST SCARE THE SHIT
OUT OF YOU.
I MUST BE
YOUR WORST NIGHTMARE.
SADIE'S OUT THERE
GOBBLING IT UP.
ALWAYS.  THAT'S ALWAYS
HOW I SEE YOU.
GOBBLING IT UP AGAIN.
I HATE THE DESPERATION.
EVERYTHING'S SO DESPERATE.
YEAH.  WELL, YOU DON'T DO
ANYTHING DESPERATE.
YOU DON'T FEEL
ANYTHING DESPERATELY.
IT'S NOT IN YOUR NATURE.
FEELING ISN'T YOUR
STRONG SUIT, GEORGIA.
NO, NOT LIKE YOU.
NOTHING CONSUMING.
NO.
- NOT PASSION.
- PASSION ?
OKAY, PASSION.
- OR PAIN.
- NO.  OR SUFFERING.
THAT'S A GIFT YOU MISTAKE
FOR VOICE, SADIE.
MY GOD.  IT'S HOW
YOU DEFINE YOURSELF.
IT'S YOURS;
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT.
SADIE'S PAIN
HAS TO BE FED, GODDAMN IT.
KEPT ALIVE.
AND WE'RE ALL HERE,
READY TO SERVE.
YOU DON'T SING, SADIE.
YOU CAN'T SING.
YOU WISH.
[ Giggling ]
[ Giggling Continues ]
MY NAME'S SADIE FLOOD.
[ Scattered Applause ]
AND WE'RE GONNA
COME TO TERMS,
PORTLAND, OKAY ?
THIS IS MY HARP PLAYER
AND MY GUITAR PLAYER,
MARK OLSEN.
[ Light Applause ]
AND MY DRUMMER--
WHAT ?
JOEY.  JOEY DENIZZIONI.
JOEY.  WHAT ?
DENIZZIONI.
JOEY DENIZZIONI
ON THE DRUMS.
[ Light Applause ]
AND GUY DAVIS ON BASS.
[ Crowd Cheering, Whistling ]
THANK YOU.
♪♪ IT'S A SONG
AND THE SIGH ♪♪
♪♪ OF THE WEARY ♪♪
♪♪ HARD TIMES
HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ MANY YEARS
HAVE YOU LINGERED ♪♪
♪♪ AROUND OUR CABIN DOOR ♪♪
♪♪ OH, HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ COME AGAIN NO MORE ♪♪
♪♪ NO MORE HARD TIMES ♪♪
♪♪ NO MORE HARD TIMES ♪♪♪♪
[ Patron Applauds ]
NO ONE DOES THAT SONG
BETTER THAN MY SISTER.
WHO ?
THANK YOU, COMRADE.
♪♪♪♪
[ Tom Waits ]
♪♪ THE PIANO HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪
♪
♪♪ MY NECTAR IS SWEET ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE COMBO WENT BACK
TO NEW YORK ♪♪
♪♪ THE JUKEBOX
HAS TO TAKE A LEAK ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE CARPET
NEEDS A HAIRCUT ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE SPOTLIGHT
LOOKS LIKE A PRISON BREAK ♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE THE TELEPHONE'S
OUT OF CIGARETTES ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE BALCONY
IS ON THE MAKE ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE PIANO
HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪♪
♪♪ THE PIANO HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪
♪
♪♪ AND THE MENUS
ARE ALL FREEZING ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE LIGHT MAN'S
BLIND IN ONE EYE ♪♪
♪♪ AND THEY CAN'T SEE
OUT OF THE OTHER ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE PIANO TUNE'S
GOTTA IRRIGATE ♪♪
♪♪ AND HE SHOWED UP
WITH HIS MOTHER ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE PIANO
HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪♪
♪♪ THE PIANO HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪
♪
♪♪ AND THE BOUNCER
IS A SUMO WRESTLER ♪♪
♪♪ CREAM PUFF
CASPER MILQUETOAST ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE OWNER
IS A MENTAL MIDGET ♪♪
♪♪ WITH THE I.Q.
OF A FENCE POST ♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE THE PIANO
HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪♪
♪♪ THE PIANO HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪
♪
♪♪ AND YOU CAN'T FIND
YOUR WAITRESS ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A GEIGER COUNTER ♪♪
♪♪ AND SHE HATES YOU
AND YOUR FRIENDS ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU JUST ♪♪
♪♪ CAN'T GET SERVED
WITHOUT HER ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE BOX OFFICE
IS DROOLING ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE BAR STOOLS
ARE ON FIRE ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE NEWSPAPERS
WERE FOOLING ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE ASHTRAYS
HAVE RETIRED ♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE THE PIANO
HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪♪
♪♪ THE PIANO HAS BEEN DRINKING ♪
♪
♪♪ NOT ME ♪♪
♪♪ NOT ME ♪♪♪♪