Gertrud.
You're still here.
I'm leaving in a moment.
Are you going to the office
tonight?
Yes - board meeting.
I'll probably go to the opera
and sit in my usual corner.
- What's playing?
- Fidelio.
Come here. Let's talk a bit.
- I have something to tell you.
- Yes?
I do. Has mother been
here today?
No.
She has to get
her monthly allowance.
Is that what you wanted
to tell me?
No. Come here. Sit down.
Tell me, Gertrud.
How would you like to be
a cabinet minister's wife?
Which cabinet minister
wants to marry me?
Minister Kanning.
That's the news. There's been talk
you'd be cabinet minister.
Yes.
You were never known as one of the
government's warmest supporters.
Not really, but I imagine
a little opposition
in the government
couldn't hurt.
And you'll be that
little opposition?
On the way home
I met the musical genius -
Erhard Jansson.
Isn't that his name?
Erland Jansson.
If that's who you mean.
Yes, yes. Erland Jansson.
Is he really a genius?
- That's what they say.
- But what do you think?
You know music so well.
- Do you know who I also met?
- No.
Gabriel Lidman.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
- I know that.
- I asked him to come visit us.
- Is he going to?
- That's what he said.
- He has been away a long time.
- Yes, 2 years.
- Three.
- There you go.
Here are some letters.
Bills, I suppose.
Thank you.
There's a picture of Lidman
in the newspaper.
May I see it?
It looks just like him.
Yes. He hasn't changed much.
Did you tell him that you're
giving the celebration speech?
He knew already.
I look forward to
seeing him again.
Why did you break it off
with him?
Let's not talk about it.
No, no - that chapter of your
life has been forgotten.
You said it's over
and I believe you.
I've always thought your
relationship to Gabriel
was not my concern.
You were a free
and independent woman.
You were an artist
and he was a famous poet.
- It's another story.
- Is it?
Yes, of course.
What are you laughing about?
I'm just smiling, thinking about
all the poor human beings
who allow themselves to love,
whether they're artists
or famous people or not.
Have you seen my large
briefcase?
Yes. It's out in the hall.
Thank you.
How beautiful you are,
Gertrud.
I got this mirror from
Gabriel Lidman.
It should have been in the
bedroom, so that I would have
something to look at
when I woke in the morning.
- Yes, that's what he said.
- Yes, I know.
Later I received something else
from him - a bit less rococo -
and now his mirror hangs here -
with you - in your room.
May I kiss you, Gertrud?
- It gets dark early now.
- I should probably go.
I seek your lips and
you give me your cheek
and the door to your room
has been locked up to me
for more than a month.
I used to be welcome there.
I often lie awake,
thinking of you.
I've thought you might be in love
with someone else
and I've wondered who
it could be.
Damn it. Mamma's here.
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Gustav.
- Good afternoon, little Mamma.
Those stairs!
Good afternoon, sweet Gertrud.
Good afternoon, mother-in-law.
- Come and sit down.
- Thank you.
- Mamma, you're late today.
- I was snoozing over a book.
Even when you're old,
you still like to keep up.
- What was the book?
- What was it... I've forgotten.
- Who wrote it?
- I don't remember,
but it was an artistic book.
- What was it about?
- God knows. I've forgotten.
Not that I understand what
they write these days.
Would you like a cup of tea,
mother-in-law?
Thank you, my sweet.
I'd rather have a glass of port.
- Gladly.
- Thank you.
Dear Gertrud, she is truly a
sweet and good wife to you.
- Yes, she is.
- I tell that to everyone.
- Do people ask you?
- Ask? No one asks.
But people gossip, you know.
Since you've been married, not a
soul has said a word against her.
Up 'til now in any case.
And that old story with her
and him... what was his name?
- Lidman.
- That was just gossip, of course.
Of course.
They say you're going to be
a cabinet minister?
That's what they say.
What does one
get a year for that?
One has to sacrifice for
one's country.
Bless you. You'll regret it.
Think of your father, my son,
think of what he sacrificed.
What did he get out of it?
A couple of medals.
No, Gustav, mind your law firm
and stop thinking
of the fatherland.
That's my advice.
Mamma, I'll become a cabinet
minister because I want to.
Gertrud's coming to the
court ball, isn't she?
She's completely
indifferent to it.
- If you please.
- Thank you.
What do you think about becoming
a cabinet minister's wife?
What shall I say,
it hasn't been decided yet.
The Minister of State will call
at five o'clock.
Listen, let's not forget,
you have to have your money.
I'll get it.
Can't you get
your mother to go?
I've something I want to discuss
with you, something serious.
Mamma dear, unfortunately,
I have a meeting
and Gertrud has to leave.
It's past four-thirty.
And I have so much to do.
Listen, you didn't get
your money.
- Thank you. Goodbye, Gustav.
- Goodbye, Mamma.
Goodbye, little Gertrud.
Goodbye, mother-in-law.
What's on your mind?
Something I wanted to tell you
for a long time
and I dare not put it off
any longer.
This will hurt you.
Gustav, I'll not be a cabinet
minister's wife.
What are you saying?
I no longer
want to be your wife.
Gertrud, what do you mean?
Remember what you said when
you gave me the ring.
If the day ever came when one
of us wanted to be free,
then the other must step aside.
- Do you remember that?
- Yes, I remember.
I felt a little sorrow then.
I thought we should be together
our entire lives.
When I saw how much
you loved me,
I came to you and said
I would be yours.
I wouldn't have had it any
other way for the whole world.
And now you want to leave me.
Gertrud, I don't understand.
Gustav. So much has changed.
We've changed.
I love you, Gertrud.
Love - such a big word.
There's so much you love.
You love power and honor,
you love yourself,
your intellectual life,
your books,
your Havana cigars,
and I am sure you loved me
at times.
How can you say such a thing?
You know,
when we sit here in the evening,
do you realize you can sit
for hours on end,
staring into space
without saying a word?
I have many things
to think about.
- Things?
- Yes, my cases, my work.
Your work. There we have it,
you think about your work.
- You believe it is indifference?
- It's worse than indifference.
It's a lack of feeling.
A woman loves her husband
above all,
but for him, work comes first.
Isn't that the nature
of the universe?
Naturally, it's a man's
nature to work, to create.
But work mustn't exile
the woman from his thoughts.
I feel this way often, as if I
have no husband at all,
as if I'm just atmosphere
for you.
What more do you want to get
off your chest?
That you, in a very
humiliating way, show me
how little I mean to you.
Am I absolutely nothing to you?
You never guess my wishes
or my thoughts.
Whether I am happy or sad
is completely uninteresting to you.
I understand your reproach for
being absorbed in my work.
The man I'm with
must be completely mine.
I must come before everything.
I don't want to be
an occasional plaything.
Yes but, sweet Gertrud,
love alone
is not enough in a man's life.
That would be ridiculous
for a man.
Perhaps it would,
but see for yourself
how little I mean to you
and how insignificant the void
becomes when I leave now.
Gertrud, what are you hiding
from me?
Is there someone else?
You may call it that,
if you want.
- Then you're admitting it.
- Yes.
- Has it already happened?
- No.
But it will happen then?
Gertrud, you're
driving me crazy.
Oh, no. The woman that can drive
you crazy doesn't exist.
You don't believe that either.
Who is he?
You don't think I'd answer that,
do you?
Is it someone who wants
to marry you?
Perhaps I will sing again
as before and fend for myself.
Gertrud - Who is it?
I can only tell you that he
doesn't belong to our circle.
Where did you meet him?
Gertrud.
Will you leave
and not come back?
No, my friend, but I feel
I had to tell you now.
We can speak again about
the how and why,
but tomorrow we have to go
to the celebration.
If you could just explain how
this has happened.
Things are easier
when one understands.
What more can I explain?
I don't understand it myself.
All I know is that love
has me in its clutches.
And it doesn't mean anything
to you to tell me this?
It's as if you're resigning
a position.
I have suffered day and night,
wondering how I should tell you.
Gertrud - I can't take this.
You took it easier than
I had feared.
It went easier for both of us.
And where will you go now?
As I've told you - tonight
I'm going to the opera.
Goodbye, Gustav.
- Have you been waiting long?
- Yes, too long.
Forgive me, darling.
I'll try.
Do you love me?
You have to say it.
- I love you.
- Say it again.
I love you.
We must talk seriously
about this.
What I can ever be to you?
Let me go my way.
I can never be yours anyway.
You are everything to me,
- my life of desire and sorrow.
- Sorrow?
Yes, much to my sorrow I must
love you as I do,
though I don't understand you.
I'm nothing more than
a whim for you.
You sent me roses.
That was after
your first concert,
two roses and a card,
and I never received an answer -
not one bit of thanks.
But I still received more roses.
And when we met... Remember
our first kiss?
I remember many kisses,
a rain of kisses,
kisses that went through
my bones,
kisses that made me gasp
for breath.
I couldn't get you out
of my mind.
When I saw you at the concert
I had to have you.
And when I ask you to be mine
completely, you retreat
and yet you still say I mean
everything to you.
It is you, and do you know
how you became so?
I had never heard your voice.
I had to hear you speak to know
whether it was you I had to love.
So I went to see you.
I wonder how I had the courage.
Lucky I was home.
Yes, come in.
Eternal winged child and god
Once again my heart
obeys your stern call
Yes again I've become lonely
in the midst
of your satisfied flock
Here your ardent harshness
may yet bring me happiness
Darkness has formed a pearl
Night has borne a dream
Hidden shall I reside within
Dazzling, white and tender
The song must sound in the heart
Painfully sweet and cruel
While my sparkling pearl
Grows in its dark room
How beautifully you sang. As if I
had never heard the song before.
I'm tired.
I was out on the town
last night.
As usual. Is that necessary
to be an artist?
I don't know. I know only
that I have to.
Some of us wasted away
the night together.
We ended up at a bar where
we played cards
with a couple of con men.
They took all our money.
Nice types - well -
poetic justice.
Did you play too?
I sat mostly, half-asleep, and
meanwhile worked on a motif.
I still have it in my head.
I could make a symphony
out of it,
if I could pull myself together.
You shouldn't go out like that.
You're destroying yourself.
You'll stay home tonight,
won't you?
- I've been invited out.
- With whom?
A guy I know. He's arranged an
apartment for a girl he likes.
Her name is Constance.
It'll be christened this
evening. I'm going.
Don't go.
Why shouldn't I?
Because I'm asking you not to.
I also asked you something once
that you could've given me.
Erland, there's so much music
in you that wants to get out
into the world,
out among people.
The way you live, it'll die,
perhaps soon,
perhaps sooner than you think.
Your inspirations from a smelly
bar after a sleepless night -
Erland, they're worthless.
Erland - I beg you -
beg you as if I were begging
for my life. Don't go.
I live as I want and must live.
It's in my blood.
Even if I did promise you to
stay home, I'd go anyway.
Then it is better
that you promise nothing.
I live hard because I like to.
Tomorrow is a new beginning.
Gabriel Lidman the great poet,
has returned home
and will be honored tomorrow.
He turns 50 as if it were
some feat to turn 50.
So we'll see each other.
I'll be there too.
- Is your husband coming as well?
- Yes.
The politician.
And now he'll be
a cabinet minister.
Why does he bother?
You're speaking about a man
you don't know.
I'm sorry.
Before I left home, I had
a long talk with him.
That's why you had to wait.
Today I have set myself free.
Now I am a free woman.
- Does that mean?
- Yes.
You said I could never
be yours...
but Erland, I can be.
From now on I'm
completely yours.
- I dreamt something last night.
- What did you dream?
I was running naked through
the streets, dogs chasing me.
And when they caught me,
I awoke.
And I realized we two are
completely alone in the world.
Give me your mouth.
Your wonderful mouth.
Where do we go now?
Your place. Come.
Gertrud. Do you dare?
I mean, if...
Erland - I love you, Erland,
and if you ask me if I dare,
then I will answer you,
yes, I dare.
I dare for I believe in you.
Do you care about me?
I can never, never care
about anyone else.
I just couldn't imagine living
not having been with you.
Strange woman.
Who are you, really?
- I am many things.
- Who?
The morning dew, dripping from
the leaves of the tree.
White clouds sailing
where, no one knows.
Who else are you?
I am the moon. I am the sky.
And what else?
Yes, I am a mouth.
A mouth seeking another's mouth.
Sounds like a dream.
It is a dream. Life is a dream.
- Life?
- Yes.
Life is a long, long chain
of dreams,
drifting into one another.
- And the mouth you spoke of?
- A dream.
And the mouth you seek?
Also a dream.
Play something.
- What shall I play?
- A nocturne.
Debussy's.
No, your own.
Coming home from the office
so many thoughts
raced through my head.
How a person can dream
his life away,
while others busily rush around.
Slowly and helplessly,
life slips through our hands,
whatever we do.
I thought how the dearest and
sweetest in my own life
was now slipping
through my hands
without my being able
to understand why
or explain how it had happened.
I was reminded of an old verse.
It went:
"Pay attention to the treasure
God has sent you,
don't let it slip through
your hands."
We're never attentive enough
to what we possess
and loathe to lose.
I longed for my wife,
longed to walk again side-by-side
through the streets
with her arms in mine,
as so many times before
when we were happy.
Then I thought I'd go meet her
at the opera.
May I help you with something?
I am here to pick up my wife.
She may have left
before the last act.
Mrs. Kanning was not here
at all this evening.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I've been here all evening.
- Do you know my wife?
- I should know your wife.
She has sung here.
There you are.
Oh, Erland
here, with you, I'm alive again.
I can't tell you
how happy I am.
- Are you quite yourself again?
- Yes.
Now we shall live together.
Do you think we could live
together?
I love you. Erland
all my love awaits you now.
Gertrud.
Erland.
You'll not go to Constance's
party now, will you?
In Florabakken.
Lights ablaze today we carry
The fire burns clearly
as your words
Our torches burn in your honor
Be welcomed to your native soil.
See us hoist the golden candles
Widely traveled, lofty free spirit.
Hear our pleas from the
young hearts of the nation
Give us new works from your hand
Lights ablaze today we carry
The fire burns clearly
as words of truth
Our free thoughts are our honor
We'll fight proudly
for all we believe
We will exorcize the power
of winter's might
That's the goal for our future
See us emerge from the
paths of life
Amid hope's beautiful fiery glow.
Dear Gabriel Lidman.
We are gathered here on behalf
of the students and youth
to honor you as the great
poet of love.
Most young people today have
been raised by parents
who were married in church
and lived an ordinary life,
a life having nothing
to do with love.
These past generations' idea
of sexuality
as something sordid
and simple,
has always been foreign to you.
Their doctrine of love
is that true love
is only thinkable with a union
of heart and mind.
Your hymns to love describe
two people completely devoted
to each other in a love-giving
and intimate life
together, in perfect warmth
and tenderness.
Let me cite the following lines:
"He held fast to her mouth,
"still deeper they sank
into each other.
"He felt as if he were
on a journey in space
"in the white moonlight,
a red star, first faint
"and about to end,
then stronger and closer.
"It grew and enlarged into
a flaming well of fire.
"He burned without pain
and the flames
"swallowed his tongue
like sour wine."
In erotic ecstasy, people find
infinity and eternity.
This is the greatest part of
your erotic idea.
This is love without borders.
To this idea of love, all
humankind is created and called.
Two things for me
have always been
and still are more important
than anything else:
these two things are
Love and Thought.
You've spoken about love.
As far as thoughts go,
we should have courage
to think good thoughts,
for good thoughts bring us
to the summit of truth,
and truth is the only thing
worthwhile.
This thinking can lead
to the truth,
pure truth without
predisposition.
In your search for this truth,
be true to yourselves
and don't compromise.
Have courage to think
good thoughts.
Remember the words of the
French philosopher:
"A true soul need not hide
his thoughts."
Thank you.
Yes, we are coming -
listen to our voices
You shall know, your words
have weight
Speak strong and clear,
so no one forgets
the fight for the nation's
new open generation
Our minds are young
and full of vigor,
pure wills made from hard steel
We shall reach every goal
for which we strive
Show us the way to yet
greater goals
Honorable Vice-Chancellor.
Ladies and gentlemen.
It is a great honor to be asked
to give a speech tonight
in tribute to my old friend
Gabriel Lidman.
Gabriel Lidman is the aristocrat
among our poets.
The most outstanding trait in
his character is honesty,
honesty in the great
and the small.
He derides the mediocre,
even when it hides
beneath a noble
and proper veneer.
His essence is curiosity,
captivating curiosity
in his exceedingly
subdued appearance.
When he speaks,
it is with such tranquillity,
one is forced to listen.
He never becomes pathetic.
Do you feel all right?
The torches make it
warm here.
His speech can be colored with
light but caustic irony
which does not sting.
He loves stillness,
inspirational stillness...
Do you feel ill?
Lidman has cultivated
succinctness as an artistic form.
He never writes a word too many.
Each sentence is well considered
and as sharp as a razor.
He shuns vague speech,
sentimentality,
false pathos and the
unextraordinary.
You can sit here undisturbed.
Would you like the door
to the main hall closed?
Yes, please close it.
A Professor Nygren wishes
to see Mrs. Kanning.
- Is that you, Axel?
- Yes.
- I thought you were in Paris.
- I was,
but I had an errand here at home,
then Lidman. You understand.
It was nice of you to come
on a sick call.
Yes, I heard you had a
terrible headache.
Look here. I have some
perfectly splendid tablets
that take away headaches -
though they're large.
- What kind are they?
- They're a Viennese concoction.
- From Paris?
- Yes, all of Paris knows them.
You can hold the powder. Could I
get a glass of cold water?
Of course.
I'll get it from there.
Professor Nygren is here,
go back to the celebration.
Fine, if Mrs. Kanning thinks so.
Then...
Yes, and I am most grateful
for your care.
It was my pleasure to be
of assistance.
Thank you.
Well?
Just think,
I already feel better.
Axel, it is so good to see you
again. You have not changed.
Neither have you
the same magic illumination.
The last time we spoke
you were working on a book.
Yes. On free will.
I'm still working on it.
I'm glad you still believe
in free will.
My father was a sad fatalist.
He taught us that everything
in life is predetermined.
I remember what you said
will is a choice.
But my father said there's
no such thing as choice.
One doesn't choose, he said, not
his wife or his children.
One gets them and one has them,
but doesn't choose them.
Fate decides everything.
Then you know your life's
destiny.
I'll choose my own husbands.
Thank you.
- Plural?
- Yes. You were in Paris.
- What did you do down there?
- Studied.
- Psychology?
- Yes, and psychiatry.
Lots of things are happening
in those fields.
- It must be exciting.
- It is. Some of us meet
in the evening and work
further on our own.
- How?
- We hypnotize each other,
we experiment with thought
transference,
and we've found a lady
who has a sixth sense.
We're really happy
to have her around.
Otherwise, we discuss and argue
until we're blue in the face.
- About what?
- Everything possible.
Psychoses and neuroses,
dreams and symbols.
How I envy you.
Come to Paris and join
our group. You'd like it.
I'm sure I would, but -
That, that's the dream I had
the other night.
Attorney Kanning
has finished his speech,
so he'll be here any moment.
It was nice to see you again,
Axel.
It's too bad you have
to go back so soon.
Good gracious.
Gertrud, you look better now.
I feel much better now,
thanks to some wonderful pills
Axel gave me.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
The important thing is that
they helped.
- Goodbye and be well!
- Goodbye, Axel.
Hope to see you again soon.
I have to speak to you,
now that we're alone.
Last night when I came home
your door was locked.
- I must have slept well.
- That's impossible.
Why?
I took a cab home from
the opera.
Were you at the opera?
That's not what you'd say
if you had known
that I too was at the opera?
Right?
You say nothing.
Do you know why?
Because you don't want to lie.
You weren't at the opera,
nor were you home.
Why do we have to talk
about this? Do we have to?
Yes, we do, you should know
I went to the opera
not to spy on you but because
I longed for you
and was sick with the thought
of your leaving me.
I beg you,
please don't say more.
Answer me, Gertrud.
Where were you yesterday?
Gustav, after our talk
yesterday,
you must understand your
question is meaningless.
I'm your husband, Gertrud.
I am still your husband.
I don't know you any longer.
Is that you, speaking this way?
You made a fool out of me
yesterday at the opera.
You already knew what you were
going to do.
Yes, I knew what I was
I fooled you to spare you.
Not out of cowardice or
treachery. You know I'm truthful.
Yes, God knows.
No woman should be so honest.
But I won't let you go,
you can believe that.
Will you lock me up?
Be reasonable.
You'll be with me tonight.
Our last night.
Then you can go wherever
you choose
and ruin your life,
if that's what you wish.
You don't know what you're
saying. I'm going in to rest.
Well, here you are.
How is Gertrud?
She felt ill but she's
better now.
Let's hear about you.
How does it feel to be
home again?
On your native soil.
Oh, yes - the native soil of
the fatherland
is all well and good -
I mean the earth,
the air, the fields and forests,
but the people,
Kanning, the people - damn!
I ended up in mixed company
last night,
somewhat mixed company,
one ought to say.
Well, it doesn't matter.
I was out to enjoy myself.
So, I shouldn't take it too
seriously. Better to laugh it off.
What is it we were talking about?
Oh yes, listen.
I want to go back to Rome.
I can't work up there.
I hear you'll be a
cabinet minister.
It sure looks like it, if you
believe the newspapers.
You have to. You have to believe
in something in this world.
Attorney Kanning - the Vice-
Chancellor would like a word.
I'm coming.
Come sit here.
You're still young and pure,
like a bride.
The light is hurting my eyes.
You look as if something
unpleasant has happened to you.
Yes. I was in bad company last
evening, but it was my own fault.
I don't want to think about it.
It's over.
Everything is nothing.
In the old days you always
spoke of your life's work.
You've become a great and
famous man,
and now everything is nothing.
What's the matter, Gabriel?
Oh, I'm feeling old.
Can you tell me, Gertrud,
why did I come back here?
I was just going to ask you
the same question.
There was a kind of homesickness,
especially for one street,
a street I often thought about.
One spring day I walked down
that street and wept
in the midst of the sunshine.
Yes, I've often wept.
It's not so bad.
It eases you.
Let's speak of happier things.
You've come home a hero.
A hero? Yes, yes,
I dare say we're probably not
talking about the same thing.
In the only battle I ever cared about,
I was defeated.
Gertrud, why did you leave me?
We shouldn't talk about it now.
As I said before, I was in
bad company last evening.
I ate lunch with an old
school friend and it ended up
with someone asking us to go
to a little party
at his girlfriend's -
Constance.
- In Florabakken.
- How did you know?
Oh, I've heard about her.
The city is not so large.
No. Well, I went with them.
Holier men than I have sat at
the table of a courtesan.
Well, what else happened?
Now I am curious.
What are they playing?
What are we listening to now?
"Song in the night" by
Erland Jansson.
Of course, I heard it in Rome.
I remember I was
completely moved
when I noticed in the program the
composer was a fellow countryman.
It's a lovely melody.
Yes, it is beautiful.
Wasn't Erland Jansson supposed
to play here this evening?
That was the talk, but I
don't care. I don't like him.
- You know him?
- Yes, unfortunately.
I wish I didn't.
Where did you meet him?
I know him, too.
Gertrud, Gertrud.
Why did you leave me?
Listen, now you're getting off
the subject.
You wanted to tell me about
last night's party.
I met Erland Jansson last night.
He showed up late in the night.
You didn't mind sitting
at a courtesan's table.
Why should he?
No, naturally -
but I don't like him.
He boasts about things
others keep to themselves.
- Such as?
- He bragged about his lovers.
No, that wasn't nice.
No. In this mixed company,
in this atmosphere of drinking,
playing and whoring around,
he spoke aloud
of his last conquest.
And he named her,
her beloved name.
Gertrud, was I wrong to
tell you this?
I don't know.
I don't understand.
I know nothing.
I felt I had to, Gertrud.
I had to - had to.
You had to.
Gabriel, help me understand
all this.
I don't understand it myself.
I only understand what I do -
should have done.
This I don't understand.
He must have been ill.
Well, I don't believe so.
It was so horrible of him.
But he was drunk,
and he's so young.
Yes, he is so young.
And he belongs to a
completely different circle.
Yes, yes.
Gertrud, now you'll break it off
with him?
I love him. I love him.
- That's madness, Gertrud.
- Yes.
And no one can advise you,
no one can help you?
No. I've known all along
it was madness,
but I had so little to lose,
Gabriel.
My life was so terribly
lonely and empty.
Last night my life was
shattered
when I heard the one I loved
more than anything -
when I heard her name dragged
through the mud
by a reckless young man -
one suddenly feels old.
Gertrud, I'd never thought
we'd meet again this way.
Nothing happens like
we think it should.
How do you think it should,
Gabriel?
Gabriel,
Gabriel, don't take it so hard.
No. No, don't leave me
this way.
Gertrud - the Vice-Chancellor
asked me to say hello
and that he hoped to hear you
sing this evening.
And what did you tell him?
I said I would try to convince you
to sing a song or two
but I didn't promise anything.
Yes, I would like to.
Where?
In here.
Shall I have accompaniment?
Mr. Erland Jansson has
agreed to do it.
- But there's no piano here?
- It's in there.
I'll take care of it.
Over there.
Many thanks.
I'm not angry
even if my heart is broken
In the midst of my hopelessness
I see how cruelly you suffered
and no anger, and no anger.
Even though your brow
gives a youthful glow
I know how heavy your heart is
I've known it for a long time.
I'm not angry,
my eternally lost friend.
- Have you been waiting long?
- Just a few minutes.
I couldn't come sooner.
You don't look well.
I know, but I had to speak
to you anyway.
Tell me, why did you collapse
last night?
I was overtired, from having
quarrelled with my husband.
- Was he cruel towards you?
- How could you think that?
I mean, if he loves you,
he'll be hurt if you leave him.
It's not his nature
to be cruel.
Well, I hardly know him.
He seems fairly nice.
What do you have
against him anyway?
Why do you want to divorce him?
We could be good friends
just as well.
Erland, I want to go away.
That's why I wanted
to meet you.
Does that mean you've come
to say goodbye?
- That depends on you.
- What do you mean?
Erland - come with me.
That's impossible, Gertrud.
- Is it because you have no money?
- No, I don't.
I have enough to get started.
Are you saying I should live
on your money?
Yes.
You'll despise me.
Then you don't know
what love is, Erland.
I would despise myself.
You do that anyway - sometimes.
Yes I do.
I can't despise myself because
I do what I have to do.
I have to confess I went to
Constance's party
in Florabakken after all.
- I had to.
- Yes, you had to -
had to -
that's the key word to everything.
Is it just for the sake of money
you won't leave with me?
I'd have to think about it,
Gertrud.
You said before we could love
each other without a divorce.
That sounded ugly.
I don't understand. It didn't
embarrass you the other day.
Erland - When will we begin to
speak the same language -
Erland, my love,
come away with me.
We don't need to marry.
We'll just live together
to be near each other.
I love you. Let's go away.
When you no longer love me,
you can leave me.
- Well - and then what?
- Then?
Then nothing will matter.
Gertrud. I can't go with you.
I'm not free.
You said - not free?
Yes, she's older than I.
She's meant much to me. Helped me
when things were difficult.
I can't leave her in the lurch.
Besides, she's pregnant.
And you never said a word
about it.
I didn't believe
it was serious between us.
What did you believe then?
I thought you were just out for
a little adventure
and I saw no harm in that.
And now the adventure has passed.
Do you hate me for it?
I love you but it's over.
I'm leaving and you'll marry.
Gertrud, come with me.
- Where?
- To my place.
I love you but you don't
love me back.
I no longer belong to you.
Okay...
No, I don't love you. If I did...
I'd leave with you and think
of nothing else.
I have a dream about a certain
woman but it's not you.
She'd be innocent and pure.
She'd obey me and belong to me.
You're too proud.
I thought at first you had the
usual pride of a fine woman.
This is worse.
Your soul is proud.
Leave me alone, Erland.
Gertrud, forgive me, let's not
part as enemies. Forgive me.
Forgive?
I wish I believed in a God
so I could ask him to
protect you.
You don't believe in God,
Gertrud?
Do you?
I don't know.
There must be a higher spirit,
somewhere, otherwise so many
things are inexplicable.
Well - now you must go.
There's a call for Mr. Kanning.
Just a moment, please.
By all means.
It's you, Gabriel?
Yes, I've come to say goodbye.
I leave tomorrow.
- So soon?
- Yes, and you?
- Will you stay here?
- No.
I'll leave soon enough.
I've long felt homeless here.
Gertrud. You're leaving
and I'm leaving.
Let's leave together.
Let's live together.
Gabriel - you don't know
what you're saying.
Have you never on lonely nights
heard my heart call out to you?
You asked yesterday what made me
long for home.
It was you, a longing to
hear your voice
and look into your eyes again.
How strange all this is.
I knew you were married
and to whom
and I thought - maybe her life
is now as empty as mine.
Nothing's like one thinks.
No. No, nothing's ever like
one thinks.
Gertrud. Did you ever love
your husband?
Love him? I don't know.
I was thinking about your creed,
remember?
I don't know what you mean.
No, one never remembers everything
but the creed went:
"I believe in the pleasure
of the flesh
and the irreparable
loneliness of the soul."
Oh yes. That sounds like me.
I didn't forget it.
All those words at a time
when I thought
our dream would become a reality.
You wrenched me from
our dream of happiness.
We fell apart.
So, I took refuge in the pleasure
of the flesh and only that.
There, you have my marriage.
I thought so.
Gertrud. Come with me.
No, Gabriel - for me there's
only loneliness.
You've broken it off
with him then - Erland Jansson?
I'm nothing to him.
Gertrud. Come away with me.
How can you still believe
we could breathe life
into what's dead and buried?
Come, let's sit here a moment
as we so often sat together
at your place.
Don't think I've forgotten
all I owe you.
You taught me love's
wonderful miracle.
You made me a woman with
every drop of life's blood.
I belonged to you with
all my senses.
We grew together
and became one.
There was no shame
between us.
Love cleansed me of everything,
of what was low and miserable.
It opened me up
to the good and beautiful.
I found in you a man with whom
I could share life.
I asked myself whether I truly
deserved so much happiness.
Gertrud, why did you ever
leave me?
Gabriel, do you really
believe I left you?
Don't you realize
it was you who pushed me away -
gently... gradually.
I have never loved another.
I believe you - as much
as you could love.
But what was I to you?
You were tired of my love.
When it became clear, I left.
Gertrud, there's truth
in what you say.
Work took you away from me, but
never did I want to break it off.
You couldn't break it off.
That's why it was good
that I could.
Your work divided us -
and honor -
and fame, and money.
You desired these.
Love had become a burden for you.
You wanted the pleasure
of the flesh, not love.
It's the terrible truth.
I felt it.
I'll tell you when I knew
for sure.
It was during the time you
hadn't had any meaningful work
for a long period.
A difficult time.
For me, too.
Then one day I visited you.
And I decided to tidy up.
I wanted to write you
a few words.
Some scrap paper you used
for notes lay on your desk.
On one of them,
you drew my profile
and those words
that devastated me.
"A woman's love and a man's
work are mortal enemies."
That's when I knew for certain.
And my life was ruined
by a bit of scrap paper.
Ruined? You got what you wanted.
Nothing has been won.
No, but one must choose.
And one always loses the thing
he cherishes the most.
Always.
When I realized everything...
my heart grew old.
I was ashamed and loathed
being a woman.
I saw how men who become great
never know or understand love.
They look down on love.
They despise love.
You had become like them.
And I don't love you.
Gertrud.
My life is those three years
you loved me.
You left me. How could you?
How could you?
I knew it would hurt you.
I knew from your letter.
It hurt more than I had thought.
You became great but for me
you are as cold as stone.
I want pure, warm blood.
I don't care about greatness.
There's no greatness, Gertrud.
The night is long,
space endless
but the earth is small
and people are small.
What I remember from my life
is my love for you.
You taught me love is
everything.
We shouldn't be alone.
I have been alone much too much.
We shouldn't be many.
One needs to be two.
Gertrud, we two belong together.
Yes, one should be two.
To think you understand that,
now that it's too late.
It's never too late.
Come away with me.
We'll live in a house by the
sea and nothing or no one
shall separate us.
Nothing but death.
There's no happiness in love.
Love is suffering.
Love is unhappiness.
Gabriel, an empty space
is in your breast.
I can't help you.
Look for nothing from me.
Too late and in vain.
My life's epitaph -
in vain.
You must excuse me.
It took some time.
Gertrud, how do you feel?
Fine, thank you.
The Minister of State
wouldn't let me go.
I've got to be going.
Wait. We must have
a glass of champagne.
374.
I'd like to speak to
Professor Axel Nygren.
Axel, is that you? It's Gertrud.
I'm calling to tell you
I'm coming to Paris.
You'll help me get registered
at the Sorbonne?
Yes, yes, I'd love to join
the group you talked about.
I'll write before I come.
What's your address?
Number 72. Thanks.
Goodbye Axel. See you soon.
There you are.
Gertrud, you've come
just in time.
- Champagne?
- Yes.
I've agreed to accept
the cabinet position.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- And from me.
- Thank you Gertrud.
You don't look well, dear.
You said you felt much better.
It's nothing. I'm just tired.
I'll go lie down soon.
- You haven't eaten all day.
- I'm not hungry.
As you wish.
So you've become a cabinet
minister's wife after all.
Yes, I might as well enjoy it
as long as it lasts.
Not long. Gabriel already knows
we are parting ways.
- Then you told him?
- Yes.
Each of us will go his own way.
Let me begin by saying goodbye.
- Goodbye Kanning.
- Goodbye Lidman.
It'll be a long time before
we see each other again.
Yes, I suppose it will.
Goodbye, Gertrud.
Goodbye, Gabriel.
Goodnight, Gustav.
I'll go to bed now, I'm tired.
Gertrud, I've thought it over.
I believe I've found a solution,
but answer me first.
Did it happen? What we
discussed yesterday?
- You know it did.
- Yes, I know.
But Gertrud, you must not
leave me.
Stay with me.
You can have your new love -
since it means so much to you.
But stay with me and we'll
live together
as good friends.
I ask for no more.
You want me to stay
because you hope
and believe the severed bond
between us can be renewed.
- Isn't that right?
- That's right.
I'm leaving.
- With your new love?
- Alone.
The new love doesn't want me.
Good God.
Is there a man alive whom
you love and doesn't want you?
I don't understand.
I could stay here for his sake
but I'd like to be myself now.
That's why I'm leaving.
Goodnight, Gustav.
I'm so tired... so tired.
Tell me,
tell me you loved me once.
Why do you torture me?
When we met I'd already left
my love behind.
But my senses were alive and
my blood flowed.
There was something between us -
something resembling love.
Something... resembling?
Leave. Get out!
I never want to see you again.
Never hear of you again!
Gertrud.
There's a Professor Axel Nygren
here to see you.
Really? Is it Axel Nygren?
Show him in.
So you came on my birthday?
Yes, I came to give you
my new book.
It comes out next week.
It's a beautiful book - RACINE.
To remind us of our days
in Paris.
Thank you, Axel. Sit down.
Yes, I live here like a hermit,
forgotten, erased.
I like it that way.
I need solitude -
solitude and freedom.
Here's the paper.
Remember to wash the
kitchen floor.
The kitchen floor, of course.
That's all the house help
I have.
And what do you do?
I bake my own bread, wash my
chemise, mend my stockings.
I see you have a radio.
Yes, one must keep up with
what's going on in the world.
I wrote to you some time ago.
Yes, your letter's here,
as you can see.
You might have sent me
a few words.
No, Axel, I can't use a machine
to write an old friend.
Forgive me. So do you still
care about me a little?
I've always been very fond
of you. I still am.
Come.
I wonder how long it's been
since we've been
to a lecture together.
It must be 30-40 years.
Our friendship has lasted
that long?
A friendship that never
turned to love.
But you've been
a good friend to me.
You're still young, your skin
is so white and smooth.
I'll get more wrinkles and
my skin will turn yellow.
- Do you know what I'm thinking?
- No.
- Do you want your letters back?
- Yes, I would.
I'd rather not have strangers
reading what were warm
and good words spoken
from your heart.
There you are.
Would you mind if I burned them?
Now the letters are yours.
Do what you wish.
Have you ever thought
of writing poetry?
Yes, I have. Actually
I've written a poem,
one poem when I was 16.
Here it is.
Shall I read it to you?
It has three verses.
Read.
Just look at me.
Am I beautiful?
No
but I have loved.
Just look at me.
Am I young?
No
but I have loved.
Just look at me.
Do I live?
No
but I have loved.
Sixteen year-old Gertrud -
my gospel according to love.
Remember what you said:
There's nothing else in life
but love.
Nothing. Nothing else.
Do you still stand by
those words? Do you regret them?
No, I don't regret them.
I stand by what I said,
there's nothing else in life
but youth and love,
unending tenderness
and quiet happiness, Axel.
When I'm near the grave and
look back on my life,
I'll say to myself...
I suffered much and often
made mistakes,
but I have loved.
You think a lot about death
and the grave?
Yes, I've already bought
my resting place.
I know where I'll be laid to rest,
under a mulberry tree.
Yesterday, I ordered the
head stone for my grave
and I decided
what shall be on it.
- Your name, of course?
- No, just two words.
Amor Omnia
Love is all.
Yes. Love is all.
The gardener has been told that
only grass shall grow on my grave
and in springtime I shall
have anemones.
You'll come by one day,
pick an anemone and
think of me.
Take it as a word of love that
was thought, but never spoken.
Now you'd better go, otherwise
we'll end up
by running off to Paris.
One day your visit will be
only a memory -
as all the other memories
I cherish.
Sometimes I bring forth the
memories and lose myself in them.
I feel as if I am gazing at a
fire about to be extinguished.
Thank you, Axel.
Thanks for visiting.
Thank you for your book.
Goodbye, Gertrud.