I am a mutant. And so were you.
_
REED: Dad?
We need to talk to you
about your work. At Trask.
They're experimenting on mutants.
My own best friend was turned.
He's working for Sentinel Services.
OTTO: A research project
to eliminate the X-Gene
in you... that was what
brought me to Trask.
REED: When I was sick?
Dad, I nearly died.
ESME: I'm a telepath
and I've been getting some very weird
thoughts from one of the others.
Hey.
CAITLIN: You don't have
to talk. Just think.
Who did this to you? Where are they?
I can see it.
It's a building.
Some kind of lab.
North of here.
OTTO: My father and his sister Andrea
were known as Fenris. The Wolf.
They had the same
abilities as your children.
Have they held hands?
Shoot him!
SS AGENT: Don't worry, Dr. Campbell,
we're going to get you to a hospital.
Gus. I'm gonna make them
pay for what they did to you.
- LAUREN: What happened with your dad?
- REED: He died today.
Oh, babe.
- [BIRDS SINGING, CHILDREN CHATTERING]
- _
Andy!
CAITLIN: Nice. I didn't
know you could do that.
I have all kinds of secret talents.
[CAITLIN LAUGHS]
REED: Hey... This is good, right?
Well, don't get cocky, but yeah.
It's really good.
It's been too long
since we've done this.
- I'm sorry work's been so crazy.
- Don't.
We understand.
What you do, it's important.
It's just, I've missed you.
The kids, too.
Well, I'm here now.
- [LAUGHS SOFTLY]
- They doing all right?
CAITLIN: Yeah.
I mean, Lauren's been
a little distant lately,
but I think it's just
normal teenager stuff.
It's nice to see them
not bickering for once.
Wanna try that?
- No, I'm not gonna do that.
- What do you mean?
I don't skateboard.
Yeah, you can. Here.
Back foot on the tail,
front foot halfway up the deck.
It's fine, it's easy.
Pop and flick... like
a karate kick, okay?
- Halfway up...
- I'm gonna fall, no.
No, you... Trust me.
I'm... I'll be here. I can catch you.
- Promise?
- Yeah.
Help me up.
Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
LAUREN: Okay.
[LAUREN GASPS]
Hey!
You guys all right over there?
Yeah.
Messing around.
♪ ♪
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
[BIRDS SINGING FAINTLY]
_
♪ ♪
ELLEN: Reed, don't.
Your father's working.
ELLEN: But you're leaving
me to do this all on my own.
He needs you.
He's your son.
What do you mean, you
can't come to see him?
[EXHALES]
Hey, you.
[CAITLIN EXHALES]
I woke up and you were gone.
I'm sorry.
Couldn't sleep.
Thinking about your dad?
I hadn't spoken to the
man in 20 years. I...
didn't think losing him would make me...
[SIGHS]
I get it.
My mom and I couldn't be
in the same room without her
bringing up every screwup
of my teenage years
to remind me how perfect
Jenny and Danny were.
[REED SIGHS]
When she got sick, we finally started
to get past all that crap, but...
it was too late.
I almost think it's worse
when you're not close, because...
you realize how much time you missed.
Yeah.
Reed, I...
I hate to bring this up, but...
I have to ask.
If Otto was a mutant...
and your grandfather
and his twin were, too...
I-It's just, I...
I thought mutations were random.
Mostly, they are.
But they can be passed down, too.
Then why did it skip you?
[EXHALES]
Did it skip you?
My dad's work at Trask Industries...
He spent his life trying to find a way
to suppress the X-Gene...
in me.
[EXHALES]
And he succeeded.
But it came back. In our kids.
I... Did you know?
- Of course not. What?
- I-I...
Did you think I'd keep
something like that from you?
I'm sorry, I-I'm just
trying to wrap my head around
how this never came up
after all these years.
Your mom, she...
For two years, we thought
I had leukemia, Cait.
He kept it as a secret from everybody.
And it destroyed my family.
Well, we're not going
to let it destroy ours.
[BIRDS SINGING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
ESME: We need to go
after the Trask lab now.
We have to rescue those people...
Have to? You're pretty new here to be
telling people what they have to do.
You don't get it!
My family is in there.
- They're running out of time.
- Okay, well, slow down.
THUNDERBIRD: You got
all that information
from the woman they sent after us?
Yes.
I mean, her mind was hard to read.
Confused. But I got enough.
The mutants in that
lab, they were desperate.
I-I could hear the screams.
I could see the bodies.
I could feel the agony
when they turned that
woman into that thing.
And it's all happening in that building.
We know where this place is?
I'm assembling a site map now.
So why are we standing here?
Did you get anything on their security?
No. It... Her mind was too cloudy,
but what does it matter?
We are the last hope
those prisoners have.
You saw what they did to your friend.
We sit on our hands,
and that happens to more people.
No one is sitting on their hands.
Now, we will make a move on that lab,
but if we go in blind...
we die.
Johnny? Are you all right?
[THUNDERBIRD SIGHS]
How can I be "all right"?
Maybe Esme has a point.
But she's just a scared kid,
who has no idea what
she's talking about.
She was right about one thing.
Pulse.
I left him behind
and they took him to that lab.
That's not on you, Johnny.
And continuing to blame yourself
is not doing anybody any good.
Besides, d...
don't you think it's strange
that she knew about Pulse?
- I mean, she just got here.
- She's a telepath, Sonya.
Maybe she picked it up off of me.
It doesn't change the fact
that I gave up on my friend
and they turned him into a monster.
I'll be damned if I'm gonna
let that happen to anybody else.
Hey.
Lauren.
You awake?
[SIGHS] Yeah.
I can't stop thinking
about what Dad said.
About Grandpa Otto being...
like us.
Not just him.
Here, check this out.
I found this in the library.
You know where the library is here?
Who are you and what
have you done with Andy?
Ha ha ha.
Look, this section's on the 1950s.
Andrea and Andreas von Strucker.
They called themselves "Fenris"?
Yeah, I think it means
"wolf" in some language.
LAUREN: Oh, my God.
- They did that?
- Yeah.
They combined powers by holding hands.
They wiped out an entire building
full of people in seconds.
This is crazy.
This is our family history.
Look, it says here
they're "rumored to be
part of a shadowy
international organization
called the Hellfire Club."
Does it say what happened to them?
I think they disappeared
fleeing from the X-Men.
They were some of the
most powerful mutants ever.
Yeah.
It also says they were monsters.
- Well, I'm just saying...
- I don't care.
Go to bed.
[BABY CRYING IN DISTANCE]
Hello?
[CRYING STOPS]
[DISTORTED BABY CRYING]
- [CRYING FADES]
- [GROANS]
Marcos.
Marcos! Marcos, what's happening?
[ECHOING]: Marcos!
[GRUNTING]
[BABY CRYING IN DISTANCE]
Oh, no.
- [CRYING CONTINUES]
- No, no, no...
No, no, no, no! [SOBS]
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
Hey, hey, hey, it was just a dream.
The baby... the baby's at Trask.
No. Hey, the baby's here.
- Hey, the baby's fine.
- [PANTING]
POLARIS: Marcos, in my
dream, Trask had the baby.
We have to get into that lab.
- We have... we have to help those people.
- Yeah.
ECLIPSE: We will. Hey.
We will. I promise.
I promise.
[ECLIPSE PANTING]
- [DISTANT SIREN WAILING]
- [OVER P.A.]: Dr. Barnes...
[PAINED GROANING]
How's he doing?
Docs said Campbell was burned
pretty bad, but he'll live.
Said he didn't want surgery.
I guess his mutant has skills.
[PAINED GROANING]
The Mutant Underground's
gonna be looking
to launch another attack...
we got to put a team together.
Come on, be tough to sell
an operation like that
without specific intel.
Washington was pissed about
losing those two agents.
Washington's pissed?
I'm the one that had
to tell the families.
Look, we got all the intel we need.
The Underground knows
about the Hound program now.
They're gonna have
to hit Campbell's lab.
The place is top secret...
how will they even find it?
What are you talking
about? They're mutants.
They can shoot lasers
out of their hands.
I'm pretty sure they
can find a building.
I know I'm right about this.
We can bury the paperwork.
Just... get some techs on it, all right?
Yeah. I'll see what I can do.
[PAINED GROANING]
I've been looking into the Trask lab.
This place is out in
the middle of nowhere.
There is no information on it.
But there is this.
THUNDERBIRD: A bar?
What good does that do us?
I cross-referenced credit card activity
with places near the lab, and this place
is popular with Trask employees.
I could go in.
Pull some information out of a guard
or an operations person.
That's a good idea.
I'll go for protection.
- No. I will.
- Are you sure, babe?
I mean, you haven't
really been sleeping well.
I'm okay.
Marcos, if you want to get
information from a guy at a bar,
you don't send a girl and another guy.
We'll be fine.
Hey. Hope you're hungry.
I have a nondairy
cheese and chive omelet
with your name on it.
[REED CHUCKLES]
How are you handling all of this?
[EXHALES]
I know it's not fair, but I...
I keep thinking how different
everything would have been
i-if Lauren would have just
told us she was a mutant.
- Come on, we can't go down that road.
- Or if your father
would have just told everyone the truth.
Our whole lives would be different.
Your job.
H-How we raised our kids.
- I mean, Andy may have never...
- We did the best that we could.
[SHUDDERING EXHALE]
Hmm.
What about you? If...
if you'd known then what you know now...
would you have done
anything differently?
With us?
No.
Cait...
[SIGHS]
there is one more thing
I haven't told you.
My dad told me
that his father and aunt...
were terrorists.
- What?
- They had
the same powers as Andy and Lauren.
And when they combined them together,
they were massively destructive.
I... And you...
you think Andy and Lauren
can do the same thing?
- I don't know.
- Well,
- we have to tell them.
- Do we?
Isn't that like
- handing them a loaded gun?
- Your father, he didn't tell you
you were a mutant... you
think he did the right thing?
[SIGHS]
No more secrets, Reed.
POLARIS: So, you're really in charge?
Of the entire security system?
I mean, not like the boss boss,
but of my shift? Yeah.
Basically, I... I run it.
- Hmm.
- Wow, that sounds intense.
DREAMER: Mm-hmm.
You don't know the half of it.
The place is like a fortress.
You know, automatic guns, detectors...
♪ ♪
I shouldn't be telling you any of this.
Must be so scary to work with mutants.
Do you ever worry they'll attack you?
Oh, they have a whole program
in place to make them behave.
Remember when they
were calling themselves
"Homo superior"?
Well, they're not so
superior when you...
crack 'em in the head with a nightstick.
I mean, one good shot to the temple...
they drop...
A little like that?
Lorna, what the hell?
What? I'm just teaching him
- to respect the genetically different.
- [GROANS]
Quit crying. Nobody
saw. Just do your thing.
Give him anything to remember us by?
Mm. Just a lonely night...
till he cracked his head on a urinal.
Best girls' night ever.
♪ ♪
So, you guys are for real right now?
Like, seriously serious?
Yes, that's-that's why
we thought we should...
deal with this as a family.
I think we learned the hard way that
discovering mutant abilities
by accident isn't ideal.
REED: Look, it might be nothing.
My dad could possibly be wrong.
Just because the von
Strucker twins could do it
- doesn't necessarily mean...
- What if he's right?
You want us to destroy something?
- Definitely not. No.
- No. No.
Th-That's... that's
why we wanted to test it
in the vault... just to...
[SIGHS] ...to see if
there's anything there.
Okay.
[ANDY EXHALES]
[LAUREN EXHALES]
♪ ♪
So...
this is weird.
[SIGHS] But is...
is there... anything?
Yeah. Andy's hand is sweaty.
CAITLIN: O-Okay. Well, then maybe
there's... there's
nothing to worry about.
Maybe it's nothing.
No. Wait. Just give it a chance, okay?
Maybe we gotta, like,
squeeze harder or something,
actually want something
to happen. Come on. Please?
We got to try.
♪ ♪
Hey.
Hey, hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey!
CAITLIN: What happened?
LAUREN: I don't know.
It was like...
- I could feel...
- Everything around me.
All we had to do is push.
I-I don't understand.
Did you use the power?
Dad...
if we tried...
Did you feel that?
Everything coming apart?
- Kids, what happened?
- LAUREN: We were about
to bring down the entire building.
We would have killed everyone here.
♪ ♪
Sonya and I have been going
through the memories she got
from that guard and
it does not look good.
What are we up against?
Well, the lab is hardened
against mutant attack.
They have motion and
infrared sensors connected
to heavy-caliber guns that are
mounted all over their building.
- Guns? I can handle guns.
- ECLIPSE: I know, but it is
way too dangerous when there's
this many, at this range.
Clarice, can you get
us past their defenses?
No. It's too far.
I don't know the first thing
about the inside of that place.
I could blink us into
the middle of a concrete wall.
Well, there has to be something.
I did find one vulnerability.
There is a power
substation a few miles away.
If we took it out, we
could get into the lab
before their systems came back on line.
- So what are we waiting for?
- We don't have enough heavy hitters
to attack both places at
once. And we're checking with
- the other stations now.
- Well, how long is that gonna take,
- because my family...
- Listen, I understand...
Believe me. This means as
much to me as it does to you.
But we are gonna get one shot at this.
We can't miss.
So, what happened in the vault?
CAITLIN: What did you feel, exactly?
ANDY: Everything around us
kind of... just disappeared.
And it's like, there
wasn't two of us anymore.
There was just one.
It's like... we were
seeing out of the same eyes.
You said you could have
destroyed a building.
- How did you know that?
- I could feel it.
Andy pushes things apart, right?
I do the opposite, I
can pull them together.
Combined, it was like, we could
do whatever we wanted. I mean,
we were looking at the
wall in front of us,
and-and we could have
just... vaporized it.
- Maybe if we practice, we...
- Practice?
What? We can do it, we might
as well get better at it.
REED: Eh, you've been given
a gift, and a power like that
could hurt people, you can't
just go around using it...
So we should just stuff it down
and bury it like your dad did?
How'd that work out?
- That's way out of bounds, Andy.
- ANDY: Mom.
It's who we are, okay? It's who I am.
Andy, sometimes you can't
control your own powers.
ANDY: I see.
So I'm just some kind of monster.
That's not what he meant.
At least you guys have one
kid you can actually trust.
Mom...
Let me talk to him.
LAUREN: Andy...
- Andy!
- What?
You know Mom and Dad are just
trying to protect us, right?
Yeah, yeah, I totally get it.
I'm a freak because I
don't hate my powers.
You think I hated that?
I've never felt so powerful.
It scared me...
because it felt good.
Do you remember that time
that it happened before?
At the park.
- You felt that?
- Yeah. That was before
I even knew I was a mutant. I mean, I...
That's when I started
messing up at school.
It's 'cause I couldn't
get it out of my mind.
Me, too.
All I want to do right
now is try that again.
Does that mean...
does that mean we're gonna be like them?
The von Struckers?
Honestly... I don't know.
So this is the substation?
Uh, yeah.
Sage was able to get it using
the guard's system access.
Look, are you sure we can't
take this down ourselves?
I'm good with electronics.
Sage said we get three minutes tops
before the generators kick back on.
- We'd never get back to the lab in time.
- [SIGHS]
Listen, we need to talk
about the other night.
It was a nightmare. It's nothing.
Nothing?
It's not nothing.
I think all the furniture
in our room would disagree.
- Look, if you're worried about the baby...
- If?
Of course I'm worried about the baby.
Why?
I'm not sure that this
place is gonna make it.
No matter what,
I will protect you, and that kid.
That's a promise.
I don't know if that's
a promise you can keep.
[QUIETLY]: What?
Hey.
Am I interrupting?
Yes.
No, it's all right.
- What is it?
- I have an idea.
For the power station,
how to knock it out.
Yeah? What's that?
We use the Strucker kids.
[HORN HONKS IN DISTANCE]
No, it's-it's probably gonna
be another late night...
PAULA [OVER PHONE]: What else is new?
JACE: I know, I know.
Look, I'm sorry. It's just,
we're on to something, here.
We're getting really close.
I-I just don't like that
you're going back to work
- so soon after...
- Babe.
This is exactly why I have to be here.
This isn't just about me.
I want justice, for
Grace, for all of us.
Just...
come home safe.
I will.
When the job is done.
When the job's done.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
What do we got, Ed?
I called in some favors.
[DOOR CLOSES]
I was able to pull together
a team to look into the lab.
All right.
Good job.
Just know: we're out on
the skinny branches here.
An unauthorized investigation
into a covert facility?
If this fails, we're talking
to the FBI in handcuffs.
Then we best not fail.
ECLIPSE: We need you
to do the same thing
to the substation
transformers that you did
to the prison convoy bus.
We know it's a lot to ask, but...
now we just don't see another way.
Look, we want to help,
but why does it need
to be Lauren and Andy?
Well, because we need everyone else
with combat powers to assault the lab.
Now, we think that we can
take down that power substation
without putting them at any risk.
So exploding high voltage
transformers is the safe job?
In this case, yes.
ECLIPSE: Sage hacked
the security cameras.
The station only has
a handful of guards.
Clarice will get everyone
in. Sonya will guide them.
THUNDERBIRD: We've been
through every option.
This is the only one that works.
I'm down.
Let's do it.
Okay.
But Caitlin and I need to be
the ones monitoring the security.
If our kids are there, we are, too.
Look, Sage will set you
up, show you what to do.
THUNDERBIRD: All right,
everybody get ready.
We move out in an hour.
♪ ♪
[CAR DOORS CLOSING]
All right, this is it. Gate's up there.
We'll go check it out, see
what we're dealing with.
Sounds good. We'll get the party favors.
- ESME: [GASPS] Oh.
- That's a detonator.
Drop it too hard, this ends quick.
- Sorry.
- You seem a bit jumpy.
Have you ever done
anything like this before?
Not exactly.
Okay, before we go in there,
you got to understand something.
When the shooting starts,
everything changes.
If you're not ready, then I...
I... I am ready.
I just, I slipped. Okay?
Look, if you're here
because you think this is
gonna be some adventure,
you're making a mistake.
[ECLIPSE SHOUTS]
POLARIS: Marcos!
[SHOUTING]
[GROWLS, SCREAMS]
Hey.
Have you ever been so angry
about someone you love getting hurt
that you would do
anything to stop the pain?
That's why I'm here.
For the people I love in that building.
I can't leave them.
They're a part of me.
ECLIPSE: That is a long stroll
from the fence to the building.
Well, we knew it wouldn't be easy.
Yeah. Says the bulletproof guy.
This would have been so much
easier if we had Pulse with us.
- Yeah.
- He could've taken out
- every automated gun in that place.
- [GRUNTS]
Course, we'd be hearing tales
of his awesomeness for months.
[LAUGHS] Yeah.
I miss him.
Yeah, me, too. But John,
you weren't the only person
that left him there that night.
That's on all of us, not just you.
And today, we get to make it up to him.
[ZIPS BAG]
[BEEPS]
We're in place.
REED: Copy that. We're en route.
We're almost at the power substation.
Okay, be safe out there.
What we're doing here, it's
a parent's worst nightmare.
- We can handle...
- Andy, we know.
We know you can.
We're doing this because we trust you.
Hey, Struckers, heads up. We're here.
[BRAKES SQUEAK]
[PHONE BEEPS, DIALS]
Yeah.
- We're ready.
- Okay.
Bypassing firewall.
And you should have
picture in three, two, one.
REED: Okay. It's working.
SAGE: I looped the camera feeds
so security won't see our team.
But they'll notice
eventually, so be quick.
BLINK: Okay, guys.
I'm gonna need some room here, kid.
Uh, yeah.
- ANDY: Bye, Mom.
- Okay.
We got this.
BLINK: Um, guys?
It's a little trickier
than holding an elevator.
Can we hurry this up please?
WEEKS: Turner.
We've checked into everything.
No irregularities at the lab,
no alarms, no nothing.
What about lab employees?
Anything unusual going on there?
All the background
checks came back clean.
We've got a guy out
of town for a funeral,
one sick leave...
Who's the sick leave?
Security guard. Called last night.
Access the Trask employee network.
Pull up his record.
I think it's a dead end.
Guy passed out in a
bar, bumped his head.
Probably sleeping off his hangover.
JACE: Right there.
He accessed information
on the power station.
WEEKS: Power station? That's miles away.
JACE: Yeah, but it powers the lab.
They hit that, they could get in.
- I'll call the lab.
- No. No.
The mutants could be monitoring
communication there...
we're not calling anybody.
We need a tactical team.
Remote units, everything.
We're not gonna be able
to do that under the radar.
I don't care, this is it, man.
I can feel it, okay? Let's go.
Hey. Can you hear me okay?
We made it inside.
We can hear you just fine.
All right, we're going in.
Hold on.
There are some workers in
the hallway in front of you.
[MUFFLED CHATTER]
Okay...
Okay, you're clear.
Sure you know where you're going?
Um, pretty sure.
The guard I borrowed
the memory from had only
been here a few times,
so it's a little hazy.
The transformer we need to take out
is in the middle of the building.
So why didn't you just portal us there?
CAITLIN: Hold up, there's a
conference room on your right.
Can you make a portal
through a hundred walls
into a room you've never seen before
and land safely next to a
high-voltage transformer?
- CAITLIN: Okay, you're clear.
- No.
Yeah. Neither can I.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
Incoming, door to your left.
What are you doing here?
Oh, did they not call?
From the front desk?
No, I didn't get a call.
Hang on just a sec.
Come on. You remember me.
Or maybe you don't remember.
Reed...
REED: Nice job, Sonya.
THUNDERBIRD: All right, remember,
once the Struckers take
down the transformer
at the power station, we
only have three minutes
to get the charges up
by the automated guns
- and get inside of Trask.
- Don't forget about the part
where if we're off by a few
seconds, we all get slaughtered.
- Marcos, not helpful.
- I'm sorry, it's just,
look, once we get in there,
we don't know what we're doing
or where we're going.
Well, that's why she's here.
First, we free the prisoners.
Then we destroy the
mainframes and the research.
Yeah, right. So these prisoners...
how do you know they're gonna help us?
Believe me, they'll help.
Okay, uh, the next few
hallways seem clear.
DREAMER: Got it. Thanks.
[CAITLIN SIGHS]
They're gonna be all right.
Yeah.
When you used to go on busts, how'd...
how did you deal with it... the nerves?
The first few times, I... I threw up.
Really? You never told me that.
Well, we were still dating.
I was trying to impress you.
I still am.
I found that if I
focused just on my plan,
it got better.
Now, our plan is to watch over the kids.
To keep them safe.
We'll get through this.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
WEEKS: Sir, I still don't buy it.
Do you really think they'd come here?
I thought they were going
after Campbell's lab.
They will. They will.
It's not a coincidence that the guard
that called in sick accessed specs
on this power substation.
I'm telling you, it's the mutants trying
to disable the lab
security before they go in.
Zone 1 is clear.
You're making a lot of leaps, here.
I mean, if the remote
units don't find anything,
we're done... you know that, right?
SS TECH 2: Pushing
past Zone 2. All clear.
SS TECH: Zone 3, clear. Advancing to 4.
Come on...
Sir. Remote unit just targeted.
We've got mutants.
Yes, we got 'em.
We got 'em, we're hot. Let's go!
Oh, my God.
Wait.
- Oh, my God.
- What is it? What did you see?
Hold on. I...
Oh...
Look! There.
Sonya, get out of there.
Get out of there now!
- CAITLIN: Get out of there!
- Wait, I don't understand.
- What's going on?
- Reed. Look!
There is a Sentinel robot and
arms teams in the building!
Get out of there now!
We got to go. Now.
- What the hell is going on?
- They know we're here.
- They're coming for us.
- JACE: All units move in.
All units move in.
Sir, the Sentinels... they
were destroyed last time.
Not this time. Techs have
been working with them.
They've been learning...
This time, they're ours.
- What about the power transformer?
- There's no time!
Clarice, you gotta get us out.
I don't even know where
we are in this building.
I don't know which direction.
The-the, there's too many
hallways, I don't know.
Hurry, please!
I-I-I know, I'm trying.
Okay. Okay, I got it!
Guys! Guys! Hey, guys, guys!
- Andy!
- Uh, yeah, m-move, move.
Move! [GROANING, STRAINING]
Run!
DREAMER: Clarice!
No!
Go! Go!
Reed.
Sonya? Sonya! Do you copy?
[SHRILL ELECTRIC FEEDBACK]
We have to go, Reed.
We have to help them!
We can't, we can't go in the
building, we'll get caught.
We can't help them if
we're captured, too.
[ALARM BLARING]
ECLIPSE: Hijo de perra...
What happened? Did somebody see us?
MAN [ECHOING]: We're on full lockdown!
MAN 2: Mutants tried to
hit the power station.
MAN 3: Sentinel Services caught 'em,
said we might be next...
No, they're not coming for us.
We got to go. Operation's
blown. Come on!
What? What? No. No, we-we can't go,
- we have to get in there!
- That's it.
- They have our team at the substation.
- I am not leaving.
- We have to get in there!
- We're going!
- Come on, it's over.
- No! No, please, my family.
- Don't make me leave them behind!
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- Come on.
- No! No...!
WOMAN [OVER P.A.]:
Attention, all employees.
This is not a drill. The
facility is under attack.
Observe full lockdown procedures.
REPEAT: full lockdown
procedures are in effect.
ANDY: What are we gonna do?
Sage gave me the codes.
[AGENTS SHOUTING]
- ANDY: Come on!
- LAUREN: They're coming!
DREAMER: Come on, hurry!
- Freeze!
- ANDY: Behind you!
- Run.
- LAUREN: Wait...
- Run!
- ANDY AND LAUREN: No, no, no!
AGENT: Get down on the ground, now!
[ALARM BLARING]
[INDISTINCT GUARD CHATTER]
We can get out.
We can get out if we
did what we did before.
Like Fenris.
- What are you doing?
- We can't...
- We have to!
- No. We're in the basement of the building.
If we do it,
everyone's gonna die.
- Stay where you are!
- [WEAPONS COCKING]
- JACE: Andy... Lauren.
- [LAUREN GASPS]
JACE: Don't move.
- REED: No.
- CAITLIN: Oh, my God. No!
No, Cait, what are you doing?
- Those are our children, Reed!
- We can't.
We can't. There's nothing we can do.
It's over.
Get on your knees.
- Reed, we can't just leave them.
- Cait, Cait...
[CAITLIN SOBBING]
Get on your knees, now.
[MOUTHING]
[COLLAR POWERS UP]
Oh, my God.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --