'Thanks to Kunnankulam
Guruvaayoor, Mullaseri residents'
'One shouldn't mock at
the deficiencies of a person'
'Because they are deficiencies
of the whole humanity'
'Swami Vivekananda'
'Celebrating 125th anniversary
of the spiritual leader of this era'
'We pay our respects
to his memory'
'Molikutty'
'What have you
prepared for supper?'
'- ls milk porridge ok?
- Sufficient'
After finishing that
Slice this too
Tomorrow morning forAppam
vegetable stew is the curry
- That would be better
- Then...
'When husband meekly surrenders
to wife a miracle happens'
'This truth is known as
'Peace in Family"
'Through his personal
experience it was discerned...'
'...by honourable district
magistrate Kuriakose'
Don't you require this?
What is it?
I need it
This is sufficient
I have kept here required
items for coconut milk
What are you waiting for?
Stan it soon
What is it?
These are your
encomiums for me
It was not for nothing
'Magistrate warns Cl'
There were clear-cut reasons
'Magistrate says Cl Radhakrishnan
is a disgrace for the state'
'If incompetent better quit
Magistrate tells Cl'
'An accused in over
70 cheque cases'
'He was a fraud'
But could you present him
at least once before me?
In 30 years of my court service
for the first time...
...l am seeing an accused like him
and an inefficient police officer like you
I agree sir
It is all my incompetence
Countless criminals who
escaped police's drag net...
...were all apprehended
by me with ease
But I admit I couldn't
tackle this guy
To atone that I have come
to meet you even at this odd time
ls midnight the time
for atonement?
Sorry sir
Xavier, bring him here
Greet you sir
He is the guy all these days
from your mouth I...
What?
I mean he made me hear
abuses from your mouth
He is the accused in
the 70 cheque cases
Vivekanandan
Name of the great
spiritual leader of India
- Have you heard about him?
- Yes, I know sir
Sri Ramakrishna Paramahamsa
swami's disciple Vivekanandan
Asanyasi who participated
in the World religion meet...
...at Chicago and enthralled
the entire world
Will there be any one in our country
who does not know him?
Being that great man's namesake
how could you do all these nonsense?
I was not named by me
My dad did that
I told my dad many times
this name would become an irritant
Sir, do you want to hear
my dad's response to that?
Swami Vivekanada said
Kerala is a 'lunatic asylum'
One day you would realise
the verity of what he said
That day you would respect your name
and also your dad who named you
That's great
Dad and son are great
I have a doubt
How did you manage so long
to escape his dragnet?
Did you not hear him?
There is a difference between
police and the accused in one respect
What is that?
The accused can run anywhere
But the police can only follow him
Sir, papers are ready
Are you going to remand me?
Right now
At this place?
A magistrate's place
is deemed as a court
I know that sir
Without even looking at the face of
the accused you would remand for 14 days
I know that too
But in this case
I have something to say
I pray be large-hearted
to hear me, sir
Let me hear
what he has to say
-ls it required sir?
- Stay out
Take this
Before Molikutty returns from
prayer slice all the vegetables
This is meant for
morning's vegetable stew
Sir
I have something
to share with you
I will hear you
You are not going to slice
vegetables with your tongue
It is with a knife
Carry on
- Sir
- Vivekananda
There are sufficient grounds
to remand you for 14 days
Yet I did not do that and am
prepared to hear what you have to say
Have you understood that?
So first slice vegetables
While doing so elaborate
your life story
Sir ginger
Should it be minced in mixer
or should it be fine sliced?
How was your life?
Do that way
tiff
"He doesn't know the tale
Yet he is great"
"The story that he
recounts is a beauty"
"Ajourney without
any rectitude"
"But it has a drama
not known until now“
"Amidst slickers
He is an handsome guy"
"His sweet tongue
always gets him troubles"
"It is true, he is canny"
"He is a glutton too"
"He needs thick griddlecake"
"Wants good chicken curry too"
"Rice flakes, dhall ada
or vada (Indian snacks)"
"These drum rhythms
express joy"
tiff
"When he forced all
these into his throat"
"He could not utter or speak"
"All his game plans failed"
"He changed his strategy"
"He could neither
move nor learn"
"Poor young boy
His psyche is young"
"But he would be darling
in the times to come"
"He doesn't know the tale
Yet he is great"
"The story that he
recounts is a beauty"
"Ajourney without
any rectitude"
"But it has a drama
not known until now“
"Amidst slickers
He is an handsome guy"
"His sweet tongue
always gets him troubles"
"It is true, he is canny"
"He is a glutton too"
"He needs thick griddlecake"
"Wants good chicken curry too"
"Rice flakes, dhall ada
or vada (Indian snacks)"
"These drum rhythms
express joy"
tiff
'Paalathra Balakrishnan'
'He is my dad'
'He was a middle level
leader of our place'
'He fought for our
justifiable needs always'
This government could not give
us even a drop of water
I use this opportunity to say
they are the curse of this nation
'I was the only
male child for him'
'After politics
he liked me most'
'He manifested his love
for me this way'
'Liberation from imperialism'
'Banish imperialism'
'Down with Japan
drinking water scheme'
'Check mafia'
Dear
I got this from
your dad's pocket
'When the entire world
is sinking down...'
'...there will be no
liberation for you alone'
'Happily I am handing
over my debts to you'
'You redeem it'
'Pay attention to
an important thing'
'My letter's content
should never be...'
'...revealed to your mom
or your siblings at any cost'
'I don't mind even
if they come to know'
'Sathi sister'
'She is my elder sister'
'Next to my dad
she loved me most'
Mere 50 soverigns
and 1.5 acres of...
...rocky land with no water was
the dowry given for me
But when I ask 5 lakhs...
...for my hubby to start a business
I have become a baddy
What dad earned through politics
is solely devoured by you
lam only asking
a share from that
Have water
Drink water
I must get the money
If you don't give...
...don't think you both can
live here peacefully
- ls that so?
- I mean you also
'This is how sister
showed her love for me'
'Brother-in-law Sethu
Sathy sister's husband'
'Poor fellow'
'He was very
com passionate'
If you don't give 5 lakhs, same way
I would break everything...
...and set fire to this house
Come on lady
'He didn't know a better way
to express his compassion'
Brother, what have you
decided in my case?
'Younger sister Geetha'
'As her brother
I was her role model'
What?
- I am past 24
- That is not my fault dear
All my friends are married
and have 2 kids
It is not because of
lack of proposals
- It's because you didn't give your consent
- How will I give consent?
Sister was given 50 soverigns
and 1.5 acres of land
I must surely get 75 soverig ns
If you have no plans
to give that...
I swear on our dead dad
I would elope with some one
With whom?
Lots of them are after me
With any one of
those mean fellows
But don't think after that...
Saint Vivekananda can
call himself my brother
Viveka brother
Do you recogonise me?
Are you not
contractor Krishnan's son?
Yes, for quite some time
I was trying to see you
- See me
- I have seen you
But I have something
to talk to you
Go on, go on
Your sister Geetha
and me are in love
It is 7 years since
we started loving
I am ready to marry her
without a penny as dowry
But she is not prepared
75 soverigns of gold
Have you seen my head?
I have lost all my hair
But I haven't yet
shown this to Geetha
Before I take charge
of the 75 soverigns...
...as each day passes
the remaining hair will also fall
At last when the goods are ready
and if Geetha refuses to marry me
That day I would stab you
Shall I take leave of you?
'Mother'
'She was the only person in this
world who did not love me'
'She expressed her
dislike for me every day'
Have one more SOH
Enough, belly is full
But you didn't eat much
Those days you would eat
many dosa's in one go
That was long ago mom
Today's Vivekanadan is different
That's right! Of late,
you have changed a lot
All the time you are
running helter-skelter
SiOP
Stay there
Stay there man
'Running away from
the debtors of dad'
'Mom was referring
to this run'
Lord Gurvaayoorappa
Save me
Pray earnestly
He would save you
But he would
test you before that
If you get over the test
You are safe
Lord Narayana
'A test before protection'
'My friend Naijeeb Kaichery
gave me such a test'
SiOP
Was there only sufferings
and miseries in your life?
Amidst the turmoil created
by your dad and sisters...
...did you ever had
moments of happiness?
Did not God
give you that?
I can't get you sir
Did anyone love you?
Amidst these adversities
did any girl...?
Did no girl come
in to your life?
Yes sir! There was
a girl in my life
Roo pa
Then now narrate
that love story
Sir Naijeeb Kaichery is
cycling all the way
Let him come
Narrate this first
When she entered your life?
Was there a dip or appreciation
in Roopa's value? (pun-rupee)
Based on international
market fluctuations...
...the rupee soars high
or gets devalued sir
Who was that
international market?
- In other words the US guy?
- Her brother
Sub inspectorAjith Kumar
Shall we go?
Hold tightly
I know many people
who ogled that girl
But her police brother
demolished all of them
Have you understood up to this?
Yes, understood up to this
Even otherwise your debtors
are waiting to thrash you
Amidst this do you
want to make...
...the home department
also to your foe list?
No, I don't have
such desires
- Are you sure?
- Yes
Then get on to the cycle
Let's leave the place quickly
'Thus I decided to forget her'
'Her house'
'The route she passes through'
'Her music class'
'I tried to avoid
going to these places'
Where has she gone?
Foolish girl
Are you...?
My God
Learn to read
So as we discussed?
Let things move on
Give money before you go
What did you say?
Money
Have you not
recogonised me?
How can you ask money
to a social worker?
Aren't you ashamed?
I would hold a poet's
meet and pay your debts
You...!
It's alright! For the time
being I forgive you
Pay and leave man
For the time being have this
Balance I will
pay you tomorrow
But don't repeat this any more
Poor fellow
He is scared
Naijeeb
Naijeeb I got the phone
I shelled out
6000 rupees for this
lfl had so much money...
...l would have paid at least
interest amount of one debtor
Vivekananda, this is
the period of globalization
These days the expenditure
for love would be more
Olden days love letters are
replaced by these mobile phones
There I have a doubt
We haven't talked to each other
We haven't even
exchanged glances
In such a situation
giving a mobile phone...
...as a gift to that
girl would be
What do you know about
the popularity of a mobile phone?
This is not
a mere mobile phone
This is a questionnaire
Question number 1
Do you love
someone else?
Does she?
If the answer
is in the affirmative...
...she would not accept
this phone and reject it
That's right! But that
does not solve the issue
Though I am older to her
she must like me
What should I do for that?
- It depends on how smartly you talk
- Then let me try
Vivekananda
For all the love affairs in this world
we social workers extend our support
That's why though initially
I dissuaded you nowl am with you
Now after you present this gift to her
if we happen to meet we will meet again
What is this guy saying?
Brother is not at home
I did not come to meet brother
I have come to meet you
- To meet me?
- Yes
What's the matter?
There's an young guy in this town
who loves you more than his ATM card
Through this Bluetooth phone
he wants to express his love to you
Haven't you understood?
Please happily accept his gift
You...!
Tell me what happened afterwards
What I feared happened
Why did you get this model?
Can't you buy an iPhone?
Not I phone
your phone, it's your phone
iPhone, I mean iPhone
Oh you mean phone
We can get that
You first call him
Then tell him that
you got the gift
What was that phone?
My phone?
Not my phone, it's iPhone
Yes that phone would
come to you in no time
Then I would call him right now
Tell me the number
984704263-
My God, brother
What is this guy doing here?
What should I say?
Greet you sir
I came to see you sir
Our club is celebrating
National language day
You should inaugurate
the function
I can clobber you
I don't know anything else
What's it girl?
Go in
Then I would invite
you for wrestling
Heymhey
ls the tyre deflated?
Here...here
What is the last number?
- Is it one?
- No, it is four
- ls it four?
- Four
- Ok
- Bye
Did you say four?
My number ends in one
Vivekananda
People normally say
social workers are idiots
I am not like that
In case SI gets
the number from her...
...and take away the guy
Who would be affected?
Me?
No, he would be affected
The unfortunate guy
whose number ends with 4
In a nutshell this means
my 6000 rupees is gone
When I talk about glorious love
don't talk about petty things like money
How will I keep quiet
The loss is mine
We can capitalise everything
I am not available for a week
To study about simple living there is
a camp of social workers at Taj Hotel
When I return from the camp
I would visit the house once again
What for?
Then I would tell her
last digit is one and not four
Then will I not become
the unfortunate guy?
Symbolically indicating
your union...
...that number would be stored
in her heart's memory card
Until such time you dream
Make her yours at least
in dream Vivekananda
Dream Vivekananda
'If it had been a film, this is
the right situation for a song'
'But there are
no songs in real life'
'Sol passed that
one week this way'
My god, it is locked
Brother, is there no one?
- They are not here
- Where have they gone?
They shifted to some other
place one month ago
She had gone sir
She left the town
and the house
That day I didn't know why she left
or where she had gone
Didn't you inquire?
No sir, I have suffered
many losses in life
That was also one of them
Pathetic
I thought you
would have got her
Not when you get
when you lose, love becomes eternal
Naijeeb consoled me like that
As you said
he was cycling all the way
What happened to the new idea
he was talking about...
...the new experiment
It is good times for you
Your brother in law Sethu...
...who quarreled and left
you for not giving 5 lakhs
- Wants to meet you
- What for?
I don't want to meet any one
Not for asking money from you
- He wants to help you
- Help me?
Yes, he has learnt about
your plight somehow
How?
ls he not your
brother in law?
- Will he not feel bad about it?
- Yes, that's rig ht
Besides he is
financially well off now
His business is flourishing
God it would be good
if he is well off
Vivekananda, you must go
Fortune is tapping your doors
Don't try to ignore it
Just get on bike with
your right foot forward
Hold it
What a set up is this?
Greet you, Sethumathavan
-105
- Thank you
Come in
What is it?
What happened?
Nothing wrong with me
You are very much reduced
What happened to you?
Nothing wrong with me
Brother in law
Nothing wrong with him too
Come and sit down
What happened
to this lady?
- You know Mr...
- Kecheri, social worker
Vivekanandan may be
angry with me
When I didn't get
the money I wanted...
...l had broken precious
household items
That was not his fault
That was because of
my incomprehension
It's alright
What happened
because of that?
Vivekananda
When I didn't get the money I wanted
I worked hard for that
Nowl own a big industry
But no use talking about that
God has pushed me to a stage
where I can't manage it single handedly
Last week I was
in the hospital
I had an heart attack
Doctor says I may need
an immediate bypass surgery
You must help me out
lam handing over it
to you from today...
...the responsibilities of
running my business empire
Yes
As I am being lack of children...
You must run the business
as your own business
Tomorrow he has called for
a meeting of the clients
There I will officially
declare your appointment
All the best
Thank you
Hello
My brother in law has given
me a big responsibility
I will do my level best to carry out
the responsibilities thrust on me
I take this opportunity to give
that assurance to you all
Thank you
I knew long ago
he is very affectionate
It is my son's good fortune
Brother if you are
managing the company...
...will they not provide you
big quarters for your stay?
Not quarters
It is called villa
I have asked the astrologer to find
an auspicious date for shifting
Will you not take us
also with you?
Why do you talk like that?
When it is happy
events for me...
...how will it be happier
when you all are not with me?
- Good brother
- Do it fast mom
tiff
Driver! I can't find
anyone here
Who would come to
a company that is closed?
Closed?
Yes, this company was
locked out 3 months ago
Naijeeb
No way
No company can be closed
without our knowledge
- How can you say that?
- We only make them close down
Don't kid
Call brother in law
'The subscriber you call...'
Greet you
- What happened?
- This number is not in use
- Greet you
- Greetings
Settle my dues first
I am always the first
person to give loans to Sethu
I am also in that category
No ruckus please
Sethu's brother in law has come here
to settle the dues of all of us
- Can we start now?
- What is it?
Disbursement of money
The amount that
is due from Sethu
Have you forgotten
your promise so soon?
Finish it off quickly
We have to leave
for some urgent work
One minute
Seems it is going out of our control
Call Sethu's number once again
This number is
not in existence
Seems he has trapped you
in this and has escaped
What will I do now?
How will I pacify them?
How did you managed to
pacify such people earlier...
...do the same thing
tiff
Don't chase me anymore
I would jump
- Don't jum p
-I would
Then jump man
Come
Come fast
This is a kin to a miserable guy
getting a petrol vehicle as dowry
Exactly
Who was the guy staring
at you from the vehicle?
- Which vehicle?
- In this vehicle
They have a photo
of yours with them
Yes, yes I am about
to talk about that
Please be patient sir
'In the rest period between two
of my fleeing these people came'
Are you not Vivekanandan?
So what?
Tiff
Tell me the truth
- Are you guys paid killers?
- Yes
I will not asks you
who has sent you...
...because all those people whom
I owe money have that rights
Before I die I would like to
talk to my grandma
Don't have such hopes
Yes she is hopeless, bedridden
That's why I want to talk to her
- At least can I talk to my mom?
- Not possible
Don't you have
mom and sisters?
Don't prattle
Sit quiet
Don't make us exert
tiff
70 cheque cases
But not caught in any of them
Neither police nor court...
...or the people who lend
him money on interest
...could catch him
in their dragnet
In that perspective
you are the right guy...
...to be emulated by those
who borrow money in Kerala
You are an expert conman
Vivekanandan, do you
know Pappachan sir?
Running a private
financial institution...
...in many pans of Kerala
A poor business man
You may know when I say
the name of the institution
- Elamuttam financier
- I know, I know
Long ago I have pledged
some gold in your institution
But you didn't redeem it
It was auctioned
Then my circumstances
were like that
Circumstances are
the real troubles
Circumstances only make
a man a killer or a saint
You have come before us
because of your circumstances
Not yours, my institutions...
Those guys have come
Has boss gone?
What brother?
- Bastard why did you do that?
- I didn't do it purposely
- You, idiot
- My god!
Was that your
dad's money?
If you don't pay the money
you would be...
Take him away
It is nothing
He is our Coimbatore
branch Manager
He did a small deceit
This is my response for that
I was asking
an explanation from him
Only after getting the explanation
I take disciplinary actions
Sir, you haven't told me
why you called me
We need a manager for
our Kadapuram branch
If you accept
I would be very happy
You might ask me on what
basis I offer you this job?
70 cheque cases
Elusive guy
That smartness is
your credential
All these days I was
on the lookout for...
...a genuine person who
could outsmart conmen
In Kadapuram branch
many people get loans
Loans are given against
mortgage of land documents
They would only borrow money
But no one would repay
even a single rupee
And if we go for inquiry...
Whom do you think would
come out of the house?
Might be male members
of the house
If you come here
asking for money...
...l would slash your
and give it to the lamb
My god
She is a good cultured lady
Males get loans
and go hiding
I have to somehow
take them to boss
If I do that...
...boss has promised to
take care of my lenders
That's a good deal
But how will you take
them before boss?
Somehow we have to...
But you have
the documents with you
What if we confiscate their
movable and immovable properties
Asking for the loan money...
...if anyone goes there to
confiscate their properties
No one would return
alive from there
What is required is not might
we should use our intelligence
You're fortunate because
I have more than required
- What...?
- I mean intelligence
At last it will be
useful for you
You need not do such
rashness for my sake
- I know what to do
- I mean...
Dear Kadapuram residents
Biggest conference
against money lenders
Against higher interest
rates and exploitation...
...of private financial institutions
a united opposition by borrowers
On November 25th
at Community Hall...
...those borrowers whose property and life
are intimidated because they borrowed money
Bear this in mind
and participate
This is a last opportunity
Attend the conference and liberate
yourselves from the debts and liabilities
Hello testing
Mike testing
Dear Kadapuram residents
We did a secret survey here
Elam uttam Pappachan
He and his financial institutions have
lent money to many people on interest
To recover the money lent
he is indulging in acts against...
...humanitarian considerations
we have information on that
But we must shut him away
That is our aim
To achieve that all of you must participate
in the meeting to be held at Community Hall
This is an humble
appeal to all of you
So if we attend the meeting
don't we have to repay the money?
- You need not
- Then we would attend
We would attend
and be smart
'Kadapuram borrowers
at the meeting hall...'
'...were handled by Pappachan's
goons they way they wanted'
'Thus the meeting
became a grand one'
'No, don't hit us
We would'
"Rivers, mountains, gardens
For earth..."
- Boss
- Who is it?
- It's me Viveanandan
- You scared me
You honoured your word
- Now it is my turn, isn't it?
- Yes, you are right
For 3 months none of your
lenders would trouble you
These 3 months
you would work...
...as a manager in one of the branches
of Edam uttam Financiers
If it is Kadapuram branch they would
whip me with flap nose ray fish tail
You need not go there
I have found
another place for you
After seeing your work in that branch
I would decide about other things
- I have another request
- What's it?
If you can provide him
also somejob...?
- What are you credentials?
- I am a social worker
ls that your credential?
He does that because
he has no other options
- Then let him do recovery
- What do you say?
Recovery manager
Confiscating vehicles
Head for that wing
Many thanks
Take it from me Vivekananda
If boss likes, you think
your times have changed
You...thrash
If he doesn't like me...?
Then also think
your times have changed
This is the manager's cabin
This is the locker key
This is not a mere key
You can open heaven
and hell with this key
Decide what you want
by your acts
Have you seen this?
This is ginger
- Ginger?
- Yes ginger
We call gold as ginger
Ginger does not merely mean
dried ground ginger root
It also means
pep and prowess
It's true, if we possess this
liveliness and energy are different
These are pledged items
This represents aspirations
and failures of many people
You must handle it with
great responsibility
lf something negative happens here
it would solely be due to your negligence
If something positive
happens here...
...rightful credit for that
would go to Elamuttam
Lord Gurvayurappa
Make everything fine
- What happened?
- It's over sir
Who said it's over?
You are just going to start
Do you know
to slice a fish?
- Fish
- It's very easy
-ls it?
- Yes!
If you have
any doubt ask me
Yesterday when I went to market
I got good sardines
When it comes to taste and quality
no other fish can match sardines
- Do you know that?
-Yes, I know
Then make a fine
start to slicing it
- Take this
- I mean
I just gave a fine start to
my manager's job there
I have not forgotten that
All these days
you were a vegan
From now on you are
going to become a non-vegan
Like a good sour and
spicy sardine curry
Stan slicing
While you slice
tell me the remaining story
You are right sir
Eating onions, sambar
and curd rice...
...l was leading a peaceful
life in Elamuttam finance
Suddenly took a U turn
and became non-vegan
Like this dried sour sardine
- Excuse me
- Sit down
I am Roopa
I had pledged an item here
I have come to redeem it
That's ok
Where is the card?
I have it with me
Vivekananda
Roopa (pun-rupee)
I don't have
Go from here
Not that, I mean
the other Roopa
- Where?
- Look there
- You mean Roopa?
- Yes, she only
Is it?
-It is she only
-ls it?
- Thanks
- Okay
Roo pa
Do you recogonise me?
Just brush up your memory
You are the guy who turned
my life upside down
9847042634
That was because
I committed a small mistake then
Because of my scare
for your police brother...
...l deliberately made a small
change in the last digit alone
Four instead of one
It was not a small change
You didn't bear in mind
the distance from 1 to 4 is big
Now that one...is sitting inside
If you don't mind,
you can meet him
He is the guy
Vivekanandan
Sit down
What is it?
What?
I was just thinking
about my folly
I don't know when
girls like me would realise...
...what is required is not
beauty but intelligence
No, Roopa's...
Value
No life...
Value is a better word
That has come down
My police brother met
with an accident
Very glad!
- Did he die?
- No
Didn't you guys know
he is bedridden with paralysis?
No when was it?
We didn't know
When was it?
After a while we shifted
from that place
What made you come here?
I had pledged few ornaments here
I came to redeem it
- Sorry
- Yes
Are you here?
ls your work over?
Mohan meet
Mr Vivekanandan
I am the manager
of this branch
Don't you know Mohan?
The wrong digit
that you gave me 4
Mohan he is the real
owner of that phone
So instead of him
I entered your life
As far as I was concerned
it was a wrong call
That too from a beautiful girl
like Roopa in her beautiful voice
When she asked me
did you send this phone?
I could not say 'no'
In a way what I did to
Vivekanandan is a betrayal
But your friend who
gave the wrong number...
...also did the same
betrayal to you
If she had given
the phone and number...
...to his police brother and
asked him to break my ribs
What would have
happened to me?
But she didn't do it
She would not do it because...
...my poor Roopa
knows only to love
Because of your
folly I lost her
Giving a wrong last digit
has caused me a loss
Do you know what that
loss has cost me?
When he said
'My Roopa'...
...l was shattered
Do you know that?
Each girl has a destiny
as it is written in each groin
No I meant grain
God has written in each girl's
forehead her hubby's name
Roopa was destined
to be Mohan's wife
You, me and that mobile
was just a cause
Anyway that girl was saved
That's enough
Will you please get down?
Genuine friends
must be like you
- That's it
- I am very glad
ls the distance to home
7 kilometers from here?
- Yes, might be
- You pig, walk the distance
- Go man
- Stop!
I can't get any vehicle
even for hire from here
That is your fortune
You mean me losing her?
To spoil the peace of men folk
women have emerged in earth as demons
Gold and women bring
conflicts in this world easily...
...is Kunjan Nambiar's maxim
Do you believe he
wrote it for nothing?
Kunjan Nambiar merely wrote it
But it's me who experienced it
I experienced it
to a great extent
Vivekanandan
You have a lucky charm
After meeting you many
positive things happened to me
We were planning
to buy an house
There was some
glitch over price
Yesterday night its
owner came and told us...
...he agrees for
the price we demanded
To pay the advance amount
we need 10 lakh rupees
There is no use in
keep in gold at home
Pledge this and give
me 10 Lakh rupees
One minute
Sivag ami
Bring 10 Lakh rupees
cash to cabin quickly
Sir cash
You need not
pledge the entire lot
You can take back
anyone of them
That...l don't know
what to choose
You may take one
and give it to me
- My God, me
- No issues
In case Naijeeb had said
1 instead of 4 that day...
...you would have been
my life partner
Then take this
This would be
fine for you
Vivekanandan
This is called
the congruence of mind
I also thought of
the same chain
Please sign here
- Keep it in the locker
- Okay sir
The loss is not yours
It is mine
Mr. Mohan...?
Your relationship
with Mohan...?
Are you not happy?
There are no retake's
in life Vivekanandan
Today my life is a mobile number
with a wrong last digit
- Boss asked you to come
- Okay, I will
Greet you boss
ls your house document
with the co-operative bank?
Yes! Why do you
ask about that sir?
- Any confiscation?
- Yes...!
But not for the house
It is for you
Who is she?
- She is Roopa
- I asked who is she to you?
She is my friend
So was it a joint
deceit by you both?
You son of a dog
Not only to nurture you
I also know to weed out
Look at this
This is all gold coated
Gold coated jewels
Mohan Menon Tushar Villa
#13, Pavaratty
The green walled one
- This is the one
- We must behave decently
- ls there no one here?
- Softly, go in and ask
Sir
Who is it?
We've come
to see Mr Mohan
Who is Mohan?
- No 13, TusharVilla
- Address is right
But no one called
Mohan lives here
We mean Roopa's
husband Mohan
There is no one called
Mohan or Roopa here
This is my house
Someone has misguided you
Sir, we would leave after
meeting Mohan once
Please go, please
Like your brother in law
She has deceived you
For offences like this
Pappachan sir's punishment...
...was breaking both limbs and
sell to some mendicant company
But in my case he
made a small waiver
I will give you
one month's time
By that time bring
either cash or ginger
If you don't bring
either of them...
Not only you...
...your mom and your sisters
would also suffer
Do anything to me
but leave them
When you have good times
who are the beneficiaries?
Your near and dear
ls it not?
So when you have bad times
should they not share that too?
You may 9°
I don't mind even
if you kill someone
But come with cash
- That is...
- What happened?
Ahmed Kuttty sir has
stopped money lending
He says if he lends
the loss will be twofold
He will lose the money
and also the relationship
I have again inquired
through many channels
There are people to lend
against mortgaged documents
But you would not get it
Because your
track record is so bad
What will I do now?
10 Lakhs in one month
My God, how will I make it up?
One way is
'Tomorrow is the draw day'
You must win a lottery
or you should steal
Stealing?
'Discipline
Responsibility'
'Intelligence
Achieve goals'
Theft is not a thing that
any vagabond can do so easily
That is an an
So the thief is an artist
'Kesavan'
'He is the ever green hero
of the art called theft'
'He is based in this field
for quite some years'
'But he is never
nabbed in any case'
'He runs classes for new thieves sneakily
in the driving school he owns'
'Case study classes about classical
thieves are Kesavan's current activity'
What happened Kesava?
ls what I wanted ready?
Giving me a task...
...and praying to Lord
Guruvayurappan are same
Both would happen
But there is a difference
Guruvayurappan would not steal
But Kesavan would steal
Come
This is great
How did you
manage to get this?
It was parked in
a workshop for repair
I went there in a cops
uniform to drive it here
When the hero is chased
by the villain cop...
...l need a vehicle to be
pushed to the ravine
What to do?
I am a film
production controller
I have to arrange for
things the director demands
There will be film shooting
in this area for a month
I may require
some more properties
I would come later
Call the set guy
'When Kesavan heard
about our problems...'
'...he promised to help us'
'But even then
I was against theft'
What's it?
Even if you are to die, don't steal
was my mom's advice
We are now stealing
to save that mom's life
You know about Papachan sir
He means business
Theft is not a bad thing
This is a kind of inspiration
- Inspiration?
- Yes
Have you seen the recent films?
Most of them are about stealing
If you ask them they would say
it was an inspiration
We have also inspired others
What you want
is Rs 10 lakhs
There are houses who
don't want that money...
...that inspires us
That is neither
a wrong nor a sin
Instead it is a rig ht
It's the right of a guy
who needs money
He is right
'I was dead against theft'
But I decided to go
Move forward
There are 3 kinds of people
Lower, upper and middle
We have to get in to
the upper class guys house
Similarly there are
houses of different types
Houses with good features
without good features...
...that can be made good
that can never be made good
In other words troublesome
We should select a house
with good features
Feng shui is not
a deceitful concept
As I understand it
It's also a science like theft
How is this house?
- Not bad
- But it is bad
The feng shui is wrong
The kitchen is at a wrong place
So there will be low peace of mind
Whose peace of mind?
- Yours
- Wife's
When wife's peace of mind is lost
how bad this house would be...?
So we should
discard such houses
Houses with good features are like
women untouched by men
Such houses would
tempt you to visit them
They would tell you
'come and steal me'
They would yell
at us this way
Like this
Look there
This house is
the most ideal one
Well featured
in all respects
How was my comment?
Is it not ideal in all respects?
Have a look
Master bed room
is at south corner
Kitchen is at South west corner
North west for
another bed room
The omen is also good
No more inquires are required
We would fix this
- Can we fix it?
- Fixed
This is the key
for the house
But I don't know
which one is the key?
Let's try with
any one of them
'Use that key
to open the gate'
'After opening
the gate you get in'
'Now open the door
and enter the hall'
'The bedroom is after that'
'The main bureau
is in bedroom'
'That lady would have
taken one of the keys'
'Another key is inside
the fish tank in living room...'
'...beneath the conch'
Come
Here is the conch
'Go there, enter,
take the key...'
'Open the safe and...'
'Take the amount not required
by them and then return'
'What do you say?'
Any way we have stolen
Why not take it entirely?
No Kaichery
I prayed Lord Guruvayurappan
so that I can replace it some day
Let's take only 10
1, 2, s, 4, s, s, 7, s, 9 and 10
Lord Krishna, save us
Gently
Hi
My God
Lift, lift
Whom do you
want me to lift?
Lift your hands dog
Don't move forward
If you move,
I would kill you
Forgive us
So you need
10 Lakh rupees, right?
No sir, we don't want
We don't want a penny
from this house
Yes, instead allow us to go
Leaving this house
will you not go to another house?
No sir, we would not go
We are from
respectable families
I am a social worker too
Then how will you
redeem Pappachan's debt?
Tell me, how will you redeem?
I don't know sir
Shall I help you?
Don't mock at us sir
It was out of helplessness
I know, that's why I asked
Shall I give you
10 lakh rupees?
Not as a gift
in return you do me a help
What help?
A person has to be killed
Kill a person?
Should I take the pistol?
No sir!
God has sent
you guys before me
This house is full of
hidden camera's
From the moment
you entered the house...
...everything is recorded
in those camera's
If I handover that
to the police...
...l hope you can guess
what would happen
I don't want you guys to be behind bars
for a wrong not committed by you
But you should also
reciprocate that gesture
Whom are you
asking us to kill?
Venkiti
My friend called
Venkitakrishnan
He is my foe now
'Venkitakrishnan is
a jack of all trades'
'He is an expert in over 10 languages
including foreign languages'
'But he showed his
skills in another domain'
'In a domain called women'
'He was the greatest
womaniser I have ever seen'
'He could take any woman
known to him to his bed'
'No one could match
his skill of alluring women'
- Do you know one thing?
- What is it?
Our new MD
Susamma verghese-
- Are you fine?
- Yes
Come
Yesterday night she slept
at my house in my bed
Similarly countless women
were at his bed
I don't know if it is
out of rage or jealousy...
I challenged him over
People whom I
thought were virtuous
What's it man?
New copywriter Tanuja warrier
Can you bewitch her?
Come to my house tonight
You can see me with Warrier
Hi
- What is this?
- Come
Ginseng, asparagus,
sarsaparilla
Ashwagantha and Chamomile petals
Mix all these in boiled oil
Roots of milk tree,
nuts of thorn tree, Maca root
...crush all these and mix
it in dried cow's milk
Mus“ roots, garden crass
and anethcﬂe...
...mix all these in equal quantities
and add Fritillaria roylei
Grind it add sugar
cow's milk, ghee...
...fry and make it
as a flat cake
I consume this daily
Then will I not be like this?
I have memorised his recipe
Ginseng, asparagus, sarsaparilla
Ashwagantha and Chamomile petals
Mix all these in boiled oil
Roots of milk tree,
nuts of thorn tree, Maca root
Crush all these and mix
it in dried cow's milk
Mus“ roots, garden crass
and anethcﬂe...
...mix all these fry
and make it a flat cake
Let me try ifl can
overcome Molikutty?
You do your work
You would have noticed
a girl going out from this house
Devaki, my wife
I don't have kins or kith
She was a gift to me
by the period of time
We loved for 6 months
and then got married
I was thrilled and believed
entire world was beneath me
But that happiness
did not last long
'I was tested
through an accident'
'The tragedy happened
during my honeymoon'
Now Devika is working
as a subordinate to him
lam sure he would
have marked Devika
That is my apprehension
Before that happens
he should die
Not for my sake alone
For the sake of all those men...
...who have wives and sisters
For the sake of all women
You must also understand
what you're going to do is not a sin
Venkitakrishnan must die
He does not deserve to live
Nothing to ponder over this
Don't accept that offer
Vivekanandan, murder
is not like theft
It is a sin
Humans don't have rights
to kill life given by God
Absolutely right
Not only that
The section would be 302
Can get up to
death sentence
I knew all these
But my mind did not
go through the good path
It was a night where
I had lost everything
What have you decided?
We agree
But we wouldn't
kill Venkitakrishnan
Then?
We would kill her
Your wife Devika
Let it be any man
anywhere in the world...
...however great
a seducer he is
...he can't even touch
a woman without her consent
When Venkitakrishnan
attempts to seduce them...
...if the women are ready to fall
a prey are they not to be blamed?
Anyway unfortunately your wife is
at the edge of such a situation
To start with
it would be interesting
Later it becomes habitual
As days pass by it would become
an unavoidable necessity
In between, you would become
an impediment to your wife's merry making
Afterwards like
any other woman...
...she would think about
getting away from you
Even now you
are sitting like this
She would not find it
difficult to do away with you
You don't know
you are sleeping with a foe
You must understand
that at least now
One who welcomes
will only become popular
So she is the wrong doer
from start to end
And she alone
Then what did he decide?
On one side he had great love for his
wife who was like this boiling milk
On the other side like this tea
dust...there was Venkitakrisnan
If one tea spoon of
Venkitakrishnan falls in the milk...
...the resultant one would not be his
wife whom he thought was his own
Instead she would be
an altogether changed Devika
When he realised this
he gave his consent
But on one condition
That she should never
know he was the killer
- Can little sugar be added?
- What do you say?
I asked ifl can
add sugar for you?
Little sugar will do
So a short tea break
tiff
Why do you think so much?
You could just place it here
Aren't you ashamed man?
How could you play like a child
with an accused brought by police?
Have you finished your prayers?
Molikutty he has stopped the story
at a critical juncture
Agirl is about to die
Thought about a small relaxation
before I come to know about it
Molikutty come this side
Though I hear his story
I consider his story as a statement
Only after knowing
what happened to the girl...
...l have to decide if he is to
be remanded or punished
Until then please
don't disturb me
Continue man
You need not stop talking
becausel am here
I would go
- She is my husband
- What?
I mean wife
What happened later, tell me?
Wanted to build a close
relationship with Devika...
...whom I was supposed to kill
So that I can
kill her anytime later
That was my plan
tiff
'NRl'
'After making a fortune overseas
returns to Kerala with business plans'
'Non resident Indian'
'My advent was
in that disguise'
Please come
- Come
- Thank you
Please
- Good morning ma'am
- Good morning
- Can we...?
- Sure
Thank you
'Devika was a marketing
head in Metro consultancy'
'To establish close connections with her
there was no other better alternative'
Many people do not know the role
of a consultant in a business venture
A good start is
half the battle won
No body does
even remember this
These are successful products
designed and marketed by us
It's all because we do
our home work correctly
- That's rig ht
- Now tell me
What kind of business
you have in mind?
Anything!
See ma'am we-
- Liquor
- What?
Liqour...!
Even ifjust only
one Malayali is alive...
...it is a commodity that
would surely be sold
sorry
Liquor does not require a market study
or consultancy in Kerala
- Ma'am we-
- Please
- Will you please come out?
- What for?
- Come
- Why?
Please come
ls the seafood
product's file ready?
Who asked you to talk
about liquor business?
Why? Was not
that you idea?
Then we can now
change the business
If we change now,
it may not make sense
They would think
we are not serious
Think how we can take
advantage of the faux pas
Come
Are you going
back again?
Come man
Come on man
Has she gone?
Are you serious about it?
- Might require some investment
- Approximately
Must require about 50 lakhs
That would not be a problem for us
Excuse me
- Please
- Just a minute
Please
For years I toiled overseas
and made a fortune
If I don't have the rights to decide
what business I should do...
...it is really difficult
Madam, do you know
about one thing?
Kerala is ranked first in
alcohol consumption in India
I did not say you should
not venture in to business
I just said that doesn't
require a consultancy's services
Why is it not required?
That's my question
Among normal liquor consumers of
Kerala which is consumed more...
...Branddy, Whisky, Rum or-
I don't want to
hear all these
I have difficulty in accepting
this proposal of yours
That's what I ask
Why is it so?
- Devika
- One second sir
This business of
yours is anti social
It is opposed to the society
I am personally against
promoting such a product
Why?
That's what I am asking
Hello
Excuse me ma'am
It is a hectic day
I can't Krishnan
Don't cry!
Move away
I have a severe headache
I can't tolerate this
Don't weep
I am with you
Cool! Compose yourself
To tell you the truth, I can't
tolerate such anti social elements
He has come with
a business proposal
Come on
Damn with his
In fact we went there
to become close with her...
But see what happened
We had to fight with
her and break apart
It's all because of Kesavan
Did I know it would
happen like that?
I feel it is all for good
Using this dispute we can
establish a relationship with her
Relationship?
- He does not mean that relationship
- I have a doubt
- Where did she go with that pencil?
- Not pencil Venkiti
Both are same
Where did she go?
To his house, where else?
Without clear evidences never raise
such a charge against a woman
That is not honourable
Will you be satisfied with
the evidence of Venkiti's servant?
Sir and madam came here
They were here
for 3 to 4 hours
Then I went straight
to Harinarayanan
Your wife was
at Venkiti's house...
...where he is staying
alone for 3 to 4 hours
You can imagine what would
have happened there
No, you need not
wait anymore
She must die
as early as possible
Madam this is the plan
It must include the company's
requirements as given in their bio
Like id proof
and other similar things
Good morning ma'am
- Who permitted them to enter?
- They wanted to meet you madam
- I don't want to meet any one
- Excuse me, I have to tell you something
Madam said she does
not want to meet you
lam also a client
Sorry sir, madam is
not interested
Madam's interest is
not my problem
As a client I have
my own rights
- Excuse me
- Yes
I will explain,
please come
Sorry sir, I haven't come to meet you
I want to meet Devika madam
Hello you can meet her
But I have something to talk to you
Okay come
Liquor is the villain
that shattered Devika's life
Devika's husband is
now on wheel chair
A punishment given
by God for drunken drive
That may be the reason
Devika behaved like that to
your liquor business plans
Anyway sorry
Sorry for the trouble
I will inform Devika
She will abide with me
- I know that
- What do you know?
- I have understood
- What have you understood?
Yesterday when I saw you both...
...l could understand the chemistry
between you both
If I not mistaken
Shall I say something?
You both make a good pair
Made for each other
- Thank you
- Welcome
Damn with his thanks
Naijeeb, shall I
ask you one thing?
What do women
see in this beggar?
Why women fall an easy prey
to Venkiti's seductions?
Is he handsome?
Does he have money?
Damn with his
french beard
To seduce women neither money
nor beauty or intelligence is required
The only requirement is
you must be spineless
I don't understand
Whatever absurdity they say
just say it is great
All the time praise them
Venkiti must be
an expert in these two
You're right
This is not right
This plan is not correct
See Sherin
In Kochi metro's proposed plan
it extends only up to Aluva
In future it may extend up
to Nedumbaserry airpon
Then how will this
construction work out
Sorry madam
Sorry can't be an excuse
May I come in ma'am?
Yes
- I have already told you that
- I have discarded that project madam
Hereafter I would
never sell liquor
Liquor is a Satan
that fells many families
Sir does not require money
earned by selling liquor
Baby food for kids
I'm sorry
Instead of liquor we are
planning to start that
I have to thank you
for this change of mind
You have taught me money is not
something to be earned by selling liquor
In appreciation of that
I have decided to name my
new business as Devika Baby Foods
With that Devika's hatred
for me mitigated a bit
When I invited her to visit my non
existent business's nonexistent office
She gladly agreed to visit
tiff
It is on top
Come madam, please
Please come
This is supposed to be
the 7th floor of this building
In this 7th floor I am planning
to have my office's main block
No, you should never do it
Having a consumer product's office at
such a height would in no way help you
You are viewing it from
a consultant's point of view
But as far as I am concerned this
place is very close to my heart
I mean sentimental attachment
Madam do you know
about a thing?
My God!
'There can't be
a better place to kill her'
Madam do you know about it?
If you look from here, you can
see Guruvayurtemple's flag mast
You mean that one?
ls that the flag mast?
That's not the flag mast
That is a mobile phone tower
Madam you come this side
Come here
Look from here
- From here?
- Yes have a look
You would never
see from here
lam even planning to name
this building as 'Dwaja Darshan'
- I don't believe
- Come...come
Move towards left a little
- Look from there
- I don't see
Pray the god Krishna Guruvayurappa
and look, you will see
You...!
What is this?
Who is it?
These people only yelled
- What's it man?
- Boss is on line
- 'Son of a dog'
- What sir?
Along with your lady love
are you planning to commit suicide?
Yes!
No, who said so?
As long as I am alive I would
not allow that to happen
I know...l know
Either money or ginger...
...or yours, your mom's
and sister's
...6 kidneys and other organs
that can be sold for money
I would not settle
for anything less
Okay boss, see you then
Bye
It was a call from boss
Calls me at the wrong time
Because this was goofed up
why do you get dejected?
There are many more ways
What ways?
May be highways
Yes it is highway
Away to kill her in highways
I don't understand
- You knowl am a stealer
- Yes I know
- Do you also knowl am a mechanic?
- Yes, I know that too
When a thief and mechanic come together
do you know what will happen?
Come I will show you
What is this guy
going to show us?
Come on man
Your pain Devika
would end today
I would show you the way
Come on
tiff
Park vehicle somewhere else
My God! These people
work in her office
He is coming
What happened?
ls it ok?
Stan the vehicle
Get in
What did you do
in her vehicle?
Did you do this?
No, coming out of office
she gets in to the vehicle
Yes gets in
She starts the vehicle and leaves
Yes leaves
Enroute she applies brake
What would happen?
The breaks would fail
This is where I differ
from you guys
For first brake pedal press
brake would function
Until when?
Until vehicle is switched off
Once vehicle is switched off
and then switched on
Neither she nor her dad
can make the brake function
But if she doesn't
switch off the vehicle
That's it
If she doesn't switch off until
she reaches home this may not work out
Anyway we will do one thing
She comes this way
We will wait somewhere here, stop her
car and make her switch off the vehicle
...and make her
start the car again
When she applies brake
then will it not be ok?
- It would be ok
- Then we will stop here
tiff
Poor girl
Why d0 you say so?
Her car was moving fast
A banging noise
And then ambulance returns
ls it not sufficient to guess?
That is sufficient
But please come here sir
Look inside the ambulance
My god
-ls it notyou?
- Yes
How did this happen?
Kesava, where all should I
look for you?
Why are you all here
We were
No we are searching for a guy
You can do that later
Now get in to the vehicle
What for?
I brought a vehicle
for the first time
I have come to give
a treat to Kesavan
Now all of you
can get in to the car
No if we go now
come guys
It was my fortune
I saw you guys here
Lazy fellows
KL 46 F 5944
ls that vehicle 44 or 45?
This is 44, why is it not good?
This is good
But was that vehicle
- When did you get this vehicle?
- About a month back
Was it one month back?
Then no issues get in
Come, I have to get back
to shooting location
After two pegs, will you not
drop us back here?
Only two pegs
Come
For one month
I was negotiating the price
Just one hour before
we came to an agreement
- What are you talking about?
- About this vehicle only
Immediately I drove
the vehicle out
Did you buy this
vehicle one hour before?
- Yes!
- From whom?
From Metro consultancy madam
- Which madam?
- Devika madam
Before you met us, did you switch off
the vehicle and switch on it again?
Yes, I switched it off
before I asked you all to get in
Now what speed
are you driving?
- Maximum
- ls it so?
Then place this wreath
on your chest
Why?
You may require it
With that for the time being
I stopped my efforts to kill her
Instead of eliminating her physically
I attempted to shatter her mentally
That was my plan
Then
'3 months later'
Baskets please
Well, Babu
Catch it
Move
Devika
- Was it you?
- Yes
Where were you for
quite some days?
We were in outstation
Today Venkiti has
arranged for a party
I have come for purchasing
I also want to buy a gift
What about you?
I came to meet you specifically
We came to know about
your stories only yesterday
Seems your husband
is in wheel chair
So sad
I pray daily
Not for anything else
That chapter should
close at the earliest
No, to close that chapter
Killing you
- Where?
- She has gone
- Is it?
- Quick
If the useless wheel chair
bound husband's life is over...
...will you not become free?
Thereafter you can lead a happy life
with person of your choice
Venkiti is waiting
for quite some time
After today's party
she should not go out alive
She should die
during the party
How, tell that also
She should be
stabbed to death
Who
You?
Then all of us
can be behind bars
If we were to kill her directly
that could have been done long ago
She should not only die
no one should know that we did that
I have found a way out for that
How?
Do you know what is this?
Fish
Dagger
Not a mere dagger
It is an ice dagger
If you stab with this,
the person will surely die
No cop can find out
who killed him
The stabbers finger print
would also melt away
- How is my intelligence?
- This is not your intelligence
ls it not Kamalahassan's intelligence?
Did you not steal it
from film 'Pushpak Viman'?
Don't call it stealing
Call it inspiration
Then it is ok
Will it be alright or not?
- What?
- Dagger
It will workout
ls it not universal hero's idea?
It will surely succeed
Okaymokay
Hi
tiff
Vivekanandan
I am waiting for you man
Thank you
You're the chief guest
of this get together
Were you a cop abroad?
Devika please come
How did you find out
our secret so quickly?
Don't mock at me
Come here
Did I not tell the truth?
Amidst the so many girls in your life
is not Devika the last one?
Yes, she is the last one
To announce that publicly
I have invited all these people
Hear me
About the conclusion of
my relationship with her
Dear friends and colleagues
Avery important moment in my life
to share it with you all
Today I have arranged
this get together
I have decided to get married
Bride
Bride is none other than
tiff
Tanuja
Tanuja Warrier
Venkiti congrats
Tanuja, all the best
It is a mere announcement
Officially I would let you
know the wedding date
My god
Take it away
Just missed
Congrats
Thank you
Venkiti used to look at
women merely for pleasure
There was a change in him
That made me shudder
Me too
The full credit for this
goes to Devika
Her proximity changed Venkiti
without her own knowledge
ls it so credible?
She took Devika to his house
that day where he was living alone
The servant also said they were
together alone for 3 to 4 hours
That's rig ht
But apart from Venkiti
and Devika there...
...was one more person
at that house
Then how anything wrong
could happen magistrate sir?
My God!
Sorry sir
I meant Venkiti's mom was
also there at that house
You did not ask about mom?
I answer only to
questions posed to me
My mom lights
a lamp daily and prays
We are going to reap
the gains of that good deed
We were prepared to kill
a person for 10 lakh rupees
Now we're going to get the money
without doing such a henious crime
I don't understand
When Harinarayanan comes to know
there is no extramarital relationship...
...between Devika
and Venkiti as we thought
Will not Harinarayanan
become happy?
Then will he not agree to give
money he promised us?
- Will he?
- He will
His suspicions made him burn
like a volcano with in
In one stroke we are
going to demolish that
Harinarayanan would happily give
the 10 lakhs he has agreed to give us
Here is the 10 lakhs
the amount I promised to give you
My hands are shivering
Hold this
Guruvayurappa
What did he give you
to fabricate a fib like this?
Who?
Lies?
It is not a lie
It is true
I saw it with my own eyes
ls it not?
I know who is Venkiti
more than all of you
Wedding is a camouflage for him
Hari, you should
You guys Ca" 9°
Our contract ends today
But she
Devika would die
Move man
Excuse me, madam
One minute
Don't shudder hearing
what I am going to say
Don't think your hubby is sitting
in a wheel chair like this
Any moment he
would kill you
- You have got 2 slaps
- Yes I got 2 slaps
You could have told Devika
what really happened
But she should hear me
On one side Harinarayanan
preparing to kill his wife
On the other side Devika
not prepared to listen to the truth...
...and is prepared
to die any moment
Elamuttam on another side
Yes in between the time I sought
from him was about to expire
He was also reminding me
from time to time
Venkiti please
At least you must please
understand me
What is your motive?
ls it cash?
Venkiti please,
it is very serious
Either you are insane
or you need some good thrashes
Hereafter don't come to me
with such fabricated stories
Venkiti what I say
Get out man
One thing is sure
He would kill Devika
Let him kill
She does not believe us
- Let her die
- That shouldn't happen
Devika should never die
Who made Harinarayanan to dislike
Devika by casting aspersions
I did that
If Devika dies because of that
will I not have to bear the sin lifelong?
- We can't do anything
- No, we can
We only can do
I see only one way
to stop Devika's death
Harinarayanan
He must die
He has multiplied his
suspicions on Devika
Now he has become
a son of psycho
To save a poor girl
from a person like him...
...we can go to any extent
I mean any extent
Harinarayana
Hari
Oh God!
He has deliberately
planned this trip to kill her
But that shouldn't happen
Must save her somehow
What if we complain
to the police
Police
That's the only way out
That's howl reached the station
Then on the cheque cases
they not even listening...
...or considering
what I had to say
...Cl Rad hakrishnan arrested
and brought me before you
Sir, Devika must be
somehow saved
I am prepared to be
in custodial remand
But nothing should happen to her
Sir please sir
- Radhakrishna
- Yes, sir
Come here
I am not remanding him
lam giving him bail
On his own bail
Sir as per the sections
under him he is charged
ls bail not permissible?
Law and sections are made
to reform human beings
Even if thousand
criminals escape...
...not even a single innocent
person should be punished
ls the basic tenet
of our legal principles?
I don't think
lam doing a wrong
You may 9°
After all misunderstandings
are cleared
When Harinarayanan and Devika
return as new human beings
You must also be
a witness to partake their joy
Sir, how will they come here?
They would come
We would make them come
Metro Consultancy's
marketing chief Devika's...
...suspicious husband Harinarayanan
may kill herany moment
Whatever be the risks involved
that crime must be stalled
This is not a request
An order
Order from the judiciary
Sir
That was great
lam thankful to you sir
Lots and lots of
thanks for you sir
I have to reciprocate this
If you had not come
slicing those vegetables...
...my back would have
been broken
Go with fortitude
I will also pray for Devika
- Thank you sir
- Go
Don't go, wait
What absurdity have you done?
If the Cl informs the press
as to what happened...
...will you not lose yourjob?
Yes, then I can do full time
slicing of vegetables and fishes
My dear Molikutty
You have only
a well built physique
- You don't have a heart
- That's true
- lfl had that
- Don't talk
lam arranging
a companion for you
Get in
I said go in
Today I will show him who I am
Jesus! Make all these right
- Have you not gone sir?
- Where?
To find out Devika
Let her die or live
I care a damn for it
Sir, please don't talk like that
Then what do you
want me to say?
In the thief and police game
today you have won
But mark my words
After 5 kilometres from this place,
I would apprehend you
Thejurisdiction of
that place is different
Magistrate is also different
At least for one day I would
imprison you in sub jail
Sir you may imprison me
or do anything you want
I am not interested
You may go and find her out
Sir, don't think you are not
the only guy in the department
There are officers above you
Let me see ifl can trace her
with their help
Do it man
Go and find her
Sir, magistrate sir
This man
Don't go there
Come here
Sir, you go this side
and find her
Go
Go man
These guys are out
to get me fired
With the help of police...
If you hide in magistrate's house
did you think I will not come to know?
- You son of a dog
- No boss
Won't your mom come, if she
comes to know her son is dead?
- Thrash and kill him
- You may kill me
But give me an opportunity
to make a call
Aman is coming with
10 lakhs I owe you
I have to tell him
he need not come
What did you say?
Afriend of mine has started
with 10 lakhs that I owe you
I have to tell him
not to come
Then tell your friend
to come with cash
- Tell them to leave my hands
- Leave him
- Hi Basheer
- You son of a pig
Hi thank you
Thank you
- Have you started?
- ls it to shave off your mom?
Where is my money?
Basheer! I started with
the money I owe you
But Pappachan sir is holding me
as a hostage before his house
Hello, hello
How does it help me?
If you can come here soon
you will get 10 lakh rupees
Come quickly
Have you started
with 10 lakhs?
Okay, I would wait here
Thank you
- Will your friend come with the money?
- Sure, he will he not come flying?
Look there
Where is the money?
- Take out the money
- Ask them, ask them
- Take out the money man
- Move away man
- Don't touch me
Give me my money
This is not right
Don't show your tricks
My God, let them settle
it between them
Has the vehicle come?
Escape
What are you pondering?
If it is about Devika
You need not
Since Cl Radhakrishnan
has washed off his hands...
...finding her out
will be very difficult
- Can we get explosives?
- What?
I mean substance that explodes
They are used in temples
for fire cracker display
Or a rock blasting
explosive will do
- For what purpose?
- It is required
Keep some small
quantity ready
Dammit! Who is calling
at this midnight?
Sir! By tomorrow evening
in different parts of the country...
...there would be serious
bomb explosions
Jesus
Terrorists with expertise in explosion
have planned this operation in Kerala
They are camping at house number 30
in Subash Nagar area
When I called Cl Radhakrishnan
to inform about this...
...he insulted me
If the nation is shattered
in bomb explosions...
...he said it's like his pub ha-
said he cares two hoots for it
When I said I will report this to IG
he mocked at me sir
He said IG is a moron dull head
and he can't do anything
ls it right sir?
Radhakrishna you dirty
Forget about it
Who are you?
- Acitizen
- Citizen?
A person with concerns
for nation's safety
An extraordinary citizen
- Sir, what I want to say is
- You need not say a damn thing
If the country is shattered
in bomb explosions...
...do you care a damn for it?
Is thelG, I mean me
a moron dull head?
Unfortunately the situation is not right
Else I would have thrown you out
Take a snap
RDX
Nothing to suspect
This is surely
the handiwork of Lashkar-e-Taiba
Apprehend him wherever he is
Send messages to all
stations along with photo
I must get him before dawn
without any damage
Sir this is fake and deceptive
- We must not
- No, first obey my order
Sir
Hari, I sawa terrific dream
Me shooting you
while you are asleep
Was that your dream?
That was not a dream
That's the reality
Killing people who are asleep
is not a manly act
So it was a deliberate slip
What did you think?
Did you believe?
I would tolerate you
if you and Venkiti deceive me
Whatever Vivenkanandan said is true
You must die
Who is Harinarayanan?
Sir
You can't even stand up
Yet you would
terrorise people, isn't it?
Tell me the truth
What are the locations
where you have planted bombs?
What are you saying sir?
Do you mean we have
planted bombs?
Bomb'?
- ls this pistol yours?
- Yes
You are an handicapped person
Why do you require a pistol?
- That is for myself protection
- You dirty son of a dog
ls planting bombs in country
yourself protection?
I would not care
that you are a patient
I would beat you hollow
Sir!
Who are you man?
I am Vivekanandan
who made the call to you
- Well done Mr. Vivekanandan
- Thank you sir
Even the state intelligence
could not do it
But you have done it
single handedly
- But I have a doubt
-You may ask sir
How did you manage to learn
there secret operations?
Few goons followed
to attack me
To escape from them...
I entered into his house
I'll showyou invalid guy
Then I had to be a witness
to their terror meeting
It is a lie sir
It is a damned lie
- Look what he says...
- Shut your mouth
Sir one minute
I have come to share
another secret also
- Tell me
- Please come this side
In the conspiracy some
others also took pan
Who are they?
They are our own countrymen
For the sake of money
there may not be people...
...spying their own
nation in all countries
I have stored their
photos in my mobile
Show me
- Who is this?
- This is Sethumathavan
This is Sathi
This is Mohan, Roopa
- This one
- Elamuttam Pappachan
Com e com e
Come fast
My God
Will you plant bombs
in country?
Bomb'?
Vivekananda
Tell me the truth
What are the places
you have targeted?
I swear, we don't
know anything
We haven't even
seen a bomb
- Haven't you seen?
- My God
Let me see ifl can
make you tell the truth?
We don't know anything sir
I wouldn't leave you
until you come out with the truth
- We don't know anything sir
- You can't get you, isn't it?
Vivekananda didn't you see this?
I will make you understand
Thrash out his nuts
- Tell me man
- Please don't hit him sir
Will you plant bombs
in the country?
Bomb'?
Mr. Vivekanadan what is this?
Tell me the truth
Where have you targeted?
We don't know anything sir
- We haven't even seen a bomb
- Haven't you seen?
Move that side lady
I will make you tell the truth
- My God!
- Where have you all?
I swear sir
It is out of my hands
Will you plant
bombs in country?
Bomb'?
Come here
Tell me the truth
Where have you targeted?
I haven't seen a bomb
Then I would show you bomb
I would make you tell the truth
Come out man
Tell me
My God
Sir, DGP on the line
It is not over
I will give you some more
What's all this?
- Vivekananda
- Very glad
When you guys deceived
and pushed me to a ditch
None of you thought
about a retaliation like this
It's all Lord
Guruvayurappan's blessings
For all those who were
responsible for all my problems...
...this is a single panacea
After his talk with DGP...
...lG would again start
thrashing you all
If you don't tell him the exact places
where you kept bombs...
...it would be a gone
case for you all
We haven't planted any
bombs brother in law
- We haven't done anything
- Haven't you?
My life was shattered by
the bomb planted by you
Vivek you must forgive me
I only gave the gold coated
ornament through her
She is innocent
You need not repay
the 10 lakh rupees to me
I would pacify the lenders
All my doubts are cleared
We would lead
a happy life hereafter
It is interesting to
hear confessions
But it is too late
But if you don't suffer
at least one tenth of what I suffered
Lord Guruvayurappan
would not pardon me
Our land is the paradise
of deceivers
That is not because
of your com petence
That is because
love trust and honesty...
...of ordinary guys like me are
exploited by you people
That must come to an end
It will come to an end
This is the beginning of that
Bye
I would take care
not to meet you all once again
What have you decided?
Will you people come out
with truth on your own...
...or should I make you
tell the truth?
They would tell the truth
on their own volition, isn't it?
Tell me where all you
have planted bombs?
Tell me
Pappachan
Where did you
keep the bomb?
- Why are you laughing?
- Nothing sir
I was laughing over
the games Lord plays
God's deed make one travel in
palanquin in just two days time...
On the shoulders of these dirty
guys who occupy the palace
The same God's
adorn with shawls
I am taking leave sir
I have to make an earnest
prayer at Guruvayurappan
You may go
lam proud of you
- Thank you sir
- Go ahead
"He doesn't know the tale
Yet he is great"
"The story that he
recounts is a beauty"
"Ajourney without
any rectitude"
"But it has drama
not known until now“
"Amidst slickers
He is an handsome guy"
"His sweet tongue
always gets him troubles"
"It is true, he is canny"
"He is a glutton too"
"He needs thick griddlecake"
"Wants good chicken curry too"
"Rice flakes, dhall ada
or vada (Indian snacks)"
"These drum rhythms
express joy"
Guruvayurappa
I believe the testing
period is over
All these days
I lived for others
At least for few days
I want to live for myself
Bless me
Why are you leaving
without taking the bag?
Bag...?
Bag is not...
This tendency to
forget is not good
God! Are you
testing me again?
Or like transforming
Kuchela's hut as a palace...
...are you blessing me?
Whatever it is...
I don't want it solely for me
Including this
From now on...
...fifty percent of
what I get is for yours
Mr. Vivekanandan?
What if...?
'It was not a journey
towards another testing'
'Those guests invited
me to a new life'
'A life sans problems
and tragedies'
'Ajourney towards
a flourishing life starts here'
'It's all Guruvayurppan's mercy'
"He doesn't know the tale
Yet he is great"
"The story that he
recounts is a beauty"
"Ajourney without
any rectitude"
"But it has drama
not known until now“
"Amidst slickers
He is an handsome guy"
"His sweet tongue
always gets him troubles"
"It is true, he is canny"
"He is a glutton too"
"He needs thick griddlecake"
"Wants good chicken curry too"
"Rice flakes, dhall ada
or vada (Indian snacks)"
"These drum rhythms
express joy"
"When he forced all
these into his throat"
"He could not utter or speak"
"All his game plans failed"
"He changed his strategy"
"He could neither
move nor learn"
"Poor young boy
His psyche is young"
"But he would be darling
in the times to come"