Why are you practising here? Go back to the institute.
Master has promised us to return to the institute!
If you're late, do one hundred frog jumps.
We'll go now!
Hurry!
You're still not going?-Yes!
Subtitles brought by Tornado Team at Viki
Then they will start to recruit students.
The features inside the building are advanced.
All are the most advanced technology.
The training base's funds are over a hundred thousand.
I'm telling you,
Institute Competition is yearly,
but coach ShenNing's training base
is not yearly.
So, we must take this chance,
do you understand?-Understand!
Institute President.
The red pocket that I told you to deliver, did you deliver it?
When I was at the entrance way, I got kicked out.
Look, I got such a big lump.
Well.
Don't worry.  We have other methods.
If we can't move them using money, we can move them with feelings.
What is that?
Good question.
Our method is
1. Cry 2. Beg3. Kneel down
I'm telling you,
LiuBei relied on crying. Cry to your heart's content, do you understand?
Twisting history, teaching the children wrongly.
Hall Master, I don't think it went like that. Shut up.
Everyone remember this.
In front of Coach ShenNing, we have to cry to terrify the lands, the ghosts and the gods!
Let her feel our sincerity.
Then We can have a chance.
Cry! Cry loud!
Cry loud! Cry sincerely, cry! You, cry!
The list of selected participants that everyone is awaiting,
Coach ShenNing is thoroughly over-checking.
The list will be announced this weekend.
About this list... it's still in the stage of being classified.
But I can tell everyone very confidently, that this list will not disappoint anyone.
BaiCao, did you see? I think that list definitely has you.
You're the biggest dark horse of this institute competition after all.
You even defeated Senior LinFeng.
Although the champion was XianWu.
If our SongBai's top three could get into the base,
then the future contains unlimited possibilities.
If Coach Shen was as legendary as people say,
then I believe she would choose every participant with thorough consideration.
I'm confident in Brother RuoBai and Brother YiFeng.
Then what about you?
I...
Do I really have the chance?
Of course! 10000%, okay?!
If the three of you get in, then SongBai will have hope to get more students.
When that time comes, I will have to make SongBai
AnYang's number one.
Who was her Master?-Qu XiangNan.
TingHao.
I got a book for you.
If you have nothing to do, read it and see.
Young master Fang came to visit me,
only to know about the participant list, right?
But I have to say beforehand, I won't consider any other people's opinions.
In the end, nothing can be kept from you.
I know you've always been fair and square, you never take short cuts.
But as the funder, to be able to see the participant list the day before is not asking too much, right?
If you want to know about XianWu's situation, I can tell you.
XianWu has the most number of participants.
You think I want to know about XianWu?
The one I want to know about is SongBai.
Mum.
We got the Institute Championship this year.
Very soon,
Yu ChuYuan will compete with me.
This time, I will definitely defeat him.
It has been my wish for so many years,
it should be over soon.
What time is it already? What's going on?
It can't be that our institute didn't get in?
Hey! Stop your jinxing now!
That's right, that's right.-A small source already said, Brother RuoBai definitely got in.
We should be calm now. What we can do now is one word, continue to wait.
Fang TingHao?
Fang TingHao?!
No, what is he coming to do?
BaiCao! BaiCao! Why are you here?
So he came to find Brother ChuYuan.
I thought he came to find BaiCao.
TingHao.
Many years ago, I already said that I would defeat you.
Do you still remember?
I've already left Yuan Wu Dao.
I won't compete with anyone anymore.
Moreover,
the championships that I received, you already got.
That proves it all.
You should forget about this, there's no point.
You want to forget,
but I can't.
Since I was young, I've always lived in your shadows.
You were a genius,
you're the small LeeYunYue.
Everyone said that you become the next Yuan Wu Dao master, nobody could compare to you then.
All of the championships that I got,
were won after you left.
What's the point in getting championships like these?
I want you to officially compete with me.
I want to let my Mum and everyone know,
you, Yu ChuYuan, is not a difficult opponent to me.
In the past, every time when I asked you,
you would reject. But this time, it's different.
You should know about Coach ShenNing's training base.
All of the people in AnYang wish to get onto that list.
I believe that SongBai will be the same.
The lucky thing is, there is somebody who got in.
But whether they got into the list, it'll depend on whether I agree or not.
Coach ShenNing's participant list. Seeing her style, she won't easily let others change it, right?
Be a bit more realistic.
The training base was funded entirely by us, the Fang family.
Say whether she will agree?
He's threatening with the training base.
Because of our private grudge,
you're going to use other people's futures as a joke?
You're not this kind of person.
What if I am?
Tomorrow morning, nine o'clock.
Come to our institute, I'll wait for you.
If you're willing to participate, I'll keep their names.
This is my last warning.
Don't test my patience.
That's too much! How could he do that?-Exactly.
Bullying people.
Wait.
Brother RuoBai.
You don't need to be so arrogant.
He's already left Yuan Wu Dao. This has nothing to do with him.
Moreover, if this participant list could be changed as you wished, because of your relations,
our Song Bai's disciples would not go
to this kind of place.
No! Brother RuoBai!-No!
This is Coach ShenNing's training base. The people who are trained by Coach ShenNing,
of ten, eight are national champions and even international champions.
Brother ChuYuan, say something. We can't waste this chance.
I'm making the decision for this issue.
Nobody can say anything more.
RuoBai, you're still quite protective of him.
ChuYuan, your indifference to SongBai,
you want to leave them when you want.
But they're still quite emotionally attached to you. Coach ShenNing's participant list,
whether you want to do something for them, will depend on you.
Anyway, tomorrow morning, nine o'clock.
Old place, we'll decide once and for all.
He's too much! If Brother ChuYuan hadn't left Yuan Wu Dao,
how else could he become champion?
Brother ChuYuan, you should teach him a lesson.
We'll see who'll want to bully SongBai in the future.-That's right.
Teach that Fang TingHao a lesson. So that he'll grow a brain. Bastard.
Are you all taking my words as the wind?
Yu ChuYuan and Yuan Wu Dao have no relations.
If Fang TingHao comes to challenge him, it's not his turn to make the decision.
But Brother RuBai, how good of a chance the training base is.
You must already be on participant list. You can't give up.
If Brother ChuYuan wants to...
Brother ChuYuan, please.-Please, Brother ChuYuan.
You all go back to practise.
From today on, the training base has no relations with us.
Brother RuoBai!
So mad.
I'm so mad too.
You guys...don't be like this, you guys!
Yu ChuYuan!
My grandpa said you're better than me, my Mum also said you're better than me.
Everyone says you're better than me. I don't believe it!
Today, we'll compete!
TingHao.
So he wanted to compete with you since you were kids.
In the end, when his Mum got injured, his will became more powerful.
But, no matter what, he used Coach ShenNing's participant list to threaten you,
that's not fair.
I can't blame it all on him.
We grew up as kids. He might seem widely known,
but he's really kind.
Maybe he's really close with his mother.
After that accident,
he became easily provoked.
Brother ChuYuan, you already left,
he's forcing you this way, but you're still speaking good words for him.
BaiCao, why have you never asked me the reason that I left?
Because this is your decision. I believe, you must have your own reason,
so there's no need to ask.
Like my Master, no matter what others say, I believe him 100%.
So, no matter what others think, what others say, I'll still support you.
BaiCao.
You're so foolish.
That's right, Brother ChuYuan, tomorrow morning, are you really going to compete with Senior TingHao.
I won't run away from this challenge.
But I still won't attack TingHao.
When he thinks that there's no point in competing,
he'll give up naturally.
If you don't attack, you're going to let Senior TingHao take his anger out on you?
If I can let him undo the knot in his heart...
I hope one day,
you could wear it again.
Little Grass,
Brother ChuYuan did so much for me.
Say, should I do something for him too?
I must do it.
I told you to come watch, why did you bring so many things?
This you don't understand, brother.
Things like defeating Brother ChuYuan is a historical event,
of course I have to save it. Look,
I've prepared the recording.
How is it?
Brother.
Yu ChuYuan, you're finally here.
Tomorrow morning, nine o'clock.
Old place. We'll finish it once and for all.
ChuYuan...will he go?
Senior Ruo Bai!
Senior Ruo Bai, there is big news.
When i've heard of it, I couldn't help it and rushed as fast as a rocket
- It's.. - Tell me
Senior ChuYuan went to Fang Tinghao's competition meeting.
I was wondering who would come half an hour early.
Turns out it's you.
I have practice later so I had to show up early.
Don't waste time.
Let's start.
What kind of joke are you making?
You want me to fight you?
The only person I want to fight is Yu Chu Yuan.
But the person I want to fight is you, Fang Ting Hao.
You can challenge Brother ChuYuan without reason,
I also have the rights to challenge you.
If I win,
please don't bother Brother Chu Yuan again.
I don't understand.
What is so good about Chu Yuan that you would do this for him?
Brother Chu Yuan has a kind heart.
Even when you kept forcing him he still only  had good things to say about you.
He already told me
about what happened to Ms. Fang. It was really only an accident.
Enough!
I am not foolish like Chu Yuan.
I will definitely do what I've decided to do.
You want to compete with me, right?
Fine. I'll accept your challenge.
But if word got out that I fought with a girl here,
people will laugh at this joke.
If we're going to compete,
we'll do it a different way.
What is counted as a win?
There's only one rule.
In one jump, kick and break the vase.
If the thought of failure worries you, you can pay the price.
What price?
Let Chu Yuan compete with me.
How about...SongBai withdraw from Coach Shen Ning's training base altogether.
The video's evidence.
Then I'll go first.
Watch and learn.
Brother Chu Yuan!
Ruo Bai, what are you doing here?
I came for Song Bai.
Such strength!
If you're still here...
Who's competing with Fang Ting Hao? Who else is also here?
Did you learn?
What can I do? With my leg strength I can't break  that vase in only one kick.
Qi Bai Cao your competition with Fang Ting Hao is to measure your leg strength.
Girls usually aren't as strong.
But if you're thinking of breaking that vase in mid-air
your level is still far, far from enough.
Also, if you force it, there's a chance you will hurt your leg.
Why are you scaring the girl?
Kicking the vase doesn't only depend on jumping strength, but also the strength of the leg.
Yuan Wu Dao is martial arts after all. If your abilities are lower than your opponent's by a whole lot,
then there's no need to compete.
You should give up.
If I give up, you would still challenge Brother ChuYuan, right?
What do you think?
So, I will definitely not give up.
Good. If you're going to persist,
then go ahead and try.
Not bad. Very smart, she knows to use Continuous Kick.
No yet, again!
How could it be possible?
It will definitely become popular on the internet.
Just by jumping up once, she could complete a Triple Continuous Kick. Her abilities,
are even better than I thought.-Oh my.
BaiCao did a Triple Continuous Kick.
It's too unbelievable!
BaiCao.
Why are you here?-I...
I wanted to challenge Senior TingHao.
Yu ChuYuan!
She came to challenge me because of you.
I promised her, if she could break the vase, she would win the challenge.
That way, I won't force you to fight me anymore.
No! I didn't do it for Brother ChuYuan!
A challenge is a challenge, it's not for anything else.
Senior TingHao is the international champion. To be able to challenge him is my honour.
But, BaiCao, you're really brilliant.
A Triple Continuous Kick that requires that kind of strength, an average girl can't usually do it.
Even for guys,
they might not all be able to do it either.
But the vase has still not broken yet. Does that mean BaiCao lost the challenge?-That's right.
BaiCao,
you lost the challenge. I don't need to keep any of your promises.
Yu ChuYuan.
Shouldn't it be your turn right now?
That's right.
It's time to make a conclusion.
He withdrew from Yuan Wu Dao early on. If you're going to challenge,
it should be SongBai's disciples' responsibility to answer to it.
Next round,
I'll do it.
Look! The vase broke!-Then BaiCao won the challenge, right?!
BaiCao, BaiCao...
you're really my nemesis.
Senior TingHao, I hope you can do what you said.
I don't understand.
What's good about Yu ChuYuan,
that you have to always protect him?
Because...
It's not important why it is. Tell me next time.
The thing I promised you, I'll do as I said.
BaiCao, you're too good!
Brother ChuYuan, I told you not to worry. Just like you said, as I persisted
with my dream, you can also be determined with your decisions in the future.
Thank you, BaiCao.
Lets go, we're about to be late for practice.
Talk about it, you went around in such a long way,
to force Yu ChuYuan to come out. But in the end, it was all for nothing.
I don't have any other way. Who told him to get a number one fan?
But this time, I should thank you too.
I used your name to act out a scene.
It's only you who would think of doing such a bad thing.
You knew I wouldn't change the name list, but you still went to scare SongBai's people.
In the end, you never really intended
to stop SongBai's people from entering the training base.
In the end, you became their enemy too.
But, Coach Shen Ning really does have good judgement.
No wonder you name Yuan Wu Dao's golden scale.
You gave me such a high and mighty name.
What are you trying to play at now?
What is it?
There's a Yuan Wu Dao competitor named Qi BaiCao.
Can you give her a chance?
I only let in friends in,
I don't care for customers.
If you still want to continue...
I need to go on with my business.
Sis, help me out.
I'm going.
BaiCao, why still can't you do it?
After I came back, I've never done the Triple Continuous Kick anymore.
Maybe that time was really dependent on good luck.
I won't be able to do it anymore.
No, no! If there's a first, there'll be a second.
After you go to Coach Shen's, if you ask for her guidance, you might be able to succeed at it again!
You're consoling me again.
Could getting into Coach Shen Ning's training base
be that easy?
You defeated AnYang's number two, Lin Feng.
If you still can't get in, then Coach Shen has no tastes.
I knew Coach Shen Ning would definitely let SongBai on to the list.
A dream-like chance.
Long live Coach Shen!
Is the list out? Who got in from our Institute?
You say it.
Brother Ruo Bai.-That's great! I knew my idol was great!
Brother YiFeng.
Although he usually likes to sleep, being able to get in is also good.
And then? And then?
There's no more.
No more?!
BaiCao, why can't you do it?
After I came back, I couldn't do the continuous triple kick anymore.
Maybe that time really was because of good luck. I might not be able to do it again.
No, no. If you have the first time, there'll be a second time.
After you went to Coach Shen, if you ask for her help, you might be able to do it soon.
You're comforting me again.
How could it be that easy to get into Coach ShenNing's training base?
But you defeated AnYang's number two, LinFeng.
If you still can't get in, then Coach Shen doesn't have good tastes.
That's great! I knew Coach ShenNing would let us into the participant list.
It is an incredible chance.
Coach ShenNing, long live!
Is the list out? Who went in from our institute?
You say.
Senior RuoBai.
Good! I know my idol is excellent.
Senior Yi Feng.Well, although he likes sleep, it's best if he can go.
And more? No more.
No more?!