Previously on
The Girlfriend Experience...
No, you're not getting the point.
No, I think I'm getting the point.
Look, if you don't want
to come, that's fine.
No, I want to come.
I'm just...
curious.
It's just drinks.
Also, he calls me Ashley.
Ashley?
It's my online profile.
You find guys online?
I find everything online.
I get it.
I don't need that.
It's just a gift.
I know what it is.
Should I be Chelsea?
You can be whoever you want to be.
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
How's it going?
Hey.
It's been pretty non-stop.
Let me get this to you now.
You know, some of Stacy's
friends are having
a party over at Logan Square tonight.
You want to come?
Does Stacy want me to come?
Yeah, she's the one who
asked me to invite you.
You should come.
You'd really like her.
She's pretty incredible.
Did you tell her about us?
Not yet. But I'm sure she'll
understand, it's in the past.
Don't be naive.
Cash it soon.
You're so cynical.
See ya.
I want you to amend claim 32.
Hold on.
You've got great organizational skills.
It's all up here.
I know where everything is.
I'm hearing some rumors...
Christine...
Ben Holgrem.
Learn this guy's face.
He's the devil.
My client is suing the
shit out of his client.
I heard XHP is unhappy with you.
Tell Susan to hold my calls.
He wants you to hold his calls.
I mean it's not something that
I want to make into a career,
but I actually enjoy it.
I like meeting new people,
I like having sex.
And I only do it a few times a month.
Do you meet all your clients online?
A few.
This woman, Jacqueline,
vets them for me,
and takes care of the bookings.
Why? Do you want to meet her?
I could introduce you, if you want.
No, just curious.
Okay.
But there's a difference
between being curious
and actually following through.
I'm aware of that.
If you meet Jacqueline, she's
gonna wanna book for you.
You're smart and hot and funny.
You just have to want to do it.
I mean I get off on it.
I like the rush...
All the attention, knowing he wants me.
Then there's the money.
And at the end of the day,
if I don't get along with a client,
I just move on.
All I really have to do is
listen and ask questions.
And fuck?
Yeah.
And fuck.
Here's sixty.
Thanks.
- Hi.
- Hi, come on in.
You're gonna have to play
catch up. We're two deep.
Think I can handle that.
Look who's here?
Chelsea!
Hi.
Hey, glad you came.
Me, too.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
No, it's interesting because
we have some sizable estates,
and there's no better sport
than watching the wealthy try
to hang onto their money.
Or try to get some
they think they deserve.
It just never gets old.
Really?
So it's not just the same
story over and over again
with different names?
Not yet.
And I've been doing this for 20 years.
Huh.
Do you have a lawyer?
Me? No.
Seriously? You should.
You can be my lawyer.
I would happily be your lawyer,
but then...
this would have to stop.
Why?
We're just starting to
get to know each other.
Keep it.
Welcome.
- Are you checking in?
- Yeah.
- Do you have any luggage?
- No.
Make yourself comfortable.
We're good?
Yeah. Great.
Drink?
Yes, vodka, please...
um, with soda.
Thanks.
Come here.
Do you like that?
Yes.
Yeah, listen, my 12 o'clock's
here now, so I gotta run,
but we'll talk about it later, okay?
Yeah...
We'll sort it out, I'm not worried.
Okay, bye-bye.
Jacqueline.
You are Christine.
I am.
You didn't tell me she was so beautiful!
She's great.
Federal Circuit has a monopoly
on all patent appeals.
It was established by Ronald Reagan and
is hardly met a patent it doesn't like.
If they make an error
interpreting patent code,
then every later judge is
obliged to follow their ruling.
The whole system is a complete mess.
It's so great you know this stuff.
Stuff like law?
Yes.
I do realize it's the result of
years of hard work and school,
and that's your passion.
Well, it's costing me enough.
It'll pay off.
At least from this end.
Now I already have a couple
of exceptional men in mind
who I think would love you.
Do you have any photos?
Okay...
We'll get you some.
Don't worry, no one will
ever see your eyes.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Where do you want me?
Just up against the curtain.
That's perfect.
You look great.
Angle your chin up a little bit.
Beautiful.
Now just slowly start to
unbutton your blouse.
Perfect.
Beautiful.
Yeah, just chin up just a little bit.
And turn to face the window.
Great.
Just lift the back of your
skirt up a little bit.
Gorgeous.
Beautiful.
It's whatever you're comfortable with,
and how much you wanna get paid.
I want to make sure that
you're matched properly.
For reasons I will let you figure out,
most of your clients will be white
and approaching middle age.
It should also be enjoyable for you.
I mean the more you enjoy
it, the more they will too.
My big question is...
Why would I go with you
when I can do this myself?
You mean why pay me?
Yeah.
Well, it's just math really.
And quality of life.
The hours that you would spend
finding and then vetting clients
could be spent with
clients, making money.
I'm the infrastructure.
You don't work for me, you work with me.
And if you're unhappy...
you leave.
There's no contract.
I already have one client.
Hmmm...
At least I think I do.
Okay, well, he's all yours.
Can I tell you about Ryan?
He's assertive.
He knows exactly what he likes,
but everyone who's seen
him had a great time.
What are you comfortable with?
Did you and Avery talk about it?
A little. I mean I get the gist of it.
Mm-hmm.
Bareback blow jobs?
Overnights?
Dinner at the Y?
Yeah.
I'm fine with all of that.
Great!
More wine?
Chelsea?
Ryan...
You're late.
I'm always late.
She's older.
Of course she is.
So you have one sister.
What does she do?
She's a math teacher.
What grade?
Middle school.
- Any kids?
- One.
A boy. He's 4. He's got a lisp.
A lisp?
That's cute.
What's his name?
Sean.
Bullshit.
Come on, you gotta rehearse this stuff.
Look, I know you're new,
but Jacqueline should be runnin'
bio drills with you or something.
Okay, she doesn't have a kid.
She could have 10 kids.
She could be a he. I don't care.
I think you should move
closer, "Chelsea".
Okay, "Ryan".
How was your day?
Are you on the pill?
Yes...
But I'd like to use a condom.
Yeah, I don't have any.
I do.
Let's go to the bathroom.
Face me.
Perfect.
Just like that.
Fuck.
Water is included.
Electric would be separate.
Take your time.
I think this place is great for you.
It's too expensive.
I can't afford this.
What if I cover the deposit?
And if you keep working,
it'll figure itself out.
Emery, this is part of the process.
I'm not trying to manipulate you!
I'm sure that when you come down...
Hey, we're doing
everything we fucking can!
Hello?
Shit!
We already gave you a chance.
This is how things move.
Don't fucking lecture
me on how things move!
Three mistrials.
Three fucking mistrials, David.
Explain to me why I need
to hear anything else
out of your mouth other
than you fucked up.
This is not the time to switch counsel.
You will lose if Kersner
sees you have doubts.
Do you get that?
I think what David is trying to say...
I don't need to hear the same
goddamn words in a different tone.
I completely understand where
you are coming from, Emery.
We, or maybe I should
just speak for myself,
I just want to know how to fix this.
How do you see this moving forward?
He didn't say. I don't know.
Maybe his wife's coming to town or
maybe he's just not
that into me anymore.
Either way, I have to pack
up my shit and leave.
It's really not that big a deal.
Just stay with me until
you figure it out.
Maybe Jacqueline can lend you
money. She charges enough.
How much are you paying her?
Same as you...
30%.
Kind of steep, no?
Yeah, but it's pretty standard.
Why, you don't like her?
No, she's great, I just...
30%'s a lot.
That's all.
You can tell me if you don't like her.
I like her.
Don't tell her I said anything.
Of course.
So, you can sleep in here.
Obviously, I haven't slept in
it, but it seems comfortable.
Ahhh, if you need to do
your laundry, it's the...
closet right next to the kitchen.
Yeah.
This place is really nice.
Still getting used to it, but I like it.
How much do you pay for it?
Probably too much.
Don't you have loans to pay off?
Yeah, Jacqueline actually put the
deposit down, so that helps.
So you can take "in calls"?
No, I am paying her back.
She was just helping.
Oh.
Here.
Just pay me back when you have it.
I have credit cards, I'm fine.
Speaking of which, let's go to lunch.
It's on me, it's the least I could do.
We'll have the forest
mushrooms, the kale salad,
the ahi tuna tartare, diver
scallops and two mimosas...
Please.
Thanks.
You deserve it.
We deserve it.
So how is work?
Which work?
I'm currently burning a
candle at three ends,
which I didn't know was possible.
Maybe one should go.
Yeah, maybe.
For now, it's fun.
And have you noticed that
people are fucking insane?
Hello.
Christine. Hi, it's Jacqueline.
Listen, I have someone
I'd love you to meet.
Are you free for lunch on Thursday?
Yeah, I can make that work.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
When did she pass away?
It's been eleven months now.
That's gotta be hard.
I think it's been harder on the kids.
Are you close to them?
I was...
Least I think I was.
But they're adults now.
They've got their own lives.
Why it's so nice to spend time
with someone and just talk.
Especially to a...
to a beautiful young woman.
We can talk whenever you like.
Jacqueline?
Oh, she-she's wonderful.
We're having a really
nice time together.
Declined?
Well, that's surprising.
Yeah.
Hang on.
I'm just gonna use the restroom.
Okay...
2226.
Christine...
What is it?
Was having problems sleeping.
I'm really sorry, I shouldn't
have brought him here.
Can I lie down beside you?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, I should have asked.
I can give you half for letting me.
- I'll give you $500.
- I don't want your money.
Jacqueline won't call me back.
- She won't tell me why.
- Go to sleep.
I have to get up at six in the morning.
Oh really? Fuck, I'm sorry.
You're really warm.
Thank you for being there for me.
Of course.
Kiss me.
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com