Midnight's girl
Sera is not there..
The person you are calling is not available. Please leave a
message after the tone. Extra charges may...
It's probably broken or something...
What is this?
Let's close down the karaoke.
Why?
Aigoo!
Hyung, do we have to turn this place into a storage?
What kind of crap are you saying?
If you regret it so much, then you sell it for me.
Why? Do you feel attached to it?
I have a lot to organize. Quick, put those chairs up.
Mr. President!
Are you closing down?
Yeah, well... it seems so.
I'll buy it.
Really?
It seems like there were customers
from time to time during night.
Mr. President, then let's go outside and talk more about this in depth.
Sure.
Closing down? Nonsense.
You, don't leave! Wait for me, wait!
Closing down? What did you mean?
Closing down?
♪ So I can wash away my sorrow ♪
♪ So I can add to my joy ♪
♪ So your eyes can shine more brightly ♪
♪ I will always be the tears in your eyes ♪
♪ Because I am so weak ♪
♪ Because my heart is too young ♪
♪ I'm afraid that I cannot even protect you ♪
♪ Because I look so miserable, I did not say anything ♪
Hello?
♪ I will promise you one thing, that I'm here for you ♪
This is my daughter, Sera.
She has just been lying like this because of a car accident.
I've waited 4 years.
It's Sera's handphone.
Its battery should have been drained,
but maybe there was a little left
when I received the call from you.
The first person to call us in four years...
But...
It can't be...
Why?
Nevermind.
I thought you looked like someone I know
but I think he was a lot  more handsome that you.
♪ I will give you ♪
♪ everything I have ♪
♪ Suddenly tonight ♪
♪ I will give you everything ♪
♪ There is nothing that I cannot do ♪
♪ For you, I will ♪
Ah, this really is not working.
Ah, this really isn't working.
Ta da!
Are you doing magic for the talent show?
No, it's a club. Magic club.
Oh, there's such a thing? Freshman?
Yes.
But, a flower is too cliche so why don't you try something else?
Here, I picked this out from a toy coin machine.
A dolphin instead of a flowers.
Ah, the truth is I'm singing as the 12th grade representative tomorrow.
So, I was here to practice...
Can I watch you practice, Jidan oppa?
How do you know my name?
Ahh..
I didn't know because of that...
I'm your fan.
Ah, really?
Yes, since very long time ago.
Really?
Hey, Handsome! What are you doing here?
All the girls from other high schools rushed here to hear you sing.
Come on! Hurry, Hurry!
I've to go.
Jidan oppa, you will be a very good singer.
Sera always said...
..to wait and see.
That, you will be a good singer.
I also wished that you would become a good singer
so, that Sera would be able to see you on TV
But you came so soon.
It's just, there's someone I want to help.
The person she want to help...was me.
Sing once!
I'm sure there is at least one person in this world who is waiting for Gong Ji Dan's song.
That person can be close or far away.
So she came to me...
...and left
In that blind moment, when I sleep.
I'm just finally starting to get to know you..
She stayed in my mind and left.
♪ Even when I am born a thousand times again ♪
♪ there will never be a person like her. ♪
♪ Warming up my sad life ♪
♪ She's a person to be thankful for ♪
♪ For a person like you ♪
♪ I wouldn't mind my heart aching ♪
♪ Even if I can't say the word  "love" ♪
♪ Even if I can only stare at you from far away♪
♪ Because I can give you everything,
because I can love you ♪
♪ Although I am sad, I am happy ♪
Song is something that can move someone's heart,
and send a message of someone's mind.
It's like magic, don't you think so?
I'm just finally starting to get to know you...
Code blue! Code blue! Second floor, room 201!
♪ Although I don't want anything ♪
♪ Your smile would still make me happy ♪
♪  Love is for giving, just for giving ♪
♪ Although I am sad, I am happy ♪
Hello?
Ouhh, my Gong Ji Dan
You're still rolling around on bed, aren't you?
Ah, what is it?
I'll give you one hour.
Hurry up and come outside. Go~
Hello? Hyung?
Aish!
Oh! Hey! I'm going to Maldives tomorrow!
9 nights, 10 days!
Hey, is my son an average son?
National superstar, Jidan!
and I'm his mother
I'm his sister!
Ah, busy busy!
-Oppa!
What is it?
- Of course I'm busy~
Your autograph please..
Oppa~! Oppa~!
AAAHHHHHH! SHUT UPPPP!!
Please hurry up! You're going to be late!
What with this car?
Ha! I give up on the moneylending business and get one!
This should be enough to serve our superstar!
I'm not a star yet. I'm gonna ride the subway.
Stop overreacting, please!
Hey! Hey!
Hey, don't be late and be here by 2!
He left.
I heard that dolphins can communicate with each other
even if they're thousands of kilometers away from each other.
Thousands of kilometers...No, more than that.
Sending what your heart feels.
Even if we're far away, my mind and feelings,
can I really send them on to where you're?
Of course!
Talking to myself making me even hear things.
Why do you talk to yourself?
♪ The person I want to give everything to, ♪
♪ you are my first love ♪
♪ The person that I want to keep in my heart ♪
♪ My heart pit-a-pat, it must be love ♪
♪ What should I do with you? ♪
♪ Inside my mind ♪
♪ is filled with you and I don't know what to do ♪
♪ What should I do? ♪
♪ The person that I want to gve everything to ♪
♪ You are the love I was looking for ♪
♪ My heart pit-a-pat, it's like I'm dreaming ♪
♪ I love you ♪