MARISOL: Don't lie to me.
I know that something is up.
VERONICA: Why do we have to keep
talking about this? It's over.
Look, he's not all that, anyway.
- But I like him.
- Marisol, it's a free country.
Just because you have a crush on
him doesn't mean you own him.
You didn't even notice him until
you found out I liked him.
-(SIGHS) Please. Get over yourself.
- It's true.
You could have any boy you want in
this school, and you choose him.
Look, nothing happened. Okay?
Can we be friends now?
DIANA: You fucked him.
I did not.
You're lying.
You had sex with him?
(SIGHS) Guzman, you suck.
It didn't mean anything to me.
If he prefers me over you,
is that my problem?
Maybe it's time you took
a look in the mirror.
It's time for a makeover.
Apologize to her.
Excuse me?
-You heard me. Say you're sorry.
Yeah, right.
Come on, girls, let's bounce.
I'm telling you, that bitch is psycho.
Get off me, you fuckin' bitch!
(STUDENTS CHEERING)
(BELL BUZZING)
Jesus. American Gladiators.
MR. PRICE: Show's over.
You kids are late for class.
You're fucking crazy, Guzman!
You started it, you fuckin' bitch!
-Enough!
- She's lying! -BOY: Yo,
Tiny, check your sister!
- You know what you did. -MR.
PRICE: Both of you are at fault.
- I didn't do nothing! -Except
be your stinky, skanky self.
MR. PRICE: I said hustle, or all
of you end up in detention!
Report after school, or you're suspended.
See you.
You are another story. Now come on.
This is your fourth fight this semester.
You simply can't continue
to behave like this.
Have you ever considered how
much more effective it would be
to talk about your disagreement?
You have a serious problem.
In or out of school, your life is
only gonna get harder because of it.
You might want us to find someone
who can help you deal with this.
I don't need any help.
Fine. It's up to you. I am out of options.
One more fight, and you're expelled.
Who cares if I'm expelled?
Diana, ask yourself that question.
SANDRO: Up the ante. Up.
- Money on the wood.
- MAN: Hey there, it's Diana.
Oh, yeah, the gym's probably closed by now.
- I got held up at school.
- You in trouble again?
No.
Here. Tell Hector I'll have
the rest for him next week.
(SNICKERING) Not after this game.
- Where am I going?
- Take the 61 to York.
It's near the water.
Why you sending your girl down there?
'Cause she's paying Hector. My good
man from Panama's training Tiny.
Man, you're the living
likeness of your mother.
- I was just saying...
- Just play.
Later.
(RAILWAY SIREN BLARING)
(TRAIN MOVING OVERHEAD)
(BEEPING)
You need some variety. I give it to you.
I'm looking for Hector.
The ring in the back.
The right, Tiny.
Remember your combinations, Tiny.
(BEEPER GOING OFF)
- Last round.
- You said we go to four.
He's not ready.
- RAY: Not ready, huh?
- Oh!
Where the hell's Don?
- DON: What's up? -You better
keep your eye on this bozo.
- He don't listen to a word I say.
- Well, make him listen.
What the fuck?
That's my brother, you little shit.
RAY: Let me go! I'm gonna get her!
I gotta put you in a cage?
- The ho hit me first. -I
mean that crap in the ring.
TINY: It's embarrassing. Being beaten twice
in a day makes me look like a pussy.
Hey, watch your mouth.
- Why'd you mess with Ray like that?
- He's a punk, Tiny.
- We were sparring. -It
didn't look that way to me.
Here, this is from my dad.
You Sandro's kid, too?
How come I never heard about you?
I don't know. I'm his pride and joy.
TINY: (SIGHS) Jesus Christ.
Nice meeting you.
Yeah.
(SCOFFS) You been humiliated.
You fight dirty with a little kid.
Then you got slapped by a little girl.
That's weak, Ray.
The bitch is lucky I didn't kill her.
- You spared her some mighty force, huh?
- That's right.
Who's the dish?
Mmm. Should have me a taste and find out.
Little man.
- You know I was just playin', right?
- I know.
Can we shake?
Thought you had a friend.
Come on, man.
Hey, killer.
I forgive you, too.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I mean, I guess you never
learned how to be a lady.
You shouldn't hit people like that.
I couldn't resist.
Tiny, let's go.
Got that scholarship
application I told you about.
- For that art school?
- Yeah. It's cool.
You gotta learn all kinds of stuff
before you can do any work.
You know, to get a foundation.
You would think that's cool.
Sounds like a waste of time to me.
Learn how to draw. What's
that gonna get you, Tiny?
A job painting somebody's house
out in Long Island somewhere?
Maybe.
Edward clean you out like he said he would?
Yeah, well, he screws himself
when he talks like that.
I'm not finished.
I know.
So, how was school, champ?
It was okay. Lots of excitement.
When I was a kid, school was so boring...
I thought I'd piss in my pants
waiting to get out in the world.
So, did it happen?
- What?
- (PHONE RINGING)
Did you get out in the world?
What kind of question is that?
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
- TINY: Dad.
- (SIGHS)
(WHISPERING) It's Ms. Martinez.
SANDRO: When?
No, she didn't mention it.
Yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
Why you always gotta fuck up like this, huh?
Veronica asked for it.
You embarrass me. Sometimes I
don't even think you're mine.
- (PLATE SHATTERS)
- Maybe I'm not your kid.
SANDRO: That better be cleaned
up by the time I come back.
If I was enough of a skeez,
I could pull that off.
Why would you want to?
Veronica say anything to you?
(LAUGHS) Yeah, if she wants
to choke on her teeth.
Always with that damn mirror of hers.
(IMITATING VERONICA) "Let me
get made up just perfect.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) "so I can suck your dick",
"which is all I'm good for, anyway."
- Let it rest with her already.
- How come?
Because she can be bitchy, but
that's not all she's about.
- Some fucking loyalty.
- Don't be like that.
She treats you like shit. Why take her side?
Diana, I don't take sides.
Veronica don't even mean
half the stuff she says.
Look, I just wanna be friends with everybody.
That's the way I am.
Yeah, well, I hate her,
and that's the way I am.
WOMAN ON TV: Set his wife on
fire, then fatally shot himself.
Neighbors of the slain woman expressed
shock and sorrow today as...
(SWITCHING CHANNELS)
Knock-knock.
It was open.
You here to beat me up?
No.
Remember her from the other day?
The bare knuckles.
You should've seen Ray's face.
- (SPEAKING SPANISH)
- (LAUGHING)
Hey, I'm trying to say something.
I wanna train with you. I wanna be a boxer.
Sure. It's a great workout.
No, for real. I wanna fight.
- You can train, but you can't fight.
- Why not?
You just can't.
Girls don't have the same power as boys.
Why not aerobics?
Am I talking to you?
Nice.
There's plenty of things you can
do better with your life than box.
Prove it.
You got money? 'Cause I don't work for free.
A little.
I charge $10 a session, and that's cut-rate.
I don't have that kind of cash.
Well, there you go.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
- Dad?
- Hmm?
You know how you pay for
Tiny to train with Hector?
Well, I was thinking on how
that's like an allowance.
And I should get one, too.
It's not an allowance.
Then what is it?
I'm preparing him for the world out there.
- Yeah, but...
- Look, it's insurance.
These kids are gonna eat him alive.
- That's not true.
- Tiny, it is true.
What if he doesn't want to box?
Sure, he wants to. What kid wouldn't?
He could go to college, Dad.
He could do all sorts of stuff with himself.
You think I don't know that? You think
this is just spending money for him?
He ain't over at A&S Plaza buying
lipstick or whatever you girls do there.
Please. Don't front like I'm some
girly-girl when you know I'm not.
Would it kill you to wear
a skirt once in a while?
Look, your mother was a receptionist
in a very nice office.
You want some extra money, get a job.
I ain't giving you anything until
you show me you deserve it.
It's not like you give me anything, anyway.
(SIGHS)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(CHILD CRYING)
You think I don't hear you?
Shut up, already.
Stop doing that.
(BELL BUZZING)
You again.
Relax. Jab. Jab.
What are you doing here?
- I got the money.
- I didn't promise nothing.
You said once I got the cash.
-Hey...
You seem like a nice kid.
It's just not right.
Diana...
This is bullshit. You said once
I got the money, and now I do.
Wait a minute. You're
gonna train with Hector?
Yeah.
- Why?
- Why not?
Well, what about Papi?
- You tell Dad, and I'll kill you.
- Take it easy!
Please.
I'll train you.
You will?
If you don't sweat for me,
you're out of my life. Got it?
- Got it.
- Oh, man!
Tiny, come on.
Fuck. Now he hates me.
Rule number one, no personal
business in the gym.
Watch me.
Hands close to your body,
hands up to your face.
Jab. Snap, snap. Springs back to you.
Snap, snap, springs back to you.
Twist it.
Now throw the right.
Soon you won't think
while you're doing this.
You'll be daydreaming.
What's that, huh? What's that?
You got no balance that way.
Better.
Nothing stays still in the ring.
Move around the bag more.
Watch your footwork.
Hey.
You can't stop.
Ninety-eight...
Ninety-nine...
Come on, last one.
(GRUNTS)
You're done for today.
Go see Ira about getting a locker.
Sure, he'll make the weight.
The kid's been sleeping in Saran
Wrap for the past two weeks.
Hey, who's bright idea was it to keep
him at junior lightweight, anyway?
Exactly.
Saturday, he'll be at 29.
Okay. Talk to you later.
You're the girl Hector told me about.
- You need a locker.
- Yeah.
Well, we ain't big-time, hon.
We're not really set up for the ladies yet.
This neighborhood don't really
catch on with the lawyer types.
We don't use this too much anymore.
It's yours if you want to
throw your stuff somewhere.
Thanks.
(SIGHS)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Okay, what is mass?
Mass is the measure
of a body's resistance to acceleration.
It is different from, but
proportional to that body's weight.
What is weight?
Weight is the gravitational force
exerted by the Earth on that body.
Now, this is why
if a body is outside the
Earth's gravitational pull...
Girls.
I think you both know how this works.
- Yes, Mr. Coolidge.
This is why...
Make a fist.
How's that feel?
Feels good.
Jab, jab.
Jab, right.
Good, now jab, right, hook.
Too wide.
- How long is this going to last?
- What are you talking about?
(IMITATING TINY) "What are you talking
about?" Stop being such a tough guy.
What do you gotta do this for?
You can't pay for it.
- What do you care?
- You should tell Dad.
Are you for real? This would drive him nuts.
- Keep your mouth shut. -I
can't believe you sometimes.
You still got two rounds.
Yeah, but I can't do it right.
Then get back over there till you can.
But it's pissing me off.
It's pissing you off?
What, do you think this is
gonna happen overnight? Huh?
You think it came natural to these guys?
You think it's gonna
come natural to you? Huh?
No.
(BEEPER GOING OFF)
This time, work the bag slow and steady,
and don't stop till the red light goes out.
What you laughing at?
You laughing at me? Huh?
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Oh, mira, look.
Your bodyguard.
Guess the slave girls get a day off
when you slum it with Marisol.
I've had it with your dismal crap.
You're sick.
- You don't even know me.
- I know all I have to.
Quit it.
She hangs out with you to get to me.
You should know. You're the
center of the universe, right?
It's the truth.
We're gonna be late.
(BELL BUZZING)
Later, Diana.
You said you'd do my braids.
Yeah? Well, call me when there's
an opening in your busy schedule.
(PANTING)
Jab, jab.
Jab, jab, right.
Too much power. Let's just box for now.
Hey, you deaf? I said too much power.
(EXHALES)
Jab, right, hook.
You been working on your hook.
This time, finish it with an uppercut.
Same combination.
(LAUGHING) All force and no technique, huh?
Come on.
Power is half the story.
Are you scared of me?
No.
- That's funny. You look scared.
- I'm not scared.
I got you against the ropes, and
I'm gonna dance on your face.
Ah, see?
Someone gets you where you don't
wanna be, you get outta the way.
Keep your footwork smaller.
(MAKES BOXING SOUND)
That way you can punch
from different angles, okay?
Try it.
Now we're boxing.
You should start roadwork. Run
three miles four times a week.
Three miles? You gotta be kidding me.
At least three.
At this rate, you couldn't
last one round in the ring.
But I got power. You said so.
Big deal.
You got the endurance of a corpse.
I guess I'll use the track at school.
Don't bother about clocking yourself yet.
So, were you ever a fighter?
Oh, sure.
In Panama.
I had my day once.
So, what happened?
What happens to most of us who do it?
We lose.
There's only two of you in that ring.
It can be a lonely place.
How're you doin'?
- Have you seen Adrian?
- (BEEPER GOING OFF)
CAL: Yo, Adrian! You got a visitor.
DIANA: Most of these guys
here, what are they,
just dreamin'?
HECTOR: Sure, they are. They got no choice.
These guys, this is what they live for.
This is their whole life.
Was it like that for you?
To fight?
Probably not.
I didn't have what it takes.
So what does it take?
To be great, I mean.
I don't know.
A real strong will.
I was gonna go to a fight
at the Forum next week.
If you want to see some lightweight action,
Ira gets discount tickets sometimes.
I can come?
It's no big thing.
For real?
Maybe you'll learn something.
Yeah.
Oh, here.
Thanks.
TEACHER: I hope you've all
completed the assigned reading
and finished your workbooks.
This chapter deals with
a fundamental concept in science.
The second law of thermodynamics.
The primary element of this law
is a word that we use all the time,
though it's tough to define.
That word is "heat".
What is heat, anyway?
A simple definition is this.
Heat is the energy possessed by molecules
because of their motion.
It takes part in every physical occurrence,
from the growth of one blade of grass
to a key starting a car's engine,
to the explosion of a star.
(PANTING)
(RINGING)
Testing those reflexes.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Friday, you spar.
I'm ready to?
You're a quick study.
I am?
You gotta pay me for last week.
- It's real silver. -I can't
sell it with these pictures.
Strangers to everyone but you, huh?
Yeah.
I'll give you 40 bucks for it.
-That's all?
It's not worth more than that.
Sixty.
(LAUGHS) Gimme a break.
Please?
I'll give you 50 bucks. Final offer.
You sure this is a good idea?
Ray knows. No funny stuff.
Try to be a gentleman.
Just keep it loose. No pressure.
Take it easy on me this time, okay?
Don't be a dick, and I'll try.
Why did he have to say that?
Ignore him. Here.
(BEEPING)
CAL: How's it workin' with her?
Gotta pay the bills.
When you get that desperate, borrow from me.
Hey, Frankie, let's put in
some quality time.
- Sorry.
- HECTOR: Come on!
Don't be sorry. Don't ever be sorry.
Look at him.
(BEEPER GOING OFF)
Okay.
HECTOR: When you throw your jab... Spit.
Rush him with some of the combinations
we been working on, okay?
It's like I forgot everything
you've been teaching me.
Stop thinking so much. You're doin' good.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
You've been working hard.
- Yeah, I guess so.
- Guess so?
Cal's got you conditioned real good.
Thanks.
I'll be seeing you, Hector.
- How you gettin' home?
- The 61. I'm in Red Hook.
I'm driving that way.
I don't mind the bus.
This place is deserted at night.
- I'll be fine.
- It's okay. No trouble.
I'm just in Gowanus.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
The "F" and the "G" are my nightmare trains.
"G" is the worst.
No wonder people move out of Queens.
You're lucky you have wheels.
Lucky's winning the lottery.
My old man, he's a mechanic.
He has me running all around Brooklyn,
running errands for this ride.
Always gotta be thinking "expansion".
(SCOFFS)
Anyway, you in high school?
Yeah, my last year, I hope.
You still in school?
- Am I immature or somethin'?
- No, I just thought...
(CHUCKLES) I'm just playing with you.
I graduated last year.
- My only achievement in life.
- Yeah, right.
It's true.
My mom cried when I got my diploma.
That's nice.
You gotta tell me where to turn.
We can stop right here.
- Right over here?
- Yeah.
You live in a project?
All my life. Canales Community Houses.
What floor you on?
The 11th.
- You're up there.
- Yeah.
Thanks for the ride.
I'll be seeing you.
What?
- You're late. -I was
hanging out with Marisol.
- Thank your brother for dinner.
- Thanks, bro.
And do me a favor. After
you eat, take a shower.
You smell.
(SNIFFING)
Hmm. I think I will.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
You looked all right in there
with Ray today.
It's more tiring than it looks, huh?
What's he after, anyway? Making me fight.
I just want to make him happy.
(SNICKERS) Lots of luck to you.
(BELL BUZZING)
How can the history of the
world be so fucking boring?
And all those people are dead, too.
You still holding a grudge against
me because of that Veronica thing?
If you are, I gotta tell you...
You were holding a grudge against me.
I was pissed at you for stirring up shit.
I guess I was an idiot.
Shouldn't tell you who to hang out
with, even if your friends are lame.
I wanna hang out with you, but you
never wanna hang out with me.
Seems like you always got places to go.
You gonna deny something's goin' on?
- You're gonna laugh at me.
- What?
You're gonna think I'm full of shit.
- Is it a guy?
- No.
- Is he at P.S. 20?
- No, it's not a guy.
Then what?
I'm training to be a boxer.
Oh, be serious! (LAUGHS)
I am serious.
I'm training with Hector Soto at the
Brooklyn Athletic Club on Front Street.
You mean, like pow-wow-wow?
Oh, that's cool.
You get hit?
- In the face?
- It happens.
You fight guys?
That's all there is right now.
You got guys hitting you in the face?
You don't understand, Marisol.
It's like you're all you've got.
You're all alone in there, you know?
I can't explain it exactly.
You are crazy. My crazy friend.
(CHUCKLES) It's fun, that's all.
Doesn't sound like fun to me.
Well, there is this one guy.
I knew it. Name.
Adrian.
Adrian? What kind of girly name is that?
Hey, hundred percent man,
if you know what I mean?
And?
And what?
- How do you know about this percentage?
- Guesswork, Marisol.
How come everything's
gotta be a romance with you?
I live for that shit. What can I say?
ANNOUNCER: Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
We'll give you the formal
introductions, if you don't mind.
Will all the boxers kindly
turn in their passports?
All the boxers please
turn in their passports
over here at ringside.
HECTOR: Piece of work, right?
DIANA: Who is he?
Some hotshot promoter.
Always got new flesh to peddle.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Come sit with us.
No, thanks. I got my chair over there.
Thanks, anyway.
Don't feel social?
I understand.
(BELL RINGING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Two, three, four, five.
(BELL RINGING)
Break. Break.
(BELL RINGS)
So you're becoming a serious fan?
- I liked that guy Lopez.
- Yeah.
Garcia came back strong tonight.
If my payday was as sweet as
his, I'd come out fighting, too.
I bet you would.
You think we could go get something to eat?
I'm starved.
I can't. Got a date with my wife tonight.
I'll have a bacon cheeseburger.
Make it a deluxe with extra bacon.
Rare.
What? I said I was hungry.
- WAITRESS: And for you?
- (CHUCKLES)
A cup of soup, a garden salad with
Italian dressing on the side.
That's all.
What kind of dinner is that?
Trying to stay at my weight.
Got a lot of speedy fighters in my division.
- You compete?
- Yeah.
You like it?
Sure. Keeps me out of trouble.
You a delinquent?
Not anymore. (SNICKERS)
- How come you train with Hector?
- You mean, like, at all?
- Yeah.
- Because I want to.
- Aren't you afraid of gettin' hurt?
- What, are you're not?
No, it's just... It's a dangerous sport.
I didn't make the cheerleading team.
How long you train for?
Almost a year. Cal's got a
whole plan mapped out for me.
I might be lined up with Ray
in the next amateur heat.
- Your favorite guy. -I hope
you cream that asshole.
(CHUCKLES)
He's not that bad.
Yeah, just another harmless prick.
You two are friends?
I feel like I should lie and say no.
Don't lie.
We grew up in the same neighborhood.
Yeah, he's cuckoo, he's fucked up.
You know, he's harmless.
Not everybody's blessed
with brains and talent.
(SNICKERS)
So how come you didn't sit next
to Hector like he asked you to?
'Cause I didn't feel like it.
He thinks you're a good fighter.
Hector got me started.
Yeah? How come you still
don't train with him?
Because I'd be 50 before
I got a pro fight with Hector.
What's the sense in doing this if I'm
not gonna make any money, right?
I can't work for my father forever.
My little brother, right out of
school, he enlists in the marines.
No, thank you.
Besides, I don't think
Hector believed in me.
DIANA: You wanna see where my mom was born?
Right there, 37 years ago.
You didn't have to walk me home.
I don't mind.
I mean, I can take care of myself, you know.
I know.
I wanted to.
So what's it like in Gowanus?
In places like this, no one matters.
No one and nothing.
That's not gonna be my life, man.
I'm gonna turn pro, and I'm
gonna move far away from here.
Someplace where I'm not gonna
get killed doing my laundry.
Right. Or raped in your
own fucking stairway.
(SCOFFS) Shot for a pair of shoes.
(CHUCKLING)
That girl who's been at the gym, all
dolled up, watching you spar...
Is she your girlfriend now?
Karina?
Sometimes.
Oh, so she's your sometimes girlfriend.
You know, it's cool between us.
She's pretty.
Yeah, she is.
She's sweet on me, but it's
like I don't have time to...
- Be a Romeo?
- Yeah.
Half the time...
I get a feeling that she only
likes me 'cause I wanna go pro.
You being exploited?
I'm serious.
She's gorgeous
and all that, but it's like...
Sometimes we don't have much to
say to each other, you know?
Sounds like a dream date for most guys.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah, it is.
Guess I don't know what I'm
supposed to be looking for anymore.
Well, what do you want?
Fuck if I know.
Why'd you do that?
I don't know.
You taste sweet.
Funny.
I always thought of myself as salty.
(CHUCKLING)
You're wrong. You're sweet.
I gotta go.
I'll talk to you soon, all right?
Yeah.
MAN: Yo, where are you going?
GYM COACH: That time of year again, ladies.
Time for the Presidential
Physical Fitness Exam.
I don't give a shit what the president
thinks of my physical fitness.
A mile's not gonna kill any of ya.
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
(SOUL JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
This year, ladies.
Good work, Guzman.
Looks like those hormone
treatments really do the job.
One more lap.
She's got a good chin.
I know.
Hey, champion! What are you doing here?
Hi. Nice seeing you.
DIANA: Ah, man, I just seen that
guy fighting on TV yesterday.
MAN: Good fight, champ.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
How you doin'?
HECTOR: He popped you real good.
I popped him back, didn't I?
Well, you're getting the hang of this game.
(DOOR OPENING)
You gonna walk home?
I'm taking off.
My dad will give me grief
if I keep coming home so late.
Does he know?
Know what?
About this?
Not unless he has binoculars
this very second.
So what exactly is this?
Who knows?
(SNICKERS)
You still like me with my black eye?
I think I like you more.
Hi, Dad.
You stole money from me.
- I'm gonna pay you back. -Who's
this guy you're running with?
What the hell happened to you?
Did he do this to you?
Adrian? No.
- How could you let him do this to you?
- Get away from me.
That's how it goes?
You hook up with a creep
who knocks you around?
Right. You're so reformed now,
you're giving me advice?
- I won't let this happen to my daughter.
- TINY: What's going on?
- Go to your room.
- You're not my mother.
- Get out of here, Tiny.
- No!
I said get out of here!
Don't you fucking touch him.
You think Mom would give
me the same wise advise?
That's it.
Give me back what you took, and if I
catch you with this pendejo again...
You'll what? Fucking kill me?
That was fast.
I ran.
I can see that.
My parents are light sleepers.
So what happened?
You think I could stay here tonight?
Yeah.
But no monkey business.
I thought all guys jumped at this chance.
(CHUCKLES)
I guess I'm not prime trim, huh?
How'd you get so fucking crude?
How'd you get so fucking polite?
Shut up.
So you're serious?
Cal told me to keep a lid
on it until I fight Ray.
You two are gonna go at it?
It's just a preliminary. Amateur stuff.
So that "no sex" shit is for real?
(LAUGHS) It's for real.
Let's sleep.
Yeah, yeah.
Are your parents still together?
Not really.
My mom died a long time ago.
Oh.
So what happened, if you don't mind?
She killed herself.
Man.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Me, too.
Dream of me knocking Ray
out in the third round.
I already have.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- What?
- (RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
TINY: Can I come in?
Yeah.
I hear it's true, you got a lover.
Oh, man.
First comes love, then comes marriage.
Sensitive.
It's not funny.
Look, I don't know how you pay Hector,
and I don't think I wanna know.
But Dad's wasting his money
on me, and, well...
He won't know if you use it instead.
What are you gonna be doing when
you're supposed to be at the gym?
I'm a geek.
I'll do something constructive with my time.
Thanks.
Hi. You must be the new boxer. I'm Candice.
Not bad for an old fart.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(LAUGHS) How are you doing? Happy birthday.
Oh, thank you. I was just talking about you.
I've come to defend myself.
Hey, remember when I told you
that girls can't be boxers?
Yeah, I remember.
Girls... Excuse me...
Women have a lower center of gravity.
Maybe they're more grounded
once they build strength.
It makes 'em a different kind of boxer.
- Are you serious?
- (CHUCKLES)
It's just a theory.
The way to prove it is to get
more women in that ring.
One-twenty-six.
Must be all that muscle you're building.
- What division?
- You're a featherweight.
- You're not mingling.
- Huh?
This is a party. You should be dancin'.
- I'm not much of a dancer.
- Sure you are.
I mean, you dance, right?
- Hector says my footwork gets sloppy.
- Looks okay to me.
Let's box. Come on.
No, bro, not in Hector's kitchen.
But you're all serious and shit.
Come on. Be a man.
You know...
They say love kills you in the ring.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Hector, I gotta go.
But you just got here.
Sure you can't stay longer?
No.
It was better with the ice cream.
How you feel?
Tired.
This is a waste of time.
Look, Adrian's got a bout coming up.
I don't mean to insult you...
What's the big deal?
There's no one near Adrian's
weight to spar with today.
Might as well give my gal a chance.
I don't like it, Hector.
Tell him to think of her as a warm-up.
This equality crap has gone too far.
Should we just forget about it?
-No.
Just get rough on her in the first round,
and Hector will stop it real early.
- (BEEPER GOING OFF)
- Go ahead.
Come on. What'd I tell you?
Hit me!
Hit me already.
I'm not gonna fight him
if he doesn't hit me.
Both of you, enough bullshit! Now box!
You okay?
Stay inside.
I love you.
- I really do.
- (BEEPER GOING OFF)
Diana.
Come on.
I'm not running after you,
if that's what you want.
HECTOR: "A gender-blind
amateur boxing proposal"
"is a statewide initiative that
responds to the ongoing demands
"for officially sanctioned amateur matches
"while also addressing the expanding
presence of females in the sport.
"Male and female amateurs
within the same weight class"
"are allowed to compete
with each other in the ring."
Now that they're mixing up
the guys with the girls,
you could have a lot more opponents.
They got you fighting this
girl from Buffalo next week.
And you can have a fight
every week if you want.
REFEREE: Hey, Vince. Long time no see.
Let me get this straight.
She's had three amateur matches,
and she's already turning pro?
That's a little premature, don't you think?
- BOXER: Damn it! -Trainer
says kid's got a high fever.
Dead on his feet with strep throat.
I'd fight that yellow kid with one arm.
Missy from Buffalo's 33-years-old, and
she can make some money as a pro.
The fight's totally called off?
Why bother with small-fry
stuff when she can be on TV?
Calm down. There'll be other matches.
Not soon enough.
IRA: It's a pathetic turnout, but I've
gotta give these people their $10 worth.
And half of my fighters haven't showed up.
Come on, Ira. Let's just
see this thing in action.
All right.
If it turns ugly, you can't
say didn't warn you.
- Nervous?
- No.
All right. Remember,
you're judged on points.
Be aggressive and make legal punches.
- Nervous?
- No.
ANNOUNCER: Welcome to Brooklyn A.C.
in cooperation with the New
York Amateur Boxing Initiative.
Let's welcome a new boxer into the ring.
From Brooklyn, 18 years old, 125 pounds,
Diana Guzman.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Challenging Diana in the far corner,
let's welcome Raymond Cortez,
from Brooklyn, 19-years-old,
also 125 pounds.
Both of these boxers' originally scheduled
opponents couldn't make their fights.
And these kids wanna rumble.
Let's give a big hand
for their fighting spirit.
You know the rules.
Let's keep it above the belt.
Fight a fair fight, and good luck. Touch up.
Stay loose and relaxed, okay?
(BELL RINGS)
Box!
Okay, off you go.
HECTOR: Come on, Diana.
(BELL RINGS)
Stop!
HECTOR: Good. You're doing good. Relax.
CAL: Hey, Sandro. How you been doing?
I haven't seen you in a while.
COACH: Keep your head on. She's
getting a lot of good punches.
HECTOR: At least he's predictable.
And what's with all
the wild swinging bullshit?
DIANA: He really wants to kill me.
Okay, he's lunging at you thinking
you're gonna back away from him.
Use that to throw your body shots.
Stay with him. Hey!
(HAZY) You gotta box more, okay?
Are you listening to me?
Stay inside of him...
Boom, shoot an uppercut.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
- I'll try.
- (BELL RINGS)
Box!
HECTOR: All right, come on, Diana.
Yeah, Diana, come on. Come on!
Break!
REFEREE: Stop!
One, two...
Three, four...
Five, six...
Seven, eight...
You okay? Box!
- You don't have it in you.
- Stop! No talking. Box!
- (BELL RINGS)
- Stop!
I don't have the stomach for this.
What the hell are you doing, huh?
Don't let him bully you like that.
You are a better fighter than Ray.
Come on!
(BELL RINGS)
Box.
Stop!
That's below the belt.
This is a warning. Box.
Stop!
- What a prick.
- He can't do that, right?
Last warning. One more time,
you're disqualified. Box.
- RAY: What's below the belt anyway?
- Ain't nothing but a pussy!
- Yeah, I wish I had thought of that.
- DIANA: Fucking asshole.
What are you doing?
Hey, I gotta warn you, too.
I'll say it one last time.
- No pushing.
- Catch you next time.
Box!
Stop! That's it, Cortez. It's over.
Get out of the ring.
The match is over.
I've had it with you, kid.
(BOOING)
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
in a unanimous decision,
Ray Cortez is disqualified,
and Diana Guzman is declared the winner
of this preliminary featherweight match.
SANDRO: All this sneaking
around, and for what?
To get the shit beaten
out of you, that's what.
(SCOFFS) Thanks a lot, Dad.
But you know, it was
almost like entertainment.
Hey, I won tonight. You hear me?
I won. What do you think about that?
I think you're ridiculous.
You're nothing but a street fighter.
You looked like a loser in there.
Everything I know about losing
I learned from you, Dad.
- I'm your father.
- Yeah, some father you are.
The only thing you had the heart to
love you practically beat into a grave.
- Shut up with that. -You just
had to push her, didn't you?
I mean it!
Until she'd rather die
than answer to you, huh?
I said shut up with that!
(GRUNTS)
I could snap your neck right
now if I felt like it.
- I could kill you if I felt like it.
- No, no, no. Please.
Mom begged. Did you stop
when she said please?
- I can't remember.
- TINY: Diana, stop it!
You belong to me now.
How does it feel to see
so much of yourself so close?
- How does it feel?
- Diana, stop!
Please, Diana, stop.
Just stop.
(COUGHING)
All these years, you just
looked right through me.
Look what the cat dragged in.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- Who are they?
- Those are Hector's kids.
He doesn't see them too often.
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey.
Never mind.
Who was that?
Nobody. Quit it.
- Oh, please.
- No, I'm serious.
This athletic shit makes you,
like, a class achiever.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
Well, now that I got school all covered,
I only have the world outside
of these walls to fuck up.
Damn, girl, that's grim.
It's the truth.
- Holy shit.
- What?
Ex-hundred percent man is to your left.
(WHISTLING)
Stop being so obvious. Damn, girl.
- That's him with the forearms?
- Yeah.
Well, if he's such an ex,
what's he doing here?
I don't know. Maybe he's a glutton
for punishment or something.
A glutton for punishment, loca?
Yeah.
-Shit, you better go over there.
I heard you fought Ray.
You're right. He's a fucking case.
I feel pretty fucking stupid out here,
waiting for school to be let out.
Then don't.
Right.
So, where's your woman when she
doesn't have her tongue in your ear?
Or do you only bring her out
for special occasions?
I came here to say I'm sorry.
(SCOFFS) Sorry for what, Adrian?
Proving to your friends you can
still snag the pretty girl?
You got yourself a fuckin' trophy now.
- Bet it makes you feel
real big inside, huh? -No.
I don't feel too big right now.
As a matter of fact, I feel
pretty fucking small around you.
Must be nice.
Yeah, well, it's not.
You and me, we just met each other, right?
We barely know each other.
No problem.
So, then leave.
- Maybe I don't wanna leave.
- Why?
You're off the hook now,
free to do whatever.
That's not all I wanted to say.
I told Karina it wasn't
gonna work out with her.
I told her I finally met somebody that...
Makes something happen for me.
Just 'cause it's true doesn't mean
I know what to do about it, okay?
You got anything to say to that?
Hey.
So I'm someone, huh?
Yeah, you are.
HECTOR: I was wrong.
There's more than one of you out there.
And I hear she's good.
She's a southpaw, and she's won
most of her matches 'cause of it.
These next couple of weeks
I'm gonna train you so hard
you'll be wired like a machine.
There's all kinds of fighters out there.
The more versatile you are,
the better prepared you are.
You gotta learn how to manage your
power, 'cause you got more of it
than people realize.
How you gonna do that?
First, you're gonna strengthen your jab.
Feels funny, right? Southpaw now.
Okay? I'm Ricki. I'm Ricki.
Come on. Good.
Jab, jab.
Very nice. Very clever.
Girls, I want a good, clean fight.
It's my decision if one of you
needs a standing eight count.
If you score a knockdown, go
to the farthest neutral corner
and stay there.
Don't come out until
I tell you to resume fighting.
Got it? Let's go.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
The key to this is not losing your cool.
(BELL RINGS)
The judges are gonna give that to Stiles
'cause they see her hands moving.
Remind them you're in there with her.
(DIANA GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
That was nice.
(BELL RINGS)
Okay, your punches are making contact.
Your defense is strong.
But you gotta stagger her.
These judges won't give you any points
if they can't see you slowing her down.
(BELL RINGS)
(CROWD URGING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- (BELL RINGS)
- REFEREE: Stop.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a split decision.
Hill judges 29-27 for Guzman.
Ferrara judges 29-27 for Stiles.
Anderson judges 28-27 for Guzman.
And the bout goes to Guzman.
IRA: Based on the results
of the preliminary matches,
you've been advanced to the finals.
Even though the first fight was stopped?
Yep.
You scored better than a lot
of the kids in your division.
That's great.
So, uh, who's next?
Come on, Cal. You saw her with Stiles.
- What's going on here?
- I'll tell you what.
This rinky-dink operation...
excuse my candor, Ira...
Let this goddamn gender-blind
program get out of hand.
You signed him up for it.
Boys are different from girls.
What's so wrong about saying it out loud?
No girl has what it takes to be a boxer.
Neither do most boys.
I'm gonna petition the fight.
Oh, come on, you're the
one always complaining...
you can't get enough matches for your guys.
Adrian's young. He works hard.
He's a good-looking kid.
A year from now I want him
grooming for the pros.
Then you're pushing him.
You can't humiliate my guy like this!
Ira, I need your support.
File your protest, but don't
ask me to get involved.
I will say this.
Let the boxers box,
and that'll speak for itself.
Unbelievable.
Adrian.
Hector, if this happens...
I'm telling Adrian no mercy.
You understand?
Yeah. So will she.
This is crazy.
And Cal's right. This fucks with my record.
It's your amateur record.
At least we got the same disadvantage.
We know each other's habits.
Fuck!
Come on. Stiles makes fights, right?
You said it yourself.
You have lost your mind.
I got it. I won't make my weight.
What?
-I'll eat for a fucking change.
I won't fight you, and that's it.
- Who says you're the only one fighting?
- I'm sorry, Diana.
I haven't trained all this time to
be stuck in a ring with a girl.
Stuck with a girl.
Okay.
Stuck with you.
- You're afraid I might win.
- No.
You're gonna play it all manly
and protective on me now.
Look, I'm just being honest.
You're just like any other guy.
-Oh, yeah?
What kind of a guy goes around
beating up a girl that...
That he what?
What?
Just forget it. It's not right.
Fine. All I know...
is if you don't fight me in this match...
you're less of a man than you think you are.
What is it that you want from me anyway?
You want me to take you
a little more seriously, huh?
Is that what you want?
Is that your idea of Prince Charming?
You need to take yourself
a little more seriously.
Who's the one who said it was
all about the challenge?
Who's the one who said
that they love to win?
Well, I'm not gonna love winning this one.
Then maybe you shouldn't be a boxer.
(SCOFFS)
(CHOPPER WHIRRING OVERHEAD)
¶ Oh, say can you see
¶ By the dawn's early light
¶ What so proudly we hailed
¶ At the twilight's last gleaming
¶ Whose broad stripes and bright stars
¶ Through the perilous fight
¶ O'er the ramparts we watched
¶ Were so gallantly streaming
¶ And the rockets' red glare
¶ The bombs bursting in air...
Oh, I'm sorry. This seat
is saved for someone.
¶ That our flag was still there...
You know what? Forget it.
They're not coming.
¶ Oh, say does that star-spangled...
The card says Diana Guzman. Look.
Must be a misprint.
It doesn't look like a misprint to me.
¶ O'er the land of the free
¶ And the home
¶ Of the brave ¶
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
How you feeling?
Like I got nothing to lose.
Good, then.
Inside, you know him?
- Yeah.
- How's he fight?
He's always stepping left.
He relies on his right for power.
He jabs low, and his right
cross can knock me out.
Inside, you know yourself?
Yeah, I do.
Then that's all you need.
ANNOUNCER: Welcome, ladies and gentlemen
to history in the making.
New York's first gender-blind
amateur boxing finals.
(CROWD CHEERING)
In the gold shorts,
weighing in at 125 pounds...
Lead him with your jab.
Keep moving to your left.
Force him to come to you.
- ANNOUNCER: Adrian Sturges.
- (CROWD CHEERING WILDLY)
And in the lovely purple shorts...
- I can't go through with this, Cal.
- Yes, you can.
Just do some damage in this round
and it will be short and sweet.
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and
gentlemen, clap your hands for.
Diana Guzman.
(CROWD CHEERING WILDLY)
- (BELL DINGS)
- Box!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BELL DINGS)
Pick up the pace, okay?
You're doing good by leading him.
I got to get to his body more.
So she's got some defensive skills. So what?
Take her out and finish her.
Give me.
- (BELL DINGS)
- Box!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BELL DINGS)
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
His jabs are getting low
and his swings are wild.
That leaves him open.
Work your way inside and go for
his brain every chance you get.
Okay.
I don't care who this guy is to you.
Don't be afraid to hurt him.
(BELL DINGS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(INAUDIBLE)
Get up, get up, get up!
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(GROANS)
(CROWD CHANTING INDISTINCTLY)
(CROWD CHEERING WILDLY)
Boxers, center of the ring, please.
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a unanimous decision.
The amateur featherweight
champ in these finals is.
Diana Guzman!
- Yeah!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
Satisfied?
(LAUGHS)
In all my life, I never been so proud.
Never.
Let's go.
(SIGHS)
(SOBS)
(SNIFFLES)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
You got a deadly hook.
Someone really worked you over.
Your right cross is no powder puff.
I gave you everything I had.
Me too.
Boxing, going pro...
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
I want it to be my ticket out.
But I gave you an opening. It was stupid.
But that's what happens.
You just take advantage.
Yeah.
So, now I lose your respect, huh?
No.
After the other night? Come on.
You boxed with me like I was any other guy.
You threw down and you showed me respect.
Don't you see what that means?
That life with you is war.
Maybe.
Maybe life's just war, period.
(SCOFFS)
You said it.
My life's been a mess since I met you.
So, you gonna dump me now?
Probably.
(SCOFFS)
Promise?
(SIGHS)
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)