[♪♪♪]
All right, let's talk
a little bit more about you.
You-- Right there.
That's where you're gonna be
in, like, six weeks.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Um....
My number-one focus of purpose
is to share with you who I am...
...and to...
...give you as much of myself
as I possibly can while I can.
And I'm excited. I'm excited.
I want you to come sooner than later
so I can still hold you-- Unh!
Hold you and--
You in my hands and my arms.
And use all that stuff--
Just--
Just love you.
MAN:
The 6th of October, 2001.
We're heading down to
the OSU-Washington State game...
- ...where the game is sold out.
STEVE: Homecoming.
MAN: Homecoming.
Another beautiful day...
...in Spokane, Washington.
[MAN LAUGHS]
Oh, it's a great day.
Cougs are favored by 10.
Steve doesn't like it. I like it.
Oh, man, it's a beautiful time.
It's a beautiful time for the Cougs.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER 1:
Steve Gleason has...
...what every college football coach
is looking for in a linebacker.
ANNOUNCER 2:
Really, really fast.
Really, really aggressive.
ANNOUNCER 1: He's small, but no one
can deny Steve Gleason's ability to hit.
I think that playing football,
you know, is a great time for...
...every guy to get
out there, you know...
...and let out your aggression
and just kind of be a free spirit.
Cougar football at its best.
Gleason and me. Two legends.
He pass blocks,
you take a step back.
He run blocks,
bam, you're in there.
For the average college linebacker,
he was too small.
And he was way too small
for the NFL to play linebacker.
He had to work harder, run harder,
train harder...
...just so he could be the guy that was
gonna be on that 53-man roster.
I'd never seen a guy
cover kicks the way he does.
It takes a certain type of psyche
and mindset to do that.
It's actually kind of a crazy,
sort of loose cannon...
..."this guy's obviously got
a few screws loose" type of mindset.
And that's what made him so good.
McKENZIE: I consider Steve a real
kamikaze of sorts, you know...
...notorious for sticking
his head in there...
...totally giving up his body, tough.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
REPORTER 1:
There are reports from New Orleans...
...of people trapped in buildings...
...that have come down around them.
REPORTER 2: The Superdome became
a symbol of failure and despair.
Twenty thousand refugees lived here
for one miserable week...
...without power, water or sanitation.
[CROWD CHEERING]
ANNOUNCER 1: A beautiful day
and an unbelievable scene...
...here inside the Louisiana Superdome.
MAN: Who are we?
ALL: Saints!
MAN:
Are we ready?
This is New Orleans!
[WHOOPING]
ANNOUNCER 2: A moment almost
unimaginable 13 months ago is here.
ANNOUNCER 3:
Look out! Right through!
A pickoff by Steve Gleason!
And it's scooped, and score
by Curtis DeLoatch!
Touchdown! New Orleans!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER 2: And for those people
who look to the New Orleans Saints...
...as something that will
uplift them, uplift this city...
...uplift the entire Gulf Region,
they've just had it!
That night, and specifically Steve
blocking the punt...
...was like a signal to everybody
that not only is New Orleans back...
...but it just felt like the rebirth
of something really, really big.
[LAUGHS]
Can you effing believe that?
All right, we need
another performance.
BOTH:
♪ Back to back with the Rio Grande ♪
♪ A Christian born in the devil's land ♪
♪ She learned the language
And she learned to fight ♪
♪ But she never learned
How to beat the lonely nights ♪
♪ In Lonesome Dove ♪
♪ Lonesome Dove ♪♪
STEVE: I want to teach you
how to hold the camera.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- How's that?
- Fine.
- Are you there?
MICHEL: I'm here.
You don't like to talk behind the camera?
I'm a filmer, I'm not a subject.
Yeah, but a good filmer...
...asks really good questions
to get really good material.
Are you almost done?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Good question.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[♪♪♪]
When I first got to know him,
he plays--
He had long hair
and played for the NFL.
I thought he was gonna be
a complete cheeseball.
But when I met him,
he was perfect.
I thought he was
the greatest thing I've ever met.
He lived in a small house
and didn't have a TV...
...and drove a truck
and was different than Southern boys...
...and he loved to, like,
adventure travel.
I liked to travel at the time too.
He was this superhero athlete
but also super smart.
He was the best of
both worlds, let's say.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
VINNIE:
With the kind of person that Steve is...
...he was attracted to
the free spirit of Michel.
The kind of honest bluntness,
willing to try anything...
...really no airs about her.
[PEOPLE CHEERING
AND CLAPPING]
I don't know, you can never think
of Michel settling down.
She was always the life
of the party.
She was always having fun.
Is Michel really gonna settle down?
Is Michel gonna have kids?
No way. That's not gonna happen.
[STEVE LAUGHING]
STEVE:
No, you gotta try again.
Watch your hands.
[STEVE LAUGHS]
RYAN: As unique as Steve is,
Michel is equally as unique...
...and I think she was still
trying to find herself...
...and didn't know
where she was going.
And I think when she met Steve,
they just started clicking.
[♪♪♪]
And I think it's such
an amazing thing...
...that both of you said
to me yesterday.
Even if it's pouring rain,
it doesn't matter.
We have each other.
Our family and friends
are gonna be here.
And isn't that, really,
as all us married people know...
...it's how we act,
not when things are great--
It's easy to be loving to each other
when things are great.
But how do we act
as a couple together...
...when things aren't great?
When things are difficult?
[ALL CHEERING
AND CLAPPING]
Bye!
[PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
REPORTER: Now I guess we could say
you're officially a New Orleanean.
You married a local girl, you live
in a historic neighborhood.
Are you a New Orleanean?
It's a city that I love.
I'm very thankful for all that has come
to me through this city.
REPORTER: Is it okay with you,
the fact that you're kind of...
...synonymous for one play?
You played nine years in the NFL.
You were on the Saints team that won
the first-ever playoff game.
Look, if you gotta pick one thing...
...that you're gonna be known for,
that is fine with me.
REPORTER: And before we go,
I wanted Steve to wear...
...his Number 37 jersey
for this segment...
...but he just said
he won't put it on.
I wear my jersey on the field.
Those days are done.
[♪♪♪]
So I've been having
some strange medical issues...
...going on with me recently. Um....
I've been having some
muscle twitching in my arms.
Mostly my upper arms,
shoulders on both sides.
And some in my chest...
...in my back,
a little bit in my upper legs.
I then also talked to my naturopath...
...and he seemed
a little bit concerned about it.
He spoke about these types
of symptoms on three levels.
It could be some type
of molecular problem...
...or it could be some type
of mechanical problem...
...meaning my neck or my head
have some type of trauma.
I might have a bulging disc
or a ruptured disc...
...or calcification in my vertebrae...
...from all my football trauma.
Thirdly, it could be some
type of neurological disease.
The disease that he mentioned as--
Obviously the worst-case scenario
would be ALS...
...which is Lou Gehrig's disease.
I have been diagnosed with
amyotrophic lateral sclerosis...
...which is a disease
in the motor neurons.
And this disease is almost always fatal.
My first reaction was
kind of frustration or anger...
...at the doctor for saying it.
And I just was like,
there's no-- There's no way.
He's telling me this, but I don't
necessarily believe what he's saying.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Although this is part
of the challenge...
...like, yeah, I wanna beat ALS...
...I want to win that part of the game...
...but for me,
the biggest part of the game is...
...beating all the other shit that you and I
have talked about is...
...karma from our parents...
...or relationships with family...
...or relationships with friends...
...or your own spirituality...
...and just peace in your heart.
But I just think there's
a bigger battle there...
...about being able to say:
"Okay, I have been--
Have this diagnosis...
...and it's not gonna--
It's not gonna crush my life...
...even if it does crush,
you know, crush my body."
I think you look really cute today.
I haven't smelled you,
but you look really cute.
STEVE:
I wish I could zoom in on that.
Damn.
MICHEL: Is it hard not to tell?
Especially if he's real hung?
I know it's a boy.
STEVE:
And I know it's a girl.
- But I know more.
STEVE: Yeah, right.
Before this,
we wanted a baby...
...and after this,
just because it meant that...
...I'd have to help
take care of him.
It wasn't a big enough reason
not to have a baby with him...
...and have all the beautiful things
that having a baby...
...you know, bring to a family
and a couple.
MICHEL:
Here you go, Steve-O.
It's definitely in there.
[♪♪♪]
What is this all about?
I am making a video blog of myself.
This is intended to be a gift for you...
...my child who I have not yet met.
MICHEL:
Do you think it already has a hard head?
GAIL: It could. Ha-ha-ha.
MICHEL: That comes from his dad's side.
[LAUGHING]
My intention is to pass on
as much of who I am...
...as I possibly can to you.
And I think if I can do that
in a good way...
...it can be even more meaningful...
...than having a father who's around...
...for 30 or 50 or 60 years of your life.
Now, I hope that happens too...
...but this is a nice little
backup insurance plan.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
STEVE: For me, the weird thing is--
The scary thing is, like...
...every week or so
there's a new thing...
...where I'm like,
"Oh, I can't do that."
I'm losing that.
I lost that, just lost that."
MAN: The only way we're going
to get started...
...is we have to have
a pregnant woman to start us.
Is there any pregnant women
in the house?
We got one pregnant woman!
Well, get in, girl,
you're the starter.
- On your marks.
MAN: Here we go.
- Get set.
MAN: We're set!
MICHEL:
Go! Go, go, go.
Go, go, go, go.
It was interesting
because not everybody knew...
...that Steve had ALS.
They were treating him
like he was still...
...a healthy ex-football player.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING]
[MAN WHOOPING]
I hadn't cried, I think,
in a long time.
It's just kind of like,
this is gonna be okay.
But seeing that kind of,
like, awkward gait...
...it crushed me.
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
- Come on, three-seven!
MAN 1: Whoo!
Three-seven! Fuck, yeah!
MAN 2:
Three-seven! Yeah, buddy! You did it!
MAN 1:
Yes! Whoa!
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[MEN WHOOPING]
[MAN 3 GRUNTING]
Stretch! Stretch. Stretch.
- Good job, dude.
- Are you injured, brother?
No one knows what
I'm feeling right now.
I don't want him
to go through this.
I don't want to deal with this.
For the first time, you don't want
to realize that this is the truth.
And in those moments
you realize it's the truth...
...and, like, this is fucking happening
to my husband.
This is happening.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[♪♪♪]
STEVE: I think the big question is,
"Why is this happening?"
You know, me and Michel
are so good together.
We're so perfect,
being really good people.
So I kept asking
over and over again:
"God, if you have some
control over this universe...
...why would this happen to me?
If you have control over this...
...then save me, you know.
Help heal me.
Because I don't want Michel
to be here by herself."
I'm sure there are people
that get this diagnosis...
...and just kind of shut down...
...whereas it's kind of ignited
a fire in me...
...where I'm not gonna shut down.
Not only am I not gonna shut down...
...I'm gonna go a little bit further,
you know?
Push the envelope a little bit.
[♪♪♪]
Whoo-hoo!
♪ Yes, I understand
That every life must end, uh-huh ♪
MICHEL: Hell, yeah!
- Hell, yeah!
- Halleluiah!
MICHEL: Yahoo!
♪ Oh, I'm a lucky man ♪
♪ To count on both hands
The ones I love ♪
You know, I was torn.
A lot of people were saying...
...I shouldn't necessarily go on this trip.
I should be seeking out ways
that I can get healed...
...or get some treatment.
In the end,
I think I decided that...
...the odds of me finding
some type of treatment...
...in the next six months
were too small.
It's gotten a lot harder
for me to do stuff.
The other thing
that's really frustrating for me...
...is the talking.
So it's getting harder
for me to talk.
I know I've said this
before on film...
...but it's not gonna stop,
I guess.
It's probable that it won't stop.
♪ Hold me till I die ♪
♪ Meet you on the other side ♪♪
Quite possibly one of the coolest things
I've ever done.
We've been, what,
around the world...
...and in front of millions of people...
...but that plane flight was amazing.
MICHEL:
Glacier landing versus punt block?
- I don't know, it's close.
- Heh-heh-heh.
Want to tell the baby anything?
I think, um....
We had a destination in mind
when we came up here...
...and I would say we are there.
Be present now, right?
Better late than never.
Better now than never.
BRENDAN: Yeah. Yeah.
STEVE: Talking?
Sorry.
Where are you going?
Over here?
My favorite part is
to do things like this.
- Hello. Hello.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Hey, how are you?
Oh, how are you now?
Well, things changed
since you were here to now.
Nothing has changed for me.
It's a couple seconds.
For you, though? Huh?
Things have changed.
[LAUGHS]
STEVE:
Like, it's weird...
...that I'm potentially having
a conversation...
...initiating a conversation...
...with someone who
I actually might never talk to...
- ...in a real conversation.
- Mm-hm.
The baby will be born in November.
So I'll talk to it, sure.
But like let's say a real conversation...
...starts at like 4 years old.
Maybe I'm not having
conversations at that point.
It's fucked up.
So then it's like...
...well, if I was that person...
...what would I want to hear people say?
What would I want to hear my dad say?
You know?
You just want him to be real.
Yeah, so that's why I'm like,
"Look this is just raw...
...and unprepared."
I mean, the same shit...
- ...we want when our dads are alive.
- Yeah.
We dislike what so many parents do...
...is like, "I'm a parent now.
I'm not a person anymore.
- And I'm not real."
- Yeah.
"I don't have all the exact
same flaws as you.
I don't do the exact same
stupid shit that you're doing."
Yeah.
The big thing that's happened
since I've been diagnosed...
...in January is that one thing
I want to accomplish...
...is to have all my
relationships in order...
...is the term I've been using.
In my teenage years, my dad
was very strict and protective.
His only way to teach how to live life...
...was to teach it out of fear.
STEVE: As much as possible,
try not twist like that.
I won't once we get going.
You got all your questions there?
STEVE: Yeah. Yeah.
- That's good.
So I think a good place
to start, Dad, would be, um--
How about your birth?
Yeah, that's what I was
gonna say, was...
...the very first memory of me
as a very young child.
What were some of
the things that you remember?
- Is that thing on?
- Yeah.
It can hear what
you just asked me?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
He was a reader, pretty cerebral.
He wasn't an introvert,
but he was more on the quiet side.
I can remember he was
about 6 years old...
...and I had him in the backyard.
He was at the farthest end
of the lot in the backyard.
I bought him a Wiffle ball
and a bat.
I said, "Now, Steve,
keep your eye on the ball...
...and watch the ball hit the bat."
So I tossed it to him.
First time he swung the bat,
he hit the ball over the house.
And we're talking a plastic Wiffle ball.
And I thought, "Holy crap.
What do I have here?"
Our parents got divorced
when I was 15...
- ...and you were 11 maybe?
- Something like that.
And so growing up,
what I remember...
...is that they would fight all the time.
A lot of verbal abuse. Um....
Our parents literally
screamed at each other...
...for hours, just, like, screaming
as loud as they could...
- ...for hours and hours and hours.
- Yeah.
There reached a point
between Mike and I...
...where things got pretty bad...
...and the boys did not like that...
...especially when I started
going to therapy...
...and learning how to stand up
for myself again.
Then that got pretty tense. Um....
I didn't have tremendous experience...
...in how to bring somebody up
and raise them.
My father was never home
when I grew up.
So I didn't really have an example...
...of how a father should be.
So I was just doing the best I could do.
I probably over pushed you
in some areas...
...just because I just saw
a lot of talent there...
...and somebody that had
fierce determination.
So I thought, well...
...there's a lot this kid can do.
[CROWD CHEERING]
MAN:
And here come the Cougars!
There's Stephen right there.
When you saw--
How the interaction was
at home as a family--
And things weren't right
between your mom and I--
That you can take all that
frustration out on the field.
And it was a great way
for you to release...
...pain, anger, uh....
And I hate to say it, but that was...
...one of my motivations
when I played ball.
Because my own life with my parents...
...was pretty dysfunctional.
And you grew up in a pretty
dysfunctional marriage.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
The biggest thing my dad
has contributed to me is...
...just determination, perseverance.
Hard work, I mean, the guy,
to a fault, he works hard.
I ended up in a 12-step
recovery program...
...for workoholism and anxiety.
This a Biblical principle...
...and it's in the Old Testament,
but it says...
...when the kings
and their sons would sin...
...it said that the generational sin...
...would go from one family to the next...
...unless somebody in the family...
...would get before the Lord and say,
"Okay, God, forgive me for this.
We're gonna knock this off for my family.
I'm not doing this anymore."
Somebody has to stop the sin...
...or else that same sin
runs from one family to the next.
Okay, a topic-based blog here.
Today's topic will be religion.
God. I don't believe God
is a father figure...
...white-haired man up in heaven.
I don't believe in the fear
that is in the Bible.
The fear tactics
that are used in the Bible.
I believe in love.
Treating someone else
as you would like to be treated...
...is my number-one, um, rule.
The more I pray, and the more
I read about this stuff...
...the more I believe
God wants to heal you.
Now, wait a minute,
if that doesn't happen...
- ...I can accept that.
- Okay.
The more I hear you saying,
"God wants to heal you.
God wants to heal you,"
and I'm like:
"Hm. That's interesting
because it says in the Bible...
...that we don't know God's mind."
- No, that's not truth.
- It does say that, though.
No.
So are you saying that since I'm--
I'm not saying--
Since I'm sick and if I die it's because
I don't have the mind of Christ?
- No, I'm not saying that at all.
- Okay.
I would never say that.
Never.
MICHEL: I'm feeling open
and a little bit anxious and nervous.
- How are you feeling?
STEVE: About the same.
About the same.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
MAN: Let's give Kevin
a warm welcome as he comes.
[ALL CLAPPING AND CHEERING]
It's a privilege
to be back here again.
I think we were here about
three years ago, wasn't it?
Four years?
Three or four years ago.
From 1843 on...
[WHISPERING]
When I started reading that book...
DEDMON:...you could see how one
generation's ceiling...
...I started feeling inside of me...
DEDMON:
...became the next generation's floor...
...that I should lay hands
on my own son.
DEDMON:...and it's important,
absolutely important...
...that we know our heritage...
But I was scared, just like he was,
because I didn't want it to not work.
DEDMON:...our lineage,
so we can obtain our inheritance.
Well, just do it.
DEDMON: The Bible says
that if you honor a prophet...
...in the name of a prophet,
you'll get a prophet's reward.
We're gonna get there. This whole thing's
gonna be easier, Michel.
DEDMON:
So if we study history....
It's gonna take time.
DEDMON: We're gonna focus
on ourselves right now...
...and we're gonna put our hand
on our body parts.
Later, we'll put our hands
on other people.
Later on.
But we'll start here first.
And then I want us to sing:
"It's the End of My Pain
As I Know It."
- Are you ready?
- Let's do it, Kevin.
ALL:
♪ It's the end of my pain as I know it ♪
♪ And I feel fine ♪♪
DEDMON:
Okay, now, check your body out.
Try to make it heard.
Try to do something
that you couldn't before.
And see if there's, like...
I'm gonna go run.
DEDMON:...10 percent, 20 percent,
30 percent difference...
...50 percent, 100 percent improvement,
some kind of improvement.
Come on, try to make
it heard real quick.
Now, wave your hand if you
had some kind of improvement.
Right there. Right here.
Right there. Right over here.
Right back there. Right here.
Right over there.
I'm gonna run.
DEDMON:
Okay, go for it. Right over here.
I'm gonna run.
DEDMON: Right here. Right there.
Wow! Look at this.
Should I run?
[ALL CHEERING AND CLAPPING]
DEDMON:
This is awesome.
Just go do it.
This is-- Go. Just go ahead.
Just check it out.
Try to make it heard right now.
Okay, wave your hand if you've
got some more breakthrough.
Look at this. More.
Okay. All right. Good try.
Here, let me have your hand.
Good try.
Try again.
Yeah, that was how many steps?
Four steps.
[ALL CLAPPING]
Let's get a couple
big guys here as well...
...and come alongside of him
to run with him.
- You're a big guy.
- Come on.
- You in the blue.
- There you go.
Don't touch me.
DEDMON:
Wait, wait, wait.
This is bullshit.
- It's not bullshit.
- Yes it is.
DEDMON:
So at this point, what we're gonna do is...
...these guys are gonna
go back there and practice this...
...while I continue.
There you go.
Keep up with him.
Keep up.
MICHEL: He's gonna tell you
it will happen when he leaves you.
He said usually things happen
once he's gone.
Just so you know.
MIKE:
Michel, you're his partner.
You need to trust and believe with him.
STEVE:
She's with me all the way.
I am with him so much, Mike.
Don't you dare say that to me.
It's okay.
- Michel, come on in.
- Everybody's different.
WOMAN: I know. That's what she
just said, though. That's what she said.
[CHATTERING]
STEVE: I feel sick.
MICHEL: Okay.
The team's gonna come this way
and go past us that way.
- Okay.
MAN: Okay.
REPORTER:
It was a surprise appearance...
...by Steve Gleason.
His first appearance on camera...
...since going public
that he had been diagnosed...
...with ALS.
Obviously, I don't, uh....
...how to move or talk...
...quite the way I used to.
[♪♪♪]
STEVE:
When you're good at something...
...it's fun to see other people admire you.
And I think that's a good thing
to be so good at something...
...that people admire you.
But I think it could be dangerous
if that becomes obsessive.
And I certainly struggled
with that when I retired.
If you're not doing something
where there's tens of thousands...
...or millions of people
that are admiring you...
...can you still be happy?
Tough question.
REPORTER: It was just prior
to the Saint's home game...
...on September 25th
with the Texans...
...that Gleason went public...
...that he had been
diagnosed with ALS.
He was named an honorary captain
for that football game...
...and came out at mid-field
to lead a "Who-Dat" chant...
...that no one will ever forget,
especially Gleason.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
STEVE: When I would play football,
during games...
...I would have this fear of walking
onto the football field.
And I would tell myself,
"Hey, if I die today...
...or on this play, then I'm okay.
I've had a good life,
and I feel good about...
...kind of accepting death."
At the same time,
I think that...
...that thought and maybe
the actions that followed it...
...sometimes I think that's--
That might be why...
...I have ended up
where I am right now.
And now I think about it,
and I don't want to die.
[CROWD CHEERING]
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Who-dat?! Who-dat?!
Who-dat say
de gonna beat dem Saints?!
[♪♪♪]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
REPORTER:
So for now, Gleason's goals are clear.
Live each day to the fullest...
...and spread the word about ALS.
If I could help show
and inspire people to--
That have been diagnosed
with ALS...
...to continue living their life...
...and if we can, as a group...
...if we could help those people--
Those people who have been
diagnosed continue to live...
...a life that's enriching
and extraordinary...
...then I think
that's part of my goal.
MAN:
We have to define your purpose.
To me, there's two things you can do...
...in terms of medical disease
related fundraising.
Either for research for a cure...
...or for services, equipment,
technology, etc.
I chose services and equipment,
as opposed to research.
MAN:
Okay.
I want to accomplish two things.
I want to advance those technologies,
services and equipment.
And I'd like to provide people
with purpose.
We had a kid who e-mailed me. He said:
"I'm 29, I just read your entire blog
about going to Alaska.
That's been a dream of mine forever.
I got diagnosed with ALS
two months ago."
My idea is to create ways
for ALS patients...
...even if they can't move,
to participate in these...
...projects, these expeditions.
But that's-- If all goes my way...
...that's what I'd like to do with the money
that we raise for this foundation.
JIM:
Legally, for the formation....
No, no, no.
We do need something
legal for foundation.
Yeah, for, so, Jim--
[JIM SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
ON COMPUTER]
Thank you so much, guys.
Have a great night.
MAN 1: All right, thanks.
MAN 2: Thanks, bud.
MAN 3:
Late.
That was sweet.
STEVE:
Hi. Hi.
- Good morning.
- Hi.
STEVE:
Hey you. I'm sorry.
MICHEL:
That's okay.
STEVE:
I don't know why I did that.
MICHEL:
Heh. I don't know either.
STEVE:
You are so important.
You know that.
You are, you're it.
Like, you're, you're it.
You're it.
All that other shit doesn't matter.
MICHEL:
Okay.
STEVE:
I'm telling you, I'm serious.
But I am kind of excited
because I think...
...we could create something here.
MICHEL: Buddy, I think it's great.
I mean, I think it's great.
STEVE:
We have a passion, a project...
...something that we have to live for.
- Steve, this is--
- That's raw, you know.
MICHEL:
This is-- Look, this is--
That is nothing why I'm crying,
this has nothing to do with that.
- I don't know why I'm crying.
- I want you to help me create it.
I know.
Steve, I'm here with you in every step.
It's not like I'm not.
STEVE: I know. I'm just saying
I want you to feel like...
...we need you to create this.
This is-- There's things
that you can get too involved in...
...but I think that this is great stuff.
MICHEL:
The contractions, I can't even tell...
...because there's so much
pressure all the time...
...and they've moved
from my hernia down to my--
STEVE:
It's go time. It's go time.
JULIE [ON PHONE]:
Michel, that is how labor is.
It's not back labor.
Do you have any fluids
coming out at all?
MICHEL: I just had a tiny little thing
of pink this morning.
JULIE:
Okay. You're in labor!
MICHEL:
Julie, but we don't know yet...
...so I don't want to be
one of those people--
JULIE:
Yeah, I know. Okay?
Sarah's sitting right here and she's like:
"She's having a baby."
You're having the baby today.
Steve, are you ready?
STEVE:
No choice.
[ALL LAUGHING]
JULIE:
No choice.
I'm letting you know in advance...
...it's going to be difficult for me...
...pushing this thing out of that little hole.
You're gonna do great.
I'm gonna help you.
And.... And....
There's things in life that are hard,
but you just gotta do.
I know, but do you understand
what's about to happen?
- Yeah.
- If it happens.
Yeah.
WOMAN:
Michel Varisco.
Well, it's October 19th, 2011.
We've done several of
these types of journals...
...but it's go time.
I've been scared about
doing this for my whole life.
STEVE:
Come on out, little buddy.
Come on out.
Oh, sweet Jesus, Steve.
I want a kiss.
You got it.
- Michel, I love you so much.
- I love you.
And we're doing the--
Really, the coolest thing...
...we could do together, right?
- That's right.
- Fucking right, dude.
[♪♪♪]
[MICHEL IMITATES FANFARE]
DOCTOR:
Let's see. All right, this is it, guys.
NURSE:
There you go.
[DOCTOR SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
DOCTOR:
We're gonna do most of the work.
Deep breath.
Give me a little half push.
There we go.
All right, no more.
Let's go straight up,
Steve. Ready?
Straight up.
Hold right here.
Ready? Watch this.
MICHEL:
He's little.
I want to see him.
DOCTOR: Okay, Michel,
look at your baby.
- Look at this baby.
- Look at that beautiful baby.
DOCTOR: All right, Steve,
get your hand right here.
- We got it, it's okay.
- There it is.
- We got it.
- You got it, I don't have it.
You got it.
You got a baby boy.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Wait, can you hold him?
- I got him.
MICHEL: I knew it was a boy.
NURSE: That's Rivers.
- That's my boy.
MICHEL:
I just want to see him.
I don't know how to hold him.
I don't think that's mine.
MICHEL:
You don't?
I mean,
it doesn't even seem real.
[RIVERS CRYING]
It was so easy.
NURSE:
You did it good. You were great.
STEVE:
Mick, you did great, dude.
I'm ready for number two.
[ALL LAUGHING]
STEVE:
Well, okay.
♪ Rivers and roads ♪
MICHEL:
STEVE:
♪ Rivers and roads ♪♪
That's Rivers Varisco Gleason,
your grandson.
MIKE [ON PHONE]: Rivers.
That's what you named him, Rivers?
Yep.
What's his middle name?
Varisco.
Oh. Just like her last name.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Rivers Varisco Gleason.
Rivers.
All right.
[ALL LAUGHING]
So, are you at the hospital?
Oh, yeah, dude.
Dad, we had the baby,
like, half an hour ago.
Half an hour ago.
Yeah, man.
What's up, Rivers?
You're right here.
Ahem. All right.
October 20th, 2011...
...and this will be...
...my first video journal...
...where we're in it together.
How about that?
It's also the first video journal where...
...I get to...
...talk to you in, what,
the first person...
...rather than using pronouns.
I'm scared.
We don't know
what the hell we're doing.
Anyhow, the big thing is...
...I'm writing a bunch about...
...what the word and the name...
...and what rivers
actually mean to me.
I came up with this
several years ago...
...but I decided that rivers
are the source of fire.
Here's my logic.
A fire burns wood as its fuel...
...and this wood comes from a tree...
...that drinks from the rivers...
...and so the rivers
are the fuel for the fire.
And you are the rivers...
...for my fire.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
♪ I can hear her heart beat
For a thousand miles ♪
♪ And the heavens open
Every time she smiles ♪
♪ And when I come to her
That's where I belong ♪
♪ Yet I'm running to her
Like a river's song ♪
♪ She give me love, love, love, love
Crazy love ♪
♪ You give me love, love, love, love
♪ She give me love, love, love, love
Crazy love ♪
♪ She give me love, love, love, love ♪
♪ She give me crazy ♪
♪ She drives me a little crazy ♪♪
MAN: Stephen Michael Gleason,
Michel Rae Varisco.
Today I'm gonna talk about, uh, um...
...my insecurities.
I think I cared a lot about
what people thought of me...
...and I suppose I--
I battle that even today. Um....
[CLEARS THROAT]
I wonder sometimes
if I'm doing too much...
...because people
want me to do a lot.
You know, people are like,
oh, you're a hero, you're-- Uh....
[CLEARS THROAT]
You're, uh--
You're an inspiration,
so I'm, like, okay...
...what can I keep doing
to continue to be an inspiration?
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
MICHEL: Hello.
MELANIE: Hi, is this Michel?
- This is she.
- Hi, Michel, it's Melanie...
...and I am here
with Jim Eutizzi...
...and then a couple people
that I work with.
- Oh, okay. How are y'all doing today?
- Good.
I'm here with my husband Steve,
and our baby Rivers.
And we've got a--
A message to give Jim.
[RIVERS SCREAMS]
MICHEL:
That was from Rivers.
That was hello from Rivers.
And from us,
we wanted to let Jim know...
...well, ask him if he'd like to, uh--
To go to Italy with his son...
...because we've already
bought him tickets...
...for about 12 days in June.
MELANIE [VOICE BREAKING]:
Here are your tickets.
[ALL SOBBING]
MELANIE:
Okay, Michel.
Well, does he want to go or not?
MELANIE:
You want to go, right?
[VOICE BREAKING]
Oh, God.
I don't know what to say.
WOMAN:
That is so awesome, Melanie.
JIM:
I don't know what to say.
[CHUCKLES]
[♪♪♪]
Hi, this is Kurt Warner,
and I support Team Gleason.
No white flags, baby.
Hi, I'm John Elway
for Team Gleason.
No white flags.
I'm Reverend Jesse Jackson.
I support Team Gleason.
No white flags.
- I'm Mike McCready...
- Ha-ha-ha.
...badass guitarist for the greatest
rock band ever, Pearl Jam.
Hey, I'm-- I'm Steve Gleason.
I'm a totally incredible human being...
...doing fantastic work
with Team Gleason.
- Always remember.
BOTH:
No white flags.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
STEVE:
It's my belief that...
...most of what ALS takes away
from people...
...technology can give back.
[CLEARS THROAT]
It transpires that
my oeuvre has evidentiary...
...not literary, merit.
Damn it.
MICHEL: You lose your voice
when you have ALS.
And so he found--
He researched this place...
...where you can actually voice bank...
...so his mechanical voice...
...instead of being like
Stephen Hawking...
...his is gonna be his voice.
STEVE: Senator Russ Feingold
of Wisconsin...
...also took himself
out of the running.
Then it goes to eye technology
where he talks with his eyes...
...but he's talking a letter at a time.
WOMAN: When you see
the green dots in there...
...that means it's picking up on it...
...on your eyes.
First, let's get back--
Let's get you back. There you go.
Got it.
Do you just get really--
As you get used to it,
can you do it faster?
WOMAN:
Oh, gosh, yes.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
Hi, Michel, you rock.
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
It's the first time today,
man, I watched...
...some of my videos
from the last couple days...
...and I listened to myself
and I was--
Sound-- Probably sound--
Sound ill.
Sound sick.
And that, uh--
It's tough, man.
[STEVE MAKING SNORING SOUNDS]
I've been thinking
about fathers and sons...
...a lot since you've been born.
And...
...at this point it looks like
we're not going to have...
...the normal father-son relationship.
I can't go out and play catch with you.
I can't throw you batting practice.
But I want to do everything I can...
...to be a good father...
...to give you what a son needs...
...from his father.
And....
I'm gonna be around, buddy.
It's not gonna be easy,
but it's gonna be awesome.
And I'm gonna be around...
...until you are able
to stand on your own...
...as a man.
MAN:
Steve, how old are you?
- Thirty-four.
MAN: Thirty-four.
MAN: Do you know what
your weight is right now?
- One-ninety.
MAN: One-ninety.
So it's gonna be 24 inches wide...
...it's gonna have the casters up here.
The casters up here,
you don't have them on this chair...
...because it's a little more stable base.
[♪♪♪]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
STEVE:
It's crazy, man.
I am to the point where...
...I barely go out of
the house by myself.
Michel goes everywhere
with me now.
She helps me shower.
She helps me
put on my clothes.
She helps me eat.
You have a mom
who's just incredible.
Incredible.
Remarkable, amazing.
And we're both
so lucky to have her.
I think any caretaker,
you're always kind of there...
...trying to make things
easier for him.
I just feel like it's what I do...
...and it's our relationship,
it's what we do, it's--
It's just kind of, like,
part of our life...
...like this is-- This is what it is.
So I set up things for him
in the morning...
...I set up things for him at night...
...help him walk,
help him brush his teeth...
...help feed him, and it's--
It's just kind of like
a new part of life.
Just like it is learning
how to take care of Rivers.
[MUMBLING]
[COOING]
[RIVERS CRYING]
STEVE:
Hey.
Hey, man, you're okay.
STEVE:
Kids are a lot of fricking work, man.
And we get up
every three hours...
...to feed you,
and when I say we...
...I mean Michel.
You like that?
STEVE:
And I can see it's taking a toll on Michel.
She's getting tired.
And I'm gonna think of ways to--
To help her.
Either having someone
stay over at night...
...or something,
we gotta figure out something...
...because I'd like to somehow
ease that burden...
...a little bit from her.
So do you-- Are you in that?
I mean, are you familiar
with any of it?
Are you in the-- I mean,
you're obviously in good shape.
I mean, like, you are you, like,
in the therapy world, or--?
STEVE: No.
- No?
He's a neighbor and, big enough, like....
He's going to move me
where she might not be able to.
You know, he was my hero. This is
the guy that I wanted to be growing up.
Turned out, you know,
he was dating Michel...
...and Michel used to
baby-sit me as a kid.
When he was diagnosed,
she asked me--
She gave me an ultimatum.
She said,
"Blair, you either quit your job...
...or I'm gonna kick you
in your dick."
[STEVE GRUNTING]
Blair and I's life purpose was
to make sure Steve was happy.
There's times where Steve would say,
"What am I doing? What's the point?
This is awful."
And we'd be like...
...okay, like, what can we do?
Do a dance, build him up.
And it was--
We had a fucking badass unit.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[♪♪♪]
MICHEL:
The journey into the lake, part one.
--three, go.
Damn!
Rivers, be a part of
the fucking team...
...and eat your goddamn food.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
[BLOWING]
Hey. Hey.
♪ How long have I known you, brother? ♪
♪ Hundreds of lives
Thousands of years ♪♪
I feel like, in many ways,
I'm fulfilling my purpose.
I feel excited every day
to get up and make...
...a difference and an impact
on people's life.
I feel like I've put together
a good team of people...
...to help take care of me.
I've put together
a good team of people...
...to look for solutions.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
People will say,
"Oh, it's such a sad, tragic story."
It is sad, and so they're right...
...but it's not all sad.
And I think there is more
in my future than in my past.
I believe my future
is bigger than my past.
And so that's uplifting.
That's inspiring.
[RIVERS COOING]
BLAIR:
Bah!
[GIGGLING]
MICHEL:
Bah!
Lately, the coolest stuff
for me has been...
...you falling asleep on my lap...
...while we drive around in my chair.
MICHEL: Which you need to name,
by the way.
You mean my electric chair.
This isn't the electric chair, though.
MICHEL:
EC.
You should call it gonorrhea
because it's temporary.
MICHEL:
Gonny?
- Gonny.
- Gonorrhea's temporary?
MICHEL: You just coined it--
Yeah. Penicillin cures all that shit.
And doxycycline.
Somebody told me that.
June 17th, 2012.
MIKE:
Are you gonna shoot it?
Look at the camera, Rivers.
Oh, Dad--
What?
MICHEL:
It's a video.
Oh, it's a video.
I didn't know that.
Why didn't you--
Why didn't you tell me that?
Then I won't be
sitting here like a s--
Stuffed pepper.
Hey, buddy.
So, what are all
the numbers for, Steve?
[LAUGHING]
What am I missing?
Am I missing something?
MICHEL:
All right, he's doing his--
June 17, 2012.
Oh, I get it.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
All dads never think that they're...
...annoying their kids like they do...
...so I have no idea
how I will annoy you.
[SIGHS]
I hope it's not the way
that my dad annoys me.
So your taste buds
still working pretty good?
All right. You still taste stuff?
[CHUCKLING]
You act like you've been eating ****.
You got all embarrassed.
Your sense of humor still working?
[ALL LAUGHING]
I'm sorry, Steve.
- Dad.
- What?
I just asked if your
taste buds were working.
Do you know anything about ALS?
Not a lot, but it looks-- It's not-- It's--
It doesn't affect your taste buds.
I didn't know that.
So I was not embarrassed.
I was laughing at you.
Oh, you were laughing at me.
Because I didn't know that.
Okay. All right.
MICHEL:
That was one of the best just now.
What-- He's got--
My dad will go from zero
to over the line.
Then like you're like, "Wait, what?"
[ALL LAUGHING]
So weird.
[♪♪♪]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
STEVE: There's almost
nothing more personal than...
...a father-son relationship,
you know.
What I think is
so interesting is that...
...this is obviously--
This whole thing,
these video journals, this film...
...all this is about
a father and a son.
Um, my dad and I, I think...
...believe a lot of
the same things...
...but he's this wacky,
fundamental, literal, uh...
...kind of single-minded man...
...who thinks that I should believe...
...exactly what he believes...
...in order to be saved, I guess.
[VOICE BREAKING]
I was diagnosed with a terminal illness...
...and I know that when you get scared...
...you're going to jump to your camp
that I need to pray like you.
I need to believe all the same things
you believe.
You promised me
that you would not question my faith.
Okay.
But every time you question my faith,
it crushes me.
I-- I can understand that.
Because here's the thing about faith...
...you can't argue with someone's faith.
That's true.
You can't debate with someone's beliefs.
Because there's no proof either way.
Stop trying to understand...
...with your mind...
...the relationship
between my heart and God.
Okay.
My soul is saved.
[VOICE BREAKING]
Okay.
Don't be angry at me. Please.
[MIKE SOBBING]
Stephen, you're my son.
You don't know
what it feels like inside...
...that I might lose you, man.
You don't know what it feels like,
it's killing me.
[MIKE CONTINUES SOBBING]
[STAMMERING]
I love you, Stephen,
with everything inside of me.
I love you too, Dad.
[SCREAMING AND CRYING]
MICHEL:
This is a good idea?
Who the hell brings their kid
to this thing?
All right, ready?
[MICHEL MAKING
CAR ENGINE SOUNDS]
I'm out of breath. Are you too?
I think part of what we do every day
is search for...
...something that's...
...a permanent stabilization, and,
you know, maybe that's not out there...
...but I'm hopeful. I'm hopeful.
All right, bud. You're gonna do great.
Prick you here, okay?
All right.
There's been cases
where stem cell has worked.
Some ALS patients
will have the procedure...
...and they will not progress
any further.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MICHEL:
We spent lots of time in the hospital.
Like, just sitting there...
...so I needed to do something
so I just started drawing.
When I was drawing,
I could completely ignore...
...any of the doctors
that came in...
...or anybody who came in
that I didn't want to talk to.
I just completely can zone out.
All right?
WOMAN:
He wants us to call an ambulance.
[STEVE MUMBLING]
- Ask him if we should.
WOMAN: Ask him if we should.
BLAIR:
After that surgery...
...there was definitely
an adverse effect...
...and he was in such
a large amount of pain...
...he was convinced that
he was gonna die.
- I love you.
- You love me?
I love you too, are you scared?
You are?
[STEVE GRUNTS]
Earlier this week I had stem cell therapy.
And, um....
So far, not so good.
MICHEL: All right, with steady pressure,
gently insert enema tip into rectum...
...with a slight
side to side movement...
...with tip pointing toward navel--
STEVE:
Michel, look...
...you have to be able to do this.
Okay.
Don't get me down there and make me
wait for fucking 10 minutes, okay?
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
MICHEL:
Is this your butt?
[LIQUID INJECTED
WITH FLATULENCE SOUND]
BLAIR:
Oh, my God.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
MICHEL: Okay.
BLAIR: Is it all in?
MICHEL:
It's all in.
Besides the stuff that's in his--
STEVE:
I don't think anything went in.
MICHEL:
You didn't feel it?
STEVE:
Nothing.
God-fucking-damn it!
Who knows about enemas?
BLAIR:
Judy Robert, thank you for coming.
We have some--
We have some questions for you.
Judy, do you know what you're
about to get yourself into?
I have a whole bottle of lube.
What kind of lube did you bring?
Is it scented?
Actually, I think it is.
It is. What scent did you get?
Baby powder fresh.
I love that smell.
It's a truly beautiful smell.
So, what are you expecting
out of Steve today?
Um, a lot of shit.
- I hope to get a lot of shit out.
BLAIR: Ha-ha-ha.
JUDY:
All right.
I'm gonna know you
in a whole new way.
So, do you feel it?
I mean, does it feel--
We quoted-- Quoted Steve earlier.
"I feel like there's
a football lodged in my anus."
Okay, so, yeah,
there's probably like this:
MICHEL & BLAIR: You all right?
STEVE: Mm-hm. Yeah.
Judy...
What?
...am I the hottest guy
you've ever ass-fingered?
[ALL LAUGHING]
[STEVE GROANING]
JUDY:
That's it. That's it.
Rivers.
I'm having a bad day.
I'm an asshole to people, and...
...I don't care.
I can't talk.
I think the, the last of my...
...talking days are here.
The drugs I take don't work.
I have no faith that I can heal.
I have no hope.
No hope whatever.
I want to punch...
...something, but I can't!
The only thing I can do is scream.
[SCREAMS]
BREES:
"On Monday, September 25th, 2006...
...Steve Gleason was responsible for...
...one of the most dramatic moments
in New Orleans Saints history.
He blocked a punt in the first quarter...
...of the team's return to the Superdome...
...following hurricane Katrina.
That blocked punt, that season...
...symbolized the rebirth
of the city of New Orleans."
Amen.
[PEOPLE CLAPPING]
[♪♪♪]
Yesterday,
about five minutes after I got home...
...I pooped all over myself
and my wheelchair.
And I think it's crazy that I can go from...
...people saying, "You're my hero," to...
...having to be helped onto a toilet
with my pants full of shit.
It's an incredible example of polarities...
...and dichotomies, and juxtapositions...
...that is my life.
ALL:
♪ Happy birthday, dear Rivers ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪♪
[ALL CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
[CHATTERING]
WOMAN: When you blow out,
you gotta blow out hard and fast...
...because it's measuring
how much you get out...
...in one second, okay?
A normal breathe in.
Suck in. Now blow, push!
Push. Push, push, push,
push, push, push...
...push, push, push, push,
suck in big.
That's terrible.
Uh-uh. We're not accepting that one.
It's supposed to look like that.
When did you get this?
You didn't have this
last time when I saw you.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
A few weeks ago.
That's so cool.
STEVE:
This setup I have costs $6,000...
...but others cost 20K.
Mm....
- Ma.
- Mom.
Alligator.
- Alligator.
I love you.
Daddy.
[LAUGHING]
Say it again, bud.
STEVE: Oh....
- Daddy.
Daddy.
I love you.
[GIBBERING]
Oh....
I love you.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
Rivers, I want to talk about obstacles...
...in adversity.
No matter what, how wealthy you are...
...how poor you are...
...we all face adversity.
I do not want you to fail...
...but I want you to
put yourself out there...
...and available for potential rejection.
In ways, I think
that's how we succeed...
...because that's how we grow...
...and that's how we gain perspective.
♪ When I'm wiser and ♪
♪ Grown taller ♪
♪ I will see your ways ♪
♪ And when I've come to ♪
MICHEL:
Bee-po.
♪ The places I'm going ♪
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
♪ I will know your ways ♪
[GIGGLING]
♪ I can feel the hurt now
I can turn this pain to blame ♪
♪ I'm trying to see it clear
But I don't know why it's here at all ♪
Moon!
♪ You can keep yourself down
As long as you want now, but do you? ♪
[PLAYING MUSIC]
♪ You can push it on another
But, damn, that man's your brother ♪
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
♪ When I'm wiser and ♪
♪ Grown taller ♪
♪ I will see your ways ♪
♪ And when I'm wiser ♪
[LAUGHING]
♪ And grown taller ♪
♪ I will see your ways ♪
♪ And when I've come to the.... ♪♪
[CHEERING]
STEVE: Mwah!
MICHEL: Yay!
[RIVERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[CHATTERING ON TV]
MICHEL:
I wasn't sleeping at night...
...because I was caretaking for Steve.
And then the addition of Rivers
getting a little bit more needy.
It was hard doing that
plus taking care of a kid.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
M, at some point put Rivers on my lap.
Rivers? Rivers. Look at me.
STEVE:
M, at some point put Rivers on my lap.
MICHEL: Rivers, look at me.
You do not hit your mom.
You cannot hit your mommy.
You're going to go to time out.
[RIVERS CRYING AND SCREAMING]
All right, buddy.
Now you know you cannot
hit your mommy, okay?
All right? You understand
why you went in there?
Because you hit me three times.
You cannot do that, okay?
All right, bud?
MICHEL:
People started saying, like:
"Michel, you need help,
you need help, you need help...
...you need more help,"
and it's kind of like...
...well, this has turned
into my purpose...
...and I don't want to seem weak...
...and, like, I see
other people doing it.
[♪♪♪]
Can I get a pillow?
[RIVERS CRIES]
Come on now.
[STEVE WHIMPERING]
Honestly, I think the enormity
of what she's going through now...
...and dealing with this situation...
...just takes all of her energy.
I still think
she's trying her best...
...to do as much
as she can for people...
...and especially for Rivers
and Steve and her family...
...and struggling just to deal
with the situation.
It's easier, almost,
to, like, make a difference...
...with the world with this disease.
It's some face time on TV
or some speeches...
...or some tweets...
...versus, like, the reality...
...of the hardness it is
to maintain relationships...
...when you can't move
or help or talk.
And so we're just kind of
traveling like this:
Like we're not separating...
...but we're separated in what
we wanted to do with life.
REPORTER 1 [ON TV] Tonight
the federal government is saying no...
...to some devices that give
people with disabilities...
...a voice, literally.
REPORTER 2: Recent changes
to Medicare and Medicaid...
...have limited ALS patients' access...
...to speech generation devices.
PAUL: Team Gleason became
one of the only entities...
...that was giving
these speech devices...
...so the people
that couldn't afford it...
...through Medicare anymore
still wanted to communicate...
...and we wanted them to be
able to communicate...
...so we just started fulfilling
all of our requests...
...which meant it was 2 and 3
and $400,000 a month.
We were able to fill every request
that people asked of us.
So much so, that it's depleted
our money that we had...
...so we're now actually going out
and beating on doors...
...and asking people for money again.
[♪♪♪]
REPORTER: Former Saints team captain
Steve Gleason...
...and his foundation
organized Gleason Gras...
...a music celebration
at Champion Square...
...to raise money
and awareness about ALS.
When I say "Gleason,"
you say "Gras."
- Gleason!
ALL: Gras!
REPORTER: Thousands gathered to
celebrate the inspiring effort...
...of one man.
[♪♪♪]
You've changed my life.
You're so great.
We went up to Washington
and met with the Secretary...
...of the Department of Health
and Human Services...
...and pled our case.
We hope to pass this law...
...and once again
Medicare will pay for these devices.
[RIVERS CRIES]
- No.
- Yeah.
One bite of this,
and I'll give you chips.
We had no idea Steve was just going
to get bigger and bigger and bigger.
I think with Team Gleason--
He's putting too much
into Team Gleason...
...and not doing enough
of his video journals...
...and stuff for Rivers.
I think it's a balancing act.
We all have to balance things.
It's kind of his balance.
And it's a huge-- It's super-hard.
[SIGHS]
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
This is the most significant achievement...
...for Team Gleason to date.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
What's going on here, Rivers?
See all the cameras?
You like it in here?
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
Hey, Baboo, what you doing?
What you doing?
Steve just wanted to be a hero,
and it's amazing that he has gotten--
And he is legitimately a hero.
Like, of a town
for blocking a punt...
...and now, like, the face of ALS.
But people come up to me
and be like:
"Congratulations."
And you're like, "For what?"
Like, "What are you talk--?"
Because, like, "What?
What do you mean?"
It's just such a--
This whole thing
is a huge mind fuck.
[♪♪♪]
[MACHINE BUZZING]
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
It's important to me...
...that we do Rivers' sandwich
and nose kiss every night, Michel.
That's the only physical time
I get with him all day.
Okay.
STEVE:
You tried to skip it tonight.
Okay.
And you took-- Okay.
STEVE:
Thanks.
You're welcome.
I didn't mean to skip it.
I just didn't think about it.
STEVE:
Are you okay, Mick?
I'm great.
Yeah.
Shit.
STEVE:
Are you okay?
Yes.
STEVE: I feel like you have
no compassion towards me.
Everything is rushed.
You always have
somewhere else to be.
You finish my sentences.
You rush any care
that you give me.
I don't understand
what I did to deserve it.
Please tell me how I can improve.
You walked by me 10 times tonight...
...while Rivers was on my lap.
I tried to get your attention.
You didn't even look at me.
MICHEL:
I'm sorry.
Um, I don't think it's anything
you can improve.
I think it's how I can improve.
STEVE: Do you feel angry
when you are with me?
MICHEL:
Um.... No.
I feel more angry with myself,
for how I feel in general.
STEVE: What can I do
to be more important to you?
MICHEL:
I don't know.
STEVE:
If you want to talk-- You don't have to...
...but if you want to, I will listen.
MICHEL:
Thank you, buddy.
[PLAYING ROCK MUSIC]
MICHEL:
That's my favorite song.
BLAIR:
Your favorite song is "Come Back"?
[CHATTERING]
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]: I must say,
I have done some amazing stuff...
...in my life, but this experience
was right at the top of the list.
I just interviewed Pearl Jam
on their latest album.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
The music you guys have created...
...has plastered the wall...
...of my adolescent and adult life.
I want to thank you...
...for providing the significant portion
of the soundtrack for my life.
I have my son, Rivers.
I am assembling a video
journal library for him...
...in case the experts
are right about my timeline.
You did not know your dad.
What are a couple things
you wish you knew about him?
Yeah, I'll see if I can get through this.
Um....
That's a great question,
and coming from you...
...um, I couldn't appreciate it more.
Um....
Of course, I think
just deep down I just would--
Would have wanted
to know just, you know...
...if he loved me
and how much, you know.
I get the idea that he did,
you know.
But the other nice thing
would have been...
...just having someone
of my own blood...
...give me some insight of--
And, you know...
...what it would be like to...
...grow up and, you know,
be a man, a good man.
I wish he was around now...
...and I like to think
he'd be proud of me.
STEVE:
Thanks, man.
I knew this was going to
come in handy for something...
...but I didn't know what. Ha-ha-ha.
Steve Gleason sitting in
for Barbara Walters this week.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]: Rivers,
you are an awesome boy or man...
...depending on what times in your life...
...you happen to watch this.
But the world can grind on you.
Do not become obsessive...
...to the point where you are unhappy.
Let your best stand for what it is.
If it's not sufficient, that's okay.
You did your best. Move on.
We're a grassroot...
...pretty much, you know,
pro bono kind of things...
...volunteers,
that has done in two years...
...some incredible things.
To live with ALS
is hard enough as it is...
...but I think to live in the way
that Steve is living with it...
...you know, to be so
out front and public...
...there's a lot of sacrifice
comes with that...
...and I think it's a sacrifice,
you know, on your family...
...and to have your priorities
in the right place.
You know, we have to reflect
on where we need to be.
I think it's going to be up to Steve...
...knowing that all these people
want to partner up...
...with, you know, where he wants to go,
in which direction.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]: I realize
that I have pushed us to the point...
...we are right now, but I think
I need to get more into balance.
I am frustrated
because I have only written...
...two or three journals
in the past few months.
I am tired.
Michel is tired.
I think we, Michel and I,
need to pull back quite a lot.
FUJITA: It was like music to our ears
because it's like...
...finally Steve is going
to take a step back...
...and just focus
on what really matters...
...and that's his health,
his relationship with his wife...
...and his son Rivers.
I have never wanted
to be a saint.
I've never been a saint
before Steve.
I'm never going to be a saint.
I don't want to be, like, a devil...
...or a dick face, but I don't
want to be a saint, either.
I just want to be a real person.
MICHEL:
One, two, three.
[GURGLING]
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
This is brutal.
Just when we spoke to that
doctor a couple of weeks ago...
...he's like-- Essentially,
you can live as long as you want...
...but there's a reason
people choose not to...
...because life is so sucky...
...that it seems, like, that they choose...
...like, "Hey, this is
a better option," you know?
Um.... So I think that's
what I'm really scared of...
...is, like, I have a little bit
of control over when I die...
...maybe, but may--
That might be false...
...like maybe not.
Maybe there's--
I don't know
how it happens, you know...
...when people with ALS
get to the death point, you know.
Give him a big one.
Give a big-- Is it a salami sandwich?
[MICHEL PLAY CHOMPING]
I think it's a chicken sandwich.
[RIVERS GIBBERS]
I know when we first met
when you were able to communicate...
...very clearly at that time,
early in the process...
...you were very clear
that as things moved forward...
...you were gonna utilize
any available technology...
...to stay in the game.
Comfortably, with the best quality of life
that you could have.
And that I know has been your goal...
...but I wanted to revisit that with you.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
I have had the opportunity...
...to contemplate my own death...
...quite thoroughly the past few years.
I say it's an opportunity...
...because I think understanding
one's mortality...
...can help open a person
to lead a more meaningful life.
I fight to stay alive for my son...
...for my wife, my friends and family.
I am not giving up.
[♪♪♪]
One of the things that I
always admired about him...
...it felt that their relationship
will continue for a long time...
...is that they could tell each other
everything and anything.
Honest as could be, truthful...
...and that has been lost in the process.
Oh, my God, I can't believe.
I just hit the wall
from two nights ago just now.
WOMAN:
Aw....
Why don't you-- Why don't you go--
Just lay down. We'll be quiet. Ha-ha-ha.
I'm working on a masterpiece.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
And you are planning a bronchial sweep.
DOCTOR: Yes. I'm going to look down
with a flexible scope...
...and suck out all that stuff
out of your lungs...
...so that hopefully that sticky sensation
that you're feeling...
...will be gone.
STEVE:
Great.
Well, I am anxious,
but feel good with you.
Thank you.
I appreciate it, okay?
We're going to take good
care of you, I promise.
All right. I'm going
to head on down...
...and make sure everything's
set to go, okay, buddy?
I'll see you in a little bit, okay?
I promise you,
we'll take great care of him.
[♪♪♪]
STEVE:
Sorry you have to deal with this.
MAN:
No white flags, Gleason. Go get them.
If for some reason
something happens...
...and you can't understand him,
come get us, okay?
We're staying right here, baby.
I'll keep you guys posted.
And we'll take
good, good care of him.
[♪♪♪]
MICHEL: It's a hard time
because it's all of a sudden...
...like I don't want to think
about how sad it is.
I don't want to think about
what we're missing out on.
I don't want to think about myself
because it's depressing.
I don't want to think
of these things.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
MICHEL: It's finished.
- What's that called?
WOMAN:
That's beautiful.
BLAIR: It's called
"Commotion of Colors In Motion"?
MICHEL:
Yes.
WOMAN:
You have to give your--
Ooh. Ooh. Okay.
And that's called "emotoling."
It's emotion doodling.
Emotoling.
- Emotoling?
- Emotoling.
Emotional doodling.
Emotionally dood-- Okay.
I like that.
The dilemma is
obviously we want him to live...
...and the longer he lives,
the harder it'll get.
But-- And for her...
...it's realizing that the longer he lives,
the longer she has to deal with it...
...so it's just-- It's tough.
RIVERS:
What's that?
That's a trach and a vent.
Because guess--
Remember what Dad has--
Daddoos has? ALS.
Remember?
ALL:
♪ Happy birthday, dear Rivers ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪♪
MAN:
Blow them out.
WOMAN:
You have to blow harder, Rivers.
[ALL LAUGHING]
- Last two.
MAN: All right, Rivers.
WOMAN:
It's not a yay yet.
He's a chicken.
[LAUGHING]
WOMAN:
I want you to finish strong.
All right. Whoo!
[ALL CHEERING AND CHATTERING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
RIVERS: I got--
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]: Rivers...
...did you make any
new friends today?
No. I didn't....
STEVE:
Did you play with Goren today, bro?
No! He had fever.
STEVE:
Can you count to October 19th?
- One.
STEVE: One.
- Two.
STEVE: Two.
- Three.
STEVE: Three.
Four, four...
...five, six, seven--
Oh, one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
STEVE: My second reading of
"The Little Pea."
I'm excited for the day...
...when you are
teaching me things.
As a father, my goal
is for you to be--
To teach you
to think for yourself...
...and there's a downfall to that...
...that eventually you'll
be thinking things...
...that are different
than things that I think.
In the weirdest way,
that's the goal...
...but then you don't think
the things that I think...
...and we have disagreements
or debates or, um...
...differing opinions.
So my point is that
I'm saying now to you...
...that I am excited for that day...
...even if, when that day comes,
I'm frustrated.
Okay, tough guy,
so what kind of questions...
...are we going after here?
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
Four years ago...
...we had a similar conversation.
What has been the most
challenging moment for you...
...since my diagnosis?
Having to deal
with the day that you die.
Well, you asked me.
And I ask myself why--
You know, why did it have to happen
to Stephen?
But a simple answer for me
is, I mean...
...it's the way you played, Stephen.
That's why those coaches loved you.
Because you were just relentless.
STEVE: We've had a couple
on-camera moments...
...talking about our spiritual beliefs.
Do you feel at peace about that?
MIKE:
I was talking to you about some things...
...and you were starting
to lose your voice...
...and you says,
"Dad, don't worry about my soul.
My soul is saved."
And I don't think you could
speak that out of your heart...
...if you didn't really believe
that your soul was saved, Stephen.
So I believe your soul is saved.
STEVE:
If you could go back...
...what would change about
your philosophy of fatherhood?
Oh, man. Uh, probably being gentler.
Uh, I'm sure I could have worked...
...a little smarter at things.
STEVE:
I think you did well.
Well, thank you.
I think you've taught Rivers...
...more about love and gentleness
and kindness at an early age...
...than I even knew about.
But it's pretty cool
to watch how you sing to him...
...on that computer...
...and get him in your legs
and he rolls around with you...
...and you say bedtime stories to him...
...and it's pretty awesome, Stephen.
Rivers feels all of that in his heart.
[♪♪♪]
Someday he'll walk through
that Saints locker room...
...and he'll see your picture...
...on that picture Hall of Fame
for the Saints...
...and, you know,
he'll walk to the stadium...
...and see his dad's statue,
and, you know.
I just hope he doesn't feel...
...like he has to try
to accomplish as much as you.
All I know is that you wouldn't put
that kind of pressure on him.
RIVERS:
Go!
One, two, three.
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
Rivers.
♪ A year from now
We'll all be gone ♪
Hold this. Come on.
All right, Dad, let's do it.
[RIVERS & BLAIR LAUGHING]
Go! Say "Go, Daddoos, go."
MAN:
Go, Daddoo, go!
♪ And our friends will be gone away ♪
I think his main purpose now is,
you know, being a dad for Rivers...
...the best dad that he can be.
♪ Nothing is as it has been ♪
♪ And I miss your face like hell ♪
I've lost a little bit
of the happiness and light...
...that was a big part
of my personality...
...and I'm trying to find a place
where I can get that back...
...because I think it's important
because it's a big part of me.
I think of having a show at some point.
That's way out of my comfort zone
and I'm not there quite yet.
Yeah. Being an artist is just, like...
...kind of complicated.
Luckily, I'm not an artist. Ha-ha-ha.
[YELLS]
MICHEL:
I think I'm better than last year...
...and so next year
might be even better.
But this is a motherfucker.
That's that. I'm still pretty funny.
Dah. Dah!
Dah.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
- Whee!
- Whoo!
STEVE [OVER COMPUTER]:
Rivers, that was awesome.
REPORTER [ON TV]:
The Steve Gleason Act...
...is now the law of the land.
Word came down tonight...
...that President Obama signed the bill
into law today.
The Steve Gleason Act
will give immediate relief...
...for patients who have
been denied access...
...to speech-generating devices...
...and it will ensure that
eye-tracking technologies...
...are covered under
Medicare and Medicaid...
...for ALS patients.
♪ Rivers and roads ♪
We've gone from a family
member who has ALS...
...to now almost
a hero-slash-poster person...
...who started a movement...
...and the movement
is its own entity now...
...and it's strong,
so it's taken its own life...
...and I think that's probably
as critical as anything.
♪ Rivers and roads ♪
STEVE:
Fundraisers and all that stuff--
Really none of that is as important...
...as this right here.
That's all that matters,
is me passing myself to you.
Here's a memory from
my high school years.
How to build a campfire.
- Dating.
- Obstacles.
Trying to give you
everything that I can.
Even if I'm not present physically...
...you'll have this...
...and I feel so much better...
...when I just sit down
and share myself with you.
♪ Rivers till I reach you ♪
Because that's what dads do.
They pass stuff on,
the best of themselves...
...to their kids.
♪ Rivers and roads ♪
♪ Rivers till I reach you ♪
Out.
♪ Rivers till I reach you ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
STEVE:
All right.
Test, test, test.
Test.
Rolling.
It's right in the middle of the state--
[CHUCKLES]
That's your mom, dude.
What the hell?
That was awesome.
She's a piece of work,
I tell you what.
MICHEL: When I feel something
strong enough...
...it takes over my head,
and I had to just say it.
So I had to say "Steve, I had
a dream that I liked you...
...and I think that I like you."
- Boo!
- Heh.
This is me giving you a hug.
Just....
Making these videos is my hug.
♪ Set him down on his knee ♪
♪ A wave came crashing
Like a fist to the jaw ♪
Unfortunately, this is real life.
Um, it's....
It's not a movie, so...
...I'm trying to make it as
hunky dory as possible.
But I think sometimes
real life gets in the way.
♪ Power ♪
♪ He's flying ♪
♪ Whole ♪
♪ High, wide ♪
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[SHRIEKING]
My thoughts for you...
...and tattoos' remembrance is this.
Do not get it of
your girlfriend's name.
Or your wife, for that matter.
Hey.
Or your wife. But your mom...
...you can get one of your mom
if you want to.
And I do believe that in five years...
...I'll look back on this video
and say "Wow...
...that was the beginning of,
you know, this journey...
...that has turned out so much
for the better in my life."
♪ And he still gives his love
He just gives it away ♪
♪ The love he receives
Is the love ♪
♪ That is saved ♪♪
I just want to say
I feel like I'm exploding on the inside.
I love you so much, man...
...and that's a great thing...
...and I hope...
...you love me
as much as I love you...
...but it's impossible.
I think even better is
I hope you love your children...
...as much as I love you.