How do I know if a girl fancies me?
Or how can I make her notice me?
Do girls really like sucking dick?
I need to get laid this summer.
My body can't take it anymore.
I don't wanna keep waking up all sticky.
If my parents made love a month...
...before I was conceived...
...would it be me being born?
Or another boy?
If they made love two minutes later?
You can be an orphan
even when you have parents.
If you have nothing in common with them
somehow you're all alone.
Nacho!
What? Hold on for five minutes
Yesterday Nacho
and I rode bikes all day long.
And I noticed that Nacho
has more hair under his armpits
I have thin blond hair
What does he think about
when he's playing football?
And when he's wanking
what does he think about?
Let's go.
Hello
- Hi
What's up?
- Nothing, just passing by.
I picked him up at the football pitch
and we came over.
Are you training these days?
- No, I'm rehearsing with the band.
We have a band.
- We have a band.
With my brother.
I'm learning guitar these days.
And I sing.
Where are the toilets?
- That necklace?
What?
- That necklace
It's a present.
- Is it from here?
No.
The bathroom is that way.
Over there, to the left.
Shall I wait here?
- Yes.
Did you do the medical examination?
- Yeah, that's why we're inside.
Otherwise you can't get in.
Next.
Who's next?
Take off your T-shirt and shoes.
My trousers as well?
- No, not yet.
Say Ahh
Good.
Let me see your hands.
Turn them around.
The other side,
lift it a bit.
Show me the sole.
The other one.
You have athlete's foot, I'm afraid.
I'll give you a prescription.
You should wash your feet.
Dry them well.
Apply this cream between your toes.
And in ten days you can come back.
- I can't get in now?
Can I get dressed?
- Yes.
So you're sunbathing, fucking cow.
- Mecha!
Messing around with my husband
you bitch.
You're mad, let go.
- I'll smash your face in.
Come on
Go call the police bitch. Cunt.
You're insane.
- Fucking cunt.
I'm gonna teach you,
for fucking my husband.
You'd better have fucked him well then.
How dare you.
- Get off me.
Come here you bitch.
I'm gonna stick this up your ass.
Get off me.
Oily fucking cunt.
Let's see if you can sunbathe now.
Come on, sunbathe.
Come on. Fucking cow.
Fat cow.
What a greasy fucking pig.
Fucking pig.
What a shitty life.
Have you seen my headphones?
- What?
My headphones.
No, I didn't see them.
He can't find his headphones.
The small ones I'm looking for.
- No, I didn't see them.
I didn't see them.
Now, go on.
What's up?
- Nothing.
Can I have a ciggie?
- No.
Why not?
- Give him one.
Come on, just one.
- No, you're too young.
We just had lunch, I want to share
a ciggie with you guys.
Can I have a cigarette?
Stop it.
Flor.
Leave your shoes outside,
it smells like a zoo in here.
What's this shitty program?
- Meeting Point.
Can I change the channel?
- Don't.
Can you get out of the way?
Get out of the way mum.
Why do you have to sit
right in front of me?
Where are you planning to sit?
- Here.
You're blocking my view.
- Have you eaten sweetie?
Have you?
Do we have anything to give this kid?
What have you got in your hair?
- Nothing.
You have something.
- No, I don't.
Did you wash it?
- I took a shower last night.
You must have some kind of product
in it then. - It's been cut like that.
It's a spiky haircut.
- But it's dirty, it's all sticky.
Did you have a good day?
The day after tomorrow dad's
coming for dinner. - Really?
I'm telling you to make sure you're here.
I won't be here.
Well, try and change your plans
to be here.
So we can all be together.
- I can't.
The day after tomorrow?
Have you suddenly forgiven him?
- Well, yes.
What's your problem.
- You're crazy mum.
What?
- We have to put up with you afterwards.
He's an asshole, how can you invite him?
- Don't say that about your father.
He's a human being, who makes mistakes
and regrets them. - Yeah, right.
Listen, you're just a kid.
- I'm not a kid, I'm 16.
Exactly.
- I'm a grown up.
You're not old enough
to understand certain things.
I do understand, he cheated on you a
hundred times. That's easy to understand.
But I'm the one who should forgive him,
not you. - Do whatever you want.
Come over here, please.
- No.
Hey, take it easy.
Hey, you got a ciggie?
- No, I don't smoke.
Does your mummy
not allow you to smoke?
What is that for?
Give me back the bike.
Give it back.
- Don't get pissed off.
Hey, come over here.
Follow him on the bike.
- What's up?
What's up?
You want more?
Guys.
I've brought some new lyrics.
I'll try them out while we rehearse, ok?
Cultivating panties, culture of love
To die in plenitude
Is to die wlth attitude.
Russian men and women
taking their clothes off.
My arms are hanging.
My arms are hanging
Can I have a look?
- Let's see how long it is.
What?
- Are they too long to fit into the song?
The thing about the Russians, it's
because my grandparents were Russian.
I thought, if I'm here
it's because they had sex...
And took their clothes off, that's why...
You know what Maty told me
the other day? - What?
That he'd been to a sex motel
with his girlfriend.
Where?
- To a sex motel.
- In Neuquen.
There were loads of rooms to choose
with different themes.
What do you mean?
For instance,
one room was like a jungle.
So you'd be fucking in bed
with lianas hanging above your head.
Another one was like the Batcave,
from Batman.
There was the Bat...
- Batmobile.
Was that the bed?
- Yes.
You'd enter the room and find.
- Any Batcondoms?
There was a closet with costumes.
Like Batman clothes?
- Yes.
Wicked.
And who was Batman? Maty?
- Yes.
What about her?
- Catwoman.
So cool.
Maty Superhero.
Batmaty.
Imagine Maty in a Batman suit.
I'm reaching further.
- It'd be nice to go to a sex motel.
What?
- To go to one of those motels.
With a girl.
- Obviously.
Why?
- Do you wanna go alone?
Go and wank on the bed of a sex motel?
Is there more?
Let's save some for later.
Shall I put them back in?
- Yes.
Yummy...
Open your mouth.
My dad's coming tomorrow.
What for?
To have dinner I guess.
Weren't they on bad terms?
- Sometimes.
His flat is gonna be free.
We could do something there.
Yeah, a party.
- Aweekend party.
I'd have to escape.
- Why?
Cause my dad's coming.
I can't tell them I'm going.
Let's go.
- Ok.
Ring again.
I rung once, why should I ring again?
Hello.
- Hello.
What's up?
- Nothing, just passing.
Where you walking past?
- Yeah, we were passing by
And we remembered
that your house has a balcony
We almost called
on your neighbours' house.
What a nice house.
It isn't nice.
- I like it.
What a silence.
Were you sleeping?
- No.
Have you eaten anything?
And yourselves?
- No.
You wanna come in?
Keep going. And...
...turn right. Upstairs.
Does it bother you?
- No, I like it.
It's right in your face.
Look what I found.
I found it at the video store.
On the counter.
Read the other side.
'Pick me up. I will bring you good luck.'
You're lucky.
- I picked it up by chance.
I put my hand on the counter and
there it was. As if it came to me.
What is it?
- It's from Saint Gaucho Gil.
You've gotta write copies and throw them
in the street for other people.
Have you done that?
- Not yet.
You can put them anywhere.
Throw me on the streets or sidewalks.
St Gaucho Gil is very miraculous.
If you find this letter make
two copies everyday for 20 days.
During that time you will have a surprise.
What does it say?
Asurprise...
For...
- You and your family.
No, for you and your family.
Aman found this letter
and won the lottery.
What if I win the lottery?
But he stopped making copies
and lost everything, even his job.
Tell me where you're gonna put them
so I can pick them up.
That's not fair.
Do you want something to drink?
- Ok.
What?
Milk.
- Milk... with chocolate.
How many spoonfuls of chocolate?
Three spoonfuls.
- I want plain milk.
Cold?
- Yes.
I'm gonna have chocolate milk too.
- Ok.
How do I look?
- Silly.
Shall we tell her about going to Neuquen?
- Yeah, later.
Stop it.
Get off me.
I'm a kitten.
The kitten wants cuddles.
Wanking monkey.
Eat it, eat it...
Eat this cock.
I'm itchy.
Get that look off your face.
I've an itchy ass.
Open or closed?
Do I have to guess?
- Yes.
Closed.
- No, open.
Very good.
Did you get it?
- No. I mean yes but, let's try again.
Good.
Very good.
I don't understand.
What is it? Is it a pisstake?
No, you're supposed to notice
if it's open or closed.
But what is it that's supposed
to be open or closed?
That's what you have to guess.
I don't like that game.
Wait until you get it.
This weekend we're going to Neuquen.
Neuquen is wicked.
Have you been there?
- Yes.
My dad lives there.
His flat's gonna be free. Just for us.
My dad's coming here.
Do you wanna come with us?
Ok.
When?
- This weekend.
Friday.
- Ok.
I reckon we'll to stay till Sunday.
- We'll bring some food.
Great.
Who else?
- You can bring a friend if you want.
Leticia is off to the lake. You know her?
- Yeah.
Jimena.
Who's that?
- The girl from the swimming pool.
From the other day.
- We'll have to see if they'll let her go.
Why?
- They might not let her go.
Ask her and we'll call you later.
- Ok.
And I'll ask them here.
Will they let you go?
- Yeah. It won't be a problem.
I'll ask my mum.
It's gonna be great.
Yeah, sure.
I think mum's just got back.
You'd better go now.
Just in case.
Ok.
- Come.
Go now. Go that way,
through the window.
Here.
Come on, Lucas.
Come on.
What's up?
- I don't dare.
It's not so high.
- Andrea, where are my pills?
What's all this mess in the kitchen?
I'll clean it up later. - You lock
yourself up in your bedroom all day.
I'll clean it in a minute.
- I can't do it all on my own you know.
Could you lower your voice a bit?
No. Give me a hand here.
- I can't now, I'm studying.
When I say now I mean now,
come here Andrea.
For fuck's sake, come here.
D'you hear me?
They were dirty.
Open or closed?
Closed?
Tell me the secret.
Look at my mouth.
Good.
Very good.
What is it?
- It's the mouth.
Now do it for me.
Yesterday I went for a walk
to the lake.
And I was thinking that the world is huge.
And that human nature...
The big bang when it all exploded...
It brought...
...tons of things, the lakes,
the mountains, all the animals...
And it also brought human beings.
I sound like a school book.
And...
But human beings are much more
complex. While a tree is just a tree...
...a person is something more locked off.
It's like we're stuck
inside the soap opera of life.
And we have to live, we don't have
a choice. But we're not capable...
...of seeing the world for what it is.
And...
...see that we're all here
only for organic reasons.
And it all goes beyond.
The simple fact that my parents
conceived me. It all goes further beyond.
Where do tears come from?
I don't know.
What's the difference between
kissing a boy or a girl?
Boys have beards.
Otherwise it'd be the same thing.
I want to travel.
Why is it that boys don't cry?
I thought you were sleeping.
You alright?
Why can't you play a whole track?
Please.
I'll play your favourite song.
This bus follows the rhythm
of the music.
Andrea, it's Lucas
Yeah, we're in Neuquen. What's up?
Yeah.
But, why not?
We wanted to pick you up
at the coach station, but...
Ok. It's alright
Big kiss
See you when we're back.
Bye.
Shit. She said she would come
It's here. I won.
Come down.
Here.
Where?
Water?
What are these?
- Models.
Models?
Come on, let's have a look around
- I'm coming.
I've got a glue lollypop.
Another fifteen year old girl
has committed suicide
The tap.
It's dripping.
You hear it?
- No.
Right there.
Right there. No.
That's it. Yes.
Right there.
Like that's alright. Yes.
Don't change the channel.
Don't change it.
Where are you going?
- Home.
Why?
My mum's gonna freak out.
Stay over.
- No, I gotta take the bus.
Don't be such a cunt, stay.
My mum's gonna kill me.
Bye.
Hi.
What happened?
What do you think?
Looks like you sniffed all my glue.
Very clever.
What time is it?
Half past nine.
Don't tell mum about this.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
Look at this.
Your T-shirt.
What's this?
Can't believe this.
I've seen things, but this...
Will this one suit you?
Is it a bit too serious?
No, I like it.
Did you come here alone?
- No, with Nacho.
Where is he?
He left.
What's your shoe size?
- Forty two.
Forty two.
They're too big for me, I'm forty one.
You have to help me clean this mess.
How do we clean up the glue?
- Don't know. We'll find out.
I'll help you.
- Ok.
Here you go.
Let me do that.
You don't do this once a week, do you?
Leave it like that.
Let me have some.
Bye.
Promise.
For...
...the next three weeks I won't look
at my tits to see if they have grown.
I wonder what Lucas
and Nacho are doing now.
Maybe they're rehearsing.
Why do girls never have rock bands?
Why are there girl's things
and boy's things?
Can I be friends with boys?
Boys are more fun.
I want to be brave.
Like a man. I want to be a man.
Not be scared of cockroaches.
Not be scared of thieves...
I want to French kiss.
Right now. Can't wait.
I want a juicy kiss.
A deep French kiss.
With fleshy red lips.
With the taste of cherry lollypop.
Want some?
Is it too strong?
I gotta go.
- Ok.
Fucking asshole.
- We used to make fun of that fat cow.
I knew that fat fuck
wanted to fuck everyone.
And you just go and fuck her.
Slow down cause you're losing it.
- Ok, you know what I want?
What?
- What you doing?
Are you insane?
- Get the fuck out and never come back.
Get out.
You don't deserve this family,
you are a sick fuck.
Hi.
I gotta go.
I'll call you guys in a couple of days.
We'll do something.
You guys alright?
Don't know what's wrong.
Sorry.
Can I have one?
You don't inhale.
Yes I do.
I can't sleep.
It's already light.
Maybe I should have a wank.
I imagine the town's completely empty.
With no one around.
And Nacho?
I wonder what he's doing.
Is he sleeping?
Am I in his dreams?
I wanna touch Andrea's tits.
One, two, three.
Are we done yet?
We're going to play a song.
Russian men and woman
taking their clothes off
Without curtains the light burns you out
Stains on my skin,
pleasure disease
To die with plenitude
and live with attltude
Desert. Desert. Between my legs
Desert between my legs
Make me wet
My pen explodes
My ink explodes
I ink you with red wine
Pumping bodies getting intertwined
Shaking bodies mixing up
We want more.
- We want more.
We don't really play that well...
...but there's a band coming now,
they are really good:
Los Wanos Band.
You both smoke?
- Yes.
What's that?
- Acocktail.
Wanna smoke?
The gig was great.
Has anyone ever tickled
the roof of your mouth?
Here, with the tongue.
Open your mouth.
Open it.
Now you do it to Nacho.
Do it to Nacho.
Pass the drink.
What are you doing?
I've never been
in the men's toilets before.
You're leaning against the walls.
Men's toilets are smellier.
- No.
What time is it?
- Late.
Close your eyes.
Look up to the sky.
Higher.
How old were you?
When?
When you first kissed a boy.
The first time?
- Yes.
Fourteen
And you?
Kissing a boy or a girl?
Agirl.
I was twelve.
Wow, so young.
Good morning.
Well, good afternoon.
What a night last night.
I've got a headache.
- No wonder.
Take an aspirin.
Are you expecting anyone?
- No.
It's dad.
Where did he get that?
What's he doing?
- He has a van.
Dou you think he bought it?
You alright?
- Yes.
Nice top.
Where did you get that van from?
- I borrowed it. You like it?
It's very comfy, we can all fit in.
I got a plan. Let's go somewhere
for the weekend, the four of us.
Get a bikini, a sweater...
Do you have that game with the words?
I think so.
- Bring it over.
Get a sweater.
I have sleeping bags for everyone.
What's wrong?
- You guys go.
Let's go the four of us.
Come on, the four of us together.
Bring some warm clothes
for the night.
And keep that top on
cause it really suits you.
Come on, hurry up guys.
Three days?
I forgot my shorts,
ask Lucas to get some for me.
They won't fit you.
- Yes, we're the same size.
Come on.
Is there anything to eat?
Ok, let's go.
That one. Put it on.
Let's go.
Are we on time?
- Perfect.
I'm not going.
- Come on, Mecha
Come on.
- No, I get scared.
Really?
- Yes, you guys go.
Ok, let's go, Lucas.
It is safe?
- Yes
It's not gonna fall out of the sky, is it?
Be careful.
How long are we gonna fly for?
- Whatever you want.
We'll be fifteen minutes.
- Ok, no longer than that.
Let's not waste anymore time.
This is expensive.
Is this plane safe?
Look, dad
They're are like models.
Look dad, the train.
CAMPING
Didn't you ask for any instructions?
You have to stick this in.
I'm going inside.
Someone has to put this peg in for me.
I'll do it.
Shit.
- Can you help me?
Stick it in there.
That's the hole.
- Must be like this.
Lucas, be careful with that.
I need something to use as a mallet.
Here,
Your father's just useless.
He brings a tent and he can't put it up.
I don't get it.
What are these?
- Oh, don't worry about them.
I didn't bring any warm clothes.
- I told you to bring some.
You said bring your swim suit and I did.
Bring your red bikini, you said.
Fucking hell.
And he's laughing, what an ass.
- Where are you going?
Come back.
Come here. I'll fix it in a sec.
There are bags floating on the water.
It's true.
What do you think they are?
- Plastic bags.
No, they're flamingos.
- I can't believe we have to do this again.
We should get started.
Hi
- Good morning.
What are you listening?
Look.
Does it happen to you sometimes
that you're walking...
...and...
...you see a leaf on the floor...
...and you say to yourself
I must step on it...
...otherwise something really bad
will happen to me if I don't step on it.
Do you shave?
Sometimes.
- Never.
Don't lie.
- And you?
I do sometimes.
Sometimes.
Once a week.
- Do you wax?
Your legs and everything?
There's a demonstration.
I think it's the factory workers.
I saw them today.
Have you ever noticed
that we act differently...
...around friends than with family?
My mum used to get mad at me.
Because of that.
Let's go