I regret to say that
entry is not included
the tour price.
Sorry.
Here must pay.
But, good news
are only 10 szlotys.
So no
so bad.
Sorry
Trial Of God
It is forbidden to take pictures.
Photography groups
are by appointment only.
When you get there,
give him your card
the good doctor.
The examined.
Free.
Do not say that I
care about you.
This is a typical hut.
They had to
thousand people here.
When I got a new transport
made space for...
well, you can imagine.
Were
a selection.
Each cabin in
was given a card
for older
on the block, the overseer,
and then go
the selected area.
Straight.
Come on, shoulders back.
Stop.
Do not move well.
You look like dead.
Leave me alone.
... You're dead.
Try not to see you angry,
or be the next.. (I'll be fine)
I taught my
numbers? See?
Add them, 18, 18,
is the number of life.
You can meet up soon
Lord your God with.
It's very cold here, yes?
Imagine the day
selection.
Nobody knew what was the
selection criterion,
so all
afraid.
Well, this way.
I do not understand.
Do not see how this could happen.
How could afford?
You know there
a story
that prisoners
set up a tribunal here
and conducted a trial.
Prosecute
they thought
was mainly responsible
for what happened to them.
Can you imagine the look
my wife?
Suppose if I need
someone to wash dishes.
Move.
These people wait
see the doctor!
Become Wait and see
by the physician.
Jewish 85 years
in my house.
What I do
with her?
Some things
he can think.
Move.
Send the old Kuhn
left.
If you go left, you'll
to heaven with the old Kuhn.
Other live.
Silence.
Just point out the facts.
live.
you die.
Have you sent the right?
Right.
And you?
Left.
Was nice meeting you.
Come here. In!
In!
Come on. In!
Your notif..!
Come on! Move!
Move!
Move, move!,
Thanks to the efficiency
rail system of the Reich
this pile of steaming
Polish garbage has
arrived a day early.
Those of you
that have been selected,
know to which sleep
morning in their beds.
See this?
You know what I mean?
It means that I am a criminal.
A convicted criminal.
What are you?
Lawyers?
Doctors?
I spit out there.
Well, here,
is the opposite.
Here I am king.
Chancellor.
I am president.
Fuührer. God I.
The world just flip them
and you will have fallen into.
It is better
become accustomed.
This is a terrible place.
But if you help us,
it did.
The day of liberation
each day is approaching.
War will end
and with the aid of
God will see.
frankly,
should sleep on the
floor tonight
but if either of you
sick,
are those who
give their beds.
Monsieur,
In what part is?
Lyon.
I had a cousin there.
Contini was called.
Do you know him?
Everyone knew him.
He was a doctor.
A very fat,
with lots of money.
He escaped,
Any idea?
Maybe.
I have not heard.
Open your mouth.
Lucky you.
Let me grab this
gold tooth,
I'll give you half
my weekly ration yeah?
I need my tooth
to eat.
Do not worry
for that.
Not to eat
much here
Do not worry, keep your
tooth while you can.
Let me get him out.
It only takes a minute.
Here.
You'll need it.
Soup is the only food..
You'll need every drop.
How about you?
I was sent to the left.
Take it.
If you do not, one of
Kapos will.
He has expressed
their favor... Kuhn
We are his people.
He has shown his favor.
What are you praying for?
What will these
praying?
That is not you?
That will be me
instead of you?
Of course not.
Moshe?, Let him alone.
Who then?
If not me, who?
C'mon, name them, choose
Moshe?, Shut up.
At times like this,
You should pray for you.
Someone else reads?
Someone else is helping
God to decide?
I'm praying for him.
It is the rabbi
of Zamkevitz.
Melamed and is a healer.
Healer!
This interrupt
his work, no?
All we are healed.
They say it is
one of 36.
36 What?
36 rabbis Russians
that groan?
The Lamed-vovnik.
The holy secret
We carry on their shoulders
They have put their
souls in God,
and for their sake,
He does not destroy.
Gypsy piece of scum!
Please.
The Lord our God
can hear you, even here.
He listens to me, not
does anything about it.
Moreover bastard
I thought.
He listens to me and not
nothing.
It's an evil bastard.
He should be here
not us.
We should prosecute
the bastard.
So perhaps we listen.
And what will you do if
is guilty?
Arrest him?
Or wait to be delivered?
They can stop this?
They can stop
this blasphemy?
In fact, there
be blasphemy.
Abraham negotiated with
God for Sodom.
Jacob wrestled
with the angel.
The name, Israel,
means "he who has
struggled with God ".
Basta.
Tomorrow, we could be
facing our creator.
And tomorrow, our Creator
could enfréntanos.
It is a very old story.
Many who are
know the story.
It gives some sense.
Why not prosecute?
At least had to listen.
Not needed
judges and others?
three justices.
For a rabbinical court,
need to three.
Part of the tragedy
this place
is that it was packed
of scientists, artists, lawyers.
Baumgarten.
Yes, I was professor of
criminal law in Berlin.
Teach bright
students and admired.
I ate at a large table.
Coffee, brandy and
conversations with men
who are now..
in their government.
I do not know much
of the Torah.
There are many here
who know the Torah.
But I know how
lead a court.
Sorry.
"I knew you...
a teacher
in college?
Excuse me,...
Could you...
I do not have much time.
I do not want to waste
my last hours on this.
Look,
if we are to continue
through with this,
we can at least
ask the saint,
that God has someone
to defend him?.. Rabbi..
Rabbi.
They ask whether
talk to them.
It is a fool.
Look, I'm a rabbi.
I have translated
psalms.
I've written several
books on law.
I wrote a piece for our
theater in Wotchz... Sorry
Professor Schmidt?
Idek?
They said that they had
come to America.
Nobody has escaped?
I might serve
Dayan.
Idek is the best student
I have taught.
I'll stand up..
he does not.
please.
Please stay
out of it.
Strictly speaking,
the dayan
should be a rabbi.
Are you a rabbi?
The dayan is the
question, right?
I have a lot of questions.
Idek is a brilliant scholar.
His knowledge of
Torah is...
Auschwitz was not
mentioned in Torah
That's the point.
So I am a father
of this court,
Baumgarten is the boss
of the court.
And our
friend here
is, dayan, the Inquisitor.
For a point of order, for
that this court is lawful,
should have a
copy of the Torah.
...We
as evidence...
of its existence here.
Well, I'll sniff
at the library
and get one, no?
They want something more
while I'm gone?
Girls?
Cigarettes?
Cushions for their
bony back?
Rabbi Akiva
has been learned
all our holy
memory writes.
Recites
constantly.
In these sad days, we have been
a source of freshwater
He is called
"The Living Torah".
Sorry.
Over here, Rabbi.
So, for starters.
Who is charged?
Yo.
I will.
What are the charges?
Of which he is charged?
You see?
Murder...
collaboration, murder!
You know what
did to my mother?
My sister?
My brothers?
Murder, partnership,
and more murders.
I think we should
be more precise.
Suffering is part
God's plan.
A child knows that.
"If we take happiness
the hand of God,
we should not take
pain, too? "
It is not
an indictment.
Are you saying that
no reasons?
The charge would be
breach of contract.
The Jews
have a...
have a contract
God,
some kind of
special arrangement.
A pact.
Well, the accusation is that
broke the agreement, the pact.
Therefore, God is a
cheating bastard!
That is fine with me.
Please, please.
They can stop you?
In the desert, Moses led
a covenant with God.
He said the people
obey God's law,
and on the other hand, God said
of all peoples,
we would be theirs,
his chosen
a priestly nation
The psalmist sings
"I agreed with the chosen one, I swear
my servant David.
"I did sign your dynasty
forever.
Your throne will last
from age to age.
My own translation.
Therefore the case
before us
is not fulfilled
with this covenant.
Who wants to start?
"No enemy will
able to mock him,
"No evil overtake.
"Crush
his enemies before him,
annihilate opponents.
So?
Has the
His promise? No.
Well, it's hard to see
and refute the charge.
What defense can there be?
Continue?
Bad Things
have happened before.
Read the Torah.
Lean... read
its history.
We are Jews.
We suffer.
Please.
Identify at
the court.
My name is Kuhn.
I'm his father.
I'm his father, and
However...
he joins them
this shame.
It helps knowing
it hurts.
That is the kind
a son he is.
Got something to say, father?
Apart from usual?
Look...
when we were released
of bondage in Egypt,
find land
fiancee, What happened?
We were taken captive
again in Babylon.
When we
released again
and rebuild
temple,
what happened?
The Romans razed.
What happened
on Massada...
Spain...
Russia, and now here?
I think
the witness
is saying that his failure
the contract is common.
To clarify the position,
God defend or attack
Mr. Kuhn, think this saying...
.. he can speak for itself
Our ancestors,
our ancestors,
our parents
all suffered.
But it aired.
That is the reason that
we're still here.
This is a test
of our faith.
We pass our test
as they passed his.
Do you think we
be here?... (Please...)
They kept the light of Torah
on in times of darkness.
We must do the same.
We must keep the faith.
We maintain pure
our hearts,
and we must pray.
Why?
If God has
betrayed, why?
The point is...
The point is to be a good Jew.
A good Jew.
The point is to keep the faith.
Why?
We are
tested!
Tests are part
of this covenant?
Did someone mention
evidence to Moses?
In the same psalm,
we are told,
"If their descendants
deserting my law
"and not follow my commands,
"if they violate my decrees and does not
keep my commandments
"I will punish their offenses with the rod,
his guilt with his whip
Mr. Kuhn said,
before blaming God, we
look at ourselves.
Perhaps it is God who
breaches the covenant, but us.
Yes
There is... he knows.
Es.. is
mipnei khata'einu
because of our sins.
Or your sins.
May be you
who is to blame.
Thank you.
I agree
with the court.
It is a punishment.
The court has not said
such... (Still)
I agree.
Some Jews have
turned their backs on the Torah
They thought they knew better.
Our children have left
to cities.
He bought a
fancy hat,
a good costume, they became
socialists or Zionists
capitalist
or anarchists.
God only knows what.
Forgetting everything
of the precious scriptures.
So you're saying that
this is my fault;
is that?
God is destroying all the people
Jew because you're disappointed in me
Is that it?
Look what you're doing!
A trial to God?
Do not you think
can hear you?
Do you think
not here?
We must maintain
order here.
You are Jews, no?
If nothing else,
must respect the law.
Well, since I am accused,
I call
a witness.
Forward.
This gentleman.
Name?
Ezra Shapira
of Zamkevitz.
Did I do something wrong?
No, Ezra
Zamkevitz.
He came here with
Rabbi believe,
from Zamkevitz.
Tell me,
Ezra Shapira
turned their backs
the Torah
in Zamkevitz?
No, sir.
In Zamkevitz,
loved the Torah.
On Shabbat, the windows of the
shops were all closed.
The Scriptures wrapped its wings
of quiet about us,
and the world simply
vanished.
Every man had
his prayer book.
On national holidays, festivals,
workdays,
the Torah was...
The air was
that breathed.
In our poverty,
We dressed and housed us.
He was our palace
and lived
in its splendor.
So what went wrong?
They came.
They killed all
the elderly.
And they did the rest
bury them.
I buried my own mother.
I did remove the
ring fingers
and give it to them.
See any reason why
God would be a good Jew
desecrate the grave
your own mother
in order to punish
a poor Jewish
For example, I?
I said that was
a good man.
I try, but I do not know if I am a good man,
I do not know if you are an evil man.
For example, he.
I do not know.
Know me already
Do not worry.
So God reserves the right
to punish the wicked.
This is in the covenant.
The question is, why did you choose
punish this good man here...
...and not, for
example, Hitler?
Does anyone have
an answer?
God is just;
so we have
done something wrong.
We should examine
our consciences.
In law, the punishment
should be proportional
crime.
What crime
may justify a
punished like this?
And children, some children
on the field.
What punishment is
deserves a child?
If I may?
Not long
the punishment is proportional.
The flood engulfed
Worldwide
with the exception of Noah.
God asked Abraham to
sacrifice his own son.
Sir, my mother was
a good woman.
The mistake is to make
it's personal.
God does not work
against the person.
His alliance is with
the Jewish people,
Ezra not
of Zamkevitz.
This is not personal.
Can I ask you, Ezra,
see any object in a
God is not personal?
God as the object?
Does it depend on me
use to find God?
Do you know what is a god
that is not personal?
No.
Is the weather
That's all.
Maybe we should eliminate the word now
punishment procedures
Can I ask a question?
Ezra, let me ask you,
Your mother was a good Jew?
How can you ask
So even here?
Let me talk about something.
Let's talk
purification.
Twice in history,
and perhaps here today again
God has done events occur
of such destruction,
that after this, nothing
was the same again.
Nothing was the same
because, over time,
we come to understand
all improved.
Imagine that God
is a surgeon,
and has to remove a leg or an arm
with gangrene to heal the body.
It is a violent act.
It's painful.
But it is love.
What would
if we were living through
a moment like this?
No punishment,
purification.
Let me ask you... of its time.
Time is what we have.
These purifications
are in your covenant?
You say, occasionally,
no more betting,
e inundare the place?
Sometimes, just for
a change, you're...
surrounded and
you'll be whipped,
you bring dogs,
and I cornered
in a field...
since you ask...
The first purification
was the flood.
The second was
the destruction of the temple
by Nebuchadnezzar.
We were taken
into exile in Babylon.
We were one nation
without a country.
With no land,
went to the world,
and take our
knowledge of the Torah
and only God Almighty,
into the open.
If we had stayed as
we would have achieved so much?
We would be a tribe
the desert, nothing more.
It was painful, but
also was wonderful
What if we were going
other catastrophic event?
What if those who survive this
will be the holy remnant,
and live in an age of
wisdom, understanding and knowledge?
What if something good
would come out of this?
What great good?
How do we know?
Already some say
that the Messiah himself.
Perhaps a return to Israel.
So what?
So it might be
something beautiful.
So you see, maybe
There is a reason
Why a good woman
like your mother was taken,
and not some evil.
Because she is a sacrifice.
A holocaust.
And when a man sacrifices
something must be better.
The most beautiful thing.
Can I call Idek?
Can I interrogate him?
Can I call first to Idek?
The point is related.
Can you tell the court
what happened to our
Masada ancestors?
Masada was... one
fortress in the mountains
built by
Herod the Great.
It was a kind of
self-shelter
in case of war.
Of course, anyone can build
a wall against death.
Herod died,
and the Romans arrived,
destroyed the temple.
There was a great
uprising.
A revolt.
And the rebels ran
into the mountains,
this Masada.
The Romans besieged.
They wanted the rebels
starve.
So they built a huge wall
around the base of the mountain.
There, 15,000
Roman troops.
Less than a thousand
Jewish fighters.
That spring,
rebels
decided that
was better to die
to be enslaved.
Ten men were chosen
for homework
to kill all others.
When you have 10 one was chosen
to kill the other nine.
The latter had to
take his own life.
Two women hid
of this slaughter
and lived to
tell this story.
These fighters do
kind of men were they?
The bravest
and better.
The... Israel flower.
They were martyrs.
And yet, were
crushed by the Romans.
Well, in a sense, yes,
But what did the Romans?
Jews live like
Romans, and abandon the Torah.
And where are the
Romans now?
They are dust.
And the Torah?
He still lives,
still... blooms.
Still illuminates the world.
Thank you.
So we should not
despair.
Our suffering is a privilege
if it is part of God's plan.
We are fortunate
purifying the people living
through our grief.
Do not let
would take away their faith.
If this is strong,
grow.
A small fire is extinguished by
the wind, but a major fire
only grows stronger.
Hitler die.
The war will end.
The people and the Torah
live.
Precisely.
There is, right?
If.
The Torah will live.
Therefore, we
trust God.
Can I question the witness?
Not this.
The previous one.
Ezra Zamkevitz.
Sorry, I'm
a witness.
know, do not testify
nothing of God.
manufactures and sells gloves.
I used to make and
sell gloves.
Do you feel better at
that the judge has said,
your mother is
a sacrifice?
Yes, sir.
Although the judge
you have said
God demands sacrifice,
a sacrifice
of the best Jews.
You want me to feel
better or worse?
We just want the truth.
Well, I know the truth.
I do not know why
such things happen. "
I used to make
and sell gloves.
Can I sit now,
please?
I do not know how to respond
these questions.
Thank you.
So the suffering
is God's work,
is that true?
In other words,
Mengele work for God.
Hitler is working for God.
Is that true?
It's unpleasant,
but it is possible.
When Nebuchadnezzar invaded
Israel, and plundered the temple
and led the people
into exile in Babylon,
God called him
"My servant Nebuchadnezzar.
he was the scalpel and God
Surgeon.
We hate the scalpel,
but we love to surgeon.
If Hitler is
doing God's work,
then logic says
stand in the way of Hitler
is lodged
God's way.
Take up arms against
Hitler is wrong
Now, do you think someone
here in that?
Is there any way
that it can from
somehow be true?
Is not that... madness?
Who you are heading?
We must maintain
order here.
We should try to
maintain order.
I would call
our foreman.
Call me anything you want.
You can call it
he is not Jewish.
I would tell the court
what does all day.
Do you know
what I do.
I take care of you.
They are like my babies.
I am like a mother
for you.
Why?
"Dinos
why you took a
job like this?
I got the chance.
They asked me because I speak German,
and because I have a brain.
And if any of you were sufficiently
smart, do the same.
I think you could
have said no.
I want to live... That is
I do this. Want to Live!
Not like you scum
already dead,
delivered as soon as they got here.
Not ashamed
what you do?
I have no answer for.
Or your court
or to your God.
I do not care
know God.
Because what I do,
let me tell you
what I do is nothing,
nothing compared to what
the Sonderkommando ago!
Sent to other Jews
to the gas chambers.
The push within
and close the doors.
I removed the spoons
and sell them to other Jews.
They have cornered the entire
market spoons
closing the doors
those of the same species.
I signals.
Do you think
survive this?
Maybe, maybe not.
And Professor Schmidt
says that when...
Look, let me tell you
about your God.
I leave here
alive, okay?
One day the war will end.
They might even lose.
In which case,
I will be out of here.
All I have to do is
stay alive until that day.
How?
What is it that
going to kill me?
They.
How do I stop them?
Pleased.
And how do I do that?
Keeping you
locked in order.
What is the worst thing
I can go?
To be left without
Jews who kill.
Then kill me.
When they are finished
to kill them.
When this transport
arrived today
that transport
these Poles.
You know what I did?
Cheers.
That's what I did, and then
custom, said,
"Thank God. "
Wait!
listen!
Listen! Look!
Did I hit?
No.
Do you know why?
Because I'm making
work the bastard.
Here I am God.
I am!
And your God,
your God of Abraham,
do not care
a damn!
Otherwise no
I have given them.
I'd like to make
another question.
Got that?
We can not
to some other witness?
I'm not sure
this is helping.
Professor Schmidt
you said
when the disaster ends
world could be better.
Perhaps
the Messiah comes.
Perhaps return to Israel,
but who will survive this?
The foreman, the Sonderkommando
Who else?
The vicious
the crafty,
the scoundrel,
ruthless...
What kind of Messiah
want these
as his people?
What kind of Israel will
built by such people?
"Build a nation of wisdom
and understanding and knowledge?
Not them, God.
How?
We can not know.
He can do everything.
'He can do everything. "
Well, if you can do
However, why can not
purify your people
without gassing?
He is almighty.
How can it be
powerful and just?
Or is all powerful,
in which case
could have stopped this, but chose
not to because he is not just, o..
would have liked to
end to this, but could not.
The answer is very simple.
They should know of the Yeshiva.
The answer is free will.
Yes, there is evil in the world
because God gave
man free will
and opted to make the
evil is very simple.
Simple?
We are not puppets.
We choose.
We can always choose.
Free will?
Free will, my ass.
I will give you free will.
Where is Liebler?
Liebl, arise.
Wait for the
Judges call you
Ask Liebler for their children,
and then tell me about free will.
I call Liebl.
You can not call anyone.
Judges
call witnesses.
I called Liebl.
Tell the court
your children.
I will not.
If he tells them,
I'll tell him.
The court did not
I asked to speak
We have
order here.
When they arrived
to their village...
I'll tell you.
If you can tell,
then I who
should tell the tale.
I come from Hoengen.
Near Aachen.
And the Einsatzgruppen came.
When?
It seems like
hundred years ago.
They broke the doors
of the synagogue.
They burned the Torah
and the ark.
And then we
cornered inside.
We thought we were
burn there and then...
If only it
have done.
Were carried
children.
I have three children.
The greatest
Will have seven now y...
They're so beautiful.
That does not...
never mind.
Placing children
in a truck.
I ran after
them and shouted,
"Please give me my children!
Give me my children. "
And this officer,
I listened.
She stopped and said:
"What are yours?"
I thought I would
to give it back.
I showed
my three children.
The eldest, was crying,
and the other two...
No, that's not all.
He said,
"Three cute guys.
"I tell you what you can do.
"Choose one.
"Pick one.
Choose one and you can
stay with him. "
And the boys,
listened.
Spread
their hands.
Were
so scared.
They tried to get
to me and said,
"Please, my elíjeme.
Elíjeme to me. "
This gentleman,
you always said
can choose.
Which should
choose?
The youngest?
At most?
The weakest?
The fittest?
To Choose?
To which I should choose?
I can not say.
The court has heard
what is supposed
is to have free will, but...
Sorry, I do not want free will.
I love my children.
Of course...
You talk about free will.
Where was then
my will?
What choice had?
That official,
could choose, not me.
Where was my
Free Will?
The war will end.
Hitler die.
The people and the Torah
survive.
You say that the people
survive...
...but tomorrow
morning
half the people in this
room will be dead.
They do not share them
in his covenant?
His part is to witness,
keeping the flame alive
Does anyone have something to say
in defense of God?
Rabbi did not ask
it was... difficult.
I asked him why
you said earlier
about what
beautiful it is.
I would like the final
was beautiful
because my children
are beautiful...
...and tried to care for them.
Of course it does.
God knows that if.
Have you heard anything?
Are they here?
Two of them
are... twins,
and I understand that...
likes to Mengele
twins.
They are treated better
because it has
interest in them.
A Mengele interested
and God no.. Stop.
She is in heaven and can not
see beyond the clouds.
Job, chapter 22.
What?
Your argument that
God is indifferent
is not unprecedented
as it happens.
It is written in Job.
Good.
You say also
God should be here in the
gas chambers, not us?
They can detain you to put
these thoughts in my head.
There is a possibility
that this confusion is the precursor
of some great event,
the fire that burns us
is a refining fire...
...to create
a golden age.
If your children were taken by it,
were taken as martyrs.
To be a martyr, a man
should choose martyrdom.
We are not being martyred
by our faith, but because of our race,
not by the Torah, but
by our ancestors.
But He's here.
Who?
God.
I know he's here
although he does not understand.
Some days
in spring,
fell... snow
and the first rays
heat of the sun
since...
who knows.
Do you think the guard did not feel
the sun on your back?
The sun on your back, yes,
but that's not what I felt.
I felt Him
The guard did not
felt that.
That heat is not
enters his uniform.
I would change with him.
But maybe what you said about God
suffering in the gas chamber.
Maybe that's what
is happening here.
Perhaps he is suffering
us.
Who needs a God
suffering?
We need a God to send the
angel of death to our enemies.
Where... is?
I do not know much about God.
Maybe God never changes.
Perhaps if.
Perhaps it is not almighty.
Maybe we need
to be complete.
Maybe that's why we did.
Well, it's hard to see how
could be of some use
in our present condition.
Yes, but even so...
...in the city
of Baranowicz,
We killed a
Purim, and the rabbi shouted,
"Do not forget it
this day means!
L'Chaim! "
And singing, while
shoot him.
But your...
you keep asking,
"Whence comes
all this evil? "
But where does
all this goodness?
And you thought that while
he took your children?
Even the foreman
I think.
He thinks the war will end
and the Nazis lost.
Even he thinks
good win.
What do I know?
I do not know what he
can do and not do.
"I've ever given orders
morning... "
...or sent to his post
dawn?
"Have I ever walked
at the bottom of the abyss?
"What is the way
home of the light? "
"What gives light
frost... "
Here you are sir,
just as I suspected.
Yes, silence.
How many are you?
Twelve.
This is a place
very well directed.
Yes, there were complications
this morning
caused by the rapid
arrival of transport,
which makes his induction
is not yet complete.
My apologies
for the inconvenience.
Auschwitz is not
a nursing home.
You work or you die.
The choice is yours.
Come on. Up! Arise!
Come on.
Arise!
Stand up. Arise!
Remove it.
I have to use
for health reasons
Just remove it.
This is the dentist.
Come see early
in the morning.
Excuse me, Rabbi.
Can I?
I think the trial
I listen to an end.
Please.
No.
It's important.
For me is important.
You started the trial.
should complete it.
Should continue
the procedure
and cite precedents and.
be men.
They think that we are not
men, but if you are.
We removed
that from us.
Yes, true, but I have
reached a natural conclusion,
and may be a case of...
He gave us the law,
and debate the law, even
in such a terrible topic
is a kind
prayer... No
No, no, listen
discuss this...
...comforted us.
I felt I was listening,
who was with us.
If.
Well...
in brief...
we know that...
we can not know
the mind of God
God is too great.
And all we can
do is pray,
have faith.
Hitler die.
The war will end...
No, no, no,
That's not going to be.
Ask us to accept predictions
as evidence.. no, no, no
The argument returns
to its beginning.
If you take it to a vote now,
I vote guilty.
It is certainly true of
we can not understand
the mind of God.
His ways are not our own...
It touches us understand the mind of God.
...and therefore...
We are not concerned his mind.
... we must respect.
It is his covenant.
We have
to understand that.
All this writing.
We just have
to determine
if broken
their conditions or not.
Where is...
Where is the scholar?
Psalm return
the psalm.
Tell us the psalm.
Everything? Is,
is very long.
We were getting somewhere when
spoke on Psalm
I forget.
Psalm which was?
81.
David's throne will last
for all time
and their descendants...
The...
The throne of David
shall at all times,
and their descendants...
It has begun
Beginning in
block 7.
I took a couple
of hours to get here.
I still have time
to smoke a cigarette,
sleep with a
few women,
write a sonnet.
Schmidt
continues to say that
people survive.
That's what it says
in the pact.
God guarantees the survival
the Jewish people.
I say that God is guilty
because survival
the people
It is not safe.
No, not you.. How can
our people cease to exist?
Oh, believe me,
that's the plan.
Destroy us.
That's ridiculous.
When I came here,
He had lived all my
Zamkevitz life.
When I walked through these doors,
that was the largest number of people
I had seen in my life.
I saw more people in an hour
that in all my life.
I thought,
How is it possible that
many people are alive?
But now...
...How is it possible that
many may die?
Please surely know
that the numbers are not important.
When a child dies
tuberculosis,
this is terrible.
"It's worse if a million die?
When a child dies,
Can you believe that
happens for a purpose,
or do not pass the test.
We can not know
the mind of God.
We are not talking
of his mind.
We are talking
covenant,
a deal that promises
we will survive.
Survive as a people
and not be annihilated.
But there are Jews all over
the world, not only in Europe
My brother
has a friend
in Woudge - he told me...
Do you think if
they kill us here
Left alone to
friend of your brother?
We may be the last.
Maybe our
end is near.
We consider
that we in this room,
we are the holy remnant.
It is therefore important
what we decide.
If you're the last,
We can finish the story.
We can finish it here,
the story that started
with Moses at Sinai
3,500 years ago.
We can finish it,
we can break the covenant.
So I think
that when they come
you, they'll say,
"Oh, no
we are Jews.
Open the doors.
We're going home? "
We're still Jews,
will always be Jews.
Nothing changes for us, because
we are not defendants here.
It is God who is being
defendant, not us.
Aah! Taisez-vous, imbeciles!
He says to shut up.
I understand.
vou et les nazis
sont tous pareils.
Says we're like...
no, we belong to a...
have something in common
with the Nazis.
I am translating.
Maybe wrong.
Scream all you want.
Kill me if you want, just
I will die in the morning.
How many stars do you
there in the universe,
Excuse me, but before...
...before he dies,
I was physically in Paris.
A hundred thousand
millions of stars
in our galaxy.
Only in our galaxy.
"God made all
those stars?
Very likely. The prophet
Amos tells us... Why?
Pardon?
He created one hundred thousand
millions of stars
in our own galaxy.
How many of them have
planets, we know.
And yet, his whole attention
is focused on a small planet
just the outer edge
of a spiral.
And even with
whole planet, no.
Only the Jews.
This man,
I believe one hundred thousand
million stars,
signed a contract
with Jews.
Only Jews.
And even with all
Jews, no, no..
because Jews
I do not count.
So tell me this.
If so loved the Jews,
Why do
Anything else?
Why not filled the universe
with Jews instead of stars?
What is the point?
We do not know the point.
It seems incredible, too,
that throughout the universe,
should choose us.
It is not surprising.
It's crazy.
It is simply
wrong.
Newborns think
that are the focus
the universe.
They think they do
sucking milk believe
that the world fades
when they close their eyes.
They are wrong.
In the Middle Ages, men viewed
that the sun orbited the earth.
They were wrong.
It is an illusion caused
to the point where you are
at that time.
And it's the same with God.
The same.
So, think.
Please think.
In the past, a nation
could have 50 gods,
one to grow corn;
one for the river to rise.. I do not know
Men make their societies
the image of their gods.
Therefore, companies
many gods
have many leaders,
different centers of power.
welcome you to strangers
and to new ideas.
As the Egyptians.
Then next to them
came the Jews...
...with his great idea.
A great idea.
There is only one God.
Amazing.
And what happens?
create a society
where,
all powers
are concentrated
in the hands of a
man, a king.
An effective partnership.
An efficient ship.
And he has this idea that
God loves them more than anyone.
Thrive.
They maintain that God
for themselves.
They try to isolate themselves.
But then someone comes
even better idea -
Christians.
They say, yes,
there is only one God,
But not only
He loves the Jews.
Love all.
We must conquer
all...
The Romans
They loved it.
Developed.
They conquered all.
A god.
A king.
This is how it is.
It is the
power and control,
and what
lost.
But midway
the Romans are gone... Because
Because someone
had a better idea.
Hitler...
had the idea,
there is one God, and that's me.
Here,
Hitler is God not?
But still
we're here.
We are still
here tonight.
You deny God.
What has given you?
What?
There are many here
who have denied God.
They became, taken by
wife a goya,
turned their backs
to the Scriptures...
Sorry. Is
talking about me.
We're here to point
die, and what
you dislike the most
is the fact that I married.
But where did he give?
Where you feel you are
different from me now?
What you got?
Please.
Please point out one point.
These kids educated
Like my son,
like this man
said they saw a truth
that we did not see.
But here they are,
all equal
Facing death.
Look at Ricard.
Outside
was a rich man.
He had many friends.
But here,
is scared.
He can not believe
he will die.
Because I will not die.
Your going to die,
pious idiot.
He has been selected.
I've been selected!
You were sent to the
left like me,
and now you're scared.
The cheats and steals
because he thinks
have more bread than the rest
of us will make you happy.
And think the pray
going to save your life.
4000 years using dumb
hats and still
continue its course
to death!
There is a wasp.
It is called
Ichneumonidae.
The eggs are laid
in the Caterpillars.
The eggs hatch
and then the larvae
wasp
eat the caterpillar
from within.
Eat out
offline.
What kind of God
would design something?
And yet...
Sorry.
Y... my grandfather
planted figs.
There is a wasp...
I'm sure you know.
And this wasp lays
eggs on the flower.
And when the young wasps
are ready to fly,
collect pollen.
Not accumulate against the
as another wasp
or a bee or wind.
They stop
and collect pollen.
You can see them.
And then carry
pollen
the other trees.
This did not help.
They can not eat.
They do..
It is a beautiful arrangement.
Surely God...
Say,
this wasp.
Does this for
all figs
or only for the Jews?
They laugh at me...
I laugh at you.
Just do
observe things
not like babies,
but as men
Men of reason.
Use your right.
We speak
of reason.
What is the reason?
When caught you at your university in Paris,
where you looked as not Jewish,
spoke as a Jew,
thought as a Jew,
and you put
here with us,
that part played
reason in this?
What is the use
of reason
in a world governed
by madness?
The decision
be voted
of judges.
Sorry, judges
court,
You were wrong
about my children?
Is there anything
hope after all?
Nothing.
Get used to this.
The judges granted.
I'm not Jewish.
I never knew
my father.
I did not know he was Jewish.
He died when I
was still a baby. "
My mother was a...
a good German.
He returned home and resumed
her maiden name.
They thought that every
had been forgotten.
At school I was
a good boy.
I became
a good father.
My children joined
the Hitler Youth.
It was a year ago
The Gestapo came for me.
That was the first
I heard from my race.
I thought it was a
normal German.
I was German.
A German
hated Jews.
He knew nothing about
their customs.
The learned here.
I have never heard a word
of the Torah before coming here.
But I am not alone.
They must understand that...
...I grew up learning
that Jews were
dirty, misleading
and disorganized.
And when I got here, I saw that
everything you thought was true
This place was chaotic,
dirty and disorganized;
I thought I was
because of the Jews.
How could this be another
dirty thing?
There is only one latrine
for 5,000 people
That's why.
Think
is a mistake?
Do you think
German engineer
not put
adequate plumbing
by mistake?
No.
This is not how it was.
Nothing here is accidental.
The soil is
part of the system,
like...
the fence, spotlights y...
the other equipment.
It serves a function.
This is where they
take away their dignity,
their humanity.
Our dignity.
Our humanity.
It is part of the process.
So they can...
Germans get
Common kill us,
should show
that we are what ordinary Germans to
are taught to think we are...
dirty,
and without a God-fearing.
When they arrived here,
took away their property;
people took their names;
cut their hair;
took their children...
wives, mothers...
even filling in their teeth.
All
which were removed
made them to be men
Do not let you remove
your God, too.
No matter how...
how stupid and useless
may seem,
the pact is his.
God is his God.
Even though there is.
Keep it.
Leave something that
not be removed.
Us.
Judges are
three in number
to always
have a decision.
To be unanimous
or has a majority
for a
point of view.
The accusation is
God has broken his covenant
with the Jewish people.
Who brought us out
Egypt?
Finally some
common sense.
God brought us out of Egypt.
Another question.
Why
at first
were in Egypt?
There was a famine, and by
Therefore we take refuge.
Who sent the famine?
Well, hunger,
not know much about...
God sent famine.
So God
sent to Egypt
and God
out of Egypt.
Exactly.
And then we got
Babylon,
in order to..
And when we out of Egypt
how did?
With words? Visions?
A miracle?
Moses asked the Pharaoh...
And when Pharaoh said no?
Pests.
Moses became the first
Egyptian water into blood,
then God sent
the plague of frogs,
then the plague
mosquitoes,
then, a plague of
flies, then killed
their livestock,
then the plague
the rash
then hail,
crops that abused
and even the trees
and structures everywhere
except in Goshen,
where the Israelites lived.
And yet Pharaoh
disagreed.
And so the plague
locusts
and then the days of darkness
and, finally, what?
God killed the
firstborn of Egypt
and us out of Egypt.
He killed the firstborn,
from the firstborn
and heir of Pharaoh
the firstborn from the
slaves in the mills.
Murdered them all.
God killed Pharaoh?
No, I think
because then...
He was the Pharaoh who said no,
but God let him live
and killed their children
instead.
All children.
And then the
people of Israel
could leave,
taking with them
gold and silver
and jewelry and clothing
dress of the Egyptians.
And then God drowned
soldiers
who pursued them.
It closed the waters to the
soldiers could not follow.
He waited until
were following
and then
closed waters.
And then what?
Then the desert
Finally, the
promised land...
Now, the Promised Land
was.. is empty?
A new place,
fallow?
No. There was...
As written,
"When the Lord your God
"I take you to land,
"sacrificed many
nations before you,
"much bigger countries
"and more powerful
you.
"You
"will annihilate
and completely destroyed
"and will do no
covenant with them
and will show no compassion
toward them. "
He showed us his favor.
We are his people.
And gave us a
king in Saul.
Now, when,
the people of Amalek
fought
town of Saul,
that's what
ordered the Lord God?
I ask the student.
"Crush Amalek.
Put it under the curse
of destruction ".
Saul showed mercy?
In save someone?
"No, unless... "
"I do not salves,
"but kills.
"Murdering men and women,
"babies and newborns,
oxen and sheep,
camels and donkeys. "
Therefore, Saul
prepared to do so,
and on the way, is
met with the Kenites.
However, these were not
people of Amalek.
I had no lawsuits
with them.
He urged them to
flee.
And the Lord our God,
was pleased
Saul's mercy?
For justice to Saul?
Was not.
And when Saul decided
not all cattle slaughter,
but take it for
feed its people,
God was pleased
by his wisdom, his charity?
No.
No, it was
He said: "You have rejected
the word of Adonai.
Therefore, he will have
rejected as king. "
So please search
the Lord our God,
Samuel brought the King Agag
and tore it to
the Lord in Gilgal.
After Saul came David,
who took Batsheba,
the wife of Uriah the Hittite
for himself
making arrangements for
Uriah kill...
against
God's wishes.
God punished
David for this?
In a way
to speak.
Batsheba punished?
In the sense that when...
Adonai said,
"Since I have sinned
the child will die. "
Questions before,
who punishes
a child?
God does.
Now, the child dies suddenly
mercifully, without pain?
In Chapter 12, we
learned that in reality...
Seven days.
Seven days, children
go die in pain
while David
wrapped himself
in bags and
ashes and fasted
and tried to show
their pain to God.
He listened to God?
The child died.
He knew that child
God was fair?
thought the Amalekites
that Adonai was fair?
Did you think the
Mothers of Egypt
mothers...
thought they
that Adonai was fair?
But Adonai is our God, segur..
What.. God did not create the Egyptians?
Do not set up its rivers
and grew
their crops?
If not him,
Then who?
What... some other god?
And what created them?
To punish them?
To die
hunger, fear,
to massacre?
The people of Amalek,
the people of Egypt...
as it was for them
when Adonai
turned against them?
Was.
Today, there
a choice, right?
When David defeated
the Moabites,
What did?
He had to lie down
on the ground in rows,
and chose one that will live
and two who will die.
We've become
in Moab.
We are learning how
went to the Amalekites.
Faced be extinguished
by Adonai.
They died for their purpose.
They fell like us
're falling.
They were scared as well
us.
And what did they learn?
They learned...
that Adonai,
the Lord our God...
our God...
not good.
He is not good.
It was never good.
He only stayed on our side.
God is not good.
Oh, at first
when He repented
that it had created human beings
human and flooded the land,
Why?
they had done to
deserve to be annihilated?
What could
have done
to deserve such
slaughter?
What could they have done
that was so bad?
God is not good.
When asked Abraham
to sacrifice his son,
Abraham should have
said no.
We should have taught him to our God
Justice was in our hearts.
We should have faced.
He is not good,
simply has been strong.
It has simply been
on our side.
When they brought us here,
they brought in train.
a guard
slapped me.
On their belts,
wrote,
"Gott mit uns".
"God is with us. "
Now, who says
who is not?
Maybe it is.
Is there another explanation?
What we see here?
His power...
His majesty, its strength.
All these things, but
against us.
He is still God...
but not our God.
It has become...
our enemy.
That is what
happened to the pact.
He has made a new
deal with others.
We are now entering
to the gas chambers.
So...
him guilty.
Found God
guilty, yes,
for not complying
with the agreement,
for breaking your
covenant with us.
Every day 6,000 people were
taken to the gas chambers here.
39,024.
38,483.
38,497.
38,511.
38,532.
I thought I was going to
calling and called my son.
Lucky you are.
Please.
I'm ready.
He is not ready.
Please,
Do this for me.
Send me,
not him.
38,562.
38,052.
38,511.
Shut up.
Just move.
Please look at me.
I can be me.
I am young,
might be useful.
How can they be
to them and not me? Please
Nonsense.
Making Sense
not my job.
Well, then,
who is?
I think you're reading
wrong cards.
Please, just
checked the cards.
Please checked
cards.
38,675.
38,692.
38,695.
You.
What now?
38,702.
Now that God is guilty,
What now?
38,711.
Now...
now pray.
39,055.
"From time to time,
"before the
mountains were born,
39,066.
"before the Earth
will become,
"from everlasting to everlasting,
"You are God.
"You bring us back
Dust saying... "
Not the best
bed in place,
but... is out
selection.
"We bring back to dust
saying,
back to me... "
"It's blooming
and growing.
At night, it was
is withered and dry. "
38,544.
Please.
move your butt!
No, no, you
the wrong person!
We
same surname.
The boy
is very useful.
It's me you want to.
It's in my...
Look, you've heard
numbers.
I!
I'm fine.
38,652.
You, there.
Move.
Good man.
It is not their number.
It's mine.
Back... back!
38,697.
38,702.
38,701.
"Who knows the
power of your anger?
"Since your anger
is so great...
as the fear that
you intended. "
"In the morning, will
as the grass grows.
In the morning,
grows and flourishes.
"... It is as long as time
ails us,
the years in which
experienced disasters.
"terror...
by your indignation.
"Since we passed quickly,
and we went flying.
"Who knows the power
of your anger?
"Now that your anger is so great
as the fear of you properly.
"We will sing and be
happy all our days
"May our joy
is so long
"as the time
that affect us,
the years in which
experienced disasters. "
And their
prayers answered?
We are still here.