Captioning made possible by
lions gate entertainment
[thunder]
[birds squawking]
[faint conversation]
He had a live-in
nurse but...
She was nothing
but a bother.
I not like her.
Would be better if you live
in again, mr. David.
Hanna, stop it.
If there's any emergency,
you call me in new york.
Uh, mr. Jimmy,
more coffee?
What?
Oh, well, yes.
Why not?
Just half a cup, hanna.
Isn't hanna
a peach, hmm?
But she tells me
that you haven't been
sleeping very well.
Well, it's these ridiculous
pills they prescribe.
For instance, the luminal.
The next day I go around
as stupid as a stone,
Well, then my mind's
going off in a hundred
directions at once.
Then take the luminal.
Well, yes, but today I wanted
to be alert for your visit,
Particularly as I saw so little
of you at the hospital.
Jimmy, look, I'm sorry,
But with this
picture and two
difficult stars...
It's no pleasure making
you feel guilty.
You don't want to miss
your aeroplane.
I like your new cezanne.
Oh.
Well.
Good-bye, hanna.
I get the door.
[door opens]
[clears throat]
[whistle blowing]
Who is this new yard, man?
Mr. Boom...
I-I don't...
I hire him while you
were in the hospital.
He came cheap.
♪ bells of hell
go ting-a-ling-a-ling ♪
♪ for you
but not for me ♪
♪ o death, where is thy
sting-a-ling-a-ling? ♪
♪ grave where
thy victory ♪
Good morning.
My name is whale.
This is my house.
And your name is?
Boone.
I couldn't help but
notice your tattoo.
That motto..."death
before dishonor."
It just means that
I was a marine.
Ah, the marines.
I suppose
you served in korea.
[grunts] yeah.
Well, I'm gonna
get back to work.
Well, when you're through,
feel free to use the pool.
And we're
quite informal here.
No need to worry
about a bathing suit.
I got another lawn
to do this afternoon.
Oh, well,
then some other time.
Yes, keep up
the good work.
[whistling]
[sighs]
[rain falling]
Woman: Jimmy!
Privy needs cleanin'.
I have me class tonight.
Don't get
above yourself, jimmy
Leave the drawing
to the artists.
Quite so, mum.
To the privy.
[clicks heels]
"quite so"?
Jimmy whale.
Who are you
to put on airs?
Jimmy whale.
Is there iced tea, hanna?
Yes, mr. Jimmy.
Ah, cucumber sandwiches.
An interview,
after so many years.
Very exciting.
It's just a student
from the university.
Mm-hmm.
[doorbell rings]
[man talking, faint]
Hanna: This way, please.
Mr. Kay, sir.
Oh, yes, of course.
Mr. Kay.
I'd
almost forgotten.
My tea-time guest.
Mr. Whale,
this is such an honor.
You're one of my favorite
all-time directors.
I can't believe
I'm meeting you.
No, I don't
suppose you can.
And this is your house.
Ah! The house
of frankenstein.
In a great big villa
or a mansion.
Ah, well, one likes
to live simply.
People's movies
aren't their lives.
[imitates frankenstein's
monster] "love dead.
Hate living."
[high-pitched giggle]
That's my favorite line
In my favorite
movie of yours--
"bride of frankenstein."
Is it indeed?
Hanna, I think we're
going to take our tea
Down by
the swimming pool.
Would that be good
for you, mr. Kay?
Sure.
Well, lead on,
won't you?
Oh, I love the great
horror films,
"the old dark house."
"the invisible man."
They have style,
and they're funny!
So, mr. Kay, what
do you want to know?
Everything.
Just start
at the beginning.
Well, I was born
just outside london,
The only son of a minister,
who was also a schoolmaster.
Grandpapa was a bishop,
church of...
[bell tolling]
Stop lagging behind, jimmy.
We'll be late for church.
Man: Come on!
Stop lollygagging!
[bell continues tolling]
They'll think
you're a nancy boy.
[men, women talking, faint]
Mr. Whale?
Your father was
a schoolmaster?
Yes, of course.
And I was going
to go up to oxford.
But the war broke out
and I never made it.
You cannot imagine what life
was like after the armistice.
The 20's in london.
A break with everything
dour and respectable.
I had a knack with
pencil and paper,
So I was hired to design
sets for stage productions.
Ah.
Yes. Help yourself.
Cucumber sandwiches.
[sighs]
Thank you, hanna.
And you can go now.
There was one play
in particular,
A beautiful, grim study
of war called "journey's end."
Every experienced director
turned it down.
Not commercial.
So I offered myself.
"journey's end"
made the careers
It was only a matter of time
before hollywood beckoned.
How much longer before we
get to the horror movies?
Am I right
in assuming, mr. Kay,
That it is not me that
you are interested in,
But only my horror pictures?
No, but it's the horror
movies you'll be
remembered for.
I'm not dead yet, mr. Kay.
Uh, I never
said you were.
Or w-will be soon.
So, "journey's end"
brought you
to hollywood.
I've got
a little proposal.
This line of questioning
is getting old.
Don't you think?
I don't mind.
Well, I do.
Let's make it more
interesting for me.
I will answer truthfully any
question that you put to me,
And in return,
for each answer,
You will remove
an article of clothing.
I thi...
That's funny, mr. Whale.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
My life as a game
of strip poker.
Shall we play?
So the rumors
are true then.
Oh? What rumors
would those be?
That you were
forced to retire
Because of, um,
a sex scandal.
A homosexual scandal,
you mean.
For me to answer a question
of that magnitude,
You'll have to remove
both your shoes and socks.
You're a dirty old man.
Oh.
Oh, it is kind
of you to indulge your
elders in their vices,
Just as I indulge
the young in theirs.
No, there was no scandal.
My only other vice.
I expect you'd like a fuller
answer to that question.
It'll cost you your jacket.
Too warm
for a jacket anyway.
You must understand how
hollywood was 20 years ago.
Nobody cared a tinker's
cuss who you slept with,
So long as you kept
it out of the papers.
Well, outside
hollywood who even knows
who george cukor is,
Much less what he gets up
To with those boys
from the malt shops?
George cukor?
Who made
"a star is born?"
Take off your shirt, and
I'll tell you all about it.
George is famous for his
Saturday dinner parties.
Great writers, artists,
society folk,
All rubbing elbows
with hollywood royalty.
But how many of those
oh-so-proper people
Know about the Sunday
brunches that follow?
Armies of trade eating
up the leftovers,
Followed by some strenuous fun
and frolic in the pool.
Can we talk about
the horror movies now?
Is there anything in particular
that you want to know?
Will you tell me
everything you remember
About making
"frankenstein?"
[whispers] ohh.
Can that count
as one question?
I can't believe
I'm doing this.
Just like going
swimming, isn't it?
Well, maybe you'd like
a swim when we're through.
I don't swim myself,
so the pool tends
to go to waste.
Ok. "frankenstein."
Who came up
with the monster's
makeup and look?
Oh, my idea, mostly,
from my sketches.
Big, heavy brow.
The head flat on top
So you could take out the old
brain and put in the new
Like tinned beef.
[laughs]
He's one
of the great images
More important
than the "mona lisa."
Oh, don't be daft.
It's just makeup and
padding and a big actor.
It's hardly
the "mona lisa."
How did you ever
think of casting him
as the monster?
He'd never even starred
in a movie before that.
Mr. Whale?
Is something the matter?
[grunts]
Mr. Whale?
Please excuse me.
Mr. Whale,
are you all right?
[groaning]
Just...
Need to lie down.
Studio.
There's a day bed
in the studio.
[gasps]
oh, my god.
Mr. Whale,
wh-what's wrong?
Is it your heart?
No, head, not heart.
Water.
Glass is in sink.
Which ones?
I bring them all.
Luminal.
Mr. Kay, you're not dressed.
I was gonna
go swimming.
So you were.
Mmm.
You should probably go home.
[clicking tongue]
[screen door opens]
[door closes]
[inhales deeply]
You must think
I'm terrible, hanna.
I don't think you're
anything anymore.
Already you're
chasing after boys.
Oh, shut up.
All we did was talk.
Perhaps I should
get you uphill
Before the pills
knock you cold.
No, no, no, no, no.
Please, no.
Let me stay here.
Thank you.
[soldiers shouting]
[gunfire, bombs exploding]
Man: Quiet on the set, please.
Father: You're
a disgrace!
Mother: Jimmy,
privy needs cleanin'.
Mr. Whale.
Open your eyes.
Now look left.
That's right.
And breathe out.
[exhales]
Let's see
what we've got.
You're a lucky man,
mr. Whale.
Whatever damage was
done by your stroke,
It left your motor
abilities relatively
unimpaired.
Yes, dr. Payne, but what
about from the neck upwards?
What's the story there?
That's what I'm
trying to explain.
The central nervous system
selects items
From a constant
storm of sensations.
Whatever was killed
in your stroke
Seems to have
short-circuited
this mechanism.
So you're saying there's
an electrical storm
Going on inside my head.
Well, that's as good a way
as any to describe it.
I've seen far worse cases.
What about all the rest?
The killing headaches.
The phantom smells.
My inability
to close my eyes
Without thinking
of a hundred things
simultaneously.
I've never
encountered the olfactory
hallucinations before,
But I'm sure they're related.
So, what do I do?
Take the luminal to sleep
And whenever you feel
an attack coming on.
What you're saying is
that this isn't just
A case of resting
until I'm better,
But that my condition
will continue
To deteriorate until
the end of my life.
You will take them all,
mr. Jimmy.
Yes.
Don't you worry, hanna.
Good night.
Thank you.
[whispers prayer]
Ohh!
[continues praying]
[chuckles]
[equipment thuds]
[equipment rattling]
Clay: Shit.
Everything all right,
mr. Boone?
I didn't mean
to disturb you.
It got away from me.
I was just going
to buzz hanna
To bring down
some iced tea.
I'd like it very much
if you'd join me.
I kinda stink to
high heaven right now.
Let me ask hanna
to bring tea for two.
Or would you prefer a beer?
Uh, no.
Thanks. But tea is fine.
Splendid.
Come in, mr. Boone.
This is my workshop,
my studio.
Hardly somewhere where
a sweaty workman
Should feel out of place.
Are these your paintings?
Excuse me, but, uh,
are you famous?
Oh, well, you know
what they say,
If you have to ask...
Look, I'm just a guy
who cuts lawns,
But, uh, some of these
do look kind of familiar.
Well, that's because
they were familiar
when I painted them.
The one you're looking
at is a copy of a dutch
still life
Done nearly
300 years ago.
And there's a rembrandt
here somewhere.
Yeah, copies.
I got ya.
But before I retired,
You might say I had
my time in the sun.
Tell me, do you like
motion pictures?
Yeah, sure.
Everybody does.
Why? Were you an actor?
Oh, good lord, no!
No. Well, actually,
I was in my youth.
But never in hollywood,
no, no.
No, here I was merely
a director.
Really?
Well, what were some
of your movies?
The only ones
you may have heard of
Are the
"frankenstein" movies.
And, um, uh,
"bride of frankenstein?"
And son of, and
the other ones, too?
Uh, no. I-I just
directed the first two.
The others
were done by hacks.
Yeah, but still, I mean,
th-those were big movies.
I mean, you must be rich.
Look, hanna's here
with our refreshments.
Could you get the door?
Y-yeah.
How are you feeling,
mr. Jimmy?
How's your mind today?
My mind is lovely.
And yours?
You remember what
the doctor tells us.
I have invited
mr. Boone in merely
for a cup of tea.
[sighs]
We'll have a brief chat,
And then he'll
finish the yard.
I am not forgetting
your last "brief chat."
Will you go away?
We can manage.
He looks plenty big.
He won't need my help
if anything goes "flooey."
Go.
Avaunt.
[chuckles]
Comic maid.
No, she's a love, hanna.
But when they've
been in your employ
for too long,
Servants begin to think
they're married to you.
Please sit down.
Oh, and do help
yourself, mr. Boone.
So, what did she mean by
things going all "flooey"?
I'm recently returned
from a spell in hospital.
Nothing serious.
Touch of stroke.
Huh.
You must excuse
my staring,
But you have the most
marvelous head.
Huh?
To an artistic eye.
Have you ever modeled?
What, you mean,
like, posed for pictures?
Sat for an artist?
Been sketched?
Mmm...
[laughs] no.
What's to sketch?
You have the most...
Architectural skull.
And your nose, it's...
Very expressive.
Broke is more like it.
Mmm.
Oh, sorry to go
on like this.
It's just the Sunday
painter in me.
I quite understand
your refusal.
It's a great deal
to ask of anyone.
You mean, you really
want to draw me?
I would pay
for the privilege
of drawing that head.
And it's just my head
you want to draw?
I mean, nothin' else?
And what are
you suggesting?
If I include a hand
or a bit of shoulder?
No, I mean,
you don't wanna...
Draw pictures of me in
my birthday suit, do you?
I have no interest in
your body, mr. Boone.
I can assure you
of that.
Well, uh...
[chuckles]
I mean, hell, I could
use the money.
Excellent.
Here are the trade papers
you wanted.
Hi. Look, I know you
already paid me.
I'm just here to...
The master
is waiting for you.
He's down in his studio.
Here. Take this
with you.
Uh, I'm sorry, lady.
I'm just here so he
can draw my picture.
What you are doing is
no business of mine.
What are you talking about?
What kind of man are you?
Are you a good man?
Something about me
make you think I'm not?
You will not hurt him?
Lady, I'm gonna
sit in a chair,
And he's gonna
draw my picture.
Is that gonna hurt him?
No.
I'm sorry.
Forget
everything I said.
I will take the tray.
Yeah, you do that.
Ah, mr. Boone.
Come into my parlor.
Ah, hanna. Good.
Thank you.
And, hanna, good-bye.
Well, now, I'm sure you
would like to wet
Your whistle
while I work. Hmm?
Oh. Beer.
And we'll take it,
uh, slowly today
Because this is your
first time modeling.
Oh, hey, did you see this?
They're showing one of
your movies tomorrow night.
You don't say.
Which picture?
Uh, "bride of frankenstein."
No, I much prefer
"the invisible man"
or "showboat."
Right. Now,
shall we begin?
Yeah. I'm, uh...
I'm ready when you are.
Oh, that shirt,
mr. Boone.
Hmm?
Oh, it's new.
It's just too white.
It's too distracting.
W-w-would it be
asking you too much
to take it off?
Well, I'm not wearing
an undershirt today.
I'm not your
aunt tillie. [laughing]
You did say that
you just wanted to draw
my face, right?
Oh, well, if it's
going to make you
feel uncomfortable,
Perhaps we can find
something else
for you to wear.
Yes, we could
drape this across your
shoulders like a toga.
Would that help
you overcome your
schoolgirl shyness?
All right, all right.
I'll take the shirt off.
Kinda warm in here anyway.
Oh, yes.
That's better.
Now...
And if you'd like to sit
slightly sideways...
To me.
That's right.
And then just put your
arm on the box there.
Just so.
Why don't you
take a picture?
It'll last longer.
That's exactly what
I'm going to do.
[mutters] yeah.
Hmm.
It's just like being
at the doctor.
You have to remain
perfectly still
While I examine
and scrutinize you.
[sniffing]
Dripping.
Huh?
Do you ever eat dripping
in this country?
The fats from
roast and such.
Kept congealed
in a jar,
And then used
like butter on bread
and toast.
Sounds like something
you'd feed the dog.
Only the poorest
families ever ate it.
We used to keep ours
In a large, blue
crockery jar.
Your family ate,
uh, dripping?
Oh, of course not.
No, no.
As I said, only
the poorest families.
God, it's ironic.
I've spent much of my
life outrunning the past,
And now it floods
all over me.
There's something about
the openness of your face
That makes me want
to tell the truth.
Yes, our family
ate dripping.
Beef dripping.
And four to a bed.
And a privy out back
in the alley.
Are you also from
the slums, mr. Boone?
Well, we weren't rich, but
w-w-we weren't poor either.
No, well, you were
middle class, hmm?
Like all americans, hmm?
Well, I don't know.
I guess you could
say we lived
On the wrong side
of the tracks.
Well, in dudley, in
the north of England,
There were more sides
to the tracks
Than any american
could imagine.
Every englishman
knows his place,
Our family had no doubt
about who they were,
But I was an aberration
in that household,
A freak of nature.
I had imagination,
cleverness, joy.
Now, where
did I get that?
[chuckles]
Certainly not from them.
They took me out of
school when I was 14
And put me in a factory.
They meant no harm.
They were like
a family of farmers
Who've been
given a giraffe
And don't know what
to do with the creature
Except to harness him
to the plow.
Hatred was
the only thing that
kept my soul alive
In that
soul-killing place.
And amongst the men I hated
Was my own poor,
dear, dumb father...
Who'd put me into that hell
in the first place.
Mr. Whale?
[groans]
I apologize, mr. Boone.
Since my stroke, I am often
overcome with nostalgia.
Well, I'm not that crazy
about the old man myself.
You know what I mean?
Um...
Shall we just have a break
for five minutes, hmm?
[sniffs]
Just what this place
needs tonight.
Couldn't get
any deader, doll.
Set me up.
Your friend
want one?
Yeah. One for
what's-his-name here.
I say we let lover boy
watch his movie
And be grateful
he's not cuttin'
shirley temple's lawn.
Why is everyone breakin'
my balls tonight?
Jesus, boone.
'cause
some old coot wants
to paint your picture.
We're just bringin' you
back to earth.
Can't imagine a real
artist wanting
To spend time lookin'
at that kisser.
That you couldn't lay
under it a couple of times.
[laughing]
I bet he's just
some fruit pretending
to be famous
So he can get into
the big guy's pants.
What makes you say that?
Well, why don't you
just keep your dirty
thoughts to yourself?
He's interested in you
for your conversation.
We all know what
a great talker you are.
Fuck you.
Not anymore, you don't.
We're watching
the damn movie, harry.
Ok, we're gonna
watch the movie.
Calm down.
We'll watch it.
[dramatic score playing]
James whale!
Right there. Huh?
What'd I tell ya? Huh?
What should I do then?
Aah!
If you don't wanna watch it,
just go wash some glasses.
All right?
[growls]
Good old una.
[screaming]
Gobbling like
a turkey hen.
[laughs, imitates
una screaming]
Oh, that monster.
How could you be
working with him?
Don't be daft, hanna.
He's a very
proper actor.
And the dullest
fellow imaginable.
To a new world
of gods and monsters.
[laughs]
[laughing]
Man: The creation
of life is enthralling.
Simply enthralling,
is it not?
These old movies
were such a hoot.
They thought
they were being scary,
But they're just funny.
Maybe it's supposed
to be funny.
Scary is scary.
Funny is funny.
You don't mix them.
Woman.
Friend.
Wife.
Sick stuff.
Necrophilia.
The monster's lonely.
He wants a friend.
A girlfriend, somebody.
What's so sick about that?
Man: Do you know who
henry frankenstein is,
And who you are?
Monster: Made me from dead.
I love dead.
Hate living.
Man: You are wise
in your generation.
It's beating perfectly.
[gasps]
Oh, she's horrible.
The bride
of frankenstein.
She's beautiful.
Monster: Friend?
[mutters]
You don't want him.
I can't leave them!
I can't!
Yes.
Go.
You live!
[growls]
[sniffs]
I'm sorry, mr. Jimmy.
Your movie
is not my teacup.
Still, glad it has
a happy ending.
The bad people are dead,
And the good people live.
[applause]
My god!
Is the audience
to presume
That colin and I have
done her hair?
I thought we were
mad scientists,
Not hairdressers.
Only a mad scientist
could've done this to a woman.
Oh, no, my dear. You
look absolutely amazing.
There's no way
I can compete with you.
The scene is yours.
In the sequel, james,
Two lady scientists
should make a monster,
And our monster
would be gary cooper.
I'd have thought
mr. Leslie howard
Would be more your line.
More your line, I think.
My line nowadays
runs to rin tin tin.
Colin! Here!
It's time!
How is he tonight?
Yes, colin, come see what
they've done to our elsa.
I'm not quite
myself today, jimmy.
A touch of the flu,
you know.
Now, you just relax,
dear boy.
You can do this
scene in your sleep.
Hmm?
I gather we not
only did her hair,
but dressed her.
What a couple of queens
we are, colin.
Yes, that's right.
A couple of flaming queens.
Pretorius
is a little bit
In love with
dr. Frankenstein.
You know? Hmm?
Uh-huh?
Yes. I think we're
pretty close.
Mm-hmm.
Shall we give it a go?
Why not?
Quiet on the set,
please.
[bell rings]
Lights!
Sound!
Man: Ok for sound!
And camera.
Scene 215, take one.
Action.
The bride of
frankenstein.
Well, that was
a weird movie.
Let's take
a little walk, huh?
What do you say?
A little walk and talk?
I really feel like
talking tonight.
This old guy's exactly
the sort of person
I expected to meet
when I moved here.
You know? He's really done
things with his life.
Do you realize
you're more interested
in this old goober
Than you ever
were in me?
That's different
he's a man.
Besides, you got no business
callin' him a homo. You know?
It never crossed
your mind?
He's an artist,
but, you know,
He's too old to be
thinkin' about sex.
All the old men
I know think about
nothing but sex.
Hey, hey, hey.
What is eating you tonight?
You picked up that girl
right in front of me.
No, I'm actually kind of
glad it happened.
It made me wonder
what the hell I was
doin' with my life.
I still have time
to get things right,
Get married again.
Y-you don't mean...
[giggling]
You're not
marriage material.
You're not even
boyfriend material.
You're a kid.
A big, fun,
irresponsible kid.
No, I'm not a kid.
No? What
are you, then?
What'll you be
ten years from now?
Still cuttin' lawns?
Still bangin'
horny divorcees
in your trailer?
So I guess this means
you don't want to fuck.
Is that all this conversation
means to you?
Whether I put out or not?
Yeah, you're damn straight.
I'm tired of playin' games.
Hey.
Look, this is comin'
out all wrong.
Betty!
Forget it, boone.
You're just another loser on
the other side of the bar.
Hey. Hey!
Hey, betty!
Oh.
Man: We are friends,
you and I.
Monster: You hurt
my poor friend.
Woman: Isn't
the monster dead yet?
[elsa laughing]
Elsa/shelley: Perfect night
for mystery and horror.
Monster: Bad.
Friend good.
Elsa/shelley: The air itself
is filled with monsters.
[electricity buzzing,
crackling]
[groaning]
[urinating]
Does the yard man
come today?
Of course.
This afternoon.
Hey!
The master wants to know
if you are free for lunch.
I tell him you'll be
having other plans,
But he insists I ask.
Well, I do have a lawn
this afternoon,
But I'm free until then.
Expect nothing fancy.
The master is dressing.
I'm to offer you a drink.
There is whiskey.
There is iced tea.
Yeah, tea's fine.
No, no, you're
a guest now.
You go sit in
the living room.
Um, I'm more comfortable
in here, hanna.
It is hanna, isn't it?
[sighs]
So, uh, hanna, how long have
you worked here for mr. Whale?
Oh, long enough.
Fifteen years.
Yeah?
You have people, boone?
They're all back
in joplin, missouri.
Oh, your wife?
Uh, I'm not married.
Why?
I don't know.
I guess because, uh...
No girl in her right mind
would have me.
A man who is not
married has nothing.
He is a man of trouble.
Are you proposing what
I think you're proposing?
Don't you think I'm just
a little bit young for you?
Oh, men!
Always pulling legs.
Everything is comedy.
Oh, how very amusing.
How marvelously droll.
So, uh...Have you
ever been married?
Of course.
I'm married still.
What does your husband do?
He's dead now.
Well, then you're
as single as I am.
No, no, I have children,
and grandchildren, too.
I visit when I can.
Of course, now mr. Jimmy
cannot be left alone
For long, so I do
not get out much.
[sighs]
poor mr. Jimmy.
There is much
good in him,
But he will suffer
the fires of hell.
It's very sad.
You sure of that?
That's what
the priests tell me.
His sins of
the flesh will keep
him from heaven.
Hell, everybody's
got those.
No. His is the worst.
The unspeakable.
The deed no man can name
without shame.
What is
the good english?
All I know is "bugger."
he's a bugger.
Men who bugger
each other.
A homo.
[chuckling] yes!
You know.
That is why he must
go to hell.
I do not think
it's fair,
But god's laws
is not for us to judge.
So, what you're telling me
is that mr. Whale is a homo.
You did not know?
Uh...
No. I wasn't very sure.
You and he are not--
Oh, no, no, no.
Hanna.
[laughing]
[gasps]
That's what I hope.
I did not think you
were a bugger, too.
Whale: Hanna?
Oh. You must
go in quickly.
He would not like
to think I've had
you in the kitchen.
Oh. How are you,
mr. Boone?
I'm so glad you could
come for lunch.
"her majesty's loyal
subjects in the motion
picture industry."
"cordially invited to
a reception at the home
of mr. George cukor."
The pushy little--
[sighs]
Horning in on the
queen's little sister,
And then offering
to share her with
the whole damn raj?
This is a world I
finished with long ago.
And I expect them to
return the compliment.
Cheers.
I, uh, I watched
your movie the other night
with some friends.
Did you, now?
Yeah.
Did anyone laugh?
Pity. People are so
earnest these days.
Why? Was it
supposed to be funny?
Yes, of course.
I had to make
it interesting
for myself, you see.
So, a comedy
about death...
The trick is not
to spoil it for anyone
Who's not
in on the joke.
But the monster
never receives any
of my jibes.
He's noble.
Noble and misunderstood.
In korea, mr. Boone...
Did you kill anyone?
I don't like
to talk about that.
It's nothing
to be ashamed of.
In the service
of one's country,
Something
to be proud of.
Any jerk with a gun
can kill someone.
Well, that's true, yes.
Hand-to-hand combat
is the true test.
Did you ever slay
anyone hand-to-hand?
No.
But I could have, though.
Yes, I believe
you could.
How free is your
schedule this afternoon?
Well, I gotta trim
the hedges,
And then I got another lawn
out on la cienega.
Suppose we say "phooey"
to the hedges.
Can you spare
an hour after lunch
to sit for me?
Um...I can't.
Well, I'll pay
you our going rate,
Plus whatever you would
have got for the hedges.
I-I just don't feel
like sittin' still today.
All righty.
I understand.
You ever been
married, mr. Whale?
No.
Well, not in
the legal sense.
What other sense
is there?
Well, one can live
as husband and wife
Without getting
the law involved.
So then you did have a wife?
Depending on which
of us you asked.
My friend david lived
here for many years.
Oh.
Does that surprise you?
No, um...
You're a homosexual.
Mmm!
If one must use
the clinical name.
I'm not, you know.
I never
thought you were.
You don't think of me
that way, do you?
And what way
would that be?
Well, the way that
I look at women.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
Would break my neck
if I so much as laid
a finger on you.
Besides,
you're not my type.
So we understand
each other.
Hey. Live and let live.
I hope this has
got nothing to do
With your refusing
to sit for me today.
Oh, no.
What are you afraid
of, mr. Boone?
Surely not a frail
old man like me.
Tell me more about
yourself, mr. Boone.
Have you
a steady companion?
Not at the moment.
Well, 'cause I guess
you gotta kiss ass
Just to get a piece of it.
Nicely put.
A man's gotta
make up his life alone.
A philosopher. Mmm.
Thoreau...
With a lawn mower.
Yes. But do be
careful, mr. Boone.
Freedom is a drug,
you know, much like
any other.
Too much can be
a very bad thing.
Is that why you and,
uh, your friend split up?
'cause he wanted to be free?
I know it's why I
stopped making pictures.
You might not think
it to look at me now,
But there was
a time when I was
At the very pinnacle
of my profession.
The horror movies
were behind me.
I'd made "showboat."
Major success.
So now I was to do
something important.
The picture was called
"the road back."
It was an indictment
of the great war and
what it did to germany.
It was going to be
my masterpiece.
What happened?
The fucking studio
butchered it.
They brought
in another director
to add some slapstick
And the movie
laid an egg.
A great, expensive bomb
for which I was blamed.
And after that
I was out of fashion.
I could
no longer command
the best projects,
Why should I spend my
time working in this
dreadful business?
Do you miss it?
Oh, it was all
so long ago.
Fifteen years.
Making movies
is the most wonderful
thing in the world.
Working with friends,
entertaining people.
Yes, I suppose
I miss it.
But I chose freedom.
David,
of course, was still
in the thick of it,
A life chockablock
with anxiety and
studio intrigue.
I didn't fancy spending
my golden years
As "the friend,"
So I finally
drew down the curtain
and closed the show.
And, um, when the
fetters are loosened,
A certain hedonism
creeps in,
Oh, there was a time
when this house was
full of young men.
Some of them
even posed for me,
Right where
you're sitting now.
Of course, they weren't
nearly so bashful.
Oh, no,
this studio was full
Of bare buttocks
and pricks. Mmm.
Hard, arrogant pricks.
Isn't it bad enough
that you've told me
you're a fuckin' fairy?
And now you're gonna rub
my face in it?
Mr. Boone, I assure you,
I didn't mean--
Fuck this!
From now on, I'm just
the guy that cuts your lawn.
Got it?
[door swings shut]
Man: Jimmy?
Come on, jimmy.
Watch me dive.
Clay: Hey, harry.
Set me up.
[jukebox country swing]
Where's betty?
Took the night off.
Some guy she's had her
eye on for a while.
Hey!
Hi!
[panting, moaning]
Hello, helen.
It's clay.
No, I'm not in jail.
No, I don't need
any money. Thanks.
There's this movie guy
I met out here.
She'd get
a real bang out of it.
Just let me talk--
where is she?
You don't know.
Yeah, I'd give you
my phone number if I had
a phone, wouldn't I?
Put the old man on.
Yeah, you know, forget it.
Just let him sleep it off.
All right. Yeah.
Time's up, helen, now.
[voice on phone, faint]
I'm out of dimes.
Uh-huh.
Have one for me.
Mr. Boone.
Thank you, hanna.
I wanna sit for you again.
Only if you promise to ease up
on the locker room talk, ok?
Scout's honor.
[chuckles]
I'm curious, mr. Boone.
What convinced you
to come back?
I don't know.
I like your stories,
I guess.
Oh, everyone's
got stories to tell.
Not me.
And the fear that you
displayed at our last session.
How did you overcome that?
More like disgust.
Oh, same difference,
mr. Boone.
All part of the great gulf
that stands between us two.
Am I right in assuming that
you have little experience
With men of my persuasion?
No teammates in football?
No.
You must think that
the whole world is queer.
Well, you know what?
It's not.
And war certainly isn't.
Oh, there may be no
atheists in the foxholes,
But there are,
occasionally, lovers.
You're talkin'
through your hat now.
No, I'm not. I was
in the foxholes myself.
You were a soldier?
I was an officer
in the trenches.
No, my dear,
the crimean war.
Well, what do you think?
The great war.
There were trenches
when I arrived
And trenches when
I left two years later.
Just like in the movies,
only the movies, ahh,
They never get
the stench of it all.
The world reduced
to mud and sandbags
And a narrow strip
of rainy sky.
What were we talking about?
Oh.
Love.
Love in the trenches.
Barnett.
Was that his name?
Leonard barnett.
He'd come straight
to the front from school.
From harrow.
And he looked up to me.
Wasn't like the others.
He didn't care that
I was a working-class man
Impersonating my betters.
How strange to be
admired so blindly.
I suppose he loved me.
I remember one morning
in particular,
A morning when
the sun came out.
There were days
when the weather was
enough to make one happy.
He and I stood
on the fire step.
I was showing him
the sights of no-man's-land.
It was beautiful.
Beautiful.
With a tall, apple-cheeked
schoolboy who loved me...
And trusted me.
You will not do
this to me again, mr...
[gasps]
mr. Boone.
You will not set me on
another walk down memory lane.
I...I won't.
[sniffles] oh, why do
I tell you all this?
I never even remembered
it till you got me going.
You started in on this.
You can't understand.
You just sit there.
"yes, the poor old man,"
you're thinking to yourself.
Yeah. "the crazy old poof."
Why are you here?
Let's get this straight.
What do you want from me?
You wanted me to model.
Remember?
What do you think I am,
so fucking senile?
Uh, uh, mr. Whale?
[murmuring quietly]
oh, I'm so stupid.
Stupid, stupid.
Mr. Whale,
you all right?
What was I thinking about?
Oh, would you go?
I'm sorry. Please.
Why don't you just go?
I just don't get it.
First you creep me out
with this homo shit.
Then you hit me
with war stories.
And now you're
upset with me because
I listened to you?
What do you want?
I want...
More than anything else,
I want a glass of water.
Sick.
Thank you.
I do apologize. I'm...
I have no business
snapping at you.
It was foolishness to start
this portrait, you know.
You mean you don't
want me to sit
for you anymore?
Would you like to come
to a party with me?
A reception
for princess margaret.
I thought you said
you weren't gonna go.
If you don't mind driving...
I'd like to take
you as my guest.
Yeah, sure,
I'm game. Why not?
Very good, clayton.
May I call you clayton?
Clayton?
Yeah, sure.
Clayton's fine.
Mr. Boone, he's
an interesting friend.
I'd hardly call
our yardman a friend.
Oh, no, but someone
you can talk to.
That needs
pressing, hmm?
Do you miss having someone
to talk to, hanna?
I have my family.
Also our lord,
jesus christ.
Tell me, how is
the old boy these days?
We need a hat with that.
There's a panama.
Oh, maybe in your old room.
No, no,
in the storage closet.
[sighs]
[ringing continues]
Hello.
Oh, eva.
[speaking
scandinavian language]
[soldiers shouting]
[gunfire, explosions]
Whale: Gas masks on!
[shouting continues]
[gunfire, explosions
continue]
Oh, mr. Jimmy.
She said she and her
husband are coming to
town this afternoon.
Here. I'm sorry,
mr. Jimmy.
I will make it short.
I will be out
myself this afternoon.
Remember?
I suppose you'd
like the top down.
If that's all
right with you.
Nothing would
please me more.
[engine starts]
[speaks
scandinavian language]
Whale:
Oh, good old george.
He loves
to put on the dog.
Slim pickings.
Mind you,
it's early yet.
Perhaps this is a good
time for us to go and
pay our respects, hmm?
Thank you.
Thank you for coming.
Charming.
[gasps]
I had no idea
you would be here.
How are you?
Fine.
I'm just fine.
Splendid, now that I
know that you're around.
Can we get together
while I'm in town?
I so badly want
to sit for you again.
Sit?
I've changed my hair,
You see, since
our last session.
Those old snaps look
rather dowdy now.
Oh, dear.
Have I made a blunder?
The pleasure is mine.
James whale.
I am such a goose.
I mistook you
for cecil beaton.
It's the hat.
You're wearing one of
cecil's hats, you know.
George, james whale.
David lewis's friend.
I used to make pictures
myself, ma'am.
Without hitting
one of us old
movie directors.
[both chuckling]
Ma'am, may I introduce
mr. Clayton boone.
My gardener.
How do you do?
Clay--
clay boone.
Quite.
I adore gardens.
[all chuckling]
He's never
met a princess.
Only queens.
Well, george, ma'am,
This has been an honor,
And one that
I shall remember
For the rest of my life.
Great place.
Mmm.
[chuckles]
Hello.
What was that all about?
Oh, don't worry.
Just two old men
slapping each other
with lilies.
I'm sorry.
[woman laughs]
Who's that?
The friend I thought
was in new york.
No, the girl.
Oh, it's
elizabeth taylor.
Oh, thank you.
Yes, david produced
her last picture.
What are you doing here?
I was just going
to ask you the same thing.
Thought you were
still in new york.
I was, until last night.
I was going to call.
David lewis.
Our yardman, who's been kind
enough to serve as my escort
To george's little do.
Should you be drinking
in your condition?
Oh, david, will you
stop being a nanny.
I think I'm gonna go
and get another beer.
You should've seen george's
face when he saw clayton.
Oh! [giggles]
You didn't, jimmy.
Mind you, princess margaret's
an absolute doll.
Well, we're all equals
in her eyes...
As commoners, I presume.
You only
embarrass yourself.
I'll never work
in this town again.
You know what I mean.
Your reputation.
I have no reputation.
I am as free as the air.
But the rest
of us aren't.
Can't you
remember that?
No.
I never could.
I suppose you regret
having got me invited here.
I didn't ask george
to invite you.
Oh. Well, then, who did?
I have people here
I need to speak to.
You'll be all right
on your own?
Yes, yes, perfectly.
I'll drop by tomorrow
for breakfast.
Oh, yes.
Oh.
Oh, I say.
Thank you very much.
Just the one. Hmm.
[sighs]
Mr. Whale!
[high-pitched giggle]
Mr. Whale.
Bet you never thought
you'd see me again.
I didn't know
if you'd be well enough
to come to this party.
I'm the one who got you
on mr. Cukor's guest list.
You, mr. Kay?
But how do you know
george cukor?
I interviewed him
after I met you.
I'm his social secretary now.
Well, assistant
to his secretary.
Yes, I commend you. Yes.
If you're going
to pursue poofs,
Go after those who
can do favors for you.
You just waste
everyone's time when
you court dinosaurs.
Don't think
like that, mr. Whale.
I love your movies.
That's why I wanted
you to come,
So I could see you
with your monsters.
My monsters?
Don't go away.
[giggles]
Uh, excuse me.
Miss lanchester.
Yes?
[whispers]
Elsa.
Jimmy!
How are you?
Mmm.
[giggles]
I saw una o'connor
a few weeks ago.
She said you'd been
under the weather.
Oh, well, nothing
out of the ordinary.
Getting old.
Ah, what's our
pesky friend up to now?
Mmm?
Is that boris?
Our little chum appears
to be arranging a reunion.
Oh, dear.
Boris, darling.
Elsa. Elsa!
And james.
James.
How good to see you.
I didn't know you were here.
These public revels
are hardly up your alley.
Actually, I'm here
for the sake of miranda,
My great-grandniece.
Koochie-koo.
And what do you make
of our royal visitant?
Perfectly charming.
What did you expect,
a hussy in tennis shoes?
[laughs]
Hey, you,
with the camera.
We got a historical
moment here.
Come, get
a picture of it.
This is
mr. James whale,
Who made
"frankenstein"
And "bride
of frankenstein,"
And this--forget
the baby a second--
Is...The monster...
And his bride.
Oh, karloff. Right.
Don't you just love
being famous?
To a new world
of gods and monsters.
[gunfire,
explosions continue]
[screaming]
Are you all right,
jimmy?
Yeah. Yeah.
Got it.
Clay: Mr. Whale.
Are you ok?
I'm tired.
I'm a bit tired.
Are you enjoying yourself?
Actually,
I feel a little
out of place here.
Well, neither of us
really fits in here.
That must've been
funny for you, seeing
your monsters again.
Monsters?
The only monsters are here.
[thunder crashes]
[guests chattering,
screaming]
Oh, fuck.
We left the top down.
You wanna run for it?
"run for it"?
It's raining.
Woman: Hurry! Hurry!
Whoo!
[hooting, laughing]
Mr. Whale?
Mr. Whale.
Let's get out
of this fuckhole.
You sure you don't want
to wait it out?
We aren't made of sugar.
We won't melt.
"oh, that this too, too
solid flesh would melt."
I'm getting you home
before you catch your
death of pneumonia.
Catch my death?
Are you ok, mr. Whale?
Jimmy, please, hmm?
Call me jimmy.
[engine starts, revs]
[thunder continues]
Hanna, we need some towels!
We're soaked to the bone!
Well, if we soil your floors,
it's your own bloody fault!
Oh, I don't believe it.
Oh, don't worry.
She'll be back.
She just can't say "no"
to her daughter.
Well, you certainly
have better things to do
Than to baby-sit an old man.
I didn't have
anything planned.
Well, you go and get
a shower upstairs
And I'll get you
something dry to wear.
[thunder continues]
Well, what do you think?
Hmm?
Mr. Whale?
Where are those
clothes you promised?
Mr. Whale?
He trusts me, you know.
Jimmy?
Oh, yes.
Mr. Whale?
Huh?
Yes, of course,
uh, clayton.
Now, I promised to get
you some dry clothes.
The trouble is,
you're so large.
You wouldn't want to attempt
to get into my pants.
Uh, n-no.
Definitely not.
Very good, clayton.
Now...
Oh, I know!
This--this absolutely
swims on me,
So that should deal
with your upper half.
And now we just need to deal
with the rest, don't we?
Do you have any baggy shorts
or pajama bottoms?
Uh, no.
I'm sorry.
Uh, my pajamas
are all tailored.
Would it be too
distressing for you
It's hardly more
immodest than a kilt,
you know.
How very sporting
of you, clayton.
Say, is this, um...
Yes, it's the only
memento I ever kept.
My original sketch
for the monster.
Uh, shall we?
Yeah.
[thunder continues]
If hanna's not back, shall
we try a few more sketches?
I thought you'd given up
on my drawing.
Yeah, but I'd
like to try again.
It'll give us something
to do while we wait.
Tell me something, clayton.
Do you believe
in mercy killing?
I never really
gave it much thought.
You must've come across
such situations in korea.
A wounded comrade,
or perhaps even an enemy.
You know, someone for whom
death would be a blessing.
I never went to korea.
I never even made it
through boot camp.
That I was a marine,
which is true.
You filled in the rest.
Oh, I see.
My old man was a marine.
Lied about his age,
and he enlisted.
Is this the great war?
Yeah. Yeah.
By the time he was
ready to ship out,
So, he felt like
he'd missed out.
Well, it was
a very lucky thing he did.
That's not
the way he saw it.
To him it was
like his life never
really got started.
Nothing else
seemed to matter.
Certainly
not his family.
Is that why you became a marine,
for your father's sake?
I figured it'd be
the next best thing.
I mean, but, you know,
I loved it, too.
It was a chance
to be a part of
something important,
Something that's bigger
than yourself.
So, what happened?
Didn't have
the guts for it.
Hmm?
Literally.
My appendix burst.
They gave me
a medical discharge.
And the only thing
I can think is,
How the hell am I gonna
tell my father?
And you know what
happened when I finally
did tell him?
He laughed at me.
Well, them's
the breaks, huh?
No war stories
for this pup.
That's where
you're wrong, clayton.
You just told me one.
A very good story indeed.
[thunder continues]
Whew. This storm
is getting worse.
"a perfect night
for mystery and horror.
The air itself is
filled with monsters."
That's from one
of your movies, right?
Very good.
"the only monsters
are here."
Don't remember that one.
This afternoon at the
party when you said,
"the only monsters
are here,"
I was wondering
which "here" that was.
No, I--I don't recall.
Memories
of the war, perhaps.
Barnett.
Barnett on the wire.
Your friend.
He caught his one night coming
back from reconnaissance.
I wouldn't take him,
but mcgill did,
"just to give
the laddie a taste."
They were nearly home when
a maxim gun opened fire.
Barnet's body
landed on this wire
That was as thick as briers.
It was hanging there
the next morning.
It was only a hundred yards
from the line, but too far...
For anyone to fetch it.
So we saw him
every morning stand-to
"good morning, barnett,"
we used to say to him.
"how's old barnett
looking today? "
"he seemed a little peaked.
Looks a little plumper."
And if he hung there...
[exhales]
Well, at least until
we were relieved.
We introduced him to the new
unit before marching out,
Speaking highly
of his companionship.
God, we were a witty lot.
Laughing at our dead, feeling
that it was our death, too.
But I tell you, for each
man who died I thought,
"better you than me,
poor sod."
You know, a whole generation
was wiped out by that war.
[thunder continues]
You survived it.
Can't hurt you now.
No good to dig it up.
Oh.
Friend, it's digging
itself up.
There is nothing in the here
and now to take my mind off it.
The parties...
Well, you were there.
Reading...I can't--
I-I can't concentrate.
There's no work, of course,
And, uh, love and,
uh, painting and, uh...
Drawing, I mean.
Look.
Your portrait, clayton.
It's all gone for me now.
All gone.
They're nothing but the
scribblings of an infant.
There's nothing.
Nothing.
You said you wanted
to draw me like a statue.
There.
It's going to
happen after all.
What did you say?
No, it won't do.
What won't do?
You're much too human.
Well, what do
you expect, bronze?
Don't move.
[grunting noise]
I want you to wear this.
Just so I can see
the artistic effect.
Your very human body
against the inhuman mask.
Oh! Very striking.
Mmm.
I don't know.
Just for a minute, so
I can see the effects.
From the first world war,
isn't it?
Fasten this
around the back.
Let me help you.
There.
Hmm?
[sniffing, gasping]
Uh...
Now what?
All right,
let's take it off.
Uh, it's too tight.
I can't breathe.
Oh, no, l-l-leave it.
I'll help.
Leave it to me.
Wha-can you--
I'm still here.
Um...
Mr. Whale.
Oh, what steely muscles
you've got there.
Just take the fuckin'
mask off me now, ok?
What a solid brute you are.
Hey, just get your
fuckin' hands off me!
It's no use, clayton.
I can't hear you.
I can't hear a word.
Oh, well, then, maybe this.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
[whale groans]
Ohh!
How will you ever
get yourself back?
I told you,
I'm not that way!
Get it through your
fuckin' head, all right?
You feel
so good, clayton.
Uhh!
Didn't even sting!
[grunting, laughing]
Wait till I tell
my friends about this.
Won't they be surprised.
I haven't done
anything with you
[gasps] you
undressed for me.
I've been kissing you.
How will you ever be able
to live with yourself?
What do you want from me?
[laughing hysterically]
I want you to kill me.
What?
Break my neck.
It'll be
so easy to choke
the life out of me.
Come on, clayton.
We've come this far.
I'm losing my mind.
Every day a new piece
of it goes,
And soon there'll
be none of it left.
But if you kill me,
death will be bearable.
You could be
my second monster.
Come on.
Please, do it now.
Make me invisible.
[panting, groaning]
I am not...
Your monster!
[sobbing]
[grunts]
[sobbing continues]
You're a bloody pussycat.
My deepest apologies.
Can you ever forgive me?
No, I suppose not.
[exhaling]
I've got to go to bed.
Are you ok?
Oh, clayton.
Do you need some help?
Pray, you
undo this button.
I don't seem to be able
to manage it when I'm tired.
Do you believe
people come into our
lives for a purpose?
Ok, I can manage now.
When you die, make sure
that your brain is the
last organ to fizzle.
You'll feel better tomorrow.
[grunts]
[groaning]
Good night.
[exhaling]
[thunder continues]
[gunfire, bomb whistling]
[explosions,
gunfire continues]
[telephone ringing]
[snorts, gasps]
Hanna: Hello?
Oh, hello, mr. David.
No, he did not tell me,
but that's no problem.
I make the breakfast.
Yes, very good.
Good-bye.
[groans]
Hanna, this is not
what you think it is.
[shoes land on floor]
aah!
All I ask is you
get dressed and go.
Hanna, I need to talk
to you about mr. Whale.
There is nothing you could
say would surprise me.
Maybe, but I still need
to talk to you about him.
[scoffs] I blame
my daughter for keeping
me out so late.
I only hope you did not
get him excited.
You could give him
new stroke.
Why do you do it, hanna?
What I do?
Like he was your
own flesh and blood?
I did it when he was
happy. It was easy.
It's only fair I do it
now he is ill.
Oh, enough of this talk.
I must go wake the master.
Mr. Jimmy, good morning.
Mr. Jimmy?
What have
you done with him?
You look for him.
I put him to bed
last night.
Mr. Jimmy?
Mr. Jimmy!
[grunting]
Crazy son of a bitch!
Oh! No! No! No!
Mr. Jimmy!
Jimmy! Jimmy!
H-he wanted me to kill him,
and then he did it himself!
I didn't do this!
Mr. Jimmy.
It says here,
"good-bye."
I find in his room.
Sorry, he says.
He's had wonderful life.
Oh, my mr. Jimmy.
Poor, foolish man.
[moaning]
You could not wait for god
to take you in his time?
You must leave.
You were not
here this morning.
Look, I did not do this.
Police will
not know that.
They will want
to investigate.
You want them to question
you about mr. Jimmy?
Please, clayton, it's better
that I find the body alone.
How are you gonna explain how
you got him out of the water?
[muttering in
scandinavian language]
You're right.
[sniffles]
Uh, we must put him back.
Wh-uh...
Oh, mr. Jimmy, we do not
mean disrespect.
You will keep better
in water.
[muttering in
scandinavian language]
[violin playing]
[moaning]
[growls]
Who are you?
I think you're
a stranger to me.
I cannot see you.
I cannot see anything.
You must please excuse me,
but I'm blind.
Blind man:
Perhaps you're afflicted, too.
We shall be friends.
It's very lonely here,
And it's been
a long time since
Any human being
came into this hut.
I shall look after you,
and you will comfort me.
[monster grunting]
[blind man laughing]
[monster growling]
No, no.
This is good.
Smoke. You try.
Smoke.
[blind man laughs]
[grunting happily]
Good! Good!
[grunting, chuckling]
I was all alone.
It is bad to be alone.
Alone bad.
Friend good.
Friend good!
[blind man laughs]
[orchestra finale]
Time for bed, sport.
What did you think
of the movie?
Pretty cool.
Better than most
monster movies.
Yeah? I knew
the guy who made it.
Is this another one
of your stories?
No.
It's the original sketch
of the monster.
Is this for real?
Clay, the trash,
before it rains.
Come on.
[grunts]
[thunder rumbling]
Captioning made possible by
lions gate entertainment