A film by Carlo Lizzani
The Gold of Rome
Excuse me.
- Are you the president?
- Yes.
Major Kappler of the SS awaits you at
the German headquarters immediately
to issue you regulations for
Israelites residing in Rome.
- But.. right away?
- Yes, immediately.
Could you not tell me...
We have orders only
to accompany you.
Let's go.
Come.
President, I'll accompany you.
Thank you. Perhaps it's better
that there's two of us.
Giovanni! Giovanni!
- Be careful, don't scare Tilde.
- Dad, Dad, where are you going?
We'll be back soon, you'll see.
Is Giulia there, please?
Yes, she's here. I'll call
her right away. Giulia?
Hello?
Yes, Dad, calm down.
Yes, dear, I'm calm, but
just seeing them,
and knowing they're dealing with us.
Come soon, we must be
together, we must decide.
Yes, Dad, yes.
- I have to go.
- I'll come with you.
Yes, but let's not tell anyone,
it bothers me.
Keep us informed, dear.
I didn't know you were Jewish.
Now you know.
- Goodbye.
Well, both of you come to my place.
- Both of us at your house? - Yes.
- But your parents don't even know us.
No, Massimo, you're very kind...
My parents are good people,
they'd be happy to help you, I'm sure.
It's a heartfelt offer,
and we'll keep it in mind.
You've moved me, young man.
- Giulia.
- You too think that we're in danger?
Well, certainly, with the Germans...
How many members of the
Jewish community are in Rome?
Thank you.
There were the persecutions,
many have left.
It's difficult to say.
I understand, I understand Italian!
Are the Jews in Rome in good health?
Misery and disease is rife.
It's difficult to find or buy medicine.
It's the war.
But it's more or less the same
for the others in Rome.
Is it true that the Jews are the
most ancient citizens of Rome?
And they don't pass under
the Arch of Titus because
their vanquished ancestors
were brought there?
Indeed, it's so. It's a most ancient
tradition that is still handed down.
Hopefully the new Italian
government will soon be formed
as an ally of the Reich,
so that they'll deal with you.
Today we must deal with you directly.
The Führer wrote wherever there's a
plot against the Reich, there's a Jew.
From Cain to Marx, the history of the
Jew is the history of humanity's shame.
The Third Reich demands at once
from the Jewish community of Rome:
One hundred pounds of gold.
- What do you mean one hundred pounds?
- Fifty kilos.
Yes, fifty kilos. Fifty.
By noon in two days time.
How can we find fifty
kilos of gold in two days?
The day after tomorrow at noon.
It's one or the other!
Either the gold or the heads of
two hundred families as hostages.
Fifty kilos at these times?
It's absurd.
I've been a goldsmith for thirty years.
Everyone has sold their gold.
Calm down! Calm down! Wait!
No way! This time we want
to listen too! Let us in!
We have rights too!
We want to hear!
- You can't enter.
- No, no! Let me in!
We'll all gather in the temple and
if they enter they'll be cursed.
We must not make a pact with them.
Let's pray to the Lord. He'll protect us.
We can't hold them any longer.
They want to come in!
- Let them hear too.
- Let them in.
- Calm down! Calm down!
- Wait at the table!
It's only right that you know too.
Do you understand? They
want fifty kilos of gold.
But fifty kilos of gold would be
about 12,000 rings like this.
And our community is down
to a few thousand members.
Whoever had any wealth is long gone.
It's absurd, we can't do it.
Friends, it's hostages or gold.
It's true that we're just a few,
but we have to find the gold.
There's no alternative. I'm sure
the Germans will keep their word.
Friends, maybe we didn't
explain ourselves well.
If we won't hand over the gold,
we'll have to pick 200 hostages.
Two hundred heads of families
to hand over to the Germans.
Do you want to gamble with
the lives of our children?
If we don't want to yield to blackmail,
we'll have to draw up
a list of 200 hostages.
I... I will be the first.
Right, president.
I agree on this.
But I ask you, do we go to the Germans
or do we wait for them to come here?
I say we wait for them.
Let them come and get the hostages.
They'll need at least one German
for every Jew. Each takes his own.
And mine won't be
returning home, I swear!
When the lamb is in
the jaws of the wolf,
he can only hope that the
beast isn't too hungry.
If we give them the fifty kilos
of gold, we'll lose power.
We'll be even weaker!
The Germans will do as they please
with us. But if we say no: No!
Then it will be heard everywhere!
In Rome, in Italy.
Everyone will know and
everyone will be on our side.
And the Germans will have
to take that into account.
Their days are numbered, now.
Can't you see they've already lost the war?
We need gold to be able to eat.
Shall we chicken out just
when the Americans are coming?
But they won't arrive in time for us.
The Americans, yes.
They saw them. Alberto, tell.
Yes, two days ago, the
raid of via Nazionale.
He was with me but they didn't take him.
They took me to Nettuno to dig trenches.
And some workers who helped us escape,
had seen the American paratroopers.
That same night.
They were preparing the landing.
Everyone's talking about it.
I swear to you.
Friends. For now the Germans
are here and so are we.
We all know about the second front.
The Americans will land.
I both believe that and I hope for it.
But where?
And when?
We've only got a day.
Oh young people, bless them,
they don't know better.
They're always surprised
about everything.
From the Romans until now, how much
gold, how many tears have we shed?
We've always had to pay.
During the reign of the Popes,
the rabbis went to the city leader's
capitol to pay tribute.
He took it and raised his foot like
this. As if to give him a kick.
It was a symbolic gesture
but it was enough.
What guarantees are the
Germans giving us?
For me, our friend Davide is right.
No way can we rely on the Germans.
- Exactly, professor, you're right.
- Calm down, brothers.
I'm telling you that even this
time we will pay our tribute.
And that's all I have.
Wait, Mr. Sermoneta. Davide!
Listen! This is a serious moment.
We all have to be in this together.
United! Together!
Davide, what now?
You heard them. They just
want to hand over the gold.
I certainly can't convince them.
I don't know what to say.
In my opinion, Davide, you said
exactly the right thing, you know.
Because I'm sure we'll not benefit
from this gift. I did what I could.
Listen! Start gathering
up all your gold at home.
We will call all those who
live outside the ghetto.
Tonight we have to warn everyone.
Everyone!
- Piperno, seven grams.
- Seven grams.
- Is this how you respect the curfew?
- I was just closing.
Oh, he's just closing!
Right this minute!
See how good at it these Germans are?
- How much do you have to give?
- 50 kilos. - 50 kilos!
And what's this?
- The Tables of the Law.
- And you wear them around your neck?
- Yes, sir.
50 kilos in Rome, 100 in Milan,
and we here aren't good at anything.
Because we're not organised!
With a hundred kilos of gold
we could rebuild a militia!
It's no use,
the Germans will be Germans.
But you, all this food,
anything that's pork, is forbidden?
- But why, if it's so good?
- Because they're Jewish! Go away.
My aunt wouldn't eat meat on
Fridays even if she was dying.
Even when it could be got hold of.
- But you like pork, no?
- You bet! Whenever I can!
Can you smell it?
It's good, eat some.
Come on, it's an offer from a comrade.
Come on! So you can tell us about the gold.
How much have you collected?
Go on! Eat!
Leave him alone. Maybe he hasn't eaten
since morning and pork makes him sick.
Come here! Sit down and keep us company!
Just a bite, come on! No!
This time you have to accept.
No, I don't ever eat that.
I've already eaten, I'm not hungry.
He's not hungry! Listen to that!
That malnourished face!
He's shy! Come on, try it!
Don't make me lose my patience, come on!
Chew! Tell me if it's good.
Come on!
- Did you see!
- Let's go, Simone.
It's late.
Simone.
Calm down now.
Calm down, come on!
Look, I'll take you home, OK?
Thanks, Davide. I'm going.
- Let's go.
- Thanks, thanks.
- Tomorrow you'll come, right?
- I don't know, dear.
I need to think about it.
Even if we won't be coming to
your house, I'll call you.
Listen, Giulia.
It's my fault, I never dared tell you.
Maybe I shouldn't tell you even now.
But I love you.
For a long time I wanted to tell you.
And I've only found the courage now.
But you don't want to hear this, I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
It's so beautiful what you just said.
I'm almost no longer scared.
Then it's better that I stay with you.
No, you can't.
I too don't want to leave here.
I love hearing your voice.
I could forget about everything, Massimo...
Curfew! Go home!
- Look, we need to split.
- Yeah, will you come then? - Yes.
Bye.
Amalfi Simone, five grams.
Prepare the receipt.
No, what are you doing?
Please, don't. Why?
Mr. Amalfi, you wouldn't want to
give our enemies your memories too?
- Just the gold is enough.
- Ah, you're right.
May I sit here? I want to follow the
collection, watch how it's going.
Take a seat, there's plenty of room.
Perhaps over there. I won't be any trouble.
- Here. - Your name?
- Anselmo Finzi, son of Aldo.
- Name?
- Sonnino.
Give me the stone, please.
It's not worth anything, but
it's the last memory of my husband.
Of course. Take off the stone.
- It's thirty grams.
- We could use it.
If we give them it, it won't be
any use to either one of us.
They'll never make it.
It's our old silver mezuzah.
It's not worth anything
but it's a memory of being a child in
Livorno, it comes from Palestine.
But now it's pointless moaning.
Have we forgotten anything?
- No, Dad.
- Let's go then.
Listen, with this goatee you
look just like a rabbi.
And what should I do then? Cut it?
And then remember that in life
you need to keep a certain dignity.
Well, Davide, are the shoes here or not?
These two have to go all
the way to Tivoli on foot.
Where is all that you
took from the barracks?
What do you think we stole?
Weapons! Only weapons!
- We can't pay you.
- Alberto told you.
Take these. They're spoils of war
but better than going barefoot.
So, where are these weapons?
- You hid them?
- Of course, we need them.
We're Sicilians. Where should we go now?
Sicily is liberated, we're
organising ourselves here.
We have commanders, weapons, everything.
If the Germans dare, you'll see a storm.
But we don't have anything to eat, to
clothe ourselves. Tell him, Alberto.
Yes, I told him already, I told him.
Help me move it.
Then we'll talk about the shoes.
- What you doing? Are you nuts?
- I'll explain later, help me.
In fact, I won't explain anything.
You'll realise later why
I moved the cabinet.
Is your hideout far from Tivoli?
Amerigo, would you like to take a
nice bike ride up to Tivoli this evening?
- And you?
- Well, yeah. - We could get up to there.
- Twenty pairs of shoes?
- Just about.
Perhaps we could come to a deal.
Goods for goods.
- But, by any chance, you want..
- We're worse off than you.
Didn't you get that?
The men are all my sons.
The women, my daughters-in-law.
And the kids, my grandchildren. This is
all of us. And this is my brother.
A hundred lira per person per day.
To eat and to sleep.
Up there the air is good,
and then there's the journey.
- And how much for the journey?
- 100 each.
- But not for the kids.
- A hundred lire each.
- Vincenzo, what do you say?
- There are 21 of us, Mum.
We'd need the Bank of Italy.
- Perhaps the men then?
- Yes, you go.
No, no! Either all or none.
- 100 is too much. Less.
- But I'm risking my skin!
I'll just find
someone else who'll pay.
Tell me, not even if we pay with gold?
Sure, gold is better than cash.
But the sum is still the same.
It's no use making that face.
I'd told you so. Hiding is impossible.
The little gold we have isn't enough
to get our personal safety,
but it's useful if it's put in the heap.
We needn't be discouraged.
It's just noon. We still have 24 hours.
The collection isn't going badly.
Many members of the community
have some gold. We can do it.
I've no more gold. We need to
pawn something to bring in money.
The bed. I'll pawn the bed!
I say there's no way out.
We'll have to do as the others do.
If only it were useful!
But then everyone must give their gold,
got it? Everyone! - Yes, Mum.
Understood? Come on then, let's go.
- Come here a minute! - But I've
only got this and I want to keep it.
You and that Davide!
Don't try and be smart.
I've got eyes for everything.
- Mom! - Remember that! And ears!
Believe me, I did everything
I could to alert the Red Cross
but every communication with
Geneva was interrupted.
You see them?
Even here.
They arrived an hour ago and
are now in command of Rome.
One moment.
- It's all that I can do.
- Thank you.
Governorate of Rome
You, where are you going?
Is anyone there?
The mayor, the governor?
No, no, there's no one.
General Command
Wehrmacht Command Zone A
K-Factory
Workshop Group
Mr. President.
Sermoneta.
- Tell me, what is it?
- I've reflected on the situation.
If you insist on gathering the gold,
there might be a use for it.
To hide the people.
In the countryside, with the peasants.
Or in town.
Are you not aware of the situation
in which we find ourselves?
I went around the city in search
of the Italian authorities
but they've all vanished. Rome is
paralysed by uncertainty and fear.
Public offices and streets are deserted.
At home the talk is all about
the landing of the Allies.
But meanwhile the Germans
have everything under control.
You're expecting a miracle.
We are the authorities.
For my part, I know what I must do.
You have faith in the
Germans but not in us.
We are men, no? We can organise
ourselves, defend ourselves.
We have over 5000 years
worth of history behind us.
And we've had to endure
too many persecutions.
For more than 5,000 years we've fought,
and remained ourselves.
Is this not strength?
But they have the power
of the machine guns.
And I tell you one thing:
your prudence is madness!
- What are you doing here?
- Davide, listen, I'm doing it for you.
For you men. Everyone's giving
their gold, don't you see?
Come here, let me see.
What have you brought?
A watch, Davide.
It's all we had.
Even you don't understand.
But come on, I'm your son.
- Don't you recognise me? Davide.
- Yes.
And don't you think that I might
be right at times? Answer me!
But I don't know anything. Don't ask me
questions. I'm doing what the others do.
It's fear that stops you thinking.
You're like the others.
At home, I'm in charge.
This may well be of some use to me.
Davide!
I never had to use this, fortunately.
- Is there any bullets?
- What can you give me?
- Excuse me, but we always
keep them closed. - Don't worry.
- Dad, sit down, you'll be tired.
- But, are you staying?
- Shall I help with that?
- No, thanks. So, what do you think?
I waited all morning
by the phone.
It's not much but we'll try to settle it
as best we can. It's the only room.
- Now I'll call my mother.
- Thank her!
- And so? - The Jews are being persecuted.
You don't get that, do you?
And the girl is also my university mate.
She can't sit the exams because she's a Jew,
but she's smarter than many others.
Is she the one who always calls you?
Lots of people call me.
It's not forbidden, I hope.
And then...
I'm in love with her.
It's true, I'm serious.
She's the smartest girl I've ever known.
And if it were possible, I'd marry
her tomorrow, if she'd let me...
Enough! Enough! It's all clear now.
To begin with you brought her here.
- Come on, Mum!
Listen to me, try to understand.
I also have something
to say on this matter.
But without hysterics, for goodness' sake.
It's a serious matter and so we should
talk seriously as we do in this house.
Giulia and I won't have coffee.
Excuse us, we're going to terrace.
Excuse me.
Forgive me, Mr. Ortona,
but of course, between parents, it shouldn't
be difficult to talk about these things.
- You... - Thanks.
- .. with your beliefs..
yes, well,
with a religion different than ours...
- No, that's fine.
- What do you think about..
the marriage of your daughter?
The marriage?
But what's all this about?
Unless Giulia...
I didn't know that Giulia...
The Germans will persecute you too
if you have a Jewish wife.
It would be worse for both of us.
All the young people of
my age have already fled.
For now, we medical students
are using the hospitals,
but soon I'll have to hide too.
Then I am right, I'd be a burden
for you. It would be absurd.
Giulia, you have not yet
told me that you love me.
It's not absurd to want to be happy.
And if this happiness were to end, Massimo?
Everything in the world ends. It's
just important that it happened.
Smile at me, Giulia.
Smile at me.
Go on, move.
- Go and collect the receipt.
Madam, take a seat. Have patience.
Next please.
- What's this?
- Don't worry, they're clean.
It's not because of that
but what will you do now?
For everything you can find to
eat nowadays, I don't need them.
- You're right. Next. - Thank you.
- Go ahead for the receipt.
It's a salt shaker.
It's gold, right?
Certainly.
But you're Mrs. Di Veroli?
- I sold it to you, don't you remember?
- Oh, sorry, I didn't recognize you.
A very long time ago now, Mr. Piperno.
- Madam... - Never mind,
I'll send her the receipt. Next please.
Just think, they were among
the richest in the community.
Weigh it, go on.
Terracina Angelo.
Mrs. Di Veroli, fifty-four grams.
Terracina Angelo, fifteen grams.
Let's go, quickly please. Name?
Your name, madam?
- Anonymous. - But for the receipt?
- Don't bother.
- No receipt.
- Very well, madam.
- I'll write 'a Christian' then.
- As you wish.
No, no, you may beat it.
Rather than let it
in the hands of the Germans.
If you agree, we can do a first check.
I think we can,
there's already a few kilos.
Come in.
May I?
Amalfi... Amalfi Simone.
I had a bakery.
Perhaps you gentlemen remember it.
Then the government stripped me of
my licence and so I had to close it.
- Sure, I remember it well.
- I tried to keep count.
There's no more than seven kilos.
It's already six. Tonight by the curfew,
we'll need to stop collecting.
There's not much time left,
we won't make it, trust me.
There's a lot of people, but not enough.
- We would need many more.
- Yes, it's true, but you know...
Sadly that's how it is.
We need to face reality.
You were right to come to me.
But I ask you not to go around
saying these things.
I won't say anything to anyone.
Indeed, excuse me, excuse me.
Look, stay here, don't go over there.
I've got the impression
that this poor chap...
We're in trouble if
he spreads this despair.
That poor chap scares me.
We need to do something soon,
that man is right.
From now on check the weight hour by hour.
Start weighing the gold right away.
Look. We would need
one of these for her too.
Massimo De Santis,
born 18th of March 1926.
- But you were born in 1922.
- Don't you get it? It's a fake ID.
The town hall of Ceprano was bombed.
They can never prove that it's fake.
And now we'll talk about the marriage.
It's feasible.
At this time there is also
a special dispensation,
conversion to Catholicism wouldn't be
necessary, but I had a very delicate task.
- From my mother? - Exactly. Your mother
wants a Catholic daughter-in-law.
A fair request. I repeat, it's not the
church who demands it but your family.
It's prejudice, I understand, but it
exists and has to be taken into account.
I thought this concerned only us. I
didn't think I had racists in my family.
You can't say that. It's difficult
to fight against old ideas.
I understand you very well,
but I have my responsibilities.
And then I'm not the only priest in Rome.
Thank you, you've done all you could.
Massimo, you'll create a rift
with your mother if you carry on so.
Forgive me, Miss, but I
wanted you to be aware too.
You did the right thing;
it's better to know everything.
A rift? It will be her who
will have asked for it.
- And now? - Nothing,
it's exactly the same for us.
Everyone, everyone against us,
ready to strike us.
But why? What have we done?
It's my fault, I've caused only
trouble for you. For your father too.
We need to warn him. In fact, Giulia,
tonight you'll stay with close friends,
and tomorrow I'll find
a priest who's not my relative.
I want do things properly, understand?
You're willing to disobey your parents?
It's a lesson for them,
so they'll understand.
It's our future, we can't give in!
Massimo...
Now, Giulia, listen to me carefully.
You need to trust me.
Don't be scared.
No one can ever separate us.
You don't even ask me if I agree.
Since yesterday you do everything alone.
And what am I to do?
I love you.
Here we go: Vittorio, Alberto,
Gianni, Mario, Samuele, Angelo,
Settimio, Abramo, Pierpaolo.
Here we go: eight male children.
Four kilos and two hundred grams.
- Twelve kilos and a few grams.
- Are you sure?
Twelve kilos.
I really thought there was more.
That guy was right.
We won't make it if it goes on like this.
- How is it going?
- Forget it.
- Did you weigh it?
- How much?
I don't know, I don't know. What do you
want me to say? I'm only the doorman.
- Why won't you tell us? - I don't know
anything! It's no use insisting!
- Here's your receipt, ma'am.
- Thank you, thank you.
Did you weigh it, at least?
Can't you tell us how much is there?
I told you, I don't know anything.
What should I tell you?
- What's happened?
- Nothing, madam, it's nothing.
- They don't want to tell us.
- But why don't they?
So we won't make it?
Relax, madam. Stay calm, everyone.
It's insane. It's insane to
place our hopes in gold.
Only the Lord will be able to warm
the hearts of our persecutors.
Gold.. Gold!
The Germans have thrust this false
idol upon us and we adore it.
Since yesterday we pray for
gold and not to the Lord.
Reconcile yourself with Him instead!
For millenniums, He never abandoned us.
But what do you think?
That I haven't been praying?
I've spent entire days just talking to Him.
But it doesn't help!
It's not true that our God helps us!
He's abandoned us. And my children?
Are they bound to die?
You want them to be taken as hostages?
The gold won't be enough.
It won't be enough.
I suggest that it's returned to the owners.
No one wants to pray anymore.
You've all forgotten our faith,
so everything is lost,
our people are lost!
Will you shut up, rabbi?
Mum, take me away.
Calm down, calm down, brothers, friends.
Listen! - Quiet!
- Stay calm.
We've got to stay calm.
- Here we are.
- Very well.
- Evening, Mr. Amalfi.
- Good evening.
- What's happened?
- We can't make it. We can't make it.
- Who's that crackpot?
- No, it's a priest.
It's a Jew, yes, a Jew,
inform the Italian police.
This is the ghetto.
Here, there and also over here
are the small groups of Jews,
but the action must be
concentrated here.
In the ghetto there are
around two thousand Jews.
The ghetto is easily dealt with.
There are four access points.
Here a single troop is enough.
Here we only need thirty men.
Again, thirty men are
more than enough here.
According to the phone reports,
they will not get the gold,
and we are inoperative.
Read me the plan.
For capture and transport,
three thousand men are set aside.
Five platoons in battle formation,
seven tons worth of trucks,
forty of them subject to change,
twelve carriages at a minimum.
Means of disinfection: ninety kilos
of creolin. A medic.
Competent controls at the carriages.
Three platoons with an officer.
A field kitchen. Supplies to military
regulations. Full field equipment.
Plus some vegetarian food
for the deportees.
- So do we have all that?
- Two weeks ago we made a request to
Field Marshal Kesselring's command,
but without reply.
You can thank the interference of
the consul for these difficulties.
- There's no-one around.
- What should we do. - Follow me.
Would you like to know what's behind
this wall? I'll show you now.
Take this.
Here we go.
Turn the light off.
Go on, enter, don't be scared.
Here we are, we've made it!
Your workshop? And who'd ever suspect it?
Understand, big head?
They'll never catch us in their trap.
Now go away.
Back the same way, so you won't forget.
I'll get our shoes ready. In half an hour
everyone ready for departure. OK?
Ah, it's you.
Now I understand why you don't
even greet when you pass my shop.
You're going.
Tell the truth, Giulia.
Are you ashamed to have gone
to a Jewish school with us?
Me? Why?
No, I'm not ashamed at all.
Do you remember what
they made us recite?
Today slavery, tomorrow freedom.
Here this year,
next year in the land of Israel.
Thousands of years we repeated that.
How naive!
But in these words there's something
that moves me even today.
And you would forget everything?
I remember...
We all had a little crush on you.
You were the sweetest, the most beautiful.
And intelligent too!
We used to always say,
"Look how they are, these Jewish girls."
- I was really pretty?
- Yes, very beautiful.
I would've kissed
the ground beneath your feet.
But now it's different.
Are you going?
You chose the perfect moment,
that can't be denied.
But of course, being Jewish
is not easy at this time.
Better get yourself a Catholic fiancé,
a husband, and blend in with the others.
Davide, you're offending me.
Don't you realise that?
And I thought you were so different.
One can be so wrong at times!
But in the end...
you're really beautiful.
That's something.
- Are you crazy?
- Why, because I'm a Jew?
You're nothing but a pretty face.
A shame, you deserved better.
Bye, Giulia. And good luck.
Go away!
Get on your bikes!
Come on, pedal!
Giulia!
Hi, Giulia.
Any news?
- Did Massimo call you? - Yes, yes.
For that reason I rushed here.
You should have hinted something at least.
Sure, it's more difficult with your
father, but I hoped that you'd trust me.
And then arguing with his parents
isn't the best start.
I understand with such a mother in law..
But going away like this, by yourselves..
You've really made up your minds?
Yes, I think so.
I always admired Massimo.
And now I love him.
Next to him I feel different.
I'm no longer scared.
Our poor people!
Come on, let's go, go.
Why did you do this, my brother? Why?
This way, this way!
You see, my beloved Fiorenzo..
Such nonsense shouldn't be done.
- No.
- Be strong! Pass me a seat.
Otherwise, what do we do?
What do we do?
Yet some times...
Bah!
You've got other stuff to think about.
Massimo, it's you now
who is responsible.
I'm staying at home,
I've already told Giulia.
There's no need to say goodbye,
as we'll see each other tomorrow.
Listen, come here.
- I don't have anything else.
- And you, Dad? - I?
But this was your mother's, yours
by right. I've got my pension, heck!
Dad, I'm coming with you.
What are you saying? Massimo!
What sort of fiancé are you?
Make her see reason.
Go, go, tomorrow you'll marry
and give me great joy.
Giulia, your Dad wants you
to come along with me.
Yes.
Absolutely, absolutely.
What can they do to us old folks?
You youngsters need to hide yourselves.
Dad, what if I stay here tonight?
Poor Rosa.
Did you see, Giulia? Did you see?
He was scared that
we wouldn't get all the gold.
He was such a good man!
Here, take it.
It's the last that we have.
But, wait...
you hadn't already given it?
Did you see? They haven't given their
gold. They've still got it at home.
Why are we here? There's no more time.
What are we waiting for?
They have to give it.
They have to!
Calm down, Giulia!
Come on, stop!
- Giulia, Giulia, don't cry!
- Massimo! Massimo...
- What do you want?
- We want to speak with Mr. Giovanni.
Mr. Giovanni, they want to speak
with you no matter what.
No, no. I don't want to see anyone.
The gold that you took, where is it?
Smash down the door!
No, you can't!
Are you all crazy?!
Mr. Giovanni!
- Stop! Stop! Let go of me!
- Here mom, get it! - This is assault!
What do you want with me? Let me go!
You'll regret this!
Help! Help!
- Did you find it?
- Yes, it must be in here.
Don't you realise that even if you give
them the gold, you won't be saved?
- Listen, listen, I've got an idea.
- Let him speak!
How many of us are there?
Five, six families?
Good, leave it all to me.
I'll hide you.
I have many friends,
leave everything to me.
Enough! Damn scum!
Far away from here
no one will recognise you.
Don't give the gold to them!
Don't give it to them!
It won't save you! It's futile!
It's futile!
Who knows what he's looking for up there.
He wants to take a photo of you.
Can't you see?
Imagine if he landed here near us.
Climb in and away.
Where would you go?
Well, maybe to Palestine.
There at least everyone is like us.
And then?
Do you really believe it's better there
than here? With the Arabs, the British?
They aren't like the Germans, sure.
But for us it's the same everywhere.
But why do they have it in for us?
I never understood it.
Because it's convenient.
Wars, shortages,
the government is never at fault.
The blame is always on the Jews.
Just write it in the papers,
and everyone believes it.
But after all this bloodshed, let's hope
there's a better future for my son.
Otherwise it is better to become Buddhists,
and do away with all of this.
Quiet!
- What have you heard?
- It's not yet midnight.
Surely they can't be here already.
After the war things will change.
Palestine?
That's a great idea.
But I am from Rome, Italian,
why should I go over there?
Who did I ever bother here?
A bit of respect would suffice.
- That they let us be.
- Yeah, you hope!
Even after it'll still be as it always was.
No, it won't be like that.
Things are changing.
- Provided that...
- Provided that?
Even a dog rebels
when being mistreated.
But we never do, never!
No one has the courage to open their
mouths. All we know is to accept it.
But things have to change.
It must change!
Here they are!
- How does it work?
- You stick the magazine here.
Then draw it back.
Try it out.
- Have you given everyone weapons?
- Yes, everyone.
What are you doing? You crazy?
There's loads of Germans here.
- Yeah, you're right. But, you see..
It's magnificent!
It's amazing!
This morning early.
Yes, certainly.
As much as possible.
We have to deliver it at midday.
We're way behind.
I implore you.
Thank you, thank you.
- So, what shall we do?
- We'll do like the others: let's give it.
I don't care, we're discriminated.
It really doesn't concern us.
- I'm so scared.
- We need to leave right now.
- Yes, I'll let the others know.
- And you call me at this time?
But I don't have anything else.
Gold? And where should I find it?
- It's extortion.
- Is there any hope?
- But it's impossible.
- Hostages?
- No.
- Yes.
- I don't have anything else.
- OK, we'll try.
His Excellency?
Yes, His Excellency.
Yes, wake him up.
It's a vital matter.
OK, understood, I'll go right away.
Hello?
Yes, as soon as the curfew is over.
Yes, I'll come at seven.
That's fine.
Will you go to him?
Yes, we have to try everything.
I'm beginning to despair.
How... how would they select the hostages?
Yes, Marshall.
It is common knowledge that the Jews
will not have enough gold.
Unfortunately, my commando is not in a
position to carry out the deportation.
Yes, please give your assistance.
I want my gold back, understand?
My gold.
Three kilos worth
and I want them back right away.
Right away, otherwise
I'll denounce you to the Germans.
They broke down my door.
They wanted to lynch me!
But I'll have them thrown in jail!
- And that other son of a...
- Calm down. Don't shout.
We didn't know anything about it.
Why don't you sit down?
Here's my gold. They robbed me.
They robbed me. A burglary!
Three kilos! Three kilos!
Let's not joke!
I want everything back. Everything!
Maybe things are the way you say,
but I have a proposal.
This gold, all or part of it,
we can buy it.
Sir, you see,
we're hardly getting to 50 kilos.
We've 5 hours to noon. If now you
take away three, it will be a disaster.
Three kilos is massive for us.
And what will you give me in payment?
Sterling? Dollars?
- What are you saying? Now?
- It's toilet paper, no?
You'll give me toilet paper.
I want the gold. The gold is mine.
I earnt it!
I earnt it with the sweat of my brow.
And I want it back. I want it all.
Every single last gram!
- Stop, stop, stop it!
- It's all mine!
I'll have the gold returned to you,
but stop with this scene.
His Excellency awaits you.
Yes, OK, very well.
It's many years, cousin.
I trust you haven't come to burden me
with the trouble in your community.
It was also yours, before you disowned
the name of your father, cousin.
I've 7 million in this case.
Collected yesterday lira by lira.
We need 7 kilos of gold, and your bank...
My bank only gets involved in good deals.
That's it.
We need the gold within four hours.
Sit down.
- You don't want anything?
A coffee? A cigarette? - No.
What you're asking is absurd.
It's risky. Forbidden by law.
And I don't regularly do business
with the German command.
Otherwise this could merely
be a reallocation of funds.
I consider it a loss-making deal.
No, I don't see any possibility.
I've betrayed you, eh?
It's you who ostracised me,
because I wanted to be like the others.
And rise above your futile pride.
For what I was worth.
And I'm worth a lot, if you deigned
to turn to me at such a time.
I'm also flesh and blood like you.
It's only that they want to persecute me.
They want to, understand me well, not I.
Because I'm Jewish.
Good or evil, to them doesn't matter,
I'm Jewish and that's enough.
And it's true that I'm Jewish.
But you too are.
You wanted to forget it.
You thought you had succeeded.
But now here I am.
I'm here, on mandate of our persecutors,
to remind you of that.
I believe we've said everything.
I don't deal in Italian money,
nor in blackmail.
Are we understood?
No gold, I'm sorry.
Ludovico.
I was thinking:
You have changed little
over the last forty years.
You were an eager Zionist.
Do you still believe in the unwavering
destiny of the Jewish nation?
- Good morning.
- May I sit?
- Please.
Perhaps two blows of the hammer...
The heel is coming away.
Can it be repaired?
Let me see.
If you're happy with a home-made heel,
I can fix it right away.
- I was wondering. How old are you?
- Twenty-five, why?
At your age, I wanted to travel
around the world, incredibly so.
For the cause of Zion.
I had already organised it.
Then the war came, the other one.
Tell me frankly:
what would you do in my position?
You already know what
I think about the gold.
I haven't changed my mind.
But now I'm not the only one who thinks so.
My friends are now as decided
as me about defending ourselves.
And we won't be going to
the concentration camp.
For every Jew, a German.
That's the price to pay.
Let them come and get us.
Ask them about it.
Let them try!
You're proposing to me the destruction
of the ghetto? A massacre?
Now the world is against the Germans.
Everyone will be with us.
As long as we are ready to fight.
Here, it's ready.
I'm not just the president
for the young people.
In the ghetto there are also children,
women.
Well? What do you propose?
If they grant us an extension,
we'll make it. I'm convinced.
And after?
They will keep their word.
There's nothing else to do.
Listen.
Yeah, yeah, you're right.
They'll keep their word.
They've sworn to exterminate us,
and this is the word they'll keep!
Believe me, we're convinced that
we can meet your request,
if we could only get three or
four more hours, until six.
- OK.
- Still nothing from Kesserling?
No, Major, the trucks aren't there yet.
The wagons are still occupied.
So we shall grant them the extension.
In the meantime,
go and press for an answer.
Even with the delay, it might not succeed.
Stay alert.
We must convey this situation.
I will personally write to a
Field Marshall, you only need to go.
Yes, Major.
Grant them until... six.
An extension of six hours has
been granted, until six.
- OK.
- Good, it's the final deadline.
Final deadline.
Yes!
Thank you.
I'm not Jewish.
And besides I only have one of them.
Look.
However, if you'll accept it.
- Dear lady, everything helps.
- Thank goodness. - Thank you.
I'm the secretary of His Excellency.
Yes, I imagine so.
Right away, that's fine.
Please, those who have already
given their gold, leave.
Wait a sec,
I want to see what happens.
So, those who have yet to give,
go on this side.
The secretary of His Excellency is here.
He's brought gold!
There's seven kilos exactly.
Tell His Excellency that we thank him.
- Very well.
The payment when the president comes.
- Very well, I'll wait.
There must be about 47 kilos.
Forgive me, Monsignor, if I insisted
on speaking so hurriedly.
I must make an urgent request.
Maybe you've already understood
what it concerns.
Speak, speak freely.
Indeed, I hope you'll understand the
precautions I had to take for this meeting.
All of Rome is under surveillance.
Certainly, I understand well
the seriousness of things.
But it's a commitment that's so...
for such a vast amount...
If at least I had the time to consult.
However, you must not lose heart.
Keep going, you still have several hours.
If not, we'll loan you the gold
that may be missing.
- And about the reimbursement?
- When the community is able to.
Thank you,
we're counting on it, Monsignor.
We'll try and make it by ourselves,
but you have reassured me.
- I'd get back to the community now.
- To Lungotevere Cenci.
I already know what will happen later.
Will the Germans be done with us
after this piece of blackmail?
What does the Vatican think?
Do you have any information?
Maybe I shouldn't. I'm sorry.
But our frame of mind in these hours..
- I completely understand.
But who can say what
the Germans have in mind?
Indeed.
Who can say?
- Add the 7 kilos.
- No, it's not possible.
- Let's not get confused, wait a minute.
- Yes, 43 kilos 300.
But if you add the 7 kilos...
50 kilos 300!
- 50 kilos 300!
- We have got 50 kilos 300.
We've made it!
Dad, the president is coming!
- What are they saying? Is it true?
- Your cousin... 7 kilos!
He sold it to us.
He accepted our funds in payment.
It's over.
We've done it.
- Finally I feel like someone else.
- Yes, Giulia.
Now we'll just think of each other, right?
Us two and no one else.
Put the cupboard in place, quick.
It's over! We're saved!
We're all saved!
Our children are safe, get it? Safe!
And woe if you do something wrong.
- We're here. - So, what do you want?
- The collection is over, we did it.
What do you think you solved?
You crazy?
Leave them be now.
It's better it ended like this.
We could've had the Germans at home today!
Vincenzo! Vincenzo!
You've already calmed down, huh?
Close the door.
And now what are you thinking of doing?
You must do something,
they're all deluded.
Everyone thinks that now there's no danger.
- It's late, the Germans are waiting.
- It's not a crime to hope, sonny.
You think that all this
doesn't sadden and humiliate me?
But I'll manage to obligate them,
at least on a moral level.
And I ask you, in fact I order you:
no more trouble.
And no stupidity. Woe betide
if we gave them any excuse.
Any excuse?
But what excuse have we given them so far?
Which?
5 kilos.
50 kilos.
Watch out, this is fraud.
There aren't 50 kilos.
No, this is fraud.
There is only 45 kilos, not 50.
This is absurd. 10 receptacles,
5 kilos each.
Look here, look: 6 and 4 is 10.
There are 50 kilos.
- This is absurd.
- Absurd?
No, I was saying,
there are 50 kilos. 50 kilos 300.
We've brought 300 grams extra.
We can repeat the weighing if you wish.
There are 10 boxes and each
contains 5 kilos in it.
- President!
- 9 or 10boxes, it's a fraud.
Again in batches in 5
Recheck everything, even the carats.
And if the 5 kilos are missing,
I'll take it as a personal affront.
We are not some crooks.
We've fulfilled our commitment.
I hope you will keep yours.
One day it could be
the other way around.
And we could find ourselves
on that side of the table...
in your place,
and you here, in ours.
I'm the Police Commissioner
who escorted these gentlemen here
to avoid a potential robbery.
On my honour as state official, I guarantee,
Major, that the weight is correct.
I only asked for better controls.
No time to lose. Get started again.
Alberto! Alberto!
Amerigo!
Violence must be condemned by society.
People must become united once again.
Children of a single creator...
of one God.
Our law tells how to reach
this different, renewed world:
the Messianic world.
So then.. Therefore our duty...
How did it go?
The weighing was worse than the collection.
But at least a receipt, something,
a guarantee, in short?
No, nothing.
Because I believe, believe with every
ounce of my being more than ever...
that the destiny of man is different.
Different... better.
And in the name of God, it is man who
must create this destiny for himself.
Each man with his own hands.
According to the codes of our law.
Age old.
Merciful.
Giulia, I wanted to apologise for yesterday.
You thought I was a traitor, right?
You wanted to teach me a lesson, right?
But what should we do
if not try to survive...
to be happy for the little that we can.
You must live, Giulia.
Free yourself from everything.
What I said yesterday was nonsense.
You were right.
One can't be who they want here.
We're the first to not want this.
In the past we were a courageous people.
But for too long we had not
the courage to stand up tall.
You know, I'm gonna leave too.
And where are you going?
I decided moments ago.
I will regroup with my friends
who are already on the run.
So I will no longer be a struggling Jew,
but an Italian.
An Italian like many others,
who fights against the Germans.
You know,..
I would have wanted to talk to you,
ask you many things.
How we've changed, Davide.
If I disappointed you, I'm sorry.
I too wanted to be goodness knows what.
And instead..
I'm any old girl.
You did everything yourself.
And you're the best of all of us.
Giulia?
- Good evening.
Mrs. Giulia De Santis. Look.
On this piece of paper we're
already married. Are you pleased?
And I've even found a great apartment.
It's well hidden.
Davide.
Bye, Giulia.
He was my old friend here in the ghetto.
Here's another link that's broken.
You don't have to sacrifice
anything for me, Giulia.
Not even the smallest thing,
I don't want it.
Are you sure that you'll
never end up regretting it?
I'm asking you for the last time.
Massimo, you don't love a Jewish girl,
who has loads of problems to solve,
but you love me, Giulia.
Only Giulia.
A girl who's smitten and that's all.
Fire!
If he gets the machine gun back,
he'll kill all of us.
Kill him!
Why don't you kill him?
Buddy, this isn't the life for you.
Change while you can.
It's better for everyone.
But why?
Killing disgusts me.
For five thousand years, we Jews have
preached about the horror of bloodshed.
But today I saw it.
I've learned.
What are we waiting for?
For the Germans to raise the alarm?
Davide is coming with us,
by now he too has become one of us.
Come, come on.
Listen, darling, a short while ago
I felt a little feverish.
Maybe it's better... after all,
it's very early. I'll stay home.
Yes, Dad. It's better you stay.
After all this only concerns me.
Giulia, I baptise you in the name
of the Father, the Son...
and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
The Germans are here! The Germans
have come to take all the Jews away!
Help him!
Sarah! Sarah!
Where's mum?
Let her come here with us.
Run!
Jump out the window, quickly!
Giulia! What is it?
Please, listen to me.
I love you, Massimo.
But something terrible is happening.
The Germans are taking everyone away.
Even the elderly and the
children, you understand?
And I'm here and I see it.
Massimo, I...
I must go too.
I understand, Giulia,
I understand.
Now listen to me. Where are you?
Are you calling from the usual place?
I.. I'm happy to hear your voice.
But I want you to remain calm.
No, no...
Try to understand, I..
I'll come back.
And if not, time will pass.
You will be a man and have
much to do and live through.
Leave...
Leave a place for me in your memories.
We have to live together,
Giulia, Giulia!
But all the others, Massimo?
It's not only my father,
but all of my people.
Do you understand?
If now.. I were able to escape...
to come to you...
you would not love me as much any more.
I would not be Giulia any longer.
Bye Massimo.
Do not forget it, our October.
Bye dear.
Bye.
Now I must go.
No, you can't go.
You can't go away, Giulia.
We must stay alive! Giulia! Giulia!
Giulia!
The events depicted in this film are true.
The producers and authors
thank the Jewish Community of Rome,
who consented to the shooting of scenes
in the same locations where
the tragic occurrences unfolded.
Subtitles: TMDaines