I want to be clear.
I have never abused my office.
Alicia,
I know this has been
hard on you,
But you have to believe me--
I'm innocent.
Jackie:
He needs you
To forgive him, alicia.
Jackie, he took everything
I thought we had
And he just put it
out there for everyone.
He didn't want that.
The press...
Oh, jackie,
stop it.
Peter wasn't thinking of us.
Kalinda sharma.
I'm the in-house.
Oh, the investigator.
You're peter florrick's wife.
That's right.
Ryan thinks there's
a good chance
The appellate court's going
to listen to my case.
If they overturn it,
everything goes back to normal.
Peter, it's never
going back to normal.
Golden:
This was after you dropped
your kids off at school?
Alicia:
Yes.
Golden: This was
on the 16th?
Yes.
And who first told you of
your husband's infidelity,
Mrs. Florrick?
Cnbc.
(laughs)
I'm sorry,
I don't understand.
I was at the cleaners.
I was waiting in line.
Cnbc was playing on the tv.
I saw it on the crawl
at the bottom of the screen.
And, just so we're clear,
You never once suspected
your husband's infidelity
Before that moment, is that
correct, mrs. Florrick?
That's correct.
I'm-I'm sorry to ask these
personal questions,
But I'm really
on your side,
And as your
husband's attorney,
Our appeal depends on proving
that your husband made
Untruthful
statements at work,
Not because he was
trying to cover up
Illegal acts as a
state's attorney,
But that he was trying
to hide an affair
From his wife.
You understand?
I understand.
Good.
Uh...
Let's turn to
the call girl.
She made some statements
in the press.
(phone rings)
Alicia florrick.
When?
Are you sure
you need me now?
Um... I'll call your office
to arrange
To do this
another time?
I just want to let you know
that peter has a lot of friends.
Judges, lawyers,
business folk
Who didn't like the way
that this went down.
They want to help.
I'm just saying
if you need anything,
Day or night,
Give me a call?
We're fine.
Ah, one more thing.
Um...
We're looking
for correspondence
That may have taken place
Between peter
and a gerald kozko.
Just like the store,
only with a "k" and a "z."
The real estate
developer.
Peter says all
of his private correspondences
Are at your apartment.
It would help a lot
If you could look for a letter
or a card from him.
That's it.
Dentist visit... Is over.
Alicia.
I heard you were coming
on board to replace bree.
Could you...?
Sure.
Ah, talk about
complicated.
Jury selection
took a week.
We got five more of these
Filled with medical testimony
and the depo dump.
Did you read that?
I was on will's felony case
till 30 minutes ago.
Yeah, I was on
a slip-and-fall
Until diane yanked
me on this.
It's just "all hands
on deck," you know?
But this one's
pretty cool,
So come on, I'll get
you up to speed.
Diane:
And what is an
ironman, ray?
Ray:
Running, biking,
ocean swimming.
You swim 2.4 miles,
Bike 112 miles,
And then run a
full marathon.
And you placed third
in the hawaiian ironman,
Is that correct?
Ray:
Yes, I did, yeah.
Diane:
So tell me what
happened on the 12th,
Ray.
Ray:
Well, it was right after
The ironman.
We were back
at the hotel,
And I felt
this migraine coming on,
So I took these...
Pills my doctor
prescribed me
And the migraine
just...
...Seemed to be getting worse.
Ray demory.
He's our test case.
If diane wins
this one,
There's a massive class
action in the wings.
Ray:
...I felt unsteady.
The next day at the hospital,
I found out I had a stroke.
And these pills you took--
they were zennapril, correct?
Your honor...
The drug manufactured by these
three gentlemen over here.
There's nothing I enjoy
more than watching
Miss lockhart perform
Her courtroom magic...
James mccloon-- killer
defense counsel.
They call him
the velvet shiv.
Mccloon:
...My clients
manufactured
Zennapril,
And stop poking
at them like perps
On america's most wanted.
Funny,
I didn't hear an objection,
your honor.
Let's just please refrain
from the crosstalk.
Yes, your honor.
I will try not to interrupt
miss lockhart again.
It will be difficult,
But I will try.
So, ray,
How would you describe
your physical condition now?
(chuckles)
You're looking at it.
Mostly it's been
hard on carol.
We got married a year ago,
before my stroke, and she...
She didn't buy
into this.
I mean...
One day her husband's an ironman
and the next day he's a...
(sighs)
...An invalid.
Brandon, lahna, you take point
on legal precedent.
Cary, you take alicia
and review anything
That could undercut
the class action.
I don't want
to win the battle
and lose the war.
Use kalinda
if you need to, okay?
Let's get to it.
Mrs. Demory.
Hmm?
Can I get you
something?
No, I'm fine.
Sorry, must have had
a zombie look on my face.
No, no, no.
We all need a moment.
I'm alicia.
Right, you replaced bree.
Nice to meet you.
Oh, this.
This is what keeps us going.
Michael graff.
He took zennapril
after a little league game.
Jenny hollis.
She was a dancer.
They all wrote you?
Yes.
138 of them.
I...
Sorry.
Just...
They're all counting
on us, you know?
If we don't win,
they're stuck.
It's just a lot
of responsibility, you know?
Objection.
Relevance.
Isn't it the case,
Mr. Demory, the only reason
you're not suing your doctor is
Because his pockets aren't
as deep as my client's?
Objection!
Your honor!
Can we have a ruling?
Please, your honor.
Approach the bench.
Get me all references
To secondary prescriptions
in ray's deposition.
Right.
Alicia:
Kalinda, I need you
to look into this.
So, what are you saying?
Someone's bribing a juror?
I'm not saying
anything.
I just found it.
Look, this could
be anything.
A seating chart
for a garden party,
A football lineup.
With 12 linemen?
What's that?
Alicia:
Yep.
We should talk
to the hostess,
See if anyone from the court
eats here regularly.
No, we should take a deep
breath, show this to diane...
Shh!
Man: ...Only spot in
chicago not stuffed
full of yuppies.
Been coming here
three times a week...
I don't think we need
to talk to the hostess.
I come here
so often,
I asked them to name
a sandwich after me.
Waitress looked me dead
in the eye and said,
"we don't serve ham."
(laughter)
(no audio)
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
It could be anything.
It could be
just a doodle.
We don't know.
And you found it
in our depositions?
Yes, but it could have been
on the floor and stuck to one.
We just thought it should be
brought to your attention.
Remember last year?
Yep.
Diane: Was mccloon
ever cleared of that?
Will:
It's still up for review.
So you think
we should-- what?
Don't go to
the judge.
It makes no sense.
How does it end
up in our depos?
Mccloon sticks it in there.
He wants a mistrial,
But he wants us to go
to the judge and request it.
Or he's just screwing
with your head.
There's another
possibility.
There's a young associate
on his team-- a redhead.
She came over and introduced
herself this morning.
Said she worked as a paralegal
here last summer.
So, what, mccloon has
a whistle-blower in his midst?
Young, idealistic junior
associate sees something wrong,
Feels bad about it,
slips us a warning in our depos.
I could see that.
Okay, this is what we do.
We do our homework
and look into juror number two.
And juror number 11.
Mm-hmm.
Or juror number 11.
We go to the judge
if we have anything.
You don't want a mistrial,
right?
No.
Ray was good on the stand.
The jury liked him.
And mccloon's defense seems
to be a variation
On holding his breath
and threatening to turn blue.
This trial is sounding
more and more fun.
Let's see if you got
a bad juror on your hands.
Put in for an alternate.
Okay. I'll put
Kalinda and cary on it.
Excuse me...
But I'd like to do this.
Okay.
Juror number two
is marilyn wolk,
A hairdresser
from south bridgeport.
We scored her an 85 positive
on our bias scale,
One of the highest scores
we've ever given,
So we believe
she's firmly in your camp.
Now, I know that you pay me
only to help select jurors,
But if I knew
what you were after,
I could offer
further consultation.
No.
This is good.
Keep going.
Uh, juror number 11
is calvin tober.
He's a grad student
in comparative history.
We scored him only
a 62% positive
On our bias scale--
Well within the range
of acceptability,
But we like him.
Being african-american,
he's more prone
To mistrust authority.
He's intelligent, but not
to the point of overcoming bias.
Not like asians
or mexicans.
We talk in racial stereotypes
because you pay us to,
And we find
racial profiling works.
But if I'm
not needed...
You're not needed.
Thank you.
You've got issues?
Paying her $100,000
for three months
Of high school-level
psychology--
Yeah, I guess I do have issues.
Okay.
So, what are we thinking?
(sighs)
Wolk worked as a rent-a-chair
hair stylist, right?
Which means she
only gets paid
When she actually
has a customer.
She could have claimed
financial hardship
And ducked jury duty.
So why didn't she?
Civic duty?
Jury tampering pays better.
Okay.
But let's look into both.
Hi. I hate to trouble you,
But I'm from
the next building over
And the delivery man left this
at my door by mistake.
Is there a mr. Tober
in the building?
Hi.
I'm sorry to bother you.
My name's kalinda,
and my husband and I
Were thinking of buying a home
in the area.
I can always come back later,
If you know what time
he gets home.
We're interested
in the preschool
Around the corner and...
...Or anyone else in his family.
I just wanted to get a sense
of the neighborhood.
Tober, I think his name is.
Usually, I don't like
black people much,
But he seems nice.
They're the wolks.
She's a hairdresser.
And he's...  Actually,
I think he's out of work.
Oh, I'm so sorry
to hear that.
Mmm.
Hard times, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
But their house
is so lovely.
Looks like they put
a lot into it.
Storm windows
in front
And air-conditioning...
They bought a car, too.
Guess they came
into some money.
Hey, there he is now.
That's the
husband-- derek.
(car alarm chirps)
Oh, gosh!
I'm sorry.
I forgot-- I have
to meet the realtor.
Oh!
Thanks so much for your time.
Diane:
Objection, your honor.
Is this
really necessary?
Mccloon:
The demorys are
seeking damages
For loss of consortium,
your honor.
The jury needs
to understand that loss.
Counsel...
Diane:
Sir, the term,
"consortium,"
Is not limited...
Mccloon:
I know what the term
Consortium means.
Counselors, please.
I have prided myself
in not using my gavel once
In my 30 years on the bench...
What's going on?
...But you are truly
making me reconsider.
What?
Now, miss lockhart,
I just... Overruled.
Ka-ching.
Cary:
I heard you were on
Some hush-hush project.
What is it?
It's hush-hush.
Mccloon:
Mrs. Demory,
Before your husband's stroke,
How often did you
have sexual relations?
I don't know-- I guess...
Twice a week.
Mccloon:
And since the stroke,
How often do
you have sex?
Carol:
I don't know.
Mccloon:
Would you say
it was less?
Yes.
Less.
But your husband
Isn't completely paralyzed
from the waist down, is he?
Carol:
No.
No, I'm fine.
I'm just...
Angry at myself for
letting him get to me.
Well, it's hard when they
treat your private life
Like a crime scene.
Yeah.
But I guess there are...
Greater tragedies.
(phone ringing)
Alicia florrick.
Ah. Alicia.
I'm glad I got you.
It's daniel.
Who?
Peter's lawyer.
Oh, hi.
Do you have a minute?
Actually, I'm a bit busy.
I was just wondering if you had
A chance to look
for the kozko letters.
We're struggling
with these weekend meetings
That he had with peter,
Um, last March.
Uh, the ninth, the 16th
and the 25th.
I haven't looked yet.
Anything that will show
That peter did not know,
going into those meetings,
There was something untoward
will help us.
Daniel:
Oh, uh...
Alicia, um...
I was chatting with
the headmaster at briarcrest
On another matter,
and he mentioned
That they have scholarships
for your kids.
Mr. Golden.
Yes?
Don't. Please.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
(indistinct conversation)
(sighs)
Kalinda (over phone):
$35,000 can buy you
a lot of stuff.
Alicia:
That's a bit tenuous, isn't it?
Her husband works
at mccloon's firm?
Look, I'm not saying
it's a smoking gun.
I'm just saying that she
didn't put it on her voir dire,
So if we wanted to get rid
of her, we can.
I say we bring it to diane
and see what she says, okay?
Thanks. Bye.
Grace: Zach, give me
back the remote!
Zach: We've already
seen this one.
Peter (on video):
Shh. Not so loud.
(girl giggling)
Peter:
I don't hear the front door.
Is she gone?
(girl giggling)
Peter: Oh, I thought for sure
she suspected something.
(sighs)
Oh, yes!
(laughter over camera)
Zach, give me the camera.
Peter:
I'm not alone in this.
I am not alone in this.
It wasn't even my idea!
Let's go!
Hurry up.
Yeah.
Peter:
Okay.
Here we go.
Put a lot of
this on, right?
Do we have
sprinkles?
Peter: Hurry up.
She's coming back.
What the heck do you do?
I don't know; it's a
little too thick.
All right... I'm gonna do
a little surgery.
I just wanted to lay
on it a little...
You know what I mean?
Straighter.
Yeah, push it...
Peter:
I know, but it's sticking
to the bottom.
Grace: Dad, you were
supposed to get rose petals
Already petaled,
not roses.
I know, but this is what I have.
Zach:
Dad, that looks...
Okay.
How does that look?
That looks
terrible.
Grace:
Oh, my gosh.
Zach:
That looks expensive.
Peter: There goes your
college education.
(all laughing)
Okay, let's get ready.
The day you were talking about--
the 16th--
The day he was supposedly
with kozko...
Well, he couldn't have been.
He was with us the whole day.
Okay.
I'll bring it by your office--
30 minutes.
Hey, jackie?
I'm heading out.
Oh, but I'm making dinner.
Wow.
That's big.
Mmm.
Where did this
come from?
Well, it was on
the doorstep.
I think it's
from your work.
It's very nice of your
firm, wasn't it?
Uh, dear, what...
Oh, dear.
Alicia,
what are you doing?
(sighs)
What else was in the basket?
(stammering)
I don't know. Bananas.
Anything else?
I don't know.
Cookies?
Oh, good.
I'm so glad.
Uh... You have the tape?
Why, yes.
And something else, too.
A gift.
What is it?
Ham, ipods,
Some half-eaten bananas.
Don't you ever
try to buy me.
And don't you ever try
to buy my kids.
You understand that?
We're still working on the
other juror-- juror number 11.
And we're not saying
that juror number two
Was definitely
bought off.
We just think that
based on appearances
And the fact that it
just takes one bad juror
To toss out a favorable verdict,
We should use
that as pretext
To bump juror number two
and put in the alternate.
They make a good point.
Better to be
safe than sorry.
What does the jury consultant
say about the alternate?
The alternate's
a republican.
Not as good for us as
the current juror.
So what if juror number two
wasn't bought off?
I've just replaced a good juror
with a bad alternate.
So, smoke out mccloon.
Bring the potential bias
to the judge,
But don't insist on
replacing juror two.
Just bring it up.
And if mccloon goes crazy,
you know she was bought,
And fight for her expulsion.
And mccloon doesn't go nuts?
Just say you were
following your duty
As an officer of the court.
Back off.
It's your call.
We don't know what this means,
your honor.
We just know it wasn't in
juror number two's voir dire.
I don't even look at the guards
at my reception;
I go straight down to
the parking garage.
I don't understand,
miss lockhart--
Do you want juror number two
off the jury or not?
Well, we're undecided,
your honor.
We merely felt an obligation
To bring it
to the court's attention.
Hey, if miss lockhart has
any hesitation at all,
I say let's dump her.
Of course, we are willing
to stipulate
To the fairness of this.
Mccloon:
Let's just put in
the alternate.
We have no objection,
your honor.
Judge:
All right, fine.
Juror number two is out.
We'll put in
the alternate.
We got played.
What happened?
It was a mccloon setup.
He put the placemat
in our depos
To get us to dump
our best juror.
We don't know that.
Mccloon didn't fight it.
He welcomed it.
He wanted number two
off the jury.
Right.
Because we were wrong.
It wasn't number two.
It was number 11.
Or it was no one.
Okay, maybe.
But we find out.
I don't know.
We thought number two
looked guilty
Because she wanted
to serve on a jury.
But she was just
being a good person.
So?
So, if that x was
on juror number five
Or eight or anyone,
We would pry into their lives
and we would find something,
Because from the outside
people look guilty.
Yeah, and sometimes,
People from the outside
look guilty
Because they are guilty.
I mean, what's your point?
We don't look?
(sighs)
I don't know.
I don't like prying.
Then don't.
Let me.
(knocking on door)
Oh, thank god.
I hope you can help me.
I just locked myself out
Of 4b and I left
my purse inside.
So, where's tober?
He left earlier.
Jury duty, I think.
But he said to ask the super--
Hey, you're ozzie,
right?
Yeah.
But I've never seen you before.
Look, I know
this is awkward, okay?
I met calvin
last night.
He let me sleep in
while he went off.
Please.
I'm already so
late for work.
In our phase I and
phase ii trials,
We never once found
a causal link
Between zennapril
and brain stem stroke.
Mccloon:
Dr. Winsor,
Is it possible that mr.
Demory took a wrong
Dosage of zennapril
for his migraine headache?
Well, he shouldn't have taken
any zennapril at all.
It's not indicated for
headache relief.
Zennapril's not
Approved
for migraines?
Winsor:
No.
It's a powerful drug
Intended only for patients
suffering schizophrenia.
Daniel:
I want to apologize
for last night.
I sent that basket before
we had our conversation.
No one will ever
send you anything again.
Thank you.
(sighs)
(chuckles)
I, uh...
I don't mean to keep doing this.
I need to ask
another favor...
Regarding the videotape
that you gave me.
Okay.
On the tape was a present--
a bracelet.
I need you to look
for the receipt.
Why?
I want to use the videotape to
try to get peter a new trial.
I think it's very effective.
But I'm afraid that the
prosecution will suggest
That the present wasn't
paid for by peter.
Why would they
suggest that?
(sighs)
Mrs. Florrick, as you know,
Technically,
I don't represent you.
I represent
your husband.
And so, as much as I would like
to be completely forthcoming,
In these circumstances,
I don't believe I can.
So kozko gave peter things,
And you believe peter
regifted these things--
This bracelet-- to me?
I can say this:
It would be helpful
if we could find the receipt.
(rattling)
Alicia...
If it's money
you're concerned about...
What?
You don't have to be so proud.
I know you're carrying
a great deal
Of responsibility right now.
The rent alone...
Well, I just want
you to know
That I have
more than enough room.
Oh!
You know, we're okay for now.
But thanks.
(message alert beeping)
(line ringing)
Woman:
Yeah?
Hold on.
Kalinda?
Kalinda:
Hello?
Hi, it's alicia.
I'm returning your call.
Who was that?
Donna.
Look, I found out something
About juror number 11,
calvin tober.
I was talking to the super
in his building,
And he let me
into his apartment.
Why would he let you
into his apartment?
You really want to know?
No.
Here's the thing:
Tober's bank account--
He just deposited
$20,000 in cash.
I think we have
our bribed juror.
Yes, it's ours.
You lost the receipt?
And I need a copy
for my tax records.
It's a beautiful piece.
One of our finest.
When was it purchased?
Um...
February or March.
Maybe January.
I'm sorry,
you said "florrick."
Yes.
I found the receipt, but
it's not under florrick.
Might it be under
a different name?
I'm not sure.
What name do you have?
I'm sorry,
I'm not able to give out
that information.
Could the name be kozko?
I'm sorry.
I'm afraid I can't give out
that information.
Kalinda:
Hey!
So, I tracked down
tober's ex-wife.
She says he was five months
behind on alimony.
Then last week,
he paid her ten grand.
He claims he took out a second
mortgage on his house.
Is that all?
Tober doesn't own a house.
Did you hear me?
Yeah.
Kalinda, do you know
someone named kozko?
Gerald kozko?
The real estate developer.
What does he have to do
with my husband?
I don't know-- does he have
anything to do with him?
You worked at the state's
attorney's office for how long?
Two years.
Did you ever see anything?
Like what?
Payoffs, gifts--
I don't know.
I don't even know
if I want to know.
Look, you don't go to the
state's attorney's office
To find saints.
I'll get back to you
about tober.
If his payoff's $35,000,
Then mccloon owes him
another $15,000.
My guess is he gets it
before deliberations.
That's at the end of today.
I better rush then.
Mccloon:
Objection, your honor!
This is a research document,
not promotional material.
Judge:
Overruled.
Diane: Then let me
continue quoting:
"primary outcome for zennapril
include a 40% reduction
In the average frequencies
of migraines."
We test drugs for all
possible outcomes.
It doesn't mean that
we recommend them.
Could you please
tell the court...
What this is, doctor?
Objection.
We haven't seen this.
Discovery materials, item 469.
I'll help you, sir.
This document is an
application to the emea,
Seeking approval to market
zennapril in europe
As a migraine medication.
Am I correct?
Yes.
Filed 20 months ago.
Dr. Winsor,
Would you please
tell the court
Whose signature is
on this application?
Uh, my signature.
Diane: No further
questions, your honor.
Then that concludes
the trial testimony.
We'll finish the day
with summations
And jury instructions,
And then ladies and gentlemen
of the jury,
The trial moves
into your hands.
(starts engine)
(quiet groan)
Diane: And she's sure
it was a payoff?
No. She saw an envelope
exchange hands,
But she doesn't know
what was inside the envelope.
And she didn't
see the driver?
No. She saw
a dark green suv.
Uh, kalinda saw
a partial plate-- j15.
She's running it now,
crossing it with make and model,
But that could take a while.
Start with mccloon's
legal team.
Oh, I don't know.
The jury's already
deliberating.
They've sent word to the judge
They may have a verdict
by today.
So if we pull the
trigger, we do it now.
Diane: I'd have to bring
the judge everything.
The place mat,
the $35,000, the alimony.
You request another juror now,
it'd be a definite mistrial.
(diane sighs
heavily)
Diane:
But I feel like the
jury was with me.
I mean, the summation--
they were nodding.
They want to give this to us.
Yes, unless juror
11 torpedoes it.
Either way, we're
risking a mistrial.
Damn.
This is roulette.
This isn't law.
Will:
We're talking about
A felony crime here;
we have an obligation.
(knocking on door)
The judge wants
you in chambers.
This should be interesting.
In the next ten minutes, we're
going to figure something out.
You're honor, I would like
to request a private meeting.
Your honor, may I please...?
In the meantime,
I would like silence.
Not mccloon silence,
Not lockhart silence,
Just silence.
Unless I point to you,
You will
not speak.
Your honor?
Sergeant largon!
Sergeant, come in, please.
And wait right there.
Anyone who speaks
without my permission
Will be held in contempt.
Now, the jury
has reached a verdict.
I'm holding that verdict
Until we settle an issue
that has arisen.
The foreman has approached me
about being followed by someone
From one of your legal teams.
Who would that be?
You may speak.
Your honor,
We have reason to believe
that mr. Mccloon bribed
One of the jurors.
We intended
To bring these charges
to your honor,
But first, we wanted to be
certain of our information.
And so you had one
of the jurors followed?
Mccloon:
Your honor,
I am stunned.
Judge:
Mr. Mccloon, without
The outrage, please.
Clearly, miss lockhart
has nothing solid,
And she's trying to torpedo
This verdict
before it comes in.
She's worried
it won't go in her favor.
Judge:
All right, miss lockart, I am
Holding you in contempt.
You owe the legal
defense fund $80,000
To be paid no later than Friday
Of next week.
And I think
I am damn well owed an apology.
Judge:
Uh, uh, uh!
I did not point to you.
That'll be $10,000,
mr. Mccloon.
Now...
We are all going back
into that courtroom,
And we are all living
with this verdict.
If you have evidence
of jury tampering,
Miss lockhart,
take it up on appeal.
Too many people
have selflessly
Invested their time
For your playground tactics
to throw this into a mistrial.
Now, that's it.
Judge:
Ladies and gentleman
of the jury,
Have you reached a verdict?
Yes, your honor.
Judge:
And what is your verdict?
"we, the jury,
find for raymond demory
"and against
"the defendant zennapril
pharmaceutical.
"and we assess damages
in the sum of $800,000
"in compensatory damages
And three million
in punitive damages."
Judge:
Thank you for your service
To the state of illinois.
The jury is dismissed.
Court adjourned.
(applause)
Settle, and I won't
pursue an appeal.
I still have
my class action clients.
Right. I'll get you some
numbers by the end of the day.
So, we were wrong?
It happens.
People sometimes
just look guilty.
Carol:
Alicia?
Thank you.
Oh, it was...
It was all diane.
I want you to
have something.
These are the people
that you helped today.
(sighs)
Thanks again.
(laughs)
It really is amazing.
Is it?
Yes.
Ever been
to the hungry kitten?
The restaurant?
Sure. Ray loves it.
And you borrowed
our deposition books?
Yes.
Why?
Wow.
Diane wanted us to look through
ray's earlier statements.
You didn't have to do it.
You would have won.
We did win.
They bribed
the foreman.
Our clients did.
They drive a
dark green suv.
Their license
plate prefix
Is j15.
There was no
whistle-blower.
Our clients bribed the jury.
Maybe.
No. It's true.
We need to bring this
to the judge.
We already did.
We brought our suspicions
to the judge,
And he overruled us.
Yes, but now we know.
We fulfilled our obligation
under the law.
It's wrong.
No.
We follow the law, alicia.
Sometimes it's wrong,
Sometimes it's right,
But we always follow the law.
And today, you helped a lot
of people in pain find justice.
(door rattling,
closes with an echoing bang)
Peter:
How are you doing?
Good.
I hear that work is going well.
It is. It's good.
You sound like grace.
"how's school?"
"good."
"how are your teachers?"
Are you having fun?
That's the most
important thing.
(laughs)
Fun as disneyland.
Well, I'm... I'm, uh...
I'm glad you're making a life
for yourself.
It gives you a break
from this whole...
Situation.
Right, daniel?
Alicia can handle herself,
I know that.
So...
(clears throat)
uh...
Daniel and I wanted to talk
to you about something.
Alicia, um, we've been going
over our appeal strategy,
And, um...
(clears throat)
...We need you to
Do something
that we didn't expect.
We need you to testify.
Peter:
I'm sorry,
But we have gone over this
every which way we could, and...
Daniel:
We need you to say
On the stand
when you found out
About the affair,
so that we can show
That peter was lying
to protect you.
Oh, um, from the affair.
Peter:
Well, I mean,
It's bill clinton
all over again.
Remember what we used
to say about him?
They were using sex
to crucify him.
They're doing
exactly the same thing to me.
Crucifying you?
Daniel:
Alicia,
We need you to do this.
I wouldn't ask you
if I didn't need it.
Will you testify?