Good morning, sir
Good morning, madam.
Before we enter the apartment,
I’ll give you some info about this building:
It has six units.
It's very quiet and in perfect shape.
It also has an underground parking garage,
which is accessible from the elevator behind us.
Another big plus is
it has two entrances.
Good Morning, Night
The second is through the kitchen.
So when you exit the garage with
packages for example…
you can walk to the kitchen directly…
without passing through the apartment.
Directed by Marco Bellocchio
It's very peaceful
and private…
like the entire neighborhood.
Let’s go in now…
and start the tour.
Here we are.
I'll open the windows.
We can see it better that way.
Here's the foyer, roomy yet functional.
The door is armored...
you can feel safe here.
The finishings are very high quality.
The floors are in marble and parquet.
Here’s the living room
I'll open it.
There.
As you can see,
the apartment's very bright.
This way is...
the garden, exclusively for this apartment.
Hello, Micione!
We even have a lovely cat.
OK.
It isn't maintained very well
because nobody’s been living in this unit,
but with some water
and some newly planted flowers…
it’ll look completely different.
This is an important part of the apartment.
Since it's at ground level...
people outside will pass by
your windows.
This is like a natural cover...
it will block out inquisitive eyes.
OK, let's continue our tour
together with the lovely little cat.
Here…
we have the two rooms…
I'll open it...
to give you a sense
of how bright the place gets…
and the condition of the rooms.
The other room is in back.
This could be used as an office.
Hopefully later…
it will be your children’s' room.
Unfortunately, you'll have to forgive me...
but I have many appointments to
show this apartment today.
Don't hesitate to call me...
I’m at your service anytime.
- Goodbye sir.
- Goodbye madam.
See you later.
We're almost there.
It's almost midnight.
-  We're almost there.
- Maestro Borghesi.
Over to you Maestro!
...Minus stealing, minus
scandal, minus robbery, minus doubt!...
Viva 1978!
Happy new year, everyone!
Come on! Happy New Year!
I hope 1978 will be a lucky
year for everyone.
Sorry, my bedsheet
dropped into your garden.
I live upstairs. I'm Sandra
It's nice to meet you. I'm Chiara.
- Come in.
- Thanks.
Ernesto, my husband.
- Sandra.
- Nice to meet you.
Thanks
- Excuse me.
- Not at all.
- Goodbye.
- Bye
What you just heard is
"The March of the Don Cossacks."
That was our neighbor.
Do you think she did it on purpose?
I haven't gone out. It’d be
impossible for her to see me.
End of transmission.
Our program, "Arguments"…
will broadcast the opera, "L'Opera dei Pupi."
Television News
Special Edition.
Good evening.  The chairman of
the Christian Democratic Party,
Aldo Moro, has been the victim of
a most serious crime.
According to our initial reports,
Aldo Moro appears to have been kidnapped.
This information has been confirmed
by the Minister of the Interior.
It was a bloody affair.
5 people were killed.  They were all
members of the Christian Democratic Party
president's escort.
Three police officers and two bodyguards.
It appears there were numerous gunshots
from machine guns and revolvers.
The body of police chief, Leonardi,
has been identified.
I have to pick up my son. Can
you look after him for me?
I'm very sorry, I can't.
Just for a moment?
Wait!
Let's remember that Aldo Moro, one of our most
illustrious contemporary statesmen,
was the mastermind of the new majority...
who brought about a new era
in Italian politics.
In his speech on February 28th, in
fine political form,
he persuaded the Christian
Democratic Party
to work towards a parliamentary alliance
which included the Communists.
It's no accident that he was
kidnapped today.
A terrifying political motive seems to
have inspired this action
which resulted in the deaths of
his entire security force at the site.
Now let's take a look of the scene
of the assassination this morning.
Above all, a map of the area
where the event took place.
No, I heard we were trying to
form a liaison with Parliament.
Quickly, the reactions.
Yes,  the reactions this morning
were very strong once the news
got out.
Senator La Malfa urged
his colleagues:
implement a state of emergency and
the death penalty.
This is a very strong reaction.
The Christian Democratic Party
is meeting
with Zaccagnini.
Everyone has tears in their eyes,
obviously moved and in shock.
Let's fix it.
- Can I help you?
- No, no problem.
Slowly, slowly!
Put it down.
Where's the head?
He's awake
...message from his family in solidarity
in the name of the Christian
Democratic Party and the entire nation.
This is first-hand news...
Thanks.
See you later.
- Who was that?
- No one, a kid.
- A kid?
- A newborn.
OK.
Do you understand who we are?
Yes, I understand.
You have just seen the
five covered bodies.
The white Alfa that escorted
the politician's car.
They didn't have time to get out of the car.
Only one man tried
to grab his weapon.
He was coldly murdered.
At 10:15, an anonymous
person made a phone call to Milan,
according to the newspaper "La Notte":
"This is the Red Brigades:
we've struck at the heart of the State."
"The hostage is in our hands."
You can see the car of
the president and his escort,
in front is the white Fiat 128...
He must have broken his ribs.
He's having trouble breathing.
Go to the pharmacy,
get this medication.
Without a prescription?
Make something up.
Also get an elastic bandage,
to keep it set.
A film script?
Weird.
And our savings?
I'm going to withdraw it all.
I keep it all at home,
and spend what I need;
and the rest goes to Switzerland.
It's safer over there, for the time being.
No one knows what the future holds.
At least it's in a safe place.
But that's illegal...
Stop!
Thanks, comrade!
Look at me!
Workers on strike!
We're going to the labor union.
I'll come with you, I can't work like this.
How can you go on strike after
Moro's kidnapping?  Such a good man...
an important figure...
Mariano.
All that should be burned.
- This too?
- Everything.
People are talking about civil war.
We've already been fighting one!
But this time,
it's not a matter of
a battle between one small group
of people and another.
Not at all!
We have a group of professional terrorists
who are attacking our institutions,
and our liberty!
We're dealing with a small
group of assassins!
Why's no one responding?
They can't agree with everything he's said.
Why don't they rebel?
They're all applauding.
Why?  They should be hissing!
Calm down.
...that we conquered thanks to
our combat.
We have to open our eyes.
We must make an appeal,
in accordance with our president's message:
to our political forces,
our schools, our men of culture,
our society, and our families.
They're living well somewhere...
these young people...these men...
or women, unfortunately,
who allow themselves to take
part in such criminal acts.
There must be some families
which can say that...
He knocked.
Moro knocked.
...the chaos in
which we're involved.
I think
under these circumstances, we should
appeal to the spirit of non-violence.
This is a serious matter.
A necessary procedure of detoxification.
Didn't he eat anything?
He only wants to drink.
He's breathing poorly.
He asked me to leave
the door ajar.
I'll take guard duty.
You can take the next shift.
Go to bed.
Turn off the TV, please.
Chiara!
How are you?
You're very tan!
Did it snow a lot?
They're all going nuts!
Shall we go elsewhere?
The boss was terrified.
He left with his mistress.
What a moron!
Mass arrests are in order!
Close the universities!
And the labor camps!
Bravo, hard labor camps for you!
What is this bullshit?
You, conscientious objector,
you're a coward!
If you're not a soldier,
you're a coward?
The terrorists are risking their lives!
Don't listen to him.
Hello?
Hi.
-Am I disturbing you?
- No, I'm glad you called.
- I never hear from you.
- You know I live with my boyfriend.
He doesn't have a phone.
- I'm always there.
- How were the mountains?
Yes, it was nice...the weather was great.
It snowed.
- You'll come Sunday?
- I don't know if I'll come or not.
- It's your father's anniversary.
- What about my father?
- We're going to the cemetery.
- I'll make lasagne for you.
You can eat all you want.
- Sorry, I didn't hear you.
- I'll make lasagne
Lasagne...that'll be perfect.
- We'll talk later, OK?  I have work to do.
- Bye.
Excuse me,
no smoking in here.
Didn't you see that?
It's not my graffiti.
Let me by, I want to see it.
Call the police.
This elevator has to be blocked off.
Newspapers?
Hi Chiara.
So what's up?
Nothing new.
Where're you going?
To look for bread.
What did people at work say?
Everyone's talking about us.
Yeah, but what are they saying?
They say we're assassins.
Ask at the factories who the real
assassins are.
Someone drew a graffiti of our star.
Where was that?
In the elevator.
Then it's done.
If the workers are rebelling,
it's done.
Sorry.
Primo!
The newspapers.
A burglar.
Who was that?
Just a burglar.
A burglar?
Incredible.
Come in.
You've got the wrong person.
I don't have any political power,
nor do I have a governmental position.
You represent the
Christian Democratic Party.
We don't want to judge you as
a citizen or a father,
but as all that you represent...
the symbol, the function,
the party you represent.
Like me... I represent
the working class.
My party is truly populist,
it's a very large group
composed mostly of everyday folk:
blue collar workers, peasants,
employees.
You speak of "people," yet
we speak of "classes"...
of class struggle,
of class hatred.
I don't have any hatred for you.
And I don't believe that class struggle
is the engine of history.
People are frightened,
they want to live in peace.
My party is simply a party of peace,
of charity,
of modest welfare...
This is reactionary thought.
...has a white shirt, no suit and tie.
We can't see his hands or feet.
No trace of any scars on his face.
There's a cat outside.
On top of the birdcage.
- Where?
- Bring it back inside.
What's the format of the photograph?
Four by six, I said
What was President Moro's expression?
Rather calm. We can't see
any harm to his face.
We received some pictures
and a message.
We'll run a special edition.
- Mr. President, some soup?
- Yes.
Close it again.
We ask for wisdom from
the authorities,
an acute sense of responsibility,
clarity, firmness, and determination
in the implementation of the
necessary means to restore order.
and to defend justice and freedom.
This is a heavy burden on them,
and that's what we're waiting
for them to do...
above all else.
I give to God, with his
infinite mercy,
the hearts of these victims,
the bodyguards and policemen,
who are very dear to their families...
and today, also to the Italian people.
I call for everyone's support
and prayer from the believers,
in the name of those whose supreme
sacrifices have immortalized them.
I ask from God
that their bloodshed
will help unify us
in this time of
fragile civil peace.
And that the families, struck so cruelly,
can find, with God's help,
some consolation.
Nothing can ease the pain wrought
by these infamous assassins.
You don't have to understand,
just confess.
You want me to confess?
In the sacrament of confession,
penitence is obligatory.
But what do I have to repent for?
For my entire life? I won't be believed.
I should admit things that you know of
but I'm unaware of.
Should I then obtain your
benevolence through lies?
You speak to me of Proletarian law,
of Proletarian justice...
but tell me how it works,
how does it function,
what laws govern this kind of justice?
Proletarian justice is
not that of the bourgeoisie.
I want to remind you that our justice
is punishable by death,
without the possibility of an appeal
or overrule.
Death.
"Give me liberty or give me death,"
as someone once said.
You certainly can't sentence me
to life in prison.
I want to write to my wife.
And also
to my friends from the party.
Of course.
He wants to write a letter.
Did he understand?
I don't know.
What should we do with the minutes?
- Huh?
- The minutes, the letters.
- What do we do with them?
- Destroy them.
That's your job.
Just keep the originals.
Chiara, are you tired?
We have this message from
the Red Brigades.
Also this photo.
We've studied with great emotion
a photograph of Aldo Moro,
looking melancholy and resigned.
We are encouraged
to see that he's alive
and in good health, I imagine.
In another message from the Red Brigades,
they address the issue
of a trial for Aldo Moro.
That seems to be the ridiculous intention
of these assassins, of these criminals
who are responsible for his kidnapping.
The working class must rule over all.
Annalisa?
No, she's on sick leave.
What are you looking at me for?
You could really be more beautiful.
You have the look of a nun.
What gives you the right?
- Hello?
- I'm Enzo Passoscuro's mother.
It's your mother.
- He doesn't want to speak to you.
- Then I'll come down there.
Since you don't want to speak to her,
she's coming over here.
- That's all.
- Then come down.
Goodbye.
- How's your mother?
- Dead.  My father too.
I'm so sorry.
Why?
- You must be pissed off.
- No.
You're happy?
Yes
Are you content with being
just a petty civil servant?
I don't believe you.
Don't believe me.
You're 20 years old now,
look at what you've done.
Don't you have a passion?
A dream?
For me, it's writing.
I don't know if I'm talented or not,
but I love it.
I write novels,  poems.
I even wrote a screenplay.
It's called "Good Morning, Night."
It's a verse from Emily Dickinson.
Would you read it?
I don't have the time.
Are you kidding?
No one actually works here!
Thanks.
Are you engaged or married?
Don't you ever work?
This is my mother's ring.
- Hello?
- Chiara, it's Zia.
- Zia!
Do you remember what's on Sunday?
- Yes, lunch, of course.
- Bring your boyfriend.
- I don't know.
- But he's your boyfriend.
- He's my boyfriend, but he
may not want to come, OK?
- Convince him.
- I'll try to convince him.
- I can go.
- We made reservations at a
great restaurant by the Tevere River.
- Oh yeah?
- Are you listening?
- I'll try to convince him, OK?
- Can't wait to see you.
- Bye.
- Are you joking?
- No.
...met in various groups
on the Transatlantic
to read and examine it.
According to a popular
quote from Andreotti,
as written by Mastrostefano,
who is a member of the D.C.
Experts believe the letter is
in Aldo Moro's writing,
but it doesn't sound like him.
Andreotti's comment
sums up the political reaction
to Moro's writing.
I quote: "No matter what he
writes, they're not his words."
- Hi.
Did Mariano leave already?
No, he's with the president.
Are you afraid of death?
Why do you ask?
You do, however, believe in the afterlife.
In the Garden of Gethsemane, Christ
was afraid of death too.
As a child, I was really inspired by religion
so I wanted to die in order to
get to heaven as quickly as possible.
- How absurd!
- You weren't afraid of death?
Everybody dies.
But not all deaths have the same significance.
I think our advantage is this:
we're prepared to die for our ideals.
Communists are just like that.
Like the early Christian martyrs.
Basically, you have a religion...you too.
Much heavier than mine.
It scorns the body
much more than us Catholics.
Christianity was like that once.
But that's in the past.
The last crusade was in the year 1270.
The last witch was burned in Switzerland
at the end of the 18th Century.
Anyway, I'm going to read what you wrote.
I'll discuss the plan with my comrades.
Did you send my letters?
Yeah.
No response?
Your friends don't recognize you anymore.
They don't recognize me anymore.
Me neither, I don't recognize them.
They think I've turned into someone else.
That's the case, in fact.
But not in the way they think.
I'm always myself.
I'm going to lay down a bit.
Wake me up around midnight.
What's the matter with you?
- Can you tell that I'm upset?
- Yes.
I miss Giulia.
Of course you do.
I can't even drop her a line.
You know...
I know, but I have faith in her.
- We're soldiers.
- How you talk!
I didn't even do my military service.
Comrade Ernesto, a little
revolutionary enthusiasm!
You were gone for 5 minutes.
You sound like my mother
at the gas station!
I want to be sure he's still there,
that this isn't a dream.
- Seeing him there makes me feel reassured.
- Would you rather this be a dream?
I don't know.
I solved the problem:
I don't dream anymore.
Oh God, grant the
serenity of saints
on our departed brothers.
In all your graciousness,
give them eternal peace
and let shine on them undying light.
May they rest in peace.
Amen.
Daniel,  we salute you
in the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Ghost.  Amen.
Until next year.
I'd like to say two things.
Forgotten time doesn't forget
the partisan.
We came from up north
to pay our respects to our friend,
the father of Antonio and Chiara
who, each year...
Each year, he rambles.
Listen to him, you might learn something.
He believes in the great potential of mankind.
He says if people realized
even 1/5 of their potential,
all the world's problems would be solved.
We control love, peace,
justice, fraternity, and the joy of life.
Newlyweds!
Cheers to the new couple!
- There's truth in that.
- Oh yeah?
People do a lot less than they could.
It's a real waste of vital energy!
If people gave it their all,
the world would be different.
There are people who always do the
same thing,
and then suddenly, they want to
change the world with a revolver,
without noticing that their daily
lives amount to nothing.
I read that between two of the assassinations,
a member of the Red Brigades
masturbated while watching porno films.
What's the matter with the Red Brigades?
How's that?
They give their lives for the exploited.
They deserve some respect.
Are you listening to your brother?
They're better than me; I just roll
my joint, quietly.
Fuck you!
Charlie, you remember it, sing it,
and we'll respond.
Sing of happy memories!
Come on Charlie!
Wind blow,  tempest roar,
tattered shoes,
but we must move on
to conquer the red spring
where the sun of the future rises.
If cruel death surprises us
strong will be the revenge of the partisan
it's all worked out
the fatal destiny
of the cowardly and traitorous fascist.
The wind stops, the storm subsides
the proud partisan goes home.
His red flag flies very high.
We'll be free and victorious in the end.
What is it?
...nothing will be solved
by breaking the law.
The new law that's been introduced
revises the text of the
existing health reform law.
A mentally ill person becomes
a normal patient like any other.
Without being segregated, they'll be placed
into various hospitals around  the province.
Please stand up.
The trial ends here.
The Proletariat knows what the
Christian Democratic Party regime stands for
because they are the primary victims of it.
The trial of Aldo Moro is just one stage
in the trial of the State
and in Communism's class war.
Aldo Moro bears the same responsibility
as others in the State,
his guilt is the same.
The Christian Democratic Party
will be swept away
by the Communist fighting forces.
Aldo Moro is guilty and
thusly condemned to death.
That's all.
Should I bring him a tranquilizer?
If he wants one.
- What's wrong with him?
- I don't know.
He said he wanted to be alone
so he could write.
He's trying to get them to negotiate.
Did you sleep?
The president wrote to his wife.
You should leave it tomorrow,
after work,
at the same place,
in the usual church.
- Can I read it?
- Yes.
My dear Noretta,
we have arrived, I believe,
at the conclusion.
Stay united in remembrance of me.
I'll do the same.
I beg you, live your life as before.
Kiss and hug everyone for me
each face, each eye.
Express my undying love for them.
Be strong, my sweet,
through this absurd and
incomprehensible ordeal.
This is the will of God.
I'd like to understand with my
little eyes
how we can see each other again.
If there were light,
it would be so beautiful.
My love,
always know that I'm with you,
and hug me tightly.
Hugs and kisses to Fida,
Demi, Luca...
My love,
tomorrow morning, a firing squad
of the fascist republican guard
will put an end to my days.
My love,
tomorrow morning, a firing squad
of the fascist republican guard
will put an end to my days.
I want to tell you before I die,
that you are my first, my one, and
my only love,
and that if I survive,
I want to make you my wife
and I'll make you very happy.
In these moments, the most
tragic of my life,
my life flashes before my eyes,
like in a movie.
- I need to see her!
- Don't move.
He's not intending to run away,
you don't need me.
We have to fight the revolution
with people like you, who only thinks of
screwing his fiancée?
Our lovers must become "B.R." like us.
I'm a wolf...I don't want any
woman but the one I love!
I'm leaving.  Kill me if you want.
- You're no longer one of the B.R..
- I don't give a damn!
She'll understand.
Shut up!
Let me go!
What should we do?
In any case, he'll come back.
My father used to hunt me
down with a bat.
You were lucky.
Who are you writing to?
To Luca, my grandson.
He's two years old.
He'll read it one day.
Do you have any children?
Yes, a son, but I haven't
seen him for a long time.
That really hurts me.
It's like he never existed.
We must find a way
to negotiate with them.
Consult a higher authority,
one above parties.
God.
- You're back?
- Yes.
The great escape, is it over already?
We're soldiers,
that's what you said.
What's up?
I'm thinking about the letter
that Moro wrote to his wife.
I read it in the newspaper this morning.
It reminded me of a book that
my father used to read to me:
"Last Letters of Communist Partisans
Condemned to Death."
Moro is still alive.
What are you trying to say?
Those people in the book are all dead.
- Moro is still alive.
- Do you think they'll kill him?
They won't get anywhere if
they don't kill people.
They're crazy and stupid.
- And it scares me.
- I don't understand.
You're making me nervous!
Hold on...
You speak of the Red Brigades as if they
were crazy,
masturbating men
who are the lowest of the low!
Can't you see the other side?
The powerful Christian Democrat,
his lackeys, his hypocrisy?
The Red Brigades are worse:
they want to imitate them!
They write nonsensical communiqués.
Can you imagine if they were in power?
Do you write any better? Your screenplay
rings false from start to finish.
Then you've read it.
How is it false?
Imagination has never saved anyone.
Imagination is real.
I'd like to think that there's a
woman among the kidnappers.
A woman?
I changed the ending...
I imagined a girl, young,
in the army,
but not because she read
Das Kapital...
- she's a little like you.
- Why me?
I imagined her to be like you.
Young, beautiful,
but does everything to hide it.
This girl wants to save the prisoner
without betraying her comrades.
Calling the police would be
too great a betrayal.
Don't you agree?
- I don't know.  Continue.
- But she has to take risks,
She may have to risk her life,
otherwise it would all be too easy.
She's forced to risk her own life
Like one of the terrorists that took part
in the kidnapping rationalizes it...
Why?
How could she in less than two months...
Must you always have a logical explanation?
The assassination horrifies her.
She's lost her faith.
It infuriates her to have
been so stupid.
She has to do something...
to prevent herself from going crazy.
What are you doing?
So do you think they'll kill him?
...I've arrived just after the
skirmishes in front of the Senate.
I heard noises, like tear gas bombs.
At Place San Pantaleo,
a police chief told me:
"We responded with tear gas bombs
after we were attacked
with Molotov cocktails"...
...the only way to reach the
frozen lake is by helicopter.
You can see the that the center
was opened in the summer by divers.
For the moment, no results...
Primo, what are you doing?
Come in! You can see for yourself.
The canaries flew away.
What's going on?
Nothing, the canaries escaped.
- Was it you who let them go?
- Shut up!
The cats must have eaten them.
Your leader isn't there?
He left.
He'll be back tomorrow.
May I read you the letter
I wrote to the Holy Father?
I'd like you to give me your impressions.
I've tried to write it many times.
I'd also like to read it to your colleagues,
your comrades.
I'd like to know their opinions...
It's my last chance.
You can leave the door open,
I'll turn my back.
Come over here.
Be careful,  the door is open.
- May I begin?
- Yes.
"Your Holiness"...
Is there a women among you?
I can tell because my socks are folded.
"Your Holiness,
"in this difficult time,
"permit me to address you,
with all respect and with hope,
"in the end, that with
the grandest moral authority,
"and in the grandest Christian spirit,
"you can intercede
"with the Italian governmental authorities
"for an equitable result
"regarding the question of the
exchange of political prisoners
"and my safe return to my family.
"My presence and my assistance
areindispensable to them.
"Only Your Holiness
"can impart
"on the sensibilities of the State
"the moral imperatives, and the right to live."
"With the utmost gratitude
and profound respect,
"yours sincerely, Aldo Moro."
So?
Ask your comrades if I
could improve it further.
I must find a word that
goes right to the heart.
There's only one.  Not two.
You've made her cry.
How old is she?
23.
I want to ask her a question.
She's here, she's listening.
I want to ask the young lady
if her emotions mean that my letter is moving.
No, I don't like it.
It's cold, resigned, formal.
But you cried.
Yes, but out of anger.
Then I have to rewrite it.
I don't know.
An old man's going to read it.
Presidency of the Council of Ministers
"Unconditionally"
"...In the name of holy Christ
"who I pray to and who, certainly,
won't ignore me.
"I'm begging on my knees
"free president Aldo Moro,
"unconditionally."
L'Unita - the Pope.:
"Free him, unconditionally"
Corriere della Sera, L'Unita
and Lotta Continua, please.
- Can I tell you something?
- Sure, go ahead.
Your husband cheats on you.
Thanks.
I declare myself a political prisoner.
What's wrong Chiara?
Why are you taking him?
What's he done?
Are you Bernardo,
our spiritual guide?
Thank you for joining us here.
As you must know,
Aldo Moro was sentenced to death
by the Red Brigades.
We want to know, above all,
if he's still alive.
Spirit of Bernardo, we ask you,
if you would,
to tell us where Aldo Moro is imprisoned.
Where is this place?
"The Moon."
Come on Bernardo, don't kid around,
comic spirit.  It's a tragedy..
We die from heroin
and enslavement.
I don't give a damn if
Aldo Moro dies too.
I've come to consecrate the house.
I'm the priest of Santa Lucia.
- Am I disturbing you?
- No.
Let's pray together.
God, please bless this family,
so that all of its members
can be reunited, with love and peace,
which are gifts from resurrected Jesus.
We pray.
God, please bless this family.
Please God, assuage the fatigue of
those who work hard
and assure that they won't lack
happiness or bread.
God, please bless this family,
so that their passed members
can be together in that great place in the sky.
Blessed art thou, Our Holy Father,
in this house.
By our Lord Jesus Christ.
She's exhausted, she didn't
sleep all night.
- Is she pregnant?
- Yes.
- See you at the baptism.
- Yes.  I'll give you a donation.
- I'll see you out.
- Thanks.
Goodbye.
Unfortunately,
still no news of Aldo Moro.
We were trembling, yesterday,
as we reached the deadline
set by these men
who are self-proclaimed
judges and executioners.
And we tremble again
in hope and in prayer
that we are spared--
Rome, Italy, the whole world,
and especially his family and friends--
the perpetration of this crime.
This waiting allows us to keep hoping.
I can't abandon my grandson.
He loves me very much,
he'll fall ill.
He couldn't handle my disappearance.
As a good Christian,
I can accept death,
but I can't die now!
I could be your prisoner for life.
I give you my word that
I won't try to run away.
We'll keep trying until the very end.
In the meantime, write.
What more is there to write?
I've already written to everybody,
and I even made my will.
I'm not just talking about your family.
Make everyone understand that
you've run out of time.
You don't understand that I'll
become a martyr,
I'll be the idiot that destroys you.
You must understand.
When the TV shows images
of my dead body,
people won't understand you,
they'll hate you!
In the meantime, write.
Have you decided to kill him?
Yes, we all agree.
Why'd you ask him to write?
So he can kill time.
The pope himself begged you.
Isn't that enough for you?
Why? Many comrades were impressed.
Haven't you read it?
Freedom, unconditionally.
If we set him free unconditionally,
we're fucked in the head!
We have to set him free
unconditionally.
They don't want to acknowledge us.
And why would they?  If you don't
acknowledge them?
"You"?
You're not one of us now?
Yeah, but I don't understand
why we have to kill him.
Nothing can convince me that this is right.
I can say that, can't I?
The workers revolution can't
be subject to humanitarian limitations.
Nothing is prohibited.
For a Proletarian victory,
we're entitled to kill even our own mother.
What appears inconceivable, absurd,
or inhuman to us
is a heroic act of annihilating
our subjective reality.
It's the best of humanity.
We have to reason this way!
And everyone agrees:
the central base, the leadership, all...
"Everyone"?
We're the ones who've imprisoned
him for almost two months.
We're the only ones entitled to decide!
Can't we wait?
No, it's too dangerous.
Their negotiations are only
to buy time.
- Tonight?
- Unless something comes up.
You're tired.
Tonight, you must sleep.
Eat something.
OK.
The Aldo Moro affair.  The leadership
of the D.C. will meet tomorrow.
Another attack in Milan:
A doctor is kneecapped.
The attack was carried out
by the armed Communist Proletariat.
Shooting in Bologna after
post office hold-up.
Don't eat.
We've made a big mistake.
People will be on our backs.
"People"?
The bourgeoisie?
For example, my fiancée and her family...
- Have you spoken with her?
- Yes.
- About us?
- What do you take me for?
Calm down.
We're no longer heroes, but assassins!
According to who?  La Repubblica?
You're nuts!
Where are you going?
Did you hear what the president said?
Think about it.
They want him to die.
We'll do them a service by killing him.
Think about that!
We've proven ourselves the strongest.
Pity won't stop us.
We only respond to the working class.
Fuck you!
That's the last time.
You'll never see me again!
Give me a hand.
- Is he not feeling well?
- He said he's not hungry.
I'll take his plate.
I'm not hungry.
I'm going to bed.
Aldo Moro was killed
on May 9,1978
after being imprisoned for 55 days.
One by one, the kidnappers
and assassins were arrested
and sentenced to life,
a penalty which they serve
under a system of semi-freedom.
The solemn ceremony of
the State funerals
was conducted by Pope Paul VI
at St. John in Lateran Cathedral
and in the presence of the entire
Italian political class.
All that was missing was the
body of Aldo Moro,
due to the refusal of his family,
who chose to have a private ceremony.