Silence! What do you think
you're all playing at?
We are not playing, we are arguing.
l'm just five minutes late, and you are
all getting at each other's throats.
Come on, sit down.
Danielle, l'm surprised. You
and Max are going about.
lt's nothing, honest. l just
asked her to come for a Greek meal.
And l just thought we'll have
a little bit of this...
and a little bit of that.
lt's the little of bit of
this and that, that l don't like.
Jivani, what were you and
Van quarelling over?
He was making fun of Santa Maria.
Santa Maria, the Virgin Mary?
No, Louis G Santa Maria, the
ltalian foot baller.
ltalian foot ballers, are bad.
You shut your mouth,
you big Spanish onion.
lf you spend half as much
energy learning English...
as you do on arguing with
each other, you'd be perfect by now.
You have a lot to learn, and
it's just a week to your examinations.
And l don't think you're
quite ready at all.
Excuse please, you're
committing a mistake.
No, l'm not.
You may have mastered a few words,
but you speak English atrociously.
All we need is a little electrocution.
- Elocution. - Okay.
Part of your exam will consist
of how well you speak...
as well as notes.
So before we break for tea, l'm
going to go around the class...
and l want each of you to speak
for a minute in turn...
on whatever subject l give you.
We'll start with you Danielle.
Your subject is sea side.
The sea side?
l like to go to the beach...
take all my clothes off and lie in the sun.
Tell me which beach, l'll come and watch.
Don't interrupt Jivani, sit
down. Go one Danielle.
One weekend, l went to the isle of the Man.
- The isle of man? - Yes,
but l was very disappointed.
There were not all men.
Thank you Danielle. That will do. Well done.
- Ali. - Yes please?
Television.
Jolly good. l'm liking very
much the English television.
Every night l'm watching the Crosswords.
- Crossroads. - Yes please.
l'm also liking all the advertisements.
l'm learning lots of useful English things.
Like graded grains making finer flower.
And little perforation.
Fairly good.
- Only one thing l'm not liking.
- What's that?
Paying the money for the license.
Not to worry. Thank you. Well done.
- Chuilie, your subject,
philosophy. - Very good.
ln democratic republic of China...
philosophy is for the poll where all
property invested in community...
each member working
according to his capacity...
receiving according to his wants, as
opposed to western countries...
where people are exploited by capitalism...
That is not true. Sit down.
Jamila. A minute please, on art.
- Art? - Painting.
Okay, painting. l like very much, painting.
Last Wednesday, l did painting.
You painted a picture?
No, not picture, l painted the
kitchen door.
l don't mean that sort of painting.
l mean, works by the great masters.
Leonardo Da Vinci, Turner, Matisa.
Oh... Now... last weekend,
l am going to Tatty gallery.
- Tate. - Yes Tate.
And, l am not like what l see.
Painting of ladies, bare foot...
up to here.
And, showing their bosoms and all that.
Also, paintings of undressed
gentlemen, showing all their...
Thank you, that will be all.
Anna, can you speak for a
minute on life after death.
Yes. l do not believe in life after death.
When you are dead, that is the end.
Well, us Catholics go to heaven.
- What about everybody else?
- Everybody else go to hell.
lf heaven is full of Catholics
like you, l'll prefer to go to hell.
l don't think we'll pursue that
subject for the moment...
if you don't mind. Thank you, Anna.
Max, a minute please, on British birds.
l like British birds, especially blondes.
Perhaps that's not very funny, Max.
Sorry.
Everyday, in the garden of
my lodging house, l have many birds.
Blackie birds, cocky sparrows...
and sometimes, a blue breast.
Tit, a blue tit.
Okay. Yesterday, l see a red robin tit.
lt's a robin, red breast.
Okay. British birds much confusing.
Well done. Okay Jivani, what should
we give you to speak about?
- Girls. - l don't think so, Jivani.
- Have you any hobbies? - Sure.
My favorite is hobby is girls.
- Not any other hobbies? -
Sure, but not as good.
l'm not stopping you, but try
and speak for one minute...
without bringing girls
into your conversation.
Okay. l have two other hobbies.
- The first is making wine. -
What's the second hobby?
Drinking it.
After l drink it, l do my third hobby.
But you don't let me talk about it.
My friend, Finchanso,
his hobby is pinching.
- You mean he's a thief?
- He's not a thief.
You said his hobby was
pinching. What does he pinch?
You don't let me talk about it.
Thank you Jivani that was good.
Ranjit. What can you tell
us about evolution.
Nothing at all.
- Why not? - l'm not knowing
what it means.
Well, it means the origin of
the species, where we all came from.
- Now l'm understanding. - Good.
l came from Punjab, he came from ltaly.
- She came from France. - No,
you're taking me to literally
l want you to speak about how
life itself began.
A thousand apologies.
Life began with man and lady make love.
Yes, but before that, what happened?
They put the light out.
No, the story of evolution Ranjit,
was not created...
but evolved from a distinct form.
The first forms of life were in the sea.
Then came creatures who got out
of the sea and crawled on their legs.
Then came four-legged mammals.
Then came creature who
could stand on two legs.
Then the great apes.
- Van. - Yes.
Let's see your observation on the stars.
What? Okay, stars.
- There is plenty stars. - Name some.
Sophia Loren, Michael Douglas.
- Van! - Sorry Mr. Brown, just ajoke.
Just? lf it isn't too much trouble...
can you try being more
serious for a minute?
Yes, for one minute, l speak serious.
Stars. ln the heaven, plenty stars.
Some big stars, some little stars.
Some not so big stars,
some not so little stars.
Some bright stars, some dull stars.
Some not so bright stars, some not so...
- Thank you, Van. - Hey,
l not speak for one minute.
Well, l think you've spoken
for long enough.
- Deryll. - Yes sir.
A minute please on childhood.
- Not want to speak about childhood.
- Why not?
Very bad time for me. No parents.
- No parents? - Santa
Maria. He's a miracle baby.
Mother, father killed when
l was a small boy.
Childhood, very lonely.
Did you lose your parents when
you were a little boy?
l didn't exactly lose them,
l just don't know who they are.
You were an orphan?
- Yes. - That's terrible.
When l was about two weeks old...
l was left on the steps of an orphanage...
in Jeremy street. And hence
my name, Jeremy.
Oh deary me, l'm being
very sad for you.
Not having a mummy!
Oh cheer up Ali, what
you never have, you never miss.
Matter of fact, until was
about two, l was convinced...
my mummy was a big
woolly teddy bear.
Well, l must say l often
wonder sometimes...
whether l have any
brothers and sisters.
Hey! We be your brothers and sisters.
Sure, we all become one
big happy family.
And l will be your brother.
And l will be your
sister. Well, not quite sister.
Well, that's very kind of you
all. l think we'll break for tea.
- Good evening Mr. Brown.
- Good evening Ms. Courtney.
- Headache? - Thanks,
l already got one.
- You want a couple of aspirin?
- l think l need a drink.
Some black coffee might help.
A double scotch might
help a bit more.
l need a break. A nice quiet
10 minutes away from my students...
will do me a world of good.
- One tomato juice please. -
l'm only wanting coca cola.
A glass of milk please.
Look, l only got one pair of hands.
They are beautiful hands.
- Thank you. - You are a beautiful girl.
- Very young. - What did you want?
Brandy.
lt's not here. l'll have to go
to the other bar. l'll be a minute.
Hey boys look, here is Mr. Brown.
What are you all doing here?
- We need a change.
- Canteen coffee not very good.
Can we buy you a drink?
That's very kind of you, but l've
got a bit of a headache...
so l'll go and sit over there.
- Hello Mr. Brown. - Hello Sid.
- Yes please? - You ever get drunk?
Every night; can't face the wife.
You got any family, Sid?
- Any family, any children?
- Oh... yes and no.
- What do you mean, yes and
no? - We had a little one once.
l was out of work, l had no
money. Got a bit desperate.
Wrapped the baby, took it out, &
put it on the steps of the orphanage.
- An orphanage?
- Yes, in Jeremy street.
Jeremy street?
lt wasn't on Easter Monday, was it?
Yes, it was.
Sid, your father? Are you sure?
Quite so.
- l haven't told him yet. - But you must.
Some things are best left alone.
l mean, after all, it was a
long time ago, nearly 30 years.
- The truth, Mr. Brown, must be
told. - Do you think it's wise.
lt's a bit of shock to realise you
are related to someone...
so rough and vulgar.
Rubbish, l think Sid will
soon get used to you.
Thank you.
You know, come to think of
it, and looking at you now...
there's quite a resemblance.
- Sid and me? - Yes, specially the profile.
- Like father like son. - Oh dear.
- What about your mother?
- Yes, what about her?
According to Sid, she sounds like a dragon.
Well l think, it's very romantic.
Enter.
l just came to put the stock room key back.
Sorry, l'm not protruding, am l?
No Sid, ofcourse not, quite the opposite.
lnfact your presence
here is most opportune.
Mr. Brown has something to say to
you. Haven't you, Mr. Brown?
- Yes. - Well, l'll leave you two alone.
- What do you want to say, son? -
Son? You just called me son.
lt's nothing unusual, l call everybody son.
They are just words.
ln any case, l'm old enough
to be your father.
Come, sit down, Sid.
Cigarette Sid?
No, l'm sorry, l just run out of them.
- No, l'm offering you one.
- Oh, that very kind of you.
Thanks very much.
Listen Sid, what l wanted to ask you is...
- Well... how are you keeping? - l'm fine.
Oh good.
What is it you want to say to me?
Well you see it could be
a bit embarrassing.
lt's not about the cape of good hope, is it?
Cape of good hope?
The soap that we use in the wash basin.
- Soap? - l only did it once.
lt was easy, it was a big shop.
l only flicked about half a dozen.
- You stole six bars of soap? - Cases.
l sold them.
l wish you hadn't told me about that.
- lt wasn't about the soap?
- No, l never even heard about it.
Then about the crockery?
- Crockery in the canteen.
- You've been stealing crockery?
l just took about a dozen of
each. Some were old and chipped.
You'll tell me next
you've been nicking the chairs.
- Nicking the chairs.
- No, l never nicked any chairs.
- That's a relief. - Can't make any profit.
- l wonder if it's hereditary. Pardon?
No... Look Sid, tell me about
your wife. What is she like?
Pain in the neck.
You must have been fond of her once.
She's always nagging. Nag nag nag.
- Perhaps she feels neglected. -
She deserves to be neglected.
l'd divorce her if it wasn't for one thing.
- What's that? - We're not married.
Not married!
No, we thought about it, but
never came around it.
- That's terrible!
- Well, it doesn't worry us.
- But that makes me... your
child... - Alright look...
Listen Sid, please.
You must get married. lf for
my... for your child's sake.
l mean, to give it a name.
lt's too late for that now, and in
any case, we can't afford it.
l mean, she wants a new outfit,
a proper do.
lt's not wise to waste all that money.
- Look Sid l'll pay. - You'll what?
- l'll pay for the wedding.
- Why, what for?
- l want to. - Can l have a new suit?
- Yeah. - And a car with flowers?
- Yes. - And booze afterwards?
- Naturally.
l know it sounds strange, but
l have got my reasons.
Can you and your wife meet me in Red
line pub after school tonight?
- That will be alright.
- See you there then.
See you at night, son.
My own father a thief!
Yet l suppose l should
be grateful in a way.
lf he hadn't left me at the
orphanage steps...
but brought me up himself, what
would l be like today?
- Dad... - What?
- Your drink. - Oh, drink, son.
- l brought this as well.
- What's this? lt must be 50 quid.
- 53. - Where did you get it from?
l flicked it from someone's pocket.
Chip off the old block, eh?
He didn't realise?
No l suppose, he didn't bash me up.
l could pick one too.
Quite enjoying yourself?
Very good, son.
- Mr. Brown... Mr. Brown!
- Yeah darling, what...
Sorry Ms. Courtney, l was miles away.
Well, did you tell him?
No, l don't really think l ought to.
But ofcourse you must tell him,
Mr. Brown.
- There's no other alternative.
- Oh, there is.
- What's that? - l could cheat myself.
Danielle, what are you doing tonight?
Why you ask?
There's a dance at the students club.
You want to come?
Hey l was going to ask Danielle
to come with me.
Too bad. l ask her first.
- What you say? - Well,
l like very much to dance.
Good. l'll show you how
to do the ltalian shuffle.
You stand like this, then
you put your arms around my neck.
l put my arms around your waist.
Then we put our cheeks together.
- What do we do next? - Who cares?
l hope l'm not interrupting anything.
l as just showing Danielle how
to dance the ltalian shuffle.
What kind of shuffle, l'd like to see.
Part of your examination next
week will consist of reading aloud.
So l hope tonight, we have a
practice of reading out a poem.
Jolly good. l'm hearing
ajolly good poem last night.
There was a young lady called Nelly.
Who was tattooed all over in Delhi.
Right down her back, the Union Jack.
And God save the Queen on her belly.
Thank you Ali, sit down.
The poem l'm going to
read is called Daffodils...
by William Wordsworth.
l'll ask each of you to
read out a line in turn.
We'll start again with you, Danielle.
- l wandered lonely... as a cloth? - Cloud.
Sorry.
That floats high on air,
valleys and hillies.
- Valleys and hills. - Jolly good.
- When all at once l saw a clout. - Cloud.
- A host of golden daffodilies.
- Daffodils.
Besides zhe lakes, beneath zhe trees.
- THE... THE... THE. - Zhe... zhe... zhe.
Fluttering and dancing in the breeze.
Well done.
Continuous as stars shine.
Continuous as the stars that shine.
Better.
And tinkle on the milky way.
- Twinkle! - Thousand apologies.
Anybody know what the milky way is?
Yes senor. Chocolate.
The milky way is a luminous
collection of stars.
l see. Sophia Loren, Michael Douglas...
No Van. Go on, it's your turn.
Okay. They stretch
in never ending light.
Around the marching of the bale.
l'm sure Mr. Wordsworth
would have found that...
quite an uplifting experience.
Mr. Brown, l just got a call
from your... from Sidney.
He asked me to tell you that
when you're finished...
he'll be waiting for you at
the bar of the Red Line pub...
with your... with his wife.
- Hello Sid. - Hello Mr. Brown.
- Where is your wife?
- She's gone to the wash room.
- He won't be a minute.
- She ordered the drinks?
Yeah, l told her you'll
pay for them when you came in.
Hey Sid, where's that teacher?
Meet my wife. Don't laugh.
- Hello - Pleased to meet you, Mrs...
- You might call me Ma. - Ma.
ls it true what Sid says that
you are going to pay for our wedding?
Yes, Ma.
- That' a great relief, Sid. - Yes.
- But what l don't understand... -
l'll try and explain.
Remember you told me
about leaving a baby...
- at an orphanage in
Jeremy street? - Yeah.
One of the reasons why l
want you two to get married is...
is that your child will be illegitimate.
What a lovely thought!
l must give you a kiss.
l'll tell you something now.
30 years ago...
you left that baby in
the orphanage at Jeremy street.
- Yes, it was about that
time. - On an Easter Monday?
Well, even l was left at
an orphanage 30 years ago...
in Jeremy street on an Easter Monday.
Sid, what a coincidence!
lf l tell you l was that baby...
would you say that was a coincidence?
- No, a blooming miracle. - Why?
Because that baby as a girl.
Oh dearie me! l am losing again
- Good evening all - Hello Sid
- How you doing? - What?
- How you doing?
- Very much! l'll have a pint
l said ''how you doing'' not
''what you having?''
- What? - Never mind! Come on
Hello curly! What can l get you?
- How about excited?
- Congratulations
You are the five hundredth
person to say that tonight
You win our star award, a beer mat
- Thanks! A pint for Sid! - Thelma Ritter
Thelma Ritter, eh? l'm Giovanni Cupello
That is not her name! Thelma
Ritter's a pint of bitter!
- Cockney rhyming slang
- Sure l remember
42 pence!
And a packet of assaulted
peasnuts please!
- Cheers - Thanks a lot
- How is the Las Vegas kid doing, eh?
- Terrible
- You never win nothing on this
machine - l tell you! lt's fixed
Oh no, lady behind bar is telling me
lt is nearly time for somebody to
be winning the Jack in the pot
l try again!
But this time l am not looking!
See l tell you, you not win nothing
Yes but l am getting three bars! Look!
lf l'm holding them,
next time l will be winning
You've already spent one pound
Yes but if l am getting another
bar, l will be collecting five pounds
Oh dearie me! l am not
having any more ten p's
Could you be changing this please?
Sorry Ali, l spent all my change
- Max - l got any ten p's
l'll be losing the jack in the pot
Ah professori!
- Good evening - Good evening
- You want a Thelma Ritter? - Pardon?
- Thelma Ritter, bitter - You've
been talking to Sid the caretaker
Sure, he's teaching me more of
his cockeyned slanging rhyme
- Cockney - Excuse me
- Max! - Yes Mr. Brown
lt's your point of interest! You
have to remember what a cockney is
Sure, lt's someone who was
born near the sound of Bows Balls
- Bells - Hockay
- You want a drink? - No thanks
- l just called for some cigarettes
- Excuse me please Mr. Brown
Would you be having any changes for
a pound to be putting in machine?
- You're wasting your money
Ali - No l'm sure to be winning
- l'm holding three bars - lt's
your money! Let's have a look
- Good evening everybodies
- Good evening Ranjeet
Excuse me!
- What are you doing you damn fool?
- l'm having a go on this machine
l'm winning the Jackpot
That is my winnings
How can it being your winnings?
l am putting the money, 10 p. ln
Here's your ten p. Back
- Take your dirty hands off my money
- lt is my money you bearded bandit
Quiet the pair of you! Why
don't you share the money?
lt's a good idea! There's five of us
That's one pound each
l mean between Ali and
Ranjeet! Then you've both won
- You are as wise as a Holy Guru
- Thank you
Actually, it's time you all
go back to school
lt's your exams tomorrow! You should
be taking every opportunity to study
- l know - Okay
- We go - l go
Come on Ali! You too
- Waiter? - Pardon?
A gin and tonic and a lager please
l'm afraid you're making a mistake
Don't be ridiculous! l know what l want
A gin and tonic for me and a lager for
my husband! He's just parking the car
No, you don't understand!
l'm a school teacher
That's nothing to be ashamed of
l think it's quite commendable
That you should supplement your
income by working in a public house
Look Madam, l am not
what you think l am
And l am not interested in
your personal problems!
l just want a gin and tonic and a lager
- Yes... - Now
A gin and tonic and a lager
- Good evening Mr. Brown
- Hello Sid, how are you?
l'll have a gold watch
- Pardon? - A scotch
l wasn't offering you a drink
- You are? - Nevermind
A scotch for Sid! 20 cigarettes for me
And a gin and tonic and a
lager for that lady over there
She thinks l am a waiter
- What? - She thinks l'm a waiter
- How long have we been doing it?
- What?
- This waiting - l'm not! l'm not a waiter
- You are? - Never mind
One pound 60 please
Well actually these drinks are for
that lady and gentleman over there
- They've still got to be paid for
- Yes but...
Never mind l'll pay for
them and they can pay me later
How much is it for the
gin and tonic and the lager?
- 72 - 72
- Good health - Good health
There you are! 72 p. Please
- Didn't l see you take a drink of
my lager? - Yes, it was only a sip
Oh yes l suppose you were tasting
it to make sure it was fit to drink
lt was purely accidental
l've a good mind to report
you to the brewery
Frankly, l couldn't care
less what you do
Your attitude is typical of
the working class mentality
lt's people like you that are ruining the
country! You're nothing but a peasant
And you sir are a bourgeois
snob! 72 p. Please
l refuse to pay for a drink that
has been contaminated by your lips
l see
All right don't pay for it!
Have it on me!
Here you go!
Silence
This is disgraceful! Ten minutes past
seven and Mr. Brown has not arrived
But you are mistaken!
- He is here, isn't he Anna? - Ja
- That's right! He's always early
- Yes please
Tonight, he was being so early that he
was here ten minutes before he arrived
- He's just gone out
- Where has he gone out to?
- Tea room - Toilet
l beg your pardon!
- Toilet - Tea room
Would you like to try again?
Vot they mean is, first he goest to
tea room, then he goes to toilet
Yeah
Hello Miss Courtney, sorry l'm late
- But you're not - Really?
According to your students, you
were here all the time
- Oh yes well
- And where exactly were you?
- We told you, he... - l'm asking Mr. Brown
- Well? - Ah yes...
What is going on?
l don't know, but from
their sign language
l think they're trying to say
l was having a cup of tea in the toilet
Actually Miss Courtney, l'll tell you the
truth! l am late, and the reason is this!
l'd just called to the pub
opposite for some cigarettes
l was mistaken for a waiter, bought two
drinks for two people l'd never met before
Was called a peasant and finished up by
pouring a glass of lager over a man's head
You're an even bigger liar
than your students!
l would have thought you'd have
made an effort to be early this evening
After all, it's your last
chance to teach them something
Before they take their exams tomorrow
Yes, miss Courtney you're
quite right as usual
Not that l think any of them have
the remotest chance of passing
ln your places please
- She thinks ve are stupid
- l think she may have a point
- Por favore - Yes Juan
What you think about this
exam? You think we pass?
Do l think you'll pass? Juan,
for the past 13 weeks,
you've all been coming here to study
13 weeks of hard work,
diligence and application
13 weeks of blood toil and sweat
Slowly, little by little, you have improved
When you sit down to take
your examination tomorrow
l will have no doubts whether you'll pass
or not! You haven't a cat in hells chance!
Quiet!
Oh blimey, you are not
giving us any confidence
Maybe some of you may
manage to scrape through
But l shall be most
surprised if you all pass
l shall pass to plove supeliolity
of lepubric of China
Yes we'll see about that!
ln the meantime, l want tonight to
talk about the exam and afterwards
lf any of you have any questions about
any points you're not sure of
They'll just ask and l'll
do my best to answer them
- Excuse me please - Not yet Taro
l want to talk about the exam first
- Then you can ask a question - Ah so
Now the first thing is
l shall not be taking you
Excuse please Mr. Brown, where
will you not be taking us to?
l mean l shan't be here
tomorrow when you take your exam
Jelly good! We can be reading all
the answers from our books
- There will be somebody here
- Oh dear
l am thinking l am going
to be up a gummy tree
ln any case, you're
not supposed to cheat
lt's customary for another
teacher from another school
To take an examination of this kind
Excuse me please
- Later Taro please - Ok
When you take your examination, the lower
Cambridge certificate is not too difficult
The exam is divided into 3 parts
There will be an oral exam and a
written one! Then comes dictation
ls that his name?
ls that who's name?
The man who is going to be taking us to
be doing the examination! Dick Tation
Dictation is when a person reads something
out aloud and another person copy it down
Like a short fingered typist
- Short hand typist - Yes please
Excuse me please
You can ask your question in a moment Taro
When you've completed your examination,
the papers are taken away to be marked
And you will be notified
of the results by post
So please make sure you write your
names clearly on your papers
Christian name and surname
- l cannot do that - Why not?
l am not a Christian
lf you want to be pedantic about it
Ranjeet, write your surname and forename
l am not having four names also
The prefix fore in this case is spelt FORE
and means first for example ''forefinger''
Uno momente! Four finger - one thumb
- No not four fingers - Si, si
One, two, three, four
- This is my forefinger - No, it's only one
l wonder if l should cancel tomorrow
- Por favore? - Never mind
Excuse please
- Yes you can ask your question now Taro
- Requesto permission to visit toilet
- Yes of course, sorry - Thank you
Has anybody else got a question?
Yes, after tomollow, will we see you again?
That depends on so many things,
whether l'm engaged for another term
Or whether any of you decide
Whatever the results of your exam to
come back for a further course
l will give you my address!
You can come and see me any time
Quiet, quiet!
Mr. Brown, can you spare
a moment please?
Certainly, l suggest you all
study your verbs until l return
As you know, another teacher will
be taking the exam tomorrow
Yes
The gentleman who used to be the principal
of this college will be supervising your class
He's in my office now! l thought it
might be a good idea if you met him
- l'd like to - Do try to make
a good impression
lt does no harm if he's
favourably disposed towards you
This is our English teacher Mr. Brown
- lt's you - lt's a small world, isn't it?
Silence please!
Exam in progress
Good evening Mr. Cupello! All
ready for your examination?
Sure, everything's gonna be ''Oki talki''
Bueno Serra everybody
- Has anybody got a pen? - Yes
- But prease lemember who it
berongs to - Sure l will
What are you doing?
l tell you! l just been studying my verbs!
So l'm gonna write them down on
my hand so l don't forget
- Typical of western dishonesty
- l think it's a good idea
You want to write verb
tenses on your hand too?
No, l'm ok on verbs but
not good on pronouns
- So write pronouns - No need
l already write them on handkerchief
Smart!
lt is wrong to cheat
- Don't you agree Ali? -
Not at all, l am also cheating
You have got something
written on your handkerchief?
No, it is in my hat
This is terrible! lf you are found
out, you will be disqualified
Old japanese philosopher he say
''Man who deals flom
bottomo, usually end up on top''
- You as well?
- Taro not good on adverbs
So have some written on chair seat
Good evening everyone
Nice to see you all are bright and early
l expect you're feeling a bit nervous
- l am not nervous - Good
- l am putrified - Petrified
Well do your best!
l'm not supposed to be
here so l shall be in the pub
- All right? - All right
But if you all call in when you finish your
exam, l'll buy you all an end of term drink
- Good luck Taro - Thank you
You must be nervous! That's the first
time you haven't stood up and bowed
- Good luck Juan - Muchas gracias
- Good luck Giovanni - Thanks professori
You're not too nervous to
shake hands, are you?
- Si l am very nervous
- Nonsense, come on
- That didn't hurt, did it? - Not a lot
Ranjeet
- That's funny, where did that ink come
from? - Maybe your pen has got a leak
- Let me see your hand Giovanni
- There's nothing there professori
- The other one
- There's nothing there either
There's something there now, isn't it?
Oh no, my pen is got a leak as well
And l suppose while it was leaking, it
just happened to write a few verbs down
Sorry professori, my
verbs are a bit bad
l suggest you clean all that off
- l don't seem to have a handkerchief
myself - Max has got a hankerchief!
- l got no handkerchief - What's
that sticking out of your top pocket?
Oh that, lt's not a proper handkerchief
Maybe Ali's got a proper handkerchief
Let me see that handkerchief Max
- l see, pronouns are your
weak point - lt's right
l'll keep this
How many other little
tricks have you been up to Ali?
You're very quiet, are you
keeping something under your hat?
Blimey, how are you guessing that?
l didn't!
While l'm thinking of it, Taro would
you like to stand up please?
Very ingenious!
- Now Juan, where's your little
crib hidden? - Por favore?
Never mind por favore! l know it's
somewhere, it's written all over your face
No, no write on my face
This is no laughing matter
- Come on Juan, where is it? - Under table
- Ranjeet - A thousand apologies
Danielle, Anna, Jamila, Su Lee?
We no cheat! Plefer to pass
exam on own melits
l'm grad... glad to hear it
Some last minute coaching Brown?
- No, no l just came in to wish them luck
- They're going to need more than luck
Goodbye Mr. Brown
- Listen, l'm sorry about
yesterday - Goodbye Mr. Brown
Goodbye! Good luck
Now l want absolute silence during
this examination, understand?
- Same again! - Don't you
think you've had enough?
How can l have had enough?
l'm still standing
- You've been to the loo once
- That doen't mean anything
You're making it up
- Hello Sid - Same again, thank you
Half a bitter please Mavis and
whatever Sid's drinking
- Sid tells me you're not
married - That's right l'm not
- l'm not married as well
- Congratulations
- l haven't even got a boyfriend - Really?
- How about you?
- l haven't got a boyfriend either
Not a regular one anyway!
Look, have a drink on me
alright? These are for you
- There you go Sid! There's your pre-exam
- Pre cheer! You learned it, aint you?
- Yeah - Good old chap
- How's your Lil? - She's still living
- You don't mean that - Yeah
You know when l was courting her, l used
to worship the ground she walked on
Now l worship the ground
that is coming to her
- That's not a very nice thing to
say - No, but it's more sincere
- You take my tip son, stay single
- l haven't much choice at the moment
l can't afford to get married!
- Still l've got Josephine
- Who's Josephine?
- ls that your bit of
crumpets? - No my siamese cat
- My students will be all hard at it
now - Yeah, there's a lot of it about
l was talking about their exam
- l shall miss them next term
- Cheer up son
- What you want is another
drink - Yeah, good idea!
Yeah, this time l'll have a pint
A penny for them!
l was just wondering how my students
were getting on with their exams
- l expect they'll be all right - l hope so
l won't know what to do with myself now
that the term's over in the evenings
lt must get a bit lonely
for you living on your own
l don't live on my own
exactly! l've got Josephine
Yeah she's marvellous! l don't
know what to do without her
She's very affectionate! Every morning she
wakes me up by nibbling in my ear
That must be nice for you
- l didn't allow her in the
bedroom at first - No?
lt wasn't as clean as she might be
She used to sleep in the bathroom
- That sounds a bit uncomfortable
- No, she was quite happy on the floor
She must think a lot of
you to put up with that
She does! Every evening when i
come back home, she runs up to me
And rubs up all against my leg
How erotic!
- She's Siamese
- Oh well that explains it
The trouble is like most Siamese she's
inclined to be a bit oversexed
- She sounds it - l'm
thinking of having her doctored
And l thought you were
such a nice fellow
- Pardon? - Nevermind
- Where is Sid? - He's gone
back to the school
That is if he can find his way back
- Sid - Yes Miss Courtney
- You reek of drink
- l beg your pardon?
- Drink - lf you insist
- l'll have a drop of your sherry
- You had more than enough already
- Have you finished? - Yes please
- How'd you do?
- l'm very well! How do you do?
l mean how did you get on
with your exams?
We hope we have not let
Mr. Brown down
Miss Courtney!
- Would you care for a sherry
before you go? - l'd be delighted
Do sit down!
lt takes me back... Here in the old office
l expect you miss the hurly
burly of the school life
Yes l sleep nights now
- There we are - Thank you
You know Miss Courtney,
l didn't know you indulged
l don't really, just an occasional sherry
Ready for another?
- Everyone got a drink? - Yeah
l just would like to say
l wish you all every success
lt's been great teaching
you and l shall miss you
You have been giving
us much wisdom
l am so sad
- You are a vonderful teacher - Si, si
- We never forget our
English teacher - Yes
You are the nicest impe
lionist l have met
Professori, lt's been a real pleasure
Si, it won't be the same next time
We owe you big debto
Well cheers!
- Cheers - Good health
- l really must be going! l'm meeting my wife
- Just one moment before you go Mr Short
How do you think the foreign
students got on with their exams?
Terrible!
How do you think you got
on with your exams?
Fantastic!
The answer to the
question: ''What is a sentence?''
The chappie in the turban answered
''A sentence is what you
get when you are sent to prison''
The questions were being
very easy to answer
To the question: ''What is the
past participle of l write?''
The Spanish fellow answered,
''l have wrotten''
l answer everyting OK
The chinese lady was
writing backwards
Of course, l don't know how
they answered the other questions
But if what l saw is anything to go by, then l
shall be very surprised if any of them pass
Goodbye Miss Courtney
l'm very proud of you all!
l know you wouldn't let me down!
- Shall we have another drink? - Yes
- Whose round is it? - Yours
Waiter! Oh dear
- What are you doing with my
wife? - Nothing, l just...
- You stupid fool - l'm terribly sorry
- Let me buy you both a drink
- No, no, no please, please
Have this one on me!
Principal's office
Good evening Sidney
Good evening Miss Courtney, just
giving your door a bit of a touch up
Had a nice holiday?
l spent seven days in sunny Spain
- Pardon? - Sunny Spain
- That sounds nice - lt rained
Oh, l am sorry! Still l expect you enjoyed
all those exotic Spanish dishes
- l got food poisoning - Oh sorry
Did it rain every day?
Oh no! When l got
food poisoning the sun came out
When l got better, it went back in
Apart from the day before we
left. That was absolutely glorious
- Well at least you had one
good day - l got sunburnt
What a pity!
- Hello Sid - Mr. Brown, welcome back
- Ta, is she in?
- l've creamed out your bin
- No, is she in? - Yeah,
but she's in a shocking temper
- l'll see her later then
- Glad to be back?
Yeah, l shall miss my old class
But l shall enjoy the challenge of
starting again with fresh minds
l wonder how many different nationalities
l'll have to deal with this term?
Good evening
Pleased to meet you
Thank you
Do you speak English?
- Hungry? - lgen
You want something to eat?
- Hungry - Hungary
l'll put you in my register
What is your name?
Your name
- Zoltan Szabo - Zoltan Szabo
This is yes
This is no
Yes... No
Good
l am Mr. Brown, your teacher
l hope that was complimentary
Never mind
Do you know any English?
Yes
- Gud sev de kwin - God Save the Queen
More? Some more English?
- Pliz, thank you - Good
- Shtones - Shtones?
- Rolling Stones? - Yes
Good evening Mr. Brown
l am most happy to
be seeing you again
Anna, Ranjeet! What
are you doing here?
We failed our exam but we are
coming back for more lessons
That is correct! Like Roberty Bruce say
lf at first you are not succeeding, try, try
Again!
lf at first you are not succeeding...
Never mind
Were you not expecting us?
No the authorities don't notify the
individual teachers of the results
And as usual Miss Courtney has
kept me in the dark
She took the lights out?
No, she never told me!
This is Zoltan, Ranjeet
Delighted to be making
your acquaintance
What a nice man! He
is giving me a present
He wants you to read out
something from his phrase book
A thousand apologies
Waiter my soup is cold
Pleased to meet you
Thank you
Good and this is Anna
How do you do?
Yes, Thank you
Would you both like to sit down
This time l sit at front, then
l can be learning quicker
l will be sitting in my
accustomed place
Well, l was hoping that l had
a hundred percent pass record
But still, two failures
out of ten isn't bad
Good evening master
Four failures out of ten
Jamila you failed
Sorry Master
But maybe next time
l shall be winning
l'm sure you mean winning
- And you, Taro - Ah so
Loss of face
Not goodo for Japanese
First, considered Hara-kiri
Then decide to como
backo for more lessons
But if no pass next time
Just make sure you don't do
it on the classroom floor
Well, as you can see you re not alone
This is Zoltan
Jamila, and Taro
- Pleased to meet you
- Good evening
Jamila, you want your place back?
No, l sit at backside with Taro
No Jamila! You will sit at the back
Backside is what you sit on
No master, what l sit on is chair
Yes, l can see why you failed
Buenas noches everybodies
Juan! Don't tell me you failed
lt's all right! l not tell you
- You don't need to tell me!
l know - You plenty smart
That's more than l can say for you
- Por favore? - Never mind
This is Zoltan! This is Juan
How you do?
ls for me?
He's really saying he's
pleased to meet you
He doesn't speak English
lt's all right! l teach him
That would be like the
blind leading the blind
Blind
He not see!
- You feel - Juan he's not blind
l was just using a...,
never mind! Sit down
Ok! l sit here
- Good afton - Good evening
- l here come to English learn
- l come here to learn English
We together sit
No, we can't do that
What is matter? There is
wrong something with me?
There is wrong nothing with you
- l very much like you - l am your teacher
Teacher? You are too
young to be teacher
Thank you
- ls that your name? - Yes
- lngrid Svenson - lngrid Svenson
- l take it you are Svedish...
Swedish? - Ja
- Where from? - Stockholm
- Stockholm! And what is yourjob?
- Au pair
Very nice
Where shall we sit you?
There's a place here with me
There is also a place here beside me
Here please
l think we'll sit you at
the front for the time being
You're sitting next to
Juan, behind you is Ranjeet
At the back are Taro and Jamila
She is Anna and he is Zoltan
And l am Ali
- Ali, not you as well
- As well as what please?
- You failed? - Yes
l am getting twenty out of one hundred
That's nothing to be proud about
You're supposed to get at least fifty
to pass! Twenty is disgraceful
Last year l am getting nothing at all
So l am doing better! l sit
- Scuse please! Get up - What for?
- That is my seat
- l not see your name on seat
Get your big Spanish
bottom out of my chair
You no talk me like that! l punch you
That's enough! Seats
are not reservable
Sit somewhere else, Ali
Ok, l sit at the back
You big spanish bottom
We'll wait a few more moments in
case there are any more new students
Buena Serra
lt's just like old times
lt's a big surprise, eh professori?
l am not disappointed to be back
- Who is that?
- This is lngrid! She is Swedish
She is also sitting in my seat
- You will move yes? - l will move no
- You can sit next to me
- No, you sit next to me
That's right! You sit beside Max and
Giovanni because l want to sit here
l'm sorry Danielle! But l think it's
important the new students sit at the front
- l don't like you - l'm so worried
You can come and sit next to me
- Sit between us - Ok
Well l must say that l'm
extremely disappointed in you all
lt's not your fault professori!
We not pass because we're stupid
- And what does that make me?
- More stupid
Exactly! Out of ten students
l've nine failures
Vely solly l'm rate
Congratulations! You are
getting ten out of ten
Well l really don't know what to say
Oh blimey, if you are
not knowing what to say
How are you going to be teaching us?
- l'll ignore that stupid remark
- Jolly good
Because you have all failed, l have failed
lt's perfectly true
This term, l want much
more effort from all of you
You must all pull your socks up
lt's all right
No Juan, l was speaking figuratively
- Por favore - Never mind
You must all concentrate
much harder this term
We shall start at the beginning again
And this time l shall be giving
twice as much homework as last time
l want a hundred per cent
effort from all of you
Now tonight l want you each to tell
me what you did during the holidays
- Please? - Yes Zoltan
l do not understand what you are saying
Never mind! Just keep quiet and listen
Never mind
l speak
No speak
- Thank you Juan - lt's all right
Now, what have you been
doing with yourself, Jamila?
l went on holidays to visit all my family
- You went to Bombay? - No Birmingham
Birmingham, the Mecca of the Midlands
- And you Taro? - Ah so
What did you get up to?
Went on fishing holiday
- Good, did you catch
anything? - Catcho heavy coldo
Did you enjoy your break Ali?
l am not breaking anything
- The holiday - Jolly good
l am learning how to be
driving a motor car
Good, that's very useful! When
do you take your test?
Oh blimey
l'm already failing my test
The examiner man was
jumping out of the car
When l was going down a hill
- l expect you were going too
fast - No, l was going backwards
- What did you do Su Lee?
- Spent time lighting
- Lighting what? - Lighting book
Ah book
What sort of book are you lighting, writing?
ls called The Democratic way of Life
All about glorious freedom-loving Chinese
l see, a work of fiction
Tell us what you did with yourself Ranjeet
l have been looking after my cousin
while her husband has been away
Very commendable
He is being discharged this week
Discharged? He's been in hospital?
No prison
And he is being sent to
prison for something he didn't do
- What really didn't he do?
- He didn't run fast enough
Quiet! Tell us what you did Giovanni
l went to Marsgate
- Margate - Scusi
l met this fantastic girl
She had the biggest...
l'm sure we all get your meaning
Every day we used to go on the sand for a bit
- For a while - Scusi?
To go on the sands for a while
To go on the sands for a bit can imply you
were, well doing something naughty
That's right, we were very
naughty on the sand
Silence!
Mr. Brown, miss Courtney
wants you right away
Thank you Sid
You can have an early tea break and
we'll continue with this later
- Please - Yes Zoltan
No, you must try to speak! Speak
You
- Girl - Yes please
- No you re not a girl - You
Ah, you have a girl friend
- l understand, go on - Girl English
An English girl
- You - Me
You want me to write a letter to your girl?
Please
What do you want me to write?
What l write?
l think l get the general idea
Sidney!
Yes Miss Courtney
Did you tell Mr. Brown
l wanted to see him?
Yeah definitely
l think this should be all right
Dear Miss, l'm writing to tell
you of my feelings for you
l think you are beautiful
l want to hold you in my arms and kiss you
Please say you feel the same about me
All my love
Yes!
Thank you
- What is going on here? - Nothing
lt certainly didn't sound like nothing
l was writing a letter for
Zoltan to his girl friend
He was showing me his
appreciation in Hungarian
Kindly leave us
Go, l said go! Go
Now Mr. Brown
l understand none of your
previous students
Passed their lower
Cambridge Certificate
l think there were a few near misses
That's not good enough
Obviously Mr. Brown,
you are sadly lacking
ln the necessary
qualities required to teach English
- Just a moment - Don't interrupt
l shall be keeping a very close
eye on you this term, Mr. Brown
Unless l see a marked improvement,
out you go
- lt's not... - l have no
wish to listen to feeble excuses
Pompous old cow
- What was that?
- l said l'm just going now
Hey, you not speak nothing?
He is not knowing the English as
well as what we are knowing
- l speak with him
- Blimey, he speak Hungryarian
Sure l speak Hunarian
- Football - Football
- Puskas - Pele
- Kepkens - Beckenball
- Bobby Lee Shutkan - Bobby Lee Moor
You see, l told you
l speak the language
You like England?
Ya! l also very much like teacher
- You not make the eyes at
Mr. Brown - lf l want l will
Mr. Brown does not like the blond ladies
Swedish girls are the beautifullest
Swedish girls are too big in the bosoms
French girls are too big in the mouth
ln China, looks are not important
lt is brains and intellect that matter
- Absolument - Su Lee is right
We women are not symbols for sex
- You agree Jamila? - l not understand
We Women are not here to
give the men the pleasure
l like give men pleasure
Trying to find a few winners?
No l'm trying to find out if
l can afford to leave the wife
- Pardon? - Premium bonds
A hundred thousand pounds!
l could be lucky
Somebody's got to win it
- How many bonds have you got? - One
You're as bad as me! l've only got one
One, double F, two,
three, two, three, two
You've got a good memory
lt's not a difficult one
One, double F, two,
three, two, three, two
That's right
- That's it - That's what?
One, double F, two,
three, two, three, two
l don't believe it
Are you sure that you
got the right cucumber?
- Cucumber? - The number
Positive! Look
One, double F, two,
three, two, three, two
That's right! You've won a
hundred thousand pounds
- What are you going to
do? - What am l going to do
Celebrate of course
- Gladys - Yes Mr. Brown
Coffees all round
Everybody please! l want to read
you all my letter of resignation
No, no! l'm definitely resigning
With one hundred thousand pounds,
l no longer need to teach English
Dear Dracula
This is to inform you
That l think you are a rude, obnoxious
and self-opinionated old dragon
And if l ever see you again,
it will be too soon
Yours disrespectfully,
Jeremy Brown
- Ali - Yes please
See that Miss Courtney
gets this straight away
Jelly good
Thank you
- Please - Oh yes Zoltan, your letter
Glad, where's Sid's paper?
- He went and took it with
him - Took it with him?
- l got a paper Mr. Brown
- Great Max, thank you
Here it is, one hundred thousand pounds
Today's number is One E, F, two, three
Wait a minute! That's not
right! lt should be one double F
We apologize for the misprint
printed out early in the day
l have not won anything
- So you won't be resignating
after all - Resigning
That letter...
Hello please
Ali, the letter to Miss Courtney
- She is not in the office - Thank God
Mr. Brown, Mr. Nadim!
Did you want to see me?
- No - Yes please! This is for you
Thank you
l'd like a word with you Mr. Brown
l'll have you in the office
Close the door
l'll just see what this letter is first
l wouldn't do that! You don't know where
it's been! lt could be full of germs
Don't be so ridiculous
l seem to recognize this writing
lt looks like yours, Mr. Brown
No, it's nothing like
mine! ltjust looks like mine
- Well l'd better open it - l think l'll go
l haven't finished with you yet
You will have when you read that letter
- l beg you pardon? - Nothing
Good Heavens
Miss Courtney
l've never read anything like it in my life
- l can explain... - Just listen to this
l'd rather not
Dear Miss, l'm writing to tell
you of my feelings for you
You see l thought l'd won... Pardon?
l want to hold you in my
arms and kiss you
You did write this letter Mr. Brown
Well l... Not to you
lt's the letter you wrote for
that Hungarian student
- Yes, you see what must have
happened - You don't need to go on
Obviously he's been
smitten by my charm and beauty
- Pardon? - l have told
you before Mr. Brown
l do have a strange
fascination for the opposite sex
Oh yes very strange
You may not believe this, Mr. Brown
But when l was a young
girl l was very plain
A cup of tea Gladys please
Everything ok, Mr. Brown?
Yes! l must have put Zoltan's letter to his
girl friend in my envelop to Miss Courtney
- He's not going to be very happy
- Why not?
He's gonna give the letter you write
There you are love Thank you
Sugars on the table
Give us a cup of tea, Glad
One of these days Sid,
you'll actually buy one
And l'll drop dead of shock
- Buy one? - Yes
Free tea is one of the
perks what goes with the job
There 'Ow are you fixed
for a quick touch?
- l beg your pardon? - l mean money
l'm a bit glacier mint
You're always skink Sid! l'm sorry! No
- Hello lads - Hello Sid
How are you, my old Japan?
- Japan? - My old Japan
Your rhyming slang meaning friend
Not Japan! China, china plate - mate
Jelly good
- l don't suppose any of you could...
- No Sid
- lt's only till pay day - No understand
- Sorry please - lt's alright
Gladys, give us that pack of
cards from under the counter
l'll get some money somehow
What are you going to do?
A little game of find the lady
Nobody might want to play
They'll be enough to play when
l give them the old come on
Come on what?
- You know l've got a
quid till pay day - Yeah
lf l get somebody to win that, it
can't stop! lt never fails
Now all l've got to do now is find a mug
- Coffee please - Hello mug... Max
- Max, would you... - No Sid
No, no! l'm not trying to tap you
- l thought you might fancy a game
of cards - l don't like to gamble
Don't be silly! lt's just a bit of fun!
Come and sid down! Enjoy yourself
This is called Find the Lady!
The lady is a queen! Now there's a
queen and there's the other 2 cards
What l do is l shuffle them about
And the object is to see if
my eyes could deceive your eyes
The quickness of my hands
deceive your eyes
- Where is it? - There
Oh you're right! Very good! You
have good sharp eyes, haven't you?
Sure l have
You would have another go! Yes?
- Where is it? - This one
Twice on the turn! You are
very very good, aren't you?
- Pretty smart, eh? - No
one's ever beaten me twice
l'll tell you what! lf we had any
money, you'd have one two quids now
- Two quids? - Yeah
- Do you want to try again? - Hockay
- Only this time, l bet a pound
- l thought you said you don't play
My father he teach me
two rules of gambling
First rule, always bet on a certainty
- You want this pound? - Yes,
there's nothing wrong with that
Why not?
Now there's the queen!
There's the cards!
- Where is it? - This is the lady
Three times on the trot!
That's fantastic!
l like this game Sid
- Do you like it? - Yes
- Good! Double or Quits? - Quits
What?
- l dont want to play
anymore - But you can't do that
The second rule my father tell me!
Always quits when you're winning
Good evening please
Ah Ranjeet! You're late! l
thought you weren't coming!
You missed first half of the session
A thousand apologies but l am
falling asleep on the underground tube
l am going right past
my getting off stop
- And not waking up until
Cockiefosters - Cockiefosters?
- Perhaps you're working too hard
- l am working three times too hard
What do you mean?
Well my properjob is working on
the underground railway tube
And l'm working the
early morning shaft
- l think you mean shift - That is correct
l am working from six o'clock morning
time until two o'clock afternoon time
Then l'm doing otherjob for garage
Pumping the petrol until
six o'clock evening time
Even allowing for the
time you spend here
You could still have eight hours sleep
Oh no, when l am leaving here,
l am working in public house
until after the midnight
l think you're overdoing it Ranjeet
All work and no play
makes Jack a dull boy
This Jack, is he having three jobs also?
lt's just a saying!
Why are you working so hard?
l'm saving up for the airplane
- You want to buy an airplane?
- No, no
Just a ticket, to Punjab
You're not leaving us, are you?
Only for one weekend
My mother is being sixty
years old this week
So l am giving her the
big surprise of myself
l am now having the
money for the airplane ticket
Two hundred and thirty
English pounds
That's a lot of money
to carry about Ranjeet
You could get mugged
on your way home
You are speaking absolute wisdom
- Here, you keep for me - Me?
Most definitely,
then if l am being mugged
The mugger man will not find money
- lt's too big a responsibility - Please
You keep for me until tomorrow
- Then l buy ticket - Very well
Thousand thank you
Right! Come along everyone!
We have a lot of work to do
Quickly now! Go on
Right! Now, for the rest of this
evening, we're going to have a debate
Can anyone tell me what the
word debate means
And l don't want to hear anybody say
debate is what you put on the fishing line
Can anybody tell me what a debate is?
Come along! Su Lee, what
is parliament noted for?
Collupt poriticians making unjust
raws to oppless working crasses
Agreed! We call that debating
Quite simply it means to
discuss or dispute a given subject
That is what we are going to do
Do you understand what we
are talking about Zoltan?
No understand
We're going to have a debate
- an argument
- Fight? - No, no
Not with fists, with mouth
- Kiss - No, with words
Just do your best to follow us
Now the first thing we're going to do!
We're going to need
somebody to chair the debate
- l'm good at that - Have you done it before?
Sure, every Saturday, l
go to chair my football team
l'm talking about chair, not cheer
- Scusi - Right
l shall be the Chairman
- Now what subject shall we debate? - Girls
Girls is not a subject
Subjects for debates are
in the form of questions
For example, should men and
women have equal pay for equal work?
Should capital punishment
be brought back?
Should Enoch Powell be deported?
Thats the general idea
For our debate, l think we'll
take the subject of Television
ls Television a good or bad
influence on the community?
Now we need two proposers
and two opposers
ln other words, two to
speak for good and two for bad
- How about you Juan? - Por favore
- Good or bad? - Sometimes l'm good
Sometimes l'm bad
Not talking about you personally Juan!
Do you think television is good?
Sometimes good, sometimes bad
Make your mind up Juan
ln a debate, you can't sit on the fence
Not sitting on fence! Sitting on chair
Look forget l asked you
- What you ask me? - Forget it
How can l forget if l don't remember
- Never mind - Alright
- Taro you can be the 1st proposer - Ah so
Now we need a lady, Jamila! You
can be the 2nd proposer
Now two opposers
- Ali, How about you? - Yes please
And Danielle
- Am l good or bad? - Bad
l like being bad! Because
when l am bad, l'm very good
Just remember, we're talking
about television
Now, pay attention everyone
Taro will speak first with the proposition
that television is good for the community
- Go ahead Taro - Ah so
Television is very goodo for everyone
More people watcho, more people buyo
And Japan make besto television
Japan make besto everything
- Cars, cameras, radios...
- Thank you Taro
Remember you're speaking about
television not doing a commercial for Japan
Ah so
Television is goodo for teaching
l learn many English words fromo television
Like 'what a gay day'
And 'Don't forget fruito gums mum'
Thank you Taro
Danielle, would you please
present your case against television
Oui
l think television is very bad
Because it makes people stay up at night
lnstead of going to bed to make love
Not everybody wants to go
to bed to make love
That's right! Sometimes, it's
much better to make love outside
ln Sweden, we make love everywhere
l think we're getting... You do that?
Getting off the subject! Now, come along!
Make love much better proposition
than television
Stick to the point please Danielle
l think television is very bad for the eyes
Yes and also bad for the legs
- Legs? - Si
My brother Miguel, he had
bad legs from his television
Juan, how can your brother have
bad legs from his television?
He dropped it on his foot
l shouldn't have asked
Carry on Danielle
l cannot sink of anymore to say after this
Jamila, would you like to present your
case for the good of television?
l like very much television
The television makes people
happy with many good programs
Like Carnation Street
- Coronation Street - Yes
Last week, l am watching This Week
How can you be watching
this week last week?
This Week is the name of
a programme, Ranjeet
A thousand apologies
And also, television is for free
- You have to buy the licence
- What licence?
- Haven't you got a television
licence? - No, no need licence
- l'm sorry Jamila but you do - No
Look Jamila, it's an
offence not to have a license
lf the detector van comes
round you could be heavily fined
- No - Don't argue Jamila! lt's the law
- Not for me - Why not for you?
No have television set
Watch next door! They have licence
Thank you Jamila
- Ali, your turn - Jolly good
l am thinking television is very bad
Because it is showing too
much of the violence
- A good point - Thank you
Last night, l am seeing
somebody being drowned, then shot
And then having their heads chopped off
What was that? The Professionals
or Starsky and Hutch?
Tom and Jerry
Excuse Mr. Brown, can you
spare me a moment?
Just a minute Miss Courtney
We're running in the middle of
an interesting debate
- Could you waitjust a minute
please? - Certainly not
- Very well! Giovanni, out here
- Certainly sir
- Would you take the chair? - Sure
- No l mean will you chair the debate - Scusi
Let Ali finish, then throw it open! Give
everybody a say then take a vote
lf l'm still not back by then, you
can dismiss the class and go home
Hokey
Okay, you heard what Professori said
Ali's to finish
We have a talk, we have a vote
- Then we go home, ok? - Alright
- You finished Ali? - No l haven't
- l was... - You finished
Anybody wanna talk?
Ok, we take a vote
Everybody thinks Tv's okay,
put up hands
Everybody who think Tv's
not ok, put up the hands
We call it a draw! Class dismissed
Going somewhere?
Would you care for a drink Miss Courtney?
No thank you Mr. Brown
l want to get to the Post
Office to catch the last post
l wonder if you'd post a letter for me
- Yeah certainly - Good
This is the one
- Good night Mr. Brown - Good night
- Another day done, Sid - Worse luck
- l'm always glad to get home - You
wouldn't be if you lived with my missus
- Oh hello - What's the matter?
Here! lt's full of bees and honey
- l wonder whose it is - l know whose it is now
Don't you think you ought to
take it into the police station?
Don't be ridiculous! lt's finders keepers!
Oh Sid!
Enter!
Mr. Brown
- Hush - Don't you shush me
Miss Courtney, l'm in terrible trouble
You certainly are! You're ten minutes late!
Worse than that! l lost 230 pounds that
Ranjeet gave me to look after
- How on earth did you manage
to do that? - l have no idea
lt must have fallen out of my
pocket! l've looked everywhere
l went to the police to ask
if anyone had handed it in
They just laughed
- What am l gonna tell
Ranjeet? - The truth Mr. Brown
You'd better do it in private
You can use my office! l'll send him to you
l suppose the direct approach would be best
Ranjeet, l've lost your money
No, that's too harsh! l
should soften the blow a bit
Ranjeet, come in
Have a seat! Would you like a cup of tea?
Ranjeet, l have something to tell you
- Are you sitting comfortably?
- No, l'm standing up
Ah Ranjeet, come here and sit down
Have a cup of tea
- There isn't any tea
- l'll go and get you a cup
Miss Courtney said you have
something to tell me
Yes Ranjeet, l am human,
you are human
And human beings are fallible!
l am fallible, you are fallible
Oh no, l am Punjabi
What l am trying to say Ranjeet is...
l've lost your money
Did you hear me?
The money you saved to go and
visit your mother! l've lost it
Ranjeet
l'm sorry Ranjeet
- Good evening - Hello Sid
You look as if you've lost a
hundred quid and found ten p.
There's many a true word spoken in jest
Come on! Cheer up
- Have a cigar - No thanks
- Things can't be that bad
- They're worse
Look at me! Yesterday
l hadn't got change for 1/2 p
Today, l could lose a tenner and not notice
You couldn't lend me two hundred and
thirty pounds, could you?
No chance
That's all there was in the envelope
- What envelope? - The envelope
l found outside the school
- You thief - What are you talking about?
That was Ranjeet's money!
- You still got it? - Yeah
Why didn't you hand it in?
- Wait, what are you doing?
- Ranjeet, we found your money
Praise to the Holy Guru
l will be able to be visiting my mother
Oh, she'd be so happy to be seeing me
There's only one hundred and
thirty pounds in here
That's right
- Where's the other hundred? - Here
- What is this? - A betting slip
l put in on Rainbows end on the
6:15 in the night race at Windsor
6:15! We can still make it lads! Come
on everybody quickly! Quickly
Mr. Brown, what is going on?
We're just taking an early tea
break in the betting shop
6:15 at Windsor
The horses are lining up for
the start and they're off
Come on Rainbows End
And right away it's
Ernies Boy in the lead
Followed by Debs Delight, Golden
Wonder and Skylark
Then come Royal Peacock and Slimline
Where is Rainbows End?
And bringing up the rear is Rainbows End
And that's the order at the bend
With Debs Delight closing a little and
Skylark now overtaking Golden Wonder
Royal Peacock is dropping back
And who's this coming
through on the inside
- Rainbows End? - Slimline
And as they come into the straight
lt's still Ernie's Boy,
Debs Delight and Skylark
And here's Rainbows End making
a run on the outside
Come on Rainbows End
And with four furlongs
to go its Ernies Boy
Debs Delight and Rainbows
End now in third place
Ernies Boy is pulling away slightly
But Rainbows End has overtaken Debs
Delight and is challenging strongly
Two furlongs to go and Rainbows
Ends is gaining on Ernies Boy
They're neck and neck as
they come to the post
And at the finish it's
Rainbows End by a nose
How much are you winning?
At five to two, that's
two hundred and fifty quid
Hundred for you and the rest for me
Come on! Let's go draw it
One moment, there's a stewards inquiry
The red flags gone up
Oh blimey, it's a Russian horse
Rainbows End's been disqualified for
bumping and has lost
We are losing and l won't
be able to visit my mother
Poor Ranjeet
He was so much looking
forward to seeing his mother
He will see his mother
But he was going to be
catching plane on Saturday
How can he be getting one
Hundred pounds before then?
We'll get it for him
Even if we have to beg,
borrow or steal it
Yes, yes!
Excuse please
Thank you
You want photograph! Very cheapo
Three for one poundo
You buy pretty violets for your pretty wife
- You want pretty violets for your
pretty wife? - No, thanks duckie
Get your salami sandwiches here
All made with French bread
Shoeshiner! Shoe shine! Twenty p's
Come on! Shoeshiner
Come on young man! Have your fortune
told! Madame Jamila will tell your fortune
Have your fortune told
by Madame Jamila
Please do cross my palms with fifty p.
Come on now! Where's the lady?
That's not the lady, i'm telling
you! That's the lady here
l'll do one more for you to
show you can be wrong
You can't be wrong all the time
- Giant balloons, 25 p each
- 25 p. On balloon
There's one for you
Mr. Brown, please hold! Please hold
- Good evening Miss Courtney
- Good evening Mr. Brown
l hear you managed to raise
the money for Mr. Singhs fare
Yes, he'll be at the airport now
How is he going by plane or balloon?
- You heard about that! - Yes
lf there haven't been someone on
the roof to catch my legs
Heaven knows where l'd be now
Where you usually are Mr.
Brown, with your head in the clouds
- Good evening class
- Good evening Mr. Brown
Firstly, may l say thank you for
all your efforts yesterday
To help me raise the fare for Ranjeet
No, no! lt was a remarkable effort
l wish l could say that for your homework
- l'm not happy with your answers -
We are also not happy with the questions
l got an idea
You're not happy, we're not happy
So if you not give us homework,
we both be happy
Silence
Look, in the future, you will
be given extra homework
And l hope to see some improvement
Some of you are simply not trying
For example, Max
The opposite of anti-meridian is
not uncle-meridian but post-meridian
What you're laughing about Giovanni
Your answer to the question write a sentence
using a metaphor was unbelievable
But l did write a sentence using a metaphor
Yes, last night l found my
girlfriend in a metaphoradream
- Ali - Yes please
For your information, a polygon is a term
used to describe figures
with angles and sides
and has nothing to do with
the disappearing parrot
Mr. Brown, Miss would
like to have a word with you
Ah, new pupil
Would you like to sit over there?
No sit! Look for Ranjeet
Well l'm afraid he's not here!
He's gone this weekend to visit his mother
As a surprise for her birthday
That is terrible
- Why, what's the matter?
- l am his mother
l came over for my birthday
to surprise Ranjeet
You're his mother?
Hello, is that Parkers?
Look, l'm going fishing this
weekend and l need some bait
No, just on the Thames,
the maggots will do
l'll send somebody round to collect them
Oh by the way, those trout flies l bought
from you have been very successful
Especially the cochy-bondu
Seems to attract the trout like a magnet
Yes, thank you again
Bye
Excuse me
You startled me
Would you mind knocking
before you barge in?
Sorry
ls that better?
- l've lost it - Lost what?
l've lost my favorite fly
l had it in my hand a moment
ago! l must have dropped it
Can you see it anywhere?
What does it look like?
lt's about two inches long; red
and black with a curly tail
Perhaps it's flown out of the window
lt's a fishing fly! A cochy bondu
- A cochy what? - Bondu
- lt must be here somewhere
- lf it's here, we'll find it
Perhaps l should come back later
Ah Mr. Brown, you can join in
Well l'm not really that religious
We're looking for a fly
A fly?
Yes! lt's 2 inches long! Red
and black with a curly tail
Sounds quite lethal
- Would you mind helping us
look for it - No, not at all
- l found it - Where?
lt's here! Just under the desk
- l'll get it - No, stand
back Sid! Leave this to me
What are you doing Mr. Brown?
Stay where you are Miss
Courtney! lt could be dangerous
Yeah that's right! lt's not moving!
- Mr. Brown... - Just a moment
Better to be safe than sorry
l've just remembered! l've
been expecting the boiler
Have you quite finished Mr. Brown?
Or would you like to borrow a hammer?
One can't be too careful where
strange insects are concerned
Have you any idea where it came from?
- Yes! W. Parker and Son - Pardon?
- Fishing tackle suppliers - Fishing
- lt wasn't... - lt was
Oh dear!
Got any glue?
l don't think trout are
particularly fond of glue
No l suppose they're not!
- l'll buy you another - See that you do
Excuse me
Hello... Speaking
Pardon?
ls it you?
ls it really you?
lt is you... lt's him
Coming here?
You're not coming here
You are coming here... He's coming here
Yes, yes, yes... Half an hour
You'll be here in half an hour
He'll be here in half an hour
Very well... until then
- ls everything all right? - lt was him
Yes and he's coming here in half an hour
But who is him... l mean who is he?
A man l never thought l'd see again
My ex-fiance
You mean you were actually
engaged at one time?
There's no need to sound so surprised
lt was over twenty-five years
ago... l was just...
l was very young
l met him at Oxford in the high!
lt was raining and he offered
me shelter under his umbrella
Then he insisted on buying me a
cup of tea and a sticky bun
- How romantic - Yes,
that was how it all started
- Why didn't you get married?
- lt was awful! He left me
- At the church? - No, in the lurch
Mr. Brown, l have never
told anyone this before
- Well if you'd rather... - No, sit down
For years, l've kept this
terrible secret to myself
Now he's coming back into my
life l must tell someone
And l think l can trust you Mr. Brown
l'd rather not if it's going to
cause any embarrassment
- lt won't embarrass me
- lt might embarrass me
l'm sure it won't
Anyway, he asked me to go
down to Brighton with him
For one of those
- you know - weekends
- Double room, Mr. And Mrs. Smith?
- Exactly
- And you refused? - Oh no, l went
l even remember the hotel
- The Bellavista, opposite the
abatoir - Very Bellavista
Well, we booked in and Albert, like
the thoughtful man he was
He let me go upstairs first to
prepare myself as it were
While he had a drink in the bar
- Getting up a bit of dutch
courage - l beg your pardon?
Not that he needed it with such
a lovely person waiting to be
- What happened then?
- He didn't turn up
He got drunk, passed out and spent the
night on a settee in the resident's lounge
How despicable!
l went home and refused
ever to see him again
l heard later that he
was working in the Far East
But l must admit
l have always cherished a secret
hope that he might one day come back
- Excuse me please - Yes Ali, what is it?
Come quickly please we are
having plenty trouble in classroom
- What do you mean, trouble?
- Max and Giovanni
They are murdering each other
- l'm ready when you are -
l am ready when you are
You come on
You're gonna be sorry
We see whose gonna be sorry
Okay, l'm waiting for you to come on
Stop this brawling
lt's lucky for you! Professori stop
me from giving you a black eye
l will not have fighting in class
Fighting! lt was more like dancing
- l was just warming up - Me too
- What was this all about?
- l tell you professori
He was calling me a wop
And he's calling me a grease boy
Go on, sit down everybody
l wish you could pick up proper
English as quickly as you pick up slang
l have enough trouble with Ali and
Ranjeet without you two start falling out
Now shake hands, come on
Right! Now, tonight l want to
concentrate on English conversation
The sort of things you have to
say during the course of the day
For example Ranjeet
- Where would you take a
cheque? - To Czechoslovakia
- Not that sort of Czech
- A thousand apologies
A cheque for a certain amount of money
- Where would you take it? - To a bank
- Thank you! Juan - Si senor
- lf you felt ill, what
would you do? - Go to bed
- Before that - Take the clothes off
- You would go to the doctor's - No, no, no
Doctor kill my uncle in Madrid
- Really? - Si
My uncle, he has pain in the
chest! He goes to see doctor
Doctor he looks at him and say...
lt's alright
Ten minutes later, in the
street, my uncle... finito
- He got a heart attack? - Motor car
You could hardly blame
the doctor for that
Si, si, the doctor,
he was driving the motor
- Taro - Ah so
Although we have news
metrics in this country
We still use an old
system which is known as what?
- Sorry not know
- Does anybody know?
Avoirdupois
- Excellent - Merci
- Does avoirdupois ring a
bell now Taro? - Yes
Avoirdupois is French for
have you some peaso
Taro, l can't believe you're that stupid
Sorry, justjoko
Well in future, kindly leave
yourjoko's at homo
- Zoltan, l'm gonna ask you
a question - Yes please
- Which shop... - yes, shop, shop
Which shop would you go to to buy
a packet of cigarettes? Cigarettes
No shop
Come on Zoltan! You must go to some
sort of shop
Zoltan no smoke
Excuse! Zoltan, where you
go for chewing gum?
- Ah, sveet shop - Sweet, sweet
- Anna tells me sveet - No, sweet, sweet
Sveet, sweet! What's the difference?
The difference Anna is that you
must learn to say wer, not Ver! Wer
Verwer
You nearly got it then! Try again
Try saying Verwer without the Ver
Erwer
Almost! Try again but this
time don't say Erwer, just wer
- Wer - Wer
- Wonderful - Wonderful
- Wednesday - Wednesday
- A wet weekend in Winter
- Very good - Werry good
- Ali - Yes please
- You have a headache - No sir
Assume you have a headache! Where
would you go to get some aspirin?
Tanduri takeaway
- No Ali - Yes please
My jelly good friend who's working
there always have plenty aspirin
l meant to buy some aspirin
Why should l be buying them when l can be
getting them from my friend for nothing done
Alright, where do you go for aspirin when
the tanduri takeaway is closed?
Oh Blimey, Taj Mahal curry house
Jamila, would you please tell
Ali where would you go to get aspirin
- Ok, the chemist - Thank you
- Where are you going now?
- To buy some aspirin for headache
- But you said you don't have a
headache - Oh blimey, l got one now
Oh go and sit down
Excuse me Mr. Brown,
the old dragon wants you
Please Sid, do be a little more respectful
Especially in front of the students
lt's up to us to set a good example
Sorry
What does the old dragon...
Miss Courtney want?
l've no idea, but l don't
think she's very well
She actually smiled at me
Enter
- Are you feeling alright? - Yes, why?
- You sounded as if you were
in pain - l was singing
l am sorry to bring you
away from your class Mr. Brown
But before you leave this evening,
would you mind checking...
that Sid's locked up properly
Absolutely, so should be
l was referring to the building
You see, it's quite likely that
l may be leaving early
To think he's come back into
my life after twenty five years
l think l might need another
cherry to settle my stomach
- What's the matter? - He's here! Look
- Where? - Down there
You stupid fool! You have
crowned my Albert
- How do you feel? - l feel terrible
l've got a splitting headache
l'm sorry! lt was an accident! This
is Miss Courtney's office
Wait, wait! Look, have you got somewhere
where l could comb my hair?
And brush myself down
l must look presentable for our
first meeting after twenty five years
- Yes of course! lt's down
there on the right - Thank you
Enter
Hello darling
Pardon?
lt's you
Where's Albert? You haven't pushed
him down the stairs, have you?
No, no! He's just gone to comb his hair
ls he all right? No damage done l hope
- l'm afraid there is - Oh dear, is it bad?
The plantpot's broken
l was referring to Albert
Oh Albert, he's fine
l'll get it
Darling! Oh it's you
This is darling... Miss Courtney
- Albert - Dolores
Dolores?
Haven't you a class to attend to?
Yes of course darling...
Dolores... Excuse me
l've dropped a two p. lt
must have rolled away somewhere
l'm glad to see you're all working hard
What are you studying lngrid?
''How to improve your bust
line''! Very educational
- You can borrow it if you
wish it - No thank you
What's keeping you occupied Juan?
''Gals Galore''
There's not much English in this
No, but some beautiful pictures
Zoltan
''Gorgeous Chicks''
l'm sure this isn't about poultry farming
- But... - Nevermind
Anna! ''True Romances''
Max, ''Football Review''
Danielle, ''Toujours L'Amour''
Don't the French ever think about
anything else other than love?
To the French, there's is nothing else
Giovanni, ''L'Amore''
ln ltaly, we're just like the French
Ranjeet, ''Cartoon Capers''
l am reading all about Bugs the
Bunny and Woody the pecker
Ali, ''The World's Most Exotic Dishes''
l didn't know you were
interested in cookery
Oh Blimey, when l am buying it l
didn't know it was about cookery!
Jamila
''Knitting made easy''
Taro, ''The confessions of a Geisha girl''
You can all learn English
much more quickly
lf you began by reading a
better class of litterature
As you're obviously
so keen to learn English
l'll give you extra homework tonight
Quiet! lt's time you
took these lessons seriously
Now before we break for tea,
l'm going to ask you each a question
And anyone who gives an incorrect
answer will be fined 10 p.
The money will go to charity
Who's this bird charity you're
giving our money to?
Charity is not a bird
lt means an organization...
a deserving cause
- Juan, spell ''quiet'' - Por favore
- Quiet! - Ah quiet
No spell ''quiet''
- How much we pay if
we're wrong? - 10 p.
lngrid, give me an example
of a preposition
Will you to dinner take me?
l said a preposition not a proposition
A preposition shows the
relation between a noun or pronoun
And some other word
A gift from Mary, a house for sale
- A date with teacher - Yes
all right! l'll accept that
- Good, tonight we go
- l meant l'll accept your answer
Ranjeet, how do you pronounce
the following?
B O U G H, C O U G H, T O U G H
You are trying to be catching me out
- B O U G H - Buff
- T O U G H - Toff
- C O U G H - Cow
Three out of three wrong
Thousand apologies
Giovanni, what is meant
by vice versa?
On second thoughts,
l won't ask you that
- What is a diphtong?
- ls it like a dipstick?
What do you think?
l think l owe you ten p.
Ali what does the term
coup de grace mean?
And don't you dare say cutting the lawn
l'm never hearing of it
lt means the final stroke! lt's French
Oh blimey, l am having enough
worries learning the English
lt's a phrase that's in common usage
Ten p. Please
Thank you
- Taro - Ah so
Decline the verb to jump
l jumpo, you jumpo
He jumpso, she jumpso
We jumpo, they jumpo
Very good Taro
But you must try not to
end every word on O
- Ok? - Oko
Cheese! 10 p. Please
- l am not understanding
- lt's a fairly common phrase
They are as alike as chalk and cheese
But chalk and cheese
are not being alike
Exactly, so it means they are not alike
l'm thinking it is easier to
say they are not alike
Than to be talking about
chalks and cheeses
Yes l admit we do tend to
complicate our language
Max, give me an example
of a principal clause
Santa Claus
Quiet
Just for that Max you can
write out 20 times
A clause is as sentence which
is part of a longer sentence
Hockay
Not now, in your own time
And you can give me 10 p.
Thank you
Danielle, as handsome
as a Prince! As ugly as?
A Swede
As ugly as sin
- 10 p. - lt was worth it
Anna give me two different
meanings of the word blow
You can blow like so
Or you can give somebody a blow
Thank you Anna
- Zoltan - Yes please
Can you give me the past
tense of the verb to see
- See, saw - Ah, seesaw
No Zoltan
Today l see, yesterday l saw
lt's not really fair to
take one from you
Alright then
80 p. ln 3 minutes
At this rate, we'll soon
have a small fortune
- Another cup of tea,
Albert? - No thank you Dolores
- A glass of cherry perhaps?
- No, l don't drink now! l've given it up
- lt's a very bad habit - You're so right
l only keep it for visitors
Oh dear
Come on Dolores! Think of
something a little more sparkling
- l wonder... - Yes
- Will you... - Oh l will
Pour me another cup of tea
- Tea? - Yes please
- You said you didn't want any
more - l've changed my mind
As a matter of fact, there is
something else l'm going to ask you
Yes
l know it might seem silly after all this
time and not writing and everything
- But l never forgot you Dolores - Yes
l couldn't believe my good fortune tonight
when l discovered you hadn't married
l never married either
- Didn't you? - No
- Would it be too much to expect... - No
- l mean would you consider... - Yes
- l mean will you marry me?
- This is so sudden
- Oh Albert, my cup is overflowing
- So is mine
Oh dear, l'm so sorry
lt doesn't matter!
- Well what do you say? Will
you marry me? - Yes please
l'll get a special license! We
can be married next week
So soon?
We've already wasted 25 years! We
don't wanna waste any more time
- Wait - What's the matter?
We can't! We'll have to wait
My money's still tied up abroad
lt'll take several weeks to
transfer it over here...
l've got enough money
Dolores, l couldn't let you pay for the
wedding and honeymoon and everything
- What's mine is yours
- No, it wouldn't be right
Nonsense, don't be so proud
l'll tell you what l'll do
l'll use your money on the
strict understanding
That l pay you back when mine
comes through
- Very well, if you insist
- l most definitely do
Oh Albert, l'm so excited
So am l
Just a moment, l...
l have a little engagement! l've
got to meet a fellow down the road
A little business! Lt'll only take a few minutes
Then l should come back and take you to
dinner somewhere... just the two of us
That would be lovely
- Don't go away - Never
Mind where you're going
- Albert? - ls everything alright Sid?
ls everything alright?
l've just seen a fellow l haven't
seen for years! Albert Collins
Albert! Miss Courtney's boyfriend
- Never - lt's true
He's a crook, a con man
You must be mistaken! He's
just come back from the Far East
He's been away for over 20 years
He's been away all right, doing porridge
He's been in prison?
He was in the nick with my brother-in-law
He's in and out of there like a fiddlers elbow
Do you know what his specialty is?
Finding lonely women,
asking them to marry him
Taking their life savings and scampering
l'm getting married in the morning
Enter
Ah Miss Courtney, l've got
some rather disturbing news
Nothing you could say to me
today would disturb Mr. Brown
- l think this might! lt's about
Albert - Ah Albert, my future husband
l've just been speaking to
Sid and... Husband?
Yes, we're getting married
by special license
Oh no
Now Mr. Brown,
l know you were fond of me
But you mustn't take it too hard
Has he tried to borrow
any money from you?
l fail to see what business that is of yours
He has... l hate to have to
tell you this Miss Courtney
But your future husband is a crook
- Don't be so impertinent - lt's true l'm afraid
He's a con man! He specializes in proposing
to lonely women and taking their money
Nonsense! l don't believe it
Ask Sid, his brother-in-law was
in prison with him
- Prison? Are you sure?
- l'm afraid so
- Perhaps he's reformed
- You don't really believe that, do you?
No, l thought it was too good to be true
He's coming back to take me out to dinner
- What shall l do?
- Don't worry Miss Courtney
l'll deal with him
Leave everything to me
l've got a message for
you from Miss Courtney
- Oh yes - Push off
What?
We know all about your little games
So l'd advise you to get lost
quick, before l throw you out
- You and whose army?
- Me and this army
Yeah, well... perhaps
l had better be going
All right Miss Courtney, he's gone
Oh thank you Mr. Brown