Well, let's start
with soft targets.
These are reductions you can make
without further layoffs
or reorganization.
Is one of them IT?
Why don't you just tell us?
Certainly. Annually,
you spend $10,
000 on paper products.
Cups. You're kidding.
We would suggest moving
to a self-policing
hydration policy.
You spend $38,000
on season tickets
to the Chicago Cubs.
Yeah, but that's good business.
We entertain clients.
We would suggest season tickets
for a less expensive
sport franchise,
the Chicago Red Stars.
The...?
Professional women's soccer.
We got to cut somewhere.
The floral budget for
the firm is $28,000.
Yup. Cut somewhere.
We would suggest moving
to perennials or going artificial.
We also suggest you no
longer validate for parking.
The self-policing
hydration policy would be
presented as going green
with fact sheets
posted next to coolers
on reducing landfills.
Hello.
Oh, it's...
Uh, hi. Is, uh...?
Uh, no. Alicia left
her phone at home.
Oh.
You want to leave a message?
No. She's with another lawyer.
I'll try him. Thanks.
Okay.
Good morning.
Dorfman & Associates.
Sorry, we don't have our
phones in yet, Mr. Gardner.
Let me tell Alicia.
Mr. Gardner wants you
to start without him.
Thanks. Can you get us coffee?
Partners offices here.
Conference room there.
Waiting room.
I think this is some
kind of flowing thing.
What is it?
A glassed-in waterfall.
My daughter's the designer.
We have the drywall in next week.
Wow. No longer a
mom-and-pop operation, huh?
Last time we saw you,
it was in a storefront.
Not quite Stern, Lockhart,
but we're on our way.
You're walking through a wall.
Oh. Sorry.
We heard Stern,
Lockhart was in trouble.
Tammy.
No. We've had a few layoffs,
but we're steady now.
Where's all the money coming from?
Insider trading.
Dad's joking.
New corporate clients and
a depressed retail market.
What's this?
The world's 14 highest peaks.
Annapurna, Broad Peak, Makalu.
You climbed these?
Two left. Dad's hobby.
I don't know how it happened--
the outdoorsman sired a homebody.
So, shall we join suits?
I'm all right if we
combine lawsuits,
but we really need to combine.
No stabbing in the back.
You represent
the union employees,
we represent the nonunion.
Yeah. You have
something written up?
Over a handshake.
That's how I do everything.
We're junior associates.
We do everything in writing.
Okay.
Federal agents!
Put your hands on your head now!
All right, spread out.
Everything goes--
computers, files,
every box. Come on, Rivers.
This is harassment.
No, Eric. This is an arrest.
For what?
What did I do?
Maybe you didn't hear.
Hands on your head. Ma'am. Hey!
Come on. These are my lawyers.
They'll have me out in 24 hours.
Not this time. Okay, okay.
What's the charge
this time, Rivers?
First degree murder.
Who did I kill?
Kelli Gerber Smith.
Oh, come on, you lost a case.
When I lose a case,
I don't go pee on your lawn.
She was innocent,
and you gave her over to that scum.
Hey, that's ours.
Sir, we are lawyers with Stern,
Lockhart & Gardner.
We are not employees of this firm.
And we do not grant you permission
to confiscate our work product.
Well, given that I
can't distinguish
between work product in the field,
I'll segregate the files, and
you can get a court order
to have them returned.
Well... No.
What's his name?
AUSA Rivers.
It's federal.
I don't know the
cast of characters.
These are my lawyers.
They'll have me out in 24 hours.
What's he saying? ALICIA:
He telling them
that we're his lawyers,
and we will get him
out in 24 hours.
Uh, you led him to believe that?
No.
No. We were there on
the furlough lawsuit.
The metro suit.
We decided to marry union
and nonunion.
So why did Dorfman get arrested
for murder?
Well, Dorfman was defending
a drug dealer,
and there was this witness
testifying for the prosecution,
a Kelli Gerber Smith.
Supposedly, Dorfman gave her name
to his client, the drug dealer,
who then had her killed.
Who was the drug dealer?
LeMond Bishop.
Bishop's one of Dorfman's clients?
Uh, he wanted us to take
over his ongoing cases,
just while he's being held.
He doesn't have his
staff lined up yet.
He also wants us to
argue for his release.
He can pay us. It's a drug case.
First things the Feds will
do is freeze his assets.
He can pay us when
they're unfrozen.
He seemed good.
Yeah. We'll take it under review.
What was that about?
Either they don't like him,
or the rumors are true--
Stern, Lockhart's going down.
Oh, damn it.
And I have student loans.
Alicia?
Your husband.
Yeah, at least
you have someone to fall back on.
No, no. No, it's nothing.
I just can't find the tax returns.
And why do you need them?
You know Eli.
He needs to look
into anything that can
be used against us.
Uh-huh. Uh,
under my bed
in a box marked,
I think, house files.
Good. Thanks.
How are you doing?
Well, I was almost got
arrested this morning.
You... What?
Do you know an AUSA named Rivers?
Yeah.
Very intense guy.
Out to save the world.
Why, what happened?
He was arresting
this other lawyer...
It's a long story, but I almost
got caught up in the sweep.
He's a zealot.
Never look a zealot in the eyes.
How are you?
Good.
I made a BLT.
I'm very proud of myself.
You know, this is the closest
we've had to a normal conversation.
Yeah. I like it.
Maybe we should talk
on the phone more.
Speaking of which,
you left your cell phone here.
Will called.
Yeah.
He already got in touch.
Okay, back to work.
Back to work.
I say judges are skins this time.
Hello.
Mr. Gardner, AUSA Rivers.
That's okay. We won't
hold it against you.
Suit up.
You phoned.
You wanted your work product back.
Yeah, but at my office.
This is a friendly County game.
You're thinking about
taking the Dorfman case.
We would advise against it.
Really? And what else
would you advise?
Mr. Gardner,
you're having money issues.
You can't afford troubles
with the federal courts.
Wow.
This is like the movies.
You have to threaten me
with an audit or something.
Oh, that's the IRS.
It would be a federal crime
to influence the IRS.
Guys, I'm being
threatened over here.
Can you believe it?
Ooh... Poor baby.
Mr. Dorfman is in trouble.
He is guilty,
and his assets are frozen.
It would be a mistake
to represent him.
Too late. I already am.
As of when?
As of ten seconds ago.
Congratulations, Rivers.
You just won Dorfman an attorney.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
This is how it works.
Germs enter the
political bloodstream
via anonymous Twitter accounts.
These are picked up by
political blogs that...
I'm going to drop that metaphor.
Why? No. No. Keep going.
See where it takes you.
There's an anonymous Twitter
account out there-- Upriser7.
It's saying things
about you and Alicia.
Well, isn't that, uh,
to be expected?
Some of them are true.
Like what?
"Saint Alicia, as she's called
behind her back, is despised
"because of her close
connection to boss, Will.
Widely hated,
she's given all best cases."
Are we saying that's true?
"Alicia and Peter sleep
in separate rooms.
"He is in maids quarters.
She's in the master.
Not even a real marriage."
So, the danger is that it'll
be picked by a political blog,
and then move into the mainstream.
I mean, I can reduce the
damage by flooding the zone
with bogus tweets
that say the opposite.
Any search engine will
be overwhelmed by both.
Wait a minute.
Who knew that we are
in separate rooms?
There's also stuff about Mrs.
Florrick's work,
her competition for a job,
and her connection with her boss.
What did that one say?
You don't want to read it.
That she's sleeping with him.
All right.
Let's find out who's
sending these tweets.
Thank you, Mr. Gardner.
My father is just so thankful.
No problem.
We'll see what we can do.
Yup.
Not my playground.
All rise.
Mr. Rivers, what do we have today?
Several motions on Eric
Dorfman, Your Honor.
And I'm sorry to hear
about your accident.
Thank you. I got your card.
I imagine you're seeking
detention pending trial?
Yes, Your Honor.
Mr. Dorfman, in our opinion,
released a witness
list to a killer,
and given that there will be
vulnerable witnesses in this case,
we ask for pretrial detention.
Your Honor, this is a
simple case of harassment.
AUSA Rivers failed to convict
LeMond Bishop on RICO charges
and is now going after
his lawyer as retribution.
In your opinion?
Excuse me?
Yes, in my opinion.
He's trying to subvert the Sixth
Amendment right to counsel.
Mr. Gardner is prone to
hyperbole, Your Honor.
Kelli Gerber Smith offered
to testify against
one of the most dangerous
kingpins in this country,
and in our opinion,
was brutally tortured and murdered
for her troubles. Your Honor,
the prosecution's
evidence is thin at best.
Generic carpet fibers
found on the body,
access to a witness list.
That hardly makes Eric
Dorfman suspect number one.
In your opinion.
Yes, Your Honor, I'm sorry.
I thought it was obvious,
when I speak, it's my opinion,
and when he speaks, it's his.
Oh, boy.
Mister...?
Gardner, Your Honor.
It is equally obvious
that I'm a judge,
and yet you continually
refer to me as "Your Honor."
All I ask is that you do
the same with your opinion,
and remind yourself and the court
that it is in fact your opinion.
Your Honor, if I could
return to the facts.
Mr. Dorfman was one of four
people to hold the witness list
that was sealed
under a court order.
There were carpet
fibers found on the tarp
covering Ms. Smith's body
that came directly from Mr.
Dorfman's law firm.
And in our opinion, he was the
only one with anything to gain
if her name got out.
This is a vindictive prosecution
and should be treated as such.
In my opinion.
The court disagrees, Mr. Gardner,
and orders pretrial detention.
I'll see you both
back here on Wednesday
at 9:00 a.m. for pretrial motions.
It's their courtyard,
you play by their rules.
They're so cocky.
It's just another courtroom,
and they treat it like St. Peter's.
Didn't we agree to not take this?
No, we agreed to cut the
flowers and paper cups.
The least I can do is
take the cases I want.
You sure this isn't pride?
Of course, it's pride.
What's wrong with pride?
Pride built the pyramids.
And Watergate.
God, those do look fake.
Those are the real ones.
Okay, four people had
access to that witness list.
Find out who they were,
where it went.
Rivers, the court clerk,
Dorfman, the judge.
Good.
Now, did they or anyone
around them leak it?
Also let's look at the
prosecution's assumptions:
the witness in this
original case...
Kelli Gerber Smith.
Are we sure she was
even actually murdered
due to the case?
And if she was, did the killers
really need the witness list
to know she was going to testify?
How do we find that out?
Go to Bishop.
You want to go ask a drug kingpin
whether he really needed a
witness list to kill somebody?
Well, there's probably
a better way to put it.
But in theory,
he wants his lawyer out, too,
and if he could help
steer us towards evidence
that would exonerate Dorfman,
that'd be good.
You up for it?
Sure.
Uh, excuse me.
Mr. Bishop?
So you're my lawyer's lawyer?
Actually, she is.
Arms out, ladies.
It's all right.
The lawyers are on our side.
Didn't you hear, Tony?
When we were picking sides,
they got the cops;
we got the lawyers.
Beautiful horses.
They're not mine.
Rich people need
places to board them.
One of your legit businesses?
Hey, I'm all legit these days.
Isn't that right? TONY: It is.
So you wanted help with Dorfman?
Good.
I like him.
Did he show you his
rock collection?
I think he just picked
those rocks up off the street.
Guy has these rocks from the top
peaks from around the world.
Everest? No, not that one yet.
Mountain climbing never
made much sense to me.
Bunch of idiots who just
need something to do.
But he's a good lawyer.
And lucky.
We didn't even have to go to
trial with that witness dying.
You mean being murdered.
Mr. Dorfman has been accused
of leaking the witness's identity,
allowing you to murder her.
Well, as I'm sure you're aware,
he didn't do that because
I didn't do that.
Right.
But if you could steer us
in the direction of
what really happened,
I think that could help Mr.
Dorfman.
"What really happened"?
Is there some evidence
that points to the murder
happening for other reasons?
Reasons that didn't
require the witness list.
I own a chain of six
sporting good stores,
four restaurants, ten dry cleaners.
I am a businessman.
So I don't want you
making the same mistake
as the government,
thinking that, because of the
color of my skin, I sell drugs.
Because that would be racism,
wouldn't it?
Well, this is an exciting day.
You wanted to come.
So...
here's the thing.
I won't say much,
I won't answer questions,
but Bishop likes Mr. Dorfman,
thinks he got a raw deal.
We do, too.
Rivers found the black SUV
that carried this dead witness.
Unfortunately, this SUV was
never meant to be discovered,
so it may not be as
clean as one would hope.
Was Dorfman ever in this SUV?
Again, if there is any
attempt to subpoena
or question myself or Mr.
Bishop, we will deny this.
But Rivers found the
SUV two weeks ago,
right after the murder,
and he's kept it under wraps ever since.
Why?
Keep it out of your hands.
Surprise you at trial.
We would advise you to
fight its inclusion.
Talk about a pact with the devil.
We're taking trial
advice from killers.
Objection, Your Honor.
This SUV was kept
from us intentionally.
The only reason the court
knows about it at all
is because we brought it up.
It should be thrown out.
I'll give you some leeway,
Rivers. Go ahead.
In addition, Your Honor,
we discovered an impression
made on the console from
a hastily written note--
"Gerbre."
This of course
was the middle name of the victim,
and as you can see the last
two letters were inverted.
This clearly matches
the accidental inversion
made on the witness list.
We submit it into evidence.
Objection!
Again, Your Honor, this evidence
was intentionally withheld from us,
summarily removed from
all exhibit lists,
and should be excluded.
In your opinion.
Yes, in my opinion.
While Mr. Gardner and
his white-shoe firm
may have the resources to
process evidence expeditiously,
in our opinion, Your Honor,
the federal government does not.
Not according to your
own lab's time stamp.
In my opinion, Mr.
Rivers was holding on
to this key discovery evidence
for weeks, Your Honor,
lying to this court about
its very existence.
Mr. Gardner is working
with old information,
in our opinion.
I would submit this revision
of the evidence room stamp.
Objection.
I'll accept. Continue, Rivers.
Thank you. I would like to name...
Excuse me, Your Honor, I objected.
Yes, I know, Mr. Gardner,
and I accepted Mr.
Rivers' evidence.
Yes, but you failed to rule.
My ruling is implicit, Mr. Gardner.
Now, sit down.
No, it isn't, Your Honor.
And I will sit down when you rule.
Would you like to be held
in contempt, Mr. Gardner?
No, I would not, Your Honor,
but I would like a
ruling on my objection.
You are trying my patience...
I understand that, Your Honor,
but we both know
if you don't use the proper
form of "sustained" or "overruled,"
the matter can't later be appealed.
And I was surprised
in reviewing your past court cases,
how often you encouraged
lawyers to move on
without actually ruling,
therefore avoided having
your nonrulings
overturned on appeal.
In my opinion.
Mr. Gardner, I have
never been quite so offended
in all my years on the bench.
I understand that, Your Honor,
but I still want a ruling.
A ruling I can appeal.
Your Honor,
this evidence is necessary
for our prosecution.
A conviction is necessary
for your prosecution.
That doesn't make it
a worthy argument.
One hour for lunch. Your Honor...
I said, one hour for lunch.
What the hell was that?
Do you have a map?
Do I have a what?
A map so I can show
you where you live.
That, my friend,
was a Chicago defense.
Get used to it.
Even if the judge kicks the SUV,
which given my
courtroom performance,
isn't all that likely...
Although fun....
we still need to undercut
the carpet fibers
from Dorfman's office.
That's the only thing
that ties him to the body.
Dorfman's carpet is US Taupe Dream.
It's one of the most common
in the country. Good.
Anything on the witness list? Yeah.
Two other prosecutors in Rivers'
office had access to it.
They were listed on
the initial filing
before Rivers took over the case.
I'm data-mining them now to find
any connection with Bishop's crew.
All right, Cary,
you stay on the carpet.
And, Kalinda,
you stay on the data-mining.
And, uh...
I'll go back to my office.
Yes, I do have a home. Good.
Maybe you should try using it.
Interesting case?
Yes.
May I help you, Mr. Gold?
"Saint Alicia is not just
sleeping with her boss, she is
also using him to get promoted."
Upriser7-- a tweet.
About, uh, two hours ago.
About me? Yes. And Peter.
But mostly you.
At first,
I thought it was intended to derail
Peter's campaign, but then
I realized, no... it's about you.
We're just collateral damage.
This is on the Internet? Yes.
And Ben Smith just linked to
it as part of a remainder item,
so it may get wider play.
Please excuse the melodrama,
but do you think there's anybody
here who's got it out for you?
Young guy, 12:00?
But would he know that
you and Peter are
in separate rooms?
That's in here?
Even mentions the name
of the moving company
that put the bed in.
"Saint Alicia" doesn't
sound like him.
That's the thing
about the Internet.
Nobody sounds like they seem.
Hi.
Want to make a call, Mrs. Florrick?
No, um, I just...
It's...
You know the movers
who came out last week to put in the bed?
Your apartment? Yes.
Is there any way Cary
could've heard about that?
Heard the movers
put in another bed?
Yes. No.
No, I don't mean on purpose.
I'm discreet, Mrs.
Florrick. Yes, of course.
It's not... it's just,
you know, the Bluetooth.
Sometimes you can be
near someone...
Never mind. Forget it.
Yes, hello. Um, can you stop Mr.
Gold from leaving?
I think he left...
My mistake. Uh, never mind.
Kalinda.
What's up?
Can you come into my office?
Certainly, ma'am.
Can you look inside that bag?
Wow.
Where did that come from?
I have no idea.
$200,000 and the vague
whiff of marijuana.
What did you say to him? Bishop?
Nothing. We just asked
about the murder.
What's up?
And why does it smell
like a frat house in here?
Oh.
Bishop?
Our best guess.
I'll make the call.
It's your retainer.
I didn't know you were hiring.
I'm not.
I need new lawyers.
Don't you already
have representation?
In jail.
I need someone now.
Business is piling up.
This is a bit unorthodox.
We represent your current lawyer.
Yes. My experience
is lawyers are good
at making the unorthodox orthodox.
Why us?
One of my aides saw him in court.
I was off-script.
Nice touch bringing the black guy.
For your information,
I'm an equity partner.
Where you from?
None of your business.
I have a corporation,
a large one,
with a lot of employees.
And they sometimes
get into trouble.
I need a firm to look after
their interests and mine.
Help me make the best financial
and legal decisions.
I pay well. I pay on time.
And I help those who help me.
You have a DUI involving
the Baja Fund CEO.
I could tell you things that would
help you with the
arresting officer.
I met your husband once.
Taller than I expected.
Yes, he is tall.
Electronic monitoring's
a bitch, isn't it?
They don't validate.
How can they not validate?
They're going to argue about this,
then they're going to say "yes."
Maybe. No. No "maybe""
Money makes things predictable,
so here's your signing bonus:
This Rivers-- I have something.
It isn't the same
as Sheffrin-Marks.
You don't even believe that.
How's it different?
You know how many kids died
from their asthma medicine?
Oh, my God, the sophistry
here is just blinding.
Sheffrin-Marks has white
employees in suits.
Bishop's crew has
African-American men...
Don't try to sell this
on the back of racism!
Sheffrin-Marks didn't set
out to murder anyone.
Shane Marx, Paul Din,
Johnathan Graham-- all murderers.
Accused murderers.
Now who's the sophist?
We're not in a court of law, Diane.
It's just you and me.
We represent murderers.
We get them off.
No. We keep the courts honest.
And why shouldn't the courts
be kept honest about Bishop?
Everybody deserves representation.
Does that stop suddenly
when it comes to...
A criminal organization
whose sole purpose is to sell drugs
and to murder to control territory?
Sure. Put it any way you want,
it's still a true statement.
We're doing this for the money.
Of course we are.
We're not a charity.
We do this or we lay off
half of Acquisitions.
That's ten lawyers
and ten families.
Not to mention your season tickets.
I'm sorry.
He gave a parting piece of
information about Rivers.
What?
Rivers was sleeping
with Kelli Gerber Smith,
the murdered witness.
Objection, Your Honor. Overruled.
How's that, Mr. Gardner?
Do you approve of that?
I do. Thank you, Your Honor.
So, if there are no
more pretrial motions
maybe we can move this along.
Actually, the defense
requests that AUSA
Rivers be disqualified
as prosecution's representative.
On what grounds?
That's my question, Mr. Rivers.
Yes, Your Honor.
On what grounds, Mr. Gardner?
Your Honor, this is a signed
affidavit from the clerk
at the Lake Avenue Motel
saying that Mr. Rivers
spent the night with
Kelli Gerber Smith
on nine occasions.
Uh...
Relevance, Your Honor?
Your Honor,
do I even need to respond?
Is this true, Counselor?
Uh, Your Honor...
Answer the question, Mr. Rivers.
Yes.
But I assure Your Honor that
it will in no way affect
my ability to prosecute this case.
Motion denied, Mr. Gardner.
However,
I am reconsidering the SUV.
How did you find that out?
How? Inside source.
Too bad it didn't
disqualify Rivers.
We didn't want it to. It undercut
the judge's trust in Rivers
and got her to kick the SUV.
Cary.
Do you have a second?
Sure. What's up?
Are you tweeting about me?
Am I tweeting about you?
Are you Upriser7?
What are you talking about?
Someone's gossiping
online about me.
And you thought it was me?
Yeah.
Yeah, thanks. Yeah, it's good
to be working with you, too.
Hello?
In here, hon.
How was work?
Where's...?
In the shower. Kids are in bed.
I let them watch a little TV.
Have you ever seen When
a Stranger Calls?
The movie?
A long time ago. Hmm.
We just traced the IP address
for the last anonymous tweet.
And?
It's coming from inside the house.
No, just a bit of an emergency.
Rivers found another
way to get the SUV in.
Through the GPS.
So I'll need you to come in. Sorry.
No, it's all right.
Um, I'll probably be half an hour.
Great. Thanks.
No problem.
Is that Will?
Yes. I have to go back in.
So what do you think?
I don't know.
Maybe one of them is angry.
Either about me running again or...
Or me at work. Yeah.
Do you really think it's possible
that our children would do that?
It's crazy, Peter.
Maybe someone was using our
Wi-Fi without us knowing?
Eli's checking it.
But we still have to talk to them.
I'll do it.
Tomorrow.
All-nighter?
No, just a few more hours.
I found condoms in
your bedside table.
I was looking for
your letter opener.
I thought maybe they
belonged to Zach.
You know, you found
them in his room.
But then I thought,
you wouldn't take them.
You'd have a sensible conversation
with him about responsibility.
So then, I thought they were yours.
But that didn't make sense
because you have an IUD.
I had it removed.
Oh, really?
So condoms do make sense?
They do.
For who?
Check it, Peter.
I said I was looking for your letter opener.
I have other drawers, too.
Did you check these ones?
I said that I was looking...
How about over here?
Did you check this drawer?
What is it you need to hear from me?
I will never touch
another woman again.
What do you want, a prize, Peter?
It seems to be the
minimum prerequisite.
For both of us.
Then trust me.
Then don't go to work tonight.
Trust me.
But the GPS isn't the same
as the SUV in our opinion.
It's contained in the SUV
in my opinion. RIVERS:
But the data is separate
and tracked through satellite imaging...
Which is only accessed
through the SUV,
which was thrown out!
Your Honor, the GPS shows
this SUV drove right from Mr.
Dorfman's office
to the site where
the body was dumped
on the night of the murder.
You have no proof my
client was in the SUV
or at his office at those times!
This isn't about Mr.
Dorfman pulling the trigger.
We don't need to prove that,
Your Honor,
in our opinion. This is about
whether or not he was complicit
in the witness' death.
And the inference is that...
Was the GPS factory installed?
What? I don't know.
How is that relevant, Mr. Gardner?
If the GPS was installed at the factory,
it should be considered
part of the automobile regardless
of whether or not the tracking
information was pulled
from satellite technology.
The GPS was manufactured
by Botheon, Incorporated,
Your Honor.
Not General Motors.
A separate corporate entity
that uses separate satellites
that gather information.
Therefore, we should
be able to introduce
this information into evidence.
Overruled, Mr. Gardner.
The GPS data is
allowed into evidence.
We're still looking for ways
to undercut the GPS,
but we need to know:
Were you at your law
office that night?
The night of the murder? Yes.
But you didn't
talk to or see any
of the Bishop crew?
No.
Then why were they at your office?
Because this GPS has
them at your office.
I don't know. They could've been
parked there for all we know.
All "we" know? Who's we?
We.
Dad and me.
You were there?
Yes.
Okay, we'll try to do what
we can to undercut the GPS.
Thanks. Mrs. Florrick.
Could you stay a minute?
No, Tammy. We're fine.
Your daughter had
access to the witness list
and she leaked it to Bishop.
Why?
To win the case?
I had a struggling firm.
She wanted to show Bishop we
could handle his business.
And you, you knew?
Well, then that's your defense. No.
You even think of using her to free me,
and I'll confess.
She's not my client.
I am your client
and I will confess.
Eric, this... I don't
think you understand.
With that information,
Bishop will kill her.
No. He knows if he
moves against her,
I'll tell Rivers everything.
I've got some files socked away,
and attorney-client
privilege be damned.
Then what are you going to do?
Because if I found out
your daughter leaked
the witness list,
Rivers can't be far behind.
Will you take a message
to Bishop for me?
It's not a big deal.
I won't have a talk.
No scolding, no mothering, just...
I want to know.
Well, I don't tweet.
Y-you guys think that...?
Mom, this is stupid.
Don't say "stupid."
There were two IP addresses used:
the Internet at your
school and here.
I can't believe this.
This is like a police state.
Don't be melodramatic.
I'm asking you a question.
No, you're not.
You're not saying "no."
Grace, don't.
You didn't do this?
You didn't write these things?
Mom! What?
Let's at least pretend
we know what happened
here the last six months.
That was different.
We didn't tell you
about the pictures,
because they were
trying to hurt you.
It was a lie, Zach.
And not one.
It was over and over again.
But a lie like lying about
having Jews in your basement.
You know, like, with the Nazis.
Let's trust each other again.
My defenses are down.
Let's go. Just tell me.
I told you.
He did it.
That's the way he and
Becca talk all the time.
Uh, not really how I
wanted it to, but...
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I don't know...
Becca?
She's still in class.
Will you excuse us, ladies?
It's okay.
Have you got a problem?
That depends, Upriser7?
Oh, so what are you, like,
the Internet police?
No, just an interested
bystander who wants to protect
his six-figure income.
So, you and Zach talk a lot.
He talks a lot about his parents,
is that it?
Oh, no.
Have I been a bad girl? No,
dear Becca, because that would only
make you want to do it again.
You know what you've been?
Gum on the bottom of my shoe.
Spoiled little brat who
will get pregnant at 17,
have an abortion at 18
and meet some sweaty frat
boy over spring break,
and work as a dental hygienist
until the day you die.
And you...
you're a perv.
You better get your
story straight, perv.
Oh, Mr. Gold. I'm sorry.
Don't worry, Officer.
Just a daughter of
a friend of mine.
She's all right now.
Aren't you, Becca?
I'm good.
See, I have a lot of friends,
I'm sure you do, too,
but only difference is,
my friends are not in homeroom.
So I want you to listen to me.
Stop tweeting.
If you tweet,
I will know you tweet and I will...
Have you seen Drag Me to Hell?
It will be just like that.
Do you understand?
I want to hear the words.
I understand.
Good. And enjoy high school.
It really is the best
time of your life.
This way, gentlemen.
My name is Tony Gurstelle,
and I am guilty
of the murder of Kelli Gerber... WILL: Hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey!
He's surrendering himself freely!
Get out of my way!
I acted alone and with no
consultation from anybody else.
I had no access to the witness list
or any other information
other than my own.
I don't have anything
further to add...
What kind of deal did you make?
You got your murderer.
Come on, what kind of deal
did you make with Bishop?
Do you expect an answer? Really?
What kind of deals do
you make every day?
With drug dealers, killers?
I am in pursuit of the good.
You're in pursuit of
your own sanctity.
Take your suspect.
He killed your girlfriend.
You won.
You wake up with fleas, Counselor.
You pay your rent,
you go to your restaurants,
but you still wake up with fleas.
I'm firing you.
No reflection on your work.
I just feel more
comfortable with Dorfman.
And keeping the evidence
he has on you secret?
Well, that doesn't hurt.
Good work on his defense,
by the way.
Good work on your deal.
Dorfman keeps everything
he knows under wraps
and you turn over the murderer.
Well, we only ended up there
because of your defense.
Look, we can work with Dorfman
and share your business.
No, thanks.
I need an up-and-comer.
Someone who's hungry.
You don't think we're hungry?
Not like Dorfman.
Guy's a mountain climber.
Sorry it didn't work out.
So, I'm pitching our
firm to this drug dealer.
I'm telling him we'll
validate for parking again.
They don't teach you
that at law school.
And he said, no.
He said he looked at our financials
and he thinks we have a year left.
So what are we going to do?
I don't know.
Lay off Acquisitions?
Or split up.
Do you want that?
It's an option.
I take my people, you take yours.
Or we could shop for
another drug dealer.
Hey, they're the only ones
making money these days.
Or find a third partner.
How does that work?
Find a replacement for Stern.
Bring him in as equal partner.
Somebody with a client list,
some equity.
You're okay with giving up a third?
Of what, a sinking ship?
Sure.
We'll kill each other if
we don't find a referee.
A third partner?
Someone neutral,
someone we both agree on?
An optimism fills the void.
I think that's alcohol.
Just as good.
You sure? Yeah.
Come on. Let's go
before I change my mind.
Just wait.
Come on. Let's go.
Just one second.
I need to get something of mine.
* *
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com