Mommy?
Police!
-Jake, come on!
-All right, children.
Come on. Come on.
What's going on? Oh, my God!
Where are my kids? Where are my kids?
What's going on?
Oh, my God! We got kids in here!
-Control that dog!
-l'm trying.
-Where are you taking us?
-lnto that car.
What was going on in that garage?
-They was cooking something.
-lt smelled bad.
Medicine.
l had nothing to do with it!
-Do you know who this is?
-That's our mom!
-Call welfare for these kids.
-We're already on welfare.
Look, we don't know
who these people are.
My mom has nothing to do with them.
We just stayed here.
-Are they gonna put us in jail, Mom?
-What? No.
No, they're not gonna put us in jail.
They're just trying to help. Right?
Please, l don't want my kids
to see me like this. Please.
-You handle this.
-We've got no one to look after them.
-We won't cause any trouble.
-Get in the car.
Get those kids out of here now. Now.
-Okay.
-Now!
Come on. Come on.
No dog! No dog!
-Get in the car!
-No.
-Gracie, are you gonna help me or what?
-Mom!
Down, boy, down. Lay down, boy.
Gracie!
-Get in the car!
-l love you.
Come on, Spike. You can do it.
Come on. Don't slow down.
Come on, Spike!
Faster, Spike!
-Come on! Come on, Spike!
-Speed up! Don't give up!
Come on, boy!
Okay, everybody duck.
You too, Rose.
l thought we weren't stopping
until Grandma's.
l am not in the mood.
Let's make this good.
lt's just me and my daughter.
l will have the money for you in the
morning. l swear on a stack of Bibles.
-No credit card?
-Credit card?
l'm lucky to have the clothes on my ba--
These aren't even my clothes.
They're my neighbor's.
Oh, God. l must look like hell.
What exactly happened?
This crapped-out guy next door
was smoking and burned the place down.
Can you believe?
Our grandmother says that she's coming
tomorrow with money and clothes.
How early will she be here?
-Very early.
-Crack of dawn, man.
What time do you get up?
-Why?
-Because we wanna cook you breakfast.
Cook me breakfast?
Why would you do that?
Because you deserve it.
Because you're a sensitive man.
And not many people see that.
But who does?
-We do.
l wish l had long hair like you.
My hair used to be longer than this.
lt used to be down to my butt.
When you were young
and lived in Wyoming?
Yeah, when l was young.
Well, you still are young, Mom.
-That's what l like to hear.
-Yeah, Mom. Tell us about Shamire.
Oh, Shamire.
Shamire was the most beautiful horse
in the world.
-Arabian.
-All white, huh?
Oh, honey, he was pale.
He was a ghost.
-You rode bareback like an lndian.
-Oh, l was wild like an lndian.
l rode him all night long.
My hair flying out...
...Shamire snorting, tossing his head.
His hooves were galloping,
thunder in that prairie grass.
You forgot the wolves.
Oh, no. No, no, because the wolves,
they was a-howling.
And the wind, it was a-blowing.
-But you wasn't scared.
-Oh, hell, no. We didn't care.
lt was just him and me
in a dead-out run.
Oh, man, my heels were boring
into his belly.
l could feel every breath he took.
God, l could feel his heartbeat.
We were galloping forever,
never wanting to stop.
And we didn't stop until we got
all the way to Montana.
And Grandma Lou had a cow, right?
She had so many cows,
she could have had a cow farm.
Hey, hey.
Mom, we're gonna wake up the manager.
Killjoy.
Hey, Mom, when do we
get to go to Wyoming?
Soon, baby. Soon.
-ls Shamire still there?
-No, silly.
Shamire's dead like your grandpa.
Shamire lives in the barn in Wyoming.
We'd better get everybody to bed.
Okay, okay. One, four, three.
-One.
-l.
-Four.
-Love.
-Three.
-You!
All right, come on. Come on.
Are we blowing the joint?
Kids, towels, towels. Come on.
Got it?
Ready to put it in? Okay, ready?
Count of three. One, two, three.
Go, go, go.
Hey, hey! Hey, you!
Come back. You didn't pay!
Hey!
Grandma Lou! Grandma Lou!
Looks like we've got some
company, unexpected.
-Grandma!
-Oh, my Lord.
Hi, Grandma.
Oh, yeah!
-Guys, these are for Grandma's guests.
-Rowena, l hope you're not staying...
...because l've got my monthly
Bible meeting happening.
-Put that one back.
-Now, don't touch those.
-They're for the Bible ladies.
-Put it back.
Don't put it back. Eat it now
that you've got it. Don't put it back.
Nobody wants to touch food
dirty fingers have touched.
-Oh, there's sandwiches!
-Ladies, this is my family.
Ladies, go right on with your meeting.
When's the last time
these children had something to eat?
These kids have been through hell...
-...but l have so learned my lesson.
-Oh, Rowena. Oh, l've heard that before.
-l mean it.
-All right.
All right. l'm gonna do it.
l'm gonna do it.
l'm gonna help you. God help me.
But you can't stay here. No, no.
Yes, l'll help you find a place,
but that's it.
-Hi, Rose.
-Hi, Gracie.
Hi.
This is the last of my dishes.
You have cleaned me out, Rowena.
Of course, you never
take care of anything.
Look what we found by the canal.
Mine is Shadow,
and Rose's is Snowball.
Look at them.
Oh, they're so tiny and cute.
Well, now, that's all you need
is two stray cats.
l mean, how do you know
that they don't have germs?
Can we keep them?
Of course you can keep them.
They look hungry.
Why don't you go get them some milk?
And pick me up some hamburger...
...and a can of tomatoes and some paprika.
Gotta have paprika if you're gonna cook.
-Will you make Rudy's Hungarian goulash?
-l don't know, Rose. You want me to?
-Yes.
-Well, then, hell, yeah. l'm gonna make it.
Who's Rudy?
Mama...
...Rudy was a Hungarian friend of mine.
Only now he's in prison.
Which commandment did he break,
stealing or murder?
What's a commandment?
''What's a commandment?''
-The Ten Commandments--
-That God gave Moses, Rose.
Don't you know anything?
l know you never take the kids to church,
but you should get them back into school.
Tomorrow!
Damn, do l have to write it in blood?
Well, don't just stand there gawking.
Go get the milk.
-And the stuff for the goulash?
-Forget the goulash.
Yeah. Your mom's gonna be too busy
cleaning up her dishes.
Would you give them some money
for a frozen pizza?
''Rom-- Romeo, Romeo...
...wherefore art thou, Romeo?''
''Wherefore art thou, Romeo?''
She's not asking where he is.
She wants to know why he's called Romeo.
''That which we call a rose
by any other name would smell as sweet.''
Go on.
''Deny thy father...
...and refuse thy name...
...or if thy while--''
Wilt!
''Or, if thou wilt not,
be but sworn my love...
...and l'll no longer be a Capulet.''
What's your name again?
-Gracie Thompson.
-Okay, Thompson.
You ever heard of Romeo add Juliet?
l know what a Romeo is.
But the story, the play,
Romeo add Juliet...
...Shakespeare, star-crossed lovers,
West Side Story....
They're from two different families
at war with each other.
She's willing to give up everything
for him.
lmpetuous, passionate!
Do you kids have any passion?
Thank you, Mr. Bodell.
-Are you okay?
-Today sucked.
So tell me about it.
-Rose.
-Hi, Gracie.
-How was your day?
How are you?
-How you doing?
-Oh, hey, girl.
Hey, honey.
What do you think?
l think that's my T-shirt,
and it's too small for you.
-Look at the scale Mom got for us.
-Mama, l know what this is.
The police are gonna be back.
Do you think my boobs
are too small for it?
Oh, come on.
You're not upset, are you?
-l paid for it, didn't l?
-Whatever.
l want you to meet somebody.
Ray, l want you to come out
and meet my little sister, Gracie.
-Mom!
-What? He knows l'm kidding.
Anyway, people do think
we look like sisters, all the time.
-You didn't tell me Gracie was so cute.
-She is.
-How you doing?
-You are so cute.
Gracie. She's always been jealous of me.
-She should be.
-Yeah.
Gracie, you awake?
l am now.
What do you want?
l'm sorry. Can l talk to you outside
for a second?
-What?
-Well, come on.
l'm not gonna bite.
Where's my mom?
She passed out in the bedroom.
Come over here. l just wanna talk.
Kids have had a hard time.
l can see that.
Your mom, she drinks too much.
l just-- l just wanna be a friend.
l'm gonna be living here now.
Good luck.
You're a smart girl.
l could tell that right off.
The whole bunch depends on you.
l'm sorry. Did l scare you?
Hey, little girl, l know.
l know how hard it is for you.
There's no one, no one to help you...
...love you...
...there's no one to touch you.
Hey.
Oh, yeah, you are one nice, little--
You bitch.
You like that, huh?
You like it rough.
-What is going on?
-She's coming on to me!
-You liar!
-Stop it. Go to your room.
-Look at my face!
-That's enough of your smart mouth!
-l can't believe you're defending him.
-l am so sorry.
-l am sorry she got out of control.
-He is a complete sleaze.
-He could have broke my jaw, Mom.
-Don't mess this up.
He's the one.
The one what?
Gracie, l'm young. l like him.
l really like this one a lot.
Please.
What happened to you?
Wait a minute.
Who hit you?
-l walked into a door.
-Yeah, right.
Tell me what happened,
or l'll take you to the office.
What difference does it make?
l've been hit since l was born.
-Where do you come from?
-All over.
-Where ''all over''?
-All over!
Campgrounds, trailer parks, motels.
We even lived in a car.
l've been to so many schools,
l lost count after 41 .
-Did you ever tell anybody about this?
-No.
l'm gonna have to report this.
Why?
Oh, hey. Hi, girls.
Where are the boys?
Look what we got, doughnuts.
-l got doughnuts. Who wants them?
-l do. l'm starving. Can l have two?
Yeah, yeah.
We're gonna get fat.
-Mom, you're way skinny.
-l am? Am l too skinny?
-No.
-Let me see.
Turn around. Oh, that's cute.
-l got jelly for you.
-You've been gone for three days.
We had nothing but cereal.
No money, no milk.
But l don't-- l don't deserve a life?
l can't have a little fun?
You kids on my tail all the time.
Thanks.
Shadow, you meanie. You bit my finger.
Do you think mom will let us keep them?
lt won't be like Spike, huh?
-Remember that dog that my dad got us?
-Yeah.
Remember how he used to kick it?
Come on. Kids, kids, get up! Get up!
-Come on, cops.
-Mom, what's happening?
Get the kids! The cops are here!
You guys, get your stuff together!
Gracie, come on! Yo, yo, yo.
You gotta help me with these kids, man!
-The hell with the kids. l'm out of here!
-Gracie!
You have the right to remain silent.
-Come on.
-Where are you taking us?
Children can't stay with parents
who have drugs.
Please don't take my kids!
He showed up last night. l don't know him.
l swear to you,
l didn't know he had any drugs!
No! Are they gonna kill Mom?
-No, baby, they're not. She'll be back.
-Gracie, do something!
Please, Gracie!
Okay, boys, Ryan and Jonny
in the first van.
-Wait.
-You and your sister, come with me.
No, no, you can't separate us.
Just for a few days
until this gets straightened out.
-Gracie, do something!
-No, you don't understand. He's fragile.
-Ladies, don't make this worse than it is!
-Gracie, this is all your fault!
-You should have kept your mouth shut!
-Where are you taking him?
-No!
-Let go of him!
He's deathly afraid
of people he doesn't know!
-Please call my grandma!
-Ryan, Ryan, don't get in the van!
Please call my grandmother!
-Don't take him! No, no!
-Please call my grandma!
Let me go! Open the door!
Open the door!
Stop it!
You can't do this!
Get undressed.
Put your bags on the counter.
l put all your stuff in paper bags. You get
everything back when you check out.
This is for your hair. Lice.
-We don't have lice.
-You don't know.
Scrub, or l'm gonna do it for you.
Hit the showers.
Did you see her eyes?
Cat-woman.
At least this smells better
than that stuff Mom used to spray on us.
Yeah, roach spray.
How many kids in this world
get sprayed with roach poison?
lt probably got into our genes,
and our kids will be deformed.
Can you believe Mom's in jail?
They're probably spraying her too.
-That'll show her, huh?
-What goes around comes around.
-You could say that again.
Wake time is 6 a.m. Breakfast is at 7.
General clean up at 8.
You have to be washed,
combed, beds made.
You'll get your assignments for chores:
kitchen, laundry, restrooms, showers.
-Okay, you're in here. Not you.
-Wait a sec.
-We wanna be together.
-There are no beds together.
We can sleep in the same bed.
-Don't give me a hard time.
-lt's not a problem. l wanna--
-No, l wanna--
-Take her.
What are you doing?
-Let go!
-Gracie! Gracie!
-l just wanna--
-No, Rose!
Don't hurt her!
Move it!
Come on! Come on!
-Are you okay?
-lt was freezing in that horrible, little room.
-And they kept the lights on all night.
-Poor baby.
So cold in her little, padded cell.
She's so special, she got
the only single in the hall.
l don't think l can handle this, Gracie.
-She doesn't think she can handle this.
-lt's all right, Rose.
--three. Bigger! Come on, girls.
What about the boys? Do you think
they're going through this?
-Poor little Robbie.
-Poor little Robbie?
-Who's he?
-Another sister, probably.
Better toughen up, little baby.
-Want your diaper changed, stupid?
-l'm not stupid.
-Hey, Rose, don't.
-Hey, Rose, l heard your mother's in jail.
-l heard she's a hooker.
-Oh, well, look who's talking.
Fight!
Don't touch her!
Stop it!
Gracie, get off her!
Where are my brothers?
l have a right to know!
l demand to call my grandmother!
Gram.
-Oh, my little Rose. Grace. Girls.
-Why didn't you come for us?
Well, honey, l--
Nobody told me you were here.
Nobody ever called me.
Every time l called and called,
all l got was recordings.
-Oh, my God. All kinds of recordings.
-What about Robbie and Jonny and Ryan?
All of you are going to stay with me
for a while.
We'll see how it works out.
Let us try it for a while,
and l think that's good.
-Get in the car where it's warm.
-Grandma, you're using a cane.
Grandma Lou, can we please
go get our kittens?
Well, why not?
Shadow?
Here, kitties.
Your mother's still in jail.
So, what happens when she gets out?
She is not allowed to live with you kids.
She can't even see you,
and that's the deal.
Else l don't get to keep you.
l can't get the money to keep you.
Grace, Grandma's got to have some money
to feed you kids.
l got to have the help.
l can't keep cleaning up her messes.
My heart just won't take it.
l hate my mother for doing this.
-No.
-Snowball!
-Shadow?
-Rose.
-They're not here.
-l can't find them.
We'll get new ones.
Gracie!
-Gracie!
-Oh, my God! You've grown!
-l swear you've grown.
-You didn't call us.
-l had no idea where to phone.
-Those mean kids called me a retard. Am l?
-Of course not, Robbie.
-What did you do to your hair?
-Does Grandma have any hair gel?
-Maybe not, but Jell-O.
Come on!
-Hi, Grandma.
-Hi, big boy.
Oh, it's good to see you.
Get in the kitchen.
These kids are driving me nuts. Every time
l turn around, one of them's there.
Yeah, well, Robbie's fine
as long as he can see you.
This morning l went in the bathroom,
and he followed me in there.
We have to keep telling them that we're
at Grandma's and we're safe.
Yeah, which means more commandments.
''Thou shalt go to school.''
l hate school.
Gracie.
Okay, okay.
-Don't take all the covers.
-And don't wet the bed.
l won't.
Gracie.
We don't wanna be alone in there.
Just for tonight.
All right. Just be quiet.
-Grandma says we gotta say our prayers.
-Just whisper it.
Now I lay me dowd to sleep
I pray the Lord my soul to keep
If I should die before--
-You look like a bunch of little animals.
-l won't bite them.
Boys do not sleep with girls!
ls that one of those commandments?
You bet it is.
lt's God's commandment.
And you get out of this bed right now.
You go back to your room,
and you stay there. Do you hear me?
-Shouldn't you be in class?
-Lady, l gotta pick my brother up.
My name is not ''lady.'' lt's Mrs. Thurston.
l'm a counselor at this school...
...and you will help me
gather up this mess.
-l'm gonna need to talk to your parents.
-Good luck.
-lf you find my dad, l'd love to meet him.
-Don't give me attitude. l just want answers.
-Now, what about your mother?
-She's in jail.
-Who's the head of the household?
-Supposed to be my grandmother.
-Who buys the food and prepares the meals?
-l do.
You gotta do something
about your schooling.
l don't know how you made it
to the 1 2th grade.
l don't know what they discuss in class.
Thing is, your lQ tests
say something completely different.
You're just behind, but you
cannot skate through this school...
-...like your others.
-Some days l have to leave early.
l don't want to hear
about you ditching.
lt's not ditching.
l need a job to make money.
Gracie, making money is not
as important as going to school.
Now, look, l can't help you at home,
but l can make sure you do your best here.
l am doing the best that l can.
And l think you can do a lot better
if you put your mind to it.
Can l be excused?
Or whatever l'm supposed to say.
-l have to pick up my brother.
-lf you really have to pick him up, go ahead.
But listen, my friend,
you better get your act together.
All right, Wolverines.
She thinks she's so hot.
Ladies, on your marks.
Get set.
So how'd you learn to run so fast?
-Running from truant officers, l guess.
-You should be on the track team.
Yeah, the coach asked me...
...but l don't have time for this.
Yo, Tommy, out here!
-lt's only her first week here.
-What are you doing here?
My fault.
l thought she deserved a day off.
She has had plenty of days off
since she met you.
Did you help Grandma with supper?
And the boys?
Did they finish their homework?
Jonny was working
on some stupid model.
He was using toilet-paper rolls
to build columns.
He's making a model of Acropolis.
Maybe you could have helped him.
Miss, could l get a burger
and a chocolate milk shake?
lf you can pay for it.
Please. Please, please, Gracie.
He forgot his wallet.
-l forgot my wallet.
-Fine.
l'll pay, but don't come again
without your wallet.
-Please. l gotta be able to depend on you.
-Okay. Thanks, Gracie.
Hey.
You going home?
-Yeah.
-l'll give you a ride.
No. lt's not far.
And l take the bus.
My car broke down.
Guess we're going
in the same direction, though.
And don't laugh.
My mom's a psychiatrist.
-Who's laughing?
-Everybody.
She's always asking me crazy stuff.
l don't really wanna tell my mom.
So, what about you?
You haven't said anything about yourself.
-You're not giving me a chance.
-l'm a motor mouth when l'm nervous.
-l make you nervous?
-Hell, yeah.
Okay, it's your turn.
My mouth is sealed.
You asked for it.
This is my house...
...and l live here with my three
half brothers and half sister.
We're all bastards.
We have different last names, different
fathers. l haven't seen mine since l was 2.
Our mother's a drug addict,
and she's in jail right now.
We live with my grandmother
as wards of the court.
All my brothers have ADD.
Jonny has ADHD.
Attention-deficit hyperactive disorder.
Robbie, the youngest, who's a little
slower, has trouble being alone.
-Okay, is that enough?
-No.
-l mean, l'm sorry.
-Don't be.
-l'm not.
-No, l mean, l like you.
l just wanna know you.
-Come here.
-What's the matter?
l don't have time for this.
l run a zoo.
How about l give you a ride tomorrow?
-l told you, l take the bus.
-That's okay.
So tomorrow we'll both take the bus.
What?
You are knocked up,
and l'm the last person that you tell?
-l knew what you'd say.
-This is stupid.
-How are you gonna raise a kid?
-See? l knew it.
You can't quit school. Mom quit,
and look what happened to her.
l hate school.
So you're gonna live with Ricky
and then what?
Clean houses for other people?
Stay here.
We can raise the baby together.
-Oh, Lord.
-Another one won't matter.
-Rose, Ricky said to hurry it up.
-Bye, you guys.
-Rosie, make sure that boy marries you.
-Rose, wait.
We've never been separated.
Hurry it up, babe.
l am saying goodbye to my sister,
Ricky, so just can it.
Look, l know what you're thinking.
That l'm gonna end up like Mom.
But, Gracie, l love him.
l can't do this without you.
lt had to happen someday.
l'm not like you.
You can do anything.
Just take care of yourself, huh?
l'll call you.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Could you help me with my computer?
l'm having some problems.
Go away.
So how's it going?
This is right up my alley.
The Black Plague was caused by bacteria
that lived on fleas that lived on rats.
-l know about rats.
-l'm having problems with my computer.
Why don't you come over there
and just, you know....
-lf you don't, then--
-Stop it.
Something's wrong. l don't know--
l don't know what it is.
You have to clear some space.
-Just press ''escape.''
-What if l don't wanna escape?
-Gracie, that report is due tomorrow.
-l'm almost finished, Mrs. Thurston.
Yes, you are.
Jeez.
She's not that bad.
l mean, she's on my case a lot,
but it's actually kind of nice.
-You know, she cares.
-l care too.
Why don't you invite me to dinner?
Meet Grandma Lou and the kids.
lt'd be fun.
l won't bite.
-Okay.
-There it is.
-All right.
Robbie...
...we have to bless the food first.
-What do we say?
-A prayer.
Now I lay me dowd to sleep
I pray the Lord my soul to keep
If I should die before I--
Your grandma means
to have God bless the food.
-Thadk you.
-l don't know that one.
Yes, you do. Good food, good meat,
good God, let's eat.
-One, four, three!
-Mom!
Monkeys!
Where you been, Mom?
Oh, oh, hello, my monkeys!
-Did you enjoy your trip?
-Trip?
-Where you went since l've been gone.
-l would hardly call that a trip.
Hi, Mama.
-These kids been good to you?
-Yes, Rowena, they have.
Oh, that's good. That's good.
Everybody, this is Franco.
-Franco, everybody.
-How do you do?
And who is this?
You sure don't look like one of mine.
This is my friend Tommy.
Tommy. Well, l'll be.
lt looks like Gracie got lucky, huh?
Mom, would you mind if l talked
to you in the hallway?
Not at all, baby.
What you eating?
Lettuce. Franco, make yourself at home.
l'll be back.
Would you care to join us?
-l didn't know you had a boyfriend.
-He's not my boyfriend.
Whatever he is...
...he sure is hot.
You can't stay here.
What gives you the right
to tell me what to do?
Because l don't want another trip
to a youth facility.
And that's exactly what's gonna happen...
...if you and your friend
don't get out of here.
l just got out of jail, Gracie.
You don't wanna give me
a ''welcome home''?
You don't wanna give
your mama a hug?
Thank you.
l missed you.
Look, we're doing really good right now.
Please don't mess this up.
l am not gonna mess this up.
--he's got the big rig there.
vadderpool with the turdaroudd....
-Well, hey there, Tommy.
-How you doing?
-Where are you two off to?
-l'm taking Gracie to meet my folks.
Oh, yeah, and we weren't invited?
Hi. l'm as ready as l'll ever be.
You could use a little makeup
if you ask me.
-You look great.
-Thanks.
-Okay, well, good night.
-Oh, hey, hey!
Try doing something l might do.
Bye, Mrs. Larson.
-How many people live here?
-lt's not that big.
Yes, it is.
Tommy, oh, my God, my entire house
could fit in your garage.
-Do you think l need makeup?
-Will you knock it off?
Tommy, they are not gonna like me.
Listen, l like you.
They're gonna love you. Come on.
Mom, Dad!
So Tommy tells me
you have three brothers.
-And a sister.
-Older, younger?
-Younger.
-How much younger?
-She was a sophomore.
-ls this the lnquisition?
l'm just interested, Stan,
so just leave us alone.
Her name is Rose, and she's getting married
and expecting a baby.
Oh, goodness.
l hope that's not giving
you two any ideas.
-Well, l thought you wanted a grandbaby.
-l do, but not yet.
Where's the powder room?
The bathroom.
lt's through the door and to the left.
-Tommy, show Gracie.
-lt's okay. l got it.
-Gracie, how do you like your burgers?
-Cooked.
Powder room?
l keep telling your son
he has to visit some colleges...
...and make some decisions.
-What colleges are you looking into?
-l hadn't really thought about it.
Well, you'd better.
There's lots of competition.
Oh, are you still hungry?
lf no one's gonna eat them,
may l take them to my brothers?
-My grandma has a microwave--
-Of course not.
-We have some buns. We got some cookies.
-Get some containers.
-They're just little children.
-What am l supposed to do?
Rowena, l have asked you
not to smoke in my house.
Oh, okay.
That Franco fellow is upstairs
asleep on my bed...
...and little Robbie told me
that he saw you in there with him...
...doing exercises with him...
...and l know them exercises.
ln front of your own children!
What am l supposed to do?
There was no lock on the door.
Well, l'm sorry, though.
l mean, that-- Oh, God.
l don't want the kids to see me
like that, either.
l mean, what am l supposed to do?
l don't have much. He's all l've got.
Rowena, the children are so upset.
They've promised not to tell anybody that
you're here, but they're little children...
...and Robbie, he doesn't understand.
Oh, God. Your daddy,
this would just about kill him.
Listen, Rowena, that check
is gonna come tomorrow...
...and why don't you and your man
take the check.
Why don't y'all just leave,
because you know what?
lt would really be best for everybody.
-l bring nothing but misery.
-l didn't say that.
No, you did. You might as well.
Let me get Franco.
l'll get out of your hair.
Please come to Mama.
Listen to me, honey.
lf you just get back into the church....
Mom.
Why don't you admit
l should have never been born.
Oh, God. Don't say that, Rowena.
You're my baby.
Oh, God. l will not turn you out.
My sweet baby. My little baby.
Oh, my God. l love you so much.
l love you too, Mama.
Oh, my baby.
God, l love you.
We kdow your mother's
at your graddmother's.
l just have to ask you one question.
Are there any relatives
that would take you and your siblings?
Not that l know of.
We'll have to find foster homes.
You're not separating us.
We've been through that.
-lt's not juvenile hall.
-They take the kids for the money.
l'm not stupid.
-Look, l'll get my mother out of the house.
-lt won't work.
Your grandma will take her back.
-She says she won't, but she does.
-l'll take them.
l'll take them. l'll get an apartment away
from Grandma, and l'll save up my money.
-That money is for junior college.
-l can always make more.
Gracie, you're 1 7 years old.
You have to be a legal adult to be a foster
parent. You'd have to be emancipated.
l can do that?
Yeah.
Even then,
a judge would have to go for it.
-That's too much on your shoulders.
-lt has always been on my shoulders.
Look, this is a solution.
You can't separate us.
l'll be their mother.
You...
...are not their mother!
-ls this so you can get the caregiver money?
-You are doing this to get the money.
This is all a setup! She gets the money,
and she gives it to you.
Only because it belongs to me,
you bitch!
No, don't curse your daughter like that!
You shut up!
-You are not taking my kids!
-Your kids?
Just admit that you had us
for the welfare money.
Too bad you had so many miscarriages
because there would have been more!
-You go to hell!
-l was born in hell!
They are never going to give them to you.
Not to you.
Just leave...
...before l call the cops.
Oh, my little baby grandchild.
l love you.
Oh, God.
-We can run away.
-We don't have any wheels.
We could take a bus, get jobs
and find a place to live.
-Wyoming.
-We can't run away, guys.
That's how Mom deals with her problems,
by skipping town.
We have to ask the court.
You take care of us,
so why do we have to ask the court?
Judges are smart
and listen to both sides...
...and they figure out
what's best for us, right?
We already know what's best for us.
Why don't l read you guys a story.
We've read Bambi about 1 00 times.
Don't knock it.
lt's the only book we've got.
l don't think you know
what you're doing.
-You understand they must stay in school?
-Yes, sir.
You're employed part-time.
You have a work permit?
-Yes, sir. Through the school.
-This has been a very trying day.
l've had half a dozen children
who had to be placed.
Well, your school records have
certainly improved. Mrs. Thurston?
Yes, Your Honor?
You're a counselor at Gracie's school.
What's your assessment?
Gracie is doing extremely well, and l'm
also encouraging her to apply for college.
All of the children are making an effort.
Ryan and Robbie are in special day classes,
and Jonny's pulling in A's.
What happens to them
when Gracie's at work?
My grandmother can come
to my apartment after school...
...or there's foster-family daycare.
l know it's not perfect,
but it's very important to me...
...and to my brothers
that we stay together.
Where is the mother, Rowena Larson?
l talked to her yesterday.
She said she would be here.
Well, how did these children
get here today?
-Easy. We took the bus.
-You don't have a car?
We're getting one.
Look, l don't understand this money
problem with your grandmother.
She's getting $520 a month
for each child.
The thing is, Your Honor, my grandmother
gives the money to my mother.
We don't ever see it.
Gracie buys us our shoes and stuff, sir.
l mean, Your Honor.
The money would have to go
directly to you.
That's gonna make Grandma really mad.
Because my mother
will raise hell about it.
-l mean, heck.
-You don't have to worry about her.
Just worry about these kids.
You got a checking account?
-l can get one.
-What about an apartment?
l found one. lt has to be approved.
How will you handle it?
You got telephone, electricity.
These children gotta have
their own bed, dresser.
-Yes, l have the list.
-This is ridiculous.
-l'll give you a week to get it all in order.
-l can do it, judge.
Well, if you can do all that, maybe
we should give you a job around here.
Okay.
This is just temporary,
but we're gonna give it a three-month trial.
But l'm gonna be watching you. l want
reports from the doctor, the dentist...
...and copies of report cards.
This is highly unusual, but l'm giving you
a chance to keep your family together.
l hope it doesn't come back
to haunt me.
-Thank you, Judge Donner. Thank you.
-Next case.
Tough neighborhood. l don't know.
lt's better than most places we've lived,
and we can stay in the same schools.
Well...
...you're gonna have to clean it up.
l have plenty of experience
scrubbing out bathtubs and cupboards.
Well, put some pictures up.
Family stuff. Make it cozy and warm.
-l'll be back in a week.
-Does that mean you approve it?
Done.
-You did this without telling me?
-l was afraid you'd think l was nuts.
No, my parents think you're nuts.
l, on the other hand,
think you're incredible.
l didn't have a choice.
Before l know it, l'm picking out beds.
-What do you think of this one?
-lt's way too soft. You know what?
We got a twin bed in the garage.
Okay, how much money you got?
l've saved a few thousand,
and with the foster-care money--
Wait a minute. You've been saving
your money in a sock?
Yeah, underneath the mattress.
Why didn't you just put it in the bank,
you know? Earn some interest.
What's that?
The bank pays you a percentage
for the use of your money.
Free money?
That is a great, great idea.
-This thing's awesome!
-Go, Gracie, go! Go, Gracie, go!
Grandma...
...could you cut this for me
right there on that line?
Left, left, left, right, left.
-Up the stairs.
-Left, left, left, right, left.
We found a kitten!
Can we keep him, please?
Yes, we can. You all are gonna
be taking care of him, okay?
What do we call him?
-Lobo.
-That's a good name.
Okay, thank you, Jonny.
That's good enough.
What did l tell you?
We do not jump on the furniture.
Put it in the corner. Thank Mrs. Turner
when we give it back to her.
We don't have any pictures,
so what pictures do we put in the frames?
Keep the ones that are in there.
lsn't Mr. Bessey supposed to be here?
l'm late for my open house.
-Don't worry. He will be here.
-Now can we go out and play?
No, l don't want you guys
getting all dirty again.
Mr. Bessey is never late,
so something must have come up.
Okay, that's him. Okay, come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
Okay, everybody ready? Clean hands?
Elbows?
-Okay, good.
-This is such bull!
-We're gonna miss the whole thing.
-Calm down, Ryan.
Hello. l'm Sandy Jacobs.
l'm your social worker.
Hi. You know what?
There might be a mistake.
Bob Bessey, Mr. Bessey,
he's actually our social worker.
Your file's on my desk now.
That's the way it works.
Okay.
You're late.
-Sorry. Traffic.
-Yeah, right.
We have a phone.
You could've called.
They're upset because they had
an open house at school tonight.
Yeah, it started an hour ago.
Yes, well, this takes precedence
over an open house at school.
lt's very homey.
-You have gas, electricity?
-Look at our kitten, Lobo.
lt means ''wolf'' because he bites.
-We got our teeth cleaned.
-Me too.
Yes, l have the reports.
Who are these people?
Aunt Beth Ann and Uncle Mike.
-And where do they live?
-Portland.
They do?
Okay, l noticed in the report that
your Grandma Lou checks here regularly.
-We have a stable support line.
-Very stable.
And l noticed that Brian
has communication problems.
Do you mean Ryan?
Oh, yes, Ryan. Sorry.
So many families. So many children.
l don't wanna upset him.
l would rather discuss this in private.
l think you should consider
counseling for him.
That-- That's a great idea. l will do that.
Okay, well, l have to make my report
to the judge.
All in all, l would say, ''Good job.''
l'm gonna grant you
a three-month extension.
Good work, boys.
Grace, l have got to hand it to you.
You have a lot of patience.
And you're a better mother
than l ever was.
Grandma, we never could have
done all this without you.
Who drank all the milk?
lf you drink all the milk, we don't have
anything left for the week.
Why couldn't we get cereal?
Because it's too expensive.
Ryan will eat the whole box.
lt's got too much sugar.
You're hyper enough.
-Gracie, who are those guys?
-Mind your own business. Get in the car.
Down, Robbie! Get down!
Gracie! Gracie!
Stay down, Robbie!
lt's okay.
You can't give us any description
of the shooters?
You didn't notice the make,
the color of either vehicle?
l was covering up my brother.
That's all l thought about.
-Where exactly were you?
-Where were you?
Don't talk to my sister like that.
She pays taxes!
-Show some respect.
-You were caught in a crossfire.
They shot our car! Through the door,
the rear-view mirror, the windshield!
-They blew a tire off! My sister came home--
-Ryan, get a grip!
Go upstairs. l'll be up in a minute.
Now!
Excuse my brother.
He thinks he's my husband.
This is all so terrible.
You could have been killed.
Grandma!
Robbie, honey, go upstairs
and get ready for bed. Take Lobo.
Jonny will read one of the stories
we bought.
Good night, Mr. Policeman.
-You are not helping this.
-l know.
l shouldn't have said that,
but l couldn't help myself.
-l know, Grandma.
-These things were always happening...
-...to your mom.
-Gracie! l came as soon as l could.
You okay?
-What's wrong?
-l think l'm gonna puke.
Okay, you guys say your prayers?
All right. Good night.
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
-Good night.
-Good night, Tommy.
Hey.
Hi.
l can't believe you threw up
on that cop.
Yeah, it was a real projectile too.
lt was a freak accident.
lt could have happened to anybody.
lt just brings up so much old stuff,
you know, with my mommy.
lt's like nothing has changed.
You're not in that life anymore.
-lt's time we made plans.
-Plans?
Tommy, l can't even plan
on lunch next week.
l'm going to court
every time l turn around.
l'm going from social worker
to social worker.
l have to do the laundry
and the groceries by myself.
-l put shoes on their feet.
-They're getting older.
Your grandmother can take over soon.
-You're not hearing me.
-l'm hearing you, baby. Yes, l am.
Next year, we're gonna get
our own place.
l'm gonna go to Braxton.
You'll go with me.
-Tommy, l can't afford college.
-On a scholarship.
Gracie, you're getting A's and B's.
Baby, l love you.
We're gonna get through this together.
Think about you for a change.
Forget about it.
Think about it.
Right now l'm thinking
about something else.
-So, what do you think now?
-lt's very ivory-tower.
-You like?
-l like. For you.
What makes you think
they'll give me a scholarship?
-This. l went on the lnternet.
-By yourself?
Oh, very funny. Look,
foster-family scholarship application.
-All you have to do is apply. lt's a lock.
-Yeah, right.
-Do you know what a college degree means?
-More money?
No, more us.
You know, have our own kids,
start a family.
lnstant family, just add Tommy.
You want?
Yes. Tommy, l want very much.
Good.
l've never once seen you take a break.
l'm applying for a scholarship,
so wish me luck.
College? l thought you were saving
for a wedding dress.
That'll come later.
And l'm renting a wedding dress.
l'm not gonna buy anything
that l'm only gonna wear once.
Hello?
Gracie, it's for you.
Grandma.
Hi. l'm here.
lt's gonna be okay.
Rowena?
No, no, Grandma. lt's Gracie.
You're running around
without your shoes...
...like when you ride your horse.
-l told you a million times.
-No, Grandma. lt's Gracie.
l've got my shoes on.
l knew you'd come, Rowena...
...because you know
how much l love you.
You know l spoiled you.
l spoiled you when you were a little girl,
but l was too strict...
...in all the wrong ways.
Parents aren't always so smart.
But l promise,
l'm gonna make it up to you.
Oh, forgive me, Rowena, please.
You forgive your mama?
Yeah. Yeah, l forgive you.
Just rest now, okay?
Just rest because l need you.
We all need you.
Just rest.
Lord, when we hear the words
of your commandments...
...that you giveth and you taketh away...
...so often we look only at the part
that's half empty, the taketh away.
Yet, even as we are filled with sadness
for the loss of our beloved Louella...
...we are also here to celebrate
what she gave us.
Louella Larson, proud mother to a fine
and wonderful daughter, Rowena...
-...loving grandmother....
-lsn't Mom supposed to be here?
She told Rose she was coming.
--just plain Lou, although
Lou was anything but plain.
We ask you, dear Lord, to take her.
l'm starving. All l want
is chocolate all the time.
Kids!
Boys!
Oh, my God. You guys.
We couldn't find the church.
Tommy, you're still around, dude.
That's rocking.
Well, look at you.
My girls, my little girls.
My baby girls.
Hi, Mom.
Get out!
Oh, my golly.
Can you believe it?
l'm gonna be a grandma.
Poor Grandma Lou, huh?
You guys, listen. l want you
to know something, okay?
lf you want anything...
...of your grandma's, a little trinket
or keepsake, you let me know.
She didn't have much. She only had
$ 7000, which she gave me, of course...
...you know, and the house and furniture.
Listen, where are my boys?
They're outside.
-Come on, come on.
-Hey, boys, guess who's home.
Well, what's up?
Come on, Jonny, Robbie.
-Well, come on! Yeah, Robbie!
-Mama!
Hi, baby.
How's my boy? Come on.
-Jonny, let's go, man. Come on.
-Oh, Mom.
Ryan?
Come on, man.
That's the way l like to see it.
Do you think she's gonna try
and take the boys?
Who knows what she's gonna do?
l got her.
Come on.
Gracie, that guy over there,
he wants to talk to you.
Okay.
Will you cover for me? Thanks.
What can l do for you?
What you can do is get your ass
over here and give me a hug.
Who are you?
Gracie, l'm your daddy.
What's the matter?
You don't believe me?
-l don't know. l-- l can't--
-Listen...
...have you got a little place where
we could go talk for just a minute?
Come on.
Yeah.
Look at you, you're the manager.
l mean, that's fabulous.
You know, and you look real pretty,
like your mom.
You turned out great, Gracie.
No thanks to you.
There's no smoking in here.
Come on, don't be mad.
You know, l just-- l couldn't see you
because of the restraining order.
-They'd have put me in jail.
-You beat me.
No, no, no. Your mom beat you.
ls that true?
Sweetie, l've just been
thinking about you all these years...
...and waiting until you was 1 8
so that l could see you.
Have you ever heard of a phone call?
Jeez. Gracie, you know, l kind of had
some problems of my own for a while!
But, you know, the thing is,
now your mom--
She's trying to stick me
with this back child-support thing.
She's claiming that Rosie
and the boys are my kids.
Well, you know they're not, right?
So, what l need--
l just need you to sign this thing
that says that l was long gone--
This is why you came to see me?
Well, she can't get away with it,
because they're not my kids.
No, they're mine!
Good luck with your
child support, Daddy.
You guys, what is this?
Well, wake up and smell the roses.
Congratulations!
-Thank you.
-You have to stay in bed.
-Breakfast in bed, like on TV.
-Oh, my goodness. One, four, three.
-Come here.
-One, four, three, Gracie.
This looks delicious.
Jarrod Tarlatod.
Gracie Thompson.
Yeah! All right, Gracie!
All right, Gracie!
Your parents must be very proud.
Exactly.
-Gracie!
-Hey, there you are.
-Hold it. Hold it, guys. l want to get this.
-Cheese!
-Beautiful.
-l am so proud of you.
-Congratulations.
-l told you you could do it.
-Hey, there's punch in the corner.
-Gracie, Tommy, there you are.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you, Mrs. Thurston.
-Let's get a picture.
-l'm so proud of you.
l am sorry l was a pain in the ass.
l hated your guts.
Don't worry about it.
l hated yours too.
l got a job this summer
doing books for an escrow company.
This from the girl who once told me
she couldn't do math?
l'm loading numbers into a computer,
that's all.
Whatever it is, you're starting a new life
and with a new scholarship.
Now, that is the best news.
You proud of that? l can't believe it.
Boys, do you want to say hello
to Mrs. Thurston? Say hello.
Hi, Mrs. Thurston.
So when were you gonna tell me?
l don't know.
-l just got all messed up.
-You found out you got a scholarship...
...and you threw it away?
How do l go to college
and leave the boys? A few years--
Robbie's 7 years old.
That's a long time, Gracie.
Look, l just gotta know.
Do you love me or not?
Tommy, you know that l do.
Say it, Gracie.
But l can't turn my back on the boys.
Even if l wanted to, l can't.
Let somebody adopt them.
lt's a good opportunity--
lf anybody's gonna adopt them,
it's gonna be me.
Do you know what you just said?
So you're serious.
-You're gonna try and adopt them yourself?
-l don't know what l'm gonna do.
Look, the boys adore you...
-...and l know that you love them.
-l love you, damn it!
l want to be with you!
l want to marry you!
l want us to have our own kids,
not with them.
-Tommy, don't say that.
-You've got to make a choice.
Look, l'm sorry, Gracie.
l'm only 1 9.
Got my whole life ahead of me.
l can't.
Gracie, your family is ruining your life.
You don't even see it.
You expect me to take this pro bono?
l don't expect anything. l'm hoping.
-Do you know your mom will sign a release?
-l don't.
The only way she'd sign it
is if she was high on pot.
They'll assign her a lawyer.
You only get one shot in court.
You'd have to luck out
with an understanding judge.
-We had one before.
-And what about the fathers?
l don't know who half of them are.
Neither does my mother.
You have to get a hold of relatives. You
have to check out last known addresses.
You have to put ads in newspapers.
You've got to locate these people
so parental rights can be terminated.
-Ancillary costs can add up.
-l know. l'm prepared.
l went through all of this stuff
with an adoption worker.
There's little or no precedent for this.
A person as young as you--
Are you gonna help me or not?
Robbie?
Don't wrinkle it. l just ironed it.
lt's an expensive shirt.
Belonged to my boss.
Come on. We gotta get going.
We can't be late.
-lt got a big stain.
-Tuck it in and it won't show.
-Why can't we ever get anything new?
-Why don't you start mowing more lawns?
-Are you scrubbed good behind your ears?
-My hair okay?
What is that smell?
l used some of Tommy's cologne
he left in the bathroom.
-Well, you used too much.
-ls Mom gonna be there?
Come on.
All right, l want you to sit over here.
You're in charge.
Do not talk to anyone, okay?
Excuse me, while l go barf my guts out.
Would you mind if l had two of those?
-Aspirin?
-Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
l come here this morning
thinking l was doing some good...
...and they took my children away
from me.
What kind of people take babies
away from their mothers?
l don't....
Sorry.
l mean....
l hope-- l hope it works out for you.
lt's a great idea. Gracie's gonna love it.
-Hi, Gracie.
-Look who's here, Gracie.
Well, hi there, Gracie.
Hey, what do you think?
-They said l should look respectable.
-She looks pretty, doesn't she?
l do feel like my mother.
Maybe l should add more lipstick.
-You're beautiful, Mom.
-You look-- You look fine.
-Mom wants to take us to Wyoming.
-Well....
We could all go.
Gracie, you too. You're invited.
-We could start over.
-We can take Lobo.
She's gonna sell Grandma Lou's house
and buy one in Wyoming.
We're gonna have a ranch house with
cottonwood trees and a pond and a pasture.
We're gonna have a huge garden.
Because we'll grow
all of our own food, right?
Oh, and she says we're gonna have horses.
Arabian horses like Shamire.
Yes, yes, yes.
l know l wasn't a good mother...
...but like l told the boys, l loved you.
l love all of my children.
l'm gonna make up for it now.
Please don't do this.
l'll raise them like l was raised.
My parents were good Christians.
l had a good upbringing. lt's just that
l got a little off track, that's all.
-l'm in a parenting class now.
-You've only attended once.
Well, that's because l only found out
about it in the end...
...but l'm gonna go
to the next session, l swear.
Judge Marks, this is all a mistake.
l want my kids. l want to give them
a good life. l've always wanted that.
Are you prepared to get a job?
You won't raise them on welfare.
Well, l'm taking it one step at a time.
Thank you.
Will any of the children's fathers
be present here?
Oh, golly, no, no, no.
No, they owe me way too much
child support. l never had a penny.
But l will tell you that these kids
were conceived in love.
l understand, but according to the petition
signed by your daughter--
Oh, yes, l read that.
Gracie is a good kid,
but that's all she is is a kid.
lf you don't see me fit to raise the children,
they should go to families that'll help them.
No one helped them more than l.
Please. l've gone over dozens of reports
from social workers.
They'll tell you l've been the one
that's been responsible...
...for feeding and clothing them.
l get them to school. lt has always been me.
You should know that she has sex
with a boy in the--
-That is not the way it went! He loved me!
-Yes, it is!
-lt is the way it is.
-And l loved him.
Will counsel on both sides please
try to get a grip on your clients?
Miss Larson.
l'd like to call the children
to the courtroom.
Let's.
Boys, the judge wants to see you.
-Come on.
-Come on, Robbie.
Ryan Walker...
...Jonny Blicker...
...and Robbie Locascio...
...you've been sworn in,
and l've explained what that means.
Now l'm going to ask each of you
a very hard question.
Ryan, you're the eldest,
so l'm going to ask you first.
Who do you want to live with?
Ode, four, three.
l love you, Mom.
l will always love you.
l'm sorry,
but l would rather live with Gracie.
What?
Well, he's been brainwashed.
Wait, wait, wait.
-Jonny, what about you?
-Jonny. Jon, Jon, Jon. Now, look at me.
-Miss Larson!
-Look at your mother.
Clearly, she has-- She's--
She's poisoned them or brainwashed them
to be scared of me...
-Counsel, l've warned you.
-...and told them that l am bad.
l'm not bad. l'm not bad.
l'm just looking for another chance.
One more chance, please, to be
their mother. Boys, come to me.
Jonny...
...come to me, my babies.
Boys.
Boys, l know this is going
to be very difficult...
...but ignore what your mother
just said to you.
Just try and stay with your feelings.
Jonny...
...who do you want to live with?
Your Honor, we've been with Gracie
all our lives.
She feeds us and reads to us...
...and helps us with our lessons.
She fixes us up when we're hurt
and when we're scared.
That's what a mother does, right?
She changed our diapers
when we were babies.
-Mom, you know that's true.
-Robbie?
Robbie, what do you say about this?
Robbie, pay attention.
Who do you want to live with?
l would like to live in Wyoming
and ride a horse.
-Wyoming?
-Yeah, it would be fun.
Yeah, yeah.
But l would like to sleep in my own bed
and go home with Gracie.
l can take care of it.
l've been with this case
for some time now.
lt seems the children
have finally found some stability.
l don't want to disrupt that.
Miss Larson, l know you feel
pain and remorse...
...but it's all coming too late.
Parental rights are terminated.
ls that--? ls that it?
l can't see my babies anymore?
You're not my babies anymore?
Oh, God!
l love you, my boys. l love you.
l will always find you.
No matter where you go, l will find you.
l hope you know
what you're doing today.
This is a huge thing you're taking on.
There's no turning back.
These will be your children now.
l understand.
They've always been my children.
They've never been anyone else's.
Now, can we blow this joint?
-He means, are we done?
-Almost.
-Diesel, like Vin Diesel.
-That's stupid.
-Potter, like Harry.
-Guys, we gotta get serious.
We have five minutes
to come up with a last name.
-Lobo.
-That's the cat's name.
Savage.
Jonny Savage.
No, how about Weatherly?
Because we've been through
bad weather.
-Weatherly. Jonny Weatherly. Okay.
-Okay with me.
All right, Weatherly.
Weatherly, Your Honor.
Ladies and gentlemen of the courtroom,
for the record...
...l'm happy to present
the Weatherly family.
-Yes.
Gracie Weatherly...
...Ryan Weatherly...
-...Jonny Weatherly...
-Yes!
...and Robbie Weatherly.
This is a miracle. lt's a first.
l want to see you guys
when you graduate.
lt's heroic what you're doing.
l wondered, when l was
reading the case...
...if l'd make a mistake by granting this.
But l know in my heart
l've made the right decision.
-l just hope you can handle it.
-l will. l can do it.
lt's gonna be hard.
You've got your own little family now.
You can make it happen.
We are proud to present the Weatherlys!
[ENGLlSH]