Why?
Did he say anything to you?
Did he say nothing?
Why?
Isn't it strange that out
of six question words...
...the first one we think
of has no clear answer?
The questions who,
what, where...
...when and how must have
definite and correct answers...
...but "why" always gets you different
answers and raises new questions.
You can see the answers to all the other
questions, and even touch them...
...however, "why" is hidden
somewhere inside us.
Is that the reason we wonder
most about why, grandpa?
Here I am.
Look, I came.
To be able to touch your hand,
to see you with my own eyes.
To ask the greatest question
of those who stayed...
...and to learn the answer
of those who left.
Just damn this smart-ass
attitude of mine. I came to you.
Why? I miss you so much,
where are you, grandfather?
Today, you have received
your report cards. Children.
Children!
Did I say you could go?
Here they come.
Charge!
Get the fuck out
of our neighborhood.
We aren't going anywhere.
Like you own the place.
We do. You thought we were
going to turn it over to you?
- This belongs to everyone, man.
- Not everyone.
What will you do now
that school is over?
You can't go whining
to the teacher anymore.
Here, shove this up your ass.
That's vulgar.
We have our girlfriends here.
Don't cross the Namık Kemal bridge
or you will frighten the duck.
I planted a pine in your mother's pussy
and then put her on a truck.
Wonder what you will do.
You are bound to go through hour
neighborhood to buy yogurt.
You bashed his head, man!
Grandpa.
You son of a jackass.
Boy, are you never going to wise up?
What in the world are you doing
fighting with people like a rabid dog?
I come all the way
down to school to see...
...your report card and
what are you doing?
You are making war and bashing
people in the head with rocks.
But, I didn't do it.
it was Hüseyin and them.
I was just standing there.
Zip it, you liar.
Am l to believe you or my own eyes?
- You were throwing rocks.
- I threw a few, but l couldn't hit them anyway.
Man, are you the one raising hell?
Are we raising you to be an outlaw?
Just look at your knees. If a dog licked
them he wouldn't be hungry anymore.
Okay, grandpa. Let me get in the car
and you can yell at me inside.
I'm not letting you in the car.
I'm going to make you walk
all the way as a lesson for everyone.
And, by God, l won't let you ride
in the car ever again. Asshole.
But you are going to
let me wash it, right?
I talk about pretty lass and
you talk about the hair in my ass.
And he laughs, the dirty rascal!
But, look l got my report card,
grandpa.
Grandpa,
I got my report card.
What do you think we
came down here for?
Walk faster.
Keep up with the car.
But, we are downtown now.
Come on, let me get in.
And I got straight A's look.
Are you going to look?
Besides, you didn't let me
kiss your hand.
You little bastard.
Straight A's.
Math was a B but there stare all A's.
And, what do you get for
getting along with friends? Just a C.
Those are behavioral
and they don't count anyway.
One of these days,
I'm going to make them count.
If you don't get an A for your
relationship with your friends next year...
...I will take you out of school and
make you work in the garden. Hear me?
- I hear ya.
- Give me your word.
- Promise. Cross my heart and hope to die.
- We’ll see.
Are you going to give me money
for my report card, grandpa?
You pimping whore longer.
You certainly keep me in practice
when it comes to cursing and swearing.
Grandpa, did you go down
to the sea again?
Have a good day.
- Are you coming from the sea, Mr. Mehmet?
- No, we came over land in the car.
Have you received some news?
My dear Durmuş, the news is over;
we have returned to your normal programming.
Mr. Halil, I hope business is good.
Mr. Hasan, I hope business is good.
Right foot first, right!
You are going to bring bad luck to the store.
Grandpa, why don't you lock
the shop when you go out?
The shop shouldn't be
locked in the daytime...
...it would be an affront
to the neighbors.
It would seem like I didn't trust them.
It would also be impolite to the customers.
They would view the lock like a dead-end
wall and be turned off of the shop.
You will work here part time
on your vacation. Learn all of this.
Here, take this too. Go show your
report card to everyone at home.
- Come on.
- Thanks, grandpa.
Monday, you need to be at work,
Don't let me down. Got it?
Damned infidel is what he is.
And he mocks me to boot.
He's forgotten the days on his island
when he was eating snails.
Fine but what are you getting
all bent out of shape for, Durmuş?
Or, is there some account
you're trying to settle?
You are going to get beat
with a shoe if you don't watch it.
I don't know, but Uncle Mehmet
is a decent guy. And, everyone loves him.
Get the fuck out of this store.
I saw this collar on Şöhret's daughter.
I wanted one just like it.
They cut this one from a model.
I'm home!
Lord have mercy, son.
You scared me half to death.
They said they lost the pattern.
They're jealous and don't want
anyone else to have it.
Yours will be different.
I'm going to make it even better for you.
Ozan, where's the report card?
Straight A's.
I got a B in math. The rest were A's.
Well, that's our boy.
Good job, son.
You're gonna turnout alright.
Next year, bring your math up.
I'm going to the beach.
No. It's too early for that.
Stay right where you are.
Why not? School is out.
Summer is here.
Look how sweaty l’m.
It's already warm enough.
Nope. You can't go swimming
before we move to the vineyard.
Yes, you can.
Grandpa was there today.
I'm going to the beach.
I'm going to the beach. I'm going to the beach.
Oh, that's enough.
Mom, aren't my flip-flops here?
My goodness, this crazy
boy isn't going to stop.
Nadire, you shouldn't have bothered.
Saime, wait a bit, my dear,
he won't give up.
- Hello?
- Aysun.
- How're you doing, dear. This is Nurdan.
- Fine, Nurdan, how're you doing?!
I'm fine l reckon.
Connect me to Ercan's beach, will you?
Have you not moved
to the vineyard yet?!
I guess we’ll be going to the
vineyard the day after tomorrow.
I suppose you waited
for the boy's school to finish.
- I've got work to do. Put me through, if you will.
- Fine, suit yourself.
She just won't stop.
Nurdan, do you think
this looks a bit long?
- "Nurdan, do you think this looks a bit long?"
- Hush.
We still have to hem it.
That is a temporary stitch. Oh brother...
- Hello?
- Ercan. This is Nurdan.
What's up, dear?!
This boy is insisting
on going swimming.
You going to be around
to look after him?
Oh, yes, of course, don't worry.
Thanks Ercan.
I know we're putting you out.
- Don't mention it, my dear.
- Say hi to Haktan.
- Okay. You say hi for me too.
- Sure thing. I’ll tell him. Have a good day.
I'm going to the sea.
Look, at his report card dear.
Run along then and hurry back.
Go see your father too.
Remember, if you're not back
in an hour, you’ll get a whipping.
Okay. The money?
Have you already gotten
some from your grandpa?
I didn't ask him for it.
He gave it to me himself.
He said it was report card money.
You have become the
hungry dog from a rich home.
You way lay your
grandpa and then me.
Mister soldier. Mister soldier.
You have made
the semen a bit angry.
They were yelling about
when this hole is going to be filled in.
Sir, Çolak Ibrahim's sewer
has always caused problems.
They are making the complaint.
Whenever we start digging,
they yell at us to close it back up.
Then let's do this: Tell everyone to meet
at the teahouse in the town square.
- That's my boy! Hey, did you hear that?
- Yikes! Deputy, you frightened me.
Hey everyone, did you hear that?
That's my boy.
Friends, he got straight A's.
Come on, dad. Put me down.
You're embarrassing me.
That's alright. He doesn't let us
love on him. The boy is like a kitten.
Stop, stop. You've got a passenger.
Stop. You've got a passenger.
Money, please.
Ozan!
Look at that!
Grandpa was here
this morning, Ercan.
Okay, I got it and hid it when he left.
You don't need to look for it, boy.
There's no reception here.
Leave it alone, will you?
That static is giving us a headache.
Son, sit still.
Mehmet, turn that thing off, will you.
Oh brother.
I'm going to hand you
over to crazy Peruzat.
We'll let her nail
you rears to the ceiling.
Don't scare the boy like that.
She is one of our people too.
I'll be right back.
Poor woman.
May God grant patience.
I don't know they stand it here.
Her mother is a wonder too.
How old is she?
She must be in her80s.
If she would just pass on.
How can she make
it out here by herself?
It would be real tough.
They stayed here, didn't they?
They never go down from here.
Just give her to me,
dear, let her mother rest.
My dear one.
Grandpa, what drove
this woman crazy?
There are some things
that kids can't ask.
She's not crazy;
she has a different mindset.
I'll tell you about it later.
- You can't be serious, dad?
- Using language appropriate for his age.
Don't you go explaining everything?
He is confused enough as it is.
No, everything must
be explained to children.
Not only will it serve as a warning,
it will teach them about people.
And, teach them to love
and respect them.
Yeah, well he's
talking in his sleep.
- What does he say?
- He is going to take a rifle
and shoot JR in Dallas.
I did not.
But, for the love of God, is there
anybody around here in their right mind?
I don't know if it's
the water or the air
but everyone around here
is missing a few marbles.
I guess the grandson takes after us.
How could it be any other way?
Here we are.
My God! My house,
my beautiful, wonderful house.
Look at him runaway,
afraid he’ll carry bags.
You had to wait here patiently
through that long winter.
- Pick this up, son, take it.
- Hey neighbors.
- We're here. We're here.
- Take this too.
Muazzez! Emine! Yusuf!
My dear, no need to
scream like a banshee.
Son, around here they communicate
by howling like jackals.
Come on, take this.
We were irrigating.
I saw the car and came.
Dear me,
where have you been, girl?
Girl, don't just stand there yelling,
come help.
- Now we have that. Perfect.
- This is a sweet machine.
- Come on grandpa, let's me and you do it.
- Okay, hold your horses.
You have all gone completely wild.
Come on.
- Mom, we will be doing it first this year.
- Great. We'll watch.
Mother and daughter-in-law,
they're doing it.
One, two, three.
I hope the whole
summer is filled with laughter.
Isn't that right, girl?
Isn't that right, sweetie?
Mustafa.
We're back.
Alright, come on.
Let's open the bottles.
In the name of Allah,
the Merciful.
You shameless she at hens!
It's not a sin until you get to this line.
I talked with Him about it.
So, I reckon that means
you will drink half of five bottles.
Now, doesn't this look beautiful.
God bless our neighbors,
they have taken...
...a simple meal and
turned it into a feast.
Being the first day and all,
we couldn't do much.
Looks like we'll be going
to bed hungry tonight.
- Did you invite Peruzat and her family?
- I did. They'll be here for coffee.
So you've opened the bottle, Mehmet?
Well, what did you expect me to do?
Break it?
So, what's the status
on the other bottles, Mr. Mehmet?
They're on the way. On the way.
I'm full. I'm going to bed.
How could you be full?
Let him go. He'll be getting up
early tomorrow anyway.
What's the matter with you?
Do you consider yourself
better than your grandpa?
Don't be rude or l'll be
teaching you a hard lesson.
- We are Turks. Turks l tell you.
- Of course, we are. What about it?
No! You are infidels
and you support the infidels.
Fear not,
for the crimson flag...
Let me check the baby girl.
Our national anthem
must never be left unfinished!
So, let's sing it to the very end.
Fear not, for the crimson flag that...
...proudly ripples
in this glorious twilight
Shall never fade
What are we celebrating?
Good morning,
hope business goes well.
Good morning to you, sir.
I swear l didn't do anything, grandpa.
Good morning to you.
What can I do for you?
I was going to ask a favor, sir, but...
Come in to the shop.
Let's have a morning coffee.
- No, don't trouble yourself.
- Don't be silly, man.
- How do you take your coffee?
- One sugar please. If it's no trouble.
Come on, son.
What're you standing there for? Hurry.
Hasan! One medium coffee
and whatever my grandpa drinks!
Okay, coming right up.
I thought he could learn a trade.
And besides he doesn't need to be
wandering the streets like a stray dog.
If there is a need, sir,
my Tahsin would do the job.
The money's not important.
It doesn't matter
whether you give him or not.
I can vouch for my boy.
He's hard-working and well-behaved.
- He will do you right here in the shop.
- Oh my goodness. Foreman Berat.
You are a foreman, right?
If l remember correctly.
That's right, sir.
I have brought my grandson in
as an apprentice this summer, but...
May the Lord protect and preserve him.
That's alright, I understand, sir.
It would be great to have two apprentices
in the shop working together.
It has to be swept every morning.
You will pour a bit
of water on the floors.
The bucket and mop are over here.
The tap is over there.
Use this to wipe the shoes.
When a customer comes in, you have to
stand up, and say, "How can I help you?"
When they ask
for something, don't say,
"We don't have it".
You say, "We're sold out."
That's enough for now.
Ozan will explain the rest to you.
I'll be damned if l do.
When you are measuring fabric,
always give the man extra four fingers...
...and an extra finger of cologne.
First of all, we never
want to cheat anyone and secondly,
it is a gift from us to them.
When an apprentice can cut the fabric
from beginning to end in a single swipe...
...straight and clean, that is when
the apprentice becomes a journeyman.
Remember.
A single swipe without any tearing.
- Uncle Mehmet, l found 100 lira on the floor.
- Give it to me. Put it right here.
Whoever dropped
it will come back for it.
- Tahsin, go order yourselves two fruit tea.
- No, uncle, I don't want one.
Order it, I said. Now, run along.
- Did you throw that money on the floor?
- No.
My son, listen, I'm asking you nicely.
Don't make me pull you by the ear.
You think l don't know
that when you lie...
...you turn as yellow as a lemon?
Just like this.
Well, that's what you did when
you brought in a new apprentice.
I thought you had forgot.
It was just a test, you know.
What would have happened
if he had taken the money?
You would have come
and told on him, right?
Man, you think you
can give an accomplished...
...soloist singing lessons.
Get out of my sight.
Leave and don't comeback.
You'll never be a man. That's clear enough.
- Grandfather!
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Huddle up now. I have something to say.
- Hey, Ozan is here.
You remember infidel Tahsin?
He came to the shop
with his father...
...and they made my grandpa
feel sorry for them.
Now, he's an apprentice
at the shop.
You call everyone an infidel,
but your grandpa is an infidel
Is not! We are Turks! Turk!
They say your grandpa
faked your circumcision.
The foreskin is still there.
Fuck it's there.
Look at this!
You see?
They’re Turks.
If that's so, let's go to war,
we'll see who's more Turkish.
Let's see who will
break the most glass.
- You going to the immigrant neighborhood?
- To war!
Don't leave a single
window unbroken.
If you catch the girls,
pinch their tits, man!
They come and settle in our town
and the government does nothing.
They've taken over.
It's only these kids doing something about it!
Stop it. Stop.
Hey kid, do you want
some lemonade?
Hey, what are you doing here?
I thought you were apprenticing?
I work until noon.
Did you forget, oh great intellect.
Are you hungry?
Shall I put something on for you?
No. I'll have a sandwich
at the what cha-call it.
What do you mean,
'what cha-call it'?
To the sea, again?
You stay right where you are.
Not again.
I've only been once.
If you are going to be like this
at the beginning of the summer...
...we're going to be
butting heads for months, Nurdan.
How dare you talk like that?
I'll cut your tongue out.
You were the one
that said no sea...
...before we moved
out to the vineyard.
Here we are at the vineyard
so that means l can go.
Besides, I'm going to walk,
so it's free.
You make sure to tell
Ercan you are there.
- Is Ercan blind? Like he won't see that I'm there.
- I'm telling you to let him know.
If l see him,
I'll tell him and I'll tell him...
...to bring me coffee
with milk too.
You impertinent thing.
We'll see if l let you go.
Come here you little imp.
Run, boy, run!
You bastard,
no offence to your father.
Have a ground beef pita over there
at Muzaffer's. Drink ayran not cola.
Here, take this.
Take it, son.
My goodness, you're an apprentice.
Obviously, I'm going to feed you.
If you get back early,
sit in front of the shop and wait. Okay?
Okay, Uncle Mehmet.
Way to go, Mehmet.
I swear you are
how we know summer...
...has arrived.
Take a dive for me too.
- Come on, I'll take you too.
- Thanks, but l can't.
Mr. Ercan, you'll keep an eye
on my grandson, right?
Yes sir, don't you worry.
I'm keeping an eye on him.
We'll have you out to the
vineyard for dinner sometime.
Why, we'd be honored, sir.
We miss your company and our chats.
- Okay bye.
- Bye now. Have a nice day.
Stop.
The glass is going to shatter.
You're going to cut yourself.
- Stop it, you're going to break it.
- Yes, I'm going to break it.
Lord have mercy.
Aren't you ashamed of ripping that up?
Look,
I ought to tell your grandpa.
People are going to
cut their feet on this.
Liar!
I thought you were picking
these things up and keeping them.
That is something your grandfather
has enjoyed for years. Leave him alone.
- I'm not going to leave him alone.
- And, just why is that?
Because we are Turks!
- Has somebody called you an infidel, son?
- Yes, they have!
Son, if we were to look at it like that,
half the people here are infidels.
Everyone is an immigrant here.
You don't know.
Everyone mocks us.
Your grandfather is a Greek infidel.
With those bottles...
...those bottles of his.
He writes letters and sends information.
They say he is a spy.
You know those people
who greet him with a smile?
Well, they always
talk behind his back.
Ercan, do you want me to
come over tonight?
Sure, come on over, dear.
But, if it going to
be a half-ass job...
...like it was the other night,
then don't bother.
- I wasn't there. It's a lie.
- What's going on, man?
- They're raising a ruckus again.
- Shame on you, young people, don't do that.
Mr. Mehmet, I need to
have a quick chat with you.
I sent Ozan home.
Don't worry about him.
Please come in, Mr. Ercan.
Don't mind these tactless bastards.
Tahsin, you sit here.
I don't know if...
...their teachers are
teaching them this...
...or what but it's
clearly bothering him.
He cried for quite a while.
It broke my heart, Mr. Mehmet.
The poor boy is really hurting.
Apparently, they are making fun of him,
calling you an infidel from Crete.
For goodness sake.
Where does the kid get this from?
Who could possibly be mocking us?
They are the faithless,
the one who follow the pack...
...who say "Yes, sir"
to your face...
...but when you turn
your back on them...
...it turns into a different tune.
Sleeping serpents.
Plus, Ozan loves you deeply
and holds you in the highest regard...
...so you are
basically a hero to him.
As a result,
he can't stand it that
anyone would say
anything against you.
In fact, if you ask me,
that is the issue anyway.
It isn't patriotism,
it is how much he admires you.
Doesn't that just be at it all.
I'm sure this isn't something
he has communicated.
Children don't show their
affection, Mr. Mehmet.
...shot by three people.
Three bombings
last month’s led to
the evacuation of!
Especially at times like these.
These are difficult times
of testing, Mr. Mehmet.
It's not my place to tell you,
but l would say
you need to talk to your
grandson and win his heart
After all, he's just a kid.
He doesn't understand.
I'm about to pass out in here.
I've grown accustomed
to these a breezes.
Hey, Ozan. Listen.
That is the first
cicada of the summer.
Well, I'll declare.
Summer is here at last.
Hush, hush!
What'd you go and do that for?
Just because! I don't want
him chirping. My head is hurting.
Well, if you sit under the hot sun on the
beach until sun down
like a stray dog...
...your head and
your ass will both hurt.
Drink this.
Let's put some yogurt
on that back of yours.
I don't want any.
Let it burn.
Aren't you a cranky one.
Cheer up a little, man.
Muazzez and Yusuf are coming tonight.
We're going to eat together.
They come every night.
I don't want them to come.
They should eat at their own house
for a change. I've got a headache.
He has become a complete jackal.
He doesn't want people around,
the little outlaw.
Look, your grandpa's here.
Is that Mr. Ercan in the front?
It sure as heck is.
Mr. Haktan is here, too.
And he never tells us.
If we had known,
we would have been ready.
We'll have to make
do with three dishes.
- Oh my goodness, look who's here.
- Welcome. Come right in.
This crazy husband of yours
insisted, Mrs. Nadire.
He said we had to dine with you.
We went and picked up Haktan too.
Good for you.
My goodness,
the watermelons are out.
You can't come to visit the prettiest
lady in town empty-handed. Here you go.
Oh, that was so sweet.
You've embarrassed me.
- Welcome!
- Thank you!
- How are you, Haktan?
- Hi, how're you?
If we could put this in the fridge...
lf it weren't for you,
Ercan, I swear there isn't
a soul in this world
who'd bring me roses.
Come on girl.
We haven't brought you roses!
You didn't even send me a handful
of blossoms from the chaste berry tree.
Ercan, you just keep on spoiling them.
You just have to put with
their whimsical way, my dear Ibrahim.
No more chirping!
Would you like a drink?
If it's no trouble, sir.
She shouldn't have any, son.
It gets to her.
Oh mother, please. Don't interrupt.
Oh what a modern evening
this is, isn't it? I just love these parties, sir.
Peruzat, I'm Ercan.
Well, my lands, Mr. Ercan.
How are you, my dear Peruzat?
What can I say, sir?
I'm just waiting.
- Just waiting.
- I wish she hadn't had any. It gets to her.
Oh, I wish my late
husband was here.
Here's to Mr. Hüseyin.
May his ears ring.
May his ears ring,
because they hear us.
Let them know that
we have not forgotten them.
Something’s just can't be forgotten.
For example, the place of your birth.
Even the places you remember
just barely when you've grown up a bit.
Sit down over there.
Tonight, no one leaves this table.
I've taken everyone prisoner.
I'll shoot you right
between the eyes with this.
It won't kill you,
but it'll make you suffer.
What were we saying?
Oh yes, the fuzzy memories we have.
I had just turned
8. Some of it l can
still remember down to
the minutest detail...
...some of it is a bit fuzzy.
I remember a white house in Crete,
in the village of Rethimno.
You could hear the sea
from far off, Emine.
I can still hear the sound
from way back then.
There was a tavern
in the distance too.
We could hear the sound at night.
A young girl would sing.
I have no idea if the tavern
is still there or not.
Anyways. The rooms
were all white washed
and the whole place
smelled wonderfully of sea.
Always hot.
A bright yellow heat.
The cicadas would chirp constantly.
My mother had
gathered carob pods
and poured them out of her
skirt on to the floor.
My older sister and I came running.
Mustafa was still a baby in the crib.
If only you could have seen it.
It was a hell of a lot of fun.
My sister and l would share
the carob pods right away.
My father was a mason.
He was very domineering.
He would come home every night
carrying tons of food.
He was huge, he could
barely get through a door.
Missus, I'm home.
Ladies and gentlemen,
look at the camera. Smile!
Look for the birdie.
They also put Mustafa in my lap and
took a picture of the two brothers.
I was shocked to see
my own picture on paper.
Me and the baby Mustafa.
The pictures were left
behind in the house.
We couldn't take them
in the hurry to leave.
We were happy, like we are now.
May the Lord make it ever so.
Amen.
Tons of stuff got left
in that house. Tons...
In 1923, things started to heat up.
Everyone was talking about
something called the "exchange”.
Apparently, we would have to
depart these lands and leave our house.
What could we do?
You can't stop fate.
They sold and dispersed
everything they...
...had for practically nothing.
We gathered our stuff.
All the while,
my mother cried that...
...we were leaving our
neighbors and our houses.
My father said all of the
Turks were emigrating.
We left before dawn in the morning.
My mother took
the lemon tree...
...sapling from the yard
at the last minute.
It was as if she was taking
the house with her, too.
Sister.
This way, go this way,
come on, to the harbor.
Let's go toward the harbor.
Get out Turks!
Get out of our country.
Stop it Talos.
This is shameful.
Our neighbors for all these years...
Stay out of this, woman.
The Turk is never a friend.
They should thank God
we haven't killed them.
- Go in peace.
- Don't worry.
Get out Turks!
Go to the bottom of hell!
Fatma, give the
baby to Cemal, to Cemal.
Come here my child.
Move along, move along.
Children, don't be afraid.
Don't get separated.
Stay together.
We'll beat the harbor soon.
Oh Lord, help us!
Don't cry. Why are you crying?
They say a ship called Gülcemal
will come and pick us up.
They said we just need
to wait a bit longer.
We're going to our homeland.
What else could we want?
Don't cry.
Hold on. You guys wait here.
Let me ask around.
How this is going to work out,
and what will we do.
Enise, cover me so
I can nurse the baby.
- Have you wrapped the baby up tightly, Fatma?
- Yeah, I've wrapped him.
- Is it cold? Are you chilled, my son?
- No, father. I'm not.
Look how many
stars there are, father.
It's been two days.
When is this ship supposed
to arrive, Hasan?
We are running out of bread.
Should I run to the house?
Maybe get some potatoes and onions.
- We could roast it here on a fire...
- No.
You can't go.
Why?
We don't have a house
anymore, Fatma.
They would not let
us in the door.
Come on, Gülcemal.
Where are you?
Good bye, my Crete.
He has a fever.
We were some
of the first to migrate.
Later, 50 ships carried
2 million people
from here and there.
It took a whole year!
His fever is very high.
Let me talk to the captain...
...and see if he will take us inside.
What is this, Hasan?
Don't let Mehmet and
Hatice get near the baby.
Don't look.
Cemal. Take the children
somewhere else.
Come on, kids.
Let's go somewhere else.
Brother, my condolences.
Listen, Hasan.
The journey is long, the journey is long,
do you understand?
Typhus is spreading on the ship.
A typhus epidemic.
The baby... into the sea.
Come on.
Give her, sister. Let go
God is great.
He will grant you patience.
Let go, my sister.
It's providence.
Fate.
Look, Mehmet, look,
there's fish going by.
I don't know how many
days we traveled.
It was early in the morning.
It was the first time l saw lzmir.
I made the place outback for him
so that he would have a gravesite.
My brother became the Sea Boy.
Then, you know the place
they call "Quarantine" in Izmir.
We are the ones that
gave it this name.
- What's your year of birth?
- What's your year of birth?!
The doctors and
nurses spoke Turkish.
They would say,
"open your mouth"...
...and I barely understood.
I don't know how many days...
...they kept us under quarantine...
...to keep the typhus
from spreading.
They put us in the baths
and washed us down.
I was just a kid so
l was embarrassed.
I said to myself, 'They don't like us.'
Over there, we were the spawn of the Turk
and here we were Greek infidels.
It was the last time
I saw the land of Crete.
First we settled in lzmir
And they all died.
Then I came here.
Life was hard in the big city.
I was 25. I opened a shop,
spending everything we had.
Thank goodness, we found you.
You became our people
and we became yours.
I established myself
and got married late in life...
...but we are happy now.
May the Lord keep it that way.
Our family came
from Thessaloniki.
I came over in my mother's womb.
Our family came from
Thessaloniki too. I was born here.
I grew up quick.
I grew old fast as well.
But, that house...
...my childhood, it is still there.
I was never a child again, you see.
I was always curious about
who lives in that house.
I wondered if a small boy
like myself still wanders those rooms.
That is there a son that l put letters
in the bottles and send them to Crete.
So that whoever lives in that house
will know about me when
they find it and read it.
I send them greetings from here
with the little bit of Greek that l remember.
If someone even in
Chios were to find the bottle,
that's right here,
under our nose...
...they would send it on to Crete.
They will send it.
It will happen.
If someone finds those bottles
and says, "We found them,"...
...then l will believe that
all of this really happened.
That is what the bottles
are really about.
Let everyone, the ignorant
and informed alike, take note.
The people who mock and ridiculous
are the same thieving opportunists...
...who robbed us blind because
we came from abroad destitute...
...and they took our gold
and possession for a song.
Don't get me started.
Maybe one day we can all go together.
To see my house.
- To pay our respects.
- Once, you talked about going.
In fact, it was with
your son-in-law, wasn't it? Many years ago.
Yeah, yeah.
But, that's the law.
If the registry of birth was over there,
for example mine is Rethimno...
...they won't give us a visa.
We can never go back.
They said you had to find out
what the name was changed to...
...after the population exchange...
...and have your registry
corrected accordingly.
We said that's fine and I went down
with my son-in-law to the office in lzmir.
I was so happy that
we would be going,
It was a bit shaky. They might turn
us away at any moment, but anyway.
We were leaving the next day.
If it weren't for bad luck,
I'd have no luck at all.
And when Nurdan turns on the radio,
we hear about:
The invasion of Cyprus.
All of the permits and
visas were cancelled again.
What can you do?
It wasn't meant to be.
Maybe when my grandson
has grown up a bit he can take me.
He will say:
"Come on, take my arm, grandpa.
We're setting off."
Right, Ozan?
I didn't make it in time. I was putting
my daughter to bed. Are you leaving?
Mr. Ercan,
I'll drop you guys off.
That won't be necessary.
We'll just walk and take this shortcut.
Leave those alone
and come here for a minute.
Why don't you come and
help me instead?
If we don't cleanup,
the dogs will be attracted.
Let them come.
What could happen? You come too.
Okay, here I am.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
Look what l have.
At this hour?
Everyone is sleeping, you crazy fool.
We'll keep it low.
Just two songs.
Look, what l just bought.
Halil brought it from Germany.
Crystal Gayle.
You mean the lady with the
long hair that you admire so much.
I have loved one woman.
And, I loved her dearly.
This heart has no room for anyone else.
And, there never will be.
Mr. Mehmet,
I hope business is good.
Good morning, Halil,
you're early today.
Good morning.
Don't stir up the dust.
We're washing a car here.
How many times do
I have to wash it?
Do you know how to drive the car?
Yep, but l don't because
the police might catch me.
We could buy a Mercedes if we wanted,
but my grandfather doesn't like them.
He says it would be
an affront to the poor.
What in the world are you doing, man?
- Well, get out of the way, will ya.
- Fighting again?
Nope. He got a little water on him is all.
Accidentally.
Tahsin, you take the buckets.
How can I help you, ma'am?
I hope business is well Mehmet.
How're you doing?
- Thank you, my dear. Welcome.
- Thank you.
I want number 70 white Oren Bayan.
Newspaper won't work for this.
Wrap it in white paper. The ink will rub off.
You don't need to wrap it.
I'll just put it in my bag.
Here you go.
Those are two hundred and fifty lira.
Look, he know sit by heart. Hello?
This kid has passed
you up as a shop-keeper.
Thank you.
- Good day, Mehmet.
- Have a good day. Good bye.
Kids, come here.
Now, I'm going to ask you a riddle.
Let's see which of you will get it.
Put your eye right here.
Slowly, don't cut yourself.
Give it to Tahsin.
- What do you see?
- Nothing.
A white triangle.
In other words, nothing.
Look again.
There are flowers, Uncle Mehmet.
There are flowers.
Tap it on the bottom. It will change.
For goodness sake, boy.
I didn't ask you to do a strength test.
I said tap it.
Oh well, tell me
what made those flowers?
Different colors.
Now, both of you think about it.
What does this mean?
Don't tell me the answer.
Just think about it yourself.
- And, go ahead and order tea and fruit tea.
- You stay, I'll go.
Bayram, come right in.
Take these. Look, there is food
in this one and clothes in the other.
Take these out since the weather is hot.
These are for you to wear, okay?
Now, you go down to Sebahattin's bath.
I've already spoken with him.
Wash up and come back.
I'll go to the barber with you.
Do you hear, Bayram?
Okay, we'll see you later.
What are you doing now, kid?
What is eating at you?
Grandpa, don't let
Bayram come into the shop.
- And, why is that?
- He stinks to high heaven.
Now, that's enough.
You think he enjoys it?
That's enough, son.
Put it on your balls too, why don't you.
Why are you so afraid
of Bayram every time?
I'm not afraid. It's just that he looks at you
with those eyes, you know.
What is he supposed to look with?
Don't talk like that. It's a sin.
He is one of our people too.
Come right here.
Tahsin, you listen too.
You remember Peruzat?
She was the most beautiful woman
in the seaport when she was young.
She even became the
tangerine beauty queen once.
They called her
Greta Garbo Peruzat.
And, this Bayram,
he fell in love with her as a youth.
The poor thing was a half-wit sharecropper.
Quite destitute.
People were bored, of course
and said, "Let's have a little fun."
They wrote a letter that purported
to be from Peruzatto Bayram.
Of course, Peruzat had giventhem
the cold shoulder...
...and they were going to get
their revenge on her. What small minds.
They called Bayram
to the coffeehouse.
They read him the letter,
saying that she wrote it.
It was such a love letter.
They had Peruzat saying, "I'm dying,
I'm burning for you, Bayram.
Come and ask my mother
for my hand in marriage."
- Good day, Mehmet.
- Thanks dear. Goodbye.
Where were we now?
Oh yes.
Bayram brought his mother
along and the two poor souls setoff.
Greetings were
exchanged at the door.
In the end, the woman says,
"Are you crazy?"
Peruzat is studying
at a vocational school.
She is going to be a teacher...
...and doesn't have
a clue about any of this.
You need to be on
your way, neighbor.
Granny Şengül, right?
Well, she did the right thing.
You're so inconsiderate.
Of course,
Bayram was devastated.
He was angry at everyone
and never opened his mouth again.
Later Peruzat met someone
at her school and they got married.
They settled in the capital
where they were studying.
Of course, she had no clue
about what had happened here.
Her mother didn't tell her
so she wouldn't be saddened by it.
Years passed by and Peruzat
returned home full of sorrow.
She returned home.
Her husband had been arrested
because he was an anarchist.
They had interrogated
Peruzat for a while, too.
They caused the poor
woman a lot of grief.
When she returned she found out
about Bayram from her acquaintances.
So she had to bear that sadness, too.
Her husband is still in custody,
where about is unknown.
No one knows what happened.
It's the grace of God, that's for certain.
So she doesn't believe it.
She sits waiting for
her husband to return. That's how it is.
You can be sure that the evil people
do hurts worse than a scorpion bite.
All creations tarts
talking and asks for mercy.
But people have
no mercy and pass on by.
Oh, what small minds!
Oh, now that is much better.
Okay, now, let's you and
me go to the barber.
I'm going to get
my moustache trimmed.
We might as well look our best,
right Bayram?
I'll be back in half an hour.
I don't want to...
...hear a sound from you.
Behave yourselves.
- What a pity, isn't it?
- Hey! Don't talk to me.
Besides, just wait until
my grandpa comes back.
I'm going to tell him you took
the triangle and hid it.
You think I'm an idiot?
That l didn't see? You thief. I'll get you fired.
- Good day.
- Thanks, you too, ma'am.
- Uncle Mehmet?
- Yes, son?
I took this out of the trashcan
since it was just being thrown away.
- Are you crazy? I was just joking.
- Okay.
No, it's not okay.
Tell me what is going on.
You know, the flowers that
you see when you look at it.
They are similar to the flowers
where we come from.
I was small,
but l remember it a little.
My sister Kiraz, though, was a baby
when we came here.
She never saw them, that's why.
She doesn't know what it was
like and is always asking.
I was going to show her
the flowers inside and say:
"Look, this is what they were like."
That was what l was going to do.
Nothing more.
- He was going to tell on you, wasn't he?
- No, Uncle Mehmet. I swear he wasn't.
Beat it! Go home
and get out of my sight!
What's the matter with you, man?
What's the matter?
My grandpa ran me
out of the shop.
Shut up, man!
Because of that boy Tahsin?
Should we ambush him somewhere?
We'll beat the shit out of him.
He's become a total show-off.
Okay Tahsin, go have lunch.
Have a pita, or meatballs if you like.
Put it on my account.
Have dessert too.
I'm going to run into Izmir.
I'll be back in two hours.
You can open the shop.
If there is anything you can't handle,
ask Uncle Halil for help.
- Okay, son?
- Okay, Uncle Mehmet.
Great.
Hey kid! Where are you headed?
I'm headed for hell!
I'm going home, where else would I go?
And my name's not "kid".
It's Ozan. Got it?
Ozan!
Where is your husband?
I'm... I'm waiting. He'll come.
Bullshit! Your husband's an anarchist!
They killed him.
What do you think of that!
Sea Boy, I have
something to say to you.
But you won't be pleased.
Grandpa has found himself
a new grandson.
He has forgotten you too.
Did you know that?
See, you are just going
to lie there. Idiot.
He has forgotten me too.
I declare a yellow little puppy
has come to our house.
Are you talking to Mustafa?
What Mustafa! Do you think
l would talk to an empty grave?
What do you think l am?
Crazy like you?
Well, my ears were ringing.
I must have been mistaken.
You were mistaken, of course.
Go wash your ears.
I ought to rip your little penis off,
then you'll see, you bitch in heat.
What is the matter with you lately?
The older you get the
crazier you become.
Your grandpa has never forgotten
you or the Sea Boy.
But, he drove me from the shop.
I'm sure it's because
you were unruly.
I'm going to go and work
at my uncle's cinema.
What cinema?
The cinema is closed.
Doesn't he have a summer cinema?
Oh, so you'll come home at
1 o'clock in the morning.
You are going to become
a vagabond at this rate.
What is it to you if l do?
I wish I had died instead of Mustafa.
No one can die
in place of someone else.
On the contrary,
they are born to take their place.
Do you know why we
love you so much?
When you were still a baby...
...your grandpa would whisper
in your ear all the time.
He would ask God to give you the lifespan
that he took away from Mustafa.
You are a grandson and a
brother to your grandpa. Don't forget that.
That means that
when he embraces you, he is doing it twice.
You don't know these things...
...which is why you
strut around here...
...fat and lazy with
a dick no longer than...
...your balls because you haven't...
...a thing to worry about.
You just keep it up.
As soon as we find
something to be happy about,
you hit us on the head with a stick.
Grandma.
Yes, my child.
- What does "on the contrary" mean?
- It means your mama's poontang.
- What does poontang mean?
- What is going on? No one can sleep.
Who did you have this child with?
The boy's demon-possessed.
I'm going to have an imam with clout pray
over you. Otherwise, it's hopeless.
He's going to strangle us in our sleep
when he grows up a bit.
Help me, neighbors.
I can't get Peruzat under control.
What's the matter, girl?
Ozan, quick. Go up to your sister
so she doesn't wakeup.
What is the matter?
It scared us to death.
Is that Peruzat?
OneDrima, 5 meters of curtain backing,
80 centimeters clean skirt fabric.
Uncle Halil cut it with the scissors.
It will be put on Ayşe Durmaz's bill.
She didn't pay.
Good job, Tahsin.
You are going to be alright. Look.
There was also a really
old lady stopped by.
I said, "How can I help you?"
She said, "You wouldn't know," and left.
That's okay. I'm sure it's nothing.
Here, take this.
When you leave tonight,
take it to her sister.
Peruzat, it's okay now.
It's okay, sister.
Peruzat. Open your hand for me.
You have made a fist and I can't open it.
I wonder if we could give her Diazepem?
Should I bring some?
Not without being sure.
Let me make a phone call from Halim's.
We'll have the doctor come
and give her a shot or something.
That would be best.
Run, Muazzez, run.
Okay. Hand it to me, neighbor.
I wonder why
it happened so suddenly?
Your grandson just kept saying,
'Your husband died."
And she just threw herself down.
Ozan!
Bayram, what happened?
What happened to the kid?
What happened?
Did he fall?
They've busted his head, the bastards.
Hurry, put him in the car.
- Halil Usta, close up the shop!
- Okay.
Ozan. Don't run off!
Come here!
You know what
I'm going to do to you?
Are you trying to kill somebody?
Nurse, call a doctor right away.
Ozan!
Ozan, where are you, fool?
Look, I'm not going to beat you.
I won't.
Okay, you might get you rear pulled
a bit, but that is all.
Ozan!
We gave him three stitches, Mehmet.
Your apprentice is fit as a fiddle.
He'll be just fine.
They are children.
What can you do?
Does he have a childhood left,
Hamide, my dear.
Does he have a childhood
left anymore. What is this?
Oh, Mehmet, sir.
Foreman Berat.
Sorry about all of this, man.
Thank you, sir.
Can I see him?
- My dear son. What's happened to you?
- Nothing, dad. I'm fine.
Who did this, son, tell me.
Uncle Mehmet, I swear, it wasn't Ozan.
He wasn't there.
Then who was it?
Spit it out.
And what am l asking for.
Who else?
Obviously, it is that other
pack of bastards.
I don't know.
Sorry, l won't touch it again.
Stop crying. We'll find him.
He's around here somewhere.
If he is here,
he should come out then.
There are jackals and wolves.
They'll eat my boy.
Give me a break.
Do you think we live in the Amazon?
- Aren't there any wild boars?
- You are right.
- Ozan.
He's not over
by our place either.
Have you looked over by the
old chaste berry tree?
I've looked everywhere.
Ibrahim, hang on, this won't do.
Let's make a plan and
search methodically.
That's right. We shouldn't all pileup
in the same place. Oh, Emine.
Emine.
You don't reckon
he'd go to the sea again, do you?
If he had,
Ercan would've grabbed him
by the ear,
and brought him back by now.
- Where is Mehmet Bey?
- You look in the vineyard rows.
I'll go out on the road.
I'll go to police for the last resort.
The little bastard is probably hiding
and doing this on purpose, the little beast.
Don't call him a beast, lbo.
Look, my hands are shaking.
Son, are you crazy?
Where are you going?
I'm going to lzmir.
I'm gonna find a job.
I'm gonna work.
I don't want you.
I wasn't gonna hit you, son.
- Would I ever hit you?
- You hit me once before.
I did hit you once, yes.
Come here. That's my man!
Aren't you afraid
all by yourself out here?
What kind of kid are you?
- I don't understand.
- Why should I be afraid?
Turks are the most fearless people
in the world.
Good for you, then.
I can even let my hands go if l want.
Hold on, you’ll fall off!
What he needs is a sound beating,
but we aren't used to that as it's not our way.
Let it go. It frightened him.
Let's not make it worse.
Well, alright. Good night everyone.
Those sons of asses you call
friends busted Tahsin's head open.
You were clearly the cause.
You pushed Peruzat over the edge
just for the heck of it.
And on top of that you
ran away from home.
What do you have
up your sleeve next?
Why don't you
go ahead and kill us?
You would be rid
of us and we of you.
- You live here and we live in glory.
- Father.
Hang on, Ibrahim.
This discussion is going to take place.
He has come to his senses.
This has gone too far.
He's never known poverty or difficulty.
He's never gotten a beating from
any of us, so what's his problem?
We have dropped
everything to take care of him.
What is it that you want, kid?
Answer me.
You could string him up by his toenails
and he would still be a wall.
He's gonna talk! He'll talk
if we have to sit here until the sun rises.
Why are you like this, son?
Why are you acting
so wickedly, son?
- I'm not wicked.
- You are wicked.
I am not.
A wicked man will not say
he is wicked. He won't believe it.
He has already seared his conscience
and he doesn't even know it.
Listen to me.
I'm telling you.
Your heart is wicked.
Stop this childishness, grow up
and screw your head on straight.
My friends don't like
the people you do.
They are different.
Not like you.
I'm the one that is all alone.
Am I to have no friends?
Everyone does it.
You think it's just me?
You keep talking
about the good old days.
About your homes and your people,
but l have nothing.
What am l to do?
What about me!
Am I to live all alone?
The wind kicked up again today.
But Lord, it's like a furnace.
- Did you slice tomatoes, mom?
- What do you think l am doing?
Just look at my husband.
10 eggs, is that enough?
I don't know. Wait till they come.
If it's not enough, we'll make more.
Look here, the little
prince has arrived.
A little prince has awoken
and is looking at us from over there.
My goodness,
but isn't he handsome.
I made the scrambled eggs
and tomatoes that my son loves so much.
- Without peppers.
- You're kidding. Don't we get any?
I don't know.
If Ozan says it's alright, I'll give you some.
- Son?
- Is grandpa gone?
- He's left.
- Today's Sunday?
Come on, let's wash our faces.
The devils probably licked
your face until sunrise.
Down you go.
Come on, wash your face.
Lean over, lean over.
Stick your head under there.
But, it's cold dad. Come on.
- Ozan, your grandpa is taking us to the sea.
- Ozan, we're here.
We're going to the beach,
to the beach!
Alright! Bless my soul.
Good morning.
Sit down everyone.
There were three
more kids but they must
have fallen out of the
car along the way.
Bankruptcy!
The locusts have come for our crops.
Nadire. If we run out of molasses,
we have Hüsey in here.
We can bust his head
and let it ooze out, for a change.
We're here.
Hold on!
Everyone will stay
between me and the beach. No further.
Who made these
stuffed bell peppers?
You can't beat Nadire's
stuffed bell peppers.
Eat some pastry, eat up.
Mehmet. Good day.
I hope your business is good.
Good day, Mrs. Güssün.
I hope it's just as good for you.
I stopped by the other day.
You were out.
Why don't you get my burial shroud ready?
Then, I'll be on my way.
Hold on, Sister Güssün.
It's a bit early for that.
What's the matter?
Well, the time is
approaching, Mehmet.
I thought I’d come and get it
while I could still get out and about.
- I'd feel better if l got it taken care of.
- Goodness gracious, Sister Güssün.
Well, you just get
my package ready.
You see, I'm running
off to my husband.
Whatever you say. Have a seat.
Would you like tea or coffee?
Make it tea.
Coffee aggravates my heart condition.
In the name of God,
the Merciful.
This time it has to be done
without scissors. Look and learn.
You can't use scissors
on a burial shroud.
It has to be done by hand.
These are so that the dead
smell good when they are buried.
This is the interesting part of this job.
Learn this.
Do you know what they
do with this cotton?
He was not born
and He doesn't give birth!
Is the tea for you, Sister Güssün?
- Here you go.
- Yes, it is. Thank you.
Did you come to buy
a new dress and shoes.
You know, something flashy.
Hush, you dog.
What would I do with a dress?
I'm just getting some stuff.
- How's your mother doing?
- She's as well as could be expected.
Give her my greetings.
Your jackass got
loose the other day.
He got into my garden and
ate every flower l have.
Now, my garden is poor and barren.
You bring some new ones
and plant them by fall.
Oh, of course.
I have nothing else to do anyway.
Shut up. I'll bust your head.
Bring some saplings
and we'll plant them together.
Good, sister. Enjoy your tea.
- Hope business is well.
- Thanks, Hasan.
Here you go, Ms. Güssün.
This is yours.
- Is this it now?
- Yes
Take this too.
Look, it just came in.
It is beautiful. Roses and leaves.
First, you make yourself
a pair of trousers from these.
Wear it happily until it wears out.
And finally this.
May the Lord delay the end.
Thanks. How much is it?
Well, we don't charge for this.
You must have forgotten.
- You don't charge?
- No. That is the tradition.
OK, fine.
May the Lord give you
and your grandson a long life.
Thanks very much.
Their faces have all been
erased from my memory.
Well, Ozan. You need to grow up
and take us with you across the sea.
I never forgot that look.
The long summer ended right there,
for you and me both.
And right after the first cicada too.
What is the yearning for?
Will you tell me?
Was that the day
you made your decision.
That hot afternoon? In the middle of the day?
In the summer?
It was not the thousands of stories...
proverbs and pieces
of advice that raised me.
It was that look of yours.
That look l couldn't understand.
You.
The you I couldn't understand.
Hey kid!
Would you like some lemonade?
Do you like it, my little prince?
Who is the man?
A guest.
Somebody I've been expecting.
Is he coming to your house?
Yep. The length of the road symbolizes
the length of the wait, sir.
The luludia flowers he is carrying
represent hope and happiness.
Do you like metaphors, little prince?
I do.
Is that a suitcase in the distance?
Did he leave it there?
Bravo. You immediately understood
what l wanted to express.
Bravo.
You immediately understood
what l wanted to express.
I don't like suitcases.
They are very depressing.
They remind one
of returning and departing.
He has left it behind because
he will never need it again.
Then, he must be coming to stay?
- Like for good.
- Now you deserve a kiss.
It's for good.
That is such a nice expression.
For good.
Grandma, what is a metaphor?
They happen at sea
and when a storm comes up...
...they spin and pull ships
and people down under.
That's not right.
Mom what is a metaphor?
I sit something like camphor?
You know, the stuff they
use in cough medicine?
No, it's not.
Meta is a Greek word.
It means "later". And, "for" is English,
so it must mean, "for later."
Dad, grandpa.
What does metaphor mean?
Metaphor. It means
to compare one thing to another.
For example, if l were to say that
my heart is an oyster
and you are the pearl...
...then, l am comparing my heart
to an oyster and my love to a pearl.
He hears it all the time on television.
Metaphor, schmetaphor.
Forget it. Today, I made a decision.
God help us.
As soon as summer
is over and before school...
...opens we will go
on a family vacation.
Where, dad?
First, we will go
by plane to Athens...
...and then take a ferry
from there to Crete.
Fantastic.
As you know,
we can get our passports now.
What's the matter? You are looking
at me like you just saw a ghost.
We are going to travel.
Is that so bad?
The shop has tied us down.
For example, have you
ever boarded a ferryboat, darling?
No, l was on a rowboat once.
- That doesn't count.
- But, what about the baby, dad?
She'll come too.
Right, my little princess?
Of course.
Ozan?
Good for you, boy.
What about it, Nadire?
Weren't you the one
who saw those senior
British tourists and said,
"They know how to live"...
...the one who said they were
seventy years old but still trucking?
Stand up for a minute
and rouse yourself a bit.
By God, you're talking now,
Mehmet.
Let's go for real.
We should go see some people.
Those infidels won't
kill us there, will they?
- Grandpa is here!
- Don't yell.
- Welcome home, grandpa.
- Good to be here.
Man, no shoes and no hat,
get inside.
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
Come on, their mom
says dinner is ready.
Mom! Grandma
is calling you to dinner.
No need to shout.
We're coming!
Put that in the fridge, darling.
- Is that bottle back again?
- Was it hidden before?
What's the matter? We kept the
fast all summer for Him above.
Now Ramadan is over.
We have to look
out for ourselves a bit.
Lord have mercy.
You're going to be struck down one day.
He knows my heart,
so nothing bad is going to happen.
- Besides, we are celebrating tonight.
- What celebration?
What do you mean,
what celebration?
We've got them for all of us.
We leave next week.
How in the world are we going to
get ready in one week, Mehmet?
Oh brother. It's just a suitcase.
Did you think we were moving?
But, it is a bit shaky.
They could turn us away
at the border at any time.
Our situation is a bit complex,
you know, our place of birth and all.
Maybe we should've stayed
at the vineyard a bit longer.
It's still awfully hot.
There is a James Stewart film tonight.
Mr. Smith Goes to Washington.
Why is he going, grandpa?
Huh, grandpa?
- Yes.
- I asked why he is going?
I don't know, son.
We'll watch it and find out.
Why were you so
preoccupied that night
when you were so close
to realizing your dream?
I remember that you were
always a restless spirit
at the grape harvest.
But that year...
All by himself against
the whole Congress.
That is what it means to be an idealist.
Good for him.
It was a different
restlessness, wasn't it?
Something only l noticed.
Maybe l was making up.
Who knows, maybe you were
going to say damn it all,
let's go, fall in line,
we're out of here...
...but as always,
my wonderful country
is full of fresh surprises
that robust of...
...the opportunity to
reflect even for a moment.
Just like an
adventure comic book.
- What's going on?
- Oh my, good news I hope?
- What's happened, father?
- Nadire just got up to wash for prayers.
Dad, has something
happened to mother?
No. Don't worry.
She turned on the radio.
There has been a coup, son.
What!
Easy son, take it easy.
...9th Army Corps commander
Sabahattin Cambazoglu...
...the provinces of Erzurum,
Agri, Kars...
Well, dad, the anarchists
are done for. Isn't that better?
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Ibrahim! Ibrahim!
Way to go Kenan Pasha.
Have they come for us?
- Dad. There's a military vehicle coming.
- The books, Nurdan. The books.
Hold your horses, now.
Let's see what they want.
How can I help you, son?
- Are you Ibrahim Erdinç,
the deputy mayor? – Yes l am.
You will come with us.
Why are you taking him?
What has my husband done?
Okay, Nurdan. Everything's fine.
It's obviously for questioning.
- I'll come too.
- Not you, sir.
What do you mean not me?
Dad. Just cool it.
Nothing's going to happen.
They just want to ask questions.
I'll come too.
There is a curfew. They told us
to bring the deputy mayor, only him.
Come on, man.
I can't walk in the neighborhood
I've lived in for 40 years?
What small minds!
- Mister, don't give us trouble.
- Don't start with the 'mister'.
- We respect the army, but don't piss me off.
- Get inside mister!
Father.
Welcome,
Mr. Mehmet, welcome.
Thanks.
- Ozan, how are you?
- I'm fine.
Welcome, Mr. Mehmet
How're you Ozan?
School opens tomorrow.
We thought we ought...
...to come down once
more with the boy.
Good idea.
Just look how empty the place is.
There is not much
to enjoy around here.
Autumn has come
early this year.
Yeah, the joy has
gone out of everything.
- What can l offer you?
- I'll have some tea if it's no trouble.
Right away Mr. Mehmet.
Of course, your vacation
has gone up in smoke.
Forget the vacation, Mr. Ercan.
- Just look at what they've done.
- What's happened?
They aren't pressuring
Ibrahim too much, are they?
No, they just keep asking
him about this and that.
He just says he doesn't
know anything about it.
They call him down there
every morning like it's a regular job.
Now, they are removing
the mayor from his post.
They say the military
junta will appoint a new mayor.
Ibrahim will keep his job,
but it won't be easy.
Still, it's not too
bad around here.
Istanbul and Ankara
are something else-total turmoil.
Death sentences have been issued
for several young men.
There is so much suffering.
I can't even talk about it.
We are cannibalistically
eating our own young, like a crocodile.
We just couldn't
get your haircut.
Teacher won't say anything
on the first day.
Stop it, Ozan. Stop it, son.
You're wearing me out.
You're in the 5th grade now.
I did that on purpose
to make you laugh.
And, one on this cheek
for your dad. Come on.
- Is Dad not getting up?
- He came home very late, son.
And, our apprentice is here too.
Give half of it to Tahsin.
I don't have change,
but it is for both of you.
My goodness,
is this little angle your sister?
Goon then. May the Lord
give you all a sharp mind.
Look, Ozan, this is my sister Kiraz.
She is starting first grade.
Kiraz? What a name?
I'm glad to meet you.
My name is Armut.
- Is the first grade hard?
- Very hard!
I told you it was easy.
Why don't you believe me?
My teacher's name is Necla.
Is she nice?
Man, you are in for it.
She'll beat you black and blue.
Just joking. She is really nice.
Never beats anyone.
That is what
my brother said too.
He also told me, "You have two
older brothers at school me and Ozan."
Here they come.
Greetings friends.
Thank you, thank you.
Which of you is Ibrahim Erdinç?
That would be me.
Pleased to meet you.
I look forward to receiving
all of the personnel...
...in my office in half an
hour for introductions.
- Good day.
- Thank you.
Mr. Ibrahim, come to my office.
Let's not waste any time.
You and I have a lot to do.
It sure looks that way.
This room, sir.
And, just what is this?
Why isn't this gone?
There hasn't been time since
everything happened so quickly.
They only told us your name yesterday.
We are just taking care of it.
Taking care of it, ey?
We are going to have to get used to
how you talk around here.
...In spite of what is commonly
held to be true...
...this word is never used around here
or in the Aegean region, sir.
It is an expression
of affirmation...
...that is used in other
areas of the country.
Unfortunately,
it is a word that poor theater script...
...writers unfamiliar with
the Aegean dialect...
...have used on state television
programs and in village plays.
You know,
how they have this idea...
...that every villager
absolutely must use it.
They told me you were clever.
No matter, I came well-supplied.
Well, since they don't use 'ey' here...
...and, since you can,
when you want, employ your...
...pure Turkish perfectly,
then you'll say, "yes".
I am delighted to say "yes"
to everything that is right, sir.
Where have you been, Ibrahim.
I hope you eat your own bullshit.
Getup, Ibrahim.
Be quiet, for God's sake.
I don't have the strength.
He knew how to
conduct a fair fight.
But, he had no weapon
for a dirty one.
He didn't know how
to wage those battles.
He had probably always thought
that the world was a place full of dignity.
That was true for both of you.
Then, one day you looked around...
...and saw that those
beautiful people...
...had got on their beautiful
horses and ridden off.
Now, this place they
call Partridge Island.
It seems like a pretty
destitute place.
- Miss Ayşen.
- Yes, sir.
Prepare a report describing
the characteristics
of this region and send it
to the ministry of culture.
Mr. Gürkan, that would be a death knell
for all of the beaches there.
Most of the locals make
their living from fishing.
We would destroy both
the beaches and the fishing.
From there search
we have conducted...
...a chain of hotels in that area...
...would harm the environment, and pollution.
- Do you have a better idea?
We are researching it, sir.
For three months
you have opposed...
...everyone of my initiatives.
I'm tired of it.
You are the deputy mayor
not the opposition.
You are supposed to be
making my job easier.
But we haven't moved forward
an inch in three months thanks to you.
This country has failed
to develop because of the...
...backward mentality
of people like you.
We have to develop and grow.
There is no other way.
I have no objection to that.
But, if what you call
development means...
...turning over the
beaches to your friends
in parliament for a song,
well l object to that.
Effective immediately,
you no longer work for the city.
Empty your office and
get the hell out of here.
I would have resigned long ago...
...but l didn't want to leave
the place to jackals like you.
But, don't forget the power
of the people, Mr. Mayor.
They may have a thing or two
to say about all this.
But, they didn't.
Or, if they did, we didn't hear it.
Not even a whisper.
If you remember,
my father was sued for
issuing a threat, abuse of power
and other things.
Ibrahim,
what are you doing here?
I'm sitting.
Come inside and sit then.
They are selling the country,
Nurdan.
Selling it piece by piece.
Whoever heard of such
brazen shamelessness.
Not a single person
stood up for me either.
Cowards!
Ibrahim, for the love of God, don't yell.
Let them sell it.
Let them all starve to death.
Whatever happens will
happen to them and
they'll all be beating their
heads against the wall.
Are you saying the
same thing, Nurdan?
What can I do, Ibrahim?
What do you want me to say?
We have children.
I'm thinking of them,
not a world of strangers.
We aren't hungry, we aren't homeless.
You can get another job.
I can make clothes again.
It'll all workout.
What do I care about
everybody else?
So, that is the kind of country
we leave to our children?
How will we look them in the eye?
What will we say to them?
Are we just going to say:
"Sorry, kids. We couldn't do it.
And, if you want to
make it in this life
you're going to have to be
a thief and a fraud."
- I'm sorry, dad.
- That's alright, son.
Listen...
...we have a shop here.
- Dad, don't say that.
Hang on. Don't interrupt me.
You have this house. We have a vineyard.
You have me and Nadire.
Above all, you have a wife
and two kids here.
Right now, they are your country, son.
First, realize their value.
You have done what you could for
your country and done it for years.
Now, it's up to them.
Seeing that some people
don't deserve it...
...there is nothing you can do.
But, don't turn your back
on the people who do.
Come and take care
of your family.
You're right, dad.
You always said they
are our people.
And we are theirs.
Well, where are they, dad?
Are they hiding?
Who knows, maybe they are.
But, one day
they will certainly come out of hiding.
- How can I help you, Mehmet?
- I'm going to see the mayor.
- Do you have a rendezvous?
- Rendezvous?
That's what you have with a lover, son.
I came to see the mayor.
You can't see him
without an appointment.
Listen here. Aren't you
the son of Resul, the machinist?
- Yeah, that's me.
- Don't you recognize me, son?
Are you a guard here now?
Who are you protecting and from whom?
I'm going to talk to the
mayor not shoot him.
What is all this noise, man?
Come, right in.
Thanks. I'll stand.
Ibrahim Erdinçis my son-in-law, mayor.
My name is Mehmet Yavaş.
Yes?
I have come to you alone
and of my own free will.
No one knows anything about this.
I'm going to ask you a favor.
You are going to ask me
to bring your son-in-law back.
No.
I want you to drop the lawsuits
that have been filed against him.
Why should I drop the suits?
Because my son-in-law
is not the sort of person...
...who would abuse his office
or threaten others. I can vouch for him.
So you will vouch for him.
And just who are you?
Why should I believe you?
If there is a 65-year-old man
standing in front of you...
...who has never asked a favor of anyone,
then I reckon what he says can be believed.
Sir, you know nothing about us.
Thank the Lord, we have never had to
depend on anyone all these years.
My son-in-law does
not need a job here.
But, making slanderous
accusations against...
...a fellow and
sullying his reputation...
...is an affront to his rights.
I'm not going to tell you
how to do your job.
I'm sure you got over-enthusiastic.
But, we are people who have lived
for years by a code of honor.
This is more than we can bear.
So, when you get in trouble...
...you always garner pity
with talk about honor and reputation.
- The same old story.
- Always the same?
This is the first time
I have stepped through that door.
This is the first time that
I have ever had to say this to anyone.
Or, maybe you are confusing
me with someone else.
Okay, sir, okay.
Go on about your business.
Look, I've got work to do,
leave me alone.
Mr. Mayor, your work is the public.
And, since I am a member of the public,
I am your work.
Alright, sir, alright.
Where were you, man?
Didn't you hear the bell, man?
- Show this gentleman out.
- Come on, Uncle Mehmet.
Hold on, son. What are you doing?
You might as well beat me.
- Mehmet, come on now.
- Leave me alone.
I'll show myself out!
I have one last
thing to say to you.
This atrocity is going to
come back to haunt you.
And, let me tell you,
there will be no place for you to hide.
What is this Tuncer? Do you have
one of these buttons in your office too?
Do all of you coming running...
...like a dog when the mayor
pushes a button?
- Mehmet, that's shameful talk.
- No, shame on you, shame on all of you.
What small minds!
Damn you! Go to hell.
Ibrahim
- It's alright. He's fine now.
- What? Tell me the truth.
He's fine, mom.
Come here, mom.
Calm down ladies.
There's no need to be upset.
Why did you bring Ozan?
Take him out, man!
He heard about it at home and came.
What could I do?
Why doesn't grandpa
want me around?
That's crazy
He didn't want you to be frightened.
Why? Why would I be
afraid of my grandpa?
Everything's fine, Ozan.
Tonight we'll go home and
it will all be over, son.
Your grandpa is just feeling
a bit faint, that's all.
There's nothing to fear, son.
One shouldn't complain
about their blessings...
...but this damn stuff
is inedible without oil or salt.
No, sir. You have to eat it.
And you have to take these too.
Fine, but do you have to scold me
like a little kid?
Look, the salad will
add some variety.
The food is just like everything else:
No taste or flavor.
I've eaten so many greens,
I think l will soon turn into a goat.
I'll be climbing the
walls of the house and...
...perching on the
TV before you know it.
Come here.
Uncle Ercan found you on the shore.
On the telephone,
he said you had drowned.
Your "drowning"
was like a bad joke.
No one believed it but they didn't
want to consider any other possibility.
My mother was
looking for proof of...
...what it was she had
to come to grips with.
She wanted to put a period
at the end to finish it.
Because, as you know,
finished sentences...
...are less painful
than unfinished ones.
Or, did you believe
exactly the opposite?
In commas?
Is that so?
Don't come, Saime.
For the love of God, go back inside.
Daddy.
Nurdan.
Nurdan, please stop.
I beg you, stop.
Brother Ibrahim, if you'll let me,
I'll take Ozan and the kids.
They can play together.
They shouldn't hang around here.
I'll bring them back tonight
when things have calmed down a bit.
In the letter,
you held no one responsible,
you apologized to all of us,
but said:
"I can no longer live in
a world like this."
You said that you
loved me very much...
...but that you would rather die
and get it over with while still alive...
...than die bit by bit
right before my eyes.
You hoped that one day
I would understand.
Did you write this right
where the two seas meet
right between going and
not being able to go?
According to my mother, 'with a fountain
pen and in beautiful handwriting."
Then you dragged almost
the whole town behind you.
You started a game
of hide-n-seek and...
...tagged them all,
so they all came out of hiding.
All of your people.
And what a coming out it was.
Stop that, Muslim people,
that is a sin.
Take it, son.
Hang on. It should touch
the ground first. Throw it on, child.
The angel on your right
shoulder will mark it down...
...as a good deed about
as much as the sand grains.
May the Lord give you the days that
He took from your grandfather.
If you were to ask today,
they might say...
...this is too traumatic
for children.
I don't know what is right.
But, we confronted...
...everything we faced.
That is how we grew up.
If he is there with you,
why don't you ask that angel...
...if he marked me down for a good deed
as much as the sand grains.
No matter if he did or not...
...but you and your people are
what made me who I am.
May the sin and the merit
hang around all of our necks.
They are your people.
Of course, with a genuine
and heartfelt humility.
The people to whom
we belong as well.
Ladies can't come,
keep your distance.
What kind of a funeral is this,
anyhow?
Luludia will suit him perfectly.
Come here, Ozan.
Let's see if you can
find the metaphor in this painting.
- I sit grandpa's hand?
- Bravo, Ozan.
Will the deceased
always wave his...
...hand at us from
up there on the wall?
What did my grandma say?
We don't know if it's
the water or the air...
...but everyone around
here is missing a few marbles.
But l haven't told you the most
amazing news yet.
Maybe you won't believe it.
I can only take refuge
in this very cliché expression.
Nothing is as surprising as life itself.
- How are you, Nadire?
- Thank you, son.
- There is a package for Mehmet Yavaş.
- Who's it from?
Well, the name is foreign.
It says Eleonora.
That's clearly a woman's name.
What? A woman?
What are you saying, mister?
- Look, you gotta sign right here.
- I'm not signing that.
And, l won't take
the package either.
- That's okay. It's not a problem.
- Mom, just hang on a second, will ya?
I know ya'll.
I'll just leave it right here.
- I can sign it myself, you know.
- Hang on. Bring it here.
My hand is shaking from laughing
so hard. I can't even sign it.
- There, is that okay.
- Sure, that's fine.
- Here. Give that to me.
- Here, I'll take that.
- How about that?
- Good bye.
- I'm opening it.
- Open it!
What in the world is this?
May the Lord take...
...my life and rescue me
from the shame.
A whore sends
flowers to our house.
Oh my, you are not done
with your surprises.
Hang on just a second, mom.
It is written in Turkish!
- It has a few mistakes, but it is Turkish.
- Read it then, sir.
What does it say?
"Hello.
My name is Eleonora Theodorakis.
The bottle you sent us...
...are found by some neighbors,
Mr. Mehmet.
From the description you gave,
you were born in our house.
A neighbor who knows a bit of
Turkish is writing the letter now.
After you left, my father-in-law
bought this house.
I moved in as a daughter-in-law.
We have been here for 35 years.
My husband passed away
two years ago.
As you say,
may Allah have mercy.
The children work in Athens.
One in Limni.
One of them is married.
One is not.
I live alone in Crete.
I would love to have you come
someday and be my guest.
I'm writing an address below,
both in Latin and Greek letters.
I'm also writing
a telephone number below.
It's Mr. Todor's
bed and breakfast.
He knows a bit of Turkish.
Before you come, call him
and have him let me know.
Wishing health and happiness...
...to you Mehmet and
greetings to your family.
I am sending a bottle of ouzo
as the gift of a neighbor.
I hope you enjoy it,
my neighbor."
No. I mean,
it's just a normal bottle, of course.
Look, the seal has
never been broken.
You can never be sure.
They're Greeks after all.
What if they injected the poison
with a syringe and didn't open it.
Come on now.
There is a letter.
So, they had it written.
Damn,
it does look good though.
Damn sure does.
Why don't we have
the mayor drink it first?
If nothing happens to him,
we can continue.
Ozan Erdinç.
Years had passed after receiving
Eleonora's letter.
Our family just kept putting off...
...accepting the invitation
for various reasons.
My father's lawsuit,
which went on...
...for years,
but which he finally won.
The pain in
my grandmother's legs.
Nihal's school and
many more excuses.
Even years later when we called
Mr. Todor's bed and breakfast...
...and learned that the
woman was still living...
...and still expecting us,
they still didn't come with me
Either they had
become really weary...
...or they were unable
to face fresh disappointment.
And that's right, you heard correctly.
I have embarked on the journey.
Are these the waters
you crossed through...
...a thousand perils,
where you left your baby brother?
Are these the waters that defied us
and separated us; this haughty...
...and magnificent sea
that we loved even un to death?
Actually, if you had wanted,
you could...
...gotten over your hang ups
and come anytime.
But, I don't think you ever wanted to.
You just wanted to think that
everything you remembered...
...all of those crumbs of happiness,
were still there,
unchanged after all these years.
Holding on to your
own truth like Peruzat.
It's just like those
valuable crystal glasses...
...and have sat there for years...
...never used with the fear that
they would get broken...
...but always with the
hope of using them someday.
It's time for you metaphors
to get out of my head.
- You are Ozan, right?
- I am Mehmet's grandson, Ozan.
My dear.
Welcome.
Great.
I have been waiting
for you since morning.
Here you go.
Look what I've made.
Stuffed grape leaves.
Cucumbers and yoghurt. Salad.
Eat up, young man.
- These are gifts from my mother.
- She shouldn't have troubled herself.
Thank you very much.
It's so beautiful.
Just wait, I'll be right back.
Something’s your family left.
My father-in-law found this first.
He said to keep it. Perhaps the person
who left it will come and get it, he said.
We found this too.
This must be your grandfather.
Grandpa.
That's life. What can you do?
Tavern? Tavern?
Yes
They start playing
in the evening. Listen.
They're playing "Gülbahar."
It's a beautiful song.
Everything is just like you left it, grandpa.
Nothing has changed.
This happy ending is for you.
I am sending a message...
...to you from the other
side of the same sea.
From the beach in front
of the white house.
All of the things that have transpired
since you left are in this letter.
The Sea Boy
will deliver this bottle to you.
Maybe, before that,
he will stop by my country...
...to pick up a prayer
for you from our people.
When you receive the letter,
greet the angels.
Say, "That's my grandson.
The little fellow grew up
and came like I asked him to."
Come on, Ozan!
Come on!
In memory of my grandfather
Mehmet Yavas