Subtitles by DramaFever
- How about we write a book together?
- Are you interested in me?
I feel like my head
is going to explode.
You finally look
like an anchor now.
You've grown up a lot while I was gone.
Cha Ki Young's world is gone now.
How dare you bring home a low-class,
uneducated girl like that! Marriage?
I don't want to get married either!
Cha Ki Young! I swear,
I'll kill you if you show yourself!
Reporter Park, what should I help you with?
Go! What do you want?
- I can't get an abortion.
- Call your future husband.
I almost killed my baby once!
How can I do it again?
Do you want me to date
a cheap girl like Hyun Myung Yi?
I won't forgive you!
- She's pregnant.
- It's true that she's pregnant. Is it yours?
- Are you crazy!
- Come quickly! Cha Ki Young!
I got a sperm donation and
am now successfully pregnant.
[Episode 5]
I want a child more than I want a husband.
That's why I went to a sperm bank
and received a sperm donation.
I am now successfully pregnant.
Anchor Cha, which hospital did
you get the sperm donation from?
No comment.
- Are you stepping down from your job?
- No.
There is no clause written
in the station's policy
that states I must step down
if I become pregnant.
That's what you were planning?
Anchor Jo, when did you first find out
about Anchor Cha's pregnancy?
There are pictures of you carrying
Anchor Cha to the hospital.
- How do you explain this situation?
- Get out of my way!
Stop!
Get out. I said get out!
A sperm bank? Are you joking right now?
You think I don't know that you're
trying to hide the identity of the father?
I feel so relieved.
I think my nausea is finally going away.
Do you think the broadcasting station
and the institution of marriage is a joke?
You're done for. I'm going to destroy you.
- Anchor Cha! Please say something!
- Who is the father?
I... am currently three months pregnant.
That's why... I went to a sperm
bank and received a sperm donation.
I am now successfully pregnant.
Oh no! I'm late!
- You think she'll get fired?
- Her career is over.
- Are you just getting in?
- I had to go to the hospital.
Has anyone gotten
hold of Anchor Cha yet?
Yes, we had no idea she was pregnant.
- I swear, I'm going to go nuts.
- Hello?
If we don't tread carefully, the whole
news team is going to get fired, too!
We have no idea what's going on either.
Who is the baby's father?
- Isn't she your daughter?
- Yes, she is.
I am currently three months pregnant.
I want a child more
than I want a husband.
That's why... I went to a sperm
bank and received a sperm donation.
I am now successfully pregnant.
Excuse me, but I can't release
a patient's information.
It's illegal and unethical.
Look here, which newspaper
do you work for?
Asking these kind of questions is illegal!
The reporters have been calling, and
I was wondering what was going on.
One of my nurses showed me a
recording of your press conference.
Director, a mass of reporters
are gathered outside.
Kick them out and lock the doors.
Unplug all the phone lines as well.
Yes, Sir.
I'm sorry you have to go through
this because of me, Il Jong.
Why did you say that
you got a sperm donation?
It's not very favorable for me
to marry the baby's father.
You think his family won't
do anything when they find out?
It's not only the baby's father.
Besides you, nobody would stand for it.
Regardless of the situation, it's my job
to encourage women to have babies.
What's your reason for trying
to have a baby this way?
I'm following my instincts
for the first time in my life.
I'm sure I'll get hurt quite a bit.
It doesn't matter if I get hurt.
I just don't want my baby to get hurt.
Please help me.
Are you asking me to say that you got
the sperm donation from our hospital?
I'm sorry... but please
do that for me, Il Jong.
Legally and by policy...
I won't confirm or deny it.
Is that good enough?
- Open the door!
- Is the doctor inside?
- It's Anchor Cha!
- Anchor Cha!
Which hospital did you get
the sperm donation from?
I have to go and relay the news right now.
Please get out of my way!
- Are you going to announce the news today?
- Of course.
Work and being pregnant
are two different issues.
It's not a normal pregnancy. Do you think
the broadcasting station will accept it?
Why is my pregnancy not considered normal?
Are you saying it's a crime for a
woman to have a child on her own?
Our country was ranked having
the lowest birth rate in the world.
I don't think that's a question
a reporter should be asking.
- It's not that...
- Anchor Cha! Anchor Cha!
Anchor Cha! Just a moment!
Will you be stepping down
as an anchor then?
I...
[Hyun Myung Yi]
Reporter Park, did you see the press
conference on Anchor Cha's pregnancy?
How could something like
this have happened.
I was certain Anchor Cha
aborted the baby.
I followed her and saw everything.
Where is Cha Ki Young right now?
We haven't been able to get a hold
of her after her press conference.
Her phone is turned off as well.
What are we going to do about
the evening news tonight?
Let's fire her, President Seo.
In any case, the board
members have all agreed
that letting her go
is the best decision.
As time goes by and the viewers start
to sympathize with Cha Ki Young...
It will be difficult to fire her.
Don't you think the women's group or
her fan club will interfere on her behalf?
In order for the viewers
to forget Cha Ki Young
we have to fire her right away.
What about Cha Ki Young's successor?
Ever since the rumors
of Cha Ki Young's pregnancy
Anchor Jo has been preparing someone to
take her place. Her name is Kang Young Joo.
[Anchor Cha Ki Young declared herself
a single mother by sperm donation!]
815... don't be scared.
If anyone gets hurt, it'll only be me.
You just tuck yourself away in
my stomach. I'll protect you.
Something like this won't kill us.
Go back! Please go back!
- Anchor Cha is here, Anchor Cha is here.
- What?
[Announcer Kang Young Joo
promoted to nine o'clock news.]
Hello.
Is the cue sheet out?
- Not yet.
- What about the news articles?
You didn't see the announcement board yet?
Bring the cue sheet and the news articles
to the dressing room when it comes out.
Did she not see the announcement board?
What's wrong with her?
She did something crazy, but she
really must have lost her mind.
She's not our anchor anymore.
Hey, Cha Ki Young is
getting ready right now?
Yes.
She's not preparing to
announce the news, is she?
Maybe she really didn't get a chance
to see the personnel appointment.
Go get that announcement letter
and show it Cha Ki Young this instant!
Anchor Cha is preparing herself right now.
Hey, go somewhere else to put your makeup
on, and prepare to announce the news.
I don't want any one of you
to show Cha Ki Young the cue
sheet or the news articles!
Did you get the news
articles and the cue sheet?
- Right here.
- The first impression is very important.
- You can't make a mistake! Get going!
- Yes, Sir.
Park Tae Young, what brings you here?
You don't do interviews.
You're just a food reporter.
- Open the door!
- You can't interview her right now!
What is it?
Is... Myung Yi inside?
No.
- Have you seen her?
- No.
If you see her... please tell
her to call me as soon as possible.
Sure.
Why are you looking for Hyun Myung Yi?
[Starting today, I will be the nine o'clock
news anchor. My name is Kang Young Joo.]
- Anchor Cha is coming!
- What? What are you talking about?
- Didn't we change anchors?
- What are you talking about?
Is the news not out yet?
[Personnel Appointment]
The news, not this!
Anchor Cha, I'm sorry
that this has to happen.
But, as you can see, there has
been a change in personnel.
Are those the news articles?
I'm sorry, but I can't give them to you.
Director, what should we do?
Should we drag her out?
Just what the heck is going on right now?
I'll go and take care of it
personally, President Seo.
Yes, Ho Pyung?
I thought you took care of Cha Ki Young!
Just what are you doing?
I got it, Ho Pyung. That stupid idiot!
- Eun Cha!
- Kang Young Joo, you follow me.
Move.
Don't embarrass yourself by getting
dragged out of here in front of everyone.
Try and protect whatever pride
you have that's left over.
Anchor Cha, this is the last of my pride.
I thought very highly of you.
But, is this how you repay
the station that raised you?
By stabbing us in the back?
Director, I sincerely apologize
for this inconvenience.
Take the chair away.
I'll send you to study abroad, so go
over there and have your baby quietly.
Then I'll reinstate you.
I thought of doing that many times.
However, I don't want to run away and hide
like a criminal in order to have my baby.
Because it's not a crime to have
baby without getting married.
So, you're saying you will
continue to relay the new?
While your stomach is growing?
Yes, that's what I would like to do.
New personnel has already been announced!
In the meantime, go home for today,
and let's talk about it again tomorrow.
I would like to protect my position today.
Will someone please bring me my chair?
Hey, Park Tae Young.
You're not worth it. Go!
It's five minutes before we go live.
President Seo, what should we do?
What are you guys doing?
Hurry and drag Cha Ki Young out!
Kang Young Joo, go and take her place.
- Let's go.
- Don't do this.
- Let go! Let go of me!
- Let's go.
- Let go of me!
- You have to leave!
- Let's go!
- Why are you doing this?
- Leave!
- Let's go!
Are you okay?
President Seo, this isn't
going to work out.
It's two minutes
before we go live.
Let her announce the news for today.
I will personally make sure
that Cha Ki Young
walks out of here on her own.
Are you sure? You promised!
Yes, President Seo!
Hyun Myung Yi! Hurry up and bring
Cha Ki Young's chair! Quickly!
Everyone go back to their positions!
Quickly!
Ten seconds before we're on air!
Where is the chair! Just bring
whatever you can find! Quickly!
- Will this be fine?
- It's fine! Put it in there!
Standby!
Hello, this is Channel Korea with your
nine o'clock news. This is Cha Ki Young...
and Jo Eun Cha.
Our government made
a formal complaint
in connection to the revoked
statement of apology
of the crimes committed towards our
women during wartime against Japan.
Reporter Oh Dong Shik
has the details of the story.
Director, what should we do now?
They say happiness plays a huge factor
in order to live freely among the public.
You said everything was taken
care of with that child, right?
Yes.
I want a child more
than I want a husband.
That's why I went to a sperm bank
and received a sperm donation.
- I am now successfully pregnant.
- What is this now?
Welcome.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I hope you have a good night.
This was Channel Korea with your nine
o'clock news. My name is Cha Ki Young...
and Jo Eun Cha.
We've headed over to commercial.
Good job, everyone.
- This is no joke.
- What a mess.
I told Hyun Myung Yi to bring the chair.
Where did she disappear to?
- I don't know.
- How is the bulletin board?
The server has crashed
and the SNS is no joke.
Photos of Cha Ki Young was ranked first
and her declaration of being a single
mother was ranked second on the internet.
Cha Ki Young has been the talk of
the town today. Are you pregnant too?
I ate like crazy today.
I'm throwing up on purpose because
I'm afraid I'll gain weight.
Why did you buy so much clothes?
You told me to wear cheap clothes.
You said you hated cheap clothes.
You said you have to wear designer
clothes if you want to meet a rich man.
Yoo Ri, can you introduce
me to a guy? Someone decent.
- Did you fail to seduce Park Tae Young?
- Yeah.
Why?
Since I'm a knockoff, I wasn't able
to handle a luxury brand like him..
I got indigestion, so I gave up.
Since I'm lacking, too
much luxury is a burden.
So, introduce me to a mid-grade brand.
Among all the doctors and lawyers
take out the men who were raised in Gangnam
and graduated from ivy league colleges.
Someone from the country.
A simple, country bumpkin.
You know... a man who was raised in the
country and doesn't know women very well.
Someone who lives by himself
in a seven hundred square foot studio.
They have potential, but they're
men who are easy to manipulate.
To Seoul please.
We're in Damyang County.
I know, so hurry up and take me to Seoul.
Hey.
I want to see you. Are you home?
- Go ahead and talk.
- I want to talk to you face to face.
Come up.
I thought I should see you
at least once and tell you.
About what?
I'm sorry.
This is what I wanted to say to you.
Why would you be sorry towards me?
I liked you.
But, I decided that marrying
you would be difficult.
If I become a part of your family, I would
have to completely throw myself away
and become an empty shell.
That was difficult for me to do.
I have no idea what it is that
you're trying to say to me.
It would be hard for me to have
the baby if your family finds out.
And even if I did...
I felt like they would have
taken the baby away from me.
If it's about your baby,
I'm not interested.
Go back.
- Yes, Father?
- Is Cha Ki Young's baby your baby?
It isn't mine.
Then what in the world is going on?
It hasn't been long since that
crazy wench came to our house.
What kind of nonsense is
she blabbering on the news?
I don't know too much about that either.
I'm in the middle of a meeting right now.
I'll call you later.
If you have nothing more
to say, can you leave?
Make sure your parents understand.
- About what?
- That it wasn't your baby.
It's not mine!
You're right, so please
tell that to your parents.
Even if by chance that
sperm did belong to me...
It has nothing to do with me!
Because you already aborted my baby.
815, the world...
is a lot colder than I thought.
I went to Choi Il Jong's
maternity clinic to confirm
if Cha Ki Young's sperm donation was true.
Man, they are completely
tight-lipped over there.
That hospital...
belongs to the husband of
Announcer Na Yoon Hee
Cha Ki Young's best friend.
- So what?
- What do you mean so what?
They could have lied
and conspired together.
So, are you saying that Cha Ki Young
might have a secret boyfriend?
I can't believe you're a
paparazzi with that brain of yours.
This... did you take it?
- No. A man named Pedro took it.
- Pedro?
- Who is Pedro?
- He's a freelancer.
Ah, I have his number.
I got you.
Coming.
I'm coming.
Is the baby's father inside?
No.
Where did you hide him?
Ki Young, it's fine that you're pregnant.
Where is the man?
- I don't have one.
- Why don't you have a man?
What are you going to do?
Let's abort it, okay?
- I don't want to.
- What are you going to do then?
- I'm going to have it.
- Oh my gosh, you've lost your mind.
You're not even married! How could you
say that you're going to have a baby!
Let's go and abort it
first thing tomorrow.
You can have a baby
after you get married.
- I don't want to get married.
- Then you have to abort the baby!
I can't do that!
Then... let's just kill ourselves!
Mom!
- Mom! Don't do this! Mom!
- Let go of me, you brat!
Do you think I'm able to
think clearly right now?
How can I live when I'm too embarrassed
to even lift my head back home?
- It's better to just die!
- What's wrong with you? Don't do this!
Let go! Let go of me!
I can't go on living! I just can't!
Let's go and abort the baby
right away tomorrow.
Even when you were married
to someone like Dad
you said you couldn't leave him
because of your children!
Then why can't you understand
where I'm coming from?
What's to become of your life
if you go through with this?
I raised you so well!
How could you destroy your own life?
How? How could you do this?
You've lost your mind, haven't you?
You're not in your right mind, right?
What do you think you're doing?
It's better to just kill yourself
if you're going to have the baby!
Mom!
Just die!
Mom.
Mom!
I have to go to work.
The news won't be aired until the evening.
What's the point of going out this early?
People are doing everything
they can to get rid of me.
I need to go and protect my spot.
Unbelievable.
A woman is following her
instinct to have her baby.
Who do they think they
are to interfere?
- You should eat before you go.
- I'm fine. I don't have an appetite.
You say you're pregnant, but you're
going around and starving yourself.
I'll be back, Mom.
I'm not going anywhere
until you abort the baby.
My poor baby.
What are we going to do now?
What are we going to do?
It's Jo Eun Cha!
What can I help you with?
- He's so handsome!
- He's so good-looking!
It's fine.
We're from Yeo Heng Man.
Please give this to the president.
But, where exactly is Yeo Heng Man at?
Tada!
We're a support group that advocates
a woman's right to be happy.
I swear!
The broadcasting station
isn't a place where
anyone can just come
and go as they please.
Please leave! Go away! Leave!
We have over ten thousand
members in our group.
If Anchor Cha gets kicked out,
you, Jo Eun Cha
will be branded as a man who
trampled a woman's happiness
and become the number one person
on every woman's blacklist. Got it?
By any chance,
is Park Sun Nyeo also a member?
Who is Park Sun Nyeo?
Do you know her?
Didn't Park Sun Nyeo send you ladies here?
We don't know a Park Sung Nyeo.
- We don't know her!
- We're from Yeo Heng Man!
The scariest thing in this whole
world are middle-aged women.
But what's even scarier than
them are feminists. Feminists!
One of the women's group
sent a statement
saying that they are
supporting Cha Ki Young.
I'm going crazy.
- What were the ratings for last night?
- Yes, Sir.
It went up five percent.
[Nine o'clock News
Overall Ranking and Rating]
The news is the least of everyone’s concern.
The people are more interested in whether
or not Cha Ki Young is announcing the news.
Even so, the ratings can't continue
to rise because of her scandal.
The elderly and male viewers
are throwing a fit
and demanding that
we fire Cha Ki Young.
The female viewers and people
in their twenties and thirties
made a fan cafe on the internet.
And they're continuing to support her.
Of course we should we fire her.
She's a woman who's not even married.
To watch her relay the news while
her stomach gets bigger everyday?
We can't allow that.
Jo Eun Cha.
You promised me that you would
have Cha Ki Young quit voluntarily.
She came to the station since
dawn to protect her position again.
Jo Eun Cha, what are you going to do?
If only we can find the man
who donated the sperm to her.
What are you talking about?
President Seo.
Do you honestly think the meticulous
and flawless Cha Ki Young
would accept a sperm donation from
a faceless man and become pregnant?
Then...
Did you guys see Cha Ki Young's
press conference yesterday?
Yeah, I thought she was awesome.
She relayed the news with such confidence.
She's amazing, but she still has her phone
turned off. I can't get a hold of her.
It's probably turned off because
the reporters won't leave her alone.
'Talk and Taste' is going to be a huge hit.
It's almost as if someone knew we
would be launching our book soon.
and they just decided
to promote it for us.
The birth of A Korean Angelina Jolie!
Editor, what do you think
about this headline?
It's awesome. We'll easily sell
a hundred thousand books.
Right?
Stop overreacting and focus
on preparing the book launch.
It's totally useless if
Cha Ki Young decided
to cut off all contact
and keep silent.
- Continue to call her.
- Yes, Ma'am.
- Check ahead and find out where she lives.
Got it?
- Hello?
- Is this Pedro?
Who are you?
Reporter Jo Nam Chul from Deep Focus
gave me your number to call you.
He said you have pictures of
Jo Eun Cha and Cha Ki Young
going in and out of the hospital.
Will ten million won be
enough for that picture?
Ten million won?
Wait a minute.
- You know me, don't you?
- Who are you?
You're Park Sun Nyeo's boyfriend.
No, I'm not.
Seeing how good-looking you are,
you're a player, aren't you?
How much are you getting paid to do this?
Watch what you say.
Ah, my back! You bastard!
Stop right there! You bastard!
What is this?
The doctor said it's going to take
two weeks for me to completely recover.
Because your boyfriend
inflicted bodily harm onto me.
Sun Nyeo.
I'm not the father of Cha Ki Young's baby.
You're a legend in the journalism world.
Have you lost your touch?
An exclusive article of
you and Cha Ki Young
is going to be
published this month.
You are the only woman for me.
Why won't you acknowledge
my feelings for you?
My boyfriend is going to
get angry if he finds out
that we're even talking
to each other!
What? You mean that
naive and innocent punk?
Ah, seriously.
Honey, it's me...
By any chance, did you hurt Jo Eun Cha?
I'll take care of the hospital bill
this time, but don't do that again.
Honey, his body is totally
different from yours.
He won't heal because he's so old.
It's just a waste of hospital fees.
So, hold it in from now on, okay? Promise?
Right now?
Okay, baby.
Okay, baby?
My boyfriend said if he doesn't see
me everyday, he'll get a brain tumor.
One centimeter at a time.
I swear!
What is this?
[Talk and Taste]
Park Tae Young and Cha Ki Young
are publishing a book together?
They're publishing a book together
but they're acting like
they don't know each other.
I got you.
Hey, Prosecutor Park.
I need a favor from you.
Yes. I'm counting on you.
A place where she can
abort it quietly without
having to worry about
rumors being spread.
Make sure they know what they're doing.
I plan on taking her this Saturday.
Welcome.
I'd like to lease my studio.
Why... you worked so hard to get
it and it hasn't even been a year.
Hey, Sun Nyeo.
Are you the father of Cha Ki Young's baby?
No.
Then it's true, Jo Eun Cha is the father.
- What are you talking about?
- Hey.
Don't you know that she
cheated on you with Jo Eun Cha?
Why do you think she accepted
him as a double anchor?
It's because they had something
going on between them!
I'm busy so hang up.
Whether it's a lease or monthly basis,
I'd like to move out as soon as possible.
Sure, I understand.
Do you have anything
open on the tenth floor?
- I do, but it's a little expensive.
- The price doesn't matter.
The water pipes are also broken.
There's quite a bit that needs to be fixed.
That's not a problem, just fix it.
Anchor Cha Ki Young lives on the 11th
floor and she's very sensitive to noise.
A song writer who used to live on that
floor moved because she complained so much.
Well, I only cook, so it should be fine.
Cooking doesn't make any noise. Now,
let's sign a contract for the tenth floor.
Really?
But...
You're absolutely sure that Anchor
Cha Ki Young lives on the eleventh floor?
Of course!
Are you Anchor Cha Ki Young?
Chairman Park Kang Rok
would like to see you.
I'm working right now.
She said to let her know ahead
of time if you want to see her.
- What?
- But...
she's busy this month so
she can't make time for you.
Unbelievable! Honey, just
what in the world did you do?
- Tae Yun.
- Why are you crawling back in again?
- I'm moving in indefinitely, Father.
- Says who?
I've completely broken up
with Cha Ki Young.
Just what in the world did that
crazy girl mean with her words?
She got what from what bank?
You crazy fools!
- Please sit down.
- Bunch of crazy idiots!
Please sit down. Sit down.
Goodness.
You still haven't ate, right?
It's been awhile since we've
shared a meal together as a family.
I'll call Sun Nyeo to come home early.
Go up to your room and get some rest.
Eat it while it's still hot.
Is it good?
Even though I'm from the country,
I'm quite ahead of the times.
If you were the daughter of a farmer...
I might have applauded you.
Is it necessary to get
married in this day and age?
I know too.
I know, but...
because you're my child...
my head and heart are telling
me two different things.
Why is that?
The pain you will have to go
through after you have that child...
Just thinking about that pain...
It breaks my heart.
I feel the most sorry towards you.
Making sure that I marry well...
I know that was your only hope.
I made an appointment this
Saturday at a hospital in Damyang.
Mom, I feel like I'm going
to die if I abort the baby.
If you have that baby...
I feel like I'm going to die!
- It's not Tae Yun's baby, Father.
- Then why did he bring her home?
You know Tae Yun always
does whatever he wants.
If it's not your baby,
isn't that girl really crazy then?
I mean, she came here to introduce
herself so she could marry you.
And now she's pregnant
by going to a sperm bank?
- Why...
- Father.
I don't think Tae Yun is the father.
I think her personal life has
always been complicated.
There are pictures of her being carried
inside the hospital by a different man.
If not, she would've used
the baby as an excuse
and tried to trap Tae Yun into marriage.
Why would she announce that she
got pregnant from a sperm donation?
I'm pretty sure she said that because she
can't reveal the identity of the father.
Or maybe he's married.
What?
Hey, that's why you ended
it with Cha Ki Young, right?
Stop talking about her.
You stupid fool! Of all the women out
there, you picked a crazy woman like that?
Sit down.
Your father's not done eating.
Why is it that both of our children
are always lacking in some way?
We have one who brings home a crazy woman!
And an idiot who is almost
forty years old and still single!
I'm going to get married.
Who is it this time?
A woman that you and
mother are pleased with.
Will we be able to live
separately once we get married?
No. We'll have to live with my
parents until they pass away.
I'm the only son since
the last four generations.
Eleven memorial services
are held every year.
You'll have to wash my seriously prickly
and abnormal sister's underwear.
And you will have to wear
traditional clothing everyday.
Ah, I see.
What is your salary?
It's about forty to fifty
million won a year.
Do you have any debts?
I have a mortgage that's almost paid off.
If it's a house mortgage,
then do you own it or is it leased?
Ah, the men and women in our
family don't eat together.
You'll have to prepare everyone's
meals separately, three times a day.
Is that so?
But... there is one way to
live separately from my family.
It's a lease.
You got a loan to lease the house?
I wanted to live without getting
any support from my parents.
My dream was to buy a house
of my own before
the age of thirty-five by saving
money from my salary.
The cost of buying a house
is so expensive
that it's impossible to buy one even if I
saved every penny for the rest of my life.
Do you want to cut all
ties with your parents
and live in a measly three hundred
square foot room with me?
My salary is forty million won.
If we scrimp and save
for about twenty years...
We would be able to buy a a seven hundred
square foot apartment in Seoul.
Will you be willing to work
if we get married?
Yes!
No one has been able to get in touch with
Anchor Cha since the press conference.
No matter how much I call her,
she won't answer her phone.
She won't even agree to a single interview.
She relays the news, though.
I was told she disappears as
soon as she's done with the news.
And she goes around avoiding
the reporters like a ghost.
I heard all interviews have been
banned at the broadcasting station.
They're afraid she might
cause an accident again.
Seeing how she's not
even answering our calls
I don't think she's going
to show up for the book launch.
Do you think it's best to postpone it?
Just proceed as we planned.
Anchor Cha Ki Young.
The book launching party is tomorrow.
We can expect that you'll be there, yes?
It's two o'clock at the press center and
I'll call you tomorrow to confirm.
You scared me!
Oh, you're real. I thought
you were a mannequin.
There are rumors
going around that
you've been setting a mannequin
in that seat lately.
There are also rumors going around that
your soul is stuck right in that seat
because of your grudge against the
people who wants to kick you out.
You know what I'm talking about, right?
A living ghost.
If feelings of hatred are extremely
strong from a living person
Those emotions separate itself from
the person and manifests into a ghost!
I'm scared!
Hey, why is it so cold
inside the studio lately?
Are you... a ghost or a person?
- Are you going home?
- I'm going to the restroom.
Hey! What are you doing?
Do want to see Father collapse?
Don't you know that he
absolutely detests you cooking?
I hear you've been going on blind dates.
So, did you find a woman that you like?
I like all of them, but I
don't know who to choose.
The book is out.
It's nice.
The book launch is tomorrow.
You're going to come, right?
- No.
- Why? Is it because of Cha Ki Young?
Why are you avoiding her?
You did nothing wrong.
Frankly, you're the one who
wrote this book, not her.
That's enough.
I'll cover you, so come tomorrow.
- I told you not to mess around with this!
- Father!
- You bastard!
Are you trying to play house, you bastard?
Father, no! That's a new book!
That's a new book! Father!
You're here.
Yoo Ri.
Yeah? What is it?
Is it okay if I spend
the night at your house?
Why? Are the reporters camping
out in front of your place again?
My mom is waiting for me so we
could go to Damyang tomorrow.
She made an appointment with an
obstetrician. To abort the baby.
Sure. It's easier trying to convince people
who talk ill of you than your own parents.
There's no where to go.
[Hyun Myung Yi]
Hey.
Tae Yun, it's me.
Can you come and pick me up?
Besides, I always went to you.
- Come to me just for today.
- Where are you?
You came.
I got my wish.
Why is a young lady drinking
alone this late at night?
I'm not a young lady anymore.
I was before I slept with you,
but I'm not anymore.
Don't lie!
I have something to say to you.
That's why I asked you to come.
I wanted to talk to you face to face.
I was so happy that I slept with you.
Even if you don't like me and
your heart lies with Cha Ki Young
for a moment... I was able to
be by your side, and I was happy.
Of all the guys I've seen...
you're the best, Tae Yun.
I am so sick and tired of you women.
Let's go.
There's no reason for you to break up
with me since we haven't started anything.
But, I'm going to end it with you today.
Forever.
It hurts so much that I want to end it.
Thank you for everything.
I won't call you from now on.
Please don't call me.
Do you have some time tomorrow?
Why?
The launching party for
'Talk and Taste' is tomorrow.
Come to the event. You helped
me out, so you should come.
No, thank you.
Mom, I'm sorry.
Just... go by yourself tomorrow.
Where are you right now?
I'm not going to get rid of the baby.
Mom, I'll call you again.
Have a safe trip tomorrow.
- You must feel terrible right now.
- Yeah.
Besides dying first, disobeying your
parents is probably the next worst thing.
So, you do know.
What about Il Jong?
An obstetrician is on standby
twenty-four hours a day.
Seriously, who is baby's father?
I'll tell you later.
Honestly, if I was
courageous like you...
I would've just had a
baby and not get married.
Why? Il Jong is a thoughtful husband.
People are different than what
they actually appear to be.
All married couples have issues
that people have no idea about.
Married women have to take care of all the
housework, the children, and the in-laws.
We have to wash our husband's
clothes and cook for them.
Your situation is far more favorable
if you think about those things.
People say the institution
of marriage is going
to collapse and disappear
in fifty years.
I should've been born fifty years later.
You came.
Eun Cha, don't ask me to do these errands
for you. I could get fired for this.
Prosecutor Park. Whether you get fired
because you didn't listen to me or
you get fired because you got
caught running an errand.
Isn't that the same thing?
Thank you.
Put this over there and...
- get more staff in here.
- Yes, Ma'am.
Is Cha Ki Young really coming?
No way. She's been avoiding
the reporters like the plague.
You think she's going to show up?
It's Cha Ki Young!
Miss Cha Ki Young!
Anchor Cha Ki Young, what did you mean
by declaring yourself a single mother?
Please explain to us why you
decided to receive a sperm donation.
Why do you only want a
child and not a marriage?
Anchor Cha, please say a word.
We've set up a separate time for everyone
to do an interview after the signing event.
Please come this way!
- Reporter Park, you came.
- Yes.
Ah, just a moment please.
Excuse me, thank you.
The book is to die for.
I actually paid for it.
To receive a masterpiece like this
for free would be disrespectful.
Who should I get a signature from?
Ah, it splattered this way.
As usual, I've always liked women the best.
Here you go.
[Calls and Text Message Transactions]
I told my father that it's not my child.
I have the right to claim
half of your pregnancy.
You've turned me into a sperm donor?
Do you want everyone to
know and get kicked out?
Or do you want to step down of
your own free will with honor?
Do you want to sign here.
Or over here?
Subtitles by DramaFever
Well, the stage is already set up.
I hope the ending is dramatic.
Is there anything else besides this?
Ah, how about wearing some rubber
gloves and cleaning the bathroom?
The most evil thing in this world
are people hurting the ones they
love for the sake of success!
- Let's go out.
- 32-24-34.
Natural eyes, natural nose
and natural breasts.
Let me know how much it costs. Let's
negotiate the terms of our relationship.
815, you must be hungry. I'm so sorry.
I don't have an appetite these days.
I swear!
Also, don't be disrespectful to my woman.
You might just die from it.
- What were the ratings from last night?
- Three percent.
Put your life on the line and
raise the ratings by five percent.
If you don't, you're all fired! Got it?