I'd like to have broiled rice cake.
Makdong.
Do you want to hear my story?
There was a black looking
bastard long time ago.
He received no education and
he was abandoned by his own parents.
But he tried to survive in
Seoul where he knows none.
He moved sluggishly like
a maggot in excrement.
One day...he was so hungry,
so he
sneaked in to a restaurant
And ate little bit of
sushi and some drinks.
But he was found by
the owner of restaurant
and locked up in jail
for the first time of his life.
Do you know where that restaurant
located? It's right this spot.
Can you imagine what happened
to that black looking bastard?
He is trying to build new
building in this very spot now.
He ground out an oath while
he was locked in the jail.
Wait and see what will gonna
happen to you fucking bastards.
Makdong, what's your dream?
Yes...
Boss.
Who's looking for me?
Hey! Viet Cong!
Who the hell is it?
I'm not sure, but they were
waiting for you for long time
You sure looks
better then before!
That asshole was as
black as real Viet Cong!
His temper was as
dirty as Viet Cong.
That bastard grew up
only with his guts!
- Boss, do you want me to beat them up?
- Hold on.
Long time no see, brother.
I'm deeply moved for
you calling me brother.
I thought you forgot all about me
since you haven't come to see me
while serving a prison term.
I haven't got enough time to go
there since I was busy.
I heard how you've been.
Did you quit from
prostitute business?
Just let me know if
you have nothing to do.
I will help you.
There is something you
have to help me already.
I'm gonna open a new nightclub
just across the road.
And I want your help.
I heard you are a
big man in this town.
Long time ago I had this puppy
which I used to kick
whenever I want to.
And one day this puppy grow
up and became big dog.
But still this dog can't even bark at me.
Do you know why?
Because he is
so afraid of me.
Bye. See you again.
Sir, you know well how I grew up
in this town, don't you?
It took me ten years to
get rid of all the gangs.
I finally got this place
after the ten year war.
But this Yanggil Kim,
this asshole is trying to
Start to ruin me right after
he released from the jail.
I'm sorry talking about boring stuff
while partying for your promotion.
Congratulations sir.
You did a great job.
Great job? Cut it out. I worked in
police station for thirty years
but I'm only a section chief.
Do you feel the frailty
of human life for that?
Hey, what are you doing?
Why don't you sing a song?
Call band in.
Cut the creep out. I want to
talk between you and me alone.
Yes, sir. Everyone get out.
I want to die right now.
My wife is having an affair.
My son is in college and
We lived twenty years
together but...
What kinda life this is.
Hey, you deacon!
Can't you do it right, asshole!
Hurry up! Dig it fast!
Come on.
That will do.
Stop now and
Take all the clothes off!
What?
Take your clothes off,
you idiot!
Please help me.
Jesus Christ.
Aren't you gonna take it off?
Hurry up!
You have great body there,
take it off!
Help me.
You are a deacon in the
church, aren't you?
That's right.
How long have
you been a deacon?
About ten year or so, sir.
And you are having an affair?
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
You should go to hell,
'cause you are such a sinner!
Please, help me. Please!
Oh, God. Help me!
I know you did nothing wrong.
It's all your thing's fault.
This thing is a cause,
this little creep!
Stay still, asshole.
This is all for you.
Are you suffering for this?
Because of this,
you are committing sin to God
And bother other happy family
And also bothers you.
Stay still, you asshole.
Damn, you dirty bastard.
Which is not an
element of this drink?
Take a guess. Okay?
Number one liquid-fructose, two dextrin,
three Vitamin E, four sodium.
- Can you repeat again?
- Again?
Number one liquid-fructose, two dextrin,
three Vitamin E, four sodium.
Number three.
- Number three?
- Number four.
Number four? Sodium?
No, number three.
Vitamin E. That's correct.
Now then what is this
drink's license number?
This question is quite hard.
License number...
One 01-01-026
Two 01-01-027, three...
Makdong, you look
you are a pure person.
Who is this?
My father.
You two are look alike.
where is this?
That's my house.
You have this big
tree in your house?
It changed a lot now.
Can I keep this?
I want it.
Sure, you can.
Makdong, have you
ever been in love?
Haven't?
Not even once?
Haven't actually.
You've never been in love
by now?
Have you ever kissed a girl
with love before?
Tell me.
Not really.
Really?
Can I teach you how?
Mr. Taekwon Bae ask me
to come home right now.
What you gonna do?
I will do as you like.
Are you coming or not?
Tell me.
Well, we have to.
Boss said so.
Sure.
Let's go.
Did you go for train?
Why do you always leave
as you end up going back again?
You can never escape from me,
you know the fact.
I got you a present.
What is it?
Some clothes.
Try it on.
Later.
It's really expensive one.
I don't want to.
Why don't you try it on?
I'm sorry for this.
You know I love you,
don't you?
I think I have to visit my house.
Why? Do you have
some problem there?
No. It's my mother's
birthday tomorrow.
Then you should go.
With this,
buy her some presents.
It's okay.
Take it.
Thank you.
Let's drink.
Come on.
- Okay!
- Come on drink.
Here, I will treat you.
What's the matter with you?
Stop drinking.
Cut it out.
If I don't drink today
when can I ever?
You had enough.
Please stop it.
What a behavior!
Do you have to embarrass
me in front of my family?
What did you say last night?
You promised in
front of your son.
Didn't you say you're gonna
quit your job if you drink one more time?
Do you want to
beat you up?
Hit me, hit me!
Hit me in front of
the whole family!
Why can't you!
why don't you hesitate?
Mother. I live like this.
Just like what you've seen.
I'm sorry, honey.
Get off.
Forgive me, huh?
Let me go!
Now, let's sing.
What have you done!
I don't know why I'm like this.
I spilled it all over!
- I don't know why I'm like this.
- Get up brother.
I can't pick it out exactly but...
What is this?
What a mess!
What do you live for?
What are you doing, huh?
What? Did I say
something wrong?
Look at him?
Do you want to live like that?
So? So do you live well then?
Damn
Fuck you.
Me? Damn?
Want to die today?
Yeah, asshole.
You guys are so bad.
How could you do this.
Especially today!
Excuse me?
I'm sorry.
What the hell? You bastard!
Dongjoo! Are we ganster?
Answer me! Are we?
No, sir.
Why did you do it, then?
- Forgive me boss...
- Shut your mouth up!
You damn stupid bastards!
Don't you know who I am?
I'm Taekon Bae.
Don't you know me asshole?
Boss, why can't we fight
back to Yanggil Kim?
Don't we have to cut them
out before they get bigger?
That's the only
way to survive, boss.
Do you know what the life is?
Answer me, asshole!
What do you know
about people?
How do I know
such a thing, boss?
They are the real
fucking bastards!
I know him well.
I go with my own way.
Got it?
Now, Go ahead and
have some fun.
- It's room number 503, sir.
- Room 503?
Can you memorize that?
You have a bad memory.
Hands off!
Mr. Taekon Bae, I did everything
he ordered me to do.
Don't I look like
a well-trained cat, huh?
Get in, are you drunk?
Yeah, I'm drunk.
That bastard made me to drink.
Do you know what he said?
He said Yanggil Kim and
Taekon Bae is all trash.
That asshole prosecutor
is really smart!
- Get in.
- Let me go!
I hate you. Let me go,
I don't want to ride with you.
Get in.
Don't touch me.
I hate to ride with you!
I'm sorry.
It's all my fault.
You go alone.
I won't ride with you.
I don't want it,
fucking asshole.
I've gotta go.
Where do you think you are going
Come here.
Don't you wanna fuck with me?
Just tell me. I will.
I do such a thing for everybody,
and why not for you!
Boss bbazie, Sieddo Samunoi bojae.
Lie down.
My body is not really clean.
Is it all right with you?
Okay, right?
Makdong.
Yes? Yes, sir
There's a gloomy feeling
going around here.
Something's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
Hold on.
Drive a car backwards!
Backwards!
Stay still.
Hey, Viet Cong Viet Cong,
Yanggil Kim boss says hello to you.
Where are you hiding assholes!
Asshole, you bastards.
I'm sorry about distreat boss.
I'm very sorry.
I think there was some misunderstanding
but I will make it clear.
Sure, I understand.
Now among puppies,
Some doesn't know whether they
are from a mongrel or a good dog.
A mongrel doesn't know what
it is and act like a good dog.
Then we have nothing
to do but one thing.
Then you should tell that
it's from some mongrel.
Cheers!
What did you say
what your dream is?
Living with my own family,
running a small restarurant.
That's good.
To make dream come true, I've climbed
from the bottom to the top here.
It wasn't easy at all.
- Sir?
- Yes?
You didn't zip up.
- Are you kidding me?
- Look, you really didn't!
Boss, Boss!
What's the matter?
A call for you.
Turn the music off!
Turn it off!
Hello?
Is that you, big brother?
It's me, Makdong.
Is mom there? Where is she?
Yes. I'm fine. I'm okay.
Don't hang up.
Don't hang up. Don't.
Don't.
Do you remember?
Red bridge, Red railway bridge.
We used to go fishing
when we were young.
You know I once went there
to catch a green fish and
Iost my shoe
so, you and brothers
searched for the all day long.
And Soonok, she got stung
her buttocks by a bee
so, second brother was
making fun of her.
Big brother, do you
remember back then?
Can do you
Boss!
Have you had a meal?
No, I haven't
but I'm all right.
How old are you again?
Twenty-six, boss.
What happened?
Stay calm.
Sieddo Samunoie Bojaeddio,
Sieddo Samunoie
We've got our customer.
Come on in.
Get off!
- Meal is available?
- Yes, come on in.
Come on in.
Soonok!
Come in.
The place like here can be
better than any others.
Whould you please order?
What's so special here?
Everything's good.
What's youngyangtang?
Something good for body.
That will be good for you.
What is that?
Dog soup.
If you don't like it
then have some chicken soup.
It's our domestic.
Is it really domestic?
Sure. We caught it right here.
You can see if you want.
We can show it to you.
It's okay. It's not necessary.
Why don't you have a look at it later.
We can hardly trust anybody these days.
So, you want chicken?
Yes, I do.
Chicken soup for two?
- What a chubby!
- Good choice, huh?
Give me the chicken.
What took you so long to
get here from market.
Why?
Where have you been?
Nowhere.
Was it good?
Yes. It was pretty good.
Do you live in those
apartments over there?
Yes. We just moved in.
Then often stop by
we'll treat you with best service.
It looks nice to have old
pictures under one frame.
You think so?
I like the idea.
- Good bye.
Haven't we met before?
Well, I have no idea.
What did you do before?
I worked for the government.
You look pretty
familiar to me.
Good bye!
Thank you!
Have a nice day!