This film is an adaptation of the journal, written by
Alain Marécaux in detention and published by Flammarion in 2005
Your civil status?
Alain Marécaux...
Born 27 May 1964,
at Linselles, Northern France.
Profession?
Bailiff.
Your marital status?
Married to Edith Vauchelle,
three children.
How was your family life?
Good, it was...
my reason for living.
Only problem was...
I worked too much.
I wasn't home enough.
How was your work?
Fine.
I really liked my job,
my team,
the application of the verdicts,
in respect for the law
and the parties.
I felt I was being of use.
I was proud to be
an agent of justice.
What do you do in prison?
I try to read, but it's hard.
I watch TV.
I smoke.
I lie on the bed and I wait...
I wait for it to pass.
The toughest part...
is having gone
from twelve-hour days,
to doing nothing at all...
and not seeing my wife and kids.
I've not heard the word "dad"
for 2 months.
PRESUMED GUILTY
What's going on?
Visitors.
I'll go see.
- What's up?
- Mr Marécaux?
- Yes, why?
- Captain Dury.
You're under arrest.
We'll now search the house.
What?
Have you letters rogatory?
Fabrice Burgaud,
investigating magistrate.
You could show your card.
So what am I accused of?
You and your wife are accused
of raping under-15s.
What? That's outrageous!
Stay here, madam.
Let go of her!
Let go of me!
- Easy on!
- Get off me!
Calm down!
Or I'll cuff and floor you.
Let me.
Wake up.
What's going on?
Mom!
We're the police.
Who are they?
- I'm here, darling.
- What's going on?
Hurry up.
Stay!
Be right back.
- Madam, keep your distance.
- What?
Just ask him to get dressed.
Not taking the diskettes?
- They're blank.
- Seize them anyway.
What'd we have to do with rape?
It makes no sense,
must be a mistake.
What's in there?
No idea, never looked.
Open it!
Sign here.
- Well?
- Nothing.
And here.
Come back here!
Let go!
At least let me reassure her.
Easy, pet.
I love you...
Don't worry, it's a mistake.
It'll all work out.
I love you pet, I love you!
Let's go.
I want to talk to my lawyer.
Later, for now you come with me.
I found this.
Wow, hot stuff.
Is this yours?
No, it's my wife's...
Don't piss me about.
It's yours.
No, she got it as a joke
for her sister's wedding.
To give her a bunch of photos
of naked men.
But it was too crude.
Forgot it was there.
Sure it's not for showing to kids?
That's sick! For what?
Found this!
Stashed in the wardrobe.
Now we're talking!
What's on here?
I don't know, ask her!
It's her wardrobe.
Where is she?
Where are my kids?
Let's have a look.
Here!
Christophe Dugarry with a shot...
What a goal!
What do I do with him?
Put him outside.
I can't, there's no fence.
Can I call my parents
to fetch him?
You call no one.
Better give him food and water.
It can wait till tonight.
It might take you a bit longer.
Let's go.
Know these people?
Think not, but I can check.
Apart from Thierry Delay,
for a welfare case...
the others, no.
May I know exactly why I'm here?
Know these people?
No.
But earlier,
you said you knew Thierry Delay.
No, I said
I served two writs on him.
My office handles over 6,000 a year.
And his wife, Myriam Badaoui?
- Neither.
- And the two below,
David Delplanque,
Aurélie Grenon?
They say you and your wife
raped their children,
since the winter of '99.
Are you crazy!
That you sodomized them,
had them perform oral sex.
That's nonsense!
That you came on to them
with animals
on a farm in Belgium,
filming them
to feed a paedophile ring!
To accuse us of such monstrosities,
it must be a mistake!
And they don't ring any bells?
I think number 1
is a school buddy
of my kid son Sébastien.
He said he and his brothers
came to your house...
That you made advances...
Come on, that's rubbish!
- Think we arrest on a whim!
- We have proof!
You stand accused by four people.
So you'll talk.
Right now!
You filthy bastard!
Child raper!
Alain Marécaux.
This way.
Get undressed.
Undress!
Your ring, watch...
And your belt.
Over there.
Remove your laces.
Your socks.
Face the wall, drop your shorts.
Face the wall.
Remove your shorts!
Hurry up!
Hunker down and cough hard.
Okay, get dressed.
Door!
Stop here.
Marécaux Alain.
Edith!
Let's go!
Be brave, my love!
It's a mistake, it'll work out.
I love you.
Quiet!
Go sit down.
Sit down!
Good day, Mr Marécaux.
So?
- Still won't confess?
- Of course not.
I'm totally innocent.
In that case,
I'm extending custody.
A pity you persist in denying...
after what your son Sébastien
just told us.
My son? What did he say?
Let's go.
- What did he say?
- This way.
I want to see him!
How were things with your wife?
We'd argued in recent years.
She said I worked too much,
not caring for her and the kids.
But of late we were rebuilding.
How often did you have sex?
- I don't have to answer that.
- No discussion, just answer.
When did you last make love?
Answer.
Monday.
Marécaux, we know you're homosexual.
What?
You lied.
That gay mag was yours.
Not at all.
I explained.
And it was in my wife's wardrobe.
And the gay porn links
on your computer?
But everyone used that computer.
Just come clean!
As you're a fag,
your wife needed sex with kids!
Your reasoning is totally warped.
You had sex
with your wife on Monday,
but without penetration.
She was indisposed.
A mere detail for a sodomizer
like you, no?
Admit you're a fag!
Can't you quit that?
Not till you admit
that at least you have tendencies,
goddammit!
We have proof!
Okay, maybe I visited a site or two!
Happy now?
At last!
We're getting somewhere.
Alright?
Hungry?
Want a cigarette?
Here, that's for you.
Listen, I see criminals and rapists
all day long.
I know you're not that kind.
You're just ill.
And we're here to help you.
So, here's what we'll do.
I'll take your statement...
and tonight your wife and kids
will sleep at home.
Well?
What do you say?
You can do that for them, no?
Great.
You won't regret it.
I'm listening.
I want to talk to my wife first.
You can't see anyone.
But you'll see her later, I promise.
Now, go ahead.
I'll say nothing
until I've spoken with her.
Goddammit!
Don't come crying
when you've got twenty years!
Hello, Mr Marécaux.
Hubert Delarue, barrister.
Your lawyer, Mrs Thérin,
asked me to defend you.
Hello, sir.
Thank you for coming.
Here, this'll do you good.
Thank you.
So?
How was custody? Tough?
A nightmare.
Any news of my family?
No, but I'll find out.
So far I've only read
the police transcripts.
Seems like one hell of an affair.
I don't understand anything.
People I don't even know accusing me
of doing things to their children
that I wouldn't dare repeat.
And what's more,
it seems my son said stuff too,
but I don't know what.
Come now, Mr Marécaux,
you're no longer alone.
Nothing actually happened?
Of course not!
Then rest assured,
I'll free you.
Good day, please be seated.
So...
as investigating magistrate
in charge of the case
the State prosecutor
has asked me to indict you
for having committed, at Outreau,
by violence or threat,
acts of sexual penetration
on children Delay and Delplanque
and sexual interference
on your son, Sébastien,
qualified as rape and molestation
of under-15s and punishable by law.
Sir, any comment?
Given the absence of proof
and my client's denial
I feel the case is too weak
to warrant indictment.
Presumption of innocence
should apply
at this stage of the procedure.
I disagree.
I hereby indict you
pending referral
to the custodial judge.
That's all for now, Mr Marécaux.
Hello, Mr Prosecutor.
Mr Marécaux.
It's not looking good.
Your wife and four others
are being held for the same affair.
Let's go see the judge.
Given the gravity of the accusations
and apparent proof,
investigations required
to ascertain the truth,
the need to safeguard
the evidence
and the disturbance
of public order
whereby children live in fear
of their aggressors,
I ask for Mr Marécaux
to be remanded in custody.
Mr Marécaux, anything to say?
I'm living a nightmare.
I'm innocent.
You're totally mistaken.
Committing
a huge miscarriage of justice.
At the Prosecutor's request,
I hereby remand you in custody
at Beauvais prison.
My client is presumed innocent,
as there is as yet
no material proof of his guilt,
conditional freedom should prevail
over detention.
Nothing warrants such a decision.
Whatever you do,
in jail, mention
neither your profession
nor the alleged crime.
Rest assured, I'll appeal
this decision immediately.
Good day.
This is Mr Marécaux.
- Thank you.
- His kit.
Have a good day.
Hello.
I'm not allowed to.
Offenders like you
are very much at risk here,
but I guess you know that?
So for safety, stay in your cell.
Right profile.
Higher...
A bit more...
Now, eyes straight ahead.
Let's go.
Stop.
Go ahead.
Where's Riton?
Visiting room.
And his things?
There.
The criminals vanished aboard
a second car but without their loot.
A seeming case
of domestic paedophilia
has taken a more serious turn.
In Outreau,
six children were abused
and twelve adults are being held.
This report from Erwan Marsiac
and Bastien Sartis.
At 8:30 this morning
a cortege of unmarked cars
arrives at Boulogne courthouse.
Leading the investigation
is Judge Burgaud.
Poverty and debt
drove this Outreau family
to sell its young children for sex.
See how many they are?
They were raped
by local shopkeepers,
and gradually the ring
of abuse widened
to include a bailiff
from a neighbouring district
his wife and a priest.
A Boulogne taxi-driver
even drove them to Belgium
for the shooting
of a paedophile video...
Sure you're alright?
Other arrests may be made
in coming days...
The alleged murderer of little
Caroline Dickinson
is being extradited from the US...
Workshop.
I'm still eating.
Move it.
A bit of space.
I'm sick of that workshop.
So? Any news of my family?
Hello, Alain.
It's a sordid affair.
Two couples
who raped their own children.
Apart from Delay,
who denies it all,
the other three are accusing
others of taking part
in their orgies
including you and your wife.
But there's no material evidence
only allegations
which under scrutiny turn out
to be random and contradictory.
And Sébastien, what did he say?
The questions posed by the police
were very suggestive,
very insidious, like:
"Did your mom or dad ever touch
your willy or bottom in play?"
What you never say to a kid.
So they got him to say
ambiguous stuff like...
that you'd lie on him,
your willy against his leg,
at times it was hard...
I don't believe it.
Yet the very same day
they sent him to hospital
where the doctors declared
he was perfectly fine
and showed no signs at all
of sexual interference.
But even if he was led on,
why did he say that?
I don't know...
Unless he was influenced
by little Jimmy,
the most traumatized
of Delay's sons,
who inundated the school with tales
of a highly sexual nature.
Who knows what he told your son?
How do you explain the gay magazine
wrapped in a Playmobil catalogue?
I told you already,
my wife bought it
as a joke on her sister.
No relation
to your homosexual tendencies?
I don't have homosexual tendencies.
You admitted you did.
I never said that.
Under police pressure
and in all honesty
I admitted to visiting a site
or two, but that's all.
Your son Sébastien spoke
of a game you played,
"The kissing machine".
Can you explain?
What was this game, Mr Marécaux?
You chase, catch
and kiss all over.
With no ambiguity,
despite what you imply.
Your son also said you touched
his willy in your wife's absence
and that he felt your penis
was hard.
Any comment?
I don't know.
I can't understand why.
Your Honour, the police questioning
was strongly suggestive.
That same day, Sébastien
made no complaint to the doctor
specialized in child rape testimony.
That's all you have to say?
I dunno...
I worked a lot,
barely saw my kids
so on Sunday mornings
we'd tussle on the bed.
I may have rubbed up against him
and he misinterpreted it.
In what way?
I'm just trying to understand
why he said that!
My kids are my whole life,
why'd I sully them?
I'd have to be mad!
How come Jimmy Delay declared
that you sexually abused him?
How come?
I don't even know the kid!
He's my son's friend,
we barely spoke.
Under police questioning,
Jimmy accuses my client,
but photo-identifies someone else.
Yet he recognized the room
where you and your wife
made advances?
Impossible,
he never came to our house.
He also says his brothers were there
during the alleged rape,
yet they denied it
and couldn't ID the house.
Sir, I'll take your remarks later.
How do you explain Badaoui,
Grenon and Delplanque's claim that
you sodomized their children
in various ways
and had them fellate you?
According to the adults,
all the children were raped,
yet five, except Jimmy Delay,
deny it. It doesn't hold up.
Stop interrupting, Sir,
and let me question.
Why would these people
incriminate you
admitting their own involvement
if it does not undo
their responsibility?
Hell, why must I explain?
Maybe they mistook me?
Wanted revenge on me as a bailiff?
Or maybe it's a frame-up?
Of which your son is part?
Sir, over to you.
Have you seen Edith and the kids?
Edith is coping well.
The kids are with host families.
They're fine, they send their love.
- Why not with their grandparents?
- The judges refused.
To protect them
from influence by family
over critical
of the investigating magistrate.
But we've appealed.
I'm sorry...
How are Mom and Dad?
They're okay.
It was tough at first, but...
They're bearing up.
And you, my brother,
how are you faring?
You look exhausted.
I'm totally innocent.
You believe me?
Of course.
Everyone believes you.
What did I do
for Sébastien to say that?
I wasn't caring enough?
Or I cuddled him too much?
I just don't know...
Lord,
I know I'm not here through
God's justice, but that of men.
Yet I beg you,
help me,
protect my wife and children
and help that young judge
to have little common sense
and lucidity.
Remove his handcuffs.
The first time he came
with an inspector, as I owed money.
They noted the furniture and left.
He returned alone that afternoon
and I found it odd that a bailiff
should joke with my husband.
He came back that night.
David, Aurélie and their kids
were there too.
It was tough,
because the kids didn't want to.
I had to beat them
for them to obey.
They raped them.
Penetration and oral sex.
Exactly when and where?
In early 2000.
Three times at home
and twice in Belgium.
How was he dressed?
Grey pants,
a blue shirt
and a khaki jacket.
Miss Grenon, you declared that
Mr Marécaux sodomized the children
with his penis, a dildo
and had fellatio.
Do you confirm this?
Sure.
Where, when and how many times
did he rape them?
Twice,
at Mr and Mrs Delay's,
in '98, when I used to see them.
What was he wearing?
Both times,
he wore a dark suit,
but I can't recall what colour.
Mr Marécaux, as Miss Grenon's
testimony confirms Mrs Badaoui's
what do have to say?
Are you kidding?
They disagree.
On both clothing and dates.
Mrs Badaoui says 2000,
while this lady says 1998.
Miss Grenon says it took place
in 1998 and you in 2000.
Can you be more exact?
I must give precise dates?
Yes, be as precise as possible,
Mrs Badaoui.
Well, it took place both in '98
and in 2000.
Twice in '98,
once in 2000 at home
and twice in 2000 in Belgium.
Madam, you first said my client
raped the children in 2000
and having heard Miss Grenon
you now say '98 and 2000.
Can you explain
this discrepancy?
I made a mistake.
He came once in '98,
when nothing happened,
and later, twice for sex.
Can you date
these events of '98 exactly?
I can't recall,
but I know your game.
You want me to catch myself out.
Where's that mad woman going?
She admits raping her kids
and heads off home?
So to be with my family,
I must say I'm a child raper!
Don't be silly,
this is all so pathetic and surreal
it simply won't hold up.
Yet I'm still here?
I'll immediately request
your liberation and face offs.
Chin up, you'll be home
for Christmas.
Marécaux, you leave in one hour.
You sure lost weight.
So I hear you're a hunter?
Not at all, why do you ask?
Where are we going?
Your place, for your khaki jacket.
Madam, please!
Any news of the kids?
Thessy said they're fine.
And you?
I wrote, but no reply.
Did you get my letters?
No, and mine?
Please, that'll do.
You look worn out.
Hang in there, okay?
Sure, don't worry.
We'll be out for Christmas.
What are you looking for?
Prints from the Delay kids.
We told you, never came here.
Forget it, they'll find nothing.
Enough, now shut it you two.
That's my kids' stuff!
The Delays identified it.
Ridiculous.
They say it's theirs.
But they were never here.
They're making the whole thing up.
Okay, that's enough.
Let's go.
My darling wife...
our life has changed dramatically,
but this day was one of joy.
What a delight to see you,
to touch, embrace and smell you...
I felt happy for a moment.
I hadn't felt us
this close in years.
I found you so beautiful, so strong.
I was so proud of you.
I always thought
I was the strongest, but no.
I love you.
Marécaux, visiting room.
- No news from the Clerk's Office?
- No.
You're sure?
Yeah, but I'll check later.
- Hello, Mr Chairman.
- Alain...
This comes as a surprise.
Your sister let me have
her visiting slot.
I'd like to assure you of my fullest
support and solidarity.
Thank you.
So?
How are things at the office?
I wrote all your clients to explain
that your incarceration is temporary
and that you remain
presumed innocent.
I'm glad you did that.
We feel it's now...
but a matter of days.
Good, I'm delighted.
Yet there is one thing...
Excuse my directness,
but your image has been tarnished
and even if you do get out soon,
perhaps you shouldn't rejoin
the firm.
But I'll be totally exonerated.
Yes, I know, but after what happened
I feel you and your family
should leave the region.
To go where?
I was born here, my family's here!
I'm sorry.
You're right.
You'll need to sell your practice.
I shopped around
and I got a few offers.
But you know it's worth far more.
The last is not too bad.
The longer you wait
the more value it'll lose.
But of course, it's your decision.
What matter,
compared to this hellhole!
Your resignation...
You must sign that too.
Hunker down.
Cough.
Turn around.
Drop your shorts.
Cough.
Okay.
Drop your shorts.
Hunker down.
Cough.
Marécaux, a notification.
DOUAI APPEAL COURT
My sweet, my wonderful love,
all five letters,
they moved me so.
God or no god, I'll never forgive
their taking my loved ones.
I was against having more kids.
Now I think it'd be a good thing.
Keep this news in mind.
May it strengthen you.
I miss your warmth.
Dear Dad, I'm writing
to give you some news.
First, I was in the same family
as Sébastien,
but from bawling him out
for what he said, they changed me.
We all still meet...
Hi Dad, I really miss you.
I'm writing to say I love you.
My auntie is very nice,
and I call Thomas and Cécile.
School is good too...
Dear Daddy,
I'd really love to see you.
I think of you, I miss you.
I'll send you loads of letters
and drawings?
Lots of hugs and kisses, Daddy.
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year...
What are you doing here?
What's wrong?
What is it?
Mom is dead.
What happened?
Since your arrest,
she'd stopped speaking,
she'd stopped eating,
she cried all the time.
She was waiting for you.
Time to go now.
My brother...
Mr Marécaux, please...
Alain!
Are you alright, Mr Marécaux?
Alain...
Alright, sir?
Alain?
Want to postpone the questioning?
Your civil status?
Alain Marécaux...
Born 27 May 1964,
at Linselles, Northern France.
Father's name?
Léon Marécaux.
Date of birth?
He was born in 1925...
Can't recall the date.
Profession?
Retired teacher.
Mother's name?
Reine Wyart.
Born in 1927.
Profession?
I'm sorry...
I was just told of her death.
Yes, I know.
But what was her job?
She was a shopkeeper.
Two chilling new revelations
in the Outreau affair
say that a six-year old girl
was beaten to death
after being raped by two people.
Claims which, sadly, seem credible.
This report...
After an early evening break,
the police resumed their dig
in this garden in Outreau,
Pas de Dalais,
in their search
for the body of a little girl
murdered in 1999
after having been raped.
Corroborated by a woman accused
of selling her own children for sex,
she led the investigators
to the spot
where the child may be buried.
Nothing is taking its normal course.
Impossible to contact the judge.
I still don't have all the elements.
Others accused by Badaoui and family
haven't even been questioned.
As for her murder claim,
it's total lunacy.
Yet it feeds into Burgaud's frenzy.
He'll end up digging in your garden!
But as he never finds any proof
the balloon must surely burst.
I think you're in depression.
You feel responsible
for your mother's death.
We must end this distress,
so I suggest a stay
in a psychiatric hospital.
No, I refuse, I'm not mad.
I didn't say you were,
but you've had a major shock
that you need help to cope with.
Don't let the word "psychiatry"
daunt you.
Sure...
You want to commit me,
but all is well.
I've no place in an asylum.
Even less than in jail.
Your head will be shaven
They'll put you in chains
Your back will be broken
And I'll die of pain...
I didn't kill
I didn't steal
But my mother I didn't believe
And I recall she loved me well
As I labour without reprieve
So, how do you feel?
Better... Much better, doctor.
Only, the judge is against
your being here
due to risks of outside influence.
I can't go back there, I'd die.
I can ask to have you sent
to the medical unit in Amiens.
It's a new facility specially
equipped for people like you
with adapted treatment.
Go ahead.
Excuse me.
Yeah?
- Got any medicines?
- Depends what you're after.
Tranxene, Xanax, Prozac...
Theralene,
Anaphraline and Stilnox.
Should have Stilnox
later in the week.
I'm interested.
Your hairdresser said
you made an appointment
on 24 February 2001 at 12 noon
- unusual for you -
and that you asked for:
"A change of look".
Why did you make this appointment?
I don't know.
I guess my hair was too long,
and so what?
Delay and Badaoui
were arrested on 20 February 2001
and you dash to the hairdresser's
on the 24th to change your look.
How do you explain this coincidence?
Not coincidence, chance.
I guess the 24th was a Wednesday,
so I was near my hairdresser's
and I needed a haircut.
You knew the Delays
had been arrested?
I didn't even know them!
So why did you shave your beard
in June 2001?
Sorry?
I've never been clean shaven.
Then why did people say
you'd shaved and cut your hair
if not to change your look?
Hell, I don't know!
Shaving irritates my skin.
I'll ask you one last time.
Why, at the very moment
your name figured in this case,
did you cut your hair and shave
if not to avoid recognition?
I told you,
I never shaved my beard.
Ask my colleagues, my friends,
the Prosecutor, whoever,
I've always been bearded.
Why insist, Your Honour?
He told you three times he never
shaved his beard, next question!
That's my decision, Sir.
I didn't ask you to speak.
Fine.
Charlotte Vilanelle,
neighbour of your beach house
declared that
on the night of 27/28 July 2001
noise of children and adults
could be heard.
Can you explain?
It's a place where we entertain
and that we often lend.
Have you ever slept
with children there?
Never. There's one room for the kids
and another for us.
So how come Mrs Vilanelle
heard you spend the night
with children
and say: "Pyjama's on!"
What is this? A bad joke?
So what if I did?
What are you trying to prove
with such tattle?
Mom...
I know you're there, I beg you...
I cannot bear the pain.
Help me to be with you.
Help me.
Come on now.
You can do it, sir.
Can you hear me, sir?
Alain?
Can you hear me?
I have good news, Alain.
Your wife
has been released on probation
and Burgaud transferred to Paris.
We'll ask for new face-offs
and re-appeal your detention.
Guard!
Yeah, what's up?
Should be a release order for me.
Can you go see?
The office is closed now.
No outs before tomorrow.
Here, for you.
Raise your arms.
Okay.
Thomas was being very difficult
and dragging Sébastien down too.
The grandparents
couldn't handle him,
so I tried taking him,
but to no avail.
He won't get out of bed,
won't go to school, runs away.
He saw his mom one weekend,
it was a disaster.
So the family judge decided
to place him in a home
and he agrees.
He suffers for you.
Constantly asks to see you.
But the judges refuse
for fear you use him
to pressure his kid brother.
And Edith?
Any news?
I've had no letters since she's out.
Edith has cut all contact with us.
It appears she's met someone.
And just so you know,
your in-laws haven't exactly
redeemed your image
in the children's eyes.
Visiting time's over.
Finish up.
You have to sign
for the sale of the house.
I got the money
for the practice.
Enough to pay you later
and keep the bank at bay.
Chin up, my boy.
Keep the faith.
Delarue has appealed anew.
Dear Mr President,
I wish to inform you of my dreadful
ordeal of the past 20 months
and my intention to die in prison
by going on hunger strike...
Dear Minister of Justice,
I wish to inform you of my dreadful
ordeal of the past 20 months...
Dear Chairman of the Senate,
I wish to inform you
of my dreadful ordeal...
Dear mayor,
I wish to inform you
of my dreadful ordeal...
Dear Mr Prime Minister,
I write to you as a last resort,
that my distress be heard
and my innocence recognized.
You are Alain Marécaux,
number 251266A?
Yes.
It's my duty to summon you here,
as you've begun a hunger strike.
Are you continuing it?
That makes one more.
Goodbye, sir.
11.5, a bit low Mr Marécaux.
A deep breath.
Ready.
There you go.
You may get dressed.
Mr Marécaux!
Are you okay?
Sit yourself down.
How do you feel?
I'm okay.
Like a glass of water?
It's not too hot?
I'm numb.
And there?
Get the doctor.
Feel anything?
We warned you, Mr Marécaux.
You risk losing
the use of your legs.
Your ordeal is an outrage.
I've appealed anew,
but the judge is dragging his heels.
So I wrote to the Minister
of Justice holding him responsible.
I beg you, Alain,
you must stop this.
You must hold out
till the Assize hearing.
I promise we'll win.
Can you hear me, Mr Marécaux?
Do you have children?
What ages are they?
You don't remember?
And their names?
Mr Marécaux, you've been freed.
Wake up.
The ambulance is on its way.
Come, Mr Marécaux, you'll be treated
in a special hospital.
Up you get, nice and easy.
That's right.
- Is this okay?
- Thank you.
Mr Marécaux,
be a nice chap and eat something.
It's got no taste.
It's normal, taste and smell
take months to recover.
You'll be
on probation till the trial.
You can neither see your kids
nor leave Haute-Saone
where your niece agreed to host you.
They prefer that an alleged
paedophile live
with three young children
than at his father's.
Where?
Blackcurrant?
No, redcurrants!
The phone's ringing!
We'll pick other fruit.
Off you go.
Hello?
Yes, fine.
Soon time for their bath.
Sure... No bother at all.
Have fun.
Well, I never!
Hello?
It's me...
Alain.
Am I disturbing?
No...
Are you okay?
Fine... And you?
I'm okay.
Do you see the kids? Are they well?
I saw them today at my Parents'.
They were good.
They said you'd written
and they'll answer soon.
Why are you doing this, Edith?
It's over, Alain. It's too late.
I no longer love you.
Hello, pet.
I want custody
of Cécile and Sébastien.
- And Thomas?
- No.
I can't handle him.
He's increasingly tough
and disobedient.
Wait!
I'll go get him.
Mr Marécaux?
And you?
Forbidden, for now,
from looking after them,
I must agree.
But I'd like visiting rights.
They're still highly traumatized
so I'd prefer visiting rights later,
when they're better.
I tend to agree.
And Thomas, unfortunately,
is an unruly child
needing special care.
I see no other solution
but to leave him in the home.
I disagree.
True, Thomas isn't easy.
But when I left him
he was a top student.
Today, he's out of school,
drifting from home to home,
drinking, smoking,
attempting suicide.
All because of you judges!
My kids needed love and care
not to be treated like misfits
and given to strangers.
All rise!
The court is now in session.
And all the others you accused
during the inquiry
but not investigated by
Judge Burgaud, are they guilty too?
For example, Gilles Bertrand?
Don't know him.
Yet you claimed
he drove your children to Belgium.
Problem is, he's handicapped.
He can't walk unaided,
he can't even drive!
Maybe I mistook him.
And...
Dr Marielle, remember?
You accused him too.
He's different.
I accused him out of revenge.
For what?
One day he hurt my son.
How? While examining him?
Yes.
So you lied?
He never raped your children.
True, I lied for him.
But only him.
But if you lied for those two,
Mrs Badaoui,
what proves you're not lying
for the 13 others here present?
Don't shun responsibility
by implicating innocent people.
Weigh your words carefully.
Those accused
risk 20 years in prison!
All the accused here present,
they all did something.
The hearing will resume at 2 pm.
Mind what you say.
I hope you get 20 years,
you sick bitch!
Child rape is vile!
Like accusing innocent people!
Look me in the eye!
I can say I'm clean!
Hello, Jimmy. Are you well?
Recognize these people?
Jimmy?
Do you recognize any of them?
Yes.
They all raped me.
So you went to the Marécaux's?
Yes.
And what happened?
They made advances.
And who else was there?
Can you show me?
Sandrine Lavier was there?
No, she did nothing.
She was nice.
Yet you accused her too?
I made a mistake.
So, who else was there?
- Alain Marécaux?
- Yes.
He was there.
Can you point him out?
Well?
You don't recognize this man
whom you accused for 3 years?
I thought he was a lawyer.
Roselyne Godard was there!
I saw her kill her husband
with a spade!
I'd ask you to stop
this police interrogation!
You insinuate he's a liar,
when he's a victim!
We have many questions for Jimmy,
given that he's accused
over fifty people!
Including, here present,
13 men and women
jailed for 3 years
mainly on the basis
of his testimony!
Your Honour, Mrs Badaoui
has important revelations
to make to the court.
Then let's hear her.
I don't know how you'll take it,
but I have to say it.
Roselyne, you did nothing.
Sorry.
Mr Godard, neither did you.
Karine, you did nothing, sorry.
Mr and Mrs Marécaux,
I don't even know you.
You did nothing.
Sorry.
David Brunet,
Thierry,
Pierrot,
Sandrine and Franck,
you did nothing either.
Sorry.
I'm sick,
I'm a liar...
But I didn't want my boys
to be called liars
so I backed what they said
from the start.
I lied about everything.
Only four of us raped the kids,
from beginning to end.
Me,
my husband,
Aurélie Grenon and David Delplanque.
That's what I had to say.
Your Honour, if I may?
Mrs Badaoui,
If you didn't know the Marécaux's,
how did you come to accuse them?
The judge told me the kids
mentioned a bailiff.
I had debts
that bailiffs Lambert and Pascal
were dealing with.
So I gave their names.
But the judge said:
"No, another."
"Think hard."
But as I didn't know any others,
I asked him:
"What kind of name is it?"
And he said: "The children
gave the name of Marécaux."
"And children don't lie."
So I confirmed it.
But that's not how it's noted!
Well, that's how it happened.
Yet you photo-identified them?
Easy, their names were written.
Well,
I propose we adjourn for today.
We can't stop there!
I have jurors here
with trains to catch.
I demand that
the court acknowledge
what's just been said!
It can wait until tomorrow.
Adjourned till 9 tomorrow morning.
Mr Burgaud!
Like to comment?
Any comment?
Are you aware of the new
developments in this case?
I did hear about
Mrs Badaoui's clearing of
the 13 accused and her retraction.
And does this beg
any questions for you?
I came here to explain
my methodology of investigation
with no certainty
but a critical eye.
As for new elements,
I've no comment.
So what material proof did you find
of this paedophile ring,
by way of DNA tests,
phone-taps, investigations
and searches in France and Belgium?
Admittedly, nothing very conclusive.
So "methodology" and "critical eye",
but no proof?
Due to media coverage
elements were doubtless destroyed.
Your naivety is staggering!
For you, all was in order.
Weekly, Mrs Badaoui and her children
were making
ever crazier allegations.
The Belgian police found no farm,
crime, but no corpse...
Didn't it ring a bell?
Of doubt?
The Belgian inquiry proved
fruitless, yet it was just one lead.
But behind it all are human beings,
broken lives.
My client repeatedly
attempted suicide,
his mother died.
A 14th accused person died
in jail of depression and pills.
How do you feel about that?
Our job is not emotion.
It is to analyse a dossier,
a purely technical task.
My decisions were vetted
by the examining chamber
and if they ratified them,
it's not for me to say.
But you are also human.
So kindly leave the judge aside.
I'm addressing you
on behalf of these men and women.
Look at them.
Look at them!
No need to, I know them already.
But with no proof
you don't let people rot in prison!
Was that technical too?
Fear pervaded this case.
Each time, detention was referred
to the custodial judge.
So you have no qualms.
You repeatedly hide
behind other judges.
You regret nothing in the disastrous
way you led this investigation?
No further questions, Your Honour.
As for those remanded in custody,
it does beg certain questions.
And rightly so.
And I bow
to those unjustly implicated,
who deserve our compassion.
Yet what is indisputable
in this case,
which Judge Burgaud's
thorough investigation
has all too clearly demonstrated,
is the suffering of these children,
the existence of a murky coalition
of certain people tacitly profiting
from their prostitution...
The devious behaviour
of certain parents
with regard to their own children.
We denounce an unprecedented
collapse of the law, firstly
the incompetence of a young judge
who investigated solely
upon accusation,
but also of all those bodies
meant to supervise him,
starting with the State Prosecutor,
you yourself,
as judge and part,
whose apparent reason for being here
is to save the institution
of the law by ensuring
that this trial does not end
with 13 acquittals!
The Assize Court
hereby returns its verdict.
The court and jury,
having deliberated
for each of the accused, sentences
for rape, sexual molestation
and corruption of minors,
Thierry Delay, please rise,
to 20 years' imprisonment...
Myriam Badaoui,
15 years' imprisonment...
David Delplanque,
6 years imprisonment...
Aurélie Grenon,
4 years' imprisonment...
Dominique Weil,
7 years' imprisonment...
But I'm innocent!
Franck Lavier,
6 years' imprisonment...
We didn't do anything!
Some justice!
Thierry Dausque,
4 years' Imprisonment...
Like the liars said,
they did nothing!
Silence in court!
Daniel Legrand junior,
3 years' imprisonment...
I don't even know them!
For sexual molestation of his son,
Alain Marécaux,
an 18-month suspended sentence...
Sandrine Lavier,
a 3-year suspended sentence.
The Assize Court hearing
is hereby adjourned.
Well done!
I'd have preferred 20 years
for Jimmy
than 18 months suspended for my son.
We'll appeal, Alain.
But I'm flat broke.
Don't worry.
Mr Marécaux,
would you care to comment?
Mr Marécaux!
No, Mr Marécaux!
Mr Marécaux, stay with us.
What's going on?
You attempted suicide.
You were in a coma for two days,
but it's okay now.
I suggest you apply for the status
of handicapped adult
entitling you to a small allowance
and a therapeutic apartment
with home treatment and care.
What do you think?
The Appeal Court finally acquitted
Alain Marécaux and the 5 remaining
defendants on 1 December 2005
triggering the greatest French
legal scandal in living memory
The Supreme Judicial Council
acknowledged blatant negligence
by Judge Burgaud
and imposed a reprimand upon him
on 29 April 2009
No other judges were sanctioned
Alain Marécaux resumed his functions
as bailiff on 14 March 2007
All rise!
The hearing is now in session,
you may be seated.
This morning, the swearing in
of ministerial officers.
Please, step forward.
In the absence of the Prosecutor,
Deputy Prosecutor, you may sum up.
Thank you, Your Honour.
By order of the Ministry of Justice,
6 February 2007,
Mr Alain Marécaux
was appointed bailiff.
May it now please the court
to receive and register his oath.
Bailiff Marécaux,
kindly raise your right hand.
Do you swear to fulfil
your functions with probity
and honour
all their incumbent duties?
I swear.
Subtitles : Peter Leonard
Subtitling: C.M.C.