["Gypsy" by Stevie Nicks]
♪ So I'm back ♪
♪ To the velvet underground ♪
♪ Back to the floor that I love ♪
♪ To a room with some lace
Some paper flowers ♪
♪ Back to the gypsy that I was ♪
♪ To the gypsy that remains ♪
♪ Faces freedom
With a little bit of fear ♪
♪ I have no fear ♪
♪ I have only love ♪
♪ But she was just a wish ♪
♪ She was just a wish ♪
♪ And lightning struck only once ♪
♪ And your gypsy ♪
♪ Your gypsy ♪
[jazz music playing]
Seems like the perfect holiday
for the Faitelsons.
I'm sure that it is life-changing.
Yeah, well, I'd rather backpack
than end up on some fancy wine tour.
Well, and you can't ride a bike.
Fuck you.
-Jean, it's been too long.
-Oh, hey, Allen.
Congrats on the new grandson.
-You did a great job with this.
-Thank you.
Well,
Michael did a wonderful job in Texas.
-Aw, thank you.
-I heard.
You guys looking at the Burgundy trip?
-Ah, well...
-No, I think Jean wants to rough it more.
I think maybe an ashram in India,
or something or a silent retreat.
[Jean]
I never said that. He's being ridiculous.
-She's thinking it, though.
-[laughing]
-[Allen whispers]
-[Michael] Okay. All right.
Okay, um, have you had enough small talk
with my colleagues?
Oh, you know how I like
to play the perfect wife.
You do a very good job of it.
[Michael] Mm.
Did you see, um...
Hey, Alexis. You look beautiful.
You too, Jean.
-[Michael] Hey.
-Hi.
Enjoying the party?
Yeah, I mean,
I don't know half the people here,
but it's an open bar.
My attitude exactly.
It sounds like you guys had fun in Texas,
at least.
Yeah. It was pretty uneventful.
Yeah, it was, you know, work, hotel...
Still, must be nice to be
in the middle of nowhere, right?
Yeah, I guess.
-Hey, honey. Um...
-Yes?
-Can you grab me another?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
Looks like Alexis needs one, too.
-All right.
-Thanks, honey.
Okay.
-[Jean] How are you?
-[Alexis] Good.
Oh, wow.
[Alexis] Wish I could afford that.
-It's so evocative, right?
-Yeah.
[shutter clicks]
So, how's the writing coming along?
Michael mentioned
that you were pursuing it on the side.
Yeah. Good, actually. I, um...
I just found out that one of my stories
is going to be in n+1 magazine.
Wow.
It's kind of like
an indie version of Salon.
Honey, did you know Alexis's story
is going to be in a magazine?
-Oh. Oh, well, congratulations.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
-It's, um, it's the one you read.
-Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-About my dad.
[nervous chuckle]
-[Alexis] Cheers.
-Cheers.
[Jean] Congratulations.
That's, uh, fantastic.
Oh, it's Bill and Leslie.
I didn't say hello. Would you mind?
-Sorry. Excuse us, sorry. Okay.
-Of course.
-I'll see you later?
-Yeah.
[chattering]
When did you read Alexis's story?
A couple of weeks ago. She wanted me
to give her some feedback, but...
-I'd like to read it.
-Oh, really?
Since when are you into creative writing?
Maybe I'm into a lot of things
you don't know about.
I'm sure that you are.
At this point, nothing would surprise me.
[exhales]
Do you ever wonder
what your life would've been like
if you'd ended up with Catherine?
No.
No!
What's bringing this up?
I don't know. Just...
You used to be a major stoner back then.
Used to smoke all the time, right?
-Just made me think of her.
-You rejected me.
And I was dulling the pain.
No. You fell hard for her.
Nearly killed me.
I thought about you the whole time.
Yeah, right. Even during sex?
Especially during sex.
[laughing]
You always know what to say, don't you?
[Michael] Mm-hmm.
[exhaling]
[Michael grunts]
-Are you okay?
-Yep.
[Michael sighs]
-I got it.
-No, no...
-Oh.
-Oh, yeah.
-[Michael grunts]
-[groans] Honey.
[Jean sighs]
[sighs]
What?
I guess I'm just really tired.
Oh.
Yeah.
[laughs]
-Yeah, me too.
-And full.
Yeah, well, I'm dying to get to bed.
We'll reschedule.
Okay.
Oops.
Sexy.
[Jean chattering]
-It's cool, right?
-[Sidney] Yeah, I love it.
It's so evocative.
Mm, well,
it sounds like you had a fun night.
Though, you didn't send me
a picture of yourself.
Hold on.
[phone chimes]
-Where are you?
-Home. What do you mean?
When can I finally come over?
-Whenever you want.
-[Sidney laughs] Bullshit.
No, seriously.
I was thinking tomorrow night?
What's your address?
It's 309 West 81st Street.
-What?
-Nothing. I, uh...
I almost dropped my phone in the bath.
-You're in the bath?
-[Sidney] Yeah.
Now I'm picturing you.
I'm scrubbing coffee grinds
out my cuticles.
Super sexy.
Self-care, it's important.
Thanks, Mom.
Mothers know best.
-Do they?
-It's what they say.
I really don't care what people say,
I just don't understand
why you can't come here...
right now.
I mean...
I might have to touch myself.
Oh, God.
Give me a consolation prize.
Like what?
Your last name.
Hart.
I told you. I'm not on social media.
Yeah, yeah.
You're a fucking ghost, I know.
Well, it's too bad.
I would've let you watch, but...
I guess you'll just
have to wait till tomorrow.
[shudders]
-[Jean sighs]
-[door closes]
[Claire] "The two most important days
in your life are the day you're born...
and the day you find out why."
Mark Twain said that.
And Zane ended our meditation
with that quote.
And all of a sudden,
everything came into perspective.
The purpose of my life.
-Which is?
-To give.
Not unlike yours, actually.
I mean, when Rob left my neighbor Pat,
I took her in for two months.
Let her stay in my guest room,
'cause I didn't want her to be alone.
And I made her oatmeal every morning,
and I took care of her.
Well, that's great, Claire.
-It's good to be giving.
-Yeah.
But it's also healthy
to have your own needs. We all do.
But, ultimately, by serving others,
we serve ourselves.
And by accepting myself as I have,
honestly, truthfully,
I hope my daughter will accept me.
Hmm. I have the same hope.
So...
I have been telling her about my work
in here and my work in meditation.
You know, the whole "letting go" thing.
And she has agreed to see me!
[Jean] That's great news.
I'm really happy for you.
[Claire] Yeah, so I wanted to know
how we could work out some time with you.
What for?
Well, I mean, she wants to come in
and do a session with me,
and do you remember at the beginning
of our work, you suggested it?
Right.
And I feel you're the only person
who could do this healing process
with us, Jean.
Right. Of course. Um...
It's just I'm not really, uh...
an unbiased source anymore.
I'm very much a part of your journey,
your perspective, and...
I wouldn't want Rebecca to feel attacked.
I think it would be good
for the two of you to see someone...
that can be fair to both of you.
I'm not very comfortable with that.
-I understand, but--
-Jean...
I really need this.
Okay.
If you truly think
Rebecca will be open to it,
let's-- let's do it.
-You mean it?
-Against my better judgment, yes.
-Hey.
-Can we talk for a sec?
-Sure, what's up?
I don't want you to panic,
but it's a little troubling.
Oh, no. Is something wrong?
Well, it's about Texas.
Uh, if they are recanting
their statements again,
-I'm telling you, I am not--
-No. Nothing about the case.
Oh, okay.
-It's about your assistant.
-Alexis?
Apparently, there's a story
going around that you...
were intimate on the trip.
Are you kidding?
Wow.
Okay. Listen.
Look, Allen, I would tell you.
I consider you to be a friend.
I would own up to it
and tell you if I fucked up.
I mean,
that happens to people all the time.
Nothing...
like that happened.
Okay.
Then it's a non-issue.
Just wanted to hear from you.
Well,
I appreciate you coming to me directly.
Of course.
Hi, Rebecca. It's Diane.
Listen, I need to speak to you. Um...
It's a long story. Can you call me back
when you get a chance?
Thanks.
[knock on door]
Hey, come in.
I have to talk to you.
Yeah?
-You missed it.
-What?
My a capella show.
-Oh, fuck, Lar.
-It's fine. It's fine. I'm...
-Honestly, I'm so over it by now.
-No, I'm so sorry.
But, um, it did make me think...
in general,
you've been really absent.
You're right.
-I haven't been there.
-The more I think about it,
how selfish you've been,
how addicted to your phone,
or how you're just lost
in your own world...
I realized that I recognize this behavior.
I remember the signs from Daryl.
He was so aloof, and he was so forgetful.
-Operating like no one else existed.
-You know me.
Larin, I'm not cheating on Michael.
I couldn't do that.
You remember how paralyzed I got
when things weren't good between us.
But you're right.
I haven't been a good friend.
Okay.
[sighs]
[whispering] What the fuck am I doing?
So, I found many mentions in print,
but no images.
I told you, I like my privacy.
Mmm. It's like you're not a real person.
I mean, you have nothing out there.
[Jean exhales]
-Hey, delete that.
-Or what?
I mean it.
-Oh, you're cute when you're angry.
-I'm not fucking around.
All right, fine.
-Deleted it. See?
-Good.
What the fuck happened to you?
What do you mean?
Something bad must have happened.
I mean...
you don't go AWOL with no attachments
if your life's been peachy keen.
How do you know?
I don't think you're a criminal, either.
Yeah, well, I could probably rob a bank
and no one would notice.
They might even hold the door for me
on the way out.
-So you're invisible?
-Mm-hmm.
And you think that means
you can do whatever the fuck you want?
Doesn't it?
Look, whatever it is, I don't care.
With our lives and our jobs,
we could easily just hit the road.
[Sidney chuckles]
Where would we go?
Have you ever been to Marfa?
-No.
-Well...
We can road trip there...
fuck around.
And then drive our car off a cliff
like Thelma &amp; Louise.
-Yeah, well, that's not how I'd do it.
-Oh, yeah?
If you really want to escape,
you need a plan.
I'd start by renting a Westfalia,
send my apologies to my colleagues
for missing any deadlines,
tell them I have a second cousin's funeral
that I have to attend in South Dakota.
No, fuck it.
South Dakota's way too specific.
Maybe Cleveland or outside Sacramento?
And we'd go on a regular week,
not a holiday.
And...
that way, people would be consumed
with their real lives, their work.
And then, I'd sell off
all my ex-husband's jewelry.
The kind you can't wear
for emotional reasons.
And then we'd burn through that money
with reckless abandon.
[heavy breathing]
Dude, you're taking way too long
on your breaks.
Suck my dick.
[Alexis chuckles]
What did Allen wanna talk to you about?
I need you to be honest with me, okay?
-Should we go into your office?
-No, we shouldn't.
That'll just make it worse.
-[stammering] What worse?
-Did you tell anyone about Texas?
-Of course not. What do you mean?
-Did you mention...
anything about me...
on our trip to anyone?
Are you crazy?
Why would I open my...
mouth?
Dan and Lena in accounting
did mention something similar at lunch.
I thought they were just
making assumptions.
They probably just picked up
on something.
There's nothing to pick up on.
-Right.
-Could you hand me that, uh...
that file?
-I'm gonna have to move your desk.
-Don't do that.
That'll only make you look more guilty.
-Make people more suspicious.
-I know that.
We didn't even do anything.
Doesn't matter.
Now, it's basically the same as if we did.
[church bell ringing]
-Hey! What's going on?
-Shh! It's okay.
Hey, just wait a second. Tell me.
I shouldn't have gone
to that fucking meeting, okay?
Look, I'm not proud of myself.
Did you?
It was a moment of weakness. Okay?
Couldn't help myself.
-And you were with Tom?
-Yeah.
Because I don't have anywhere else
to fucking go.
Amber's boyfriend moved back in.
He's a raging alcoholic.
I can't live with my mom.
At least, with him,
I have somewhere to stay.
I can sleep through the night.
How do you walk away from that?
Just to feel good
for one night is something.
We could talk to your mom.
Would that help, if I go with you?
I told you I'm not ready. Don't push me.
I won't push you.
I'm sorry.
I just want a chance to be a real person
in the world.
Like you.
-I'm only as real as you are.
-No, you're not.
No, you got things.
No, you got things!
Imagine if you couldn't go home
to your fucking suburban life?
-All right, I'm just gonna call him.
-No, hold on.
Look...
I have a solution.
Just for a few days,
until we talk to your mom, okay?
Please.
What is this place?
[door closes]
It's a friend's.
She's out of town,
so sometimes I check in on it.
Diane?
Yeah.
Expensive looking.
You know, I'm trusting you here.
You really are a miracle worker.
No, I'm not.
My friend Drew, remember?
Her mom said the same.
Maybe you're my magic pill.
Well, I just wanna help.
-It's my job.
-No. No one cares.
They say they care.
They look you in the eye and tell you
that your problems matter to them, but...
Soon enough, they're back
debating what to watch on TV,
what restaurant to eat at.
I just want you to have a real chance.
I don't want you going back to drugs
just because you don't have any options.
You know, if I had a mom like you,
I'd give it all up.
-Hey there, hot shot.
-Hey. What, you got groceries?
Yeah, I was gonna make
some turkey meatballs.
Oh, that sounds delicious.
How was work?
Um, it was good. It was good.
[panting] Allen thought,
you know, we did a good job...
in Texas,
and he was happy to see you the other day.
[basketball dribbling]
Looking good, mister.
-[Dolly] What's your name?
-Oh, you know my name, honey.
Mommy, I'm trying to memorize my lines.
Oh, for the play.
It's so hard when one minute I'm Dolly,
and the next, I'm Peter Pan.
It's confusing.
Well, it's acting.
It's supposed to be fun.
And you get to pretend to be someone else.
Yeah.
The best way is just
to go over and over it
so much that
you don't even have to think about it.
You know it so well,
and it's inside of you.
You start to believe it yourself.
-Can you read Wendy?
-Sure.
What's your name?
Wendy Moira Angela Darling.
-What's yours?
-Peter Pan.
Where do you live?
I don't know.
[heavy breathing]
Look at me.
-Look at me.
-I'm looking at you. What?
[heavy breathing]
Hey.
[Sam]
Things with Emily are really good.
She's lost some weight
and is actually more adventurous.
I mean...
Last night, in the middle of sex,
she even slapped me.
-How did you like it?
-The slap?
I hadn't felt that way in a while. Um...
-That kind of intensity.
-Hmm.
Why do you think she did it?
Guess she wanted to get my attention.
And what were you thinking about?
Um, I don't know.
I was in the moment.
Emily's really helping me move on.
She doesn't even let me
say Sidney's name anymore.
That's good, Sam.
But as you pursue a relationship
with Emily,
it's important that you continue working
on your unresolved feelings for Sidney.
Right, but I'm over her.
I don't want to talk about her with you.
You seem a little angry.
Was there any aggression?
Did things ever get physical
with you and Sidney?
Depends what you mean by physical.
Sidney calls it "good pain."
When you're just toeing that line between
hurting and complete fucking ecstasy.
I'm sure drug addicts get it
when they shoot up, I don't know.
What did she do...
to make you feel that way?
[sighs]
Well, she'd get mad at me, right?
And then, we'd fight.
And then, she'd say something
like she was gonna go...
blow the guys
at the bar down on our street.
Take them all home and make me watch
while she sucked them all off.
And while she'd start to tell me this,
she'd suck on my cock.
It was crazy.
How did you like it?
Well, I never came as hard
as when we did it like that.
It's sick, I know, but I couldn't help it.
And can I ask...
how does it make you feel
thinking about it here, in this room?
[heavy breathing]
What are you doing to me?
Seriously...
You think you're helping?
I'm telling you I moved on.
I'm fucking happy.
What do you want me to say?
That I think about Sidney
every time I fuck Emily?
Sam, it's clear that you seem
to have a lot of...
emotion surrounding this subject.
[stammers] I'm sorry for raising my voice.
Look...
I'm happy
that Emily's helping you move on.
It's just what I want.
You know that, right?
But it's important that you release all
of your feelings here with me.
[knock on door]
[Larin] Come in.
-Hey.
Can you talk for a sec?
[Larin] Sure.
What's up?
I, uh, wanted to apologize for yesterday.
You were...
right to say something.
I haven't been honest with you.
I actually haven't been honest
with anyone.
I, um...
I have been having issues with Michael.
What kind of issues?
Just been fighting a lot
and it's part of the reason I've been
on my phone so much.
The other night, I was awake at two a.m.,
and he wasn't in bed,
and he was in the bathroom talking
to someone on the phone.
Is it his assistant?
Honestly, I don't know.
I know he's interested.
I can tell from the way he...
He tries to leave her out of stories.
The way he forces himself
not to say her name.
Oh, God.
That's so hard.
I haven't even spoken to him yet.
I don't know if he trusts me
after everything that went down.
I mean, that's possible.
When you shut someone out emotionally,
you know, it's hard to get the trust back.
And you blurred so many boundaries.
But I was protecting Melissa.
I couldn't tell Michael anything about it.
It would be implicating him.
She's the patient.
I get it, but you know,
somewhere along the way,
Michael lost you.
I get that's the price for doing business,
but it still has an effect.
I don't know who I'd be without him.
It's like I'm so anxious, and so...
I'm a mess.
[sighs deeply]
Seriously, I'm scared of you.
Oh. So, how's it going?
How's your sister doing?
-She gets out in about two weeks.
-Oh, yeah?
We still haven't spoken,
and I'm actually a little worried.
And she's still at Bellevue?
Yeah. It's all pretty intense
for my family.
Especially my mom. She's spiraling.
Saugraves! Focus!
What, are you getting me
into trouble, Diane?
-You wanted to see me?
-Yeah, hey. Come and sit.
[Scott] Man, I'm still exhausted.
I gotta dep downtown--
Hey, everyone in the firm thinks
something happened with me and Alexis.
Yeah, I heard that, too.
Nothing happened, Scott.
Oh, I wouldn't say "nothing."
You know I saw Alexis leaving your room
in the morning.
I don't think that you'd be happy
if Jennifer knew that.
Why are you threatening me?
I didn't say shit.
I depend upon my reputation, Scott.
And I can't have paralegals whispering
about me.
And I can't fire her now
when everyone thinks that
I'm sleeping with her, which I am not.
I didn't say a fucking word.
Then...
how...
did it get out?
Tell me. Enlighten me, Scott.
It is so obvious, dude.
She's in love with you.
She wants everyone to think
that you're fucking her.
It's why she came to Texas.
It's probably why she fucked me.
But you're in major denial, man.
You don't think you had
some responsibility in this situation.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
How is it my responsibility?
By bringing her with you on that trip
and hanging out.
Knowing the way you clearly both feel
about each other.
It's hard to say
where you draw the line, dude.
Okay, thanks.
[clattering]
[ripping sound]
[♪♪]
This is Jean Hart.
These are my recordings.
-Can I help you?
-Hey. Liza, right?
Oh, Diane. Hi.
Hey.
Look, I actually left my ID here
the other night.
And, uh, I--
-I don't mean to barge in on you, but--
-Okay.
[Jean] Rebecca.
-God, Diane.
-Oh, sorry.
[breathing heavily] You scared me.
Where are you off to?
Costa Rica. A bunch of us are woofing
on a farm down there.
Wow, sounds cool.
Look. I, um...
I stupidly lost my ID,
so I'm just trying to retrace my steps.
I tried calling you.
I haven't seen anything.
Oh, and, uh...
tomorrow, I'm going to a new exhibit--
exhibition at the Rubin Museum.
-Are you free?
-No, actually.
I'm...
I'm finally seeing my mother.
Wow. That's great progress.
Well, she's been insisting that I join her
in therapy for so long now.
And I made some pretty big
life decisions. Seemed like...
the right moment
to get things off my chest.
What-- what kind of decisions?
Um...
Dax and I are having a baby.
But I just really need
to fully separate from my mother
before I can become one myself.
I, um...
I actually-- I wrote her a letter,
since I'll probably be too... nervous
to say all this to her face the moment
that I'm looking her in the eye.
A letter, that's-- that's intense.
Well, will you tell me
if this makes sense?
Now I'm worried.
"Mom...
I forgive you,
but it's partly 'cause I'm moving on.
What I realize now is I can't continue
to work on me
or fulfill my life's duties while
I'm still trying to take care of you.
So, until you can love me
the way that I need,
I think we should take a break."
What do you think?
Honestly, I don't wanna negatively impact
your progress with my experiences.
Come on.
Tell me.
Here's what's gonna happen.
The therapist is gonna ask your mom to
go through all the ways that you hurt her.
And the truth is,
it's her therapist, so...
even if she tries to be neutral,
it's always gonna be biased.
-I mean, she's been treating her for what?
-Years now.
Right, exactly.
If I were you, I would just...
take the trip
and take some time to rest
for yourself, without your mom.
I can't take care of her anymore.
[sighs]
I don't know. I must've...
Did you find your ID?
No, I must've left it
at the gym or something.
But hey, listen.
Congratulations on your pregnancy.
That's big news.
You know, I'm beginning to think
that we fight so hard against our mothers
because we're really just in denial
that we might actually become them.
[sniffles]
-[steam hissing]
-[chattering]
Hi. I wanted to pick up some coffee.
-Ground?
-Sure.
How daring are you?
Well, do you want
the more intense blend or the mild?
Oh, well, it's for my wife.
We'll go with intense, then.
-What's her name?
-Jean.
[cash register beeping]
There you go. You can keep it.
Thanks.
-Here you go.
-All right.
Oh, and here's a flyer for my band.
You can check us out on Instagram.
Okay.
-Have a good day.
-You too.
[sigh]
Yeah, you're kinda the only person
I can talk to right now.
[Nancy] Oh, I'm glad.
-Looking forward to seeing you.
-Okay, good.
Sounds good. Thanks, Mom.
-I love you.
-I love you, Jeannie. Bye.
-[Michael] Hello?
-Hey!
Hey.
Hi. We're still good for our date, right?
-It's nothing fancy.
-Well, I still wanna look good for you.
-Um, I got you something.
-Yeah? What?
What were you doing there?
Well, I know how much
you like the coffee and, um--
Just thought I'd check it out.
It was nice. I can see why you like it.
Thanks.
The barista gave me a flyer for her band.
Listen.
["Francine" playing]
What flyer?
♪ Oh, Francine, don't you be so mean ♪
Not bad, right?
♪ You don't belong to me ♪
It's okay.
[woman vocalizing]
-It sounds so familiar.
-Yeah. All those bands sound the same.
♪ I'd keep you if I could ♪
Maybe.
♪ I'd make you mine, yes, I would ♪
Were you into the girl or something?
What? No. No.
No.
[laughs]
-Why the fascination?
-No, I was curious...
[stammering]
Oh, yeah, I Iike it
when you're jealous, though.
No, you don't.
♪ You and me and my man makes three ♪
[vocalizes]
All right.
Anyway, I'm gonna take a shower.
♪ Oh, honey, you look so good... ♪
[breathing raggedly]
[phone dings]
[sighs]
[knock on door]
Hello?
Hello, who's there?
[water running]
What was that for?
Don't ever go to my coffee shop again.
[heavy breathing]
[both moaning]
♪ Oh, Francine, you ride like a dream ♪
♪ Just like light through a stone
On a crown on a Queen ♪
[vocalizes]
♪ Honey, you look so good
Look so good ♪
♪ And you feel so good, feel so good ♪
♪ I'd keep you if I could ♪
♪ I'll make you mine, yes, I would ♪
♪ I'll make you mine ♪
♪ Oh, Francine, don't you be so mean ♪
♪ You don't belong to me, belong to me ♪
♪ Belong to me, belong to me
Belong to me ♪