Subtitles by DramaFever
[The Virtuous Queen of Han]
[Episode Thirty]
Since the Empress left the palace,
signs of rainfall keep appearing.
It is enough to prove that
in the Empress' absence
the wind and rain would come.
The Empress arrives!
Happiness and peace to the Empress!
Great blessings to Your Majesty.
You may all rise.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
- Thank you, Your Majesty!
Since Empress is already here
I shall see if it is as
King of Huainan said.
That with Empress on the platform,
rain will not fall.
I ask that Your Highness leave the
platform as soon as possible
for the sake of the people and nation.
I've already pleaded with the gods
to soon bless us with rainfall.
Should Empress' presence infuriate
the gods and cease the rainfall
wouldn't that cause more
suffering to the people?
How could Your Highness bear to do so?
- Yes, exactly.
- Please leave, Your Highness.
Your Highness, please leave now.
- Please leave now.
- Leave now.
If my departure would
bring rain and wind
I would retreat to the
other side of the world.
If sacrificing my life would bring
rain to my suffering people
I wouldn't dare stay living.
But the climate cannot
be changed by a ritual.
I am of the imperial family.
I will not allow anyone to confuse
the public with superstition.
If rain is to fall,
how could it be ceased by me?
If rain is not to fall
how could it be changed by
King of Huainan?
Today, the gods will be our witnesses.
We shall see who is
right and who is wrong.
May the gods bless my
people of Great Han
not to be swayed by superstitions.
I'm willing to share the worries
and joys here with the people.
I will wait here for rainfall
to nourish my people.
Empress holds the umbrella
to pray to the gods
for rainfall to nourish the people!
I ask that Your Highness
leave the platform quickly
so that I may plead to Tai Yi again...
Empress holds the umbrella
to pray to the gods
for rainfall to nourish the people!
Leave now! Don't stay here!
Shut up!
Empress is praying for rain!
- Leave now!
- Leave!
Whether it rains or not
I will be be your god
and watch over you.
Emperor and Empress are of one mind!
Their kindness will bless the people!
Gods!
Please don't rain yet.
Rain after the Empress leaves.
Help my Jiao Er, gods!
Emperor and Empress are of one mind!
Their kindness will bless the people!
- It's raining!
- Prayers for rain are answered!
- Gods bestowed rain upon us!
We owe this to the Empress!
Yes!
Thank you, gods!
God of sun, Tai Yi,
took pity on us!
Empress prayed for rain!
Gods bestowed rain upon us!
Empress holds the umbrella and
gods bestowed rain upon us!
It is finally raining!
- It is raining!
- This is great!
This is great!
The rain came just in time.
If it keeps on raining,
the drought is sure to be relieved.
Great Han is truly blessed.
What was important was that
Sister made it in time to the platform
and broke the rumor of the jinx.
King of Huainan is really cunning.
When it started raining, he immediately
knelt down to thank the gods.
Exactly.
It was as if he was the one
who got the rain to fall.
What an act he put on.
His Majesty will never let him off.
Xi Niang, now that you are
the general's mother-in-law
you've definitely changed.
You're so insightful now.
How could I be compared to you?
You're suddenly so knowledgeable.
You understand everything,
from astronomy to geography.
You could tell it was going to rain
just by watching the ants move.
Such remarkable foresight!
I think you're praising me,
but why do you sound so sarcastic?
Are you so unwilling
to give me credit?
We really owe it to Uncle Yi.
If it hadn't been for Uncle Yi
Liu An would have gotten
away with his scheme.
Not only would the Empress be the jinx
but the reputation of His Majesty
would also be damaged.
Sister is vindicated again.
It was all Uncle Yi's doing.
Vindication came because
of the Empress' kindness.
The gods are aware of her virtue.
We owe it to Uncle Yi's quick wit
for challenging Liu An with
his own conflicting theories.
You made use of his 'Pattern of Heaven'
to allow the people to see the truth
and not be swayed by superstition.
Stop praising me.
Actually...
Actually we all deserve credit for this.
How could he take all the credit?
Wei Qing should take credit
for stalling Liu An's ritual.
Master Duan escorted the Empress to the
ritual platform in the nick of time.
And His Majesty is wise and decisive.
I reported to him
that it would soon rain
and His Majesty immediately made
all the right arrangements.
That's how Liu An failed.
How delightful!
Don't forget me!
You? Why do you deserve any credit?
Jia Er and I kept yelling
to boost the morale.
We were the ones who
started the chants.
We were yelling at the
top of our lungs!
We even got all
the people to yell with us.
Wei Qing, don't you think that
we deserve some credit?
All right, all of you deserve
some credit for it.
His Majesty will definitely
keep it in mind.
Your Highness, Bai Min is here to report
that His Majesty summons you.
[Feichang Palace]
Your Majesty, Her Highness is here.
Great blessings to Your Majesty.
Greetings to Your Majesty.
You may all rise.
You've been aggrieved.
With the wise arrangements
of Your Majesty
and the assistance of everyone
not only have I upheld my reputation
but the people are also
unswayed by superstition.
I do not feel aggrieved.
Duan Hong, Wei Qing. I shall reward
the both of you well for your credit.
I wouldn't dare take credit for it.
Your Majesty, the one who deserves
the most credit is Uncle Yi.
Yi Han has indeed
performed exceptionally.
If you hadn't discovered the
moving of the insects in time
and the changes in
the winds and clouds
Empress would have had
gained a bad reputation
and the dignity of the imperial
family would have been at risk.
I am but a civilian.
I just happened to know
some common knowledge.
It allows me to spot signs of rainfall
and the affection between
Your Majesty and Your Highness.
It's rare that you don't
take credit for this.
Is it common knowledge to have read
'Gan and Shi's Celestial Book'
and 'Pattern of Heaven'?
You may just be a cook,
but you are well-educated and profound.
Your Majesty, I was only putting
what I learned to use.
I am not profound.
You do not have to be modest.
None of the court officials
are as good as this cook.
It seems that you aren't simply a cook.
I wish to reward wise men.
But the more I think about this,
the more confused I get.
Since such a wise man has stayed by
the Empress' side for so many years
why didn't you assist me as well?
Could it be that I am foolish...
or that I am not virtuous enough
to get your assistance?
Your Majesty, I am but a...
Stop it.
There are only two kinds of people
who are not employed by the emperor.
One is a prisoner who fled
from his punishments.
And the other is an enemy
who has conspiracies in his heart.
Tell me now.
Which one are you?
What is your intention,
hiding in the palace for years?
Yi Han, answer me!
Are you a fugitive or my enemy?
I am not your enemy.
I am a sinner.
Sinner?
I have sinned deeply.
I am ashamed to use my real name.
Not to mention rendering my
services to the imperial court.
How have you sinned?
I met my mentor when I was young
and inherited his knowledge
of medicine, divination
astronomy, geography,
and all sorts of other things.
But I was to be blamed for
my own arrogance.
I was over-confident in my intelligence
and the favor of my mentor
so I challenged my senior to a
contest of sorcery and divination.
Although I defeated my senior
my mentor was then resented
and executed by my senior.
His skills weren't as good as yours,
so he murdered out of jealousy.
Didn't the local officials
do anything about it?
I wouldn't dare to lie to Your Majesty.
Although my senior was later
sentenced to death for his actions
my mentor still died because of me.
Therefore, I swore to myself
that I'd conceal my identity
and stand aloof from worldly affairs.
I burned myself and use the
pain as a constant reminder.
Your Majesty, I am willing to
vouch for Yi Han's character.
I met Uncle Yi when I was just a child.
He gave to me the teaching
'don't fight, don't stand out,
don't show.'
Since then, I've lead my life and
treated others with that lesson.
'Don't fight, don't stand out,
don't show.'
It is indeed how Empress has
conducted herself.
So Empress can lead the harem in
harmony because of Yi Han's lesson?
I wouldn't dare take credit for that.
Her Highness is kind and
generous by nature.
She needs no reminder.
These are just words of
modesty from the Empress
to show her respect for the elders.
Your Majesty, Uncle Yi not only
taught me the ways of life
but I also know deep in my heart
that I was favored by Your Majesty
because of Uncle Yi's assistance.
That year after the flood,
food was scarce.
Empress was still a child then,
but she shared her bread with me.
She saved my life.
Her natural inclination to
self sacrifice was impressive.
Years later, when we met again
Her Highness was as modest
and generous as she used to be.
She was even more virtuous.
Your Majesty happened to visit
the Pingyang Manor then.
I saw that Your Majesty had
the look of affection so...
So you used the seed of a fruit
to help highlight me
before His Majesty's eyes.
The fruit could be of assistance only to
one who would sacrifice to help others.
It helped show your virtue
before His Majesty.
It was because I feel deeply for
Her Highness' virtue.
If she can stay by Your Majesty's side
it will be a great
blessing to the people.
When I had wanted to
leave the palace for good
Uncle Yi gave me an accessory.
That was to make His Majesty
notice me and keep me with him.
Your Majesty, Yi Han not only
assisted the Empress
but also taught me much
about commanding armies.
I went to the battle in
the western regions
armed with Uncle Yi's knowledge
of the local conditions.
Yi Han deserves credit for that as well.
You just said that you wanted to
stand aloof from worldly affairs.
Why have you stayed
in the palace for so many years?
Years ago, Yi Han was the head chef
at Pingyang Manor.
Princess recommended him to the
palace to be of assistance to my sister.
It was not Yi Han's intention
to stay in the palace.
Your Majesty, the Empress ran
into great obstacles
in her first few years in the harem.
I believe that Yi Han chose to stay on
in order to protect Her Highness.
Your Majesty, I dare to guarantee that
he never seeks to take any credit
for taking care of me all these years.
- Not to mention any desire for fame...
- That is enough.
Speak up for yourself.
This is all because it was
my destiny to meet the Empress.
I stayed to repay her
kindness for saving my life.
Her Highness is the role model for all
and I thought that I could finally
retire to return to my hometown.
But then Her Highness was framed by
villains to stain her reputation.
I had no choice but to go against
my oath and approach the platform.
Your Majesty, although Yi Han
concealed his identity
I can guarantee that he
is loyal to Your Majesty.
It was Yi Han who spotted
King of Huainan's scheme
and exposed his lies on the platform.
Without him, it would have been hard
to clear Her Highness of a bad name.
Yi Han does indeed deserve credit
for having anticipated the outcome.
Since you know well of
astronomy and geography
I will appoint you as the Grand Scribe.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
But I had only hoped for Her Highness
to be free from false accusations
and that the people would not
be swayed by superstition.
That would ease my guilt of
having broken my oath.
As a sinner, I'm ashamed
to be awarded a title.
I beg Your Majesty to allow me to stay
as a cook to atone for my sins.
Since you do not want to
be appointed as an official
I will reward you with a manor so
that you may live and work in peace.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I am deeply grateful.
But Her Highness, General Wei,
and Master Duan
treat me as their family.
How could a manor be as good as
being together with my family?
All right, I'll bestow you
an imperial entry permit.
In addition to Jiaofang Palace
I hereby order Wei Qing and Duan Hong
to set up your quarters in their manors.
So that you may stay
at their homes at will.
- I'll obey the orders.
Your Majesty, thank you
for being so understanding.
I will also award you with one
thousand taels of gold.
Your Majesty, Yi Han is not
one who seeks benefits.
I bow to thank Your Majesty
for your rewards.
I am not after the rewards
but disasters have struck and
the people are in difficulties.
I plan to use the rewards given to me to
help those who are alone and in need.
Please allow me to do so.
- Get up now.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
I didn't expect you to
have such kind thoughts.
I shall bestow the title
of 'Elder' to you.
I will also reward you with a carriage
that carries the flag of goodwill.
It should come with a crossbar to
indicate that you're meritorious.
You shall drive the carriage of goodwill
to relieve the people of the disaster.
I thank Your Majesty on behalf
of the people for your kindness.
Those who offer comfort to the
people will all be rewarded.
But those who create trouble and confuse
the people will not be let off easily.
Your Majesty, I have brought you
Liu An, King of Huainan.
Sinner Liu An asks
Your Majesty for forgiveness.
You ask for forgiveness.
You left your territories
without permission
and confused the people
with superstitions.
You've slandered the Empress
and stirred up a commotion.
Which sin are you
pleading for forgiveness?
I am confident of my
knowledge in Daoism
and know a bit about astronomy.
My deceased mentor spoke
to me in my dreams
to save the people from suffering.
In response, and with haste,
I made a huge mistake.
This heavy rain is just
like a timely warning.
I know that I have sinned greatly!
You have indeed sinned greatly!
It is enough to take your life!
Your Highness is kind and generous.
King of Huainan might have sinned
but it was all for the
sake of the people!
I beg Your Highness to sentence
him to a lighter penalty!
I do not dare to agree with
the Chancellor's opinion.
Should everyone use the people
as an excuse to break the laws
what good are the laws and regulations?
King of Huainan has
committed a deadly crime.
How are we to discipline the
officials if we let him off lightly?
Your Majesty, I've practiced
Daoism and wrote books
in order to seek the best
interests for the people.
Since I left Huainan
I came to the capital on my
own to plead for rainfall.
Although I had no intention of treason
I do have the intention
to die for my deeds.
Fortunately, the gods bestowed rain
upon us all and the people are saved.
Your Majesty's and the Empress'
reputation are further glorified.
I have no regrets.
I am willing to accept
the death penalty.
All right! Since you've confessed to
your crime and accepted the penalty
I will grant you your wish!
- Guards!
- Hold it!
Your Majesty, Meng Tzu once said
that the people come before the
nation and before the ruler.
I might be a man of military training
but I have also had tuition
since I was young.
I know that even as officials,
we have to put the people first.
Although King of Huainan did not
follow the laws of the nation
and offended the Emperor and Empress,
the people still owe him gratitude.
I hope Your Majesty will reconsider.
Master Duan misuses the words of
the saints to cover up the sins.
It is ridiculous.
The people comes first and therefore
they must be protected by laws.
If we make an exception for
not punishing the wrongdoer
there will be more cases of wrongdoings
that will cause the people more harm!
My father often said that
to err is to be human.
It is also acceptable to make up
for one's sins with one's merits.
King of Huainan has always been
known to be virtuous.
His many kind deeds to protect
the people are documented.
It should be enough to make
up for one reckless mistake.
Your Majesty, King of Huainan
once pledged with his own life.
It is evident how much he
cares about the people!
Moreover, King of Huainan is
already of an old age.
He traveled alone to the capital
and is now exhausted and weak.
It is said that the old and
the young shouldn't be punished.
I beg Your Majesty to spare
him of his punishment.
The old and the young should
not be punished, indeed.
King of Huainan Liu An left
his territories unauthorized.
He confused the people and
slandered the Empress.
He deserves to be slain for his sins.
But in regards to his concern for
the people, I'll spare him his life.
I command him to leave
the capital immediately!
Thank you, Your Majesty!
In regards to Liu An's old age,
he is unfit to travel long distances.
I shall bestow to him the cane of
turtle-doves as an elderly
to retire in peace in Huainan.
He will no longer need to be here
in court to seek audience.
Thank you, Your Majesty!
My King, your carriage is ready.
You may embark on your journey.
His Majesty said that I do not need
to seek audience with him anymore
but the truth is that he forbids me
to enter the capital again.
I might never have the chance
to be in these walls again.
Master Duan, please excuse me.
Allow me to look at
Chang An for a bit longer.
My King is a man of sentiments.
Master Duan spoke up for me
without any fear of His Majesty.
You are the one with great sentiments.
Master Duan spoke boldly
in defense of justice.
Please accept this bow of mine.
Please get up, My King.
I don't deserve this.
Actually, I stood up for
you not for justice
but for my own
personal interests.
Master Duan, feel free to
tell me what it is about.
May I ask how that
amber beast came about?
Master Duan is referring to this?
This accessory looks familiar to me.
My father once had a similar accessory.
What? Could it be that I have
met your father before?
It's a pity that I am leaving soon
and won't be able to pay
your father a visit.
When I was young, I was separated from
my father when we fled from a disaster.
I have hoped to reunite with my father.
My King, do you remember that
many years ago
you saved a man who gave that to
you to thank you for saving his life?
That man is about my age.
Now that I think about it, he does have
the same surname as Master Duan.
He came from...
Is it Pingyang County?
It is indeed Pingyang County.
This is truly a linked destiny.
Many years later, this accessory
is given back to his son.
It seems that by fate, I was
to come to Chang An for you.
May I ask where my father is now?
Back then, he was severely poisoned
and on the verge of death.
Fortunately, My King tried all
sorts of antidotes on him
and made him a remedy
with tofu to treat him.
I've heard of King of Huainan's
filial affection.
You made food remedies for your mother.
Who knew that my father had the
honor of trying it for himself
and was even cured?
Unfortunately, right after he recovered
he left this behind and left.
I have no idea where he is now.
I remember that your father once
said that he would live in Huainan.
Master Duan!
My King is my father's savior.
You deserve my salute.
Since my father is in Huainan
I beg My King to help me search for
my father so that we may reunite.
Please get up.
Master Duan, please rest assured.
I will definitely do my best
to search for your father.
Duan Hong will never forget
King of Huainan's kindness.
Master Duan's filial affection
has moved the gods.
As long as I shall live,
I will fulfill your wish.
I'm afraid that after
I've returned to my territories
I might not even be able
to fend for myself.
I might let you down.
Why would My King say that?
The favors of the Emperor
are unpredictable.
Now that His Majesty doubts me
he bestowed this copper cane
to ban me from the capital.
Who knows if he might one day bestow
poisonous wine to me to kill me?
By then, in order to prove
my loyalty to His Majesty
I can only give in and
wait for death to take me.
My King cares about the people
but you came to the capital
for them without permission.
Hence, His Majesty misunderstood you.
Although My King never means to
go against His Majesty
one way to protect yourself
is to have your own army.
Master Duan, why have you said so?
The imperial court plans
to promote enfeoffment.
The title of the feudal king
and lands will no longer
be inherited by first born sons.
Feudal kings are allowed to leave
their lands to other children as well.
It might be called enfeoffment
but the effect of it is to weaken
the feudal kings by taking their lands.
Master Duan, thank you for the heads up.
I have spoken too much.
A Prefect of the
Gentlemen-of-the-Palace
who is said to be the
Emperor's favorite official
is actually so foolish!
My King used but a few words,
and he was already deceived.
How difficult could it be?
It is gods' blessings that I met him.
A small accessory is actually
identical to one his father had.
I just went along and made up the
story of how I met his father.
Kinship is always
difficult to get rid of.
Moreover, he was separated
from his father for years.
When it came to kinship,
he let his guard down.
He would believe anything I said.
He sees My King as his savior.
He even revealed the new policy
to weaken the feudal states.
I said that his father is in Huainan
so he will naturally come
to warm up to me in the future.
He is the Prefect of the
Gentlemen-of-the-Palace.
He holds the great power of
safeguarding Chang An.
It will be of great use to
stay friends with this person.
My King is wise.
Do good for the sake of the people?
He actually had other plans in mind.
If he truly is virtuous
why would he try to
win you over right away
when you mentioned the accessory?
I was born in poverty.
Why would my father possess
such a valuable belonging?
He was so eager to win over my favor
that he didn't even think twice before
establishing a connection with me.
It seems that Liu An came
to the capital alone
to slander the Empress for
his own conspiracies.
He didn't just plan these recently.
Once all these events were put together
I couldn't help but think that
Guan Fu and Chancellor Dou
were referring to King of Huainan
when they said that Tian Fen
had conspired with someone
to go against Your Majesty.
I thought that as well.
Therefore, I had no choice
but to let him go free.
I'm afraid he may have conspired with
others of power in the name of virtue.
Moreover, his brothers and
sons are all still in Huainan.
Who knows how many soldiers
and provisions they now own?
Now that the drought subsided and
there are enemies at the frontier
Wei Qing will go to war.
If the feudal kings act up now,
we could be in danger.
Your Majesty had no choice but
to use this delaying tactic.
I hope that releasing him
will turn him into our bait
and we can lure out all
of his partners in crime.
I'll wait patiently for the right
moment to wipe them all out!
Otherwise Your Majesty could have
him die a thousand times over
with any one of the
crimes he committed.
It's been hard on you to
put on this act with me.
You pretended to be
friendly with Liu An.
I'm afraid that you might be
misunderstood as ganging up with rebels.
I would risk it all to rid
the nation of villains
and seek revenge on
Guan Fu and Chancellor Dou!
It is so tiring to take a trip.
I even had to give out bag after bag
of rice to the victims of the disaster.
If My Lady finds it too tiring,
you should have stayed in the manor.
You don't need to be out
there doing such hard work.
Fortunately, this satin outfit
of yours isn't stained.
I couldn't afford to
pay the compensation.
My son-in-law has gone to war
so I definitely have to be out
doing charitable work
to get some blessings to
pray for his safety.
In that case,
work harder next time.
That jade bracelet is quite nice!
You could give that to the victims...
This was bestowed to me
by Empress Dowager!
It must not be sold or given to another.
I couldn't bear to be
punished for disrespect.
Then those earrings...
Jia Er gave these to me!
What about that hairpin?
What would victims of the
disaster want hairpins for?
They can't have it as food.
If you can't bear to part with anything,
how can you do charity work?
Even if there are blessings,
I'm afraid you won't get them!
Just now, those victims kept saying
Thank you, My Lady.
Warm blessings, My Lady.
Yes, yes. My Lady doesn't
usually do charitable work
but now that you do,
you're blessed with offspring!
Knock on wood!
How could I be blessed with offspring?
Don't assume that you can say such
nonsense because you're an Elder.
What are you thinking?
I am saying that your daughter,
Jia Er, is carrying a child.
Anyone can tell that my
daughter is carrying a child!
Her stomach is already so big!
Do I need you to tell me that?
But do you know if she is
expecting a son or a daughter?
You know how to foretell that as well?
Is it a son or a daughter?
Tell me!
- A boy...
- It's a boy?
Or a girl is equally joyous.
Is that so important?
You're teasing me!
Go on and tell me
if it's a son or a daughter!
I won't let this go!
Tell me!
She's given birth, My Lady!
She gave birth when she
went to visit the Empress!
Is it a boy or a girl?
It's a boy!
Both mother and son are well.
The gods have truly blessed us!
Charitable families are
bound to have great joy!
- This is great!
- Great! Great...
Your Highness, if you aren't
satisfied with this jade loop
I will be sure to make
alterations to it right away
so that Your Highness can take it
with you to Chang An in time.
It is fine.
This just needs to be polished
a bit more so that it shines.
Yes.
General Wei has returned!
The army of Great Han has won again!
This is great!
This is such wonderful news!
Indeed. General Wei is valiant
and skilled in warfare.
On his way back to Chang An
there must be people who are
cheering for him along the way.
Great Han has gained great
victory in war again!
This is truly an occasion
to be celebrated!
Tonight, before the banquet for
all officials and marquesses
I wish to gather with my family first.
Wei Qing!
Present!
Our enemies are at bay.
You deserve the most credit for it.
Your sister and your wife are
both very proud of you.
I will award you the title of
Marquess of Changping in front of them.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I will definitely do my best
to serve Your Majesty.
Good!
There are two joyous events for
the household of General Wei.
Your child was just born.
Have you named him yet?
Your Highness, we have yet to name him.
This is Wei Qing's first child.
I will give him a good name.
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
What about... 'Kang'?
'Kang' stands for unyielding will,
courage, and righteousness.
Your Majesty, thank you
for blessing this child.
It also means to be of a great match.
It refers to the affection of his parents.
Both meanings of 'Kang' are good.
The child shall be named Wei Kang.
Do you have any objections?
Wei Kang is a very good name.
Thank you for naming him, Your Majesty!
Thank you for your kindness, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, the Marquess of Ruyin
seeks audience.
- Summon him.
- Yes.
Marquess of Ruyin, Xia Hou Po,
greets Your Majesty.
Don't stand on ceremony!
The national banquet is yet to begin.
Marquess of Ruyin has
arrived very early.
I know that Your Majesty is
having a family gathering
so I especially came over in advance.
I am here to greet Empress Dowager
and all the relatives.
I heard that General Wei
was valiant and skilled in warfare.
You have gained victory
once again for the nation.
I hereby congratulate General Wei
on your victorious return.
Your Majesty, Ruyin might be small
but I hope to contribute to the nation.
I wish to donate Ruyin's annual profits
to serve as the army's provisions.
The profits of the territories are
originally the salary of the marquesses.
It is rare of you to offer your salary
besides the time for tributes.
When the army of Great Han wins again,
I am sure to give you some credit.
I didn't do this for rewards.
I only ask that...
I may say a few words to the Princess.
Go ahead.
I heard that Your Highness has been
searching for a good mentor
for the young marquess.
There is a talented
man of both literary
and military skills in Ruyin
by the name of Sang Yi.
Sang Yi is known for
his kindness and virtue.
When the Emperor was just born
your father had wanted to invite
him over to be your tutor.
I have heard Mother mention him before.
But this man does not seek any
titles or rewards.
He would rather retire to the
countryside and cultivate himself.
Even though royalties went to beg him
he refused to leave the
mountains to teach them.
I've already convinced this great man
to tutor the young marquess
in Pingyang County.
Princess can be at ease and no
longer worry for the young marquess.
She won't have to travel between
Chang An and Pingyang so often.
This is such a great gift.
Of all the tributes that kings
and marquesses have given
none is as precious
and valuable as yours.
Your Highness, may I be
so bold as to ask you
that if I use this gift as
a betrothal gift
is it of appropriate sincerity?
I have admired Princess for a long time.
I am willing to protect and
follow her until the end.
I beg Empress Dowager to
grant me permission.
I beg Your Majesty to grant me my wish
and bestow this marriage to me.
Marquess of Ruyin is not only
concerned about the national affairs
but also willing to share the
burdens of the Princess.
I have no objection to this marriage.
But even as the ruler of a nation
my sister's marriage must be
decided by my sister herself.
I wonder what Your Highness
thinks of this marriage?
I ask that Your Majesty consent to it.
You have my consent.
Sister, why have you asked me over?
Have a seat.
I asked you over to try some of
Uncle Yi's grilled meats.
Uncle Yi will be going down south on
his carriage of goodwill tomorrow.
He won't return to Chang An
for quite some time.
I still remember years ago
when I was accused of murder
and imprisoned in Lateral Courts.
Princess had wanted to please
Empress Dowager
with Uncle Yi's grilled meats,
in order to save me.
Princess has never backed down,
even if she was implicated
from trying to save
the both of us.
Today, Princess will leave Chang An
to be married to the faraway Ruyin.
She is marrying so well.
We should be happy for her.
Princess is getting married but
you feel reluctant, don't you?
No, why would I?
I'm truly happy for her that
she has found a great husband.
Marquess of Ruyin comes
from a prestigious family.
His lands are rich
and he is well-educated.
He is a good match for Princess.
Empress Dowager was right, after all.
Empress Dowager?
She had asked about you and Princess?
At that time, there were widespread
rumors about me and Princess.
Empress Dowager summoned me into the
palace and listed all the consequences.
Now, it seems worthwhile.
Otherwise, Princess would have been
accused of supporting her familiars
to gain authority in and out of
the palace for conspiracies.
You would also be reproached by others.
It must be difficult for you.
But can you really let it go?
At the time, I really couldn't...
But now I am at ease.
However, Princess has a tough character.
Should she learn of the truth
I'm afraid that she would bear
grudges against Empress Dowager.
Don't worry, my brother.
This matter is only known to us.
I will never say a word about this.
Marquess entrusted Princess
and young marquess to me.
Not only is the Princess blissful now
but the young marquess has
also gained a great tutor.
Now I can finally be relieved.
You think of only the commitment,
but what of yourself?
More than anything,
I want to know if you are happy.
Please don't worry.
Jia Er and I are getting
along very well.
That's good then.
I only hope that Princess and her
husband can support one another
through life's ups and downs,
in both joy and bitterness, like we do.
That lowly stable boy thinks
that he can defeat me?
Look who's got the lady in the end?
My mission is then accomplished.
If anyone should learn that I was the
one who told you to spread the rumors
in order to overthrow the emperor...
How would I dare to tell anyone?
If your tongue is too loose
and stirs up great trouble
I will definitely take
all your rewards back.
And then punish you heavily.
I understand.
- Leave now.
- Yes.
Subtitles by DramaFever