Subtitles by DramaFever
Episode 19
Why did you do it?
Why did you?
Why?
Shi Won.
What are you doing here?
You're not...
The son of the doctor?
What are you talking about?
Don't move.
Are you okay?
Who are you?
Trust me.
Stay here.
It was you?
It was you. Wasn't it?
You killed Kyung Mi.
Who are you?
No!
How did it go?
What happened?
How did you know about this?
I got the intel from the agency.
I see.
What happened to you, sir?
We didn't have time. We had to call the
SWAT team to take control first.
You could have told me.
Like you said, it could have been
too late if I did.
This was about catching Chairman Cho.
Unfortunately, we lost him.
But we found the narcotics factory.
Good work, sir.
It's too dangerous for you.
Why?
Because I know you? Or...
Because you know me?
I want to know more.
Can you tell me?
Why? Why did you save me?
My sister.
Did you really kill her?
Why aren't you talking?
You don't even have an excuse?
I'm here thinking that
you killed my sister.
Why aren't you saying anything?
I...
I didn't kill Detective Lee Kyung Mi.
You could have told me earlier.
I could have killed you!
If I had shot you. If I had killed you.
How would I live with that?
It's been a long time.
Yes.
Please take a seat.
Forgive me for not being
cooperative with the police.
The fellows that escorted me here.
Are they your private team?
Did you enjoy the hospitality?
I did very much.
They were well-mannered.
I think we can really
get along from now on.
What do you think, Mr. Min?
I totally agree with you sir.
Do you now?
Then there is something I'd like for
you to take care of.
Take the attention away from me to
Moon and Doctor's Son.
How I will help you will
depend on how much you can
help me with this.
Mr. Cho.
Please cut the crap.
You're finished.
I'm sure that you've noticed.
Your bribed prosecutor
turned away from you.
The son of the doctor, Safari,
Moon Duk Bae, and Ji Hyung Min.
They are all out to get you.
That's why you called me to
beg for your protection.
Isn't that right?
If you want to live, you'd better
duly note what I have to say.
The only way for you to live is to
help me to attack the D.A.
You want to know about the district
attorney's secret closet.
Not just the D.A. The people
whose asses he kisses too.
Oh.
I will be protecting you from now on.
The service done by the prosecution
will now be done by the police with me.
I like the idea.
Unfortunately, Safari
took all those documents.
I'm sure that you have
the original copy.
Original copy?
There is no such thing.
You're the one hanging by
the string here. Not me.
You and I are in the same boat.
You killed Kyung Mi. Didn't you?
Who was it?
I had no other choice.
Are you sure that
he didn't see you?
Yes sir.
You couldn't handle the body?
I'm sorry, sir.
What about the phone?
The situation went badly.
I couldn't take care of it.
How did it go?
Go back and watch him.
Make sure that you don't get seen.
Yes sir.
Thank you.
For saving me.
Thanks.
I'm really glad that it wasn't you.
Hey.
You're drinking again?
Would you like some?
Sounds good.
What about the doctor?
No news yet.
Have you heard?
Hear what?
The narcotics factory that Kang Mok
wanted to get was fake.
Something big happened to the police and
the D.A.'s office at the same time.
Did you hear this from a friend?
There's something else.
Cho's original factory was
raided by the police.
It was done by Director Min.
Don't you think that it's strange?
What is?
Safari was working for Cho.
How did Min know about the factory?
Get out.
Yes ma'am.
Are you going to
make her like Hae Su?
You know the girl that saved your life.
Did Mr. Cho introduce her to you?
May I ask who that person is?
You know, the politician.
Staying with Ji Young Min
will be safer.
What about you then?
Go.
You're also in danger.
You can quit.
You're asking me to leave.
But why can't you quit?
Even if I'm not the one
that killed your sister
I'm still Doctor's Son.
Get out of the car.
As you all probably know, Kang Mok's
testimony was false.
We have found Cho's real factory with the
intel received from the secret agency.
Now that Cho has fled the scene
all we can do now is to prove
that the factory belongs to Cho.
Interrogate the staff
arrested at the factory.
We have to track all the documents
and cash the traffic of Bokam University.
Let's get going.
Inspector!
Yes?
Have we identified the dead body
found at the university?
No, not yet.
We're finger printing right now.
We will have it by tomorrow.
Report to me ASAP.
Yes, sir.
Yes?
Yoon Su Min will go in now.
Don't ever send her out again.
I'm counting on you.
I understand.
Why didn't you answer the phone?
Do you know how worried I was?
I'm sorry.
You didn't...
No, I couldn't shoot him.
He saved me.
The target was not the son of
the doctor, but it was you?
Yeah. He took the bullet for me.
His name is...
Jung Shi Won.
You had known him all along?
Yeah, but I didn't know that
he was Doctor's Son.
How?
When I worked at the convenient store...
Kyung Mi also knew Doctor's Son.
What are you talking about?
When he talked about Kyung Mi
he sounded like he had known her.
Su Min.
It's all over now.
You've done a great job.
I'm sorry for everything.
Wow! Just wow.
Su Min! I have to get going.
Keep the door locked.
Call me when you
have to go out. Okay?
Where are you going?
Where else? Work.
Call me if you need anything.
See you.
Wait.
I want to go see Ji Sook.
Can't I?
Su Min.
I think you'd better stay.
Just forget it and think about your safety.
Just for the last time.
I will just go see Ji Sook.
Hi Ji Sook.
Where are you?
I'm at your office.
Then come up to my room.
Sit down.
Can I borrow your clothes?
What?
No?
No, it's just.
You're clothes are better.
Yeah, my clothes are prettier.
Should we go out?
Where?
Ji Sook.
Actually I...
Since when?
Huh?
How long have you
known Shi Won?
Tell me.
Before I had met you.
At the convenient store
that I used to work...
Was it since then?
I...
Do you love Shi Won?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Su Min.
I'm really sorry.
I'm not ready yet.
Can you give me some time?
What happened at the factory?
Exactly what you saw.
Who did it?
Can you handle it
if I tell you?
Say it.
Yeah...
You're Doctor's Son.
There is nothing you can't do.
Who do you think sent
me as an undercover here?
It was Min Hong Ki.
Did you know?
No.
Yeah.
It was Min Hong Ki that sent me
to Busan to get Cho at Busan.
It was him that abandoned me.
It was also Min Hong Ki that
tried to shoot and kill me today.
Then? Was it Cho that killed
Detective Lee Kyung Mi?
No, I lied so that you would help me.
Why? Why?
Why are you telling me now?
I'm sorry.
What are you doing?
How long are you going to work
for the man that killed your mother?
You will not be enrolled.
What will happen if Moon finds
out that you're a cop?
You will never be able to catch him.
You could even get killed.
Then your revenge...
You will be an undercover.
No one will know that you're a cop.
Your life will depend on it.
Do you understand?
Why did you send Kyung Mi there?
Who was it?
Who killed Kyung Mi?
We're currently investigating.
You're the prime suspect.
You have to join the
organization in Busan.
That's the only way you can get
Safari and Busan.
You have to find out
who killed Kyung Mi.
Shim An Ju. He was a former cop.
He got his hands on some drugs
while being undercover.
He was one of the best shooters
in the academy.
He had won all the competitions.
We couldn't find his rifle.
But a bullet shell was found on the rooftop.
7.62 mm NATO bullet shell.
Undercover, first-class sniper,
NATO bullet shell.
And sir...
He was part of the
narcotics team five years ago.
But it was Min Hong Ki
that organized the team.
Shim An Ju.
What about him?
I just want to know
how he's doing.
Shim.
I have never seen him after
he quit for something he had done.
Is that right?
Why do you ask?
He died yesterday.
Did he?
How?
He was found dead next to
Cho's narcotic factory.
Was he?
He ended up joining a cartel.
Ji Hyung Moo. That bastard.
I heard from Su Min.
Why did you save Su Min?
Because you were going to think that
I had killed her too.
You were right.
Shim An Ju was a former cop.
First-class sniper.
Did you kill him?
Never mind.
You wouldn't have asked me to
look into him if you did.
Bye.
Shim An Ju killed Kyung Mi?
That's what I want to find out.
Orphanage director! Hi, this is Su Min.
Do you know Jung Shi Won?
Jung Shi Won?
Of course I know him.
The smart kid.
He liked Kyung Mi a lot.
Kyung Mi liked him as if
he was her brother.
Of course, you wouldn't know.
He ran when you were just a baby.
That house! Kyung Mi's house.
Shi Won had bought that place for her.
Whenever Kyung Mi was going through
a hard time, he came to help.
Kyung Mi became a
cop because of Shi Won.
Get rid of her.
Yes, sir. Understood, sir.
Hi.
I'm sorry. I'm trespassing here.
Do you know Ju Young?
Ju Young likes you a lot.
Please take good care of her.
Can I wait here for a sec?
What the hell is wrong with you?
I'm sorry.
Are you betraying me
like Jung Shi Won did?
No sir. I'm not.
Remember! You're a cop.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Go back and stand-by for the next order
before it looks suspicious.
The actually owner of the narcotics
factory turned himself in.
What do you think?
The D.A. has the final say like always.
I heard that you had found
Cho's factory yourself.
I just think that it's a pity that
your efforts have been wasted.
It was not in vain.
I got something more important.
About the information
between you and Cho.
It was very useful.
It even has information about Senator Cha
being behind your back.
Excuse me Min!
I think you'd better keep it quiet.
Fine. What is it that you want?
You want me to back away?
I'm finally seeing your true colors.
You can't back out now.
There is only one thing that I want.
I want the police to have equal
power as the D.A.'s office.
It is thanks to the D.A. that
Korea has gotten so corrupt.
You should choose
your words carefully.
Corruption?
Don't you know that that word
isn't even allowed in this world?
What the people want, and
what they live for...
Think about where the
people place their values.
Do you think that the police can fulfill that?
People like you are only
making the world more chaotic.
You don't understand what we
have been sacrificing for.
I had maintained the
orders and values.
Fine! I will acknowledge your work so far.
But it's about time that we change.
I will make the change.
You will need to help me
from now on.
See you.
Sir?
Min lost his last chance.
Do you know what I mean?
I understand.
Do not make a mistake.
Yes, sir.
What did he say?
Is it serious?
You don't need to know.
I need to go out.
Where are you going?
Kim Pong.
Sir?
Just go back home and farm.
What happened?
Were you worried about me?
Worried, my ass.
I haven't seen anyone as
vicious as you are.
There is nothing to worry about.
You didn't worry just one bit?
Geez.
I get sick sometimes too.
What happened at the factory?
Min Hong Ki came to the factory.
And?
It's better for you that
Min Hong Ki raided the place.
That's good enough. Isn't it?
What are you talking about?
Min Hong Ki.
You think I didn't know
about you and Min Hong Ki?
Whatever.
Min Hong Ki and me...
We are all just losers to you.
Jin Sook.
Why?
I love you.
I love you, but you
wouldn't understand.
Yeah.
I have something to say.
What?
What should I do with Cho?
What do you mean?
It will be hard to get
Cho now. Won't it?
But we still have to do it.
I had been thinking.
I'm just going to kill Cho.
Shi Won.
I will.
We need to talk.
I have something to tell you in person.
Mr. Cho?
Yes?
I found out where the doctor's son is.
Really? That's great news.
Shi Won! Look!
Hey Ju Young!
Su Min! Ki Cheol wanted me
to tell you something.
Where?
Okay.
It's me.
Yeah.
Okay. I will be right there.
Shi Won! Look over there.
Damn it.
I knew this would happen.
Are you all right?
Damn! Damn it!
Let me take a look.
Ki Cheol.
Sorry, boss.
Was it Min?
Sorry.
Answer me! Answer...
If you were going to betray me, then you should
have done it before I noticed.
Mister!
I'm fine.
Shi Won!
The doctor's son! Jung Shi Won.
Take this. I don't
need this anymore.
You can use it.
It's all in here.
There is a list of everyone that
received bribes from Cho.
Take it.
You went through a
lot of trouble for me.
This is my token of appreciation.
Shi Won! Why did you
become a cop?
To get revenge?
I'm sorry.
That's enough.
I just regret that I
couldn't get Min Hong Ki.
So why did you abandon me?
When?
Oh back then?
Because I felt bad.
I was the one that
got you in this mess.
I felt so bad that I couldn't
tell you that I was a cop.
I'm sorry.
Geez...
Shi Won.
Mister!
Wake up! Hey!
Wake up!
Hey!
Why couldn't I just leave you alone?
Why couldn't I just leave?
I should have just left when I thought
that it was going on the wrong tracks.
Why couldn't I?
Let's go to Ji Sook.
I miss her.
Okay.
What the hell?
What happened?
What happened to him?
Hey!
Wake up.
Wake up!
Stop kidding around and wake up.
I'm calling you!
Wake up!
Wake up now you asshole!
What should I do?
Shi Won!
I feel so bad for him.
I feel so bad.
Yeah, it was me.
You were trying to kill me right?
You betrayed the police.
I did?
Yes.
There is something I really
want to ask you.
Why did you do it?
Do what?
Kyung Mi.
You promised that you
would protect Kyung Mi.
Why? Why?
I did so to protect you.
Kyung Mi knew about you more than anyone.
Everything would have been over
the minute you were exposed!
The undercover agent, Safari, and Busan!
Everything would have been over!
I had to protect you.
I had done it all to protect you!
Do you understand?
No.
That wasn't for me.
It was for your own good.
I just wanted to change
this corrupted world.
Stop!
Don't you say another word from now.
I'm the one talking.
I will not forgive you.
So...
Don't you dare have regrets or
ask for forgiveness.
Just stay where you are.
I will kill you.
You are going to betray me?
Okay, fine. Try.
I'll kill you first.
Just wait.
Yeah, take your shot.
Subtitles by DramaFever