You gonna get up today, Hannah?
What's this?
That's orange juice, Hannah.
Don't ya know
I'm allergic to orange juice?
Is that on your chart?
How the hell should I know?
It should be.
You're sure you're allergic
to orange juice?
Well, better safe than sorry
I always say.
Let's getcha
a little milk instead.
We go through this
every other week,
it's always news to her.
Wouldn't you like
to get dressed today
and eat with the others?
I wanna see Rachel.
Hannah, Rachel's very sick.
I know she's sick, goddammit.
Only her family can see her.
I'm family!
Don't get yourself all ruffled.
I'll have to give you something.
You know your blood pressure.
You tell Marge
I wanna see her mother.
All right, I'll tell her.
But I told her
day before yesterday
and she said no;
it would just upset you both.
Rachel's gonna die alone!
Her daughter comes
to see her every day.
But Rachel needs to see me.
She must be an old friend,
isn't she?
Friend doesn't even say it.
Please...
You could dress and powder me...
I'll go sit with those
basket cases down the hall
if you'll just let me see her.
You let the
nurse's aide dress you.
You have a good lunch,
then we'll see.
It'd mean a lot
to both of us.
Well, that's what we want.
That's what we're here for.
Can you imagine?
Doing that for a living?
She'll end up in here herself
when she's 80.
At least this room's got
a view and a window that opens.
The freight train goes by
at two every morning...
I listen for it.
I'd kill myself if all
I could see was parking lot.
I wonder if you can
hear the train?
You guys are getting
real good at this.
Good morning, Hannah!
Oh, you have got
some mail this morning!
Oh, I know I saw something
in here somewhere...
Oh, there it is!
It's a postcard from Alaska.
Oh, look at the size
of that fish.
It's a... it's a...
Halibut.
Oh, it's a halibut.
Look! 356 pounds!
How would you even
catch something like that, huh?
How would you like
to go swimmin'
and see something like that
in the water with you, huh?
No thanks.
So would you like me
to read it to you, hon?
I'll just read it to you
like I usually do, okay.
It says, "Hey, Hannah.
The mud got another one.
Love and regards,
Nettie Bobo."
What on earth does that mean?
Do you have any idea
what that means, huh?
Well, I'm sorry, honey
I have just got to go.
But I'll see you tomorrow.
That's some fish.
My hubby would sell his soul
to hook into a fish like that.
Alaska. How do you know
someone in Alaska?
It's people like that
drive me nuts.
Trap us like rats
and then talk us to death.
I can't just walk away
like I used to.
I didn't like somethin',
off I'd go.
That's how I ended up
in Alaska.
No roads. Everybody flew.
I flew over that tundra
like it was my backyard.
Nettie's still there...
82, canoes to work.
Digs tourists
out of the mud flats.
They sink down in that ooze
and stick like cement.
I loved it there...
but I had to come back.
I always had to come back...
For Rachel.
She'd never leave Michigan.
Had the kids.
Peaches to can
and pies to bake.
She looked like someone
dipped her in flour.
She looked like Mt. McKinley.
I like that -
being compared to a mountain.
It was a compliment.
You were gone
so long that time
I thought you were
never coming back.
You got married.
To escape my father's temper,
not you.
I had to get out.
And girls are
supposed to marry.
Well, at least I married
the dullest man I could find.
Yeah, well, he was
a good provider,
but you'd have been trapped
for the rest of your life.
If Mr. Johnson hadn't
had the misfortune
of dying on that excursion boat.
Everyone ran to the side to wave
goodbye and the boat capsized.
Never marry a weak swimmer.
You waited months to write,
till after the twins were born.
You tried to mourn him,
but it was always me
you wanted to cook for.
Don't be smug.
You always thought we were
the only girls
who did what we did.
Whenever and wherever we could.
Of course after it was over,
you'd ask me to leave
and you'd go back to your Bible.
Never seemed to be on my side.
Neither was your family.
They still aren't.
Your daughter
sits with you for hours
but she won't let me see you.
Has the nerve to tell me
it's for my own good.
I'd like to look at you
just once and die.
Be a nice way to go.
Isn't this a switch.
For once you're staying in one
place and I'm the one leaving.
I had to go.
I had to see things.
Oh, Alaska,
New Mexico, Paris.
My Lord, even Ohio.
Now why Ohio?
It's Michigan, only flat.
Some of Ohio is very pretty.
You've just never seen it.
Every once in a while
you just had to leave me.
You knew I'd be wild for you
when you finally got back.
I've been everywhere...
Even South America.
That's where I found
the seeds for your moonflowers.
Mr. Johnson...
used to walk around with
his eyes down on the ground,
like he was
looking for lost change.
He wouldn't know
a moonflower from a lilac bush.
What do wives find to
talk about with their husbands?
Mr. Johnson and I
ran out of conversation
in less than two years.
You and I never did.
Nope.
Sometimes we'd sit
in the yard
and watch your
moonflowers come out;
they'd unfold in seconds,
just bloomin' in the night.
Then later in the night
I'd call you my moonflower...
when I was pressed up
under your nightgown.
And by morning
the moonflowers had shriveled
and you had
your hairnet back on.
How was I supposed
to cook breakfast
without my hairnet?
You have the most
beautiful hair.
Oh, Hannah.
Don't start something
we can't finish.
Hello, Hannah!
Jesus, Marge, I can hear!
I just can't walk
or see worth a shit.
The nurse says you've been
wanting to see Mom.
Of course I have.
We can't have you
upsetting her.
Upset?! Wh...
When did I ever
upset your mother?
All her life.
Well, if that's the case,
it was her choice.
Marge, please let me see her.
We need to see each other.
This is no way for us
to end our lives -
in two separate rooms.
She has her family.
I'm her family!
Please. Don't.
I used to tuck you in!
I told you stories.
I sat with you
when there were storms.
You never knew your father,
but you knew me.
You knew I'd always
look after you.
When you weren't busy...
Going to Alaska or New Mexico.
I sent you postcards.
I sent you presents.
I sent your mother money.
Don't act like
you were there for Mom.
You weren't. We were!
Roy and I were there!
Dammit, you were children.
You had to be there!
Hannah, I grew up
a long time ago.
I lost my Barbara, my daughter,
in a car accident.
I have grown grandchildren.
I cook, I clean, I can peaches.
I recycle my newspapers.
And once a year we drive
to the Mackinac Bridge
and I have a little piece
of fudge by the water.
And then we drive home.
And I mow the lawn.
But when Mom needs me,
I come.
You always came
when you darn well pleased.
You don't know
anything about it.
I will tell Mom
you asked after her.
She was a cute little girl,
but she's been
a pain in the ass
ever since she joined
the Baptist Church.
Hi.
Are you Grandma Hannah?
What?!
The nurse told me
I should speak with
'Grandma Hannah'
about my project for school.
Grandma Hannah?
Jesus Christ,
don't call me that.
Sorry, she must have... uh...
What?
Women's Suffrage?
The Civil War?
What is it you want
my sage advice about?
I'm busy.
The Depression.
I went to Alaska.
Caught everything I ate
except chocolate.
Are you writing it down?
I voted for Roosevelt
because I liked Eleanor.
The war broke out,
I lied about my age,
I joined the WACS,
and I flew planes.
I invested in computer stocks
in the 50s.
That's how come
a Depression rat like me
can afford this beauteous
single room in Hotel Hell.
That's it. Posterity.
You get asked this a lot.
They send all you in here.
Perk me up.
What in the hell
do you think I am -
the public library?
Go ask your parents
what it was like
getting raised in the 60s.
My parents are dead.
Well, so are mine.
Please, take me home!
Mama! Mama! Mama!
What an awful place.
Always have a gun handy
to shoot yourself
in case you fall off
a goddamned roof.
In Alaska if I'd fell off a roof
a bear woulda ate me
and made some use out of me.
Sit down.
You've been to Alaska?
I lived in Alaska.
Look at this...
From a friend of mine
who's still livin' up there.
Lord, now you're
robbing the cradle.
And I thought I'd seen it all.
Nonsense.
Living in Alaska's nonsense?
Nah, I'm just mumbling to myself.
Old people do that.
No, Alaska was great.
I was real happy living there.
How'd you survive?
Had a high school diploma.
Taught school in Barrow.
Skinned things.
You get by.
You just went and did it?
Most people dream and stay home.
There is nothing wrong
with staying home.
I'd really like
to go to Africa,
but I'm afraid
if I need a blood transfusion...
Why? You sick?
No.
So don't get sick.
The blood supply in Africa
is so tainted with AIDS.
What if something did happen?
God forbid
something should happen.
Trust me, kid,
you can 'what if' yourself
into a real boring life.
I really don't care
to listen to this.
You call this something?
I went to your wedding!
What?
She's being ridiculous.
Uh... nothin'. Forget it.
So you married?
Nope.
It's hard to tell.
I wonder...
Girls used to wear
pinky rings and men's socks.
How old are you?
Twenty-one.
Maybe she doesn't know,
but I sure knew by then.
Have you ever been married?
Not to a man.
Oh, yeah?
You gonna put that
in your paper?
Maybe.
Is she dead?
Almost.
They got her in some
other wing in this dump.
They won't let me see her.
She's in a coma,
they still won't let me see her.
Trying to protect us
from each other.
People were always doing that.
Is she who you talk to?
I can't go to her,
so I bring her to me.
And she comes on her own.
I still talk to my parents...
especially when I can't sleep.
You're the only person
I've told.
Well, I'm pretty damn safe.
I won't tell.
They died last year.
Car accident.
Rachel's been
in a coma a while...
Stroke.
I was in the hospital
all busted up
or I woulda taken care of her.
And now her damn daughter...
That's her legal family,
you know,
so, anyway, here I sit.
And Rachel's right here
in this nursing home?
Beats the hell out of me
what they think
I'm gonna do to her.
I just...
I wanted to say goodbye.
Her daughter's
with her all the time?
Well, she goes home at night.
God, I'm just so afraid
that she's gonna die alone.
Late at night.
That'd be her way,
slip out real quiet-like.
But if it was up to her,
she'd want me there.
Don't be too sure.
You're so funny.
She's being funny.
A nurse told me
that people can visit
24 hours a day
if they want.
Nobody wants to.
But they can.
I mean, I could.
Could come by
at three in the morning,
swing by your room,
visiting you.
Take you for a stroll
to Rachel's room...
You mean that?
Um...
You'd have to help me
into my chair.
Is your back strong?
Don't worry about it.
I play softball and basketball.
Uh huh.
So it's no problem.
Good.
Because she could
go in a year,
or she could go tonight.
And I don't wanna miss her.
Then let's go tonight.
Three o'clock sound good?
Yeah.
How come you're goin'
outta your way for me, kid?
I don't know.
Maybe so somebody'll
help me out when I'm old.
Yeah, don't count on it.
You seen my horses?
Nope.
Got nothin' in here but goats.
You might want to check
the TV room down the hall.
I'll just do that.
How the hell
they got outta the barn,
that's what I wanna know.
This way?
Turn left
at the drinking fountain.
See ya around, toots.
He a regular?
Never seen him before.
At least he's got
all his parts.
It's those diabetics
with stumps for legs
that depress
the hell out of me.
Especially when
I knew 'em before, you know.
Some of these kids
are from school.
Is there anything you need?
Anything I can
bring you tonight?
Just Rachel.
Three o'clock.
Thanks, kiddo.
That's not the first time
you've waved somebody
under my nose.
That missionary...
followed you
all the way from Brazil.
Do I have to hear
about her again?
I mean it's ancient history.
Clean food and American toilets
is what looked good
to her, not me.
Everything she ate
down there gave her the runs.
Why do you have
to give every little detail?
You always were one
to pull the curtains.
Some things are private.
You mean hidden...
Pretending.
Your dead husband's
photograph on the mantel
and flowers on his grave
on Decoration Day.
And there you were
with all the good widows
at the cemetery.
Then you'd come back home
and hop back in bed with me.
I can't talk to you.
You sure used to.
I'm going back to my room.
Fine.
Used to be we'd make up
by doing the deed.
I'd stay after you until
I had all your clothes off.
Don't you dare follow me.
Baby, I'll only be in Brazil
for a month,
and the money is good.
My God...
A whole month
without your apple pie.
A month without the smell
of your hair.
A month without your eyes...
Shut up.
I'm still mad at you.
I know.
I still feel it.
I want you
just like I always did.
Not the way I am now,
plugged in like a lamp.
Well, it's that
time again, Hannah.
Let's put you on the toilet.
But I haven't eaten anything.
I don't need cleaning out
if I haven't eaten anything.
You know we do it
every three days.
It's on your chart.
But I'm not bound up, dammit.
Well, that's thanks to this.
My body's gonna forget
how to shit on its own
if you keep
shoving that up me.
Just leave me alone.
Hannah, we don't want
to have to restrain you.
Just try it.
Doctor knows
what's best for you.
I haven't seen that
little asshole in three months.
How does he know what I need?
Look, I don't get paid
a fortune for doing this.
I've got enough on my plate
without having to argue with you.
I don't have the time.
There's more to
taking care of people
than reaming them out
every other day.
Don't I have any rights?
There's endless beauty
in Alaska, Rachel,
but some days
it's almost too much.
I want beauty I can hold...
You.
The bald eagles are just like
everything else here -
bigger than you can imagine.
And the mountains
grow like wildflowers.
It'd be heaven on earth
if you were here.
Rachel, what's so wrong
with wanting to see the world?
I can't spend my life
lookin' out just one window.
But mountains, eagles,
Broadway marquees -
what's any of that
when I hold it up to you?
Well, I gotta sign off.
This is gonna cost me an arm
and a leg in postage as it is.
I wish you'd write.
A penny postcard, something?
Don't stay mad.
Please...
I had to leave.
I couldn't stay there
and see you with him.
I love you, Rachel,
I truly do.
And I wish you well.
Think of me sometimes...
Your old friend,
Hannah Free.
Hannah, wake up.
It's time to go see Rachel.
I found her room.
The coast is clear.
Let me just
get your wheelchair.
Uh, do you have to
go to the bathroom?
I'm sorry, yes, I do.
I always have to go
when I wake up.
No big deal.
Do you use a bedpan?
No!
Don't you let her go
in that bathroom with you.
Get a grip on yourself.
Get a grip on me;
Let me help you up.
I can't believe I'm finally
gonna get to see her.
Don't wake me.
I'm sleeping soundly.
We'll be quiet.
What?
Ghost.
Don't call me a ghost.
These aren't my slippers.
Yeah. Bought you a new pair.
What, are you adopting me?
Maybe.
You are hard up.
Lean on me.
Bring the chair.
I can do it, I can get in.
You're always
so darn independent.
Always so damn independent?
Right here.
Lock the wheels.
I appreciate this.
Dammit, Linda!
I'll just be here,
out of the way.
God, you could run a farm
on all this fuckin' machinery.
All these goddamn tubes.
Poor kid.
You go ahead and sleep, Rachel.
I just wanna be here.
We were together all our lives.
Together and apart...
Right, Rach?
It's just that I've
never seen her
look unattractive
at all in some...
in makeup.
And I said, I said...
Oh, bring your husband...
Gimme, gimme!
Hannah!
You're in the wrong room.
No, I'm not.
Look, Hannah,
you should be asleep.
You're gonna get yourself sick.
How in the world
did you get yourself in here?
I drove.
Hannah, you know how
her family feels.
I'm her family.
Let's take you
back to your room.
No!
What is the harm?
Rachel should not
be here alone,
not now,
not just before dawn.
That's the soul's midnight.
And that's the time
all us old folks die.
Trust me,
people die all day long.
Please let me stay.
I'm sorry, hon, but you're
not supposed to be in here.
Let's wheel you
back to your room.
- No!
- Hannah...
No!
Hannah, you are not
the only person in this home.
I've gotta get
back to the desk.
- You come with me.
- Leave me alone!
This is my great grandma.
I brought Hannah here tonight.
I take full responsibility.
I haven't seen you before.
I flew in a couple days ago.
Now look.
This is
Grandma Rachel's best friend.
Of course she should be here.
It's a funny time of night
to come visiting.
It gives them more privacy.
Why don't you just
go on back to your desk.
Well, maybe for another
15 minutes,
then you take her
back to her room.
I don't wanna find her
in here when I check again
at... 3:45.
I'll take her back at dawn.
She's not hurting anyone.
Oh, all right.
I guess she's not.
But if that daughter of hers
comes before Hannah's gone,
I didn't see
either one of you.
- Deal.
- Okay.
What a load of bull.
I think I'm rubbin' off on ya.
I hope so.
Did ya hear that, Rachel?
I get to stay.
This is Marge.
I want to make sure that...
King me.
Okay...
Hannah, I'll check in
with you later, okay?
That Greta...
she reminds me of somebody.
I'm not lookin' at her.
Even the squirrels
move slow around here.
Pretty day.
Yes, sir, I was in the CCC.
We planted
rows and rows of trees.
Lots of discipline...
Good preparation for WW II.
And what did you do
after the war ended?
Whaddya mean 'ended'?
Oh.
Say, aren't you Betty Grable?
Greta? Why, I had no idea
you were in town.
Nope.
Weren't you gonna stop by?
Wasn't planning to.
Are you a friend of Betty's?
Betty?
Betty Grable.
Uh, sir, I would like you
to meet Tallulah Bankhead.
I'm sure that's
some kind of insult.
What kind of a name
is Tallulah?
What are you doing here?
Same thing you are - visiting.
Well, that's nice, I guess.
If you won't
spend time with me,
at least you're visiting Mom.
I enjoyed talking with you.
Have you seen my horses?
No!
Maybe you should
check down the hall?
Much obliged.
Save me a dance, eh?
Well, how long are you
gonna be in town?
As long as I want.
Must you be so rude?
Yes, I think I must.
I messed up with your mom.
I wish I could do it over.
That's something.
Please stop by
for lunch some day.
I'll think about it.
Maybe I'll even bring my lover.
She likes a good lunch.
Oh, is this some
kind of test?
It's just the truth.
Why am I not surprised?
Yeah, why aren't you?
You just knew I was
gonna turn out bad, huh?
I didn't mean...
I need to, uh...
make sure they turn Mom.
I don't think
they do it often enough.
Marge? Grandma?
Yes?
Make sure you're
not doing it again...
screwing things up between
Great Grandma and Hannah.
I don't know what you mean.
I'll bet you don't.
It's sad, it's really sad.
It's not the same thing.
It's not
the same thing at all!
Can you believe Katie
got in trouble again?
I'm not that surprised.
She gets in trouble a lot.
We better not.
There.
Don't do that.
Don't wipe away my kisses.
You want me to
go get Dewey Russell?
You wanna kiss him?
I don't want to kiss anybody.
So it's not just me?
Especially not you, Hannah.
Rachel!
If you don't
feel funny about this,
why are we
in this chicken coop?
I'm shy.
Don't laugh at me.
I wasn't laughing at you.
It's just
you make me nervous...
like you're gonna
kiss me again.
Do ya want me to?
No...
Yes.
Oh, my.
You liked it?
Why aren't you a boy?
Do you really want me
to be a boy?
No...
You kiss me this time.
I have to go.
I have chores to do.
Meet me here Saturday.
We're going into town
for supplies.
How 'bout Sunday after church?
I can't do this on a Sunday!
Monday after school?
All right.
But just for one kiss.
# Rachel, Rachel #
# Give me your answer do #
One, two.
You're gonna be awake all night,
drinking coffee.
Oops! I'm sorry.
More mail.
My, you are popular.
You get more mail
than all the other people
in this place put together.
That's pretty damn sad.
Hmm... Hallmark?
That's for me to know.
Awww...
You look very
tired today, Hannah.
Couldn't you sleep last night?
Now if your eyes are tired,
I'd be very happy
to read that...
I can still read!
Well, would you like
to buy some stamps?
I haven't any money up here.
Yes, you do.
Your little friend left $20
next to the front desk
so you could buy yourself
some little extras.
You want me to get you
a pop from the machine?
Guess not.
Well, the offer stands.
I'll be back tomorrow.
You are always
gettin' somethin'.
I suppose there are some people
who think she means well.
Wars break out
every other week
'cause of some asshole
who means well.
What do you think?
You think anyone in here
knows you're gonna
be my lady tonight?
"My Lady."
Wow... Unbelievable.
So... who's that from?
Friend.
New Mexico?
Yes, and don't get all agitated.
Look at me.
One minute...
thirty seconds...
I'm going back to my room.
No, wait, wait, wait.
I'm paying... attention.
Your mind's in New Mexico.
She's just an old friend.
I'm sure after all those years
working at Los Alamos
she glows in the dark.
Don't tell me how
that woman glows in the dark.
When I'm gone, you'll probably
conjure her up for company.
Her life is full.
You like that about her.
Yes.
Honey, you don't
have to envy her.
She was no match for you.
You always said she was witty.
So are you.
Why doesn't she visit you?
I'm sure that Jackie wants
to remember me the way I was.
I guess I would, too.
I don't want to
see me in her eyes.
So...
Are you coming tonight?
Hope so.
That girl's bringing you?
It's the only way
I can get there.
Why is she helping you?
Because I'm just so
fascinating she can't resist.
Oh, speak of the devil.
- Hi.
- Hey!
I was here earlier,
but you were napping.
I'm surprised you're out of bed.
I'll have you know I've been
up here roaming the halls.
Wow, kid, you really know
how to have a good time.
So how are you?
Tired...
And grateful.
No problem.
I left you a little money
at the front desk.
Now you've
got them tipping you.
I hope you don't mind.
I just know
that you can't keep money
up here in your room
or else it might get stolen,
so this way you can
treat yourself to something.
She is thoughtful.
Well, thanks, kid.
I don't want anything.
Not even a stamp?
Pair of shoelaces?
A magazine?
Read? Tie a shoe?
God it makes me tired
just to think about it.
I had so much energy,
but I squandered it.
Now my body parts
are all worn out.
But I'm still here.
Got my hands,
my heart, my mind...
I'm refining myself
down to the essentials.
So we goin' on vacation
again tonight?
- You willing?
- I am askin'.
- Three o'clock?
- I'll be here.
Thanks.
It's all right.
Hey...
I wanna give you something.
I thought of what
you might like.
Just keep
your clothes on, Hannah.
In there.
It's my journals.
You'll find the Depression
in there someplace.
You mean it?
You'd let me read 'em?
I can quote from 'em?
I thought somebody should
get some good out of 'em.
I'll try to skip over
all the personal stuff.
It's all right.
If you can read
my handwriting, honey,
you're welcome to 'em.
So there you go.
Maybe you'll learn something.
I bet I will.
I bet she will.
See you tonight.
It's a date.
Aren't you just
the nursing home Romeo.
Well, she is pretty cute.
Something 'bout the way
she walks reminds me of you.
You have such a great ass.
Is that why you couldn't
keep your hands off of it?
Near death has really
brought out your racy side.
You old flirt.
You never let me read those.
You're in 'em.
I hope you were kind.
Not always...
They're not just journals.
I wrote a novel
when I was snowed in.
Beat alcoholism.
Am I in that too?
I think you'll
recognize yourself.
Why'd you give them to her?
I want somebody
to know I was here.
Well, I know.
I want somebody to know
you were here too.
The real you -
not the you smiling
at church bake sales.
I wanted people
to know about us...
who's not afraid
of what 'us' means.
I want somebody to know
that I took you to bed...
and I loved you.
We know.
Yeah, but what about posterity?
Posterity?
Yeah.
Good Lord, what next?
Well?
Well what?
What are you doin' in here?
Isn't this my room?
No!
You old men
are in the basement.
Go ask the nurse
to show ya.
I'm lost.
I know you're lost.
Ask the nurse
to take you to your room.
Do I know you?
I wish I had a picture
of you when you were younger.
What's your name?
You wanna take a guess?
No.
Well, then tell me
who you are.
How soon do ya
have to know?
Here you are.
He never knows
where his room is.
Come on, let's get you
back to your room.
I know you.
Not anymore you don't.
Your friend,
she don't talk much.
You should take a nap.
Your little friend will be
waking you up
before you know it.
I used to wake you up.
I'd wake up and my nightgown
would be unbuttoned.
Honey, it's light out.
I've gotta get up.
It's cold outside the covers.
Gotta feed the chickens,
make breakfast for the kids...
I'll feed the chickens.
Take your long johns off.
You first.
It is cold.
I hope that's not in
those books you gave that girl.
I wonder if she has
a little girlfriend.
I'll bet you anything
that she's just like us.
I never could convince you
that we weren't the only ones.
You never thought
what we did was right.
Don't be silly.
Didn't we sit
on my front porch
holding hands,
watching the sunset?
Maybe not when we were 30,
but when we were 60.
Well, then they just thought
we were a couple
of cute old ladies.
No one ever thought
you were cute.
Everyone in this town
knows what you are, Hannah,
so they know about me too.
I sat there
knowing full well
I was hanging out
my bed sheets.
It meant so much to you
that I finally just
let go of my privacy.
And let people,
family, neighbors...
know exactly who I am.
Now...
You show me somebody
in one of your magazines
from California that does that.
I stood my ground,
lived my life,
and I loved you...
despite everything
I was brought up to believe.
I'm tired.
So am I.
I wish we could
take a nap together.
I'll be there.
Quiet around without them.
I'm sure they're having
a great time
camping with the Wilsons,
mosquitos and all.
The Wilsons are
a little churchy for me.
I suppose you want me
to find some heathens
to take my children camping.
Might be more fun.
Ohhh!
It's almost time
for Arthur Godfrey.
You want me
to turn it on for you?
He makes you fall asleep.
I need my rest.
Mmm... that's good.
I already pulled the shades.
You keep after me to write you
more than three sentences.
It took me half an hour
to find a pencil,
but here goes.
The ground is frozen.
We've had snow.
The Canada geese
are on the lake,
taking a rest
on their way south.
I miss you, Hannah.
I wish you'd stay home,
but at least this time
I know you're doing war work.
New Mexico sounds beautiful.
You've been having dinner
with the same woman
all the time.
What's that mean, 'dinner'?
Well, I'm not knitting you
any more warm socks,
if you're down there
'having dinner'
while I'm up here
squirming in my sleep.
I know people read your mail,
so I won't say any more.
I don't know
how many more times
I can let you leave me.
At least I'm busy.
I'm working
three days a week
at the hardware store,
bookkeeping.
The man who used to
keep their books
is serving in Italy.
I'm so thankful
you're not overseas.
Be careful
in New Mexico, Hannah.
Watch out for snakes.
Check your boots.
Come home soon.
You know I love you,
but I'll say it anyway.
"Know ye the Lord,
He is God;
it is He
that hath made us,
and not we ourselves;
we are His people..."
Who the hell are you?
"...and the sheep
of His pasture.
Enter into His gates
with Thanksgiving..."
I said who the hell are you?
"...and into His courts
with praise."
You can't just waltz in here
and start spoutin' over me.
Mary, I'm here to help you.
And my name's not Mary.
Don't call me Mary.
It says Mary H. Freed
on your door, Mary.
Well, I don't give a
rat's ass what the door says.
Profanity is not the language
of our Lord.
Don't you want salvation?
Don't you want to sleep
in the loving arms
of Our Lord Jesus Christ?
No.
Now Mary, you don't mean that.
My name is Hannah...
Hannah Free.
No one has ever called me Mary,
not even my own mother.
So why don't you just
go talk to some other poor joker
who can't talk back.
I can see I haven't caught you
on a very good day.
I don't have good days anymore.
Knowing Jesus
would lighten your burden.
Believe me...
"The Lord is Good;
His mercy is Everlasting."
So you're on the road to Heaven?
I have my mansion reserved.
And I'm going to hell?
If you don't accept Jesus Christ
as your personal savior.
You paint a pretty
mean-spirited picture of Jesus.
Don't you think
that Judgment belongs to God?
Mary, you are an old woman.
God may be
calling your name soon.
The next time the friendly
hand of Salvation
reaches out to you, Mary,
I'd grab it.
My name isn't Mary.
It's the name you
were baptized with.
It's the name
the Lord will call.
What a friend we have in Jesus.
Never forget that, Mary.
Have a nice day.
You can have your mansion!
I'll be just fine in hell!
I hate this about gettin' older.
Think I'm just flappin' my gums
to stir up a breeze.
Rachel?
Well, if you're not gonna come
I'll get a radio...
drown out those
crazy people in the hall.
Course they probably think
I'm crazy too.
Sittin' here alone
talkin' my head off.
Jesus, someone's got
"As The World Turns" on?
What in the hell
are they doin'
spendin' their
last minutes on earth
listening to
"The World Turns"?
I know.
You loved that show.
Lisa and Nancy and Dr. Bob.
Bedpan. Full.
Rachel?
One last game of checkers?
I'll let you win.
My turn?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
King me.
Shit.
I don't think that was fair.
I'm gonna have that kid
bring me a radio.
I can choose my own noise.
You don't hear
anything, do you, Rach?
You're barely here.
You're tryin'
to leave us all behind,
and they won't let you.
Rachel...
Are you still there?
Guess I shoulda knocked.
Yes, you should have.
They yours?
Yes.
You were busy
while I was in Alaska.
Still pissed at me?
Yes. And must you
use that language?
Yes.
You didn't write
you were coming.
Didn't wanna warn you.
You just visiting?
Are you a widow?
Yes.
I believe I'm back.
I appreciated the money
you sent me from Alaska.
I didn't want to use it.
I shouldn't have...
You don't have
to explain, Rachel.
In fact...
I wish you wouldn't.
I wasn't paying for anything.
If you ask me upstairs,
I don't want you
mixed up about why.
I haven't asked.
I bet you will.
I'm a mother now.
So?
Get out!
I'm sorry.
You left me, remember?
You got married!
I didn't think that meant
I was going to lose you.
If I had stayed,
what were we supposed to do?
Trade recipes?
I needed you, Hannah.
Don't need me...
Want me, Rachel.
It isn't right.
Why? Because Mr. Johnson
went belly up
in the lake like
a dime store goldfish?
Only you would
put it like that.
This is right for us, Rachel.
Tell me you don't want it.
You know, up in Alaska
when they're lightin' dynamite
someone'll yell,
"Fire in the hole!"
I think that kinda sums us up.
You're just terrible.
The more you shake your head,
the wilder you are
under the sheets.
Put those babies
down for a nap.
If we start...
promise you won't leave?
Cute babies.
They got names?
Promise?
Tomorrow I want you
to bake me some biscuits
wearin' nothin' but this apron.
Hannah, I need an approximation.
How long will you stay?
I don't know.
I don't wanna know.
Rachel, I need life
to surprise me.
If I bake you those biscuits...
will you promise
to stay till spring?
You make me those biscuits
I'll stay through the summer.
Maybe till the fall...
You can carve me up
for Halloween.
Let's put Marge and Roy
in their cribs.
Marge and Roy?
Yes, Marge and Roy.
I shoulda been here
to help you name 'em.
I gotta go home soon, Mama.
You know how Mason
has to eat on time.
When I started
coming up here every day,
he said that was my business -
just so long
as I got home in time
to cook his supper.
And I do. Faithfully.
Sometimes I cheat a little bit,
mix it up ahead of time
and heat it up in the microwave.
He doesn't seem to care.
Just so long
as when he sits down
at exactly 5:30
and leans forward with his fork
he's got something
to stick it into.
My goodness,
sounded a little racy.
And we both know
Mason is anything but racy.
The only time he gets romantic
is after the Super Bowl.
I talked to Roy.
He said that he can't
fly down right now.
His youngest is still
in drug rehab,
and Linda is on
her third divorce.
He does have his troubles.
Glad my family never
got into that dope.
At least not that I know of.
Course you never can tell
about Barbara's girl, Greta...
I know. You warned me.
I said, "Barbara,
you have a choice to make.
You can either ruin your life
with that godless commie
or you can come home."
What are they gonna do
in a big town like Minneapolis?
He's a passionate young man...
and she loves him.
Marge, don't make her choose.
Mama, he's a Buddhist!
I could never understand
why a woman with your good sense
would spend her life
with that darn Hannah.
It's wrong.
And everybody says it's wrong.
The Bible says that it's wrong.
Not that I would ever
admit that you did
what everybody in this town
knows you did.
If somebody baits me,
I just say
how weird Hannah was,
and that you have always been
kind enough to stay her friend.
Not that you two didn't have
your knockdown, drag out fights.
I would hear you
through the heating vents.
The two of you would
rather lose an arm
than say anything
against each other in public.
I should do that with Mason.
At least he doesn't
bore me with his talk.
He doesn't ever
really listen either.
Did Hannah ever listen to you?
I guess she did.
She finally stopped traveling
and stayed home.
You would always look at her
like she could cure cancer.
She wants to see you, Mama...
and I want you
to die in peace.
And Hannah never
brought you peace.
I've gotta go.
Mason's gonna be
cuttin' that placemat up
into tiny little squares.
I love you.
Goodnight. Sleep tight.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Why can't you
do that in the garage?
'Cause it's cold out there
and there's not enough light.
Besides, you're in here.
Oh, baloney.
Why don't ya
come to bed, huh?
I could wear something else
to Lily's funeral.
My bowling shirt's clean.
It's not like I'm gonna be
the star attraction.
They're all gonna be
lookin' in at Lily
to see what hair color
they went with.
Wait.
You know I've never been
good at waitin'.
Come on.
Your neck hurt?
I'll never get over this.
Now you kiss me.
You're in so much trouble.
Get in here.
Dear Jackie,
You write such lively letters
I can't compete.
We don't do much
whitewater rafting
up here at the home.
Yes, I think about New Mexico.
But that's not where
my life is...
My life's here.
I guess it always was.
Go watch the sun rise over
the mountains for me, will ya?
And good luck
with your golf swing.
Yours truly...
Much love, Hannah.
Hi.
Hey.
Feeling down?
No.
Why do you keep
comin' back every day?
If I was your age,
I sure as hell
wouldn't be wastin' my time
listenin' to some
old broad beat her gums.
Well, maybe you just weren't
as sensitive as I am.
Hannah?
Still here.
I hope you won't be mad.
Don't worry.
Whatever it is,
you can outrun me easy.
You know those books
you loaned me?
Yeah what happened to 'em?
Your dog ate 'em?
Hannah, they're wonderful.
Especially the novel.
I couldn't put it down.
So what's so bad about that?
You said it wasn't any good.
Well, that's what I was told.
Hannah, I hope you
won't be upset...
I faxed the first chapter to
this professor friend of mine.
She loved what she read.
And if you let me
send her the whole thing,
I know she'll publish it.
It's not a big
New York publishing company,
but people could
read your book.
Jesus, I'd love to see that.
But you'd better tell 'em
not to keep it too long
at the printers.
- Hannah!
- Well...
Why wasn't it
published years ago?
Hell, I tried.
I sent it out.
And I got it back. A lot.
Some guy at Random House
or Scribners
wrote me a really lousy letter.
He said he wanted to
'save me from further
embarrassment'.
Why? Because it doesn't have
some guy jacking off
in a bullring in Spain?
I suspect the reason was
because it was about
two women together.
But it's good.
Doesn't that count?
Happens all the time, honey.
What the hell.
I've had a good life.
I did what I wanted,
pretty much.
Except now.
Well, even now...
if I could
just be with Rachel.
It's not so bad
coming to the end
if you're not alone.
Shit. You're awful.
So why do you
keep comin' back?
The truth?
Always.
She really is
my great grandmother.
She who?
Rachel.
I wasn't lying when
I told the nurse that.
Are you kiddin'?
No, I'm not.
But I met all her family.
And you met me.
Years ago, you took me fishing
so I wouldn't hear
Marge and my mom
fighting about Daddy.
And we never came back
to Michigan after that.
But I always remember
Rachel's hot chocolate
and going fishing with you.
You're Barbara's girl.
And you were wearing
a yellow dress.
Boy, I sure didn't
have you figured.
I had you figured.
You and Rachel.
I came out a couple years ago...
I've always had
crushes on girls.
So you want me to be
your lesbian heritage?
You gonna write
a song about me?
I just wanted to
get to know you better.
You and Great Grandma Rachel.
Jesus Christ...
That means Marge
is your grandmother.
Sorry.
That's why I wanted you
to get to like me
before I told you.
So...
You seen the old battle-ax?
Only once up here.
And not on purpose.
And last year
at Mom's funeral.
Rachel and I were
in here by then.
Mom was kind of like
how Rachel is now...
Lots of tubes and machines.
It was up to me.
I had to let her go.
I wish I could do that
for Rachel.
Well, why don't you?
I mean, what's the worst
anyone could do, arrest you?
Lock you up somewhere?
Got a point there, kid.
You must hate
seeing her like this.
I just don't know
if I've got the guts
to say that last goodbye.
- Hey.
What are you doing
with that suitcase?
What suitcase?
The one under the bed.
You just kicked it under there
when you heard me coming.
Where do you think
you're going?
The Himalayas.
Why?
I just need a change.
Michigan doesn't
have any mountains.
I mean, I know
you've got the Porcupines...
Michigan has me.
Well, you could come.
Hannah, I'm older than dirt.
Right. And you've never
crossed the state line.
I've never needed to.
What are you looking for?
I don't know, exactly.
I just need something different.
Different just for the sake
of different?
Yeah.
Well, that's the stupidest thing
I've ever heard in my life,
and I've been listening
to you for over 40 years.
I'll be back by spring.
Don't you dare!
What?
If you walk out that door,
don't come back!
Get your junk out of my garage!
And don't send me
a Christmas card!
Just go. Go!
Jesus.
Don't you know
where your home is?
Don't you know that yet?
Hannah, a dog
is smarter than you.
Well, what about what I want?
All our lives have been
about what you want.
This is about what I want.
You've had your chance to roam.
Now, dammit, stay home!
Sit on the porch with me,
and mow the lawn.
Put your clothes in the closet.
Clean the cat box.
Don't just visit...
be with me.
I know every inch
of this place -
every flower, every nail,
every bullfrog.
There's just never
anything new for me to see.
If you can't find yourself,
be yourself,
here with me,
where can you?
- Rachel.
- It's not out there...
It's here.
I'll try...
I'll try.
Do better than try.
It's almost dawn, Hannah.
Just let me sit with her
for a few more minutes.
Well, sure.
Look, we don't have
to do this tonight.
We can wait till tomorrow.
I never liked doin' that.
Neither did she.
Wash the dishes now,
don't leave 'em.
Right, Rachel?
It's time.
Rachel...
What am I gonna
do without you?
You'll never be without me.
I look at you two
and that's what I want.
I'm just sorry you never
got to really know Rachel.
I do...
Through you.
Goodbye, kiddo.
Shit, I heard that.
So, finally it's your turn
to leave me, huh, Rachel?
I just wish we coulda had
Greta and her gal over.
You know, sit and eat
your potato salad on the porch?
Wouldn't we have liked that?
We coulda gone to
visit Greta in Minneapolis -
if I ever coulda
gotten you outta town.
Ah, Rachel, there are parades
and festivals, newspapers,
and women's bookstores,
that we never
in our wildest imaginings...
I just wish it
could've come sooner.
So, is that, is that,
uh, is that the one?
'Cause I don't wanna
just unplug the clock.
You're sure this is
what you want?
Hannah, I've had a full life -
oh, my God,
what a life -
but it's over.
Let it be over,
please, Hannah.
What is going on here?
I'm giving your mother
her life back.
You get away from her!
Grandma, let go of her.
Where do you get off?
Hannah's just trying to do what
you should've done months ago.
You wheel her down here?
How could you?
She has every right to be here.
She does not!
Of course she does.
They're lovers.
Oh, I hate that word.
I don't give a shit.
That's what they are.
You shut up.
You have no idea
what this is about.
Of course I do.
Just stop it,
both of you.
Marge, I'm glad you came.
Oh, I bet you are.
It's time, Marge.
You and I oughta
do this together.
It's not about you;
it's not about me.
It's about her.
We both love her.
And saying goodbye to her...
hurts us more than
anything in this world.
But it's time.
I can't.
She's ready to go...
We gotta let her go.
I love her so much.
And I've always been
so jealous of you.
And I always
wanted her to myself.
Did you hate us?
I never hated you.
Remember the moonflowers?
I still have some
in my garden,
but I'm the only one
who appreciates them.
I would.
Please.
What was that?
Her.
Can't be.
Listen.
Please.
She said please?
She wants you
to help her, Grandma.
Why don't you
turn off the I.V.
Greta...
You unplug that.
If anyone asks,
if there's ever any trouble,
I will say I did it.
It's okay.
I'll be so lonely.
Oh, Mama...
I love you.
Rachel.
Wait! Wait for me!