Episode 15
How are you? I am fine!
(In Japanese, famous line in the movie, Love Letter)
Why aren't any tears coming out?
No matter how much I try to squeeze
them out, there's nothing.
But then again, it has
been over five years.
How are you? I am—
You are 1501 Han Mi Mo, right?
Yes, I am.
Your ex-husband sent you this.
What!? How would you know?
It's written there, in big letters.
What?
From your ex-husband, to his ex-wife.
What? He answered me? I only just
tried calling his name out loud.
Finally, I found someone I want to be with.
I've decided that we can
"thank" each other.
Please come and congratulate us.
Kim Seung Jae.
How did things get so
twisted and complicated...
You have an appointment here?
You too?
If possible, let's sit far from each other.
I might lose my appetite,
in this gourmet restaurant.
You think my appetite will be good?!
By chance, are you?
Are you, by chance?
You are?!
That person is...
What, do you know her?
Should I say I know her? I
might say I know her a bit.
How can we have this kind of fate...?
I know, right?
We meet again. Our fate is so...
What are you saying?
That is Oppa, these two
were college classmates.
Oh, is that right?!
Not so close classmates.
Not so close classmates?
By looking at their expressions, they
just might not be close classmates.
What happened that you called
each other unfriendly?
Ah, that is...
That is, he was a Goo Seul Ah's fan.
When Angels disbanded and I was having
a hard time because of Good Seul Ah,
he was one of those fans who
used to send poison in the mail.
What?!
It's all in the past. We
just laugh about it now.
Honey. Were you really her crazy fan?
I was a bit of a crazy fan, but
I think you're misinformed.
I wasn't that big of a fan who
would send poison in by mail.
Just when I ran into Han Mi Mo
at school, it was unpleasant.
I disliked her for bothering Goo Seul Ah.
Have you seen her in person?
She's really annoying.
It's because she bothered an angel like
our Mi Mo, and that's why they disbanded.
It must have been so difficult for you when a big guy like
him was being hateful towards you. Weren't you scared?
I was scared. That's why I used
to avoid him and run away.
Seung Jae has a very cute side to him.
At that age, everyone admires a girl group.
It's fortunate he didn't
like Han Mi Mo of Angels.
Or else, this gathering
would've been awkward.
Min woo, happy birthday!
Me too, Happy birthday!
Thank you.
Tada.
You two aren't close...
But the gifts are the same...
Oppa, it's promising. Even though
you two aren't very close,
they might actually get along once they shake off the
hard feelings since they both have similar taste.
Is that right?
As a chance for them to get closer
should we meet up together
before going back to America?
I don't think we need to do that...
I'm just joking, joking..
If you give it some time
they'll come around.
My Goldfish is such a charming woman.
Oppa.
In Korea, it's my first time seeing
someone so lovable who'd been wounded.
She is cute even when she makes a mistake, and
she's lovable even when she does something wrong.
She is adorable even when she's angry.
She's adorable even when she's angry?
Why, do you not agree?
No. It's possible. Our Shi Ah is
probably adorable too when she's angry.
But she never gets angry.
She's a woman who understands in any situation
and circumstance, and doesn't take it out.
People who failed in their first marriage
tend to want to be compensated for it.
The person who is sitting next to me right now and her
are wanting to show that they have someone better.
You haven't had time to eat right?
Thank you.
Coffee too.
This is awesome.
Ta da!
Hae Joon, would you like
to eat some sushi with us?
I'm okay, I have a lunch appointment.
It looks so tasty.
Doctor! The man you are matched with
this time seems to be very doting.
After seeing him a bit, he looks
like a nice person, I'm so jealous!
Does he look like that?
You should hold on to him, it's hard
to find a genuinely nice person.
Enjoy yourselves.
Doctor, please have some.
I'm okay, I don't really like sushi.
Is that right? I wonder why
he bought sushi then...
Looks like we'll be able to eat up.
Thank you for the food!
When he took the shots of eggs in my
place that time, he was totally cool.
And the worried looks in his eyes
looking at me was so touching too...
I got sucked into them. How can
I not get sucked into them?
You have me in your eyes.
My eyes are like that.
They pull in everything.
Especially you.
My Seung Jae has those
looks in his eyes, too.
Although they are a bit different than
Oppa's... How should I put it? Burning?
Soo Hyuk is lovely from
the head to his toes.
Even his nostrils are pretty.
Look! His nostrils are in heart shape.
Where is it in heart shape?
If you look from this angle... Look.
See it?
If you look this way.
Love is springing up
between the two of you.
I am totally blinded by love.
So I can never be apart from him.
I plan to be glued to him
for the rest of my life.
Right...
I guess I know why you put up an iron guard
to So Yeon. You are being loved like this.
What kind of fate is this...?
Unbelievable...
Soo Hyuk's little sister... Kim Soo...
Thank you.
What?
For loving, Oppa Soo Hyuk very much.
Ah, yes.
I am a bit disappointed for a certain
someone getting hurt, but it looks good.
To have such a great
girlfriend next to him...
Please take good care of
him from now on as well.
Stay right next to him and treat
him as well as you do now.
With your boyfriend... When
are you getting married?
In a week.
What?!
That fast?!
The main wedding will be in America.
So in Korea, we're only planning to just
invite close friends/family over dinner
and simply exchange rings.
Because it's Seung Jae's second marriage,
that's why we want to do it quietly here.
Shall we go out?
Yes.
That's right, Han Mi Mo.
That's what I'm telling you!
It's so awkward!
I did not even imagine that
my ex-wife would be here.
Dad!
Let's go.
Shall we go?
What should we eat?
Anything except fish.
You don't like seafood?
Yeah, because it smells.
No matter how fresh it
is, it's always smelly.
Is that right? Then you'll probably
hate sushi, too. I like it though.
Then we should go eat, I can
always order something else.
Like teriyaki. I like that.
Okay, let's go.
Is Yeon Soo well?
I guess so.
Every time I see you guys,
it's so fascinating.
How could you guys break up
and work at the same place?
Because it's work.
That too can become affection.
Whenever you turn around, you feel secure
knowing she's there, sort of stability.
Affection?
There is someone I want
to introduce you to.
There is someone, a woman Min Woo likes.
A Woman?
Yeah, my younger sister.
You have a younger sister?
Yeah I do.
Her name is Song Shi Ah. When I caused
a trouble and flew back to America,
she didn't ask or argued.
The younger sister who embraced me warmly.
That time, I couldn't see anything
and hear anything.
But as time passed, I saw Min Woo smiling
and I could hear him talking.
The person who made that
possible was my sister Shi Ah.
She's a nice sister.
That's how I was able to gather
courage and come to Korea.
I'm so curious, how she'll look.
What is the occasion,
coming here to my office?
Here.
What is this?
Lunch.
I asked them to pack something
while I was eating.
You used to love this.
Eat it, I'm leaving.
Whether you meet him for
1 year or 10 years,
the thing you can't ever
be sure about is a person.
Although I met him briefly,
the Goo Hae Joon I knew,
had a beautiful back-view.
I thought I knew him better.
CEO, are you coming in now?
Ah, this is our manager.
You've seen her once before, right?
Yeah, hello.
Ahh, this is the person who
swayed our CEO back and forth.
What?
Well, her mental status was
a little off recently.
Ah, I'm hungry, I'm going
to have a late lunch.
Eat a lot!
Because of work, I'll be
gone today and tomorrow.
Work? Did you find a job?
Yeah, I can't starve Min Woo.
I need to earn money.
Thank goodness.
And it's the type of work you'd want to do?
Of course, don't worry.
Then...
Don't be upset you can't see me for a day.
Soo Hyuk.
Yeah?
Well...
It's nothing, be safe.
Mi Mo.
Huh?
I'll be back safely.
How was it seeing Han Mi Mo again?
Are you still uncomfortable?
Is there a reason to be concerned? It's not
like we'll be seeing each other often.
But when I see it, why does it
seem like it's bothering you?
Shi Ah.
To be honest, I have something to tell you.
Tell me what?
It's nothing.
You silly.
What?
I wanted to spend some time with
you, so I asked for a vacation.
A vacation? You'd get scolded by your
goddess wasting vacation time like this.
I get scolded for this and that.
I get scolded everyday.
So if I am going to get scolded anyway, I might
as well do something I like and be scolded.
It's cumbersome.
Fine then. I'll void the vacation time.
I got it. Where shall we go first?
What's with her?
Why does it have to be that jerk?
How can it be twisted like this?
- Ah seriously... -Should
I give it to her later?
Song Soo Hyuk. Song Min Woo.
And the same last name.
Han Mi Mo.
Kim Seung Jae
Previously husband and wife
Actually there is no problem in kinship.
But my conscience is not clear.
The heaven and earth knows.
When are you getting married
with your boyfriend?
In a week.
Ahh, everything will end in a week.
Han Mi Mo! Can you give
up on Song Soo Hyuk?
Are you going to give up like this?
Should I ask Kim Seung Jae a favor
for both of us not to say anything?
No. No... That will...
- Eat a lot. - Okay Oppa.
It's delicious.
She is a good cook.
You cook well.
- Honey, ah! -Uhm, ah!
Look at this happy face!
Her face is glowing after we got married.
Drink it.
Let's finish eating and go to bed early.
Miss Han Mi Mo?
Yes.
You got mail.
What is this?
Who is it?
I know what kind of relationship you
had with Kim Seung Jae five years ago.
And you want to marry Song Soo Hyuk?
Are you human?
You wish for a happiness making a
mess of someone's family registry?!
Aigoo.
Couple Love Note
Terms of endearment.
Write down your terms of endearment here.
Now you need to use these beautiful
terms of endearment to call each other.
Hey! You! Look! These won't do, right?
Don't call so and so's
mother or father either.
Terms of endearment that is full of love.
Call each other sweetly with
those terms of endearment.
Love has come back.
What are you doing?
Homework that is assigned
by the couple camp.
Homework?
Movie date. Going to market together.
Learning yoga together...
Well, there's a lot.
I have to take photo as proof
after we do it together.
There is a prize of trip for the
first couple completing the tasks.
Then you wouldn't be so enticed.
You wouldn't put much
effort for winning a trip.
It's not like you can't take a trip because you
don't have money. It is the time you don't have.
Do you have any terms of endearment
to call your boyfriend by?
I broke up with my boyfriend recently.
Ah, right. Sorry.
Well, it's okay.
But... my terms of endearment
were Jajang and Jampong.
- Uh?
- Because our likes were so different.
Think simply. Doesn't have to be grandiose.
Wh-what...
This will prevent from getting
bruised on your pretty face.
Did you wait long?
No.
I ran quickly, but I'm late.
What do you have to say?
The thing is...
What is it?
Why so serious? You are making me nervous.
There's something you need to know.
What's wrong? Something happened?
You look nervous.
Honestly, I have something to confess...
Tell me. I'll listen to it all.
- All?- Yeah.
You wouldn't have lied about your age
like I did. You are a teacher after all.
Tell me. I'll listen to whatever you'd
have to say and forgive everything.
Did you tell him? Is it why you are alone?
He dumped you and left you, didn't he?
See... Ending it early...
I couldn't tell him.
What? Why?
I couldn't say it.
He believes I am an
innocent and honest woman.
I couldn't tell him looking at his
deer-like eyes and say "you got fooled."
Then, where did that guy go?
- His part-time job.- Part-time job?
Unnie. This is the reality for
you and for your formula baby.
You have a career and that
kid works at a part-time.
You still don't get it?
Han Mi Mo, what's wrong?
Da Jung, what do I do?
What? Kim Seung Jae?
He had to be the fiancee
to Song Soo Hyuk's sister.
- Are you sure? - We even had a meal
together, so what's there to be sure?
What are you going to do?
I just... I just have to give up.
His sister and Kim Seung Jae
are getting married in a week.
Hey, what do I do? What do I do, Da Jung?
What should you do?
Did you tell Soo Hyuk?
What would I tell him?
He'd only get shocked.
But still you need to discuss it together.
Thinking Soo Hyuk getting
shocked pains me already.
If it wasn't for me...
If I didn't get entangled like this...
What's the theme for today's shooting?
Promise.
Are you perhaps talking about the promise
a man and a woman holding hands and vow?
Uh, that vow.
I shouldn't have used my vacation time.
Don't you have any theme that is more
dynamic and more exciting? Of all things...
You are quite a lucky guy being
able to joke about that.
- Yeah?
- Holding hands like that with someone
is a very difficult thing.
It is a very hard thing.
I got it.
Let's go eat now.
- Ah, cute.- The couple, the couple.
Yeah. Look to the front.
One, two, three.
They are looking at us.
- See...- We don't have to hide, do we?
Take it.
Yes. Smile prettily. Smile.
Taking a vow is quite cunning.
You can take a vow but it's nothing
if you don't register for marriage.
Registered for a marriage,
but void if divorced.
It ends if you divorce and
turn your backs on each other.
If you forget about the vow
you made in your head,
then it's over, isn't it?
But I still want to do it.
And tell her I'd get the stars and
the moon from the sky for her.
That's corny. You even say
that kind of thing these days?
Why? Is it too childish?
What else doesn't keep its
place more than the stars?
What else changes more than the moon?
You should rather get something else
that doesn't change. What do we have...?
Changing is inevitable.
How you change is important.
Seung Jae, I beg of you, you give
up, I can't live without him.
I am already getting old and other guys
won't deal with my anger as you've said.
And if I cry, I became intolerably ugly...
Is this too subservient?
Seung Jae!
- Hi, Sister-in-law. - Hello.
Wow, you came looking so pretty.
Of course.
What should we have for dinner?
Song Soo Hyuk.
What brings you here without calling?
I was on my way home and thought of you.
Just give up one of the two.
You can't have both.
Which one is more precious...
Wouldn't it be easier
once you figure that out?
This woman told me once
while walking away from me.
Just spit and forget about it.
Oh, thanks.
No, no. I'll do it.
Why? I was only going to rinse the dishes.
No. If you get the dish soap on your hands,
you'll get those wrinkles you hate so much.
Oh, that's right. I would.
Go on and rest.
Then, well.
It's suspicious. Something's definitely up.
What?
Washing the dishes, throwing away food scraps,
and even ironing. He won't let me do any of it.
I came in first to go to bed,
but he even filled the water in the
humidifier and wished me a good night.
Any other man would say,
"I'm doing all the housework."
"But you're sleeping. How can you sleep?"
Wouldn't that be a normal reaction?
It's nice if he's good to you.
Why be suspicious?
Since he works at a beauty company, he probably heard
a lot from other women and is doing what he heard.
You should consider yourself lucky. Why
are you making up problems for yourself?
When someone is perfect,
it means something's up.
Unnie, do you not remember how strongly
I got back stabbed at the wedding?
For some reason I am getting
that feeling again.
For sure this is a smoke screen.
If you go any further than that, you'd
be having a delusional jealousy issue.
No. I'll definitely find it.
Damn.
Terms of endearment
What'll be good?
I'm not sure.
How about this?
Alkong Dalkong.
That's tacky and overused.
Right?
Then what about this? Opp...
ah. Yobo... ong.
Oppah. Yoboong. Too difficult to pronounce.
Manager Kwak from my office used Jjajang and Jjambbong
because their taste buds were so different.
That's cute. Shall we use it?
Jjajang (black bean noodles)
and Jjambbong (spicy noodles)?
Uh, they don't sound greasy
but feels a bit spicy.
Then, what would you be?
I'll be Jjambbong, and you be the Jjajang.
It sounds okay.
Let's write it down.
Baek Jja Jang
Kim Jjam Bbong
Since we got the terms of endearment,
shall we go do the first task?
♪1?
♪ 1, Go to the market together
and make food for each other.
Should we?
You are the female younger sibling to
Song Soo Hyuk, who lives above him?
It keeps beeping telling you it's
wrong, so why don't you go home now.
Min Woo told me it was this.
What is that? 5995959?
How did you know?
I changed it because it was tacky.
What? With what right?
With the right of being
Song Soo Hyuk's girlfriend!
And because I don't like a female
going in and out of his place.
Give me the code!
I wouldn't have changed it if I was going
to give it out that easily, would I?
Don't get antsy and go home.
In time... You might get a chance.
Promiscuous Goldfish
The person you are trying to call is...
Is she sleeping?
What unfinished business
do we have between us?
I'd think ending your relationship
would be more urgent.
The relationship was ended already...
five years ago.
Unfinished business is this.
There's no way you didn't register
the divorce paper, right?
What a scary thing to say...?
What's in the envelope?
Confirm it yourself.
Insurance Policy Application
This...
I continued that policy because
because I didn't want to waste it.
But if I leave it the way it is...
You'd be the beneficiary if
something happened to me.
I checked with the insurance company, and
even though we are no longer married,
having your name on the policy,
you'd hit the jackpot later.
So?
You take that and change it yourself.
Put my name as the policyholder
and the beneficiary.
Hey, Kim Seung Jae.
It's not like I am asking for too much,
and I've been paying for it too.
The thing you want to finish
up is the insurance policy?!
Do you know how much I've
been paying for that?
Don't you think it's being
wasted if it were you?
Is this something that absurd?
You never know how to
moderate your emotion.
Hey! After meeting you
and Song Shi Ah today,
do you know what kind of
agony I was in all day?
Agony...?
Wouldn't you be?
Since you are getting married,
it wouldn't matter. Is that it?
What are you talking about?
Forget it if you don't want to.
I'll give it up.
Fine, you give up!
Fine. Throw away that paper or burn it.
I said to give up!
I said I got it.
You give up. Don't you
know what I'm saying?
What now?
I can't give Song Soo Hyuk up!
So, you give up.
What are you talking about out of nowhere?
Out of nowhere?
Are you saying it is
expected that I give up?
Or shall we drag this into a mud?
Should I ignore everything and
get into the Song family?
What are you...?
We are going to be entangled as a family.
No matter how we much we close our eyes
and close our ears and close our mouth,
we'll see each other at the family's
events and holidays at least.
If I don't give up...
What are you saying?
That is Oppa... Oppa.
Laugh? Is it funny? This situation is?
It is funny. Isn't it funny to you?
Let's not drag this into the mud.
I am dumbfounded that you even thought
about that, and it makes me laugh.
I am saying Song Soo Hyuk
is that important to me.
Even so this isn't it. No matter how much you
love him, there is the line you shouldn't cross.
Let me tell you a fact that will
help you to make your decision.
We are getting married in a week.
Isn't it obvious who should give up?
Oh, what do I do?
Why are you crying in the rain?
You'll catch a cold.
What did you say?
I wrote my reason here.
What's wrong all of a sudden?
I've been thinking a lot.
Is it because of the age thing again?
When you read this, you'll understand.
Are you being sincere?
Yeah.
I got it.
I'll read it.
Then...
Are you leaving?
I am getting up now.
I wrote down my heart there. You'll
know my heart after reading it.
I wrote about how I feel in here.
I got it.
Be careful in the rain.
Okay. I'm going.
Jung Woo, I actually lied 3
years of my age like you did.
So our age gap is 9 years
which we can't overcome.
I am sorry. Looking at those
deer-like eyes of yours,
I can't deceive you any longer.
Please know this one thing.
All that was because I
didn't want to lose you.
Thinking about it, when you
were eating baby food,
I was learning multiplications
and divisions at school.
Divisions... Right I was learning about the
divisions (homonym for knowing one's place)
Now I think I should get my head
straight and know my place.
I'd like it if you can understand that I am at the
age to meet and be married to an appropriate man.
I'm sorry. Let's break up. Dong Mi.
How can he not hold my arm even once?
As if he'd been waiting for it...
Right. What Ae Ran said was right.
If I keep the relationship going like this, he'd
say "thank you for all this time Noona" to me.
Oh my, how heartbreaking that would be?
Ayissi. Fine, good riddance Ahn Jung Woo.
This umbrella is broken...
It's not opening.
It opened now.
My shoes are uncomfortable.
Uh my feet hurts.
- Is it just your feet that hurts?- Huh?
Your arms and legs or
your head doesn't hurt?
This is why it's tiring to have relationship
with a woman who is full of the first time.
Go Dong Mi, tell me honestly. You haven't
had many relationships, have you?
How did you...?
Asking for a breakup is not
something you should say lightly.
What are you talking about? Me
and you are really breaking up.
You idiot! Is this the letter written
by someone who wants to breakup?
No.
If sincere, one phrase
let's break up will do.
No need for a long explanation like this.
This is confessing I really like
you very much letter. You idiot.
Idiot. Just tell me that
useless thing again...
Go Dong Mi, don't eat my heart and runaway.
Wait. We'll probably
overcome the 9 year age gap.
Let's wait and see, okay?
Do you have an umbrella?
Yeah.
It's raining a lot.
I have to go meet someone real quick.
Now? At this time?
Yeah, I have to meet them for sure.
Okay. Don't get rained on and be careful.
Don't cry, huh?
If you continue, you'll look ugly.
Let me tell you a fact to
help you make your decision.
We are getting married in a week.
- Is it fun?- What?
Seeing your ex-wife suffering?
We've been running into each other lately.
I was angry about some things, too.
I just didn't want to say it with my own mouth
for the things that'll be known anyway.
It'll be known anyway, but
even for just a few days,
don't you think about the person
who'd be in pain for that time?
I can guess why you guys divorced.
What did you say?
Don't hurt Shi Ah. She is
a precious sister to me.
But, I don't think I should see
you anymore because of my woman.
From this moment on, I will remain a
disappointing and bad older brother to Shi Ah.
So you be good to her.
Of course you would though...
Yes.
I got all the materials.
Now? Yes, I understand.
You weren't sleeping?
When did you come?
A while ago. But, you were
staying here like this?
The thing is, Soo Hyuk...
Soo Hyuk, the thing is...
We have to break up.
Mi Mo.
I see. You guys were married?
I am sorry to entangle you
uncomfortably like this.
It's not a pleasant relationship,
but it isn't fatal either.
Oppa Soo Hyuk and I are not blood related.
We say we are family because of
the good relationship we've had.
But you are more important to me.
Thank you... for thinking
about it that way.
And, I'm really sorry.
This jerk...
I am sorry Goldfish. You've been
suffering alone, haven't you?
I'm sorry.
Do you know how much...
I am sorry. I should've
introduced you more clearly.
I did wrong. I'm sorry.
Why did you say she is a family member?
Why didn't you put "kin" in front of
younger sister and why the same last name?
I did wrong.
Ah, Song Soo Hyuk!
Oppa!
What are you doing in the hallway in the
middle of night? What if Min Woo sees this?
She is that sister's younger sister.
Oh, I see.
I want to see her next to me.
Even if she changes... It's okay
as long as she doesn't leave me.
That will do for me.
You just live with her. You'll ask her to sit
back when she is trying to get near you.
And if she tells you that she is taking
a trip for a month makes you happy.
And so envious of the
weekend husband and wife.
Ah, seriously.
I am serious.
Marriage Notification
I recognize who this is.
I don't know.
By chance, are you cheating on me again?
Why do you have a screen lock?
If you got nothing to hide,
then unlock the screen.
You unlock your first,
then I'll unlock mine.
Give me a day.
You smart for nothing! With that time, I'd get rid
of all the evidence even if I am cheating on you.
Insurance Policy Application
I am turning it over because I don't want to
hear that I might hit the jackpot by keeping it.
Was it fun for you to see me suffer?
I already got scolded for it
by someone, so give it a rest.
- Who?- You don't need to know.
It was really tiresome us
living together, right?
It was... Because neither
one of us want to lose.
Shi Ah is perfect for me.
Song Shi Ah. The person I am grateful to.
I don't know what kind of man Song Soo
Hyuk is, but I wish you the best.
The man who is only looking at me.
The man who is on a different level from Kim
Seung Jae who plays with a woman's emotions.
The man who puts my feelings
first in any situation.
The man who worries all the
time that I might get hurt.
Seeing you, I covet Song Soo Hyuk
even more because of the comparison.
I am curious. Is that
spray really effective?
What?
No, just...
You are just spraying there, so I
am wondering if it's effective.
Omo! Omo, omo!
By this time the germs
would have been invaded.
If you do that too much, you won't get immunity
and will have more difficult time later.
If needed, you should get hurt a bit.
Omo what kind of rash talk...?
Omo! Who put the papers on the walls?
It is done by your line of people, right?
Please get rid of them, I am asking.
Okay.
What a...?
The path I am walking towards you.
Even if it is a painful path
stepping hundreds of chipped stones.
♪ If your frozen heart ♪
I don't love you because I love you.
But I love you because I can only love you.
♪ as you sometimes do ♪
♪ Would you say to me that I was
in your heart, all along? ♪
♪ If you find me here someday ♪
♪ I always was a dreamer,
wished for a rose in December ♪
♪ If you remember my voice, my promise ♪
♪ I will sing with the blue bird ♪
♪ Kiss the rain, the bird ♪
♪ If you're coming closer ♪
I am... Sexy Han Mi Mo.
Humanity Han Mi Mo.
Hard-working Han Mi Mo.
Fighting Han Mi Mo.
Innocent Han Mi Mo.
I like all of them.
However, the Han Mi Mo
that I like the most is...
In this moment, the happy Han Mi Mo.
If I promise to make you
laugh like this once a day,
♪ If a little little bit
of love is waiting for ♪
♪ Why don't you come a little closer here ♪
Will you... Marry me?
♪ In my heart now ♪
Yes!♪ I see a girl ♪
♪ Dancing all day in the rain ♪
Please tell him yes!
♪ For a fallen star ♪
Soo Hyuk, I have something to tell you.
♪ As you brush against my heart, you
appear, come to me, and shake me up ♪
♪ I didn't know my love for you and
how my heart flutters for you ♪
♪ Your bright eyes, your shaking hand ♪