THE END
Love stories are all the same.
Happy beginning and an unhappy ending.
My story is quite different.
My birth for example.
No mother, no father.
So this is me.
My first photo.
You were on the blanket kicking your little feet,
but I didn't even have legs.
I've only got a head.
What a state of being.
But that's getting ahead of myself.
At that moment I was yet unborn.
And then there was... click...
And I was born.
One.
Has he got any children?
Five - seventeen.
What's the time?
Be brave my son,
soon you'll stand before Our Lord
and the Virgin Mary.
That's disgusting.
One last cigarette?
Such beauty!
It was a bit cold,
but the birds were singing, and this smell...
So this is the world!
According to section...
[speaking backwards]
Nice, very nice.
And it is only the beginning.
When I grow up I'll learn to play
violin, or start bullying cats.
Oh Lord, so many opportunities!
I can't wait!
According to section 836
[speaking backwards]
But there are formalities,
the world is not a pigeon loft,
I understood from the very beginning.
...in the name of republic.
Finally entered the real world.
Supported on both sides.
Left, right, left...
My legs were rubberlike,
I still could not walk properly,
but these gentlemen were patient.
The one with the umbrella
gave me life advice.
First of all they had to untie me.
Bring out the prisoner!
-I hope so.
-May God forgive you.
Let us pray, my son.
-Do you know all of the Ten Commandments?
-I threw 'em out of the window.
What did you do to that man?
He died?
Eternal life awaits only those
who sincerely regret their sins.
That would take a long time.
Confess, my son!
Tell me everything.
Get up! The execution!
The lyceum I was brought up in
had an excellent reputation.
The educational system was sophisticated.
Boys and girls were separated.
Headquarters understood
our natural playfulness.
We horsed around all day long!
Through play, we were brought up
to become sturdy individuals,
who in future could hold positions
of responsibility in society.
As I was looking around
at the other kids,
I thought: there are generals to-be,
ministers to-be among us...
Who knows what else?
One educational method
was returning food.
When we handed over
every last grain of rice,
we all gave the same.
We were untouched by selfishness,
and other ugly vices
which spoil one's character.
I was encouraged to be self-reliant.
My work became my pleasure.
I couldn't imagine my life
without unsticking those sacks.
Every sack was a piece of my youth.
"What are you going to be, Bedrich?"
my mates often asked me.
And I said: an "unsticker".
Those boyish dreams!
The smell of glue was everything to me.
Little did I know how fond
of meat and blood I'd become.
When I was almost ready
to enter real world,
I felt a desire to revolt,
when they said...
-Take the condemned.
-No, please!
Anything you want to say?
The court found the defendant guilty
and condemns him under section 382...
[speaking backwards]
...the death penalty.
Don't worry, everything will be fine.
What do you think, doctor?
The court will now retire
for deliberation.
Finally something sensible.
Yes, I did it.
So, you did it?
How long will you continue to deny?
-We know everything.
-But this is a lie!
Silence!
Or I'll clear the court.
As I said before,
I didn't kill anybody!
I'm asking for the last time:
Did you kill your wife and her lover?
I didn't notice anything.
And you didn't notice the
suitcase was dripping blood?
Landlord maybe, or the laundress.
And who put the corpse
into your suitcase?
The judge.
He already asked me.
-Who asked you?
-I don't know what else you want from me.
The judge asked me about everything.
One more question for the defendant.
My name is Bedrich Frydrych,
a butcher,
born on 1st of September 1889 in Trumberk.
What's your name and occupation?
You were born...
Not at all!
You don't suffer any mental disorders?
So let's begin.
A few formalities
and goodbye for good.
You know, leaving the place
where you've learned the basics,
how to sit and how to walk,
where you know every grate,
it is not easy.
It's easy to say,
go and take care of yourself.
Fortunately they give me
something to start with.
A ring from a principal,
a comb,
a knife, 11.60 in change,
a watch, keys,
an older handkerchief,
but also beautiful
silver bracelets.
Very kind of them.
Farewell, my native courtyard, farewell.
The gates to the world stood
open in front of me,
with all the fairytale
possibilities ahead.
You're under arrest!
How do you know?
You did this!
A hand!
This is your wife!
Sadly, she isn't whole.
Cigarette?
Ugh!
A head!
A leg!
This is a woman!
I don't know.
Birdseed maybe.
What do you have in this suitcase?
Hand it over!
I've brought a fishy man
with very suspicious luggage.
Buzz off!
I'm sorry, inspector.
This was my first experience
with ordinary people.
Oh, how much kindness
is hidden under rough skin!
They took my hand.
I couldn't hitch my wagon to a star
because they furnished me with a porter.
But when I desired for
my independency,
they let me go.
Oh please, please try it yourself.
How proud my guide was,
watching me doing
better and better.
Among people like that
I'll never be alone. No!
There will always be someone
to rely on and confer with.
Someone to share my joy with.
They knew I need a wife and handed
her to me. Including the suitcase.
I was standing there confused
over my bride-to-be,
Not knowing how to express my thanks.
This good man sensed my abashment.
He backed away discretely.
Eagerly I grabbed my wife,
and ran towards life,
love and happiness.
They allotted me a flat in
a well-built house.
This comforted me.
I couldn't bring my wife
just anywhere.
She's still dismantled
and I didn't know much about her.
Only that she weighs about 70 kilos.
Not bad.
Much better than some 20 kilogram weed.
The flat looked also good.
At the lyceum we had
much smaller windows.
But it wasn't nearly this messy.
But I'm not going to clean up.
First I'm gonna make my wife.
We can tidy up together and
it'll be done in no time.
It wasn't easy.
It was the first woman
I've ever met.
At first she looked
quite ordinary.
I used to see women from the lyceum window,
but they were already assembled.
I've got no instructions.
She'll be the way I put her together.
One little mistake
and I could create a monster,
which I couldn't allow out onto the street.
What name should I give her?
Natalia, or Eulalia?
No, it's too long.
Life is short.
I've got it!
Julia. Julia!
I felt like the Creator,
like God.
And then I made up my mind.
I'll be a butcher!
She was beautiful.
And I knew that I loved her.
She was divine.
She was glamorous.
She was assembled very well.
Our happiness can begin.
But not in the bathroom!
Hm...
Her body was so flexible!
And light, soft and supple...
I was smitten with her supplenesses.
Hop!
Also the finger.
I almost forgot.
She might think I
can't count to five.
She was charming.
Those movements...
That grace, that charm...
Those gestures, that nobility,
that temperament!
Now to remove
this little blemish...
and finally I've heard
her first sweet words.
You brute, you killed him!
Then I realized that life,
is full of tricky surprises.
Instead of enjoying my first
pleasant afternoon with Julia,
something totally
unexpected happened.
That dandy showed up,
who apparently thought
that Julia was made for him.
With symptomatic arrogance
he flew in through the window,
just to spoil my happiness.
His name was Birdie.
Watch this!
And he watched.
I forced him to help
me with the tidying up.
He was quite good at it.
He took half of the room
and was pretty fast.
Pray!
For salvation of your soul!
-Such a trash-talker!
-Mangy dog!
But he started to act obtrusively.
-Without any wicked intention!
-What?
You got into my bed?
Bedrich, for heaven's sake!
He just came to play cards!
Oh, please!
First the bed, now cards.
What a lazybones!
This slacker was just interfering.
I shut him in the closet.
I hope, he's not going to
steal my spatterdashes!
Like a woodshed!
Bedrich, be reasonable!
What will the flat look like?
I'm gonna pluck the very last
feather out of him!
What are you doing, sweetheart?
It was so nice here!
She was acting like a puppy.
I had to teach her the difference
between order and mess.
-He is there! I know it!
-I don't know what you are talking about.
-I was crocheting just now.
-What a surprise, huh?
Finally I caught you napping,
you... you...
He is there!
-You're not in Pardubice, Béda?
-Open up!
How does he impress her?
Maybe because he can fly...
I was never into
these fopperies.
But she wanted to be alone with him
and I was thrown out.
I'm coming, sweetheart.
Who is it? Mrs. Slavickova?
See? Now I'm Mrs. Slavickova for her.
I don't know why,
but it's wiser to retreat,
I don't want to start
the marriage with a fight.
It's not Julia's fault,
she's been there only a few minutes.
I had to explain her,
it's not suitable behaviour
for young lady to throw
her husband out of a flat,
making excuses about Pardubice.
-Julie, you're awakening a beast inside of me!
-Impossible.
He is sitting on the train now.
Are you sure your husband won't return?
-I can't resist the passion.
-I'm a married woman!
I'll be ashamed. No!
-No...
-Don't resist!
-What are you doing, Jene?
-Let's make ourselves comfortable.
This is not possible Jene, no, no, no...
No.
This will be much nicer.
Where are you dragging me?
It was so innocent.
No, this can't be, Jene!
-A souvenir.
-Oh...
A ring!
Oh, you didn't have to.
Why? Might there be something wrong with that?
Excellent!
I'm afraid we will cross
the bounds of pure friendship.
Do you know what I'm dreaming of?
Kissing you at least once in my life, Julia.
I baked those!
Delicious!
Wonderful, really wonderful.
I'm glad you like it.
I always have an appetite.
Special!
Delicious!
Do you like it?
Excellent!
A delicacy!
Well done!
Thank you, Julia.
Okay, you can call me Julia.
I'd like to call you Julia.
And you can call me... Jenik.
Or dominoes.
Why don't we play game of cards,
Mrs. Frydrych?
There's nothing to hide Mr. Birdie.
You've just come for a visit.
Your husband should be happy
that we've become friends.
I started to get nervous.
What if there was familiarities?
Julia was just in her nightie,
what if he wants to dress her up?
No! He can't be that daring!
Do you mind if I pull down the blinds a bit?
It's by my uncle,
he died of gout.
Lovely!
-Oh, how noble!
-We can sit in the lounge,
-Do you like coffee?
-Not at all.
It's perfect orderliness.
Come in. Please don't look around.
I didn't expect you.
It's little messy.
-It means you're alone.
-Pig.
-Calf?
-My husband went to the relatives. To butcher.
This is something for you, flowers.
Is your husband at home?
Welcome.
-That's lovely!
-Hm...
Hello!
Coming! Just a second!
At last!
But my relief was
soon jolted.
Isn't it suspicious?
He arrived without a tie,
and now he is strutting around
in my spatterdashes?
Usually I'm good-tempered,
but this is too much.
My own wife is handing
out my wardrobe?
There should be a good reason.
Yes, no doubt.
In these tragic moments
of my life, a rival
between Julia and I.
At home I found out that I have
a child. It struck me numb.
Is Birdie behind this,
or had I just not noticed before?
Damn discursiveness!
I had to pretend
that nothing was amiss.
Ta ta, sweetie.
Papa's off to slay a piggy.
Yeah! I can't wait
to see that cousin.
Excuse me! The woods are full of them,
we tramped through them.
You bought mushrooms, hmm?
-What are you gonna do?
-My cousin.
Where?
In the woods, with my cousin.
You're here at last!
I'd like to know where
you've been all this time!
I was playing with the kid
instead of going to Pardubice!
Calm down, I said to myself.
Let's check this cousin out.
It annoys me a lot,
that we have to lie,
ma'am.
True friendship goes hand in
hand with truth. Doesn't it?
-My cousin.
-Whom will you say you've been with?
I think I stepped on a splinter.
Really?
You can't imagine how glad I am.
You can visit me,
my husband is going somewhere.
It's true!
I couldn't believe it.
But there's no point in covering my eyes
from the truth, however ruthless.
I feel like a little girl.
Do you like me?
Yes, it's disgusting.
Sand is better.
There used to be no mud at the lake,
do you remember?
Hop!
My husband can never do that.
She was right.
Even as a child I didn't like
to jump legs first out of water.
One never knows where one's gonna
land. You could jump on somebody.
I think it's irresponsible,
but Mr. Birdie's view seems to be different.
That's typical.
Don't you feel sorry for her?
Such a beautiful fish!
Just like you Mrs. Frydrych.
What a gorgeous day!
-There's strange magic in it.
-It's just a matter of practice.
-Goodness, where do you get all these fish?
-I knew. I knew right where they were coming from.
He earned his living this way!
He steals from poor animals in the zoo.
He was hiding his loot
in the pram of our Pavlinka.
He doesn't care that she could be
in serious trouble if found out.
Oh, how generous they are.
Trainers give them
tons of fish.
It's not easy to teach them
such an unbelievable trick.
Do you think every animal
can learn this, Mr. Birdie?
A whole loaf.
It's nothing for him.
May no one spot us.
It's strictly forbidden.
That's why I come here for lunch.
It's very cheap.
I see, but why among the animals?
-I was anxious to see you again.
-What did you say?
You're exaggerating.
Since I almost drowned,
I've been thinking about you all the time.
Two o'clock exactly.
-I'm punctual, am I not?
-Hmm, rather hungry.
-Those animals are violent, did you hear?
-As I said, just like you.
I didn't understand.
Can you speak louder.
That day I noticed
a trace of alienation towards
Mr. Birdie on the part of my wife.
The reason is pretty clear.
His petty theft removed
the rose tint from Julia's eyes.
To steal from a bank is okay.
But to pauperise a hippo
is a different story.
This mute creature,
so vulnerable,
helped my wife to understand,
that cruel villain can't
compensate for a husband
who's been working hard
to feed his family
and make his wife happy.
"Fresh meat delivery"
I felt I'd won.
In a few days only fragments of
memories of Mr. Birdie will remain.
Maybe a date or two
and then it's over.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-Okay, you can go then.
-At the lion's cage, two o'clock.
-Your wife?
She's got a date with the other man.
What a surprise!
It was Franta's duty, wasn't it?
Can I go to the zoo?!
Boss.
I was happy again.
The work was pleasurable. The cows
started to grow under my hands,
and I was thinking
about my sweetheart.
I was thinking about our
plans for the future.
When Birdie disappears,
I'll buy clothes for Julia.
A nice tight dress
which fits her closely.
I also decided
Juli will get a maid.
So she can have a lie down
in peace.
She can get up after ten
then go shopping,
or for slaughter,
uh, I mean a stroll.
We can spend our holidays
somewhere far away.
Julia loved mountains.
And I wasn't against it.
-Oh, that's amazing!
-Yeah, it is amazing.
It was amazing.
Because soon will be
the end of Julia's acquaintance.
Mr. Birdie's stumble in the zoo
built an obstacle between them,
and Julia wasn't willing
to overcome it.
Finally, the day
of their last meeting.
He thought I couldn't see him.
But I was closely observing
what was going on.
This tragedy was a pleasure to watch.
You should've seen his rueful face!
That's your problem, man!
That's for flying
into the third floor!
Now you're gonna find out
what true love really means.
The world is full of swindlers
and lazybones,
who pursue their mingy goals,
but true love will always prevail.
Oh!
Horse butchery, my dear.
-Whatcha you gonna buy, Béda?
-A chimney-sweeper.
-What? Who did you meet in the morning?
-What a fortune!
I could hardly forget this day.
It brought me top-notch luck,
but also great disaster.
That day at the races
I gambled away all my money.
Well, that's life.
I'll drop you a note.
Get lost!
-You're very generous.
-Me? Yes.
Do you think of me and
the lake sometimes?
You know how much I love horses?
What a surprise, Mr. Birdie?
Mr. Birdie left our life,
but poverty arrived instead.
It was hard to pretend,
that nothing happened.
I was heartbroken
giving away
hard earned money, which could
secure our happy childhood.
But when the stress overcomes us,
there was our Pavlinka.
She was really talented.
She had a sense for
our financial problems.
All she needed was a small fire.
She could pull bills out of it.
Sometimes a hundred koruna,
or at least five.
Thanks to her we were
doing better and better.
She was able to give us almost 2 litres
of milk per day. That's 700 litres a year.
After a while we obtained
quite a fortune.
She was rewarded well.
We tried hard.
We patiently sucked
the air from balloons,
just to hear laughs of excitement
from this humble little being.
But soon there was an end to our joy.
Our lovely child got
smaller and smaller.
She can't start fires anymore,
she lost her teeth and can't walk.
She lay down more often,
and finally can't even get up.
She's only 3 kilos.
The end was inevitable.
One day we lost
Pavlinka for good.
Our mourning
didn't have to last long.
We receive a message that our
father-in-law is going to be born.
Julia won't be an orphan anymore.
Of course, we were curious
as to what he will be like.
They said he was gonna be a very rich man.
At that moment he was elegantly wrapped.
Full of anticipation,
we brought him home.
We couldn't be present
for his birth.
I was with Julia far away,
while he was still in the incubator.
News of his birth reached us
at a mountain lake.
While we toasted
to his happy life,
I realised how lucky I was.
It was wise of me to excuse
this little misdemeanour of Julia.
My deliberation finally paid off.
We were happy.
You can surely understand
the outburst of anger in my heart,
when this dandy
appeared again
to take my Julia.
I was astonished by his arrogance.
Hurt deep inside, I kept
asking myself,
why is he doing it?
Does he really think
I'll sit here with idle hands,
watching my happiness crumple?
I'm so happy that you were rescued.
-Hm...
-Oh!
And then I made up my mind.
This man must die!
It's horrible to say that,
but it must be done.
Otherwise this gadabout
will never learn his lesson.
He's alive!
I didn't feel like a murderer
at all.
No, no, no!
I wasn't murdering in secret.
I decided to drown him in public,
like adulteresses were drowned in the past.
It didn't surprise me much
that the others approved of this.
He was well known, this Birdie!
They knew him as irritating vermin.
They were glad.
He'll finally stop being a bother.
That's it!
Béda...
Béda!
Someone is drowning!
I didn't feel guilty.
But Julia gobsmacked me.
That was quite a stunt, Béda.
It was almost unbelievable.
She was laughing!
Only moments after the man for whom
she was willing to betray the family
disappeared into the waves!
Her treachery shocked me.
Trump!
I run away from the place where
I discovered the true face of my wife,
the wife I loved until yesterday.
Under the circumstances
we can't live together anymore.
Yes, I will leave Julia.
I will leave her when
we arrive home.
You have to eat something
before your difficult journey.
I don't need a remedy, Julinka.
-Give it to me!
-Just a second, Béda!
-Patience is the best remedy.
-She was crazy.
I was hungry.
Any other woman could roast a turkey,
she couldn't even butter bread.
One moment!
She was acting like a lunatic.
What's taking you so long?
I'm almost blind from hunger!
Julinka!
Juli!
I'm your kitchen girl, eh?
That too, but rather a fried egg.
-Do you like sardines?
-Hm.
Also Prague Woman, Her Daily
and Czech Word.
The landlord will take care of it.
We have to cancel the milk.
So, what is Bedrisek going to eat?
A dressing gown.
-Looking for something?
-Soft-boiled eggs.
-I'm gonna make a delicious breakfast.
-I wonder what.
You know what? Good morning.
Our last wedding night began.
It wasn't easy
restoring her virginity.
You hurt me a lot.
Other way around, Julia.
I won't be your baby girl anymore.
-And that's my point.
-Why don't you think about my happiness?
-A few seconds more.
-Please, Bedrichu, what are you doing?
-Are you a virgin?
-No, I don't want to!
-I don't want to, Béda, no...
-You'll get used to it.
Turn the lights off, Béda!
-Do you really love me?
-Not at all.
-I'm afraid, it will be awful.
-You're gonna like it, believe me.
Why are you hurrying so much?
I'm starting to dislike it.
It makes me happy.
Calm down, sweetheart.
No man saw me in
my nightie before.
You can't be serious.
Another button...
I'll be ashamed.
No, this is terrible.
What are you gonna do?
Take your time,
it was so nice until now.
No, no... Béda!
We can sleep separately
today, don't you think?
-Yes and forever.
-Do you love your baby girl?
Finally I can return
Juli to her family.
I can do it with honour.
She was intacta.
Cheers and questions were endless.
What was her marriage like?
When she goes to the pulpit, will she
be looking forward to her innocence?
Topsy-turvy, you can imagine.
When all those aunties, nieces and
cousins come to see
how a married woman enters
single status.
[speaking backwards]
...my poor wife Bozka...
Let's eat!
I grasp the opportunity to get rid of
the junk that hampered me for years.
-Very nice, thank you.
-Thank you.
Thanks, really!
Thank you.
A moorcock, thank you.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, Amálka.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
-Oh, a big knife, what for?
-Thank you, Auntie.
It's for killing.
For the meat, Julia, the meat.
Only formalities
before God remained.
God bless you.
May you live a happy life.
What God puts together,
man cannot separate.
-I do.
-I'm asking you, Julia, here in the presence of God,
do you take Bedrich to be your husband?
-I do.
-I'm asking you, Bedrich, here in the presence of God,
do you take Julia to be your wife?
-No.
-You're not too uncomfortable?
One part of my life is finished.
Now I was drinking from
the cup of freedom.
I took the last trinkets
I'd forgotten about.
It's time to say goodbye to
the biggest mistake of my life.
Farewell, may we never meet again.
At this moment my heart
started pounding like mad.
I spotted a girl
who put a spell on me.
Her name was Anezka.
She was a window-dresser.
I fell in love with her immediately.
From that moment I could only think
about how to ask for her hand.
Is it just coincidence, or my destiny?
When I saw her lovingly
touching those limbs,
I knew she could understand
my complicated soul.
She will be a better
wife than Julia.
I didn't know how many obstacles
I'd have to overcome
before we could embrace each other.
I celebrated my freedom
a little bit wildly.
So what, I'll be okay in few days,
and start my new life with Anezka.
But that horror of seeing
Julia next to me again.
It can't be!
This must be a bad dream!
What is going on here?
Huh! Father-in-law is here too!
I hope he doesn't want to return Julia.
Although, he doesn't look like he does.
So, my children.
If I am correct,
you already made up your mind,
-and don't get in my way.
-I'm afraid to say,
-that Mr. Bedrich is right.
-If ma'am was reasonable,
this wouldn't happen.
Father-in-law had no objections.
But disaster struck!
Just at that moment,
mother-in-law was born.
It had been so much better for her.
She was a nice and quiet person.
Every time I see new life begin,
no matter if it is a chickling
or a crocodile I'm happy.
But not this time.
I felt something wicked.
Help!
Over my dead body!
Fortunately I'm still here!
I cannot allow something like this!
Surely not, what are you saying?
I made up my mind,
and I will do what I want.
I'm gonna thwart your plans!
You can be sure!
You'll see who I am!
[speaking backwards]
She had the gift of a gab!
She's not even in school yet.
She'll grow to be a vixen.
Another good reason to get
away from this family.
If not by fair means then...
I'll return Julia by force
and get away.
If one can kidnap,
then one can give back.
It was cunning.
Julia blended in with the geese,
so her parents wouldn't know
she was nearing their house.
Julia had no idea
what was going on.
That dull creature thought
that it was only fun.
She's sound asleep
to the world.
They will be surprised
to find Julia in her bedroom.
It was a great success.
Now I'm free to be
with my beloved.
Hurry up! Anezka's waiting!
But alas!
How could I have anticipated that
they'd send Julia back in no time?
It was like a game of ping pong.
Before I could pack my things,
she was back again.
They were faster than me.
I was desperate.
Oh Bedrich,
we are together again.
That's terrible.
My parents are opposed to our love.
My ex-wife was still
gibbering about love.
They probably talked her down.
Seems there is only one solution.
Mutual settlement.
Our decision is definitive.
I won't budge an inch.
-I have the character for this.
-What an assurance!
Do you know what it means
to our family?
Well, cows, pigs and stuff like that.
Simply the stock, Mr. Councillor.
Bedrich slaughters calves
you know, mother?
That's my interest too. Just like any
good mother I know what is important.
This is nice indeed, but
I want to know something else.
What is your occupation,
Mr. Frydrych?
Memories, but primarily the
grandchildren Mrs. Councillor.
I knew it.
But what does that leave us?
Your daughter.
Julie.
Far from it!
And what it is Mr. Frydrych?
Carpet or something?
Probably some antique, right?
Mr. and Mrs. Councillor,
I have a fervid request.
Our daughter hinted that you
have some kind of request.
Yes, a few drops of rum.
Do you want to pour
something into your tea?
Well, Julinka, propose
something to our guest.
I hope you'll be a friend
of our family forever.
-No way!
-We should make public your deed.
You're a brave man.
Please, come in.
Good evening madam.
Frydrych.
Papa, Mammy,
This is Mr. Bedrich, my rescuer.
Who could it be?
I went to the cabaret.
This one is experimental but my
favourite for their moral efforts.
Girls are dressing up in
warm clothes, set to music.
Sometimes rheumatically.
I was thrilled.
Suddenly I was petrified!
Julie was there again.
I felt like swooning.
My life is desolate
when I know you're not mine.
Are we all supposed
to commit suicide?
Why not? You can start.
Julie, don't you want
to have a serious talk?
I think I could never do that.
I almost succumbed to despair,
but the man on stage
gave me an idea.
Julia must disappear.
I remembered how easily
I got rid of Mr. Birdie.
Ok, one more murder.
There's no other way.
I needed an alibi.
My love, your suicidal tendencies
are tearing my heart apart.
I love you and
would like to persuade you.
Come to the cabaret tonight.
You need to have fun.
Loving Bedrich Frydrych.
But cautiousness made
me destroy this alibi.
I covered all my tracks.
It was time for action.
This place was great,
not a soul around.
It will look like a suicide.
But she fights back,
so I was unable to do it.
Ok.
Wait! Wait!
They had to follow their schedule
and didn't want to go back.
My fault.
Next time I'll be faster.
Julia just turned deaf a little,
but that was all.
My next plan was more canny.
And...
...success!
Julia! Oh my god!
What are you doing?
Don't do it!
She did it.
My second attempt was a failure.
As a hitman I was useless.
Downcast with failure and tormented by
desire I decided to take an action.
I simply moved Anezka
the window-dresser to my place.
She was truly touched
that she could stay.
Seeing her trousseau,
I recalled distant events.
My heart ached.
Why didn't they have this
girl in stock at the time?
Everything would be different.
But what happened next!?
That tiresome Julia was here again.
It was the last straw!
What have you done to me,
Mr. Frydrych?
-I thought that you loved me.
-Out of the question!
-I will finally kick you out!
-You promised me a wedding!
Indeed! Of course!
You allow her to slouch here...
Enough!
My Anezka was simply good.
For all the trouble Julia caused,
she gave her several wiglets.
-I had to call her to order.
-That's enough!
She could give away everything.
-You have another?
-You have another!
Who is this woman, Mr. Frydrych?
What is she doing here?
That gimmer? Bedrich!
Anezka, I told you not to come.
Well! Julia expelled
my lovely Anezka?
I was mad!
I will kill her right now!
With anything at hand.
This is it!
Soon, she will kick the bucket.
And I can run after Anezka
screaming: come back!
The urge to stab her
throat was strong.
Here!
Okay...
Little bit deeper.
Okay!
The bone is in there,
Just to nail it in a little...
Here we go!
Okay...
But wait!
I assure myself via palpation.
The finger is the most delicate instrument.
Finished.
Now, I'll just wait
for her last breath.
That's okay, Mr. Frydrych.
Bonelet maybe.
It's delicious.
That taste!
Wellaway!
She had the lives of a cat.
She could even swallow
a combine harvester.
My mind was possessed with one thought.
What if she's immortal?
You're neat-handed.
You're experienced.
What irony!
Once I was able to assemble great things.
Not these miserable tiddlers.
-What a shame!
-You're not just a fireman.
You're also a cook.
That insult helped me to come up
with fantastic idea,
That doesn't come to mind every day.
Now I was sure that Julia
was finally finished.
When I saw you for the first
time you had it on, Frydrych.
I felt that it was the start of
something beautiful,
-something eternal.
-You were wrong,
-only a few seconds and it'll all be over.
-This ladder is so long.
But in your arms I feel safe.
Nothing can happen to me.
-Well, we will see.
-The damage will be substantial, won't it?
I'm starting to believe that you
were sent to my arms by fate.
Maybe it was the cat.
Someone had to start the fire.
It was horrible!
What if I died in the fire?
-It doesn't matter, miss.
-I owe you my life.
Who are you, brave fireman?
Close your eyes to
avoid getting dizzy.
Oh my god!
It's so high.
Don't be afraid.
The worst is behind you.
Hop!
May your ashes rest in peace, Julca.
Free again, I chased after Anezka.
But when I reach my goal
I was overwhelmingly hesitant.
I knew that I'd be punished for
killing Julia. Jail awaits me.
It was a long goodbye
with my true love.
I was under the conviction
that she'd wait for me.
I spent the next 30 years in prison.
It was tough,
just water and bread...
I survived thanks to
my love of Anezka,
who waited
30 long years for me.
And there was the day
when the gates of prison opened!
Us both with greyish hair,
old man and old woman,
tramping through senility,
babbling sweet nonsense.
Happy at last!