Let me enter. I have come
here today with a request.
Allow me to speak.
Another one?
Will it ever stop?
My liege, what is your bidding?
Where is Omodaka?
He must be present today.
Should I order his
presence, my liege?
No.
It is of no consequence.
Let him in.
You are considering, my liege, receiving
this Ronin (masterless samurai)?
We will listen to
what he has to say.
I was told that you have come to request
use of my premises to commit seppuku?
I come from Geishu in Hiroshima, where I
served my former lord Fukushima Masanori.
My name is Tsukumo Hanshiro.
After the downfall of the clan, I have
been searching elsewhere for a servitude.
But my search remains in vain.
As such we currently live
in times of great peace,
I could only lead a life full
of hardship and poverty.
But I could no longer
bear this shame.
I wish to die as a warrior
by eviscerating myself.
For that reason I am before
you most humbly beseeching:
Allow me to fulfill my wish on the
grounds of your inner courtyard.
I have the highest respect
for your sentiments.
As well as empathy.
I have heard that Fukushima-dono's
subordinates have
always first and foremost ensured
the safety of their lord
before they surrendered the
fortress of Hiroshima to the enemy.
Thereby allowing the secession
to proceed without conflict.
Truly an exemplary
act of a samurai.
You served the Fukushima clan.
Are you acquainted with a young samurai
among the retainers named Chijiiwa Motome?
I do not know him.
He claimed as you do, to have been
once a retainer of the Fukushima clan.
The rice harvest amounted
to 498,200 Koku yearly.
There were only 572 retainers
and their subordinates.
And if the members of their
households were to be included,
an uncountable number including
myself had to wander
around aimlessly after
the loss of their worth.
Indeed.
At the beginning of autumn
he stood before our gates.
Chijiiwa Motome. A samurai warrior.
One who no longer serves a lord.
He came with the same
request as you do now.
Would you like to
hear his story?
That of his fate?
Please proceed, I am listening.
20th of October, Year
11 of KAN'EI (1634)
Please let me enter.
I have come here today
with a request.
Please allow me to
speak with your lord.
Someone has arrived.
Have you all seen him?
How emaciated
and weak he appears before us!
A masterless samurai.
It is of no consequence
wherever he takes his own life! Especially
when it concerns such a rowdy dog.
The bigger the house of the lord in which
a samurai dies, the greater is the honour
accorded to him in death.
- Should we just kill him?
No.
Give him a few coins and send him
away, before it becomes troublesome.
What do you think, Omodaka-dono?
Are you cold? Do you
need anything else?
No.
How old is he?
He appears no more
than twenty, my liege.
He is then younger than you.
This is undoubtedly another ruse,
pretending to request to commit seppuku.
The thought of it
alone angers me
that such an unworthy person has knocked
on our clan's door for such a purpose.
- A ruse?
- Indeed, my liege.
It began with an impoverished
Ronin requesting
permission to enter the
house of Fujishima.
He said, "My life is unbearable.
And I wish to end it."
Allow me to end my wretched life
here and now upon your grounds.
The older samurai at the
gates were so deeply moved
and tried to dissuade
him from his intention.
They introduced him into their ranks,
which then spread like wildfire in town.
As a consequence
Many masterless samurai request audience
at the houses of the great lords.
Some would be employed,
the others would be
pacified with a few coins
at the very least in order
to save their honour.
What a disgraceful undertaking!
Many Ronin now believe that they would
receive some coins if they threatened
to commit seppuku. This man
is another one of them.
- Omodaka.
Do you really believe that
this man is playing a ruse?
Indeed.
We must make an
example out of him.
Thereby deterring any more
from knocking on our door.
He is currently
residing in the house.
It is for this reason that
lyi-dono would grant you audience.
He will meet me personally?
Follow me to the baths.
There you will receive the
attire with which you are
to present yourself with.
Yes.
Come along and observe.
A truly rare event awaits us.
Watch carefully and observe attentively
what you are about to witness.
Yes.
Omodaka-dono.
Here are his swords.
Inspect them carefully.
With those he intended in all
earnesty to commit seppuku.
Put these on.
Thank you.
When you are done,
proceed outside.
Just a moment! Wait!
Is something the matter?
Am I to meet lyi-dono in funeral attire?
- Iyi-dono?
He had to leave the house
suddenly for an urgent matter.
Your desire has been
presented to him.
He is thoroughly convinced
that you could not
be dissuaded from your
honourable decision.
For this reason he asked us
to make all the proper preparations
to fulfill your request.
I implore you.
Allow me some time!
What is the matter?
Are you done?
Everything has been prepared.
You can now commit seppuku.
Just as you have requested.
How do you find it?
What do you think?
What happened afterwards?
My name is Saito Kageyo.
A subordinate of lyi-dono.
This clan has been regarded highly for
the bravery we have shown in battle.
But very few remember today the great
battles of Sekigahara and Osaka.
Most of the men present
here are samurai.
But none of them had once
fought for their own lives.
They have no
experience of battles.
The country is peaceful.
In peaceful times such as these
I am deeply moved
by your request
to commit seppuku on our grounds,
as a great honour to our clan.
Let these young men bear witness
the unique death of a samurai
by committing seppuku.
I have assigned Omodaka
Hikukoro as your second.
Matsusaki Hayatonosho has been
appointed as the observer.
To the side is your
assistant, Kawabe Umanosuke.
I ask you: Are you prepared?
Please allow me another request.
That would be?
Please give me one day.
Just one day. No more.
I will return. You have my word.
- Leave it!
- Such pathetic whimpering!
- Just one day!
I will come back.
You have my word.
Or even a few hours.
- I beg you.
- Spare yourself the trouble.
This house will not tolerate
a ruse feigning seppuku.
I am not feigning.
I swear to you, I
will commit seppuku.
I beg you!
- Just one day!
- How could you even consider it?
Wait.
It is not that simple.
We have mobilised all
our resources in order
to promise you your request
will be fulfilled.
And we have kept our word.
You came to us with
that request yourself.
Just like other clans, our house
keeps strictly to our rules.
A warrior never
changes his mind.
Never.
Have you understood my meaning?
Or perhaps not?
I suggest,
you use your own sword
for this purpose.
A truly impressive
wakizashi (short shord).
Use mine.
- Stop!
- Do not risk it!
I beg you.
Give me three ryo.
I need a physician for
my sick wife and child.
How dare you beg for money?
Have compassion. Just three.
Three ryo.
And thus we hear
your true request.
How shameful.
As a warrior of the
Fukushima clan, I
Chijiwa Motome,
am committing hara-kiri
and leaving this world.
Stab it and turn it to the side.
Do what I say.
Omodaka.
Second.
Turn it around, you coward.
- Do it!
- Turn it to the side!
More. Go on.
Come, turn it around!
A truly sad story
you have told me.
Sad?
And?
Have you changed your mind?
Do you truly believe
that no one would find out?
Disappear. Go.
I would in no way
do such a thing.
A warrior never
changes his mind.
On the contrary. I
will honourably
commit seppuku.
Then so be it.
You should know
what you are doing.
- You would need a new attire.
- No!
That which I now wear
on my back is beffiting
for the last days of
an impoverished Ronin.
A last word:
You have accorded
me great respect.
And I do not know how I could show
my gratitude for such great honour.
Allow me if possible to
express a final request.
I grant it to you. Speak.
My deepest gratitude.
I would like as my second
Omodaka Hikokuro. That is all.
Omodaka?
His reputation precedes him.
He is considered one of the bravest
retainers in the house of lyi.
Indeed.
He is indispensible.
Hikokuro!
Tell me, where is he?
I have not seen him. He has
taken leave of absence.
You heard him. Omodaka
is absent today.
Ono will be your second. He too
possesses extraordinary skills.
No. My last wish
shall not be denied.
No.
Bring him here.
I thank you, my liege.
- He did not return last evening?
- Indeed.
Go and search for him.
I hope he can justify his absence.
Otherwise
there would be heavy
consequences to deal with.
As you wish.
- Say, there are more samurai missing?
- Indeed, sir.
And I am told of it only now?
And?
Where is Omodaka-dono?
What is not, is not.
In the case of
Omodaka-dono's absence,
I thereby request instead
Matsusaki Hayato or
Kawabe Umanosuke as my second.
Both of them are also indisposed.
My men are searching for them.
How is that possible?
I do not understand.
That has never happened before. None
of the three returned last evening.
Feind!
What have you to do with it?
Wait.
I beg you. Please compose
yourself for a moment.
For I would like to
tell you something.
Something that you have to know.
Indeed, lend me your ears.
Afterwards you may tear me
into pieces as you wish.
Step back!
Speak.
I will.
Chijiiwa Motome, who came to you two
months ago, is of some acquaintance to me.
We stood close together in
reality, as you and I do now.
Chijiwa Motome
was of some acquaintance to me.
June, Year 3 of GENNA (1617).
Father?
I have to go back to the castle.
Father.
Miho.
Don't be afraid. Will you
wait for me here alone?
A short break! Rest a while!
Chijiiwa-dono.
How far along are you with the repairs?
The outer wall can wait.
Most important is that the inner
portion is finally finished.
I agree
but without the permission of the
Shogunate my hands are regrettably bound.
We have already submitted it six
months ago to the Shogunate.
Be patient. Until then,
just continue as you have.
For a few repairs
the Shogun would surely
allocate nothing.
And if so, what then? We could
not possibly take such a risk.
If we break the bushido code,
our clan will be dissolved.
That will not happen. Begin at least
with the works at the citadel.
No. We have to wait
first for the permit.
We know that!
But it is our duty to guard the fortress.
- But
- Go to work, all of you.
- As you wish!
Chijiiwa-dono. What is wrong?
Say something!
Shouldn't you be resting in bed?
It is a crime to be lying
in bed on such a nice day.
Welcome.
What a huge melon!
Compared to yours my sword
is a mere piece of iron.
Where did you acquire
such a masterpiece?
It is a gift from our lord.
He has bestowed it to me after
the Battle of Sekigahara.
Allow me a question.
I am slightly concerned.
The Shogun has yet to give us his
permission for the castle reparations.
I find it very suspicious.
Could it be a conspiracy?
One to destroy the clans
which were once enemies?
We have allied ourselves
with him rather late.
Hanshiro.
Please don't say such a thing.
Surely, that could be
something true indeed.
But what use is it to be
worrying about such things?
Enjoy the finest
pleasures in life.
Jinnai-dono.
She looks more and more
like your late wife.
Admit it. She is more important
to you than your own life.
If one considers that we can't do anything
else in life outside of the battlefield,
and that we have
both lost our wives,
we haven't done wrong with
bringing up our children, have we?
Motome has grown up
to be a stately lad.
Only, unlike myself he seems
to prefer reading and writing.
"The works on the fortress which
have begun without my permission"
are considered to
be a crime against
the code of the Samurai and
thereby deemed illegitimate.
For this reason I have
decreed with the threat of
strict punishment, June,
Year 5 of GENNA (1619)
the aforementioned construction
to be removed from site
and the entire fortress down to the inner
citadel to be destroyed immediately.
Disregard of my clear instructions
and thereby insubordination
are an intolerable provocation as well
as an unforgivable insult to my person
and would therefore require
the gravest of consequences.
Each of you are to immediately
vacate the premises
and make way towards Tsugaru.
"This is an order which every single one
of you must obey. The Shogun, EDO."
I am not worthy to be in
charge of construction.
I should have gone to the
Shogun to commit seppuku
So that the destruction
of the fortress and the
dissolution of our clan
could be prevented.
The Shogun promotes and disposes
of men, just as he pleases.
Not once did his
advisers contradict him.
What a shame.
Don't close your eyes.
Hanshiro
Rest assured.
If it comes to worst, I will
take your son under my care.
Just like if he were my own.
Hanshiro.
Please forgive me.
Do not say such things.
Please open the door.
I'd like to see the fortress.
How beautiful and stately it is.
Indeed.
EDO, June, Year 6
of GENNA (1620)
It is just like with studies.
Or with swordfighting. When one
works hard everyday, he
would sure make progress.
You two must not worry.
Aren't you eating, Father?
I have to go out for a while.
Then we will wait for you.
No. Go ahead. I am meeting
with an acquaintance.
Go ahead. As long as it's still warm.
Who knows?
Maybe the food tastes
nice only when warm.
- Thank you for the food.
We have no luck today.
I had hoped that we
would catch a carp.
The books say that carps
are good for weak people.
And especially for weak girls.
Hand it over! Grab the net!
Quick!
We can fry the carp and
give it to Miho-dono!
Good.
What a grand house.
It belongs to Lord lyi. We
have allied ourselves with him
before the Battle of Sekigahara. And then
drove the enemy together towards retreat.
One day I would serve in
such a house, and then
I would be able to repay the kindness
Miho-dono and Tsugumo-dono has shown me.
May, Year 7 of KAN'EI (1630)
He must marry Miho off.
Otherwise he would never
ever get an employment.
Greetings, my child.
- Good day.
You're absolutely right.
He was there again. The director
of merchant-house Koshuya.
Isn't that already
his fifth visit?
But most probably the answer
again this time is "no".
You have to finally get
married, Miho-sama. That
would be greatly advantageous
for your father.
We simple folk understand
nothing about such things.
With Samurai is everything
always complicated. Really.
Please excuse me.
I have returned, Father.
Father
I have made more today
than I have expected.
You have brought over a lot of work.
Don't overdo it.
Father.
Do not concern
yourself over nothing.
Father.
Rice cake.
Would you like a piece?
Go ahead and eat first, Father.
I will eat mine later.
A delicacy loses its
taste when eaten alone.
Thank you, sir. Goodbye, sir.
To confess the truth:
I had been worried
about this thin roof
and I am at a loss at what to do.
- I am greatly honoured by your visit.
Ah, do not be.
I have not seen you in a
long while, Motome-dono.
I am deeply thankful to you
For using this hut for such a purpose.
- I thank you
For all the kindness you
have bestowed upon me.
- Yes, yes.
That is for you alone. I have
already eaten one with Father.
A delicacy loses its
taste when eaten alone.
What? What is so funny?
I shall pour some hot water.
Uncle.
What has led you here?
Thank you.
Since when have you been
collecting stray cats?
Something is bothering
you, Uncle.
Could you perhaps
imagine marrying Miho?
Miho.
Is that possible for you?
I have no employment.
It is not yet possible for
me to take on a wife.
Feelings are all that counts.
What do you feel for Miho?
I will..
For Miho-dono, I will give
up my life to protect her.
- You would?
- Yes!
Upon my word.
Motome. Your words
do you honour.
What counts is only what
your heart tells you.
Understood? Only that matters.
Father!
Give him to me. You are
getting heavier and heavier.
Miho. The food is ready.
I'm coming.
Our gratitude, Father. For
giving us this splendid fish.
It is of no consequence. Forgive me,
that is isn't much bigger. - It is huge!
Don't exaggerate.
Thank you, Father. We do not know,
for which we have earned it.
What's there to know? He
is after all my grandson.
Don't be so formal.
So, Kingo, here we have your
first time eating solid food.
And now open your mouth!
Here.
Open your mouth!
How about some fish, Kingo?
Not for you? Try it.
Kingo!
Now let us eat.
Yes.
- Thank you.
You come later.
I must be gone. I am currently helping
in the temple school of an acquaintance.
Go ahead. And take
care of yourself.
Don't stay too long outside.
What is the matter?
You have always been sickly as a child.
I hope that doesn't get any worse.
Take care of yourself.
Father.
Please do not be concerned.
I am fine and healthy.
Like a fish in water.
Miho.
Stop trying to deceive me. When
you need help, just let me know.
Understood?
Yes.
- That is tantamount to extortion.
- Yes.
Furthermore directly
in front of the house!
How horrible. You are right.
That is improper.
Tsugumo-sama.
What is the matter?
I would not like to keep you.
But are you perhaps acquainted with
the samurai who lives over there?
The young one? Apparently
he had feigned Seppuku.
Feigned Seppuku?
Indeed. It is now in trend. Have
you heard nothing of it? - No.
It would never have occured to
us simple folk in our dreams.
Let alone in real life!
A samurai requests audience
at a lord's house,
asking to use the premises
to commit harakiri.
Even though he had no
intention to at all!
One hopes for charity.
The real trick however is bringing the
lords into a compromising situation.
Miho.
Welcome home.
What happened?
Nothing.
The cat is there again.
It has come home
after a long time.
I see.
It came home to die.
It is lying there as usual.
As if in sleep.
Go in. I will do it.
Miho!
Miho
I am fine.
Could you pay more for that?
They are unfortunately
worth not much more.
Unlike those which you wear on your belt.
I would gladly buy those swords.
How dare you?
Sadly there is nothing
else I can do.
Wait.
Three pieces for you.
Thank you very much.
Fresh eggs!
Fresh eggs! Eggs! Fresh eggs!
- Come get me!
- You'll get it!
Forgive me.
You need not apologize. Rest.
That was not necessary.
You need not worry.
Take your medicine.
And eat something. That
would do you good.
Lie down.
I will bring you to a physician.
He would make you healthy again.
A physician? We definitely would
not be able to afford one.
I am but a burden to you.
Please forgive me.
It is a man's duty to provide
for his wife and child.
Do you understand?
You and I, we're two
halves of a whole.
Do not concern yourself
with unnecessary matters.
Everything will be better.
Believe me.
Try to sleep.
"Pawnshop"
Thank you.
That would be 50 Mon.
I am feeling much better today.
You have to take it easy.
Father.
How ever could I thank you?
You need not thank me, Miho. Rest.
Understand? Sleep a little.
Please take care of yourself, Father.
Living alone as you are.
Do not worry about me.
Please forgive me, for
giving you so much trouble.
Father.
Motome.
Forgive me.
What for?
- What do you speak of, Father?
- Motome.
Forgive me.
I could not do anything.
Miho will get better.
I am convinced of it.
Yes.
Indeed, she will. You are right.
Motome.
I will do everything
in my power.
The fever has not
subsided for three days.
He is very hot. We must
fetch a physician.
I have already gone to him. But
he demands three Ryo in advance.
Three Ryo?
Three Ryo.
Motome.
How do we get our hands
on so much money?
Father.
Would you please stay here and take
care of Miho and Kingo for me?
Leave everything to me.
What do you have in mind?
Rest assured. I will be
back in the afternoon.
Be in haste. We must not
lose too much time.
Yes.
Kingo.
Hang in there.
You must not give up.
Miho!
Kingo.
Are you hungry? Come!
Drink.
Kingo.
- Why would you not drink?
- Miho.
- Kingo.
- Stop this instant.
Leave him.
Miho.
Stop, Miho!
Your breastmilk will
only be detrimental to
him at your current state.
Set him down.
Miho!
Put him back down!
Why is Motome taking so long? He
should have been back by now.
Are you all right?
Kingo.
Wait.
Drink.
Drink up, Kingo!
You are the son of a samurai.
Drink!
Come.
I beg you.
Drink something.
Miho?
Miho
Come.
Miho.
Lie down.
Why is Motome not back yet?
Kingo!
Hang on! Kingo. Open your eyes! Kingo.
Come on, wake up! Wake up! Kingo. Wake up!
Kingo!
- Kingo!
Lie down.
Do you hear, Kingo? Open your eyes!
Wake up!
- Open your eyes, Kingo.
- Kingo!
Kingo!
Wake up. I beg you. Open your eyes.
Please!
Kingo!
Stop, Father!
Forgive me. I hope
it didn't hurt.
Forgive me.
Father.
It is my fault.
- Forgive me, Father!
- It is no fault of yours!
- Forgive me, Father.
- Miho! It is not your fault.
- No one is blaming you!
- Forgive me, Father.
- No one!
No one is blaming you!
Is it Motome?
Motome is back.
Is this the residence of
Chijiiwa Motome-dono?
Forgive us, sir. We are
servants from the house of lyi.
Chijiiwa-dono asked for
permission to enter our
gates this morning, in
order to commit seppuku.
We have given him our inner
courtyard for his purpose.
Seppuku?
Please take this as condolence.
We must go. Our task is done.
Wait.
Wait!
Wait! Please wait!
Tell me quickly, how
Motome passed away!
- He committed Seppuku.
- He would never do that!
Our only duty is
to return your his corpse.
- I believe none of it!
Tell me the truth!
- Tell me what happened!
- It has been decided in our house
that feigned seppuku will
no longer be tolerated.
Feigned?
Wait! Please wait!
Stay!
At first we thought our
superiors would prohibit it.
Tell me everything. I want
to know how Motome died.
Forgive me. I know nothing.
Tell me!
Here, eat.
It's delicious.
Motome pawned his sword
in order to save the
lives of his family.
My sword is for me the
most revered object.
I would never give it to anyone.
The life of a samurai
depends exceptionally
on the unforeseeable
changes of destiny.
That which either bring him
to fame or towards downfall.
It is simply that way.
Motome could have very
well been one of you.
And one of you could have very well
suffered his very same tragic fate.
But even though he found himself
in such a difficult situation,
and that it is undoubtedly reprehensible
and unforgiveable to feign seppuku
in order to take
advantage from it,
The request to commit Hara-kiri
with a bamboo sword is mocked
while your house is praised for
hosting such a ritualistic suicide.
No one here understands with what courage
he drove that bamboo sword into his flesh,
in order to bring attention to the agony
eating away at him and his family.
I empathize with your pain.
He could not be dissuaded.
Despite every objection he
insisted on committing hara-kiri.
Therefore we provided him our
inner courtyard for his purpose.
It was his mistake to think that he would
not have to act on his words till the end.
A warrior must kill himself
once he has committed
his word to it.
According to the code, indeed.
But had you no
sympathy for a man
who in his desperation stooped
so low as to come to you
and beg for charity for
his sick wife and child?
Were you so indifferent
to this man's fate?
Is there no one among the
warriors here present
who has enough
compassion in themselves
to put themselves in
Motome's position?
Has your stable employment in this
lord's house made all of you blind?
We have accorded him all the
respect a warrior deserves.
You speak of compassion? He
would not be discouraged.
Is a warrior also not a man with
blood flowing through his veins?
Tsugumo-dono.
We have been forced to teach
a lesson to deter others.
And he was the unfortunate one.
Every man has his honour. And a
man without honour is no one.
When he lacks the heart
& courage to keep
his honour, he has lost
his worth as a man.
Yes, indeed.
Each of our warriors
have such a heart.
You claim that none of
your men fears death?
Just because they as
samurai possess honour?
And that they would sacrifice their
life to maintain this honour?
It is as you say.
Tsugumo-dono.
There is nothing
left to be said.
The three of them have
not been sighted since
they left their quarters last evening.
There are no traces of them.
- You have yet to find them?
- Indeed, sir.
- Go and search further.
- As you wish.
What has happened to my men?
Take these back.
It is of no worth
to me any more.
I have something else. Something
which would like you to have.
Matsusaki Hayatonosho's topknot.
Kawabe Umanosuke's topknot.
And Omodaka Hikokuro's topknot.
You could return these,
if you so desire,
to the missing men.
Without their topknots
your three warriors
fear treading outside, where
people could see them.
The head is still intact.
But the face has been lost.
Who are you?
Who are you? State your name!
Chijiiwa Motome. Does that
mean anything to you?
They are ashamed that
instead of their lives
only their topknots have
been taken from them.
Since then they have
hidden themselves from
the world and dare not
leave their hole.
You spoke of honour. What of it?
Of a samurai's honour?
As all of you could see,
that honour you speak of is
nothing at all. Meaningless!
Nothing but a farce!
Your honour is but a farce.
Kill him.
Whoever speaks of
honour should know
that it is not something that
a samurai puts on the line.
- Silence!
Have you lost your mind?
Do you really believe
that I have lost my mind?
I have only lived
every year waiting for spring.
You bastard!
Father!
Get inside!
We have found them!
We have restored everything
to its proper place.
Just as you have ordered.
Has it been thoroughly polished?
Indeed.
The red armour
is the pride of our noble house.
SubText: NoRMITA.326