Fairytales are usually
crystal clear.
lt's impossible to love
and not love someone...
...at the same time.
You have to take a stand.
But l know.
l felt that with Nadia.
l felt it every day, it was
much stronger than me.
Maybe our fairytale
was expired.
Nadia landed in a place
we considered our own.
lt wasn't a plain cafeteria.
lt was our home.
Our boss had gathered us
here from newspaper ads...
...but he was so much more
than an employer.
-How was it?
-Fine.
-Did it hurt?
-No.
-Here's 30.
-You said 45.
-He wasn't satisfied though.
-You promised 45.
Look, he was a low income
customer. Yellow.
lt was hard to push him-
and you had to be tested.
lf you do well in the
future, as l know you will...
...you'll get better johns
and make more money.
Your cut is 50%.
-l don't have where to stay.
-Come again?
Can you give me some extra?
l'll pay you back tomorrow.
l never pay in advance.
lf you want, l can give you
another job for tonight.
l've three on hold. Green.
Stay the night with them...
...then l can get you a
hotel room. Deal?
Make up your mind, l also
have Martha to take care of.
l treat you better 'cause
you're new - an investment.
Martha is anything but.
Soon, l'll have to pay
for them to fuck her.
-How much?
-1 00. All night, their place.
l'll take you.
Martha! Prove me wrong!
-How was l?
-Good. No surprises.
l want you to tell me
how good l was!
Sorry, not really up for
a chat right now.
The boss always told me:
Martha, never be pushy!
But l didn't understand.
l really wanted to be good.
And l was sick of Zois
escorting me to the jobs.
l wanted the boss to
take me, just like Nadia.
But she was 1 6 and a beauty.
At 1 7, l was feeling old.
l was sure her clients were
getting more pleasure...
...were begging her
to stay more.
All of us had followed up
an ad for a part time job.
Greeks only. The boss
insisted on our nationality.
And he understood our needs.
He had Zois to protect us...
...and the Whistler to provide
us with any drug we wanted.
Nadia was not like us.
ln the beginning,
she never spoke to anyone.
Unlike us, she just came,
picked up the post-its...
with client info and took off.
l don't know where she went.
Even the boss had realized
she was a special breed...
...and treated her
differently.
His great passion were
the fucking post-its...
...but he had a soft
spot for Nadia.
Over here, when you complete
1 00 post-its we've a ritual.
Come, l'll take you.
This really annoyed me.
But l knew the Whistler
was on his way.
Miltos was more eager
to see him than me.
The Whistler had
a strange habit.
He only spoke
through horoscopes.
Today is a lucky day
for Capricorn.
Dare risky investments, but
beware of your love life.
No way. l go with no one
more than three times!
-But he pays double!
-l don't care!
l can't stand softies!
They get obsessed,
specially the limp ones.
You can't trust them.
Am l right?
l've no problem. lf l picked
them, l'd be out of work.
How would l make a living?
That's why you do it,
to make a living?
What else?
For a hobby?
-Maybe for fun.
-Nice thinking.
Argyris was gorgeous.
Super-sought after.
He wasn't smart, but he got
more than any of us.
His clients, of course, are
much more sensitive.
He gave you a bonus.
For me.
Maybe you like what you do.
You never know. Time'll tell.
Time? All l want
is to make a living.
l think you might
be a plain slut.
You sit here all day,
worshipping an asshole...
-...who acts like your daddy.
-What about you?
l'm not here to stay.
lt's just a stage.
l couldn't accept my defeat.
l had to find someone too.
And our job's misunderstood.
They either put it in the
news with a violin score...
...or they think it's the
easiest job in the world.
But fucking 3-4 guys a day
really wears you down.
You can't date a stranger.
He'll never understand.
So, we started
dating each other.
Like a Beverly Hills
TV episode.
We felt like accomplices.
We had a common secret.
Nadia kept staring at me.
She knew l was jealous.
And even though Argyris was
madly in love with her...
...she started taking
a greater interest in me.
''Presentation of new model
high-security door.''
Most of them are from out of
town and out of their ease.
Give them small talk...
...show interest in their
work, don't force it!
What do you wanna be
when you grow up?
-Astronaut?
-Knock it off!
-Policeman?
-l'm serious.
-Hairdresser.
-Really?
-l'm not sure.
-That's ok. l'll be famous.
-How?
-Can't tell you.
Follow me.
-Why did you do that?
-Solidarity. Let's go peep!
-Why are you doing this?
-l need an ally.
The others are chickens.
They don't get it.
-What about Argyris?
-Argyris won't make it.
And you need someone
to take care of you.
You're losing it!
-Nadia, l'm older than you.
-So what?
She was soft.
l really liked that.
For the first time,
it felt like fluffy clouds.
You get laid to buy cds?
Now that's twisted!
-What's this?
-Past glories.
Let's play shrink, since
you're so bloody restless!
-Truth or dare?
-Truth.
l want to know...
how you left your home.
Are you sure
you want to know?
Promise you won't
get scared of me.
l couldn't stand my parents.
And they weren't even mean.
Just incredibly boring.
My mom especially,
deserved instant death.
One day l set
the house on fire...
...opened the door and left.
What do you mean
set the house on fire?
Matches, alcohol,
the works!
-And your parents?
-They were sleeping.
l think they are ok.
They never made the
news, anyway!
You're mad!
You promised you
wouldn't be scared!
l then dyed my hair
and looked for a job.
How did you leave?
Come on!
l didn't exactly leave. l've
lied that l'm in university.
-Where?
-Alexandroupoli.
lt's the farthest away
l could think of.
-What if they bump into you?
-They won't. They don't care.
l had thought of
burning my house too!
Martha... you truly
disappoint me!
Why don't you
fuck me right here?
Right before the boss, so
he might finally get it up!
No, not here.
Are you daft, or have
all the people who...
...fuck you made you
officially gay?
Piss off! l don't enjoy it,
l just get paid.
lf l enjoyed it, like some
others do, then l'd be gay.
-So why don't we fuck?
-Don't want to.
You're gay!
l'll super-educate you!
-Would they ever accept us?
-lf you pay, you get in.
Simple as that?
We're planning to take off
and study abroad!
Lovely!
And then we'll come back,
buy your place and fuck you!
l'll get a plastic dildo,
much bigger than yours!
lt's made of rubber...
So, since you have
such high aspirations...
...l'll tell you about mine.
Today, l'm introducing
a new range of appointments.
Purple!
They're double the reds.
For you and for me!
There's a party at a
fancy house tonight.
And the chosen ones are...
You, Martha!
And you...
Nadia!
Leave it,
l'll get it later!
Ten sharp!
Take this and
go buy something fancy.
And don't be late.
Good morning.
l came for the ad.
Today,
Mercury enters Libra.
Be calm and patient,
specially in family matters.
Argyris is saving money
to take her abroad.
Abroad my ass.
Nobody is going abroad.
You're always broke,
you definitely won't!
That's ok. You're purple.
You'll take care of us.
What's wrong,
are you feeling ignored?
Are you in love?
l want us to have a
relationship...
...like real people.
Do we have anything in
common with real people?
-l do.
-l don't.
Don't you want to have
a family?
Good luck tonight.
Good evening.
Goodbye.
Here's our new baby.
Marvel at your new baby.
Adopt me and l'll sing!
You want me
to fuck your husband?
Will you watch,
or do something?
Nadia is jealous.
Nadia loves me.
Nadia is right.
l'm a slut.
And l like, really like
to get paid and fucked.
Martha tonight
has a new id:
Name: Slut, Address: Slut
Religion: Slut.
She's in a great mood,
she's gonna make you proud.
Give you
the best party ever!
Nadia go fuck yourself!
l'm not going anywhere.
lt's not a stage.
This is where l want to be!
l'm sorry, l don't know
what got over me.
You nuts? You were great!
Blew them away!
We're so much alike,
you and l!
-But l fucked up.
-Don't worry, we'll avenge!
l have a proposition to make.
l rented an apartment.
Want to live with me?
We'll pay half rent and
live together, like family!
Want to?
Please say yes.
lt really means much to me!
-Yes.
-Yes?
When l'm very happy, l have
a hard time showing it.
My throat dries up and
my ears whistle.
l wanted to start jumping up
and down and show my joy...
...but l stayed put,
like an idiot.
l don't think
she minded though.
You need to have doubts
in order to mind.
We want our money.
For last night.
The boss wants
to speak to you.
l heard you
messed up the party.
-Where is he?
-At the hotel. Training day.
Training day is laying
the path for others.
We had all gone through it,
except Nadia.
The boss had a room
specially for that...
...and to entertain friends
in special occasions.
He often called up on me.
One day, 5 guys gang-banged
me in that room.
-What's up? Going on a trip?
-l'm moving, maybe...
We want our money
for last night.
After what happened,
you're asking for money?
-You fucked up big time last night.
-Bullshit!
l talked with the client.
l said it's good to talk,
but there's a limit.
These people aren't
interested in your problems.
Do you have any suggestions?
-For free.
-Come again?
We'll work. For free.
Hear that Nadia?
Do you have any other ideas?
Now leave.
We'll discuss this later.
Calm down. Drop it.
Let's go home.
We need to go on vacation.
Charge our batteries
before things get rougher.
-Vacation? We just moved in.
-So? Don't you want to?
Rougher?
Will it get rougher?
What do you think?
Are you happy?
-Yes.
-l'm not.
We need to speed things up.
lt's your fault, right?
We must go slowly now.
Start from the top.
l think you are special,
l want to treat you special.
But l need to trust you.
When l help you, you
must help me. Am l wrong?
Sorry for not helping much.
Not a good month for me.
That's ok.
Nice house. But l
expected it cozier.
What's up Miltos?
How come?
Shit, what drugs
are you on?
What's this?
A gift from a client.
Who cares for me.
Nice client.
Give it to me.
Why did you move in with her
and not with me?
Don't you like me?
-l'm just a little tired.
-We can fix that.
Bloody hell!
She threw me out!
Keep going,
don't let me stop you.
Don't let this happen again.
You've worked for one year.
You were bound to have
some accident.
-lt's not from work.
-Then what?
Maybe it is a client.
l'm not sure.
Tell me. What happened?
-Argyris. He got crazy.
-How crazy?
Remember when they came with
Miltos, totally fucked up?
Argyris wanted action,
l didn't.
He gave me a line, then
opened my legs...
...and plastered me with coke.
He wanted to snort it
from down there.
-What?
-He really fucked me up.
l fucked up. l'm sorry.
Come on. Let's play.
-Will you teach me?
-Let's go shoot some cats.
What's this nightie?
You look like a prostitute!
Thanks. l can't believe
you're all fine with him!
Give the prick a lesson!
Don't worry, l know what
l'm doing.
-Sure, you always know.
-Be patient.
We're going on vacation soon.
-You fucked up big time.
-Yes, but l said l'm sorry.
l don't care.
Yes, but what on earth
do you want me to do?
-Make me laugh.
-What?
-Fuck!
Ok, so be it.
Do you believe in Superman?
-No.
-You just lost a friend.
You liked that...
Peace?
Listen, l don't want you to
worry about a thing.
Everything will be fine.
Three more jobs
and we're off!
-Can you work?
-l'm fine.
Today l'm breaking my rules.
l'm going with a softy.
And it's a double offense.
This will be the fifth time.
-How come, are you in love?
-You don't get it, do you?
lt's a secret gig. He's an
accountant at a magazine.
And he gives me 1 00 a night.
He's obsessed with me!
Aren't you scared the boss
might find out?
l can't put in words
the way l feel about you.
l really want to help. Tell
me, what can l do for you?
Our vacation was calm,
in absolute silence.
That was the plan, we didn't
let anyone come with us.
Nadia picked a totally
deserted beach.
We spoke to no one,
not even each other.
Silence was a gift.
She only broke up one time.
Soon l won't be able
to picture myself...
...doing anything beautiful.
Nothing that will interest
anybody.
And that's not fair, Martha.
We'll grow old,
we'll keep getting screwed...
...and no one will know.
Or care. People should care!
l need you to promise that
you'll stand by me...
-...no matter what.
-l promise.
l'm looking for Nadia.
Can you help me?
Her mobile's out of service.
Can you please help me?
Come to think of it...
...l wish this silence
had lasted longer.
As soon as we got back,
the boss awaited us...
...with brand new post-its.
Purple! lris Hotel, room 121 .
Nadia, though,
didn't look too impressed.
l was eager to see Miltos.
l'd missed him...
...especially when l saw
Nadia drooling with Argyris.
But she was right once more.
Miltos couldn't take it.
l'm not sure if she just
wanted to get back at him...
...or had realized that he
was pissed off and had...
...set us up with Zois.
But Nadia knew what she
was doing. Always.
Do something!
Come on!
Please!
Go and get changed.
We'll meet you later.
And throw away your
clothes.
Let's forget it.
Play happy family.
You don't have
to say anything.
Don't be afraid,
no one can harm you.
Anyway you didn't
do anything wrong.
You just watched,
because Argyris forced you.
Did you do anything wrong?
No.
Neither did l, right?
What?
Argyris did it all.
No you didn't. He did.
-Truth or dare?
-Truth.
But l want to tell you
something by myself.
Miltos and l rarely had sex.
Neither of us really cared.
One day, he showed up
out of his head...
...and wanted to fuck me
on the kitchen table.
-So? Big deal!
-We weren't alone.
-Where was l?
-ln your room.
Fine, who was
the third party?
He told me that he found me
very sexy, that he would...
...prefer to be fucking me
and not him.
Ok, fine, who was it?
Forget it, let's say he was
a stranger.
Which means he's not.
Who was it?
They were really fucked up.
There was nothing l could do.
''You won't believe it...
...but l really wanted
to come with you.''
l want you to go out.
We need to be alone tonight.
-What?
-Please.
-l'm flying!
-Where?
High above.
l can see God!
-What's he doing?
-Laughing at us.
Put your hands down, man.
This ain't no TV series!
1 -2-3, 1 -2-3. Best is worst.
Nadia and l are going
to make a family.
God is coming down
and l'll stop thinking...
...like Nadia, l've stopped
thinking, 3-4-5, 3-4-5...
...l don't want to know,
someone else should know.
Best is worst,
we deserve the best...
...we'll be fine, we deserve
the best, we'll be fine.
Nadia surrendered like
the ultimate victim.
They held her for a while
but she had everything.
She was lost, beautiful,
under-aged...
...and had mr. Softy
who really loved her.
ln the beginning,
l didn't understand why...
...she asked me
to give him her old photos.
Then l remembered that he
worked in a magazine.
And the magazine's publisher
was interested in Nadia too.
And he knew well how to
cut and paste.
So, Nadia became
the face of the month.
lf it wasn't for her,
l'd be lost...
...like everyone else.
And she was so pretty...
...that girls wanted
to look like her...
...and boys masturbated
at her pictures.
Sure enough, the Perfect Man
would soon come for her.
Juvenile tragedy
Know them?
Do you have to watch this
every day?
They could do me no harm.
They had no proof.
l told them what Nadia
told me to.
l didn't do it for her,
l did it for me.
l didn't want any trouble.
-Know him?
-Yes, it's Argyris.
Why was Nadia with him
at the murders?
She was his girlfriend.
She just watched.
He forced her.
-Why?
-l don't know.
Turned him on probably.
He wasn't well...
He did drugs, you know.
-And this?
-lt's fake.
l don't know where they found
the old photos.
We've always been victims.
They're taking advantage
of us, even now!
How do you feel
after your acquittal?
-Fine.
-Just fine?
We were victims. Now we
must move on with our lives.
Can l have some water?
You don't really like me,
do you?
You've been getting fucked,
for what, 3 years?
l've been for 13!
You should try and relax!
-l'm getting a job today!
-What?
-On TV!
-What kind of a job?
l'm gonna ask
for a music show.
l already know so much,
and what l don't, l'll learn.
Think the others
are better?
-l don't know.
-l do. They suck.
You promised things
would change.
You're doing the same shit
all over again.
l disagree.
Nadia had sky-rocketed and l
was left guarding the house...
...and reading her letters.
Sometimes, l was convinced
l had turned invisible.
You can select songs
and make dedications.
l need us to have
an open line between us.
l want you to write in,
specially those...
who've suffered like l have.
Together, we can change
something.
The best letters and
e-mails will be read on air...
...only if you want me to.
Nadia carefully observed
the pyramid of her new job.
Above every publisher,
there's a bigger publisher.
Nadia found him, easily.
l didn't want her to
bring them home...
...no matter how important
they were.
l was convinced that we'd be
together. We'd be happy.
But he seemed to know how
to realize her dreams.
-Did you like my TV show?
-Yes.
-Just yes? No comments?
-You were fine. As always.
Sounds like
you're sick of me.
lt's hot. Why don't you
take off your shirt?
-What?
-l want to see your breasts.
-You're mad.
-Maybe. Do it!
-You're gonna get us killed!
-l don't care. Do it.
See? lt was that simple.
Was it worth dying for?
-Why don't you come in?
-Don't want to.
-She may be back in a while.
Just tell her l came by.
She didn't betray you.
She's different from us.
Don't try to understand.
Nice, isn't it?
Do you still like me?
Of course.
So why do you cheat on me?
Think it's the right time
to make a scene?
Everyone thinks
we're a couple.
We live in the same house,
we share almost everything.
What do you think?
Screw everyone else.
-No.
-No what?
l don't think
we're a couple.
Exactly. We're much
more than a couple.
Others can never understand.
Please get a job, leave the
house, you're going crazy.
l don't want no job.
l know no job.
Whatever.
Will you leave us now?
l helped you.
Didn't l?
Can you please
pass the butter?
Thank you.
Babe, are we
going on vacation?
Yes babe, but not tomorrow,
l have work. ln a few days.
-Where are you going?
-Rome.
-Rome?
-Can we come too?
No, l thought you could
keep the children.
Can you keep the children?
-Let's all go together!
-Why can't we come?
Sorry guys,
l'm going with my babe.
Come on. lt will be great!
Fine, can we go
somewhere too?
Don't you want
to have a family?
No. l have you.
-A child?
-No.
-Never?
lf you did, who would you
have it with?
-Nobody, l guess.
-With Argyris?
With no one. What's wrong
with you? Getting old?
-What are you doing?
-Nothing.
l'm dead. Christmas show's
in a week.
Will you come?
lt'll be nothing special.
Nothing special?
lt's your dream, no?
Yes.
Do you love me?
Are you happy?
So came Christmas.
Season of Love.
But l didn't know how
much love l had left.
And Nadia was getting more
and more distant.
Maybe l was to blame too.
l need to go
to the bathroom.
The New Year is ambiguous
for Water Signs.
Friends will hurt you,
professional doors close...
...but you'll find a new,
much clearer balance.
What the hell do you think
you're doing?
Didn't you like it?
l thought they liked me.
l just don't think they'll
call me again.
Let's go live in a farm.
Or on an island,
open a salon.
That's what you want,
isn't it?
l need an ally.
The others are chickens.
They don't get it.
Martha won't make it.
And you need someone...
...to take care of you.
You're losing it!
But l need you to promise
you'll stand by me.
No matter what.
Nadia asked me to call you.
She'll be home soon. Come in.
l think we need
to go find her.
ls it possible
to love someone...
...and not love them
at the same time?
People think it isn't,
but l know better.
-Where are we going?
-To the sea.