Subtitles created by sijuvrm.
Edited by joeshmoe.
Dominic Toretto,
You are hereby sentenced
to serve 25 years to life.
At the Lompoc maximum
security prison system.
Without the possibility of early parole.
This is all the aftermath.
Of a daring daylight breakout.
There were 26 high risk inmates.
Every one on board has been
accounted for.
Except for one - Dominic Toretto.
Police released the identity of the man they
believe orchestrated the shocking escape.
That amazingly resulted in no
fatalities this afternoon.
He is former federal agent
Brian O'Conner.
A fierce manhunt is
underway for three fugitives tonight.
Multiple federal and local agencies
have joined forces.
In the search for - Dominic Toretto and his
accomplishes Brian O'Conner and Mia Toretto.
Despite every eye in the country
looking for them.
Where Toretto and O'Conner are now
is any ones guess.
Let's get out of here.
Mia...
Buster....
Dom here yet.
No.
- When was the last time you heard from him?
A couple of weeks ago, up
in ecuador somewhere.
- How does it feel ?
- Whats that?
To be on the other side of a
wanted poster.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
Time for bed little one.
Can I bring him?
Of course.
Excuse me, sorry.
Why Rio Vince?
You mean after you screwed
everything up in LA?
Ended up free fallin thru
South America you know....
Hittin every hell hole on the
way down
Would have kept on going
if not for Rosa...
Does he know ?
So...listen.
There's a job coming up
I was hoping Dom was gonna
be here by now, but...
This one's clean enough,
we can do it without him.
Its a good gig.
Couple of high end cars, easy targets.
A guy I know is putting together
a team to swipe em.
Just need a few more willing bodies.
Bud, I don't know.
Look, the way car seem is down here, we
can unload them quick and get top dollar.
Its easy money.
From where I am sittin,
It looks like you both
could use the pay day.
What are you reading?
- Travel guide.
- Yeah?
Tokyo.
Moscow
Goa
You know what all of these
places have in common.
No?
No extradition.
Here we go.
Excuse me, buddy.
Ok, we found em.
Yeah, second to the last raider.
What, what is it?
DEA tags. This car is seized.
Look, who showed up.
Oh! GOD, I'm so happy you're ok.
- I thought I told you to lay low.
- We were running on fumes.
Had to make a call.
Hey quit talking, we only
got a two minute window.
Lets go, Vince.
Ladies first.
See you baby.
Change of plans,
wait for my call.
Lets go.
Where is she going?
We are being robbed.
Go stop the train.
Access card, get the access card.
There's a bridge.
Luggage car is clear.
??
Freeze.
You had to make the call, huh.
Shitty call, O'Conner.
Shitty call.
You two stirred up quite a
bit of trouble today.
Three of my men dead.
Three dea agents, along with.
Of course, this is business.
Sometimes things go astray.
All I care about is the car.
Tell me where it is.
And I'll let you go
*** full of shit
I don't know how you guys do business
in your part of the world.
But here in Rio... I like it when all
parties know what they're up against.
That's funny, cause it goes both ways.
You know...
I hear your sister is
very beautiful.
Wherever she hides, I will find her.
Mia?
Hey ..
- You ok?
- Yeah, you alright?
Yeah, just like a toretto.
Where's Vince?
That's a good question.
He'll be here.
Guys, we are all over the news, they're blaming
us for killing those DEA agents on the train.
Which means we just jumped to the
top of the wanted list.
The feds have got to show
their agents are off the limits.
They are gonna send their best guys,
we gotta get out of here.
One thing we know for sure.
Is that they wanted this car.
- Something's in it.
- We find out what it is,
we'll know what we're up against.
Alright, listen up. The men we're after are professional runners.
They like speed and guarantee to go down the hardest possible way.
So make sure you got the thunderware on.
We find them, we take them as a team and we bring them back.
And above all else, we don't ever, ever let
them get into cars.
The crime scene's 10 hours
old and counting men. Lets go hunting.
Agent Hobbs? Chief of police.
Sorry to hear for loss of your men.
Is all this really necessary
to apprehend two men?
Let me tell you little something about these two men.
One's a former federal officer, been in deep cover for 5 years.
Knows every way we're gonna come for him.
The other one's a professional criminal, escaped prison twice,
Spent half his life on run
avoiding folks like you.
Well, if there's anything
we can do to help...
Two things.
One - I need a translator.
Alright, We have plenty...
- Elena Neves.
- A patrol officer?
You heard me.
But why? We have many more
experienced people.
I like her smile.
What's the second thing.
Stay the fuck out of my way!
Brian.
There's something I have to tell you.
Goddamn.
What a mess.
Where you have been Vin.
You better check that tone.
- You better answer the goddam question.
- Stop it, both of you.
Where were you Vince.
Guys are all over the favelas
asking about you.
Couldn't get out of there without
leading them straight to you.
Had to wait them out.
That is such a horse shit,
that was your job.
Enough O'Conner! If he said he
didn't do it, he didn't do it.
Go walk it off.
Look, I would love to expand my
operations in your country.
But quite frankly.
Your business methods are too ??.
Let me tell you true story
500 years ago
Portuguese and spanish came here.
Each trying to get the
country from the natives.
The spanish arrive guns blazing,
determined to prove who is boss.
But, the natives killed every
single spaniard.
Personally, I prefer the
methods of the portuguese.
They came bearing gifts.
Mirrors, scissors, things that the
native couldn't get own their own.
But, to continue receiving them they
had to work for the Portuguese.
And that's why all Brazilians
speak Portuguese today.
Now, if you dominate the people with
violence, they will eventually fight back.
Because, they have nothing to lose.
And, that's the key
I go into the favelas, and give
them something to lose.
Electricity, running water,
school room for their kids.
And for that taste of the better life
I own them.
Gentlemen.
Pardon me gentlemen.
Almost wish I didn't see that.
Almost.
Wait, Dom
Mia was on that train
I didn't.....i didn't know
I wouldn't do anything to hurt her.
You set off the deal
I thought the job was for the cars
I didn't know. All they
want is the chip.
Damn.
You should have come clean.
What's going on out here?
- Nothing.
- Please, Dom.
Just, let me have the chip. I can
take this to them.
I'll give it to Reyes and set
things right.
Get out!
What?
You never listened to me.
Not when I told you he was a cop
and not now.
You never trust me.
Now, look where its gotten us.
Look at our family now,
I can't go home.
Your sister is stuck in this life
and where is Letty Dom?
Where's Letty?
Plasma car.
Wilkes I want a list of every place
within 50 miles that distributes compressed gas tank.
Pass me that evidence bag.
Officer Neves, been waitin for you.
- You asked for me ?
- I did.
May I ask, why?
My smile is not that great.
Your husband was an officer,
who was gunned down in the favela.
Six months later you up and join the force?
You're motivated.
Plus I figure you're the only one in Rio
who can't be brought. Am I right?
- Yes.
- Of course I am.
Good new, bad news.
You know I like my dessert first.
I checked the rail-Line like you asked, found a
couple of spots where they unloaded the cars.
One set of tracks headed west until it hit
the main highway and then disappeared.
And the another set of tracks headed east
170 inch wheel base, half inch track.
The GT 40 ? -That was missing from the manifest.
Followed the trail a couple
of miles.
Pretty easy in this scrub. Can't
move without leaving signs.
Give me the damn veggies.
The ground rolls into a hard pack
and we lost that track too.
Not necessarily.
That road hits through
hill into the favelas.
Couple of years ago it was washed out by a storm.
So dirt from a mile from where you were.
If they headed that way,
you'll pick up the tracks there.
Come prepared?
I'm motivated.
All right then, lets find ourselves a car.
What do you say?
Its definitely a custom chip.
Look at all these side menus here,
for data entry. Lets check this one.
Look at that. Same building,
same order every week.
Its a delivery schedule.
Drugs? No, that's a dealer pack.
See, the most major player they weigh their money
so they don't have to cost somebody to count it.
Right there that's 49 kilos.
49 kilos is a million in twenties.
So, each one of these shipments
is worth 10 million dollars.
Yeah.
I thought so....
So, what is that?
A 100 million plus in cash houses?
That how he keeps it off the grid.
I think it's safe to say that Reyes is smart
to want this pack.
I mean it's his whole network right there, just laid out on
the chip.
Wilkes let's go up the middle,
rest flank north.
What about me?
Stay here.
Police! On the ground!
I got torreto.
Hold your fire. Policio!
They already know who you are.
Let's go.
You ok here ? Yeah.
Almost, thank you.
They are gonna be looking for the
three of us together now.
We need to split up. You and Mia head south
I'll lead them away.
- No.
- Dom's right.
We got lucky, but what happens next time?
We have no choice but to split up.
I'm pregnant.
I already lost my family once
I'm not going thru that again.
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
I'm not going anywhere. Ok.
Dom, promise me we stick together.
I promise.
Family just got bigger...he he.
Something doesn't add up.
Toretto and O'Conner...
They stay when they are supposed to run
They steal gas and then give it away?
And now they're killing
federal agents?
It doesn't make any sense.
Here's what makes sense.
All these guys names are names on a list.
They come up, we take'em down.
Not a phone call more, not a bullet less.
Wilkes! We get anything?
Standard forensics, sweep prints,
hair fibers. Prints are all over the car.
Anything else?
Yeah, we track the owner
off the vehicle ID.
They are couple of shell companies in between a
corporation owned by a investor named Hernan Reyes.
Investor?
If there is anything illegal
happening in Rio, Reyes is involved.
Okay, then so are we.
If you get us any closer to our guys,
I want every thing on em.
Chato, be on the roof. I want you on watch
in case somebody comes back for something
Mac give me a cross-Check on Reyes, full specs, he goes
to the john, I want to know how many times he shakes it.
You got it boss.
Lets put all this mess back together.
Well, that's gonna take a while.
Then you better get started.
They were taking this
car apart for a reason.
Lets put it back together
and find out whats missing.
Hey Dom, what do you remember
about your father?
My father...
He used to....he used to
have a barbeque every sunday after church.
For everybody in the neighbourhood.
If we didn't go to church
we didn't get any barbeque.
Every single day he was in the shop.
And, every single night he was at the kitchen
table with Mia helping her with her homework.
Even after she went to sleep he would
stay up for few more hours.
So he could learn the next
chapter and help her the next day.
I remember everything about my father.
Everything.
That's just it.
I don't remember shit about my dad.
I don't remember him yelling,
I don't remember him smiling.
To be honest with you, I don't even
remember what the hell he looked like.
I don't remember him...he was just
never there.
You ain't gonna be like that Brian.
We can't keep running Dom.
We got to get out.
We got to get out, now.
You're right.
This is how we're gonna do it.
We are gonna use this.
We're gonna do one last job.
We are gonna take all of Reyes' money.
Every dime of it.
And disappear .. forever.
New passports, new lives,
no more looking over our shoulder.
- And we're gonna buy our freedom.
- That's right.
You realize we're talking about going up
against the most powerful guy in all of Rio.
Yes, we are.
Then we're gonna need a team.
Alright, lets run through the bases
real quick.
Who do we got?
First, we're gonna need a chameleon.
Someone who can blend in.
Anywhere.
What else?
A fast talker. Someone who can
bullshit their way out of anything.
I got that.
This guys gonna have a lot of surveillance. We're
gonna need someone who's good with circuits.
And with those circuits,
Reyes is gonna have walls.
We're gonna need guys
to punch through those walls.
- What else?
- Utilities and weapons.
Someone who ain't afraid to throw down.
Someone to backup every position.
Yeah? What else we need?
Most importantly we're gonna
need two precision drivers.
Guys who don't crack under pressure.
Guys who never lose.
You know we got that.
Ah... hell nah
I see they really scraped the
bottom of the barrel ..Huh
I guess they did, since your ass is here.
When you gonna give Martin
Luther King his car back?
As soon as you give Rick James
his jacket back.
- Whaddup man.
- Whaddup.
Sexy legs baby girl.
What time do they open?
They open the same time
as I pull this trigger.
Want me to open them?
Yeah anybody can talk shit
in spanish, homey.
Two fails, I am not fail.....two fails.
Who are these clowns man?
Circus clowns.
I thought cock fights were illegal
in Brazil.
I see, you've all met.
There he is.
You know when you called me to come to Rio, I assumed
it would be for something more exciting than this.
- I missed you man.
- I missed you too.
This is Tej, the best
circuit man on the east coast.
This is my boy Roman Pearce, we go way back.
I met this cat in juvi.
I pulled that job with him Miami.
I heard about you.
- Nice digs.
Yeah, well the Ritz was sold out.
So, whats this all about Dom?
Yeah man, why'd you drag us
half way around the world.
Cause we got a job.
Alright, so target's name is Hernan Reyes.
He runs the drug scene out there.
He has never been busted because
he doesn't leave a paper trail.
No paper trails means no banks.
No banks means cash houses.
That's right.
Tell him what we do Jack.
Its spread throughout the city.
And we're gonna hit em all.
- All of em.
Sounds crazy. Bring us to whole nother country
so we can rob the dude who runs it.
I thought this is business.
Sounds personal to me.
Is that what this is?
I got love for you all,
but personal ain't good business.
I can't do this homie.
So, what we're talking about
is a 100 million dollars.
You say what ? Hun...hun...
See, sometimes I be over thinking man
and I know .we just met...but.
You just kinda...gotta.
A 100 million dollars.
And everything we take,
we split even.
So, that's over 11 million a piece,
I am down
I'm in.
11 million? Sounds like a whole
lotta vaginal activity to me.
You can't pull off all ten heists
on the same mark, you just can't.
Yeah, as soon as we hit the first one they're gonna
do everything they can to protect their asses.
Exactly.
That's all of it.
You're dead men. You're all dead men.
You don't have a place to hide.
Who's hiding?
Are you crazy ? Are you crazy?
Do you know whose house this is?
Whose money are you stealing?
We ain't stealin it.
You tell your boss, exactly who did this.
Tell him there's more coming.
Voila ...
Turn it over.
Its running on all eight,
checks out fine.
Keep looking.
Boss, if something was missing
we'd know.
Its a goddamn shame to put bullshit
like that on a classic.
Might as well slap neon lights on it.
They took the chip.
We got a hit on the police scanner.
Armed robbery at a house in Leblon.
I just cross checked against a property
owned by Reyes Corporation.
Alright if that's our guys then whatever was
on that chip led them directly to that house.
Its them for sure.
How do you know that ? - Because no one
else in Rio is stupid enough to rob Reyes.
Number 1 is on the move man.
Two is on the move.
I got mine
I got eyes on five.
I know you all said they were consolidating
the money somewhere, but ...
Y'all ain't gonna believe this.
Well this job just got a lot harder.
If he's moving it into a police station he's
got some serious brass in his pocket.
Hell yeah, we can't do this.
Can't you mean shouldn't.
I think this doesn't change a thing.
I say we stick to the plan.
You say wha...this just went from mission
impossible to mission infreakin' sanity.
Whatever man!
I ain't scared. I'm just lettin y'all know..
Going in that building is crazy.
I got this.
What time was the robbery.
Around 11' o clock.
Here we go.
Enhance it.
Their faces are covered.
Run it through FRS.
Well, hello you son of a bitch.
Wilkes, run the photos of known associates of Torretto and
O'Conner against customs entries into Brazil in the last 2 weeks.
Check planes, trains, boats and everything
short of the goddamn space shuttle.
They can change their names
but, they can't change their faces.
Something big is going down.
That's a 1970 charger.
Let's go.
Upload these specs into the database
have the computer cross check them with.
The overhead satellites at every 15 minutes.
Stand behind in two.
If these vehicles move on the streets
of Rio, I wanna know about it.
Everything ok ?
This Federal Agent ??
A gringo.
He requested a rookie patrol officer as
his assistant.
The beauty of public offices.
Public records.
This is where he's keeping the money.
The vault in the evidence room.
Yeah..Um. Can I get everyone's attention right here for a
second, we are talkin about breaking into a po-lice station.
Is anyone listening to those words?
Anybody? Po-Po.
Five-O, One time, pigs
people we don't like.
You know police stations are designed
to keep people in not out.
That's why its a stealth mission.
We'll be in and out before they even know we're there.
Well, we need to get eyes in there.
At least, to find out the make
and model of that vault.
Who's the folks you know, do all this.
Wait...wha do you mean?
Why me?
Cause you got the biggest mouth.
That's for damn sure.
Hello beautiful......look at those dimples
sexy.........sexy.
Love those glasses,
where did you get them from.
Are those like gucci frames or somethin?
No, no...
Who are you sir?
Special agent O'Conner.
Us federal bureo of investigation.
It says caucasian?
Well, its the tan....you know tan.
Look....i am working this case
and I got some evidence here to be held.
But I need to get in....and check your
storage facility first.
- Nope.
- Look man I know you're a true professional ..
and I respect you, I promise.
You know...it look like you workout a little bit too.
What you benchmark 3-350.
Look I'm just tryin to do my job man. My boss
sent me here to just make sure everything was safe.
It will be safe. - Ok..Well let me
just come in and take a quick peek.
- Nope.
- Come on man.
Hook a brother up please.
- Nope. And you are not my brother.
Brother from another mother?
Look..No one enters the facility
but authorized evidence personnel.
Now stop wasting my time. I'm going to
call the embassy.
I am going to call
the embassy. No...no, no.
We good...we don't need to call them..For
what?
We good.
Here, I got the box.
We all good, I promise you.
Thank you so much for your time
I swear to god, if you was on the other side of that
glass I'd bust your damn face in .. now translate that.
You see, I think I make a better
special agent than you ever did.
Well, that depends on how you
define special.
C'mon man, lets see what we got.
That's funny.
Alright come on.
Yo, you still can't drive. See that .. now I
see why you always gettin into accidents.
You can't even drive a damn
remote control car.
I don't need this, I don't ..
-Its crazy.
-Shut up right now.
- I am not gonna shut up...
- Man, strap him in his safety belt man.
Give me the remote...go left. It looks like
something right over there to the left...what is that?
Bingo.
What is that ? 6 x 6?
8 x 12
7 x 12. 18-Inch thick steel. Reenforced walls, with
insulated copper core to protect it against thermal lens.
The class 3 electronic lock with a sure fire ?? tumbler.
And a biometric palm scanner.
Ten tons of top of the line security.
Do I wanna know, how you know all that?
I had a life before you know me O'Conner.
Lets just leave it with that, alright.
She is a beauty, though.
Beauty as in good?
Beauty as in you know...
start off playing hard to get.
And, no matter how much I caress her, no matter how much I
love her in the end she still ain't gonna give up that ass.
Two to one says you blow the wrong pipe.
Yo, why you gotta be so negative
all the time?
I ain't negative.
I'm just positive you're going to
mess it up.
I'm telling you, you've
got issues.
Next time, if there's no elevator,
I'm not coming.
You need to learn to relax, loco .
You better hurry up, we got less than
a minute.
Why do you always set the timer
so short ?
Vaminos.
I hope you know where you're going.
I got this....relax man relax.
.. a police station.
Relax.
You used too much explosive! Again.
Too much .. too little ..
It's all the same.
That's some Buddha shit you learned from a
book in the prison library, isn't it?
And what you're doing there on the wall ..
You got that from the same book, huh ?
You're so negative.
Got it...we got it.
Yeah...we are looking at four cameras.
Now, that's some high end shit too.
Marker optics.
100 degree field of view,
10 seconds oscillation.
Nah...that's a narrow window man?
Can we just stop the scanner
and replace the image.
Nah...its hooked  into a digital sync.
They'd know we were in the system.
The best we can do is peek.
We're gonna need some real
fast cars to get thru this.
And, not just fast... we've got a
hard right and a hair pin.
We need something agile.
You guys mark up a track.
O'Conner, lets go get some cars.
.Interval...Go have something!
//subs dedicated to ma mom and bumbo//.
Home...sweet home.
Or that.
How about that?, all motor no tuning issues?
I always wanted one of those.
Held the record on the
avenida 3 years running.
You got a lot of bones to bring
your problems here torreto.
Not to mention a cop.
Yeah, we can keep that on the low.
Word on the street is that a
lot of people are looking for you two.
What, you didn't think
we'd recognise you.
Well, we were kinda counting on it.
That little coupe may run the streets around here but
that monster has never seen a set of tail lights, ever.
Well she's about to.
Dominic Toretto's ride, in my garage.
Now that .. will be a nice trophy.
Lets go .. legend.
Car for car.
Car for car?
If you want it, come and get it.
Really?
Where'd you get that from?
Poppa's market.
Ok O'Conner, give it your best shot.
- How was that one ?
- Camera caught you.
- What?
- Yeah it still caught you.
And I was milkin the hell out of that
thing too.
We're gonna need a faster car.
I want my money .. c'mon.
Exactly why your ass ain't been
driving. Terrible.
I think I'm in love.
That was a real solid work.
I think camera 3 still caught you though.
Let's do it again.
That's the piggy bank you ordered?
You kiddin me ?
Where in the hell can I get one of these?
Well we had a life
before you met us.
Alright, well I get to work
on the electronics tunneler.
But there's still another problem.
Palm scanner.
And without Reyes' hand print,
Houdini himself couldn't open this bitch.
How do you know its Reyes' hand print?
You got 100 million dollars in a safe.
You gonna put somebody
else's hand print on it.
There you go with that negativity.
How are we supposed to get
Reyes's hand print?
Han, you're up.
Sure, gotta make the easy stuff.
Lets go, I 'll drive.
That makes six bodyguards.
Seven, do you think that guy with
a fanny pack is a tourist?
So, how long were you in the army?
That gun you pulled the other day was
a Jericho 941.
I got out of the military probably the same
time you quit smoking.
The amount of chips you eat.
The way you always have to keep
your hands and mouth busy.
You were a two pack a day man.
For sure.
Unfiltered.
Well, this is a bust.
How you gonna get Reyes
fingerprints out of here.
We need to do some more recon.
Call in a couple extra guys.
Uh uh. You don't send a man
to do a woman's job.
We gonna figure this out, I promise you.
Whats that?
I thought she was more of a thong man?
We got the prints.
Where?
Ok. That's crazy.
So, did he just like slap that ass.
Or, did he like grab and hold on to it?
Yeah..Hey...this will work.
I'm impressed. - Got it?
Got it. But, you still
didn't answer the question.
Guys...guys...guys....we have a problem.
- The whole team just got burnt.
- Now we're all wanted.
Hang on a second.
Us diplomatic security service
issued the warrants.
Agent L.Hobbs.
Hold on a second.
Hey Dom,
Is that the guy you saw in the favela?
Yeah.
Hobbs is the leader of the
elite task force for the DSS.
So he's good.
When the FBI wants to find somebody
that's who they call.
Because he never misses his mark.
This guy is....he's old testament.
Blood, bullets, rap the GOD
that's his style.
And right now he's hunting us?
Dom, we gotta move up
our time line.
Yeah, but how?
This thing has already been difficult
without Wyatt Earp on our ass.
If anything ..
We need more room to breathe.
Roman's right.
I think we need to get some fresh air.
I've got a hit. We've got his Charger
Let's get a move on.
East bound on 90.
Move....move....move
Stopped...about a block ahead.
Park it...we're going on foot.
Hey .. Toretto.
You're under arrest.
Arrest?
I don't feel like I'm under arrest.
How about you brian?
Nah .. not a bit.
- Not even a little bit.
- I'll just give it a minute .. it'll sink in.
We didn't kill those feds.
- That was Reyes.
- I don't give a shit.
Just here to bring in two assholes
whose names hit my desk.
Yeah, that's sound like a real hero.
That's funny.
From a guy who took the oath of a cop and
then went against everything he stood for?
Or, some wanna be tough guy prick who beat
a man half to death with a socket rinch.
That's real tough.
You turn around and put
your hands behind your back.
- I don't think so.
- You're mistaken to think you got a goddamn choice boy.
Your mistake ? Thinking you're in America.
You're a long way from home.
This is Brazil!
Come on boss, another day.
Come on, it's a lotta heat.
I'll see you soon, Toretto.
I'm looking forward to it Hobbs.
Yep.
Tracker's on.
Got em.
I don't understand. Why come here?
Why risk it all for
20 dollars worth of silver?
Cause its worth it.
You should run you know!
Hobbs will find you.
You have every reason to leave. Why stay ?
Why do you?
My husband was a good police officer...an
honest man...we both grew up here.
Three years ago, has was murdered in
the streets.
Right outside our door.
Reyes owns this favela now.
He give things to people.
And everything has a price.
People here need a new start.
They need to be free.
You didn't killed those men in the train
did you?
Now why would you believe anything
I'd tell you.
Hey!
Was she so special too?
I never thought anyone could
understand how much.
But you do.
Close, but not enough.
Time window's too small, man.
The only way we're gonna beat the cameras,
is with .. invisible cars.
And I know just where to get em.
Lets take a ride boys.
Don't hurt yourself.
Its been a while since I've been behind
the wheel of one of these.
First time I've  ever been in the
front seat.
Hey, Rome, what took you so long.
I thought for sure, you'd be showing up
with some chrome spinners or somethin.
Ha.....hah....real funny
I got a 100,000 that says I can
take you all in the next quarter mile.
Yeah, your broke ass has got a 100 grand.
If we pull off this job, I will.
Next two lights, a 100,000.
If we don't pull this job off,
we're probably dead anyway.
Lets make it a million.
I like that.
Alright, million dollar quarter mile.
Alright then.
We only live once, lets do it.
What do you say Dom?
Are we talking or we racing?
Just don't cheat this time.
You gotta let that go.
Yeah .. owned you .. owned you.
- Good race, O'Conner.
- Thanks, Dom.
You know how long I've been waitin
for that shit ?
I told you he didn't see it.
The man right there!
He let off the throttle at the mile.
You didn't do nothing.
He let you win.
Bullshit.
Vince, what are you doing?
Quiet, they've been tracking you.
I know she's here!
Find her!
Go! Go! Go!
Its..Ok...wait.
Reyes's guys were waiting for
me at the market.
Vince saved my life.
You hungry?
Yeah, sure.
Good!
Cause you're saying grace.
Thanks Vince.
Yo you burned it!
Relax!
Yeah, but your mom is the worst cook
in the world.
- C'mon baby we be livin.
- Cheers...cheers.....cheers.
So we in Brazil.
The good life.
Yeah.
So, you got a.....you got a little
more than 10-11 million dollars coming.
Whats you gonna do with your money?
Me?
Yeah.
Actually...man, I have been thinking
about opening up a garage back home.
A place where people can bring their cars, and not
get completely ripped off, you know what I mean?
Really?
Yeah.
So, your dream is to start a day job?
That's...that's stupid...man, why would..
Nah...that's not stupid at all..Man
I love what I do.
You wanna know what I'm
gonna do with my money.
Find some cooking lesson for my man.
- See, see? There you go with that negativity man.
- You know me .. money ain't a goddam thing.
Its gonna take a little more than
money to learn how to cook...that's home.
But, I heard they were looking for a chef.
Down at this animal shelter.
Where you might....wanna.
I know the manager .. I'll call him.
Hey Dom,
Listen, I know you're all set for this
job tomorrow.
If you need an extra men
You're in.
There's always room for family.
Thank you!
Get something to eat.
Yeah.
Can you believe Mia calls it the curse.
She might be right.
You really like doing that stuff, huh?
When your life is on the line,
that's when you learn about yourself.
That's a fair deal.
We're less than 24 hours from the biggest
celebration of our life.
You gotta re-fill.
This is some serious stuff.
- No, I'm good.
- Cheers, baby.
- I'm good .. no.
- No, she can't.
What do you mean?
She can't.
What do you mean, she can't?
Are you serious right now?
Is that the reason you let him beat
you in the quarter mile?
That was a baby gift.
- That was a baby gift.
- No, that's messed up.
No, you are not taking that from me.
Wait, wait...hold on a second.
Did he just smack that ass or,
Did he grab that ass..
- Just wanna know.
- Thanks .. Thank you ..
It's crazy, huh
Its your boy. Why would you keep
somethin like that away from me.
Baby gift huh ?
I have no idea what they're
talking about.
Toast!
Money will come and go, we know that.
The most important thing in life.
Will always be the people in this room.
Right here, right now.
Salute de familia...
salute...salute...
I'm all set
Santos, van good?
Yeah, it's always good bro.
Hobbs is on the other side of the city.
We're not gonna get
a better window.
Ok guys, its showtime.
First team in position,
lets go. -Come on lets do this.
Hey Dom, I got eyes on Mia.
Moscow, Bali, Goa, Hong Kong.
What do they have all in common.
No extradition.
- We're one hour away from the rest of our lives.
- Yeah.
Dom!
You just made a big mistake.
Took me a while to find
that tracking chip.
But, not as long to flip the receiver.
You're going down Torretto.
I'm right here.
Dom!
Stand back, I got this.
Dom .. please Dom.
Stop!
Dom!
Yeah?
We're comin in now.
Have the marshals meet us at the
airport when we land.
Ambush!
Wilkes, suppressing fire.
Set em down.
Grab the back, cover me.
Watch that.
Cut us loose! Come on!
Cut us loose!
You get em? Let's go!
Let's go!
Hey Dom, you didn't meet my son
Nico
I will.
He's a good kid.
You know, we named him after you.
Dominic.
You've got my word Vince.
You were always my brother.
?? Nico now.
We need to move, we don't
have that much time
I got us a flight out that leaves Rio
in the rear view in next 5 hours.
Not to run away ..
To finish the job.
Are you crazy Dom ? We can't.
It's a suicide mission.
That's your man over there
on the table.
The plan is busted, this is bullshit man.
Reyes knows we're coming.
He's right.
They tripled the detail at the police
station. Its gonna be a wall of gunfire.
Reyes doesn't get away with this.
Its a trap man, you know that.
Dom! Listen to them.
Run, before its too late.
Leave Rio, you can be free
I don't need freedom.
You should know that.
You know you're all free
to make your own choices.
I'm in.
I'll ride with you Toretto.
At least until we kill that
son of a bitch.
So whats the plan Dom?
Can't just go sneaking around
any more.
We don't sneak.
The only thing that he cares
about is his money.
We pull that, we pull him.
See
I called in every cop on our payroll.
We're covered.
We've got every entrance covered with weapons teams.
God himself couldn't get at your money if he wanted to.
God isn't my worry.
You ready?
I'm ready.
What's happening?
They're taking the vault.
What ?
The vault!
Follow me! Quickly!
Let me through!
Don't move!
Stay down!
Call it out Mia!
You got a straight shot for
two blocks.
Go right.
Got it.
Well, the plans working.
You guys have every cop car
in Rio on your tail.
You guys have to move fast.
Whats the best route?
Keep going straight
another half mile at Rua Pasega.
And then go left.
That ain't gonna work.
Spikes ahead Dom....we got spikes.
We're going right.
Nah .. its too tight ..
we're not gonna fit.
We got no choice. Now!
Sh...it!
Holy....shit!
Guys I am hearing all this chatter,
did you just take out a bank?
Two inbound.
Alright! There's an ally
coming up on your left.
Yeah! I got it.
You little bastard!
Alright good job Dom. Right hander
right here .. right hander.
Guys, there's a big group
coming at you from south.
You have to do something now!
Hey go wide.
Yeah!
You're all clear on the left.
Good afternoon officer.
License and registration please.
Yeah! This is big boy stuff.
We clear on the right.
- Thanks guys.
- Anytime
I'll see you on the other side.
You guys just cropped out a
10 second window, make it count.
Zizi, stay on them.
They can't outrun us on the bridge.
Heh Heh .. They have no way out.
No .. there's too many of them.
Hey there's too many of them.
We are not gonna make it.
You're right, we aren't.
- You are.
- What are you talking about.
Just let the vault go.
Get out of there.
You're a father now, brian.
I'm not leavin you.
Now you stick with the plan.
It was always the plan.
Take care of Mia.
Dom you listen to me.  Now, ok.
You cut loose right now!
Hey, what is he doing ?
We've got him!
Close down the bridge!
Do something, asshole!
Kill him, dammit!
Kill him now!
I thought I told you to go on.
Yeah! I had to make a call.
Help me.
That's for my team
you son of a bitch.
Its a hell of a mess.
Yeah, it is.
You know I can't let you two go.
I ain't made that way.
We'll see that you bring
yourself 24 hours.
The money stays though.
If I were you I'd use the time.
Make peace with whatever
demons you got left.
Cause come tomorrow ..
I will found you.
Toretto
I'll see ya soon.
No you won't.
Thanks guys.
I'll see you on the other side.
You guys just cropped out a
10 second window.
Make it count.
Come on baby, don't be mean.
"For Rosa and Nico. See you soon.
Uncle Dom"
MONACO
You sure about this ?
You know I am .
You don't need to do this.
Just leave me alone.
Bro, I'm not trying to be negative,
but casinos ..
.. are the kinds of places designed to take money
from guys like you and me.
When I win here I'm buying you a lifetime
supply of anti-depressants.
You don't put ten million on red!
- Enough already !
- You put it on black.
No more bets, thank you.
Right this way my dear.
Stay right here.
I'll be right back.
So, this is your dream..Huh.
That's enough of me man.
I take it that's your dream.
- Absolutely...what up .. boy.
- Whats going on?
- You good.
- Yes, yes.
You know what's crazy?
There's only four of those cars
in the whole world.
And I got the only one
in the western hemisphere.
I made a sheikh in Abu Dhabi
an offer he could not refuse.
- Huh .. that's a nice lady you got there too.
- Oh absolutely.
So we got to go man. Lets do this.
Ok, I'll drive.
In that? Come on man .. no .. no way.
No .. no .. not in this .. in that!
Are you serious right now.
Man this is crazy.
Yeah.
I guess that means there are two
in the western hemisphere..Huh...huh.
Whats your smart ass gotta say now?
Well you know what,
we can always shine together baby.
Get dressed man,
we got things to do.
So where to now?
I don't know.
Never been to Madrid.
I thought you wanted to go to Tokyo.
We'll get there.
Eventually.
This is the happiest I've
ever seen my sister.
It's cause were free.
You know, I wanna another shot.
Yeah?
Yeah.
No wagers, nobody else,
just you and me once and for all.
You sure you can handle
the disappointment?
Are you?
Alright, O'Conner.
Lets see what you got.
Diplomatic Security Service Headquarters,
Washington, D.C.
You need to look at that.
Berlin, 3 am this morning.
A team of hikers,
hijacked a military convey.
- Torreto?
- Nope!
Ain't interested.
Yes you are, keep looking.
You believe in ghosts?
....www.subscene.com....