Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Out of the way, a beggar!
With caution.
Captain.
-Khadin.
Dole?
How dare you touch me,
filthy beggar?
Ruoskikaa him, Captain.
The host is certainly satisfied.
His expectation is finished.
This is attractive to you, El Sharif?
Katsina, Katsina ...
Your tongue.
How does it move at all.
What it can not.
Herättäisit patsaankin life.
Holly Acheson, Edward Acheson,
U.S. chain store king -
the only daughter and heir.
Inger Lindström, actress.
According to Western press
"Scandinavian goddess of love."
Last but not least.
Amena Cordoba.
Jumping the European champion.
Prepare the antidote.
Their time has come to wake up.
Katsina.
Someday
for you to Samarkand -
and you seem sulojasi
under the stars.
Tomorrow, El Sharif?
You have promised it for a long time.
Tomorrow does not work. But soon as possible.
Tomorrow will be an important guest.
-Sheikh Umar?
Sheikh Umar?
No, but the Kaiser
United States -
will persuade me.
The answer has always been the same.
-He gives us only the droplets.
Its small aavikkopläntin
below is a bottomless well, Adam.
Oil is a huge
and we need it.
We drop by drop
but a huge torrent.
I know, Doctor.
We tightened
a ruthless son of a bitch -
who happens to own
over one hundred hectares of sand.
American companies helped
to the building.
Roads, refineries,
oil pipelines, military.
Kuunteleekohan he
to reason at this time?
I believe in a personal
diplomacy into force -
and I believe I can say
I'm usually right.
Welcome to the.
My name is ILSA.
I am Sheikh harem khadin.
These are the assistant -
Satin and Velvet.
Harem? Not!
Why is it so terrible?
You will come to life
easy and luxurious life.
You are beautiful
than you dared imagine.
You will be spoiled
and each of your wishes are met.
We were kidnapped in order ..?
-Exactly.
You are crazy! You will not survive this.
We have friends and relatives!
What are they looking for you?
They find only
that you have lost.
You have only one task:
to serve a master without question.
Not! Not!
We have our means to make
obedient to you. Velvet.
So beautiful.
We have a cage for it.
It penetrates between the feet.
It is looking for moisture.
Then it selects the
what goes into the hole.
And then -
its sharp teeth -
begin to chew on
your flesh from the inside out.
His name is ILSA.
What do we know about him?
We will not change.
I would not want that kind of woman
to meet a dark alley.
So I hear.
Watch out when we get there.
I do not want you fair poorly.
I am only his adjutant.
Papers to prove it.
He does not know who I am.
Counter intelligence?
Their best-husbands.
Dr. deceive me -
even before arriving.
He did not see anything, El Sharif.
I take care of it.
Maybe he will,
as it is heard the rumors.
It's impossible.
We can not take the risk.
He may find
kidnapped girls.
The risk is too great.
Do you want to
that they are eliminated?
There is a better way.
Sold them to a slave auction.
They have come to expect
scum of the earth cuisine.
Of these, they pay well.
Think of the Arab, ILSA.
My job is to serve you.
-Excellent.
But not for new entrants.
I like them under lock and key.
They become the harem
magnificent jewels.
But first -
I need to take care of
one disciplinary matter.
This man is guilty of
an offense against the El Sharif.
He entered the harem as the animal
and lying on one with the girl.
He claims the girl's vietelleen,
but it is not important.
The girl has been punished.
He demands their rights as a soldier.
Martial trial.
We agree to his request.
If he wins,
he was pardoned.
He is struggling with his bare hands -
against them.
Let him go free.
Maybe.
Let's see.
Begin.
Hoidelkaa it!
Welcome eunukkieni set.
Anoint him properly.
His skin should
be smooth for the host.
This will cause further problems.
Does not cause.
He remembers,
that the rat is hungry.
Ajelkaa he was smooth.
El Sharif to keep hair
only between the legs.
Kidnapped and held for one man
enters the next.
Blonde hair, blue eyes -
and the divine body.
The man just for you.
Men do not need to drag
to me as a slave.
Yes bother to wait.
First we need to try to push.
A little blackmail.
But in the end -
need to find a
Sheikh skeleton closet.
Something he does not want to
Arab friends to know about.
Or the rest of the world.
Harder!
Language is his favorite tool of choice.
You have to learn to use it.
Downward. Between the legs.
Lick, bitch!
Good.
Lower!
Use the language.
I do not command a second time.
You have a lot to learn.
Do not turn your eyes!
This is what is left
haaremitytöstä and eunukista.
They were very stupid.
Tried to escape from the desert.
They do not come very far.
If you exhaust your mind juolahtaisi -
remember this sight.
Why did not he eat? -He
were fed two hours ago.
It is not enough. He is progressing
too slowly. Eunuch!
At your service.
-Give him up. Now!
No, no, no ...
Shut up, bitch!
Feed him every hour.
He is progressing nicely. He
get a good price at auction.
You make a village
very happy, Jasmin.
Add wine to my friends!
Take more, Kalam.
Women, Sharif?
Where are the women,
we came to see?
To buy, Kalam.
Since
Buyer shall not -
access to the goods in advance?
Patience, my friend.
Products are being prepared
for tomorrow's auction.
Host must tend to
destroy their beauty.
He can do for them what they want.
He got off easy.
Khadin?
Excellent.
-This way.
Buyers want to flesh on the bones
around it. Use of silicone.
Unbelievable. El Sharif called you
little white neitsyekseen -
seeing your pictures.
Even then, you were spoiled by the disease.
It must not be hidden.
You underestimate my skills.
They do not do not see any -
before it is too late.
Amazing that you got an agent
inside the fortress.
It was not easy -
but I found a very
determined young woman.
And very patient.
When he was a child, El Sharif
tortured to death in his family.
All these years he has
waiting for the opportunity to take revenge.
I do not understand how he
could get anything out.
Simple as that.
He has a bugging device.
They will find it.
Do this.
I designed it myself.
Maybe he will,
as it is heard the rumors.
is a better way.
He remembered,
that you have not been entered.
I wonder ...
I wonder where he gets hupinsa.
There is no mention of lovers.
Maybe he has a different taste.
Not to my knowledge,.
Have you thought of approaching
through the back door?
Kingdoms have in the past
captured between the sheets.
Brilliant! Add to wine buyers.
This work will be thirsty men.
Sheikh Kalam? Here he is.
Girl where you liked.
What do you offer?
5000.
-Such a gem?
Offered to 6000?
-6000!
Be offered more?
-7000!
These alone are worth it.
These buttocks worth looking at.
Try your own hand, Kalam.
She will enchant you.
You feel a stallion again.
11 000!
-Which Fish Sold 11 000, respectively.
This girl is a Risala. His
the body gets the sap to flow.
He is perfect.
Offered to 10 000?
Offered to 11 000?
11 000! Does a 12 000?
-12 000!
Offered to 14 000? 20 000?
Do you beat your brother, Mahmoud?
I offer 50 000!
What do you say 50 000 C, Ahmed?
-Do not run out of women for this.
Sold Sheikh
Mahmud 50000 respectively.
Next, an exotic
and the beautiful Erika.
Remember his special skills.
If you buy him,
you get 20 women.
What this
Multi-woman is offered?
Offered to 40 000?
Been offered. Be offered more?
60 000 have been offered.
65000. Be offered more?
70 000 patients receive a one-woman.
Buy this, you do not need another.
100 000 dinars.
This is your choice?
-Offered to more?
Sold Sheikh Ahmed. 100 000
TD, has today the highest price.
Something must be done first.
-Whatever. The woman is yours.
I do not like grinding of the teeth.
A friend of mine,
something exceptional -
they have a different taste.
Look at what the body.
Cast skinny son to go.
I offer you the right man.
Come closer.
Give it a try on his muscles.
Experiment with how heavy
stuff he has on offer.
counter-intelligence?
-One of their best men.
He did not see anything.
I take care of it.
We can not risk anything.
He can not find the abducted girls.
Not . Sold them
a slave auction.
Expensive toys dancing girl.
Who gave it to you?
I found it.
Did you find koneenkin?
I stole it.
Who these interesting
toys are?
It was Dulciman. A girl,
a soldier who was caught with.
I found them to her room
after his death.
He was a good spread her legs.
But that these things?
I do not think so.
I swear that it is the truth.
What else do you want to hear?
The truth.
I could have
escape from this trip.
If we pay what he asks,
we have to go bankrupt.
Unless the Sheik Umar
not spoken to him makes sense.
Sheikh Umar is too stupid
to come up with anything like this.
Who was it?
-I have told everything I know.
Who is your contact?
What do they want to know?
Stop it. Please.
You will feel the pain.
Listen carefully, bitch.
You will feel a lot worse pain,
if you do not tell the truth.
Each of the screw turning ...
Each of the screw rotation
cause more pain -
until every nerve
screaming in pain.
Until the end -
breasts ruptured and detached.
Is that what you want?
It was Dulcima!
Jopas occurred. Dulcima is dead.
If the crease
does not get him to talk about -
ten thousand
friend will receive.
How can he dance,
if he does not have legs?
Please indicate the
when he agrees to talk.
Come closer.
The skin is so smooth.
They are incredibly beautiful.
One is still
unchecked, El Sharif.
Yes!
I promised that unohtaisitte
other toy.
More ants.
Are you ready to talk about?
I am!
My expectations are terminated.
Your guests will soon arrive.
They do not fit odotuttaa.
Tell me that I
a business meeting.
I'll leave you to manage asioitanne.
Khadin!
You have done a good job.
Whose payroll are you?
N. ..
S. ..
A ca
Who is your contact?
His name is ...
I just hope that I do not have to
eat sheep eyes.
Sheep eyes?
They are considered a delicacy.
Served only to guests of honor.
I have eaten them
throughout the Arab world.
I can not eat any more.
Are you sure?
He was involved in the plot.
To kill me?
-He does not know the reason.
He knows only that his
was to gather information.
That man should be
a visitors come here -
but for him to keep -
to give a lesson.
Your presence is a credit to low
majalleni, Dr. Kaiser.
Friendly, your Lordship.
Adjutant, Commander Scott.
This is the ILSA,
housekeeper.
Does the Commander's first name?
-Adam, Your Excellency.
You'll probably want to start
discussions as soon as -
but today is a celebration dinner.
It's beautiful.
I am spared the
such an occasion.
The American is handsome.
He is our enemy.
He became just as
said, without shackles.
He is a deceitful bastard.
But we have a whole evening time.
If I want to ...
Requirements do not ever met.
Then the oil taps are closed.
Stubbornness is not
in honor of the Arab world.
The reason is simply greed.
I have oil, 'Umar.
Not you.
Gives rise to jealousy
strange alliances, is not it?
Choose whether or not my friend.
I am married.
But, far from home.
Looking for something?
Someone might be?
Maybe.
-I?
But in your country
needs money, El Sharif.
Needs? Look around you.
What about your people?
They do not know anything about
wealth of the feet.
They do not live in
in the past forever.
Why not?
For them, the only black kultanne
Curse of the ruin of their niittynsä.
But one day,
they get to know the truth.
What then?
Are not you afraid
rebellion or revolution?
Afraid of the lion jackal?
Jackals can bite, El Sharif.
Not if it is
removed from the teeth.
My application right
is a quick and final.
Do you see this man?
He is a servant.
He is a servant
position of trust.
Is it not?
But he decided to
confidence to use incorrectly.
He was caught for theft.
Tell me, Doctor -
what is your country
are thieves?
Depends on
what he stole.
Here, it is not important.
When a man has tasted
something new -
He may want to drink again.
The next time more.
Do not, El Sharif!
El Sharif, do not!
My apologies, but the right to use my
is a quick and final.
Do you agree with this?
What is he stealing?
Let me show you.
It is very beautiful.
It's not just a rock.
Look at the detail.
The microphone.
Ingenious man
Designed by an ingenious device.
A friend of mine, tonight -
we celebrate a very
special guests -
traditional sacrificial ceremonies -
to show how
with great respect -
we feel towards him.
His own beloved sheep eye.
Such a representation
excite most of the men.
Yes, most of the.
-But you are different?
It is a genuine issue
a poor substitute.
I like a woman who does not
afraid of uncharted waters.
Teistäkö shall I fear?
You could be overwhelmed.
-Imartelette yourselves.
They did not quit yet.
Will you look at that?
No thank you.
My back ...
Is my guest eunuch?
Shows that you do not have.
How do I?
Thou dare!
What's the matter, ILSA? Are you
have forgotten what is the right man?
Do you think me a whore?
Go to your room. This is over.
Not on my part.
I say to the guards to help me.
They take you out.
Are you crazy?
They come running when I shout.
Why do not you do it?
Let it go. Scream.
Or are you curious?
Small teränne takiako?
You have not yet seen it.
But it is waiting for you.
What will you do?
First of all this.
Sheep eyes, Sharif.
Hassan I, your Excellency.
El Sharif has sent me.
Why is that?
-To serve you.
I do not need anything.
I'm going to bed.
Serve with you there.
I do not need help
going to bed.
In bed.
I do what you want.
In bed?
El Sharif said,
that you do not want a woman.
You want a son.
Here I am.
He said ..?
I want to ..?
It is miserable ...
Do not take it away!
And then this.
Only one stitch.
Now.
I do not understand.
Spread your feet.
Relax.
Just about.
That is no longer needed.
We need a second,
a stronger weapon.
I am married!
-I will please you.
Not!
-I get a penalty if I do not do it.
Need to do you happy.
-I am happy.
My throat is cut.
Cut off ..?
Would he do it?
Let me stay here;
Your Excellency.
What is your name was?
This is not possible ...
Do not say anything.
Feeling, and just listen.
The upper.
Do your job, whore.
Please you, El Sharif?
Get out of my sight.
I have never felt
sinunlaistasi man, Adam.
I would hope -
that I do not
need to leave in the morning.
You can stay here.
I would like to stay.
But what I say
Dr. Kaiser?
Say you're sick.
Say that you come from the stern.
Say anything that we can
have a couple of days together.
I have to go back to Washington.
Wedding day is coming.
I have been asked to stay
for a few days.
Be careful that your neck does not break.
He did not suspect anything.
He just wants to make love.
He may do something carelessly.
No trace of the agent?
No. I am afraid,
that we have lost him.
Do not underestimate him, Adam.
-No, sir.
See you soon. Good luck.
-Thank you. Goodbye.
He is still alive.
-It is enough observation performance.
Plastic explosive.
It is a new type.
Safe until you turn on the power.
Velvet.
Look at the El Sharif.
It is placed in his sisälleen.
Rakastelukone show
exactly what happens.
Come back sermin.
There, you will be safe.
More quickly.
Deeper.
What is the way to a man to die!
Passion for excellence at the time.
It is the enemy,
deceitful to a neighbor.
Sheikh Umar?
He does not suspect anything.
But what do we girls?
Katsina.
I give you, Sheikh Umar
a gift of peace.
Legacy soon?
-A couple of days later.
When  khadin has prepared you.
Must be very careful.
Does he feel anything when you wake up?
He did not know anything.
Guarded him carefully.
I gave those orders.
What about American?
He is a joy to me.
But only so far.
He is just a toy.
He may not live as long
that sees orjakaravaanin.
He does not live.
And kunniavieraammekaan.
Not even he.
Arrange an unfortunate accident.
It can easily be arranged.
I do not interfere in affairs.
You can enjoy him.
But watch out.
Toys can become precious.
I have already
tired of him.
Adam ...
I thought ...
At first I thought -
that we have only one
one enjoyable night.
But you are different.
Point ...
It hardens.
Yes, El Sharif.
And my tongue will taste of sweetness.
I am here to serve
roads, El Sharif.
Stand up.
Tarib!
Captain Tarib!
A couple of hours yet, and he's talking about.
-You are interrogated throughout the night.
Tarib is an amateur in these matters.
I know how she breaks down.
You say you're a freedom fighter.
-I will not tell any more.
I'm getting the truth out of him.
No.
We do not receive any more information about him.
He dies before.
You do not practice it?
You want to give it
more oil? Okay.
For that you want.
Öljyäni.
Mr. Scott -
why are you so silent?
He has not been
the trial.
He was caught in the act.
What else is needed?
In my country, man has the right to
to be heard and defend himself.
Oh, yeah.
Ye ye might learn
how to save a lot of time.
As you can see,
punishment is a crime with.
I do not want to see him
alive in the morning.
You have delayed enough.
It is the commandment, ILSA.
Yes, El Sharif.
Why is telling me this?
Since I do not want to die.
You wanted it sooner.
When you were my enemy.
What about now?
Say it, ILSA.
You are my lover.
I look like when you wear.
You have reason to dress himself.
This man has seduced you.
Capture them.
Let go!
Do a good job.
But you are too independent.
You have to learn obedience.
You need to remind -
who you serve.
Your body has betrayed you.
It needed love.
It is your thirst.
It must be cultivated -
in order to eliminate the need.
Good.
I think that you've learned your lesson yet.
So I am.
I consider myself kyttyräselän.
If you are not obedient -
you get to experience this again.
The next time
it is done publicly.
In the middle of the market square,
all the people to see.
For the first time should not be.
Forget it American.
Half an hour, and he is dead.
I need to get to her.
What we say to them?
Promise of freedom, gold,
whatever they ask.
Satin, the guards treat the area.
Velvet, treat harem
until I return.
Hurry! Take the gun!
Do not haaskatko time! Eunuch!
Stop.
I came to see it
pig dies. Where is he?
There.
Suddenly. There is not much.
Fight, if you want to live.
Wait a minute.
Why do you want to throw him to power?
We can manage one.
With the Son.
What is the boy?
Come, I will show.
Come on now.
Prince Selim, Sheikh's nephew.
The last rightful heir.
The battle has begun. Let's go.
He is safer here.
You are right. Let's go.
Now it's my turn to.
You gave me a gift.
Kyttyräselän.
I'll give you a gift.
Katsina.
He will be tomorrow
Sheikh Umar -
but she must perform
yet one mission here.
Katsina,
El Sharif has been promised for -
The last wish -
before he was executed.
Yes, khadin.
He wants to make love
the last time with you.
Valitsiko he me?
Then you can go.
Oh  khadin ...
Use your tongue.
Kiihota him best.
Help him to Within
and to reach the final ecstasy.
Let him die
happily, Katsina -
so you get your freedom.
khadin Where is it?
Excuse me,
your Highness.
That's right, Katsina.
Do you see how strong you make him?
Let him go deeper.
Help him. Louder.
A suitable end to a man who had
fleshly pleasures.
What about Katsina?
Why, what evil he had done?
-He had no significance.
You even filthy bitch.
Is your lover become cold?
-Frigid.
I introduce myself to the prince.
I am commanded to kill him.
My job is to protect you
unpalatable decisions.
You managed to do it well.
-I just want to serve you.
As the server enoanne.
-This is your home if you so desire.
American need to leave,
so that you can manage alone.
I need him.
-You do not need. I will help you.
I would advise you, negotiate
on your behalf. Opastan you.
I am the right hands.
You clicked on your loyalty,
when the server enoani.
Until then, when he behaved
as a monster. Then I decided to strike.
For you to come to power and
perintöoikeutenne get back.
He saved your life.
-I agree to your request.
Kingdom is a place for you.
-Thank you, your Highness.
Until his death.
Let me out!
This is not my doing.
Goodbye, ILSA.
-Son of a bitch!
Let me out, you bastard!
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
by Jengroro3