...And she did it
in her lover's apartment.
Slitting wrists sounds scary...
You think she bled a lot?
It must be hard with her Dad gone
and her Mum doing that.
Sachiko doesn't have a Dad?
- No.
Did you know Natsuko?
No.
HARMFUL INSECT
I'm finished.
Are you a bit late today?
Run along.
See you later.
Bye honey.
Good morning.
You're late.
Dear Ms. Sachiko Kita, how are you?
Things have finally
settled down here.
I'd be lying
if I said I wasn't scared.
But I can't let myself run away now.
When's your period?
Hey, come on...
Rise.
Bow.
Be seated.
The male of the 'Beta' fish
blows froth to make a nest,
and after luring a female inside,
he bends his body
and forces the eggs out of her
by squeezing her body.
A group against nuclear power plants
interviewed me today,
asking why I quit being a teacher
to work in such a place.
I can't give them the answer
they expect,
so it was funny to think why I was
chosen for the interview.
What is this?
Here.
I wonder how Sachiko's doing?
Sachiko Kita? Who cares?
Hey, what we were saying,
I'd choose Hanasaka.
He's taller now.
In grade school he was so cute.
Was he popular?
- Don't know.
Mr. Kyuzo!
Mr. Kyuzo...
I saw a strange dream.
There were no stars or moon
in the night sky,
and there was garbage all around me.
Here.
Thanks.
I'm home.
Hi honey.
Sachiko.
A girl named Miss Yamaoka
came by today.
So, you haven't been going to school.
I'm not angry at you
or anything like that.
You can go back to school when you
feel you're up to it again.
Who does she think she is?
She doesn't care about you, Natsuko.
Let's stop doing this. It's no use.
That rumor about Sachiko
and her sixth grade teacher?
The teacher quit his job
and disappeared.
Isn't that weird?
No wait, let me explain...
Huh?
No, that's not true.
When you were angry before,
it wasn't my fault...
I'm saying it's a misunderstanding.
You're acting strange lately...
Don't push it.
I mean,
why did you clear out my room?
I've had it with you.
Are you... alright?
Hello? Yeah I'm fine, it's nothing.
I'll tell you later.
Oh, can I come over?
Okay, see you.
Wow. A piece of cake.
Can't believe he had so much.
No thanks.
Yeah?
Mr. Kyuzo!
Arsehole!
Go to hell, you piece of garbage.
Where is this?
Takao's place?
You again?
That's the Yamakawa's
and they're not in.
Your friend's place is
on the forth floor.
Isn't he silly? He's mistaken
his friend's room again?
Friend? Doggy's friend?
What happened?
Wait, I'll go get Mr. Kyuzo.
Mr. Kyuzo!
A fight?
Does it hurt?
The hospital?
Go to the hospital.
I can't go to the hospital.
But you have to.
I can't.
Why not?
How much do you have on you?
What?
I'll get money.
How?
I'll borrow some from Mom.
It's okay.
Do you want something?
I can help you, you know.
Money, right?
You want money, right?
How much?
Let's discuss it inside.
I'm home.
Hi there.
Oh, hi honey.
This is Mr. Tokugawa.
He's my friend.
Your kid?
Yeah.
Hello.
Do me a favor?
I want to try it, too.
Try what?
Test my nerves. Fake an accident.
What are you saying?
If you say no I'll do it myself.
When a car comes like this,
you go like this.
- Timing is the key,
so watch closely.
- Right.
Don't go if I signal you.
It's dangerous because it's too fast.
Forget it, let's go.
- Why not?
Money's not worth it!
It's not for the money.
We won't do it, let's go.
No.
Want one?
What?
Nothing.
Hey.
Yeah?
Let's run away somewhere.
Far away?
Yeah.
Okay. When?
Tomorrow.
Okay. Let's go.
Then tomorrow, ten o'clock,
at the floating pier.
Tomorrow at ten, okay?
Mr. Ogata, if I went away
to a place you don't know,
would you be lonely?
Or would you not care?
Thinking such things confuses me.
But right now, I feel fine.
I think you mean the so called
'Battle Fish', Sachiko.
The males apparently battle against
each other savagely.
Those tiny fish bite each other
for an entire day and night.
Hi, you're home.
You're late.
Mr. Tokugawa brought some
expensive beef from home
and we were waiting
to have dinner with you.
But we've already started.
Want some?
- Yeah.
If you write your dreams in
your diary everyday, you die.
If this is true, it's a bit scary.
I've decided to start going
to school again.
The seasons change differently
from where you are.
Well then,
take good care of yourself.
You're always on my mind, Sachiko.
School Festival Program: CHORUS.
Okay, first the conductor.
Any volunteers? Recommendations?
I'll name somebody if not.
Okay, Hanasaka.
Huh? Me?
Next, the piano accompaniment.
Oh, Miss Kagemaru is absent so...
Anyone else want to try?
Recommendations?
Anybody?
Yes! Miss Kita can do it.
She plays piano really well.
I've heard her before.
Miss Kita, how about it?
If there's no one else,
it'll be you or Miss Kagemaru.
We'll discuss this again
when she returns.
Okay, next...
Thin fog covers the harbor where
The ships come in,
white with morning frost
Only the call
of waterfall is heard
The house on the shore
is still silent
When a=3, then y=3x.
- Right.
So, the answer...
No, y=15 so this x...
- Go away!
Cool.
Hey, give it back.
Kunpe!
Crows call out high
in the trees
People are in the fields
treading wheat
How peaceful is this
warm winter day
Flowers blooming out of season
can be seen
You like Natsuko Yamaoka, right?
No, I don't.
- You do!
Good luck!
Wait, I don't.
Your face is red...
Storm blows,
the clouds fall
Winter rain falls,
the day fades
If not for the faint light
leaking through
The village would go unnoticed
We did great.
Yeah. Good job.
It was fun.
I'm exhausted.
Where's Soko?
- Don't know.
Oh.
Here.
Thanks.
Nice place.
Yeah.
Yamaoka?
What?
Can we talk?
Come on.
Been smoking?
What... why? Since when?
Yeah...
Yeah.
Right.
He asked me if you liked anybody now,
so I told him probably not.
You two should go out.
I'm all for it.
Yeah...
He's a nice guy.
Nothing to worry about. You're cute.
Yeah...
Yep.
Bye.
You want some apples?
No. Not now.
I'm home.
Hi, Sachi.
I borrowed that key under the planter.
I think Mom will be back home soon.
Mrs. Kita.
Sachi's in trouble!
Mrs. Kita,
a man was attacking...
It's okay, Sachi.
It's okay...
Mrs. Kita!
Poor Sachi.
This isn't...
Why?
She's finally
coming to school again.
Her father's gone
and her mother tries to die.
Sachi's in pain, too.
We're only in seventh grade.
Why does Sachi
have to suffer so much?
I feel so sorry for her...
Is it true that happiness deserts
anyone who tries to commit suicide?
Does this mean that
Mom can never be happy again?
You're still thirteen,
so you probably should be
dating boy's your age.
I heard that a man
ran out of her house.
Her Mom's boyfriend.
The same one as before?
I heard it's not.
Hey, I heard that he is.
Didn't we agree yesterday
to leave her alone?
Who cares? She's not here listening.
Oh, Sachi.
We have a meeting after school,
so will you wait?
Let's go home together.
I'll be alright.
Go home with Kunpe, then.
Hanasaka's cleaning the clubroom.
Want me to go get him?
Or do you want to?
Yeah.
Okay.
Bye, then.
Bye.
Those rumors about her...
I wonder how much is true?
- I want to know too.
- Don't you?
Natsuko, you know, don't you?
No, I really don't.
I think she'd tell me about it.
Then, why'd you suggest
throwing a party for Sachiko?
Did you think she'd
stop coming again?
Mr. Kyuzo! Where have you been?
Don't!
Don't, you'll get sick.
Okay, by adding hydrogen peroxide
to the manganese dioxide,
a gas is generated.
Now, to find out what this gas
that we've just collected is,
we're going to test it's nature.
Stand back.
Now,
by gradually lowering this...
What do you want?
Have you been avoiding me?
I don't know what's going on,
but tell me
anything that's on your mind.
You're my girlfriend, right?
But, there isn't anything.
A guy from your grade school told me
about your sixth grade teacher,
Ogata...
Wow! It's really growing.
When I saw the charred,
splattered toad I felt sick.
I wonder if you'll laugh and say you
can't understand me anymore?
If all evil is the essence
of human existence,
and if goodness
is state barely not evil...
The thing that appears to be
furthest from the truth...
You're not much of a talker,
are you?
Well, suit yourself.
Behind your seat there's a
brown paper bag.
There's some apples, take one.
You're hungry, aren't you?
No, thanks.
Don't be shy.
You're still young.
Here.
It's not poisoned.
Eat it.
It's good.
But you know, being young is great.
I feel so old...
A dog?
A cat.
It made it across so it was safe.
When they stop from the shock,
splat.
Have you ever had a dog or a cat?
As a pet?
No.
Do you know what it feels like
to be almost hit by a car?
That?
Yes, that's the
Akifaya Nuclear Power Plant.
Hello, Narushima Electric.
Could I speak to
Mr. Satoshi Ogata?
Why?
I didn't say that.
I don't get it...
You're not from around here,
are you?
Ran away?
Excuse me!
Thanks.
I'm not saying running away is bad.
I can really understand.
I mean, I've done it as well.
But if you're gonna get along alone,
you'll need cash, right?
You're really cute.
Hello?!
So, if you want,
I can get you an easy job.
How old are you?
Seventeen?
Why couldn't you forgive yourself,
Mr. Ogata?
What?
Nothing.