Harley Wilkes was your father.
He left you his practice.
We are
at your engagement party.
You know how difficult
this is for me.
Difficult never stopped me.
ON:
This needs to stop;
I can't handle it.
I'm trying to move on,
a-and you won't let me.
OE:
Judson-- he broke up with me.
Yeah, I heard. There
was a town pool-- when
y'all would break up--
and I had, I had 100 bucks
on tonight.
I was trying to
get over someone,
and I shouldn't have
dated, but I wanted to
- because I liked you.
- No one knows
what's gonna happen
between two people.
Until yesterday
I was having such a good time.
Good morning,
Zoe Hart.
You, uh, want
some coffee?
I get it, you're probably trying
to cut back on the caffeine.
You seemed a little wired
recently, Doc.
What's that?
Oh, corn flakes.
Yeah, oh, they
do look good.
I'll have some, too.
I love me some corn flakes.
You do?
You love corn flakes?
I do, yeah.
Great.
Oops.
Oh, here, enjoy
your breakfast.
So I take it you're
still mad at me
for the whole breaking
you and Judson up thing?
So Agnes is baking us a bunch
of sample wedding cakes.
She's going to bake us
caramel chocolate cake,
a chocolate
sour cream cake.
Wait a minute, I thought
you wanted lemon cake.
Honey, I know how much
you like your chocolate.
You would give up
your signature fruit for me?
George Tucker, I'd give
up anything for you.
Thank you.
Give me that-- no, I'm okay.
So, what are
you doing today?
Ooh, I am driving to
Mobile to pick out fabrics
for the bridesmaids' dresses,
I'm meeting with the caterer,
I'm going to reconfirm our
block of rooms at the inn,
and I'm gonna find
Pete Terwilliger
and get him to fix that
wedding invitation typo.
Okay, okay,
you know what?
That-That's, that's
way too much stuff.
Why don't,
why don't you go ahead
and save that for Saturday,
and I can go with you?
And, I don't know,
you can take today off.
I cannot take the day off.
Lemon, now that I know what
you've been dealing with--
finding your mother
with another family and...
I get why you've
been stressed out,
but, baby, let's face it, you
need to blow off some steam,
so...
I... guess I can
use a break.
So why don't you go ahead
and give me that to-do list
that I know you got
in your ourse?
Your list,
the one in your purse.
I don't...
I know there's one
in there.
That's weird, it's not there.
You got a list in there--
I know you do.
All right...
great, great.
Okay, as of right now...
the only thing
on this list...
...is to relax
and have fun.
Yes, relax, have
fun-- I can do that.
All right, I love you, babe.
Love you.
She's gonna blow.
Any minute.
It worked this morning.
Huh, mm.
Ain't that
always the way?
Something seems to be
working perfectly,
then all of a sudden,
it's not.
One minute, you and the
volcano are rock solid.
The next minute, the volcano
won't even return your calls.
Okay, Lavon,
so far today I have heard you
compare Didi to a volcano,
a bowl of grits, and Dash's
pet cockatoo Pickles.
No, no, no,
I said Didi
wasn't like Pickles
because Pickles knows
how to use a damn phone.
I just don't get it.
Things were finally going well
with me and Didi.
Then she runs out,
won't return my calls.
Well, at least you didn't take
your girl out line dancing,
only to have her escape
out the bathroom window.
And I'm a good dancer.
Joelle climbed
out the bathroom window?
When did that happen?
Last night at
Tricky Rick's.
Women-- why are they
so confusing?
What we need...
Hmm.
...is some insight.
Zoe.
What, are you kidding me?
She's the most confounding one
of 'em all.
Still isn't talking to me just
'cause I put a little wager
on her breaking up with, uh--
what's his name?
Judson.
Yeah.
Hello, Lavon.
Lavon, I'll see you later.
Bye.
Listen, Zoe,
I, I need a favor.
Anything.
Well,
as you may know, uh,
Didi and I had a...
romantic encounter
after the
Sweetie Pie dance.
Then, all of a sudden,
she said
she wasn't feeling well
and she left.
Now she won't answer
the phone.
Well, did you do something
to make her angry?
Can you find out for me?
Well, you know, relationships
aren't really my forte.
Just ask Judson.
Please.
For you, my best friend
in BlueBell, I will try.
Ah, thank you.
Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
I will take you to the Rammer
Jammer tonight to thank you.
You take me to the Rammer
Jammer almost every night.
Yes, but tonight
I will let you pay.
Ooh.
AN:
Come experience
the wonders of science.
Mr. Sunberg.
George.
Hey.
Who are you today?
Y-You-You're
Copernicus.
You're Galileo.
Hey, stick around,
you might relearn something.
Gather round, everyone,
gather round,
for I have a rather
weighty subject
that I'd like to discuss.
I am speaking, of
course, about...
gravity.
Mr. Sunberg,
Dash Dewitt for the Blawker,
BlueBell's number one
online gossip site.
We did The Odd Couple
together, Dash,
I know who you are.
Right.
Well, I just have a few
questions about this experiment
that you and your
wife are conducting
later on tonight
in the town square.
I understand
that you're attempting
to communicate with aliens.
Uh, that's really none
of your business, Dash
The experiment we're
conducting is personal.
It doesn't
concern you.
Oh, really?
A teacher who believes he talks
to aliens doesn't concern me?
Well, uh,
my beliefs are not relevant.
If you're telling the aliens
to touch down in BlueBell,
I think the people have
a right to know.
Look, Dash,
I am not talking to the aliens.
They are talking to me!
Say what?
I just can't
believe it.
I mean, the man
seriously thinks
that aliens are really trying
to talk to him.
Yeah, well, I can't say
it surprises me.
Man's been two bricks
short of a load
ever since he married
that crazy-pants wife of his.
Yeah.
Women sure do have a way
of ruining things,
don't they?
I guess that depends
on the woman.
Speaking of which...
Oh, hey, Joelle, you are
looking lovely today.
I'll, uh, talk to
you later, Wade.
What are you doing
here, Joelle,
looking for another window
to climb out?
I know you're mad, okay,
but I had a real good reason
for jumping out that
window last night.
Oh, do tell.
I'm on the run.
From who?
My ex-boyfriend Ed.
See, things
didn't exactly
end well between us, and I
sort of set his lawn on fire.
You, you sort of set
his lawn on fire?
I didn't mean to,
but, you know, with the
dry season and all...
Anyway,
Ed got his pal the sheriff to
issue a warrant for my arrest,
so I hightailed
it to Georgia,
which is where I'm
supposed to be right now.
So why do you have
to leave?
'Cause last night Ed
came into Tricky Rick's,
and I think he saw me,
so now that he's
on my trail again,
he's not gonna stop till he
finds me and puts me in jail.
I'm sorry, Wade.
I really thought we could
have been something.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
now hold on a minute, hold on.
If he only caught
a glimpse of you,
he can't be sure
what he saw,
so all we got to do is
find the guy and, uh,
convince him
it wasn't you.
Sweetie,
you don't want to get
mixed up in this.
Ed finds out you're
involved with me
and he will be
all over you.
Trust me, okay,
look, just, uh,
just go back
over to my place,
hide out,
and I'll figure this out.
Okay.
Thanks, Wade.
All right.
Mmm.
Lemon is set
on having dinner served,
but then people got
to wait for their food
and there's not enough time
for dancing.
Know what I mean?
It's true, dancing is fun.
Yeah, but then, you know,
if we have a buffet,
then people-- they got,
they got to wait in line,
so...
People hate lines.
Yeah, they...
Oh, hey, Zoe, what
are you doing here?
Uh, well,
since Addy and Brick
are doing
a mobile vaccine clinic,
Tom Long is filling in
at the reception desk.
This has to be the
highlight of his year.
That's exactly what he wrote
in his e-mail to me.
Well, you are more than
welcome to hide out here
as long as you need to.
Thanks, pal,
I appreciate the safe haven.
George, George,
school board just fired me.
All the man did
was tell the truth.
He is a vehicle for
extraterrestrial contact.
Don't worry, Dotty,
George is gonna fix this.
Aren't you,
George?
Uh, y-yeah.
Yeah, I'm going to,
I'm going to do my...
You know what? This
is probably a talk
we should have
in my office.
It's always interesting
around here.
You know
what's interesting?
This Kardashian sister.
Yep.
She finally connects
with someone,
thinks things are going great
when suddenly...
he doesn't call her.
Poor Kardashian.
Actually, Khloe is
very happily married,
but I see
your point.
Okay, I have to
tell someone.
Yes, I'm
ignoring Lavon,
but you would, too, if
you knew what I know.
Please don't tell me it's
some weird, kinky sex thing.
It's worse.
I found this hidden
under his desk.
Under his desk?
Hidden.
He told me recently
that he's hung up
on someone, and I think
that someone is Lemon.
Shh.
What should I do?
Should I
tell George?
That poor, sweet man is
planning their wedding.
Wait, don't tell
anyone anything, okay?
I'm sure that there's a
logical explanation for this.
I'm gonna find out
what it is.
Transcript by Addic7ed.com
Sync by flapinha
AN:
Look, I'd be perfectly willing
to write
the grant proposal myself,
but time is running out.
Okay, okay, so we'll call
an emergency session
of the town council
and have it approved.
I'm sure we can
get that...
Lavon!
Oh.
Hi, um, can I have a quick word?
Zoe, I'm in a meeting.
It's important.
It's about that fruit problem
we're having.
Our oranges,
especially our Lemons.
Uh, I'll be
right back.
What do you mean
talking about lemons?
Didi has been
avoiding me because
she found this...
hidden under your desk.
Oh, my God.
I forgot that
was under there.
What was it doing there, Lavon?
Please tell me
it doesn't mean
what I think it might.
Look, Zoe, just
forget you saw this...
Forget? You have a picture
of Lemon hidden in your office,
which indicates more than
a mayoral relationship.
And I don't hear any denials.
I-It's over.
"It's over"?
Wait, you mean, like,
it was not over?
It was a thing?
You and Lemon?
Oh, my God.
Does George know?
No. And he can't know.
No one can ever know.
But Didi already does.
Mayor... Mayor Hayes,
we've got a deadline.
Right. I'm-I'm sorry.
I'm coming.
All right.
Okay, l-look, Zoe, I'm...
I am gonna tell you everything,
I want to tell you everything,
but right now you have got
to cover with Didi. Please.
I can't just lie to her.
This gets out,
it will hurt
a whole lot of good
people, myself included.
I'm sorry for putting
you in this position,
but you have got
to keep this secret.
You don't know what
you're asking me.
Zoe, as your friend,
I'm begging you. Please.
Okay.
Thank you.
Okay, uh...
IC:
Look, George, I know
this may sound crazy, and
I don't blame you for being
a nonbeliever-- I was a
nonbeliever before I met Dotty.
But a year ago, I convinced him
to come to Roswell with me
and participate
in this experiment...
And the very next night
I had a dream
that I was taken up into space.
He thought
he had a dream.
And then about
a month later,
I started having
these episodes
where I would lose
control of my tongue,
like somebody was trying
to talk through me,
and my arms
would go numb.
It's like they're trying
to talk to us in code.
Okay.
Have you...
considered
a medical explanation?
Of course. I've been
to Mobile, and I went
to doctor after doctor,
but no one could find
the explanation
as to what was
happening with me.
Eric can't
really be fired
for his beliefs, can he?
If he kept them to himself,
no, he couldn't be.
But unfortunately,
he talked about them
at an official school function.
George, you know
what teaching means to me.
There has to be
something you can do.
Hey, sweetheart.
Almost finished?
I'm sorry to have
to do this to you, baby,
but I'm gonna have
to cancel dinner tonight.
I've got to mount an entire
defense to the school board
for Eric Sunberg
by 10:00 a.m. tomorrow morning.
Oh, it's okay.
Don't you worry about me.
Okay.
How's the day of fun going?
So good.
I'm having the best time.
Ah.
Right.
What are you doing right now?
Picking bridesmaids' fabrics.
Lemon!
Oh, Lemon,
I am disappointed, okay?
You were supposed
to be relaxing.
Fine, George, fine.
Next time you see me,
I will be so relaxel,
you'll just think that
I've joined a reggae band.
So, did you talk to Lavon?
I didn't need to.
Look, Didi,
the truth is...
the picture's mine.
I-I took it
from Lemon's house
when I was trying
to be a Belle.
Yours?
Well, why didn't you say
so in the first place?
Because...
I was embarrassed.
Thank you. I've been wanting
to fit in to BlueBell,
and I figured Lemon,
queen of this town, was key.
And if I studied her--
the way she did her hair
and how she dressed-- then
maybe I could fit in, too.
You haven't done anything
at all to be like her.
I tried.
In my house,
by myself.
Then I realized
it was futile,
you know, because Lemon...
well, she's perfect,
and I could never achieve
that level of wonderfulness.
'Cause, you know,
she's so pretty
with that blonde hair.
But why'd you hide the
picture under Lavon's desk?
Well...
I was looking at it,
like I do, in Lavon's study
when I thought I
heard someone coming.
So I hid it.
Because, you know, I don't
want anyone to know--
especially Lemon.
Because of what I said--
you know, she's so perfect,
so pretty.
I think I get it.
This happened
with my cousin Donna
and her gym teacher.
And I am so glad
you feel you could
confide in me.
Thank you.
I'm just so relieved!
Now things can
finally get back to normal--
'cause I didn't know
how I was gonna keep
working at that office
knowing this terrible secret
about George's fiancée.
Yeah, that would've been hard.
He's the sweetest
man I've ever known.
Besides Lavon.
And I don't think
I could've lived with myself
had I kept it from him.
You know?
Well, lucky for you,
you don't have to.
Hey, you two.
Hey,
George!
You still
hiding out
from, uh, Tom?
Yeah.
I should get back, though.
It was good to see you.
Good-bye.
Okay. See ya.
Oh, yeah.
YOGA TEACHER
In Warrior pose.
No.
No, the seafood option
should be local.
YOGA TEACHER
Cartwheel down...
into Plank pose.
Ugh!
Lemon, what is wrong with you?
It is just so great
to finally see you in action.
Doing your doctor thing.
Just restocking
the shelves.
Uh, yeah, well, you're
doing it super awesomely.
You think
I'm doing a good job?
Well, yeah,
sure, I guess.
You're answering the
phones, and you got me
that coffee that I wanted.
Oh... oh, I forgot.
Uh, you missed a phone call
from George Tucker
a while ago.
What?
What did you tell him?
That... you...
weren't here.
Oh, good.
That is good.
Whew!
Always tell George
that I'm not here, okay?
Zoe Hart left the building.
Hey, Zoe? Um,
this is... this is
Eric and Dotty Sunberg,
and... we have a little bit
of a situation here.
The board refused to drop
the charges, but I figure
if I can prove that there's
a medical explanation for it,
I might be able
to get him his job back.
I'll get a history on him
and I'll run some tests.
Call you later.
Or better yet, e-mail.
I-I know Mr. Sunberg can
be a little bit kooky,
but he made a major
impact on my life.
So I... just want to
thank you for doing this.
I knew I could
count on you.
You're a... you're
a really great friend.
You, too. I'm
sure that you have
a ton of work to do,
so I'll see you around.
Oh, don't worry about me--
I'm gonna be here
until we find out
what's wrong with him.
Okay.
The initial test
results are in,
and everything confirms what
the doctors in Mobile found.
Mr. Sunberg
is perfectly healthy.
Even the mental evaluation
didn't raise any flags.
Yeah, you see, George?
No earthly explanation.
Am I the only one
who just got chills?
Dr. Hart, can we have just a...
just a quick word?
I'd rather we didn't.
What?
What? Nothing.
So what's our
next step here?
I mean, CT scan
or an MRI or...?
Well, he's already had all
those tests done in Mobile.
Maybe you should consider
that Mr. Sunberg made
the whole thing up.
Why would he make it up?
Maybe the story
makes him a celebrity
at Star Trek conventions.
I don't know, George.
Sometimes people just lie.
Even the people we think
we know and like.
Th-Th-The aliens are talking.
Right pupil is nonreactive.
You can't fake
nonreactive pupils.
So I guess he's not lying.
DE:
No, Joelle,
you do not have
to shave your head.
Or leave town.
Look, just let me
figure this out, okay?
Bartender?
I will have a mint julep,
please.
What? It's a perfectly
respectable drink.
Yeah. If you're a hundred.
Lemon...
what are you doing here,
middle of the day?
Shouldn't you be off,
you know, bossing someone
around somewhere?
I... took the day off.
Day off from what?
Very funny.
George made me.
"Relax, have fun,"
he said, you know?
But I couldn't,
Wade, I couldn't.
Lying there doing
nothing just made my
brain go into hyper-drive,
and it just made me
more stressed out
than I already was.
Oh, I didn't order this.
Yeah, well,
mint julep won't
cure what ails you.
Lemon, you know
how to have fun.
All you got to do is,
you know... let go.
Can't.
Turns out Lemon Breeland
is just as anal and uptight
as everyone thinks.
Well, then...
maybe you should stop being
Lemon Breeland for a night.
Wade.
Wade!
Hmm?
What?
No one's ever gonna
believe I'm Joelle.
Look at me.
I am.
You look exactly
like Joelle.
Damn, woman, you're hot!
Shut up.
I will not.
Come on, let's go.
Mmm! Rrr! Mmm!
Hey, Zoe...
Didi came over and apologized.
We're back together.
Fantastic.
Hey, Zoe,
um... Oh.
Sorry, I didn't...
realize you had company.
Hey, Lavon.
I'll just...
And George--
you remember George, right?
Sweetest man in town?
Look, Zoe,
um...
I'd like to tell you everything.
Can we please just
take a walk and talk?
I'm not in the mood to talk.
I've already lied to Didi,
I'm lying to George.
You've put me
in a terrible position.
Thanks, Lavon.
Thanks a lot.
Anything?
Unfortunately, no.
Zoe, come on.
Hello!
I brought snacks.
In honor of our Zoe's
cultural heritage... bagels!
Or biscuits with
the middle cut out.
Well, it looks
delicious,
Tom, thank you so much.
You really are a nice
guy, aren't you?
Honey, you should
eat and drink something, too,
what with all that blood
they took.
Dotty, you got to get going
if you're gonna conduct
the experiment.
I'll be back
as soon as I get
the data we need.
But drink your juice.
All right.
Mr. Sunberg, do you
drink juice often?
I do.
May I?
That tattoo, it's fading.
Where did you get it?
Well, I got that
on my wedding day.
We were down in this
tiny town in Mexico.
You know, it seemed
like the thing to do.
Actually kind of gives me a
tough-guy rep with the kids,
which is cool.
I have a feeling it may have
given you more than that.
I think your tattoo may have
given you lead poisoning.
Stop, stop, stop.
This is a bad idea.
We're gonna get found out.
We're gonna get
ourselves killed.
Lemon, you've watched too
many Patrick Swayze movies.
Now, you were
the one who said
you didn't want to be
Lemon for a night.
Well, this is your chance.
Lemon,
we're in Fairhope; nobody
knows who you are.
They don't?
You know, I don't like
the sound of that.
I bet they've heard of me, okay?
No. Look, all we
need to do is find
this Ed guy, and then convince
him that you were the one
who was here with
me last night, okay?
Then you can go home
and you can make lists
and you can order
people around
or whatever it is that
you do to have fun.
No, no, what, what...
Lemon, Lemon.
What?
You are no longer
uptight Lemon Breeland.
You are super fun
Roxy Rumley.
Yeah, who
apparently isn't
scared of getting hepatitis.
Yo, Bobby, beer me.
Sure thing, Ed, my boy.
And, uh, we'll take two
down here.
Hey, weren't you
in here last night
with a girl named Joelle?
Well, you're right that I was
here, uh, last night, but, uh...
But my sugar lips
was with me.
Hm?
And my name is Roxy.
Yes, it is.
Roxy.
Mm-hmm.
My mistake.
Y'all have a good night now.
It happens; take it easy.
Sugar lips?
Oh, my God, just tried to
think of, like, something
I would never say
in a million years,
and "sugar lips"
just kind of came right out.
It was just so spontaneous!
Just so exciting.
The good news is,
I think he bought it.
We can split.
Wait.
You know what else Lemon
really would never do?
I really don't want to know.
Shots with Wade Kinsella.
Bobby!
Line them up!
The chelation challenge
confirms it.
Lead poisoning.
You are so smart.
How did you know?
Well, juice can have
traces of lead.
For most people,
it's no problem.
But for someone whose body is
already filled with toxins
from a lead tattoo, it can
exacerbate the symptoms.
Say it again.
The good news is that lead
poisoning is easily treatable,
so, Mr.Sunberg,
you should be fine.
The good news
for you is that lead can cause
any number
of neurological symptoms.
Like making you believe that you
were being controlled by aliens.
Wait, what?
Look,
all we got to do is tell
the school board that you
had a medical condition.
And as long as you promise not
to talk about UFOs and the like
at any school functions,
then we're gonna get
you your job back.
So, you're telling me
that there is no chance at all
that my spells were caused
by extraterrestrials?
You are 100% alien-free.
Zoe, thank you so much.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go get some dinner,
and then I will be back
in a while to check on you.
George, I'm sure you
have to hurry off
and go write some torts
or briefs or something.
See you.
Hey, Zoe.
Hey, wait up.
Hey!
Jeez, I didn't realize
how fast you walked
with those little
legs of yours.
Oh, you know us New Yorkers.
Hey, George, I got
your Save the Date.
I'll see you there.
Oh. Great.
So, your Save the
Dates went out, huh?
That's why you've been acting
so strange today, isn't it?
What?
You didn't get a
Save the Date.
Um, I am so sorry.
Oh, yeah, that's-that's
why I've been weird.
Look, Zoe.
I really want you to know that
I do consider you a friend.
It's just, the wedding,
you know, is...
I just want that to be
Lemon's special day.
I hope you understand.
So, you guys are doing
well, then, huh?
Yeah, we're doing great.
Actually, I mean,
we had a rough patch after
the holidays, but she finally
told me about some things
that had been going on.
Really?
She told you some things?
Yeah. Yeah, she had, um...
some problems with her family.
And, you know, she'd
been dealing with that,
but then she finally
decided to tell me,
and now that she has,
it's brought us
a lot closer, you know,
and being a lawyer, I see
people split up all the time,
you know, because they can't
be open with their partners.
So, it feels good, to know that
we're gonna walk down the aisle
without a secret
between us, you know?
I'm really happy for you.
Oh, sorry.
Wade.
Hi, Wade.
Wait, who's-who's Roxy?
Wait, what are
you talking...
What? No, don't, just...
You just, you stay there.
You st... I'll be right there!
I'm sorry, I got to go.
Uh, we'll talk
tomorrow? Yeah?
Okay.
This is George Tucker;
please leave a message.
Hey, George, it's Zoe.
Can you call me
when you have a chance?
There's something
I need to tell you.
Okay, you know, time to go.
Why? This is so fun.
I'm having so much fun.
Lemon, you're drunk, okay?
Who's Lemon?
My name is Roxy.
And Roxy wants
one more dance.
You get one more dance, one
more, and then we're leaving.
All right?
Thank you, sugar lips.
Whatever.
How are you feeling?
De-alienated.
Hey, can I ask you a favor?
Sure.
Well, if my wife asks,
don't tell her that
it was the tattoo
that gave me lead poisoning.
I don't have to tell her
anything you don't want me to.
But why?
I'm going to tell her
that it was
an extraterrestrial
implantation device
that gave me
lead poisoning,
and that you
removed it
and gave it to
the authorities.
Why would you do that?
Dr. Hart, I know
our beliefs may sound silly.
They sounded silly to me...
before I met Dotty.
And then she sold me.
Believing something
else is out there--
it's what makes
Dotty and me us.
We're happy.
So, if a little lie
keeps us going,
you know,
who's to say that's wrong?
You know, you should be
real thankful you got Roxy
and not Joelle.
'Cause that girl is crazy.
I was all set to
propose and everything,
and then she saw me talking
to my female neighbor,
talking, and that crazy girl
set my clothes on fire.
But you got a keeper
here, my friend.
To Roxy!
To Roxy.
Thank you, Lemon.
You were... You went
above and beyond.
You deserve better, you know.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about Joelle.
Burning a man's clothes
'cause she was jealous?
Yeah, she's real
classy with a K.
Well, thank you, uh,
but you're drunk.
I am.
But drunk or not,
Wade, I know you.
We were friends once,
in high school.
I always thought that you'd
rise above your upbringing
and have a life as
big as your heart.
I believe that
you deserve better,
even if you think you don't.
Oh, what?
"Achy Breaky Heart" look out!
Whoo!
You have got to help me.
Okay? I cannot get her
off the dance floor .
I bet.
And she's, no, she's
gonna blow our cover.
George, just remember
to call her...
Roxy. Roxy, I got it.
Oh, Georgie!
Roxy, I think it's time
about time to go home.
Let's just go, let's go.
Oh, come on.
Just do one dance with me.
Hey, everyone, this
is my fiancé, George!
Wait. I thought
she's with you.
Well, see that's an
interesting question.
Uh, it's-it's a
bit complicated.
Wait a minute.
You're George Tucker.
You defended my cousin
last year for tax evasion.
Uh...
Yeah. Nice
to see you.
See, my fiancé-- he's a genius.
Okay?
You should come to our wedding!
Shouldn't he?
I mean, y'all should come
to our wedding.
What? Wedding?
Yeah.
Oh, you lying
son of a...
Okay, run! Run!
Run! Run! Run!
Come on, come on!
Okay, look, you can tell
whoever you want to,
but please, first,
let me explain.
I'm not sure I want to hear
the sordid details, Lavon.
It wasn't sordid.
We were in love.
You were in love?
At least I was.
It started
around Christmas
last year.
Lemon was going
through a hard time,
George was in New York,
and I was just trying
to be a good friend.
But then,
something happened.
We just...
ran to each other
like it was home.
We would, uh, just
get in the car
and just drive,
no idea where we were going.
Sometimes we'd end up
at the beach,
sometimes the woods,
sometimes
some small town.
For the first
and only time
in my life I was in love,
and, uh...
I saw a future
with us together.
So, what happened?
Six weeks in,
George came home...
unexpectedly,
and I was
sure she was gonna
tell him the truth,
that things were over
between them.
But she didn't.
He proposed,
and she chose George...
instead of me.
I'm sorry.
And my heart broke.
My God.
Yeah, I don't know.
I mean, maybe, uh,
she made the right decision.
I mean, they-they...
they seem happy together.
They do.
Okay, look, if you... if you
need to tell George the truth...
I'll understand.
Do whatever
you think is right.
Hello.
Hey, Zoe. Um, sorry it took me
so long to get back to you.
What was it
you needed to tell me?
Yeah, George, um...
If Mrs. Sunberg asks,
can you tell her
the lead poisoning came
from an alien implant?
Well, okay, then.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay.
Bye.
How'd it go?
Did you find Ed?
Yeah. Yeah, I found him.
Had a nice little chat, too.
Tell me again why you, uh,
why you burned his lawn?
What did he tell you?
Enough.
Look, Joelle, I...
I think maybe you ought to, uh,
head back to Georgia after all.
You're breaking up with me?
Yup.
Yeah, I am.
Just need a little less crazy
in my life right now.
Crazy?!
Um...
I'll show you crazy!
Now, now, hold on.
That might not have
been the word I was...
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Do not...
Oh, my God.
You... No.
No, do not smash that!
Oh, I'm not
gonna smash it.
Don't worry.
Put the lighter down.
- Say good-bye!
- Lighter down!
I'd love for you
to try...
That's my favorite...
Don't you call me crazy!
Maybe we should
go help him?
No, I think Wade can
take care of himself.
What about you?
How you feeling?
You need, uh...
you need aspirin?
Mm, no, I feel great.
Oh.
Feel electric.
Oh. Oh.
Okay.
My God, it has been so long
since I have just
let loose like that.
I had no idea
how much I needed it.
Thank you.
Oh, no, don't thank me.
I just really simply
said, uh, "Relax."
I didn't say, "Get sloppy
drunk and go dancing
under a fake name at a
roadhouse with Wade Kinsella."
Well, you know me.
I never do anything halfway.
Yeah.
Well, I guess, tomorrow,
it's back to real life.
I guess so.
Well, I, for one,
am not ready to say good-bye
to Roxy Rumley just yet.
Hmm.
What are you
thinking about?
Well, why don't you follow me
and find out?
Hey, Dr. Hart!
Thanks for all
your help.
Too bad the Feds
showed up so soon
and took that device away.
I know. Damn Feds!
Hey.
You know, I realize
that I can never presume
to know what makes
a couple tick.
Maybe George and Lemon
will live happily ever after,
and the secret
will never come out.
All I know is,
it's not my place to tell him.
I'm sorry I ever put you
in this position.
You're in a tough position, too.
Yeah.
Can't be easy to see
the two of them together.
No.
Do you still love her?
Sometimes I think I might.
Sometimes I think I'm over it.
All I know--
I... I'm just trying to move on.
Oh, this is
the best day ever!
I didn't think
about anything.
I just was totally
in the moment.
I just went where
the day took me.
I wish every day
could be like this.
Oh, George,
we're not even 30 years old.
We have the whole world right
in... right in front of us.
Why don't we just be
running hell-bent towards it?
We shouldn't be sitting here,
waiting and planning.
That's not life, George.
This is life.
You and me, right here,
right now.
What are you saying?
Let's elope.
Really?
Yeah.
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net