Hello? Dad?
What? Leukemia?!
I understand.
Lili!
Doctor, what exactly is her condition?
I can handle the results.
If it's really leukemia,
how many years do I have?
Every sickness is different,
but generally the chance of surviving 5 years is 10%.
So that means
I have 5 years, at most.
No!
Lili, don't worry. It's alright.
Yes, Lili. Take care of yourself, be more optimistic.
When your mother fell ill,
didn't they keep saying there was a low chance it could be cured?
But hasn't she been doing well?
There are medical advances everyday.
My mom won't be able to handle it when she hears I'm sick.
Don't worry about your mom. I'll take care of her.
You need to take good care of yourself.
Take it easy. Don't worry.
No matter how hard it might be,
I'll do whatever it takes
to help you through this crisis.
The cause of cancer is extremely complex.
But, based on your situation,
it's probably hereditary.
Uncle Liu, when you married my mom
did you know about this?
She and I may become a large burden on you.
A life-long burden.
I'm more than happy
to look after you two.
I'd be happy.
Coming!
How come you three all come back together?
I have something in the oven.
Mom!
Lili, what's wrong?
- Aunt Li-- Don't.
It's all Qianren's fault.
Qianren's company started an initiative to find errors,
He scolded Lili harshly in front of everybody.
Of course Lili feels wronged.
I asked what happened downstairs just now.
I, I told him off, too.
Lili. Is it necessary to cry like this?
What really happened?
Sorry, Aunt Li. I was definitely in a bad mood today.
Once this came up, I couldn't control my temper.
I upset Lili today.
Don't worry. I'll look after her in the future.
I'll never upset her again.
Such a silly child.
Wasn't it just criticism on your work?
What's the big deal?
Qianren is stern so you'll do better in the future.
Alright, alright. Don't cry.
If you keep crying, I will scold you.
Aunt Li, don't scold Lili.
Let her cry to her heart's content today.
Tomorrow is a new day.
- Lili.- Mom.
We haven't spoken in awhile.
Let's sleep together today, ok?
Of course, tonight
mom will sleep with you.
The soup will all boil off soon.
Mom, I'll help you.
You have to help Lili keep her illness a secret.
Especially from her mom.
Dad, when you got married to Aunt Li,
you didn't worry her illness might relapse?
If I say I wasn't, I'd be lying.
But being with her everyday
makes me happy. That's most important.
But, you knew all along about Lili's hereditary history.
You don't mind one bit?
Lili is Aunt Li's daughter.
I love her like I love you. Why would I mind?
When you love someone, you love everything about them.
Qianren, wait until the day you sincerely fall in love.
You'll experience the same feeling.
Dad, I want to discuss something with you.
I want to take care of Lili.
As more than siblings.
I want to take care of her for the rest of my life.
If you sincerely and truly mean that,
I support you.
Thank you, dad.
Mom.
It's been a long time since I slept under the same blanket as you.
I miss the time when I would make my way into your covers everyday.
You're so old and still acting spoiled.
Mom.
Do you remember right after dad died
every night you would sit by my bed
and lull me to sleep?
Sometimes, when you thought I was asleep,
you would break down and secretly cry.
How did you make it through then?
When your dad passed,
I felt like the sky would collapse.
When your father was alive, I couldn't even cook.
Let alone change a light bulb or fix the water heater.
Many times, I thought
about leaving with your father.
But looking at you, I absolutely couldn't leave you.
I could only carry on making you food, washing your clothes,
watch you laugh, watch you cry.
And life went on like that.
Sometimes, I think that old saying makes a lot of sense.
Between husband and wife, the first one to leave
suffers less.
And the one left behind, every day, every month,
lives in suffering.
I'll be with you a lifetime, we'll never be apart.
Whether we go to heaven or hell,
I will always be with you.
If I make him watch me
slowly walking towards death, what will
Pei Shangxuan's life become?
Anyway, luckily,
I met Uncle Liu.
Unlce Liu is a good person.
Yes. During the most difficult time of my life,
meeting your Uncle Liu
used all my life's luck.
But I'm most grateful for the change in Qianren.
When I got sick this time, he not only found a specialist
but brought me medicine. While doing so many nice things,
he never brought it up once.
He's really a good kid.
Lili, in the future you have to repay
Uncle Liu and Brother Qianran.
Li Jun was just here.
She dropped those off and left
not long ago.
Jun
Hello? Jun. You came by.
I returned all the stuff you gave me.
Since we're over, there's no need to keep them.
I've returned them to you, cut things off cleanly.
I won't take back the things I gave you.
Keep them as souvenirs.
If you really don't want them,
throw them away.
Why don't you throw them out yourself?
Also, throw out that necklace I gave you.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by Timeless Lovebirds Team @ Viki
Daniel Music Studio
Where did you go, young man?
I thought that you went missing, I almost
cancelled all your afternoon appointments.
Da Wei, those advertisements have lost their meaning.
I've decided to go to Korea and experience some more.
Really? That's great!
Could you please immediately prepare the plane tickets and the contract,
before I regret this.
I'll go do it now!
Dating me, won't it be hard?
Of course not.
This is so thrilling!
I shall wear the "Golden Hoop" (used in the novel "Journey to the West" to keep the Monkey King under control)
so that I'll think about my girlfriend everywhere and at any time.
At least you know.
This is the string pulling the kite.
When you see it, you'll think of its owner.
-Let me put it on for you.-Okay.
I'm done.
Everything has ended. Good bye.
I worked so hard to get here
I never thought, before accomplishing anything,
I have to leave.
Lili, your newest design plan received great customer reviews.
First, recover.
The future is full of possibilities.
You don't need to console me.
I know my situation.
I've already contacted the best hospital in Beijing.
They're researching a new form of treatment.
If you can't recover,
they might at least extend your life
until the medicine is more advanced.
You can turn this around.
Why are you wasting your energy on someone who's going to die?
I just want to leave quietly.
Those pointless hopes can only bring me and my loved ones
even more suffering.
I don't want you to die.
We're a family.
Not just me, your mom and my dad.
Especially your mom.
Do you plan to keep hiding the truth from her?
Then one day, we suddenly tell her you're gone.
Tell her there was a chance you could have survived.
But you didn't tell her.
Wait until the parent sends off the child.
Do you think she will accept it?
You think she won't suffer this way?
Aunt Li is a great woman.
She's already suffered too much in this life.
Her only source of strength to continue is you.
So, Lili, if you aren't a selfish girl
put in your best effort.
For this family,
for you mom. You must strive to live.
Help me set up going to Beijing.
And, before deciding on surgery,
besides you and Uncle Liu,
I don't want anyone else to know.
Including him?
Lili, why did you suddenly quit? We can't bear to see you go.
Yeah, you're the best out of all the new people. Keep it up!
Lili, you're the best. Good luck.
Lili, we have faith in you. Good luck!
Good luck.
Thank you for looking after me.
No problem.
Yichen, today is my last day at Aochuang. I want-
Sister Li, I was looking forward to working with you.
I never thought you'd be leaving. It's too sudden, too unbearable.
No matter if what you said is true or fake,
the past is the past.
There's no need to be angry at someone you'll never see again.
It's meaningless.
Lili, you're really leaving.
Because I'm transferring for work
I might have to move to another city.
This room...
Why don't you find another girl to room with?
I don't want to.
This place will always be reserved for my best friend, Lili.
That day you came home drunk scared me.
Are you and Daniel really going to leave it like this?
It's nothing I can't bear.
Jun,
You're the most thick-skinned girl I've met ever in my life.
I hope you make full use of this talent
to quickly forget that bad guy, Daniel.
As long as you're on my side,
even if I'm faced with greater difficulties, I can immediately respawn with full health.
Boys come and go, best friends are forever.
You're the best.
Oh yeah. If you're going away for work,
what will Pei Shangxuan do?
Long distance makes cheating more likely. You have to be careful.
I know.
Lili, are you here?
Speak of the devil.
Are you there, Lili?
LIli.
Where did you run off to? Did you know if I hadn't found you, I was going to the police station?
I'm fine, I was just too busy with work.
Is there something wrong?
Your face is so pale. Are you alright?
I'm great. I told you before
about the company sending people to Beijing.
They've decided that they want me to go.
What's your decision?
I think it's a good opportunity.
I can come into contact with resources of top industrial insiders.
I don't want to give this up.
But, if I go, it'll probably be for a long time.
My future work and even my whole life
might all move to Beijing.
I've thought about it,
it's not fair to you.
- So...- Silly girl.
What are you thinking? Leaving such a handsome boyfriend all alone in Shanghai,
and going by yourself to Beijing,
Aren't you afraid that someone else will take this opportunity and take your place?
I'm afraid that you're going to have to suffer in an unfamiliar environment.
Don't think too much, I'll go with you.
No, you just started your business,
all of your resources are here.
If you go to Beijing,
you'll have to start over again.
Don't forget, if it wasn't for you,
I would still be working at the bar right now.
You pulled me out of the mire and gave me a life full of hope.
So no matter where you go,
wherever you go is my next destination.
You've already done enough for me.
You should think more about yourself.
Your world is so big, it doesn't just have me in it.
What if one day...I were to leave this world before you...
Then that would be my last day in this world.
Without you, what's the point for me living by myself?
How about going to be with you.
If not, I'll be a living like a zombie.
You musn't.
I forbid you from having such silly thoughts!
No matter what happens, you have to continue to live well.
Otherwise, how could I leave this world in peace?
Li Li, what's wrong?
You're talking so strangely, as if we were to part and never meet again.
Are you sure you are okay?
It's probably because I'm about to go to Beijing.
Farewells always make one feel hurt.
Look at yourself.
Then when are you leaving for Beijing?
After I take care of some matters for the company, I'll go find you.
The date isn't set yet.
Northern winters aren't like Southern winters. Even if winter is over, it still won't warm up as quickly.
When the time comes, tell me in advance, I'll help you--
Don't you worry about these things, the company will take care of it.
But you
When I' not around
you have to take care of yourself.
This is my biggest wish.
Idiot.
Aren't we going to see each other very soon?
Li Li
Eat by yourself. Such good dishes, why don't you eat more?
Li Li, are you okay? You don't look too well.
Look at you, white as a sheet of paper
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I'm just worried about company things.
Really?
Auntie Li,
the company wanted to send some capable workers off to Beijing.
Li Li was chosen because CEO Lao admired her.
Leaving home to another place for work is a big thing.
She's probably feeling indecisive about that.
Going so far as Beijing.
When you want to come back home on New Year's day or other festivals, you'll run into increased passenger transportation.
Then the days when we mother and daughter can see each other will decrease even more.
Mei Qing, look at yourself.
Li Li just graduated not long ago and already got recognized in a leading position.
You should be happy for her, right?
As parents, don't we want the best for our children?
You're men, how can you understand the feelings of mother and daughter?
Ever since Li Li moved out,
I always look forward to her coming home every weekend to eat.
But now she's going so far away,
I won't even have a chance to wish such a thing anymore.
Listen to what you are saying,
Beijing, Beijing isn't that far. It's not overseas.
If you miss Li Li that much, we can...we can move to Beijing.
That's right, Aunty Li.
And this time I've also been assigned to Beijing.
If you and Dad want to go, then we can all go as a family.
Living there is also very convenient and there are lot of places that are worth to visit.
Like the Bird's Nest (Beijing 2008 Olympic stadium), the Water Cube (National Aquatics Center), the Great Wall or the Forbidden City. You two can go to all these places.
Mom, I will miss you.
But I have to go.
Enough,
just accept it, okay?
You guys are so in tune (working together), I can't object even if I want to.
Then you go. Our family will go together.
Okay.
Let's go as a family.
Come, eat.
You also eat some prawns.
♫ Do you still remember the images left on the window after the rain? ♫
♫ The diary entries are all about us two. ♫
♫ How are you today? ♫
♫ I’m talking to you while separated by the sky. ♫
♫ Can you let me walk you home again? ♫
♫ My thoughts are transparent and my words are clear. My racing heart is the answer.♫
♫ Your smile can light up the wishes under the night sky. ♫
♫ It might be because I don’t know how to express myself. ♫
♫ My fingertips replace♫
♫ the hidden words that I wanted to say. ♫
♫ I wrote you down in my years of youth. ♫
♫ It’s reflected on the edges of the windowsills. ♫
♫ I'm thinking of you every day, every year, every winter to summer. ♫ [Pei Shang Xuan, I won't be able to like you again this year.]
♫ It drifted into the next harbor. ♫
♫ Looking for your direction in life while carrying dreams. ♫
♫ I’m used to having you beside me, ♫
♫ looking for your direction in life while carrying dreams. ♫
Li Li, Li Li Are you home? Li Li
Li Li
Auntie, can I ask you
where is the family on the second floor?
Oh, you're talking about the Liu family?
They moved out.
Heard that their children found work out of town.
The parents followed to retire.
Ey, then do you have their contact information?
Oh this child.
How can I have their contact information?
Sorry, the number you dialed has turned off their phone. Please call again later.
Where have you gone?
Here, drink it while it's hot.
I don't want to drink.
You have to eat something for your body to get better.
The tour I booked for Aunty Li at most only has half a month left.
If you mother sees you ill after coming here,
then I can only tell her the truth.
Stop telling me more,
I'll Drink.
Here.
Here, I'll go with you to the bathroom.
You go.
Go out.
It's really boring staying in hospital, isn't it?
Do you want me to bring you some books?
Then you rest for a bit. I'll bring you some water.
Cover yourself well.
Birds.
What did you say?
Will you get me some paper and pen?
Okay.
♫ It must have been hard for you to make this decision, too. ♫
♫ What do I need to say? ♫
♫ You probably understand me. ♫
♫ Pretend to be strong, you understand me. Don’t let it be exposed. ♫
♫ So many promises can’t be fulfilled together, ♫
♫ but a promise needs to be taken seriously by one person. ♫
♫ I will be fine. ♫
Someone once told me that people who do not miss the past
♫ I’ll work harder to make myself ♫ -are those that have never experienced a devastating farewell.
Li Li, when you left, I looked for you like crazy.
I looked in every corner where our memories are hidden.
I finally believed that I lost my Li Li.
Did you know?
"None Off the Field" got another seven teams today.
-I'm working hard to make them better.
But next year, can we go see the migratory birds together?
I want to become a free bird in my next life.
Not being confined by any bonds. Even if I'll die far away.
The feathers that I leave will also prove that I have been to this world.
Li Li, you didn't listen to me again. Why are you out here painting when it's this cold out?
Hurry and put this over yourself. What happens if you get cold?
I'm about to be bored to death just sitting in the hospital room all day.
I wanted to finish painting this today because it was sunny out.
I heard that there's a migratory birds painting exhibition recently. Maybe you can go and try.
To contribute? I don't really understand.
As long as you're interested, I'll prepare it for you.
Thank you, Qian Ren. These years, you've taken care of me too well.
I'm about to slowly become an idiot at living life.
I'm sorry for bothering you for so long.
Don't say such ridiculous things. I promised Auntie Li to take care of you my entire life when she was sick.
You and Uncle Liu have treated us more than well.
You don't have to take that promise too seriously.
To anyone, my situation right now is a burden.
You're wrong, Li Li.
It's my life's biggest accomplishment to make you smile everyday.
I want to stay by your side forever.
Li Li, can you agree to that promise today?
Let's discuss that after we take care of Mom's business. Okay?
Okay.
Li Li,
stop crying. With you guys beside me, I can leave peacefully.
The only thing I regret is not being able to witness your marriage.
Mei Jing, We're finally back after 6 years.
On the way here, all that I saw were skyscrapers. A lot of old buildings were destroyed.
But thankfully,
our house is still here.
Mom. Uncle Liu, Qian Ren, and I have moved back.
I kept imagining you after moving back.
Every time I go back, there will be the food you made. You liked to sometimes chatter with me interminably.
But now, I... I want to hear more of your whining.
Li Li, Auntie Li told us to never shed a tear for her.
Plus, your condition now can't handle stressful things.
It's all thanks to you and Uncle Liu that we were able to prevent my mother from knowing.
If not, she wouldn't have left peacefully.
We're one family, don't talk as if we were two.
Auntie Li, don't worry. I will take care of Li Li for my entire life.
Qian Ren, you have to remember that you're saying this in front of Auntie Li.
Li Li, with Qian Ren taking care of you, your mom and I can both be at ease.
-Hello, Mr. Pei.-Hello.
Thank you for supporting this migratory birds themed painting . I sincerely express our heartfelt gratitude as the representative of the wetland protection association.
No problem, I, myself, am also a fan of observing birds.These contributions don't count towards anything.
All of the paintings here are related to birds, but only this painting has a feather signifying a bird.
I'm interested in the artist. Would it be possible for you to set up a meeting?
This artist signed a contract with us to keep their identity anonymous when giving us this painting.
We can not give you any information on the artist.
Am I not allowed to know even her age and gender?
I'm sorry about that.
But she did say that there was a chance of her coming here to the gallery.
-You two may be able to meet by coincidence.-Thank you.
Thank you.
Li Li, don't move. Let me do it. Sit.
Cleaning up isn't tiring. I'm fine.
Just sit there and watch me tidy up.
Oh right, have you decided if you wanted to open your own business or take over the position as CEO yet?
Opening up my own design company takes too much of my time and focus.
I'll just use my time to take care of you and Dad.
But it's every designer's dream to open up their own company.
You don't have to give it up for me.
Li Li, don't think foolishly.
Aochuang is a great platform. Furthermore, Director Zhang wants me to stay.
Why would I go out and risk it when I have such a good opportunity?
-Do you really think that way?-Yeah.
Right, I have something to discuss with you.
The painting exhibition in which you helped me to contribute is opening today. I want to go and have a look.
Uncle Liu always opposed me going to places with a lot of people.
But this is my first time going to a gallery. I really want to go.
Then let's convince Dad to meet up with his old friends and I'll take you out secretly.
But you have to promise me that we'll come back as soon as you see it.
Okay.
Hello. It's me.
Yes. I'll ask Secretary Jiang to send you the files on the most recent idea.
Remember to check your inbox.
Yes. Yes.
Right, the speed with which our company is bringing out the concept should be considered as fast.
Yes. I also told Secretary Jiang to add in
some problems that we met. When you read it,
let's discuss how to solve it. Is that fine?
I'm going the day after tomorrow. The day after tomorrow.
If you don't have anything planned the day after tomorrow, we can meet up and discuss it.
Okay. Bye.
The pieces here are really high quality.
No matter whether the technique of composition or the apply of colors,
the artists' hard work are visible.
The works this time are all done very carefully.
-Let's check the other side out.-Let's go.
Mr. Pei, I'm sorry. We're already closing.
Thank you.
Fifteen Years of Waiting for Migratory Birds Preview
Marrow and joint aches appeared. The patient's condition is getting worse.
She's back.
Oh my god. Li Li, where have you gone for these past 7 years?
Pei Shang Xuan is still single even after 7 years.
You see, isn't he faithful?
Hello, Lee Jun? I still need you to help me with one more thing.