[Projector clicking]
[Metal clanging]
[Water running]
[Water stops]
[Metal clanging]
[Birds chirping]
[Door creaks]
Johanna?
I'm here.
Yes.
[Sniffing]
I'd like to wear my blue
dress.
Dress.
Yes, ma'am.
[Bed creaking]
[Sighs]
[Drawer closes]
Hi. Yes.
I'd like to report a death.
Yes, ma'am.
No, um -- I don't know.
She's very old.
I-I take care of her.
No, I work here.
Yes, ma'am.
[Sighs]
[Birds chirping]
[Vehicle approaching]
I hope it was peaceful.
It was in her sleep.
Thank you.
So, you got another job lined
up there?
Yeah.
Whole new everything.
Mrs. willits' pastor set it up.
Hey, gorgeous!
Hey, dad.
Hey, Edith.
Hi.
Hey. What's going on?
I'll just leave you with it.
There's this model that I wrote
there's this model that I wrote
out to get the loan.
Out to get the loan.
'Cause I think if you check that
'cause I think if you check that
out --
are you sure you want to have
this conversation?
This conversation?
It's a really good
it's a really good
opportunity.
Opportunity.
I just thought you might be
interested in it.
Interested in it.
Why don't you just leave him
why don't you just leave him
alone?
Alone?
It is a really good
it is a really good
opportunity.
Opportunity.
There's a lady over there.
I'm, um, johanna parry from
plainfield.
Plainfield.
The pastor sent me.
Oh, yes, we've been expecting
oh, yes, we've been expecting
you.
You.
Only a suitcase and a bag?
Oh, this my granddaughter --
oh, this my granddaughter --
sabitha.
Sabitha.
She lives in the house with me.
And that makes me Ken.
I'm sabitha's father.
He's usually not here.
He doesn't live here.
Ah.
Uh, did you have any problems
uh, did you have any problems
finding the house?
Finding the house?
Oh, no, I asked in town.
Oh. Good. Good.
Okay.
We're going to the astro
we're going to the astro
later for burgers, if you want
to join us.
To join us.
Ken, please.
She just got here.
I'm just being friendly,
bill.
Bill.
Let me show you to your room.
She's gonna be working here?
Yeah.
Look at her shoes.
[Birds chirping]
[Dog barking]
[Door creaking]
Oh!
Oh, shit.
You scared the hell out of me.
Sorry.
[Sighs]
I was just looking for some
hangers.
Hangers.
Well, they're not in here.
Oh, these are Mr. mccauley's.
Yeah.
How much is he paying you?
I'm only asking 'cause he's a
cheapskate, and I wouldn't want
him ripping you off.
[Sighs]
Hey, um, don't tell sabitha I
hey, um, don't tell sabitha I
got a headache.
Got a headache.
She'll just worry about me,
she'll just worry about me,
okay?
Okay?
Thanks, gorgeous.
[Laughs]
And now turn.
[Both laugh]
Let's see.
[Chuckles]
Send it.
What's taking him so long?
So, you know sabitha from
school?
School?
What?
Uh, yeah.
Where does her mother live?
She died.
[Chuckling] Oh, my God.
Stevie thought johanna was your
mom.
Mom.
Ah!
Look.
"Sabitha's mom seems weird."
Please text him back and tell
please text him back and tell
him she's not my mom.
Him she's not my mom.
Get down.
[Chuckles]
Hey, you missed the action at
hey, you missed the action at
the astro burger, bill.
The astro burger, bill.
[Crickets chirping]
You're not gonna be home to
you're not gonna be home to
Chicago till 1:00 or 2:00 in the
morning.
Morning.
Well, I was thinking I'd just
well, I was thinking I'd just
stay and then leave tomorrow.
Stay and then leave tomorrow.
[Sighs]
I don't think that's a good
idea.
Idea.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
I'm glad you're here at
least.
Least.
Sabitha needs someone like you.
[Laughs]
Where did grandpa go?
He's supposed to take Edith
he's supposed to take Edith
home.
Home.
I'll drive her home.
You know, that's okay.
I can call my mom.
Not a problem.
Her parents don't want her
driving with you.
Come on.
I wasn't driving --
it was an accident.
It was an accident.
Okay, okay, okay!
Damn it!
And now you're trying to suck
and now you're trying to suck
up to me to get my money for
your sleazy motel Ponzi scheme?
Your sleazy motel Ponzi scheme?
The thing is, I got the motel
the thing is, I got the motel
for practically nothing, right?
For practically nothing, right?
So, when it's up and running,
so, when it's up and running,
it's all profit.
It's all profit.
I'd pay you back in three
months, four at the most.
Months, four at the most.
Yeah, well, you haven't paid
yeah, well, you haven't paid
me back from the last time I
lent you money.
Lent you money.
That was mainly for marcel,
that was mainly for marcel,
wasn't it?
Wasn't it?
I mean, I just -- I think if you
saw the improvements that I've
done, you'd jump right in.
Done, you'd jump right in.
You know, Ken, I'm really
you know, Ken, I'm really
trying here.
Trying here.
I'm really trying.
You know, marcel would have been
you know, marcel would have been
36 last month.
Yeah, I know that.
Do you know that?
I miss her, too, bill, a lot,
okay?
[Breathes deeply]
Okay.
[Inhales sharply]
I have to drive Edith home.
[Sighs]
[Water running]
[Vacuum whirring]
[Vacuum shuts off]
$18,643 on the dot.
For a savings account, I'm gonna
for a savings account, I'm gonna
need a government-issued I.D.,
and I put some x's there to show
you where to sign at.
You where to sign at.
May I have a bank book?
Oh. Thank you.
You live with Mr. mccauley over
you live with Mr. mccauley over
in South cedar?
In South cedar?
He banks here, too.
Oh.
You're the one taking care of
you're the one taking care of
his granddaughter.
His granddaughter.
Yeah.
See, um, sabitha is in class
see, um, sabitha is in class
with my grandsons.
With my grandsons.
They're twins, both football
they're twins, both football
players.
Players.
Yep.
Oh, gosh, poor little thing --
oh, gosh, poor little thing --
sabitha, I mean.
Sabitha, I mean.
Well, losing her mother in that
well, losing her mother in that
terrible accident, right?
Terrible accident, right?
And then having her father go
and then having her father go
off to prison like that.
Off to prison like that.
Just...
It's none of my business.
Thank you.
I'll be home at 5:30.
[Door closes]
[Birds chirping]
[Knock on door]
Yes?
My dad left this note for you
my dad left this note for you
in the letter he wrote me.
In the letter he wrote me.
Oh. Okay.
Thank you.
[Door slams]
Stephen.
S-t-e-p-h-e-n.
Hateship, friendship, courtship,
hateship, friendship, courtship,
loveship, marriage, hateship --
friendship!
Friendship!
Shit. It's friendship.
This woman says she can reach
this woman says she can reach
orgasm just by shaking her leg.
Orgasm just by shaking her leg.
The only thing worse than
the only thing worse than
friendship is hateship.
Friendship is hateship.
Wait, this other woman
wait, this other woman
started masturbating when she
was 8 years old, rubbing up
against some doll she slept
with.
With.
Do you think Stevie's ever
do you think Stevie's ever
had sex?
Had sex?
I heard he screwed
Robin Simpson with his socks on.
Oh, my God.
So, what do you think about?
How do you do it?
[Chuckles] Shut up.
What? It's totally normal.
Yeah, totally.
'Cause you're my best friend,
'cause you're my best friend,
I'll tell you.
My parents have a handheld
my parents have a handheld
shower in their bathroom, so
whenever I'm alone in the
house --
okay, thank you!
Okay, thank you!
Tmi! No more.
What? It's totally normal.
Everyone does it.
Totally normal.
[Knock on door]
It is.
Hold on a second!
Um, I don't know.
Let me just --
let me just --
get -- get that.
Get -- get that.
Oh, God.
Just...
[Clattering]
God, she's so annoying.
Do you think she heard?
Come in!
[Indistinct rapping]
♪ go real hard ♪
♪ go hard, baby ♪
♪ you the best ♪
♪ the kings in the club like
we love chess ♪
We love chess ♪
♪ my queens in the club 'cause
I love chests ♪
I told grandpa I'd clean up
later.
Later.
Um, I need your father's
um, I need your father's
address.
Address.
Why?
I have a card for him.
I'm just responding to the
note that he wrote me.
Note that he wrote me.
♪ what you waiting for? ♪
[Indistinct rapping]
♪ drinkin' cocktails like... ♪
you know, I'm going right by
the post office.
The post office.
I can mail that for you.
Thank you.
Oh, it's not a problem at
oh, it's not a problem at
all.
All.
I go right by there, so...
There you go.
♪ clubs and bars just for one
reason, tongue needing ♪
Reason, tongue needing ♪
♪ coke and rum meetings, love
squeezing, liquor by the
bottle... ♪
Bottle... ♪
see you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
♪ they buyin' drinks like
they buyin' minks ♪
They buyin' minks ♪
♪ there's no time to dance ♪
♪ sex in the air, on the
beach ♪
Beach ♪
♪ what you waiting for? ♪
♪ time to sip some more ♪
did you have a good day?
Did you have a good day?
Yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
♪ red margaritas ♪
♪ fucked-up senoritas ♪
♪ oh, mama Mia ♪
I waited for you to open it.
Oh, my God.
[Chuckles]
[Horn honks]
"Dear Mr. Ken gaudette, I just
"dear Mr. Ken gaudette, I just
thought I would write and send
my thanks to you for the nice
things you said in your note, in
which you included in your
daughter's note --"
ever hear of grammar?
Ever hear of grammar?
"I'm grateful for you saying
that since some people feel that
a person like me that they do
not know the -- the background
of is beyond the pale."
Of is beyond the pale."
What?
This doesn't make sense.
She capitalized "beyond the
she capitalized "beyond the
pale."
Pale."
Isn't that -- that means,
isn't that -- that means,
like, the other side of the
tracks.
Tracks.
Ah, ah.
"I was born in ames, but my
mother and my brother and me
moved to twin view heights when
I was a girl."
No.
Blah, blah.
Pbht.
"Then I cared for Mrs. willits."
Blah, blah.
"I'm afraid I've bored you long
Enough."
You can say that again.
No kidding.
"Thank you for your good
"thank you for your good
opinion and for taking me to the
restaurant.
Restaurant.
It was a pleasure to be
it was a pleasure to be
included.
Included.
Your friend, johanna parry."
Say something about her
say something about her
beautiful hair.
Beautiful hair.
This has to be realistic.
"I was so happy to see that you
underlined 'your friend.'
Someone like me, with a
someone like me, with a
checkered past, could use all
the friends he can get.
The friends he can get.
Sometimes I think, 'who is my
sometimes I think, 'who is my
friend?'
Then comes your letter."
That's boring.
Well, we can't just
well, we can't just
immediately write that he wants
to suck her titties.
To suck her titties.
Okay, how about you say
okay, how about you say
something like, "you should wear
your hair back more often so the
world can see your pretty face"?
World can see your pretty face"?
How about that?
That's good.
Yeah.
[Gasps]
Stevie!
[Chuckles]
"P.S., let's continue this
"p.S., let's continue this
correspondence through e-mail.
Correspondence through e-mail.
It's much faster.
My address is
my address is
kengaudette12step@hotmail.Com.
Kengaudette12step@hotmail.Com.
And we'll save money on stamps."
Why did you have to put the
why did you have to put the
"12 step" thing?
For authenticity.
What? Recovery is a good thing.
[Faucet shuts off]
[Faucet turns on and off]
[Door creaks]
[Groans]
I'll talk to you later.
[Sighs]
Why are you staring at me?
Oh, I'm not -- I don't mean
oh, I'm not -- I don't mean
to.
To.
Why are you even in here?
Came to --
came to --
yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
We were just kissing, okay?
Normal people do that.
[Engine shuts off]
[Car door closes]
That was my wife's furniture.
My wife gave it to my daughter
my wife gave it to my daughter
when she and Ken first got
married.
Married.
After his poor judgment killed
after his poor judgment killed
my daughter, I -- I took that
furniture back.
Furniture back.
There's no reason for him to
there's no reason for him to
have it.
Have it.
Why should he?
It just sits out here.
It seems like a waste.
Maybe he could use it in his
maybe he could use it in his
hotel lobby.
Hotel lobby.
He couldn't run a one-pump
he couldn't run a one-pump
gas station.
[Dog barking]
[Birds chirping]
[Vehicle passing]
That one doesn't work.
When will you be finished?
Well, you have to sign up.
First name.
[Keys clacking]
Click the mouse for the last.
[Mouse clicks]
[Keys clacking]
And then your password.
My own word?
Your own word.
We're staying near the
white house.
White house.
Mm. Is that boy going?
His name's Stevie, and, no,
his name's Stevie, and, no,
he's not going.
He's not going.
He went last year, so you don't
he went last year, so you don't
have to worry.
Have to worry.
Oh, okay, I won't worry.
Sabitha, is that thing
sabitha, is that thing
surgically attached to your
hand?
Hand?
Thank you, johanna.
Put that away.
[Mirror squeaking]
[Moaning]
Come back.
The ad says 10:00 to 3:00.
You don't have to get there
you don't have to get there
exactly at 10:00.
Exactly at 10:00.
If I want the job, I do.
[Coughs]
And you're gonna breathe
paint fumes all day?
Paint fumes all day?
[Inhales sharply]
That only pays like $8 an hour.
Well, it's better than
well, it's better than
sitting around watching TV all
day.
Day.
My brother manages a huge
my brother manages a huge
food warehouse.
Food warehouse.
They're always hiring
they're always hiring
forklifters, and they pay them
like 20 bucks an hour.
Like 20 bucks an hour.
I don't know how to drive a
Forklift.
[Sighs]
[Sniffs]
Ah.
He'll be back in three weeks.
[Tapping]
You'll make a lot more money.
[Inhales sharply]
[Sniffs]
He isn't gonna hire me.
Yeah.
I'll tell him to.
I got to check this out
first.
First.
Just let yourself out when
just let yourself out when
you're ready.
You're ready.
You have the 30 bucks you owe
you have the 30 bucks you owe
me for dinner last night?
Me for dinner last night?
That's not even including the
that's not even including the
blow.
Blow.
"I'm sitting here drinking a
glass of chardonnay, wishing I
could hold you tight in my
arms."
Arms."
In reality, he's probably
in reality, he's probably
sitting in his underwear
somewhere, drinking warm beer.
Somewhere, drinking warm beer.
[Chuckles]
"I must say goodbye.
And the only way I can do it is
and the only way I can do it is
to imagine you reading this in
your nightgown, thinking about
me, as you drift off to sleep."
Me, as you drift off to sleep."
[Both chuckle]
[Mumbling]
Come on, grandpa!
We're going to be late!
Hi.
I came to get my black
sweater.
Sweater.
I texted you like five times.
You -- you told me I could
you -- you told me I could
borrow it.
Borrow it.
I'm sure your grandfather can
buy you one.
Why'd you tell Melissa and
Jessica that I couldn't afford
to go to D.C.?
To go to D.C.?
You told me you couldn't
you told me you couldn't
afford it.
Afford it.
I didn't mean for you to tell
everyone.
Everyone.
That's the bitchiest thing
that's the bitchiest thing
you've ever done to me.
You've ever done to me.
God, I didn't know it was
some big secret.
Some big secret.
If I would have known, I
if I would have known, I
wouldn't have said --
if you weren't so stupid and
selfish, you'd understand that I
don't want the whole school
knowing.
Knowing.
Look, Edith, no one at school
look, Edith, no one at school
cares.
Cares.
[Scoffs]
[Door closes]
You're so evil.
[Chuckles]
Are you kidding?
She loves this.
[Keys clacking]
[Giggles]
Actually, it's pretty mean.
[Keys clacking]
[Mouse clicks]
[Mumbling]
"You're beautiful..."
[Breathing heavily]
[Door opens]
[Breathing deeply]
Mm.
[Bells ding]
Hello. May I help you?
Yes, I would like to try on
yes, I would like to try on
the suit in the window, the
shiny one.
Shiny one.
Oh, that's a lovely suit.
Yes.
Oh, it's so expensive.
Well, it's very fine silk.
It's Italian.
Hmm. Mm-hmm.
Well, of course you'll need your
well, of course you'll need your
nylons and your heels and some
lipstick, but with some
tailoring, it might work.
Tailoring, it might work.
How does it feel?
Is it comfortable?
The suit feels fine.
There's nothing the matter with
there's nothing the matter with
the suit.
The suit.
Sometimes that's just the way
sometimes that's just the way
it is.
It is.
You never know till you try
you never know till you try
something on.
Something on.
Hold on.
Why don't you slip into this,
just for the heck of it?
Come out here and look at it in
the big mirror.
Well, I better take it off so
you can wrap it up.
You can wrap it up.
Wonderful.
It's probably what I'm gonna
it's probably what I'm gonna
be married in.
[Birds chirping]
You know what why I got you
a red car?
A red car?
Because red cars get the most
because red cars get the most
tickets.
Tickets.
So, if you get any tickets, you
so, if you get any tickets, you
have to pay for it yourself.
Have to pay for it yourself.
I won't be getting any
tickets.
Tickets.
Hi, johanna.
Oh, hi.
I'll start dinner right away.
I got this for my dad for
Christmas.
Oh, that's nice.
I got this one for Edith.
She really wanted one.
Are you wearing makeup?
Oh, you look nice, johanna.
Oh, it's just -- [Chuckles]
No. Here.
Here. Try this.
It's more natural.
Thank you.
Edith.
I got this for you.
Thanks.
[Sighs]
I talked to Jessica and
Melissa.
Neither one of them said
neither one of them said
anything about why you didn't go
on the trip.
On the trip.
They're not like that.
Julie and Marie didn't go 'cause
their parents couldn't pay.
Their parents couldn't pay.
Are you gonna talk about this
are you gonna talk about this
all day?
All day?
I won't. Sorry.
Stop bragging about your car.
It's kind of nauseating.
I wasn't bragging.
Justin asked me about it, and I
answered.
Answered.
What about the pictures on
what about the pictures on
Facebook?
That's bragging.
If you got a car, you'd be
if you got a car, you'd be
doing the same thing.
So, there's a table, six
chairs, a bed, dresser, sofa,
coffee table, end tables,
side --
yeah, I'm -- I'm sorry.
Yeah, I'm -- I'm sorry.
I can't write that fast.
I can't --
there's no kitchen stuff.
There's no kitchen stuff.
Um, it's just, um, one bedroom.
It's only going to Chicago.
All right, uh...
Well, if this is it, you're
well, if this is it, you're
probably looking at...
Probably looking at...
$2,300, $2,500.
Seems like a lot.
When's the last time you had
when's the last time you had
a bunch of furniture moved?
A bunch of furniture moved?
You have somebody in Chicago
you have somebody in Chicago
who's gonna be looking out for
it when it gets there?
It when it gets there?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, we'll have my guys here
okay, we'll have my guys here
first thing Monday morning.
First thing Monday morning.
After 9:00.
They can't be here before 9:00.
After 9:30, actually. 9:30.
Okay.
Oh, you know, we'll send you
oh, you know, we'll send you
a bill for this.
A bill for this.
I'd rather pay now.
$2,300?
That's fine. That's good.
[Air brake hisses]
[Sighs]
[Knock on door]
Hello?
[Breathing heavily]
[Door creaks]
Hello?
[Floorboards creak]
[Vehicle passing]
[Floorboards creaking]
[Coughing]
[Inhales sharply]
[Coughs]
[Groans]
[Metal clinking]
[Coughing]
Oh, you're awake.
What are you doing here?
Didn't you get my e-mail?
I-I don't have e-mail.
[Exhales sharply]
I sent you e-mails.
I-I don't even have a
computer.
[Sponge scraping]
[Metal clanging]
Just so you know, I've been
sick.
Sick.
That's why this place isn't so
that's why this place isn't so
clean.
Clean.
This stove hasn't been
this stove hasn't been
cleaned in years.
Cleaned in years.
[Breathing heavily]
[Zipping]
[Door opens]
Hey!
Th-there are no buses this time
of night.
Of night.
You should just come back
you should just come back
inside.
You're gonna freeze out here.
You know, we can just make up
you know, we can just make up
the couch and sort this out
tomorrow, okay?
[Inhales sharply]
[Sniffs]
[Coughing]
How are you feeling?
[Inhales sharply]
Ugh.
Uh...I can't really tell.
A little better maybe.
[Coughing]
You're swallowing your phlegm.
Don't do that.
It's not good for you.
[Exhales sharply]
Spit it out.
You'll get in trouble with your
you'll get in trouble with your
kidneys by swallowing it.
[Breathing heavily]
You didn't find the coffee,
you didn't find the coffee,
did you?
Did you?
[Coughing]
♪ little red wagon carrying
the day ♪
The day ♪
[Singing indistinctly]
[Urinating]
[Toilet flushes]
[Zipping]
[Indistinct singing on radio]
What are you doing?
Cleaning the floor.
It could use some wax after.
You're never gonna feel better
if you keep smoking like that.
If you keep smoking like that.
Um...
You know, anyone could have
you know, anyone could have
written to you.
Written to you.
Probably those two --
probably those two --
teenager girls are pretty nasty.
Teenager girls are pretty nasty.
You really don't have to scrub
you really don't have to scrub
the floor.
The floor.
Just trying to keep busy.
When do you have to be back
at bill's?
At bill's?
I wasn't planning on going
back.
Back.
♪ one telltale sign ♪
you really don't have a
computer?
Computer?
No, I-I want to get one.
You okay?
Look, I-I don't know what
look, I-I don't know what
happened.
Happened.
I mean, I did put a note for you
in with the letter I sent to
sabitha, but I didn't send
anything else.
Anything else.
I'm sorry.
♪ ...thing to do was leave
you, but I shoulda left then ♪
You, but I shoulda left then ♪
♪ now I'm too old to leave you,
but I still get sore ♪
But I still get sore ♪
♪ when you come home a-feelin'
for the knob on the door ♪
For the knob on the door ♪
♪ I can't... ♪
♪ help but love you till the
day that I die ♪
Day that I die ♪
♪ singing, why, baby, why,
baby ♪
Baby ♪
♪ why, baby, why? ♪
♪ well, I got... ♪
♪ a crow I wanna pick with
you ♪
You ♪
♪ just like last time when the
feathers flew ♪
Feathers flew ♪
♪ you're runnin' wild,
a-kickin' up your heels ♪
A-kickin' up your heels ♪
hi.
Hi.
♪ a-leavin' me home with a
handful of bills ♪
Handful of bills ♪
hi.
Hi.
I'm Chloe.
♪ and you know it's true ♪
who are you?
Who are you?
I'm johanna parry.
Ken's friend.
Ken's friend from...Where?
From Iowa.
I was taking care of his
daughter.
Daughter.
♪ you make cry, baby,
cry, baby ♪
Cry, baby ♪
wow.
Wow.
His daughter?
♪ I can't help but love you
till the day that I die ♪
Till the day that I die ♪
her name is sabitha.
Her name is sabitha.
♪ why, baby, why, baby, why ♪
[Instrumental break]
Where is he?
Sleeping.
He's ill.
Ill.
Yeah.
Right.
♪ that every little dog's
a-gonna have his day ♪
A-gonna have his day ♪
♪ you better pay attention ♪
♪ don't you dare forget ♪
♪ 'cause I'm just a little-bitty
puppy yet ♪
Puppy yet ♪
♪ yeah, I caught you
honky-tonking with my best
friend ♪
Friend ♪
♪ the thing to do was leave you,
but I shoulda left then ♪
But I shoulda left then ♪
♪ now I'm too old to leave you,
but I still get sore ♪
But I still get sore ♪
♪ when you come home a-feelin'
for the knob on the door ♪
For the knob on the door ♪
♪ tell me, why, baby, why,
baby, why, baby, why ♪
Baby, why, baby, why ♪
♪ you make me cry, baby -- ♪
it's gonna be totally fun.
It's gonna be totally fun.
Everyone's gonna be there.
Polo just got back from Seattle.
Ugh. I'm sick.
I practically coughed up a lung
this morning.
This morning.
That Swedish guy is supposed
that Swedish guy is supposed
to bring some of this "x" that
doesn't have any speed in it.
Doesn't have any speed in it.
You do actually look sick.
[Doorbell rings]
You should probably just sleep.
That's what I've been saying.
Johanna parry?
You're late.
You were supposed to be here
you were supposed to be here
this morning.
This morning.
Everything looks good.
Thank you.
Let's get this one last...
Come by later if you feel
come by later if you feel
better.
Better.
Probably not gonna happen.
I'll call you.
I can set a place for you if
you want to stay for dinner.
Uh...
[Car door closes]
What's going on?
That's the furniture.
Does bill know you're here?
Sabitha?
I didn't tell them.
And bill doesn't know you
and bill doesn't know you
took the furniture, does he?
Took the furniture, does he?
No, he doesn't.
You just -- you just took it?
How'd you do that?
Mr. mccauley was at work, and
sabitha was at school.
[Sniffs]
And now it's all here.
[Laughs]
There's no damage to any of
there's no damage to any of
it.
It.
No.
No, I bet there's not.
I bet he's fucking freaking out.
[Laughs]
[Coughing]
Here. Here. I'll do that.
She probably just got sick of
it here.
It here.
I always drive people away.
Where do you want these?
Just right here is fine.
All right.
Maybe we can have your father
maybe we can have your father
out again.
Out again.
[Water running]
And this time, he can stay over.
I know you're trying with
him.
Him.
I am.
I don't know how johanna ever
cleaned this.
Cleaned this.
[Sponge scraping]
[Sighs]
Elbow grease.
I was in the middle of
renovating when I got sick.
Renovating when I got sick.
I'm gonna put in new carpeting
and plumbing.
And plumbing.
I just need a bit more cash.
[Sniffs]
[Sighs]
You know you can't go back there
you know you can't go back there
now.
Now.
He'll have you arrested for
he'll have you arrested for
stealing that furniture.
Stealing that furniture.
I'll figure something out.
You should take an aspirin
you should take an aspirin
before you go to bed.
Before you go to bed.
You look a little pale.
You'll be all right in here
you'll be all right in here
again?
Again?
Yeah.
What about your family?
Can you stay with them?
Um, I'll be out of your hair
um, I'll be out of your hair
tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Actually, you know what?
You can't leave, anyway.
You're an outlaw now.
[Chuckles]
I thought you might need that.
I'll see you in the morning.
♪ ..More times than in ♪
[Coughing]
♪ and I'm either fool or wise
enough to open it again ♪
Enough to open it again ♪
[Washing machine humming]
♪ for I'll never know ♪
♪ what's beyond the mountains ♪
♪ till I reach the other side ♪
♪ so I'll keep on falling in
love ♪
Love ♪
♪ till I get it right ♪
♪ if practice makes perfect... ♪
gone, just like that,
thousands of dollars worth of
antique furniture.
Antique furniture.
That's horrible.
Are you gonna file a police
are you gonna file a police
report?
Report?
'Cause you sure should.
Mr. mccauley, I -- I probably
shouldn't be saying this, but
she withdrew $21,000 in cash
last week.
Last week.
No one here has ever done that.
Well, I knew the moment I met
well, I knew the moment I met
her that there was something a
little, you know, peculiar with
her.
Her.
But I suppose you miss having
but I suppose you miss having
someone around, right?
I miss my furniture.
Yeah.
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry.
Um, I think we're all set here.
Uh, we're gonna have Stan review
uh, we're gonna have Stan review
all this, and then we'll get it
to you in your office early next
week.
Week.
All right.
Okay.
Well, thank you very much,
well, thank you very much,
Eileen.
Thank you, Mr. mccauley.
All right.
Right.
And, you know, I have to drop
and, you know, I have to drop
some documents off down at
Beckman's, and there's this new
restaurant I've been checking
out down there.
Out down there.
Quinn Davis has eaten there.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe, if you wanted to, you
maybe, if you wanted to, you
could join me for lunch.
Could join me for lunch.
That is the nicest offer, but
that is the nicest offer, but
I -- I really can't leave.
Well, thank you for your
well, thank you for your
help, Eileen.
Help, Eileen.
Thank you, Mr. mccauley.
Bye-bye.
[Door opens and closes]
Oh, you're up.
Thought you were gone for
thought you were gone for
good.
Good.
[Chuckles]
May I?
Got you some fresh milk.
Sit down.
I'll bring you some aspirin and
some juice.
Some juice.
I'll get dinner started.
Need some help?
No. I'm okay.
I cared for Mrs. willits since
I was 15.
She needed me there, so she
she needed me there, so she
didn't let me do a lot of stuff
outside the house.
Outside the house.
She didn't let you?
Well, I went to Iowa city
well, I went to Iowa city
with my neighbor, but then my
neighbor moved.
Um...
That appointment I have in the
that appointment I have in the
morning -- um, it's with my
probation officer.
Probation officer.
And then I have a narcotics
and then I have a narcotics
anonymous meeting at 4:00.
You know I spent time in prison,
right?
Right?
It's none of my business.
I crashed a speed boat with
sabitha and her mom -- marcel.
Marcel was killed.
I know.
You know.
It was an accident.
I was drunk...And high.
Yeah, but it was still an
accident.
[Door opens and closes]
Oh, hey.
I brought Chinese.
Uh, we ate already.
I got an early day tomorrow.
[Sighs]
Kung pao chicken, spring
rolls, moo shu pork, and the
pancakes.
Pancakes.
What are you doing, babe?
What are you doing?
Hanging out with "little house
hanging out with "little house
on the prairie"?
On the prairie"?
Don't say that.
In your p.J.S?
Having a sleepover or whatever?
Listen, why don't you just
listen, why don't you just
give me back the key and go,
okay?
You still owe me 200 bucks.
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
Sorry about that.
[Chuckling] You remember
them.
Them.
No, I don't.
Oh, they had --
oh, they had --
I don't.
They had eight kids, and they
they had eight kids, and they
all played different
instruments.
Instruments.
Yeah.
And then they would all play
and then they would all play
those corny songs at the fair.
Those corny songs at the fair.
I don't remember them!
Well, one year, they had a
well, one year, they had a
float in the parade.
Float in the parade.
One of the daughters fell off
one of the daughters fell off
and she broke her little finger
and they came to me, wanting me
to sue the whole damn town.
To sue the whole damn town.
Okay, wait. Wait. Wait.
I remember them.
Did they have these big old
did they have these big old
buckteeth?
Buckteeth?
Oh, God, I'm horrible.
[Mockingly] I don't know
[mockingly] I don't know
what you talkin' about, ma'am.
What you talkin' about, ma'am.
[Laughs] You're horrible!
[Laughing] Yes, I am.
Wait. Wait.
The blonde one -- remember?
She always sang that same old
she always sang that same old
song.
Song.
What was that?
[Mockingly] ♪ hello, my baby ♪
♪ hello, my honey ♪
♪ hello, my ragtime gal ♪
oh, gosh.
Oh, gosh.
[Both laugh]
Well...
[Soft jazz music playing]
I guess I should be going.
Oh, okay.
All right, um...
Um...
Yes, of course.
I'm -- I'm really happy you
came.
Came.
Thank you.
Oh, no, no, no, thank you.
No, seriously.
Thank you.
[Both laugh]
All right, there you go.
You in?
Yep.
And don't be a stranger.
No.
All right? Okay.
You know, I wouldn't want
this to ruin our business
relationship.
Relationship.
No, me neither, not at all.
[Both moaning]
[Both laugh]
[Grunts]
[Chuckles]
Lift you!
[Giggles]
Yes, right here.
[Both laughing]
[Door creaks]
[Smooches]
[Sighs]
How was the movie?
It's past midnight.
Supper ran late.
Hmm. Really late.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, really late.
[Sniffs]
Do you smell like perfume?
[Sniffing]
I can't tell whether you smell
like budweiser or michelob.
Like budweiser or michelob.
I do not know what you are
talking about.
Talking about.
Well, I don't know what
well, I don't know what
you're talking about.
You're talking about.
[Grunts]
[Sighs]
Where's Edith tonight?
Mnh, she's probably out
mnh, she's probably out
screwing Stevie in the back of
his brother's crappy little
jeep.
[Tapping]
[Inhales sharply]
[Sniffing]
Either someone on the bus
must have stolen it, or I lost
it.
It.
I'm really very good with money.
Yeah, I had my wallet stolen
yeah, I had my wallet stolen
on the bus once.
On the bus once.
But they only took $400, and
but they only took $400, and
there was a lot more in there.
There was a lot more in there.
I know because I counted it when
I paid the movers.
I told you I couldn't pay you
back for that if that's what
you're hinting at.
You're hinting at.
No.
No, I just lost $400.
Uh, I'll be back later, okay?
Are you feeling well enough?
Mm.
Well, I still feel like shit,
well, I still feel like shit,
but I can't miss a meeting with
my p.O. Unless I got all kinds
of bullshit medical
documentations and...
Documentations and...
Did you take an aspirin?
Yeah.
Hey, um, it wouldn't surprise
hey, um, it wouldn't surprise
me if Chloe took your money.
Me if Chloe took your money.
I mean, she's pretty fucking
sneaky.
Sneaky.
She is a junkie, so...
But if she comes over, don't say
but if she comes over, don't say
anything.
Anything.
I'll -- I'll handle it.
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
Hey, everybody, this is
Craig bruin.
Welcome back to the morning
welcome back to the morning
radio, live from Chicago.
Radio, live from Chicago.
Today the weather is -- let's
today the weather is -- let's
just say it's cold.
Just say it's cold.
[Speaking indistinctly]
[Door opens and closes]
Wow, that smells great.
What you making?
Biscuits and beef stew.
It's ready.
♪ baby, I can use ♪
♪ no, I won't be hanging round ♪
♪ kind of passing through ♪
♪ searching for the... ♪
[Silverware scraping]
♪ like a moth, I'm drawn to the
pain ♪
Pain ♪
you can start.
You can start.
[Chuckles]
♪ one more sacrifice ♪
I could get used to this.
♪ on the altar of... ♪
[Plastic crinkling]
[Drawer closes]
[Inhales sharply]
Oh --
oh --
oh, shit.
Oh, shit.
Sorry.
I thought you were getting sick.
No, I was throwing this out.
Sorry.
[Sighs]
[Sighs, sniffs]
[Vehicles passing]
Are you awake?
[Sighs]
I-I know I'm an idiot.
And I -- [Sighs]
I just wanted to say...
That, um --
[both breathing heavily]
[Gasps]
[Both breathing heavily]
♪ ...reasons ♪
♪ I'm getting rid of pain
that's in this town ♪
That's in this town ♪
♪ my friends all warned me ♪
♪ and they are leaving ♪
"you should wear your hair
back more often so the world can
see your pretty face."
See your pretty face."
This is embarrassing.
No, it's not.
You do have a pretty face.
I don't want to read any
more.
More.
Come on.
"I've known since that
afternoon at astro burger that
you and I will be together.
You and I will be together.
I haven't stopped thinking about
you."
You."
Well, I did think about you.
Not like that.
Well...
I do now, all the time.
They wrote all about your
past and your time in prison and
your problems and said how you
don't have many friends.
Don't have many friends.
And how did you respond to
and how did you respond to
that?
That?
I said I was your friend.
[Both breathing heavily]
I-I don't know how long I
can keep this up.
Can keep this up.
[Both breathing heavily]
It's Christmas.
Don't you want to get up?
I'm fine here.
Electronic cigarette.
It's to help you quit
it's to help you quit
smoking.
Smoking.
Yeah.
I got that.
My two girls taking care of me
at Christmas, huh?
At Christmas, huh?
Hey, you know what?
If I get that job, maybe we can
if I get that job, maybe we can
celebrate Christmas again, um,
send sabitha a better gift and
get you something good.
Get you something good.
Oh, I don't need anything.
Well, you need breakfast.
I'm gonna make it, okay?
It's got to be noon, doesn't it?
Thank you.
We go to the bottom of the
fourth with the score St. Louis
2, Chicago nothing.
It'll be 2, 3, and 4 in the
it'll be 2, 3, and 4 in the
Chicago order, bell, peña, and
Johnson against the St. Louis
righty, Murphy.
Righty, Murphy.
The 1-0 to bell, fast-ball
the 1-0 to bell, fast-ball
strike at the knees to even it
up 1-1.
Up 1-1.
Bell leads off here, but the
bell leads off here, but the
reason teruso likes him in the
two hole -- the ability to hit
and run -- excellent contact
hitter.
Hitter.
The 1-1 -- bell has swung off.
Soft fly into right center.
Will Paul...
I think we should go with
brown one.
Brown one.
It's shinier.
It'll be easier to clean.
Okay, sounds good.
[Cellphone ringing]
Oh, that's probably Rachel.
Will you tell her I'll be there
will you tell her I'll be there
in 20 minutes?
In 20 minutes?
Yeah.
We have to finish the walls in
we have to finish the walls in
1b today, just the walls.
Okay.
Hello?
Is this Ken gaudette's phone?
Yes. Hi, Rachel.
He's gonna be on his way
he's gonna be on his way
shortly.
Shortly.
I'm so sorry.
Johanna?
Is that you?
Yes.
Why are you answering my
why are you answering my
dad's phone?
[Dog barking]
He didn't say anything about
he didn't say anything about
pressing charges, right?
Pressing charges, right?
No.
No, no, he won't.
Oh.
Shit. Here he comes.
Okay.
[Engine shuts off]
Hey, bill.
The one-two pitch is a curve
the one-two pitch is a curve
ball, and strike three.
Ball, and strike three.
Oh.
Smells like you're barbecuing.
You trying to get back in
you trying to get back in
prison in time for softball
season?
Season?
[Chuckles]
Hi.
...But it is called strike
...but it is called strike
three...
Three...
We're just bringing back some
we're just bringing back some
furniture.
Furniture.
Johanna thought it was mine.
It's not your furniture.
I think that's up for debate.
I explained the history to
you.
You.
...As we heard toward the
...as we heard toward the
summer months...
Summer months...
Hey, sweetie.
...From Oklahoma state...
...from Oklahoma state...
You're, like, with her now,
you're, like, with her now,
aren't you?
Aren't you?
Yeah.
If you and Edith weren't so
if you and Edith weren't so
good at writing letters.
Good at writing letters.
He actually grew up in
he actually grew up in
stillwater, Oklahoma, was a
stillwater pioneer at the high
school there before he went to
Oklahoma state.
So, 1-0, the fast ball...
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Berkins centers in, and
berkins centers in, and
here's the one-two pitch.
Here's the one-two pitch.
Um, you boys want to help
um, you boys want to help
with the furniture?
With the furniture?
...Find the gap and roll to
...find the gap and roll to
the wall, as dango's around
first.
First.
He is headed into second with
he is headed into second with
a...
A...
Get out.
Sabitha, look --
sabitha, look --
are you deaf? Get out?
Are you deaf? Get out?
Look, I-I understand --
look, I-I understand --
if you're trying to bond with
me, just forget it and get out.
Me, just forget it and get out.
My father, um --
my father, um --
I don't care.
[Sniffling]
Your father's trying.
I know that you're mad at him.
I'm not mad at him.
[Breathes deeply]
[Sniffles]
[Sighs]
Why do you get to live with him?
We're gonna finish unloading
the furniture.
He wears that sweatshirt all the
time, the one that you gave him.
I like your shoes.
Thank you.
[Sighs]
[Indistinct speaking over
radio]
Hey, sabitha?
We were thinking that, uh, maybe
we were thinking that, uh, maybe
you should come back to Chicago
with us and, you know, stay for
the rest of the summer.
The rest of the summer.
Wow. [Chuckles]
What an amazing offer.
Or whatever you think is right,
or whatever you think is right,
bill.
Bill.
I-I mean, it would just be
for the summer.
Do you want to?
You'd come back here in the
you'd come back here in the
fall and finish school and...
Fall and finish school and...
We'd love to have you.
Johnson rounding third, but a
stop sign awaits him, and he'll
scramble back to the bag.
Scramble back to the bag.
[Speaking indistinctly]
Where you going?
To pack my stuff.
[Chuckles]
...Didn't have that much of a
...didn't have that much of a
lead.
Lead.
That may have cost him.
Her car will remain here.
Okay. Yeah.
He's like mowing the lawn,
he's like mowing the lawn,
doesn't have a shirt on, of
course.
Course.
He's all wet.
She's really cute in the video,
she's really cute in the video,
too.
Too.
She's got, like, you know, the
she's got, like, you know, the
bangs and high heels.
Bangs and high heels.
She's washing the car, trying to
she's washing the car, trying to
get his attention.
Get his attention.
It's a bit obnoxious.
[Chuckles]
What does this have to do
what does this have to do
with the Olympics?
With the Olympics?
Oh, the swim team made a
oh, the swim team made a
video to it and put it on the
Internet.
It went, like, completely viral.
♪ ...To go ♪
♪ ...to go ♪
♪ ooh, I can't wait ♪
♪ then I filled the spaces ♪
♪ right between the leather and
lace ♪
Lace ♪
[Grunting]
♪ I know where we can go
to run away ♪
To run away ♪
you think my dad will ever
pay you back?
Pay you back?
He and I are working on this
he and I are working on this
place together.
Place together.
Yeah, but you're paying for
yeah, but you're paying for
most of it, right?
Most of it, right?
We're working together.
♪ the music takes you over ♪
this smells so gross.
This smells so gross.
You ever think of all the people
you ever think of all the people
who've had sex in here, maybe
even on this carpet?
Even on this carpet?
There was this thing on the news
there was this thing on the news
once where they went in hotel
rooms and --
[Exhales sharply]
Johanna?
♪ the rhythm pulls me under ♪
♪ takes me over ♪
♪ I can't breathe ♪
you could always name it Ken
after my dad if it's a boy,
but -- eh.
But -- eh.
How about something different?
Um...Omar.
That's kind of cute, different.
What if it's a girl?
Allie's a cute girl name.
Mm-hmm.
Um...
Hey. Guess what.
Rachel quit, so you're looking
at the new assistant manager.
At the new assistant manager.
That's great.
Yeah.
I'm gonna make two bucks more
an hour.
An hour.
What's wrong with her?
I don't know.
You don't think you should
have another test?
Have another test?
The kit had two tests.
What about insurance?
Do you know how much it costs to
do you know how much it costs to
have a baby in the hospital?
Have a baby in the hospital?
No.
I'm just not ready to have to
another kid.
Another kid.
I mean, I barely just got my
shit together.
You know that 400 bucks you said
you lost and I said Chloe
probably took it?
Probably took it?
I know you took it.
And I know you probably spent it
and I know you probably spent it
on drugs.
On drugs.
I didn't spent it all on
drugs.
Drugs.
You should have told me you
you should have told me you
knew.
Knew.
I was waiting for you to do
that.
That.
And you didn't.
And then after awhile, it
and then after awhile, it
just -- it didn't matter.
Just -- it didn't matter.
It didn't matter?
Gee, thanks.
You're gonna have to stop,
you're gonna have to stop,
you know.
You know.
Stop what?
Whatever it is you take.
I hardly touch it.
I'm not stupid.
That was it?
Yeah.
You're married now?
Yeah. [Chuckles]
Here, will you take a picture?
Yeah.
[Camera shutter clicking]
Got it.
[Laughs]
Where'd you get that?
So, that was good, right?
You learned how to paint walls
you learned how to paint walls
and ceilings, pull up carpeting,
do grouting, and help pick out
the tiles.
The tiles.
Cheap labor.
It's not like solon was any
it's not like solon was any
more glamorous.
More glamorous.
I agree.
You'll be okay on the bus?
Yeah, don't sit next to any
yeah, don't sit next to any
weirdos.
Weirdos.
That's impossible.
Thanks for helping my dad.
Have a safe trip.
Thanks.
See you soon.
[Car doors opening and
[car doors opening and
closing]
Closing]
[Engine turns over]
[Marching music playing]
[Crowd shouting indistinctly]
I don't know why you don't
believe me.
Believe me.
I told you, I gave it to the
mechanic.
Mechanic.
All $600?
Yeah, all $600.
Pretty much.
I got the receipt somewhere.
Oh, just wait.
[Baby crying]
It's okay, buddy.
It's okay.
Aw. I'll take him.
Shh. What's on his face?
Okay, you ready?
We're finally gonna get this.
I think it's magic marker.
Shh. Shh.
Oh.
[Baby cooing]
Oh, I just want to bite his
oh, I just want to bite his
little toes off.
Little toes off.
Oh, you just look like butter.
[Smooching]
I just want to eat you up.
Yum, yum, yum.
[Slurping]
Oh, what's that on his face?
Ah, it's lipstick.
[Squeals]
[Chuckles]
Look at that. What is that?
Here.
Take him.
I'll go get us some punch.
Will you grab the wipes out
will you grab the wipes out
of there?
Of there?
You know, Ken, I've been
you know, Ken, I've been
known to hold a baby now and
then.
Then.
Okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, this hand.
Oh, don't wake up, pumpkin.
Don't wake up.
Oh, ga-ga, ga-ga.
What about something more
what about something more
piratical?
Piratical?
Engineering?
I think I'm gonna major in
premed, um, and I really want to
go to Cornell for medical school
after, but I think I'll do a
junior year abroad first,
possibly in like France or Italy
or england, something like that.
Or england, something like that.
[Chuckles] Cool.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Well, I was a history major,
well, I was a history major,
and you see what that got me.
And you see what that got me.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, well, I really want to
yeah, well, I really want to
specialize in dermatology
because it allows you a pretty
good schedule so I can have
kids.
Kids.
I really want a girl.
Um, so, hopefully I'll be
um, so, hopefully I'll be
married by the time I'm 26.
Married by the time I'm 26.
That way, by the time they go to
that way, by the time they go to
college, I'll still have time
to, you know, live a little.
To, you know, live a little.
What do you want?
I have what I want.
[Tammy wynette's
[tammy wynette's
"'til I get it right" plays]
"'Til I get it right" plays]
Here. You go up.
Okay.
All right.
♪ I'll just keep on ♪
♪ falling in love ♪
♪ till I get it right ♪
♪ right now I'm like ♪
♪ a wounded bird ♪
♪ hungry for the sky ♪
♪ but if I try my wings ♪
♪ and try long enough ♪
♪ I'm bound to learn to fly ♪
♪ so I'll just keep on falling
in love ♪
In love ♪
♪ till I get it right ♪
♪ my door to love ♪
♪ has opened up ♪
♪ more times than in ♪
♪ and I'm either fool ♪
♪ or wise enough ♪
♪ to open it again ♪
♪ 'cause I'll never know ♪
♪ what's beyond the Mountain ♪
♪ till I reach the other side ♪
♪ so I'll just keep on ♪
♪ falling in love ♪
♪ till I get it right ♪
♪ if practice makes perfect ♪
♪ then I'm near bout as perfect
as I'll ever be in my life ♪
As I'll ever be in my life ♪
♪ so I'll just keep on ♪
♪ falling in love ♪
♪ till I get it right ♪