Episode 21
My dish is fish soup.
Amy, is it yours?
It's mine.
you have to give me a reward.
Chris is planning on
retiring from cooking.
I've turned my cooking into
something that can hurt people.
Why are you being so mean?
We're going to lose.
I cannot assess Si Ping's dish.
I added Chinese pepper, which you hate.
Shi Wen High!
Although I didn't win this
competition with glory
but if I don't have a choice
Your competition's professionalism
has nothing to do with me anyway.
We certainly neglected
some factors in our scoring.
The winning team of this
competition should be...
Si Ping.
Subtitles by DramaFever
Spit out the seeds from our friendship?
Just remove the seeds.
Remove them...
That makes "girlfriend"?
Girlfriend?
Hold it!
Don't say it out so loudly!
If Ma Chong Sheng and the guys hear you,
it will be so embarrassing.
If it's Liu Xuan standing here today
you wouldn't be embarrassed.
Wang Mai Zhi, thanks for
taking care of me.
But I don't wish to make you
embarrassed anymore.
We'll just stay classmates.
You... Wait a minute!
I didn't mean to say that
you embarrass me.
So you mean that being
with me is embarrassing?
It's not that.
I'm just worried that our
classmates might gossip.
What about?
Gossip about...
About some...
I'm heading home now. Goodbye!
Weirdo Zhen!
What was I talking about?
Meng Chen! Slow down!
Why are you running off?
We're going to have pizza to celebrate.
Don't bother. I don't want to have pizza.
Come with us.
It's better to have pizza
with a group of people.
I'm not shameless like you.
I know that everyone dislikes me!
Why don't you just apologize
to everyone and it'll be fine?
Why should I apologize?
You went a bit overboard today.
We all worked so hard.
- You shouldn't have scolded us...
- I don't need to be preached.
Go away! I'm going home.
- I'll walk you home?
- No!
I must!
Otherwise, you might ignore me tomorrow.
So what if I do?
You have so many close classmates.
It's best that all of you ignore me!
Meng Chen!
What are you doing?
Behave yourself.
You really think that I won't smack you?
Han Jie, do you have to be so adorable?
All right then.
Since you won't let me near Fang Xia Rou
I'll have to give all my love to you.
What are you doing? Hey!
What are you doing?
- Give me a wet tissue.
- Here.
- And the hand sanitizer.
- Hey! Am I that filthy?
Here, I'll wipe it off for you.
Here?
He gave you such a wet kiss?
Fine, you're showing off
your affection that much?
Are you trying to piss this bachelor off?
I'm sorry. We didn't mean to show
off our affection on purpose.
We're always like this in our daily life.
Right?
All right, since you said so
I'll tell you the truth
about something else.
Xiao Rou, aren't you
going to tell Han Jie?
Yesterday, you left this little under...
Hold it! I don't care what
you have in your hand.
It has nothing to do with me.
Han Jie, I didn't go
to his place yesterday.
You have to trust me.
All right! This isn't hers.
This belongs to my cute pet.
Han Jie, would you like
to meet my cute pet?
Your cute pet?
Here...
It's a baby!
You have a child?
Exactly. I'm not as slow as you are.
In this aspect, you're way behind me.
Am I right, darling? Laugh at him!
You'll need to make more effort.
What's good in just
displaying public affection?
If you can, why don't you work
harder and catch up to me?
Han Jie, take care.
This new dad is off to pursue my dreams.
I'll leave Taiwan to you.
We'll are out to challenge the world.
My darling and I are off
to tour the world.
Don't miss me too much.
Who will miss you?
Get going!
I know that Uncle Han Jie
likes my bum the most.
You mustn't forget me.
I'll add you to my Facebook friends
and like your page!
It's a deal!
I love you! Bye!
Bye.
Why would you add him to your Facebook?
You never liked my posts.
We know each other so well.
- Why should I like your posts?
- How well?
I was even teased for
displaying affection.
What now?
What about that?
We have to catch up with him.
Why don't we make a schedule?
What schedule?
I don't know what
you're talking about?
The students are waiting for me.
I have to go.
If you have no objections, here I come?
I mustn't lose to that guy.
What is it with you both?
Do you have to compete about that?
You're so competitive!
The contest finally ended so well.
I hope that when we meet Chris again
you can be friends.
Stop competing about everything.
We're competitors and enemies.
Who told you that we're friends?
Are you kidding me?
I only treated him as a friend
because of you.
If not, I'd have thrown a fit.
Really?
You seem so easily bullied.
Show me your angry face.
Han Jie, you'd better watch it.
You don't seem fierce at all.
You're still so cute.
Forget it.
Chris is off to tour the world anyway.
Would someone suddenly
hop out to scare me again?
One trouble is solved, but there's
another left to be resolved.
What is it?
You saw how the contest went.
I'm worried about them.
Then what do you plan to do?
The result of the contest won't ever
be as important as the process.
That's why I have to take some measures.
It might be a bit risky
and it might affect the final outcome
but I have to do it.
You'll support my decision?
Of course!
I'll surely support any
decision that you make.
I haven't even said what I'm planing
and you're giving me your support?
- Isn't that being a bit blind?
- Blind?
I'm like a parasite in your stomach.
I already know what you have in mind.
It's just that it's indeed a bit risky.
It might also affect
the outcome of the contest.
You're so sharp?
You read my mind.
Why don't you read my mind now?
You've had a hard day. Go to bed early.
You're not to dream of me.
Why can't I dream of you?
You overthink so easily.
What should I do if you speed up
on our relationship in your dreams?
Who would have such dreams?
You're so annoying.
I'm getting out of the car.
I've installed a new mechanism.
You can only get out of my car
after doing this.
You can get out of the car now.
You're so annoying. I'm off.
- Bye.
Han Jie, if that student is upset
can you leave her to me?
I'm not worried at all with you around.
Bye.
Ma Chong Sheng.
Do you know why
we got called here so early?
It should be about
preparing ahead of time
and training for the semi-final?
We're competing tomorrow.
Are we still in time for extra training?
We aren't.
With your standard, it's useless even
if we train three more months.
It's also too late to ask around
about the competitor now?
Shi Wen High School used to gather
all the competitors' information
three months before the contest.
What's the use of having information?
They still lost yesterday.
What's there to be happy about?
I heard that a lot of schools
improved a lot this year.
So?
We're definitely going to lose?
You want to lose
but I don't want to.
Mr. Han is arriving soon.
It's not good for him to see us fight.
Who wants to argue with her?
- If she shuts up, we will.
- Exactly.
What have I done wrong?
I might even have a better idea
than our teachers
about which schools are tougher.
Shi Wen High School has been
the champion for years.
But their instructor's strategy
means everything.
The students just follow orders
without ideas of their own.
- But Qiang Ren and Yong Sheng--
- Will that help?
That's just aiming to strike
at others' weaknesses
but it won't fortify your strengths.
Mr. Han. Ms. Fang.
What should we do then?
The point of having a contest is to
have the students work as a team.
You're all training to work as cooks.
You'll need your teammates
to work with you and help you.
Only then could you run a restaurant.
We might have won yesterday
but sadly, a regrettable
incident occurred.
Ms. Fang and I have decided
to replace a contestant.
Chen Meng Chen, I'm very sorry.
I have to ask you to leave.
Your performance affected
my team greatly.
Sir, how do we compete
with one less member?
I'd also like to know
who is capable enough to replace me?
Don't worry, I've already asked
Kong Meng Zhe, Wei Qi Zhen
and Amy Fan to attend a test.
I've already selected the replacement.
Come in!
Weirdo Zhen!
I can't accept this!
Mr. Han, aren't you afraid that
this will affect the contest?
Wei Qi Zhen's skills are
too inferior to mine.
- Si Ping High School might lose!
- I'll take the responsibility.
Meng Chen, you may return
to the classroom now.
Bye.
Meng Chen.
Ms. Fang, what is it?
I just wish to tell you
that if you feel wronged
you should work even harder
to make it back on the team.
How have I not worked hard enough?
My culinary skills are
the best in the class.
In a contest,
what matters more than skills
is team work.
But it was Liu Xuan who made
a mistake yesterday.
Why am I getting punished for it instead?
This is so unfair!
I don't mind that other classmates
edge me out or dislike me.
But even Mr. Han does that to me.
This is so mean.
I don't give a damn about
this stupid contest!
Fine. If you wish to run away
from your problems, do as you wish.
It's just that once you do it
you'll surely just keep
running away from all your problems.
If that is so, I'd advise you
to give up on cooking.
I'm not running away from anything.
I was forced to leave!
Who said that you can't
make it back on the team?
Meng Chen, you were flustered
when Liu Xuan made a mistake.
You said to give up the contest
and admit defeat.
Wasn't that a grave mistake you made?
Shouldn't Mr. Han punish you?
You've always been the most
outstanding student in class.
Are you going to admit defeat
or start all over again?
It's up to you.
I won't admit defeat!
I'll prove that I'm the most
qualified contestant.
Weirdo Zhen, what are you doing?
Are you still mad at me?
Come here. I have to talk to you.
You can say it here.
There are too many people around.
You don't want me to apologize?
Wang Mai Zhi, you don't
have to apologize.
I was too stupid.
I thought that sincerity is all
it takes to move someone.
But I didn't realize that
some people don't care for it.
Wait a minute!
What should I do to get
you to talk to me?
I just realized that I'm not fit
to be Wang Mai Zhi's good friend.
Why not?
This secretive friendship
won't do you any good
if others know about it.
I'd rather just stay classmates.
At least I won't have to worry about
being discovered by anyone.
Or else you'll be mad at me
and dislike me even more.
Weirdo Zhen...
Did I make you sad?
No!
I just know very clearly
if my existence matters.
I've had a great time.
- Goodbye.
- Weirdo Zhen!
Can't you ride a bike? Turn!
Free tempo.
You can dance whatever you want.
Me? Girlfriend?
What should we do?
The rules of the semi-final states
that the instructor can
only instruct, but not cook.
It means that the students can
only depend on themselves?
Are you worried about
Ah-Sheng's abilities?
I'm actually worried about Qi Zhen.
Other than doing well in desserts
it's still a bit worrying when
it comes to her other cuisine.
She's been practicing hard.
I think that she will catch up soon.
We should give her a chance.
Han Jie, can I ask you a question?
Why did you choose Qi Zhen over
Amy or Meng Zhe?
Because she's a lot like you.
You both share a very important trait.
It's sincerity.
Her cuisine is very heart-warming.
And she has a very sensitive heart.
That's what the others don't have.
I hope that all five of them can make
the best of their unique traits
to make it through this contest.
You actually think that Weirdo Zhen
and I are very alike?
Her hair is quite cute.
Why don't I get the same perm?
Sure. No matter what you become
you'll always be my Fang Xiao Rou.
Do whatever you like.
Yours?
It's as if you had some seal over me?
I do.
I'll give you one right now.
Report!
I'm sorry, Ms. Fang, Mr. Han!
I didn't see a thing!
- Please continue.
- Ma Chong Sheng, turn around.
Mr. Han and I weren't doing anything.
What is it?
Why do you seem so nervous?
When the five of us were
getting ready to practice
we suddenly found Qi Zhen missing.
Someone saw Chen Meng Chen
taking Qi Zhen away.
- Chen Meng Chen!
- Qi Zhen!
Weirdo Zhen!
What is she doing?
Chen Meng Chen!
- Qi Zhen!
- Chen Meng Chen!
Weirdo Zhen!
How is it? Did you see Weirdo Zhen?
We searched a lot of places
but we still haven't seen her.
Mai Zi, Meng Chen and Weirdo Zhen
disappeared together.
Why aren't you concerned about Meng Chen?
Of course not.
It doesn't take much to figure out
that Chen Meng Chen was displeased
with Weirdo Zhen replacing her
so she took her away
to bully her as a revenge.
That's impossible!
Although Chen Meng Chen is a bit...
A bit what?
A bit straightforward.
But she won't bully anyone.
You're bullying her by accusing her.
Mai Zi, why don't we search
in different directions again?
Forget it.
It's more important to save her.
I'll call the police myself.
Tang Xiao Niu, what are you doing?
Didn't you say that you want a "hug"?
(Sounds like "calling the police".)
You're still in the mood to joke?
- Get off!
- What are you doing?
Why are you arguing?
- He accused Meng Chen!
- He won't let me find Weirdo Zhen!
All right, I know that you're all
eager to find them.
Have you tried calling
Meng Chen or Qi Zhen?
I've asked around for Meng Chen's
cell phone number, but nobody has it.
I called Weirdo Zhen a hundred times!
But she won't pick it up.
I'll give it a try.
Hello?
Hello, Qi Zhen?
That's strange?
Weirdo Zhen didn't answer when you called
but she answered Ms. Fang.
Qi Zhen, are you and Meng Chen all right?
What's wrong, Ms. Fang?
Your classmates said that
you suddenly disappeared, so--
Weirdo Zhen, why did you purposely
refuse to answer my calls?
Mr. Han and Ms. Fang
Wei Qi Zhen!
Get back to your practice quickly!
I'm sorry. I have to get back
to my training.
Qi Zhen!
Luckily, they are both fine.
Exactly. I was almost scared to death.
Since they are both fine
we should tidy up the classroom first.
I still have to head home
to help my grandma.
Mai Zi, where are you going?
I'm just a bit upset.
I'm going for a walk.
Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
Are you just going to leave
Wei Qi Zhen and Chen Meng Chen alone?
Although Wei Qi Zhen and Chen Meng Chen
don't perform as well
in skills or team work
they both share a trait that I admire.
They are willing to make an effort
and spend time on accomplishing a task.
What about you?
Do you really think that
you're all much better than them?
Do you think that you can get
through the second round?
Mr. Han, I almost cost everyone
the first round of the contest.
I wish to apologize to everyone.
I'll surely practice even harder.
I was really nervous that day as well.
I should also stay behind to practice
- to avoid making the same mistake.
- Exactly.
Meng Chen was right to scold me.
I should practice more
so as not to lose to Meng Chen.
Let's go practice now.
I'm used to practicing at home.
Bye.
Wang Mai Zhi!
The main gate is over there.
Where are you going?
No... I just recall that I should keep
an eye on Chen Meng Chen and Weirdo Zhen
so that they won't slack off.
Having mentored these students
for so long
they have finally matured.
They are going to practice voluntarily.
Practice doesn't guarantee good results.
No matter how the outcome might be
I believe that this will be
a great experience for them.
As long as they do their best,
it is a good contest.
You're right. The process is
much more important than...
The result.
Wrong!
How many times do you want me to repeat?
It's still wrong!
Wrong!
Did I teach you that?
I'm sorry. I'm too nervous!
I'll do it again!
How is this a thin slice?
This is a thick slice!
Seriously...
Your fingers have to push
against the blade
so that you won't cut yourself. Get it?
- Try it again.
- Okay, I got it.
Let me have a look.
It's bandaged. Keep going.
Okay.
After you've practiced knife skills
I'll train you in seasoning techniques.
You have to win the semi-final.
I'll do my best!
Meng Chen, thank you
for taking to time to train me.
Why are you thanking me?
I'm only helping you for my own sake.
You have to make it into the finals
in order for me to get back on the team.
You're not to lose. Hear me?
I understand!
Chen Meng Chen, why are you
torturing our Weirdo Zhen?
Do you know who she is to me?
I don't know. Who is she to you?
Anyway, I'm the only person in
the world who can bully her!
Weirdo Zhen, let's go.
I...
I don't want to!
Weirdo Zhen, what are you doing?
I'm the only person in
the world who can bully her!
Weirdo Zhen, let's go.
I...
I don't want to!
What are you doing?
Is this the Stockholm Syndrome?
Why are you staying to be tortured
by that Pretentious Chen?
She's not torturing me!
Meng Chen is training me very seriously.
See?
She's not a teacher.
Who is she to train you?
Fine, if you want training
I can help you with it.
No!
Weirdo Zhen, you'd rather practice
with that Pretentious Chen
than practicing with me?
Meng Chen is stricter.
I'll improve faster.
Fine. You said it.
Don't regret it.
Are you done yet? Get going.
We have a lot to practice.
Time is precious.
Wei Qi Zhen, get back here.
Hurry up.
Keep practicing. Hurry up.
Chen Meng Chen, just wait and see.
Chop quickly.
Let me have a look.
It's very thin.
Keep working hard on it.
Weirdo Zhen is such a silly girl.
How dare she turn me down?
It's fine to turn me down
but did she have to do it
in front of Chen Meng Chen?
She didn't even save me some face.
Do you have weapons in your bag?
What is it that's so heavy?
My ribs and internal organs are broken...
- Is this funny?
- Medical fees...
- It's not funny.
- Then?
Do you want to be bashed up?
- No.
- Then stay away from me.
I'm in a foul mood today.
First, you knock into me
and now you scold me?
You want to be bashed up?
You're really...
Get lost!
I'm off...
Friend? What friend?
It's all a lie!
She changes her mind so quickly
and turns on me!
What friend is that?
Lousy dictionary!
You're just a book of deception!
Forget it.
Your owner doesn't want you anymore.
Why don't you kill yourself?
Who threw this in without
finishing the food?
That's so inconsiderate.
More? Are you trying
to stink me to death?
What are you doing?
Found you!
Mr. Han...
Sir.
Can you give me two more wet tissues?
You washed your hands three times
and used the hand sanitizer.
- You still find it dirty?
- It's not for me.
It's for this.
Thank you.
It this dictionary very important?
No... It's not important...
I'll throw it away then. It stinks.
Wait a minute, sir!
No! You can't throw it away.
The contest is coming up soon
and you're not practicing?
Why were you going through the bin?
What for?
I'm so skilled that I don't need to
practice to defeat Qiang Ren High School.
Don't worry.
You're very confident. Good.
All your teammates are practicing
but you're idling around.
Aren't you worried that
they would say you're lazy?
How am I lazy?
- I was going to ask--
- Ask who?
No, I was just going to ask
some classmates to practice.
So...
it isn't that you don't need to practice,
but that you don't want to.
I guess it must be that
you asked someone to practice
with you but was rejected.
So now our World's Most Handsome Guy
is upset and doesn't want to practice?
You can even guess that right?
You're remarkable.
Mr. Han, why don't you become
a detective instead?
Let's try and guess who
you wanted to practice with?
Could it be Chen Meng Chen?
How is that possible?
How wants to practice with
that pretentious, arrogant
and rude person?
She's like a female version of me!
Version...
This is so infuriating!
It's fine that Ma Chong Sheng
misunderstood me.
Even Mr. Han misunderstands me?
Are we really such a good match?
You should ask yourself why
others would misunderstand you.
You're right. Why?
is it because I'm too handsome?
It's not my fault that I'm so handsome.
You should blame my parents.
Or is it because I'm too snobbish?
I know that I have a bad attitude
and I have a sharp tongue.
But this bad habit is hard to quit.
It's not about making the change
but if you've met that person
whom you'd change for?
Take me for example.
I didn't like desserts,
but now I have them every day.
Is it because of Ms. Fang?
Yes.
Have you met your Ms. Fang?
I think so...
No wonder I don't feel like coming
to school in my car anymore.
I find it more amusing to ride a bike.
It's not the bike.
It's the person who rides the bike
with you that makes it interesting.
It's not about doing something
but who you do it with?
You got it.
Okay, I got it.
Sir, thanks.
I'll surely practice
very hard from now on
to show that silly girl
how cool and capable I am.
Then she'll surely agree to
practice with me in the future.
Go.
Fang Xiao Rou?
What is it? Why the long face?
It's nothing.
I'm trying to draft a strategy.
In the semi-final, the supervising
teacher can only instruct.
I'm very troubled about delegating
the duties among the five students.
When you can't come up with any ideas
the best idea is not to think about it.
And bury my head in the sand?
Just have a drink and listen to gossips.
You might think of something
once you're relaxed, right?
You have a lot of weird ideas.
What gossip is it?
You want to hear about it as well, right?
I heard that our principal
has a mysterious son.
Have you heard about it?
I might have heard about it
or maybe I hadn't.
I don't remember.
How can you forget about
such an important matter?
Do you have to get so agitated?
Is it important whether
our principal has a son or not?
It has nothing to do with us anyway.
It has nothing to do with you
- but it concerns me greatly.
- Why?
Mr. Wen hasn't updated his
Facebook status for two weeks already.
That's why I've decided
to find myself a backup.
You obviously care a lot about him.
Why do you have to put on
the mask of a witch?
Are you trying to conceal your feelings?
I'm not!
It's because you don't understand.
A popular woman like me
has too many suitors to choose from.
I have too many suitors.
I'm worried about picking out a bad guy.
I have to be more careful
and compare as many men as I can.
Come on. You don't even know
what the Principal's son look like.
- You're already putting him on the list?
- Of course.
No man can escape my claws.
All right, go and ask around then.
I wish you happiness.
Fang Xiao Rou.
What bosom friend are you?
Be careful that your man
will fall for me as well.
That's impossible.
That's because I have a conscience!
You wait and see.
Mr. Han!
What is it?
Don't say that I'm not a good friend.
I got hold of Qiang Ren
High School's strategy.
So?
Come here.
Have a seat.
All right, listen up.
I'm here to talk to you about
defeating them in the semi-finals.
It's all right.
I don't need such information.
I have faith in my students.
I believe that they can win this round.
Mr. Han, why are you so confident?
I have confidence in my students.
It's so nice to be
the supervising teacher.
It's so easy.
Unlike us, as counselors,
it's so stressful.
You know that the Principal handed
the huge responsibility of managing
National Culinary Contest to me.
I have to meet
the Principal's expectations.
I mustn't make him look bad
and also not let Si Ping down.
Wow...
Aren't the students at Si Ping
blessed to have you?
Don't worry, the students
won't let you down.
Mr. Han, on that note...
Come here.
Have you heard about
the Principal's mysterious son?
Do you know who he is?
Come here.
Have you heard about
the Principal's mysterious son?
Do you know who he is?
The principal's son?
Is that important?
Of course!
He's my strong competitor.
The candidates for
the next principal election
would be me and that Daddy's boy!
I think it's still too early to tell.
Really? Why?
First of all, I don't think
that the Principal is so old
that he's retiring soon.
Secondly, between you, Counselor Li
and the Principal's son
I'll surely support you.
Daddy's boy isn't any good.
It's really not good.
Mr. Han, I didn't know that
you're such a good friend!
You'd go against
the Principal's son for my sake.
Just for that reason,
I'll totally have your back!
May the two most handsome guys in
Si Ping lead the team to victory!
Okay, deal!
Mr. Han, who is "deal"?
Han Jie!
I thought about it long and hard.
I finally figured out
how to delegate everyone.
Listen.
Ah-Sheng is quick-witted.
Liu Xuan is very stable.
They could work together on seasoning.
What do you think?
Are you listening?
Anybody home?
Who are you looking for?
- I'm looking for you?
- Who am I?
You're Han Jie.
No, I'm your...
You're my boyfriend.
Someone finally remembers
that I'm her boyfriend?
It's not that. I really need your help.
Boyfriend.
Like I just said
Ah-Sheng can team up with Liu Xuan
then Mai Zi and Xiao Niu...
No, they both of them will argue.
Mai Zi should team up with Qi Zhen.
What do you think?
Do as you said then.
Are you sure?
You don't seem to care much about it.
You know the students so well,
I should go along with your decision.
What I care about is that you've
been too busy to eat properly.
That's not very important...
I disagree.
Your health matters more to me
than anything else.
All right, I understand.
Someone is actually too busy
to care about me.
Is my ingenious chef acting cute?
Am I the cute pet or you?
What do you say?
Let me have a look!
It's me!
I'm so tired from carving that.
Shouldn't you express some concern?
Aren't you nervous that the semi-final
is just around the corner?
- Are you changing the topic?
- No, it's just...
I'm really worried about the contest.
There's nothing to worry about.
If we can't figure out the theme
we'll just be fully prepared
to tackle any theme.
- But...
- But we should
place the students in a stressful
environment to train them to adapt.
- But...
- But, however, and?
Stop thinking if you can't come
up with anything else.
I'm hungry.
Let's go for lunch.
What kind of boyfriend only worries
about being hungry?
Don't display such affection
in front of me.
Everyone!
Get ready for the contest.
I'll wait outside. Come on out
when you're ready.
Don't forget to take it easy.
Yes!
Ah-Sheng, if I make a mistake again
don't help me out.
- Why?
- Then I can remind myself
to be more serious and careful.
I think that you can do very well today.
I'll do my best!
Tang Xiao Niu!
The Empress Dowager beckons.
Eunuch Niu is finally summoned.
At your service.
Reach out your hand.
Lightly.
I'm worried that I can't cook later.
Are you insane? Who's going to hit you?
What is this?
It's Chen Meng Chen's sachet.
You made it for me?
You'd better perform so well
as if you'd been possessed by me.
If you lose the contest, you have
to stay five meters away from me.
If I win this round?
Can I stay by your side, Miss Quiet?
Whatever.
Weirdo Zhen, come with me.
Wang Mai Zhi, what is it?
Nothing. This is just
something in return.
You gave me an amulet last time.
It's my turn to give you one this time.
Why does this amulet look so strange?
Did you jinx it?
Strange?
That's rude.
I made this by hand.
Put it on.
- I'd better not take it.
- Why not?
I want to finish this contest
with my own abilities.
I don't care.
If you don't wear it,
you'll affect my mood.
Do you want me to lose the contest
because I'm in a bad mood?
- No.
- No?
Then you should just wear it.
Very good.
You're not to take it off
without my permission.
Do you hear me?
Si Ping, go, go, go!
The semi-finals of
the National Culinary Contest
is between Si Ping Vocational High School
and Qiang Ren High School!
Si Ping defeated their tough opponent
Shi Wen High School in the first round
right at the end.
Now that they are up against
a strong team like Qiang Ren
I believe that this must be
a very exciting contest!
The guys have crew cuts
and the girls are in bobs.
They are almost as scary as
the devil's team in movies.
Their aprons are even
in camouflage colors.
They are like an army.
Our theme is seafood cuisine.
The rule in the semi-finals is that
supervising teachers can only instruct
but they aren't allowed to cook.
All right. Are you ready?
Okay, ninety minutes...
The contest starts now!
The menu is...
up to you.
Is that... Is that okay?
Weirdo Zhen, what are you afraid of?
You have me.
You've learned so many different
dishes over the past three years.
This is the best time to see the results.
I'll leave the five of you
solely in charge.
I remember when we were looking
for ingredients in mountains and ocean
Mr. Han taught us how to make
fish balls from Taiwanese snappers.
We learned that all ingredients
are equally valuable. Then it was...
Mai Zi seafood gratin!
I mean durian seafood gratin.
It taught us that nothing is impossible.
And... During the Universiade
we made exotic first-class soup
fresh fish soup,
and lemon konnyaku jelly.
Which one should we make?
Mr. Han used to teach us
different dishes.
It's exotic dishes
that don't seem exotic.
Why don't we make our
seafood cuisine not seem like one?
How about that?
That's right. I thought so as well.
All right then.
Let's make seafood cuisine
that doesn't seem like one?
This is the first time that
you're cooking on your own.
I know that you're a bit nervous
but both Mr. Han and I trust in you.
So just give it your all.
Ms. Fang and I will be
watching you on the side.
Don't be afraid to make mistakes.
This is your contest.
- Take your positions!
- Yes!
Meng Chen gave me a sachet.
How can I forget about it?
It's Chen Meng Chen indeed.
I feel so inspired.
I have so much fight in me now.
Pei Ying, could you make me a promise?
No.
It's very simple.
If we win today
can you promise me a reward?
Sure.
Pei Ying, we've known each other
for so long already.
You finally know how much effort I made.
Have you thought of the reward?
If we don't lose this round
I'll decide not to kill you.
How do you like this reward?
Meng Chen, thanks for training Qi Zhen.
Let's cheer for Qi Zhen together.
Qi Zhen, you can do it!
Go, go, go!
You still end up cheering
for them with us.
Even without you,
We'll still win the semi-finals.
Just sit here and cheer
for our classmates.
I've sent out my apprentice, Wei Qi Zhen.
She alone can defeat Qiang Ren!
Just wait and see!
Qi Zhen, you can do it!
Next, it's the really difficult part.
It's the flounder sashimi
that's 0.1 centimeter thick...
It's just a flounder.
How difficult could it be?
I don't think that
it will be an issue for me.
Can you do it?
If I can't, can you?
I recommend Liu Xuan.
I think that she's agile with her hands.
She's also attentive to details.
Mai Zi, let me give it a try.
Mr. Han, how should we slice
the perfect flounder sashimi?
Think of your fingers as
the extension of your blade.
Lower the core of your body weight.
Don't put weight on your hands,
but your waist. Do it in one stroke.
Quickly.
Why is it turning out like that?
We only have ten more minutes to go.
Wei Qi Zhen! I just taught you!
Have you forgotten all about it?
My dictionary doesn't have the words
"defeat", "failure", or "cowardice".
There's nothing that I can't do.
Qi Zhen, believe in yourself.
Qi Zhen, you're awesome!
Go!
Go, go, go!
Both teams used the same concept
of a seafood platter.
But they used completely
different culinary methods.
Which team has won the judges over?
The teams of the semi-finals of the
National High School Culinary Contest
have very close scores.
But...
Si Ping Vocational High School excelled
in creativity and knife skills.
Therefore, the winner is Si Ping!
Wait a minute!
Meng Chen, thank you.
If you hadn't trained me
we might not have won the contest.
Meng Chen, you might not have
represented the school in this round
you've contributed greatly. Well done.
We won the contest together.
Meng Chen, you deserve to
take credit for it as well.
I didn't do anything.
Wait a minute.
I have to thank you as well.
I also want to apologize to you.
I didn't mean to sound so bitter.
You're really very outstanding.
I just didn't want to admit it.
I'm sorry.
- It's fine.
- Thank you, Meng Chen!
- Let's cheer for Meng Chen!
- Don't touch me!
Don't be so nice to me.
I'm still used to having you dislike me.
Where are you going?
Forget it. She's too proud.
It's best not to push her.
We'll go for hamburgers later.
It's on me.
Meng Chen!
What?
We're going to celebrate
and have hamburgers.
- Aren't you going to join us?
- Why should I?
It proves that Si Ping can still make it
into the finals without me.
Our class don't need me anymore.
But I do.
Who cares about you?
Why are your eyes red?
They aren't!
Are you upset that you
can't get back to the team?
I'll talk to Mr. Han to...
You're not to go!
But...
It's fine as long as
Si Ping can win the contest.
I don't matter that much.
Weirdo Zhen!
Weirdo Zhen, stop right there.
What is it?
- You don't listen to me anymore?
- That's not it.
Stop right there, Weirdo Zhen!
Wang Mai Zhi, let go of me right away!
The students are coming out soon.
- You'll find this very embarrassing.
- No!
I won't let you go no matter what.
What's embarrassing to be seen with you?
Goodbye.
won't do you any good if
others know about it.
I'd rather that we just stay classmates.
At least, I won't have to worry about
being found out by others
and you won't get mad at me
or dislike me even more.
Have I made you very sad?
No.
I just know clearly what
my existence means.
I've been very happy.
- Goodbye.
- Weirdo Zhen!
Weirdo Zhen!
Weirdo Zhen, I like you!
This... This can't be true...
Who said that you can hug me?
Player Zhe!
The truth is finally out!
Mai Zi has been picking on me recently.
That's because he likes Weirdo Zhen!
Mai Zi, cool!
Of course! I'm so cool that
the gods and men are furious.
Do I need you to tell me this?
I can't breathe.
Really?
Don't worry, if you faint
I'll do mouth-to-mouth resuscitation.
Wang Mai Zhi finally figured it out.
That's not right?
What's with that paternal
look in your eyes?
Is that the right reaction?
What's wrong with them being
honest about their feelings?
it's all fine apart from the fact
that they are still minors.
Stay apart!
If Counselor Li sees you
you'll have to write a repent letter.
Counselor Jiang!
Please don't walk away so quickly!
Get lost!
We already won the semi-finals.
What about a candle-lit dinner?
See?
He nearly saw you.
Ms. Fang, thanks for covering up for us.
What is it? You've been pouting.
What are you worried about?
I'm worried about the students
falling in love so early.
It's not good.
Do you think that we set
a bad example and affected them?
When did we set a bad example?
We're adults. It's normal to be in love.
The point is that the students
are still minors.
We keep displaying
public affection in school.
Would they learn from us?
This is really bad.
What should we do if the Principal
sees this when he gets back?
Didn't we say that we're going to report
to the Principal about our relationship?
You really want me to tell him?
That's not a good idea?
I'm really bad with words.
You're better with words.
Why don't you do it?
It's not a speech contest.
Just report to the Principal honestly
about our relationship. That's all.
You make it sound so easy.
Just the thought of it
makes my palms sweat.
Is the Principal that scary?
What are you afraid of?
You're not scared?
Why don't you tell him then?
You're quite good with words?
I'll leave that to you then.
I feel so relieved.
- It's a deal.
- No...
Let's discuss about it, please?
What did you say?
Let's discuss about it.
No.
You're quite pleased to see me nervous?
All right, I'll stop teasing you.
If you're really worried
we can report to the Principal together.
- Really?
- Yes, I'll be in charge.
Do you know that I've panicked
about this matter for a long time?
What's there to panic about? Silly.
Give me your hand.
Your turn!
Is this really okay?
What's not okay about this?
Weren't you afraid that
the others will know about it
and you'll find it embarrassing?
I...
I have courage now.
I'm not scared anymore.
Is that okay?
In the future, we'll...
We'll be...
In the future, you're mine.
Even if the sky comes crashing down
I'll be there to protect you.
Get it?
And in the future,
only I can bully you.
Only I can hold your hand.
Hear me?
Okay.
Lend me your cell phone.
Boy...
Hello?
You're not to hide from me
and you're not to run away
when you see me.
You also have to answer my calls
because I am your boyfriend.
By the way, open up
that amulet I gave you.
The world's most handsome guy!
Do you now know how much
effort I've made?
When you were competing,
I was dangling by your chest
to cheer you on.
Thank you!
Is it your turn to say thank you?
It should be my turn.
Where's my gift?
But... I didn't prepare any gifts.
And I've only had NT$100 left
of pocket money this month...
Who wants you to spend your pocket money?
I want that...
I want the gift that you
can't get from just a friend.
- Counselor...
- What are you doing?
Wang Mai Zhi... Wei Qi Zhen!
You're doomed!
Subtitles by DramaFever