There.
Technicals, 9 o'clock.
Oh, shit!
Did you see that?
Chief, we got unarmed civilians
getting shot down here at 9 o'clock.
I got it, Matt.
I don't think
we can touch this.
Command Super 6-4, we got
militia shooting unarmed civilians
down at the food
distribution centre.
Request permission
to engage.
Super 6-4, are you taking fire? Over.
- Negative, Command.
- U.N.'s jurisdiction, 6-4.
We cannot intervene.
Return to base.
- Over.
- Roger.
6-4 returning.
Mm.
Leaving.
General Garrison?
- No. No, thanks. I got one.
- But these are Cuban.
Bolivar Belicoso.
So is this.
Miami, my friend, is not Cuba.
I see not catching Aidid
is becoming a routine.
We weren't trying to catch Aidid.
We were trying to catch you.
Me? But am I that important?
I hardly think so.
- You're just a businessman.
- Trying to make a living.
Selling guns
to Aidid's militia.
You've been here, what,
six weeks?
Six weeks you are trying
to catch the general.
You put up reward posters.
Twenty-five thousand dollars.
What is this,
gunfight at the K.O. Corral?
It's, uh... It's the O.K. Corral.
Do you think bringing me in would
make him suddenly come to you?
Make him more agreeable?
- Hm?
- Well, you know where he sleeps.
You pay for his beds,
much less his militia.
We're not leaving Somalia
until we find him.
- And we will find him.
- Don't make the mistake...
of thinking because I grew up without
running water, I am simple, general.
I do know something about history.
See all this?
It's simply shaping tomorrow.
A tomorrow without a lot of
Arkansas white boys' ideas in it.
Well, I wouldn't know
about that. I'm from Texas.
Mr. Garrison, I think you
shouldn't have come here.
This is civil war.
This is our war, not yours.
Three hundred thousand
dead and counting.
That's not a war, Mr. Atto.
That's genocide.
Now, you enjoy
that tea, you hear?
How did he strike you?
Urbane,
sophisticated, cruel.
Yeah, he's a good catch.
It'll take some time,
but Aidid will feel the loss.
I'm not sure time is something
we got in great supply.
This isn't Iraq, you know.
Much more complicated than that.
Boss, most of Washington
might disagree.
I'm just saying, they've been calling for these
dang situation reports every morning this week.
Well, tell them the situation
is, uh, fragile.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my name is Cliff "Elvis" Wolcott.
I'll be your pilot this afternoon.
Federal regulations has designated this
a non-smoking Black Hawk helicopter.
For those of you enrolled in our
Mogadishu frequent-flyer program,
you'll be earning 100
free credits this afternoon.
And as always,
the air-sickness bags are located
in your seat back in front of you.
Number one indications
are good, Cliff. Put her on two.
6-1, this is 6-4. Go to U.H.F. secure.
I've got some bad news.
"Limo" is a word, Durant.
I don't wanna hear about it.
It is not a word.
It's an abbreviation of a word.
"Limo" is a word
in common usage.
That is the key phrase in Scrabble,
my good friend. Common usage.
No. If it's not in the dictionary,
it doesn't count.
It doesn't have
to be in the dictionary.
It does have
Listen. When we get back to the
base, it's coming off the board.
You touch my limo and I'll spank
you, Nightstalker. You hear me?
Yeah, promises.
That's a nice beach
down there.
How's the water?
Yeah, it's nice and warm.
And it's loaded with sharks.
- Name?
- Todd.
- Last name?
- Blackburn.
- First name, Todd.
- So, what's it like?
- What's what like?
- Mogadishu. The fighting.
- Serial number?
- 7-2-1-6-3-4-2-7.
Firstly, it's "the Mog,"
or simply "Mog."
No one calls it
Mogadishu here.
Secondly, I wouldn't know
about the fighting, so don't ask.
- Why not?
- Didn't I just say, "Don't ask"?
Look, kid, you look like you're about
12, so let me explain something to you.
I have a rare and mysterious skill that
precludes me from going on the missions.
- Typing.
- Can you type?
No.
- Date of birth?
- 2-27-75.
Well, I'm here
to kick some ass.
Let's bring it in.
Nice, man! Very smooth!
Single shot through
the engine block.
Shit, that's a shame.
That was a nice jeep.
Cease fire! Cease fire!
- Check your weapons.
- Sergeant Eversmann!
- Sergeant.
- Yeah?
Private First Class
Blackburn.
- Yeah?
- Reporting for duty.
Not to me, you're not. You're
reporting to Lieutenant Beales.
He should be around
here somewhere.
Can I leave him
with you?
Yeah, go ahead.
- You brought your weapon.
- Yes, sir.
Want me to shoot?
I'm rested.
- When did you get in?
- Just now, sergeant.
Hey, who's hungry?
What is this, sergeant? Another
taxpayer-funded Delta safari?
- Not if General Garrison's asking.
- Well, I'm asking.
Have a nice meal, captain.
- Hey, man, there's a line.
- I know.
- Well, this isn't the back of it.
- Yeah, I know.
Sergeant. Sergeant!
What's going on here?
Oh, just some aerial target practice, sir.
Didn't wanna leave it behind.
I'm talking about your weapon.
Delta or no Delta,
that's a hot weapon.
You know better than that. Safety
should be on at all times on base.
Well, this is my safety, sir.
Let it go, sir. The guy hasn't
eaten in a couple of days.
You Delta boys are a
bunch of undisciplined cowboys.
Let me tell you
something, Sergeant.
When we get on the five-yard line,
you're gonna need my Rangers.
So y'all better learn
to be team players.
We're done here.
Speak up.
You say this is your safety?
Well, this is my boot, son.
And it will fit up your ass
with the proper amount of force.
Is that your Jersey accent?
I'm trying to do this. Give me a break.
Take those sunglasses off, soldier.
If Delta wants to wear Oakleys,
that's their business.
I don't wanna see them
on you again. Hoo-ah?
Hoo-ah.
Is that a hot weapon?
- Is that your move?
- Is my hand on the piece?
I can mate you in three
whatever you do.
I'd keep my eye on that queen
before counselling with others.
Well, she's just lying in wait.
Griz. Yikes.
It's good.
You're really improving.
- Ah.
- If I may make a suggestion.
- Observation.
- It's a children's book, right?
Right.
They are not supposed to scare the
living shit out of the children.
This is the part of the story
where our knight, our warrior,
is about to slay
the one-eyed dragon.
That's scary. Besides,
my daughter loves this stuff.
- I thought you finished that last week.
- You done?
Hey. We are at the
ten-yard line here, men. You understand?
Can you count?
One, two, 10. Okay?
Where are my running backs?
- Where are my running backs?
Hoo-ah!
Hey, I didn't see you
in church on Sunday, soldier.
You had something
more important to do?
Not on Sunday, you don't.
Not anymore.
I will make you believe,
you understand?
It's pretty funny, hoo-ah?
Hoo-ah.
It was a good impression.
I recognise myself.
All right, carry on.
- Quick word, specialist.
- Sir.
Tell me, Pilla.
You understand why we have
a chain of command, don't you?
Roger that, sir.
'Cause if I ever see you
undermining it again,
you'll be cleaning latrines with your
tongue until you can't taste the difference
between shit and French fries.
Are we clear?
- Hoo-ah, sir.
- All right.
Listen to this.
If one skinny kills another skinny,
his clan owes the dead guy's clan
a hundred camels.
- A hundred camels.
- Camels. I wouldn't pay one camel.
Must be a lot
a fucking camel debt.
Is that really true, Lieutenant?
Well, ask Sergeant Eversmann.
He likes the skinnies.
Sergeant Eversmann,
you really like the skinnies?
It's not that I like them
or I don't like them. I respect them.
See, what you guys
fail to realise
is the sergeant here
is a bit of an idealist.
He believes in this mission down to
his very bones. Don't you, Sergeant?
Look, these people,
they have no jobs,
no food, no education,
no future.
I just figure that... I mean,
we have two things that we can do.
We can either help or we can sit back and
watch the country destroy itself on CNN.
Right?
I don't know about you guys,
but I was trained to fight.
You trained to fight,
sergeant?
Well, I think I was trained
to make a difference, Kurth.
Like the man said,
he's an idealist.
Wait. This is my favourite part.
Stay away from the cans!
Die, gas pumper!
Stay away from those cans!
Beales!
No, no, no, no.
Stay back. Stay back.
Wilkie, he's having a seizure.
Put something in his mouth.
Hey, John. It's okay.
John, it's okay. It's okay.
Well, he'll be fine,
but not in this army.
He's out of the game.
He's epileptic. Going home.
I'm putting you
in charge of his chalk.
- You got a problem with that?
- No, sir.
Now, it's a big responsibility.
Your men are gonna look to you
to make the right decisions.
Their lives depend on it.
All right.
- Rangers lead the way, sir.
- All the way.
Good luck, sergeant.
The long anticipated
meeting of Aidid's senior cabinet
may take place today
at 1500 hours.
I say "may" because
we all know by now,
with the intel we get on
the street, nothing is certain.
This is actual intel
confirmed by three sources.
Two tier-one personalities
may be present.
Omar Salad, Aidid's
top political advisor,
and Abdi Hassan Awale,
Interior Minister.
These are the guys
we're after.
Today we go.
Same mission template
as before.
Fifteen forty-five,
Assault Force Delta
will infiltrate
the target building
and seize
all suspects within.
Security Force Rangers: four Ranger chalks,
under the command of Captain Steele,
will rope in at 1546 and hold
a four-corner perimeter
around the target building.
No one gets in or out.
Extraction Force:
Lieutenant Colonel McKnight's
humvee column
will drive into the city at 1547
on Hawlwadig Road
and hold just short
of the Olympic Hotel.
Wait for the green light.
Now, once Delta
gives the word,
McKnight's column will move
to the target building
and load the prisoners
on flatbed trucks.
Immediately after
the prisoners are loaded,
the four Ranger chalks
will collapse back to the target
building, load up on humvees,
and the entire ground force will
exfil the three miles back to base.
Mission time from incursion to
extraction no longer than 30 minutes.
Now,
I had requested light armour
and AC-130 Specter gunships,
but Washington, in all its wisdom,
decided against this.
Too high-profile.
So Black Hawks and Little Birds
will provide the air cover
with mini-guns and 2.75 rockets.
Colonel Harrell.
In the C-2 bird,
Colonel Matthews
will coordinate the air mission,
and I will coordinate
ground forces.
Colonel Matthews.
Mission launch code word
is "Irene."
Questions?
Which building is it, sir?
Exactly which building
we're confirming right now.
Somewhere around
the Bakara market.
I don't choose the time
and place of their meetings.
I didn't say
a word, sir.
Make no mistake.
Once you're in the Bakara market,
you're in an entirely hostile district.
Don't underestimate
their capabilities.
We'll be going through friendly
neighbourhoods before we hit the market.
So remember the rules
of engagement:
No one fires
unless fired upon.
Let's go get this thing done.
Good luck, gentlemen.
What's the matter, Danny?
Something you don't like?
No Specter gunships,
daylight instead of night,
late afternoon when they're
all fucked up on khat,
only part of the city Aidid can mount a
serious counterattack on short notice.
- What's not to like?
- Life's imperfect.
Yeah. For you two. Circling above
it at 500 feet, it's imperfect.
Down in the street,
it's unforgiving.
What the fuck, Smith?
- Well?
- Well, what?
We going?
Why should
I tell you that?
Because I'm me.
Yeah. 3:00. Downtown.
- Bakara market.
- All right.
Listen, Smith. I need you to back
me up out there today, all right?
Keep sharp.
- Yes, sir, Sergeant Eversmann.
- All right.
Ev, it's gonna
be nothing, man.
Nothing.
It's all in the grind,
Sizemore.
Can't be too fine.
Can't be too coarse.
This, my friend,
is a science.
I mean, you're looking at the guy
that believed the commercials.
You know?
About "be all you can be."
I made coffee
through Desert Storm.
I made coffee through Panama while
everyone else got to fight,
got to be a Ranger.
Now it's "Grimesy,
black, one sugar,"
or "Grimesy, got
a powdered anywhere?"
- What happened to you?
- Ping-Pong accident.
- What?
- So guess what.
Your wish has been granted.
You're going out today.
You're fucking me.
You're taking my place
assisting the 60 gunner.
Sergeant Eversmann said to get
your stuff and get ready.
It's what you wanted,
isn't it?
Oh, yeah.
Hell, yeah.
Grimesy, I want you to stick with Waddell
and give him ammo when he needs it. Hoo-ah?
- Hoo-ah.
- I wouldn't worry about that.
Generally speaking,
Somalis can't shoot for shit.
Don't worry about it. Just watch out for the sammys
throwing the fucking rocks, and you'll be fine.
- Might even be fun.
D-boys do their thing now.
All we got to do
is cover them.
Choppers gonna cover us,
and we'll be all right.
Look, you guys, I know this
is my first time as chalk leader,
but this isn't our
first time out together.
This is serious.
We're Rangers,
not some sorry-ass J.R.O.T.C.
We're elite.
Let's act like it out there.
- Hoo-ah?
Hoo-ah!
Any questions?
We're gonna be okay.
All right, grab your gear.
Let's move out.
Hoo-ah!
You're not gonna
need that, dude.
We're not out there
long enough.
Hey, you're not gonna
need that either.
We'll be back
before dark.
You might as well take
dope and beer instead.
What?
Ammo, dude.
Take ammo.
Let me tell you something,
Grimes.
You got about 50 pounds of gear as it is.
You don't need another 12.
I don't know about you, but I'm not planning
on getting shot in the back running away.
Well, I better keep mine in.
Hey, Grimes.
The most important thing,
just remember when everybody else is
shooting, shoot in the same direction.
All right.
Look at this, Ruiz. He's taping
his blood type to his boots.
- That's bad luck.
- No, it's smart.
All Delta do that.
That's bad luck too, man.
Come on. Let's go.
It's a good thing
you're right-handed, Adonis.
If not, I don't know
what you'd do.
You're a funny guy, man.
I'm not taking no death letter.
We have a deal.
I'll give it
to you back in an hour.
Blackburn. You okay?
I'm excited. In a good way.
I've been training
my whole life for this.
- You ever shot at anybody before?
- No, sir.
Me neither.
You think he's reliable?
Well, we'll see.
It's his first time out.
- Tell him to turn his damn radio off.
- Yes, sir.
- Tell him to turn his radio off.
- Abdi, you need to turn your radio off.
Hi. You've
reached Stephanie and Randy.
Leave us a message.
Thank you.
Hey, baby, it's me.
Are you there?
Pick up if you're there.
I'm just calling to check up on you,
make sure everything's all right.
I'll call you
in a couple of hours.
You'd better
not be sleeping.
Your move, Randy.
I'm missing you.
I love you, baby.
Hello? Hello?
Thanks, bud.
You know,
it's kind of funny.
Beautiful beach,
beautiful sun.
Could almost be
a good place to visit.
Almost.
You don't think
we should be here?
You know what I think?
It don't really matter
what I think.
Once that first bullet
goes past your head,
politics and all that shit
just goes right out the window.
I just wanna do it
right today.
Just watch your corner.
Get all your men
back here alive.
Now, is this supposed to be the place,
or did his car just take a dump?
Abdi, come in. Abdi, can you hear me?
Is this the place?
Abdi, come in.
Can you hear me? Abdi.
Is this the place?
To my right-hand side,
above the café.
Sir he says
this is the building.
He's certain?
Abdi, you need to be sure.
Are you sure?
Well, it's down the road,
two blocks over on my left.
But there's too many militia.
If I go closer,
they might shoot me.
Now he's saying the building's
actually a couple blocks down.
But if he's seen outside it,
he'll be shot.
I'll fucking shoot him myself
a couple blocks down.
Tell him I want his skinny ass parked
in front of the damn building.
He's not getting paid
until he does exactly that.
It's three miles to the target area.
We're never off the main roads.
At the K-4 traffic circle,
we turn north, then east on National,
and we wait until extraction
of prisoners is complete here.
Then we roll up in force on Hawlwadig.
We load the prisoners,
and then the assault and blocking
forces, and bring them back.
Home in an hour.
Okay?
Now, there will be some shooting.
Bakara market is the Wild West.
But be careful what you shoot at
because people do live there.
Hoo-ah!
Last one of these guys shot himself in the
head playing Russian roulette in a bar.
Sir, the vehicle is stopped.
So this is the real deal now.
He's sure this time?
He sounds scared shitless.
Good. That's always a good sign.
That's it. That's our signal.
All right.
All QRF,
Out of the airspace.
All units, Irene.
I say again, Irene.
Check in when ready. Barber
5-1 up and ready. Star 4-1 up and ready.
- Irene!
- Copy Irene.
Fucking Irene!
Come on.
Good luck, boys.
Be careful.
No one gets left behind.
What's wrong?
Nothing. He's just
never done that before.
Aw, fuck!
Let's go.
Sergeant Struecker, let's roll.
Two minutes.
Why are they burning tires?
Signals to the militia
that we're coming.
5-6, it looks like there's
some friendlies on the ground.
It look like I've got intel
on the voice intercept.
But we've got burning
tires in the front of us. Over.
One minute.
What's that for?
Last rope
I almost bit my tongue off.
Touch base.
Two feet, one foot. Clear.
Little Birds
touching down at target.
Ropes!
Go! Go! Go!
Chalk One troops are on the deck.
Chalk Two deployed.
This is McKnight. Uniform
6-4 approaching staging area.
Down! Get down!
Down! Stay down!
- Everybody down!
- Down! Down!
Get down on the floor!
Let's go! Let's go!
Grimesy! No fear!
Oh, yeah, right!
Rangers securing perimeter.
Four corners.
They're shooting at us!
Colonel, they're shooting at us!
Well, shoot back.
This is 6-4. Chalks on the ground.
Going into holding pattern.
This is 6-2. Delivered chalks.
Going to cover pattern.
Super 6-2, take up an overhead
pattern to provide sniper cover.
- Over.
- This is Super 6-5.
Chalks on the ground.
Going into holding pattern.
Go, Blackburn. Go! Go!
Go, Blackburn!
- RPG!
- Hold on!
No!
C-2, we got a man fallen.
Super 6-1, you're
a sitting duck there.
Blackburn!
Take up overhead pattern
to provide sniper cover. Over.
Roger that. 6-1 coming out.
1-3, go ahead.
I need you to move
to the north of the street.
Right to the north.
Right there. Over.
Doc! Doc Schmid!
Come on!
Schmid, we got a man hit.
- Where is he hit?
- He's not. He fell.
- What?
- He fell.
Why aren't you shooting?
We're not being shot at yet.
- How can you tell?
- A hiss means it's close.
- A snap means...
- Now they're shooting at us.
Galentine!
Get me Captain Steele.
Juliet 6-4, this is Juliet 2-5.
Come in. Over.
Blackburn, can you hear me?
Juliet 6-4, this is 2-5. Come in.
Over. I can't get him.
Juliet 6-4, this is Chalk Four.
We've got a man down. We need
to get him out of here. Over.
This is 6-4.
Say again, 2-5. Over.
We've got a man down. Over.
Take a breath, 2-5,
and calm down. Over.
- Man down!
- Missed your last, 2-5.
- Fuck it!
- Say again.
Matt, it's a long way
to the humvees.
We'll get a stretcher in here.
Get him to the target building.
What did he say?
Super 6-1, we got a
man wounded on the ground.
Stretcher! Jamie, Stretcher!
Stretcher!
Come on! Come on!
Grab this end!
Let's go!
All right. Go.
Get him to the humvees.
We'll hold down the corner.
Up to the humvees.
Now!
Go. Go!
Keep moving.
Grimes, run.
- Secure.
- Let's move out!
- Everybody up!
- Let's go!
- Come on!
- Let's go! Let's move!
- Grimes, run!
- All right!
C-2, this is Super 6-1.
Beginning my orbit of the target area.
- Roger that.
- Chalk Four,
10-4 clear. Coming in.
Kilo 1-1, this is 6-1.
Providing sniper cover
for prisoner extract.
Kilo 6-4, green light.
- Ready for extraction. Over.
- Roger that, Kilo 1-1. Will relay.
That's it. We got them.
Uniform 6-4, ready
for extraction. Over.
Roger that.
There's the call. Let's move out!
Let's move out!
Hold on!
There's fire on the rooftops.
- How much longer?
- Five minutes, sir.
- What?
- Five minutes!
Nothing takes five minutes.
- What happened to him?
- He fell. Missed the rope.
How'd he do that?
Put him in that humvee.
Grimes, give him a hand.
Let's go! Let's move it!
- Move! Move! Move! Get them up!
- Come on!
Come on!
Get him in there!
Get ready to move!
We're ready for your prisoners.
Go! Everybody move! Move!
- Hey! Hey!
- Get the fuck up!
Grimes!
Come on!
Wait! Wait!
Fuck this!
Fuck!
Stop! Hey! Come on!
Move! Move!
Romeo 6-4,
I need to send out three humvees with a
critical casualty. He looks real bad.
I need to evac now.
Roger that, Uniform 6-4.
We'll chop a team
of gunships to you. Over.
Roger that. Hey, Sanderson, I need
extra security on these humvees.
I'll go. I'll take my team,
make sure they get back okay.
Do it. Struecker,
you're lead humvee.
Hoo-ah!
First three vehicles mount up.
We're moving back to base.
Move out! Go!
How are things going?
Things okay there, Struecker?
I don't wanna talk
about it now, colonel. I'm busy.
Sergeant Pilla's hit.
Christ, he's fucked up.
Is anyone hit?
Struecker, talk to me.
It's Sergeant Pilla.
What's his status?
- He's dead.
Pilla's dead, sir.
C-2, this is McKnight.
We have a KIA,
Dominick Pilla. Over.
Roger that.
Get on that 50!
Someone get on that 50!
It's mine!
Three guys with RPG's
coming up on your side now!
Stay with it!
This is 6-1. I'm hit. I'm hit.
Super 6-1 is hit.
He is hit. Wolcott's bird is hit.
You wanna pull those PCL's
off-line or what?
Right, babe.
Come on.
6-1 going down.
6-1 is going down.
He is going down.
- Super 6-1 is going down.
6-1 going down.
6-1 is going down.
I repeat, 6-1 is going down.
Hold on!
We got a Black Hawk down.
Super 6-1 is down.
We got a bird down in the city.
Super 6-1 is on the deck now.
Get an MH-6 on site.
Check for survivors.
Send in the SAR Bird.
I want ground forces to move and secure
a new perimeter around that crash site.
Can you guide
the convoy in there?
- Roger that.
- Well, move quick.
The whole damn city will be
coming down on top of them.
Star 4-1, come inbound and see if
you can land at the crash site.
Roger that. Star 4-1 inbound.
We just lost the initiative.
- 2-5, this is 6-4. Over.
- This is 2-5. Over.
2-5, Chalk Four is closest
to the crash site. Over.
6-4, I can't see
the crash site. Over.
2-5, it's due east of you.
You will find it.
Leave a security
element in place.
Take the rest of your chalk
on foot to the crash.
Check for survivors. Secure the area.
All other chalks will follow. Over.
- 2-5, do you read me? Over.
- Roger that.
Galentine! Schmid!
Go get Yurek.
Get Twombly.
Hey, there's
a Black Hawk down.
Twombly, Nelson, you're gonna stay here.
You're gonna hold this corner
and then exfil
with the humvees.
Galentine, Schmid, you're coming with me.
All right? Let's go. Hoo-ah?
Hoo-ah!
- How come I gotta stay back here?
Because you're dependable.
All right.
Let's go!
I hate being dependable, man.
Juliet 2-5, hostiles advancing
parallel west to your position.
Be advised, women and children
among them. Over.
Hit the wall.
Incoming!
Grenade!
Go!
We still got guys inside.
All right, all right.
I'm gonna go to the crash.
You take the rest
of the team.
- I'll finish loading the prisoners.
- Negative!
You'll proceed
to the crash site together.
Secure the perimeter,
wait for the humvees. Roger, sir?
- Roger that.
- Follow my lead.
Sarge,
are you receiving me?
Yeah, I heard you.
We should be leaving, sir.
All right, we need
to move out now!
I'll finish loading
the prisoners
and pick you up at the crash site.
All right.
Let's move out!
Move it out! Go!
Get in! Get in the truck!
Go! Move!
In there! Move it!
Grimes!
Eight o'clock!
Hey, Grimes,
stay away from the walls.
Hey, Grimes.
- You okay?
- Yeah!
Let's go, Maddox.
- C-2 convoy moving out.
- Roger that.
Maddox, look at these jerks,
these idiots!
Go, go!
Right, Maddox, right!
Twombly,
the convoy's leaving!
- Hey, Twombly!
- What?
- I think they've forgotten us.
Doesn't matter.
6-3 confirm. We got skinnies
moving in from all directions.
We need to get them help now.
Indigenous personnel
advancing to Wolcott crash site.
- Say again. Over.
- A lot of people closing in.
How far is Chalk Four
from the crash site?
- Six blocks, sir.
- Well, they need to haul ass.
Get down! Get down!
Scotty, are you okay?
No, don't go back!
Get down! Get down!
- Technicals!
- Got them!
Six o'clock! Move, move!
Go! Go, go, go!
Go, go!
Come on!
Yurek, leaving!
Yurek! Come on!
Shh.
Uniform 6-4, left turn, left turn.
Romeo 6-4, I need to know before
I get to the goddamn street!
You have to slow down.
There's a delay
from the time directions
are relayed
from surveillance
to JOC, then to me.
We can't slow down! We're taking heavy
enemy fire! We can't slow down!
Danny, I'm getting information
from Orion surveillance above.
So get me my fucking
directions to the crash site!
Danny, hold on. I no longer
have the best view of your route.
Then get your ass in
the right place, goddamn it!
What in the hell is the status
of Struecker's humvees?
Colonel Harrell, ETA to base,
Struecker's column.
ETA base momentarily.
Open the gate.
Get him out! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
Watch his head. Easy.
Blackburn, can you hear me?
Star 4-1 is at the crash
site to evacuate the injured.
- Over.
- Roger that.
I got you. Easy, easy.
Galentine, you all right?
Galentine, Kurth, with me!
- Cover fire now.
- Full cover!
Hey, Jones!
How many are in there?
Two pilots are dead.
Two crew chiefs are wounded.
This guy's hurt bad.
We gotta get out of here now.
All right, go ahead!
2-6, 2-6, this is 2-5. Is that you
shooting up the technicals? Over.
This is 2-6. Roger that.
DiTomasso,
take the southeast corner.
We're setting up
a perimeter. Over.
This is 2-6. Roger that.
Moving there now. Move out!
Captain Steele,
Captain Steele, come in.
Go ahead, 2-5.
This is 6-4.
We got two wounded and we got both
the pilots dead in the chopper.
We need a medivac
over here now!
2-5, they're telling me
it's too hot to land the bird.
You got to secure
the perimeter first. Over.
Where are the humvees?
Be advised, 2-5,
the convoy will be there.
They're encountering
a lot of resistance. 6-4 out.
Get the 50 up!
You should see
the crash directly ahead.
All I see is a roadblock!
All right. I'll have to
figure out another way.
Give me a defensive perimeter
so we can load the wounded.
Fire your weapon,
Othic!
Tell my girls I'll be okay.
Medic!
Hoo-ah!
Medic! Medic!
Joyce! Joyce!
Come on, help me pick him up!
Get us off this fucking street!
Where's the crash site? Say again!
- Keep going straight 200 metres.
- Roger that.
Let's go! Let's go,
goddamn it! Let's go!
- Hey, Twombles. Come here.
- What?
The humvees
ain't coming back, dude.
What?
Were we supposed
to go to them?
I thought they were
supposed to come to us.
Shit. Shit, I think we're
supposed to go to them.
Shit.
Okay.
- Let's go to the crash site.
- Okay.
Just don't fire that thing so close to
my head. I can barely hear as it is.
Okay, move out.
Shit! Get down!
What'd I just tell you?
I swear to God,
you do that again...
You okay?
Nelson, you all right?
What?
Search and rescue bird
on station, inserting medics.
Go, go!
Son of a bitch.
C-2, this is 6-8. We've been hit.
Super 6-8, there is smoke coming
from the top of your rotor.
Advise you to come out now.
Roger. Dropping last man.
Art, I've got skinnies
with RPG's at 12 o'clock.
- Go! Go!
- Can you see them?
- Got them.
- Give me 90 degrees left.
6-8 coming out.
Super 6-8 is out. Over.
Hey, Wilkie,
what's the situation in there?
Both pilots are dead.
2-5, we can't move
these guys, Matty.
We'll kill them
just carrying them.
- Stabilise in here?
- Roger.
Stabilise in the bird.
Repeat, stabilise in here. Over.
Understood, Wilkie.
We got you covered. Over.
Super 6-4, come inbound
and take Wolcott's position.
Roger. 6-4 is inbound.
Super 6-4, you all right?
This is Super 6-4.
We're good.
You sure? You look like
you got clipped pretty good.
Instrument panels are okay.
No, we're good.
Got a slight vibration
in the pedals, but we're good.
All right, put her down on the airfield,
Super 6-4. Have it checked out to be safe.
Roger.
I'm getting a lot of movement in these
pedals. Check the systems again.
We lost the tail rotor.
It's gone.
6-4 is going down!
6-4 is going in hard!
6-4 going down.
We're going down. Wait!
Get Struecker's column
back out there.
They need to get
to Durant's crash site fast.
We got another bird down.
I want them out of there.
All of them.
Captain Steele, we gotta move
or we're gonna get pinned down!
We're moving
just as fast as we can.
You let me do my job
and you do yours. Over.
Fuck! Fuck!
Ruiz, stay down! Medic!
Fuck this! Captain Steele, I'll
take out the threat in the window.
We'll rally point at the grey building.
Coming through, Captain.
- Sergeant!
- All right, let's move!
- Move! Let's move now!
- Move!
Cover me!
Let's go, let's move!
Move out!
Friendly!
Friendlies coming through!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Move up!
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
Move it out! Move up!
Go! Go! Go! Move up!
What the fuck are you
doing out there?
I'm doing my job!
We got to get to that crash site!
We got to get out on that street,
and we got to move!
You have got to keep up, sir!
Don't you ever
give me orders, sergeant.
We are combat ineffective, you understand
me? We got too many damn wounded to move!
Then give me some of your shooters,
and I'll circle us to the bird.
Grimes!
You're with Chalk Four?
- Yes, sir!
- All right, hook up with Delta!
Rejoin with
Sergeant Eversmann.
The rest of you men secure this
position, treat the wounded.
We'll wait for the convoy, then we'll
rally at the crash site. Roger!
My guys, let's go!
C-2, I have two Delta snipers,
Shughart and Gordon, volunteering
to secure crash site two. Over.
No, Super 6-2.
Negative that request.
Can't risk another bird.
We don't see anything
moving down there now.
We don't even know
if anyone's alive.
A ground team is being
organised to go in now.
- ETA on ground team. Over.
- Unknown, not long.
Do what you can from the air.
All right, gather around!
Durant's 6-4 is down.
- We're going back in to get him.
- That's crazy.
- Is there anyone alive on that?
- Doesn't matter.
No one gets left behind.
You know that.
- We're wasting time here.
- All right.
Refit and max out ammo
and grenades. You got five.
Sizemore, where the hell
you think you're going?
- With you guys.
- Not with that cast on, you're not.
All right, all right, all right.
Go get your K-pot.
Hey.
- Talk to me.
- I can't go back out there.
Thomas, everyone feels
the same way you do, all right?
It's what you do right now
that makes a difference.
It's your call. Hoo-ah?
Hoo-ah.
It'll probably help to wash
the blood out of the humvees.
Sergeant Struecker!
Can I go, sarge?
- You got some ammo?
- Roger that, Sarge!
Hop in!
Wait!
Let's go, Thomas. Get in!
Which way?
That way, I think!
Don't talk so fucking loud!
Nice donkey.
Rangers?
- Who?
- It's Yurek, you fucking assholes!
- Fuck!
- Dude, we almost fucking killed you!
- Well, come to us!
- Fuck you! Come to me!
Sorry, Sarge!
Dude, where the fuck
have you been?
Never mind.
You brought NOD, right?
No. No, I didn't bring it.
You wanna know why? You said, "You're not gonna
need that. We'll be back in a half hour."
I wasn't saying it to you.
- Aaugh!
- Nelson, cover this way.
- We're gonna need night vision.
- What's the matter with you?
- Huh?
- Oh, he's deaf.
It's my fault. I...
We need to get out of here.
That way. We can't be
far from the crash.
Which way?
I thought you might know.
Let's move out.
Nelson, Twombly? Come in. Over.
Nelson, Twombly, come in.
This is Galentine.
We need a position
of the convoy. Over.
I can't raise them, sergeant.
I can't raise them.
Sir, let's get the fuck
out of here and evac!
- Let's move out!
- All right!
Back to the stronghold!
Come on!
Ground forces have occupied several
buildings along Marehan Road,
but they're all spread out.
Eversmann's Chalk Four has set up a
perimeter around Wolcott's crash site here.
DiTomasso is in
the adjacent structure.
Captain Steele and about
40 men, Rangers, are here.
A couple blocks away.
They're banged up pretty bad.
He set up a casualty
collection point.
I don't think they're
gonna be able to move.
Sergeant Sanderson
and a small Delta team
are moving from Steele's position
to the crash site as we speak.
Draw off fire! When this asshole
stops to reload, cover me!
Go!
Sir!
Again!
Loading!
Keep going! Keep going!
I'm jammed!
I got it!
Ah, shit!
RPG!
You all right?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I can hear bells ringing.
Come on!
Come on! Go!
There's a crowd advancing
six, seven blocks from the crash.
Shughart and Gordon again request
permission to secure until convoy arrives.
Over.
General, crowd's
in the hundreds now.
From where they are, they can see
things clearer than any of us.
They know what they're asking.
Let me talk to them.
This is Garrison.
I want to make sure that y'all
understand what you're asking for,
so say it out loud and clear.
We're asking to go in and set up a
perimeter until ground support arrives.
And you realise that I cannot
tell you when that might be.
- It could take quite a while.
- Roger that.
- And you still want to go in there?
- Yes, sir.
- Harrell?
- Yes, general.
It's your call.
Roger that.
Goffena, put them in.
RPG!
Set up your perimeter!
There's a fucking rocket
in him, sir!
Othic, calm down, goddamn it! That's
live ordnance! Now get out! Get out!
Son of a bitch.
All right, lift him up!
Lift him up!
Easy, easy!
All right, get him in there!
Good, good! Easy, easy!
Get in that truck and drive.
But I'm shot, colonel.
Everybody's shot! We need
the prisoners! Let's go!
Surveillance says to take
Hawlwadig, then go straight.
McKnight, we need you to turn
around and head back to Hawlwadig.
You're shitting me!
We just came through there!
There's gotta be a better route!
That's the info I'm getting
from JOC
You need to turn around
and head back.
Roger that, roger that.
I cannot believe this shit!
Turn us around, Maddox.
They're trying to get us
all fucking killed!
- Just get it over with! Drive!
- Goddamn!
Get us out of here!
Goddamn it, drive!
Keep your foot on the gas!
Keep your foot on the...
Fuck!
Shit.
C-2, Shughart and
Gordon are on the deck. Over.
Roger.
Friendlies!
God, it's good to see you!
- It's good to see you. How bad?
- My leg's broken
and my back feels
kind of weird.
We've got to get you out of here, buddy.
Pulling him out! Cover!
Wait. I... Aah!
Put you down.
C-2, we're at the 6-4
crash site, securing perimeter.
Roger that.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm good.
You're locked and loaded. Any
skinnies come around these corners,
you watch our backs.
Hey, where's the rescue squad?
We're it.
All right, stop, stop,
stop, stop. Maddox, stop.
Son of a bitch. Romeo 6-4,
we're back where we started.
I'm running low on ammo,
I got many wounded, including me,
vehicles that are
barely running.
Okay, Danny, I need a no-B.S.
assessment here.
Can you get to the crash site?
Colonel, I can't see shit.
Negative. With the amount of wounded
we have, we'd do more harm than good.
We need to come back to base,
rearm and regroup,
-...and then we can go back out.
- Roger.
C-2, bring them back.
Get them out of there.
Roger. Return to base.
We're going home!
Let's go. Left.
Roger that. Understand.
Convoy returning to base.
- What's up?
- They're sending them back.
The convoy's headed
back to base camp.
That makes sense, don't it? We
need to exfil the wounded now
and get out of here
before it's too late!
If Colonel McKnight went back to
base, then he had a good reason.
- It changes nothing.
- All right, listen up.
We're gonna hold the perimeter, and we're
gonna hold the strongpoint. Hoo-ah?
Hoo-ah!
Conserve your ammo.
Only shoot at what you can hit.
Hoo-ah.
The convoy's gonna come.
We're gonna get home.
Loading!
Randy, I need a pistol mag!
Randy, last mag!
Gordy!
Fuck!
Gordy's gone, man.
I'll be outside.
Good luck.
We need the 10th Mountain
in there. Everything they got.
Pakistanis, Malays.
I want their tanks and A.P.C.'s.
They still don't know
we've gone in.
Look, we have stirred up the hornet's nest
here. We're fighting the entire city.
I want every vehicle possible that's
got four wheels and armour. Get it.
Get everything.
Once they've assembled,
we're gonna move our men out of the hostile
area and back to the Pakistani stadium.
The safe zone. Let's go.
Roger that, boss.
On your knees!
Get down! Get down!
Stay with me.
You just got a bullet in the leg.
See where those tires are burning?
All that black smoke?
Roger. I can see it,
but I can't get there. Over.
Go 100 metres past it.
That's the crash.
Negative.
You don't understand.
It's roadblock after roadblock. You
have to find us another route. Over.
There ain't one. The only other
route is all the way around the city.
Roger that.
Kilo 6-4, this is Kilo 1-1.
Request permission to move to crash
site number two on foot. Over.
Green light,
Kilo 1-1. Green light.
Stop the vehicle.
Let me out.
After I'm finished with this, I'll
whip you boys up some margaritas.
The usual.
Blended, no salt.
This is Kilo 1-2. We've got
to change our position. Over.
Eversmann, come in.
Eversmann.
Roger, who is this?
Sanderson. Do not...
I say again, do not fire to the east.
We are coming to you.
Understood. DiTomasso and his men
are on the southeast corner.
We need you on
the northeast building.
Roger. We'll take it.
Hey, watch out for skinnies.
They're all over the rooftops.
They're in prayer,
but not for much longer.
Hold your fire to the east.
Eversmann? It's Yurek.
I got Nelson
and Twombly with me.
We got the chopper in sight.
Where are you?
We're on the southwest corner.
Where the hell have you
been? Are you okay?
Yeah.
Hold your fire.
We're coming in.
We got to go.
Shawn, listen!
Yurek's gonna run first.
When he gets across the street, he's gonna
turn around and cover you as you run.
When you get there, you're gonna turn
around and you're gonna cover me, okay?
You're not just gonna
run to Eversmann's position.
You're gonna stop, you're gonna turn
around, and you are going to cover me.
It's important
you understand that.
Okay, you ready?
Yeah, I guess.
Hey! Don't forget.
- What?
- Don't forget.
I got them in my sight.
They're coming up on the west gate.
I see them.
Let's move out.
- Can you cover us, sergeant?
- We got you.
Nelson!
Fuck!
Twombly!
Smith! No!
You all right?
Get it off of me! Get it off!
Come on, man! Come on!
Doc! Give me some help
with Smith here!
My leg! My leg!
Come on, Jamie,
I got you!
Up, one, two, three. You're all right.
You're all right.
All right. I need
pressure on this wound.
My right thigh!
Pressure, okay?
Are my balls okay?
You still have your balls.
I need more men in here.
Twombly! Nelson!
Put him down.
Oh, man, that really...
I need that chair.
It really hurts!
Pressure.
Direct pressure on that.
- Let me see it!
- All right.
Let me get a look at that.
Oh, fuck!
What the fuck was that?
It's all right.
Hold that down.
I need a medivac now.
Galentine!
Get me Captain Steele!
Sergeant?
Sergeant Ruiz, how you doing?
They're not gonna
come and get us.
come for us.
I need you to suck it up, sergeant.
I need you to focus for me.
Can you do that?
Come on, 6-4! Come in. Over.
- Can you hold your weapon?
- Yes, sir.
Anybody comes through that door, you give
him two in the chest and one in the head.
- You understand?
- I'm still in the fight, sir.
Captain Steele! Captain Steele, I need a medivac
in here now! Corporal Smith's been hit!
- Hold on, 2-5.
- Still in the fight.
He's hurt pretty bad.
2-5, we got wounded too.
You're just gonna have to
maintain your situation. Over.
If he doesn't get to a hospital
in a half hour, he's in trouble.
C-2, this is 6-4. I'm requesting
an immediate medivac
for a critically wounded at
Chalk Four's location. Over.
Command, Chalk
Four is requesting medivac.
Can't risk it.
It's still too hot.
Captain, we cannot send in
medivac at this time. Sit tight. Over.
C-5, this is 6-4. Negative on the medivac.
It's not possible.
JOC cannot risk
another bird.
You're just gonna
have to hold on.
All right. I got him.
I want direct pressure
on the wound. Yeah.
It's gonna be all right.
It's gonna be okay.
This is Kilo 1-1.
I'm at the Durant crash site.
Roger that.
Crash site two secured.
Lieutenant Colonel
Cribbs for you, sir.
Cribbs?
Sir, they're still debating the route.
How long?
At least a couple hours.
We haven't got that long, Joe.
Pakistani general says since we didn't
deign to inform him of the raid,
it's gonna take some time to mobilise the
10th Mountain and a hundred vehicles.
You tell the general this.
I understand, but it is
my duty to remind him
that my men are surrounded by
thousands of armed Somali militia.
It is imperative that we move
them out of the hostile area
and into the safe zone.
I need his help now.
Yes, sir.
Durant.
- Michael Durant.
- Yes.
You are the Ranger
who kills my people?
I'm not a Ranger.
I'm a pilot.
That's right.
None of you Americans
smoke anymore.
You all live long,
dull, uninteresting lives.
What do you want with me?
You have taken hostages.
We have you.
My government will
never negotiate for me.
Then perhaps you and I
can negotiate, huh?
Soldier to soldier.
Hm?
I'm not in charge.
Course not. You have the
power to kill, but not negotiate.
In Somalia,
killing is negotiation.
Do you really think
if you get General Aidid,
we will simply
put down our weapons
and adopt American
democracy?
That the killing will stop?
We know this. Without victory,
there can be no peace.
There will always
be killing, you see?
This is how things are
in our world.
Mike Durant,
we won't leave you behind.
You got to take
over for me. Both hands.
It's the femoral artery,
but I can't see it,
which means that it's
retracted up into the pelvis,
which means that I have
to find it and clamp it.
It's the only way to stop the
bleeding. I got no more IVs,
so I'm gonna need you
to assist, okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Now, listen, Jamie.
I gotta do something. It's gonna hurt.
Okay?
I gotta cause you more pain,
but I have to do it to help you,
you understand?
- Morphine.
- I can't.
It'll lower your heart rate
too far. I'm sorry.
Twombly, why don't you
take his hands there.
I need you to hold the wound open.
Keep pressure on the top of the leg.
Yurek, you're gonna take
the feet and a flashlight.
On my count.
All right, Jamie. All right.
One, two, three.
Wait, wait, wait.
Okay. I feel it. I feel the pulse.
I got it. I got it.
I got it, yeah. I got it. I got it.
- You got it? Good.
- I got it. Clamp.
I got it clamped.
Hold it. Got it.
Here, grab it.
It's tearing.
I got it.
- Doc, it's going back in.
- Hold it! Hold it!
It's tearing!
Okay, get out. Hold the wound.
Okay, I'm holding.
Move your hand.
What?
Fix it?
Yeah, yeah. We got it.
What the hell are you doing?
It's all in the grind, sarge.
Can't be too fine.
Can't be too coarse.
Grimesy,
you are squared away.
Sarge, how'd you like
a nice hot cup of joe?
- Gold Coast blend.
- Sit down.
Let me take a look
at that foot.
No, it's not a problem.
Come on, come on.
- Where the hell did they find you?
- Behind a desk.
No, really.
Do you think I'm kidding?
- Anybody hit?
- We're good!
- You all right?
- Yeah!
Is everybody all right?
Yeah!
Incoming!
DiTomosso's hit.
Pull him out!
Ranger here.
This is Kilo 1-1.
This is Chalk Four. We're at the southeast
corner of the crash site. Who's this? Over.
This is Hoot. I'm coming
in with three friendlies.
I need some
covering fire. Over.
Roger that, Kilo 1-1.
Hold your fire!
Deltas coming in.
Hold your fire.
Ground personnel will have to mark
target positions with infrared strobes.
Get Little Birds on strafing runs
and keep them going all night long.
If we don't hold back
this city,
we're gonna have a hundred
caskets to fill by morning.
Yes, sir. Colonel Harrell, ground
personnel at crash site one
will have to mark the target with infrared
strobes in preparation for air strike.
McKnight.
Between the 10th Mountain and U.
N., we got enough personnel, okay?
Danny, you guys do not
have to go back out again.
I can't die here, man.
You're not gonna die, all right?
You're not gonna die.
I'm sorry.
You don't have anything
to be sorry for.
You saved Twombly.
You did perfect.
Yeah.
You okay, Twombs?
Yeah, I'm okay, Jamie.
You did what you were
trained to do.
You should be proud of that.
Be proud of that.
Ev?
Yeah.
Do me a favour.
Yeah?
You tell my parents
that I fought well today.
And that I...
That I...
That I fought hard.
You're gonna
tell them yourself, okay?
Do you hear me?
All right?
Are the humvees here?
They're coming, Jamie.
They're coming.
You just gotta hang in there a little bit.
Hold on for just a little bit.
I can. I can.
It's nothing.
Nothing.
Oh, shit. Hold the wound.
Doc.
It's okay.
What are you doing?
We need the ammo.
You did all you could here.
They should've sent a medivac.
Right now we'd be out there
defending another crashed chopper.
More men would get torn up.
- Maybe.
- See, you're thinking. Don't.
Because, sergeant, you can't control
who gets hit or who doesn't,
who falls out of a chopper
or why.
It ain't up to you. It's just war.
Yeah, well,
Smith's still dead.
Blackburn wouldn't have fallen,
none of this would've happened.
Should have or could have,
it don't matter.
You'll get plenty of time to think
about all that later. Believe me.
Sergeant,
you got your men this far.
You did it right today.
You need to start thinking
about getting these men out of here.
Well, shall we?
I need four guns
in this corner now!
RPG!
This is Barber 5-2
in position for gun run.
Jesus Christ. Look at that.
This is 2-5! I can see you.
You're right above me.
Eversmann, I can't tell who's who
down there. Too much activity.
I'll mark the target
with a strobe. Over.
Roger that.
You see it?
Nah. I can't see shit.
I'm putting it on the roof.
- You're gonna need some help!
- Cover me.
Okay, guys, we're gonna lay down some
cover fire for him! On three! Ready?
One, two, three! Go!
I got your position. I got the target.
We re inbound and hot.
C-2, mini-guns dry. Request
permission to return to base. Rearm. Over.
Roger that. Second team inbound.
Your station.
On your location, four minutes.
All right, they're here.
Get the wounded ready to move.
Move, move!
Lay down some cover fire!
I thought I heard a noise out here!
Get your men loaded up.
We're getting out of here.
Yes, sir.
2-5, this is 6-4. Rescue column has arrived.
We'll be at your location in about 5 minutes.
Prepare your men for exfil.
Yeah, roger that, sir!
Roger that!
Five minutes! The convoy's
gonna be here in five minutes!
I need a mag!
Eversmann, I'm out!
Kurth, my last one!
The convoy's here!
Sergeant Eversmann.
I heard you guys
needed a lift!
Yes, sir!
Bring your wounded right over
there and start loading them up!
I got you, I got you.
It's okay.
I want to walk.
Yeah, I would too.
Let's go!
Move, move!
We get the pilots' bodies out,
then we go to the stadium.
We're running out of room
around here.
Just gonna have to cram
into every possible space.
Okay, 10th Mountain provides security for
armour, walks us out of the hot zone.
10th Mountain? No. Sir, with respect,
my Rangers can provide rear security.
We'll walk you out of the hot zone,
then jump on the last few vehicles.
Okay, let's get out of here.
Let's go.
- All right, you got him?
- Yeah, come on.
Come on!
These things are fucking bullet
magnets. Come on, let's go!
We go when
I'm ordered to, soldier!
Careful.
Easy, easy.
Colonel, what is going on
down there?
They're dismantling the entire
cockpit around the body.
How long's it gonna take? I need
an honest, no-shit assessment.
I can't say.
Danny?
No one gets left behind.
You understand me, son?
Yes, General.
Do what you have to do.
Roger.
All right, come on.
Bring him through.
I got him.
Get all of his gear.
Get the wounded out of here.
Got you, sir!
Go! Move, go, move!
Move out! Move out!
Let's go!
Fuck!
Fire in the hole! Let's go! Move!
Let's go! Move out! Come on!
Open up the hatch!
We got men back here!
- No room!
- Go on the roof!
What's going on?
The roof?
I'm not getting on
no fucking roof!
- Sir...
- No, no, it's full!
We're running out. Keep moving.
Use the vehicles as cover.
Move it! Let's go!
All right, hold it up.
Hold it up.
Let's go! Move, move!
Get down! Get down!
Get down, lady!
I'm out of ammo!
Sanderson, I'm out of ammo!
Don't you do it.
What are you doing?
Don't you damn do it.
Kurth, let's go!
Easy. Easy.
Ah, shit.
Bullet missed your jugular by about
three millimetres. Don't move!
All right.
Hurry up, hurry up.
Grimes?
Little short on coffee,
but I got you some tea.
How you doing, soldier?
Can't feel a thing.
Ruiz.
Hey, Sergeant. Hey.
- Captain.
- Lorenzo.
How you doing?
It went in and out, so the medic said
I should be okay, a couple of days.
- That's great news.
- We going after them?
You bet your ass we will.
We got to regroup.
Don't go out without me.
Don't go back out there
without me.
I can still do my job.
You get some rest now, okay?
You going back in?
There's still men out there.
Goddamn.
When I go home,
people ask me, "Hey, Hoot,"
"why do you do it, man?"
"Why? You some kind
of war junkie?"
I won't say
a goddamn word.
Why?
They won't understand.
They won't understand
why we do it.
it's about the men next to you.
And that's it.
That's all it is.
Hey, don't even
think about it, all right?
I'm better on my own.
Hey, we started a whole new week.
It's Monday.
I was talking to Blackburn
the other day and he asked me,
"What changed?
Why are we going home?"
And I said, "Nothing."
But that's not true, you know.
I think everything's changed.
I know I've changed.
A friend of mine asked me
before I got here...
When we were all shipping out.
He asked me,
"Why are you going to fight
somebody else's war?"
"What do y'all think,
you're heroes?"
I didn't know what to say
at the time, but...
if he asked me again,
I'd say no.
I'd say there's no way in hell.
Nobody asks to be a hero.
It just sometimes
turns out that way.
I'll talk to your ma and pa
when I get home, okay?
"My love,"
"you're strong
and you'll do well in life."
"I love you
and my children deeply."
"Today and tomorrow,
let each day grow and grow."
"Keep smiling and never give up,
even when things get you down."
"So, in closing, my love,"
"tonight,
tuck my children in bed warmly."
"Tell them I love them,"
"then hug them for me and give them
both a kiss good night for Daddy."