Sl pp.
Flight.
The flight, now!
Flights!
- Fan? S what he?
- I was p? the same department n? r it h? nde.
- Everyone knew it was him.
- He was an hour? Rding f? Rr.
Now? Is he just an old man.
Vehici Khadem?
F? Nd Viktor.
Have you n? Gra diseases?
N? N r? Tteg? Ng soon?
No.
Thank you, Victor.
You can st? Ll you d? R gone?
Paul Atherton?
- 18? S. Who? R his Handl? Ggare?
- Pull? T hell.
It? S you, this output has been ??
- Fuck the list.
- Wait a little. What do we know?
The guy? R m a living? Ltavla.
We should s? Eight him with Viktor.
I h? Ller with.
I? S more worried about f? R guy.
A kid with an old r? V?
The g? R him enough upright.
P? the h? r g? rden we work.
Everyone should be assigned duties.
-? Eight-hour day? S mandatory.
- Damn,? Eight hours!
As in the real v globe.
Mr. Perry, Mr. Egan.
I t? Nkte show the new round.
- It h? R? R v? L is not your room?
- No I...
I? R in the tool shed
if n? n'll need me.
Victor and Paul. St.'ll be in your stuff,
V? lj berth g? r you at ease.
A dog ring c? it takes TV? weeks
before he comes out d? rifr? n
-without being told.
- Who was the man?
- Who Warren d ?,?
Do not worry about f? R him, he? S an pals.
No. The h? R? R my room.
No one comes in here.
Your room? We? R the three right here, and I have
lived right here in in months, p? about...
TV? Eight PM? Costs and your self.
You stink.
- L-ons by!
- I share nothing with stoners.
I? R pundare no.
The pc? S that nobody has asked? Kt him
p? 18? S, but it m? Ste be wrong.
- Who? R his n? Rmaste anh? Rig?
- A public f? Rmyndare.
A r? Adviser fr? N f? Ngelset
bes? KTE his family f? r 16? r tendon
But they did not recognize him.
- Do you n? N idea what it is about?
- No, but I continued? Tter gr? Huh.
- How m? S Sally?
- She m? S good. We m? S good. Thank you.
Attention, all inmates. Five minutes
to l? Solution. Five minutes to l? Solution.
R Increase in detention.
All inmates to their departments.
- Now l? We see, Viktor.
- Five minutes to l? Solution, guys!
I f? Rst? S what s? Offers, but I can
not. He looks on? me all the time!
Take care of it, Shane. I do not pay
a dog f? r the so-called? ll sj? lv.
Would the d? R the old man could
sl? down a j? vel Pete Ritchie?
- You m? Ste sort out your priorities.
- But he was staring all the time.
H? R you, Shane! He? S just
a silly j? vla svartskalle, okay?
Stick now, and g? R you will g? Ra!
Shane. Come ih? G who
protects you from? n the other.
All right.
Thanks, Warren.
L? Solution. All inmates
back to their departments.
- Come on, hurry up, Dave.
- Yes, Mr. Perry.
I guess SBS? S more your thing.
Yes ... They show
an s? n d? r Turkish film IKV? ll.
He? S fr? N Iran.
Mr. Egan? I m? Ste shit, Mr. Egan.
- Yeah yeah. Hurry up.
- Yes, sir.
Viktor? S not the sharpest knife.
He takes hardly what you s? Offers.
- Yeah yeah. Skip the talking, Warren.
- Tucked!
Is that all? What an anticlimax.
- Of the chain, now.
- Take the chain.
Nice work, guys.
We m? Ste be h? Rifr? N
in ten minutes, okay?
H? S gone!
Damn, not another one.
H'll turn away, guys.
Which j? Vla r? Ra.
G? R out of p? on, Shane.
G? R out of p? the.
Viktor, sl pp him.
Sl pp him, Victor.
Last chance.
- Calm down, now.
- I'll need your shirt, Paul.
Have you avbitart time around, Ted?
Calm, calm, calm.
I'll f? Rs? Ka tr? the h? r
? over her head.
Can you h? Lla of her?
H'll steadily.
It? S an hour? S gone.
Do you know her? All right.
You can give her to me.
Give her to me, Viktor.
I have her.
F greatest and last warning.
G? R you s? again? ker you out.
- Nine in months?
- Wing pens m? Ste w? Xa out.
You have already falcons right here. What h? Commits
if he can not be rehabilitated?
- Yes, what the h? Commits d ??
- You m? Ste cull n A few paragraphs.
- It would look good.
- We work with what we have.
- Exactly.
- N A few fractures?
- I can not f? Rsvara more f? Glar.
- Not if you'll just show them.
- Unlike fr? N as d ??
- Other animals shown up, Why? R not f? Glar?
- Whenever the g? R what d ??
- Show him.
Hello, boys and girls,
moms and dads ...
- You chose r? Tt time.
- I have a house ...
... that the attempts KTE strangle another
who wanted to sort out her.
Are you kidding? Should you f? Board of Directors
the approved inspection? nd it h? r?
We? S no j? Vla circus, Glenys.
- The program is based on? natural behavior.
- The g? R against everything we're going to pieces? f? r.
Nobody wants to see rovf? Glar tied.
To see them flying can be a sev? Rdhet.
- And how much would it cost?
- Not as much as you can t? Na.
And it wants you so? PPA l? S P? gen? nheten?
It? S just you, Morrie.
He adore any other.
It'll need television? Tdirectories.
All right.
Mr. Perry. ? verlever f? crucible?
Maybe.
- What is the f? R her?
- As it looks right here ...
... not light.
If you do not s? Tter momentum.
I work on? it.
Glenys like id? N.
She's? Giving that she can tr? S us up.
We can build it beyond the s? Drag wing.
? eight sm? volj? tors and large.
We can build them of what is in
the carpenter shop, s? it costs nothing.
I think it may be a good news story
f? r us, boss.
Good f? R department.
Why? When do you think you f? R coming with id? S?
- We can not take people fr? N replanting.
- Not fr? N clocks, they draw money.
- It does not take money from other programs.
- It gives them a place to g? Tting stuff.
- If n? N different n? T that so? Ga?
- Yes.
- Who will be called? Take it?
- I t? Nkte Me Viktor Khadem.
He m? Ste f? make some of my own decisions.
He has the talent f? R.
- He beat Pete Ritchie.
- He? Were never spoken.
- People will provoke him right here.
- Do you want him?
N? N? Come on, n? N? R hungry?
He had not come here if he does not
had been clean for four? r.
Ni has got s? Ga what you think.
Now k? R we.
It? S fascinating how much bullshit
that comes out of your mouth.
- It s? Do you provide?
- The only thing you gl? Mde ...
- ... Was that rovf? Glar? S holy f? R him.
- It? S the most in that part of the round globe.
You want Viktor f? R to rest
will be p? r? dda f? r him ...
- ... That they do not r? R your f? Glar.
- It has v? L Guvern? Clean also? taken.
He g? R not through a D? Rr without being
told, hope you have a dog ring ready.
- Yes, yes, yes ...
- No...
We bet double or nothing on? how
quickly he f? r you end up in hell.
It? R r? Tt schyst right here.
The h? R idiots.
They will no scribble,
the? r just b? commits.
If you'll need some thing right here inside
s? come to me.
Looking for a good job
I can fix it also ?.
- S? G only, Viktor ...
- No, I g? R no. I'll need nothing.
What do you think you can pray? Eight f? R me
I do not know?
It? S up to you, Vik.
I offer myself only.
It will be your responsibility.
Volj? Tors. Lining house.
The h? Lla everything clean.
But from? Mst called? Tseln of f? Glarna.
What the f? R I f? R privileges?
Own room?
Maybe. But it is conditional.
If you assists me assists I you.
It beh? Vs. three man f? R the so-called 'take.
S? consider p? ...
... who you want to work with.
- Do you want me v are following?
- You want v? L make it work?
You can watch? them one hour
but to see a footsteps.
If the h? R does not work,
f? rlorar my room?
It depends on? what g? r wrong,
but it may h-known.
H? R you!
I knew he had n? N.
He has a 23-? Rig son? S auditor.
Where has he been for the last 18? Pure, d ??
The h? R? R a nice, Iranian family.
Guess who Viktor m? Rdade?
His b? Sta v? N. V? Rre? N S? it will not.
- What g? R we, d ??
- I do not know. I'll take care of it.
Attention, inmates. Those with m? Ten
scheduled to report to the office.
Mr. Perry.
- Do you have some thing to ask? Eight? N?
- I take Paul. He was doing a long good job.
- Okay. Who else?
- And Shane. The d? R.
- N? N S? Rskild reason?
- I m? Ste keep an eye on? him.
Have him's? I see him, s? he
no pc with regard to problems f? r me.
Sure. S? l? nge you know what you have.
What s? T dog. ? is he yours?
- Hon.
- Her name n? T?
What? S the matter with you, Pauly?
Whenever you an s? nt d? r foster child, or n? t?
I and my brother?
Do you know...
If my mom sent a letter would
I be f? r r? dd f? r to Open it.
F? R I would be r? Dd that she had put
broken glass in it, or some thing.
"I? Wish you? Tminstone
could talk to your father. "
He has taken the h? Rt.
"He does not know ... what to believe."
J? Sses, Pauly. It l? S best not? bad.
H'll stay away fr? N my stuff, asshole.
Shane, Paul. You're going to the office.
Sure.
Now!
- He has chosen you. It? S an order.
- No! Hell no. Not with Viktor ...
It? S clear. Come on? Over there.
- Okay. ? s five dollars a day?
- We'll take it later.
- That's it, you can g ?.
- Okay. Thank you, Mr. Perry.
V? Wait a bit, Paul.
Have you talked with your f? R? Ages,? N?
- No.
- There? R's up to you.
But you collect p? you m? nga
unused telephone.
Paul!
It? S n? Gra ungtr? D d? R gone, Mr. Perry.
A to d? R. One piece...
- Okay, Shane.
- They are? Cker enough.
Observing him. He pc? Where P? g? rden,
in the canteen and now in the woods.
It? S Islam. They have more control f? R
cleanliness? s you and I f? rst? R Us p ?.
Have you l? St again?
All of the h? R r? Recorded with
your parole.
N? T you m? Ste b? RJA ponder p ?.
Have you n? N idea where to stay,
or who you can round-known to?
I have no.
The pieces? Mmer not, Victor.
Your son, d ??
No, I have no son.
He does not want k? Nd me.
He wants to come and tr? LHW you.
He will not.
I? S not good f? R him.
And if he g? R there?
I switch on Thursday.
It? S The Footy Show.
It will not b? Outer? N s ?.
And you m? Ste see WWF duds.
Crazy. The? V? Ltr? United
but still ...
- It? S not mine.
- G? M not right here.
- Last g? Ng you work f? R Warren.
- You do not understand what h? Commits right here.
Viktor! Vik, sn? Ll ...
Do not you think I know.
I live right here. You? R min.
- You do not know what he g? R.
- Do you want me's? Give? T he? Sure.
Damn!
N? N m? Ste talk with n? N
before n? t h? connects with n? n.
You did not say "sn? Ll".
Warren. Shane. What h? Connects?
I do not know. He did
Warren f? Rbannad, Mr. Egan.
You can ask? Tta it right here ...
... or p? office, d? r all watching you.
It? S up to you.
You know the d? R j? Vla Arab? Shane
s? gives his flushed down Warren's dope.
What do Warren about it?
He has lifted the f? Rbudet p? Shane.
G ?, you.
- Now you put Shane in the shit.
- What would I g? Ra, Mr. Perry?
- Do you know what he was seated inside f? R?
- I do not care. He? S a junkie.
The sta? L fr? N family and décor where a
f? r ten cents.
He d? Educated their own children.
- His own children?
- It was an accident.
An accident? Sj? Lvklart.
It was an accident f? R me also? ...
It was an accident,
he sits inside f? r dr? p.
He was h? G, gr? Presented with girlfriend? Memor
and backed the car out? over their own children.
Whenever I d? Dade my v? N
I was drunk, crazy.
He said some thing that drew shame? Ver me.
I could not g? d? rifr? n.
A small child, what had he done?
N? R n? N d? R is not about whether
the f? RTJ? United there, you know.
See item? me.
You can not even see p? Me?
Why? R did you get here?
F? R I want to know
Why? Are you crushed v? ra lives.
How you could g? Ra's? to Mom and me.
Whenever mother was thrown
we had nowhere to V? gene.
You know how it is called? NNS?
You van? S conditioned us? not even her
brother wanted us to g? ra.
No one in SL? FORCES.
Half acquaintances blamed p? her.
Who do you live with?
With your cousin, Danush.
He's been my father, not you.
They took care of Mom n? R she was d? Basis.
Not f? R you care.
You do not even come on? the funeral.
It could be you. You got COURTESY nevertheless.
But you did not give her even that.
Yes, it? S your l? Solution p? everything.
I have a wife and children sj? Lv, now.
And you will not n? Rheten of us.
Oh well.
I? S right back.
That went well.
I pray? Ttat
what the j? end cover did to us.
You beh? VDE g? Ra it.
- I never want to see him again.
- There? R f? Rst? Standable.
How m? S child?
- She m? S good.
- None of the h? R? S your fault.
Not d? and not now.
It? S important that you know it.
Even though we know it
k? NNS there's? n? r you? r children.
- Sorry it was not working.
- Why? R you got me g? Ra it right here?
What do you want?
I m? Ste find p? what you want...
get out of the h? r pc? contents.
What you want.
He? S my son.
- Wow.
- R timed well, right?
- Have you done it right here?
- Yes. There was much work.
? r the f? crucible h? rifr? n?
Where h? Lsad, sir.
Where h? Lsad, ma'am.
She comes back to you.
She named Yasmine.
Be prepared.
V? WELCOME, Yasmine.
J? Vlar! I g? S not in there.
- Breeder? R you.
- Sad.
It would not either.
She? S Glenys f? Gel.
Nothing? R l? Skigare
? n to bring? ver n? n else rovf? gel.
It will no l? Taking wing muscles f? Rtvina.
You m? Ste g? with her every day.
Make sure she is? R itself.
What is h? Nt with her?
There? S no danger.
You m? Ste be quiet around them in the b? Rjan.
New million ?, for? Mlingar. It skr? Mmer them.
It? S just carbon dioxide.
The d? R quickly and SM? Rtfritt.
You called? R them up s? that f? crucible see k? The measure.
- Okay ...
-? RN? Best not m? Ss or pellets.
She'll need bunnies, jewelry? R? each s? nt.
- S? who f? r r? ttorna?
- Falcons vr? Vats, h? Vats.
- They will no h? R? N.
- Good. I'll introduce you f? R n? N.
The h? R? R Baz.
He? S my friend.
Want to h? Read?
R? Is not her, patting her. Never.
The most important thing? R to h? Lla them wild
s? they can ck? PPA free.
We just take them n? R we treat them.
Good job, Yasmine.
You have r? Tt, do not rely on? me.
Gl? M not who you were.
D? you can g? lost p? v? gen home.
You m? Ste h? Lla firm
at what is in the heart? rtat.
And endure the rest.
What about the v? Ra privileges?
What the f? R we?
Do you want some thing f? R you work f? R it.
Just like me.
I will s? Ga one thing.
I'll take care of you,
if you take care of him.
The problem? R you clots in your food.
What about the n? R we beat? Pper you free?
You f? R g? h? rifr? n.
You know what my dad always said?
"You kids? R a potato IFR? N
To beh? huh be called? rda in skottk? RRA. "
Though it was he who held the record.
? Are you ready?
I told you, for him to pieces? Da up in g? R
and f? RRG? r. Observing the h? r.
? Are you hungry?
J? Ready, s? She has never done f? rut.
What have you done?
Was quiet at f? Glarna, I said!
I did not say a word!
You g? S nothing I ask. You pc? Dar not.
Where is the great r? Ttan?
- I do not know, I told you!
- How did you lose him? I r? Deserts.
- If you g? R you away, you can draw!
- As if I have n? Nstans to g ?.
- As if I have n? Nstans to g ?!
- Do you want to get paid f? R you working!
Lazy j? VLA Aussie.
- G? R what he asks.
- It does not matter what I g? R.
- There? R b? St to dragging.
- Hey, Warren.
Want a witness?
Do you know what hour? Connects with witnesses?
How do l? Nge have you been in the system?
Five minutes?
- I have h? Rt you have had a tough time.
- It has nothing with him to g? Ra.
He f? R g? f? r the h? r g? ng.
S? My knowledge? R he no snitch.
Shane. You? Is a snitch.
- It? S not!
- And you? R stupid.
You have not taken, right?
You will be utilized.
Viktor has got their own room,
what have you f? tt?
I told you he took
it and flushed it down.
It? S true.
I was d? R.
I hj? Lpte you with your problem.
And the? S? h? r you pay back?
It looks bad.
It cost money. S? you f? r either
work of it or pay it off.
- There? R v? L just reasonable?
- I work out of it. I work out of it.
OK good.
- F? R I n? Gra job? T you.
- Okay.
But ask? Eight f? R your buddies
how much harder it gets.
Okay, Warren.
- Thank you, Warren.
- Sure, Shane.
Mr. Perry.
It? S b? St that you are observing? the h? r.
I have a dozen s? Na h? R.
"Check room for 16 E and H."
A couple s? Na h? R.
"Fr? Ga Arab how he f? R the stuff."
False accusations.
N? S not like Viktor.
- If n? N problems with rovf? Glarna?
- No, it has nothing with them to g? Ra.
If it? S n? T p? g? ng I want
that you take care of it right away.
Then n? R we become hysterical? Ver
an organized tjallarkampanj?
Klagom? L p? the food? s one thing that we would
ignore the hard drugs? r another.
Especially now, n? R we have
m? natliga inspections.
You can g ?.
If the pc? Mmer? Does he directly!
- N? N idea?
- Yes, skith? Gene Shane to b? RJA with.
Everything? S clean.
Do you t? Nkt p? what to g? ra
If he ker like?
No, Viktor? R f? R experienced
f? r to? ka where p? n? t s? nt h? r.
Yes, especially if n? N tipped him off.
Can I g? Ra? T f? R you, Fold?
I will g? Ra you a TJ? NST.
I'll pray? Eight how to avoid problems.
- What can you cause f? R problem, old man?
- You can not g? Tting n? T f? R me.
You can not come on? n? t
I do not have t? nkt p ?.
If you pc with regard to some thing, I see it on?
l? ngt h? ll. You would not see n? T.
Fold, buddy.
You do not, right?
The h? R? S not k? Ken.
You? Ker shortly.
And I'll need no g? Ra? T.
The g? R you just sj? Lv.
I hope that his brother will,
the h? r g? ng.
- N? N has given you hard drugs, Trav.
- L-ons by.
The? R the twins.
You know, s? N d? R telepathy.
Yes. I would not be so? schyst
against Shane if I were you.
Why? R? R not you d? R gone?
? s not your family right here?
If they do not want to tr? LHW you,
Why? r they call Mr. Perry all the time?
- Did he say that?
- He's? Give it to you all the time.
Do not you think that I h? R there?
Why? Are not you talk to them?
It's none of your g? Ra.
You k? Nd not them.
You do not seem like tr? LHW them.
Sl pp there, okay?
I had worried me f? R
what my dad would think.
What he would see n? R he tr? Ffade me,
what he would f? rst ?.
He adore you. He sees nothing.
Hello, Vik. Just checking it? R l? St.
- R is not f? Glarna n? R I? R h? R.
- Okay, calm down.
I g? R just my job.
I mean, my goodness.
It was you who got game
f? r there d? g.
Quiet. Be quiet.
Viktor!
Stiff as a plank.
The m? Ste have h? Nt g? R kv? Ll.
- N? N has broken his neck p? the.
- What hours? Connects?
- What do you think?
- F? Remove him! F? Remove him!
- SI pp him!
- Did you do it right here?
Never! What g? R you, Viktor?
Your j? VLA maniac!
- F? Remove him!
- Back away!
- Stick h? Rifr? N, Shane.
- Pull? T fuck!
- See where you found him.
- Paul.
- Just right here.
- He called? Mpade received.
- Against what?
- Another rovf? Gel.
A h? K, or n? T st? Rre.
The set him up to n? Tet and
grabbed. They protect their territory ...
- No no. I know he did it ...
- You do not know. H? L k? Ften.
- Listen to? n? n who knows.
- Look right here.
The h? R? R s? R fr? N claws. And h? R
will not fr? n the h? r f? rule.
See sj? Lv.
I've seen it f? Rut. It? S not
a m? nniska who have done it right here.
It can be a duvh? K.
What have you f? R intentions?
T? Nker you come in with a klagom? L?
There I could.
I mean, I've r? RIGHTS.
- It? S up to you, Shane.
- But ...
... it would f? rst? ra
full rovf? gelsprogrammet, right?
If I had my own room s? would
be n? n sort of compensation.
- Pull? T Hell, Shane.
- Okay ...
Lie l? Gt ist? Llet, s? I send not
you back to the forest.
And Warren.
All right. I? R the physiotherapist
if n? n'll need me.
Sir.
What for? Nker he to do?
None. He ins? G
that it is not l? g in his interest.
It? S not an option. Viktor m? Ste out.
Come on, Terry. He went? Ver gr? NSE
but he has become provocerad-
- And he runs a program
you did not think would work.
They want to send you out. I will protect you
not if you abuse my f? rtroende.
- I g? S what you want.
- D? should we tr? LHW social worker.
- What should I s? To go to her?
- You will g? Her anger management course.
- My English? S not good ...
- Take English also ?.
You can? Ka out p? TV? seconds
and d? you will not be back.
- Okay.
- I'll f? Rs? Ka beh? Ll you.
But you f? R? Convince me of
you? r v? rd it.
I have taken anger management course
four g? nger.
I came? Ver projection of guilt
p? one week.
Victor? R still p? f? rnekelse.
- Four g? Nger?
- Yes.
It? S like a ... diploma course.
You know, Vik? Little renovation
would g? ra trick right here.
F? R the f? it prettier.
I was a carpenter f? Rut, I can g? Ra it.
I can l? Gga a g? Ng h? R, planting n? Gra
ferns d? r. The kr? Vs not p? lot.
What do you think, Fold?
A beautiful g? Ng the tr ?, entire row? Gene down.
F? R I think stenbel? Ggning
becomes f? r content.
What do you think, Fold?
He thinks he'll kn? Pocket Me
s? I pull.
That? S what he g? R.
L-ons downloaded, d ?. Provoke him not.
- Viktor d? Dar you if he sees the d? R.
- He did n? Town.
It was d? Rf? R he came on? Me at
mushuset. I had gl? Mt his food.
- Good night, Baz.
- It? S the d? R you g? Mmer stuff, huh?
Do not f? R interested, now.
I come in, guys.
Take a walk, Paul.
You? R fucking stupid j? Vel.
F? Rl? T, Mr. Perry.
Your mom just called.
Jas ??
What did the old bitch now?
- Do you have some sl? Kt to call?
- Why? R d ??
- It's about your brother, Jeff.
- What? S wrong with him?
He had a serious asthma attack
and the ambulance could not arrive in time.
I? S terribly sorry, Shane.
He was taken into p? St Vincent's Hospital
clock TV! -
But it was f? r late.
It? S all we know, s? You should call
n? n familjemedlem-
f? r the F? nd the details.
No. There's no one I want to talk to.
Do you want to tr? LHW social worker?
- No.
- I think you should.
You f? R t? Nka p? it. S? G to.
- He? S the d? D, this output has been ??
- Yes, it? S him.
You can come back in, Paul.
S? G to to tr? LHW
social worker, okay?
I?'m Sorry, h? R you.
I do not h? Ll his hand
p? his brother's funeral.
It? S a little late for that? Nka p? it now.
- Come on.
- Not interested.
- It? S you who? S escort.
- What skith? G you? R.
- How Numerous g? Nger I hj? LPT you?
- I've said it all along, it? S crap.
One can not h? Ll them in hand
and discipline them at the same time.
I? S the wrong person.
I t? L him, and he knows that.
D? you should have said no fr? n B? rjan,
n? r you knew what he possessed f? r.
- B? RJA not, now.
- T? Nk p? what you g? r.
You f? Rlorar a child to cancer, and he
d? dar her. Think you can handle it?
It? S probably time, Shane.
The old bitch? S packed.
It? S my sister also ?.
Observing her!
It will be good n? R you g? R set.
I will no s? Ker p? I can handle
the h? r sj? lv, Mr. Perry.
Replace PM? Der, we have a big job.
Skith? G.
N? N took the wrong. Or what, your shit?
They took the wrong brother.
- What should I g? Ra with it?
- It? S like you? R carpenter with the plan.
- Do you want to build the n? T?
- H? Promises of the wood? S miserable.
- The m? Ste sorted.
- The h? R? R good.
Metal poles f? R to s? Eight the p? location
d ?? I can not b? RJA without s? Na.
I arrange it? T you.
H? R you! Want to know a secret?
Do you want it?
Viktor called? Ller v? Rre? N he nips.
Everyone thinks he? S an h? Rd j? Vel.
But he? R s? Mre? N my dad
p? bluffing.
I give her food.
She gets a little carried away.
It? S time f? R her.
- Never. She? S not ready.
- Mr. Perry also think? it. She? S strong.
- She'll never.
- Not if we v? NTAR lengthier either.
- You have done a great job with her.
- I k? Nd her, I'll take care of her.
Her wings? S still stiff.
Wing pens will no male? XTA.
- How will she be able to hunt?
- It? S Viktor's decision, Mrs H? Ller with.
She? S your f? Gel. You f? R g? Ra it.
All right.
Yes.
Come now.
Come on, sl pp her.
H? S gone.
- It is? R not.
- It? S probably a sleeping area.
She m? Ste be h? R gone.
H? R.
Come on, hj? Lp me up.
Take it f? CAUTION.
Hell, if he falls, it becomes utredningar-
-ers? ttningsanspr? k Ombudsman.
My job.
It? S b? St that you make sure that he
shedding p? you d ?, manager.
K? MPa p ?.
K? Mpa p ?, right?
-? Is she d? R?
- Yes.
She looks to m? good.
She has one hour? Ckningsplats and everything.
Seems she have? Tit?
She may not have the d? Dat n? T? N,
she m? ste v? l land a little.
- But it? S a good start, right?
- Yes, well done.
It? S beyond belief. Up in r? K only.
If he? S in the ground, where? R he d ??
I do not know. Heaven? Or n? Nstans.
Whenever you d? R? R the end.
It? S called? Rd.
There? S nothing you can to do? T there.
- You d? Dade v? L no, huh?
- Hell no.
It was ... not the intention.
- It was an accident.
- Yes, f? R me also ?.
No. It was my fault.
I was full n? R I beat him.
I know what you mean.
Four days, Mr. Perry.
She can not survive lengthier? N S? h? r.
Maybe I made a mistake.
Maybe I should have listened to? Paul.
- It will not work every g? Ng.
- I t? Nker f? R very p? what he did.
Ist? Llet f? R p? f? rule.
- What do you think?
- About what d ??
Oh well. Yes.
Fine.
Do not f? R excited, just!
Do you think I should write the date?
Yes, you r? Tt. It is good enough as it is? R.
THE H? R? F? R MY BROTHER JEFF HARRISON
SHANE
She'll be fine.
She did it! She did it!
- F greatest f? Crucible out.
- What incited you up your f? R?
Thank you f? R you BROUGHT me!
L-ons by, Glenys. You adore it right here.
What would you g? Ra Otherwise, see p? TV?
G? R you clean it right here?
All of the h? R m? Ste be clean.
The new f? Crucible does not like
the smell of the other.
- The décor is also ?.
- Do you have some thing that's? Ga, s? s? g it.
Do you think that f? Crucible where your v? N?
You would not have r? Rt owl.
We? S just right here f? R to hj? LPA f? Glarna.
I did wrong,
s? you sent her out f? r to en? let?
- What was that?
- Same f? R you f? R her.
And f? R me.
All m? Ste come out h? Rifr? Nn? N g? Ng.
Maybe g? Is it good, maybe not.
G? R there again.
G ?, Yasmine. G? S your job.
Come on. Work p ?.
It? S not gametime now.
You think I want to be your v? N?
There's a whole clan rabbits
down at the pond.
My wife r? Knade to 50 hours? Romdagen.
They will be n? R cattle have grazed clear.
It should r? Pocket
f? r to h? ll Yasmine m? tt.
How Numerous children do you have, Mr. Perry?
None.
The h? R? R b? Sta time p? Day h? r.
The h? R? R a h? Rligt pc? Lle.
A good life.
Yes.
- Did you bring him home?
- Do not enter the house, f? R's sake.
You have g? Tt? Ver gr? NSE again.
L-ons of Leo. You might like
to sit and s? sa whole day.
St? R the "social" d? R?
No, you idiot.
The st? R "kriminalv? Rdare".
Gl? Mmer you it s? k? r they? ver you.
The lengthier the? H? R,
the st? rre risks Whenever the sl? pps out.
Sure, but there are other things? Verv? Ga.
The years past? N I t? Nkt.
He matures in the management of
people and situations.
It? S thanks to him f? Gelprogrammet
has become a success? ng.
I h with regard to,
but? is he ready f? r dagpermission?
There? S no doubt that the more he f? R
v? Well accustomed to life utanf? r, the b? outer.
I h? Ller with Matt about it right here.
We still have the problem of where to
? ka n? r he? P? dagpermission.
I think we have an ally.
N A few centimeters,
what? s the remote? ext cylinders? XTA.
H? R? R your itinerary. Yousef has also?
a copy, s? we can g? through it.
Okay?
I can not come without some thing.
My son gives me a big g? Huh.
What does he think I will TomH? Nt? That
I do not respect him or his wife?
Okay, what we're talking right here?
Flowers? N? T s? Nt?
Fr? N me. My hj? RTA.
I have no s? Nt.
Are you going? Ka and tr? LHW family?
I t? Nkte that you might
wanted l? s my leather jacket?
It? S stylish.
See you.
Your son has been calling all day.
D? K you did not even look up?
What a brilliant id ?.
To give an old r? V shortcuts? Gar.
Thank you, Mr. Egan.
I? S fully aware of it.
The urine sample? S clean,
but not alcohol test.
- How much, among other things? Ste he?
- 0.13.
- It was weak f? R five hours.
- Where we send him d ??
The g? R we do not. He f? Rlorar all
privileges and ports p? square one again.
S? Hh him in the sick cell at night.
I would not even the attempts ka.
You'll need a degree in politics.
I do not want to program falls ice? R.
You said that? R he h? Ller together.
- Yes, but he can tear it also ?.
- It? S sin p? all the knowledge he has got.
Paul can bring? Ver. He knows how to
g? race. And him we can depend on ?.
The h? R? R v? L do not personally f? R you?
It can give you on? it? s!
He bl? Ste me, you would t? Put it?
Take it f? CAUTION only. You've got food,
s? v nevertheless not back? t her b? rjan.
If you'll need hj? Lp we call Mrs.
- Whenever, Viktor back?
- What the f? Glarna Re? Of hits, never.
Gl? M there, girl.
I will no have some thing to him that g? Ra.
I did clean it.
I made a clean décor is also ?.
I have? Eight weeks away, s? I do not want to
have n? gra problems. S? G how you want it.
-? R the d? R your TV?
- Yes, but look grams? RNA.
No, look you.
I do not care.
After all the shit I has got him!
And now he comes back aspackad.
What m? Ste to g? Ra
f? r to work his way back?
Victor?
He does not even have the chance. One m? Ste
g? through rehab, f? be f? r psykologerna-
- And l? Ra to share? Nger. Victor? R
not even soon enough to fool alcohol test.
Check it out right here.
Why? R d ??
I t? Nker k? Pa a.
My brother and I t? Nkte g? Ra it.
Come on, they cost the million!
Bullshit. 350,000th And they'll need no
f? r to g? ng.
Schyst. "Including 12 m? MonthsÛ
f? retagsavgifter. "What? Is it?
Do not know. But it m? Ste be
lots of construction jobs d? r up.
It will be the end f? R salmonella.
Who chose the h? R pc? Contents? T he?
H? LSA and s? Safety at work.
You g? R it en? Adjuster f? R your self.
He did wrong, and went straight on?
booze that? s called? let to him? r h? r.
I? S shocked.
F? R only a chance with you?
Look carefully around.
No n? R up to the bar.
It? Rb? Outer? S no chance,
that? s all they f? r you.
True.
I hope you enjoy Heaven
h? rskare. Ovanf? R us we see River.
-? Is it always s? h? r people?
- F? R the most part.
They always find money
if they think they can t? na more.
I come with a falcon, an owl
and perhaps n A few kestrels.
S? G to Viktor.
I have removed Viktor fr? N f? Glarna.
What the heck did you do it f? R?
- He broke in the p? furlough.
- You can not f? Rlora him.
He f? Rst? R f? Glarna,
it? s sv? rt to find.
- Sorry, what? S? it? s.
- Alter p? the d ?.
Hello everybody. The h? R? R Millie.
She has also? become sv? rt injured
and can not do? PPA out in the open.
You m? Ste f? Rst? that nothing might f? r you
to work with f? glarna again.
Yes. But I want the attempts ka.
Your son, d ?? You failed him also ?.
It? S f? R his sake I m? Ste f? Rs? Ka.
But I can not write some thing.
All right. Take your time on? you.
I write? T you.
I want to ask? Eight f? R him Why? Am I not
com p? his mother's funeral.
It was f? R i
Drug shame? ver family.
My family did not want me d? R.
I f? Rst? S it.
If I had the g? Tt there ...
... who had d? been around d? r
f? r her and Yousef?
No one had come on? funeral
if I had got there.
My son is a good man.
He has...
...a family. A fine wife
which has given him a beautiful daughter.
Mr. Perry is a good man.
He has done a lot f? R me,
gave me a chance.
But I did not do n? T f? R them.
I f? R just me problems.
Do you know what we should k? Pa?
The h? R i h? Rnet, p? second row? tion.
Have n? N of them berth?
- F? R what d ??
- I would grams? RNAs have b? T.
As your dad have?
No, it? S an tr? Switches.
I have not r? D with.
-? R the w? Rd much?
- Yes, it? S his levebr? D.
F? R him and me.
F? R him now.
- Hello, Glenys.
- Matt!
- How? S the V? R big girl?
- Good.
She? T me? Written for a while,
but seems to be back.
She has no connection.
You give her food, but she does not care.
No. She looks on? him.
I told you.
And no other f? R sl? PPA her free.
You pc? Dar and city? Dar.
It? S all you Muslims g? R, huh?
Whenever you are not bombarded's? Commits us f? Rst? S.
It? S output has been? okay f? r s
tr? na s? d? r?
? r the s ?? ? Is it okay f? r you?
? Is it?
H? R you! L? MNA him alone, I said!
It? S? you g? r, Vik.
B the teeth want an easy job.
If it? S discreet, they see nothing.
People who do not f? Rst? Is it
become a poor f? rlorare you.
Pauly! Can you take advice line fr? N V? GG?
It? S time to tip.
How Numerous r? Tt did you f? RRA week?
- I do not know...
- Television ?. You had the tv? r? tt. I had? Eight.
I m? Ste talk to you, Paul.
Do not worry about f? R Shane f? R me.
But he can st? Ll the f? R you.
Yes, he can be a skitst? Vel sometimes.
But he? S also a buddy ?.
Have you lost your heart? Kernel?
He has never done n? T f? R you.
- What do you know about it?
- I k? Nd him.
H? Nger you are with him, s? you will s? n.
He was right here at home right here.
The g? S not you.
The h? R? R his home.
You have a good family.
You have a chance. Whenever you come out
you will not be back.
- What g? R he d? R?
- Your job, I guess.
- He? Ker in ...
- Wait, stop him.
If Viktor wants to s? Ra p? them, sure.
N? N m? Ste g? Ra it.
- What do you mean?
- You? R after his handl? Ggare, Open? Gonen.
Paul with Shane and Warren.
L-ons and two together.
I m? Ste sl? Ppa go of her.
You gave me the 50 so-called? L to
to remove him fr? n f? glarna.
Yes, it was d ?, but ...
He f? Rs? Ker really. He g? R
rehab program and tr? of hits Michelle.
He has taken on much more
? n I thought he would.
You have v? L no problems at volj? Tors?
No, I have realized a few things, just.
- He'll probably back to his own room.
- Go, now!
If you wish? Tert-? work
shall we? verv? ga it.
- Yes, I would like, Mr. Perry.
- Okay.
A close? Ga p? Paul
does not hurt either.
Shane? S not good f? R him.
I h? Ller with.
If you can prevent it, it would be good.
Paul has big problems in his head.
I do not know how to cook it.
He w? Grar talk to his dad.
He comes out about a half? R.
D? m? ste be arranged.
- I know.
- Can not you hit the father?
He has his r? RIGHTS.
It would be g? ? ver gr? NSE.
Shall we talk about conditions
f? r an? open prison.
It was not I who ignored the rules.
The g? R fr? S relaxed to the zero tolerance
p? a? gonblick.
T? Nk p? it.
You should t? Nka p? it.
It? S not r? Ttvist. We g? R all h? Rt
work, and s? f? r he? ran f? r it!
Come on? Over there, Shane.
Paul thinks it? S okay.
N? N m? Ste's so? PPA her free.
Rather, he? S self.
V? D ?, WELCOME back Fold!
You think I want to play with you?
Do you see? Now you fly well.
Hello, my son. How m? R you?
Did you write it right here, or did she do it?
I pray? Ttade. She wrote.
I do not know what to believe.
- V? Ntade him?
- No, he? KTE here directly.
Why? G? Are you the h? R?
What do you want from me?
I want to show you something.
I go? Mde the p? t? get the d? r day.
Now n? R you? R h? R ...
... we can b? RJA about?
I want you to L? K? Nd the h? R man.
H? R will probably be fine.
D? ? r she your.
The h? R? R your home.
Flights, Yasmine. Flight.
Flight.
Now she has taken.
She's looking for a termikvind.
Flights, Yasmine.
All you s? Ker, are searching for you.
It? S not f? Ngelset
who have h? rdat him, right?
No, he? S a great guy. He was doing a long
fantastic job of f? glarna also ?.
T? Nker you ask? Eight
what the h? nt with him?
Fr? Are you going?
I just want to take him home.
He and others? G into a power line, p? Gs it.
Poor thing was r? Tt badly damaged.
You have to g? Ra to patch up him,
it looks like.
Yes.
Hi dad.
You'll be fine, Yasmine.
M? God protect you.
Why? R she stops p? a pc? lle?
She'll need expanses f? R to f Numerous food.
She m? Ste collect himself a little.
It may take more? N one week
that f numerous f the greatest change.
If she h? Ller itself right here,
Why? r we see her?
Thanks, Dave.
F? Rl? T me, honey.
It? S not your fault, Viktor.
She? S an f? Gel that can not be beat? PPA free.
We do not know f? Rr? N to f? Rs? Ker.
We'll bring her back to us.
We kill her. I promise.
S? Nt h? R h? Commits.
He? S not the same man.
I f? Resl? Is it f? R Vander anyway.
You would tj? Na good
p? to s? LJA used cars.
? r he conv? nd? S? Kert.
If the g? R he f? R
dagpermission again, s ?.
Do not look f? R deep
into the abyss, my v? n.
D? watching the abyss into you.
M? Are you well?
Nietzsche. I l? See also ?, you know.
I l? L see citations? Ngst down
p? my desk calendar each day.
Have a ball. The black with dots.
You know what your problem is? R?
You t? Nker not through things.
- You do not see the big picture.
- What whole?
Viktor will beat? PPA out soon.
But you will stay right here.
R kna not with it.
- Where is Shane? Should not he? Take?
- Yes, he will.
Do you pray? Ttat
what your grumpy owl has done?
- No? N.
- He gave the Falcon's? He was silent.
D? R we have a decision
that does not g? r to take back.
Why? R s? br? a hurry?
What? Is it ... what are you looking for?
Come in, f? R all means.
What are you looking for, Mr. Egan?
You will not find some thing.
- Where f? Rsiktiga!
- I assists you, and what the f? R I?
The g? R me to m? Ltavla
f? r all idiots right here.
- I found it.
- It? S an f? Ll!
You know I would never have put it
p? the s? j? VLA silly pieces? lle!
How m? Nga? Speech do you want?
What do you think? ? r Viktor
or? r Warren really s? stupid?
All? S? stupid if they f? r the chance.
- What? S it like h? Connects?
- Viktor!
- I do not know, Mr. Perry.
- You should d ?, your j? Vel!
I'll find you and the d? Da you, your j? Vel!
I will find you! I d? Dar you!
Viktor, your j? Vel!
Viktor!
If you do not ans? Ker of release
you can f? sitting right here on television? ? r to.
I might not f? R the? Nd ?.
It depends on? you.
Frigivningskommitt? N
want to h? ra certain things.
What should I s? To go to them?
"I d? Dade my v? N"?
"I brought shame? Ver my family"?
It? S always good to b? RJA with the truth.
F? R you? R my heart? RTA clean, Mr. Perry.
I would ask? Eight anything f? R you.
? r the s ??
All right. Was it you who gave you
p? Pete Ritchie p? Pentridge?
No.
- But it was good that everyone believed it.
- Yes, I thought that it was s ?.
- Why? R fr? Inserted you?
- I wanted h? Ra the fr? N you.
- Where f? Rsiktig with her, Viktor.
- Go, go!
- The g? R good.
- Stop, Viktor.
- She m? Ste f? Rs? Ka!
- Go, go!
How will she l? Ra to Fly
if she is not f? rs? ker?
Hello everybody.
V? WELCOME to Heaven h? Rskare.
You might not know it, but it h? R
? s adaptation m? evaporator.
H? Rskaren? Ver the Australian sky.
The h? R? R Yasmine.
Kilstj? Rts? RAfter has
a gripping force p? TV? tons in the claws.
And a wingspan p? up to
TV? and a half meters.
The? V? Ldigt turf protecting,
h? ller together with its partners throughout the life-
-and can be around 50? years old.
Victor.
Come on, cry on? her.
F? R I?
Thank you.
You know how to g? R.
He will call on? her.
Come see p? f? rule.
You can sit right here.
They would do well h? R, b? Da TV ?.
Do you think?
You never know.