Tonight on a very special
Kitchen Nightmares,
Chef Ramsay
is in Eagle Rock, California,
where twins Jim and Jeff
are fighting to keep
their restaurant alive.
Right from the very beginning,
Gordon finds out he has
double trouble on his hands.
Oh, my God.
They're messy...
Make sure they say a prayer
before they start eating that.
They're lazy...
When's the last time this place
was cleaned? What a mess.
I hate cleaning. To me,
that's a 4-letter word.
They're loud...
You sure you don't
like raw chicken?
And they're emotional.
I didn't think it was that bad.
And this all adds up
to a recipe for disaster.
Will you stop acting
like a baby?
Oh, blow it out your .
Excuse me?
You heard it.
Hey, need diaper changing?
Shut up!
Will Chef Ramsay
be able to get through
to Jim and Jeff?
Right now you're making
yourself look stupid.
Or is this set of twins
the beyond saving?
It's a mistake.
It's a lethal mistake.
We can't serve them.
You'll kill somebody.
I screwed up.
What do you want me
to say now?
♪ Kitchen Nightmares 4x12 ♪
Capri
Original Air Date on May 6, 2011
== sync, corrected  by elderman ==
Nestled in the middle of
the up-and-coming neighborhood
of Eagle Rock, California,
is Capri,
an Italian restaurant which
is owned by the Thiel twins.
Hi, I'm Jeff.
Hi--Jeff.
I'm Jeff.
No, I'm Jeff.
You're Jim.
I'm Jim.
And...
We're the owners
of the Capri Italian restaurant.
Good evening, Capri,
Jim speaking.
How we got into
the restaurant business is
we used to come here
all the time,
and we loved the place,
so we said, "we'll buy it."
The feeling was,
it's like, dude, free pizza?
All right.
Yeah, yeah.
Word, word,
uh-huh. Team Capri.
The twins are like two
overgrown boys.
Jeffy's getting larger.
Let's play cymbals.
They're just kind of
immature.
Oh, I shouldn't have you
do the chicken fillets.
Excuse me.
They're just doing
what they know,
and it's not working.
Ta-da! Sorry.
Are you okay? I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Yes, everybody is entertained
by their childishness...
But it is a restaurant,
and we're here to serve food.
That looks good.
Oops.
You know what?
These guys can't cook!
Hmm.
We gotta figure a better way
to do the lasagna.
We got too many people
saying it's overcooked.
You think we should
cook it less?
The food that comes out from
the kitchen looks terrible.
What'd he say?
It wasn't cooked. It's raw.
Can't win 'em all.
It's embarrassing.
It looks like nobody cares.
You sure you don't
like raw chicken?
Here is their issue--
Jim and Jeff are lazy.
All right, I'm going to the car.
Wake me up when it's over.
Lazy is an understatement.
The twins' highest priority
is doing as little work
as possible.
There's something
that we're doing wrong,
and I'm not sure
what it is,
but the financial situation
hit the pooper--
we're broke.
Oops. Uh, pink
is never a good color.
I haven't paid them
for a few months.
We need help.
If things don't change,
I would say the doors
will close quickly.
Hello?
No, the phone's
not working again.
Fingers crossed that
Chef Ramsay's gonna help us.
"Capri, Italian dining
since 1963."
Closed since 1963?
My God.
Hideous.
What am I doing?
Hello?
Hi there.
How are you?
Pretty good. I'm Jeff.
Good to see you.
Likewise. Uh, it looks shut
from outside.
Uh, yeah,
we're not open yet.
Oh, you're not open yet?
No.
When do you open?
Uh, 4:00.
Dinner only?
Yeah.
And you're the owner?
Yeah, my brother and I are.
Okay, great.
Would you like to meet my brother?
Uh, yes, please.
What's his name?
Jim.
Jim. And you're Jeff.
Yep.
My God, look at this place.
Okay...
Okay.
It's fun to play
jokes on people.
In the twin union book,
you gotta mess with people.
Hey, how's it going?
Jeff, is your brother
not available?
No, I'm Jim.
No, come on.
No, I'm his brother.
You're kidding me.
No, I am.
Seriously.
I am serious.
Jeff, go get Jim.
Come on, don't--listen,
I've got work to do. Please.
Hold on.
Hold on. Hold on,
I'll get him.
What is this,
the comedy store?
Bloody hell,
look at them.
Are you kidding me?
Come on, guys.
Jeff and Jim.
Yes.
Correct.
Jeez. Look at you two.
You are identical.
And you're not dressing
like this especially today--
no, no, we--
we wear this as--
for the restaurant.
This is--
you've even got the same
sneakers on.
Pen there, pen there.
I didn't even notice that.
T-shirt there,
t-shirt there.
I didn't notice that.
Bit of flour there,
bit of flour there.
Yep.
It's quite scary.
Jim...
Yep.
And Jeff.
So who's in charge?
He is.
No, uh,
basically, I am.
I've worked here
longer than he has.
Okay.
Uh, but since 1963,
come on.
Oh, no, no, we bought it
about 14 years ago.
Okay. So why aren't you
open for lunch?
The Capri's never open
for lunch, which is good.
I'd rather go on the computer,
watch TV, play poker...
Problem is, for lunch, we'd have
to get another whole staff.
Goof off, sit in the sun.
You haven't even tried it?
No, I haven't.
No, I'm not ready
to jump into the lunch yet.
Okay, but you're open
every day for dinner?
Wednesday through Sunday.
Say that again?
What's wrong with
Monday, Tuesday?
So help me understand this.
Okay, right.
So you're actually closed
longer than you're open.
Yeah.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, well,
thanks for updating me.
I'm gonna sit down and, uh, eat.
Please, right over here.
Thank you.
Let me get you some water.
I'll get the water.
No, I'll get the water.
Jeez. Seriously?
Are these menus
from 1963 as well?
No, they're
getting old.
I know, we have to get--
you're kidding me.
But look at that.
Is this a joke?
That's not.
You're kidding me.
I can't believe they're--
they're falling apart.
You can't even read that,
it's so dirty.
First impressions.
Wow.
Okay, give me five minutes
to have a read of the menu...
Okay.
Go ahead.
And I'll--I'll catch up
with you guys later, yeah?
Okay.
Holy crap.
I don't know what
Chef Ramsay expected,
but it's not a chichi place.
I'm not a chichi kind of guy.
I'm more down to earth.
Hello.
Oh, hello.
I'm Colleen.
I'm your server today.
Okay. Nice to see you.
Colleen, how long
have you been here?
Nine and a half years.
a decade?
Yeah.
Seriously, what was the last
thing that got changed in here?
Oh...
This is still the same way
the original owners had it.
Really?
Wallpaper's been up there
for 35 years.
Oh, God.
Let's, uh, let's get
through the menu, yeah?
Let's start off with, uh,
meatball sandwich.
I love meatballs.
Who makes them?
They come from a company
that we order from.
You're kidding me.
No.
You can't even make
a meatball?
I can.
Okay, let's go for
the meatball sandwich,
and let's go with
the chicken scarpello.
Okay, pizza.
Ooh.
Let's go for
the Capri colossal.
You want the big one?
Yeah, why not?
Okay.
Okay, I'll let you
put that order in.
Okay.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Okay, what do we
have to make?
Chicken scarpello,
meatball sandwich,
extra large colossal.
He wants an extra large?
Jim, get me
an extra large dough.
What does he want?
The colossal.
All righty.
So it's not just the menus.
Oh, dear.
Bits of sauce
down there. Crap.
Ugh.
Just disgusting.
Bits of everywhere.
There's tape on the carpet.
Look at this place.
When was the last time
the place was cleaned?
Not lately.
How long has this stuff
been here?
20 years.
Bloody hell.
Oh.
It's like it's snowing.
Oh, oh, my God.
That's gross, no?
Yes.
That's above people's--
that's very--yes.
Jim,
two seconds, please?
When was the last time
this place was cleaned?
Uh...
Have you seen this?
No, I did not.
My goodness, me.
Who's responsible
for cleaning here?
I'm responsible.
I didn't do it.
Have you seen the fans?
I do not like to clean.
I hate cleaning.
To me, that's a 4-letter word.
So I'm about to start eating,
I give that a little shake,
and all of a sudden,
the dust just runs down.
Let me wash my hands
before I start eating.
What a mess.
You want to microwave
these meatballs, please?
Okay.
Oh, come on.
Work with me.
Cheese.
Sandwich is ready.
Okay, a meatball sandwich.
Meatball sandwich.
Um...
Okay, and so they buy the
meatballs, they defrost them,
and then, has that been
microwaved, or...
Yes.
Thank you.
Oh.
Okay, what else
do we have to make?
A scarpello.
That's nasty.
When a restaurant can't even
bother to make a meatball,
that's not a good sign,
let me tell you that.
Someone should tell him
the chicken's definitely dead.
Not again.
What's the matter
with these guys?
Okay.
Oh, my God.
What in the hell is that?
The colossal pizza.
Wow.
I mean, it's someone's
cleared out the fridge.
Look at it.
It's endless.
It has a little bit
of everything,
except for anchovies.
Ugh, that's dreadful.
Okay, thank you.
Okay.
The crap and the gunk
on top of it is just hideous.
He didn't like
the pizza?
He's not liking
anything.
Oops.
Okay, now we have
the chicken scarpello.
Oh, wow.
It looks dull.
That's not right.
Ooh.
It smells.
Is that fresh?
Um...
Can you ask him how old
the chicken is, please?
Oh, that was nasty.
How old is the chicken?
I don't know.
When did we get it?
Uh, I don't know.
We took it out
of the freezer yesterday.
Tell him
it's 14 years old.
We took it out
of the freezer yesterday.
It's frozen,
it is not fresh,
'cause we can't afford to keep
fresh meat here all the time,
because we don't serve
that much.
If he wants to donate money
so I can make it fresh,
no problem, but otherwise,
tough .
They're not open for lunch,
but so far,
what I've just experienced,
they shouldn't be open
for dinner either,
he took it out of
the freezer yesterday,
and doesn't remember
when the delivery was.
Excuse me.
Oh, dear. Excuse me.
Ugh.
Under the tables,
it's littered with gum.
Colleen?
Yes?
Look at that.
It's everywhere. Ugh.
Absolutely disgusting
how lazy some people can be.
Let's go on a gum ball rally.
Ugh.
Oh, God,
under there.
Look at the size of the gum
under that one.
Oh, look at one
at the end.
And the corner.
Oh, my God,
look at that one there.
When was the last time
the tables were cleaned?
Not ever, that I've known of,
underneath.
They've never been
cleaned underneath?
No.
Oh, my God. One, two,
three, four, five.
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
Six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
18, 19, 20 bits of gum.
Every frickin' table...
Has gum underneath of it.
Has gum underneath.
Mm.
No. Don't say that.
Come on, stop crying.
grow up,
you .
you.
Uh, Jim, Jeff.
Comin'.
I'm really nervous.
Oh, dear.
Dear, oh, dear,
oh, dear.
I'm afraid of what
Chef Ramsay has to say.
Honestly,
you seem like nice guys,
but that was painful.
The general feel of the place
is disgusting.
I can tell how much
you don't care,
you just stand there
with your foot on the booth.
Can you get your dirty feet
off your own booths?
Have a look at this.
Every table is littered
with stale disgusting gum.
We just--we never looked
underneath the table.
Didn't have the time?
Busy for lunch?
No.
Open seven days a week?
Not.
The meatball sandwich--
disgusting.
The chicken
was turning,
and then the colossal,
caked with crap. Were they
canned mushrooms on top?
Yeah.
Canned olives?
Mm-hmm.
Soggy and tasteless.
Where's the pride?
I don't know.
Come on, guys.
It's like a joke.
Find a pulse,
and get real.
Before we open
for dinner tonight,
would you mind wiping
the lampshades,
and can somebody
get under the tables
and get rid
of that gum?
Yeah.
I'm going for lunch.
I'll see you later.
I'm starving.
Capri classic Italian.
What a joke.
He said our food sucked.
And, uh, that, uh,
our restaurant's
really filthy.
I didn't think it was that bad.
After sampling
the horrendous food...
That's not right.
And discovering a dining room
that hasn't been cleaned
in quite some time...
Oh, God, under there.
Look.
Chef Ramsay
has instructed the twins
to clean up their restaurant
before dinner service.
You do the fans. I don't
want to get on a ladder.
Let's get Darian
in here.
I have a staff
to do the cleaning.
That's why I'm considered
the boss,
and they are someone
that works with me--for me.
Get in here, now.
We don't have a lot of time.
We have to turn everything over.
We got an hour before
we're supposed to open.
After the staff
takes over the cleaning
of the dining room,
Capri opens for dinner...
Hello.
And Chef Ramsay arrives...
The door shakes.
To see the twins
in action.
I've never seen a kitchen
like this before.
I mean, this place
is littered with crap.
What's that there?
Co2 for the beer.
Look at those shelves.
I mean, that's grime.
That's like
14 years of grime there.
Chef Ramsay was, uh,
"oh, there's dust here,
there's this."
It's just like,
it's not that bad.
What's in here?
Dare I?
Vegetables.
That's the vegetables?
What's this
at the bottom?
Uh, that's supposed
to be eggplant.
It's what?
Eggplant parmesan.
When were they cooked?
Last Thursday.
Last Thursday?
God almighty.
Look at that.
Oh, feel that.
That's tomato sauce.
Yeah, but feel it.
I know it's--
we just made it today.
Just made it today.
So what's it doing
in the fridge?
Hold that.
I know it's hot.
Hold it. What does
hot things do,
that are sealed,
that goes inside
a cold fridge?
The sauce goes sour.
I didn't know that.
You didn't know that.
I suggest you spend
five minutes
sorting out your first
before you start cooking, yeah?
Okay.
I should've known better.
He's right, but he's just
a pain in the ass about it.
Darian.
Want to go through it
real quick?
Yeah.
Trash.
With the rotten vegetables
thrown away...
I need an order
of wings, please.
And the orders pouring in, Jim
and Jeff get back to cooking...
Darian, order
of green beans, please.
Got it.
And begin to send food
out of the kitchen.
Make sure they say a prayer
before they start eating that.
Okay, the chicken.
But the diners
are less than impressed.
Okay. They sent this back.
They didn't like it?
They said that
he can't eat it.
What was this?
Okay.
And a pile of mush.
Big pile of mush.
Is anyone tasting anything,
seasoning, tasting?
Every time a dish came back,
it was like losing a customer,
and, uh, it hurts.
What was wrong with it?
It's too floury
and not enough sauce.
It makes me feel
like a loser.
I do really feel
like a loser right now.
Jeff,
you okay?
What's wrong?
I'm just frustrated.
I'm--I'm working on it.
Just...
Get outside,
get some fresh air.
What's the matter?
Just...
It was a failure.
You can't give up
like that.
I'm not trying to,
just...
It's not going right.
I need to see what
I've got to work with
before I can start looking
at any form of change.
You have to
bounce back, huh?
I'm working on it,
I really am.
Jeff, you've got to.
Okay.
Come on.
Let's go, come on.
Let's go.
Okay, okay.
Chef Ramsay's, like, "you gotta
pull yourself together,
get back in there
and get through the night."
How we doing?
We're doing well, sir.
Thanks to Chef Ramsay's
encouragement,
Jeff jumps back
into dinner service...
Okay, here we go.
And tries to help his brother
Jim get the kitchen
back on track...
Keep it up, Jim.
You're doing a good job.
But unfortunately,
he only makes matters worse.
Jim, what have you
done to those?
I don't know
what happened to those.
I-I really don't.
You defrosted them
in the bag?
I think they were defrosted
in the bag, and I--
Jeff?
Yeah.
The chicken tenders,
what did you do to them
to defrost them?
I put it, uh,
on the steam table.
You defrosted them
in the steam table from frozen?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
Not what you're
supposed to do?
No.
Frozen food needs to be
defrosted naturally.
Right.
Give me the bag.
Where's the bag?
Pass the--
Oh, God almighty.
We can't serve them.
You'll
Kill somebody.
Jim, talk to me.
What am I supposed to say?
It's a mistake.
It's a lethal mistake.
It's really bad.
It that what I ate
at lunchtime?
Yeah.
Oh, .
This is gross.
That's horrible.
It's disgusting.
I've been feeling a little bit
crap all afternoon.
What are you two doing?
I up.
"I up."
Well, what do you
want me to say?
I want you to step up
to the plate and be a man.
I screwed up.
You haven't told
anyone yet.
He was just being a jerk.
He was an ass.
I am so tired of him
just pushing and pushing.
Grow some balls
and take it off the menu.
I've had enough.
I'm so pissed!
I can only take so much
before I fight back.
Jim, Jim, Jim!
Out of the way.
It's an hour
into dinner service...
Oh, God almighty.
And Chef Ramsay has just
discovered a lethal mistake--
spoiled chicken at Capri.
You'll
kill somebody.
What am I supposed to say?
Take it off  the menu.
Jim, Jim.
Out of the way.
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to certain circumstance,
we have no chicken tonight.
Oh...
My apology
to everyone here.
If you just want to have
what you're eating now
and leave,
I understand fully,
and I apologize.
Hey, there may have been a more
subtle way of doing that.
Get out of my way.
is the matter with you?
When we canceled all our chicken
orders, we got screwed.
Will you stop acting like a baby?
Oh, blow it out your .
Excuse me?
You heard it.
Hey, need diaper
changing?
I'll give you something--
is it that time of night?
Is there a little
poo-poo in your pants?
He's the baby. He's the one
that's whining over everything.
I don't need
to hear this crap.
Jim, why do you have
to behave like this?
I'm not gonna get yelled at.
You're walking around like a big baby,
and I'm just asking you
to grow up a little bit,
show a little bit of respect
for what you're trying to cook.
off.
Oh, my God.
You big, wet noodle.
Do you want a blanket
and a bottle?
Do you need one?
Upside the head?
Jim, stop it, please.
Oh, my God.
What a spoiled brat.
you.
Jim, shut up, please.
You're not helping the cause.
Oh, my God.
Now you're setting
yourself on fire.
I hope so.
Oh, yeah. They don't
get their way, they cry,
or throw a temper tantrum.
Oh, my God.
To walk into the dining room
like that and scream...
That's what I said--
temper tantrum.
There's a part of me
that is very satisfied
to see the boys finally get
what they deserve--
a lesson in humility.
Okay, where are you at now?
I don't know!
Let me go check
on that for you.
Can I pass you this? They've
been here since we opened,
and they haven't
got their food yet.
Jim, some of the tables
have been waiting
two hours out there.
I know.
Well, you don't even
seem to be bothered.
I am bothered.
You know, there's only three
tables you served entrees.
Come on, guys,
just show a little bit
more enthusiasm, surely.
No, it doesn't look good.
Damn it.
This can't be happening.
It's just like a bad nightmare.
Let's drink our wine
and go.
Window wants to walk.
Cancel window.
Customers were not happy.
Some got tired of waiting and
left. It was very disappointing.
It was a bad night.
Our dishes took longer
than usual.
It was just
an embarrassing night.
Okay, today could be
summed up in one
4-letter word.
Lazy.
I can't even start
to help both of you when
you're not helping yourselves.
I really need you
to do something.
Both of you go through
your kitchen,
and clean it.
Not your staff.
You. Both of you.
Got it?
Yep.
Good night.
Night.
Get to work.
We were lazy.
Now we're paying for it.
We're failures.
Yay.
What's wrong, Jim?
I feel bad.
We are in trouble. I really
don't know if we can fix it.
That's the problem.
Go take a break, Jim.
I gotta clean this.
After the twins spend
most of the night cleaning,
Chef Ramsay arrives early,
and with the help
of longtime waitress Colleen
and pizza maker Darian,
he does something
the twins have never done--
open for lunch.
Okay, Darian...
Yes, sir?
It's gonna be fast,
and it's gonna be furious,
but you can do it, okay?
I'm game for this.
How you doin'?
Come in and have
some lunch.
Thank you.
I would like
the lasagna, please.
Pizza, up.
Lasagna up.
Lasagna. Enjoy.
This is delicious.
Mmm, this is really good.
Yeah?
Look at that.
We got a sign twirler.
"Now open for lunch."
Oh, cool.
What's going on here?
Oh, cool. Oh, wow.
I can't believe
this is happening.
Wow. This is our place?
All right, welcome.
Hi.
Thanks for making it today.
Thank you.
All right, take a seat.
Feeling a bit peckish?
Yeah.
Yeah? Let me get you a nice
little chopped salad.
This is different.
Let's start off with
a little chopped salad.
Thank you.
And make sure you save
some room
for an Italian sausage
lasagna
and a very simple,
um, margherita pizza.
Thank you.
It's a good pizza.
I like it.
Thank you.
Okay,
whilst you two were at home
nice and cozy,
I got here early this morning
with Darian and Colleen.
I think today we put over $300
in the cash register.
Wow.
Yeah.
$300--if you do that
5 times a week,
that's $1,500.
That's almost our rent,
so it's a lot of money.
Talk to me.
I'm just...
Very happy.
Jeff, I had my eyes shut,
and that was wrong.
I sat on my butt,
being lazy.
You can't have your butt stuck
to your bed every morning.
You've gotta get out
and--and break the mold.
Message understood,
loud and clear?
Yep.
Loud and clear.
After finally getting through
to the twins
about their laziness,
Chef Ramsay wants to dig
a little deeper.
He has an unorthodox plan
that will allow the brothers
to work out their issues
and their frustrations.
Time to let go
of the past,
and to embrace
the future.
Gloves on.
I'm not gonna be fighting
Chef Ramsay, am I?
I want to know
what's holding you back.
One, two.
Oh, for God's sake.
What is that?
Two--what is that?
I don't work out.
This is like starting
an old car
after a year sitting there,
it's gonna go...
Fart out a little bit.
Come on.
What pisses you off the most?
What is it?
Myself.
Why?
Huh?
'Cause I'm lazy.
When was the last time
you did something
100%?
I can't remember.
What are you afraid of?
Tell me.
Screwing up.
Damn it.
It's just screwing up.
I've done it
all my life.
I'm a failure.
You're not a failure.
Yes, I am.
You are not.
We all make mistakes
in life.
Embrace change.
Are you keen
to make this business work?
Yeah.
It's time.
I'm ready to move on,
to make a success
out of this.
Okay, last ten.
Let's go.
And again. And again.
Come on, come on.
Hit it.
Stop kissing it, come on.
Come on.
And again.
Ready to change?
Yes.
Good man.
Yeah.
Get the
out of here.
I know I'm gonna put behind me
all the laziness,
and look towards the future and
the successes that are coming.
Jeff, let's go.
Good, good, nice.
It feels good
to just let out
a whole bunch of
that I've been hanging on to.
Nice, nice, nice.
Take a breather.
Good, wow. What does this
restaurant mean for you?
A life, a career.
And you think that by sitting
on your lazy ass all day long
and turning up halfway through
the day is gonna make it work?
You need to commit.
Good. You, in here.
Let's go.
I don't want any head shots,
just one round,
and tell each other
it's time to work.
Let's go.
We can work together.
And we can be successful. We
just gotta talk to each other,
not keep anything inside.
Yeah.
Five, four, three,
two, one.
And stop. Well done.
Give him a hug.
Boxing each other,
uh, was a good exercise,
'cause it--
it cleared the air,
and it showed me that
it's time for me
to work hard for the business
for both of us.
Okay, good.
It's time for change.
Got it?
Got it.
Are you ready?
Ready.
Good.
Get cleaned up,
and meet me back
at the restaurant.
Satisfied that the twins
are ready to make some changes
within themselves...
Okay, how are you
feeling?
Good.
Chef Ramsay now wants
to focus on something else
that needs a major change--
the food.
When was the last time
you made a meatball?
Probably five years ago.
Okay, and why did you stop?
It was easier.
Lazy!
Oops.
Let's make a meatball together.
Okay.
It's been a long time
since we've made meatballs,
but I'm ready to do this.
I am a professional.
Right.
Ground beef,
season, yeah,
salt and pepper, garlic,
handful of chili flakes.
Chef Ramsay is a magician
in the kitchen.
Oh, you just add this and this
and this, and it's just like...
Jeff...
Yes?
How big do you like your balls?
Uh,
pretty good size,
I mean, you know...
Golf ball size?
What?
All right,
have a little taste.
What did you think?
It's good. I like it a lot.
Can you do that?
Yes.
Can you do that
if he needs help?
Yes.
Homemade meatballs.
The difference
is night and day.
Homemade!
Homemade.
Can't hear you.
Homemade!
It's homemade meatballs!
Get outside and shout it
in the street.
Homemade meatballs!
Tell them in the neighborhood.
We have
homemade meatballs!
I can't hear you.
We have
homemade meatballs!
Finally.
Stop, we have
homemade meatballs!
We have homemade
meatballs!
Everybody, we have
homemade meatballs!
Faced with a restaurant
that hasn't been touched
since 1963,
Chef Ramsay and his team
work overnight
to give this restaurant
one of the biggest makeovers
in Kitchen Nightmare's
history.
Right, good morning.
Good morning.
You are in for a big shock.
Are you ready
to see the new Capri?
Yes.
Good. On the count
of three--
one,
two--don't peek...
Three.
Oh, wow.
Oh, my God.
Wow.
This is nice.
Just have a look.
We have brought the Capri
from 1963,
fast forward it,
transformed it to 2011.
That's beautiful.
Look at it.
Cool, hip.
Oh, man.
This place
is gonna be hoppin'.
This is nice.
Oh, wow.
Gone is the carpet
that was stuck
together with tape.
You have the most amazing
reclaimed woods
lining the walls.
Look it.
Yeah, that's right.
We had to put you
on the wall as well.
Colleen, what do you think?
It's...
Isn't it amazing?
It's amazing.
We got rid of those
hideous green booths.
You have the most amazing
tailor-made,
cut pews as benches
from your local church.
Oh, wow.
Sit down in the pew.
Are you happy?
Yeah.
Like a pig in .
Yeah! Whoo-hoo.
It's great.
Colleen.
Yes, sir?
Come forward, darling,
and bring those menus
from the pocket there.
Oh, my goodness.
Gone are the dirty
plastic menus.
Look it.
Designed on what your kitchen
is capable of producing.
So now it's time to stop
ignoring the business,
and run the business.
Okay.
Yeah? I get nervous
when you don't talk.
Huh?
He's--
he's totally stunned.
Come on.
Just amazing.
It really is.
I've never heard you
this quiet.
I don't have
anything--
what's the matter?
Just amazing.
I'm in shock.
I never thought it could
look so different.
This is beyond what I could
ever think could happen.
It's amazing.
Wow. We're moving up,
and it's exciting.
It's a second chance
on life.
This is gonna be the coolest
place in Eagle Rock now.
Exactly that.
Right. Come through, please.
Look at this stuff.
Oh, my God.
Let's start off with
meatballs al forno, yes?
What are they?
Homemade
meatballs!
Homemade meatballs.
Okay, sellers for the table,
welcome an Italian
chopped salad.
Yay.
For me, the hallmark--
the pizza. The margherita.
Classic eggplant parm pie.
Delicious,
and just gives
a completely different twist.
Now entrees--
baked meat lasagna.
One of my favorites, yeah.
Mmm.
Baked herb chicken
with fingerling potatoes
and a white wine sauce.
Jim?
I like it, a lot.
That's Jeff.
It's cool. I'm Jeff.
That's Jim.
Right, a little taste?
Yes.
Jump in.
All right.
Oh, the broccoli
is so good.
The food looks unbelievable,
and it even tastes better.
It's excellent.
The eggplant
is amazing.
I'm starting
to get full already,
and I haven't tasted
half the stuff.
Excuse me.
Welcome!
Put you right
over here, please.
Word of Capri's relaunch
has spread through
Eagle Rock...
We have a new menu.
We have great salads
and appetizers to start with.
And the dining room
fills up quickly
with customers eager to try
the new menu.
You wanna do
the Mac and cheese?
Boneless chicken wings.
I'll go grab that
and come back.
Thank you.
All right, let's go.
Here you go, Jim.
Medium margherita pizza
and a baked chicken.
Okay.
And I want you to call it out
like a chef/owner.
Okay, I got two--
what is that?
Pot-potato skins,
two wings.
Yes, sir.
How you doin', Jim?
I'm nervous, but I have
to believe that I am in charge,
and I know what I'm doing.
Own it, own it,
own it, own it, yeah?
Yeah.
Gonna leak from the top,
buddy.
In spite of Jim's nerves...
Table five is ready.
Pick it up, please!
Food is quickly making its way
out to the diners.
Not hot enough.
Perhaps a little
too quickly.
me.
Listen, guys. Guys,
the chicken's not hot enough,
especially inside there.
Get it in the oven,
get the pan hot first.
Jim I think was starting
to really get a little panicky.
Jim, give me a time
on the chicken, please.
I-I-I got the chicken
in--in the--
what's in the pan and stuff,
it's heating up.
Jim, bounce back.
Yep.
It's not a race. Customers
will wait for good food.
Hot food in the window.
I'm dragging
the meatballs.
Here's spaghetti
meatball.
Yeah. Is that how
I showed you
to plate a
spaghetti meatball?
No.
It looks like someone
on my plate.
Damn it, Jim.
It's like, come on.
It's so easy.
Just on.
And you're more than capable
of doing that, I'm telling you.
It's not rocket science.
you can't even
grate cheese.
No, no. Stop panicking,
and focus!
I'm panicking right now, 'cause
we want to get food out quick.
But it's like,
hey, don't screw this up.
Uh...
It's an hour into service...
And Jim is struggling
to keep up with the orders.
Jim, how much longer
on my table four?
It's coming up right now.
Unfortunately, a relaunch
that had such promise...
They--did you really?
I did not see them.
Yes.
Looks like it's slipping away.
Your chicken's coming also.
Jim, look at me. What table
number is that for?
16 is--Darian,
you cutting it right now?
I got a mushroom
and a meat lover.
Put it right up.
Okay.
This is going to 16.
They haven't even
got their appetizers.
Oh, for sake.
God darn it.
Oh, come on. Come in, you.
Come here, both of you.
I need you for 30 seconds,
out of all this .
Oh, . Oh, man,
we're doing this again.
I thought we got through this.
Please don't let this
be the end.
No, no, no,
no, no, no. that.
It's relaunch night at Capri,
and with the kitchen
backed up...
Jim, give me a time
on the chicken, please.
The chicken in--in the--
what's in the pan and stuff,
it's heating up.
And diners waiting
over an hour for food...
Come here, both of you.
Chef Ramsay  has seen enough.
No, no, no, no. that.
Look at me. Look at me.
Right now you're making
yourselves look stupid.
Right.
It's a big night tonight.
Yes.
And you're pissing it up.
So please listen to me,
you have to command
your kitchen.
Yes.
You have to work together.
But it's not a race.
The customers are gonna
wait for good food.
Stop panicking,
and focus, okay?
Yes.
Come on!
Chef Ramsay is like,
"what the is this?
How could"...
And I go, ugh.
We slip back into our old ways
of doing it,
and it's like,
you gotta change.
This is a new Capri.
I need an order of garlic knots
and pepperoni and cheese.
Yes, sir!
Go help him.
I'll take care of this.
Got it.
It's time that I grew up.
It's time that I start working
as a man and not as a butthead.
Sausage and bean.
Put some cheese on it.
I put beans on this, right?
Yeah--oregano.
Oregano.
Okay, Jim, now we're
getting a system.
Conviction, yes?
Yep.
What's next?
16.
Good.
I got hot food up here.
Please serve it.
Once we started hitting
our rhythm, it was great.
'Cause things
were going out.
Excuse me.
We settled down,
and we got it zooming along.
How we doing?
So good.
The meatballs
are our favorite thing.
This is really good, though.
It's delicious.
This is made from scratch,
you can tell.
This is so amazing.
It's been one hell
of a roller coaster ride,
but we've learned a lot
from Chef Ramsay,
and he's left us with a lot
of inspiration and hope.
I can see that we will make it
if we keep doing
what we're doing.
Jim,
Jeff,
you've come a long way.
It's been a tough journey.
Yes.
And in order for this place
to continue functioning,
you both must
work at it.
Yes.
Don't clutter.
Show up early.
Yes.
Lazy is a 4-letter word.
Good.
God bless you both.
Thank you so much.
Okay?
Yeah, thank you very much.
Good luck.
We've went through a lot
to get--
you know, to get the nightmare
into a-a dream.
It's still
a learning process,
but the future
looks really good.
The Capri is gonna work.
Good luck.
God, honestly,
I'm never gonna forget
the twins in Eagle Rock,
let me tell you that.
Thank you.
Good night.
Thank you very much.
Jeez.
Yes.
Wow. That was hard.
I mean, really hard,
but I now really believe
that both Jim and Jeff
and their little restaurant can
become a huge tourist attraction
here in Eagle Rock.
Now come on--
who doesn't love a pizza
and a show?
Oh...
That was hard.
Man.
Just one month after
Chef Ramsay's departure...
Can I take a picture
of you two with Jen?
You sure can.
The twins kept their promise,
and opened for lunch.
It's excellent.
It's really good.
The new food and décor
have made Capri
a hot spot
in Eagle Rock.
Come back again, we're gonna
keep this going now.
This has been
a life-changing experience.
Thank you very much,
Chef Ramsay,
for what you did for us.
I think
it's gonna work.
It's gonna work.
By the way, we have
homemade meatballs! Yeah!
-- sync, corrected  by elderman --
Next time on kitchen
nightmares...
Chef Ramsay
heads across the bayou
where the current owners
have alienated the community.
That's just terrible.
This husband and wife team
seems to be
only focused
on the bottom line.
We're looking for financial
rewards in this business.
Chef Ramsay faces
the most deluded owners
he's ever yet.
Restaurants don't run
like this.
Disagree.
I disagree
with that also.
will they change their ways?
We are talked down to.
You are not
a restaurateur.
find out next time
on Kitchen Nightmares.