- Hey.
- Yes?
Erm, I'm looking for a job.
- Who do I see?
- Oh, ho, you're out of luck, chum.
- Who's won, mate?
- It's on now.
I heard you needed drivers,
for ballast.
- You a ballast driver?
- I'm any kind of a driver.
What difference does it make?
That block, first door,
ask for Cartley.
Ah, thanks a lot.
Must be hungry.
Thanks Terry,
bung it down anywhere.
Lovely work, Jackie boy,
Lucy loves you.
Oh, you're not Terry.
Huh, sorry.
See you later, Jackie.
Thought you were the boy
who's mending my typewriter.
I'm looking for Mr Cartley..?
- Is he expecting you?
- I'm looking for a job.
Hmmm! You'll be lucky.
My name's Yately,
Joe Yately, er...
...I met a character called Legubin.
Oh, you know Leggy.
How is he?
They've put a silver plate
in his skull.
So I, I thought there might
be a job going up here.
Why, to get a silver
plate put in your skull?
Leggy said there was
good money up here.
Well...
...I'll see what I can do for you.
Yes?
I heard you needed
ballast drivers.
You met Legubin,
is that right?
Yeah.
Did he tell you how much he
cost us in compensation?
He couldn't handle the loads,
not at the speeds we wanted.
How long have you
been driving?
- Twelve years.
- Many accidents?
- No.
- You sure?
- Now, look, I told you.
- Licence.
Hm. No endorsements, no
convictions for speeding - why not?
Huh. I guess I was
never caught.
Name and address of
your last employer.
I've been out of the country.
Where?
Around.
I want fast drivers.
Fifty miles an hour touched,
right round the clock.
- What kind of roads?
- Bad roads.
Wet or fine.
- What about the speed limit?
- That's up to you.
If you're caught you
pay your own fine.
So if you don't think you can
handle ten tonnes at that speed,
- ...just say so.
- What's the money?
We work a bonus system here.
You get seven shillings a load,
plus four shillings an hour.
- Over what distances?
- Ten miles each way.
Twelve loads a day, minimum.
Anything under, you're fired.
That's a pretty rough
pace, isn't it?
We've got one man that
does eighteen runs a day.
- And what about breakdowns?
- You maintain your own lorry at night.
If you have a breakdown,
it's your fault.
And, ah, we like you to
keep your vehicle clean.
There's a bonus each week
for the best-looking truck.
If you've got one left.
You don't like the idea?
I like the money.
An itchy palm doesn't
make a good driver.
It needs guts, confidence.
You don't inspire me.
You're looking for a sucker,
aren't you, Mr Cartley?
- Lucy.
- Yes, Mr Cartley?
Phone the shop, tell him to
bring round a spare truck.
- The usual test run.
- Yes, Mr Cartley.
Right.
You'd better not be wasting
my time, that's all.
Ed, the usual.
Once over the run.
Roger.
Here, you'll want these.
You've driven one of
this kind before?
I said have you ever
driven one of these before?
Yeah. I've been out of
circulation for a little while.
Ah.
Hop in, then.
What have you been driving?
- Oh, this and that.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, take a tip. These trucks,
they're light on the trigger.
You don't have to fight
'em, the way you're doing.
Loosen up a bit.
Good.
Now, here's a corner.
Now, don't check.
Let her run into it.
- We're going too fast.
- No, we're not, we're going dandy.
Step on it,
boost her round.
Well, let her swing,
let her go.
There, see?
The brakes don't work, didn't
you see? They failed on me.
Well, we stopped
didn't we?
Yeah, maybe they
need pulling up a bit.
Go on, back up,
I'll guide you.
Go on.
Back now, straight on.
Left a bit.
Now straighten up.
Pull left.
Great.
Oh, your face,
all them cows!
Yeah, well, I forgot
about the brakes..!
Wooh.
Now, you see, we get the
stock from that pit field.
You bring it round on this belt,
up to the ballast office.
This is the three-eight,
half-inch model.
This is the quarter-inch gravel.
It's the gravel we use.
- You know how to work it?
- No.
Now, get up there
and level it off.
The cops like it that way.
Blimey, they've let you
out today, have they, Ed?
Aye, doctor's orders.
Ah, keep your tail
down, come on.
Okay.
From now on it's the run.
I'm timing you.
Give her the gun.
Doesn't come round so friendly
now she's loaded, does she?
You gotta keep that
needle north of thirty.
Every mile you get
above that...
...you can reckon on another
sixpence an hour.
Drop below it and
you're out of a job.
Savvy?
Don't ease up.
Suppose we meet something?
Supposing we don't?
Look on the bright side.
Now, keep straight on.
Let the road look after itself.
Good for you.
Phew.
Red chasing Johnny.
Well, you didn't have to stop.
Come on, get moving.
We're losing time.
We've got a long way
to go yet.
What's the matter?
Who says anything's
the matter?
Oh, you're improving.
Now, here we are.
You've made it.
Wasn't bad, was it?
Oi! Okay, tip 'er.
Nudge 'er forward a bit.
How did I do?
So so.
Didn't get it, eh?
Come on, come on.
Wooh.
What happens now?
Home.
- Ah, well, you drive.
- Me? I can't.
The police took away
me licence.
Hey. Come here.
Lucy. Come here.
Bye bye.
Lets have another look
at that licence.
Yes, Mr Cartley.
Truck thirteen,
make out a log book.
Yes, Mr Cartley.
When do I start?
Ye...
LUCY!
Start him tomorrow.
Cards, particulars,
next of kin. Look after him.
Yes, Mr Cartley.
- Thanks.
- Well, aren't you the lucky one?
Fitter had me worried.
Ed? Oh, you needn't have.
I put in a good word for yer.
Yeah?
What did you say?
Oh, I said you were a...
friend of mine.
Why should you do that?
Do you always know
why you do things?
Huh.
Yately, Joseph.
Same address?
No.
I'm in between addresses now.
That's yours.
You've got Leggy's old truck.
Number thirteen.
For luck.
Got your cards with you?
No, I...
I've been away.
I lost them.
Does Cartley know that?
No.
Well, we won't tell him.
He's got a suspicious mind.
I'll try and get you
some new ones.
- Thanks.
- Got anywhere to sleep?
- No.
- Ask at the gate for Ma West.
All the boys stay there.
I'll do that.
Oh, by the way, there's a pull-in
across the street where they eat.
- Yeah? Oh.
- Of course...
...you might get to know some
nice local girl...
...and get invited for supper.
Do you like home cooking?
Well, yeah, if it's good.
If I cook it, it's good.
Bye, Joe.
Ah.
I know this might
sound funny, but, er...
...everybody calls me Tom.
Bye, Lucy.
So long, Tom.
Pull!
D'oh!
No, no!
Who's that fiddling
with the letterbox?
Come in or stay out,
I don't care which.
I just can't pull any harder!
Oh!
I'm in the kitchen.
Oh, you couldn't
pull your own shoelaces together.
Hullo, who are you?
Never mind, come in and
make yourself useful.
Oh, Jill, go away, you're
not strong enough.
This needs a man's hand.
Come on, young fella.
Let's see how strong you are.
Well, they told me I
could get a room here.
First things first, here, get
hold of these and pull.
- Okay.
- Go on. All right.
Nnn'uh!
Tighter!
Come on, you
won't hurt me!
Egh! Oh!
That's it. Oh,
that's it.
Steel, these are, young fella.
Supports me spine.
Had an accident.
How long do you
want the room for?
Oh, quite a while, I've got
a job over the road.
Good enough.
Thank your mother
for the groceries.
Okay, Ma.
Come on, then.
I'll show you upstairs.
That's the kitchen.
When I'm out,
the door's locked.
Front door's locked
at midnight.
If you're out after that,
you stay out.
That's me husband.
Died in a fire
twenty years ago.
Hum.
There's the bath.
That's the other place.
No scribbling.
Meals you eat out.
There's a pull-in over the way,
most of the men go there.
You can have this one.
Good enough for yer?
Yeah, how much?
Three shillings a night.
Sixpence a bath.
Money in advance.
Okay.
Good.
Any clothes you want boiling,
there's a basket in the bathroom.
I do 'em meself.
Thruppence an article.
Thank you, Mrs West.
Call me Ma.
Okay, Ma.
What do I call you?
Tom.
All right then, Tom.
See that you wash the
bath out when you finish.
Okay.
You own me ten from yesterday!
Let me go or I'll lamp you one!
- Hands off, will yer?!
- You won't get away with it, Scottie.
Now, this is your lot.
Knock it off, will yer?
- Hey, look at...
- Blimey!
Ma, she's gonna hit the
roof when she sees this.
- Ah, Tinker, what you got there?
- What's it look like?
- A mess.
- I've been after this for a month
- Now I got it.
- You can have it.
- No, you don't, I'm first.
- That's what you think.
You're a first class
driver. Oh...!
Here! Here, where d'you
think you're going?
It's ours! Put that name to
the bottom of the list.
- You fixed it, didn't yer?
What d'you mean, me?
- Come on.
- Come on, yer dirty bastard.
- Get outta there.
Come on.
STOP THAT,
DO YOU HEAR ME?!
Go take a flying jum...!
What did you say?
Not you, Ma, I was...
...talking to these tearaways.
Disturbing a gentleman
in his bath.
- Get out of it.
- Come on, you two!
Get upstairs to your rooms.
Kick my door and
I'll kick you.
What are those?
I gotta beautiful flowers,
for a beautiful lady.
Ah, thank you Gino.
- Got 'em cheap too.
- Only gentleman among the lot of yer.
- Thank you, Gino.
- Don't mention it.
- I'll go and put them in some water.
Yeah, do that.
Quick.
AND STOP THAT NOISE UP THERE!
- This place is a loony bin.
- Sure.
Where else you
put crazy people?
- Who is it?
- It's okay.
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
This is my room.
Ah, mama mia!
You give a me a fright! Heh!
- You just arrive, huh?
- Yeah.
You're beaten.
I come in.
You lie there.
You say nothing.
You, uh, have
a good laugh, huh?
No.
You know, there is so
much noise.
You hear the noise, ah?
This room is empty.
I use her for, ah...
...like a church.
You know?
Ah. You want to know I should
move these these things.
Oh, that's okay.
Come in when you like.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Thank you.
Is better in here for me.
Some people
do not understand.
They make a joke, ah?
I don't mind, but, uh...
...thank you.
Uh, are you driver with us?
Yeah, starting tomorrow.
What truck they gave you?
Number thirteen.
Legubin's.
Thirteen.
Not so good.
You know, you also
have Legubin's room?
Yeah?
How not? Ha, listen...
...the shell, the shell, ah, she
never fall in the same place twice.
No, you got a very
good situation here.
- Ah, what are you called?
- Tom.
To all the boys,
I am Gino.
Because I'm Italian, you know?
But my real name is Manuelo
Leggy, Legubin...
...he was, ah, my...
my special friend.
You have friends here?
No.
No, thanks.
You have met Red?
No, I haven't met anyone.
He's the boss.
What we call the pace-setter,
he drive like the Devil. Marvellous.
He's got truck number one.
When you see him coming you keep
to the side, that is all I tell you, ah?
Yeah, I passed him
on the trial run.
He was going like he'd been fired
from a rocket or something.
That is the one.
I'm glad that you have seen him.
Oh, our Red.
He's a special friend
of yours, too?
I hate the sight of him.
Come over to eat.
Yeah, in the pull-in
over the road?
Yeah, that's right.
Girl in the office told me.
Ah, that is Lucy. Huh.
Funny girl, Lucy.
The boys like to make out
she's, ah, what you call it, erm...
...a hot number.
You mean she's not?
Ah, Lucy's like plenty people.
Got to make a big
impression, you know?
Because, er, inside
they are, erm...
...they're lonely.
That is the trouble with girls today.
All the time they must, ah...
...fight for something.
Fight, fight.
You don't like her, huh?
I love her.
She is my girl.
Come over.
Yeah.
Okay, come on.
And I tell you something
very special.
Lucy, she don't know yet,
but when I go back to Italy...
...she is going to
come with me.
We're going to have
our own bambini.
During the war I am prisoner
here, and, uh, I like England...
...I think then I stay forever.
But now, ah, I think different.
Bella Italia is all I want.
That and Lucy.
Small place of my own.
The sunlight,
the blue sky.
Ah, the blue sky, eh? Ah..!
You think she'd
go with you?
I pray she will, caro.
I pray she will.
- Ah, go on!
- Get it in there, then.
Wait for it!
YES!
Come on, now.
I'm gonna stop playing.
Ignore him.
Come on.
- One and nine, you owe me.
Come on, boys...
- Grab a chair.
- I'll get us some matches.
Hello. New one, come
to join us, have you?
- Yup.
- What's the handle?
- Tom.
- Oh, mine's Dusty.
- There's Tinker.
- Stinker.
- Watch it!
- Father Joe.
- Yeah, beautiful bonce.
- Ya, ha, ha!
- Come on, Pop, wake up.
- What's up?
- Pop, meet Tom.
- Hello, there.
- Scottie.
- Hi, Tom, there's a seat goin' over here.
- You can sit next to me.
- Ah, no no...
...you can't do that to
the guest of honour.
- You're gonna sit right next to me.
- Yes, you sit here, Tom.
Hey, Dusty.
The new one always
get the 'ead of the table.
- You blab, I'll break yer neck.
- You go on.
Look, he's gotta learn
sometime ain't he?
This our little Jill,
our little darling.
Aye, treat her good and
you get double portions.
Big enough to look
after his self.
Maybe you're right.
Uh, my name's Tub.
Where you from, mate?
Around.
That's up North
somewhere, innit?
Go on, can't you tell a good
Welshman when you hear one?
Cardiff, innit, mate?
Near there.
A place called Blaenllechau.
Oh, that a horrible disease.
Nah, he's got the hiccups.
Give 'im some water.
So you're gonna join
the 'ell drivers, are yer?
He's a crack driver,
I tell you.
- He's come to take Red's place.
- Ya, ha, ha, ha!
Have you, have you got
your coffin ordered, mate?
Yeah, what made you decide
to put an end to it all, eh?
He's after the money.
He's saving for the blind.
- Hey, Red.
- Red!
The er, water's getting cold.
One of the very best.
Th-there's no need
to start anything, Red.
I'll get him to move.
Red.
Give us it over 'ere,
Johnny. As it comes?
- Yeah.
- Nice and warm?
Gino.
Er, your cigar's gone out.
My place.
If you think you're good
enough to sit in my place.
You have to prove it...
...uh?
Yeah.
He's as brave as
the rest of yer.
Thought you were gonna see
somethin' then, didn't you? Ah?
Who's the Girl Guide, anyway?
- He's the new driver.
- What truck's he got?
I don't know.
Hey, Tom.
What truck you got?
- He's got Legubin's truck.
- Who asked yer, spaghetti?
Nobody asked, but I
tell you anyhow.
Hah, I get it.
Him and you's pals, eh?
Well, just watch he doesn't get in
me way out on the run, that's all.
Aye, ah.
Who gets it?
I done eighteen runs.
Who beats me?
Don't look at me,
thirteen's my lot.
Minimum twelve.
No, chicken done it.
Fifteen, me. You're still safe.
- Fourteen.
- Twelve.
Lucky to get that.
Me pressure pump's up the spout.
- Fifteen.
- Ah, stinking fourteen.
Hey, Pop, you passed me
about a dozen times today.
How many runs did you do?
Look at him. Blind, deaf,
and twice a granddad.
- Hey, Pop.
- Hm?
How many
runs d'you do?
- Oh, um, seventeen.
- Seven...?!
- Hello.
- Er, Red you ain't gonna keep...
...that thing much longer.
Is gold, that case.
Here, let the new boy
have a look at it.
Look at that, ain't
that marvellous?
Feel the weight of it.
Solid gold.
Ain't that a beaut?
Do more runs that Red
in a day and she's yours.
He's the pace-setter, see?
He keeps us on the ball.
That's solid twenty-two
carat gold.
Worth two hundred
and fifty quid.
Oh, two hundred
Just think what you
could do with that!
Eh, boys, Red's overslept!
It's anybody's case today!
- Come on!
- Lets go!
Get off there.
COME ON, GET BACK!
- What's going on over there?
- Oh, Pop's trying to beat Red's time.
Fine chance he's got.
What's he wanna give way for?
If he don't, he'll have
his front stove in...
...an' he'll be off the road
for two days.
HEY, RED!
'URRY UP. THE SUN'S
FADING ME PAINTWORK.
Hey, Tom.
Where you been?
I look for you, you
are not in to supper.
Ah, I'm working on a
sick truck.
Jill, you got some
sandwiches for me and Ed?
I'll see what there is.
'Ey, Tom...
...two guys come
looking for you.
In a car. They go away.
- Me?
- Yah, at Ma West's.
Who were they?
What'd they look like?
I don't know.
I don't see them.
Ma West yell upstairs.
But you are not there.
I see them drive away in
a big car, from the window.
Gino, you doing anything tonight?
I wait for Lucy now.
Take her to see the Italian
picture at the Playhouse.
Why, ah, you like perhaps I
should do something for you?
No, it's okay.
- You tell me what you...
- No, it's okay.
Do you know Chick Keithley?
- Hi.
Gino, anybody get
the case today?
The case? Ha, ha.
Fat chance.
That's all I wanna know.
Now, listen, Tom.
This is crazy.
I see you try to
beat Red today.
Don't do it.
You listen to me.
Don't try it.
So long as he uses a short
cut, it's not possible.
Short cut?
Why don't we all use it?
Because we are not pazzo
like Red, that's why.
- You know the quarry, ah?
- Yeah.
Is very dangerous to
drive fast there.
If you drive slow, is no
longer a short cut.
Is a long cut, hah!
- Well, have you tried it?
- Yah, we all try.
Leggy tried.
He was the last.
We don't go there no more.
I see.
But Red only drives a
truck, just like you and me.
- Here you are, Tom.
- Ah, thanks.
Ham and cheese.
We've got some chicken in
the refrigerator, if you'd like.
- No, this is fine.
- No coffee?
- No. Bye.
- Goodnight, Tom.
- Tom.
- Yeah?
Don't try it, ah?
You listen to Gino.
Jill, you falling for
that guy or somethin'?
I never saw you smile so
sweet since we met.
Well, well, where've
you been, on a picnic?
Yeah. We, er, we
had champagne.
Well, just fancy.
There was I thinking of
inviting you for supper.
Thanks.
Yeah, well, I've got to
get back to work.
Work? This time
of the night?
You act as if you're running away
from a wife or something.
I'm working on a truck.
There doesn't always have
to be a woman in it.
Well, it's usually either
that or money, isn't it?
Is it?
Of course I may be wrong,
and I'm willing to learn.
Why don't you get in and
tell me all about it?
I just love life stories.
Gino's waiting for you
in there, remember?
You think I'm flinging myself
at you, don't you?
You're giving a pretty
fair imitation.
What else is wrong with me?
You wanna know?
Yeah.
- Hi, muscles.
- Hi, Lucy.
Hello, boys.
- Yeah, were are you going?
- Hey, Lucy.
Tom. What are you
doing here?
Lucy, we got to hurry, or
we miss the picture.
Hey, you want to knock off
and come with us?
- Lucy won't mind.
- No, I haven't finished the truck.
- Ah.
- Gino.
Ah?
I'm gonna take that
gold cigarette case from Red.
- You can help me.
- Huh, Tom I told you, don't do it.
Red is pazzo, he don't let
anyone take the case.
He's only a... how you say?
A carrot for us donkeys.
And I'm a donkey.
- Tom!
- Gino!
Wait a minute. Tom, how long
you been driving ballast?
- You know how long.
- Let it go.
Red been driving it for twelve
years. He knows all the tricks.
You don't.
So you don't
wanna help me.
Tom.
All right, huh, I'm with you.
But what do you want
me to do?
I'll tell you tomorrow
morning. Thanks, Gino.
Enjoy the picture.
It's like, like, ah, poison in
the blood, this thing.
They all get it.
I will try to see he
don't get hurt.
He's a nice boy, ah?
You like him?
- He's all right.
- Ah, he's my friend.
You must be nice to him.
Ah, carissima,
you look so, ah...
...ah, you look so pretty tonight.
Come, I drive. Move over
Gino, I don't feel like
a film tonight.
Especially one of those
foreign ones.
Oh, no?
Oh, it's too bad.
Is the last night for it.
Huh. I don't get much chance
to, uh, hear my own people talking.
Hey Johnny,
come on, 'urry up.
Where're we going? Huh?
Oh, I don't know.
Let's just go somewhere
and have a drink, huh?
All right.
Whatever you say.
Here, we go and,
uh, we talk, ah?
Ah, you don't know yet, but, er,
I think I got a surprise for you.
About you and me.
Tonight I tell you.
Er, Gino. If you really want to
go and see the picture..?
You change your mind again?
Let's go and see
the picture.
Whatever you say, carissima.
COME ON, HARRY!
- What's your hurry?
- Come on, shake it up.
Anybody'd think you're
fond of work!
Get out of it!
He works very 'ard don't 'e?
Yeah.
- Go ahead, boy.
- Yeah.
Come on!
Get out of it, come on!
Get out of it.
Look at that. Red's gettin'
some of his own medicine.
Ah, he'll never get away
with it.
Hey, Red, how do you
like you're own medicine?
HEY, GINO, GET
OUTTA ME WAY!
That's how it's gonna be, huh?
HEY, GINO!
- Hey, Tom.
- What happened?
It don't matter.
Get on.
- Gino, you all right?
- Ah-ha.
What happened?
Gino, what's the matter...
- ...with your leg?
- Ooh.
Ah, just a shake-up.
It don't matter, I tell you,
get on, go on.
You got a tow chain?
I've got one.
YAH!
Hey, Tom! Get going,
you got to beat him!
Thanks, Fred.
How much is that?
Seventeen shillings,
Miss Lucy. Ah.
Oh-oh, Tom, could
you lend me a...
...couple o' bob until tomorrow?
I'm short.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you very much.
I, uh, I see on the
progress report that...
...you didn't break any
records today.
Ah, Gino went off the
road, I had to help him.
Oh, is he all right?
I guess so. He's gone to bed,
he doesn't feel too good.
Well, does he need anything?
No, I don't think so.
He hurt his leg, got
shaken up.
He wants to sleep it off.
Yeah? That means he won't be
taking me to the dance tonight.
Ah, that's too bad.
Very selfish of him.
Oh, I didn't mean it like that.
In what way did you
mean it?
You know,
you've got a nasty habit.
Yeah, I got lots of them.
Which one are you talking about?
- I could like you if...
- Look...
...nobody's asking you
to like me.
You're Gino's girl.
Ever thought of
asking me that?
Look, Gino's my pal.
You're not pulling this kind of thing
on him, not with me you're not.
Don't talk to me like that!
Gino's my friend, too...
- ...and a good friend, and that's all.
- Well, treat him like one.
Y'know, the way you act anyone'd think
you're the only girl in this town.
I'll give you some fags.
That right, you done
seventeen runs today?
Yeah.
That's pretty close,
eh, Red?
Ah, what about it?
Pop's done better
than that...
...drivin' solo.
If you and spaghetti try any more
of them stop tactics on me...
...I'll show you a thing or two
you haven't even heard about.
The trouble is, when I
teach them, it's the...
...the hard way.
Maybe afterwards you won't
be in any condition to use them.
You understand me?
Yeah, I think so.
Here, where is old
spaghetti, anyway?
He's in bed.
Somebody side-swiped
him today.
That's what you two was doing
in that ploughed field, is it?
Thought you'd
stopped to have a kip.
If you saw us, why didn't you
give us a hand?
Our job's ballast,
not breakdowns.
The recovery people
don't like it, either.
If they heard what
you did today...
...ah, you'd wake up wearing
their footprints.
Why, is somebody gonna
write to them about it?
- What?
- I said is somebody gonna...
All right, I heard yer.
What you tryin' to do, be funny?
D'you know, I don't
like your attitude.
You've got a
chip on your shoulder.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
If I was to knock it off...
...your head might go with it.
Well, I'm the last man who'd
wanna walk around without a head.
Hah?
That's better!
Here, now, get a hold of this,
will yer...
I, I got two jobs here, see?
I'm the pace-setter,
and the road foreman.
That means I'll be watchin'
yer from two directions at once.
To beat yer on the road...
...and to beat yer down,
when you get out of line.
I'm not looking for trouble.
Unless I'm pushed.
Even if you're pushed.
- Hey, Tom!
- Over here, Red.
You going to the dance
tonight, Tom?
Yeah, I was
just gonna ask you.
We're all going in Johnny's car
after you've finished eating.
Do you like my skirt?
Yeah. Sensational.
Jill?
Excuse me.
Hello, Red. You boys gonna
behave yourselves tonight?
Right on, Chas.
- My dance.
- Oh! But I can't.
- Shall we sit this one out?
- Yes, dear.
- You busy?
- Well, I'm waiting for someone.
Then you're not busy.
Excuse me, sonny.
- Remember me last week?
- No.
I'll remind you.
You're not married,
are you?
No. Are you?
Silly. I like you.
You're real dry.
Hey, Dusty. Over 'ere.
Hello, how'd you
make out?
Red. All right.
There's a bird sitting over there,
remember your table manners.
Where are all the seats?
What am I, an orphan?
- All right, here y'are.
- Sit down.
Wo-ho, he's on to us!
- Hey, hey.
- Hey, cut it out.
Fellas, fellas!
Look.
It can't be.
- It is, it's Lucy.
- Done up like a dog's dinner.
- Great Scott!
- Hello, Boys.
- Look at that.
- It's suddenly awfully hot in here.
Where've you been keeping
that dress all our lives, eh?
Mind if I join you?
- Mind?!
- I've been keeping this place...
- ...'specially for you.
- Yeah...
...any fella tries to
takes you away from us...
- ...we'll fix him, won't we, fellas?
- Yeah!
Lucy, you make the rest of the
bunch here look like hyenas!
'Ere, get your
plates of meat off...
- ...get the lady a seat, will yer?
- Call yourself a gentleman?
- Your ladyship!
- Oh! Thanks, Tink.
- Oohh!
- Now look what you've done!
He'll live. I wanna thank you boys
for all calling round to pick me up.
Well, we thought you was
coming with Gino, Lucy.
Jill, do you wanna dance?
Oh, you kids go ahead and
dance. Don't mind poor little me.
- Lucy, Lucy, dance with me!
- No! No!
Get out of it!
Hey, remember me?
Having fun?
Yeah, fine, and you?
So so. There's a big brute
I want to dance with...
...and he won't ask me.
That's too bad.
What are you trying to prove?
That you're somebody's
best friend?
- Now, look...
- Why don't you get it into your...
...thick skull that I'm
not anybody's girl...
...and I'm not married!
Gino's a sweet guy.
He's in a strange country.
I was just trying to be
nice to him.
Do I have to suffer
for that?
If you don't like it,
that's your problem.
I don't want to be the one
that puts him out, that's all.
Come on, let's dance.
Come on.
- Let's dance.
- I'm, I'm waiting for Tom.
On second thoughts,
I think I will.
I just can't imagine what's
happened to my boyfriend.
I sent him for a bottle of coke
about half an hour ago.
P'haps he thought you
said "bucket of coke".
You're very humorous.
Tom.
Don't tell me you don't
feel the same way as I do.
What're you trying to do?
I'm human too, you know.
It's not fair, if two people feel the
same way about each other...
...what's wrong
with admitting it?
I suppose you're the
type who'd like to see...
...two men shooting
it out over you.
Ah!
So long as you win.
Ah, damn. I don't know
what it is.
It's not gonna work, Lucy.
It's got to work.
Are you crazy?
You don't know
anything about me.
I know.
I just love finding out.
I'm not kidding,
this is a nerve test.
- Really?
- A test for steady nerves.
- Oh.
- Steady 'ands.
Ah, you know you'll
never drive a truck if...
- ...you can't hold these like this.
- Oh!
- Here we go.
- Oh, you're not gonna burn me?!
Oh! Careful!
Steady!
Oh.
Now this is where it comes
very important.
You've gotta hold still now.
- Are yer ready?
- Yeah.
"Happy Birthday to you.
- "Happy Birthday to you."
- Oh!
- Where've you been?
- Where've I been?
I was told my old man wanted
to see me in the pub opposite.
- Wasn't he there?
- No, he wasn't.
So I looked in all the
pubs just to make sure.
That's funny.
Must've been some other
Bill I was told to look for.
Yeah, maybe you invented
the whole story...
...so you can
walk off with my girl?
That's right. You've had a
good drink, now insult me.
A man of my position,
taking care of your girl.
You're lucky I didn't
charge her for me time.
Piece-work rates!
- Excuse me.
- Oh, sure.
Oh, no, you don't.
Not this time.
Look, I said "excuse me" once.
Do you mind?
- Drop dead...
- Bill, please.
...somewhere we won't
fall over yer.
I said let go of her.
- She's my girl, and I was...
- Oh, Bill!
- ...dancing with her.
- Now, look, boy.
Steady. This is only
a joke, don't get rough.
Why don't you buzz off?
We let you truck drivers use our hall...
...and all you do is
muck up our evening.
- Yeah..!
- Ask anyone here...
...they'll tell you the
same thing.
We're sick and tired of
the lot of you.
- Hey, Red.
- YEAH?
There's a bloke 'ere says 'im and 'is
mates are sick an' tired of us.
Ah, ask him what
he's gonna do about it.
Hey Tom, Scottie, Johnny.
Come on!
- Yeah.
- Now then, Red, no trouble.
No trouble, please.
Get the police immediately.
- HIT THEM!
- Too late.
- Red, the cops!
- Blow the cops.
You get stuck in.
Come on!
HEY!
Come back, yellow belly!
Come back, you.
Hey!
COME BACK,
YELLOW BELLY!
HEY, YOU.
WE'RE COMIN' UP.
BETTER SAY YOUR PRAYERS.
COME OUT, YOU!
COME OUT, YELLOW!
COME ON, NOW!
Stop that!
Stop that this instant,
do you hear?
- But we all get...
- Red...
- ...come away from that door!
- All right, Ma...
- Here, beat it!
- I don't care what you want.
Now just hold back a bit,
will you.
Get back to your rooms
this minute.
- I'll lay into you with this poker.
- All right.
- Don't worry, we'll be seeing him...
- All right, yellow belly.
...tomorrow.
How many of those
green sweets...
...can you get for a penny?
- Three.
- Ah.
Here, you'll like these.
- BATTERED BRAZILS!
- OH, BOY!
- You've got more than half.
- No, I haven't.
Yes, you have.
Come back, you dirty little rat.
- ...I'll get you for this!
- Ha, ha! That's what you think.
How about a packet of fags?
- On credit.
- Huh!
Tom!
Huh, Tom!
- Oh! Oh, Tom.
- Jim. You all right?
I'm all right.
How are you?
Ah, huh!
Oh, you look marvellous.
We heard you were out.
- Where you been?
- Oh, what do you mean?
- Don't you read my letters?
- Letters?
What letters?
How's Mam?
I, I thought I'd try to get here
while she was in church.
Oh, Tom. Mam wouldn't
keep your letters from me.
Jimmy, the shop looks good.
How's business?
You know this
neighbourhood, Tom.
We've been paying our way.
So far.
Any of the boys still
come round, Jimmy?
Oh, yeah.
For cigarettes, you know.
How are the legs, kid?
Just the same, Tom.
Excuse me, Tom.
Morning, Mrs Lipton,
what'll it be?
Good morning, Jimmy.
I want a pound of sausages.
Myrtle's bringing her
young man to dinner...
...so I've got to make the
Sunday roast stretch a bit!
- Anything else?
- No, thank you.
That'll be three shillings,
please, Mrs Lipton.
Oh dear, up again,
aren't they?
Oh, well, maybe Myrtle'll be
off our 'ands before long.
- Remember me to your mother.
- I will.
- Bye.
- Bye, Mrs Lipton.
Thank you.
How was it...
inside, Tom?
Ah, bad, Jimmy. I can't ever
let that happen to me again.
I can't be tied down.
I know what you mean.
Killed me, Jimmy,
knowing what I did to you.
It was an accident.
I never blamed you.
Yeah.
It's more than just making
it up to you, Jimmy.
I gotta make the grade
for once.
The right way. Do you
know what I mean?
Yeah, I know, Tom.
- I took a job.
- What are you doing?
- Driving.
- Driving again! Huh.
Not what you think.
Listen, Jimmy - it's tough
when you come out.
There's only the lousiest
jobs and no money, and...
...nobody wants you, so...
...well, I took this one.
Well, as long as you're behind
the wheel, you can go anywhere.
- I'm driving ballast, Jimmy.
- Oh..!
It's tough but, well -
it's good money.
There's even a...
...little solid-gold bonus
waiting for me at the end of it.
Jimmy. Look, I want you
to have this.
It's not much, but I've only been
working a couple of weeks.
- No, Tom, I can't take it.
- Take it, will you?
No, please, I...
Hello, Mam.
What's that.
Ma, take it easy. Tom's
just tryin' to help us.
Take it back.
Why should I? It's Jimmy's
money, I gave it to him.
I make the money that
comes into this house.
And I make it honestly, with
the sweat of my brow.
Maybe it's not much,
but what there is, is clean.
Well, this is clean, too.
Oh, look, Mam, we've
got to have a talk.
Nothing you ever touched
was clean.
Ma, Tom's tryin'
to help us.
He's got an honest
job, he's...
- I don't believe it.
- Let him finish.
Will you let him finish?
Look, Mam, you've got
to forget the past.
It's not past!
It's here, all the time.
I live with it.
For you, it was just
a year in jail.
For Jim and me,
it's a life sentence.
Him stuck in the shop all
day, never going out.
I KNOW ALL THAT, MA!
Tom.
Look, Mam. I'm only trying
to put things right.
- How can I make you see?
- I'm not listening.
Tom.
Mam.
Please give him a chance.
You and him.
Always the same.
He led, you followed.
I wish you were still inside.
Oh, Mam, no.
All right, Mam.
I'm gonna have to
draw a picture.
Don't worry, kid.
Maybe it'll work out.
TOM!
TOM.
Well, what're you waiting
for, yellow belly?
All right, boys.
On the road.
Eighteen today.
Who gets it?
- Not me.
- Nah.
Thirteen, I done.
- No good.
- 'Ere, Dust, pass the other one.
You got enough
bread in that?
- Fill this out, Tink.
- Righto, Luce.
G. Redman, eighteen.
Fill this out, Red, please.
Joe Yately, eighteen.
- Eighteen? Aye, aye.
- Yes, he went over the...
...quarry today,
I saw him.
- He's brave.
- Oh, another brave one, eh?
- Hello, Gino.
- Hi.
E. Rossi. Fourteen.
See you tonight.
Miracle. Magnifico.
How you do this thing,
Tom? Is a miracle.
Yeah. It's a miracle
somebody didn't get killed.
Ah, Tom, today you proved to me
that you are a great driver.
I know you can beat Red.
But everybody is against you.
If you had a clear road - erh!
Yeah. If I had a clear road.
Tom. The money,
tomorrow.
I see you get it.
- How.
- We will change plates, ah?
You take my number
plates. It's number three.
I put your number
thirteen on my truck.
Then for me the boys
make all the trouble.
For you there is the
clear road.
You like Gino's idea?
Ah, you, you be number three.
- Yeah, but Gino...
- No buts.
After, finito. Finish here.
You go north, look for a
good job. I go south.
You take the gold
case, I take Lucy. Va bene?
Va bene, pal.
Something stinks around
here, don't it?
Maybe you ought to
change your socks?
- Ah, quick as a whip, ain't we?
- "As a wop", you mean.
Watch your
tongue, Scotch boy.
Oh, dear, dear, we're
getting tough, eh?
Yeah, tough as macaroni.
Hey, Gino, something's
wrong here.
Huh?
Twenty-four pound deduction.
What advance you take?
Four.
Five tax, uh.
No, it's wrong, this.
- We see about it.
- Buzz off.
There's other fellas waitin' to get
paid. He's got all he's gonna get.
No, no, it's not at all,
there's been a mistake.
There's no mistake.
What do you know about it?
- You, I'm talking to you.
- I'm, ah...
...not talkin' to the yellow belly.
If he wants to find out why
his pay was stopped, ask Ed.
- Ed?
- Yeah.
His stuff he wrecked.
- Who put this on Tom?
- You mean on yellow belly?
Me.
I'm the road foreman.
Yeah.
And that's not all you are.
What else am I?
You're scum.
Ha!
COME ON, RED!
- Go on, Red!
- Come on, then, Red.
- Go on then, get in there!
- Wait a minute...
- ...'e'll bloody murder 'im!
- Go on.
All right, take him.
- Huh!
- GO ON, RED!
Take him, that's it,
come on!
Come on, Red, take him!
Come on, Red!
- Come on!
- Come on in there!
- Hit 'im!
- Come on, Red!
- Give it to 'im.
- Go on, you can do it.
- Come on, Red.
- Come on.
Sort 'im out.
- Take him, come on.
- Come on, Red!
Go on, Red,
give it your best.
ARGH!
Go on, Red, you've got 'im
now, good boy, good boy!
Go on, Red. Go on.
Give him a head!
Hey, Tom!
The assistant manager!
- Come on, straighten up.
- What the devil's going on here?
Oh, er, it's nothing sir, ah...
...a test of strength, ah?
A bet, nothing.
Nothing?
Fighting like animals?
- Gibson, why didn't you stop them?
- Well you see...
D'ah!
You'll pay this damage,
both of you.
Got your pay. Get out.
Go on, get out, all of you.
Once more and it'll be
for good.
As for you - you're a foreman.
You're supposed to keep discipline.
I may be a foreman, but
I'm not a prison warder.
You think I don't know
you just done a spell?
How can I keep discipline
if we're hiring convicts?
All right, you know.
What are you
gonna do about it?
Is nothing to do
with us, sir.
He already paid once for
what he done. He told me.
Mm. I'll have to check with
Mr Cartley in the morning.
- Right.
- Come on, Red.
Well, he can look after himself,
that boy, no doubt about it.
Come on, I'm hungry.
You better come
and lie down, ah?
No, I gotta work.
Ah, this looks bad, you'd better
come and get cleaned up anyway.
You all right, Red?
Yeah.
- He kneed me.
- Yeah.
- You saw what happened.
- Sure.
Otherwise I'd 'a killed him.
Here. Hey.
Oh, well.
Goodnight.
Mailbags.
Hello.
What do you want?
I hear you're eating in the
village by yourself these days.
- How's that?
- I like it that way.
I heard what they're saying.
Is it true?
Yeah.
It's true.
And I wasn't framed, and
nobody talked me into anything.
And the judge didn't
give me a raw deal.
Happy?
You still have an invitation
to eat at my place.
- Where's Gino?
- We're through.
What have you done to him?
I told him the truth.
I told him I liked him, but
I'm not in love with him...
- ...and I never was.
- You had no right to do that.
Whose right is it?
Gino?
Gino, are you awake?
Gino.
Gino, I want to talk to you.
- London, one way.
- The early's gone, mate, that was it.
- Nine thirty-five, the next.
- All right, let's have it.
Don't you characters
ever say "please"?
Here.
Excuse me.
- Hello.
- Hello, Jimmy?
- Tom.
- Hello, boy.
Listen, Jimmy, if uh, Topper or Mack
or any of the boys come round...
...tell 'em to get in touch
with Sammy O'Dea.
Sammy O'Dea?
Are are you sure you've...
Leave me alone, Jimmy
I know what I'm doing.
Tell Sammy I'll be around
at Harry's place about...
About three
o'clock, all right?
Okay, Tom.
Whatever you say.
Okay, Jimmy, boy.
Oh, Tom, thank God, I've been
searching everywhere.
Ma West said she
thought you'd gone...
- Go away, I'm leaving.
- You don't understand, it's Gino!
- Will you leave me alone?
- It's Gino, his truck hit a tree...
...and caught fire and he's
very badly burned...
- Fire?
- You've got to come to the hospital...
- ...right away! Please!
- Come on.
What are they doing in there?
Why don't they ever
tell you something?
Tom, maybe...
...maybe I ought to go.
Maybe seeing me'll
just upset him.
I know, Lucy, but...
...look, you've gotta see him, and
tell him what I told you to tell him.
Yes, all right. I'll, I'll do
whatever you want me to.
But... you've got
to stop blaming us.
At least yourself.
- What happened would've...
- I know what happened.
You don't know everything!
Tom, listen. This set
up is a racket.
Cartleys and Reds, they don't
care how many of you are killed...
...as long as they can split their
extra two hundred every week.
Why do you think they specialise in
hiring drifters like you and Gino...
...who let themselves be
hustled for money?
But how do they make
that kind of money?
- We get good pay.
- Not all of it.
Tom, Listen.
The head office pays
basic salary for...
...five more drivers
than Cartley runs.
Red paces a short-handed
crew to meet the contract.
The cash for five drivers never
even reaches our pay window.
Did you tell Gino
about this?
Look, are you sure about...
These are friends of his,
Doctor.
You can see him.
Er...
How... How is he, Doc?
If you've anything to say to him,
you'd better say it... now.
It's Lucy, sweet.
Lucy and Tom.
Amico.
I wa-I was, I was leaving when...
when I heard what happened.
I was on the railway station,
wasn't I, Lucy?
Yes.
Gino, it was you she wanted.
All the time.
She's your girl, Gino.
Here, you, you tell him, Lucy.
No. No.
You are right for each other.
Be happy - together.
Ah, Tom. Tom, ah...
...you take care
a' my Lucia.
And one day...
You take her to Italy.
Ah? Va bene?
- No, Gino, you...
- Tom.
I drew them off.
Like we plan.
For... for you to win.
Hah, they're crazy.
You don't even come.
Huh.
You... you changed
the number plates?
And they, they thought
you were me?
I was, uh, number
thirteen. Huh.
Who was it Gino?
Was it Red?
Gi...
Wait outside a moment,
would you, please?
They...
Oh, oh, my God.
Eddie, take the recovery truck
and get out there right away.
Write off or no write off,
she'll be good for some spares.
Okay.
- COOPER?
- Yeah?
Isn't this Red's truck?
What's he doing in?
Only fuel. He's losing
it somewhere.
- I'll fix it tonight.
- All right.
He'll be out in a minute.
LUCY! Oh, that...
What are you doing in here?
Get off my desk.
Gino's dead.
Ah. That's bad luck.
You... You helped to
kill him, Cartley.
I'll pretend I didn't
hear that.
I think you'd better
get out...
...before you say something
you might regret.
About the money you and
Red are grabbing...
...by running us short-handed?
Yeah.
I know all about it.
Oh.
You do now.
I see.
Well, if you know
so much.
Why don't you go and
report it somewhere?
Because that way you'll
only get nicked.
And that's too good
for you, Cartley.
Why, you cheap lag.
You think that I don't
know that you've been...
...driving without
a licence?
How long do you
think you'll stay out...
...with your record?
Then we'll do time together.
And I'm used to it.
I'm giving you a
week to pay, Cartley.
- One week.
- Now listen, where're you going?
You want loads, Cartley,
you'll get them.
But from now on, we're getting
all the money that's coming to us.
Every penny of it.
Listen, Yately.
Now, listen, wait a
minute, damn you!
Now, look here.
You're a clever boy
and a grand driver.
I've seen it all along.
I can get you a corner on this.
It'll double your wages.
A lot better than a bonus.
TOM, LISTEN!
Listen, Tom.
I can make things much
easier for you here.
Okay.
Then I'll take over number one.
It's better than that
junk you gave me.
All right, all right!
If you want it that way
it can be arranged.
But lets talk about it first.
No, Cartley.
I don't want you and
Red for partners.
You're not my type.
Oh, now you're
being unreasonable.
Tell Red I'm after him.
Tell him I don't have any proof
yet that he smashed Gino...
...but one day he'll
show his hand.
And I'll smash him.
HEY!
Hey, what's that Mac
doin' in my truck?
- Why didn't you stop him?
- Stop him? Huh!
He knows. That slut
must have told him.
He's taken your
job and your truck.
He says he's gonna
get yer for killing Rossi.
He is, eh?
Rossi's dead?
Rossi's dead, yes.
And we're in big trouble.
You'd better get after
him quick, now.
There's number three.
- How about you?
- I'll back you up.
You will, eh?
You're comin' with me.
I want a witness in case
anything goes wrong.
I'm sick of takin'
all the risks.
- Now, don't be a fool.
- I said you're comin'.
- That means you're comin'.
- Red. Red.
All right!
What are you going
this way for?
I know what I'm doin'.
But he's gone to
the ballast pit.
And where does
he go after that?
Well, what are you
doing with number one?
I am number one.
We're here.
He's taking it slow.
Tom came in.
- Is he in the office?
- No, he went back out on the run.
I think he's in for it, too.
He took number one truck.
- What?
- Red and Mr Cartley gone after him...
- ...in number three.
- Oh, no!
Open the gate, Harry.
- Red...
- Shh.
- Red. Maybe we ought to...
- Ah?
This is cold blood.
It's murder.
I DON'T WANT ANY
PART OF THIS!
LET ME GET
OUT OF HERE!
- Ah, sit tight.
- RED!
Sit tight.
YOU'VE GOT HIM.
Oh, we haven't.
- What's wrong?
- Brakes.
So!
TOM!