Intelligence Service MI6
London 1929
We believe Mrs. Wuolijoki
is actively working for the NKVD.
The Russians call her the Poet.
We also heard she's an operative
for Germany, or Japan.
Yesterday she visited the Medea
office in Helsinki. - What is it?
A front set up by her sister
Salme Dutt, a communist spy.
Security Service NKVD
Moscow 1929
Lady Muriel Paget, a British agent
and a guest at Wuolijoki's home.
The British businessman
she helped enter the country.
Obvious connections with Ml6.
I'm sorry.
We have reason to believe -
that Mrs. Wuolijoki
works for the British.
Finnish State Police
Helsinki 1929
Moscow and London
give us conflicting information.
We have to know
who that woman is spying for!
God only knows. Lately,
she's been focusing on her business.
Buying sawmills and petrol stations,
importing Russian films to Finland.
Raivio, I want everything
we have on Wuolijoki. - Virtanen!
The lady seems to travel a lot.
- We need the lady for questioning.
I could've become
the leader of Turkestan -
as soon as I'd negotiated loans for
their coffee and cotton plantations.
I would've had all the power,
even military power. I told them no.
I told them thank you,
but no thank you.
I am first and foremost
a businesswoman.
My mother was the most successful
businesswoman in Helsinki.
She was able to supply anything.
After the war, everything sold.
Commissar Krasin
has already appointed me.
I would've had all the power,
including military power.
My father.
The esteemed Member of Parliament,
lawyer, journalist, Master of Arts.
Where's my wife?
- She's with guests, sir.
I'm not so drunk
that you need to beat me! - No.
Except all week,
and on Sunday and Monday.
You told people I was in a delirium
and you'd called the police.
What can one do when
someone's raging like an animal?
No one has ever called me an animal,
and neither will you again.
I made you a woman, Ella Murrik!
I dreamed of you
not so long ago.
I cried and ranted,
because I was afraid you'd leave me.
We agreed to build our life
together, but you deceived me.
I could leave,
without any scandal or revenge.
Go on my way, and no one
would notice! For a while.
Me, ten years old.
I would've become a man
with so little.
But not in the way you thought.
I bought the Marlebäck mansion,
in litti.
We'll use these only on Sundays.
- No, we'll eat from them every day.
Your father and I
are getting a divorce.
Do you understand? - Yes.
Good. - I read it in the paper
four weeks ago.
Annual exports rose to
20,000 standards.
How did you get a loan
from the Bank of England?
I'm a good talker.
The state police
were watching my mother-
because of her connections
with the Soviet Union.
10 years later
Mother was always
away on business -
all around Europe
and the Soviet Union.
I grew up alone in the mansion.
What are you clattering here for?
- I got hungry at the sawmill.
You made Jussi pick you up
in the middle of the night.
Jussi didn't complain.
Give me some milk, Vappu.
No one dares complain.
- Why not? I'm a democratic person.
You know that I abide by
a socialist world view.
Next year, I'll have
2,400 workers at the sawmill.
Do you pay Jussi a salary?
- I educated him.
I paid for his books and gave him
money whenever he needed it.
Klaara, does Hella pay you a salary?
I taught Klaara to be independent.
I have 8-hour working days,
collective supervisors, open books.
We're like one big family.
I've earned all I've got.
Don't eat so much,
you'll become shapeless.
Did I raise you to talk
to your mother like that?
You didn't raise me.
Fräulein raised me.
110,000 logs came from Russia,
but they have a seller's market.
We'll see once the invoice arrives.
The bank trusts me.
Have you applied for
an extension on the fee payments?
What's the rush?
- We haven't paid them for two years.
No, we haven't. - The bank wants us
to at least pay the interest.
Let them show up at my door.
And why did they contact you?
You ignore them,
even though you owe millions.
That's right. - You seem to follow
your own rules, Madam.
0ctober 29, 1929.
Black Tuesday.
The New York Stock Exchange
is in a panic.
Frantic investors have scrambled
to unload their stocks.
Everyone wants to sell,
no one wants to buy.
Suddenly the most gilt-edged
securities are valueless.
The stock market crash has come,
and the Great Depression...
Ask the bank for an extension
on the interest payment.
I already did, a few months ago.
- That was then. Ask again.
Take these to the pawn shop,
but tell them not to sell them yet.
You should pawn this too.
Not that. It's a keepsake.
It's just an object.
You should let go.
You should sell Marlebäck.
- Never.
Well, start writing then.
White Finland wouldn't dare
produce a play by Hella Wuolijoki.
Mother decided to write
under a pen name.
First, she was Felix Tuli.
Then, Juhani Tervapää.
Her first play had been published
20 years earlier -
but it was banned
in Helsinki and Tallinn.
The pen name allowed her to avoid
censorship and prejudice.
We sent plays to publishers
and theatres, here and there.
They were rejected everywhere.
We sent one to the most famous
director in the country -
Eino Salmelainen.
Juhani Tervapää,
"Any objections?"
The writer and the play
have original names.
The name of the play is bad,
but the text is brilliant.
With a new playwright, we won't
get in trouble with the union.
It's hard to find props
in these financial times.
I'm happy to help
fledgling writers.
Your assistant stage manager
told me -
that I'll get
my furniture back soon.
"The Women of Niskavuori"
won't run very long -
even though it's directed
by Eino Salmelainen.
"The Women of Niskavuori"
Premiere 1936
A marvellous performance.
Congratulations, Mrs. Wuolijoki.
Well, did they slate it?
This is sheer praise.
"The Women of Niskavuori".
The judge takes out
a brandy bottle.
"Leave the girl be. Her story is sad
in this time of unemployment. "
"Even cigarette factories are
firing people, not to mention..."
One moment! - "It's sad that Hulda
is beyond redemption as a citizen."
"Women of the streets don't vote."
"Hulda is so pretty that
it's unlikely she'll be rescued."
Can I take a cigarette break?
- Don't you like that line, Firinä?
I do, but I'd also like a cigarette
and some coffee.
I'll have Hulda make coffee
for the gentlemen.
That's a good idea,
isn't it, Firinä?
She doesn't hear or listen.
I wonder if her heart's in this.
They won't accept me as a member
of the playwright's union. - Why not?
They don't tell why.
- It's political.
I wouldn't feel bad.
- I'm not fit to be a Finn.
Or an author in this country.
Valued plays
run at the National Theatre -
and my plays under an alias at the
People's Theatre, with my furniture.
Give me a cigarette, Vappu.
I'll have Hulda smoke
in the final scene.
Smoke cigarettes and
drink cocktails. What do you think?
THE FARMER'S DAUGHTER
What a nice-looking girl.
- A real country girl.
Sitting there
with her plywood box.
I can tell she's
from our part of the country.
I am, and I recognise you,
Mr. Ali-Lehtonen.
So you are from Sääksmäki!
- Yes, my name is Hulda Juurakko.
Good evening.
I've been eagerly waiting for you.
Are you still going on
with that foolishness?
Hulda... a ring isn'
too rich a price for you.
Do you honestly believe
I want a ring from you? Never!
For seven years, you've been
weighing me up with your eyes.
I honestly don't know
why I like you so much!
I don' want to become your wife.
Do you hear me?
You're struggling in vain.
You know that, don' you?
You can' escape it.
Mother's plays were
also successful abroad.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
One of the top industrialists
in our country -
Mrs. Hella Wuolijoki,
is 50 years old today.
Her school of life
has been as follows:
Cooking school in Estonia,
university in Helsinki...
A congratulatory call from America.
Ernestine Evans.
The response has been great.
Everybody loves your plays.
That's lovely to hear.
- How can such nonsense succeed?
But they want to know
if you're a socialist.
As my agent, you can tell them
all the great writers are.
Well, I'll tell them.
Happy birthday, Hella.
As we have witnessed -
this "factory" can produce
a three-act play in a week.
What's more, the factory
has started exporting its products.
The trademark Hella Wuolijoki
is already world-famous.
Her fatherland congratulates her.
This is Hella Wuolijoki's idea of
a person corrupted by capitalism.
Listen to this line, for example:
"Dear Robert, everything that I have
I've paid for in bed."
She portrays a society lady
as a street woman and a vampire.
This Hilda Harmaalahti
talks and acts like a harlot.
Goddammit,
what stuffy sociology! - Right.
I always try to forget
stories that end sadly.
Do you succeed?
- You're too curious.
What was the story then?
- Centuries ago....
Well, what do you think?
You didn't have to kill
"Green Gold" at the theatre.
It wasn't your best play.
It's the one dearest to me.
But the critics were unanimous.
Sentimentality doesn't suit you.
- It's not sentimentality but poetry.
Why don't you
write about yourself?
As you are. That would be
a guaranteed success.
I write world literature.
I can't help it
if the audience loves it.
Dear Foreign Minister Tanner.
I escaped the bombs to Marlebäck -
and I've been sitting here
paralysed for three weeks.
The cows need to
be taken care of-
but God, isn't there anything more
I could do in this tragedy?
Are you attempting
any kind of dialogue with Moscow?
They should be willing
to get out of this situation.
I'm one of the few people
they've been friendly with.
I'm sure they would
negotiate with me.
I can contact the Soviet ambassador
to Sweden, Alexandra Kollontai.
You can't afford to say no.
Every possibility
must be taken into account.
We can't afford to say no.
Every possibility
must be taken into account.
The Ministry for Foreign Affairs
of Sweden confirms contact -
between Finland and the Soviet Union
to start negotiations.
Grand Hotel, Stockholm 1 939
Foreign Minister Tanner
has been visiting Stockholm.
As an unofficial representative -
Hella Wuolijoki was allowed
to contact the Soviet ambassador-
Madam Kollontai.
How are you, Hella?
Goddammit, Madam Kollontai.
With her contacts,
Mother arranged peace for Finland -
but once the official negotiations
started, she was pushed aside.
The situation in Marlebäck
was disastrous.
The bank called in the loans.
There was no feed for the cattle.
Mother couldn' pay the bills.
I've cleared
75 hectares of new fields.
Now we have 140 hectares in all.
The main building was renovated
in the style of Engel.
There are 22 fireplaces,
and 50 hectares of forest.
The offer of Director Laaksonen
and Mrs. Rissanen is the best.
Well, the only one.
Damn it. I've been managing
this mansion for 20 years.
Do I have to leave it now?
The contents of the house
must be left as they are.
That's the condition of the offer.
Jokela mansion, January 1 941
I live close to Helsinki now.
- Mother tried to assure Tanner -
that the Soviet Union would be
a better ally than Germany.
Their ambassador's behaviour
suggests different.
Terentyev promised to replace him
with someone better.
Finland's neutrality will be
rewarded with commercial benefits.
We can guarantee that.
I'll be frank with you.
The Soviet Union wants to
focus on more significant matters -
and not aggravate
the situation with Finland.
So, the Soviets have more
pressing matters to worry about?
I should've known better
than to handle politics with women.
Finland is entering another war.
Hitler declares that we will fight
the Soviet Union in alliance -
im bunde, with Germany.
March 1942
Madam Wuolijoki,
there's someone here to see you.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
My name is Elina Hämäläinen.
- Who sent you?
I'm looking for work.
My husband died in the Winter War.
Do you have children?
- I was ordered to see the Poet.
I'm supposed to live here
as a secretary or a maid.
Parachutists are
always caught and shot.
I bring greetings
from Comrade Terentyev.
Who was it?
- Some poor girl, looking for work.
She had injured her foot. I told her
she could spend the night.
Where had she injured her foot?
Take something warm to drink
to the library.
How could peace give the Germans
a foothold in this country?
Moscow regrets that they didn't
occupy Finland in the war.
The Soviet Union acted stupidly
after the Winter War.
And what has
their propaganda been like?
If only they'd tried
a bit of humour -
but they have no
sense of humour whatsoever.
Terentyev sent you this.
It's 10,000 marks.
He remembered his debt.
Bertolt Brecht's fare to America.
It's not a debt.
It's a reward for the Poet.
I'll keep it for you.
- I have my own money. That's yours.
Someone will make a bed for you -
but you'll have to leave
first thing tomorrow.
My real name isn't
Elina Hämäläinen.
I was sent here to find out
the situation in Finland.
How many Germans are there?
- 1 00,000, in Northern Finland.
I have to inform Moscow. - They know.
They have contacts with the English.
There's a clever British spy here.
A journalist.
We know that
the Germans are everywhere -
and that they eat
Finland's food supplies.
Do you know anything at all?
What's your position?
The Germans have their own supplies,
and they buy meat from us.
This house has hosted
peace negotiations.
You were going to
show me your papers.
I don't have
any food or clothes coupons.
I don't have food coupons either.
We're a self-sufficient household.
I'll come back for my transmitter,
once I've settled.
You'll take your
radio transmitter with you.
If they inspect the train,
throw it out of the window.
How can I contact you?
Drop her off before the station.
People might recognise the horse.
She's about 30 years old.
Height... 1 70 centimetres.
Dark hair, red lips.
- Thank you, that's enough. Please.
You're an exceptionally
perceptive woman.
Upstairs and out.
In the small hours of March 30th,
a female was parachuted into Vihti.
She came to Wuolijoki's mansion
on that evening and spent the night.
And Wuolijoki hurried to Stockholm.
- Where's my call to Stockholm?
Sofiahemmet Hospital
Stockholm
I thought this would
cheer you up.
It was nothing serious,
so there'll be no operation.
But I should eat more healthily.
You should stay in Sweden.
You earn enough money
from your plays.
No one would
harass you anymore.
Was I being followed?
Were there policemen outside?
The key to the code
is on page six.
The Swedish police will stop
when their working day is done.
Can I borrow this?
A merry-looking trollop.
Mrs. Yartseva is not a trollop,
Raivio. She's a spy.
Alexandra Nikolaevna,
or actually Voskresenskaya.
Do any of them
have only one name?
I want Wuolijoki charged
with treason. Nothing less.
Why did they send that woman to me?
- What do you mean?
The parachutist whom Terentyev sent.
- I don't think he sent anyone.
She gave me 1 0,000 marks
and said they were from Terentyev.
We'll take care of her.
Find out from Tanner and Paasikivi
if Finland is interested in peace.
Here's an English translation
of your play.
There's nothing dangerous in it.
- I can't. They'll search my things.
Take it. Unless you want to lose
the Soviet Union's trust.
Have a good journey home.
Good evening, Mrs. Wuolijoki.
Take that bench down.
I need to lie on my back.
The bench stays where it is.
I'm an old woman.
I come straight from hospital.
There's not even room to walk.
Could you dust them
while you're at it?
Did a Soviet parachutist
visit you at Jokela? - No.
We heard otherwise. - A woman called
Elina Hämäläinen asked for work.
You knew that wasn't her name.
- No, I didn't.
Why did you leave
for Sweden right after?
I was supposed to have
an operation there.
Well, did you?
- No. It wasn't necessary.
You know that messages
to the Soviet Union go via Sweden.
On what grounds are you holding me?
- Of aiding the enemy.
You met with Soviet diplomats,
or spies, in Sweden.
I will prove it.
Bring the parachutist here,
so I can see her too.
Take Mrs. Wuolijoki
back to her cell.
She knows that
we haven't caught the parachutist.
They're always caught.
It's just a matter of time.
We have to release Wuolijoki.
Since you suspect me of all kinds
of things, it's best I leave.
What can I do
if I'm not trusted?
It must've come as a surprise
that I came back.
State police 1942
Name?
- Elina Hämäläinen.
You say you're Elina Hämäläinen?
Elina Sigrid Hämäläinen.
I'm a Bolshevik.
I love my country, which sent me on
a reconnaissance mission to Finland.
Did you tell the writer Wuolijoki
your real name?
Who do you mean?
You shouldn't leave
your radio transmitter in a laundry.
You're Kerttu Nuorteva,
the daughter of Santeri Nuorteva.
From a cultural family.
Relatives in important positions.
How about I make you an offer?
We could arrange for you
to move to Sweden or America.
A betrayal of trust can be hard
for a convinced person.
The Soviet Union has left you
to your own devices.
One. Hella Wuolijoki passed on
secret correspondence -
with red prisoners
sentenced for treason.
Two. She arranged Otto-Ville
Kuusinen's escape to Sweden.
Three. She hid
the American communist John Reed.
Four. Communists spent
fancy holidays at her mansion.
Five. She hosted a political salon
at her luxury apartment.
They were all there. Film stars,
spies, communists, and traitors.
We know that, and everything else.
The parachutist confessed in full.
May 1 943
Names?
- Wuolijoki, Hella Maria.
Maiden name?
- Murrik.
Date and place of birth?
- Helmi, Estonia. 22nd August, 1886.
Occupation? - Master of Arts,
managing director, author.
Nationality?
- Finnish.
Estonian nationality,
Finnish citizenship.
Spouse and children?
- Sulo Ilmiö Wuolijoki, divorced.
Daughter Vappu Wuolijoki.
- Vappu Tuomioja, née Wuolijoki.
Height 1 60 - 170.
Face round, full, and cone-shaped.
Double chin, a scar
on the joint of her little finger.
Clean up.
The spitting bowl.
I don't use it. Take it away.
Nothing is taken away.
You're going to clean it.
I wash my own dishes,
not other people's.
You'll do as I tell you.
I brought Finland peace
from the Winter War.
The state owes me for timber.
My works are read
all over the world.
And you take
a parachutist's word over mine.
Nuorteva made a full confession.
- Is her name Nuorteva?
The daughter of the President
of the Karelian ASSR. You knew.
Santeri Nuorteva's daughter.
I didn't know that.
You'd better just
confess everything.
What does that mean?
Do you want to make me a spy?
You shouldn't be upset,
Mrs. Wuolijoki. - No.
Even though you've suggested
that my execution is certain.
Who suggested that?
- You said -
that the author Rantamala broke down
when he heard his death sentence.
It was just what I'd heard.
It wasn't a threat.
Why did you bring the message
from Stockholm? - What?
The one that was written
on your play with invisible ink!
I don't know what was in it.
I lost the key.
Is it true that Minister Tanner
doesn't want to see me? - Yes.
If I have to die useless, so be it.
But I will not die a spy.
You'll be sent to prison
to await sentencing.
September 1 943
The watch too.
Get yourself settled.
Wake up!
Emptying of the latrine buckets!
Your bucket.
I can't.
Get the lady's bucket.
Managing the Jokela farm
was left up to me.
64 hectares of land
and over 20 cows.
There were no workmen.
Everyone was fighting on the front.
My eye and heart medicine.
Ask the orthopaedist about my back.
I want Thesleff's biography
of Minna Canth.
And why can't you manage
to send me that mattress?
And the pink duvet.
I'm trying not
to think about Jokela.
It's good that you learn
what it takes to run a mansion.
Has anyone asked after me?
No one visits me.
Keep your distance!
Take your hands out of your pockets!
Keep moving!
Take your hands
out of your sleeves!
Eyes down!
Mother never talked
to Kerttu Nuorteva again.
While waiting for her sentence,
Mother began to write her memoirs.
0ne morning, at the end
of September in 1904 -
an 18-year-old Estonian girl
arrived at Helsinki station.
She had a basket and
an old-fashioned leather bag.
I'm here for having
18 food rationing cards.
I know you would've asked.
- How do you know that?
They say you ask a lot.
Why can't a rich and civilised lady
get herself more privileges?
How does one get them?
- I have everything I need.
Information and cigarettes.
I know all the messaging systems.
You need to be on good terms
with the cooks and others.
Smoking is not allowed
in the cells.
And no one sits on my bed,
especially not like that.
You don't know how the women
of the world sit in their lounges.
When I get out, I'm going to
Hotel Torni with my friends.
I'll drink myself into a stupor.
Have you had a lot of men?
I bet you have.
Men go after money and fame.
And you're a handsome woman.
"November 27th, 1 943. The field
court-martial has sentenced -
the author Hella Wuolijoki to life
in penal servitude for treason."
What does penal servitude mean?
- Less rations and privileges.
You're not allowed to receive
food from home, or newspapers.
The Minister of Justice has decreed
that prison food is sufficient.
"The sentence has been submitted
to the court-martial appeal court."
"The matter is still undecided."
Can I still be sentenced to death?
- It's possible.
December 1943
Väinö sends his regards
and wishes you a Happy New Year.
He has tried to do
everything he can.
You need a presidential pardon
before you're sentenced to death.
But I've done no crime.
They seem to think you knew
what that woman wanted from you.
All I wanted was peace. I thought
she came to negotiate peace.
I wrote the petition for you.
Read it at least.
Why do I have to petition for
a pardon, as if I was a criminal?
The girl stood alone and helpless
on the platform -
until a porter saw her
and took her luggage to a carriage.
Court-martial appeal court 1 944
I don't deny my guilt of actions
that can be considered treason -
and for which I can be
sentenced to death.
But I sincerely believe
that the relations I established -
were of great importance
to our country's fate.
I made contact with the enemy -
only to sever our country
from its disastrous ally, Germany -
and to find a way toward peace.
Thank you.
With votes of 3 - 2, the appeal
court sentences Hella Wuolijoki -
to life in penal servitude.
Mother avoided the death sentence
by one vote.
Here's part two, 21 5 pages.
Take it to the publisher.
You're not surprised. People expect
great feats from your mother.
I would've written a play too,
but my back doesn't allow it.
What's the matter?
- I'm tired.
Don't complain, you're free.
Are you tired from work?
Where are the accounts then?
- I run the farm day and night.
I take care of the loans, interest,
lawyer's fees, and salaries.
And I have to wait on you.
You make unreasonable demands.
You have never thanked me
for running Jokela.
I do commend you.
- Maybe to others, but not to me.
Why did you want a child
in the first place?
Do you love me at all?
Are you able to love anyone?
How much love did you get for
paying your husband to be a steward?
For giving your lover 300,000 marks
worth of timber stocks?
Did you record
the debits and credits?
How much did you give
and how much love did you get?
I've never had a strong man.
I was almost
sentenced to death.
Goodbye, Mother.
The child is coughing!
Who's coughing?
Peace has come!
The Minister of Justice
ordered you to be released today.
Nuorteva will be deported
back to the Soviet Union.
The winner will be demanding
heads on a platter.
If I were President Ryti,
I'd leave for Sweden.
Ryti is a moralist,
he won't escape. But I will.
Give me a cigarette, Vappu.
Well?
Do you think there's still
use for me in this country?
After the war, Hella Wuolijoki
became a Member of Parliament -
and the director of
the Finnish Broadcasting Company.
She died in 1954
in Helsinki at the age of 67.
Her plays and the movies
based on them are beloved classics.
Finally! You naughty girl.
I was in danger of becoming
a rich lady's lover.
Hello! - Hello, Heta.
Welcome, Loviisa.
- What a handsome house!
Just like Niskavuori.
- It's a few metres longer.
Marry me? An uncultured girl
you'd have become tired of.
It would've been a marriage
similar to your present one.
Cocktail, Miss Juurakko.
- Thank you, Professor.
Is this a martini?
I don' drink anything else.
Cheers, ladies and gentlemen!
I thought I'd forbid you
to visit my grave.
But do come.
Great God in Heaven,
give me love.
Give me love,
give me love!
Dear radio listeners.
As I'm leaving
the Finnish Broadcasting Company -
I would like to say a few words
to my listeners.
To all of you who have
these four years supported-
the programmes
broadcast by this institution.
Subtitles: Minna Franssila
Broadcast Text International