How was everything?
Real good honey, thanks.
Let me have a pack of
Kools too, would you?
Real nice smile you got there.
Thank you.
Good bye.
Bye.
(Gun shot)
(Screaming)
Shut up!
(Gun shots)
(Phone ringing)
Shut up, shut up!
(Woman screaming)
Die bitch!
Die!
(Woman screaming)
Well Kathys mom
said she could do it.
Hi, are you going to the city?
Sure.
Hop in.
FarangSiam thanks you.
Have Fun!
Becky.
Hello Otis.
Well, how are you?
Good.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you, too.
You got all your things?
Yeah.
You look terrible.
Okay, come on let's go.
It's this way.
Before you got
married I told you
Leroy was no damn good.
That he was trash
and he'd always be trash
and you was going to catch
it and you did didn't you?
I don't really want to
talk about him right now.
Okay by me, we don't
have to talk about it now.
We don't have to
talk about it ever.
How long are you
going to be up here?
It's hard to say.
What about Lurleen?
How long can you
leave her with mama?
I don't know.
I'm going to get a job,
make some money.
Maybe bring her up here,
I don't know.
Where did you tell
Leroy you were going?
I don't want to talk about him.
Okay, we don't have
to talk about him!
You hungry?
Yeah.
Good, I'm hungry too.
You think Leroy's hungry?
Do you want some more coffee?
Yeah, thanks.
Here.
So what kind of work do you
planning on getting up here?
Anything like...
I haven't decided yet.
What else can you do
besides dance naked?
Don't start with me Otis.
I can do lots of things mister.
Oh yea, like what?
Like waitressing
or a beautician.
Yeah.
After seeing you I might
just try brain surgery.
You're a card.
Yeah, I'm the queen.
Yeah, the queen of clubs.
Don't make me
sorry I came here, Otis.
(Door opening)
Howdy.
Hey, Henry.
I brought you a present.
Where did you get that?
Picked it up.
Whew!
Pretty nice, huh?
Sure is a beauty.
Oh, uh...
Henry this here
is my sister, Becky.
She's gonna be staying here
with us for a while like I said.
Becky this here's Henry.
Hello Henry.
Hello Becky.
Good to meet you.
She don't look nothing like you,
that's for sure.
Lucky for her.
Henry's on his way out west.
Oh, where?
California.
Oh.
She can sleep on the couch.
No, no.
Listen Becky I want you
to take the spare room.
No, Henry, thank you but no...
I insist.
Ain't that right Otis?
UP t0 you.
Alright,
but if it gets to be
a bother, we'll change.
Fair enough.
Well, I got to get going.
I got some work to do today.
I just stopped by
to clean up a little.
Where you working?
I'm helping Andy spray
some houses off La Grange.
Oh so that's working
out for you, huh?
Yeah.
Sounds like fun.
Coffee?
No thanks, I gotta go.
See ya.
Yeah.
That's it till next week.
I was hoping for
a little more work.
So was I.
You never know.
Sometimes I get a call.
You know,
these assholes want you to
be out there the next day.
You never know.
Yeah.
Here, take this.
We'll call it a retainer.
Thanks.
You don't here from me
give me a call.
Hold on.
Don't forget your sprayer.
Hang onto it.
Okay.
Come on, kid, come on.
Throw it in there.
Good catch.
Put a spiral on it.
Nice catch.
Sorry about that.
(Woman screaming)
(Sounds of a Struggle)
It's good.
And please check
the left rear tire.
It's good, too.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And what can I do for you, sir.
You got any more of
what you had last week?
I might.
Well do you, or don't you?
Yeah.
Well?
Well, I don't have
it on me, stupid.
Give me the money.
I'll bring it around the field.
I don't want you
hanging around practice.
Give me my money back.
UP t0 you.
Be in the parking lot at 6:30.
Sure thing.
6:30 tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Take it or leave it.
Great.
See ya.
Fuckin' pervert.
Oh, it's so gross.
I always did hate doing this.
I'll do it.
That's alright.
Where did you say you met him?
Who?
You know who, Henry.
What do you want to know for?
I don't know.
I'm just curious.
Van Dalia.
Van Dalia?
Sure, Van Dalia.
Oh,
what was he in for?
You don't want to know.
What did he do, kill his mama?
Uh-huh.
Come on, what was he in for?
You don't want to know.
What did he do,
rob a bank or something?
You were right the first time.
Huh?
He killed his mama.
Don't you ever
tell him I told you.
You're kidding me?
No, I ain't.
Yes you are.
Alright, I'm kidding you.
Just don't ever
tell him I told you.
He killed his mama?
With a baseball bat.
Her and one of her boyfriends.
I swear if you ever
tell him I told you
I'll beat your ass right off.
How do you know all this?
He told me, that's how I know.
How else would I know?
Were you cellmates or something?
No, we were friends.
When did he get out?
A couple of years before me.
(Door opening)
Hi.
I got some business
I got to take care of.
You going out?
Yeah, for a while,
I got to run an
errand for a fellow.
You want to come along Henry?
No, you go ahead.
Okay.
See you later.
Want to play cards?
U-'nu.
What was your daddy like?
My daddy?
He used to drive a truck
before he got his legs cut off.
I remember one time,
he brought me and my
little brother home bicycles.
He had delivered some that day
and he had a couple leftover.
But, mine was
way too big for me,
and my brother
he couldn't ride his anyway.
Daddy, he said I'd grow into it,
but, I never did.
Why not?
I never got the chance,
they sold it.
They sold them both.
So you have a brother?
My brother,
he had a bone disorder.
He was a little deformed.
What happened to him?
He died.
I can't ever remember
really liking my daddy.
I wanted to,
I really did.
One time he bought me,
when I was about five,
he bought me an ice cream cone
and I dropped it.
And he slapped me
and made me
pick it up and eat it.
I never liked my daddy.
One time,
when my momma was at work,
and I was about 13,
he come into my room
and he told me to
take my shirt off
'cause he wanted to see
how I was developed.
And when I wouldn't
he got real mad and he hit me.
And he told me he had a right
because he was my daddy
and I was his daughter
and he fed me
and let me live in his house
and he could do
whatever he wanted.
And he did.
Then he started coming
into my room a lot,
after that.
And I didn't fight him
because when
I did he just hit me.
I was afraid I was
going to have a baby
and that my baby
would be deformed
but, I never got pregnant.
I tried to tell mama,
but she didn't
want to hear about it.
She pretended not to believe me
but I knew she did.
It sure is good to talk...
to talk to you Henry,
because I know
you're not judgmental
or anything like that.
I never would have married
Leroy in the first place
if I hadn't wanted to get
away from daddy so bad.
Didn't get along
with your daddy, huh?
Did you really kill your mama?
What?
I guess I did.
How did it happen?
I stabbed her.
Otis said you hit her
with a baseball bat.
Otis said that?
Yeah.
Well, he's mistaken.
Well, don't tell him I told you,
he made me promise.
She must have
treated you real bad.
She was a whore.
My mama was a whore.
Butldon1 fault her for that.
It ain't what she done
it's how she done it.
As long as I can remember
she'd be bringing
men up to the house.
My daddy was there too
but it didn't
matter none to her.
She'd make me watch it.
That's creepy.
She beat me too, a lot.
She beat me when
I wouldn't watch it.
And sometime she'd beat me
make me wear a dress
and watch her doing it.
And then they'd laugh at me.
She made you wear a dress?
You think I'm lying?
I feel like I know you.
Like I've known
you for a long time.
I feel like I've known
you for ever and ever.
Yeah...
I killed my mama...
One night,
It was my 14th birthday
and she was drunk and,
we had an argument.
She hit me with
a whiskey bottle.
And I shot her.
I shot her dead.
I thought you said
you stabbed her?
Oh yeah.
That's right.
I stabbed her.
(Door opening)
Hey.
Anything good on TV?
I got a job today.
Oh yeah?
Doing what?
At a beauty parlor.
A beauty parlor?
I'm a shampoo girl.
What's that?
What's it sound like, you dummy?
How the hell should I know?
You ever seen me
in a beauty parlor?
I give shampoos,
a woman gets her hair shampooed
before she gets it cut
and I do it.
They pay you for that?
Of course they do.
Besides I used to
do it some back home
after I met Leroy.
Do you like it better
than dancing naked?
Don't start with me Otis.
You used to dance naked?
Sure, all the time
around the house.
Otis.
Best little naked
dancer you ever saw.
You never.
Were you really a dancer?
I danced some,
in a club,
and I wasn't naked.
I wore a costume.
But I guess it wasn't very much.
Oh.
When you gonna dance for us?
When the pope
pees in his hat, Otis.
Ain't she got a mouth on her?
I better have something on me
to defend me
from a pig like you.
(Making pig sounds)
Otis.
Them's pretty earrings
you got on Becky.
Thank you Henry.
At least there's one
gentleman at this table.
Oh, I'm sorry honey,
now don't get mad.
I was just having
a little fun with you,
that's all.
Oh, wait,
I got something to show you.
What?
Wait.
Ta-da!
Nice.
Real nice.
Put it on.
Right now?
Uh-huh.
Okay, but turn around first.
Turn around.
Okay, you can look.
What does it say on there?
I love Chicago.
Looks good,
don't it Otis?
Uh-huh.
Oh, hey honey,
Why don't you bring me a beer,
this one's empty.
I ain't your maid,
get it yourself.
Oh, now come on honey,
I ain't asking you
to wash the windows or nothing,
I just want a beer.
Come on, bring your poor
old brother a beer, will ya?
Don't do that Otis,
she's your sister!
Okay, I was only
kidding around, Henry.
Tell her you're sorry.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Now, tell her you
won't do it again.
I won't,
I swear Becky I swear, I won't.
Ouch!
Shit, Henry!
Serves you right.
Thank you, Henry.
That's alright.
Listen, I'll do the dishes.
I don't mind.
I don't.
Listen, why don't you boys
go out and get a beer.
I'll do these,
I don't mind, honest.
Well, what do you say Otis?
You want to go grab a beer?
Sure, I don't mind.
I'll just go spruce up.
That was a real
nice supper, Becky.
Thanks.
Have fun.
Yeah.
Ooh.
Ooh, easy.
Aah, mmh,
Easy.
Oh, come on, slow down!
Easy tiger, easy!
Slow down.
Now, wait a minute!
Hey come on, I'm not kidding!
(Sound of neck breaking)
Suzie?
Suzie!
Suzie... aaaaah.
(Sound of neck breaking)
Otis!
Come here,
I'll drive.
What's gonna happen
when they find those bodies?
Nothing.
What do you mean nothing?
Just what I said Otis,
nothing.
Nothing's gonna happen
cause nothing happened.
And I don't know nothing
about it whatever it is.
Do you?
Hey, I don't know nothing.
Good.
Oh, fuck.
Feeling better?
Yeah.
You want some fries?
You telling me you never
killed anybody before?
I ain't saying that.
Then you've killed
before, right?
Well, maybe I didn't
have no choice.
You didn't have no
choice here neither.
Did you?
Huh?
I don't know,
it ain't the same.
It's always the same,
and it's always different.
What do you mean?
It's either you or them,
one way or the other.
Ain't that right?
Open your eyes, Otis.
Look at the world.
It's either you or them.
You know what I mean.
Yeah.
Good.
You want a beer?
Okay.
There was only one left.
He knows nothing about this
but you can bet
a dollar to a doughnut
that when he finds out,
and he will find out
'cause I'll tell him
there'll be hell to pay.
Really.
I'll never go back there again
I can tell you that.
Not when he's not there anyway.
First of all there ain't two
of them that speaks English.
It's gone down so badly
the way it's changed
it breaks my heart.
It's like that all over.
People spit at you.
I wish I was lying.
Yeah, you can't have a regular
good time in the city no more.
Ah, shit!
Fuck.
What did you do that for?
I guess I got carried away.
Well, I guess you did, Otis.
Shit, I got to have a TV.
Well, let's go shopping.
So what can I do
for you gentlemen?
It's hot in here, isn't it?
I'm kind of cold.
We want a TV.
How much you got to spend?
What do you got?
50 bucks.
I can let you have the set
over there for 50 bucks.
Well, turn it on
we want to see if it works.
What's the matter,
don't you trust me?
Uh-uh.
Here plug it in down there.
Here?
Yeah, down there, real good.
I see you've had some college.
Like you can see
it works real good.
Just takes a while to warm up.
It's black and white!
Of course it's black and white.
What do you expect for 50 bucks?
Fuckin' 3-D for Christ sake.
Well, how much is color?
We want color.
You can't get
color for 50 dollars.
That's okay,
let's see what you got.
What have I got?
You want cable ready?
You want remote control?
You want UHF?
You want 13"?
You want 19"?
I bet you'd like to have a 19".
You want Sony?
You want Zenith?
You want a Gold Star?
What can we get for a $150?
I can let you have
this set for $150.
It's worth $300.
But here, take a look at this.
For an extra $75,
you can take this $600 set.
What's this?
It's a camcorder.
What?
It's a videotape recorder
and camera rolled into one.
You just pop in a cassette
and you're ready to go.
You can make your
own movies with that?
What else would you do with it?
How much you want for it?
It's worth a grand,
I'd take half.
500 bucks?
Yeah, half of a grand is $500.
That's a little more
than we were planning to spend.
I think we should
just take the TV.
Okay, which one do you want?
The $50 one.
You guys come in here,
I show this,
I show you that,
and you creeps got
a lousy $50 to spend.
You should have
stopped me a long time ago.
Take the $50 set
and get the hell out,
I'm a busy man.
Well, we were really
counting on a color set.
What's the matter,
You got shit in your ears?
The black and white is $50,
take it or leave it.
Sorry we wasted your time,
come on, Otis.
Don't give me
sorry, you dumb ass!
Did I stutter?
Gimme the $50 and get out!
I'll give you 50...
(Screaming)
No!
Otis,
Plug  it in.
(Music)
Oh get out of here
you're so ugly.
Lurleen, here's your Uncle Otis.
Hi Lurleen, hi honey,
how are you, hi it's Uncle Otis.
Henry come dance with me.
Come on, come on, just dance.
Who me?
Yeah.
No, no, no.
Come on Henry.
Come on do it Henry.
All right lets go.
That's it.
Get down.
Wig it as they say here.
More, more,
come on, go for it...
come on Henry, that's it,
that's it...
Work them hands, Henry.
That's it, that's it.
Lo and behold, what a guy.
Come on, come on,
see look how good it is.
Right there yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on,
more, more!
More!
More damn it!
Fight your own battles.
Get this...
Turn it off!
I want more,
just a little bit more.
All right.
That's it, that's it,
just a little bit,
all right that's it.
Hi baby.
Come on Henry, say hi.
No.
Say hi, Henry.
No more, Otis.
No more, Otis!
He doesn't want to.
Say hi baby.
I said hi.
(Phone ringing)
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
Look I'll do the best I can,
but I don't promise...
Fuck him.
Yeah, yeah, good-bye.
Crazy 9W!
What?
Some jerk off hasn't
been out of jail six months,
gets drunk,
gets busted up in a fight.
So he goes home and gets a gun
and comes back later
and shoots the guy.
They find the gun on him.
He claims he was framed.
What are you going to do?
So, everything going okay?
Yeah.
Okay,
You still working at Bobs Gas?
Yes sir.
Good, you working everyday?
Two, three days a week.
It's a little slow now.
Well, if it's less than
two days a week let me know.
We'll see what
we can do for you.
You still living
at 1801 West North?
Yes sir.
Good.
I got to cut it
short today, Otis.
My kid's scheduled
for oral surgery.
I promised to take him over.
Sure.
Good, I'll see you next month.
Take it easy.
Bye.
You got it?
Got what?
You know what.
Here you go.
You wanna try it?
Ooh!
God damn, you son of a bitch!
Fuckin'...!
Damn it!
Fucker.
Let me see that.
That little fuckin' bastard.
I ought to kill him.
I ought to cut his
fuckin' head off.
That'd be a mistake.
Look who's talking.
Watch your mouth Otis.
I'm sorry, Henry.
You kill that high school boy
they're going to slap your ass
right back in jail.
Otis that's a promise.
People have seen you together.
I'd still like
to kill him though.
I bet you would.
I'd like to kill somebody.
Say that again.
Let's me and you
go for a ride Otis.
Here, I want to
show you something.
Where'd you get this?
Careful Otis,
it's loaded.
Where'd you get it?
Guns are easy to get.
I can make a phone call
and get a gun.
Anybody can get a gun Otis.
What do you got in mind Henry?
What do you think?
I don't know.
Put up the hood.
Why?
Just put up the hood, Otis.
You guys need any help?
Otis, do you need some help,
or can you do it yourself?
Feel better?
Yeah.
Alright.
If you shoot somebody
in the head with a 45
every time you kill somebody
it becomes like
your fingerprint see.
But if you strangle one
and stab another,
one you cut up
one you don't
then the police
don't know what to do.
They think you're
four different people.
What they really like,
what makes their
job so much easier,
a pattern.
What they call a modus operandi.
That's Latin.
Bet you didn't know
any Latin, did ya?
Big fuckin' deal.
What?
Nothing.
It's like a trail of shit, Otis.
It's like a blood droppings
from a deer you've shot
and all they gotta do
is follow those droppings
and pretty soon they're
going to find that deer.
Why do we use a gun?
You can use a gun.
I'm not saying
you can't use a gun.
Just don't use
the same gun twice.
The most important
thing is to keep moving.
That way they might
never catch up to you.
I'm gonna have to pack up
and be on the move
too, pretty soon.
Where are you going?
Nowhere.
You wanna come?
We could be back this
way in about a month.
I'm not supposed
to leave the state
without telling them.
So who's gonna know?
As long as you show up
when you're supposed to?
What if they check
up on me at work?
Well, no plan is perfect.
Bring her in.
Bring her in Otis.
Come on.
That's it.
Yeah, yeah.
Sit down.
Sit her down.
Oh, good, good,
good, good, good.
Take her blouse off.
Take it off.
Oh yeah, Otis, good.
My 0h, yeah, yeah.
Skirt, skirt, skirt.
Do it Otis,
you're a star.
(Man gagged and screaming)
Shut up!
I'll do what the hell
I want to do bitch!
Leave me alone!
Do it Otis.
Do it.
Henry look.
You got it.
Go for it boy.
Shut up!
Get the fuckin' kid!
(Screaming)
(Sound of neck breaking)
Son of a bitch!
Henry, look!
(Sound of neck breaking)
(Stabbing and groaning sounds)
Hey Henry?
Henry?
What?
Hi!
Looky here, where you at.
Bye!
Where you at?
Say hello, honey!
I have to wave to my baby.
Henry, We-
Henry, look at this, Henry.
Ain't that a view.
Otis!
No, Otis!
No!
Let's go!
What are you doing?
I want to see it again.
In jail?
Are you sure?
Is Lurleen there?
Does she know?
In the what,
in the army?
Go get her, will you?
Hi.
Hi, hi.
Do you miss me?
I miss you.
You did?
That's wonderful.
Are you being a good girl?
I don't think so honey.
I know I promised, but uh...
a couple of things
have happened here.
I know, he is a good soldier.
Soon, real soon, I promise.
I love you, too.
Yeah, put your
grandma back on, okay?
Hi.
I know.
I'll think about it.
I can't right now.
I will, soon.
I can't talk now okay,
I gotta go.
Okay.
Bye.
Great, great.
Oh!
I got one,
I got one, here, look.
Oh, look, look,
look, look, look.
Look at this, look at this.
Tight on there huh.
Yeah, no, no, no,
oh, no, I like this one better.
Look Henry, Henry look.
Oh, yeah, I love it,
I love her.
Oh god, how she looks,
isn't she pretty.
Ah god, look at that dress,
look at the way it moves.
Oh yeah!
Pull up next to her, real slow.
(Hits camera)
Look what you did!
Oh God!
Oh Jesus!
Look at it, it's ruined.
Damn Henry you ought to
look where you're driving.
Who the hell told you
to stick your head
out the window anyway?
You could have killed me!
Oh, that's right.
Blame it on me!
Oh, this fucking camera!
What did you do that for?
It wasn't any good anymore.
Could have fixed it.
Shit, the lens was
busted right off!
Could have fixed it!
How do you know,
you a camera repair man.
You should have said something.
You didn't give
me a chance, Otis.
You threw the fucker
right out the window.
It ain't my fault it broke.
Oh right.
Go back and get it if you want.
Yeah.
Want to get a beer?
Not particularly.
I want a beer.
If you want a beer so bad, Otis,
go ahead and get one.
All right, I Will.
See you later.
Yeah.
I talked to Lurleen.
Yeah?
You'd like her.
God, I miss her.
I'm thinking,
I might be heading on back home.
I quit.
You quit what?
My job.
What happened?
Nothing.
I just figured it
was time to go home.
You want to come with me?
I thought you wanted
to make some money?
Yeah, but,
I'm thinking,
I don't want to bring
Lurleen up here after all.
You know, that was my intention.
There's just too
much going on up here.
She'd get lost.
We're better off
living with mama.
I can work back home,
I won't make as much
money I'm sure, but,
I won't need as much either.
And I can live with mama.
You can stay there, too.
You figure it's safe to go back?
I hope so.
Leroy's in jail for murder
and his bond's
a million dollars.
So, unless he wins the lottery
Leroy won't be going
anywhere for quite a while.
Where's Otis?
He had a dinner
date I think he said.
Really?
Well.
Come with me?
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow.
Hmm.
Better think fast Henry.
You got your ticket?
Not yet.
But my mind's made up.
Might as well just do it.
Might as well.
I'd rather ride with you.
Let me think about it.
I'll tell you what,
let's me and you
go get us a steak dinner,
I'm buying, huh.
I got a new Visa card
I want to try out.
You've got a Visa card?
Yeah, who you think you're
associating with anyway?
Great, let's go.
Alright.
Where are we going?
We'll find a place.
Grab your jacket and let's go.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
Okay.
He's passed out.
I ain't
interrupting nothing, am I?
You guys want a beer?
You got any cigarettes?
Not since Superman died.
I gotta, go out and
get some cigarettes,
get some air.
Henry?
I'll be right back I promise,
I just need some air.
You want anything?
Otis?
Uh-uh.
How about getting your
poor 0l' brother a beer?
Hi.
Two packs of Kools.
What kind?
What?
Milds, Regulars, 100's...
Regulars.
Two, sixty.
Hey, how about those Bears?
Fuck the Bears.
Okay.
Hi.
That's a nice looking
dog you got there.
Thank you.
What kind is it?
Heinz.
What?
57 varieties.
It's a mutt,
half Yorkshire, half Shitzu.
Oh, Shitzu, huh.
What's his name?
Delores.
What?
Her name is Delores.
That's a nice name.
Hear that Delores?
Say thank you.
We gotta go.
Bye now.
(Screaming)
Come here, come here, come here.
No!
You god damn bitch.
(Screaming)
You son of a...
Adios, mother fucker!
(Screaming)
(crying)
Relax, take it easy.
No, no, no, easy.
Why don't you call the police?
No, no, no.
What about Otis?
It's not a good idea.
No.
What are we going to do?
Shut up, let me think!
Shut up!
Let me think!
(Sound of cutting)
(Splash)
You want to listen to the radio?
That was so awful.
I'm scared.
What do we do now?
We just got to keep moving,
that's for sure.
My sister owns a ranch
outside San Bernardino.
She raises horses there.
She's got about
1/2 dozen of them.
Arabians.
They're beautiful.
We can stay there
as long as we want to.
What about Lurleen?
We'll send for her,
soon as we get there.
You promise?
I promise.
I love you Henry.
I guess, I love you too.
Where are we going to go now?
We'll find a place.
You want to listen to the radio?
Okay.
(Turns on radio)
This is a nice guitar.
I used to play a little.
But, I'm out of practice.
We better go to bed now.