This morning, there were 3 cockroaches
Around me when I woke up.
I put them into an empty instant coffee
can and filled it with boiling water.
I had to drink it that while
everybody was looking at me.
So I opened the door
and went in my bedroom.
Because I wanted to get rid of the roaches.
I found that I was standing
on a ship made of wood.
The ship was slowly sinking.
That was like a silkworms'
bunkhouse or maybe a cabin.
I managed to save a drowning little boy.
I felt like all the children were mine.
I then found out that my second
child had disappeared.
The boy I rescued told
me while crying:
"Dad, why didn't you rescue
my younger brother?"
Who are those children?
In my dream, they are all mine.
The children's faces appeared once again
in front of me, then disappeared.
Those are perhaps my children
who faded away before being born.
What do those dreams foretell?
Is it a good omen?
A bad omen?
Actors:
Okada Mariko
Kamoda Kaizo
Iwasaki Kaneko
Takeuchi Toru
Kimura Naho
Makita Yoshiaki
Tsutsui Kazumi
I'm lost.
Don't make fun of me. Can someone
who's lost be able to know he's lost?
But... Everybody's lost, right?
- Everybody?
- You are too!
Once you understand you're lost,
you're not lost anymore.
You can go back from where you
came, you can ask your way too.
That's to say you're
heading to a destination.
I'm looking for my mother.
In my shop, you can find
everything you want...
My mother has given birth to me
But she didn't notice I was born.
Are you her mother?
Director: Yoshida Kiju (a.k.a Yoshihige)
What on earth is the matter?
Tell me...
I went shopping today.
I saw this girl accidentally.
She told me she was lost.
I can't explain it well.
We have to find the truth.
I'm going to tell her the truth.
You're a lost girl. This is
what you said at least.
I can't believe a girl of
your age can be lost.
You followed my wife here...
Why?
It's all right not to answer. But
what's sure is we don't know you.
I have to send you back to your mother.
Do you understand?
Where is your family?
Should I cut my eyebrows?
Should I cut it as thin as
those of a Daibatsu?
Why you suddenly bring that up?
If I cut it like that, when
I will look in the miror,
I will see the face of someone else.
It might be interesting.
Why did you take this girl home?
Tell me.
Why not let her live here?
If she's lost, you could have
taken her to a police station.
But you didn't.
Who are you?
I'm Keisaka Ayu's father.
Keisaka Ayu?
Do you know her?
Mum, save me!
I don't know this man.
He's not my father.
She's always lying.
She's my daughter.
He's not my father.
My daddy is here.
She's a very troubled daughter.
She doesn't like me.
A hidden microphone. That's how
I could trace her to your house.
Ifd rather leave.
There were those stairs
made of used bricks.
When you climb the stairs,
You can see the dome on the right.
If you climb the narrow stairs,
There is a road from where
you can see the dome.
Do you know that place?
I'm not sure...
I think the dome is on the left.
It was a long time ago...
It might be on the left.
It was the summer of 1952.
I was a university student
in engineering.
That's a pity. I first walked
along this road in april.
It's the place where I live now.
I haven't been there before.
Well... Where should we go
next to find your house?
To the television tower?
To a chapel?
Maybe you even live in a wrecker car?
You don't want to go home at all.
The situation has changed.
If we don't stop our plan before
4 o'clock, we might get arrested.
The situation has changed?
How?
On April 28, the San Francisco
Treaty was signed.
Japan announced its independence
from American occupation.
The same day the Tokyo
Ambassador M. took up his post.
On May Day, gathering in public
squares was strictly forbidden.
Several thousands of workers assembled
anyway and took back the squares by force.
The Police were then sent to
break up the demonstrators.
Many of the demonstrators were killed.
800 wounded,
and 1230 people caught.
May the 30th,
During the anticolonialism fights,
Beside Shinjuku, Kabata and Itabashi,
People rebeled in five other places.
The armed conflict started.
According to reports : 3 comrades
killed and 102 arrested.
June the 2nd, Sugo incident took place.
The 7th, 4,000,000 workers
were on strike.
On the 24th, Suita incident.
60 comrades were arrested.
On the 25th, during the
events in Shinjuku Station,
30 people were caught by the Police.
July the 4th, 1952.
Today.
What is the situation right now?
3 comrades, 3 killed, 2 comrades,
2 killed, 60 arrested, 102 arrested...
Why do you always use statistics?
We are not statistics!
Explain... Why do we have to stop?
Always explain, explain, explain!
What the hell do I know?
We can't stop now! What should
we do about our comrades?
We only have one chance to stop this plan.
At 4 o'clock, the man in charge of the
attack will receive the weapon.
It is on platform 3 of Shinjuku station.
If we can't give it, we won't be
able to proceed with the plan.
But we don't even know what they look like.
Who should we give the weapon to?
How do we find them?
Comrade Onko knows.
That is her task.
Time is up. I have to go.
Well, everyone...
This has nothing to do with me.
I object to this plan.
Plan D is about getting rid of the spy.
What happened?
There was a traitor among us. Our plan
has gone straight to the ennemy.
I won't go.
Then don't.
I don't wanna go either.
Who would want such a role?
But it has to be done.
Otherwise we will be annihilated.
I was against this plan,
But it's been carried out anyway.
Nobody can stop it now.
Even if we should stop it,
That is to say, even if you
give up, Plan D will go on.
This is a responsibility we all share.
Even if you don't want to.
I will go.
It will be over soon.
Who is the other?
The man who drafted this plan,
Ato Hakuchi.
He is from the Political Bureau.
It is all right to only help.
If I refuse, what happens?
Because he abducted a young girl,
Japan will lose an outstanding engineer.
40 years old.
Graduated in 1953 from Tokyo University
of Electronics and Optics.
Became a graduate student at MIT in 1957.
Was the backbone of the group that
developed the atomic bomb two years later.
He received numerous awards,
including the famous Faraday prize.
And came back to Japan
in 1960 to get married.
Ambassador J will arrive soon.
What will you do about him?
The property of laser beams
is to travel straight.
The directivity of these high frequencies
has an impressive demolition power.
From this day, from this moment,
Ato and Sei have disappeared.
If there's something or someone interfering,
We want to destroy the organization
and keep going forward. Forward.
We don't want to be diffused like
light or electric waves.
Who are you? Why are you doing this?
Tell me!
I can't tell you.
I will contact you later.
- I haven't said I will help you.
- You will.
- I will call the police.
- Go ahead.
Mom, let's kill daddy.
Daddy? How many daddies?
19, 20. A lot of them.
So many! How will we kill them?
I will stretch a naked wire tight at
the entrance. Daddies will be caught.
Awful! Don't you have
a better method?
I will tie them to a chair.
- They will struggle.
- That's why we have to tie them.
- Then cut their necks off.
- There will be some blood.
Let's hit them with a stick like pigs.
- They will cry.
- We make them get down on all fours.
They will beg on their hind
legs for food, like dogs.
But because they can't beg
nicely, I won't give them food.
That's sad.
If I were you, I would
give them some bread.
Mom, you are too kind to them.
Any other method?
We could make a big room
with no doors or windows.
Then, we take their clothes off, and make
them breathe gas until they are dead.
But daddies are coming one
after another. There's no end.
This room will be very busy.
Why do you want to kill them?
Because they are happy to be killed.
I've done some research,
but didn't find anything.
It seems there's no lost child anywhere...
- Maybe she always run away from home.
So there's no reported lost child.
The Police might think she will
go back home anyway.
- Let's kill him quick, Mom.
- Kill?
Kill who?
- Daddy.
- That man is your father, after all?
My father is you.
I want to go to the bathroom.
Can someone replace me?
Your break is in 15 minutes.
Can't you wait for a while?
My period just started...
Let's take a look at what you have!
Finally, I know what you're up to...
They will make a scene.
It will be their death cry.
What are you talking about?
Give it back to me!
No way!
Come on! Let me see your body.
I wanna know if you're really
on your period...
- What are you doing?
- You violated office regulations.
I need to look for proof.
Why are you following me?
Your friend blurted
out your little secret.
Ritsuko!
Why are you looking at me like this?
You look tired. You have only
been released for three days.
That's not it.
I betrayed us!
What?
- Wait!
- But...
Let me talk to her.
What's wrong? Tell me.
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone!
What did you say?
I didn't say anything about the
plan. Men can't understand.
It can't be explained.
I will make you some tea.
Give me a minute.
Do you want some milk with it?
All these numbers fell into the milk.
What numbers?
I am talking about this brain of yours.
I watched you when you were sleeping.
And sometimes I just wonder...
Who is the person sleeping at my side?
In his slowly growing beard,
there's one white hair.
I also wonder what's inside your head.
When I opened your skull
in halves with a knife,
There were a lot of numbers,
equations, plans with symbols...
Those numbers seemed to come
up from a network of wires.
They were coming one by one. Overflowing.
And there was not even a drop of blood.
I was scared. I kept my hand on your
skull, but the numbers kept coming.
Don't add sugar... or numbers
into the milk, will you.
That's how you really are.
I had already decided to marry
you before even knowing you.
I don't know if I should
be happy to hear that.
That day, my grandmother
talked to me about you.
That was the day I had to
decide at last what to do.
That was a beautiful day in June.
I woke up and then I opened
the window like I am doing now.
My entire body could feel the nice
Taste of salt the wind carried from the sea.
At the time,
I spontaneously thought I would
get married with the man that was
To be introduced to me that same day.
Already ten years ago?
But sometimes, I can't help but thinking
I could have led a very different life.
I could have chosen any life.
I slept with this girl...
Why are you telling me this?
I had to confess it to you.
This is the right time.
I love you.
- I have nothing to tell you.
- I didn't come for your answer.
I just transmit the order.
Ambassador J. will visit you the 4th. You
will hold him one hour later than planned.
I don't have the right to change his schedule.
But you will have to.
I'm in love with him.
So I came to see him.
Unfortunately, he pays no attention to me.
Yesterday, I tried tempting him.
I pretended I was lost.
Then, I took him to a deserted place.
I took off my clothes and asked
him to make love to me.
But he just stood there. He
didn't even look at me.
I am telling you the truth.
Try to tell me you love me.
It has absolutely nothing to do with love.
You did something terrible.
Are you talking about when
we were watching the movie?
I didn't sleep with you.
You did something terrible.
That's it.
So, tell me,
What is love?
This morning, 12 employees from N. chemicals
got nabbed for making barricades.
What is love?
Freedom.
The workers that would die to continue
with their strike at N. chemicals,
Do you feel love for them?
I never thought in such
an old-fashioned way.
You should clearly state that
you don't care about them.
I am starting the revolution for myself.
One becomes a spy for his own interest.
Are you talking about Ritsuko?
You start as a revolutionary
and you end up becoming a lesbian.
It is the times we are living.
Or should I say surprising rats?
No. When she got caught that night,
She had been beaten with a club,
jabbed, and then she had been raped.
She eventually managed to take
refuge in a pitch-black alley.
In other words, becoming a treacherous
spy is very similar to a sexual act.
A shudder of pleasure
goes through your body...
Stop!
I don't want to defend Ritsuko.
I was waiting for you.
I knew you would come.
I already told you you were not my father.
Could you please tell me
what's going on?
I am that child's father.
You don't believe me...
That's natural.
Even my child does not believe me.
What does it mean to believe?
You can't answer?
I will tell the truth.
I don't have any proof to show you,
so you will certainly not believe me.
There are many truths for everything.
The one who can give evidence wins.
I also had my own dream
when I was a kid.
I should be designing spaceships by now.
I had already come up with a name for it.
I wanted to call this nice,
pink capsule "Lion".
After graduating from high
school, I went to Tokyo.
Instead of spaceships,
I found something else.
Are you talking about this child's mother?
The very first time we met,
She told me that my hands and
feet were covering the earth.
And that for this reason, she would
change my world completely.
I was madly in love with her.
But one day,
Shortly after giving birth to this child.
She just disappeared.
I kept looking for her,
wandering up and down.
For a long time.
Three months ago, I saw her in the street.
I decided to follow her. She was alone.
She was working at the same place.
She treated her daughter as if
she was just another customer.
What do you think she told
me when she saw my face?
Can you imagine ?
17 years had passed.
From that day, we started
living together again.
But it didn't last two weeks.
If this is about an individual privacy
matter, I should not get involved...
But this woman seems to have problems.
She's just very interested in my research.
I see.
If you send laser beams on this material,
It creates three-dimensional images.
A space with enough depth to make
People think they can actually enter in it.
But of course, that's impossible.
It seems impossible to change the
schedule of Ambassador J too.
Whatever happens, everything
will soon be over.
If people can't enter this space,
It also means that we don't possess it.
If you ask me why,
It is because we can't possess time...
If I had known you 17 years
ago, we could have teamed up.
I was already there 17 years ago.
I was invisible to you at the time.
There is something I absolutely
have to tell you.
We have to stop the plan.
I know what happened to your friends
Who attacked the Ambassador's
car at 4 this afternoon.
You betrayed us, right?
Betrayed you? I don't have
enough freedom to do so.
How do you know this, then?
I was there when it happened.
I am not afraid of failing.
I am only afraid of having
to stop the plan from going on.
And what's more...
It doesn't serve our purpose anymore.
Comrade Shoda,
You have been accused of being
a spy by your comrades.
That's a matter of great importance.
In view of this charge, the present
central committee will examine you.
You are accused of helping the
infiltrated spy called Sei escape.
I don't know anything about that.
He disappeared while I was waiting.
Did you think we would believe
such a childish excuse?
I didn't know Sei was a spy.
He introduced himself as
the dispatch organizer.
He showed me his credentials.
Are you telling me you
didn't know all this?
I was sceptical about him
since the beginning.
That's why I reported him
to the Central Committee.
There is noone called Sei at
any level of the organization,
Anywhere.
But...
Enough is enough. Just spit out the truth.
The second charge against you
Concerns the raid on Ambassador M.
Even if you knew that it might provoke
The destruction of the organization,
You decided to actively help actively Sei
and jeopardized everything we built.
Me?
What about all of you?
Me... You know we were against
the plan from the beginning.
Don't you remember?
But this plan was ordered by Comrade Ato.
At the time...
He was a member of this
present committee, right?
Comrade Ato was a spy who managed
to infiltrate the Central Committee.
We got rid of him six months ago.
Half a year ago?
Sei planned this attack only to
jeopoardize the organization.
Impossible!
At first, when the organization fell into pieces,
We ended up isolated from the others.
We had to find something
to strike the enemy.
We had a cell meeting to decide what to do.
You remember, don't you? Answer me!
At the time,
Sei brought up the plan.
He told us he was the organizer
and explained the plan to us.
I see...
You imagined the plan. Sei just had
to bring it up during the meeting.
That's why everything went so smoothly.
No.
Sei discovered there was a spy.
He decided to stop the plan because
it was too dangerous to go on.
You are protecting him again!
That's a common method among spies.
Besides, Comrade Ato was already
expelled from the organization.
In other words, Sei is a spy, an informer
and a counter-revolutionary.
And you are the one who helped him.
To our organization,
Comrade Shoda, you too are an informer,
a counter-revolutionary and a spy.
We want to expel you from the organization.
Do you have an objection?
Daddy is still standing on the main road.
Daddy comes back everyday
with a different face.
And Mommy is always looking for him.
Daddy lies on the bed stealthily.
And mommy takes off his socks.
Mother often said that I couldn't
open the door without knocking.
Please, tie me up.
Why would I do that?
I am mommy.
Mommy speaks with a weird voice.
She says she's a slave.
She asks me to hit her.
She shows me her big bottom.
Daddy is big but he is nice.
He always said he hated hitting mommy.
They're urinating together.
After that, Daddy calls me.
He seems nice, so I come
and sit on his knees.
He leads me to the toilet.
He helps me sit and pee.
I suddenly feel very sad and put my
cheek on daddy's chest. I start crying.
Mommy makes daddy drink alcohol.
He falls off the chair.
He's now on his knees.
Mommy rides him like a horse.
Daddy's feet are flapping.
Daddy's stomach is bleeding.
Giddyup, giddyup, mommy says happily.
The next morning, when I wake up,
Mommy is nowhere to be found.
This house is different.
Please stop!
Do you want a drink?
There are so many things
I don't want to remember...
Ideally, I want to be alone
but you will not let me, right?
No mistake.
You're Sei.
As we speak, many things are happening.
That's scary.
You're Sei!
No.
I'm Ayu Keisaka's father.
I came to pick up my daughter.
You can see she's not here.
I thought you already took her home.
Didn't you?
Why are you angry?
Are you afraid I might accuse you
of kidnapping my daughter?
Just think about this...
After Ato and you disappeared,
Some terrible things happened.
You seem to have misunderstood
something...
Not only am I not Sei...
There's no such person like Sei.
What did you just say?
There's no Sei.
There's a rumor that he was in West
Germany 2 years ago to work...
...for an atomic organization.
It could be him.
I've talked to him, worked with him...
For that reason, Onko ruined herself.
Sei talked you into failing to
report at the Shinjuku Station.
You failed on purpose!
No doubt about that...
The group reported as planned
but because of you,
Four team members died for nothing!
Answer me!
Don't you think it's time for you
to admit what you did wrong?
You're really stubborn!
A spy obviously...
How about it?
If we rape her, she will maybe
come out with the truth...
Will you confess already?
Comrade Onko, if as you say, you are
fighting for the freedom of the proletariat,
Why did you abandon your companions?
Tell us...
Just admit you're a spy...
We could find out who the traitor isC
catch him. We could destroy him.
It's been 10 years since we first met.
- 27 years.
- What?
It's mid-June in 1980.
It was in 1952 when I first
met the man known as Sei.
I don't believe this man ever existed.
10 years ago, you told
me the same story.
Wait a moment...
If it is 1980 now, isn't there something strange?
- What's strange?
- There are too many people here.
Someone here should be already dead.
I don't know you. Who are you?
You will soon understand.
Why did you die?
That's a horrible thing to ask...
That's a scary story.
I don't think any of you really
want to be confronted by the truth.
I don't mind hearing the truth.
Me neither.
It could be helpful for our next battle.
What are you talking about?
Everyone has the right
to find out the truth.
I've never seen you.
Why are you here?
We are holding a meeting to
determine our plan of action.
- A plan?
- We will start the revolution.
She took me here.
This girl... she's my daughter.
- There's no girl here.
- No?
I can't see anything.
You can't?
What's going on?
You should know her.
I know the girl.
I touched her with this hand.
How is that possible?
You recorded everything on film...
All right, let's watch it then.
What's wrong with you?
She's my child...
I don't see anyone.
I don't want to see it. Stop the film!
What can you see?
The girl, of course.
There's no girl...
Your emotions are getting
the better of you.
It's just a shadow.
No, you're wrong.
Then, show her to us.
I'm going to introduce you all to her.
We have to look for her.
Let's get back to what's important.
The death of Onko was politically motivated!
No... She died by accident.
It was at the beginning of autumn.
Hoodlums did it
They were infamous
for their sordid dealings.
They got arrested and said...
...they did it for fun.
That's not true.
Onko was killed by order.
On March 29 1952,
I was in the mountains in west Tama
With 50 comrades.
When we woke up in the morning,
Everything was covered with dew.
Surrounded by more than 130 policemen,
We ran away like monkeys.
We almost died of starvation
and cold the next day.
We only had chocolates at that time.
Our only weapon...
At that time,
We ran away from the swamp that
was swollen because of the rain.
I kept repeating to myself :
"Comrade Joseph Vissarionovitch Stalin...
The situation is growing strained,
But we, the proletariat, we
will eventually win in the end."
He appeared many times in front of me.
He was smiling at me.
So many times...
Stop it! You have to tell us the truth!
Ambassador M.?
Come with us!
Who are you? I don't
need to come with you!
My wife has nothing to do
with all that. Let her go.
Is this a ploy? A ruse? Do you
really have to use your guns?
You're talking too much!
The bullets in this gun are real...
What happened?
Tell me!
You, the 70's guerrilla...
You were one step behind us.
Ambassador M. and his wife
are gone on a very private trip.
We won't tell you the destination.
Ambassador M.?
We're after Ambassador J.
Whoever you're talking about...
Just find him quickly!
He's right. Let's have
them lead us to him.
Do the V sign please...
Please, look at the camera!
Please, smile at the camera.
One more time please.
Look here, please.
AFP. What are your impressions?
Freedom is everything.
AP News Agency.
Have you read the statement of your
President that asks for your security.
The group that kidnapped me told me.
News Weekly.
Before I ask a question that represents
800 million Chinese people.
In 1980, at the beginning of a glorious era,
I want to express my respect for the courage...
...you showed during the incident.
Please, do the V sign.
Could you both smile, please.
Of the 4.6 billion humans on this planet,
3.6 billion, regardless of their political system,
have been liberated from fear and hunger.
Do you think it's the result
of a peaceful coexistence?
Tell us, what are the results
of this war of liberation?
The beef steak was particularly excellent.
People of the world...
Just imagine... Without previous
notice, one day, suddenly,
You find yourself involved in an accident.
The greatest happening show being aired :
"You are a hero of the world".
This week, it was "A diplomat kidnapped."
It was broadcasted live at the same
time in 140 countries by satellite.
See you again next week!
Is that all? Nothing has been figured out yet!
It's only just begun!
We must keep fighting!
We had wonderful, ideal times.
At least, for three months...
While the Proletariats of the world
unified to fight on the same front,
Our Proletariat got nylon stockings and toothpaste.
And a face that shows no hunger.
Instead of standing in the front,
They chose to go to a Peace Festival and dance.
Not to forget the nice presents
Ambassador M. brought.
Weapons with very good performance
and machines to manufacture stockings.
They all think I killed myself, right?
You do too?
Given the circumstances, it's
natural to think like that.
However, I swear I won't die.
We failed to carry out the plan.
We will all be arrested soon.
So...
We won't be able to see
each other for 3, 4 years.
It wasn't our plan's fault though.
It's our phantom democracy
that should be blamed.
After 4 or 5 years, we'll see each other again.
In a dark corner of this society...
Even if it's not the kind of society we want.
The truth is I knew the spy.
I was the lover of Comrade Ato Hakuji,
And I knew the spy from the beginning.
Ato was the spy.
I swear it's here.
It's all right to open the door?
I don't want to see my mother.
Am I not your mother?
She killed my father. She's
certainly still in there. Hanged.
I could help her.
She might still be alive.
Why?
That's my duty.
People always have obligations.
If there were no obligation at all,
People could do whatever they wanted.
No, I don't think so.
I don't want to rescue my mother.
Now the committee will interrogate
the comrade Shoda.
The Party approved this fair inquiry.
You are guilty of being a counter revolutionary,
an informer and a double agent.
Shoda, do you want to defend yourself?
You now have a chance to speak
freely and give us your side.
Shoda... let's begin.
What I'm looking for...
What I've been trying to find for so long is...
My child.
We absolutely have to hurry now.
Please... Help me find her.
Who are you?
Are you here to testify in favor of Shoda?
I'm his wife.
A wife's testimony has no credibility.
Shoda, do you really know this woman?
Right now, we're very busy with the revolution.
Look.
Please, listen to me.
My daughter has been kidnapped. She's
been enslaved and will be auctioned off.
Don't worry...  I was 16 years
old when I was sold.
But I've not been sold to men...
I've sold myself to the revolution.
Did you give birth to a boy or a girl?
I'm not sure. Now that you ask me...
How come you don't know?
Wait!
I don't remember clearly.
When I was 13 years old,
The one who was kidnapped was maybe myself.
I can't remember.
In short, you are your own child...
No. Her name is Ayu.
So you're Ayu.
Wait! A leader has to
take his responsibility.
You have to help her find this girl.
Let's play a game to decide
who the leader is.
Who is the leader? Who is
qualified to act as the leader?
We should have a democratic election.
You are the leader!
Thank you all for electing me.
Bring the file of Shoda's wife, Kanako.
There's nothing in her file.
That's all we have.
There's no record...
...from when she was 13 years old.
Take a look at what's written
from when I was 24.
It was in 1960.
It's blank.
And when I was 34 years old?
That's the last page.
There's no record.
That is the leader's responsibility.
The leader has responsibility for everyone.
He's the one responsible.
Let's decide according to
the principle of our squad...
Guilty! Guilty! Guilty!
Guilty! Guilty!
Guilty!
What about you?
I don't know... I waive my right to vote.
You don't have the right to waive...
We must reach a unanimous decision.
Innocent!
I beg your pardon?
Your silence speaks for itself!
In this world, silence makes every
decision sound like its opposite.
I can't make such a decision.
You have to answer my question then.
What's the only qualification
needed to become a leader?
Answer me quickly!
Love...
The correct answer is "heroism".
He never told you this?
Then... he's guilty.
Death by hanging!
Comrades...
Goodbye...
Myself...
We have to stay together!
What did that person want to say?
That I shouldn't have opened the door.
Let's go back home.
Who's that? Who?
Tell me!
He's my father... Ato Hakuji.
The squad already left.
Yes... To kidnap the Ambassador...
The spy has been exposed.
Everything is in order.
The ennemy doesn't have the slightest idea...
Yes... This afternoon at 4 o'clock, third street.
They will all die soon. Until then,
they will keep playing games.
The Ambassador said that in the last 20 years,
you made a great contribution to science.
Your government gave you a decoration and
sent you here. What are your impressions?
What Ambassador?
Ambassador F. M.
In September 1989, after 20 years...
...Ambassador M. has been sent again to Japan.
The youth are taking the easy
route of going against the past.
Do you want to have a word with them?
About the development of science
plundering people's freedom...
What is your opinion?
What do you think of the young men
who turn homosexual to feel free?
Do you sometimes feel disillusionment?
Do you like the sea?
What brand of alcohol do you like?
When do you think the
study of science will end?
Please, ask me questions I can answer?
What did you want to become
when you were a boy?
A film director.
What about you Mrs.?
When your husband does
his research, what do you do?
I think about my husband...
Doctor, as a scientist, what do you believe in?
I thought the laser beams were necessary...
I managed to turn things nobody
can normally see into visible objects.
I made a revolution in the
field of electronic engineering.
The next revolution came soon
after and was superior to mine.
It was easier than crushing a baby...
The life of new technology is now very short.
From when it is born to its maturity...
And then to its death...
In a word, it's the only thing I knew...
...about life.
In a word...
Doctor, my last question...
What is your ultimate purpose in life?
To be the best husband.
You called me.
I'm sure you called me.
Why?
You're the one who called for me to stop.
What?
I didn't ask you to stop. I didn't even talk.
I'm in a hurry right now...
In a hurry? Where are you going?
What do you intend to do?
It's none of your business.
Then, take me with you!
Take me out of here.
Take you out of here?
We're at the terminus of the subway.
Anybody is free to walk here...
What is this place?
That's the place where
we're supposed to meet up.
Who? Who decided that?
I have to kidnap someone...
The person you're going to kidnap... It's me.
Nobody can kill me.
What time is it now?
Noon...
Our companions are gathering up...
- What time is it now?
- 1 o'clock.
- I'm talking. What's the time?
- 2 o'clock.
They are waiting for me...
- What time is it now?
- 3 o'clock.
They're moving now... The time?
Just half past 3.
I didn't go.
What time is it really?
I didn't give them the weapon.
They are certainly confused...
What time is it now... What time is it?
I have to give them the weapon!
You have to? It's impossible...
Give it to me! Give it!
No! You can't!
It's too late anyway...
It's not necessary anymore.
My god... my nihilism...
It's not because I was afraid.
I know... The uselessness of
all this overwhelmed you.
We'll certainly never see each other again...
I'm the spy who betrayed you. Go!
Go right now! You have to stop the plan!
Otherwise everybody will be caught.
There never was any spy...
Yes, there was! I knew him!
It's over.
You accomplished your task.
Hurry! You have to go to the 3rd
line's platform of the Shinjuku Station.
On the second bench... a man with
a bandage on his right hand...
It's completely over... Nothing's left...
- There are still things to do.
- To leave for a distant place?
I'm going to get rid of what
I thought was my God.