- Translation by Laink -
Hey, little out of the car.
Get out of the car!
Get out of the car, go!
Hey brat, you can go get him out?
Go man, go out of the car ...
Opens.
Go out of there!
Fucking come out!
Brothel down the window!
Why did you sell the car?
We could not leave
front of the house, TJ.
Why?
- It's not healthy
- It's not!
I do not want to hear about it.
Well, hello.
Good morning.
I have money to buy
to eat today?
Uh, yeah, sorry.
Thank you.
Have a nice day, TJ.
Between go.
Get up.
Please ...
You just fuck me.
Who's there?
Oh damn!
Cemino.
Cooper.
Forwood.
Edreden.
Fletcher.
Forney.
TJ Forney returned?
Welcome back, TJ.
Morrodger.
Sumner.
Well then, you're more like
a drive is it?
- Do not fuck ...
- And if you sucked my dick?
Suck my dick!
Suck my cock whore!
- Hello dear.
- Hi.
Did you have a good day?
It was horrible.
Why is my angel?
I do not know, it sucked.
You want me t'allume light?
Why?
I seem to be in the dark?
I do not know, a little.
I think I need new glasses.
In fact I do not even know
if they are mine.
They are at that time?
I do not know.
You see better with?
Your father is up?
Why?
He slept all day?
You know, sometimes people are upset
When bad things happen.
But they resumed after.
Want some milk?
Yeah.
Ok, how's the arm?
We will turn a bit
your wrist, like this ...
In the other direction ...
Well.
Considering that the dreams
take a metaphorical role
in fiction as
they do in life,
how metaphorical function
these dreams are involved?
For an actor, are they
premonitions, or desires?
Or maybe even nightmares?
Given what we know
About Mauritius:
where it comes from, how was her childhood,
I think we can assume
with certainty that his dreams
are a reflection of his relationship
with his mother.
TJ! What are you doing?
Bring me that.
Well, poor idiot!
You find that funny?
Sucking dick
you find that funny?
I'll tear your fucking head!
I'll kill you!
You think you can draw
on my car whore?
- Hey, loose it!
- Get out bitch!
- I said stop!
Well what do you do ma'am?
And you what do you do?
I have not finished with you,
little shit.
Are you okay?
I bleed?
I think so.
And me?
You want me back?
Come on.
Come!
I can not believe it
called me "madam".
I have a mind to be called
"Madame" in your opinion?
I guess ...
Thank you.
I have to look old.
So I'm a little
Now a hero, huh?
In fact, I just thought the fact
that on returning home,
I could blame all
the day if I had not helped,
and see the information, that'd have
was beaten to death in a parking lot.
I just did for me in fact,
I am selfish.
Sorry.
Sorry to be like that.
That's it.
Over.
Eh! You do not want your bike?
Shit!
Glad to have met you.
Dad?
Grandma, where is it Dad?
Hi TJ, he went to the doctor.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
Where's the washing machine?
- My father will return soon ...
- Where's the washing machine?
Why?
Have you ever been fucked in the mouth?
- No ...
- Love you be?
It's there.
But why, you can not ...
What are you doing?
What are you doing? ..
Why are you here?
You better treat me
as if I lived here.
Or I'll kill you.
And I kill your family.
You can not smoke here ...
What are you doing?
You can not smoke here.
You could turn it off, please?
And if I put out in your mouth?
TJ, who is it?
My name Hesher.
I am a friend of your son.
What's he doing here?
It is a laundry.
Can I talk a second?
Why he smokes in the house?
I told him he could not.
- A friend of yours?
- I said that ...
You know you have only four strings?
Hello, young man!
Hello, old lady.
Can I help you?
No, it's good.
Oh damn!
Shit!
For crying out loud ...
Now you have more channels.
- Why did you get?
- What?
- This is your room?
- No, the garage.
Your friend does not want dinner?
- There is no hunger.
- Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
What it does
in the garage?
I do not know, I told him he
the guitar could do it.
Oh, it's darling, it's nice to have
again a little music in this house.
This is a new friend?
Yeah, if you like ...
Your grandfather played the harmonica
for a long time.
Sorry dear,
there is more milk.
I can make you
eggs if you want.
No thank you.
Would you like to go for a walk?
I can not, I have things to do.
I mean, later this afternoon.
I do not know, ask me when I return.
Okay.
I want to retrieve the car.
It is not for sale.
But I want to buy it,
when you want how much?
Sit down.
1800 dollars, not counting
Taxes, fees ...
-I can pay.
-On top of that,
you need a driver's license,
and I'm sure you have not.
You must have a certificate of insurance,
and I'm sure you do not have that.
And even if you had all this
I could not sell it to you because it is not for sale. Point.
Now if you could
let me work.
- Hello.
- Hi.
How are you?
Uh, I bought an ice cream.
It's too nice, thank you.
I bought it there.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Hi!
That day I had prepared
a cherry pie.
Only then I realized I had
used a new product, Fluffo.
And I never reused.
I served the cake and then ...
it started to swell in their mouths,
they could not swallow it.
The fucking Fluffo.
TJ Hello, hello darling.
Who will walk with me tomorrow morning?
TJ?
I can not grandmother
I have to go to school tomorrow.
Okay, you're always welcome.
What?
The school?
Will work with your grandmother.
He is right TJ,
I would appreciate some company.
Of course.
Your grandmother's going to work
alone in the morning?
You can not lift your ass
an hour earlier?
And if she was raped?
What?
Have you not heard
the killer of the same?
- The killer of the same?
- Yeah killer ...
The killer of the same
killed 13 or 14 old.
He chokes with
their pants dirty.
I do not think it violates the
but the fingers and everything!
Ok, that's enough.
I say it like that.
Your grandmother needs to go walking
you should go.
To do that she is raped.
Why would anyone
would rape me?
Damn, I know.
But people do that.
There's some fucking tared out.
You've fucked my body,
kind of asshole!
Put your head in there,
eats the pellet!
Eat this fucking patch!
Let me go!
Eats the pellet motherfucker!
Are you ready?
I want to go.
This is for our good.
TJ, we'll be late.
Welcome to all in this group
help against pain.
My name is Meryl.
We will start
by us with
and briefly explain why we are here.
Hello, you want to start?
We are family Boulder.
My name is Colleen.
And this is my husband, Jack.
Our daughter Cynthia ...
was murdered last year.
She was the victim
a violent attack, unfair and foolish.
We're here because we need help.
We lost our baby.
Hello, my name is Jack.
As my wife said, we are here
for answers
and seek help
against this pain.
Thank you.
Colleen and Jack
welcome.
Sir?
Well, okay.
My name is Paul Forney,
and this is my son TJ.
We are here because I lost
my wife, the mother of TJ,
there are nearly two months.
We're just trying to overcome
these things ...
and we are looking ...
advice ...
about these things.
So ... that's it.
Well. Hello Paul.
Hi TJ.
I understand how it is
difficult to lose her mother.
Would you introduce yourself?
Say a few words to the group?
What's your fucking problem?
- What did you fuck?
- And you, what's wrong?
This asshole took my head
above a urinal
And you're sat there
and you have watched.
Get out.
Get out of with my grandmother!
Bar yourself.
Let me go!
I'll get dressed.
Wait for me in front of my van, right?
We're going where?
What are we doing here?
We're going. Go.
What are you f-
What are we doing here?
What are you doing?
We're going!
Shit!
Come on, we're going.
What are you doing?
What is that? Wait, stop!
Stop! You can not ...
Are you crazy?
We're going.
Stop!
You enter.
No.
Shit! No, no, no.
We're going! We're going now!
Start from here!
Please, stop!
No, no, no!
It's wrong?
Go quickly let's go!
Hurry!
Shit!
It's closed! Open!
Opens the door is closed!
Open the door!
Oh damn! Eh, eh!
- Come into the van!
- No.
Damn, just in the van, now!
I'll go for it.
Guy?
Man, whore, it was great.
You got robbed on at least two meters.
Ok, here we go.
Go.
Bonjour, Madame.
I'm from the police.
I need to speak with Thomas Forney.
- How?
- Thomas Forney, he there?
You are Thomas Forney?
Uh, yes.
We have a few questions to ask.
It's just a few questions, man.
- What?
- You can dress please?
Considers this as a warning.
Evidence or not,
you have our attention.
Turn your head to the right.
It is not good
us on the back.
What happened is a crime
that can make you stay
long time in prison.
It was you who did it?
- Not really.
- "Not really"?
I have not.
You just said not really.
What does that mean not really?
I said that I had
not, right?
Just before, I asked you if you had
done, and you said not really.
I do not remember
of what I said.
Why would you do such a thing?
- You want a peanut?
- No.
So what did they want the chickens?
In your whore?
I do not know. Delving into your cavities?
Get out, ok?
- What they have done?
- They took my fingerprints mess!
Yeah, so what?
Leave me alone.
Okay, I'll go.
But on one condition.
Do you think she shaves her pussy?
What are you doing here?
What you are you doing here?
You're not doing the shopping.
Spy on you this chick.
- No.
- Yes I followed you.
- You want to do it?
- No!
Ah, good.
You can not kiss here.
You must be much closer.
What?
- You want to type it.
- Shut up.
Dude, there's nothing wrong
you want to type it.
Stop saying that.
Dude! If you want to type it,
there is nothing wrong with that, do not be ashamed!
The man clap vaginas
for hundreds of years.
Probably more.
Dude, there's nothing wrong
to want the pussy!
Where are you going?
- My Home.
- I brought you.
No thank you.
Well, okay, but you there will be
in 5 minutes with me ...
In cycling, you there will be
what, fifteen minutes?
Okay, but not talk to me, ok?
I will say nothing.
Listen dude.
Sorry for the fire the other night
it was completely out of
control, stupid and irresponsible.
So sorry.
Hey, I want to give you that.
I do not want.
Dude, you're gay?
I understand you.
Shit ...
What are you doing?
Stop the car, I want out.
If you go out of the van, I tear the cock
and I kiss for you.
It's crap.
I'm really sorry,
I do not know what happened.
You blew my bumper,
poor bitch!
It's not true! You are a dirty brutalized!
You are really stupid!
What is your problem?
I do not know what
happened, sir ...
Be careful when
you drive a car, bitch!
I think I can help you.
I saw everything.
She was there and you're it
back into it backwards.
I did what?
What's your problem? You're it
back in, poor sod.
I do not see what you mean!
You should probably start thinking
about how you will pay that.
I do not have him back in!
Damn, you calling me a liar?
Look, I ...
What is happening here?
I do not know, you seem to me
take a fucking liar.
I do not ...
- Okay, I want no problems.
- You want no problems?
No.
I think so, Miss Piggy.
This is ridiculous!
Come on, we're going.
Your girlfriend looks sexy
to have some problems.
We're going nowhere.
You know?
- Hi ...
- Hello.
Sometimes you spend a bad day
and you think it can not be worse.
and suddenly you realize the full
different ways it can be.
No thank you.
Depart from me this.
One day two years ago, I
four chicks in the back of the van.
They had great desire to kiss,
and had already begun.
I licked one, I put
one finger to another,
but there were two other chicks
who also wanted to participate.
So with my other hand
I finger the other girl,
and I had my toe
in the bottom of the fourth.
And I was going crazy,
What was too, you see.
I do not understand who was who, I
was getting sore tongue,
my fingers were tired ...
I stopped, and you
know what happened?
They started doing stuff
them, to lick, to be fingered.
I sat and watched.
I pulled out my dick and I
motion. Everyone was a winner.
Is it a
perverse metaphor for me?
A what?
Whatever.
Stop!
Please, stop!
What was that whore?
- I saw a mouse.
- What?
You?
I think I have the
land in the mouth.
So what do we do?
Good.
- We arrived.
- Where?
Go!
Where are we?
What?
Whose house is this?
Yeah, nah, I do not like too
The Chinese food ...
Excuse me, I speak!
- She who this house?
- This house?
- Yeah.
- To my uncle.
Where is your uncle?
- Right there.
- Where?
Damn!
- You were dirty.
- Yeah, now I'm wet.
You're dirty and wet?
I'm coming.
Now I am dirty
and wet too.
R2!
R2! Turn off the fucking
trash compactors!
Damn!
R2!
All fuckin compactors
waste that level!
Shit, they shoot stuff!
Son of a bitch!
How did you meet this guy?
I do not know, he moved in
my grandmother, I think.
How?
He rents a room?
No, not really.
It's a long story.
Fish, fish!
We'll make a fire.
Fuck you, bitch!
I jumped over the fire ...
I have an appointment with the doctor.
What?
It hurts when I urinate.
Does he just leave us here?
- I think so.
- We'd better go.
Let's go.
What's his name?
- Hesher.
- Hesher is a name that?
I do not know.
- He has a name?
- I do not know.
All my shoes are soaked.
- How old is he?
- I do not know.
You know something about him?
No, not really.
Fortunately, you were behind me
when I got in that car.
I was terrified, I have no insurance,
I can not pay me,
and I could not pay
to repair his car.
How do people do?
I mean, I have a job,
but it's almost a joke.
I have been here almost a year
and I do 15 hours a week ...
Why do not they give me
more hours in your opinion?
It is because I am no?
Do you found me no
when you came to my car?
No.
I even have enough money
to pay my rent there.
I will soon have to start
stuff for sale ...
Here ...
I have two dollars.
What is sad is that I
might need it.
- Well, I give them to you.
- No.
Oh no, let it be
not a fine, pity.
Oh no.
Shit!
Shit, shit, shit!
What have I done to deserve this
chain of shit all the time?
I'm sure if I died,
no one would notice.
I notice it.
If you died now, I would notice.
Especially because I would be sitting
in a car next to a dead woman.
Do not call me "lady"
please.
- Hi, TJ.
- Hello, Grandma.
So what?
- You've fucked?
- No.
Where you were today?
The térapie, 15.30.
I had to go alone.
Sorry I forgot.
Super.
You know, it's also hard
for you than for me.
I waited outside the school
for 45 minutes.
I told you I
not want to go.
Perhaps you should let me know the next
Once you decide to not go.
- I did it, I said I wanted to go.
- No, you did not!
I've told you a thousand times!
- No you did not tell me!
- If you listen but never!
You have not said that!
You said you wanted no
go, not that you would go.
- It's been what's the difference?
- A big difference for me!
Sitting alone in
a room filled with shabby.
Boys, please.
I do not feel very well.
You can pass me my pills?
- Did you tell him fingering her pussy?
- Shut up!
- TJ!
- What?
Watch your language!
- Did you hear what he just said?
- Whatever.
Talks like that again and
you go to your room.
My room?
You start to punish me now?
Yes, maybe.
It's more for your irresponsibility
for your language.
I mean, I had to take you
with the police.
I'm sorry for making
move your ass from the couch.
And I'm really sorry I have to put
pants for the first time in months.
- TJ!
- What?
Eh! Enough!
As soon as I am right that's enough?
I do not want to hear you!
Okay.
And then shit!
Are you happy? Huh?
I missed something?
Not really.
He said bullshit,
he threw his plate
too.
But I think he did it because
he had nothing more to say.
Little was right.
He felt bad, so he left.
I do not know.
I wish I could do
something more.
- It's delicious.
- Oh, thank you.
Hey, what is green and slimy,
and smelling the bacon?
I do not know.
Think, what is green, viscous
and smelling the bacon?
Well, I do not know.
I go to bed.
I do not feel well.
Ok
- You found?
- Found what?
What is green, viscous
and smelling the bacon?
I do not know.
- Could you do me a favor?
- Yes.
Could you pass me
the bottle in the cupboard?
- Who, him?
- Yes, thank you.
Nothing.
This is the finger of Kermit the Frog.
You know, with Miss Piggy.
What is that?
Medicinal cigarettes,
to help against nausea.
- You could light a match please?
- Of course.
I can watch them quickly?
I'll be right back.
May I?
Thank you.
What is that?
It's a pipe, there is water
to filter the smoke.
This is the most
healthy smoking weed.
I'll show you how.
You see that hole right there?
You must put your finger on it.
You heat the ball.
When it filled with smoke
like that, you let go here.
That's it.
I'll turn it on for you.
Put your finger on the hole here.
I turn it on and you suck.
Go ahead, suck.
This is like that.
Take a deep aspiration.
Well.
My God.
Do it again.
No, I think it's going.
Thank you.
I'll finish it.
How old are you?
Everybody cares.
You look a little older than TJ.
- Who?
- Oh, stop.
You're not a bit old
to be the same with TJ?
- And you?
- No, I'm his grandmother.
That's true.
I had a snake, a big thing.
Every week, I
gave a live mouse.
Snakes eat other snakes
because they have good shape.
Anyway this one was eating mice.
I once put a mouse in his cage.
He found the mouse and attacked her.
And this mouse, she got up
on its hind legs
and she has done for a stroke
punched in the mouth.
You're kidding.
It happened again.
The snake tried again to eat.
and she struck again.
The snake did not know what to do.
He started in a corner and cried.
And the fucking ruled the mouse cage.
For weeks, she looked in
the cage, as if possessed.
As if it were on a couch, with a
scratching their balls and chewing peanuts.
Quiet, you know.
I tried to give other mice
but when I put in a new mouse
the cage, it hid behind the old mouse.
The snake was scared.
He died of hunger.
In a cage full of mice.
So TJ is a mouse?
I do not know, maybe.
So who am I?
You, an old lady.
No, I'm a grandmother.
Yeah, you're a grandmother.
You know what? Grandma, I will
go for a walk with you tomorrow morning.
That's nice.
Where are you going?
I do not know, I'll go with you.
Regardless, in the district, I guess.
Good.
- Have fun.
- No, I'll go with you.
We'll see when you get back.
Why you do not send it?
Of course.
I can tell you?
Wait two seconds.
Can not you see I'm on the phone?
- I must speak.
- I am at tel-, wait outside.
Wait outside!
You came for me
you can break your neck?
- What?
- I have the money.
What money?
You said that with 1800 dollars
I could get the car.
Are you kidding? I said that even if you had
1800 dollars I could not you sell it.
- It is not here anyway.
- How are you?
I feel like I have had
this conversation too many times
- And I will not get it again because it is not here.
- What does it mean?
She's not here
It's over, she's gone!
- But it is where?
- Kid, it's over. Going on.
Goodbye, going into.
What is the matter?
I have to go before
I hurt someone.
Money for the fine of Nicole.
Kisses, TJ.
Hello, this is Nicole. I'm not there to
time. Leave a message and I'll call you back.
Hello, this is TJ.
Sorry to bother you, I think
I just want to talk to you.
I have a gift for you, so ...
I'll just come and
deposit it with you.
Ok, here ... hello.
Fuck you!
Eh! Dude!
What are you doing bitch?
- Move back!
- Damn!
Fuck you! Get out!
And you're a dirty whore!
I hope you die and
no one will notice
because you're nothing but a big prostitute.
- Dude, calm down.
- Casse-toi,
or I swear I'll
shatters the skull!
I will never see you again
you and your filthy heads!
Fuck you!
I hate you!
Hey, I want to talk to you.
- Hey, man, I want to talk to you.
- Let me whore!
Dude, calm down.
Calm down! Holy shit!
I just want to talk to you a second!
- Calm down bitch!
- Well it loose, what are you doing?
Kind of fag!
No!
Fuck you, assholes!
You?
TJ?
In 15 months of school ...
An extensive training in
Athletics, Physics, Chemistry ...
I train them to be the best, and
they expect me to be the best.
- Where's my car?
- Damn!
- Are you weighed?
Tell me where it is or I
I cut the toe.
They sent to
junkyard.
It is in this fucking
car cemetery, asshole!
- That's bullshit!
- Why would I lie?
Because you're an asshole!
Tell me where it is!
They took her car to the cemetery!
I swear to God! Damn!
Damn!
If you lie, I'll cut all
your toes, right?
Yeah.
You got something to say?
- You want to go home right?
- Let me go!
Damn!
Shit!
- What are you doing?
- What?
What's your problem?
I just save you.
I said I wanted to see you!
How many times I have to tell you?
Leave me!
Come on, honey.
- Go, my heart!
- What is there here?
Let's go boys, we
will be late.
And the pizza?
- You can eat in the car.
- Cool!
Honey, what's there is there?
Take my car, you drive.
- You can open the door?
- Of course.
What a great idea.
I will be careful to tell them
our old microwave
is a gift from you.
Well, they do not even know
who I am anyway.
- Honey, what are my friends.
- I know.
I just do not know why
they must be given as gifts.
A microwave and a bottle of
whiskey that is not so much.
And flowers.
- Flowers?
- Flowers!
- Mom, you can turn on the radio?
- Yes, my angel.
Help!
What are you doing?
Back, back!
But what are you doing?
I do not know.
Where you been?
- Sorry.
- Where you been?
Sorry.
It is 10 o'clock in the morning.
How do I deserve this?
I do not know.
Go to your room.
There is someone for you at the door.
Hesher is not there.
I have come to see you.
I did not know if I should come or not.
but I could not
help but think about it.
I thought if I were you
would be angry and you hate me.
but after I told myself that if I did not come,
You would think that I do not care,
and also you would have hated anyway.
So I decided to come.
That's what I thought.
So here I am.
What do you want?
I want to apologize.
I feel bad about
of what happened.
- It is not important.
- If it's in a.
It is important to me.
TJ I love you very much.
And I understand if you do
not want to be friends.
but I never meant to hurt you.
It's just ...
Sometimes ...
I do not know ...
But I thought I
had to tell you that.
You still hate me anyway, but
I thought I'd come to tell you that.
And I said. Ok, goodbye.
Sorry I broke your lamp.
No problem.
And sorry I treated
heavy prostitute.
No problem.
You are not fat.
But I am a prostitute?
No. Maybe.
We are here
to mourn the loss
and celebrate life
Madeleine Francis Forney.
Madeleine was very much loved
as a wife,
mother, grandmother and friend.
Now, Ms. Rosowski,
a dear friend from the neighborhood, will
quickly say a few words.
I did not know Madeleine
long enough.
As soon as I moved
in the neighborhood,
She treated me as if
I was in the family.
She had a heart so
nice and wonderful.
We shared wonderful walks.
And we loved
be together.
I will miss our walks,
and above all our discussions.
I will always remember
what she said:
"Life is like walking
in the rain.
You can hide and shelters you,
or you can get wet. "
Well, thank you.
TJ, I think you should
say something.
Come on, TJ.
Sorry.
Well, we should conclude
the ceremony with ...
Yeah, I just completed
what the kid said,
because I think I know
what he meant.
What are you doing?
Sir, we ...
Touch me, whore.
Back, sitting up.
You will not want me here,
and I do not want to be here.
I've just not for me,
I come to it, whore.
She tried to tell you something,
but you were too stupid to listen.
So if you could close a few seconds
I'll say what I want to say.
and you will see me again.
I tore a gas tank
an old Chevy.
I wanted to explode,
So I did.
But I have not thought about the parts
metal that would fly everywhere.
I almost killed him.
I woke up in hospital
and a doctor told me: "Son ..."
I said "call me
son, asshole. "
He said, "you've
ripped a testicle. "
I lost a testicle, like that.
I became insane, I hit
nurse, doctor, I remember.
They put me in a juvenile detention center
and I was just thinking about my fucking balls.
What is going to do?
I had to pick her up, so I
ran away and I looked for.
I could not find her.
Well, one night ...
I was there, I chiais I
looking at my balls.
I stared at that old soft bag
where was my testicle before,
and then I saw my right testicle,
for the first time.
I thought: "Damn, man! My balls!"
"Look! I still have a testicle!"
No?
It is well, it works.
God or the fucking devil, who he is,
left me with a good ball!
I still have a fucking testicle and
works, and works as my cock whore.
You lost your wife.
You lost your mother.
I lost my balls.
Damn!
Fucking touch it!
Remove your hands from it!
Go, get out!
I told Grandma that I
take a walk with her
And that's what I'll do.
You told your grandmother you were going
take a walk with her.
This is your last chance.
Hello, TJ.
I know it's weird, huh?
I can feel again
the wind on my face.
- You look great.
- Thanks.
- Hesher left.
- How are you?
I think you should
come see this.