<SAMI>
<HEAD>
<STYLE TYPE="text/css">
<!--  Generated by KMPlayer
.ENCC
-->
</STYLE>
</HEAD>
<BODY>
<SYNC Start=448810 End=451269><P Class=ENCC>
A GIRL'S FEELINGS
<SYNC Start=451269><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=1116650 End=1119099><P Class=ENCC>
Year of Hurricanes
<SYNC Start=1117300 End=1119099><P Class=ENCC>
Solar Eclipse
<SYNC Start=1117600 End=1119099><P Class=ENCC>
(Spring Tide)
<SYNC Start=1119099><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=1119099><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=1119099><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=1159150 End=1161099><P Class=ENCC>
ASUMA SARUTOBI
<SYNC Start=1161099><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=2393920 End=2395669><P Class=ENCC>
A GIRL'S FEELINGS
<SYNC Start=2395669><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5493540 End=5495749><P Class=ENCC>
It's cloudy
<SYNC Start=5493540 End=5495749><P Class=ENCC>
Kumottera
<SYNC Start=5493540 End=5495749><P Class=ENCC>
くもってら
<SYNC Start=5495749><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5495749><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5495749><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5496620 End=5503589><P Class=ENCC>
DONUT tabetakunatta kedo
<SYNC Start=5496620 End=5503589><P Class=ENCC>
Makes me feel like<br>to eat a donut
<SYNC Start=5496620 End=5503589><P Class=ENCC>
ドーナッツ　食べたくなったけど
<SYNC Start=5503589><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5503589><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5503589><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5504550 End=5509889><P Class=ENCC>
Ano ana wa nande aiteru no?
<SYNC Start=5504550 End=5509889><P Class=ENCC>
Why does it have a hole?
<SYNC Start=5504550 End=5509889><P Class=ENCC>
あの穴は　なんであいてるの?
<SYNC Start=5509889><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5509889><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5510050 End=5512679><P Class=ENCC>
It looks cute though
<SYNC Start=5510050 End=5512679><P Class=ENCC>
kawaii kedo
<SYNC Start=5510050 End=5512679><P Class=ENCC>
かわいいけど
<SYNC Start=5512679><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5512679><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5512679><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5515220 End=5518939><P Class=ENCC>
Dare mo oshiete kurenai
<SYNC Start=5515220 End=5518939><P Class=ENCC>
Nobody gives me an answer
<SYNC Start=5515220 End=5518939><P Class=ENCC>
誰も教えてくれない
<SYNC Start=5518939><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5518939><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5518939><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5520810 End=5525649><P Class=ENCC>
But I know something
<SYNC Start=5520810 End=5525649><P Class=ENCC>
demo wakatteru koto wa aru
<SYNC Start=5520810 End=5525649><P Class=ENCC>
でもわかってることはある
<SYNC Start=5525649><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5525649><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5525649><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5526820 End=5534819><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga naitetara dakishimeyou
<SYNC Start=5526820 End=5534819><P Class=ENCC>
Let's hug when somebody is crying
<SYNC Start=5526820 End=5534819><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが泣いてたら　抱きしめよう
<SYNC Start=5534819><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5534819><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5534910 End=5537449><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5534910 End=5537449><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5534910 End=5537449><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5537449><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5537449><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5537449><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5538080 End=5545879><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga warattetara kata o kumou
<SYNC Start=5538080 End=5545879><P Class=ENCC>
Let's pal around when someone is happy
<SYNC Start=5538080 End=5545879><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが笑ってたら　肩を組もう
<SYNC Start=5545879><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5545879><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5546130 End=5548759><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5546130 End=5548759><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5546130 End=5548759><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5548759><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5548759><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5548759><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5560350 End=5562309><P Class=ENCC>
Hareta ne
<SYNC Start=5560350 End=5562309><P Class=ENCC>
It's sunny
<SYNC Start=5560350 End=5562309><P Class=ENCC>
晴れたね
<SYNC Start=5562309><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5562309><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5562309><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5562810 End=5570319><P Class=ENCC>
hashiri ni yukou dekiru tokoro made
<SYNC Start=5562810 End=5570319><P Class=ENCC>
Let's go out and run as far as we can go
<SYNC Start=5562810 End=5570319><P Class=ENCC>
走りにゆこう　できるところまで
<SYNC Start=5570319><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5570319><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5570319><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5571610 End=5576579><P Class=ENCC>
Dango ya soko ni aru yo
<SYNC Start=5571610 End=5576579><P Class=ENCC>
There's the Dango store
<SYNC Start=5571610 End=5576579><P Class=ENCC>
だんご屋　そこにあるよ
<SYNC Start=5576579><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5576579><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5576870 End=5579539><P Class=ENCC>
Let's take a break
<SYNC Start=5576870 End=5579539><P Class=ENCC>
ochanondekou
<SYNC Start=5576870 End=5579539><P Class=ENCC>
お茶飲んでこう
<SYNC Start=5579539><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5579539><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5579539><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5582250 End=5585789><P Class=ENCC>
Where did the sun set?
<SYNC Start=5582250 End=5585789><P Class=ENCC>
Yuuhi wa doko ni shizunda no?
<SYNC Start=5582250 End=5585789><P Class=ENCC>
夕陽はどこに沈んだの?
<SYNC Start=5585789><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5585789><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5585789><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5587920 End=5592839><P Class=ENCC>
Ano ko no HEART no mukou gawa
<SYNC Start=5587920 End=5592839><P Class=ENCC>
It sets over her heart
<SYNC Start=5587920 End=5592839><P Class=ENCC>
あの子のハートの向こう側
<SYNC Start=5592839><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5592839><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5592839><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5593970 End=5601849><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga taoretara okoseba ii
<SYNC Start=5593970 End=5601849><P Class=ENCC>
Let's help when somebody tumbles
<SYNC Start=5593970 End=5601849><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが倒れたら　起こせばいい
<SYNC Start=5601849><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5601849><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5602230 End=5604689><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5602230 End=5604689><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5602230 End=5604689><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5604689><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5604689><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5604689><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5605360 End=5613279><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga tatta nara sasaereba ii
<SYNC Start=5605360 End=5613279><P Class=ENCC>
Let's walk together when somebody stands up
<SYNC Start=5605360 End=5613279><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが立ったなら　ささえればいい
<SYNC Start=5613279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5613279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5613490 End=5616279><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5613490 End=5616279><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5613490 End=5616279><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5616279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5616279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5616279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5645020 End=5650279><P Class=ENCC>
Mieta ne iku beki toko
<SYNC Start=5645020 End=5650279><P Class=ENCC>
Now we find a place to go
<SYNC Start=5645020 End=5650279><P Class=ENCC>
見えたね　行くべきとこ
<SYNC Start=5650279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5650279><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5650650 End=5658649><P Class=ENCC>
honto wa saisho kara wakatteta
<SYNC Start=5650650 End=5658649><P Class=ENCC>
We noticed from the first place
<SYNC Start=5650650 End=5658649><P Class=ENCC>
ほんとは最初から わかってた
<SYNC Start=5658649><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5658649><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5658649><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5659740 End=5665169><P Class=ENCC>
It's usual to get lost
<SYNC Start=5659740 End=5665169><P Class=ENCC>
mayou no wa atarimae sa
<SYNC Start=5659740 End=5665169><P Class=ENCC>
迷うのは　あたりまえさ
<SYNC Start=5665169><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5665169><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5665169><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5668460 End=5676219><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga naitetara dakishimeyou
<SYNC Start=5668460 End=5676219><P Class=ENCC>
Let's hug when somebody is crying
<SYNC Start=5668460 End=5676219><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが泣いてたら　抱きしめよう
<SYNC Start=5676219><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5676219><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5676550 End=5678969><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5676550 End=5678969><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5676550 End=5678969><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5678969><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5678969><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5678969><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5679810 End=5687439><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga warattetara kata o kumou
<SYNC Start=5679810 End=5687439><P Class=ENCC>
Let's pal around when somebody is happy
<SYNC Start=5679810 End=5687439><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが笑ってたら　肩を組もう
<SYNC Start=5687439><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5687439><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5687850 End=5690229><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5687850 End=5690229><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5687850 End=5690229><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5690229><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5690229><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5690229><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5690900 End=5698569><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga taoretara okoseba ii
<SYNC Start=5690900 End=5698569><P Class=ENCC>
Let's help when somebody tumbles
<SYNC Start=5690900 End=5698569><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが倒れたら　起こせばいい
<SYNC Start=5698569><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5698569><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5699030 End=5701449><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5699030 End=5701449><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5699030 End=5701449><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5701449><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5701449><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5701449><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5702120 End=5710039><P Class=ENCC>
Dareka ga tatta nara sasaereba ii
<SYNC Start=5702120 End=5710039><P Class=ENCC>
Let's walk together when somebody stands up
<SYNC Start=5702120 End=5710039><P Class=ENCC>
誰かが立ったなら　ささえればいい
<SYNC Start=5710039><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5710039><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5710210 End=5713299><P Class=ENCC>
sore dake de ii
<SYNC Start=5710210 End=5713299><P Class=ENCC>
That's all it needs
<SYNC Start=5710210 End=5713299><P Class=ENCC>
それだけでいい
<SYNC Start=5713299><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5713299><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5713299><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5714720 End=5717149><P Class=ENCC>
Everybody needs somebody
<SYNC Start=5717200 End=5719909><P Class=ENCC>
Everybody needs somebody
<SYNC Start=5719950 End=5722619><P Class=ENCC>
Everybody needs somebody
<SYNC Start=5722660 End=5725369><P Class=ENCC>
Everybody needs somebody
<SYNC Start=5725369><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5732840 End=5741219><P Class=ENCC>
I hope this film has touched you and remains
<SYNC Start=5732840 End=5741219><P Class=ENCC>
in your heart forever...
<SYNC Start=5732840 End=5741219><P Class=ENCC>
Masashi Kishimoto
<SYNC Start=5741219><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5741219><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
<SYNC Start=5741219><P Class=ENCC>&nbsp;
</BODY>
</SAMI>
