(Raindrops dripping)
(Crickets chirping)
(Rain pouring)
(Dog barking)
(Rain pouring heavily)
(Laughing)
Come on.
It's gonna hit my head.
(Grunting)
I'm scared.
(Chuckling)
(Tommy groaning)
Looks like it's
clearing up.
(Laughing)
Eric, stop.
Say mercy.
Mercy!
That's not how
you play.
You go like this.
And then you
go like this.
Okay.
Yeah.
Oh, no.
Say mercy.
(Chuckling)
Say it.
Say mercy.
I'm not gonna.
No, no, no!
Okay, mercy, mercy.
(Wind whooshing)
(Footsteps thudding)
Oh!
This place is weird.
Ian: You can say
that again.
Hmm.
Bleh!
Just imagine if you
had to live in here.
Who do you think
lives in here?
Probably,
nobody anymore.
There are holes
in the wall.
(Chuckling)
Yeah, dude.
Ian: Whoa!
Guys.
(Groaning)
Oh.
Tommy: Oh, do you
smell that?
(Chuckling)
(Sniffing)
Ian: It stinks.
(Puffing)
Pshew.
Pshew. Pshew.
(Whistling)
Tommy: What's with
the sound effects?
Ian: Well...
It sounds like a bird
falling from the sky
or something.
Yeah, it sounds
like a rock, it doesn't
sound like a bird.
(Whistling)
Birds are more like this.
(Cawing)
Well, maybe a dead bird
sounds like...
(Whistling)
Pshew!
What about the last
sound effect?
(Imitates explosion)
That's like a missile.
(Imitates missile landing)
(Whistling)
♪ Sing all the song
of the song
♪ it's the song of the song
♪ with a friend
♪ and the dead bird
(Humming)
♪ I'm a little black bird
an awesome bird
♪ a little black bird
♪ I'm not little
my friend and me
♪ the friend and the bird
the friend and the bird
♪ the dead little
black bird,
my friend and me ♪
It's like in the walls
there's spiders, like,
all over.
Ew!
You're getting spiders
on your hand.
Tristan: No.
Don't play with me.
(Chuckling)
Tristan: Are you serious?
This is nasty.
Just...
Tristan: Just spiders
all over.
(Laughing)
Oh, my God.
Tristan: I'm gonna break
through the wall.
(Laughing)
Oh, God.
Oh, there's a whole
bunch of spiders in there.
That's nasty.
There's, like,
one right there.
Oh, watch your head.
There really is.
I killed it for you.
See, I just saved
your life.
What would you
do without me?
(Chuckling)
Ian, what is
that thing?
(Spray can hissing)
(Rattling)
(Hissing)
Guys, I have to show
you something.
(Grunting)
Ugh.
(Gasping)
(Groaning)
Mercy, mercy, mercy.
Guys.
You have to promise
not to tell anybody
about this.
Blake: About what?
Tommy: Oh!
Ian: Cool, right?
(Imitates gunshot)
Hey, don't. Don't.
Give me it.
Come on.
(Blake grunting)
Ian: Stop! It's my dad's.
(Grunting)
Give me it.
Let go.
(Grunting)
Give me the gun.
Ian's father: Ian!
(Yelling angrily)
Where's it?
He's coming. Hide it.
Hey!
You. Get over here.
Come here, you.
You two, stay there.
Ian's father: Did you take
that out of my shed?
(Nervously)
Dad, I'm...
Did you load it?
Don't lie to me.
(Sighing)
You should know better.
You fucking know
you should know better.
Ian's father: Get lost.
Go cry in the woods.
You two, get the fuck
out of here and don't say
anything to anybody.
(Gun clicking)
(Panting)
Tommy: (Yelling)
Ian!
(Dog barking)
Commentator: Justin Jones,
in one minute and 13 seconds
and that will make
the score 15 to 13,
kittatinny in front
of high point.
Franklin Sussex
Honda sports beat.
Let's take a commercial
time out.
(Rock music playing)
(Clicking)
(Indistinct arguing)
Eric: What are you doing?
Get out.
(Clanking)
(Sighing)
Eric: Come on.
All:  Come on, guys.
You got this.
Connor, put him
on the ground.
Yeah.
Let's go. Take him down.
Oh, you suck.
Boy 1: Come on, Colin.
Pin him.
(Clapping)
Come on. Pin him.
Come on.
Boy: Take him down, go on.
Boy 2: Take him to his back.
Boy 3: Colin, fight.
Let's go.
Come on.
Boy 1: Come on.
Get it over with.
All: Come on.
Hit him. Take him down.
Boy 1: Oh.
Tristan: Yeah.
Tristan: Colin, you suck.
Who's next?
Eric and Tristan.
Get there.
Eric: Let's go.
Oh, let's go.
Boy 1: Tristan, come on, man.
Boy 2: Come on, take him down.
Boy 2: Come on, Eric.
Boy 1: Come on, Tristan.
Get it over with. Pin him.
Stop backing off.
(Boys jeering)
Boy 1: You gotta
get out of that,
you gotta get out of that...
(Thuds)
All: Oh. Nice.
Boy 3: Good job, Eric.
There you go.
(Coughing)
You all right, man?
Yeah.
All: Let's go. Nice.
Come on, guys.
What are you waiting for?
That was a nice one.
Boy 2: Come on, go after it.
You gonna finish it?
Boy 1: Come on, Chris.
(Panting)
Hi.
Woman: Hi.
How are you?
Great.
What can I get you?
A cheeseburger and...
Do you have lemonade?
Yes.
Okay, a large lemonade.
Okay.
It's $4.50.
All right.
There's $5.
(Phone ringing)
Thanks.
Oh.
Hey!
What the fuck?
I paid for that.
I'll get you another one.
Oh.
Um, sorry.
(Chuckling)
(Slurping)
Tristan: Come on, Eric.
Eric, what are you doing?
Come on.
Oh.
Shit.
Tristan: Isn't that your
brother's friend?
(Crying)
(Coughing)
(Mother crying)
(Mother sniffling)
Mother: (Crying)
I'm sorry.
What's so funny?
Father: Look at your brother.
You look at him.
Mother: Are you okay?
Do you wanna talk
about Ian, honey?
No.
Can I go to sleep?
Okay.
Do you want me
to get the light?
Sure.
(Groaning)
Courtney: Hi,
my name is Courtney
and I went to school
with Ian ever since
i was little.
Ian was a very nice boy.
He was always
there to help.
One day, we were
taking a math test
and my pencil broke,
so he gave me his.
Also in gym class once,
we were playing dodgeball
and I got hit in the arm.
He came over just
to make sure I was okay.
I can't remember one time
that he was mean to me.
I miss Ian very much
and I know that his dad
must be really sad
right now, and I hope
he feels better soon.
Man: I hope that we
all keep, Ian's dad
in our prayers.
And in our hearts.
And I just know that
he's going through
a really tough time
I guess it's a...
Hard time for you, right?
Well, you need
to know that...
The lord has a plan.
The lord has a plan for Ian.
You know that, right?
Excuse me?
He wanted this
to happen?
Did I want it
He, the lord.
Oh, the lord.
Well, he works
in mysterious ways.
And he has a plan for,
bigger than any of us could
ever possibly understand.
And sometimes things
happen that...
You know,
life's just tough.
Man: No, the lord didn't
want him to die.
But he did die.
He guides and protects
us all, so he was
protecting Ian.
You need to know that,
young man.
God bless you, sir.
Good night.
You too, Paul.
Thank you so much
for coming.
He's with the lord
now, son.
Don't you worry.
(Tv playing)
(Dog barking)
(Knocking)
Hi. Um...
If this dog gets on
my property again...
I'll fucking
shoot it, okay?
(Sighing)
Bad doggy.
(Inhaling sharply)
(Footsteps approaching)
Hey, man, wanna
go for a ride?
(Metal clanking)
Tristan: I used to hate it
when the water turned cold
all of a sudden.
Because when
I was little,
that's where
I used to think
all the monsters were.
Do you ever
think about dying?
Eric: What?
Like dying,
someone killing you,
or you
killing yourself.
No, not really.
I do.
Why?
Tristan: I don't know,
I just do.
Are you sad?
Tristan: Yeah, I guess,
a little.
You wanna die,
because you're sad?
(Sighing)
That's dumb.
Ahh! Get off.
(Laughing)
(Rain pouring)
(Clanging)
Whoa.
Tommy, cut it out.
Daisy.
(Barking)
Eric: Daisy.
Eric: Daisy, what
do you have?
(Barking)
Shh! Come here.
(Grunting)
(Coughing)
(Whispering)
Come here, come here.
(Coughing)
Holy shit.
Oh, my God.
Tommy, take one of them.
(Dog whimpering)
What?
Eric: Grab one.
(Whimpering)
An animal?
Eric: Yeah.
The cat.
Trust me.
(Dog whining)
Eric: (Coughing)
Come on, Daisy.
Let's get out of here.
(Coughing)
Ew!
(Grunting)
(Crickets chirping)
(Dog barking)
(Water gushing)
Tommy: Come on.
(Water flowing)
Come on.
(Water gushing)
It's okay.
It's okay, come on.
Stay in.
It's okay.
It's okay, come on.
(Gunshot)
(Gun cocking)
Tristan: Damn.
Eric: Do you see something?
Tristan: There's a bunny.
Eric: Give me the gun.
(Chuckling)
Give me the gun. Let go!
(Buzzing)
Stop.
(Gunshot)
(Gun cocking)
(Gun clicking)
Stop.
(Gunshot)
Do you think
you'll die if I shoot?
I don't know.
What if I held
it to your head?
(Inhaling)
(Gunshot)
(Gun cocking)
Tommy: (Yelling)
Daisy!
(Sighing)
Boy 1: Let's go, Eric.
Boy 2: Come on, Tristan.
Boy 2: Come on,
go for his legs.
Boy 1: Come on, Eric.
Boy 1: Trip him.
All: Eric.
Come on, Eric.
Boy 1: Come on, Eric.
Boy 2: Come on, Tristan.
Pull it off.
Boy 2: There you go.
Boy 1: Come on.
Boy 2: Bitch, pin him.
Boy 1: Come on, Tristan.
Pin him.
Boy 2: There you go.
Boy 1: Come on, Tristan,
pin him.
Tristan: Who's next?
Boy 1: Eric, you suck.
All: Here we go.
Connor, you got this.
Come on, Colin,
beat his ass.
Go, right here.
Come on, Connor.
Connor, don't let
him take you down.
(Splashing)
(Scratching)
You coming in?
Come on,
it's not that deep.
I'm fine.
(Scratching)
Come on.
I'm okay.
Let's go.
No, Eric.
I'm okay.
No.
I can swim.
Let's go.
No. Eric.
Eric, no.
Eric? Eric! Eric!
(Screaming)
Eric, no. Stop.
Eric, stop.
(Splashing)
(Screaming)
Eric. Eric.
It's just water.
Eric, stop.
Alright, I'm gonna drop you,
and you're gonna swim.
No, I can't swim. I'll drown.
One...
Eric, don't do this!
Two...
Eric, no.
Three.
Eric...
(Gasping and coughing)
You all right?
See?
You're swimming.
(Gulping)
Sort of.
(Both chuckling)
(Coughing)
This isn't so bad.
Hmm?
(Exhaling)
(Gasping)
Tristan: I just don't wanna
be here anymore...
You know?
No one likes me here.
(Sighing)
I do.
Tristan: What?
Tristan: You do what?
I like you.
You're my friend.
(Clicking)
What's that?
Tristan: What is what?
That sound.
Tristan: Don't you ever wish
you were somewhere else?
Eric: I don't know.
(Stuttering)
I don't think so.
Tristan, this is so dumb.
Tristan: I hate it here.
You're my friend.
Tristan: I don't know.
(Sighing)
I gotta go, Eric.
Bye, Eric.
(Sobbing)
So you don't wonder
what it feels like?
Well, sometimes I do.
What about you?
I guess so.
I mean, yeah.
Why do you think
of this stuff?
I don't know.
It's just...
It comes into my mind.
Hmm.
Hold on.
What are you doing?
Dude, what are
you doing?
See?
We don't even
have to touch.
This is weird.
(Scoffs)
It's not weird.
It's pretty weird.
(Chuckling)
Ready?
Fine.
It felt so weird.
I didn't feel anything.
Wanna try again?
Fine.
(Chuckling) Eew.
Oh, my God.
Hey, guys.
Hi, Eric.
Hey. How are you?
Good. How are you?
Mother: Good.
Woman: Good.
Mother: You know,
it's been hard
but we're getting
there, I think.
Woman: Yeah.
Mother: Back to normal.
How about you guys?
Woman: Same.
I couldn't do it.
I wish I had someone
to do it for me.
Oh, Jesus! God!
Eric.
Excuse me.
I'm so sorry.
(Dog barking)
Daisy?
(Dog continues barking)
Eric.
Look.
Why is she on this?
I found her like that,
tied up on the street.
Let's go.
Eric?
Eric!
(Clattering)
(Clattering stops)
Are you alright?
What's wrong with you?
Eric: Let's go.
Come on!
Hold on.
(Sighing)
Oh, man,
this is just...
There we go.
Okay, I'm gonna give
you some of this.
You want some
help, honey?
What's the matter?
What?
What's wrong?
It's just a stomach ache.
Hmm. You're not
gonna eat?
What's wrong
with your arm?
Eric: It's fine.
Why aren't you
using it?
Stop.
Father:
Just let me see it.
Mother: What's going
on, guys?
I hate it here.
Mother: That's very nice.
Thank you very much.
I do.
You guys don't care.
Mother: You know what, Eric?
That's bullshit.
(Clattering)
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey.
Really?
Why do you
even care?
(Scoffs)
'Cause I'm your father.
I'm your dad, okay?
Something happens
to your hand
and I don't know
what happened?
(Sighing)
He's just doing that
to get attention.
Hey, Tommy.
The way he acts...
That's not you, okay?
Okay.
(Soft clattering)
Hey, get up.
(Drowsily) What?
Get dressed.
Come on.
Why?
It'll be fun,
just come on.
No.
Fuck you. Come on.
Get dressed
and meet me outside.
And bring
some food, okay?
Hey, Tommy!
Come here.
I wanna show
you something.
Eric: Look.
It's for Ian.
Eric: Yeah.
What are you
thinking about?
I don't know.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
You've been
here before.
You don't
remember?
There used to be
train tracks here
but they don't
use them anymore.
It's kind of scary.
Yeah.
You don't have
to go in, if you
don't want to.
No, I want to.
Okay.
Eric?
Ha!
(Gasping) Eric no.
Eric, stop.
Eric! Really!
Eric: (Laughing)
You're gonna go over!
I'm gonna push you!
Tommy: Eric, no!
Eric, stop!
Eric, really!
Okay. Okay.
(Grunting)
It was just a joke.
Calm down.
Why would you
do that?
(Sighing)
(Exhaling sharply)
It was just a joke.
It... I didn't...
I didn't think you were
gonna care that much.
I'm hungry.
No.
What?
What is this?
It's...
Why?
Well, it's Ian's dad's.
I took it cause
I thought he might
want it.
And...
I'll throw it
away someplace.
Tommy: It's rotten.
Why are you
burning it?
No. No. No. Shit.
Shit.
God damn it.
Have you ever thought
about jumping?
Yeah.
A little.
But I never would.
What are you doing?
I'm making a grave.
For what?
For the raccoon.
Do you want
to say something?
It's kind of what
people usually do.
Okay.
Dear raccoon,
I'm sorry you died.
And I'm sorry
that my brother
burned you
after you died.
I hope you come back
as a better animal
unless you liked
being a raccoon,
then I hope
you come back
as that.
Amen.
Oh.
Here.
What if I
roll off?
You're not
gonna roll off.
I roll
in my sleep.
I'll hold you.
(Spitting)
Eric: Missed.
It's all up to me.
(Chuckling)
Wow.
Oh!
Stupid.
What did he look
like when he fell...
I guess?
He, uh...
He looked like Ian.
Was he happy?
I don't know.
How was he
before he died?
He was mostly happy.
That's what he looked like.
He looked happy.
Do you think
he jumped?
Who said
I don't know, people.
You know, he...
He could have fallen.
Just playing around
like a kid.
Slipped.
Tommy: Do you think mom
will get mad at us?
Eric: I don't know.
Who cares, man?
Who cares
what she thinks?
Do you think it hurt?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, man.
You're my friend.
Okay?
Don't forget it.
(Heavy metal playing)
(Creaking)
(Door closing)
It's okay, Daisy.
It's okay.
It's okay, I got you.
I won't let you go.
(Thunder rumbling faintly)
It's okay, Daisy.
I got you.
I got you, Daisy.
Okay, Daisy.
I'm gonna count to three
and I'm gonna let go
and you're gonna swim,
okay?
Three...
One, two, three.
Boy 1:
Knock him down, Tommy.
(Boys clamoring)
Boy 2: Come on, Tommy.
In the circle.
Boy 1: Go, Tommy.
Boy 3: Get him
down already.
(Boys clamoring)
Come on.
Come on, Tommy.
Let's go.
Tommy, go.
Come on, Tommy.
Let's go.
Go!
(Boys clamoring)
(Clapping)
Boy 1: Nice job,
old man!
Boy 2: Nice, Tommy.
Me and you,
come on.
Tommy: Eric, come on.
Go Eric.
Boy 1: Come on, Eric.
Boy 3: Come on, Tristan.
(Boys clamoring)
Tommy: Get back in.
Come on, Eric.
Get up.
Let's go. Eric.
(Grunting)
Tommy: Let's go, Eric.
Get his legs.
Boy 4: Oh, shit.
(Boys murmuring indistinctly)
(Screaming)
Tristan: Damn, man.
Boy2: Come on, Eric.
Tommy: Eric?
Boy 4: Oh! Dude.
Boy 1: Yo, Tristan,
watch out!
Hey!
(Panting)
(Coughing)
Tristan: You
fucking psycho!
(Bear grunting)
(Bear snorting)
(Gasping)
(Panting)
I'm sorry.