Hear me, Satan.
Sarah?
Oh, God! No!
Take my soul, Satan.
Hear me, please.
Jeremy!
Oh, God.
- The Conversation.
- Gene Hackman.
BonnieandClyde.
Regina, name another actor
in BonnieandClyde.
I have no idea.
That´s a good movie.
You should see that.
- Faye Dunaway.
- Chinatown.
-Jack Nicholson.
- Witches ofEastwick.
Cher. Thereyou go.
What else has Cher been in?
BeavisandButthead?
No fair. That´s TV.
It´s the movie game.
No other Cher?
What about anotherJack Nicholson?
I know. TheShining.
Scary movie.
Redrum.
I´ll be on the pier puking.
So, are we still gonna
go back tomorrow night?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
Why?
´Cause Linda got these cool tickets to
this new rave, and they´re hard to get.
No, no.
I´m not keen on the rave scene.
What scene?
It´sjust a concert, right?
From what I hear, everybody´s up
all night getting blasted.
It´s not cool.
- You have no idea.
- What are they like?
Dad, I´m going! I´m almost 1 6.
Regina! You´re not going.
This is ridiculous.
You never let me do anything.
That´s not true.
Forget it!
Honey, honey.
You´ve got to lighten up on her.
She´s almost an adult.
But we don´t wanna lose another kid.
I can´t do it.
I know.
We´re gonna beat this.
Maybe not this lifetime, but--
But we will.
Not that song again!
Maybe we should drive back tonight.
- Really?
- Well--
Hatch, look out!
- Regina, areyou all right?
- You okay?
- Don´t move.
-Jesus.
My God, it´s so far down.
Jesus.
- What´ll we do?
- Open the door. You guys out fiirst.
It´s stuck.
Regina, climb over me.
- I can´t.
- Yes, you can. Here.
- Give meyour hand.
- Come on.
- I won´t letyou get hurt.
Here we go.
Be careful.
Mom!
Help! Get some help!
Hatch! Wake up!
Wake up!
Oh, my God!
Come on.
I gotyou.
Down there. See them?
Get some light down there.
Go get the basket.
Still fiixed and dilated.
No change.
Crash cart ready?
Good. We need vasodialators.
Get an I.V.
Type and cross match, fiive units.
Cut.
No change.
Deader than Elvis.
Let´s bring him back.
- Give me some prep.
- Drops in.
Areyou sureyou want to revive him
after 1 20 minutes down.
Records are made to be broken.
We both rememberwhat happened
last time.
The cardiac adrenaline.
- He´s at 89 degrees.
- Bring him up to 99.
Bring him up to 99 slowly.
Come on, Harrison, help me out here.
He´s responding to the adrenaline.
Defiib.
- Do it.
- Pads.
Daddy.
Charge to 200.
Come with me, Daddy.
I loveyou.
Moving up to 1 30.
Charged.
Clear!
Charge to 360.
- Charged.
- Clear.
There he is.
Congratulations, Doctor.
He´s got decent vitals.
Good morning, Mrs. Harrison.
My name is Dr. Nyebern.
We´ve given your daughter
a mild sedative, but she´ll be fiine.
My husband is dead.
No, Mrs. Harrison.
Your husband is stable.
I saw him die.
Mrs. Harrison...
I have a very special Resuscitative
Medicine program here.
We were able
to bring your husband back.
Mrs. Harrison, please.
- Where is he?
- He´s in ICU.
He may seem different toyou.
Was I supposed to turn
into the skid?
I don´t know.
Poor baby.
Oh, thesunandthe--
Ican tellasunnybreeze
ButIonlyhave eyes
Foryou, dear
- Is there meat in that?
- Never.
You don´t have time to eat.
In seven minutes,
Linda´s meeting you here.
What?
PearlJam?
Tonight? Oh, my God!
Thankyou, thankyou!
So excited.
And be home by 1 :00.
- Honey, midnight.
- I know.
I have to tell you a couple things.
Wait.
Oh, yeah.
I´ve been meaning to talk about that.
- You know who I think I saw?
- Who?
Sam.
- Samantha?
- Yeah.
What doyou mean?
You know, after the accident
when I was out...
I don´t remember anything.
But I guess a few wires
got crossed...
or I was dreaming or hallucinating
or something...
´cause I feel like I saw her.
She was trying
to tell me something, or--
I don´t know.
What´d she say?
How´s she doing?
She was happy.
I wanted to go to her.
Oh, honey, don´t. Please.
No, no. I´m okay.
Hatch?
Oh, my God.
Hatch, what´s wrong?
Hatch, honey, wake up.
Areyou okay?
What happened? You´re cut.
I killed her.
Come inside.
Come on, let´s go inside.
- Blood!
- It´s okay.
- I killed her.
- No, you didn´t. It was a nightmare.
Come on, honey. Oh, my God.
Let´s wash this off.
Come here. It´s okay.
Come on.
You cutyourselfdeep, babe.
You´ll need some stitches.
- Where?
- Here.
What happened?
- I was making a sandwich.
- What´s going on?
Honey, it´s okay. Daddy cut himself.
I´m fiine. Go on up. We got it.
- Sorrywe wokeyou.
- You´re bleeding.
Please, Regina. Please.
Go on.
Let me get a towel.
Fuck.
Let me see.
Wow. It´s not as deep
as I thought. Huh?
What was that?
I gotta see Dr. Nyebern.
Oh, babe.
So?
So, ifthere´s anything wrong with you,
it´s not physical.
So what was it?
An acid flashback?
Yeah, yeah. Trippy. Bad!
Afterwhatyou´ve been through, I´d be
surprised ifyou didn´t have nightmares.
Wait. He´s never had
nightmares like this.
I wasn´t asleep.
Has this happened to other people
you resuscitated?
I can´t compare Hatch
to other patients.
Why not?
Only one otherwas down
as long as he was.
Was there anything like this?
Maybe I should talk
to that other patient.
I´m afraid that´s not possible.
Why not?
- He´s dead.
- Oh, well, that´s encouraging.
No, not from having been dead?
No, no! Ofcourse not.
You shocked mywife.
Hatch, look...
God´s given you
a second chance at life.
Enjoy it. I´ll prescribe something
to helpyou sleep.
Really?
Ifanything else happens, call me.
- We´ll run more tests.
- Thankyou.
Thanks.
- So it´s good news.
- Good news.
Nothing´s wrong with me.
Daddy.
- Bye, honey. Looking good.
- Bye, Mom.
Bye, Dad.
Stylish.
What´s up?
That´s her.
Who?
The girl.
The one I saw in that--
Monday night.
Oh, well, you probably saw her
on TV or something.
I haven´t been watching TV.
Then maybe on the radio
or on a milk carton.
It´s a missing girl.
Honey...
this girl isn´t missing.
She´s dead.
She´s--
Sweetie...
the other night...
how long was I...
out there on the lawn?
I don´t know. Why?
Hey, don´t spookyourselfso much,
okay?
- Good morning, Marion.
- Lindsey, hi.
Good morning.
Honey, could you please
go through these?
- Is he okay?
- Yeah, he´s fiine.
He´s teething.
Thereyou go.
You made the papers.
Nice picture ofyou.
Though Satan´s looked better.
Something else, Marion, dear?
Well, now thatyou mention it...
I wondered...
what it was like
to be on the other side.
Whatyou saw there.
Just...
chemical brain--
It´s really scientifiic.
Scientifiic?
I think there´s a lot more
to it than that.
- What´s this?
- It´s a friend ofmine.
She´s a very special person.
She sees things.
She can helpyou remember things
ifyou want.
You know I´m not into that kind
ofstuff, sweetie.
Well, maybe it´s time
you reconsidered, Hatch.
Thankyou.
Honorstudent
andformerGirlScoutleader...
andnowtargetofapolicesearch.
Eighteen-year-old WendyStone, described
byacquaintances asamodelcitizen...
isstillmissingafter72hours.
She was lastseenat the Parkside...
atapproximately9:30 Mondaynight,
wearingablack dressandjacket.
Beyondthat, noleads orclues
point to Wendy´s whereabouts.
Sheis5foot 6,
withblue eyesandblondehair.
Concernedfamilyandfriends
have established--
- Bye, Mom.
- Bye, sweetie.
Bye, Dad.
- Bye. Where areyou going?
- To hang out with Linda.
Where?
I won´t get raped or anything, okay?
Good-bye. Have fun.
She´s gonna be okay.
Let´s rent a movie tonight, okay?
- I´ll go.
- No, no. I want to.
No, stay. I´ll be right back.
Hurry.
I thought we were going downtown.
Regina.
Lagoon Drive.
91 1. Youremergency?
Have a light?
Excuse me.
I called in the report.
Really? What´s your name?
- Arcadia Street. Phone number?
- 555-1 643.
What´s going on?
Look...
next timeyou have a gut feeling...
I suggestyou tryAlka-Seltzer.
Okay, let´s wrap this up.
Wait a minute.
You didn´t fiind the girl?
There is no girl out there.
This is all in your imagination.
Isn´t it, Mr. Harrison?
At least, I hope so.
What´s happening?
What´s going on?
Come on, honey, this is scaring
the shit out ofme.
I´m scared.
Come here, tell me.
I´m in it.
It feels like I´m doing it.
But like it´s not me.
And when I see light,
it hurts my eyes.
And I feel all this...
rage.
We had another daughter, Samantha,
killed in a hit-and-run a year ago.
When I was dead,
I think I saw her.
Maybe I reallywent someplace.
Because I feel like...
maybe she´s trying to warn me...
or trying to help me
save people´s lives.
It´s the hardest thing
to lose a child.
I´d like to schedule
another PET scan.
But...
could my situation be--
You mean, could it be
more spiritual in nature?
I don´t know.
It´s not my fiield.
I reallywant to go, but...
I don´t think it´s a good idea.
He´s really on edge.
Dying and all, you know.
Okay, okay, yeah.
Come pick me up in 30 minutes. Bye.
Kinda cute.
- What?
- He´s kind ofcute.
Yeah.
- I´ve seen you.
- No, I don´t think so.
Oh, yes, I have seen you.
It was...
like a flash forward in time.
You´re beautiful.
Perfect.
My name´s Vassago.
- That´s different.
- Different.
- I´m Regina.
- I know!
You know?
Yes, Regina.
You don´t look likeyou belong here.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Maybeyou´re right.
- No, not maybe. I am right.
I´m so right...
that I know whereyou do belong.
Let me takeyou somewhere.
Makeyou feel--
Make us both feel...
something.
We´re waiting for people.
Why don´tyou let Regina
make her own decisions?
Why don´tyou piss off?
I´ll seeyou again.
What´s the deal?
You said he was cute.
He´s a creep.
God, Regina, get some sense.
Let´s get outta here. Let´s go.
No luck, huh?
Not always.
I´m Zoe.
You have beautiful eyes.
What?
Nothing. I wasjust...
imagining the two ofus together.
I made it myself.
I like this.
I use bones in mywork.
You´re an artist, too?
Yes, ofsorts.
I´m making a sculpture.
Would you like to see it?
So, where is this piece ofart?
At my hideaway.
What areyou hiding?
You hear me? What´s wrong, baby?
Come here.
Fucker!
You bastard!
Oh, God.
I gotta get outta here.
Oh, my God.
Where areyou going?
You haven´t seen my sculptureyet.
You see, it´s my monument to hell.
Shit!
There´s only one way out!
Honey, wake up.
Oh, my God, no!
Come on, wake up.
What´s wrong?
You sick fuck!
Keepyour head very still.
It was scary.
I couldn´t wake him up.
He doesn´t remember any ofit?
No, no.
It´s probably the sleeping pills.
- Can´t fiind it?
- Sorry, once more.
What?
You were in a club last night.
I was not.
You´re lying, goddamn it!
Doyou have any fucking idea
what he was going to do?
Doyou know what
you´re playing around with?
Doyou know what he does
to these girls? He butchers them!
Slaughters them.
You hear me?
Come on. Areyou all right?
Youokay?
I´m fiine.
He´s crazy!
I got it.
Now, wait a minute here.
It´s not me.
He´s doing it.
Jesus Christ, am I seeing...
through...
him?
He was with Regina.
We´re connected somehow.
I know him. I know what he looks like.
I should call the police.
No, I should call the police.
I should call the police now
and have them lockyou in a loony bin.
Or maybe I should call an exorcist.
- I know it sounds crazy.
- It is crazy.
You need help. Rememberwhat Nyebern
said? You might have a brain tumor.
You know...
you won´t see a psychiatrist
and you scared our daughter!
She´s gotta know.
Tell me what I should do.
Believe me.
Damn it!
I´ll go see how Regina is.
I´m Vassago.
Vassago.
You know, I don´t know her last name.
Zoe something.
Okay, so no missing person report.
Thankyou. Bye.
I got it.
Hello?
Hi,Jenny, how areyou doing?
Listen, can you hang on?
Where areyou going?
- I´ll be back.
- When?
Soon.
Is this a bad time?
No, no. I didn´t want Hatch
to know it was you.
He won´t come in for more tests.
He´s completely paranoid.
Now he´s convinced he´s
psychically connected to somebody.
We must get him in.
Ifitisan organicbrainanomaly...
his condition coulddeteriorate
unless we dosomethingnow.
Dr. Nyebern, is it...
at all possible he really
is seeing things?
Like this is all somehow real,
what he´s been saying?
Is that whatyou think?
I don´t know.
I don´t know what to think anymore.
Ifitis...
psychological, then Dr. Martin
couldhelp with this.
Anything specifiic I could tell them
about this...
connection he´s imagining?
Here´s something.
It probably doesn´t mean anything.
Call me ifthere´s anything else.
Redlow...
it´sJonas Nyebern.
I know.
I think I may have a lead.
Lousy fuck!
There are no bullets in them,
butyou assume weapons are loaded.
We gotta have a gun in the bedroom.
- I´m putting it here.
- I don´t believe this.
We´ll hid the shotgun downstairs,
and getyou and Regina lessons.
I don´t believeyou bought these
without talking to me.Jesus Christ!
- I feel we need protection.
- No! I won´t have guns here!
No, I won´t!
- Mr. Harrison?
- That´s right. That´s my name.
Oh, no. Marion told meyou might come.
Please, come in.
Give meyour hand.
Why haveyou lostyour trust?
I see a child´s bicycle.
Some souls choose to live
for only a short time, Hatch.
Hold these.
Think oftwo questions.
Keep one toyourself,
and tell me the other one.
Why am I having these visions?
You´re tied to them
by a coincidence offate.
You crossed over.
- You brought something backwith you.
- What?
Something very powerful.
The one from yourvisions?
He knows you watch him.
He does?
Yeah.
Now for the second question.
Someone close toyou is in danger.
Doyou have another daughter?
Regina.
This is Regina.
But there is a puritywithin you.
And you must surrender to it.
Yourweakness...
would bring about her death.
What´s that supposed to mean?
Myweakness? Never!
Never Regina!
You tell me to surrender, and then say
my daughter might die? Bullshit!
There´s another energy around you.
That´s irresponsible bullshit!
He´s here.
No, no.Just go.
Larson Place.
Okay, fuckhead, here I come.
Hatch, what areyou doing?
Hatch, come on!
Let me in.
What areyou doing?
Goddamnit!
Skies.
Open the door, please.
Open the door! Let me in!
What areyou doing? Please.
What the hell areyou doing?
- DirectoryAssistance. Whatcity?
- In Sinclair. Skies Motel.
- Nolisting, sir.
- Skies. S-K-I-E-S.
Nolisting.
Pain. I can induce the visions.
Gotcha.
Motherfucker.
- Yes?
- Yes. I came for a reading.
- It´s late. I take appointments.
- I know. I´m very sorry.
Wait, I--
I´m very sorry.
I really need your advice.
Well, I--
Please.
- Well--
- Oh, please.
I´m sorry.
Who recommended me toyou?
Come now.
Tell me about Regina.
Oh. Vassago.
You don´t have to do this anymore.
You can stop.
I can´t.
91 1. What´syouremergency?
Yeah. There´s been a murder...
at 576 Larson Place.
I´mgoing toneedyourmobilenumber
andyourloca--
Wait a second.
" Blue Skies."
" Morton Redlow."
Hatch, what areyou doing?
He killed somebody again.
This time because ofme.
He sees through me.
Oh,Jesus!
Come in. It´s not locked.
Put that on the table.
Sorry.
You got a permit for that?
Yeah.
What can I do foryou?
Well, somebody phoned in
a murder report.
So I checked it out. There was evidence
offoul play, but no body.
- So, I thought ofyou.
- Maybe he took the bodies with him.
Another gut feeling?
Look, Detective, I know
you´ll think this is crazy...
but I know
who´s killing these girls.
He´s young, dark hair.
He always wears sunglasses.
His name is Vassago.
He´s been staying
at the Blue Skies Motel.
And, where wereyou tonight?
He´s been here all night
with me.
Maybeyou´re one ofthose clairvoyants
that sees crimes, bodies and stuff.
What do I know?
Just don´t leave town, okay?
If Rose Orwetto doesn´t turn up...
then I´ll have to come back
and askyou some questions.
I´ll let myselfout.
You be careful with that thing.
- How doyou know these things?
- I´ve been sucked into this evil fuck.
-Whyyou?
-I don´t know. I know who he wants next.
- Who?
- He´s coming after Regina.
Don´t say that! It´s not true!
- Trust me!
- Nobody´s trying to kill Regina.
I´m the one who´s got
to stop this guy.
- Don´tyou see whatyou´re doing?
- I´m trying to save our daughter.
Our daughter Samantha,
not our daughter Regina.
Samantha, Hatch. Remember Sam?
It´s notyour fault.
You didn´t kill her, okay?
Fate killed her.
The goddamn car killed her.
You didn´t.
- Please.
- Don´tyou get it?
You´re making this up soyou can be
the big hero and save our daughter.
Just listen!
Whetheryou believe or not,
this is what´s going to happen.
Tonight I´m up and on guard.
Regina´s safe in the day,
but by tomorrow night...
you and she have to go someplace,
and I can´t know where it is.
You´ve got to stay there
till this is over. Can you do that?
Is that clear?
Can you do that?
Yes, I can leave.
Because I can´t helpyou
with this anymore.
I loveyou.
- Afternoon, Hatch.
- Marion.
Be right back.
" Detective."
Themostinteresting aspectofthis case
ishis vision.
Closeronhis face.
Themuscles thatcause thepupils
to dilatehavebeen destroyed.
Theslightestamountoflightcan cause
extreme discomfort, ifnotpain.
-Specialcontactlenses filterlight.
- That´s you.
With these, he´sable to withstand
lowlevels oftungsten.
Doyouhaveanything toadd, Doctor?
Jeremy´s violentbehavior--
Nyebern.
Hispsychosishas increased.
Hehas escapedintoa delusional world--
Son ofa bitch!
Hatch, what´s wrong?
Jonas!
Nyebern!
- What areyou doing here?
- Who´sJeremy?
I wasjust thinking aboutyou.
Would you like some tea?
I´ve got to fiind him.
Who´sJeremy?
- Where did you get that tape?
- You tell me.
Tell me what´s going on.
Sorry.
- May I helpyou?
- Yes. I wondered ifanyone was here.
- Are the Harrisons in?
- No, they´re not.
Where can I fiind them?
They´re old friends ofmine.
I know all the Harrisons´ friends.
How privileged they must feel.
Mywife and I are...
having a little garden party.
And we misplaced their number.
Perhaps you couldjot it down for me.
I´ll send them an invite. I´d leave it
here, but it´s more personal...
ifthey get it at home.
I´ll put it on the back
ofone ofour business cards...
and then yourwife
can read it toyou at home.
Yes, mywife.
Thankyou.
I´ll see myselfto the door.
There´s one more favor
you could do for me.
Would you have a bathroom?
- What areyou hiding?
- Patient information is confiidential.
Confiidential? This is the kid
I´ve been seeing in my head--
I cannot divulge information
without that patient´s consent.
All right,
Jeremywas one ofmy patients.
Thankyou.
Bitch!
I was very nice toyou. Whyweren´tyou
nice to me? I just wanted information.
Do I have to call 41 1 ?
Jesus!
I´m concerned about the protection
ofyour family.
Protect my family? This fuckingJeremy
is stalking my teenage daughter!
- Tell me who he is?
- Calm down.
Father?
Tell me who he is!
Redlow.
Jeremy is your son?
Threeyears ago...
he killed his mother.
And he killed his sister,
then he killed himself.
You brought him back.
Like me.
Even as a child,
Jeremywas psychotic.
But he was my son.
You´d have done the same.
"Wonderland."
" UnderThe Roller Coaster."
Regina, areyou packed?
Hurry up.
I don´t know why I´m bringing all this.
I´m not gonna end up wearing it.
Call-waiting sucks.
I´m not getting that.
Okay. Please have left already.
I´ll giveyou the number
as soon as I know where we´re gonna be.
But we´re not supposed
to tell anybody ´cause--
Goddamn it!
He´s got Regina!
You drive.
Where am I going?
I don´t know.
Just keep going.
I´m so sorry.
Lindsey, we´ll get her back.
Fuck it!
She´s still alive.
What areyou doing?
They´re on the highway, going east.
Otherway.
- Wonderland.
- What?
He´s taking her
to that old amusement park.
Jeremy.
Oh, you.
What is this?
You killedJeremy.
No. I broughtyou back.
I broughtyou back to life.
- I came to helpyou.
- "I came to helpyou."
- I want to helpyou.
- "I want to helpyou."
Here, here.
Don´tyou get it? Huh?
I don´t wanna be saved!
I want to be damned.
Through this maintenance door.
I asked you here
to showyou mywork.
I changed my mind.
Oh,Jesus.
This way.
What?
He knows we´re here.
Regina!
What?
Through here.
Lindsey?
Daddy!
I´m here!
Forgive me.
Did you come to watch?
Good!
My fatherwasn´t able to watch his wife
and daughter die, butyou will be.
Regina´s the virgin crown
to my art.
I knew it when I saw her
through your eyes.
I´m not afraid ofyou.
I´m the one with the power.
You´re nothing!
You´re a link between
me and Regina, that´s all.
Come on up.
I´ll wait.
Shut up!
You skinny little fuck!
Here I come.
Daddy, what´s happening?
- I´m coming.
- Shut up!
Fucker!
You´re invisible.
And I´m invincible.
On your knees!
We are Vassago.
Darkness has no power in the light.
Baby.
Samantha.
Regina, he´s dead.
It´s over.
We can save him.
Watch the doors.
Get the crash cart ready.
Okay, on three.
One, two, three. Lift.
Lose the gurney.
Pads.
- 83.7.
- Watch it.
Stand by.
- Charge 200.
- Pads are on.
- Charged.
- Clear.
No pulse.
- Charge to 360.
- Clear.
We´ve got a breath!
Pulse is erratic.
We´ve got him!
What?
- It wasjust a dream.
- Ah,Jesus.
You scared me.
This isjust like that movie Carrie.
Sissy Spacek.
- Oh, Badlands.
- Martin Sheen.
- TheSubject Was Roses.
- Patricia Neal.
- Hud.
- Paul Newman.
They say he dunks his head
in ice water every morning.
Shut up and kiss me.