Lady Franklin!
- Lady Franklin!
- Get out of it!
- She's over by the pond.
Lady Franklin, Dr Mercer is waiting to see you.
- Dr Mercer's waiting to see me?
- To see you before you leave.
- To see me before I leave.
- Today, Lady Franklin.
You're leaving today, you remember?
Now, Louise, come along.
It's much too cold out here.
Go back to the house.
This way.
- Are... Are you sure it was today?
- Yes.
I'm not absolutely certain it's convenient today.
# Over The Hills And Far Away
# Over the hills and far away
# Were I sold on lndian soil
# Soon as the burning day was clos'd...
I do feel better most of the time.
Still a little down in the mornings, hm?
Yes.
Your general health is really very good now,
Lady Franklin.
It has been a rest.
Well, a nervous breakdown
requires a rest from the world,
as much as it does drugs or understanding.
But everybody's been very understanding.
I want you to continue the pills...for a while.
They do help.
Yes, they help to even out your moods.
Oh, yes, they do.
I feel much more even.
I did it deliberately, you know.
Quite deliberately.
Now, Lady Franklin, we've been over this
often before. You were disturbed.
- Depressed.
- It was intentional.
Yes, of course. A symptom of your depression.
Now that's over and done with.
I still feel it a little bit in the mornings.
You need people now.
A normal life.
Don't know many people.
- In London, you see, we didn't really know...
- Well, make new country friends.
Find new activities.
So...I'm ready to go, then.
You are.
Well, then, I suppose I must.
Norman!
Well, goodbye, then, Lady Franklin.
Please don't hesitate to...
Oh, Sister...
Please call me if you should be worried
about anything. If I'm not here...
- Norman...
- Sister will know where I can be reached.
Please give my regards to your mother
when you see her.
Nice to see you looking so well.
Lansdowne Crescent, my lady?
What?
- What did you say?
- Lansdowne Crescent, my lady?
Yes, thank you very much.
Are you employed by my mother?
We're a private car hire firm, my lady.
Quite large. I don't know who booked the job.
I suppose it was my mother.
Expect it was, yes, my lady.
Like the window up, my lady?
No, thank you.
But if you'd like it...
I don't mind at all, my lady.
Well, perhaps, then.
If you...don't really mind.
Doesn't bother me either way, my lady.
- Perhaps it would be better closed.
- Certainly, my lady.
Good driving is really quite an art, I suppose.
Well, I don't know about an art, exactly.
More of a skill, perhaps.
A skill, then.
- More of a knack, perhaps.
- Yes, that does describe it very well.
A knack.
I really am...going to have to learn...the knack.
Driving, do you mean, my lady?
Mm? Talking to people.
You seem quite good at that, my lady. I mean...
you're chatting away to me all right.
- So I am.
- You certainly are.
Yes, I am, aren't l?
Do you prefer any particular route, my lady?
Not really.
Such fun, just driving along like this.
Would you go via Radley, please?
Certainly, my lady.
Would you slow down for a moment, please?
Look what I've got!
We've passed it.
Beg your pardon, my lady?
Helen, my darling.
- Hello, Mother.
- How was the journey?
- Where do I send the account?
- Send it to Radley Grange, if you would.
- Thank you very much for a very pleasant ride.
- Thank you, my lady.
I must say, you look quite transformed.
You look quite transformed.
More relaxed.
You do feel better, don't you?
I feel a little bit as though...
as if it...
- I feel better.
- You must get out more.
Everyone will want to see you, now that you're...
Cream?
You must make friends here, Helen.
Local people can be quite fun.
Do you have sugar? I can't remember.
Sugar - two.
After all, Tom...did r-represent the county...
i-in Parliament...
..in Parliament, didn't he?
We had very few friends here.
Yes, well...
I don't think London society
was very good for you.
It was too demanding.
But it's all I know.
I'm going to Paris next week and I shall arrange
for you to meet some nice people here.
- Oh, Mother, l...
- Helen, really, you must make an effort.
- I'd rather you didn't, really.
- Look, you can't go on mourning.
- Mother...
- You're young...
Please, I'm...
Did that doctor...fellow suggest anything?
Yes.
You've always resented me, haven't you, Helen?
Just because I didn't hide myself away in black
the moment your father died.
- Of course, if he were alive...
- Mother, he's not here. He is dead too.
I hope you're not going to become bitter, Helen.
Something to eat?
...at the front, George.
Helen...
Please, Helen, please.
Wasn't here.
They need...
They needed me.
I wasn't...
I was away.
I was away and they needed me,
they needed me, Mother!
I was away at a party.
A party.
At a party...at a party...
At a party...
- Change the oil.
- Right.
- Check the tappets.
- Right, right.
- Worried about that gasket.
- Nothing wrong with it.
- Check it again!
- Come on, Steven, she's running like a bird.
- Got to give perfect service in this business.
- She will.
She is beautiful.
I admit she was a bargain.
Keep her clean.
Put that rocker cover back.
- All right, Sergeant Major.
- Put on a good show for the customers.
- That's your department.
- I want to build up a first-class business here.
First-class business with first-class accounts.
Like that Lady Franklin yesterday.
She's a good account.
Oh, yes, she phoned.
- Why didn't you tell me before?
- Didn't make no booking. Just asked you to call.
Here I am, trying to build up a business,
you don't give me the orders?
You get her ready immediately!
I remembered, didn't l?
Beautiful? Bloody wearing me out, she is.
Right, then, Lady Franklin.
Very kind of you to think of us, my lady.
Just have to check the bookings
to make sure I'm available.
- You want a cup of tea?
- Yeah.
My lady? Yes, that'll be quite all right, my lady.
Bath to Radley. Thank you.
Told you she'd be a good client.
Funny woman, though.
- How do you mean?
- I don't know. She is a funny woman.
- Do you live near your work?
- Have to, my lady. Always on call, you see.
Would you rather live in the country?
I'm not sure I do.
- Nice to have a bit of green around.
- Nice. Very nice for children.
- Children like that, don't they?
- Yes.
- How many do you have?
- Children?
Yes.
Two, my lady.
Did you say two?
Yes, two.
We didn't have any children.
How old are they?
The girl, erm...Mary...
she's just going on four.
And, er...the boy...
young Steven, he's almost ten.
He is at school, then?
Grammar school, my lady.
Ten? That's very good, isn't it?
Yes, very good.
- What will you do with him?
- You mean in regards to work?
- Yes.
- Well, the army, I think.
Reckon it did pretty well for me.
Even during the war.
Regular soldier, were you?
Regimental Sergeant Major, I finished up,
my lady.
And what about your wife?
What does she...? Ah, we turn left here.
Thank you, my lady.
My lady?
My lady, are you all right?
Can I do it for you, my lady?
My lady...
My lady?
I'll open the window.
Are you sure you're all right?
Fine. Ab...solutely fine.
It's stuffy in here.
That's quite enough chatter.
Why don't you move the chairs before you start?
Can I help you? Did you want...?
Oh, my lady.
- I didn't know she was going to...
- You get back to your work, Edith.
I had no idea you were coming back today.
It's perfectly all right, Mrs Hansen.
I'm not staying.
You're looking very pale, my lady.
Will you take some lunch?
Yes, and the driver, too.
Yes, my lady.
It's nice to see you back.
Will you come this way, please, sir?
It's about time she showed her face in this place.
It's stopped raining, Edith.
You can put those sheets out.
They do go on a long time about it, these nobs,
with all this mourning.
- You've got to get on with it, haven't you?
- I always have.
Are you her chauffeur, then?
- I've got my own car hire business.
- Edith, get on with your work.
What would your wife do
if you were to die quite suddenly?
She'd have to get on with it, I should think.
- On with what?
- Life, I suppose.
Yes, that's very sensible.
Maybe she'd look around for another husband.
Would she?
Would she really? And how would she do that?
Well, you'd have to ask her that, my lady.
And you wouldn't mind?
Hard to argue if you're six foot under.
Your keys, my lady.
You're very practical, Ledbetter.
I've always had to be, my lady.
That...is just another knack.
I will have to learn.
- Ledbetter...
- Yes, my lady?
Would you mind very much
if I was to sit in the front?
No, well, l...I wouldn't mind, my lady.
Then l...think I will.
I've always wanted to sit in front.
- What does this do?
- Windscreen wiper, my lady.
Ledbetter, I wish you wouldn't call me "my lady"
all the time.
That sort of thing's going out very fast, you know.
What sort of thing, my lady?
That's right.
I don't think you like over-familiarity,
do you, Ledbetter?
I think we all have our place in life.
We don't all have our given places.
We make our own.
I don't think people talk to each other enough.
When I say talk, I mean...
communicate with each other.
Say what they really mean.
Actions speak louder than words, they reckon.
I don't think you really like me sitting here,
do you, Ledbetter?
I'm not sure it's very suitable, my lady.
And you're calling me "my lady" again.
Habits of a lifetime are very hard to break.
Does your wife think the same as you do?
I would say so, my lady.
What's she like?
I beg your pardon, my lady?
Your wife.
You mean in regards to appearance?
Yes. What does she look like?
She's a handsome woman, really.
If you don't mind my saying so, my lady,
she's not unlike yourself, in appearance.
You mean she looks like me?
Well, yes, the same kind of looks.
The same...colouring.
Yes. Surprising, really.
I'm very ordinary.
If I may say so, my lady,
I think quite the contrary.
Your wife, what's her name?
Frances.
You must be very happy.
Sometimes.
It's nice to know
there's somebody waiting for you, my lady.
Tuesday, Thursday, at 11, then.
My pleasure, my lady.
- Give us a bun.
- No, I won't.
- Mrs Roberts always does.
- Oh, please!
I've told you before.
Now, get out, both of you. Go on.
Another cup?
No, thanks.
- Sweet?
- No, thank you, Doreen.
It's plain with jam or plain with syrup.
Another cup of tea, please.
Shall I come over tonight?
- I've got work to do.
- Well, I'd like to come over sometime.
Stay all night.
- Steve.
- I've got a very early start in the morning.
Well, I'd like to come sometime.
How about the tea, Doreen?
Oh, it's whistle and I'll come to you,
my love, innit?
Yes, that's about it.
This train is for Bristol only.
Bristol only!
Mind the doors!
Mind the doors, please!
I haven 't been here
since my father brought me.
Quite a long way for you to come.
How's your wife?
- As a matter of fact, she's got a slight cold.
- Oh, I'm so sor...
Just slight. Sorry, my lady.
- You all right?
- Yes, thank you.
Do you help in the house?
Yes, well, we all pitch in together, you know.
Do you ever take your family out for picnics?
Yes, but not in the car, of course.
Why ever not?
Well, that wouldn't be suitable, my lady.
- Did I say something funny?
- No.
Nobody knows how it got here but it's quite old.
- It's not very good, is it?
- What do you mean?
Well, it doesn't look like a horse, does it?
But it is beautiful.
Beautiful?
Well...don't you think it's beautiful?
Well...I have my own ideas, my lady.
Those boring Lahills
want to give a dinner party for you.
I think you should go.
As a matter of fact,
I think you might rather like them.
I'd rather not, Mother.
I expect they'll invite some old friends of Tom's.
I'll see how I feel.
You miss Tom very much, don't you?
Would you like some...?
Thank you very much.
Pardon me, ma'am.
My dear, I know so well how you feel.
- I know you do.
- I was terribly disturbed when your father died.
Helen, you really must make an effort.
You must talk to people more.
Mother...
..when you go to Paris,
do you stay in a hotel or in your own rooms?
- In the apartment.
- I mean the apartment.
You'll love it now. I've just had it all redecorated.
I've got rid of all that awful old brocade.
It's all been done pale powder blue.
I don't think you've ever been there, have you?
Mother, I think I will go home to Radley Grange.
Is that wise?
I mean, you've only got Mrs Hansen
and that awful girl.
I shall use Ledbetter.
Ledbetter?
Percy, will you park the van up further?
These carpets are too heavy to carry by myself.
OK, OK, take it easy. Take it easy.
Put these in the back hall, Perkins.
Then get the books from the van.
Ledbetter, will you please
take those upstairs for me?
- Oh, yes, I want that one.
- Thank you, my lady.
Coming down.
Perkins! Give me those books.
The screen in the sitting room.
Asked me to bring these books in for you,
my lady.
Put them on the shelf.
I had a middle parting then.
Break!
Come on, use your weight!
Onslow, you keep your left up!
Hook him, Malcolm.
What do you want with all this, Steve?
First of all, I like it.
Secondly, the captain asked me.
- Captain Cantrip, his class. Do us a bit of good.
- Why do I do this?
Keep your left up! Because I asked you, didn't l?
Got a lovely little girl going out of her mind
with loneliness for me tonight.
I mean, I don't see why, Steve!
That's better, Onslow.
Put some punches together, Malcolm.
Put them together, Malcolm.
Two to the body, come on.
Bring his hands down, then hook him.
That's better.
We can get the Captain's business, can't we?
All right, so we make some lovely little accounts.
What about my love life? It's all right for you.
What does that mean?
Lovely lady, driving up front with you.
Maybe that's what she's going to give
instead of handing out tips.
Come on, Corporal.
Let's give them a little demonstration.
Give them a little lesson, shall we?
Come on.
Come on, Steve, we ain't got no gloves on!
You put your hands up.
You won't need no gloves.
- Yeah, come on, Sergeant Major!
- Watch it, Steve!
- You watch it!
When you speak of a lady,
speak of her with respect!
Up in the air!
All right, lads.
Back into mufti. Finish for today.
Come on, now. Clear off. Get out of it.
That's it for today. Good night, boys.
- Good morning, Mrs Hansen.
- I thought it was the electric man.
- The what man?
- The electric machine went wrong.
We've been waiting for him all morning.
- Is that him?
- No, my lady, it's Ledbetter.
Oh, Ledbetter,
you've heard of our little catastrophe.
Very inconvenient for you, my lady.
Hello?
Try...
He really puts on airs, that electric man.
Will you give that number another ring, then?
Of course, he's the only man for miles around.
- But he must be there.
- Could I be of any help?
- Could you?
- I'd like to have a look at it, my lady.
Well, it's down here.
- I'll wait here in case the man arrives, my lady.
- All right.
Careful.
Would you be so kind, my lady?
Thank you, my lady.
Boxing championships, Hong Kong.
Only thing the cheap tattoo merchant could do
was a dragon.
Better than a boxing glove, though.
Boxing?
Regimental championships, my lady.
May l?
You're a man of many parts, Ledbetter.
Yes, I know how to look after myself, my lady.
Right...
give it another try, shall we?
That's lovely, Ledbetter.
Mrs Hansen!
You can switch on now upstairs, Mrs Hansen.
It'll do for the minute, but to tell you the truth,
the whole thing needs looking at.
You need a new generator.
I did so much enjoy our outing last week.
I'm glad.
Did you get your wife that new coat
you promised her?
- Yes.
- Did she like it?
Well, my lady, it was a bit like the one
you wore last week.
You know, the brown one.
Brown suits you better - the colouring, I mean.
But that's what she wanted, you see.
Watch it, Harry. Too hard.
- Bring her round to the right!
- No, no, left again!
- Left! That's right.
- Right!
Out shopping, Sergeant Major?
- Good evening, my lady.
- Good evening.
You certainly gave Mr Davis a fright last night,
Sergeant Major.
The boys didn't half enjoy it.
Will you get that cart out of here?
Are you a friend of young Steven's?
- What?
- Onslow, would you mind, please?
Get that cart out of here for me, will you?
Hold it!
Forward a bit, forward.
Hold it, hold it.
Is he a friend of your son 's?
- He's one of the lads from the club.
- Club?
A boxing club, my lady.
I teach there sometimes.
- Really?
- Captain Cantrip asked me. I'm glad to help.
- Cantrip.
- Do you know him, my lady?
Yes, I do believe I do.
He was a liberal candidate
when my husband stood for Parliament.
Yes, well, he may have
some funny political opinions, my lady,
but he has a very good war record.
Perhaps I should support
some of these local activities.
I ought to do something for your club.
- What could I do?
- You could give them a cup, my lady.
Oh, what an excellent idea!
- The boys would like that, and the Captain.
- And you?
Well, I always liked it
when there was something worth fighting for.
The Lady Franklin Challenge Cup.
Oh, no, no.
No, the Sir Thomas Franklin Challenge Cup.
- Good morning, my lady.
- Good morning, Mrs Hansen.
It's nice to see you looking so well.
I'm sorry I'm late with your breakfast.
I had to see my son off at the station.
- How is he?
- He's going to a new place: St Dunstan's.
They'll teach him this Braille reading.
You know, where you read by touch.
He seems happy enough.
I don't know...
How selfish one is.
Not you, my lady.
Mrs Hansen!
Read this.
I've got butter all over it.
"Your Ladyship...
We, the undersigned committee
and members of the Radley Boxing Club,
wish to offer our thanks
and appreciation of your fine gesture
and gift of a silver challenge cup to our club. "
At 1900 hours, the ushers will be in position.
At 1930 hours, the public will be admitted.
At 1945, her ladyship will arrive,
driven by myself.
- Sergeant Major...
- Yes, sir?
I thought that I might pick up Lady Franklin,
don't you think?
Sir, I thought it would be very good,
a suitable gesture,
from the committee, sir, if my own car...
It's from my own firm, you see, sir.
It's a very nice gesture, Ledbetter.
Not at all, sir.
2000 hours, the first bout. Lightweight.
Mr Pettifer will referee.
This bout is not a very well matched pair,
so it may not run into three rounds.
So I think that will end about 2010.
Middleweight bout.
I was saying, sir, Mr Pettifer will again referee.
I don't think that the first effort
will quite have exhausted him, sir.
Oh, Ledbetter, I'm sorry I'm late.
Not at all, my lady.
We're running to schedule.
Just a few minutes behind.
A formal occasion, I quite understand.
I think I really am quite nervous, Ledbetter.
You mustn't worry, my lady.
We're all solidly behind you.
- I haven't been out since...
- Yes, my lady?
Be lucky if we get a seat tonight.
- Still nervous, my lady?
- No, I'm fine now.
Sit in these chairs here.
- Good evening, Lady Franklin. How do you do?
- Good evening.
You're looking remarkably well, Lady Franklin.
- You got held up, I suppose?
- Something political, I expect?
- Is Captain Cantrip coming?
- He'll be here, miss.
May I introduce Dr Henderson?
- Good evening, Lady Franklin.
- Good evening.
If you could sit here, my lady.
- Magnificent cup, Lady Franklin. Delightful.
- Oh, do you like it?
Yes. Marvellous.
- Good evening, Lady Franklin.
- How nice to see you again.
Ledbetter.
- Ledbetter?
- Excuse me, my lady.
Don't leave me alone.
Come and sit here till he comes.
Thank you, my lady.
- lsn't your wife here tonight?
- My wife doesn't like...
Oh, excuse me.
Are you going to adjudicate the first few bouts?
No, Mr Pettifer,
I'll stay here until the Captain comes.
Yes, well...
As I was saying, my lady, my wife doesn't like
boxing. I think it makes some women nervous.
Oh, does it?
Oh, yes.
Ahem... Ladies and...
- Speak up!
- Would you mind if I had a cigarette, my lady?
Oh, no, not at all.
Actually, I think I might have one too.
The first contest is a...a...bantam-weight bout,
between Farrell in the blue sash
and Collins in the red sash.
I suppose I'd better go to this...
Connie?
Yes?
It's all right, I'm coming.
I suppose I must go to
this ridiculous boxing match.
Careful.
- Right. Drink it while it's hot, all right?
- I've got it.
Yeah, well, if... Oh, look at this mess.
- My clean sheets!
- Sorry.
If you must, you must. Really!
Sorry.
What a very undemanding woman you are,
Connie.
So long as I get what I want.
I suppose it won't matter much
if I miss the first few fights.
Go on!
The boy in the red sash
did much better that round.
- Not enough though, my lady.
- It was a good try though.
- But not enough.
- The winner: Weatherly, in the blue corner.
I told you so.
Another couple of rounds and he would've won.
But the thing is, my lady, that was the last round.
Well, anyway...
Well, anyway, you rather liked it, didn't you?
Yes. I must say, it's quite riveting.
Isn't it a bit brutal, though?
Those two? Those two are
about as brutal as a bag of doughnuts.
Oh, I think they're trying quite hard.
You should have seen some of our army bouts,
my lady.
Excuse me now. I've got to go and referee.
I must be there for the prize-giving.
Don't worry, darling.
You're always there
when the prizes are being given out.
That's my coffee. It's got sugar in.
- You haven't got a handkerchief, have you?
- Mm, yes, sure.
There you are.
I wonder if you'll make me late
for Cabinet meetings one day.
I'll do my best. But if I don't, someone else will.
God - the time!
I won't bother to walk you to your taxi.
Someone might recognise you...or me.
- You're so practical.
- Yes.
- We both are, aren't we?
- It's nice, isn't it?
- Mm.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Break!
Go on!
Go on! Go on!
Stop boxing! Stop boxing!
- What's he saying?
- Warning them for leaning.
Oops! Sorry.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
Constituency party business.
I've no need to tell you how they go on and on.
I'm Hugh Cantrip.
Oh, yes, of course.
We have met, two or three times.
Notably when your distinguished husband
beat me hollow.
- lncidentally, I was so sorry to hear...
- Thank you very much.
You've missed some very exciting sport.
Well...needs must.
- Where are we?
- This is the last bout.
God, how awful.
Still, you're the one
whose presence was essential tonight.
Quite a lovely cup. Thank you.
Glad you could make it, sir.
Stop boxing!
The winner...Thomas Torrington.
Bravo. Very good show.
So glad I caught the grand finale.
You must tell me about the rest of it at dinner.
Oh, is that on the agenda?
I think the least the club can do
is feed its benefactress.
- Well, if it's official...
- Very official.
2230 hours, chairman will entertain
Lady Franklin for dinner at the Avon.
The Avon?
Good heavens! I haven't been there for years.
Good evening, sir. I thought
you weren't going to put in an appearance.
- Sorry, Sergeant Major. Party business.
- Pity you didn't mention it before, sir.
It's difficult for us to vote for
the best boxer of the evening without you.
I'm perfectly content to abide by your decision.
In any case,
I don't know too much about boxing either.
In that case, sir, if it's all right with you,
we thought that young Torrington...
The winner of the last bout?
I do think young Torrington was far and away
the most stylish boxer of the evening.
- Do you agree?
- Well, I'd like to give them all prizes.
Yes, I do agree.
Well, in that case...
My lady, Mr Chairman,
members of the committee,
ladies and gentlemen...
The Sir Thomas Franklin Challenge Cup
for the most promising -
the most stylish boxer of the evening,
Mr Thomas Torrington.
Congratulations, Torrington.
Your party will destroy it.
It will never recover.
Your coffee and brandy will be served shortly.
Thank you.
..by a huge majority. A huge majority.
Do you know,
you're entirely different to what I expected.
Am l? Some sugar?
No, no.
You're different too.
In what way different?
Tell me the truth.
All right, then. I will.
I always thought that you were...
a rather conceited popinjay.
Well, that sounds like
a Sir Thomas Franklin expression.
Oh, no, no. No, Tom always thought
that you had great ability.
Well, that's nice.
And charm.
That's nicer.
Well, l...
..killed the old tradition of moderation,
instead of which,
he left everything to Lloyd George in Paris.
- You know her?
- I'm not sure.
I suppose you must do.
She's been talking politics all evening.
Yes, I know. It's pretty boring.
I er...I always thought
that you were...rather stiff and proud.
- Oh, dear.
- And cold.
Very Lady of the Manor, indeed.
I don't think I'm much like
the Lady of the Manor.
It's nice that we were both so very wrong.
- Vodku.
Pravda. I konyaku.
Two cognacs, please.
Bloody foreigners.
- Thank you, sir.
- Good night.
- Hope we'll see you again, sir.
- Yes, very soon. Thank you.
What a beautiful evening.
"We'll entrap an English evening's magic hush."
Who wrote that?
I'll think of another poem. Ahh, let me see...
Sergeant Major,
I hope we haven't kept you up too late.
Ledbetter, did you get something to eat?
Don't worry about the old regimental war horse.
They always get their oats.
The Grange, Ledbetter. Then take me home.
Thank you, sir. Thank you, my lady.
"From where we were,
It seemed that England was suspended
in a never-ending summer."
"And is there honey still for tea? "
Grantchester!
- Rupert Brooke.
- Rupert Brooke, of course.
"Ah, God.
To see the branches stir
Across the moon at Grantchester. "
The rhyme was a little weak,
but the nostalgia was very strong.
It's exactly how we felt out there.
Was it very bad?
Well, you are back now.
Am l?
Sometimes, I wonder.
Making good money.
Can we have someone to help round here?
Well, answer it, Steve!
Look, you're the bloody office round here.
I'm just the bleeding working class.
Hallo? Ledbetter's Motors.
Lady Franklin.
Herself?
Hang on. Hang on.
All right.
Thank you.
Her housekeeper wants you to pick up
some shopping, take it on up to the Grange.
You take it.
Ahh! Look, I've only got this whole bloody heap
to put together again, haven't l? Go on!
She's still the best bloody client we've got.
Two weeks without hearing from her and,
when she does call, it's her bloody housekeeper!
Oh, thank goodness. What a blessing.
- You've been entertaining a lot, haven't you?
- Like Lion's Corner House, it's becoming here.
Lovely lunch party yesterday: Captain Cantrip
and some of the political bigwigs.
They didn't half get through some wine.
And what they did to the best Champagne...
Captain Cantrip's been here, has he?
Well, it's nice to see
Her Ladyship enjoying herself.
- Let me help you with that, Mrs Hansen.
- Oh, thank you.
I expect we'll have to look round for more help
if we're gonna be busy again.
Oh, that silly girl.
I suppose, Mr Ledbetter,
you never thought of going into service?
- No.
- I only mentioned it.
- Mrs Hansen?
- A good position here for the right man.
Oh, Ledbetter, don't go for a moment.
Ledbetter, it is good to see you.
It seems simply ages
since that marvellous evening you arranged.
I was wondering what had happened to you,
my lady.
I have been so busy since then.
It is...ridiculous.
But I will be needing you,
for one or two days next week.
I hope I'm available.
Oh, are you very busy, then?
Hardly.
Oh, so you don't want my custom?
Of course I do and you know that.
You must know I do, my lady.
Well, what is it, then?
To tell you the truth,
I may not be in the hiring business much longer.
I don't understand. You are getting work, surely?
Work? Oh, yes, there's plenty of work.
But I'd probably earn more money working
for somebody else, for a master, you see.
I'm afraid I don't know much
about these kind of things.
Well, it's the expenses, the overheads, you see.
Yes, I suppose there must be...
Though I still don't quite see, though.
Payments on the car.
Payments?
I really don't want to involve you in my problems,
my lady.
I've told you a great deal about mine.
Yes, well, that's different.
Look, I owe it to you to listen, if you want to talk.
And you owe it to me
to trust me if there is something wrong.
Well, I'm going bust,
that's why I won't be able to see you again.
Bust?
Broke.
I'm behind with the payments on the car.
After the war, I went to an auction
and bought it very reasonable,
but I had to go to a money-lender for cash.
Now he can take away the car.
But he can't do that, surely?
Oh, yes, he can.
But, Frances...
Oh, she'll be so upset.
Well, that's another thing,
Frances is sick and treatments cost a lot.
Ledbetter, may I help?
Oh, no.
Why not?
Because it isn't your responsibility.
Now that you've told me, of course it is.
No, my lady, l...I'll just sell the business.
I'll move away from here, somewhere else.
But, moving away, how can that possibly help?
No, I've got to straighten this out for myself,
my lady.
How much is involved?
A lot.
How much?
Well, it's almost $400.
What is your first name?
Ledbetter, your first name?
Steven with a V.
- Here. Take it. I absolutely insist.
- I can't.
You have to. It's a present.
If I was to take that...
You must.
You have to call it a loan, my lady.
Call it what you will.
No, I can't take that.
- It is the least I can do.
- My lady, it isn't right.
- I have never done anything for anyone.
- That is not true.
My family gave me everything they could.
My husband gave me everything else.
I waited till it was too late to thank him,
to show him my gratitude.
- You have given me something very important.
- Have l?
Yes. When I desperately needed someone
to talk to, you were there. I never was.
When my father needed me, I wasn't there.
When my husband died, I was out
enjoying myself at a stupid, stupid party.
I insist on it, Steven.
Please let me help.
Thank you, my lady.
400 bleeding quid.
You know what that means?
We could buy a new car.
Buy a whole bloody fleet of 'em.
I told her I was a married man.
You what? What did you do that for?
I don't know how I took it from her.
She's a bad case.
Their own men can't give 'em enough,
gone all soft and nancy.
She gave you 400 quid,
cos you're such a lovely, safe driver?
You're like a virgin, squire.
It's all mine.
It's all rotten, filthy, dirty, stinking mine.
Ow!
Oh, yes, I remember the family very well.
There was Richard. He was the eldest.
It was ridiculous. Do you know, she said
they'd gone out and John had gone to sleep.
The state is absolutely powerless...
- She went to see them.
- She married Colonel Frederick Trotter,
has a place down in Hertfordshire.
- I know her. I'm not wearing any of that...
- Married John Parker...
- Well, it's...
-..who's a local squire and...
It's been lovely to s... Sorry. Oh, sorry.
Well, it's lovely to see you all again
and very good of you to come,
but I'm afraid it is time to pay the piper
and l...would like to ask Captain Cantrip
to say a few words.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Erm...
Well, I'm afraid that listening to me
is almost too high a price
to pay for even a superb lunch
as that which Lady Franklin has given us.
Huxley...Donald Shapston...
Well, the fact is, the thing I'm going to talk about
is a subject we'd all carefully avoid
if we all met at the same table.
Well, the one thing that we have in common,
apart from a tremendous regard
for Helen Franklin,
and that is...a profound regard for our county
and our country.
Hear, hear.
I know that, since the war, many of us
have asked ourselves the question,
does our-our country
or our erm...or our party come first?
Because, as we all know, the...
He's no fool. Liberals don't stand
a chance here, anyway.
..because of the interests of various parties.
And, well, sadly, this constituency, which was
so superbly represented in past years,
- must now seek a new representative.
- Sir Thomas died very suddenly, didn't he?
I am glad to say that
I shall be presenting myself on this occasion.
Not as a member of the Liberal Party,
but as an independent.
If you're going to cross the Rubicon,
you might as well do it after a good lunch.
She's bound to bring him
some of the old supporters.
She might bring him quite a bit more than that.
Lady Franklin does share my feelings
about this matter.
And, indeed, my feelings
about the political urgencies of the time.
And er...I shall be making a more official speech
at the meeting tonight.
Well, l...
Thank you.
Yes, well, Anna Maria,
she was the luckiest of the lot,
because she married the first Baron Hunsdon.
But it was the other side of the family
that was infinitely more interesting,
because they had some estates in Scotland,
Ayrshire, I think.
They go back to Malcolm lll, I believe.
.. and I said to her...
So...the end of another utterly beautiful day.
Yes, it has been a lovely day, but I do wish
you'd let me come to the meeting tonight.
I would love you to come,
but I don't think it would be politic.
It might even be a little unpleasant.
Hugh...
I feel you wouldn't be making this stand
if it hadn't been for our talks together.
I do feel a bit responsible.
Yes, you are.
You're responsible for an awful lot
that's been happening to me lately.
But I think it would be best if you didn't come.
All right.
Goodbye.
I know many of you who also put Britain first.
Together, we shall march forward bravely
to meet whatever the future may bring.
Thank you all very much. Good night.
Thank you.
This is the Captain's car, isn't it?
Yes, it is, ma'am.
I bid you all a hearty good night.
I thought l...
Would you support Direction of Labour, sir?
- You know I don't like surprises, Connie.
- Neither do l.
- Where would you like to go, sir?
- Pemberton Drive.
Yes, that'll do.
Well?
Well, what?
Look, nothing's changed between us
and nothing will change, whatever happens.
- I'm sure you'll keep on paying the bills.
- Oh, Connie.
And I'm sure you'll always come back...
whenever it's discreet.
Don't be unfair, my dear.
No, Hugh, don't you being unfair.
- Look, you said yourself...
- I don't care if you neglect the bills,
so long as you never, ever neglect me.
I think I know your requirements
well enough by now.
Exactly.
Just make sure you go on supplying them.
What a very unromantic creature you are,
Connie.
Yes, I leave romance
to the ladies and gentlemen who invented it.
God.
Pemberton Drive, sir.
What?
Well, that's fine. Thank you.
At least you could see me to the door.
Of course.
I er...I shan't be needing you any more tonight,
Ledbetter.
- I feel like a bit of a walk.
- Thank you, sir.
Well...good night.
Good night, sir.
Dear Lady Franklin...
My lady,
Captain...
It has come to my notice that Captain...
Dear... My lady...
Don't forget you've got to pick up Mrs Druce.
Surely this isn't the usual way I go?
I thought it might make a change for you,
madam.
I don't like changes.
I like the old way.
Sorry, madam.
Whatever is it?
A bit of a breakdown.
Most inconvenient.
Sorry, madam. I shall
have to try and find a telephone, madam.
That's another thing I don't like: telephones.
I shall only be a few minutes.
And I don't like being left alone, do l?
Oh, all right, all right. Patience, patience.
- Oh, Mr Ledbetter...
- Our car's broken down, Mrs Hansen.
- Could I use your telephone, please?
- Yes, I'm sure that'll be all right.
- I've got a client in there, you see.
- Oh, dear.
- How's Her Ladyship?
- Quite a gadabout. It's nice to see it.
- She's in, then, is she?
- Yes, she's in her room doing her letters.
..we arrive at lunchtime,
we'll be able to have tea in the house.
I'm sure you'll be delighted to know...
I don't think I really want to go
all the way to London, Hugh.
No, I'd love to, in one way...
I'm not a nuisance.
Oh, you're very mean.
No, all right.
Yes.
Anything the matter?
No, nothing, I was just...
What?
- Nothing.
- 2:30.
- Mm.
- I said 2:30.
No.
- Number, please?
- Radley two-three.
- Two-three?
- Yes. Radley two-three.
No answer.
- Let it ring a bit, will you?
- Please yourself.
Hello? Lady Franklin 's residence.
Hello?
Yes, I want to speak to
the mistress of the house, please.
Is that Mr Ledbetter?
Hello?
- Yes it is, yes.
- She's got a dinner party.
Oh, it's Ledbetter, my lady.
I told him you had a dinner party.
- I'll talk to him.
- Her Ladyship will speak to you.
Very nice of her. Thank you.
Good evening. What is it, Ledbetter?
I'm rather busy at the moment.
Well, it's like this...
The thing is...
The thing is, I've just come back
and got a message from my partner
who's got shocking handwriting -
looks like your name, my lady.
- Says to call you immediately.
- I certainly didn't call.
Well, I'm sorry.
Must be somebody else, then.
I was going to call you this afternoon,
funnily enough.
Yes?
Do you happen to be free next Monday?
I shall spend the weekend at Alderton Manor
and I'll need collecting.
Oh, yes, certainly, my lady. What time?
I'd like to be there for luncheon. Alderton Manor.
Thank you.
I'm sorry to disturb your dinner, my lady.
Not at all. Good night, Ledbetter.
Good night.
Thank you very much. Good night, my lady.
Your present. You nearly forgot.
- Oh, Edwina, thank you. I'm so sorry.
- That's quite all right.
- Goodbye.
- Bye-bye.
- Don't forget, you can always use the villa.
- Thank you very much. Bye.
- Goodbye.
Oh, my.
Phew!
I think I've had a little too much Champagne.
I hear you've been getting out and about a lot,
my lady, and seeing a lot of people.
People have been very kind to me.
And I'm feeling very happy.
You needed taking out of yourself.
I hear you've been seeing
a lot of Captain Cantrip, my lady.
What, do you mean people are talking?
Oh, I don't know.
Have they got anything to talk about?
They always have something to talk about,
if they want to talk, don't they?
Yes.
- They could talk about you and me, for instance.
- You and me?
Why should they want to do that?
Well, you're sitting in the front of the car,
my lady.
There's nothing wrong in that.
It's got stuck.
Could I do it for you, please, my lady?
Excuse me.
Thank you.
I'm quite exhausted.
Have I been asleep long?
- About half an hour, like a baby.
- Oh, dear.
You're beautiful.
My...
Oh, dear.
Beautiful.
I've kept you very late tonight, Steven.
- Do you think your wife would like these?
- I haven't got a wife.
- What?
- I'm sorry?
- I never got married. I never wanted to be.
I don't understand.
- Frances and the children...
- The children don't exist.
- I thought that would make you interested.
- lnterested?
- I thought that's what you wanted to hear.
- Wanted to...
Why... Why on earth should l?
I didn't want you to think
that I didn't have something of my own,
that I was all by myself.
You're not by yourself.
You have your business.
No.
What?
- I never thought of you as a lonely man.
- I am lonely.
I'm lonely all the time you're not here.
Ledbetter...
I suppose I shouldn't say things like that.
- Why shouldn't you if they're true?
- Every time you don't ring,
every time I don't take you out, I think of you.
I wonder what you're doing, who you're with.
I tried to tell you on the telephone at the Grange
the other day.
If I don't talk to you, I can't...
I can't talk to anybody about anything.
At first, well, it was just like listening to a client,
then you go back to your own life.
But I haven't got any life to go back to,
as everything is here with you.
Ledbetter, l...
I mean, we're a man and a woman, aren't we?
- Oh, yes. Yes, we...
- I'm not just a chauffeur.
You're not just Lady Franklin.
I'm not just somebody you hire, am I?
No, no, of course not.
- I mean, I am a man and you're a woman.
- Yes, w...
Well, I love you.
I love you.
I love you, Helen.
I love you. I love you.
- I love you.
- Don't.
- I love you. I love you. I love you. I love you.
- Please.
I love you.
I love you. I love you.
No.
Please don't. Will you stop it?
Oh...stop, please!
Ledbetter, stop it!
You don't love me.
I don't know the meaning of the word
and I don't suppose I ever will.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so...
I seem to have made a fool of myself.
I don't suppose you'll be requiring
my services any longer, my lady.
No.
Take me home, please.
What's the matter, Steve?
Did I do something wrong?
I'd do anything for you, you know that.
Honest, Steve. I mean it.
You know that I mean it, don't you?
Don't you, Steve?
Sounds like Ledbetter's car.
Yes, Ledbetter, what do you want?
What the bloody hell do you think you're doing?
Ledbetter?
What's the matter?
You don't know what it means, do you? Love.
- Is that what you said?
- Get out, Ledbetter, you're drunk.
You told me everything about what you feel.
Does it matter what anybody else feels?
Ledbetter, whatever you have to say,
this is neither the time nor the place.
- Will you please go?
- Of course, l...
Look, Sergeant Major,
whatever's on your mind must wait...
Don't do that.
Listen, I did my job well, didn't l?
- I mean, I did what I was hired for.
- Oh, yes.
Yeah, but now I want to speak,
you don't have the time to listen.
Ledbetter, you have always been most kind
to me and I shall always be very grateful.
Cap'n... Brave Cap'n.
Nothing.
You know what the Captain is? He's a cheat.
- He's a liar.
- I'm going to call the police.
That Captain is a liar.
Do you know what the Captain wants you for?
He wants you for your money.
He's got a girl.
He is doing... He is doing her day and night!
I don't want to listen to this.
You are embarrassing me
and making a fool of yourself.
- Now, will you please leave?
- Yes, well, my lady,
I'm just trying to tell you, I heard them -
I heard them in the back of our car.
- Ledbetter, you're abusing a privilege...
- Privilege?
Course I'm abusing a bloody privilege!
My-my-my kind always does, doesn't it?
Doesn't it?
We take every bloody diabolical liberty
in the book.
I mean, and you say you keep 'em in their place,
and so we'll keep our own.
So I'm supposed to be a chauffeur. A bloody
chauffeur, stuck on the end of the wheel.
Right at the edge of the engine.
See nothing, hear nothing.
Well, I tell you...
I tell you something, Captain...Captain...
We're nothing. I'm a bloody chauffeur.
You're a gentleman, right?
Well, I'll tell you something.
You bloody people,
you ladies and gentlemen,
you make me ill.
You make me...sick.
Come on, Captain.
Now, you hit me...
You hit me...
Mmm? You hit me once.
- You hit me just once.
- Ledbetter.
Captain Cantrip and I are going to be married.
Now, will you please leave immediately?
All right.
Well, I suppose you got what you deserved.
May I have a drink?
# It's a long way to Tipperary
# It's a long way to go...
# Rule Britannia
# Britannia rules the waves
# Britons never, never, never shall be slaves...
# Mademoiselle from Armentieres, parley-voo
# Mademoiselle from Armentieres...
# Hinky, pinky, parley-voo...
# God save our gracious King
# Long live our noble King
# God save our King