Subtitles brought to you by The ♥ to Heart Team @ Viki
Timed by Myuu
Which part of your body are you going to emphasize?
I'm confident in everything.
I think I'll look good if I do this.
What is the prettiest part of my face?
My husband said he fell for my eyebrows. So do my eyebrows, and...
Make it as big as a 500 won coin.
You have to put on more.
- You must be a strange person who likes things like this.- Bigger!
All done.
Episode 9
Hong Do, what's wrong?
♫ To me, ♫
♫ Standing up again ♫
Get up, Hong Do.
Get up.
♫ It's not like I couldn't do the hard things ♫
Yi Suk. I want to eat something sweet.
Wait a minute. Wait.
Come out.
Wait a second.
What are you doing here? Did you come to see me?
I came here because I had something to say to this guy, but seeing how it is, there won't be any need.
Then, I'll go in.
Go in where? You want to go back there?
It seemed like it was a patient, so of course I should go. He can't see patients if I'm not there.
You say he can't see patients without you? You believe that?
Then what about that girl inside? What is she? Is she not a person?
There must be a reason. I'm going to ask.
Ask what?
It was very clear. Don't be like that.
Hey, Cha Hong Do, what are you doing?
Aren't you going to guard the hospital?
Oh, you look familiar. We've seen each other before, right?
Well, since we didn't even greet each other that day, you probably wouldn't remember.
What's that?
Hey, Ko Yi Suk!
I'll wait for you in the car, Darling.
What's with you? Why are you always hanging around here?
You're really a shameless bastard.
Hong Do, get in quickly.
Hey, Cha Hong Do, what are you doing?
Don't get involved and go!
How could you do that? That girl is your ex-lover, isn't she?
So what? Huh?
Get off! Can't you see I'm talking with this girl?
Is your decision already made?
Before asking anything, you just assume that I am an as*hole and you are the victim?
Fine. You were going to last only three months anyway.
Let's end it.
Hey, remove your car. Coming here with your shitty car...
As excepted, sweet things are great.
It seems like my stress is all relieved.
You seem very at ease.
Why did you suddenly appear and make everything so noisy?
It's just I played a joke because I wanted to see you.
What kind of joke is that? Are you bored?
I feel so uneasy now that my wedding is soon.
So you came to brag about your wedding.
Hey, but what's with you hugging your ex-boyfriend so tightly.
I was almost flustered for a moment.
You were flustered? Did you miss me?
Tsch.
What? So you didn't even think about me at all?
What time would I have to think about somebody
else's bride, when I need to take care of my girl?
Would that be a waste of time?
That's right. I like you because you're constant.
That girl who got angry in front of the hospital,
that was the girl from that time, right?
Yeah.
Hey. But you must have some kind of problem, right?
You've been crossing your legs. It looks
like you are worried about something.
What's going on?
Why? You seem like someone hoping that
there'd be something wrong with my marriage?
No.
Actually, I came to play with you.
When I get married, I have to act like a good, faithful wife.
Then, I can't do that anymore. So I want to play with you, once.
What about you?
You changed your helmet.
It's cute. It looks like an egg.
I got a bandage.
I got hurt a little while trying to catch a criminal.
It seems like you get hurt at least once a year.
You suffered so much when you broke your ribs last time.
Ah that's true.
You remembered it all.
Ever since I was little, I always had the title of the
eldest grandson, and so I grew up with a lot of attention.
When I got sick, the soup could be smelled across the whole town.
If they knew you were hurt like this, the whole
neighborhood would've been in an uproar.
For sure. I won't be able to tell them.
Back then, that attention was so annoying and burdensome.
But still, it doesn't seem like you would
have been annoyed, Detective Jang.
Because you're kind.
Hong Do, there's somewhere I'd like
to go with you now. Is that okay?
I'm going.
How is it? Do you like it?
Your wedding is right around the corner, what
were you doing, not even having chosen a bed yet?
I did choose one, at the price adding
zero to the price of this bed.
Then why did you want to come here?
I just felt like it. Wondering how it
would be if I was getting married to you.
I think about it when I see even just any man passing by.
What would it be like to get married to that guy?
Is it really right for me to get married now?
It's the typical marriage blues.
That's pre-wedding depression.
It will be gone when you get married. Just hurry set up a date.
I'm getting married and you don't even have an ounce of regret?
What if this marriage goes wrong?
That bastard. That bastard from a
rich family. Don't you love him?
No.
I don't.
Please hold onto me, Yi Suk.
Special Sushi.
Th-thank you.
I'm more thankful.
It's nice to see you two. Play until morning. All the way till then.
Go, quickly.
This is really delicious.
He made it specially today, so eat and don't leave any.
Yes.
I think you got a text.
I'll eat well.
Are you waiting for Ko Yi Suk's call?
Do you still like him even though
he was holding his ex in his arms?
Hong Do, he's the first man you went out with, right?
I really don't care what kind of person he is but,
I just wish you wouldn't get hurt.
I know you're worried about me.
But I'm not that innocent. I know a few things.
You really don't know about what's going on in the world.
Open your eyes and look at it realistically.
Does it really seem to you as if he cherished and loved you?
He's playing with you right now.
I know that, too.
That I don't match with him.
He wasn't holding another girl because you're lacking anything.
That's not what I'm saying at all.
I want to go home.
I'm sorry. Eat.
Why isn't she answering her phone?
Helmet
Oppa, do you know Detective Jang Doo
Soo from the Gangnam police station?
How do you know that bastard?
So you really know him. How? Is he a friend of yours?
He was the detective in charge of the drunk driving accident.
He's the one I sued before.
That was Detective Jang?
That bastard, really. Why did you get involved with him?
That's enough. Don't even deal with a bastard like him.
You guys must have been in bad terms.
What's that on your clothes?
Oh! That's lipstick!
He-hello...
Now you even get a woman's lipstick on your clothes?
You're so dirty. How can you get lipstick on your shirt?
Who is it?
When did that get stained?
Did that happen on the bed?
You are so shameless.
Really, if you weren't my brother I'd...
Who is that woman, who is not careful?
That's why I keep telling you to stop dating just anyone.
Is it an announcer? Did you get a new one again?
Hey, please leave. I'm tired, hurry! Leave!
You would be tired, meeting all those girls...
Hey, after you wash up, draw some water for me.
Hello?
Hey, you didn't pick up the phone. Where are you?
Why did you call?
I'm giving you a chance right now.
You should have an explanation for getting in Detective Jang's car
in front of me and leaving with him. Do you have nothing to tell me?
You said we should end it.
So it's the end? Really the end?
Why aren't you answering?
You heard what we were saying just then, didn't you?
I don't know.
When I was talking to my sister about the shirt and the lipstick?
Yes. Something about the bed and whatever. I heard it all.
Are you acting as if you didn't hear? Or are you just not interested in me?
Are you having fun, huh?
Your really looked down on me.
At least I ate something delicious with Detective Jang.
So, you like it?
Yes. But I was sad.
And angry.
I had decided not to get hurt again, but it is sad.
I'm hanging up.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Who's the one who's angry?
Wow, this is the king of reversals. How dumbfounding.
Every time that girl comes, she doesn't even eat and runs away.
No matter how I see it, she doesn't seem interested in you.
It's not. I was wrong.
I did all I can do.
I don't know what more I should do.
Then, don't think about it and make progress with your body.
Like go and grab her wrist. Or say "be my girl!"
You are so nice. So frustrating.
I wish I could turn back time.
I'll be going now.
See you tomorrow.
Aigoo, grandma. I wish you'd be careful with the way you act.
I don't think that, but if Doctor Go and Se Ro
and the kids saw, they'd definitely misunderstand.
Misunderstand? What misunderstanding?
You didn't hear about it?
Our chairman with his charming, white hair
You were touching his hair, while saying
that you will dye his hair or whatnot.
Then they'd think you're trying to seduce our Chairman!
Don't you think they'd see it like that?
No! No! What's wrong?! No!
So that you won't make men misunderstand, from now on,
be careful how you act. Understood?
Yes. I'll be careful. Good-bye.
Leave carefully.
I'm in front of Ko Yi Suk's house. I'll wait for you.
Madame Oh. You're going now? I'll take you.
Uh... it's enough.
You're a really difficult person.
Do you feel burdened? Or is it that you dislike me?
I'm a bit hurt, because you're always avoiding me.
Just think of me as a grandson and be comfortable.
It's because I'm thankful that you got my grandpa to laugh.
A man should not act so cheap.
Even if you are nice to a person, you could be
misunderstood. You shouldn't be nice to everyone.
A man should stick to one person.
How are you just anybody? You're my grandfather's friend!
She's weird.
Detective Jang, what are you doing here?
I wanted to drop you off.
Detective Jang! That person is coming! That person is coming!
It's okay, it's okay.
So you came on your own feet. My
body was feeling itchy today anyway.
You bastard, let's fight.
Madam Oh! How do you know this bastard? Is he your relative?
Does she have to tell you that kind of things?
It's just that it felt like someone who works at my house
was caught by a gangster. It's not just one or two times.
You even dragged Cha Hong Do away in front
of me. Is dragging women away your hobby?
- Then, what about you? Is making women cry your hobby? - Detective Jang, aren't you going?
No, he is a neighbor. Detective Jang, let's go.
You take care of everyone in your town.
Coming with your shitty car...
Remove your car, quickly! So I can go.
Subtitles brought to you by The ♥ to Heart Team @ Viki
Timed by Myuu
I'm sorry. Every day...
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing when I'm the one who did wrong?
It's me who put you in trouble because I came
and waited without telling you ahead of time.
You should be mad at me.
I don't have any right to say this. But it's because I hate it.
Ko Yi Suk's house, Ko Yi Suk's hospital, Ko Yi Suk's
family. I hate that you're in all of these things.
I...
Today, I've thought about it.
I realized that I've been lying to people just for my own benefit.
That person. That person's Grandfather. And the family.
If they knew I'm not a granda but Cha Hong Do...
How betrayed they would feel.
After looking at myself all scared that he will found out,
I realized then, that I'm
doing something really bad.
Detective Jang... I'll take the bus.
You mean a lot to me, so
I don't feel comfortable.
I'm sorry.
I'll be quiet from now on.
Please feel at ease.
I mean, she asked me to treat her pre-wedding depression.
I knew girls were selfish, but isn't that being too shameless?
Weren't you going to give that to me?
- Here. Enjoy your coffee.  - Thank you. Do you want to try this?
Thank you, as expected.
Why are you grinning so wide?
Are you that happy that she's clinging onto you?
She wants to play.
Well, since she's about to marry, how Ko Yi Suk is the alpha male,
she is just realizing.
She wanted to play, there was no reason to refuse, was there?
That bullsh*t, really.
Hey, send that announcer to me. Play!? You're
not even a kid, what do you mean play. Aigoo.
Eun Ho's eyesight came back.
She must feel a lot better after talking about her anger.
They are both getting better because she is getting consulted with Jin Ho.
The mother was so grateful she said she'd buy you a meal.
The twins were fighting for their mother's attention.
They've grown a lot.
But did you counsel that TV presenter alone?
Yes. Why?
You were okay without Cha Hong Do?
Did your fear for patients subside?
That...
How can that be?
Is it because you didn't see her as a patient?
What are you doing? Go away.
What the heck, seriously.
Do you want to take a dump?
Hyung. I got myself into trouble.
What trouble.- Last night.
You know I like girl groups. With them,
we had a group chat and I sent your picture.
You know the picture of you looking really
handsome at the last sporting event. That one.
[sigh]
There's a girl in the group and she kept
asking me to introduce her to my friend.
She said she's going to bring a pretty friend if he looks nice,
and send me a picture. Wow, she's really pretty, totally like Miss Korea.
So I sent her your picture, instinctively.
Hey, are you out of our mind? Sell me out to get yourself a girl?
Ridiculous punk.
Man.
Tonight at 7 o'clock.
Help me out! Don't just tell me to meet women.
Let's say hi.
It's me. Can you come over here after work?
Play at the clinic?
You said you wanted to receive my counseling.
Of course you have to pay the counseling fee.
Ex-girlfriend discount?
We'll see.
I'll see you after work. Okay.
Alright. Shall we start our own counseling session?
Have a seat. Come over here.
You did well/
Do what?
Going to a restaurant with Detective Jang was a bad move,
but going to a public restaurant.
Congrats.
The girl I saw at the clinic last night. It's her, isn't she?
The one at the studio apartment last time.
I was hugging here here, alright. Got a lipstick mark too.
Why did she come?
You heard it. To receive counseling.
But why here?
She's a famous person that everyone recognizes.
Would she go to another psychiatrists to get counseling?
I should give her the counseling.
Right. Go home once Yeon Woo gets here.
Why go home? You said she's coming to get counseling.
Me... Is it okay without me?
Hey. There's a place we need to go.
So let's head there. And you can go home straight from there.
Okay? Let's go.
What's he saying?
Miss Korea.
Get that away.
FYI, she's 23, in college. Young, isn't she?
Forget it.
Hyung. When are we ever going to meet college girls?
Hey. What am I supposed to do?
The date? You can just go out there.
No, waiting.
Waiting, keeping by her side. How do you do it?
So... You just need to be her shadow.
Whether it rains, snows, or the wind blows, you never get swayed
and you just need to stay by her side. Difficult, isn't it?
Shadow?
She's pretty though.
Tonight at seven.
Seven. Not much time left. Let's go.
Forget it!
First, let's visit the tasting booths.
If you go around this way, there's dumpling,
sausage and all the other stuff. Go and eat them.
This isn't it. I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
I absolutely can't!
I'll tell you how.
First, you just walk over there.
Keep on walking, without thinking. Got it?
Here. Just go. Keep walking forward.
Okay. Second,
just go there and enjoy the food they give you. Isn't it easy?
Easy for you, but for me, it's not. It's only easy for other people.
Do you know how hard it is for me to be just standing here?
Are you really going to be like this? Don't you want to fix it?
Why does that announcer need counseling?
She's pretty and smart and doesn't have a disorder like I do.
So why am I seeing you?
I guess it's strange for you too.
When a girl like Woo Yeon Woo is the right match for me. Right?
To date me, you have to do this like a piece of cake.
Okay? I'll demonstrate first. Take a look.
Is this too soon?
She should do this much though.
Yi Suk. Take me!
Please take me!
Here are dumplings. Try one, Ma'am.
Try one, Ma'am.
It's very good.
We have dumplings. Try one!
Hello.- You can go home by yourself, right?
Why? Are you going somewhere?
I think something happened to Yeon Woo. Take a cab.
You can do that much.
You have to believe that you can do it.
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
There will be a special sale for ten minutes.
Just ten minutes! A beef set worth $100
To the first fifty customers...
Don't pick up. I don't want to see anyone.
No one. Go to a place where there is no one.
Quickly.
Subtitles brought to you by The ♥ to Heart Team @ Viki
Timed by Myuu
Doctor
The phone of the person you are trying to reach is off...
The international research team was found to be our country's first omnivorous dinosaur.[The domestic research team became the world's first to identify dinosaur fossil.]
Reporter Shin Na Ra reports.
I don't remember it.
I'm so embarassed I could die.
What hapened to me? Why am I like this, Yi Suk?
First, rest.
You are not in a condition where I can check you right now.
How can I rest when the Internet and the
broadcasting station are all going crazy!?
This is all because of you.
You always hurt my pride
So I wanted to meet someone better, get married and act proud.
But...
Why are all men like that?
My friend saw him coming out of a hotel with another woman.
I confronted him and he didn't even give any excuses.
Throw away that kind of bastard.
Cancel the wedding. What's holding you back?
After I said I'd get married into a rich family
My mom and dad were so happy.
I don't know what to do.
I can't.
I can't go through this marriage.
We've been overworking with all that's been going on,
so we're all still single. We shouldn't live like this.
So I've come up with the kind of man which the modern women prefer.
Teens. If we mess with them, we're in big trouble.
Yes, Cha Hong Do.
I'm sorry, but...
when you get off work, c-c-can you come here?
Where are you right now?
I have a lot to say.
Subtitles brought to you by The ♥ to Heart Team @Viki
Timed By Myuu
Welcome.
Excuse me. Where is the storehouse here?
What's the matter?
-A person is trapped in there.  -Huh?
Wait, but right now I...but...
Which way is it?
It's this way.
Hong Do, it's me! Are you inside?
Um...o-over here!
-The password.  -Okay.
It's open.
Hong Do, are you okay?
It's cold, right?
It must have been hard on you. What happened?
It's...
It's not Ko Yi Suk's fault.
It's my fault.
That person told me to
believe that I can do it.
But I...I...just ran away because I was scared.
Let me just ask you one thing.
Where is Ko Yi Suk right now?
With a patient.
He had something urgent to do with another patient so he went there.
Your reply is suspicious right now.
I couldn't ask him.
If there really was something going on with that woman...
Whether he was going to go back to her...
I was too scared so I couldn't ask.
Because I know all too well
that I don't match well with him.
Hong Do, you're not the type of person to be comparing yourself.
Why did you become like this after meeting Ko Yi Suk?
Here, wear this to sleep.
So you can leave me all alone?
So you can sleep comfortably.
Don't go.
What do you like so much about that girl? She's not even your type.
You're right. I even told her that.
That there was no part of her I could possibly like.
Then why?
I wasn't really sure all along,
but "this" was different.
With a person you really like.
Now I think I know.
Yi Suk, you're really cruel and petty.
That woman was real and I'm fake?
Sorry. Here.
Fine, go! Go away!
-Hello?  -Yeah.
Where are you? At home?
Yes...
Hey, why do you sound so down. Did you just wake up?
I sle...I slept...
You took a taxi home right?
Yes.
How is it? Was it doable?
Um...
What happened to that TV presenter?
Who do you think I am?
Well, since she's my ex-girlfriend, I should treat her.
Hey, Cha Hong Do. I'm going right now to meet
you so don't fall asleep and wait for me.
I'm sleepy though...
Wow, look at this woman playing hard to get.
Fine. I'll let it go since today was a nervous day for you.
Since I don't think you'll be able to fall asleep if I tell you how I feel right now,
I'll see you tomorrow. Good night.
Hello?
I'm crazy, I'm crazy.
I'm talking about that ugly thing, Cha Hong Do.
What the? Why are you here again?
You bastard, hey! Hey!
You need to get beat up you bastard.
You bastard! Bastard!
I'm going to...
Just!
You're dead today. This bastard.
Come over here. Come here, here!
Come here!
-You're dead!  -Let go!
It's all misunderstanding that arose while I was patrolling.
We'll settle this and part our ways. So you can head out.
-Are you a detective?  -Yes.
Do I look like I hit him? That bastard's the one who hit me first!
Catch that bastard! You guys are all gangster huh!?
-Be quiet! -Hey, I'm going to sue!
Hey! You're not catching him? Take him away!
This bastard, really!
Good work.
I'm going to sue you.
Hong Do
was left all alone.
At the storehouse. In that dark and gloomy
storehouse, she was trapped inside alone.
Hey you bastard, I don't know if you think
it's funny making a woman cry or be in pain,
but I can't forgive that.
So please, please just piss off, yeah?
Hey. Stop talking nonsense.
Do you really even know how I feel?
Hey, you already have that pretty and smart girl.
But why is it Hong Do!?
That woman doesn't even know anything about Hong Do, right?
If she doesn't know, are you going to tell her?
What kind of policeman gives threats?
Look at you...You're weak with alcohol.
That's why you always causing trouble!
No matter what you say, I choose Cha Hong Do.
Until when?
What?
Two weeks? One month? Can you even last three days?
This bastard's all talk.
Drink this all.
Look at him gulping it down.
I'm sure Hong Do will be the only one getting hurt.
But I won't just stand aside and look.
Before she gets hurt more, I...!
I'll put her back to what's originally her place.
Her original place?
Yes, her original place!
how hard it is to get her out. what?
that woman, in that box again...
put her back in that box-like house again?
to give to who? to give to you?
You seem to be really misunderstanding.
the original place is not that box,
It's also not next to you. But to me. Here!
Here, beside me.
That bastard, you're drunk.
Drink a bit more.
Drink.
Let's kill you for once today.
Yeah, let's do that.
grandma..
I'm going to stop disguising as you, grandma.
All that time...
I wanted to live and eat...
So I only thought of myself.
I think I didn't think about others.
I feel really sorry,
And I'm scared.
So I'm going to stop pretending to be you, grandma.
That's the right thing to do, isn't it?
Ko Yi Suk, are you playing with me?
But I like you.
Very much.
Subtitles brought to you by The ♥ to Heart Team @Viki
Timed by Myuu
What's that?
Doo Soo?
Doo Soo Jang! Did you sleep in my brother's room?
Your hair is cute. Ah, you smell of alcohol!
What happened? Did you drink with my brother?
I'm a bit late. I have to go quickly, so see you next time.
That's right, I got a role. Would it be okay
to get some experience at your police station?
We're going to start shooting soon, and I won't be able
to do it for long, so it will be for about a week.
If you send the forms to the police station, the general affairs
department will take care of it for you, so please do that.
Who doesn't know that? It's because I don't have time.
That's the good thing about knowing people.
You can help each other in need.
And you! You don't have a girlfriend, do you?
I already told you there's someone I like.
I don't think that's true.
I've investigated in many different aspects and
You don't seem bad, even for a marriage.
You and me are also very compatible.
Compatible? What are you saying?
Does it seem like a joke? I'm not joking.
I am a very impetuous and straightforward person,
But you're the first man I know to accept it all like that.
"Do whatever you want, and I'll accept it all." That kind of impression.
Will you realize it if I do this?
Aigoo, oh my word! What are you doing? At the house at that!
How can you so easily...
Hello. I'm Jang Doo Soo.
I don't remember it very well, but I think took
advantage of your hospitality. Really, I'm sorry.
Ahjuma, how is he? He's my brother's friend, right?
I don't know about that but I I saw him with your brother
I saw him crawl home last night dead drunk.
I am very sorry.
I'll be going now, then. Goodbye.
The bean sprouts fell.
I'll come to the police station!
Why to the police station, again?
I got a new role, and it's a female police officer.
I want to get a hands-on experience.
What a good morning!
Who are you calling first thing in the morning?
You know Sam Dam's president, right?
The one who used to own a rice store, located
right next to your store a long time ago.
It's his eightieth birthday this weekend,
so for the Jang Yoon Jeong dinner show,
he's sending an invitation. He's sending two tickets,
so he said you should bring your girlfriend.- What?
He told me to bring this?
You should go. I heard it's difficult to get a hold of those tickets.
Where would I be going all alone?
Then can I take those tickets?
I love seeing those kinds of things alone.
I know you love being alone, but
Why are you taking something that's for me?
What about giving Madam Oh a fancy dress as a nice gift?
If she wore it to go see a certain
singer's show, it would be really nice.
Okay, I got it, well...
ah.. my head..
Where did that bastard go?
Has he left?
Instead of me, she sent an S.O.S. to Detective Jang, is that right?
There's none.
If not a call, then there should at least be a text message.
Well, Detective Jang would be more
comfortable than me, since he's good to her.
Hello?
Hey, I have something to say, so come out.
now?
Did you forget I had another part time job
on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday mornings?
Just what is that Monday, Wednesday, and Friday part-time job?
Where are you?
Why?
Come to the hospital when you get off work. I have something to say.
Don't I always do that?
Okay.
This woman. She's not letting it out.
Ah, that was that.
That voice she had on the phone yesterday.
Ah, she cried.
Why doesn't she tell me?
Hello? What is it, Butler Ahn?
What? Evening work, you say?
Well then, it would be better after six o'clock.
Ah, I got it. Yes.
Ah, my body.
My body's aching all over.
Ahjumeoni, did everyone go somewhere? Why is nobody here?
They went out, and Se Ro went out too.
You need to keep Se Ro under control.
I don't know if it's because she's lived in America, but
going around everywhere...smooch, smooch, smooch...
What?
That friend you came with yesterday, he's dating with Se Ro, right?
That's exactly how it looked.
A friend?
Detective Jang? Hey, Ahjumeoni, you must have seen wrong.
Seriously. How can the chairman be so indifferent?
He knows full well that I like Jang Yoon Jeong,
but he's going with that old lady Madam Oh or whatever
to see the Jang Yoon Jeong show.
Ey~ So now you're upset? I'll get you
the tickets immediately. Don't worry.
Do you think I'm doing right now this because of the tickets?
I have money too! Don't you think I could get a
hundred tickets or ten tickets if I wanted to?
I don't want to see you, so go over there.
Just eat pollack soup in a little bit. Aigoo.
You're here?
You still haven't thrown it away.
So we finally get to eat breakfast together?
I already ate breakfast.
You're still the same.
I spent the night thinking.
Even if I ask anyone on the streets,
their answers will probably be the same.
I think it's right to end it.
But I... didn't know that I was such a materialistic person.
If dreaming of marrying a chaebol is being materialistic,
then all the women in the world are materialistic.
Then what do I do? Not get married?
Do it. Get married and get a divorce.
With evidence of his cheating, get a huge alimony payment from him.
Are you really a doctor?
This is something that no one can do for you.
The only thing I can tell you is this :
Whatever you choose, give it your all in that decision.
That's the way you'll live, okay?
Eat that.
Even if you're not the best doctor in this world
Even if you're a psycho, a player and a crook, you have to fix me.
Otherwise, otherwise, you're...
Otherwise... I'm gonna die right here.
Please fix me.
♫ I'm in love. ♫
I think I liked it too, that time.
It's really you.
What are you doing here?
I was on my way to work and I thought I should come to thank you.
I thought about just texting you...
If you'd done that, I'd have been resentful.
Thank you.
That kind of thing won't happen again.
I'm sorry that I was bothersome.
Why are you saying that when you know it wasn't bothersome at all?
Far from being bothersome, since you looked for me, I thought, "Ah,
Hong Do hasn't forgetten about me completely", so I was comforted.
I was really happy yesterday.
Happy that there was still something I could do for you.
Hong Do, you said that I was in your heart for the last seven years, right?
Do you know what the motto of the Gangnam police is?
It's, "The tenacious detective wins."
I'm really tenacious.
Wait and see. Right now is the start of seven years for me.
Is that burdensome?
Don't feel burdened.
You just need to think of it as winning the loto.
You get a bonus, and you get to do something meaningful.
You said you wanted to make an event, right?
It's an event. He's going to give us a bonus.
I'm counting on you.
-These workers are the best in...  -Beauty.
The enthusiastic ones, the ones who do a good job.
Yes.
Then I will touch up everyone's faces.
You can knead them until they pop.
Touching it, then?
Do well.
Yes, of course. Fighting!
Hwaiting!
It's this way.
Here. I think it's across from here. Let's see...
There. It's that house.
I'll wait here.
Go and give it to her.
Why? Let's go together!
When Madam Oh sees these clothes, she'll be really happy.
Don't you want to see her happy face?
When we go see the Jang Yoon Jeong show, I'll see it all anyway.
Just go and give it to her.
And... wait, wait.
Don't throw it to her as if you're handling a bag of chips
but deliver it gently.
Yes. I'll go quickly.
So she lived in that kind of place.
Who is this?
Huh?
What? He died?
Where's the morgue?
This punk.
Chairman! Chairman!
Did you come after your part time job?
All this time... were you playing with me?
What?
Did you get tired of always meeting pretty and well-off girls,
Since I'm a girl who's ugly,
uneducated and pathetic enough to have anthrophobia too...
Did you find it interesting and new, so you decided to play with me?
How is it, after playing with me for a few days?
Are you sick of it again? Or is it since you
met another smart and pretty girl again
do you feel like I'm really not the one?
How is it? What are you going to do now?
Now you've gotten the courage to ask?
That inferiority complex of yours, it's pretty considerable.
Yes, I'm asking you now because I'm foolish.
Answer me.
Let's go out. We have somewhere to go.
Were you lying about doing counseling with that woman
Even though you say you can't counsel without me?
You're really stupid. How did you go
to medical school with that brain?
It's just that I wanted to try it once because
it seemed I could maybe do it even without you.
What am I lacking, that I would lie to you?
So...
Was it okay?
No. I almost died.
I can't do it without you.
Why are you crying?
Let's go.
Don't worry. No matter who calls, I won't go this time.
Let's go. Go.
The mandus are on sale, the mandu!
Mandu! Mandu, mandu, mandu!
A special sale event for a special someone!
Orginal price is 6,400 won and it's on sale for 3,200 won!
[sales pitch]
A special sale event for a special someone! Please try some!
Today we have delicious fried mandu!
It used to be 6,400 won-- Welcome!
Here. Have some delicious mandu.
Don't feel burdened and have one.
Try without feeling burdened. Should I give you one?
You already have six, right? It's delicious, right?
Isn't it good?
Dumplings are on sale! Please take a look!
A special event for a special someone.
Original price is 6,400 won and it's on sale for 3,200 won!
Dduk Ddu-Ddu-Dduk Dduk Dduk Dduk! Dduk!
Here's some tasty dduk galbi! It's dduk galbi!
There is a buy one get one free sale! Round and round!
Delicious mandu. Mandu, mandu, mandu.
Madam, here, come have one.
Please buy ham.
It used to be 6,400 won and now it's 3,200 won!
This is your doing, right?
It's not me. It's not me.
Subtitles brought to you by The ♥ to Heart Team @Viki
Timed by Myuu
I was going to hold on to you and tell you not to leave. Dammit.
Did you kiss?
This is what it feels like to receive jealousy.
My next role is as a police officer, so I came to get experience. Allegiance!
You... don't hang around near that Jang Doo Soo ever again. Understand?
Not as Oh Young Rae, but as Hong Do, could I come to this house?
What a surprise.
I'm not going to accept it.
Where is this bastard right now? This bastard, this bastard.
Let's live together.
Why did you come here again? Take this and leave, okay?
i will make you have no regret for choosing me.