Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Episode 31
Halt...!
The palace maiden Chun Dong Yi
is no longer a Lady Investigator.
Going forward, she shall be treated
in accordance as a Special Court Lady...
... who has shared relations with the King.
Your Majesty!
Shared relations...?
Don't you know what that means,
Councilor?
You're not asking me to explain
the meaning of that, are you?
Your Majesty!
- Please come this way.
- Chief Eunuch!
This isn't my Lady Investigator uniform!
How can I wear robes like these?
It is His Majesty's will.
He will explain everything.
How can you elevate Palace Maiden Chun
to Special Court Lady?
That is preposterous!
She is a criminal who ran away
from the Palace.
She is not only lost her rights
to live in the Palace,
... but committed a grave crime.
How can you elevate a criminal
to become a Special Court Lady?
This cannot happen.
She is a criminal that must be punished!
Chun Dong Yi is not a court lady,
but a criminal!
Your Majesty!
When she shared my bed,
She obtained the rights
to be in the Palace again.
This is not a matter for discussion.
It is the prerogative of
the Royal Monarchy!
Your Majesty!
How can this be?
Uncle, the King is using this method
to protect the girl.
We won't be able to charge her
with a crime this way.
Ridiculous!
A Special Court Lady!
She's about to become a Special Court Lady!
- Let me through! Hurry!
- Let her through.
So they're discussing how to deal
with Dong Yi at the Grand Palace right now?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Dong Yi ran away from the Palace.
At the very least,
she will have to pay the price for that.
The peony blooms have all died.
It must be because
it is the end of its season.
Do not let it trouble you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
- Your Majesty!
- What happened?
Your Majesty!
I asked you what happened!
Hey! Is it true?
Was Dong Yi really wearing a Dang'ui?
It wasn't just a Dang'ui!
It was covered with silver emblems!
It was a Sorae Dang'ui!
A Sorae Dang'ui?
But that's what palace maidens wear
after they've shared the King's bed!
- But why would Dong Yi wear that?
- Why else? I doubt she stole it!
- Then...?
- She's been with the King!
She has shared the King's bed!
Ae-Jong, are you crazy?
Dong Yi did what?
She said Dong Yi slept with the King!
It's true!
I saw her palanquin!
Do you think it's that easy
to attract the King's eye?
- What nonsense!
- I know.
And if it was true,
why would it be so quiet here?
A decree should have been given and...
- Where is Lady Jung?
- She's in the office.
Is that really true?
I have to confirm it,
but the palace is buzzing with the news!
That's crazy!
How could Dong Yi have...?
What is this I hear?
We have to prepare for Dong Yi
to become Special Court Lady?
What is going on?
What?
You mean it's true?
Say something, Lady Jung!
You must know something!
- Your Majesty!
- You're here!
- And the girl?
- She has entered the Palace.
- She has?
- Yes.
Her residence is not yet ready,
so I escorted her to temporary quarters.
Indeed.
Was she very surprised?
She was confused because
she didn't know what was happening.
Of course.
Of course she would be.
Are you uncomfortable, My Lady?
Not at all.
Please don't mind me.
By the way, My Lady...
When can I leave?
Yes, this place is a bit uncomfortable.
But please don't worry.
Once your residence is ready,
you will move there.
Residence?
Yes, your residence
where you live, My Lady.
What?
And please speak informally to me, My Lady.
My Lady?
What do you mean by that?
Why do you address me like that?
And what do you mean by my residence?
I...
- Chief Eunuch...
- Yes, Your Majesty.
How should I explain this to her?
I mean, I did all of this
in order to protect her.
But I don't know
how she will take all of this.
What do you mean by
how she will take it?
We've had such an easy relationship thus far.
But this is like... like getting married.
She might be bewildered by all of this.
Is that how you feel, Your Majesty?
You don't feel like you're just
making her a Special Court Lady,
... but you feel like
you're getting married to her?
Of course.
I just want to know
how she would feel about this.
I don't want her to just go along with this
because she's a palace maiden,
... but because she cares about me.
Your Majesty, will you permit me
to speak my mind?
If you feel that way,
then tell her exactly how you feel.
What would be better than that?
A Special Court Lady?
Who..? Me?
Yes, that is what we were told, My Lady.
So this Dang'ui and this residence
is all because of that?
Yes, My Lady.
I...
You must be mistaken, My Lady.
- I...
- My Lady! His Majesty has arrived!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, did you know that
there seems to be a misunderstanding?
The Chief Eunuch has made a mistake!
What?
A mistake?
Yes! He thought when you visited me
last night that...
He seems to have misunderstood...
So the Court Ladies are addressing me as...
- Dong Yi.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
- It's not a mistake.
- What?
It was on my orders.
What?
Dong Yi is staying at the Residence East
of the Grand Palace.
Make sure security is tight.
Yes, My Lord.
By the way,
I don't see Officer Cha around.
Me neither.
Shall I send some men out?
No, don't do that.
Let him be.
This is what His Majesty told me.
He's going to make Dong Yi
into a Special Court Lady?
Yes, he has decided that this is
the best way to keep Dong Yi safe.
But more importantly,
this is His Majesty's true feelings for Dong Yi.
You mean you gave orders for all of this,
Your Majesty?
This Dang'ui, my residence...
Even making me a Special Court Lady?
Yes, I did.
Why?
Why did you do this?
Did you forget? I told you I would do
everything in my power for you.
Your Majesty...!
It was to protect you.
I couldn't leave you alone
in the capital,
... nor bring you back
into the Palace as you were.
You risked your life for me
and my government.
It is only right that I protect you now.
If you become a Special Court Lady,
no one will dare harm you.
Because that would be the same thing
as trying to harm me.
But even so,
Your Majesty, this isn't right.
This is a lie.
It's not completely a lie.
- What?
- Because I really care for you.
- Let's go.
- What? Already?
But you should stay tonight...
I said let's go!
Give me your hand.
I said give me your hand.
Your Majesty!
Do you remember that day
when we were at the marketplace?
I bought it that day for you.
But I didn't know then.
I didn't know that's how I felt.
Your.. Your Majesty...
None of this is a mistake,
a misunderstanding, or a lie.
The way I feel about you is real.
So will you give it some thought?
Consider being with me
and accepting my heart, I mean.
Why is my heart beating so fast?
Should I summon the Royal Physician?
Goodness!
Why are you taking so long?
Let's go!
My dear, where are you going off to?
Where else?
I'm going to Yoon's house.
What?
Why are you going there again?
You can't be going there to gloat?
You're not...?
Yes, My Lord!
I'm going there to gloat!
I'm going to go there
and laugh my head off!
How can you be so immature?
This incident has caused chaos
in the Palace!
The entire South Faction is in turmoil!
I know that's bad,
but I can't help but be pleased!
Let's go!
Why are you sitting there like that?
You rascal, let's go!
We need to go support my brother!
Can you go alone today?
- I won't get a word in anyway!
- What?
I've never had another rascal
steal a girl that I liked!
Do you even know how I feel?
You stupid boy!
Did you just call His Majesty a rascal?
Are you crazy?
You've finally lost your mind!
Yes, I've lost my mind!
How can I be sane when my girl
has been stolen from me!
I know you're my son,
but you're really something.
Ho-Yang, you're really something!
- Hey, I think that's the place.
- Yes, I saw Dong Yi going in there!
- Shall I call her?
- Call her? Who do you think you are?
Dong Yi is an exalted
Special Court Lady now.
Then how do we see her?
Who goes there!
Why are you loitering over here?
- Sir, we're...
- Take these suspicious fellows away!
Yes, sir!
- No, we're not suspicious! We're...
- Sir!
Dong Yi!
Please let them go.
I know these men.
Release them.
Dong Yi!
Sirs..!
What happened to you!
You're going to drive me to my grave!
Sir!
Come in.
I can't believe you're here!
- Don't you agree, sir?
- Yes, this is wonderful.
I caused you a lot of worry, haven't I?
Are you kidding me?
You rascal, you scared me half to death!
I'm going to die early because of you!
I'm sorry, sir.
- That's enough for now.
- What? I'm just getting started.
What's all this about you being
a Special Court Lady anyway?
I'm looking at you,
but I still can't believe it!
You know... actually...
You don't have to be embarassed,
Dong Yi. We know everything.
- But actually...
- Let's leave. You've said enough!
Actually, I've known from the beginning.
His Majesty's gaze was so hot
when he looked at you!
Say something, sir!
Don't you agree?
- We both knew from the start...
- Stupid boy! Come to your senses!
Sir!
- Why did you hit me?
- You...
She's now a Special Court Lady.
Don't you know what that means?
- I know, but Dong Yi is...
- Don't say her name!
A Special Court Lady is higher in rank
than the Chief Madam!
That means Dong Yi is...
My stupid mouth!  That's what's
going to happen to Her Ladyship!
Don't be like that, sir!
I'm just...
Please don't call me 'sir'!
You'll get in trouble!
You must never call me 'sir' again, My Lady!
Sir!
Then call her My Lady Dong Yi...?
Don't push me!
Sir!
She is a lowborn girl of no consequence!
And she's been living outside the Palace!
How could His Majesty do this?
A Special Court Lady is higher in rank
than the Chief Madam!
That means that she's second
only to the Queen in rank!
She was on the side of the deposed Queen
and threatened our power!
We must now allow her
to have this power!
But this is a matter of the Inner Court.
We have no reasonable excuse to stop this.
The Queen can stop it.
She violated her duty as a palace maiden.
As head of the Inner Court,
the Queen can punish her for this.
He's right!
How has the Queen reacted to this?
She has not granted anyone
an audience yet.
I've come to see Her Majesty.
Is she inside?
Yes, Your Excellency.
The ministers are protesting?
How can they do this?
But they have a point.
Her birth status is an issue,
... and she was out of the Palace
for a period of time.
Dong Yi had to leave the Palace
because of me.
But Your Majesty,
that is a separate matter.
The fact that she lacks the qualifications...
... to become a superior in the Inner Court
is a valid one.
Minister, it was I who asked her
to stay with His Majesty.
So how can you say this?
- Your Majesty!
- I beg you, Minister.
Please get the West Faction's support...
... so that she does not have
to suffer any longer.
My Lady, someone from the
Office of Investigations is here.
- My Lady!
- Dong Yi!
So it was true!
What do you mean you didn't really
share His Majesty's bed?
He did this to protect me from danger
when I returned to the Palace.
I see. So that's how
he wanted to protect you.
But even so, how does that change things?
This is how much he cares for you.
- My Lady, that...
- Dong Yi.
This may be the last time
I call you by your name.
So listen to me as someone
who was once your teacher.
My Lady...
Many people will try
to make things difficult for you.
They will say you are not worthy
and not qualified.
But that's all true.
How could I even consider it?
No, you are more worthy
than anyone else.
Don't you remember when you first joined
the Office of Investigations?
You said that although
you were lowborn by birth,
... your heart wasn't lowborn.
And you showed everyone
that your words were true.
You became a proficient
and expert Lady Investigator.
So how can you say you're not worthy?
How can you not accomplish this
when you've accomplished so much?
My Lady...!
But even so,
I cannot stay here.
Dong Yi...
My circumstances do not allow me
to be with the King.
I cannot.
I must not do this.
What do you mean, Dong Yi?
What do you mean by your circumstances?
Dong Yi...
This is the murderer who killed
the Officer last night and his daughter.
The Sword Fraternity Chief's daughter
is here. Find her!
There she is!
The Chief's daughter!
Father...!
Dong Yi?
We must stop her from becoming
a Special Court Lady.
I'm sure you don't want to serve her
as your superior either.
What do I need to do?
Investigate her background.
I'm sure there's something
that can be of use.
Don't miss any detail,
no matter how small.
Do you understand me?
Yes, My Lord.
I am Officer Cha Chun Soo
of the Royal Guard.
May I humbly request an audience
with His Majesty?
- Officer Cha?
- Yes, Your Majesty.
- Let him in.
Welcome... I've been thinking of
summoning you here too.
- Come closer.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Tell you how I feel about Dong Yi?
Your Majesty, I know this is presumptuous,
but I wanted to ask you this.
I want to know how you really feel
about Dong Yi.
Please forgive my presumptuousness,
Your Majesty.
Not at all.
It's about your beloved sister after all.
But before I answer that,
I want to ask something too.
Are you asking this as her brother,
or as a man?
Don't be startled.
I'm the King, but I'm also a man.
It would be a lie if I said that I didn't mind
another man being with my woman.
- Don't you agree?
- Your Majesty, I...
I don't know how Dong Yi feels
about me yet.
The only thing I know is how I feel.
Actually, that's why I'm so nervous.
What if she has another man
in her heart?
And if so,
what should I do?
To tell you the truth, she once told me
that she didn't think much of me.
What did she say?
Oh, yes.
She said she liked dark and sturdy men.
Just like you.
So answer my question first.
Are you here today as her brother,
or as a man?
Chun Soo!
It's strange, isn't it?
I'm uncomfortable too.
No, I'm looking at you
because you're so lovely.
I thought you were someone else.
Chun Soo...
But why do you look so glum
when you're wearing such lovely clothes?
Are you troubled by something?
I...
... don't know what to do anymore.
Can I stay here like this?
I keep thinking that I can't.
Is this because of what happened?
It'll come to light one day.
That I'm my father's daughter.
That my father was
the Chief of the Sword Fraternity.
Dong Yi...
I never feared that,
even after I entered the Palace.
Because I came here
to find the people...
... who caused the wrongful deaths
of the members.
But to the world,
father is just a criminal.
And I'm just a criminal's daughter in hiding.
- Dong Yi...
- But how can I be with the King?
How can I hide this from His Majesty
and be with him?
Then do you want to run away, Dong Yi?
- Can you do that?
- Chun Soo...!
Just like before...
Before you knew the King...
Can you live like that again?
Can you do that?
Just like before...
Before you knew the King...
Can you live like that again?
You've come, Madam.
How is Her Majesty?
Is she still turning away visitors?
Yes, Madam.
Let her know I'm here.
I must see her today!
- Your Majesty!
- Your Majesty..!
You've come, Mother.
I was just about to summon you.
I will go to the Grand Palace.
Let them know and make preparations.
- What?
- I said make preparations!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, are you all right?
Why? Did you think
I would collapse over this?
Your Majesty...!
This wasn't completely unexpected.
I was just a little surprised, that's all.
Don't look at me like that, Mother.
I'm fine.
Did you forget?
You were the one who said
a man can never be trusted.
Your Majesty!
I forgot something.
I forgot that I can only trust in myself.
Your Majesty...!
What did you just say?
You want to make a deal?
- My Queen!
- It is as I said.
I will unravel the mess with Dong Yi.
In return, please release my brother.
- My Queen!
- You are well aware of this.
The Ministers will do whatever it takes
to bring Dong Yi down.
And if they find a flaw,
they will not back down.
The most important thing in this nation
is a just cause, is it not?
I will give you that just cause.
Because I am the head of the Inner Court.
The Chief Steward of the Royal Treasury
has already died under torture.
All my brother did was to request medicine
for his nephew, the Crown Prince.
Do you really think you can condemn
my brother with merely Dong Yi's words?
No, you should be aware that
it has become impossible.
How did we become like this?
Make a deal?
How can we be talking about this?
Because this is all that's left.
You and I are merely
the King and Queen.
There are no more words of love
between us, is there?
Your Majesty, what will you do?
Your Majesty, I think it's best if we settle this
by demoting the Police Superintendent.
But I can't let them get away
with it so easily.
I'm not suggesting we let them get away
with it, merely to buy some time.
We cannot let Dong Yi fall into danger again
after she risked her life.
Will you let me handle this, Your Majesty?
There is something else
I must investigate.
Something else?
I will report to you
when I have more evidence.
If that is confirmed,
... then everything will be solved,
Your Majesty.
- Hee-Jae!
- Mother...
Are you all right?
I'm fine, Mother.
How is Her Majesty?
How is she?
She's suffering!
- Your Majesty!
- Brother!
How are you?
Have you been hurt?
Who cares about me?
I heard about the girl.
Why haven't you done anything?
Who cares if I die?
- You should have stopped her first!
- Brother...
This won't be the end.
What if she is made a concubine
and has a child...?
No! As long as I am Queen,
that will never happen.
Do you understand now?
That is why I haven't done anything yet.
Because I want to remain here.
That's the only way
I won't see that happening.
- Your Majesty...
- I will not give up anything else to her.
Your Majesty, are you really all right?
- You are...
- No, I wasn't all right.
I felt like my heart was ripped out.
But that's why I'm all right now.
I no longer have a heart that can be hurt.
I should have done this
from the beginning.
I should have stopped myself
from loving His Majesty.
Your Majesty...
Chief Eunuch!
- What did you find?
- She's nowhere to be found!
Where could she have gone?
- What is it?
- Your Majesty!
What is it?
I... We don't know
where Her Ladyship is!
What?
I am here as her brother, Your Majesty.
Because that is who I am to her.
- So may I ask you this as her brother?
- You may.
If she fears being with you,
then what will you do, Your Majesty?
Fears being with me?
What do you mean by that?
She may think that
she's unable to be with you...
... because of something out
of her control.
Dong Yi...
Dong Yi...!
What did you find?
She's not at the Office of Investigations.
I think she's left the Palace, Your Majesty.
- I will go out. Get ready!
- Yes, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty,
Officer Cha sent you this letter.
What?
Dong Yi's childhood home
You're hopeless!
Father, are you sure she's related to us?
- How can she be so bad?
- I think she sounds wonderful.
No, she's awful!
She's just a little good.
- Hey, stop harassing my bride.
- Why is she your bride?
When did I ever consent
to give her to you?
I don't care what you say.
I'm still going to marry Chun Soo
when I grow up.
- What?
- What...?
You heard her, didn't you?
She's going to marry me!
She sounds better than you!
She will be at the cliff, Your Majesty.
Today is the anniversary of the day
her father and brother died.
Please stop Dong Yi, Chief.
So that she can do what I wish
for with all my heart.
I will remember these things
only in my heart.
I will hold it in my heart
and avenge your wrongful deaths.
But Dong Yi... that child...
... will disappear like this.
So that nobody will ever
be able to find her...
So that she can be with His Majesty
and be happy for the rest of her life...
I will protect her.
There should be a cliff somewhere.
Find it!
Yes, Your Majesty!
It's me, Father...
Older Brother...
You can see me, can't you?
What do I do now, Father?
Older Brother?
What should I do...?
- Who are you anyway?
- What?
Who are you and
why are you loitering here?
Then who are you?
- When I strike, run!
- Sir!
- I command you as King!
- Poongsan?
The hunting dog that never lets go
once it bites!
His Majesty seems like
a very merciful person!
- His Majesty is really gracious!
- Yes, he must be!
Whether it's from His Majesty or me,
it's all the same.
- Let's go!
- Sir!
Give me your hand.
It's right here.
I... I said raise your head!
Good!
I'm fine.
I'm riding a palanquin after all.
Your Majesty!
Can you do that?
Just like before...
Before you knew the King...
Can you live like that again?
Your Majesty!
Do you remember that day
when we were at the marketplace?
I bought it that day for you.
Your Majesty...
Did you forget already?
Your Majesty!
I asked you ...
... to never make me endure
being without you again.
Your Majesty...!
What is it?
What is it that troubles you so, Dong Yi?
Can't you share it with me?
No, it doesn't matter.
Can... can you just stay with me?
May I... may I do so, Your Majesty?
That is what I want!
If I may... if I may...
I want to accept your heart
and give you mine in return!
May I...
May I do this, Your Majesty?
- Your Majesty...
- Dong Yi!
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Translator/Timer: MrsKorea
Editing/QC: victory
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com