Knights, I bid you welcome
to your new home.
Let us ride to...Camelot!
# We're knights of the Round Table
# We dance when ere we're able
We do routines and chorus scenes
With footwork impecc-able
# We dine well here in Camelot
# We eat jam and ham
and Spam a lot... #
There was always a feeling
that perhaps we could
make a film together,
a really new, original film.
# ..We're knights of the Round Table
Our shows are formid-able... #
We set out basically to
make an ordinary film,
and we were saved from our own
mediocrity by the lack of money.
# ..Diaphragm a lot! #
I often think about it as
having a sort of quality
that Hard Day's Night has,
which is about young men
not quite knowing what they're doing
but making it work anyway.
# ..In war we're tough and able... #
I think we went into this movie
not really understanding at all
that we'd probably cut off
far more than we could chew.
# ..I have to push the pram a lot. #
On second thoughts, let's not go
to Camelot. It is a silly place.
These days, Monty Python's silliness
is part of the comic language.
Their TV sketches and
movies are regularly voted
amongst the greatest comedy ever made.
Millions of fans can still quote
Python chapter and verse,
and frequently do,
and now a Python musical
is doing big business across the world.
But hard as it may be to believe now,
the Pythons' illustrious status
as kings of comedy
was not always certain.
Back in 1973, the team
was beginning to fracture.
Things weren't looking good for Monty.
John in particular felt a bit
restricted by the group,
felt we'd done as much as we could do.
He drifted off to start
doing Fawlty Towers.
Python had taken my life over!
If we weren't doing a stage show,
we were doing a TV series,
preparing for a film, making
a record or doing a book.
I didn't want to do
Python all the time.
The others were having such a
good time it didn't bother them,
but I wanted to strike out
in other directions.
And now for something
completely different.
A couple of them were very cross
with me for not wanting to do
any more, although I'd not really
wanted to do the third series.
But I think that was mainly
Terry Jones, who I remember
talked about betrayal,
or some words like that,
and Graham Chapman was very critical.
Terry Jones and Terry Gilliam,
in particular,
were anxious to do an original movie,
always anxious to do that,
because they were interested
in directing.
We'd all gotten a bit itchy
to do something bigger,
and so the thought of doing
a movie was quite intriguing.
There was never a question
that I didn't want to do the movie
cos that interested me.
In a sense, making The Holy Grail
was starting all over again,
something that we believed in
and very few other people did.
Five of the future Pythons
had met while at university,
and they all worked together
for the first time
on the BBC's famed satirical show
The Frost Report.
Chapman and Cleese were
tempted across to ITV,
writing and performing
At Last The 1948 Show,
while Palin, Idle and Jones
scripted and starred in the teatime
kids hit Do Not Adjust Your Set.
Terry Gilliam first met
John Cleese in New York,
and when he came to London,
Cleese put him in touch with
the Do Not Adjust Your Set team.
So when the two shows finished,
there were six talents on the loose,
seeking an outlet for their unique
comedy tastes and ideas.
What else could they do
apart from join forces
and call their collective effort...
Monty Python's Flying Circus.
PALIN: The first series
went out in October 1969,
and very rapidly,
against all the odds at the time,
we were offered another series
and a third series, and we did,
er...three series by 1972.
Also, during that time, we'd done
various albums, we'd done two books,
and we'd done a film called And Now
For Something Completely Different.
We decided somewhere along the line,
maybe after the second series,
that we would write a movie,
we would do a movie which we
would control and we would direct.
The Pythons' first film
had been designed to help
them crack the US market.
It was overseen by Flying Circus
director Ian McNaughton
and financed by the UK arm of Playboy.
But the team found themselves
fighting for control of the movie
with the financiers, so for Holy Grail
they were determined to take control
themselves and be able to go...
RASPBERRY
During the shooting of the
television series, Terry and I
were both sort of convinced
we could do it
better than Ian McNaughton
or whoever else was directing.
I mean, we always railing at the fact
that, "Oh, the light's not right!"
Everything was cheap,
and especially at the BBC
comedy was treated rather shabbily.
CLEESE:Terry often got into
fights with Ian McNaughton
about how the television
series was being shot,
and he and Terry Gilliam both
had much better visual senses
than I did, and they felt,
I think quite correctly,
that they could do the
visuals much better.
Get in! Get in!
They'd had a good look at television,
turned it upside down,
turned it inside out,
and I think they were just
restless for doing some more.
You know, maybe they needed
to do their Sergeant Pepper
or their White Album.
The idea of doing a movie really
appealed to us, and I think
both Terry and I were convinced
we wanted to be movie directors,
and so basically we just
proposed to the group,
"Anybody named Terry can
direct," and the others agreed.
So the Terrys would be taking
turns in the director's chair,
but there was still one question.
What were they going to direct?
Terry Jones and myself had
begun a sort of script about...
the Middle Ages and flying
coconuts and all that -
it was actually the beginning of the
film - and Arthur coming to the walls
and trying to talk to people who just
went on about unladen swallows.
The first time we wrote it,
it was sort of...
it was filled with sort of sketchy
things. There was a lot of things
in Harrods, it was modern day.
It vaguely was Graily.
We had no idea how to do narrative
in a movie, and I don't think we do it
particularly well in Holy Grail,
because we were sketch writers,
and we just wrote a lot of sketches.
It took us an incredibly long time
to actually get to the script
that you see on the screen.
It was perfectly clear that
the most successful part of it
was about Arthur and the Grail,
and so we junked all the rest of it
and said, "Well, let's write a movie
"about Arthur and
the quest for the Grail."
And that's how it began,
and people just started writing...
writing pieces, as we always did.
I mean, Python was...
We'd have an idea of what we're
doing, go and write, write, write,
and then start cramming it all together
and throwing out most of the
good stuff and leaving the dross.
Can you give me a brief
synopsis of the film?
Is that possible in the space
of half an hour or so?
Well, I don't think it is,
really. I don't think it is.
Well, try then in 30 seconds.
Right. It's about a search
for the Holy Grail, you see,
which is a large sort of creature
a bit like a dodo with a big beak.
There was a lot of fighting about the
material all the way through Python,
but that was kinda good, 'cause
a lot of it was creative tension,
which I think you have to have.
I think we must have been writing
towards each of us playing a knight,
and John would be Lancelot
and Michael would be Galahad
and I'd be Robin and Terry
would be Bedevere.
And Terry Gilliam was Patsy,
of course. So I think we must,
at a certain point, have realised we
were all gonna play a knight each.
So with the knights all cast,
who'd be the man who would be king...
Arthur?
Woah there!
I think Graham must have read Arthur
in some of the early read-throughs,
and he was terrific and had this
sort of long-suffering gravity,
and he looked good.
There was something about
Graham that just was...
not quite magisterial but aloof.
It is I, Arthur, son of
Uther Pendragon,
from the castle of Camelot,
King of the Britons,
defeater of the Saxons,
sovereign of all England!
Pull the other one!
I am!
One of the joys of Python was
playing lots of different characters.
To give up the chance of
doing a lot of characters
to be this regular, sort
of rather straight figure
that goes all way through
is quite a sort of sacrifice,
and Graham seemed happy to do it.
It was the smartest choice we made,
because he was a brilliant Arthur,
and I think we also discovered,
in that sense,
he became the straight...the centre
around which the madness spun.
What's it like being a film star?
I'm not. I'm just a...just an extra,
really.You're just an extra?
Yes. It's the crown and this
that probably makes you...
Yeah, I was looking for Graham. Ah,
yes, he's around somewhere. Is he?
Now the Pythons only needed one
small thing to make the movie -
money. To help them find it, they
turned to their industry contacts.
Mark Forstater first met
Terry Gilliam in New York
and was now working in London
as an independent film producer.
Together with the Pythons,
he approached theatrical
impresario Michael White,
who had worked with Chapman
and Cleese back in 1963.
White's colleague, John Goldstone,
had been at the recording
of the very first Flying Circus.
As Python fans, they were
interested in investing in the film,
but they seemed to be the only ones.
We were turned down
by every financing source
because they didn't
trust the new directors,
they didn't know what they would get,
um, so we basically couldn't raise
any finance from industry sources.
Python was too...
dangerous, in a way, for them.
It was unconventional...and, um,
didn't indicate any kind
of narrative form
that would convert into a film.
The Pythons had released
their records on Charisma,
a label run by Tony Stratton-Smith,
and Stratton-Smith had
some very good ideas
about who would be crazy
enough to invest in the Pythons.
For bands like Genesis,
Led Zeppelin and Pink Floyd,
it was unlikely they'd see
their hard-earned again.
You'd probably need to be
on drugs to take that chance.
Luckily, some of them were.
Rock'n'roll really understood Python
a lot more than the conventional
film-financing entities.
I think we were supposed
to be a tax loss
but, unfortunately,
I think we made money.
We probably made their tax
problems worse in the end!
They didn't do it as an investment,
in the sense of,
"Well, let's see if we can
make money out of this."
I think it was trying
to support something
that they really enjoyed
and really liked.
There was a synchronicity
between the two, I don't know why.
Pop groups used to watch Python
on the road and all that sort of thing.
They felt there was a kind of kinship
between their music and our form
of comedy, a kind of subversiveness,
or slight rebelliousness, or whatever,
something fresh, I don't know.
But, you know, thank you...
Zep, and thank you, Genesis.
With the cash in the bank
and the Pythons in control,
the Holy Grail was good to go.
Lights, camera, action!
Well, sort of.
GILLIAM: The first day of filming
for these two novice directors,
we were up in Glencoe at Seven Sisters,
and we had to carry all the
gear up a mountainside to get to
the Bridge of Death, which
Hamish McInnes and his mountaineers
had built across this wonderful gorge.
And there we are at
the top of this thing,
and almost from the first shot
the camera breaks.
It got worse from there on,
let's say that we...
That ended up being a fairly good day.
The other great discovery on that day,
besides the fact that the camera
wasn't working, Graham Chapman,
who had professed to be
this great mountaineer,
who'd adventure anywhere,
suddenly was terrified of walking
across the bridge and couldn't.
Graham sort of admitted later,
when he gave up drinking,
that he'd had a few drinks that
morning and it was a bit of DTs.
Just shaking a bit at
the prospect of doing it.
Well, you'd need a few
drinks to cross this,
but sober or not, none of the
Pythons fancied making the trip.
It's actually played by
the first assistant director
going across as Graham.
Everything was really funny that day.
Ask me the questions, bridge
keeper. I'm not afraid!
What is your name? My name
is Sir Lancelot of Camelot.
What is your quest?
To seek the Holy Grail.
What is your favourite colour?
Blue.Right, off you go.
Oh, thank you.
We did it very simply.
We just said everybody,
when asked the questions,
they were sort of squatting down.
What is the capital of Assyria?
And when they got the wrong answer,
they would just jump in the air.
I don't know that!
Aaaah!
And then we'd cut to another shot
where we threw a dummy into the gorge.
It couldn't have been cruder,
and it works!
To anyone who knew anything
about Glencoe, driving through
and seeing the head of Mountain
Rescue throwing people one by one
into this great crevasse would
have seemed a bit sort of worrying!
Also throwing himself into the
film and into the the low budget
was ex-Bonzo Dog Doodah
Band member Neil Innes,
a Python collaborator and musical
adviser from Do Not Adjust Your Set.
This time round, Innes
would not only be playing
a series of small roles, he'd
also be writing the film's score.
What are you exactly
contributing to the film? Erm...
Terror and heroics in certain points,
really do a job with the music
to either create the lump in the throat
or make the back hairs stick out.
Yes, I was going to be doing the music,
but quite frankly that didn't
really sort of excite me that much.
I've always wanted to do movie music,
but I knew it was such a low budget,
the music budget was only £3,000.
But the budget restrictions would
also help turn an inspirational idea
into the film's most loved running gag.
The original sketch that
Terry and I had written,
the horsemen went, "Clippety-clop,"
and someone with coconuts.
And we suddenly thought, "Well,
let's do all the horses like that,
so we don't have to have horses,
we don't have to be able to ride,
we could save a lot of money,
"no animals on set and
all that sort of thing."
And so the coconuts, which were
originally an economy measure,
became one of the sort of things
people remember most about the film.
I think the fact that we had
so little money made us
much more inventive,
like the coconuts, you know,
it was a perfect example.
You can't have horses, of course
you can't, so you do coconuts,
which is funny in itself and also
does make it rather easier to shoot.
After fierce disagreements
about migrating swallows...
A five-ounce bird could not
carry a one-pound coconut!
Well, it doesn't matter!...wrangling
with politically aware peasants...
You can't expect to wield
supreme executive power
just cos some watery tart
threw a sword at you!
..and conquering the ludicrously
resilient Black Knight...
All right, we'll call it a draw.
..Arthur starts finding
recruits for his Round Table.
First, Bedevere, a knight
wise in the ways of science
with a unique method
of witch finding...
Why do witches burn?
Cos they're made of...wood?Good!
..and an interesting take on geology.
And that, my liege, is how we know
the Earth to be banana-shaped.
This new learning amazes me,
Sir Bedevere.
Arthur and his entourage
come face to face with God,
who has a task for them.
Behold, Arthur, this is the Holy Grail.
Look well, Arthur, for it is
your sacred task to seek this grail.
That is your purpose, Arthur,
the quest for the Holy Grail!
A blessing, a blessing from the Lord!
God be praised!
The king and his knights
set out on their quest,
but if the plot had
finally kicked off
on the screen, off it the duress
of filming was even beginning
to get to the officially
most nicest Python of all.
It brought out the bad
side of Mike Palin.
Mr Nice was, for a brief moment,
not very,
because we had him as the mud-eater.
For a start, it meant that
you had to be filthy, so you...
you wash in the morning,
you have a shower,
you clean your teeth,
you go onto set
and get mud put all over you,
you know, teeth blacked out.
We actually had placed,
very carefully in the mud,
the edible mud,
but all the mud surrounding it
seemed to have been pigswill
and shit and piss!
"Oh, don't worry, we've
got you some chocolate.
"But it's exactly the
same colour as the mud,
"so no-one will be able to tell."
Including me! So I got there,
"Where's the chocolate?"
I'd scoop up a bit, and maybe a half
is chocolate, the other half is mud,
and it seemed to be a
place where pigs shat
and all that sort of thing,
it was just disgusting.
Michael kept stuffing stuff
in his mouth, eating it,
and then Terry Gilliam
would shout, "Cut!"
because the cart had come
in a fraction too early
or a fraction too late,
and by the eighth take...Michael
was hating chewing on this awful mud!
And I went through and I felt very...
And at the end, I said,
"Now, what was wrong with that?
What was wrong with
that?" And they said,
"I'm afraid we could just see the
top of the mud-eater's back."
And I just went, "Aaaah!"
you know, and I remember
going completely spare, and I was so
angry I just threw myself in the air,
dropped down into the mud
and just jiggled about in the mud
like some sort of rebel hound
or something like that,
waved my arms and legs around and say,
"I don't want to do this any more!"
and generally had a
rather grand hissy fit.
And there was a...brief pause,
and Graham and John just
spontaneously broke into applause.
And John says it's one of the very,
very few times he's ever seen me
really lose my temper, and
he was mightily impressed.
Alas, Palin's medley of mud
and pigshit had been for nothing
with the scene mostly ending
up on the cutting-room floor.
Ouch!
But at least he had a warm bath to
look forward to at the end of the day.
When the first assistant
director shouted,
"Cut, that's a wrap!"
there was this extraordinary rush,
people sprinted to all the vehicles
that were there to try
and get back to the hotel,
because there was only enough
hot water for half the crew.
Here we were out in Scotland,
and it was cold and it was wet
and it was sunny and it was
dirty and it was everything,
and it was really an unpleasant
life for certain urbanites
that happened to be
living in the group.
And where Terry and I
wallowed in the mud,
I'm afraid John, Graham
and Eric didn't!
John and I struck
out for pastures new.
We found something called
the Hydro Hotel in...
not far away, about 20 minutes
away, and we moved in there,
and everybody was, "Are you
going to leave us all?"
We'd go, "No, we just want
a hot bath, you know, gosh!"
And so we moved in,
and as we got there,
there were all these beautiful
women just walked in and arrived,
and we went, "Lucky, really!"
And they were in our movie.
Leading those beautiful women was
Python favourite Carol Cleveland,
a regular in the TV shows
whenever a real woman was needed
instead of one of
the lads in drag.
Carol had featured in ITV series
like The Saint and Man In A Suitcase
before comedy opportunities
came her way.
One thing to another,
I found myself at the BBC,
doing a fair amount of work
being a glam stooge to people
like Ronnie Corbett, Ronnie Barker,
Spike Milligan, Charlie Drake, who
used to have his little nose right
there in my cleavage, I remember.
And, well, then the Pythons
heard about me.
Carol was great.
Carol, within Python, was the only
woman we ever had that seemed to be
able to get the comedy and be beautiful
and fit in with everybody else.
No matter what we did to her,
she just sat in there beautifully.
I remember saying to
my husband at the time,
"Well, I don't know about this show.
"I don't think there'll be more
than five episodes, actually."
How wrong I was, happily!
Castle Anthrax, I wrote, of course,
because I was determined to get
some sex in Python for once.
Welcome, gentle sir knight.
Welcome to the Castle Anthrax.
The Castle Anthrax?
Yes. It's not a very good name, is it?
Oh, but we are nice, and we will
attend to your every, every need.
You are the keepers
of the Holy Grail?
The what? She was really
terrific in Castle Anthrax.
She just had that right attitude
of sort of slightly
dominating, but a little bit
sort of enticing at the same time.
Zoot was a lady who was in charge of a
huge number of virgins aged
between 16 and 19 and a half.
I remember how incredibly
unsexy it all was.
It just seemed wonderful
in the script and all that,
all these girls would be on the bed
and sort of... you know,
caressing you and all that.
They're doctors?
As always, with filming, anything like
that gets reduced to a sort of job.
It's a bit like mending the
plumbing or something like that.
Dr Piglet, Dr Winston,
practise your art.
It was far from being the
wonderful full-on orgy
that I expected
when I wrote it.
Try to relax.
Are you sure that's absolutely
necessary? We must examine you.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Please, we are doctors.
We had about five takes as
he's being dragged away,
and we're just there
going, "Oh, oh!"
In the final take,
I just threw in at the end...
Shit! And everybody laughed and
they kept it in, which was quite fun.
My little bit of improvising
in the film.
It's my duty to sample
as much peril as I can.
We've got to find the Holy Grail. Come
on. Can't we have a bit of peril? No.
It's unhealthy. Bet you're gay.
No, I'm not.
There was tension in the air.
It didn't seem like a happy company.
The crew were very quiet
and looked a bit disgruntled.
I then discovered that the crew
in fact were on the verge of...
downing tools. There was nearly a
mutiny, because they got so fed up
with having these two directors who
seemed to be at odds with each other.
Two directors, a double-headed dog.
It was interesting, because
Terry and I seemed to be in
agreement about everything
before we started shooting.
About life, the cosmos, everything.
And as we started shooting,
it was clear that sometimes
we were saying opposite things
to the others in the group.
It's a dogsbody's job, directing.
It really is.
You've got to organise
things and work out
what you're doing in the morning.
It's a thankless task.
We do tag team directing.
He finishes that, and he'll come out
and exhaustedly tap me on the
shoulder, and I'll rush into action.
But you treat him with proper respect?
Well... HE LAUGHS
Well...there's never
been any mutual respect
within the Python group at all,
as you probably know.
But we're withholding a lot of the
criticism we would normally be making.
Terry and Terry Gilliam,
particularly Terry Gilliam,
was so enjoying the visual
look of it and all that.
And they sometimes had trouble
persuading someone like John
that it was very important to
crouch for another 12 minutes
so they could get the sun glancing
off the top of his helmet.
He didn't see the aesthetic value
of that particular shot.
He just felt it was very
uncomfortable. But he is tall,
and bending down is probably
more difficult for him.
The only thing that seemed to
matter was the look of the shot.
I did a take with Eric where
Eric was playing Concorde.
Come on, Concorde! ARROW THWACKS
Message for you, sir.
Concorde! Concorde, speak to me!
'I want you to realise that when
making a movie, you only do about'
three or four really good takes in
the whole movie, when it all flows.
When we did one, I was so proud.
I thought, "That was a great take."
Brave, brave Concorde!
You shall not have died in vain.
Er, I'm not quite dead, sir.
Well, you shall not have
been mortally wounded in vain.
I think I could pull through, sir.
Oh, I see.Actually, I think
I'm all right to come with you.
No, sweet Concorde, stay here.
I will send help as soon
as I've accomplished
a daring and heroic rescue
in my own particular...
Oh...
Idiom, sir?Idiom!
I feel fine, actually...
Farewell, sweet Concorde!
I said, "How about that?"
And the cameraman and Terry
Jones said, "Not enough smoke."
And that kind of incensed me,
because I care about the writing,
the ideas and the performance.
So from then on, I made a
lot of sarcastic remarks.
"Was the smoke funny
enough in that take?"
So there was a bit of a tension
between the people who cared how
it looked and the people who were more
interested in what the film was about.
I think the moment it finally snapped
was when we were doing the scene
where the taunters are
pelting the knights
with cows and sheep and
everything over the battlements.
It was a
matte shot,
so I had to get everybody below
the parapet of the castle
so I could then cut a matte out and
throw these toy animals over later.
Which meant digging a hole in
the ground to get low enough.
The others in the group had to be on
their knees to get these angles right.
John and Graham were the first to go,
and just got so angry
with me for these uncomfortable
positions I was putting them in.
I said, "This is your sketch.
I didn't write this sketch.
"I'm trying to make it work.
If you don't like it, I'm off".
I know I was a bit mean to
Terry Gilliam on one occasion,
because Terry was used to doing
animation and having these cut-outs,
and he would move
the cut-out a fraction
and then move another
cut-out a fraction.
He had a tendency to treat
the actors a bit like that.
He would say, "Can you
move a bit to the left?"
And we would do that and
he'd say, "Back a bit".
And this would go on... for 15 minutes!
Once, I think I sort of exploded.
I said, "Will you get on with it?
"We're so uncomfortable!"
And I think that hurt his feelings,
poor chap, and he went and lay down.
I went off in a snit and lay down
in the grass some distance away.
"I'm not gonna play."
And Terry had to deal with him.
That was the moment that split it.
Terry Jones, I have to say,
was always slightly
more aware of the actors, being one
of the actors, being involved all the
time and having to
do a bit of directing
and then rush around and
be Sir Bedevere and all that.
What do you find is the most difficult
part of sustaining the effort?
Getting up.In the morning?
Yes, and putting clothes on.
It seemed to me the comedy
would be more effective
if you believed in that
world, if that world smelt
and you could taste
it and it was there.
Then you could do the most silly
things within that, and that
would give the comedy more weight.
I still think that's true.
They really did a
fantastic job.
When you see that boat sweeping in,
you think, "This is a proper movie."
And then it goes
back to being silly.
But it's the properness of the movie
which sets it all up, I think.
After encountering the notorious
knights who say "Ni!",
Arthur and his noblemen embark
on one last push to find the Grail.
They meet Tim the Enchanter,
fight a killer rabbit,
throw the holy hand grenade,
cross the bridge of death before...
Jesus Christ!
Baa!
Hello, dirty English knig-gets
and Monsieur Arthur King
who has the brain of a duck!
I came up with the ending.
I think it was just
out of desperation.
We were going towards a battle,
and we couldn't afford an army.
THEY YELL
I think they're something
like 25 students
from one university nearby who
are pretending to be the army.
SIREN
They're the ones, I'm sure!
I came up with the idea of
having the police arrest us.
Come on.
So it gets kind of conceptual.
I like that.
All right, sonny, that's enough.
CAMERA SMASHES
Injecting that modern character in,
I think, helped, made it very...
gave it the sense
of Python humour,
but also gave us a way of bringing
the whole thing to an end.
Bring the police in, arrest
everybody and stop the film.
That just seems so neat.
Once that idea had come up,
you couldn't resist it.
The decision to end it the
way they did is pretty brave.
I mean, we had some...and continue
to have very confused some audiences
who don't know when
to leave the theatre.
With the hardships and tensions
of filming behind them,
the suffering was surely over.
The Pythons could sit
back, ready to bask
in the warm glow of
audience approval.
End board.
We had a screening for the investors
after the soundtrack was mixed,
and it was probably
one of the worst events
I've ever had to attend,
because after the first couple of
minutes where there was some laughter,
it kind of sank into a quietness
for about 85 minutes.
By the end, it was almost embarrassing,
'cause no-one quite
knew where to look and
what to say to anybody at that stage.
It was one of those moments
where you think,
"God, what have we
done, after all this?"
And then it turns on Terry and me.
That's the problem when you're
the director. It was absolute death.
I mean, the film was just...
not working.
And we'd spent all the money.
We had mixed the whole soundtrack.
This was music, dialogue,
everything but making the print.
Neil was the one that maybe
got the short end of the stick,
because he had written more music
that was then pulled off at
the last moment, because it
ended up...they got library
music that was more epic.
We just picked the music
that sounded like
old Hollywood films,
I mean, old medieval movies.
The decision to use library
music was the right one.
It is mock heroic,
so you want "Bom-da-da!"
Even though it was boring,
"Bom da dum da da da dum, dum,
dum, dum-dum, da-da-da dum."
It's not anywhere nearly as good as...
HE SINGS TUNE
Oh, the battles.
Oh, dear. If only...I'm sorry.
I'm...becoming...overcome
with...self-pity.
Monty Python And The Holy Grail
had finally scraped
over the finishing line.
The dirty half-dozen had battled
with adversity, chaotic filming and
each other, but now they decided to
take one final, but fateful, risk.
Instead of premiering the film on home
turf, they would take it to New York.
Flying Circus had just
hit US TV screens,
but would the Americans turn
up to see them on celluloid?
When we got to New York, there were
people riding up and down Fifth Avenue,
clicking coconuts with banners saying,
"If you come and see this film,
the first thousand people
will get coconuts."
I remember being in New York,
and suddenly we were in
this hotel and people said,
"You gotta come and see
it" and you looked out
and there was this queue going
all the way round the block.
And all day long, it kept
going and going and going.
We were trapped inside the
theatre for the rest of the day.
People would come out and we'd
sign their bloody coconuts.
Impossible, by the way,
to sign a coconut.
Python breaking in America as it
did in '73-'74, was so important,
because suddenly we had
a whole new fan base.
And they discovered the series,
and suddenly we had this movie.
It really was one of the most
amazing days of my life, I think.
It was that sort of relief that
not only was it working, but it was
working on some extraordinary level
that we'd never realised was possible.
And it just grew from there.
And people loved it.
"Hey, these guys make films as well."
Good timing.
It was better than good.
Cracking the US market put
the Pythons on the road from cult
status to the comedy hall of fame.
The success of Holy Grail led to
Life Of Brian and The Meaning Of Life.
And they followed in the footsteps
of their rock investors
by selling out the
Hollywood Bowl.
# I'm a lumberjack, and I'm OK
# I sleep all night and I work all day
#I cut down trees... #
The boys have gone on to
prove that they could enjoy
separate careers and a
life after Monty Python.
Cardboard box...You're lucky.
John Cleese's first
stop in fleeing Python
was a little known
guesthouse in Torquay,
which he ran for a bit before heading
a lot further west to California.
He's not been forgotten
at home, though,
and still gets a bit of work
here from time to time.
Michael Palin's desire not to
be recognised saw him sail
all the way to the ends
of the Earth and back.
But his postcards home
proved so popular
that we keep sending
him away again.
How pay much she her you do.
Pebble number one three,
Bering Sea, ocean, sky.
Palin here, very cold, chill.
Terry Gilliam went back to America
to direct several big movies with
big visual ideas that sometimes
proved a bit too big for their budgets.
Terry Jones' overseas escapades
have taken him to Portuguese opera,
but he still enjoys the odd
spot of medieval merrymaking.
It appears that his great musical
talent lay in farting tunes.
Graham Chapman declined to give
an interview for this programme,
mostly because he shuffled
off to a better place in 1989.
His pals marked his passing
with due reverence.
Good riddance to him, the freeloading
bastard. I hope he fries.
Eric Idle's personal quest
took him from Rutland to LA,
where he finally found the Holy Grail
by lovingly ripping off
a half-remembered film
he'd once appeared in for a
musical called Spamalot.
I remember sitting there on the opening
night on Broadway and thinking,
"It's so gloriously
good-natured and silly
that it fills you with a kind of joy."
I don't think any of us were prepared
for what a success it was on stage.
Again, it caught the spirit of Python.
It was very fast, it was
jolly, silly, well done.
There was lots to watch and see.
That's what's important.
You can't do Python without
some sort of commitment.
As Spamalot makes its
triumphant coconut-shod way
from Broadway to London and beyond,
a new audience has discovered the
original material, and Monty Python
And The Holy Grail is once again
winning fans across the world.
Not bad for a film made
over 30 years ago
on a shoestring budget by
a bunch of movie novices.
There was something very
magical about this film
in that sense about how
everything came together
both in the filming,
the talents that came together
and eventually how it
reached an audience.
It was our utter naivety and high
energy that produced this thing.
And I look back and say,
"I could never do that now.
"Those were other guys that did it".
But there was no stopping us.
What has been truly
wonderful is that I was
working with people who were
totally committed to what
they were doing, and committed to try
and make the very best of something.
The general kind of
spirit of Holy Grail,
I think, now comes
through very well.
It's a good-natured film.
It's a silly film, held together very
much by Graham's performance.
How do you know so much about swallows?
You have to know these
things when you're a king.
I think it is probably closer
to a kind of reality
of our characters than
almost anything we've done.
John is a very angry Lancelot
who comes charging at things.
I do like to run away a lot,
you know, with a musician.
Michael, I think, is constantly tempted
by young women wearing very little.
And Gilliam is clearly Patsy
and Terry Jones is a sort of Bedevere,
constantly doing this and...you know.
It was extraordinarily demanding
physically, but we were young.
If I tried to do it now,
I'd be in hospital in two weeks.
I just have to write "Ni!"
on an autograph book, and people think
that's the funniest
thing you've ever done,
which saves you having to
write a very unfunny message.
Just say "Ni!" and people like it. Ni!