[choir singing]
[water dripping]
If the great Christmas icicle
continues to melt at this rate,
Christmas magic
stored in the ice crystal will vanish.
These days, children and their pups
just don't believe like they used to.
Their focus is on themselves, instead
of on giving to others less fortunate.
If they don't understand
the true meaning of Christmas,
the icicle has no chance.
And I'm afraid that's something
we just can't teach.
Soon it will be
Puppy Paws' responsibility
to show the next generation
the importance of Christmas spirit.
[laughs] Wa-hoo! Wa-hoo!
Now, Dasher! Now, Dancer!
Now, Prancer and Vixen!
On, Comet! On, Cupid!
On, Donner and Blitzen!
That was fun. Let's do it again.
I'm afraid
we're all too tired now, Puppy Paws.
Comet, please?
Look, we have a lot of work to do today.
- Like what?
- Well, for one thing,
we have to get ready for Christmas Eve.
You know,
the most important night of the year?
Fine. I'll go find some fun on my own.
Oh, that pup sure has a lot to learn
before he takes the reins
and is responsible for Christmas.
Jingle bells ring
[bell ringing]
[choir sings Jingle Bell Rings]
[horn honks]
Yippee! Yippee!
La, la, la, la
Perfect.
Three trucks done!
- [man] Here come more toys.
- [woman] I got another load.
All packed and ready to go!
[man] Wagon, coming through, people!
All right! This'll be good.
There's the bell, let's work until
we grant each Christmas wish
Hurry up and fill the sleigh
With the best things on your list, hey!
There's the bell, let's work until
we grant each Christmas wish
We'll hurry up and fill the sleigh
with the best things on your list
Santa makes it fun
He's always on the go
You'll know it's him
When the sleigh bells ring
And you hear "ho, ho, ho"
- Ho!
- [laughing]
Jingle bells ring
There's the bell, let's work until
we grant each Christmas wish
Hurry up and fill the sleigh
with the best things on your list
Hey!
[all shouting]
- It's going fast.
- Grab those...
- [laughs]
- Stop this! Stop... Ah!
- Oh, no.
- What's going on? It's chaos!
Come on.
- [playing piano fast]
- Yippee!
- Grab that...
- Uh-oh. This is getting out of control.
- [all shouting]
- Oh!
- Watch out!
- [sighs]
- I checked it a couple minutes ago.
- What do you mean?
[all] Puppy Paws!
Son, I am very disappointed in you.
You disrupted the workshop
and wasted a whole day of work.
The elves are very upset.
They're now another day behind schedule.
You know how hard they work
getting ready.
I didn't realize
it would cause such havoc.
I just wanted to have some fun.
Maybe you should be thinking
about how important Christmas is
to children and puppies
all around the world.
It's our responsibility
to deliver good puppies the gift
they've wished for the entire year.
You mean it's your responsibility.
I just want to be an ordinary puppy.
You're grounded until further notice.
That means no playing fetch
with the elves
and no flying with the reindeer.
I wish Christmas would just go away.
Puppy Paws!
What a horrible thing to say!
Do you think I was too strict with him?
Maybe just a smidgen, but...
...I'm sure he'll get over it.
Puppy Paws has to understand,
he's the future of Christmas.
Oh, Christmas tree
How steadfast are your branches
Your boughs are green in summertime
And through the snows of wintertime
Oh, Christmas tree
Oh, Christmas tree...
You pups want to sing along?
Yo, I don't sing. I rap.
Why do we even have to come here?
It's a Christmas tradition.
I've been watching the lighting of the
tree since I was a pup like you Buddies.
- [sighs]
- You're quiet this evening, Budderball.
I hadn't even
heard your stomach grumble. [laughs]
Anything the matter?
I'm still in the doghouse
for eating the Thanksgiving turkey.
Are you worried you might be
on Santa Paws' naughty list?
Pshaw! Santa Paws is just Dad
dressed up in a red and white suit.
That's all, dawg.
They just use it so we behave all year.
Is that right, B-Dawg?
Let's look at the evidence,
Deputy Sniffer.
If the jolly dude came down the chimney,
wouldn't there be a lot of soot?
I'm not really buying the whole
"Santa Paws" thing, either,
but I sure do love all the presents.
Your material desires
are those of the wanting mind.
Enough is never enough.
Buddha's right, Buddies.
Getting material things
isn't what Christmas is all about.
Christmas spirit is about the unselfish
spreading of love and kindness.
There are plenty of lonely puppies
without families
or children to love them.
Your boughs can teach a lesson
- [applause]
- [clears throat] Hello, everybody.
Thank you for coming down
to the annual lighting
of the Fernfield Christmas tree.
Not quite the turnout we expected.
Three...
...two... one!
[all cheering, clapping]
Buddies, it's Mr. Cruge,
the dog catcher.
[people screaming]
Oh, jiminy Christmas!
[man] It's probably just a faulty bulb.
[yelping]
Oh...
Phew!
[female] Oh, my!
Thank you, Lord,
for this blessing. Amen.
[yelping]
Thought you could
run wild in the streets?
Not on my watch you don't.
[Cruge muttering, laughing]
I don't wanna be
responsible for Christmas.
I just wanna be an ordinary puppy.
[cracking]
I wish Christmas would just disappear.
The naughty book
gets thicker every year.
We're just on the pups.
If Puppy Paws doesn't understand
the true meaning of Christmas,
- how could we expect other puppies to?
- Mm-hm.
"Bubba.
Offense: destruction of property.
Chewing shoes, 17 cases."
Oh, my. That is naughty, all right.
[Santa] "Budderball. Offense: gluttony.
Eating the Thanksgiving turkey."
[all gasping]
- Whoa!
- [belches]
Budderball!
Big appetite for a pup.
I have the feeling little Budderball's
tummy always leads to naughtiness.
Santa Paws, Claus, we got the mail truck
ready for a systems check.
Great, Eli.
We could use a break from this.
Haven't even checked the list twice
and we're already tired.
Hm.
Budderball. One of the five Air Buddies.
He has three brothers,
Mudbud, B-Dawg, Buddha,
and a little sis, Rosebud.
They live in Fernfield, Washington,
each with their own families.
Regular, ordinary, fun-loving pups.
They sound perfect!
[man] Hey, Eugene!
OK. The sooner you get going,
the better.
We've got
a lot of pickups scheduled.
Over 1,000 cities and towns.
Eli, sir, she's all yours.
Confirming. The route is programmed.
OK, let's run
the diagnostic tests. New Delhi.
Oh, I am liking this very, very much.
Florence.
[speaking ltalian]
All seems in the working order,
Santy Claus.
You give me the clearance,
I'm ready to roll.
That's an all-clear from the North Pole.
Well, here I go.
Time to hitch a ride to Fernfield.
Good work, team.
We're right on schedule.
Jingle all the way, Eli.
[engine starts]
[Santa chuckles]
[all] Bye!
[man] Have a safe trip.
[Santa] Holding up all right?
Good, good...
Ah, good work.
[cracking]
- [machinery winding down]
- Oh, no!
I don't like the look of this one bit.
It's happening fast.
The magic of Christmas
is fading away, right before our eyes.
[Eli whistling]
"Fernfield:
Where everything is possible."
My kind of place.
[whistling]
[grunting]
Holy Christmas spirit.
We're almost out of power.
[engine starts]
[rock music playing on radio]
[static, then
Hark! The Herald Angels Sing plays]
Oh!
[changing station]
It looks to me like we've tapped
into all the additional power we've got.
- [dripping]
- Oh, my. Another leak.
I hate to even say it, but I think
the North Pole is starting to melt.
Any thoughts, Eddy?
Well, sir, spirit is down, but there
seems to be something else going on.
The icicle is melting faster
than we ever thought possible.
Has anyone seen Puppy Paws?
He seems to be missing.
My guess would be the stables.
You know how he loves to play tricks
on Donner and Blitzen.
Come on then, you're next.
Ho-ho-ho.
[grunts] What do you want?
I was hoping you could deliver this note
to the real Santa for me?
- The real Santa?
- I know that the real Santa
is busy at the North Pole making gifts
and you're just one of his helpers.
If you could deliver this note to him,
I would really appreciate it.
Yeah, I'll see what I can do.
OK. Time's up.
There's other boys and girls
that need to see Hank.
- I mean, Santa.
- Merry Christmas, sir.
- Thank you. And God bless.
- [Hank] Merry Christmas to you, too.
[Hank] Ho-ho-ho. What do you want?
They couldn't have found me already.
[tires screeching]
[gasps]
Ah! Ah!
I did it! Holy... Oh!
Say "cheese," pipsqueak.
Man, this is itchy.
Ew! An imposter.
[grunts] All right!
- [Puppy Paws] Whoa!
- [grumbling]
What are you doing?!
- Oh!
- [grunts]
[Hank] What'll it be?
- [Cruge] Yes!
- Hey! What in the heck are you doing?
That dog. I'm trying to catch that dog!
[reindeer sneezing]
Comet, what's wrong?
Santa Claus, Santa Paws,
I wouldn't come in here if I were you.
All of us reindeer, we've been
hit with some sort of flu bug.
Could be contagious. [sneezes]
Are you gonna be OK?
[groans] I don't know, Santa.
Cupid isn't feeling the love
and Dancer isn't doing much dancing.
- We all feel really weak.
- It's a lack of energy from the icicle.
It's affecting us all.
Is there anything we can help with?
We're looking for Puppy Paws.
- Have you seen him?
- Come to think of it, no.
He hasn't been
asking us for rides... [sneezes]
Everything OK?
People sure aren't
very jolly in Fernfield.
I think it's time to call it a night.
- [woman] Thanks again, Mrs. Davis.
- [woman 2] Take care.
[yawning]
I guess I'll have to find Budderball
in the morning.
[toy] Ho-ho-ho! Merry Christmas!
Ho-ho-ho! Merry Christmas!
[man] Hey, look, everybody, Eli's back.
- [engine sputtering]
- [moans]
Hey, what happened? You're back early.
For a minute there
I thought I might have to push.
- What's wrong with the truck?
- Almost ran out of power.
Where's all the mail, sir?
That's all there was.
Oh! Sweet mama! Gingerbread cookies!
Budderball? Is it really you?
I've been looking for you all over town.
Wow! That polar bear cub
sure looks realistic.
His mouth even moves.
Come on, big fella!
Budderball! Wait!
Good boy.
[woman] Oh, my!
All right. I've just got... Hm.
OK... Just a little knot here.
What in tarnation? Huh?
[snoring]
- Excuse me?
- [snoring]
- Excuse me!
- Huh? Oh...
Oh, hello there, young'un.
Deputy Sniffer at your service.
I'm looking for a pup I just saw.
But then he disappeared.
His name is Budderball.
Oh, I've known that pup his whole life.
So you know where he lives?
Budderball lives at Livingston Manor.
Now to get there
you want to go left down Main Street,
then take a right
at the candy store and keep going.
It's on the outskirts of town.
You can't miss it.
Thanks, Deputy.
[snoring]
[man] OK, heads up, I'm sending it down.
[Jingle Bells playing]
Thanks, Budderball.
Got it.
This must be it.
[man] I think I got some in the van.
Yeah, there's a box right there.
I'll grab 'em.
Here you go!
I'll send them up.
- A bit heavy.
- OK, I got it.
OK. You sure?
Well, I think we
are just about done.
I think we should lower
the candy canes a little.
They're kinda hard to... see.
[man] Oh, that's heavy.
Off we go.
Come on, Budderball.
Whoa!
[Budderball] Oh, sweet mama.
I'm not sure how Dad does this,
but here goes nothing.
Aah!
[grunting]
- Oh!
- [Budderball] Oh!
[moaning]
Hey! Do you mind getting off me?
It's you, right? Budderball?
I finally found you!
Who do you think you are, rolling out of
my chimney and busting my candy cane?
I'm Puppy Paws. Pleased to meet you.
- Where do you come from?
- The North Pole.
Oh, yeah.
I bet you belong to Santa Claus.
Well, technically, yes.
But Santa Paws is my pa.
Yeah, right. You expect me to believe
that your dad is Santa Paws?
- Why wouldn't you?
- Who put you up to this?
No one. I was checking the naughty list
and you looked like fun.
What'd you say?
I'm on the naughty list?!
It was just a little turkey!
Don't worry, you can get off
the naughty list and onto the nice list
by doing good deeds for others.
- Like?
- Well, um...
Like teaching me
how to be an ordinary pup.
OK, well,
I'll show you what I like to do.
This is
the most magical room in the house.
What kind of toys do you make here?
They don't make toys, they make food.
The most delicious food around.
Like roast beef sandwiches,
chicken wings, chili dogs...
Is he one of your elves?
You're a real joker, aren't you?
That's the chef.
- What's he doing?
- Making cookies.
But we can't eat them,
they're for Christmas.
Huh? [gasps]
Hey, how'd you get up there?
[Budderball] Uh-oh! [groans]
[Budderball] Bad idea.
- Wow!
- What?
Those cookies.
They just changed. How did you do that?
It's no biggie.
Christmas magic is stored in here.
So I can do stuff like my dad.
But I can't quite control it.
Hey, you want a cookie?
Don't you remember?
I'm trying to get back on the nice list.
Well, suit yourself.
Om... Om... Om...
Be good, Budderball, be good.
Don't eat the cookies!
- Oh, no!
- [belches] My compliments to the chef.
I believe it's time for lunch, Budder...
-...ball.
- [whimpering]
[laughing]
Oh, yeah, laugh it up.
Now I'm going to be late
meeting my brothers and sis in the park!
Hey. How about you introduce me to them?
Once I get done with my timeout,
I'd be happy to get you out of my fur!
Thanks! You're the best!
Is Budderball fashionably late again?
I hope the dude's not in trouble.
I'll meditate
and send him some positive energy.
Om...
[Buddha] Om...
Who's the white,
fluffy dude Budderball's with?
Puppy Paws, these are the Buddies.
The mucky pup is Mudbud.
The blinged-out one is B-Dawg.
- Buddha looks like he's sleeping...
- Om...
...but he calls it meditation.
Oh. And Rosebud is our little sis.
But don't let the pink bow fool you.
She's feistier than she looks.
And this is Puppy Paws.
He claims to be Santa Paws' son
from the North Pole.
Yo, you straight up trippin'?
We ain't fallin' for that, dawg.
I'm sorry about my brother.
We've just grown
a little skeptical about Christmas.
You're not alone. No one believes
in Christmas spirit anymore.
That's why I'm here.
To learn how to be an ordinary pup.
Well, you found
the right dog to school you.
Come on, I'll show you my crib.
[hip-hop plays]
All right, dawg, I'm gonna
show you how to kick it like me.
- I like kickin' it.
- Yeah, you know, bust some moves.
Uh... Yeah, bust some moves.
Watch and learn, cuz.
I call this the four paw pop,
into the boogaloo jaw drop,
to the tail rotation
for the B-Dawg Nation.
Yeah. Way to break those moves.
Yeah, I know. I'm the best.
Let's see you give it a shot, playa.
OK, I'll give it a whirl, playa.
[Christmas music plays]
I call this the Prancer hop 'n bop...
- Huh?
-...to the spinning toy top,
to the elf hustle 'n bustle,
to the shiny toy train.
Oh!
Whoa!
Did I bust some moves?
You busted something, all right.
- Hey, dudes.
- Yo, dawg,
it is your turn
to hang with Santa Junior.
- No problemo, dude.
- We'll see about that, dawg.
Why is he in such a huff?
I don't know, dawg.
He be trippin', for shizzle.
Wowzers, dude.
You don't have to talk like B-Dawg.
Isn't that how ordinary puppies talk?
Dude, only B-Dawg talks like that.
Oh. So, what are you doing... dude?
Just chillaxing with a mud bath, dude.
Dude, can I give it a roll?
Now what are we gonna do, dude?
Let me show you my sweet pad, dude.
This is the cleanest room in the house.
Strictly off limits.
Dude!
Is it normal for mud to feel itchy?
No, dude! Don't do it!
Whoa! How'd you do that, dude?
I don't know. It just happens, dude.
[gasps]
[whimpering]
Dude...
Dudette, where are you?
What's up? Alice is about
to give me a new Christmas outfit.
Oh, no. What happened to you?
Someone played a dirty trick on me.
You've gotta hang with Puppy Paws now.
I have to wear this clean coat
as punishment.
Later, dudenator.
So, what sweet stuff
are we going to do, dudette?
Oh, brother.
Awesome, and I'll call you "sis."
I've never had a sis before.
Or a brother. This is gonna be epic!
[Alice] Rosebud! Where are you?
Like, wait here. I'll be back
with a whole new Christmas look.
Wow! Like, that should be fun.
[Alice] Hey, Rosebud.
You're gonna love this, Rosebud.
So, what do you think?
You're right. What was I thinking?
Accessories!
Hang on. I'll be right back.
What's taking so long?
[gasps] You startled me.
- That's your new Christmas look?
- You don't like it?
I think it's totally fetch.
I like it,
but it's not very Christmassy.
What could be
more Christmassy than this?
[screaming]
Om... Om...
- [Buddha] Om...
- Excuse me!
Rosebud sent me.
She was, like, totally freaking out
about her Christmas makeover.
Well, it's time for meditation.
This Buddha statue
came from the Ming Dynasty,
over 600 years old. Very sacred.
So, like, how do we do
this "meditate" stuff?
We simply sit and breathe.
A clear mind is developed
through meditation.
- Om...
[both continue] Om...
My Buddha statue!
It's a snowman,
very Zen in the North Pole.
[barking]
Hello?
[man] Anyone here?
Yes?
Hi. Um...
My son would like a puppy for Christmas.
Ha!
Well, then,
you've come to the right place.
- [whining]
- Quiet!
- Where are the puppies?
- They're hiding.
They'll come out
if they know what's good for 'em.
[man] This is the one.
She's perfect. I'll take her.
That's $300.
I thought the puppies were free for
adoption. We'll give her a loving home.
- Take good care of her.
- You're wasting your breath.
That doesn't matter to me.
I just want the $300.
It's for my son for Christmas.
He's sick.
[whimpers]
A puppy might be just
what he needs to brighten his spirits.
I have $50.
No money, no mutt.
If you can find it in your heart...
[door closes]
Ha!
- Dudes, where's Buddha?
- Buddha's always on time,
whereas I'm only on time at dinnertime.
I sent Puppy Paws over to Buddha's.
I thought he might be the only one
with the patience to handle him.
That "being one
with the universe" stuff...
So powerful.
And being present,
not just giving presents, is so Zen.
- So, how'd it go?
- I lost it.
What's the "it," Zen Master?
My temper! That's the "it" I lost, OK?
Hey, I know something
that ordinary puppies always do.
- Play Hide-and-Go-Seek.
- Hide-and-Go-Seek? What's that?
You close your eyes
and count down from 12 while we hide.
When you finish counting,
you yell really loud,
"Ready or not, here I come!"
And you start looking for us, got it?
Yo, BFFing dudes,
that sounds like mad,
gnarly fun for shizzle! Namaste.
- Oh, brother.
- [sighs]
Twelve drummers drumming,
eleven pipers piping...
Everyone go in a separate direction
and meet behind the stump.
Eight maids a-milking,
seven swans a-swimming.
Six geese a-laying, five golden rings.
Two turtle doves,
and a partridge in a pear tree.
That's twelve!
Here I come!
I called you to this stump meeting
to discuss Puppy Paws
and what we are going to do with him.
This game isn't so hard.
Puppy Paws actually thinks
that I'm buying that his pop is Santa.
I'm not even shopping, yo.
That dude got me
in some serious doo-doo.
I had the humiliation of wearing
a clean coat for the entire day.
If he's Santa Paws' son,
why'd he get me in more trouble,
rather than helping me
get off the naughty list?
And you should have seen what he did
to me. It was a fashion disaster.
But I was just trying to be like them.
Wait a second, Buddies.
We all have our own karma.
Puppy Paws is not responsible
for me losing my center.
To find faults in him,
we're really just
finding faults in ourselves.
The Zen dude is correctamundo.
He was only trying to fit in.
- Oh!
- [whimpering]
[grunts]
- [Cruge chuckles]
- I was only jealous
'cause the dawg schooled me
in the hip-hop battle.
I guess I ate myself
onto the naughty list.
It's my responsibility
to get myself off, not Puppy Paws'.
We should be ashamed of ourselves.
Poor Puppy Paws
doesn't have any brothers or sisters.
I couldn't imagine not having you guys.
Let's embrace Puppy Paws
with compassion.
[whimpering]
Where did the dude go?
[water dripping]
The Christmas icicle is almost gone.
I wouldn't believe it
if I didn't see it with my own eyes.
When Puppy Paws left,
the icicle started melting even faster.
If we don't find Puppy Paws, Christmas
as we know it will be lost forever.
All right. Come on. Come on.
Sniff, sniff. All right, let's go.
All right now.
Ah, come on.
[barking]
[Cruge] Quiet!
Come on, come on.
All right.
Yeah, you won't be needing
this anymore. [laughs]
In you go.
[whimpering]
"Property of the North Pole?"
[laughs]
Very, very funny.
What is this place?
The pound is where they put
us dogs that no one cares about.
No one cares about you?
- What's your name?
- They call me Tiny,
because I'm the smallest
of all the puppies.
I'm Puppy Paws. What's with that guy?
Did he get
coal in his stocking or something?
He lost his Christmas spirit.
No one cares about Christmas anymore.
We do.
The hope for a Christmas miracle
is all we have.
[whimpering]
Every night I look up
And pray that someone sees
The sadness in these lonely eyes
And shares his love with me
As the night grows colder
We really need to find
A way to heal the hope we 've lost
We really need a sign
We need to know
That there are Christmas miracles
This year
Good job.
Now make a wish and we'll turn it on.
[coughing]
[whispers] I wish that Santa
would get my letter.
Here we go.
[Tiny]  We need to know
That there are Christmas miracles
Somewhere in our hearts
Somewhere in our souls
We need to feel
The love, the hope and the cheer
The magic in this time of year
We need a Christmas miracle
A Christmas miracle
This year
I had no idea.
Thank you, Tiny. Thank you.
- Magicometer.
Well, did you find any way
of boosting the power?
The boys have modified the E.L.F.
compressor with the magicometers
and gotten a little more power
with the spiriters.
[gasps]
We have great news!
I think we know where Puppy Paws is.
Fernfield, Washington.
In search of a pup
named Budderball.
You know how he was saying
he just wanted to be an ordinary pup?
Santa Claus? Santa Paws? You OK?
Please, bring back Puppy Paws
as fast as you can.
Without him, I'm afraid Christmas
may be gone forever.
[gasps]
Yes, sir! We'll be back quicker
than you can say "Candy Cane Lane."
[whooshing sound]
[engine sputtering]
Well, at least we made it. I have
no idea how we're gonna get back.
[Eli] The tank
is completely out of magic.
All right. I'll try and find Puppy Paws.
And I'll see what I can do
about the truck so we can get home.
- Where's Budderball?
- That dawg ain't ever on time.
Being fashionably late is one thing,
but this is way out of style.
Dude, am I hallucinating
or is Budderball running with an elf?
It's an elf, all right.
Where does he find these dawgs?
The looney bin?
Hi, guys. Sorry I'm late.
I had another surprise visitor
from way up north.
[Budderball] This is Eddy.
He claims to be Santa Paws' head elf.
We need your help.
Christmas is in great danger.
And we need to get Puppy Paws
back to the North Pole.
Well, I for one totally love your shoes,
and will do anything to help.
Your presence indicates that
our disbelief may have been unfounded.
But, regardless, there is one obstacle.
Puppy Paws has disappeared.
Quick, hide! It's Cruge!
Come on, let's go!
- [Mudbud] Coming through!
- [Rosebud] Hurry up.
Oh, no! Do you think Puppy Paws
might be in the pound?
[B-Dawg] This way, dawgs!
- All right...
- [engine sputtering]
[sighs]
No magic in the tank,
no way to get home.
It's officially the end
of Christmas spirit.
[indistinct chatter]
- [Hank] Next.
- [man] Have a nice day.
- [Hank] Hello.
- That's great.
Hm...
[Hark! The Herald Angels Sing
playing on PA]
[man] There it is. There you go.
- Look at that. Keep it moving.
- Thank you.
If I had enough magic,
even just a little...
Hey!
Bub, look, I'm all for slacking off,
but I've been busting my hump over here
and you've been standing over here...
-...hiding out, so...
- Oh, I'm not hiding out.
I'm trying to see
if I can make this sleigh fly
so that we can get Puppy Paws back
to the North Pole and save Christmas.
[laughs] Puppy Paws! Of course! Yes!
Ooh! I have an idea!
Let's sprinkle a little fairy dust
all over the reindeer
to come alive and then
they can fly you back to Santy Claus.
Do you have some?
No. No...
If you don't get back to work right now,
I'm gonna tell the big boss, OK?
This is killing me.
- [man] You want your uniform revoked?
- Oh, of course not.
All right, follow me.
[barking]
Uh... I don't think anyone's home.
Maybe we should come back
another time, dawgs?
Dudes, look! There's a hole in the back!
[B-Dawg] Yo, dawgs, hold up!
OK, you know the plan.
Budderball, you're on lookout.
Bark twice if Mr. Cruge returns.
[Rosebud] Mudbud and B-Dawg,
you find the key.
Buddha, Eddy and I will find Puppy Paws.
- Got it?
- [Eddy] Go! Quickly!
- [B-Dawg] Come on, let's go!
- [Mudbud] Hurry.
[all] Puppy Paws!
Eddy! Is that you?
Over here, last cage.
Eddy, I'm so happy to see you.
I'm so sorry I messed everything up.
From now on,
I promise to be good for goodness sake.
We're gonna need you
to be great for greatness sake.
[Eddy] The Christmas icicle
has all but melted now.
Santa Claus and Santa Paws
need you back.
Your dad has grown very weak.
Your dad is Santa Paws?
There isn't going to be a Christmas?
I won't let that happen, Tiny.
You pups taught me
the true meaning of Christmas spirit.
It's not just about presents.
In fact, it's not about presents at all.
It's about things you can't
wrap in a box or tie with a bow.
First, find my collar
so we can get out of here.
I'll retrieve it.
- The key is not in here.
- It's not over here, dawg.
We've gotta find Puppy Paws' collar.
There's too many, dawg. Which one is it?
I remember! It looks like a candy cane.
There it is!
[grunting]
It's about time. Hurry!
Wow! I can't thank you guys enough.
That's what friends do,
help each other out of a jam.
- [door creaking]
- [gasping]
Budderball, if you're here,
then who's on the lookout?
Uh...
Huh?
Ha! They're coming to me now!
You guys go. I'll take care of him.
And we will help.
You would be willing to do that
for Christmas?
It's us or saving Christmas, right?
This job just gets easier and easier.
Get back in your cage.
Get out of here, go! Quickly!
Eli's waiting for you
in front of town hall.
You guys can do it. I know you can.
You're our Christmas miracle.
We won't let you down, Tiny.
[Puppy Paws] Come on, let's go!
Follow me.
[Budderball] Watch out! Coming through!
[Rosebud] Move over, guys!
- [barking]
- Hey, hey! No, no, no!
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
Go away! Go away!
Oh!
[gasps] Oh...
Go away. Go away!
I'm ticklish!
[laughing]
[laughing] I'm ticklish!
- [Puppy Paws] Eli, wake up!
- [snoring]
Puppy Paws!
We've got to
get back to the North Pole right away!
- How'd you get here?
- The mail truck.
But it doesn't have enough power
to get us back.
I've been trying to figure out
how to get this sleigh to work...
Puppy Paws, your collar!
It might have enough magic
to make this thing fly.
It's lighter than the truck
and it needs a lot less power.
- But we still need reindeer.
- There are no reindeer in Fernfield
other than
those plastic ones right there.
Wait a sec!
We know how to pull a sleigh.
Let me get this straight, Elf Dude.
All we have to do is pull the sleigh
and Puppy Paws' magic collar
will make it fly?
- That is correct.
- Will you guys do it?
B-Dawg is all about the heroics.
Yo, P-Squared,
you need help saving Christmas,
- we're your Buddies.
- Let's do it!
[barking]
For that little stunt,
there'll be no dinner.
[whimpering]
[Eddy] I bet you haven't
laughed like that in a long time.
Huh? Who said that?
[Eddy] We know all about you
at the North Pole.
You didn't get a puppy when you were
a boy, and it made you hate Christmas.
But Santa knew that your mother
was very allergic to dogs,
that it wasn't right for your family.
I know a lot of things about you,
Stan Cruge.
Are you talking to me?
I'm from the North Pole where we can
communicate with all creatures.
It's part of the Christmas magic.
And you know the best way
to heal your broken heart
is to give to those in need.
What has gotten into me?
Christmas, sir.
Christmas has gotten into you.
It's time to let Christmas
back into your heart.
Well, I would love to stay for eggnog,
but I have to get back to the North Pole
and help save Christmas.
Uh, dawgs, it just struck me
that we ain't playin' no more.
This Santa stuff is for real, yo.
OK, you're all set.
We only have one shot at this,
so it's important you believe you can
fly without a shadow of a doubt.
- Ready, Buddies?
- That's "reindogs" to you, bro.
Next stop, the North Pole.
Did you see that?!
They're flying.
I most certainly did.
And, yes, they are flying.
- Whoa! This is so fly! I'm flying!
- But I'm afraid of heights!
Budderball, don't look down.
Yo, dawgs, there's the dog pound.
[B-Dawg] Let's do a flyby.
[Budderball] Guys, wait.
Does anyone actually know
how to get to the North Pole?
Just follow the North Star.
[Eddy] The best way
to heal your broken heart
is to give to those in need.
[sighs]
[water dripping]
[wind howling]
- Did you feel that?
- Somewhere, somehow,
somebody just decided
they believed in Christmas after all.
It only takes one person
to change the lives of many.
Santa Claus, I do believe the Christmas
spirit has begun its turnaround.
[cheering]
You see, the magic is stored all year
round in the great Christmas icicle
and is released at Christmas.
If people don't believe in Christmas,
there isn't enough magic for us
to make the toys or fly the sleigh.
So, if there
isn't enough Christmas spirit,
then the icicle that stores
the magic will melt and...
...Christmas will be gone forever?
Precisely.
Children will never get
to experience the joy of Santa,
or learn about the spirit of Christmas.
To children, you are Santa's elf.
That's why your job as
an elf representative is so important.
You don't actually work for us directly,
but you do work
to spread Christmas spirit.
And if you don't believe,
neither will the children.
Wow. Thanks, Eli.
See, I had no idea
my job was so darn important.
Oh. Here comes my boss.
That little dog is your boss?
Eddy, this is Clark.
- He's an official elf representative.
- Hey.
Eli, we'd better get back
to the North Pole, lickety-split.
Santa's gonna need
all the help he can get.
- He can talk?
- Uh-huh.
We don't have enough magic
to power the truck.
We will soon.
Eli, things are turning around.
What happened at the pound?
Christmas. That's what happened.
- Remember your promise, Clark.
- I will.
Merry Christmas.
There it is, Buddies. The North Pole.
We can land right by Santa's house.
Yo, don't worry, P-Squared.
You are in good paws with the B-Dawg.
[all scream]
[moaning]
[groans] I guess
I overshot the landing a little.
You could say that again.
- Dad!
- Son!
I'm so sorry for not believing.
I just didn't understand
how important Christmas was.
And I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
I should have trusted you would come
to that realization yourself.
Well, it took the help of a few friends.
Buddies! Nice to see you again.
How've you been behaving, Budderball?
Any more turkey infractions?
No, Mr. Paws.
I haven't even sneaked a cookie.
Well, big fella, we'll have to see about
getting you off Santa's naughty list
and back onto the nice list.
That would make
my Christmas special, sir.
I can vouch for all the good
karma Budderball has created
since the infraction in question.
Your wisdom is appreciated,
Buddha. Namaste.
We are totally stoked to help,
Santa Dude.
Bro, that would be super rad.
I'll make sure we all do everything
we can to make Christmas happen.
Rosebud, your leadership skills
are exemplary.
If memory serves, you're near
the very top of Santa's nice list.
Thank you all for coming. We're very
behind here at Santa's workshop,
and it's going to take all the help
we can get to make Christmas happen.
[choir sings Jingle Bell Rings]
[man] Easy, easy.
[man 2] Oh, hello!
Yo, I gotta give props to those elves.
They know how to get it done.
[Santa] Ho-ho-ho!
- We are back in business!
- [cheering]
- Is that Santa Claus?
- Yes, that's Santa himself!
It's two nights 'til Christmas
There's so much work
You see
Tie all the ribbons
Stuff all the stockings
Make toys with me
Grant every wish with every gift
Young hearts will lift
So come on
Help save Christmas with me
Jingle bells ring
[bell rings]
Puppy Paws!
Oh! It's so great to see you!
What a glorious day! [laughs]
And you're right on time!
The great Christmas icicle is back!
Santa, my friends the Buddies
have come to help!
Welcome, Buddies! Ho-ho-ho!
As you can see, there's still lots of
toys to be made for children and puppies
all over the world. We're gonna need
all hands and paws on deck!
[Santa laughing]
[choir sings Jingle Bell Rings]
- [Eddy] We're back.
- [Santa] Whoa!
That's quite a haul you've got there.
From the looks of this load,
I'd say Christmas spirit is on the rise.
All right, people, let's get
these letters opened on the double.
- Christmas Eve's a-comin'.
- [bell rings]
There's the bell, let's work until
we grant each Christmas wish
We'll hurry up
And fill the sleigh
With the best things on your list
Santa makes it fun
He's always on the go
You'll know it's him
When the sleigh bells ring
And you hear, "ho, ho, ho"
[man] Hey, Budderball, nice haul.
Hey!
[choir sings It's Finally Here]
[boy] Wow!
[choir sings Season of Joy]
[woman gasps]
B-Dawg...
Thanks, Mr. Cruge. Merry Christmas!
[singing continues]
- [Clark] Merry Christmas!
- [Hank] Ho-ho-ho!
Here it comes... Yeah! There it is!
[singing continues]
- [man laughing]
- [cheering]
[crowd chattering]
[dog barking]
[yelling] Yeah, we did it!
- Yeah! [laughing]
- [barking]
All right, Santa,
we're ready for a test flight.
OK, everyone,
let's give this our best effort.
Let's cross all our fingers and paws...
[reindeer] Go, go, go...
Come on, come on!
Come on, come on. We can do it.
[all groaning]
Comet, Donner, Blitzen! Are you OK?
Sorry, Santa Claus. We still
don't seem to have enough strength
to even fly the empty sleigh.
The Christmas icicle is growing,
but not fast enough.
The Buddies and l
flew the small sleigh to the North Pole
with just the little magic
that was left in my crystal.
Maybe we can fly Santa's sleigh?
- Whoa! What's happening?
- That's what happens to the leader.
It's to light the way
for the rest of us.
I think we're going to call you Ru-Dawg.
Now that's tight.
My nose shines just like my bling.
Prepare for departure.
Good luck, son. Stay focused.
[Santa Paws] Tonight is
the most important night of the year.
All good children and puppies
are counting on you.
No matter what happens tonight,
I want to thank you, Buddies.
- You're the best friends I've ever had.
- We should thank you.
We had stopped believing
in Christmas until we met you.
Enough of this Kumbaya stuff.
I'm in it to win it!
All right, Buddies,
it's up to us to save Christmas!
- [woman] Bye!
- [all] Goodbye!
[cheering]
[church bell rings]
[choir sings We Hear Angels]
Merry Christmas.
Santa, I know it's late
to be making Christmas wishes...
And I know I've been playing like
I don't believe in Santa Claus...
I don't need any presents.
The only thing I want for Christmas...
...is for the Buddies
to be safe at home. Amen.
[wind howling]
[singing continues]
"Dear Santa,
I know this is a lot to ask,
but this year if you could find a puppy
that really needs a home for Christmas,
it would change our lives.
[Cruge] I would
take really good care of him.
And he would take good care of us.
I know we would be the best of friends
and I think my parents
will worry less about me
if they knew I had someone
to watch out for me.
We live in a small brown house
at the end of Griffith Road.
Merry Christmas.
Love, Mikey."
[choir sings We Hear Angels]
Merry Christmas.
I think you're gonna
make that boy very happy.
- [doorbell rings]
- I'll get it.
[singing continues]
[whimpering]
[gasps]
Mom, Dad, look what Santa brought me!
[Eli] First stop: London, England.
[choir sings Season of Joy]
[bell ringing]
OK, Dad said the magic will make my paws
stick to the side of the chimney.
[Puppy Paws] Wish me luck!
[singing continues]
- Paris, France.
- [speaks French]
[choir sings in French]
Love your hat. Merry Christmas.
[Eli] Sydney, Australia, mate.
[singing continues]
Yo, nice bling, dawg.
Tokyo, Japan.
[choir singing in Japanese]
This place has great feng shui.
Very Zen.
The island of Jamaica.
[singing continues]
Hey, dude, gnarly dreads.
- [Eli] Mexico City.
- [man] Mexico.
[choir singing in Spanish]
Oh, sweet mama. Bean burritos!
[singing continues in English]
[sucking sound]
[gasps] Wow!
[speaks Spanish]
Fernfield, Washington.
[singing continues]
[all cheering]
Come on, Buddies!
I need all your help on this one.
[panting]
Oh!
[grunting]
[whimpering]
Puppy Paws? Buddies? Is that you?
- [all] Tiny?
- Yeah, it's us, Tiny.
What are you doing here?
My Christmas wish came true.
Mr. Cruge brought me to Mikey, my boy.
I'm so happy for you, Tiny.
This is the greatest Christmas ever.
Well, there's no reason
why we can't make it more special.
[gasping]
Wow! Thank you, Puppy Paws.
No, Tiny, thank you.
You taught us all how important it is
to believe in the Christmas spirit.
None of this would have been possible
if it wasn't for you.
I got my Christmas miracle
My Christmas miracle
This year
Hi, Tiny.
The icicle is back to full strength.
They've done it, Paws.
They've saved Christmas!
Let's round up the reindeer
and go get Puppy Paws.
That's it, Buddies.
That was our last delivery.
- We did it!
- Uh, dude?
How are you gonna get home
with no one to fly your sleigh?
Ho-ho-ho!
I think I've got a ride.
Whoa, Cupid! Whoa, Donner!
Whoa, Blitzen! Whoa!
Great work, pups!
The North Pole is back in business!
You did it, son. You saved Christmas.
I couldn't have done it
without the Buddies.
Indeed. Your teamwork tonight was most
certainly top of the nice list material.
Which is why, Buddies,
we at the North Pole
have decided to present to you
your very own, genuine Santa hats.
Merry Christmas, Buddies.
And there's one more thing.
- You earned this, son.
- Whoa!
You're one of us now, young pup.
And with you on our team,
I think it's pretty safe to say
that Christmas is going to be in very
good hands for a long time to come.
I'm proud of you.
Now say your goodbyes, Puppy Paws.
We've got to keep the spirit of
Christmas alive all year long.
Only 364 days 'til next Christmas!
I'm really gonna miss you guys.
Puppy Paws, you know how
you wanted to be an ordinary pup?
- Yeah?
- That's impossible.
You're too extraordinary to be ordinary.
I feel the same way about you, Buddies.
Thank you for making us true believers.
And for taking us
on a way cool adventure.
Best time ever!
All you can eat cookies and milk?
- Sign me up!
- Yo, Puppy Paws,
you are now officially
part of the B-Dawg Nation.
You now have four bros and one sis.
Maybe you Buddies
can lend a paw next year
as official Santa's Helpers.
What do you say?
- Yeah!
- Fo' shizzle!
- Now, Buddies,
you'd better get home to your kids.
You still have
some Christmas wishes to fulfill,
and we've got to get back
to the North Pole. Let's go, Paws!
[choir sings We Hear Angels]
- Merry Christmas, everybody.
- Merry Christmas!
Ho-ho-ho! On, Comet! On, Cupid!
On, Donner! On, Blitzen!
Now, Dasher! Now, Dancer!
Now, Prancer and Vixen!
Merry Christmas! Ho-ho-ho!
[Santa] Ho-ho-ho!
[singing continues]
[barking]
Budderball!
I've missed you so much!
[man] Hello?
Sorry to disturb you, but we were
wondering if you'd join us for dinner.
Oh, no, no. I wouldn't want to impose.
Besides, I've got
a lot of work to do here, you know.
But it's Christmas, sir.
Oh... I'll go grab my coat.
I'm starving.
Stan, thank you.
It's great to have you here.
Thank you for spending
Christmas with us.
[indistinct chatter]
Silent night
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
Round yon virgin
Mother and child
Holy infant
So tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly
Peace
[choir sings Season of Joy]