There is hurt
And there is pain
We are bound
And broken
There are none
Without to stay
Secret things
Unspoken
I have known
The heavy hand
I am scarred
And scattered
I have heard
The very ones
Oh really matter
Come on, put the cards in.
Boys.
Come on, batter up.
Let's go hide it.
Boys.
Get on out here.
Let's go.
Batter up.
Uh-huh. Where do you
think you're going?
Who going to be first?
I'll do it.
Yeah, you'd better.
Ah!
Strike one.
Strike three. You're out.
You're done, son.
Be a man.
Strike.
You're flinching.
Stay in there. Come on, let's go.
Ready?
Strike five.
That was way outside.
What are you swinging
at that for?
Come on, stay in there.
Strike seven.
Strike eight.
Strike nine.
Strike ten.
Stay in the box.
Strike eleven.
Strike twelve.
Stay there.
Strike thirteen.
I'll stay here all day, son.
Strike fourteen.
Strike fifteen.
You're watching it.
You stay there.
Strike sixteen.
Strike seventeen.
Ah.
Strike eighteen,
you little sissy.
You're going to cry now?
Is that what I'm seeing?
Strike nineteen.
Let's do this, Cory.
Good
afternoon, Grizzlies' fans.
Welcome to Grizzly Stadium.
And today's ballgame between
your Denford Grizzlies
and the Peninsula Pilots.
Today is Young Life day
at the ball park.
If a Grizzly hits a home
run during today's game,
Young Life will be presented
with a check for $10,000.
Let's go, guys.
Here we go, guys.
Good luck.
It's time, guys.
Go Grizzlies.
Hey, Cory.
Hey, Helene.
Heard you were chatting up with
Capano at the fundraiser last night.
Oh, come on, Helene, you're
the only girl for me.
I'd better be.
He had to be really drunk to think
that was a good deal. Please.
He'd eat his first born if it
meant signing a new player.
I don't think
I signed anything.
All right.
Don't forget. Home run today.
10K for Young Life.
Okay?
You think Cory will remember
that Carlos is down there?
No clue.
Or even who Carlos is?
I don't know.
Tough conditions for the hitters today.
Sun shining down brightly.
And when you've got guys like Chris
Ashman and Brett Stevens on the mound
it's not at all a surprise
that we have a scoreless game
with only five hits so far.
Cory Brand batting 3-79
leading the league.
And he appears to be a shoo-in for
another all-star game next month.
Hee-yah.
Open your eyes, Blue.
Cory's not
going to like that call.
It appeared to be high
and outside.
De Cruz gave Ashman
the call of strike one.
Strike two. Strike two.
That was way outside. What are
you swinging at that for?
You're going to your momma?
You need to go talk
to your momma now?
Get in the box.
Go, Cory.
Three.
And it gets away
from the left fielder.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
He's going to try to score.
Slides and safe.
That's what I'm talking about.
The Pilots are going
to appeal it.
And Cory Brand
has been called out.
What are you
talking about, Blue?
He storms out of the dugout,
and gets right in the face
of umpire Vic Cruz.
He's going to be thrown out
for slamming down the helmet.
And the replay shows he
clearly missed third base.
So, Cory Brand about to
give his team the lead.
Answer you, Blue.
Why don't you cool off?
You're like your brother
Blue over there?
How did you not see that
standing right there?
What are you talking about
I ain't touch base, huh?
Touched it now! There it is.
There it is.
Get out of my face.
Play ball.
And evidently the young bat
boy, he's the honorary bat.
Oh, my gosh.
Hey, what's going on, huh?
Doc, is he all right?
Not sure what exactly happened.
Is he okay? Can you see him?
I can't.
I'm on, I'm on. As Corey
Brand went into the dugout.
Oh, my gosh.
I think that's enough ice.
Your face is going to freeze.
Dad, I'm fine.
Oh, hey, babe. How are you doing?
He's all right.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
All right, all right.
Hey, guys.
I'm thinking about
sticking around.
What? Why?
I can't leave him like this.
What can you possibly do for him?
I don't know.
Just talk.
Find out what's up.
Hey, dude, can I
hold your icepack?
Just for a second, Tyler.
It's an official icepack.
Only players and people
on the team can use it.
And I need it.
Here, take it.
Dude, the whole stadium
was cheering for you.
I know.
I was like pshhh.
Oh, and then I went
like, oh, yeah.
He's the only brother I've got.
All right.
I love you.
I don't make it easy.
Whatever.
Hey, bro.
What's this, a reunion?
Why, did she tell you to come?
We should talk, Cory.
Talk about what?
What happened to you
out there today?
Showbiz, bro.
It's part of the game.
I talked to your trainer.
Said your blood alcohol was.
15.
Couldn't find my keys
in that condition,
let alone hit one
out of the park.
It's a gift.
What are you doing
talking to my trainer?
You need help, Cory.
Are we done here?
That kid you elbowed today?
That's my son.
Karen and I adopted him out of
foster care two months ago.
You'd know that if you
read an email or...
returned one of my calls.
I'm sorry.
Want to go grab
something to eat?
You got fat.
Kick your butt.
That's without
a personal trainer,
and I work for a living.
Yeah, what are you, mayor now?
District attorney.
Got my own parking spot.
And a bathroom key. Look
at you, fancy pants.
Congratulations.
How's Emma?
She's all right.
Been hard on her and Tyler
since James died overseas,
but she says she's glad
to be back in Okmulgee.
What do we say we
go get you a salad?
A salad?
Yeah.
No cheese.
Good morning,
Mr. Popular.
He's cute.
You've been suspended
for eight weeks.
Well, good morning to
you, too, Miss Sunshine.
Come here. I want to
show you something.
"Corey Brand
injures bat boy."
A million hits.
Already.
It was an accident.
Can we talk about
this later, please?
"Boozes it up in Vegas." 364,908 hits.
That was a good night.
"Drunk at a Strip Club."
217,402 hits.
You're a disaster. Yeah, well,
I'm a 3-27 career hitter.
"Cory Brand DUI Caught on Tape".
Over a million hits.
Yeah, it looks a little bad when you
put them all together, all right?
But there were a lot of sober
moments in between them.
You still got
that condo in Miami?
Floor is a little warped.
Popped the water bed.
Here's what you're going to do.
You're going to fly to Tulsa
and drive down to Okmulgee.
I'm not going to Okmulgee.
Oh, yes, you are.
You're going to Okmulgee
and make nice with the kid.
And then I'll arrange
a very public photo op.
The kid has a name. It's Carlos.
Carlos is going to get a bag
full of crap from the Grizzlies,
and a photo op
with a celebrity.
Then go chill on the beach in Miami
for eight weeks. Yeah, lucky me.
Plus, the Grizzlies want proof that
you're attending a 12-step program.
12-step? They want
you out of sight
until you've completed
eight weeks.
And last but not least,
you're writing a check
for $10,000 for Young Life,
for that homer you screwed up.
I'll see you in Tulsa.
Ladies and gentleman, welcome
to Tulsa international Airport.
Local time is 3:34 and the
temperature is 98 degrees.
Hey, you didn't have to waste so
much money renting such a fancy car.
Don't worry about it.
How do you even get in this thing?
It's got no handles.
We're here to help farm boy.
Oh, man, Mr. Arby's
forgot my curly fries.
Hey, don't make me
go back in there, okay?
That guys nearly cried
when I signed his hat.
He did not. A grown man.
There were tears.
Right.
Hey, don't forget the Arby's sauce.
I got it.
Oh, these are so good.
Come on, let's go.
Thank you, sir.
You satisfied?
Careful.
Were you
drinking on the plane?
Let's see what
this baby can do, huh?
No, let's not.
Let's.
Would you please slow down?
Woo-hoo.
Cory, look out.
So, my Little League team is
playing the Chiefs this week.
I'm going to start reading
for the Bulldogs.
We're going to run
them into the ground.
They're not going to
know what hit them.
Yeah, I love running
them into the ground.
Hey, go to the car. I need
to talk to this hot rod.
I don't care what your District
Attorney brother says.
I will put you in jail.
Hey.
There you are.
You better pray your brother can
keep this DU I under wraps.
You are now facing
a ton of fines
on top of what the Grizzlies
are going to give you.
What do you want me to do? You better
hope for a suspended sentence.
And could you just try to stay out of
trouble while I cover your butt, huh?
Oh, jeez, the kids are here.
What kids?
Stop when
you get inside.
My brother has a baseball team.
Your brother is the
kids' baseball coach?
Why don't you just shoot
Bambi next time, Cory? Jeez.
Cory Brand.
Game face, Cory.
Yeah.
Good evening, folks.
I'm Helene Landy.
Did you sustain any injuries.
What happened?
As I was saying, Mr. Brand
is happy to report
other than a few bumps and
bruises that he's doing okay.
Cory, how's your brother?
He's okay.
Clay Brand is resting comfortably
while sustaining some injuries.
What are we talking about? Cory, have
you been suspended by the Grizzlies?
Was there alcohol
involved in the accident?
There was a tractor
involved in the accident.
And... out of love
for his brother,
Mr. Brand has kindly offered
to stay here in Okmulgee
and take his brother's place as head
coach of the kids' baseball team.
Cory Brand's coaching kids' baseball?
That's right.
Lucky team. Do the parents know their
kids are going to have Cory as a coach?
Does this mean you're
moving to Okmulgee?
That's enough. As you can imagine,
Mr. Brand's had a long day.
We'll release a statement tomorrow following
the team's first practice. Thank you.
Cory, is the field going to be big enough for
all the crowds that are going to be there?
You are way out of
line this time.
No, you are, and I'm fixing it.
Dang, I'm good.
I'm not doing it.
Oh, that should be shelved.
It's on mine by now.
Next conversation?
Now, go see
about your poor brother
while I find you
a place to live.
Hey.
How's our guy doing?
He wants two minutes with you
and then I want you to leave.
Hey, buddy.
A bit early in the
day for a DU I.
I don't know what you're saying.
Don't-don't even try.
I did what I could
for you legally.
I never thought my baby bro
would be bailing me out.
I didn't bail you out.
I'll vouch for you.
Just don't go skipping town.
I'm back.
Just the look of those polyester
bedspreads make me itch.
Okay, kid, listen up.
I found you
a 12-step program.
There you go.
You couldn't find me
a normal program?
Well, it is normal.
It's just, um,
with Jesus.
I'm not doing church.
You're doing whatever it takes to
get your butt back on the roster.
Besides, it's the only
game in town.
Celebrate Recovery?
If your career recovers,
trust, I will celebrate.
Cheers.
Yeah, cheers.
Right.
All right.
Hey, hey, where are you going?
I'm staying at Tulsa.
I'll drive back tomorrow.
What for?
Apology to the kid,
press event.
The only reason we rode
into this one horse town.
Well, how am I supposed to get around?
You're a big boy. Figure it out yourself.
I'll see you
on the field tomorrow.
And if you're smart,
you'll come ready to coach.
Just remember, you're happy to
be doing this for your brother
and for the children.
Night.
Hey, is that your truck?
You want to rent it?
My truck? Five hundred
bucks for the month?
Okay.
What's your name?
Chad.
Hey, Chad, I'm going
to need those keys.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Thanks, man.
Cory Brand.
Yeah, I know.
Hey, Chad, you know, my
fridge in there is empty.
You know what I'm saying?
Um, I could fill it for you.
With dull beverages.
And to remember to keep filling
it with the dull beverages.
Thanks a lot, Chad.
Good afternoon, everyone. I want to thank
you guys so much for coming out today.
What's up, slugger?
Cory Brand.
Looks like you got
your nose on straight.
I am so sorry about that.
Oh, that's okay. Oh, we've
got some Grizzlies gear
that's got your name
written all over it.
Awesome.
Thanks.
Let's get that on straight for the pictures.
Okay, there we go.
Stan, that's Cory Brand.
No duh, Kendricks. It's all over
the Internet that he starts today.
Carlos, how about that
famous thumbs up sign?
Go Grizzlies.
Come here.
Get that camera right here.
Go Grizzlies.
Big smiles, big smiles.
Hey.
Are you ready?
He doesn't know yet?
I don't think so.
Oh.
Oh, please, Suzanne is here?
In heels.
She hasn't been here
all season.
I can't believe
you're our coach.
We need major help.
You'll see.
We're not even close to as
good as the Roughnecks.
They can hit the ball so far, like
as far as that building over there,
which is where you can
get the best ice cream.
Ah, it's ridiculous.
Come on, guys,
warm up, tickle up.
Oh, mom. Come on.
Do I get to call you coach?
Sure.
Okay, everyone. We are done here.
Thank you.
Cory, your suspension
hit the wires today.
Thank you, everyone.
Let's go.
Good luck, kid.
We'll see you around, Carlos.
Hey, Carlos, what's your
favorite ice cream flavor?
Vanilla.
Why are we always running?
This bites.
My dad says the Grizzlies
suspended Cory Brand.
Pejerski says he drinks
like a fish.
Fish don't actually drink.
They use their gills.
Wikipedia, give it a rest.
Who is that woman?
His agent.
Yeah, I got to go do this.
Okay.
Stomachache.
Breathe.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey,
where are you going?
Home.
We're so good.
I'll call you in a few days.
What am I supposed to be doing?
Start coaching.
Cory Brand.
Emma Johnson.
It's Hargrove.
I mean, it's-it's been Hargrove
for the last ten years.
Right, sorry.
I, uh...
Wow, it's good to see you.
Yeah.
Well, thanks for, thanks for coming
out here today. I appreciate it.
Um, I'm actually one of the
Bulldogs' other coaches.
Yeah.
Look, um, I know you're caught
up in some big PR mess,
but let's be real.
These parents are never going to
go for you coaching their kids.
The are salt-
of-the-earth people.
And you're pretty much just
a wild child felon to them.
Wild child felon or not, you
guys are short a coach.
Yeah, but we don't need you.
Here comes the truth. I mean,
they'll probably tell you
that they've got a volunteer
and you can be on your way.
Dan Stanton. I own the hardware
store and gas station.
Welcome home, Cory.
Cory Brand.
Greg Kendricks. It's
an honor to meet you.
We're thrilled
to have you here.
It's a real treat for these kids.
Not to mention us dads.
If you need anything, please
feel free to call the store.
Awesome. Thanks, guys.
That's great.
Right.
See you.
So... ready
to get started, Coach?
Look, these kids will like
you and you will leave them,
so keep your distance.
Third base is yours. It's
your only responsibility.
Mom, can we do something else?
It's so hot.
Tyler, you can't just walk over here.
It's just so hot.
Oh, hi, I'm Tyler. Hey, man.
Cory Brand.
Tyler, get back out there
with the rest of the team.
Okay.
Em, is that... Look, I'm begging
you, keep your distance.
Third base.
Everything looked fine
on the outside, but, uh,
inside it was a definite mess.
What started
as a private curiosity
became, uh, something
I couldn't stop.
Eventually, I was looking
at porn at work.
Until the day
two security officers
confiscated my computer and
escorted me out of the building.
They had every website and every
minute I spent looking at them,
logged right there
in black and white.
I've... never felt such
shame and embarrassment.
My porn addiction and my
unwillingness to face it,
led to the loss of my family,
my job,
and my self-worth.
Depression followed.
How is it going?
Good.
John Townsend.
Folks call me J .T.
Yes, my agent
told me to find you.
You're the one who's going to be
signing off all my paperwork.
Hey, listen, I think I landed
in the wrong room over there.
I'm just looking for, you
know, basic 12-step program.
I think I ended up
with the sex addicts.
Not that I'm judging. It's just...
You're in the right room. Just takes
a while to know it sometimes.
Here's how it works.
After the main meeting,
we break into small groups.
We call open share, where we talk about
anything from chemically dependent,
sexual addictions,
childhood abuse,
eating disorders and so on.
Huh. What if
you have them all?
If you have them all,
then one day at a time.
I'm the ministry leader, so if you
have any questions, concerns,
jokes you feel like
you need to tell,
I'm the one to talk to.
Uh, well, I think I'm going
to head back in there.
All right.
Good to meet you.
Yeah, I still can't believe people
are talking like that in church.
Good to have you, Cory.
Thanks.
But God changed everything.
He changed me.
Long story short.
My wife and I were reunited
in marriage last August.
Because of my time
in Celebrate Recovery,
I know how to run to God
and his people
when I need help.
And he does help me every time.
Thank you for letting me share.
Welcome to everyone
to open share.
I'm J .T. I'm a grateful
believer of Jesus.
I'm currently struggling
with alcoholism.
Hey, J .T.
My name is Rick,
and, uh, I'm a Christian.
And I'm struggling
with cocaine addiction.
Hi, Rick.
Oh, I'm Cory. Currently
struggling with my agent.
We're glad
you're here, Cory.
Hey, Coach.
What's up, slugger?
Hey, Tyler.
You guys ready to work hard today?
Yes, sir.
How weird is this for you.
Weird? Actually more like scary.
So, what are we
going to practice today?
Sliding? No, we need to
practice our batting.
We suck.
I mean stink.
Could always work on winning.
That'd be nice.
You're having any
feelings for him?
You can't be serious. Yeah, actually
I'm feeling that he's in my space
and he needs to go off to
his big far away life.
Hey, hey, Tyler. Tyler,
come check this out.
Your mum and Cory Brand were the
best couple in high school.
No way.
First comes love, then comes
marriage, then comes...
Mom, why didn't you tell me?
Tell you what?
Where did you get that?
My dad. Oh, really?
Remind me to thank him.
You know, I'm going to keep this
until after practice, okay?
Keep what? It's nothing.
Let's go.
What is it?
Nothing.
Let me see.
No.
It's our year book.
Yeah.
What do we go here, boys?
Look at how adorable you are.
Okay.
Hey, Coach, does this mean that
you and Coach Emma K-l-S-S-E-D?
Carlos.
Oh, you think you're
F-U-N-N-Y, don't you?
How about you get out on the field
for a K-I-C-K your B-U-T-T-Ses?
Let's go, boys.
You can keep that.
Okay.
All right,
let's go practice, guys.
Oh, my gosh.
Yeah.
Atta boy.
All right, Kendricks. Let's
go, let's bring our boy in.
Show us how it's done, girl.
Right. Time out, time out.
Kendricks, come here.
You're a leftie just like me.
You're two
steps closer to first base.
So lay down the right bunt.
But there's two outs.
Yeah, I know.
Trust me.
Think like a gazelle, huh?
Never look back.
All right, let's go, Kendricks.
Nice!
Nice bunt, Kendricks.
Nice job, Kendricks.
It's good.
Okay, when I touch my ear,
that's the indicator, all right?
We're going to slide,
we're going to steal,
we're going to work
on our double cuts.
Our pitch outs
and our infield shifts.
We're going to double
steal, hit and run,
and suicide squeeze.
We're going to fart in
some runs if we have to.
Give me two laps, and I'll see
you at the game on Saturday.
Let's go, Stanton.
That means you, too, buddy.
Play ball.
Come on, Caleb,
just like practice.
Let's go.
Hitting strikes, buddy.
Caleb, you need to step up in
the big boy jeans right now.
Start throwing strikes at this team.
They can't hit them.
It's the Bulldogs
for crying out loud.
Let's play ball.
Let's go, batter.
Look at me son. What did I tell you?
I said strike...
Nice work.
I will step into it.
I will pull you first thing.
Don't make me.
I won't tell you again.
Say yes, sir.
What do you say we
lighten up, huh, Coach?
And what do you say you play your
game, all right? That's my boy.
All right, Tyler, my man.
Let's go, buddy.
Come on now, we got two more.
I say now shore up that stance.
A little bit closer now.
That's okay, Tyler, you
stand wherever you want.
I know where that ball
is going to go.
Yeah, just don't step into it.
A little bit closer now, Tyler.
You stand wherever
feels right, baby.
Ball.
Look at me, son.
I'll call your sister.
I will call your sister.
I'll embarrass you in front of
everybody out here right now.
You understand me?
Son.
That's not what we
trained for, is it?
Now start throwing strikes at this team.
They can't hit them.
What? You questioning
my coaching?
Come on.
Strike one. See how
easy that was?
Hey, Coach, all day long.
All day long.
Come on, Caleb.
Strike two.
Caleb, two strikes.
You know that, right?
Can't hit a ball looking at it.
Swing at it.
Swing at the ball next time.
Step into play and swing at it.
Get your head in the game.
Strike three.
You're out.
Let's go.
Hey, son.
When I said get your head in the
game, I didn't mean miss the ball...
Get over and pick that bat up.
Pick that bat up.
Let me tell you something.
Sit down. You're benched.
You understand me?
What you say
we lighten it up, Coach.
I'll deal with you in a minute.
Sit down.
What did you just say to me?
Let's go, Bulldogs.
I said let's take it easy, coach.
Did you now?
Where do you think he learned
that kind of attitude from, Cory?
Hey, Dad! Shut up, son.
You sit down.
Watching idiots like you, Cory.
Cory Brand back in
town, aren't you?
You know what?
Let me smell.
Apple doesn't fall too far
from the tree now, does it?
You know what you are, Cory?
You're a showboat and you're a
drunk, just like your old man.
You are both out of here.
Thanks, Tony.
Nice going, Cory.
I wasn't drinking.
You weren't arrested
for drinking.
Hey, I stood up for that kid the way
no one stood up for me with Dad.
You're looking more
like him every day, Cory.
That's because I was
taking all your hits.
All my hits?
What do you think happened
after you left, huh?
You're not the only one that
grew up in that house, Cory.
Yeah, walk away.
That's what you do best, Cory.
What?
You're killing me.
Assaulted an officer?
It wasn't assault.
This is your lying low?
And uploaded photo
went from Facebook to...
Just fix it.
It might take a little effort,
but I'm sure you can handle it.
My name is Rick.
I'm a Christian.
I was struggling
with cocaine addiction.
Hi, Rick.
I came to CR not for
recovery from crack,
but to fake it so that
my wife and family
would get off my back.
I came every week,
I did all the lessons.
And to my surprise, I began
dealing with my past.
I started to
understand why I used.
No.
When I got to step nine,
make direct amends to the
people you have harmed,
I thought make amends
face to face?
I don't think so.
So, I skipped over that step.
After ushering for two years,
the temptation proved to be a
bit more than I could handle
and I started taking money
from the offering each week.
During this time, I was
in the second-step study,
and I-I wanted
to finally make the...
I needed to finally
make the amends
to the people in my life.
Which meant I had to confess
what I had been doing
to the ministry leaders.
And when I met with them, I...
I expected to be
relieved of my guilt.
I received so much more.
I experienced God's love
and forgiveness.
Now, to complete the step,
I need to make
amends with you also.
Because it's your
ministry, too.
And I stole from you,
and so I stand here
and I ask you
if you'll please forgive me.
The truth is, God forgave me
long before I came to CR but...
But I still felt broken
and I didn't know
how to fix it.
And then I got here and learned
verses like James 5:16
that told me if I confessed
my sins to someone,
I could be healed.
I still mess up.
I'm not who I was.
I'm changing.
I'm getting healed.
Thank you for letting me share.
I didn't even know
they made basketball cards.
Tommy.
Next limp.
More puzzle pieces.
Oh, I found Nick.
Steve.
I found Nick, too.
Hal Osberg.
Got it.
Cory Brand.
2001?
Oh, my gosh.
Are there any more?
Uh, just the one.
Dang it.
You can have it. He busted
me on the nose, so.
I think it's bad
luck or something.
Are you bringing it to the game?
Oh, I don't know.
Come on, you got to
bring it to the game.
Yeah, I just don't
want to bother him.
He signed it. This could be...
Fifty cents.
You didn't bring enough money?
This should do it.
If he signs it, this
could be worth a ton.
We are going to be rich.
Bulldogs, huddle up!
Now, come on.
How about some new uniforms?
Grab some hats.
Tyler.
Yes?
That's my number right there.
That's you, buddy.
Way cooler
than the Roughnecks now.
Who needs some shoes?
Kendricks.
New Nike's for you.
Here you go, slugger.
Size eight.
Hey, guys, what do you say?
Thanks, Coach Cory.
All right, we got to win now
'cause we're
looking good, right?
Okay.
Let's go, Bulldogs.
Go, go home.
Come on.
All right, Kendricks,
let's go, let's go.
Good job, Bulldogs.
Nice, nice.
Good work, good work.
Atta boy.
Atta boy, Carlos.
Huh?
Syd.
Come on, let's get them.
All right, Tyler, come on now.
The winning run is on second.
That's it, buddy.
Step up in there.
Come on.
Time.
Tyler, come here.
Tyler, look at me.
How many years
you been playing ball?
Five.
All right.
How many hits you got before
you took one in the face?
I don't know.
Fifteen, twenty?
Yeah.
Fifty, sixty?
Probably.
All right.
So, what do you think the chances
are of getting hit today?
Probably not
going to happen, huh?
Probably not.
Okay.
Get back in there, step up
to the plate, hit the ball.
Okay.
All right.
Tyler.
Nothing great happens
when you hold back.
Let's go.
Come on.
There it is! Yes!
Carlos, go.
Go!
Yes!
Nice job. Nice play, son.
Bring it in, bring it in.
Where's Tyler?
Tyler!
Hey. That's what I'm talking about.
Stepping up to the plate.
Nice hit.
How about that, huh?
Great win today, guys.
Thanks, Coach.
Come on, Carlos.
Awesome game, Coach.
See you later.
Awesome base running, Carlos.
Thanks, Coach. Couldn't
have done it without you.
Come one now. We couldn't have
done it without you, Tyler.
Great job.
Thanks.
Nice game.
Yeah, we made quite the
team out there, didn't we?
How about we
grab some pizza?
Yeah.
No.
Come on, Mom. No, I'm sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
I've got, uh, you know,
we've got a thing.
Yeah.
Have fun at your thing.
Cory.
J .T.
You, uh, have plans tonight?
Yeah, you know,
some ESPN, little ESPN.
Probably some ESPN after that.
Nah, I don't have
any plans tonight.
You want plans?
Sure.
Pick you at your
motel around 6:00?
Six o'clock.
See you then, right?
Don't be late.
It's going to be fun.
It sounds like it.
In a effort to
earn the money you pay me,
I scored you a national television
interview this Saturday.
Well, well, well, so nice
of you to finally call me.
With the all-star vote coming up, we
need to get you back in the public eye
looking clean and sober.
Get people to fall
in love with you again.
Oh, please, they've
always loved me.
Ha. That's because I remind
them how much they do love you.
Okay, fine.
Book it.
Let's get me seen.
Done.
Hey, J .T.,
I'll be right back.
So, this is your thing.
Not very hospitable of
you, Emma Hargrove,
to not tell
a poor stranded fool
about the Wild West Chili Fest.
Fool, yes.
Stranded, never.
You get your
Ferris wheel on, yet?
You're missing life in the
fast lane, aren't you?
Yes and no.
Beating the Jets today, that was,
that was a new all-time high for me.
You're right about Tyler.
He just needed to be pushed.
I get, uh, I get
too caught up...
You're a great mom.
He's a great kid.
He is.
Hey, dude, it's Coach. Come on.
Coach. What's up, guys?
Hey, Coach, we found a rookie
card today at the store.
We were wondering if you
could sign it. Sure.
I didn't know you guys
collected baseball cards.
Oh, yeah.
All the time.
I got some really cool
ones back in the barn.
Seventy-three Passy,
Ninety-three Begonus.
I have Passy and Begonus, too.
Yeah? Well, we should get together
and compare cards some time.
Maybe after this we can go back
to the barn and check them out.
Oh, come on, come on, please.
Okay, sure.
Yes.
Tug O' War.
To one of the best
nights of my life.
I'm glad you found
a thing tonight.
Good old Oklahoma.
Wait till you see
this, guys, huh?
How cool is this.
Whoa.
How cool, right?
Oh, sweet.
All right.
Who's this?
Dad. Your dad played ball?
That's your dad?
Yeah, he was a great player.
He never made it
past AA, though.
Come on,
where are they, Cory?
Where's the box?
Where's the box, huh?
It's not in here. It's a small wooden
box, guys, with a metal latch.
All the important
ones are in it, huh?
it's got to be here.
They're gone.
I can't believe it!
He must have sold them.
That drunk!
Oh.
What's going on? Look, I just
wanted to show the kids, all right?
Okay, boys, come on. Get on back to the house, okay?
No, no, it's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
Yeah, right.
What is the matter with you?
In front of the kids?
Stay out of it, Karen.
No one's touched your precious
stuff in years, Cory.
Look, he did, okay? He always messed things up.
He always screwed everything up.
You can't keep playing the victim.
It doesn't work.
What do you know
about my life, huh?
What do you know about
anything for that matter?
You're just some sheltered
Sunday school teacher,
so spare me the lecture
until you've lived
through something
a little more stressful
than your kitchen sink
backing up.
I don't want to hear it.
Let's go.
Okay, kiddo.
Lights out.
Good night.
Night.
Love you.
Love you, too.
Hey.
What's this?
I know, sort of
impulsive, but, uh,
I wanted to give her to Tyler.
What?
Ls that a dog?
All yours, sport.
She's mine?
No. Look, it's all there.
Training crate, food, leash.
What are you doing?
You can't just come over
here and give my son a dog.
I wanted to apologize
for last night.
By heaping a ridiculous
responsibility on him and me?
Come on, Mom. Can't we keep him?
Tyler, we're not keeping the dog.
That figures, you always say no.
Every kid should have a dog.
You don't get to have a say in
what he should or shouldn't have.
Look, this whole thing
is so not okay.
You have to go, and take your dog.
Tyler.
Come on.
Hi. My name is Karen.
Hi, Karen.
And I'm a grateful
believer in Jesus.
I Celebrate Recovery from
sexual abuse by my father
from the time I turned
eight until I was sixteen.
While going through these
experiences I felt alone,
with no one to reach out to,
not one person to tell.
My whole life I had carried the
pain, burden and shame for my past.
Even though I've been
a Christian for years,
I hid my pain and shame
from everyone I knew.
When I-when
I learned as an adult
that I would not be able to
bear children of my own,
this was the final blow.
I felt completely
abandoned by God.
When I attended
Celebrate Recovery,
I wasn't prepared to experience
the freedom and relief
I would gain by sharing my
deep hurt with God and others.
I love that I don't have
to hide who I am here.
I can go to my step
study and share openly
without the fear
of being judged.
I'm just me.
Banged up and imperfect.
Because of the work of Jesus, I'm
no longer living my life in shame.
Thank you for letting me share.
Go.
Run, run.
Run!
You're running on.
All right, Bulldogs.
Hey. Why aren't you in the limo?
Why aren't you on your way to Tulsa?
Any of this ringing a bell?
Yeah, hey, about that,
we need to reschedule.
I am about to blow an artery if you
just said what I think you just said.
No, I'm serious,
we need to reschedule.
You are not missing
this interview.
The Grizzlies just brought
up a kid from the Springs,
and this kid is good, Cory.
And guess what?
He's not a pain in the butt.
You will not say no.
No, all right? I'm not
missing my son's game.
Your son? Is this some kind
of line from Green Acres?
No, it's not, Helene,
all right?
My son's on the Little League
team and I'm his coach.
Got to go.
I'm going to kill him.
Everything okay? Yeah, I just forgot
I had this TV interview scheduled.
Oh, you should go.
No, I already told my agent.
Forget it, it's done,
it's over, too late.
Seriously, Cory, it's your career.
Go.
Believe it or not,
we can handle it.
No, no, I'm staying.
Come on, we got a game to win, coach.
Let's go.
What's up, Bulldogs?
Huh?
High fives.
Hey, Kendricks.
What's up, Coach?
Nice day, huh?
Yeah.
Great breeze.
How's your parents?
Fine.
The pitcher is nervous.
Second baseman
has got a weak arm.
Let's shake things up, huh?
You know what I'm saying?
Stanton, was that you?
Trying to fart in the run.
You still see that play? Yeah.
Run, Kendricks.
Don't throw it.
On the go!
Don't throw it!
Go.
Go, Will, go. Go.
Go home!
Yes!
There it is. Let's
go, let's go, let's go.
Nice job, Bulldogs.
What's up? We won. Nice.
What were we training for
all week?
Are you kidding me, guys?
Woo!
Bulldogs!
Get on the bus. Take
your stuff and let's go.
All right, buddy.
Yeah.
Huh, that's quite a win.
It's so good.
Watch your hands.
Coach.
You got rubbed. It's not an
all-star team unless you're on it.
What are you
talking about, buddy?
How's the National League going
to win if you're not on the team?
Come on, let's go, son.
See you, Coach.
All right, buddy.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine. I just... forgot
that news came out today.
All right,
I'm going to head out.
See you, Coach.
Good game, Tyler.
Thanks.
It's going.
It's gone.
See you.
It's going.
It's back.
Foul ball.
Cory.
What are you doing?
Hey. Well, I was just wondering
how you were doing after
the all-star news but I...
Well, I see that you're
the same as always.
I didn't get the vote.
No, yeah, I know.
I was upset.
My career is in the gutter.
I'm out here wasting my time.
Well, I'm sure it's very
disappointing for you.
But then, adults cope with
disappointment all the time.
Ask me how I know. I know,
I know I disappointed you.
All right? I didn't just leave
to go play baseball, you know?
Being a father scared
the crap out of me.
But I've changed, Emma.
Clearly.
Wait, Emma.
Emma, stop.
I want to be his father.
Really?
Really you want to be his father, Cory?
Yes, I do.
It takes courage
to be a parent.
It is sheer bravery
to love a child.
To be there for them,
to care for them,
to love them
when they push you away.
It takes courage to put
your dreams on hold.
To juggle your own heartache
and disappointments.
And just when you think that you
might be getting the hang of things,
you lose your husband.
So, now you have no choice
but to just pull it together
and care for the most precious,
the most amazing person
you have ever known.
Parenting is not
for cowards, Cory.
You ran before.
You'll run again.
It was a mistake, all right?
A huge mistake.
The old man said I'd end up
resenting you and the kid
the way he resented having me.
He told me I'd screw
up the baby's life.
And I believed him, okay?
I believed him.
So, your only choice
was to just write us off?
I didn't write you off, okay?
You went off and got married.
Whatever's broken in you, Cory,
whatever your dad did or
didn't do, I can't fix it.
Neither can Tyler.
That hurt inside you
is going to hurt Tyler.
It already has.
He needs a father.
Well, he had a father.
But he died.
And James is the only person that
was there for us when you left.
And that amazing, unselfish man
is the only father
Tyler has ever known.
And for now
that is how it stays.
Strike six.
You're standing there
watching it.
Let me see something
out of you for once.
Strike nine.
Come on. Come on, stay in there.
Get your elbow up.
You can't hit it like that.
Strike ten.
Come on, you little sissy.
Stand up.
Go on, go get it.
You going to cry now?
Ls that what I'm seeing?
You're going to stand
there and cry?
You know, I-I-I first
thought that, you know,
Meth could be
like a-like a fun thing,
and I could-I could
stop any time,
but, you know, I wouldn't
tweak or nothing,
but... coming, coming
down was hard.
And, uh, I just...
I had to have it.
I stole from my grandma's
purse to get it.
I couldn't stop.
So, I started, you know,
going through these questions.
I-I-I forced myself to answer
these questions, you know.
L-I-l found out
why I used.
And I still, I still struggle.
But I don't feel, I don't
feel hopeless any more.
I...
It's getting better.
I can... I can feel
myself changing.
That, that's...
Thanks for sharing.
Hey, Cory.
This is your eighth week.
Huh.
Seems so official.
Thanks.
Yeah.
See you man. Hey,
you know, it's, uh,
it's your last mandatory meeting
but we hope you keep coming back.
Yeah, all right.
It's been good.
Congratulations.
Thanks, thanks.
Looky there.
Hey there, boys.
Oh. Hi, Officer Pajersky. Hi, Coach.
Officer Pajersky.
Mm-hm. What are you chewing on?
Gum.
Paid for it?
Yes, sir.
Some game you guys
played the other night.
Thanks.
You know we're coming
after you next year.
I'll see you, Coach.
Dude, should we go to my house?
Hold up there, Tyler.
Looks like you got a new daddy.
What?
You boys be good.
"Cory Brand
puts family first."
Hey, is that you?
Coach Cory is your dad?
Hey, where have you been?
I left you like six messages.
I got my walking papers.
I'm good to go.
Yeah, hey, I only got a minute.
I've got some bad news.
You're free-agent now. You've been released.
What are you talking about?
Well, it turns out they didn't miss
you that much these past two months.
Cory, you're too much trouble.
Look, it's cool.
I've made some calls...
Hello?
Hey, girl.
Yeah, let me ask. Hold on,
I'm just getting inside.
Hey, babe.
Have you seen Tyler?
Um...
Let me call you back.
Come here.
Tyler.
What are you doing here, Tyler?
Hey, what are you
doing here, sport?
Get in the car, Tyler.
Tyler, get in the car.
Em.
You had no right.
I can't believe you used us like this.
Tyler, get in the car.
Mom, no.
Tyler.
No.
Are you my dad?
I have your cards.
Your dad gave them to me.
He used to mow our lawn.
I didn't know they were yours.
Tyler.
I'm sorry.
Get in the car.
You lied to me.
Got your message.
I can't stop.
I can't make myself stop.
I know.
The first step
is the most important.
Reminding us to surrender
to Christ only.
If you've identified a new area that
you'd like to surrender to Christ
or if you've relapsed
and you're coming back,
I hope you'll come
forward today
and remember
this surrender day.
Now please stand
for the serenity prayer.
God, bring me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
the courage to change
the things I can,
and the wisdom
to know the difference,
living one day at a time,
enjoying one moment at a time.
Accepting hardship
as a pathway to peace.
Taking as Jesus did the
sinful world as it is,
not as I would have it.
Trusting that you
will make all things right
if I surrender to your will.
So that I may be reasonably
happy in this life
and supremely happy with
you forever in the next.
Amen.
My father's work took him away
from us most of the time.
And my stay-at-home mother was
verbally and psychologically abusive.
As a child,
I lived in a constant
state of fear.
I believed in God,
but I had this warped
sense of who he was.
And I couldn't trust him.
Life, for me,
was performance based.
But,
after going
through my step study,
I now believe
that God is a loving father.
He's not waiting to send me to
hell for every mistake I make.
No matter what my childhood
experiences has taught me,
I am valuable because
I'm a child of God.
I'm Cory.
And I'm a new believer
in Jesus Christ.
And I struggle with alcoholism.
Hi, Cory.
Glad you're here.
Oh, come on, you guys,
this is pathetic.
You got to at least try.
Hey.
This is like that movie where
the lady leaves the children
and then it's not fun
for them anymore.
Hey! What's that movie called, the one
with the nun and the singing children?
The Sound of Music?
Yeah.
This is just like
The Sound of Music.
Except it's not fun anymore
without Coach Cory.
You're killing me, Carlos.
Hi.
Hey, girl.
Sorry I'm kind of
popping in unannounced.
That's okay.
You want to come in?
Uh, is Tyler here?
He's around here somewhere.
Let's go out here.
Uh, Tyler called Clay
asking if we would convince you to
let him go to the ballgame tomorrow.
Oh, he called you?
I'm so sorry.
Absolutely not.
Look, no, I really appreciate
that Clay and Cory
worked out
some stuff this year,
and that your family
is doing better.
No, I'm just not there, yet.
Emma... Karen,
people don't change.
Look, honey, I love you,
but the only person who's not
changing around here is you.
Mom.
All I could say is just
taking it one day at a time.
I'm in Tulsa now, and just folks
are now doing a good job.
Would you excuse me? I've got
some really important guests.
Thank you.
Hey, what's up, guys?
Huh? Bring it in.
How's practice, huh?
Hi, Cory.
You look great.
Good to see you. Yeah?
Good to see you, guys.
How are you? I'm good. I'm good.
They make it?
No.
Yeah, it's all right.
Did you say anything about the
Bulldogs to those reporters?
Don't be stupid, Carlos.
Okay, look, we do get that station.
Yeah.
You get a player's
discount at the gift shop?
I think so. Yeah, we can
work something out.
What do you say
we hit some balls?
I can introduce you
to the team.
All right, let's go.
Good idea.
Get out of here.
Batter up, you little sissy.
Get your hands
together on the bat.
Stand in the box.
Five minutes.
Cory Brand.
This boy belong to you?
Let me call you right back.
He sure does. What's up, buddy?
Huh?
I'm sorry we missed your game.
How have you been?
Good.
Hi.
Hey.
How you been?
Good.
You look good.
Thanks.
So great to see you, guys.
You look great.
Thank you.
You guys have some time?
Yes, please.
Please, please, please.
Yes, we do.
You want to see the field? Yeah.
Huh?
So, what do you think?
Can you pop one
over that fence?
No. Oh, I bet you could.
No, I couldn't.
One day.
How is Coach Clay
treating you guys?
Good.
Yeah?
You guys beat the Roughnecks?
Yeah.
That's what I'm talking about.
Coach Pajersky wasn't really happy.
I bet he wasn't.
Time to go.
Oh, come on, Mom.
Come on, let's
bring it in, sport.
Hey, Tyler, come here.
What is it?
I got something for you.
You sure you want me to have it?
Belongs to you now.
Emma.
Thanks for coming.
Sure.
Hey, listen, there's, uh...
There's nothing I can do to
make up for what I've done.
For what I put you through.
And Tyler.
I'm sorry.
I'm so, so sorry, Emma.
And I hope you can forgive me.
Listen, I'm...
I'm not asking
for anything, okay?
But,
I want you to know
I love this family.
I believe in this family and I
want to be a part of it as much
or as little
as you'll let me be.
Yeah.
Mom?
Hm?
Nothing great happens
when you hold back.
Cory.
You hungry?
Yeah.
Let's go.
I have left The battle lines
There's a hope
That lies In front of me
I've discovered Who I am
And I found
I was
The enemy
I have struggled
For so long
I lay it down
I give it up
I'm letting go
Of this war I've always known
I wave the flag
I humbly fall
On my knees
I have tried To do it all
On my own
I surrender
I've used
alcohol my entire life
to replace the love
and attention
I never received
from my father.
But every drop of alcohol,
every drop,
every one night stand,
would never replace
the ache inside of me.
An ache that only
God could fill.
I tried to change.
But I failed every time.
And I know now that I'm
powerless without God.
But with his help,
I found a freedom
from my pain and my habits
that I never thought
was possible.
My family has suffered
for generations.
And I suffered because
of my father's pain.
And my father suffered because
of his father's pain.
But this is how it changes.
This is where it changes.
And today I begin a new story.
I'm a child of God.
And I have a father
who loves me.
On and off the baseball field.
Thank you for letting me share.
Another dream Passes through
The night
Through the night
Another night Cried
yourself To sleep
Mmmm
I'm thinking It's
over now This time
This time
I'm wishing It's
over now This time
I'm thinking It's over
Yeah I'm thinking It's over
but now it's your time
To change your life
Yeah
And this is Your moment
This is Your moment
To change Your life
And this is Your moment
This is Your moment