Hi, sweetie.
Um, where are you guys?
Call me when you get this.
Hi, it's me again.
Your cell's going straight
to voicemail.
Hope everything's okay.
Please call.
Sara.
A- are you there?
Please, pick up, sweetie.
Sara.
Hello!
- Sara...
- Frank...
And Adam
aren't here at the moment.
But please leave your name
and number after the beep.
Hi, sweetie.
Hope your date night went well.
We had a fun night here.
Adam loves watching
all the cars
passing by the condo.
Listen, I called
my doctor friend,
and she's not sure if Adam's
getting enough protein.
He looks very pale.
And hardly any baby fat.
Oh, by the way,
I tried calling your cell,
but I kept getting
a busy signal.
It's probably bad reception.
Oh, sweetie, we really miss you.
I hope you can stay for lunch
when you come to pick up Adam
tomorrow morning.
I know your father will want
to spend time with his daughter.
Anyway, give me a call
when you get home
if it's not too late, okay?
Love you.
Can't wait to see you, honey.
Here's my two favorite people
in the whole, wide world.
- Look, Adam, it's daddy.
- Say hi to daddy!
Adam, baby,
can you say "da-da"?
Da-da?
And here's my gorgeous wife.
Aw.
Those beautiful eyes
I wake up to every sing...
Hello!
- Sara...
- Frank...
And Adam
aren't here at the moment.
But please leave your name
and number after the beep.
Sara Mcandrews,
this is deputy Sanders calling
from the county sherriff's
office.
I got your message.
My apologies for calling
so late.
It's been one of those days,
and we're severely understaffed.
So regarding this trespasser
you saw on your property
this morning,
rest assured,
you have nothing to worry about.
It's probably just a drifter
passing through.
In any case,
I'll drop by tomorrow,
make sure everything's
all right, and...
Well, I'll have one
of those delicious brownies
that everyone's
been talking about.
We're here for your safety,
okay?
Hope you folks have
a great night.
- Hey, honey.
- What?
You know, next time we go out,
would you mind just leaving
one light on?
No, it's supposed to look
like we're home.
Yeah, but, like, we didn't
move in to a lighthouse.
- Yeah, you're funny.
- Such a jokester.
- Am I?
- Yeah.
I'm not as funny
as whatever you want to call
that dance thing thing
you made me sit through.
What was that?
It was awful.
Oh, come on.
It wasn't that bad.
- It was horrible.
- What?
Are you always this difficult?
No, I thought it was really
beautiful, and...
- You are a philistine,
you know that?
It involves a lot more skill
than one of your football games.
As in, a gaggle
of hairless men
running around,
rolling on top of one another,
on a large steel table...
Yeah, exactly.
Naked, hairless men?
No, men taken over
by the spirit of dance.
- And they weren't all hairless.
- Ugh, please.
Now I can't eat
in the cafeteria anymore.
Why?
Because they just installed
the exact same kind of table.
Oh, no.
I'm gonna be obsessing
over every little stain
on the thing.
Well, maybe
in between meetings,
you and Tony can try it out.
You two would make
a terrific duo.
Oh, God.
I'd definitely pay
to see that.
You guys would probably draw
quite the crowd
if we didn't live
in the middle of nowhere.
Sweetheart, you know...
Our son's gonna thank you
for it later.
He'll tell you
in his deep, manly voice...
He'll say, "thanks, ma.
"Thanks for following pa
to the countryside.
"I'm a lucky boy, you know?
"I can see that now.
I learned
what it was like to"...
Live like a peasant.
"To breath the fresh air,
"you know, to ride my bike
in the forest,
"to be able to practice
my football skills
"in my huge backyard
without being bothered
by the riffraff from your old
disgusting neighborhood. "
- Mm.
- Hey.
Nothing beats a real home.
Now, what do you say to that,
city girl?
- Mm.
- Hmm?
I say that I need
a glass of milk.
All right.
Whoops.
- Honey, could you please check
the messages?
Two new messages.
Hi, sweetie.
Hope your date night went well.
We had a fun night.
Oh, Adam loves watching
all the cars
passing by the condo.
Listen, I called
my doctor friend...
Sure you did.
And she's not sure if Adam's
getting enough protein.
He looks very pale.
And hardly any baby fat.
Oh, by the way,
I tried calling your cell,
but I kept getting
a busy signal.
It's probably bad reception.
Oh, sweetie, we really miss you.
I hope you can stay for lunch
when you come to pick up Adam
tomorrow morning.
I know your father will want
to spend time with his daughter.
Anyway, give me a call
when you get home
if it's not too late, okay?
Critters.
- Love you.
Can't wait to see you, honey.
What am I, chopped liver?
Sara Mcandrews,
this is deputy Sanders calling
from the county sherriff's
office.
I got your message.
My apologies for calling
so late...
You know...
S- she can't help herself,
can she, right?
She has to find something
to worry about.
No, she is the one
that needs to see a doctor,
'cause she always wants us
to feel guilty
or worried about something.
You know, but I...
I know exactly
what she's trying to do.
She can't stand
that her little angel
is now independent
and so far away from her.
You know, t-tomorrow...
Mm.
Tomorrow, tomorrow, tomorrow.
Tonight is just you and me...
- Mm-hmm.
Alone.
So why don't you stop talking?
- Mmm.
Honey.
What?
I have a surprise for you.
What's her name?
Seriously?
Why don't you go serve me
something to drink
instead of being such a perv.
What are you doing?
- I just want to make sure
he's okay.
She said he was fine, baby.
Don't worry so much.
I'm your baby tonight.
Baby, I really have
to have a shower.
So why don't you just stay here
and maintain your concentration?
Can I spy on you
in the shower?
Don't even think about it.
I know she will
I'm sure she will
Oh, yes she will
Critters?
When I put my arms
kitty.
Arms around her
You hear her holler
You hear her moan
I know she will
whoa, yes she will
critters.
Critters, come here.
Ooh.
Good little baby.
Are you pouting?
I'm sure she will
Let me come back home
I know she will
I'm sure she will
Frank.
Hello?
- Hi, mom.
- Did I wake you?
- Oh, no, honey, hi.
- I'm up.
So how's Adam?
Sleeping like a baby.
Home late
oh, I just may
I don't understand
why we're always having
this conversation.
Did you call the police?
Yes.
I left a message for the
sherriff. Left a message?
What kind of godforsaken place
did you move to?
Listen, make sure
the doors are locked.
- Yep, they are locked,
and all of the lights are on.
- And how about that husband
of yours?
Is he doing anything
about it?
What is that supposed to mean?
Well, he's your husband,
isn't he?
- Look, mom, he is doing
the best that he can.
You know what?
It's probably nothing.
I'm not even sure
that I saw what I saw.
Honey, if you don't feel safe
over there,
you'll always have a place here.
You can stay with us as long
as you like, okay?
Okay.
I've been really tired lately,
so I'm gonna go and sleep
for 100 years.
Oh, you do that,
sleeping beauty.
I'll see you tomorrow morning.
Mm-hmm.
Give Adam a kiss for me.
- Don't worry.
I will.
Sweet dreams, darling.
Love you.
Night.
I know she will
Oh, yes she will
Let me come back home
- glad to know
I can still surprise you.
Well, I didn't hear you.
A votre service, madame.
Oh.
Wow, I didn't realize
the waiters around here
had such casual uniforms.
Well, you know,
it helps me maintain
my concentration.
Mm.
Oh, and by the way,
is it possible
that my surprise is waiting
in the bedroom?
You little shit.
You're gonna totally ruin
your surprise.
- Come on.
- Come here.
No.
- Oh, just give me one kiss.
- No.
- I deserve it.
- Mm-mm.
Get lost. - Let
me come in. - Go.
- Oh, I get it.
- I get it.
You need to practice, uh,
your choreography, right?
Okay, just remember that it's
f- r-a-n-k.
That's really funny, babe.
- I'm gonna go out
in the living room
and rearrange the furniture,
okay?
You know, I'm gonna move things
around.
I'll see you soon, kitten.
Everywhere I go
Yeah, everywhere I go
I see that same old 158
I know I'm billed out, baby
Whoo, lord
Uncle Sam say,
"bill, don't be late"
Yes, I've got
my questionnaire, babe
And I found that
old number of mine
Now
I guess I well
to start moving
Ooh, baby
There ain't no need
of crying
All you young men
I mean, come on
and follow me
Yes, all you young men
go away.
Go away.
Lord, Whoo
Lord, now, boys,
why can't we?
I had a woman
I had a broken heart
Even though I wish
she'd tell me
What that woman left me for
That's what I been wonderin'
I been wonderin'
all day long
Maybe I will have
to wonder on
And I'll try
To make me feel good
Say my gal would be good
If she just only
understood...
Understood...
What the fuck?
S- Sara.
Can you turn the music
back on, honey?
Frank.
Ugh...
Better not be asleep.
Aah.
Oh, shit.
Critters.
Frank?
Honey?
Frank!
Why are you doing this to us?
What did you do to my husband?
I'm sorry.
I'll calm down.
I promise.
Where's my husband?
I want to see him.
Please.
Let me see my husband.
Frank!
What the fuck do you want
with us?
You fucking psycho!
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
What did you do to my husband?
Shh.
Mr. Mcandrews?
M.T.S. Security.
Are you there?
Hello?
Mr. Mcandrews?
The silent alarm was activated.
Mr...
Mr. Mcandrews, can you hear me?
I just stopped by to check
and make sure everything's okay.
Hello?
Anybody home?
Mr. Mcandrews!
I can see your lights are on.
Are you home?
Yeah, I am missing
the end of the game for this.
Mr. Mcandrews!
- Good evening, Mr. Mcandrews.
- M.T.S. Security here.
Yeah, your silent alarm
was activated,
and I am currently
on the premises...
At your door, actually.
Yeah, well, I've checked
around the house,
and everything seems fine.
I will have to notify
the local police, however.
That's a standard procedure
whenever we're called out
for no good reason, so...
If you could please get in touch
with us.
You go ahead and have yourself
a good evening...
Wherever you are, asshole.
Wait.
You have reached the king
county sheriff's department.
All deputies
are currently on patrol.
Please,
somebody's in my house.
He's trying to kill me.
Please hold as we attempt
to transfer your call
to the officer on duty.
Are you fucking serious?
555-8699.
Deputy Sanders here.
- Hello?
- Hello.
Hello, this is Sara,
Sara Mcandrews.
Oh, hey, Mrs. Mcandrews.
I don't know
if you got my message earlier...
He's in the house.
'Scuse me?
He's in my house.
Say again.
Someone here is
trying to kill me.
- I'm sorry.
- Ma'am, try to remain calm.
Who is trying to kill you?
- I don't know.
A fucking psycho.
Mcandrews, are you able
to get somewhere safe?
He's blocked out
all the exits.
I don't know if we can get out.
He's gonna find me.
Miss Mcandrews,
I need you to tell me
exactly where you are.
Where is your family?
Frank is dead.
- All right.
- I'm on my way, ma'am.
Gonna die.
- Are you in a safe place,
Mrs. Mcandrews?
I can't hear you...
Speak up.
Hello?
Fuck!
Here's my two favorite people
in the whole, wide world.
- Look at him!
- It's daddy!
Say hi to daddy! Adam,
baby, can you say, "da-da"?
Da-da?
Here's my gorgeous wife.
Aw.
Those beautiful eyes
I wake up to
every single morning.
I am the luckiest man.
I love you, baby girl.
I love you more.
I want you.
- Let me know if...
- It is.
Turn it off.
Turn off the camera.
Here's my two favorite people
in the whole, wide world.
- Look at him!
- It's daddy!
Say hi to daddy!
Aah!
Leave me alone!
Go away!
Stop it!
Please.
I called the police!
I called the police.
I had a lovely time.
You have reached the king
county sheriff's department.
All deputies
are currently on patrol.
Please hold as we attempt
to transfer your call
to the officer on duty.
For all medical emergencies,
dial 555-8699.
Sanders.
It's Sanders.
Michael...
I been...
I been shot.
I went to Mcandrews house.
You got to get out here.
We got two victims down.
It's a husband and wife.
Get an ambulance out here
right away.
The perpetrator's male.
6'1".
I'm the night watchman
And I don't be seen
in the day
I'm the night watchman
And I don't be seen
in the day
I declare
I do my work at night
Whoo, lord, and I declare
I'm happy and gay
'round factories
and saw mills
Babe, you'll always see
me there
Yeah, baby
I declare
you'll always see me there
Now, don't be scared
to call me
Whoo, lord, gal, I got plenty
of time to spare
I'm known in this country
To be the best
night watchman in town
Mmm
I declare I'm the best
night watchman in town
Now, if you'll clock me
punch in
Whoo, lord I'll punch in
on my next go round
I've got
a lot of competition
Baby, but I can't lose
Yeah, lot of competition
No, but I declare
I can't lose
I know I've got to win
Whoo, lord, I declare
with this key I use
I makes it around
Yo my clocks, baby,
every night
I makes it around
I'm mean to my clocks
every night
I declare I love
to punch clocks, baby
Whoo, lord, when the moon
is shining bright