I'm ready.
We can stop here.
- Let's carry on.
- As you wish.
I brought music,
or do you have your own?
- Yes, here.
- Sit next to me.
I'll leave you alone now.
- Chilly today.
- No, it's fine.
Good-bye.
What are you listening to?
- Bad music as usual.
- Why are you here so early?
I have to pick the kids up
in 30 minutes.
- Want some coffee?
- No, I want you.
Do you want coffee?
- I want you.
- No way.
Let me take a look at the situation.
Just in time, I'm leaving tonight.
- Padua again?
- My professor's expecting me.
When do you get back?
Never.
HONEY
Hello?
Who's speaking?
Sorry, I can't talk right now.
But you should contact
our mutual friend for that info.
That's right, call him.
No, I'm sorry, this is the procedure.
Have a good day.
Attention, please.
This is the final call for flight MEXK256
for Los Angeles.
Please board immediately.
My dog is very sick.
I'd like to put him down myself.
Good morning.
Hello.
I need some Lamputal, please.
- Excuse me?
- Lamputal.
My dog is very sick.
I'd like to put him down myself.
Excuse me.
- How old is your dog?
- Fourteen.
Poor thing.
Two.
Last stop: Forli, Piazza Saffi.
Forli, Piazza Saffi.
Good morning, Honey.
- Has she been taking the Vaxolon?
- Of course.
Give her another so she doesn't vomit,
but give her 20 drops of this first.
It'll make her feel better, calmer.
Okay, I will.
I've put the written statement
on the table.
Fine, though you won't need it.
Here she is.
- Carla.
- How are you, Honey?
Are you going to ask me again
if I've changed my mind?
Yes, Carla, you still have time.
I'll ask you one last time,
then I won't ask again.
- Do you want us to stop?
- No.
I haven't changed my mind.
All right.
Did you find the chocolate?
Yes.
- The one I asked for?
- Yes.
I'll leave you on your own a minute.
Ennio.
Ennio, listen carefully.
Listen carefully.
She has to drink all the Lamputal,
it's essential.
And remember, don't touch the glasses
once they're on the nightstand.
Understand?
Only Carla can touch them after that.
She has to do it all herself.
Do you remember what we said?
Bring the tray.
Ennio, Carla needs your help now.
You won't help her like this.
Be strong.
I'll put on the music you requested.
Thank you.
It's bitter.
Really bitter.
How long will it take?
Two, three minutes.
That's it?
Meet you there,
I have to get some lures.
I'll ask her.
It's Luciano, we're taking
the boat out on Sunday morning.
Then we can stop by your place
and eat some fish.
No, I'm in Padua on Sunday, Dad.
I told you.
That's right.
No, Irene has to go see
her university professor.
On a Sunday?
I have an appointment
early Monday morning.
Yes, me too.
But I'll leave you my keys,
so you can eat your fish at my place.
Yes, thanks.
Yes, of course, yes.
Here.
His name's Grimaldi,
he's an engineer here in Rome.
Rome?
Why are you sending me?
He'll be the only one at the meeting.
There will be no family.
Just go there, give him the stuff,
and explain the procedure.
He wants to do it himself.
What do you mean?
We've never done it like that before.
It's too risky,
for the patient and for us.
The "rabbit," as you call him,
is a reliable contact.
He's a bit unusual as doctors go,
but he's sharp.
I gave him your number
so he could explain the situation.
What's wrong?
- What's up?
- Nothing.
I feel this thing, like a flutter,
a shiver, but it's nothing.
You're probably tired
from your trip and the jet lag.
Nothing happens for months,
and now everything at once.
How many have you got left?
I had one, and I bought
two more on my last trip.
You are careful?
I am careful.
Mr. Grimaldi?
Hello?
Come in.
Good morning.
Come in, I don't bite.
Nice to meet you, I'm Honey.
Sorry?
Honey is my work name.
- Take a seat.
- Thanks.
- Do you smoke?
- No, thanks.
Of course not.
So give me all the details.
I'm in your hands.
I've never died before.
Ask me questions,
and I'll try to answer them.
Right, questions.
Will it be very painful?
No, not at all.
If you decide to go ahead with it,
I'll give you instructions
that you must follow carefully.
Then I'll give you
a substance, tetrabamate.
It's a barbiturate,
you'll have to swallow it.
Is that the only way?
No, there is an alternative,
what we call method B.
But in your case it's out of the question
since you don't want my help.
- Or am I mistaken?
- No, you're not mistaken.
But you see,
yours is an unusual case,
I always assist the patient
during the whole procedure.
I don't think it will be necessary
to meet again.
So what do I need you for?
My doctor could've prescribed
a ton of barbiturates.
Perhaps you don't know lethal barbiturates
have been taken off the market,
precisely because they're dangerous.
They can't be prescribed.
How do you get them?
Do you make them yourself at home?
Are you a little chemist?
I buy veterinary barbiturates.
- In Switzerland?
- No, I get them in Mexico.
But I don't have to tell you all this,
you can check for yourself.
You told me to ask questions.
Yes, I'm sorry, you're right.
I could jump out of the window,
we're on the fifth floor.
But then...
the onlookers, the neighbors...
Goodness, no.
My doctor said you also take care of...
the soundtrack.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
How thoughtful of you.
And do you have a repertoire?
It's a very personal choice,
so you would tell me what you'd like.
Can I play something for you?
Forgive me.
Don't worry.
Listen, I can help you.
I mean it,
but only if you want me to.
Do you have it with you, this tetra...
Yes.
But if you don't mind me saying so,
you shouldn't do it alone.
Think it over.
You could use help.
Here are the instructions,
we can review them.
And, if you have
any questions, any doubts,
if you change your mind,
just let me know.
A Labrador.
- The "Happy Birthday" kit or the "I Love You"?
- Which is the biggest?
Both have five kg of helium,
but the number of balloons changes.
"Happy Birthday" has 50,
"I Love You" has 25.
These are heart-shaped.
Which do you want?
Will I suffocate?
No, you won't suffocate.
You'll breathe easily
and immediately pass out.
You'll feel slightly dizzy,
like with altitude sickness,
because the helium brings
the oxygen level down.
You won't feel anything
after a few breaths.
Will this gas
be dangerous for my sister?
There's no risk,
helium is an inert gas.
It disperses without doing any harm.
Or they wouldn't use it
at kids' parties.
What?
What did you say?
I didn't hear that.
You won't be in any danger
since helium is an inert gas,
it disperses without doing any harm.
Read the...
No, you read it.
"Due to the rapid decline of my health,
I can no longer call this living.
I have decided to speed things up.
Let it be known, I did it all on my own.
Filippo Porchielli."
Perfect.
But you won't need it, you'll see.
I don't think I'll be seeing much.
- Will I?
- I'm sorry.
Any more questions?
Can I do it on the bed?
Yes, as long as you're not lying down.
Sitting up?
Okay.
Listen, we can stop at any time.
I'll ask you again, even tomorrow.
You can just say "stop" at any time.
- You can still change your mind.
- Tomorrow.
- Good-bye.
- Come at 11:00.
Give me time to make myself pretty.
What a shitty job you have.
No, thanks, I'll take it tomorrow.
But she's leaving soon,
I'll have to find a new roommate.
Pity she's leaving.
She's pretty.
What's her name?
Her name's Bai Xing Xing.
That's why she's leaving.
Bye, Xing Xing!
Bye, Xing Xing.
What's up?
Aren't you jealous?
Of what?
Because you have to share me.
I wouldn't like it.
- Share what?
- What's that?
- Is that your phone?
- Mine doesn't vibrate.
- You've got another phone?
- It's not mine.
- It belongs to the department.
- Yeah.
For dissertation interviews.
- Hello?
- Good morning.
One second.
- Who is it?
- Mr. Grimaldi.
- Carlo Grimaldi, remember?
- Yes.
I'm sorry to disturb you again,
but I need to ask you something
about the procedure.
- Have you got a minute?
- Yes, of course. Go ahead.
I wanted to know...
- Well...
- Yes?
If there were to be an autopsy,
would the substance leave a trace?
No, absolutely not,
it leaves no trace.
And as I told you before,
they rarely perform an autopsy.
In cases of terminal illness,
doctors certify natural death.
What terminal illness?
Why? Aren't you...
What?
No, I'm brimming with health.
Thanks for the information,
have a good day.
What the fuck were you thinking?
I help sick people!
I'm not a hired killer!
You're crazy!
Quiet.
Do you realize
what the rabbit has done?
That fucking spineless friend of yours.
Did you know about this or not?
Tell me!
If you don't know, let me tell you.
The old guy...
is healthier than
you and I put together.
He said, "I'm brimming with health"!
Understand, Rocco?
So what?
I don't kill depressed people.
Irene...
sometimes it's hard to know
where our limit lies.
- There are no rules.
- No?
- No, ma'am.
- I do have rules.
I thought you did too.
Give me the neurologist's number.
- Give me his number!
- Calm down and go home.
I'll call the neurologist. Don't ever
make another scene like this again.
- Good morning.
- Can I have a word with you?
We need to call it off,
there was a misunderstanding.
No, there wasn't, the deal is closed.
- Good-bye.
- No, you lied to me.
- You didn't ask me anything.
- Yes, but I just assumed you were sick.
You assumed.
Now if you don't mind,
Miss Honey, I'm busy.
Where are you going?
How dare you?
What are...
- What are you doing?
- Let go of me.
Yes.
No, I'll call you back.
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
Please, I want you out of here.
- Where did you put that fucking bottle?
- You have to leave!
Where are you going?
Let go of me!
That's enough now.
Get out!
- You have to give it back!
- And if I don't?
Will you call the police?
You're the one who sold me
an illegal substance.
I'll call the police if you want.
Get out!
Fuck off, you mangy old dog!
My friend's got a lot
of stamina, doesn't she?
I sometimes feel
I can't catch my breath.
It's hard to breathe.
My heart starts to beat so fast.
What's that there?
Why's it doing that?
Everything's fine, Irene, don't worry.
Everything's fine.
Dad?
Dad.
It's me, don't be scared.
Seven.
- I could've done six plus one.
- You could have.
Don't be a nag.
Pick yours up, please.
Good evening, Professor.
The police came yesterday,
they asked about you.
What did they want?
They were checking
your change of address.
They checked on me
when I moved here too.
They asked if I knew you,
they took notes.
- Everything's fine now.
- All right, thank you.
- Good-bye, Irene.
- Good evening, Professor.
The next day he sent me
a message on Facebook.
"I feel I saw a certain sparkle
in your eyes."
Can you call a number
from your cell?
Wait a minute.
Bella!
If he answers, say you've got
the wrong number and hang up.
It's ringing.
Hello?
Is Chiara there?
What?
I'm sorry,
I've got the wrong number.
Good-bye, sorry.
He sounds like an old man.
Who is he?
- Come in.
- Good morning.
Sorry about the other day,
can we talk about it calmly?
I just can't take my eyes
off the screen.
Today's contestants
are Gillian and Christina,
and the fabulous prey is Jamie.
Have a seat.
Their parents participate too.
Daddy and Mommy.
They said, "No sex."
There she is.
Now the two girls
start smacking each other.
You see, Christina just said,
"I'm a nice, funny girl."
And the blonde girl said,
"I'm sweet and passionate."
Isn't it funny?
"Sweet and passionate."
I watch it every day.
Sir, I came back here
so we could talk.
- So I could explain...
- Can you imagine?
"Hi, my name is Honey.
I'm bashful and solitary."
Isn't it wonderful?
What's your problem?
Ugly TV shows?
I don't give a shit about ugliness.
The uglier you are, the better.
Who's ugly?
That's why you want to end your life?
Not enough for you?
Is there a list of acceptable reasons?
Would you rather I told you
I have a terrible secret,
a crime to atone for?
I don't owe you an explanation.
You sell, I buy.
That's not exactly the case. I help.
But not people like you,
you can live!
For all I know, not all your clients
are on the verge of death.
- You have no right to...
- Oh, please.
All in all, I've had a good life,
a successful career.
I've been everywhere,
even Mexico like you.
I got married and divorced,
I have friends.
What else?
- Kids?
- We didn't want any.
That was the one thing
my wife and I agreed upon.
Believe me,
I've lost interest in everything.
It's all so boring and insignificant.
I can understand,
it's easier to help the terminally ill.
Nobody can stand the sight
of a body falling apart.
It's natural to feel pity then.
But if the illness is invisible, then what?
Is it just a whim, heresy?
This thing you do for money,
everybody should be able to do it.
The sick don't have
more rights than me.
I disagree.
I've already argued with your doctor.
This is not what we do,
or at least not what I do.
Is saving me some sort
of redemption for all the others?
I don't need redemption,
I believe in what I do.
But I don't want you on my conscience
'cause I disagree with your choice.
Is that clear?
I've worked up an appetite,
want to get some food?
Then there's another legend
about Suleymaniye Mosque.
Apparently the architect took advantage
of the airstreams to support the dome.
- Everything okay?
- Yes, thanks.
- Since it's not crowded, can I smoke?
- Sure.
No, thanks.
The upward air current which flows
along the flutes of the columns
helps to support the dome, understand?
Sort of.
Is that possible?
I doubt it,
but it's a fascinating story.
Actually, if you go to Istanbul one day...
place a sheet of paper
beneath the dome.
What will happen?
Perhaps nothing.
You'll let me know.
What were you studying before...
Medicine,
but just for a few years.
Right, too many years, too hard.
So this, shall we call it "activity,"
of yours is your job?
You do nothing else?
You don't have any plans, ambitions?
What we do is important.
Okay, but don't start
getting all ideological.
What are you, a group
of combatants for euthanasia?
With the rates you charge,
not many people can afford a dignified end.
You don't know what you're saying.
You're free to consider me a mercenary,
I don't care what you think about me.
No, sorry, I'm intrigued,
that's why I ask.
How do you do it, technically?
You live with your parents?
Do you hide the dog poison
in your room?
What do you tell your mom
when you return from Mexico?
My mother died 10 years ago.
An illness?
Yes.
What's that thing in your mouth?
- What?
- That.
A piercing.
What's it for?
It must have some meaning for you.
- Yes.
- Such as?
I read that Aztec priests
pierced their tongues with agave thorns.
What for?
New life bloomed from the blood
of the sacrifice, like an agave flower.
- Bullshit.
- Why?
There's no escaping contemporary idiocy.
I have to go catch my train.
You can stay at my place,
I have an extra room.
No, thanks.
You'll have to make do.
If you need anything else,
it's all in there.
Thanks.
- Good night, Honey.
- Irene.
My name is Irene.
Much better.
Sir?
Find anything?
Want breakfast?
Yes, thanks.
All right, I'll call you later.
Okay, bye.
What is it?
Still seeing her?
- Who?
- Her.
Oh, her! No.
Yes, every now and then.
Why?
Are you still jealous?
Sometimes.
Let's talk about it.
Some other day.
Give me that number.
I have to go.
Here you go.
- 0422?
- It's in Treviso.
All right, bye.
Next week in Treviso,
it's a young guy.
Sorry, the batteries are dying.
Did you hurt yourself?
Come on.
I like Italians,
they're cheerful and friendly.
And the ladies are beauties!
Italian ladies are pretty.
I really like them, such happy people.
I adore Italian ladies.
Sometimes I compare them
with Mexican women.
They're so affectionate, attentive.
But most of all they're happy,
and they like dancing.
Number 19. On the right.
Carlo Grimaldi,
leave a message. Thanks.
Good evening,
or rather, good morning.
Carlo Grimaldi,
leave a message. Thanks.
- Hello?
- Sir?
- Sir.
- Hello?
I called you a million times,
what the fuck?
When someone leaves a message,
you should call back.
Where are you?
Outside of your building.
Why?
I was worried.
As you can see,
I'm still in the world of the living.
Can I come up, please?
- No.
- Why?
I'll come down.
What do you want from me?
Leave me alone.
Delete my number.
It's the third time in three weeks
that you've just shown up.
What? You miss me?
You didn't answer,
so I got majorly anxious.
Majorly?
How do you people talk?
Don't give me that "you people" shit.
What would you prefer I say?
I was concerned about you.
I was distressed. Is that better?
It doesn't fucking matter anyway.
Know what matters?
That I ran here like an idiot
because I thought you killed yourself.
Do you feel better now?
Have you appeased
your girl-scout conscience?
Good-bye.
You're not going anywhere!
- Girl scout, my ass!
- Don't touch me.
- I came here for you.
- You're nobody to me.
You're full of shit.
Acting all stoic.
You're all talk,
you don't have the guts to kill yourself.
You're scared, huh?
That's what you are, scared.
Get it over with.
This music is really great.
But it's making me so sleepy
I think I'll go home and go to bed.
- I tired you out today.
- Tired me out?
You physically attacked me.
You deserved it.
Who else will be there?
It's not that I don't feel like it.
I'll call you later, bye.
Dad?
Maybe I'll move back to Rome.
It's up to you, your room is there.
- You're early.
- You're crazy.
The wet suit keeps me warm.
- Hi, Bella!
- Hurry up, they're waiting for us.
- What's that thing?
- You'll see.
Can I leave her in your yard?
Bella, wait!
Oh, God, wait!
- When do you leave?
- Tomorrow.
What a drag, you're always gone.
How's it going with Mr. WWF?
Whatever.
You met with him?
- Did you fuck?
- What do you think?
Does he want to leave his wife?
Enough with the interrogation!
I don't know!
Okay, take it easy.
Sorry, I don't feel like coming anymore.
Why?
I'm tired.
Tired from what?
Here you go.
Sorry!
What are you saying?
He said he dreamt of you
last night, Honey.
Thanks.
What is it?
Want the window open?
What?
He wants to look out the window.
Would you help me?
There.
Lorenzo...
you know we can stop at any time.
Just say the word.
Ma'am, I don't understand him.
Damn, was that the Lamputal?
No, the vodka.
It's no problem, I'll clean it up.
I'll move this and dry it up.
Mom will take care of it all.
I'll go get you another vodka.
I'll pour another glass.
- I'll pour another glass.
- No!
- You don't want vodka?
- Do you want music?
What do you want?
You want us to stay with you.
We are with you.
I shouldn't have left like that.
It's not right.
I should've waited till it was over.
There are rules.
Each time I make some mistake.
We can't use certain words.
We should never say,
"wish," or "see you later."
We can't use future-tense verbs.
Nothing that might
remind them that after...
We must be invisible.
They mustn't think we go back
to our normal life afterwards.
He'd chosen a song.
"Black."
A really long track,
it lasts seven minutes.
But he couldn't take it anymore.
No more music.
No more vodka.
He did it all in a rush.
Nobody really wants to die.
None of the people
I assisted in these three years...
wanted to kill themselves.
They want to live.
They all want to live.
But they no longer can call it a life.
They can't take it anymore.
Come on, what's wrong?
I don't feel like it.
Shitty place.
Not feeling well?
You're full of shit.
- You're fine.
- Whatever.
You keep lying all the time.
Nonstop bullshit.
You don't go to Padua and never have.
You don't have a Chinese roommate.
You're not doing any research.
- You know it all.
- Yes, why do you go to Mexico?
Who do you go to see every month?
Fucking spying on me?
Why do you go there every month?
Be honest, is there someone else?
I go there to buy veterinary barbiturates.
For putting down dogs.
You buy what?
In Mexico.
Get out, go!
You're crazy!
- Piece of shit!
- Get out!
Get out of my damn car!
Go!
You're nobody to me, understand?
If you need to stop for a while,
I can understand.
I'll hand this over to Diego.
No.
I want to stop for good.
I can't do it anymore.
- Sir!
- There you are.
I went to see the doctor,
professor, or whatever he is.
Dayal.
- I'll let you in.
- Lovely man.
Is he a mathematician?
He offered me coffee.
He said I shouldn't have taken a cab,
but a train, since it takes less time.
Like you do, no?
What is this?
An excuse to see me again?
Thanks, I would've come for it
if you'd told me.
Your ID is in there too.
Who knew you were a scatterbrain?
- Want to come in?
- As you like.
You never told me
you live right on the beach.
- Like it?
- Beautiful.
Too bright, though.
Too much sun,
too much sea, too much wind.
Too much.
If it's nice, it's too nice,
if it's horrible, it's too horrible.
I'm a bore, aren't I?
I am a bore.
I don't have much to offer you,
want some tea?
Sure, tea is fine.
Here's an ashtray.
What's with the sunglasses?
I found them at home,
must've been my wife's.
Like them?
Here, you can have them.
Thanks.
I'll be in Rome tomorrow.
If you'd like, I could stop by.
Don't you have a boyfriend
to spend your Saturdays with?
An official boyfriend? No.
I'll smoke one last cigarette, and then
I'll be off to take this famous train.
Enough. You should quit smoking.
Really?
Do you have a method to suggest?
Or are you relying exclusively
on my willpower?
- Sir?
- Yes?
Where are you going?
It's that way.
Right, I...
I got confused.
Good-bye.
Don't shoot.
Pizza.
Hi.
...his longtime girlfriend
and her super mom...
HONEY