Turin HORSE
In Turin on January 3rd 1889,
Friedrich Nietzsche steps out of the
Door of number six Via Carlo Alberto,
Perhaps to take a stroll, perhaps to
go by the post office...
...to collect his mail.
Not far from him, or indeed
very far removed from him,
a cabman is having trouble
with his stubborn horse.
Despite all his urging,
the horse refuses to move,
whereupon the cabman
- Giuseppe? Carlo? Ettore? -
loses his patience
and takes his whip to it.
Nietzsche comes up to the throng
and that puts an end
to the brutal scene of the cabman,
who by this time is foaming with rage.
The solidly built and full-mustached Nietzsche
suddenly jumps up to the cab
and throws his arms around
the horse neck...
...sobbing.
His neighbor takes him home,
where he lies still and silent,
for two days on a divan
until he mutters...
the obligatory last words:
"Mutter, ich bin dummm."
("Mother, i'm fool.")
and lives for another ten years,
gentle and demented,
in the care of his mother and sisters.
Of the horse... we know nothing.
THE FIRST DAY
It's ready.
Go to bed.
Hey, you!
What is it?
Can't you hear them either?
What?
The woodworm, they're not doing it.
I've heard them for 58 years.
But I don't hear them mow.
They really have stopped.
What's it all about, papa?
I do not know.
Let's sleep.
She lies back and pulls
the blanket over herself.
Ohlsdorfer turns on his side
and fixes his eyes stopped on the window.
The girl stares atthe ceiling,
her father at the window.
At times a ties can be heard
crashing down from the roof
and shattering noisily.
The gale roars relentlessly around the house.
THE SECOND DAY
Come here!
Can't you see she won't move?
Stop it!
Come here!
It's ready.
I've run out of palinka. Would you give me
a bottle? (Hung. fruk. vodka)
Give him some...
- Why didn't you go into town?
- The wind's blown it away.
How come?
It's gone to ruin.
Why would it go to ruin?
Because everything's in ruins,
Everything's been degraded,
but I could say that they've ruined...
and degraded everything.
Because this is not some
kind of cataclysm,
coming about with
so-called innocent human aid.
On the contrary...
It's about man's own judgement,
his own judgement over his own self,
which of course God has a hand in,
or dare I say: takes part in
And whatever he takes part in
is the most ghastly creation
that you can imagine.
Because, you see, the world has been debased.
So it doesn't matter what I say,
because everything has been debased
that they've acquired.
and since they've acquired everything
in a sneaky, underhand fight,
they've debased everything.
Because whatever they touch...
-and they touch everything-
they've debased.
This is the way it was until the final victory.
Until the trimphant end.
Acquire, debase,
debase, acquire.
Or I can put it differently if you like:
To touch, debase and thereby acquire,
or touched, acquire and thereby debase.
It's been going on like this for centuries..
On, on and on.
This and only this, sometimes on the sly,
sometimes rudely,
sometimes gently, sometimes brutally,
but it has been going on and on.
Yet only in one way,
like a rat attack from ambush.
Becouse for this perfect victory,
it was also essential that the other side...
think is, everything that's excellent,
great in some way and noble,
should not engage in any kind of fight.
There shouldn't be any kind of struggle,
just the sudden disappearance of one side,
meaning the disappearance of the excellent,
the great, the noble.
So that by now these winning winners
who attack from ambush rule earth,
and there isn't a single tiny nook
where one can hide something from them,
because everything they can lay
their hands on is theirs.
Even things we think they can't reach
- but they do reach -
are also theirs.
Because the sky is already theirs
and all our dreams.
Theirs is the moment, nature,
infinite silence.
Even immortality is theirs, you understand?
Everything, everything is lost forever!
And those many noble,
great and excellent just stood there,
if I can put it that way.
They stopped at this point,
and had to understand, and had to accept,
that there is neither god nor gods.
And the excellent, the great a nd the noble
had to understand and accept
this right from the beginning.
But of course, they were quite incapable
of understanding it.
They believed it and accepted it
but they didn't understand it.
They just stood there, bewildered,
but not resigned,
until something - that spark from the brain -
finally enlightened them.
And all at once they realized,
that there is neither god nor gods.
All at once they saw that
there is neither good nor bad.
Then they saw and understood
that if this was so,
then they themselves do not exist either!
You see, I reckon this may have been
the moment when we can say that
they were extinguished, they burnt out.
Extinguished and burnt out
like the fire left to smoulder in the meadow.
One was a constant loser,
the another was the constant winner.
Defeat, victory,
defeat, victory,
and one day
- here in the neighbourhood -
I had to realize,
and I did realize, that I was mistaken,
I was truly mistaken when I thought
that there has never been
and could never be
any kind of change here on earth.
Because, believe me, I know now
that this change has indeed taken place.
Come off it! That's rubbish!
THE THIRD DAY
Coat!
She's not eating.
She will.
Do eat!
You have to eat!
What's that?
What's happening?
A cart's approaching.
Who are they?
Gypsies, I think.
What the fuck do they want here?
I don't know, but they're coming this way!
The stinking rotten bastards!
What shall we do?
Go and chase them away!
What are you waiting for?
Get moving!
...There's water here...
...Come and help...!
...Come and help papa...!
...Come on, hey...!
... Come and drink...!
...Hold the horse...
...Look...
...Here comes the girl...
Here's the girl...
...Her eyes are like the devil's...
Get away from here!
Go away!
What are you doing here?
Gert away from here!
...Come with us...!
I won't!
I'm not going anywhere!
...Come with us to America...!
Are you deaf?
Let me go!
I'm not going with you!
God forbid!
...You'll like it there...!
I don't care!
Let go!
Fuck you sons of bitches!
Get the hell out of here!
I'll rip your guts out,
for fuck's sake!
Dirty rotten gypsies!
...This is for the water...
He'll kill me! Papa!
Papa! Faster!
...Just come over here, you worm...!
...We'll be back...!
The water is ours!
The earth is ours!
You're weak!
Drop dead! Drop dead!
Drop dead!
One.
Since ho-ly pla-ces
only al-low the prac-tice
of things that serve
the ven-er-a-tion of the Lord,
and every-thing is for-bid-den
that is not fit-ted for
the ho-li-ness of the place,
and since
ho-ly pla-ces are vi-o-lated
by the great in-jus-tice of ac-tions
that have ta-ken place within them
that scan-dal-ize the con-gre-gation,
for this rea-son
no ser-vice can be held there
Un-til,
though a ce-re-mony of pen-i-tence,
the in-jus-ti-ces
have been put right.
The ce-le-brant
tells the con-gre-gation:
The Lord is with you!
Mor-ning will turn to night.
Night will end...
The storm continues to rage outside.
The wind still sweeps relentlessly
across the land from the same direction.
But now there is nothing
in its path to obstruct it.
Only a great cloud of dust
whipped up by the wind...
...rushes recklessly forward.
Bone-dry dust and the ravaging nothing...
...that the wind rolls before it
as it rages unbridled
over the barren land.
THE FOURTH DAY
- Come with me!
- What's up?
- Come, quick!
- What's wrong?
The well!
Phew!
Fuck it!
Cover it!
And the palinka?
Why don't you eat?
You're not going anywhere...
Drink!
At least drink a little water!
For my sake!
Pack up clothes, dishes, needle
and thread, things like that!
Whot for?
We're not staying here. Pack!
Blankets, palinka.
Palinka!
Potatoes too.
Get the handcart!
Come on!
THE FIFTH DAY
What's this darkness, papa?
Light the lamps!
Fuck it!
Why didn't you fill it up?
It's full.
Bring some embers!
What is all this?
I don't know.
Let's go to bed.
Even the embers went out.
Tomorrow we'll try again.
We can hear them
groping their way to the bads.
We can hear them lying down,
and pulling the blanket over them.
We can hear them breathing.
Only their breathing.
Dead silence outside,
the storm is over.
Dead silence falls on the house too.
THE SIXTH DAY
Eat.
We have to eat.