My Secret Hotel
Nam Sang Hyo?
Well...
if you came by because you felt bad...
...that's okay.
Oh, wait.
I have a favor to ask you.
Your wedding...
Leave it to me.
- What?
- I beg you.
Are you insane?
Are you out of your mind?
I know it doesn't make sense at all.
Then don't ask.
I'll do a great job.
I really will.
I'll do my best to satisfy you
and Soo Ah with all my sincerity.
With all your sincerity?
- Yeah.
- For my wedding?
Yeah.
Can you really...
without any feelings...
...prepare my wedding?
I can do it.
You and I were...
over seven years ago anyway.
I have no other feelings for you.
So...
...leave it to me.
I'm sorry, but...
I don't want to.
I told you.
Whether it's coincident or for any reason,
I don't want to see you again.
Got it?
Goo Hae Young.
Don't...
...touch me.
We were over seven years ago?
You have no feelings for me?
Fine, fine. So...
let's not see each other again.
Let's not.
That jerk!
Jerk!
Jerk...
Miss, do you mind sharing the cab?
You'll do it anyway even if I didn't like it.
Well, if you really don't want to...
You'll do it anyway...
It's tough to catch a cab at night.
What's so difficult about that?
Excuse me?
That bastard!
Who is it?
You really scared me.
How did you get here?
I took a taxi.
No...
How did you know where I lived?
I saw it on the wedding paperwork.
You know...
this is clearly invasion of
privacy and private information.
Leave your wedding to me.
I said I don't want to.
That's too bad. Leave it to me.
Am I funny to you?
Do I look easy?
You are easy to me.
More than Jung Soo Ah.
I'm sorry, but...
...you got me wrong.
This is my last request.
I pushed my pride aside.
I ask you for the last time.
Hae Young.
Why are you doing this?
I don't want other people
to suffer because of me.
People at the hotel as well as
...the General Manager.
And...
...the Managing Director.
The Managing Director?
Who?
Jo Sung Gyum?
Jeez!
Forget it.
It has nothing to do with me
whether they suffer or not.
I don't care even if your hotel
goes out of business, understand?
- C'mon, Goo Hae Young.
- I told you not to touch me.
Hey, you jerk!
What's so great about you?
You...
I'll curse you.
I'll curse your wedding day!
I'm sorry I called you a jerk.
I'll take back what I said about cursing you.
Go away.
Goo Hae Young!
I said go away.
I'm asking you...
I said go away!
I told you to go away.
I told you to stop!
What's going on?
Did someone come by?
What?
Oh, well...
...a street vendor.
A street vendor?
Yeah.
Let's go inside.
I'm going to spend the night here tonight.
I'll take a shower first.
Oh, oppa!
I said to stay still.
- What are you doing?
- Animal...
Don't, oppa.
- Oh, oppa...
- Fine.
Oppa...
The street vendor is leaving.
I said stay still.
Yes, Mother.
Soo Ah is at my place right now.
Yes.
Really?
I'll send her home right away.
Okay.
What's with this?
Mr. Kim is around here.
He'll come by to pick you up.
We're engaged.
I hear other men can't stand to wait.
What's wrong with you, oppa?
I just thought you were being
cautious with me all along, but...
do you have another reason?
Am I right?
Soo Ah.
Ugh, I had no idea.
No, no, no. Don't say a word.
Okay.
This is a very important matter.
Other women will cry and talk
of breaking up the engagement.
But not me.
I'll look into hospitals.
Hospitals?
I heard there are many men
like you in their thirties.
With so much competition and stress.
But there are lots of good
medicines nowadays and...
it's perfectly...
...curable.
That's not it.
Oppa.
Let's go eat eel tomorrow.
I told you that's not it.
Why?
You don't like eel?
Then...
...raspberry?
Rasp...
Never mind.
What can I say to you...
The Madam is waiting for you.
Please get in.
Is that...
...all you have to say to me?
Oppa.
I'll leave then.
Sorry for the hassle every time.
No problem.
Alright then.
I'll get going.
Oppa!
Black garlic is good for you, too.
Be quiet and go.
Alright?
She's gone, right?
Jerk...
I heard the dead Hwang Dong Bae
making a threat to someone on the phone.
"If you don't listen to me,
I'll talk to your son."
Something like that.
Your son?
Also this isn't that important, but...
I spotted Assistant Manager Yang
from the Wedding Department crying.
Team Leader.
The phone call Hwang Dong Bae
made right before his death...
He called New York.
New York?
Are you talking about America?
Yes.
But that number is not in service anymore.
We can't confirm who he
was talking to as of now.
I'm sure he didn't call the New York Bakery.
I requested US assistant for now but
due to privacy information laws and whatnot,
it will take some time.
New York. New York...
"I have a lot to say to your son."
Your son?
You're Jo Min Tae's son?
Yes.
I'm Jo Sung Gyum.
You don't resemble your father.
Is that so?
You're much more handsome than your father.
Go ahead, sit.
Okay, thank you.
But...
why did you come see me?
By chance...
I was wondering if you knew
anything about my father's death.
I'd appreciate it if you
would tell me what you know.
Ah...
And this...
I did think this may offend you, but...
I thought I might disrupt your business and
I didn't know what I should bring.
You didn't have to.
Just...
tell me what you know.
Please I ask you.
It's different now, but...
back then...
there used to be a railing
on the second floor lobby.
I heard he fell off of there and
died from that accident.
But you know...
Yes?
It's okay.
Because of your father's triumphant success,
he had many enemies on the inside.
So...
there was much talk of murder...
...not an accident.
Your father was murdered.
Do you know who the killer is?
My father was...
...really murdered?
Come out.
Oh, my God!
Right...
She must've come to her senses.
Letter of resignation
You're early.
I just had a lot on my mind.
Goo Hae Young and Jung Soo Ah's wedding?
I guess it didn't work out?
I'll be back.
This isn't good.
Manager Nam is...
...in a pickle.
She'll take care of it just fine.
She's the "future of the hotel."
You can focus on your
purse at a time like this?
Why couldn't I?
With a fake bag...
What do you mean fake?
I bought it at a duty-free shop in Hong Kong.
You were in Hong Kong this time?
Why would I believe that?
It's not like your family is rich
and all you have is your salary.
How do you afford international
trips and brand name purses?
- Don't blow it out of proportion.
- Stop it already.
I really went to Hong Kong.
This is real, too!
Okay, okay.
What's with you? You want to see a picture?
I told you to stop.
Things are disturbing as is.
Why are we acting this way?
What brings you...
Do you need to ask us more questions?
No.
I'd like to have some coffee...
...with Yang Kyung Hee.
Are you here to see me?
Ah, yes.
Well...
Let's see...
Yes.
Let's see what?
You know...
I was just walking by.
Letter of resignation
I see you're here, too.
You must have a lot on your mind.
Sit.
Is it too difficult for you?
Of course.
I'm sure they believe you ruined the wedding.
It would be hard to ask them to come back.
But...
I believe in you whether
things are resolved or not.
I'm sure you'll do your best.
I know...
you always...
...believe in me.
I...
...believe in fate.
The fact that we know each other...
I'm sure it's not sheer coincidence.
I don't know how you'd take this, but...
if I had a daughter,
I wish...
...she was just like you.
You are like a father...
...to me as well.
I wanted to give up.
But I guess I can't.
Actually today...
I had my letter of resignation...
Where is it?
Where did it go?
Because of your father's triumphant success,
he had many enemies on the inside.
So...
there was much talk...
of murder...
...not an accident.
You're right.
The night Assistant Manager Hwang died,
what I said about being alone at home...
...was a lie.
Why did you lie about that?
I don't know what my father looked like
because he passed away when I was young.
My mom passed away from cancer
when I was in junior high.
I finished high school with much difficulty.
I've been working at this hotel...
...for twenty two years.
At first,
there were all sorts of incidents.
I had to bear...
...many rude incidents.
There were many times I wanted to cry.
I wanted to quit many times, too.
I had met someone I loved as well.
But I couldn't get married.
And I still live alone.
But now...
I've learned to get along with others and...
I started to believe I was a bit happier.
But just like my mom,
I was diagnosed with cancer.
I was told I have about a year left.
They can't do anything at this point.
I'm so scared and...
...so lonely.
I hate going to an empty
home more than death itself.
I couldn't think of...
...anywhere else but here.
In any case...
it's a place I spent my youth.
It's the only place...
...with fond memories.
I'm sorry for lying.
But...
I don't want it to be known...
...why I came here.
Come hurry!
I know who the killer is.
So the day of Assistant
Manager Hwang's death,
some strangers came and
looked for him?
Yes.
I didn't think it was a
big deal at first, but...
it kept bothering me.
I've been playing poker for 30 years.
I know how to read faces.
Don't think about lying.
Oh, yeah.
The guy with a tattoo on his hand,
he was like...
"I've been playing poker for 30 years."
He said something like that.
Hey.
How much longer do we have
to hide out in the country?
I know.
Why did you take us to the hotel?
Should we have left him alone?
I couldn't stand to see him alive.
Jeez...
Thanks to your temper...
look what happened to us.
You!
You'd better behave if you
don't want to end up like that.
Do you know what I went through
that day because of you?
I used initials for your sake.
- Here you go again.
- Hey, hey.
Stop it.
I think she's regretful.
It's not like I made things up.
Again?
It's true there was a corpse.
Joo Jung Eun!
I'll say it clearly.
Write a good article if you
call yourself a reporter, okay?
Not sensational articles like this.
Where are you going?
I'm so pissed off I'm going
to wash my face. Why?
He went through...
quite a bit that day...
...with all the phone calls.
It's Jung Soo Ah.
Oppa, don't worry too much.
The doctor said you're treatable.
Treatment?
- Is he sick?
- For now...
you need to have a complete physical.
I made an appointment for you.
A complete physical?
At the hospital?
Even if you can't get cured,
I'll never leave your side to the end.
Does he have...
...a terminal disease?
So, don't worry and let's get examined.
On Friday 2pm in Boondang at Wang Gun...
...Urology?
Urology?
Restoring impotence.
He's a renowned expert.
Oh, our poor director...
What are they all doing?
It doesn't feel like someone else's problem.
Oh, it's here.
The raspberry juice...
I sent it to your house.
If you drink that,
they say you can crack the piss pot.
Piss pot god.
She says you can crack the piss pot.
Jeez.
Oh...
Don't worry about people
talking. I didn't tell anyone.
Oppa...
Do you...
...trust me?
She says, "Trust me."
"Trust me."
What is it? Something funny?
What is it...
You're still here?
Goo Hae Young.
I think...
I can forget about you.
Thanks.
For reals.
Please.
What's this?
What?
Ugh, Jung Soo Ah...
Please give me just one hour.
I'll brief on how I'll
proceed with your wedding.
At the moment, most hotels in Seoul are
pretty much booked for the next six months.
We'll give you the best time slot
with the best service at our hotel.
Oppa!
Jung Soo Ah!
Did you receive my text?
I texted you because I thought you'd be busy.
Who cares? What's there to hide between us?
Oh, yeah! I made reservation
at an eel restaurant tonight.
What do you mean? You know already why.
Whatever!
Come meet me at the front of the mall at 6pm.
Yeah, yeah. I love you, too.
Soo Ah.
Trust me once more and leave it to
me. What happened was an accident.
Am I almost done?
Yes, you're almost finished.
Where are my shoes?
Oh!
- Over here.
- Ah...
They're over there.
Your shoes.
Here they are.
Soo Ah.
Give me one more chance.
I'm confident I can do a great job.
Please?
Welcome.
Well...
This, this and that.
Show them to me please.
$2,230.
Your wedding cost and
honeymoon cost.
We'll cover everything.
On your wedding anniversary,
we'll provide you with
the best suite for free.
The hotel pool and
the fitness room...
We'll give you a lifetime membership.
Look, Nam Sang Hyo.
I can get all that stuff with my own money.
Then...
if you tell me what you want...
Excuse me.
Yes?
Give me all of these.
I'll make it a wedding
you've never seen before.
You won't regret it one bit.
Of course, if there's something
you specifically want,
we'll gladly accept your request.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Give me everything here.
- Give me...
...all of them.
Okay.
Soo Ah.
Give me just one hour.
After you hear about my plan,
you'll be satisfied.
Just one hour.
You're really tenacious.
I'm begging you.
Fine.
I give up.
I'll think about it.
But in return...
the apology you didn't give me last time...
...give it now.
Excuse me?
Get on your knees and apologize.
What?
You can't do that?
I was going to reconsider
since you seemed so desperate.
But I guess not.
I believe in you whether
things are resolved or not.
I'm sure you'll do your best.
No.
I'll kneel.
Please give me one more chance.
I thought even a hotel
employee had her pride.
But I must've been wrong.
Oh.
I thought about it for a moment.
I don't think I can do it.
Why would I get married there not
knowing what else might fall out?
Jung Soo Ah.
Oppa.
She was bothering me.
Get up, Nam Sang Hyo.
Oppa...
Get up.
I said get up!
Don't kneel just anywhere.
Oppa.
Where are you going, oppa?
Oppa!
Miss.
You're late if you want to get
to the eel restaurant by 6pm.
How can you say that at
a time like this? Huh?
I'll be outside.
Cry as much as you want.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you take me to my room?
Huh?
Come on.
How about I tip you say, $1,000?
And you'll take care of me tonight, huh?
I don't work in room service. I'm sorry, sir.
Oh, c'mon. Let's go.
I really fantasize about Asian girls.
Ah, c'mon!
I want to see an Asian girl in control.
Hey, what the F***?
Here's $2,000 for you.
Quit immediately.
I told you it rarely happens.
You don't need to worry.
How much do you get paid there?
I'll give you that money.
Quit immediately.
Money?
Does it look like I'm doing this for money?
Then what?
If you want to work,
I can find another job for you.
Becoming a hotelier is my dream.
It's my work.
I want to do this work.
The work you want to do...
The work you want...
is bowing down to a drunken man and
saying "I'm sorry" even if he holds
your hand and drags you to his room?
Don't say it like that.
That hotel won't go bankrupt just
because you quit. Quit immediately.
Are you saying your work is
important but my work isn't?
That type of work can't be important.
Goo Hae Young.
Work in a decent field!
Oh, boy. I'm in a fix.
I have a lot on my mind as well.
You have equity in our hotel.
Please help me.
Money is one thing, but
it's my daughter's wedding.
After what happened...
To hold a wedding...
there again is...
I know it will be hard. But I beg you.
Anyway, I told them to come here.
So, you talk to them.
My daughter is quite stubborn.
I came here for some eel. What do you want?
Come.
I'm Managing Director
Jo Sung Gyum of Secret Hotel.
I've met you before.
You cry so much.
Thanks.
I'll go now.
I'll drive you home.
It's okay.
You cry so much.
Thanks.
I'll go now.
I'll drive you home.
It's okay.
Listen to me.
As much as you...
...I'm upset.
In any case...
I'll think about it.
But...
I'm not sure about oppa.
If I were Goo Hae Young,
I'd listen to your request.
That is true.
I'll leave it to you.
See you next time.
Oh, yes. Goodnight.
You, too, Soo Ah.
I'll go.
Thanks.
Sang Hyo.
You know...
Must you do that?
What?
To the extent of kneeling and begging...
Must you?
Why?
Does my work still look like a joke to you?
That's not what I'm saying.
How can you leave like that earlier?
Did you come because you feel bad?
Alright.
I'll forgive you since
you've come all this way.
Soo Ah.
Let's get married at the Secret Hotel.
What?
I must get married there.
No matter what you say...
No...
no matter how much you oppose it...
- So...
- Alright.
What?
I'll do it there.
You will?
You will do it there?
So easily?
I can't be selfish.
The hotel has so many employees to feed.
I'll do as you say.
Aren't I kind?
I'm kind, right?
Yeah.
Right.
She's strangely kind.
Nam Sang Hyo.
How did it go?
Goo Hae Young and Jung Soo Ah's wedding.
Don't ask.
It didn't work out?
Gosh...
This is a big problem.
Sang Hyo.
Don't worry too much.
Whatever way I can,
I'll look for a way.
You will?
What's gotten into you?
We have a love-hate relationship.
This is really Hong Kong?
That's right...
you've never been there.
Isn't this a photo composite?
How can I compose the photo on my phone?
Is that right?
Anyway, you have skills.
Carrying a brand name purse and
traveling with your salary.
- Here.
- What, don't you want to see more?
That's enough.
The model sucks. I don't want to look.
How did it go?
I don't think it will work.
I can't believe you can't pull
this one off, Manager Nam.
What can you do?
People can slip at times.
This is...
Manager Nam.
Jung Soo Ah is here to see you.
What brings you here?
Well?
Why do you think I'm here?
What's this?
I heard Goo Hae Young and Jung Soo Ah's
wedding is unlikely to happen here.
This is a proposal to replace that wedding.
Please review.
The Managing Director of Secret Hotel and...
...a beautiful PR Manager.
A magical wedding for two
people to represent the hotel.
This beautiful PR Manager you speak of...
Are you talking about yourself?
Of course, I am.
Is there another...
PR Manager besides me?
Director Jo Sung Gyum came
to see me last night.
He was begging me so desperately.
I convinced my oppa, too.
Why not?
Why can't we do that?
I don't think it's a good method.
I think it's a good method.
We must revive the hotel.
Worse situations can occur
rather than reviving it.
Worse situations?
You get divorced within three
months of marrying in our hotel.
We can't confirm that rumor.
Why are you so sure we'd get a divorce?
Yeo Eun Joo.
Yes.
You're supposed to marry someone you love.
No goals or benefits can...
...replace that.
Managing Director.
What is it?
Well...
I want to report the wedding of
Goo Hae Young and Jung Soo Ah will happen.
What?
Jung Soo Ah just arrived.
She says she'll get married here.
We won't need this one for sure.
You can go now.
I have something to say to Nam Sang Hyo.
Okay.
I guess I didn't think this through.
What?
What, what, what?
Why are you looking at me?
Oh?
What's with your name, Simon?
Jung Soo Ah.
Did you call me?
It really is...
...you, Jung Soo Ah.
You look just like my friend.
Well...
I was just wondering if...
...it was you.
You have a friend...
...who looks like me?
Yes.
You two look just alike.
Is your friend Kim Tae Hee or something?
No.
She's not Kim Tae Hee.
She looks...
...just like you.
I'll bring a picture to show you tomorrow.
Sure.
Thank you.
Thank you for your help.
I did what I needed to do
as a managing director.
I...
was wondering if you helped me...
...because you were interested in me.
I made you nervous, Managing Director.
I'm just kidding.
Oh.
What should I do with this?
Letter of resignation
Oh!
How is that...
You dropped it in front of my office.
No...
That's...
I'll have to process is
since you submitted it.
Well then...
I have a meeting.
Managing Director.
Excuse me.
What?
Do you want to take it back?
Yes.
Fine.
But not for nothing.
I'll forget about it if you
buy me the dinner I want.
What?
Managing Director.
What would you like to eat?
I'll buy if you tell me.
Well, that's for you to figure out.
Excuse me?
I can't give you much time.
Guess while I walk down to the first floor.
Then...
how about steak?
I'm not a fan of western food.
How about this bean paste stew place I know?
I like spicy food.
Ugh, then...
Kimchee stew.
Boodae stew.
I feel like noodles rather than rice today.
Black bean noodles or spicy seafood noodles!
That's too bad.
You have no sense.
Sense?
Managing Director.
Ramen.
Then...
would you like...
...some ramen?
Sure.
I was really going to buy you a great
dinner even if it cost me my paycheck.
I enjoyed it.
No way...
I saw you leave more than half uneaten.
Managing Director.
By chance...
instead of ramen...
do you like me?
You're not surprised.
I'm just kidding.
I asked you to eat ramen because
I want to ask you something.
What is it?
In order to realize you're in love,
do you know how many minutes it takes?
Three minutes.
The time it takes for the
ramen to cook was long enough.
Nam Sang Hyo.
What do you say...
...we date officially?
Will you date him?
Will you date Jo Sung Gyum?
I...
was married seven years ago.
My ex-husband...
You really make me out to be an idiot.
It's a picture I took
in Hong Kong last month.
There were several pictures we took together.
What do you want?
Tell me what type of wedding you want
rather than regretting it later.
How about this?
Instead of an extravagant
dress, the bride wears
a clean and down-to-earth one piece dress.
In her hands, she holds a few flowers
she likes and in their hearts...
Sang Hyo.
I have to tell you something.
I must tell you before this day ends.