Oh, sorry.
Vera?
Bob Leckie.
I'm your neighbor
from across the street.
I know who you are, Bob.
I thought I was going shopping,
but then I passed Saint Mary's
and thought I'd pray instead.
I joined the Marines.
Thought I'd do my bit.
Fifth in line.
Well, if I don't see you
before you go...
take care of yourself.
Um, wait, Vera,
let me get that for you.
Oh, thank you.
Maybe I'll write you.
All right.
Basilone!
Over here.
Excuse me, folks.
- I miss anything?
- Nah.
The movie hasn't
started yet.
Don't tell me
I missed this thing.
- Chesty's come and gone.
- Yeah, just missed him.
Come on, did I
fuck this up or what?
- Oh, yeah.
- Man: Attention on deck!
Carry on.
Fuck you.
The uniform that you wear
and the globe-and-anchor
emblem that you have earned
will make the difference
between the freedom of the world
and its enslavement.
December 7th was
quite a day
in Pearl Harbor, Hawaii.
On the same day,
December 8th
on the other side of
the International Dateline,
in places called Guam, Wake,
the Malay Peninsula,
Hong Kong and
the Philippine Islands
were also attacked
by the army, air force
and navy of
the empire of Japan.
The Japanese
are in the process
of taking half
of the world.
And they mean
to keep it
with death from
the air, land and sea.
But here is what the Japs
are not expecting:
the United States
Marine Corps.
Now never mind Europe-
the Nazis, Mussolini.
Hitler is not gonna
be ourjob,
not until they can't
whip him without us.
The Pacific will be
our theater of war.
The Marines will do battle
with the Japs
on tiny specks of turf
that we have never heard of.
You noncommissioned officers,
you are the sinew
and the muscle of the corps.
The orders come from the brass
and you get it done.
And whenever
this war is over,
when we have swept upon
the main islands of Japan
and destroyed every scrap
of that empire,
the strategy will have been
that of others.
The victory will
have been won by you-
you, the NCOs,
with the chevrons on your
sleeves and the instincts in your guts
and the blood on your boots.
Those of you who are lucky enough
to get home for Christmas,
hold your loved ones dearly
and join them in prayers
for peace on earth
and goodwill toward all men.
And then report back here
ready to sail across
God's vast ocean
where we will meet
our enemy
and kill them all.
Merry Christmas.
Happy 1942.
Man:
Squad, atten-hut!
Carry on.
I got it, Ma.
Man:
Angelo? Angelo?
- Hey!
- Where you fellas been?
We had to walk from the station
and we took the wrong street.
Yeah, Manny had the wrong street.
You believe that?
Get in here.
Come on, come on.
Salute!
Come here.
Hey, everybody!
- This is JP and Manny!
- All: Hey!
Hey, everybody.
How you doin'?
Nice to see you.
Good to see you.
Thank you, sir.
JP.
Your wife is
so beautiful!
I wish my sons
could marry someone this beautiful.
- Eh!
- Ma!
Manny:
You sound like my mama.
She could not understand how
I could get through high school
- without that wedding date set.
- I could.
All right.
Everybody listen up,
please.
JP Morgan,
Manny Rodriguez,
welcome to our home.
We're happy you
could join us tonight.
Soon two of my brothers are
leaving to serve their country.
And George,
we're losing sleep wondering
what Marine Corps boot camp
is gonna do to you.
My brother John, you've been there
rough and ready for years.
You were in the Philippines
and came back to join the Marines
because you wanted to be
the best and first in.
When all this is over,
let's say
a year from tonight,
we'll sit down at
this table again
for a welcome-home feast.
To all of you,
just get the job done
and come home to us.
- Salute.
- All: Salute.
Oh!
Those cannoli
for the guests!
- He won't catch him.
- Yeah, you know it.
Depot announcer:
Bus to Rochester leaves in 20 minutes.
Please have
your tickets ready.
Thanks for the ride, Dad.
Must be a branch or something
stuck under the wheel.
It's pulling to one side.
Ech!
Thanks for the ride.
Oh yeah, sure.
You hardly packed a thing.
Final call for
the 6:45 to Newark.
Marine's outfit includes everything
from bayonets to socks.
I just wish I could have
brought my typewriter.
Can't see why
you need that.
Oh, I thought I might fight
by day and write by night, Dad.
Can't see a thing.
Oh, I hope I don't
need a new axle.
No way I'll get one.
Yeah.
There's a war on.
Everybody's got to
make sacrifices.
Your mother said I was
a fool not to buy a Ford.
Hope she's not right.
Bus 45 and 73, direct service
to New York City,
loading at depots 5 and 7.
Well, that's it, Dad.
I gotta go.
Goodbye, son.
Son-
Eugene, I- I'm sorry.
Murmur's still there.
The boy's disappointed,
Mary Frank.
I'm his mother.
Churchill over radio:
... at Pearl Harbor
in the Pacific Islands,
in the Philippines,
in Malaya and
the Dutch East Indies,
they must now know
the stakes are mortal.
When we look at the resources
of the United States
and the British Empire
compared to those of Japan,
when we...
...we have so long
valiantly withstood invasion.
Gene, supper's ready.
Deacon, you stay!
You're 18, Eugene.
You don't need your father's permission.
I can't go
against him, Sid.
When do you leave?
I'm on the 6:00 AM
train to Atlanta.
Uh, here.
Got you something.
"Barrack-Room Ballads"
by Rudyard Kipling.
Thank you, Gene,
but I didn't-
It's just if you need something
to read on the train or...
when you ship out.
I wish we
were going together.
Yeah, well, you take care
of yourself, greaser.
Oh. You don't have to
worry about me.
Get it while it's hot.
Get your plates out.
Today's the day, Marines!
This is it.
Today's the day!
Get moving.
Don't wait for a seat.
A lot of Marines to feed!
Move move move!
Release it up! The quicker we eat,
the quicker we get topside,
the quicker we get ashore.
Come on, Marines.
Let's go go go!
Oranges coming through.
Hey, come on, guys!
I worked hard
for these oranges!
- Dessert!
- Oh, hey!
Make sure you save
one of those for me.
I just want off this goddamn rust bucket!
I can't hear myself think.
At least they give you a good
meaI before your send-off.
Yeah, like
the electric chair.
- But you, Runner?
- Yes?
You have won a trip
to a tropical paradise.
Oh, "Guadal Kenel"...
"Guada... "
I still can't pronounce it.
Yeah, well, whatever it's called,
you guys are lucky I'm here
'cause I'm planning to take out
an entire Jap regiment all by myself!
How you plan on doing that,
Sergeant York?
Line 'em up, mow 'em down.
Real turkey shoot!
I got a feeling it's gonna be a little
more complicated than that.
No, it's gonna be
a turkey shoot.
Can someone remind me
why we're here again?
We're here to keep
the Japs out of Australia.
- No, we're here to keep the Japs-
- Something about shipping lanes.
No, guys, guys, guys, guys.
Professor Leckie, enlighten us.
Wanna know why we're here?
Mm-hmm.
"Without a sign, his sword
the brave man draws
and asks no omen
but his country's cause. "
Man: Drink up!
Last chance for fresh water!
- Give me back my smokes.
- Leckie, you gotta stop this.
Let's go, boys.
Everybody on deck.
Let's move!
Topside right now!
Wrap it up now.
Get your gear.
Everybody topside for
a pre-landing briefing.
Forget all the horseshit
you've heard about the Japs.
They had their turn.
Now it's our turn.
The treacherous bastards
may have started this war,
but I promise you
we will finish it!
All:
Yeah!
Slant-eyed monkeys
want to use that shit island
and its airfield
to kill us!
We'll yank
the surviving Japs
out of their shit-filled holes
by their yellow balls.
They'll go round-eyed
when the first American plane
lands on their airfield!
Heads down in
the boats!
Hit the beach. Keep moving till you
rendezvous point some primary objectives.
When you see the Japs,
kill 'em all!
All:
Yeah!
- Go!
- Let's go get 'em!
Move it, move it! Hands on the vertical,
feet on the horizontaI.
Make it tight!
Come on!
Hand on the vertical
down there!
I could really use
a stiff one right now.
Go get 'em, navy!
Hoof it up to the beach!
Spread out!
Man:
All right, let's go! Now!
Go go go!
Hit shore, hit shore!
Man:
What took you so long?
Welcome to Guadalcanal.
Man:
Move it up the beach, Marines.
Ah, now I've got you,
you son of a bitch.
Hey, now what
do I do?
I think the islanders use
a machete or a rock.
Try using your head, Chuckler.
It's big and rocklike.
Hey, Johnny Reb.
Man: For what it's worth,
CorporaI Dobson says
the Japs might have
poisoned the coconuts.
They poisoned
a billion coconuts?
Oh, shit!
My hand!
- Excuse me.
- Son of a bitch!
What happened?
Hey, Doc!
Intelligence has it the Japs
moved back into the jungle.
Clean the sand out of your weapons.
We move in three minutes.
Let's go find some Japs.
Oh!
Gibson, you okay?
Fuck.
I'm fine.
You all right?
Thanks.
Goddamn bastards.
Keep it moving.
Man:
Take cover!
- Go go!
- Man: Cease fire!
Cease fire!
Man:
Son of a bitch.
He went to take a piss.
Somebody opened up.
Did he say the password?
I don't know.
Let's start walking.
We're moving to
the top of the ridge.
We're moving!
Jameson:
Corrigan, Stone, get over here.
We've been chasing geese, boys.
That's the 5th Marines
on the airfield.
Guess we took the airfield.
Well, let's go home.
LPs at 300yds,
no fires, two-hour watches.
Let's assume the Japs are
watching right now,
preparing to come at us.
Assume?
They are.
Let the little yellow
bastards come.
- Jesus Christ.
- Unbelievable.
Lord, can you imagine being
on one of those ships?
Looks like
the 4th of July.
Guys?
30 cal ammo.
Thank you,
thank you.
- Hope it was a fucking Jap ship.
- It was- it's gotta be.
That's AdmiraI Turner
blowing the whole Jap fleet
to the bottom of
the channeI.
I love your optimism.
Oh, we're killin' 'em.
Son of a bitch.
Where's the navy?
Gone.
We lost four cruisers.
Turner took everyone left
and headed for open sea.
We're it for now.
The Elliot's with Turner?
Zero crashed
into her midship.
They couldn't control the fire
so they scuttled her.
Bon voyage.
Yeah, well, she went down
with half the battalion's ammo,
most of our grub
and medical supplies
and all our ass-wipe.
Let's dig in, Marines!
Start diggin' in.
- Here.
- Hey, Phillips.
Want some?
It's Jap wine
left behind.
It's made out of donkey piss
but it's not bad.
The Jap navy is right over
the horizon, Phillips.
If not now, then when?
If you can't fight 'em drunk,
don't fight 'em at all.
There you go.
Man: Smoking lamps out!
Pass it down!
- Smoking lamps out.
- Smoking lamps out!
Smoking lamps out.
Smoking lamps out!
- What what?
- Stay low! Stay low!
They're just trying to
spot our position so hold your fire.
Hold your fire. They're just trying to
spot our position.
Hold your fire.
Keep your head down!
They're just trying to
spot our position.
Hold your fire.
Corrigan:
Jesus Christ.
There are thousands
of them.
Man:
The whole damn Japanese Empire.
You four over here.
Coconut plantation
used a cove about 10 miles up.
They're probably
headed there.
Don't get too comfortable
in your holes.
Set in along here.
Watch the opposite bank.
Let's go-
put the hole right here.
Man:
That's good. Keep it coming.
Keep going.
Corrigan:
"A" company made contact
three miles east.
Destroy any letters you have
with any dates...
or addresses.
Man: We got movement!
We got movement!
Hey, look look look!
Get back to your positions!
- Man: Hanging!
- Fire!
Fire!
They're flanking us!
Stand back!
Oh, we gotta move!
We gotta move!
We gotta move over
to the left flank!
Stand back!
Come on!
Come on,
just a few more yards!
60, follow me!
Move into
the forward position!
Skipper!
Skipper, are you okay?
God damn it.
He's lost it. Come on!
Keep moving, keep moving!
Get up here!
- Oh, get up!
- Move!
Left, hold up!
Get in there!
There!
We gotta move! We gotta move!
- We gotta keep moving!
- Yeah! Yeah!
Okay, let's go!
Let's go!
Block them right, God damn it!
Block them right.
Get those bastards runnin'!
All right, ready?
Go go go!
Clear!
Ahhh!
Man: Ammo resupplies
at the collection point.
Smitty, resupply
down the line.
Hey, ammo.
Look at 'em all.
I mean, we- we-
we chewed 'em up.
They just kept
on coming.
A real turkey shoot.
Lucky.
Corpsman,
we got a live one here.
Stick a pin in him, Doc.
- Shit!
- Fucking yellow monkeys!
Shit.
Man: Let's have some fun with
that son of a bitch!
- Ahh!
- Get that fucker!
- Whoo!
- Ahhh!
Ahhh! Ahhh!
Where's your Tojo now?
Run, fucker!
Marine:
Hey, what'd you do that for?
Man:
Gather any papers for S-2.
Jesus, the smell.
They got Rivers,
Morley, Abbott,
Marton, McDougal.
Stanley's blinded.
Captain Jameson's
been relieved.
I better get started on
the letters to their families.
- Want a smoke?
- Thanks.
- Oh, and Jeurgins?
- Sir?
That's a good job
moving around last night.
- Sir.
- Got you promoted to corporal.
Well, we've lost Lew.
"Yes, ma'am,
I am a corporal. "
Oh, shit, these must be
the bastards who took Guam.
I'll be damned.
Robert's voice:
"Dear Vera,
it seems a lifetime since
we met outside Saint Mary's.
This great undertaking
for God and country
has landed us in
a tropical paradise
somewhere in what
Jack London refers to
as 'those
terrible Solomons. '
It is a Garden of Eden.
The jungle holds both beauty
and terror in its depths,
most terrible of which
is man.
We have met the enemy and have learned
nothing more about him.
I have, however, learned
some things about myself.
There are things men
can do to one another
that are sobering
to the souI.
It is one thing to reconcile
these things with God,
but another to square it
with yourself. "
How long you been
sitting on this one?
A week.
Wanted to get it
really ripe for you.
How kind.
Next time don't let it
wait so long.
Man:
This is what they call Guadalcanal.
Runner:
Finally, our reinforcements.
- 'Morning, boys.
- Shit, it's Chesty Puller.
Look at the 7th, all
dressed up for Sunday school.
Hey, you guys forget
to set the alarm?
- Yeah, where you been?
- Up with the sun in Samoa
- screwing your girlfriend.
Oh!
Hoosier: I have a girlfriend?
Lucky me.
Filthy, just like you are.
Hey, Colonel Puller,
where you headin'?
Tokyo.
Care to join us?
I don't know. It's a ways, sir.
Write us when you get there.
- I will!
- You guys step aside.
- The real Marines are here now.
- And have been here for some time.
All:
Yeah!
- 7th Marines!
- Welcome to the war, fellas.
You seen those guys?
They look like they been
through the wringer.
That's one way of
putting it.
"Best wishes, Father.
Your mother would
like to know
if you want us to send you
your dress-blue uniform. "
Must think we get a lot
of fancy-dress balls around here.
Hey, if we have one,
can I be your date?
You are ugly.
I want Hoosier.
Take a number.
Hey, Johnny Reb,
it's your turn.
This one here is from
a buddy of mine back in Mobile.
"Dear Sid, I hope this gets
to you before your birthday.
You wouldn't recognize
home now.
Thousands of workers are
pouring into the shipyards.
The Gulf is blacked out now
because of the U-boats.
Your sister and I went-"
- Sister?
- All: Aww!
"Your sister and I went down to see
the wreckage of a ship they sunk.
She's worried about you,
of course, but I told her
a greaser like yourself is
too crafty for the Japs.
Truth is, you're
the lucky one, Sid.
You'll never have that
nagging thought
that you let your family,
your friends,
and your country down.
Because that's what
I'm afraid of. "
Gear up!
Gun patrol, on your feet.
- Let's go.
- Men: All right, that's it.
Hey, finish it.
"So I'll leave you knowing
that like the poem says,
'You're a better man
than I am, Gunga Din. '
Your humble and obedient
servant, Eugene Sledge. "
So your friend wants
to be a Marine?
Yeah, but his father won't let him.
He's got a heart murmur.
Ah, a murmuring heart.
Hey, when's your
birthday, Sid?
It was a couple
weeks ago.
How old are you?
18.
Happy birthday.