Harry?
Can you hear me?
One way or another,
we all want to escape.
When ordinary life shackles us,
we need to get away.
Get away from boredom.
From pain.
From fear.
[Mouthing]
But not me.
Fear is how I know I'm alive.
Unlike other people,
I don't escape life.
I escape death.
Hell of a way to make a living.
♪ ♪
[Wind whistling]
They say when you're gonna die,
your whole life
flashes before your eyes.
My name is Erich Weiss.
But no one's called me that
in a long time.
I can escape
from almost anything...
Handcuffs, straightjackets...
You name it.
But the one thing I can't
seem to escape from...
Is me.
Harry?
Are you there, Harry?
Can you hear me?
I'm the great Houdini!
Harry?
- sync and corrections by Zac -
- www.addic7ed.com -
♪ ♪
[Thunder rumbling]
17 years before I
jumped off that bridge
was the year
everything changed.
Where are the cuffs?
Uh, right, let's go.
Oh, we're the entertainment.
- You know you're late.
- Yes, it's our mistake.
We were...
We got lost.
Very sorry.
[Indistinct conversations,
laughter]
Up until then, my wife Bess
and I performed
in a two-bit magic act
on the back roads of America.
You booked us into a brothel.
Let's you and me
go upstairs, huh?
Let's go, we're not doing this.
- They hired us.
- Well, I'm unhiring us.
- Come on, let's go. Guys.
- No, no, no, we...
No, no, hold on.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The great Houdini
will escape from this trunk,
confined by these handcuffs.
Yeah. His handcuffs.
Fake.
That's right.
Well, if I had a pair of cuffs
from these premises,
I would happily...
Now you do.
May I ask how it is
that you came to possess...
I'm a cop.
Never mind the trunk.
Let's see you get out these.
[Laughs]
[Thunder crashes]
[Heart beating,
clock ticking quickly]
You mean like this?
[Crowd gasps]
[Short chuckle]
I'll be damned.
[Whooping]
At that moment, I was no longer
just a common magician.
I became something else:
An escape artist.
[Crashing]
[Whoosh]
So I came up with a shtick
that seemed to impress a crowd.
[Roars] [Applause]
[Audience cheering loudly]
But if I did it without
any clothes, well,
then folks really went nuts.
[Audience cheering loudly]
[Harry groaning]
You been drinking, honey?
[Short gasp] One glass.
[Scoffs] [Laughs]
- You got whiskey breath.
- You always
make such a big deal
out of everything.
[Sighs] [Short laugh]
Oh, Harry.
Yes, babe?
We've been at this
for two years.
You ever think maybe
it's time to pack it in?
Honey, I want you
to listen to me.
I'm not going back to piecework
in a necktie sweatshop.
Or be a locksmith.
No.
Not gonna live like my old man.
Like I was never here.
I loved my father.
But...
He was nobody.
I'm not gonna be like him...
Just disappear.
Not unless a million people
are watching.
As far back as I can remember,
I've always wanted to escape.
[Screaming]
My brother Dash
and I would get away
whenever we could to check out
the traveling shows
that came to Appleton.
No, not again.
No, stop.
Stop! No!
Help!
These will make appetizing
treats for my dogs.
Now, I forewarned that
things could get messy.
[Laughing]
Dash couldn't look, but me?
I was hooked.
Mesmerized by the illusion.
Now. I will require some
assistance from the audience.
How about you, young man?
Me?
Yes, please, come up.
Now, if you'll just
- pull this table with me.
- Mm-hmm, okay.
This is a very delicate part.
[Grunting]
Whoa. I think
she's dead.
Why don't you give her a tickle?
[Giggles]
Thank heavens.
Pull yourself together.
One, two, three.
Voilá.
[Applause]
And applause for my
young assistant.
And suddenly,
just like that,
I was somebody.
A boy that knows no fear.
I was going somewhere.
And illusion was my ticket.
[Whooping]
[Crowd gasps]
[Applause]
Mama! Mama!
[Speaking yiddish]
Look what I got, mama.
Oh.
Take it. It's real. Look.
I got another one.
I earned it. It's magic.
[Laughing]
Mama, shake me.
Shake me.
Harder, mama. Harder.
[Laughing loudly]
Shake me. Harder.
If not for my mother,
I would have gone nowhere.
Money for nothing, ma.
[Laughter]
- One day, they'll be gold, mama.
- _
She always believed in me.
_
[Knocking]
Trick or treat!
_
It's Halloween, papa.
You're supposed to
give 'em something.
_
Erich,
papa's gonna say the
brachot! Come down.
Take that off
before papa sees it.
Listen. "A magician is not
really a magician."
He is an actor,
pretending to be a magician!"
An actor.
Eree!
50 years ago, Robert Houdin
was the greatest
magician of all time.
Now it's gonna be me, Howdini!
[Knocking]
_
[Speaking yiddish]
Do you have a minute?
We need to talk to you.
Is there a problem?
Can we talk in private?
You are six
years our rabbi now,
and you still haven't learned
to speak any English.
With all due respect,
rabbi Weiss,
this isn't Budapest.
This is Wisconsin,
and that is why
we can no longer employ
your services as our rabbi.
_
Some things can hit you
in the gut worse than any punch.
I made sure
I'd never be that weak.
I've made some impossible
escapes in my life,
but my greatest escape was
leaving Appleton, Wisconsin.
My travels were short-lived,
but I learned my trade
before reuniting with my family
in Brooklyn.
My father died soon after.
Dash and I teamed up to support
ma with the meager earnings
from our new,
not-so-spectacular magic act.
Come one, come all.
Prepare to be mesmerized by
- the Houdini brothers.
- Excuse me, sir.
- May I borrow your hat?
- Why?
Oh, so I can give you back
your watch.
[Laughter]
You will now give me your hat.
Thank you.
Dash, will you clear
the contents of this hat?
Oh. [Applause]
Pick a card, any card.
Six of spades.
[Piano playing, women singing]
♪ There was a maiden
sweet Rosabelle ♪
♪ the fairest
of all that I know ♪
♪ all the beauties
of heaven... ♪
The only thing more
devastating than a punch to the gut
is an arrow through the heart.
I never even saw it coming.
[Quiet, distant singing]
[Applause and cheering]
Bravo!
So,
this Hungarian Duke
made a play for my mom,
and my dad challenged
the Duke to a duel, right?
[Imitates gunshot]
Bullet went right through
the Duke's brain. Finished.
And my father had
to flee for his life, and, uh,
you know, that's how our whole
family wound up in America.
- It's kind of romantic.
- Yeah.
And then he died.
- Poor man.
- Oh.
Is Harry Houdini
your real name?
It is now.
[Laughs]
- What about you?
- Hmm?
Are those two girls
you sing with...
Are they really your sisters?
No. We just started performing
together this summer.
Yeah?
Pick a hand.
No, not that one.
[Laughs]
Here, open your palm.
- It's pretty.
- Hmm.
Hmm. You're gonna have
to do better than that
if you want to be the greatest
magician in the world.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
How about this?
[Gasping]
[Laughing]
Blow on it.
[Singing]
Oh!
[Laughs]
Oh, look at him go.
[Fireworks popping]
Bess Rahner,
will you marry me?
A week later,
we tied the knot.
That's swell.
I guess you could say...
I want to show you something.
Our wedding night was
perfectly suited for us.
Harry, what are you doing?
- Get in.
- Harry?
Get in, get in.
Come on.
Now, crouch down.
Now, look at that.
You're perfect. I knew it.
Harry. See, Dash is way too big.
All right, now, watch your head.
Harry. Ow!
- All right, now, lift up the latch.
- What are you doing?
- It's right here in the middle.
- Wedding night.
- You find it?
- What? Where?
It's right here. Push it.
There you go.
Harry!
Are you out of your damn mind?
Honey, don't talk like that.
And you don't need
to wear so much makeup
when you're off stage, do you?
You're too cute for that.
You don't need that.
- What about your brother?
- He'll understand.
He'll understand. He knows.
He's too big.
Anyway, you know
what I was thinking?
We don't even need
to change the billing.
The Houdinis.
[Applause]
May I now have my key back?
Thank you.
[Applause]
Mrs. Houdini.
So Bess and I hit the road
with our new collection of...
Eccentric friends.
[Man laughing]
Hmm. Look at that.
Now everybody and his brother's
doing handcuff escapes.
Including my brother.
There's got to be a better
way to make a living.
To really hit it big time,
I had to step off the stage
into the real world.
Come on, sheriff.
What do you got to lose?
I don't lock folks up
less'n they break the law.
Yeah, well,
maybe you just don't have
a whole lot of confidence
in your jail.
Huh, sheriff?
Run along, Mr. hoo-ha.
This is a college town.
I pull a stunt like that,
all the fraternity boys'll
be after me
to do the same with them.
I couldn't afford to advertise,
so I just used those mavens
of mass spectacle, the press,
to spread the word.
Not if you tell 'em
they have to post bail first.
Here's a hundred dollars,
cash on the barrel-head,
says you can't hold
the incomparable Houdini.
- Quote.
- Harry, that's all we have.
It's a hundred bucks.
It's all yours.
Plus,
you get to take a free punch.
I know you're itching.
Come on.
[Harry chuckles]
Come on, sheriff.
Make it count.
Like the man says,
that which doesn't kill you
makes you stronger.
Will wonders never cease?
Did you get it?
Let me check your pockets.
Sure you want
to do this now, sheriff?
It's your funeral.
Harry?
- For luck.
- Thank you.
Hey, open your mouth.
Ah...
One more thing.
You don't get out,
I keep you here overnight
for disturbing the peace.
- Fair enough.
- Let's go, folks.
It was the kiss that
was seen across the country.
Oscar Wilde, Cy Young,
John Philip Sousa...
They had nothing on me.
Soon, the papers
weren't even calling me
an entertainer anymore.
They were calling me
something else.
_
But no matter how big I got,
I always knew that my next
escape would have to be bigger.
I also knew that along the way
someone else was keeping track
of all the headlines for me.
Bess and I were on a roll.
But I was still missing one key
ingredient to take my act
to the next level.
[Chuckles]
[Whooshing sounds]
[Humming]
[Gasping]
Mm.
[Exhaling]
[Chuckles]
[Clears throat]
These look impressive.
State of the art. New York City
police are using them.
I hear chief Rohan's got a pair
he plans to clamp on you
in Chicago.
You're Houdini, right?
Look at this.
It's a rounded key.
I've never seen that before.
I made it myself.
- You made it yourself?
- In my workshop. And look.
Hides in a shirt cuff,
too, see?
Unbelievable.
What else you got?
[Exhales]
Looks like regular picture wire,
totally flexible,
but it has teeth.
It's a hacksaw.
You just destroyed your chair.
[Chuckles]
What's your name, Buster?
Jim.
[Clears throat]
Jim Collins from Macon, Georgia.
That's where I caught your act.
- Right, Georgia.
- You changed my life.
Jim...
You think you can make
an elephant disappear?
- Sir?
- Can you get me out of a block of ice?
I could make you catch a bullet.
Harry,
we got a matinee.
Give me time and I'll figure out
the elephant.
I'll give you time.
Full-time.
- Deal?
- Deal.
[Laughing]
[Chuckles] Honey,
this is Jim.
- Pleasure.
- Amazing.
[Chuckles]
Dearest ma,
next week, I have
a big surprise for you.
I wish I could be there
when you see it,
but, at the moment,
I'm a little...
Tied up.
- Well, I don't know
how they do things
in Detroit, Mr. H.,
but here in Chicago,
when we lock a man up,
we mean him to stay
locked up.
Yeah. Seems like I've heard
that speech before, chief.
You boys having fun?
[Others agreeing]
Come on. I'll need
some help carrying him.
Yeah, great. Good shot, fellas.
Good?
Now, just to be sure...
There's this.
Smile for the birdie, fellas.
[Laughter]
Well, sir, I believe
I'll leave you to your prayers.
[Laughter]
Okay. Come on.
Come on.
[Grunts]
Let's go.
Move it.
Clear out.
[Door lock clicks]
Houdini!
[Horses whinnying]
Dearest ma,
we've come a long way
from Appleton, Wisconsin.
Welcome to Brooklyn.
This is the home
you've always deserved.
[Exhales]
Welcome.
_
[Gunshot]
[Chuckles]
What do you think?
No, no. Not with you
as the shooter.
Not in a million years.
[Chuckles]
All right, where is it?
Let's see it.
Come on.
Jim had been working
on what I had hoped
would be
my greatest escape yet.
The Chinese water torture cell.
Huh?
This was the big time,
the stunt that would finally
put me over the top.
[Knocking on glass]
[Chuckles]
- Let me try it.
- Now? Boss,
you just performed
three shows. You're beat.
Tomorrow. I'll get the boys.
We'll set it up.
Right now.
All right.
All right, boys, lower him.
All right, take it easy.
[Harry grunting]
Come on. Lock
it in there.
[Gurgling]
[Grunts]
Something's wrong.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Pull him up!
Hurry up. Get him out!
Lift him up!
Hurry up!
It's stuck!
[Pounding]
Hey! Pull him up!
Up!
[Harry grunting]
Get him up! Get him up!
Come on! Quick!
[Grunting]
Break the glass.
Break the glass!
Look out!
[Jim grunting]
Boss! Boss!
- Harry?!
- Come on!
- Harry!
- You all right?
[Coughing]
Fantastic.
[Groans]
Ladies and gentlemen,
how long can a man hold
his breath?
Shall we experiment?
[Ticking]
On the count of three,
try to hold your breath,
ladies and gentlemen.
One...
Two...
[Inhales]
Three.
[All inhale]
As you can see, seconds tick by
very slowly.
While they do,
I shall disrobe.
[Murmuring]
My ankles will be shackled
in a secure set of stocks.
Prepare the stocks.
[Snaps fingers]
After being immobilized,
I will be immersed headfirst
in the Chinese water torture
cell.
Captain O'Hare of the
Chicago fire department
is standing by with an axe
in the event
something goes wrong.
[Murmuring] And let's face it,
ladies and gentlemen,
there's always that possibility.
Raise it up, boys.
[Applause continues]
The only way to beat death
is to put your life
on the line.
But why was I so compelled
to beat death?
What was I trying to escape?
Bring out the screen!
One minute!
[Heavy thudding]
[Loud ticking]
Two minutes.
What's going on?
Something's wrong.
[Murmuring]
[Excited shouting]
Three minutes!
You have to help him!
3:15.
[Excited shouting]
Stop it!
Captain O'Hare, come on!
Get in there.
Hurry, hurry.
[Panicked shouting]
[Audience gasps, quiets]
[Audience exclaims]
[Cheering]
[Cheering, whistling]
Enter.
Do you have it?
"Houdini ideal
for our purposes.
"Commencing European tour.
Suggest you contact
- melville soonest."
- Hmm.
Houdini speaks German?
He's an immigrant, yes.
German-speaking Hungarian Jew.
Mr. Wilkie, Houdini's
the most famous man in
America, sure. He now makes
more money than the president.
But when all's said and done,
he's just a magician,
- not...
- Well, what more natural cover
than a traveling entertainer?
God only knows what the
Kaiser is planning.
We don't.
It would be advantageous
to have someone
next to that unpredictable
brain of his.
- What else?
- Houdini's very devoted to his mother.
Sends her money every week,
even when he was broke.
I like a man who
looks after his mother.
Contact Melville.
Set it up.
Way before anyone knew it,
America had teamed up
with England
to keep an eye on the emerging
threat from Germany,
an unexpected eye:
Me.
And so, one of the strangest
illusions I was ever asked
to pull off was something
called espionage.
Not a bad fit, since a magician
can never reveal his secrets.
I take it you weren't
followed, Mr. Houdini.
I made sure that I wasn't.
As instructed.
"Your country needs you.
Come alone."
That's very dramatic.
You were recommended
to us by John Wilkie.
Never heard of him.
Well, that's as it should be.
He's director of the
United States secret service.
I'm sir William Melville,
his British counterpart
in MI-5.
- How do you do?
- Uh, may I have that?
Oh, I'm definitely gonna need
some of those. [Chuckles]
Are you saying
you want me to...
Keep your eyes
and ears open, that's all.
Depend on it...
If war comes,
the United States will fight
on the British side.
What you learn
might help postpone that war.
Maybe prevent it.
Of course, you could never
reveal your services,
but you would have the
satisfaction of knowing
that you had served...
Perhaps even saved...
Your country.
That's a tall order
for a vaudevillian. I...
By the by, we took the liberty
of revising your passport.
Yeah? What was wrong
with my old passport?
We made a slight adjustment
to your place of birth.
- Appleton, Wisconsin.
- Kaiser bill
has only one good arm,
as you may already know,
but it can reach
as far as Budapest.
We thought it prudent
to make you,
shall we say, uh,
all American.
From now on, your place
of birth is officially
the United States.
You could run
for president, sir.
[Short chuckle]
Sir, I-I can't begin to tell
you what this means to me.
We'll think of something.
In the meantime,
think of me in loco parentis.
A sort of
father in residence, no?
[Bell tolling]
Where were you?
Uh...
With Jim.
Jim didn't know where
you were, either.
Is it a girl?
Girl?
No. Honey...
Where did this come from?
Y-you know me better
than that.
- Who is she?
- There is no "she."
- Then where were you?
- I can't tell you, but...
[Exhales]
I'm sorry.
I wish I could. I can't.
- You gotta trust me.
- I have trusted you, Harry.
Bess...
Honey.
Honey...
Trust me.
When does
illusion become a lie?
With illusion,
I could be somebody...
Escape from who I really was.
But when did running away
become so essential to me?
Is that why
I was still running?
From him?
[Gasps]
[Panting]
I guess there are some things
in life you never escape.
Not long after I left Appleton,
I became
a sorcerer's apprentice.
What a load of laughs that was.
Come on.
[Laughing]
Good, kid.
Very good.
Now,
I'm gonna teach you
the floating virgin.
The thing about the floating
virgin of Arkansas...
She was a beautiful girl.
She was a pale girl.
But she loved to
s...leep.
And when she slept,
she... floated.
Come.
Come...
Float!
Float, my sweet little beauty.
Come to me!
Come to me now!
[Laughing]
Look at that kid's face.
Every lesson...
[Train whistle blowing]
Every knock across the chops,
was a building block
towards what I wanted to be.
[Exhales] But was it worth it?
You doing all right out here?
Be reading about
the bullet catch.
Oh, yeah?
Think we should
put it in the show.
It'd put you back on top.
[Exhales] You're good, kid.
Very good.
But not
as good as you think.
Why won't you do it?
It's dangerous,
as I have reason to know.
That's why people
will eat it up.
And who would catch the bullet?
Me.
Say another damn word
about that bullet catch
and I swear,
I'll leave you behind
in the nearest ditch.
My son...
He died doing the catch.
Did you load the gun?
And pulled the trigger, too.
Blew the back of his head off
and his brains with it.
No!
My own boy...
[Sobbing]
- You're a liar.
- Come again?
That story's straight
out of Houdin's book.
[Laughs] How he met
a traveling magician, Torrini,
who'd killed his son
doing the bullet catch.
You're a liar.
Your hero, Houdin,
was a liar, too.
And by the way, it's "who-Dan,"
not "how-din."
Houdin never ran
into any magician
who killed his son,
and that book
you treat like the gospel?
There's only enough truth in it
to make you believe the lies.
Because that's how magic works.
Magicians are liars,
and the best magicians
are the best liars.
Was the dream I was chasing
based on nothing
more than lies?
[Loud lightning strikes]
[Thunder rumbling,
horse neighing]
I was afraid, terrified
of what I might become.
I embraced it anyway.
I became Harry Houdini,
accepting that truth was just
a story made up from a lie.
It was a hard lesson,
but it would serve me well.
My act became the cover story
for my spying.
After five sold-out shows
in Berlin,
the Kaiser requested
a private performance.
Very private.
With your majesty's
indulgence, I...
I propose a demonstration
of famous German marksmanship.
Would you kindly loan me
the use of your most accomplished
rifleman in the royal box?
[Whispering]:
You're sure about this, right?
What?
You're sure, right?
I thought
you said it was foolproof.
What?
I-I said, you said...
Never mind. Go. Go get it.
Your majesty may wish to observe
through his opera glasses.
No.
Okay.
Friedrich, oberstleutnant
der kaiserlichen armee.
Herr oberstleutnant.
Are you a good shooter,
herr oberstleutnant?
- Jawohl, mein herr.
- Great. Hand him the rifle.
I'm sorry it's so old.
It's all we can afford.
Now as you can see,
the bull's-eye stands about,
oh, shall we say, 35 feet
from the shooter?
Herr oberstleutnant,
do you believe
that you can hit
the bull's-eye,
or shall I move you closer?
[Harry chuckles]
Child's play, huh?
Very well. Fire when
you're ready, lieutenant.
[Creaking]
[Applause]
Wonderful shooting,
lieutenant. Wonderful.
I would trust you with my life.
[Applause] Bravo.
Now, let us reload.
It's quite a production,
these old guns.
As you can see, first,
take a measure of powder,
we pour it down the barrel.
This is followed by a wad
of paper, and then the bullet.
Will you inspect the bullet,
lieutenant?
Thank you, lieutenant.
The bullet is now pressed down
with the ramrod, like so.
Does that look
all right, lieutenant?
Jawohl.
Now one last bit
of child's play.
Jim, hand the lieutenant
the musket.
Lieutenant, please take aim
at the bull's-eye again.
I will now attempt to catch
the bullet with my teeth.
[Gasps]
I said, I trust you
with my life, lieutenant.
Now you have to trust me.
Ready?
[Heart beating]
Fire the gun.
Fire!
Fire the gun!
Pull the trigger!
[Echoing]:
Pull the trigger.
[Women gasping]
Pull the trigger!
[Applause and cheering]
[Laughing] Wunderbar!
Is that the bullet?
Jawohl.
Thank you.
Excellent shooting, lieutenant.
Excellent shooting.
Thank you, your majesty.
Once you know the secret,
most tricks are simple...
I owe you.
Including this one.
The bullet is now tamped down
with a ramrod, like so.
- Does that look all right, lieutenant?
- Jawohl.
All it took was a magnet
at the end of the ramrod.
[Applause] Thank you.
[Bell ringing]
Catching bullets
in my teeth was one thing,
but espionage remained
my European mistress,
an altogether
different kind of escape.
Welcome to Budapest,
Mr. Houdini.
My name is Reilly.
Does your hometown
bring back many memories?
Remember,
you've never been here.
Don't look around.
You're merely conversing
with an old friend.
How was Berlin?
I understand
the Kaiser was impressed.
Yeah, enough to invite me to
watch his cavalry maneuvers.
I overheard a few things.
They're building
seven new battleships.
They're not ready yet, but
they're definitely
planning for war.
They call it
the Schlieffen plan.
Schlieffen.
Our friend in London
will be most interested.
Meantime, he sent you a book.
He knows you love to read.
Russian grammar?
"Harry, thought
this would come in handy
for your upcoming trip
to Moscow. Melville."
[Watch ringing]
You have a performance?
Sort of.
My mother arrives on the
afternoon train from Paris.
A trip back to the old country.
How could I possibly
explain what I had in mind?
Oh, look at this. Honey.
Sometimes a guy can't even
tell his own wife about the
plans he has for a new dress.
But ma deserved the best,
because the best is what
she inspired me to become.
And I was finally given
the chance to thank her for it.
[Applause]
What's going on?
Queen for a day.
[Sighs]
Harry told me people
around here thought
his mother married beneath her
to a failed rabbi.
And she goes
along with this?
Of course.
To her, Harry is magic.
[Laughter, applause,
and people exclaiming]
Like I told you, ma...
Money for nothing.
Didn't I promise, huh?
Didn't I tell you,
one day, it'd be gold?
_
[Gasps]
Hey, hello, young man.
[Applause]
For you. Your majesty,
it's an honor
- to play the palace.
- So kind.
I'd love to see if I could make
one of your family's wishes
- come true.
- Oh.
Would each of you write
a special wish
on these slips of paper?
I see your majesty has a faberge egg.
It's very beautiful.
Would you mind if I place
the wishes inside of it?
- Not at all.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
And now,
grand Duchess Anastasia.
Will you draw one out
and hand it to me?
I just realized I
can't read Russian.
[Laughter]
Would your majesty
mind translating for me?
I'm afraid you will
never be able
to grant the wish, Houdini.
Well, let me give it a shot,
your majesty?
- What does it say?
- One of us wishes
you would make Kremlin Bells
ring again.
[Audience murmuring]
Impossible, Houdini.
The Kremlin Bells have not rung
- for... uh...
- Hundreds.
Hundreds years.
The ropes are long rotted
- and the stairs are falling away.
- Well,
if magic were easy,
your majesty,
every fool would be doing it.
[Speaks indistinctly]
[Audience laughs]
What did he...?
Uh, I'm sorry, I...
I don't know the
gentlemen name.
Rasputin.
Rasputin says you are full...
Uh...
Full of...
Ah. I get the general idea.
Well,
we'll see.
[Wind blowing]
[Murmuring]
[Applause]
Grand Duchess Anastasia,
come.
Pull the rope.
[Bell clangs]
Pull it again.
Pull the rope.
[Bell clangs]
Pull it.
So even Rasputin, a man
obsessed with religion
and mysticism,
couldn't see through
my little...
Parlor trick.
Will wonders never cease?
Huh? Hey, big guy,
I bet you'd love
to give me a punch, huh?
Punch?
You know you're itchin'.
One thing I learned
a long time ago...
Never let 'em know
what's really going on inside.
Yeah.
[Murmuring, applause]
[Chuckles]
Thank you.
[Bell clangs]
After that,
I could do no wrong.
We stayed for dinner
and they talked their heads off.
The Tsar thinks he's
going to war with Japan.
If he does, he'll lose.
Russia lose
against little Japan?
'Cause they all take orders
from that Rasputin character.
They do whatever he
says. It's crazy.
A mad monk in command? Why?
Well, it seems he's got a
little magic act of his own:
He's the only one who can keep
the tear's son from bleeding.
Of course.
The boy's a hemophiliac.
They'd do anything to
keep Rasputin happy.
He's not their only
problem. There's...
Social unrest everywhere.
One of these days, the whole
place is gonna explode.
So we hear.
Very good, Harry.
Most instructive.
So, tell me, how did you get
the Kremlin Bells to ring?
Well, that was the only
wish I was ready for.
And now, grand duchess
Anastasia, will you take one out
and hand it to me?
So then I said to her,
"I just realized I can't
read Russian." [Chuckles]
Uh, would your majesty
mind translating for me?
It was snowing so
hard I was worried
Jim wouldn't be able
to see the rope.
Harry:
Pull the rope.
[Bell clangs]
Pull it.
[Gun clicking]
They were convinced
I had spiritual powers.
And do you?
[Chuckles]:
Yes, I know.
What are your plans? Uh...
Will you return to the States?
Well, not until I figure
out something new.
Now everybody's
copying my routine.
And my name.
Blondini, Handini,
Berlini. [Laughs]
I think you need
a new challenge.
The Adelphi Theatre
is just a stone's throw
from the German embassy.
- So?
- So...
We're reliably informed
there's a copy
of the Schlieffen plan
in the safe
in the ambassador's office.
What an extraordinary stroke
of luck it would be for us
if you managed to lay
your hands on it.
You'd have a perfect alibi...
Handcuffed on stage.
Safe, huh?
[Chuckles]
Which is how I happened
to wind up in one.
[Applause]
But not that safe.
It was a different safe.
[Clicking and scratching]
The one inside
the German ambassador's office.
But let me start
from the beginning.
[Audience applauds nearby]
Soon after the act started,
I wasn't even inside
the safe anymore.
Jim had told the audience
I had about ten minutes of air.
Audiences go nuts
for a ticking clock.
[Audience murmuring]
Where is he?
He didn't tell me, Mrs. H.,
but he promised
he'd be back in time
to finish the show.
Back from where?
Uh, I really don't know.
Oh, I can't do this anymore.
This is killing me.
[Grunting]
[Audience clamoring]
Get him out!
Tonight is our
tenth anniversary,
and I know he's
going to forget.
I know it.
[Lock clicking]
[Door opening]
[Door closing]
♪ ♪
[Door opens nearby]
[Man speaking German]
[Door closes] [Woman laughing]
Right in here.
Voilá!
[Man chuckles]
Oh!
Mm-hmm.
[Laughs]
[Both mumbling]
- Mm.
- Oh!
[Indistinct chatter]
Oh. [Giggles]
Ah.
[Footsteps approaching]
[Door slams]
[Heavy breathing]
[Audience clamoring]
Get him out!
Jim stalled for time
like the pro he was.
But we both knew I had to be
back for the grand finale.
Mr. Houdini?
Mr. Houdini!
The grand finale that even had
a special surprise for Bess.
[Woman moans, laughs nearby]
All I had to do
was get out of a safe
I'd never been in before.
And there wasn't any air
in this one, either.
My brain is the key that sets
me free.
My brain is the key
that sets me free.
Try to remember the arrangement
of locks, gears
in a Jarvis safe.
[Panicked shouting]
Open it!
Joe, bring the tools!
Bring the tools!
Open up!
[Clicks]
[Scrapes]
Man:
Get him out!
[Indistinct chatter]
All right.
[Exclaims, giggles]
[Murmuring]
Finally, that old ambassador
remembered where
the bedroom was.
[Clicking]
[Gasping, exclaiming]
[Cheering]
Hey.
Got into the German safe.
Literally.
Sorry, I'm late for celebration.
A letter!
Crazy!
Is that addressed to my wife?
[Shocked murmuring]
Mrs. Houdini.
Mrs. Houdini!
All that time...
Fantastic!
[Applause]
[Gasps]
[Cheering]
What does it say, honey?
Read the note, nice and loud.
"Thank you for the ten
most wonderful
years of my life."
[Audience aahs]
"Your loving husband,
Harry."
[Women exclaiming]
Congratulations.
[Gasps]
Oh!
Happy anniversary, honey.
Happy anniversary.
And she thought I forgot.
[Laughter]
Anyway, thanks for
sticking around for
the grand finale, folks.
Thank you.
[Applause, cheering]
Bravo!
Aw, that was swell, honey, huh?
That was a surprise.
That was all for you.
No. No, it was not for me.
It's never just for me.
- What?
- It's for them.
It's for the act.
It is always for the act
- and you and I both know it, Harry.
- No.
Ah!
What are you trying
to prove, Harry?
How brave you are?
How American you are?
I... just tell me what it is.
Tell me, what?
I... don't mean to intrude, but
the car's here.
Uh...
You still going
to Lady Butler's?
Ugh...
Honey, I'm sorry.
I know.
It's... it's...
It's in our honor.
- It is in your honor.
- Sweetheart,
let's just make
an appearance, okay?
I promise, 30 minutes, tops.
It's Lady Butler.
[Guests laughing, chatting]
_
That Rasputin character
packed quite a wallop.
I tell you, he was a regular
John l. Sullivan.
I could take the punch,
but he knocked me out
with his vodka breath,
you know?
[Laughing]
- Really?
- Yeah.
[Gasps]
Ooh, I say.
- Mind if I make myself comfortable?
- By all means.
That's the true
truth, isn't it?
Very likely.
[Laughing]
Oh...
You are very pretty.
♪ ♪
Yes, sir.
Some things can
hit you in the gut
worse than any punch.
I'm sorry, what did you say?
Actually, give me a moment.
♪ ♪
Hi, Harry.
[door open]
[Harry grunts, glass shatters]
Oh, Harry.
I'm gonna kill myself.
Well, that's what
I'm always saying.
What, is that funny?
Is that funny?!
Oh, for heaven's sake.
What are you so upset about?
You were... kissing him.
You were kissing him!
No, I wasn't.
- Yes, you were!
- No, I was not!
And until you looked over,
you didn't know where I was at
that party and you didn't care.
- So stop being dramatic.
- You're my wife.
You're the wife
of the great Houdini!
Really?
I thought I was just
a woman you put in a trunk
and took out
when you felt like it.
[Footsteps receding]
[Door open closes]
What do you do
when you hit rock bottom?
[Woman laughs]
You keep digging.
Divine creature...
Hmm... [Giggles]
[Harry moans]
[Woman sighs in pleasure]
[Chuckles, woman laughs]
See...
If you can escape.
Would you like me
to release you?
Oh...
By this point,
I really wasn't up for this.
[Engine buzzing]
Shh.
Be right back.
That's when I discovered
my next escape.
What is it?
[Engine buzzing] I don't know.
A glorious one.
[Buzzing]
Will wonders never cease?
Houdini...
I don't know how
these things work in America,
but in London it's
considered impolite...
- Huh?
- To keep a lady waiting.
[Someone whistles]
Uh-huh.
[Chuckling]
Yeah. You...
[Giggles]
Ah...
[Laughs]
[Laughing]
[Laughs softly]
[Continues laughing]
[Sighs] Mmm...
Where are you?
Start without me.
What?
[Airplane buzzing]
Where are you going?
- Keep the chains.
- What about the key?!
What are you doing here?
I had a feeling
you'd be leaving.
Get me one of those.
What do you want
an airmobile for?
_
You know how it is
when you fall in love.
Flying was all
I could think of.
This time, Bess's only rival
was an airplane...
And for years, it was our
carriage to the world.
Harry!
[Harry laughs]
- Do you trust me?
- Shit, Harry!
Language, honey, please.
But everything changes.
Even flying lost its novelty.
I was falling back to earth,
and on earth,
things were changing, too.
♪ ♪
[Clock ticking]
[Locks clicking]
[Squeaking]
But audiences had grown numb
to the thrill.
[Cheering]
I hadn't played
to a sold-out house
in quite some time.
But I wasn't finished escaping.
Not quite.
You didn't grease the collar!
Sure I did.
Like hell!
Your disloyalty cost me
ten seconds.
Disloyal? I...
It's when you do it
with the water
instead of the milk.
Don't give me that.
Just 'cause there's
nobody out there
doesn't mean
that the ones that are
don't deserve the best
of the great Houdini.
You're fired.
Again?
[Door opens, closes]
Vaudeville's in trouble.
Nowadays folks are going
to moving pictures.
Ah, movies!
If it was a tough escape,
the whole movie
would be finished
by the time I made it.
And the suspense
wouldn't be the same.
Maybe you could fill
a smaller theater.
"A smaller theater"?
Me?
Sol, what are you saying?
The writing's
on the wall, Harry!
No!
I write the damn writing!
[Audience laughing]
There's your new competition.
He's not doing anything.
He's making them laugh.
That's all right.
My audience loves me.
They'll come back.
I just need something new.
What about the elephant?
It's not an escape.
It needs to be an escape.
[Audience laughing]
[Laughs]
Laugh again and you're fired.
[Thud]
"Smaller theater." Please.
Escapes can get smaller,
they have to get bigger.
People expect more from
the great Houdini.
Not less.
Maybe people are
tired of escapes.
Huh?
You've done enough of them.
What kind of tobacco is that?
Mexican.
- Pepe gave it to me.
- Who? "Pepe"?
What? From the band?
[Scoffs]
Smells weird.
Well, he said it would help
with my nerves.
He's right.
[Sighs]
What the heck is bigger?
Play the grand canyon,
why don't you?
[Laughs]
Yeah, get me room 202.
Jim?
Bring up some ice.
No. I mean a lot of ice.
[Door opens]
[Buckets clanging]
[Door closes]
[Water sloshing]
Evening, Mrs. H.
What the hell is
going on in here?
- Language, honey, please.
- What are you doing?!
- Uh, thanks, Jim.
- You got it, boss.
If I can't bring the folks
to the theater,
I got to bring the theater
to the folks.
What does that mean?
Well, movies can outdoors,
so can I.
[Laughs] Oh, Christ, Harry.
Harry?
[Sighs]
- I got to pee.
- Yeah, five more minutes, honey.
It's all yours.
We've been married 19 years.
You can watch me pee.
Yeah, I don't want
to watch you pee.
[Groans]
[Yells]
I expected the Mississippi
to be cold,
but this was ridiculous.
Well, that's that.
Maybe they could cut
a hole in the ice.
Harry, no.
Are you kidding?
You'd kill yourself.
Well, 12, 15 feet should do it.
Honey, don't worry.
Oh, "honey," my ass.
You want me to stick around
to find out if I'm a widow.
You may be crazy, Harry,
but I'm not.
Sweetheart, please.
Go to hell, Harry!
- 15 feet?
- Make it 12.
Honey?
It's just a li-little ice.
♪ ♪
[Mouthing]
Put an ad in the paper
and tell people
you're gonna do something crazy
Tuesday at noon,
and a thousand people
will show up Tuesday at noon.
Throw in a chance
of me getting killed...
- Come on, Harry!
- Hi!
You have to beat them back
with a stick.
It was the wrong moment
to start thinking.
If I started to think,
I might forget who I was.
The great Houdini.
[Audience gasping, murmuring]
[Excited chattering]
Is he still down there?
♪ ♪
[Yells]
[Grunting]
_
- sync and corrections by Zac -
- www.addic7ed.com -