Showbox/Mediaplex
presents
a Showbox/Mediaplex
and MaysEntertainment production
in association with AzitFilm
LOSING MOVE:
A BAD MOVE TO CAUSE THE DEFEAT
You have 30 seconds left.
30, 29, 28...27, 26, 25...
, 23, 22...
Put up an umbrella.
Is it you?.
I saw your game.
One false move ruined it.
I'm sorry.
Fight like a man.
Never back off.
Where have you been?.
We can chat later.
I've got a favor to ask you now.
Play a guidance game for me.
Guidance game?.
With whom?.
Don't ask too much.
It won't take long.
Can we just go home today?.
I have a bad feeling for this.
Don't worry. We'll win.
What kind of game is it?.
Play as you always have.
Will be easy.
Do you dabble in gambling?.
None of your business.
Tae-seok!
Tae-seok! Tae-seok!
Wait! Tae-seok!
Listen to me.
Remember one thing.
Do not ever lose.
Understand?.
Gotta win.
Just trust me.
Nothing bad will happen.
On 5 and 1 2.
Your skill's improved drastically.
It's just luck.
You're sweating.
Why don't you take the jacket off?.
True dandies can sweat to death
for the sake of fashion.
Is it so?. Don't get it as I'm a swagger
only in winter.
Wow, he is the tough match!
He has a sharper's move.
A real pro.
Take over.
Boss, I can handle this.
Sit.
On 1 2 and 1 2.
Stretch.
On 6 and 6.
I can't hold it.
Will be right back.
You go on.
Brother.
Can you hear me?.
On 9 and 1 2.
Attack.
On 1 3 and 8. Escape through
Large Knight's move.
On 7 and 4.
- How's it going?.
- It's strange.
- Why?.
-He suddenly got much stronger.
How come the Black is
suddenly moving so fast?.
Holy cow!
What is wrong with me?.
I'm sorry. Need to
go to toilet again.
I can't see the board right now.
Wait a bit.
Do not make any move.
You're slower than usual today.
Can you hear me?.
Just linger over.
No, that's the wrong spot!
Don't put it there.
Please don't!
Finish it.
Brother, something's wrong.
Come out right now!
You hear me?.
Get out of there!
Tae-seok!
I'm sorry.
You little prick.
Having a shadow player
at a gentlemen's game?.
You should at least
keep your manners!
Even the money is fake.
You know the rules for that?.
Please, don't!
Quiet.
I'm sorry, sir!
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive us.
- Shut the fuck up!
- Brother!
Brother!
Wait! We're not done yet.
Eat the stones up.
Or your lovely brother is dead.
If you win,
I'll let your brother go.
Start.
You can't retreat a move.
It just dropped!
I call the rules.
That's nonsense...
Please let me retreat one move.
Just one move.
Please...
Do not kill my brother.
I'm sorry.
Please do not kill him.
My brother...
I.... I'm done!
There's one left!
GO and life are quite similar.
One false move can
lead you to death.
Brother!
Look at the true dandy stabbed to death!
Only stones on the board
revive once they get killed.
JUNG Woo-sung
LEE Bum-soo
AHN Sung-ki
KlM ln-kwon
LEE Si-young
AN Kil-kang
CHOl Jin-hyuk
THE DlVlNE MOVE
Mr. Director, I'd like to have
a couple of days' leave-time.
Leave-time?.
Need to check the regulations
Should be quite tight on mops.
You know, Japanese police
once investigated
a sample of 500 criminals
and found one common point.
Can you guess what it was?.
Not a single one played GO.
What should it mean?.
That the criminals who play GO
seldom get caught.
The ones playing GO
Why?.
They're ahead in moves.
In that sense, I can say
you're one of two cases.
Whether you cannot play GO,
or are very dumb.
A week will do.
Win a game against me,
then I'll let you go out.
A large group got captured.
Did he catch me here?.
It seems so, bro.
It's like I'll go dying
stuck in this prison.
Not yet.
Let him come near.
A large group of stones
is seldom captured.
Play a game with a man here.
He's quite good.
No one's ever beaten him.
You damn fucker.
I like you!
I got bored to play
with the dumpsters.
One more game!
And don't forget to make a bet.
He's addicted to it.
Please do me a favor if I win.
Tell me.
I want beer, cigarette and
free time till I serve my sentence.
Wanna play for stakes?.
Only if you allow me.
Then what's your bet?.
You won.
Request for Ieave-days
GRANTED
But you'll have one month
in solitary cell for being cocky.
A gae, please?.
On 7 and 3.
On 5 and 1 2.
On 1 2 and 9...
Who are you?.
Let me at least
know your name.
Your company obliterated
my Ioneliness. Thanks.
Look for Drinking Christ
at Gwancheol when you go out.
Thanks for your trouble.
Now I'll have some free time.
Please train me how to fight.
Wow! Unbelievable.
Help yourself!
I got the first prize!
Wanna work for me
when you go out?.
Got a work to do.
Please do me one favor.
I need some money.
Will pay you back.
It's me who owed you.
Will buy a drink.
As long as you are alive
till I get out.
Was a tough search.
She's a real treasure.
He had a hard time to trace it.
Two.
He asks for two million.
You've got 1 0mins. Test her.
It would be too short.
Those are questions of
life and death. You know it?.
Ten mins to solve everything.
Understand?.
You take the black.
Get the white.
Changing the amount.
Pay three million.
Fuck off if you can't pay that.
He now wants 3M.
Wait!
Call me any time when
you have good stuff.
Go kill them.
But bring the girl alive.
Bring Navel in.
Could you play a game with me?.
This is not a ladies' game.
Play by territories?.
No, let's do it by games.
All in.
Master Noh, You'd better focus on training
the young now that you retired.
Who the hell are you?.
You don't belong here.
You're still okay, I guess.
Don't eat too much.
Chubby girls aren't charming.
Do you offer a special service to boss?.
He treats you too well.
You can play a game
for your life if you dare.
You can put stones
on two points first.
Guess you're intimidated.
Thought of putting
a special service as a bet.
Oh, I forgot
you can't come.
Stick to what you are.
Using your dumb brains
should make you ill.
Don't you agree?.
Thanks for the advice.
Damn, I can surely come.
Good job.
Take that kid.
Wash and feed her.
I'm not really into parenting.
I'm hungry.
How old are you?.
Seven?.
Eight?.
You're ten years old.
Your name?.
Liang Liang?.
PLACEMENT: PUT A STONE
ON THE BOARD
When's your mom coming?.
Why?.
Dead.
Do you play GO?.
No, Five in a Row.
Grandma said she'll kill me if I play GO.
Are you really my uncle?.
See you soon.
I cannot read
the moves well today.
I was just lucky.
Sir, can I play a game
with the gentleman there?.
Mr. Cho, he wants
to play a game with you.
You have similar levels.
I lost this time too.
One more game?.
Aren't you broke?.
Think I got $500 left.
Why don't you save it
for rainy days?.
Then how about
flicks on the forehead?.
Wait a bit more.
Just one hour.
Have you collected money?.
- Of course! Perfectly done.
I'm playing with a pushover
I ribbed off him $1 0K already.
This broke blockhead
lost his temper
and wants to put the bashes
with knuckles as a bet!
Sir.
Why don't you go out
and drink while we play?.
Alright! Well...
Shall we count?.
Let's see.
I won by half a territory.
I can see you're good at counting.
Then...
Let me see.
You keep the change
as the winner's tip!
We had one more bet.
What?.
Ten blows with the knuckles.
You are mad as you lost a lot today?.
You're quite persistent.
Got it.
Give me a blow!
Then....
You should at least
keep your manners!
Hit me.
Are you fucking crazy?.
You fucker, where shall l
put your dead body on?.
The left corner or right?.
Or on the center of the board?.
Son of a bitch!
Untie right now!
Do you hear me?. Hey!
What the hell!
Who are you?.
Guess you didn't study over.
What?.
What are you talking about?.
You little prick.
I can see you surely grew up.
So what do you want me to do?.
What shall I do for you?.
What are you doing?.
Oh, I see.
Hit me! I'm not afraid!
Two more blows to go.
Son of a bitch.
You can go to hell doing this.
I'm wondering if your brother
digested all by now.
The stones in his stomach.
The real game starts from now.
You play with your hand, not your tongue.
It's Atari!
Can you just shut up
and play?.
Damn, I should've noticed this trick.
What trick?.
My life's been all about fair play.
There are black stones all over.
It's like the coal mine.
Hello?. Wait there.
It won't take long
as I'm inside the building.
Didn't you lie about
your level, did you?.
If I were any better,
I should go pro.
I never lie about two things.
My GO level and my stamina.
Thanks for the good match.
Catch that prick!
Help me! Help!
Please help me. Do not kill.
You tried to cheat us?.
It was a fair game...
Wanna cough up the money
or the blood in your body?.
Money, of course!
Can I have him for a while?.
What?. Are you with him?.
You know Woo-seok?.
No.
Mr. Song Woo-seok.
Who are you?.
I know! I know, I know him!
I remember you!
Younger brother of Woo-seok!
So you were alive?.
Wow it's thrilling.
My first time to team up with a pro.
Wow, look at this place.
It's more like a blockbuster.
How did you meet my brother?.
You really don't know?.
We were the same team.
A team to survive.
Your brother was a well known devil.
I mean, a professional gambler.
Poor Woo-seok.
He shouldn't have died like that.
Have you seen this guy?.
You know, I pulled out of
the league long time ago.
You go on your own.
I'm out of this.
Join me if you change your mind.
You'll get the half of the profit.
3 million.
I am back not because of the money!
But because I want to repay
your brother's kindness!
I got you, right?. I'm good at acting,
I know.Am I in?.
Hey, Big Move.
What kind of GO master
plays at a place like this?.
No way! Not a chance.
Listen. Just two of us can have it all.
We don't need more players.
It gets too complicated.
You're stubborn as a mule.
Wait, master Song!
Is this stone dead or what?.
Guess I had a better luck.
How come the large group die?.
Damn!
Don't tell me it's THE master.
Excuse me, sir.
Could you please have
a hand talk with me?.
Don't know how to talk with hands
but surely know how to talk with drinks.
The bet is a bottle of drink.
Please teach me a lesson, sir.
I lost by half a territory.
You're much stronger than me.
Why sounding me out?.
Let's have a drink.
Okay. Let's get baptized
by the sacred water.
Now I know why people
call you Drinking Christ.
It's so good.
Have we met before?.
Definitely not.
What happened to your eyes?.
Was an accident.
I also lost my eye
in the accident.
I've got a plan.
Just take care of
the other eye.
We can win.
That blind belief
drives people to death.
Will you join us?.
Thank you for the drink.
Does the blind
dream a dream?.
Sure, mostly a nightmare.
How about when you're awake?.
The nightmare continues.
Guess she's your daughter.
How does she look?.
Good and sound.
Why don't you decide?.
What's your name?.
You can call me Big Move.
You call me Agnus Dei!
Let's go.
Are you here, Carpenter?.
I think you've got lost.
It's been a while.
Can we talk for a minute?.
Guess you're still drunk.
You go your way.
Can I have water?.
Here you are.
Why?. You thought I lost
both of my hands?.
I'm sorry.
We were quite okay once.
The happy ending's not
for the gamblers.
What brings you here?.
I'll fight against them again.
Then this is the last time
that I see you alive.
Help us.
OPENING: ENCAMP FOR THE BATTLE
I've been to gambling house
run by Killer.
It's perfectly organized.
He's Player.
He's good at acting
in addition to GO itself.
He's more like a manger
of the house.
Gamblers around the nation
gather here and play.
Cannot cheat each other...
as everyone is better than average.
Some games have huge bet.
That's the VlP room,
they get 1 0% of the bet as fee.
Player induces some rich people
to play with him.
Mainly the rich businessmen
or ones in specialized jobs,
who have high pride
and are very competitive.
We got the real pushover!
Once trapped, it would take
less than a month to go broke.
That snake-like old man is a kibitzer.
He's Master Wong.
He runs a calligraphy academy
but it's just a front.
The monthly tuition is $50 for
children and $70 for adults
but the term begins from 3-month-course.
So greedy.
Skills are great.
That ugly son of a bitch
in flower shirt is Atari.
He's the collector and looks after
illegal online gambling, too.
The meanest of all
is this one, Killer.
Damn violent
son of a bitch.
Hey Big Move!
Can we leave him alone?.
Who's that girl?.
Damn. Attention everyone!
Open your eyes, Drinking Christ.
Have you heard of Goddess Bar?.
25-year-old Kwon runs it.
She turned pro at 1 5.
Gold medalist at Doha Asian Games.
World Champion in 2006.
But retired and disappeared
when she became only 20.
And ta-da, she now runs this bar.
They call her Navel.
Navel is another term
for flower point in Go.
I think she belongs to Killer.
I need to go after this game.
Let's play for one more hour.
Finally the game starts to go well.
Sorry sir.
My wife is pregnant.
What?. Why did you make
such a bad move?.
Well, I won this time too.
$600 each, please.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- It's your lucky day.
- I guess so.
Hey, young man!
Come and join us if you are here to play.
What do you do for a living?.
I did some research in school.
Research?.
You mean a professor?. What major?.
Math.
Math! Which university?.
I have a friend
at Seoul National Univ.
He had a stroke
while playing mah-jong with me.
But when I said we were
short of one to play,
he suddenly woke up
and played again!
Anyway, great to meet you.
You know what is most difficult
in playing mah-jong?.
Nine Gates?. Hell no.
To gather four to play a game.
Such a hassle.
How did you find this place?.
I've been here long before.
Don't recall. I'm quite good
at remembering faces, though.
I was much different then.
You also play GO?.
More as a hobby.
I also play it a bit.
Let's play together someday.
Have we met before?.
Well...
Thank you for the talk.
I can't do it!
What is Carpenter doing?.
Making a chair or what?.
Give it to me.
Wow, you can make
this kinda stuff, too!
You look a bit awkward.
What can you see?.
Driver's License
YOOK Jong-duck
6 Ducks Entertainment!
I can feel a sexy vibe.
Lost again!
This seat is ill-fated!
This seat too! And this, too!
I'm getting ripped off!
Where is the lucky place?.
Hey, the cigarette!
Going broke!
- One more game!
- No problem!
You don't have 1 mm?.
You wanna suffocate me
with strong nicotine?.
One more game!
You have it all!
- One more game. Wait here. Do not move!
- I won't.
Wait right there!
I need some money here.
You! You don't look like
a brainy type.
You can read the face?.
Then change your job.
My brain cells are all dead!
- What is he doing?.
- Making adult videos.
How much did he spend?.
Hundred thousand.
Low in skills but high in pride.
A perfect target for us.
HAENGMA: EXPAND THE STRENGHT
IN HARMONY
Carpenter, did you have a test on this?.
Not a cheap stuff?.
I need additional amount
for risking my life.
The smoking will kill me
even if I don't get stabbed.
Stop drinking!
How can you kibitz?.
Low level player worries much.
You haven't thought
I could be a master in disguise?.
I sometimes think so
seeing you
regard this world
as a playground.
As this world is a playground
for the mater
and a living hell
for the low player.
Then I should be
the bottom of the lowest.
For me, the world
is the endless hell.
Go for a fast attack. Divide
wedge through the center of the left.
Approaching on 3 and 6.
Lower Pincer by one space.
On 1 2 and 1 2.
On 1 6 and 9.
On 1 0 and 9.
Good job.
Hey!
Search this bastard.
What are you talking about?.
Losing temper for losing once?.
I had lost enough here!
Let go of me, shitheads!
Found nothing?. Then I have to see
the manager. I'm clear. Poor you!
Losing is painful,
you know that now?.
You petty bastard!
I will kill you, son of a bitch!
You're dead today!
What the hell are you?.
Mind your own boards!
Mind your own games, I said!
Sir.
- Would you have a game with me?.
- I'm not in the mood.
Don't let a petty bastard
ruin your mood.
How strong are you?.
What matters is not the level,
but the condition of the day.
Right, just like making love.
Let me get some fresh air first.
Sure.
I hate cigarettes.
Have I told you already
how much I'm amazed
by your marvelous survival skills?.
Speak for yourself.
Not many options
for low lives like us.
I'm not like you.
I'm playing in the center stage.
We're in different leagues, dude.
Center or corner, the last man
standing gets all the bets.
A hell of disguise...
Fuck off!
Such a rat.
Here we are again.
We're meant to
live like this, I guess.
Have you seen a divine move?.
No, I haven't.
Is there such a move
in our life?.
A move so divine that can change
our life drastically.
Only God has the answer.
For what would you use
such a move?.
I will save my wife.
And get your arm back.
There's a better move.
Use it to go back to when
you didn't play for money.
I won.
Congratulations.
It's your jackpot day.
I'm done here.
What's up again today?.
My luck's finally getting in.
It's my wedding anniversary.
Damn the anniversaries.
Mr. Oh, come join us.
How can you make a living
as you quit teaching?.
I'm building a program.
A program?. What kind?.
Kind of algorithms for GO.
Al...what?.
A computer program
that can beat humans
in GO games.
What's the use for computers
to win humans in GO anyway?.
Like it's not hard enough for us.
I won.
What the hell?.
Nine Gates?.
It's a once a lifetime luck!
Congratulations, really.
Thank you.
Let me buy you the dinner.
Of course, you should!
I have to go, sorry.
You should not go home today.
It'd bring you bad luck.
You should play all night.
Where should we go?.
I know a good lamb place.
You'd better go home.
I won first.
But passed for you.
- Didn't know that.
- Better watch out.
As you had once a lifetime luck today,
you might die anytime soon.
I was dead already.
I've got no more life to lose.
Caller ID: Killer
Hello.
What is he?.
He really is a programmer.
His hands look too rough
for a computer guy.
He may smash keyboards
when pissed off.
Feel like joking?.
Guess the date was fun.
Partners shouldn't have secrets.
No partnership is eternal.
And your bad fortune this year
could affect the business.
I saved your mother.
Now you forgot the terms?.
It's a lifetime deal.
Terminates only when you're dead.
You never know.
Your death could also terminate it.
You always commit errors
in the final moves.
Don't try too much.
You're a dead-end ladder.
You'll end up dead
how hard you try.
Watch out the ladder breaker
when you kill. You could miss it.
A common mistake for low ranks.
It's not easy...
Hopeless bastard.
How did it go?.
What keeps you so busy?.
Share the fun stuff with us.
How was it today?.
Christ had hell of good moves.
Masters never hesitate on moves.
Go by yourself tomorrow.
You want me to walk alone
into the lion's den?.
Don't worry.
He will let you win.
What does that mean?.
Hey, tell me!
Today's not the day for me.
Thanks for a good game.
- It's for your fare.
- That's alright.
Indeed a cool guy!
How about betting bigger next time?.
Why not?.
You're a dead meat!
DANSOO [ATARI]: ONE MOVE AWAY
FROM CAPTURING OPPONENT'S STONE.
It's what I do.
Target market is China.
It's the second biggest
movie market.
Care for a sneak preview?.
Let's start the game.
- Right away?.
- Sure.
I'll have to take a leak first.
Try this in your mouth.
It gives you a vibe.
This business is in recession, too.
People watch porn on their mobile
nowadays. So it doesn't earn any dime.
Movies must have soul in it.
But it's all about groaning now
What will the youngsters
learn from it?.
Can't help but worrying
about this country's future.
Are you OK with this place?.
Feel sorry that I chose
my home grounds.
- Let's keep it quiet.
- This is how I loosen up.
- How about having a smoke?.
- I quit.
Lung is such a delicate organ
that can be compared to a lotus...
Keep your mouth shut, I said.
Oh my God, what's this?.
I thought I lost but
I won by one and a half territory?.
I will keep this in custody.
It's heavy.
Show some respect, dude.
How much did you lose?.
Two large bills.
How large?.
2millions?.
Since when did you become
such a pushover in this field?.
Don't get on my nerves.
There's a saying.
Pride goes before a fall.
Never be off guard
at this level of games.
Shut up and help me tomorrow.
By the way...
Does Killer know about this?.
Don't wag your tongue.
What's the split?.
60, 40 as always.
Let's do 50, 50.
Trying to negotiate with me?.
Well, I'm not the one
who's cornered now.
Greedy ones can never
get old graciously.
If you look at me like that again,
I'll make sure you're dead.
- You don't have to count?.
- No need.
It feels better counting at home.
You won't have to
count anything today.
It's Dansoo, Atari!
I can see it.
Shut your mouth.
Who's this bastard?.
He's not taking the bait!
On 5 and 9.
Don't exhale right to my face.
Tons of trick moves...
I recognize this play pattern.
Long time no see, you kibitzer.
Take the bait,
you son of a bitch!
Bastards!
Didn't you quit?.
I quit quitting.
I got dumped by a chick.
I am getting curious
how big your mouth could be.
This son of a bitch!
He's now playing me?.
Player, on 6 and 4.
He's pushing forward.
Women are scary creatures.
We've been together quite long
but she cut me off at once.
Quite similar to GO.
When they cut you off,
This motherfucker
is totally playing me!
they do it mercilessly.
They're messing with us!
Screw the game!
You didn't hear me?. Screw it!
What the hell!
Please don't kill me!
I beg you.
Make sure to give me
additional share!
I don't think I invited you.
Use the dagger if you want.
Came for a brain game
but now forced to use the body.
It's a part of the game, too.
Beat him to death!
I'll have to let you
play alone, Player.
What the hell!
Hold on tight!
SPIN AROUND ATTACK:
ATTACKING BY SERIES OF FATAL MOVES
The rule is simple.
Only winner can get out.
What's all this about?.
Let's play a quick game
as it's cold in here.
You should play a move before
the sandglass is done. After you.
Come on!
Look at the winter swagger
frozen to death.
Look at the true dandy
stabbed to death!
This is case of life and death.
Only one point to make the stones live.
That's the padlock code.
I need a drink.
A warm one.
You look terrible.
How about playing a game?.
For fun or for a bet?.
Well, you'll get more fun
by betting on something.
So what should be the bet?.
Granting a wish?.
Too childish.
Childish, but of tradition.
The board is unique.
Are they goddesses?.
Goddess of fortune and
goddess of destruction.
- Which one's for me?.
- Destruction suits you better.
The width of board is 45cm.
The perfect distance
to share feelings.
How can people
share the feelings?.
It would be more like
making you mine.
Dansoo.
I won't be easy.
Good move.
I was just lucky.
Be careful making a wish.
You're definitely
getting my attention.
How about playing a game?.
It'd be exciting
to put our lives as bet.
I like it.
Can't wait to see you.
I left you a gift
at the calligraphy academy.
Also turn off the freezer.
And open the cabinet.
Open the cabinet!
Untie him.
What took you so long?.
Hurry!
Log on with ID: Master Wong
PW: QWER34
Boss, I saw him!
Sit here.
Let go of me, bastards.
What's going on?.
I didn't do anything!
Player forced me to do it!
I didn't steal the money!
AII in with 6M. I only need
his tongue in exchange.
Do not listen to him.
I'll pay off the shortfall.
We're partners!
Don't be fooled by him!
CARPE DIEM requested a game.
Press ACCEPT or DECLINE.
Please, don't do this to me!
Accept it.
It's a trap!
I told you to accept.
Good, I will crush this bastard!
Got a cigarette?.
Do you know why I like GO
of all the games?.
Because it's a brain game.
Petty skills don't work.
It's the smart ones who win.
Isn't it beautifully simple?.
Give me some water, assholes!
Point counting requested.
Accept.
Congratulations!
The White won by half a territory.
Still going over the game?.
Turn the board around.
See a hole?.
It's called blood flow.
A hole to fill with the blood
from the kibitzer's tongue.
Please, I will get him.
I promise!
I will get him to you!
I' ll get him!
Please don't do that!
Out of mouth comes evil.
I can see the sign board
is missing a Ietter.
It smells fantastic!
Is it cooked yet?.
Come on, Big Move!
Let's have some feast!
Do you guys know
why I play GO?.
Confucius once said, ""It's better
to play GO than to play nothing."
You should listen to the sages.
Christ, how could you become such a
master when you can see nothing at all?.
Share us the secrets!
I saw behind others' backs.
Seriously, come on!
I want to know the secret!
When I was selling junks
on the street,
someone came to me.
He told me he'd seen me before.
And invited me to play GO.
I told him I couldn't play
because I'm blind.
Then he gave me a present.
Stone checkers for the blind.
Since that day,
we played GO every day.
He was a true master.
A real one.
And after exactly one year,
he stopped showing up.
He might be the one who
let me know about you.
Have you seen him?.
No.
When I was in the solitary cell,
we used to play GO
over the wall. I lost every time.
Who's there?.
Tell me who you are!
But there was no chalk trace
in his cell.
It's simple.
He never marked anything.
You mean he played
the blind game?.
He played the entire game in his head
and beat the pro?. Can't be true.
I heard that
there's one in Busan.
They call him the Ghost.
Ghost?.
Cheater, do you have a minute?.
Please do me a favor.
I won't shop drinks for you.
I quit drinking.
Why don't you tell me
you can see things now?.
What do you want?.
Christ, you're damn good looking!
You blushed.
It's too funny.
Oh my God!
Chicks will be all over you!
Don't worry too much.
Your daughter must be glad.
Well... it seems like
we need some running.
This way!
Wait.
You damn bastard.
Not today!
It's a big day for us!
Bring it on!
WEAK GROUP: ENDANGERED STONES
CHASED BY THE OPPONENT
Life is full of surprises
that we meet again like this.
I prepared a fun game.
One of my men died
because he couldn't solve
this life and death question.
You will have three moves.
Can I play seated?.
Seems like my toes have broken.
Game on.
Two moves left.
Please have mercy.
Game on again.
The last move.
Please, I beg you.
Guess it's your luck day.
Rest in peace, my Iove.
I recognize you now.
Thought you're dead.
I was dead, but born again.
Now I'll change your fate, too.
The bet is 6M on top of
your buddy's head.
Can't wait to see
who will win.
Try your damn best, as we have
the gallery. Your life is on it.
How about betting
my life instead of his?.
Christ...
Cheer up.
Let's have a drink after this game.
But I don't have tools
for the blind here.
I will play the blind GO.
No, Christ, you shouldn't!
Blind GO?.
No, you can't!
- You should help me.
- Christ, please don't!
Playing a blind game?.
Why?.
You can't beat a blind man?.
I'll show mercy to end
your life as fast as I can.
Flower point on upper left corner.
Strong opening for an old man.
Quite provocative.
Low 3-4 point on lower left corner.
Can't fight back
against the elderly.
Let me dodge.
Opposite 3-4 point
on upper right corner.
Flower point on lower right corner.
Declaring the war?.
Right 3-4 point on upper right corner.
I don't want to fight.
I will cut your throat if I win.
Knight's approach
on upper right corner.
Don't fight back.
Large Knight on upper right corner.
Whatever you wish,
I will go my own way.
Large Knight stretched
on lower left corner.
Lower Pincer by 3 spaces
on upper right corner.
You scared me,
I will run away.
Center, cover the cap.
On 1 0 and 1 0.
Dodge.
He's the one who struggles,
not us.
Diamond on the zenith.
Choke lower side by a territory.
Knight's move
on right side of center. Attack now.
on left side of center.
On 1 4 and1 3. Cut it!
Got him!
We got him!
You're a dead meat, motherfucker!
On 7 and 7
- He just cut it.
- Move forward!
Better be prepared to die.
How come a scumbag like you
could play like that?.
Quite nice moves
for a blind man.
Listen, Cheater.
The world isn't a playground for me.
I'm sorry.
The drinks should wait.
Go over the game
in your grave.
Drinking Christ is nailed
to the board, sorry.
If you win the game,
I will spare your friend's life.
Big Move...Do not worry.
I can't make it anyway.
- I will come back.
- No, don't!
Don't play the game.
You can't win.
He can't be beaten. The moves
are too supple to capture.
It must be a kid playing.
An innocent one.
Better do your best
if you want a happy ending.
Spare the kid out of this.
- Kill them both if I lose.
- Yes, sir.
How many handicaps you'd take
playing against god of GO?.
Two.
- If your life's on it?.
- Three.
If there's a god of GO,
it must be a child, isn't it?.
Stop here.
- Are you worried of me?.
- You can never win.
LIFE AND DEATH:
CROSSROAD OF LIVING AND DYING
Kill the Carpenter.
Same provocation as the blind man.
3-3 point?.
Crawling from the first move?.
Cover on the flower point.
Double 3-3 point?.
You don't want to win.
Care for a fight by now?.
You should go with us.
Let me think
if there's a way out for me.
Life and death
is always difficult.
That's why it always causes the fight.
Let's see who lives
and who dies.
You'll regret it.
'Cause I'll make you die in pain.
Are you throwing a stone,
or making a move?.
It's a move.
Do you know
she dies if you win?.
Don't even think about it.
What're you waiting for?.
On 8 and 1 0, cap on center.
Attack.
He made the losing move.
On 1 and 2, move forward.
On 3 and 3, connect.
On 4 and 1.
Bend.
It's Eternal Life.
We're even.
We can play forever
or you can yield.
What if I don't want to yield?.
Then we're even.
Being even isn't part of my plan.
Then we should
fight a final match.
It gets interesting.
Can't get any better than this.
Bring that bitch.
How do we try conclusion?.
Have you seen all the stones
on the board get captured?.
Take a close look.
You'll witness that.
Wearing a protection?.
How manly...
COUNTING: CALL VICTORY AND DEFEAT
AFTER THE GAME
I worked for your father.
He left something for you.
How have you been?.
Keep this.
And call me three times a day.
Isn't it too cold to work outside?.
My hands don't feel cold.
Christ once asked me
if there's a divine move in life.
I now understand
there's never such a move.
The best move we can make
is surviving every day.
Where are we heading now?.
To Busan.
THE DIVINE MOVE
Life and Death
Directed by JO Bum-gu
Translation: PIC