Well good morning, sir.
Well well, Mr Norman.
─ How are you, Franks.
Key, Harry.
─ Yes, sir.
Mr Norman.
Oh .. darling.
Betty .. Betty of my life.
I heard you were back. I heard
you checked in yesterday.
And on my day off, too.
Betty, honey.
You're more beautiful than ever.
─ Oh.
I've been sat here all morning, waiting
for you to phone and order breakfast.
I've had breakfast.
Honey. Will you tell the valet to come
up with the suit I gave him last night?
I'm in a hurry.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Good morning, Mr Norman.
Good morning, Mr Glass. How are you?
I pressed them as you
like them. Soft roll.
You press the uniform, too?
─ Sure. It came down with the other.
It was a mistake.
I'm through with that one.
[ Telephone ]
Hello.
Oh.
Yeah.
Wasn't it.
Goodnight.
Just like old times.
Mr Norman. Are you going
back into radio advertizing?
It's all I know anything about.
─ What, that same job?
Running back and forth between
New York and Hollywood?
No. I'm not going to work
for the same outfit again.
I'm going to try for something
really big this time.
I'll know in less than an hour.
Would you like me to run you a bath?
─ No thanks. I'm all bathed and shaved.
You'll get what you want.
─ How do you know?
Like you've told my son.
When he was trying
to get that first job.
If you don't seem to need a job ..
You are bound to get it.
You look like you're
on top of the world.
The job I'm after, Mr Glass.
I not only must convince
them I don't need it.
But that I wouldn't take it if they tied
me down and poured it over me.
Well, Mr Norman.
I guess that's all.
You'll .. call me if you
need me for anything?
Wait a minute, Mr Glass.
Oh no no, Mr Norman. No tip.
Tip me double tomorrow.
Today it's on the house.
─ Sure?
Positive. I'd be insulted.
Well.
Mr Norman, what did you do that for?
It's neater that way.
Now I have exactly an even
fifty bucks in the world.
You don't mean it?
But what a time to throw money away.
That's just it, Mr Glass. I want to
remind myself that money is only money.
It's a thought that will help me seem
sincere about not needing a job.
Anything?
I want a very sincere necktie.
I beg your pardon?
I want something that
makes me seem sincere.
You know: honest, genuine,
upright, trustworthy.
Well ..
Here is a hand painted
one in four colors.
At thirty-five dollars.
Is that sincere enough?
I think my friend, any more sincerity
would be downright foolhardy.
Kimberly advertizing agency, please.
41, 42, 43, or the tower.
─ Mr Kimberly.
Mr Kimberly himself?
Last elevator, please.
You want Mr Kimberly's tower.
Thank you. Kimberly's tower?
Yes?
Oh dear, yes. She did?
The first night they were out together?
Well yes dear, you're so right.
Well go on, I'm dying to hear.
Did you find out who he is?
Well, suppose we take her out to
lunch one day and get the lowdown?
Alright, dear. Call me later.
Bye.
Yes?
─ Victor Norman.
Have you an appointment?
─ I have.
Mr V. Norman.
You may go in.
─ Thank you.
80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86.
87, 88, 89, 90, 91.
No bad after a tough night.
Glad to see you, Vic. How's your wife?
I'm not married. Not the type.
Now there is a law of averages for you.
Ninety percent of the time I
get away with that question.
Now let's see.
Before the war you were with JD Richie.
In charge of the Hollywood
office for a while.
Before that, radio director for
Pratt and Burke's in New York.
What kind a job are you looking for?
─ Any kind.
So long as it pays
$25,000 a year to begin.
With a promise of more.
Much, much more.
You lay it right on the
barrel here, don't you.
Hey, I like your necktie.
Yes. I thought you would.
What?
It cost me thirty-five
bucks just to impress you.
Why tell me that?
I thought it would sound sincere.
I want you to know what
a sincere lad I am.
Ha, you're a showman Vic,
right down to your fingertips.
Excuse me a minute.
Hello?
Check.
Right, Mr Evans.
Yes, I ..
I see your point.
Right, Mr Evans.
Evan Llewellyn Evans. Head of
Beautee Soap. Our biggest client.
Of course, Mr Evans.
You're one hundred percent ..
I'll jazz up the entire staff.
Right, Mr Evans.
Yes, sir. We'll be seeing you tomorrow.
He doesn't like the commercial on
Beautee Soap's number one radio show.
The Figaro Picket Show.
He wants a commercial
that's new, novel and ..
Yet what he calls "on the beat".
One that mentions Beautee Soap at
least ten times in a single minute.
I'm sorry Vic, but I think I'd better
drop down and see Cooke.
Our man in charge of the Evans account.
Maybe we can get together another time.
Sure, sure, I'll be around.
Any old time.
Say incidentally ..
I've heard a lot about him.
He must be quite a character.
He gives us nearly ten million
dollars’ worth of business a year.
Yes, he's quite a character.
─ But a lot of trouble?
Is he really worth ten
million a year to you?
What do you mean?
The way you talked to him on
the phone, you sounded frightened.
That will give you ulcers.
Is that worth ten million a year to you?
Hey. Maybe you wouldn't
be scared of him.
Maybe I wouldn't.
Say, Vic.
Wait a minute.
I'll tell you this much.
Cooke has had enough
of Evans and vice-versa.
Now ..
You might be able to handle the job.
And then again you might not.
It might be a job I'd accept.
Then again .. it might not.
Now this is the part of your
advertizing agency I don't like.
People work down here.
When I work, I work all the time.
You worry.
─ It's not the same.
Hello.
Vic. Vic, darling!
Oh you mad character. I thought maybe
you'd died or got married or something.
Hello, Jean.
─ Darling, this is wonderful.
What am saying, it's heaven. I was
just on my way up for an audition.
Oh Jean, this is Mr Kimberly.
─ Miss Ogilvie, Kim.
Hello.
─ Aren't you pretty, Miss Ogilvie.
Well aren't you nice.
I'm doing my hair differently.
Vic, you playboy. You know,
I think the army was good for you.
Where are you singing now, Jean?
─ El Scirocco. Just for a few more days.
I'll drop in and see you.
─ Tonight?
Maybe.
─ Now, don't be like that.
You know you'll not pick up anything
better than me between now and then.
I can see you have
a lot of talents, Vic.
A lot of talents.
But we've got to, that's all.
You know how the old man is.
Well, do the best you can, but ..
Have it by noon.
It started at 8 o'clock this
morning. He called me at 8.
Cooke, you know Vic Norman?
─ Sure. Hi, Cooke.
Why hello, Vic. Glad to
see you. You look swell.
Yeah, never better.
How are you?
It's getting me down, Vic.
It's getting me down.
He insists on a new star for
the soap opera. That's the latest.
He heard the girl we've got divorced 5
years ago. He don't believe in divorce.
Kim, I tell you ..
─ Excuse me, sir but it's 11:30.
Oh yes, Have the radio department
pipe the broadcast in here.
Sorry, fellows. We're trying a
new commercial this morning.
Pipe the Beautee Soap
broadcast in here immediately.
Evans hasn't heard this one yet.
[ Radio broadcast: ]
"And now .. just plain Jane."
"Brought to you by the
makers of Beautee Soap."
[ Singing: ]
"Beautee Soap."
"Here's the kick: it's just as
good as good-as-gold."
"Use it nightly, for nine days old."
"Get to the counter
and get there quick."
"Buy a bar of Beautee Soap."
"Buy a bar, buy a bar.
Buy a bar, buy a bar."
"That's right folks. Beautee Soap
not only grooms your skin."
"But gives it that lovelier,
fresher look so necessary .."
Well .. what do you think?
Alright. I'd say it was alright.
Vic, what do you think?
I get paid for my opinions.
Well I know it’s alright. It's good.
I know something else. He'll hate it.
He's just got it in his head
that everything I do is wrong.
Now take it easy, old man.
You want Vic to think that we're
running a loony-bin up here?
Not that we don't.
But let's not scare him off.
What? Is Vic coming to work here?
Well, I wouldn't say that
but it's worth considering.
He might very well be the man
you and I have been looking for.
Vic.
I like your style.
And if not right now, some day
you're going to work for us.
Even if I have to a job for you.
Well, I'll always be glad
to talk to you about it.
So long ..
─ So long.
So long, Cooke.
Hey, if you'll pardon a word of advice.
Why don't you take the
rest of the day off.
Get a massage .. get drunk.
Oh, great. Just the thing.
Look here, Vic.
See that? Our new testimonial campaign.
Twenty-five women. Society women.
Evans picked the names out of the social
register and for all I know, tombstones.
I've got to see that every one of them
agrees to endorse Beautee Soap.
Every one of them or
he'll have our heads.
He called this morning to ask why I
hadn't done anything about it yet.
What do they get for it?
Five thousand dollars to be
paid to their favorite charity.
Who's this on top of your list?
Mrs Frances X Dorrance.
Why the star by her name?
Ah, you know. Daughter of an
English Lord. "Sir" something.
Widow of an American General
killed in the Philippines.
Evans wants her particularly.
Society plus war-widow.
You get it. Patriotic angle.
Now wait a minute, Cooke. Let's not
bother Vic with our private business.
Been nice seeing you, Vic.
Come in again sometime.
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
You know, I like that idea.
That's smart advertizing.
What are you talking about, Vic?
How can I even suggest it to her?
I happen to know that when they
gave her late husband's DSC ..
She wouldn't even allow
photographers in then.
I've been in this business a
long time but I'm not yet so ..
Insensitive that I can just walk right
up to a lady like that and ask her.
Okay, chum. Take it easy.
Take it easy.
I'm just as insensitive as they come.
I'll ask her for you.
─ Do you mean it?
You really will?
Maybe you're a little more eager
for a job than you pretend, Vic.
Let's stop being coy.
I might possibly take that job if you'd
knocked me down and forced me.
So, I'll keep my foot in the door
by doing a little chore for you.
How are you going to go about it?
I'll carry a pipe.
Women always seem to trust
a man who smokes a pipe.
If I had a dog, I'd try
and smell a little doggy.
You don't mean to tell me you're
going over there right now? Just ..
Barge in?
─ Oh no. I'll call her first.
I always give rich women at least ten
minutes to get the egg off their faces.
So long.
Here .. here .. come here.
Hello.
Mrs Dorrance, I presume?
I do hope you were
expecting me, Mrs Dorrance.
Alright. When did we meet
before, Mrs Dorrance?
Let's see .. Paris? Miami?
The Staten Island ferry?
Or perhaps we were both
being presented at court?
What shall we do, Mrs Dorrance?
Go dancing, maybe?
How would that be?
Oh, we'd have a lot of fun.
Ellen.
Yes?
Hello.
Mrs Dorrance?
Yes, I am.
─ My name is Norman.
I telephoned you.
Oh yes. The man from the Charity League.
Do come in, Mr Norman.
Run along, darling.
I'm awfully sorry if Ellen bothered you.
No, not at all. I enjoyed it a lot.
It's a sport that might catch on.
Thank you, Ellen. We must
do it again sometime.
I'm sorry everything is so disorganized.
It's the maid's day out, and the
nurse's day to be in bed with a cold.
If you just go in and
wait I'll be right back.
Thank you.
Come on, darling.
I don't know how to account for Ellen.
Usually, she's too shy
to speak to strangers.
She still hasn't spoken to me.
Please sit down, Mr Norman.
Now then.
How can I help the Charity League?
Well ..
Suppose I begin this way.
I really work for Beautee Soap.
Beautee Soap?
That is, I work for the advertizing
agency that works for Beautee Soap.
Do you know about advertizing agencies?
They're not quite the
same here as in England.
I'm an American citizen now,
Mr Norman. But you're right.
I'm afraid I don't know
much about such things.
Hmm.
People like Beautee Soap employ us to ..
Put on their radio shows and write
their magazine advertizements.
To shout their praises
and sell their wares.
To do their huckstering for them.
Their what?
─ Huckstering.
A huckster is a peddler.
You know, a hawker.
We're professional hucksters.
But with station-wagons
instead of pushcarts.
Oh. It must be very interesting.
Yes.
Well then.
I guess I'd better come to the point.
Mrs Dorrance, have you ever
noticed in the magazines ..?
I mean, lots of times, you see pictures
of people like you endorsing things.
Probably, friends of yours.
─ You want me to endorse Beautee Soap?
Five thousand dollars will be
paid to your favorite charity.
That's what I meant when I said I
represented the Charity League.
I see.
Well, Mr Norman.
My favorite charity ..
I hope you won't be shocked.
Is myself.
Is your ..?
You'll do it?
Two growing children, you know.
And General's widows aren't rich.
And I thought you'd be so hard to sell.
Mrs Dorrance, you have a lot to learn.
─ What do you mean?
I mean if you'd played hard to get, I'd
ask the company to offer more money.
You won't do it for less than
$7,500. Not a penny less.
I'll say that. Maybe
they'll come through.
Are you serious?
Well "A", it isn't my money.
And "B", I have an angle in this.
If I tell them that you were just
sitting here waiting to be asked.
That means I didn't have
much of a selling job to do.
In fact.
With someone as pretty
and photogenic as you.
I'd be willing to help if you
wanted to try for $10,000.
Oh, no thank you.
I'm afraid I can't even
accept the extra $2,500.
Although I'll be glad to say you
had a terrible time convincing me.
Frankly, I think you're
overpaying me as it is.
Hello. I'm Hal.
My sister would like
to ask you something.
Will you marry her?
─ Now!
I'd love to.
Hal, take your sister upstairs.
Mr Norman is entirely too
busy to marry anybody today.
And Hal.
Whenever you propose for
your sister in the future.
Say please.
Ellen looks like you.
You both have the wonderful quality that
you get better looking as you get older.
Oh dear, we're getting a long
way from Beautee Soap.
I think I see what you mean.
Ah .. Mrs Dorrance, shall I arrange an
appointment for you at a photographers?
Say .. tomorrow afternoon?
They're in big hurry to
get this campaign started.
Tomorrow?
Why, yes. Yes, that will be fine.
I'll be free of the children by then.
Why not bring the children along?
I'd love to see them again.
Oh, you'll be there?
If you'll bring them.
Really? Do you really like them so much?
Oh, I do indeed.
Old Papa Norman, the child-lover.
Goodbye.
─ Goodbye, Mr Norman.
No, no dear. I was under the impression
I gave you the correct position.
No, dear.
Your feet are too close together.
Your toes are not pointed enough.
Here, watch me.
Put one foot up like this and the other
one a considerable distance below it.
And don't press the legs together
otherwise they'll just bulge.
Now keep the bottle up.
Watch the label.
Now hold it.
Ah, that's perfect. Perfect.
Point the toes, dear. Point the toes.
Take a deep breath. Smile.
Hold it.
Exquisite.
Yes, yes. What is it?
Oh, I'm Mrs Dorrance.
You were expecting me?
Aha, Beautee Soap.
You're right on time, Mrs Dorrance.
Beauty Soap background, please.
How do you do, Madam.
How do you do.
─ I'm Michael Michaelson.
And you brought your children. How nice.
Thank you.
─ Would you come with me, please.
We can see what your costume is like.
Oh, a costume for me?
─ Why, of course. Something lovely.
And there's your background.
Now then, I wonder if you'll look
best in peach, cerise or black.
Is .. is this for me?
Well ..?
Oh, they want to make me look
awfully glamorous don't they.
You'll look very nice.
Very nice.
─ Well thank you, but ..
I've never worn one of these things.
Even alone in my own bedroom.
Mrs Dorrance, I'm only the
photographer. I just do what I'm told.
Now, if I were you I would
just put this on and ..
Hello, Ellen.
How is my bride of the day, huh?
Hello there.
─ Hello.
Oh, very smart.
This is Miss Kennedy from
Mr Evans' downtown office.
She's his personal advertizing advisor.
Miss Kennedy. Mrs Dorrance.
─ How do you do?
How do you do.
And this is Mr Michael Michaelson.
Mr Norman.
─ Thank you, Miss Dorrance.
Hello, Hal.
─ Hello.
Well then Mrs Dorrance, do
you think we might get to work?
Do you suppose they thought
they were hiring Lady Godiva?
I hadn't seen these.
─ Don't you like them?
Well, frankly ..
─ But Mr Evans approved them.
Mr Evans doesn't have to wear them.
I'm surprised he doesn't want to
photograph Mrs Dorrance in a bubble-bath.
Don't be silly, Mr Norman.
Beautee Soap doesn't bubble.
Well.
Could I wear a slip or
something under it?
One never does.
─ certainly not.
They are going to see through Mummy.
You're so right, Hal.
Mr Norman.
─ It will be alright.
I think we'll photograph Mrs Dorrance
wearing an evening dress.
Sitting in a straight chair
with a plain background.
Hal standing on her right
and Ellen on her left.
I'd much rather.
Perhaps you don't understand.
Mr Evans didn't suggest
this layout, he ordered it.
Miss Kennedy, you've registered
your objection. We've all heard it.
But I represent the Kimberly
Advertizing Agency.
And the Kimberly Advertizing
Agency arranged this appointment.
Now then .. there is only
one thing left for you to do.
Here's a nickel. Go telephone Mr Evans.
He'll hear about it soon enough.
And be sure and get my
name right: Victor Norman.
Do you have a plain, straight chair?
Mr Norman, if Mr Evans
thought I had anything to do ..
I'll take full responsibility.
─ I guess you don't like your job much.
Please, Mr Norman.
Vic.
Vic .. you've been so nice to me.
I don't want to cost you your job.
─ Don't worry.
I wouldn't let you pose in one
of those things. Not you.
Do you have a long, Queenly,
kind of a gown at home?
Well, I have a long dress.
─ Hmm .. good.
Set up a straight chair
on a plain background.
While I take Mrs Dorrance
home to get another dress.
Alright.
Mrs Dorrance, please. The children.
We send him off for cheesecake
and what does he bring back?
Whistler's mother.
My head! This migraine is killing me.
Migraine? What about my ulcer?
Good morning, gentlemen.
Where have you been, Vic? Where you
been? We've been looking for an hour.
I'm sorry. I've been
downstairs, cutting a record.
I have here old Doc Norman's special
prescription for ailing commercials.
Please Vic, sit down.
What were you thinking about, Vic?
─ Pretty good, I think.
It may be just what Evans looks for.
─ See that?        ─ Sure.
That's what Evans is
looking for .. my head.
I take it you have seen
the Dorrance photographs?
We've seen the photos.
─ Dignified, don't you think?
What is it? What are you trying to do?
Lose me a ten-million dollar account?
Evans didn't like the pictures?
─ We haven't heard from him yet.
This is will be the worst we
ever had. I feel it in my bones.
I'll bet it's a number three.
─ They have numbers?
We go by how many taxis
of people he sends for.
If one little thing goes wrong he starts
tearing into everything. Everything.
One day I was a few minutes late
for a meeting and he got sore.
He sent for three taxi-loads
of people from here.
Our writers had to meet
with his copywriter.
Our writers with his staff layout.
I thought maybe you were
the boy we were looking for.
I am.
Sure. And you put me in a spot like
this. What am I supposed to tell him?
You won't tell him anything.
I'll tell him.
Take me down and introduce me
as the guy that caused the trouble.
What will you say?
─ I'll think of something.
You two guys kill me.
I saw troops before D-Day in Normandy
and they weren't half as scared as you.
If they'd been meeting Evans instead of
Germans, it might have been different.
Mr Kimberly, he called. Right away.
He wants to see you right away.
What is it? Number two, number three?
Mr Kimberly .. the number four.
Now Vic, you sit here.
Mr Evans sits at the head of the table.
─ I guessed that.
And Vic, whatever you do,
don't disagree with him.
Am I supposed to look bright or
does that call for a bigger salary?
Just don't tell him he's wrong.
Nobody ever has and I
guess nobody ever will.
That's right.
Gentlemen, Miss Kennedy.
I would like to introduce
Mr Victor Norman.
Vic, this is Mr Paul Evans.
Mr Evans' son.
Mr Allison, special
assistant to Mr Evans.
Mr George Rockton, chief
counsel to Beautee Soap.
And Miss Kennedy you already know.
Mr Evans.
May I present Mr Victor Norman.
Mr Victor.
Mr Norman, you've just seen
me do a disgusting thing.
But you'll always
remember what I just did.
You see Mr Norman, if nobody remembers
your brand you won't sell any soap.
Check?
─ Check.
You see, Mr Foreman.
You see Mr Norman, I've got my
own ideas on how to sell.
I believe in selling by demonstration.
Any other way is all wet.
See what I mean?
You see, Mr Foreman, this
company gives your agency ..
Ten million dollars a year
to spend on advertizing.
Do you know why? I'll tell you.
I'll tell you a secret about the
soap business, Mr Norman.
There is absolutely no
difference between soaps.
Absolutely none, except
for perfume and color.
Soap is soap.
Oh, maybe we have a
few manufacturing tricks.
But the public don't
give a hoot about that.
The difference is in
selling and advertizing.
We sell soap twice as fast
as our nearest competitor.
Why do we outsell them? Because
we out-advertize them. Right?
Right.
─ Right.
We out-advertize our
competitors, Mr Norman.
There is something
remarkable about that.
Listen.
We spend on average, three million
dollars a year less than they do.
We out-advertize them.
And out-sell them, but on less money.
Does that convey a thought to you?
It does to me. It means to me
that we know what we are doing.
Well, sales principles are not theory.
They are proven facts.
Example.
Beautee Soap, Beautee Soap,
Beautee Soap!
Repeat until it comes out of their ears.
Repeat until they say it in their sleep.
Irritate them, Mr Norman.
Irritate! Irritate! Irritate them!
Never forget!
Irritate them, knock them dead!
See what I mean?
Now, sir.
Here Mr Doorman, is a little idea
that just happened to come to us.
Just dropped down out of the blue.
A mere detail that we did a chat-chat
about for nearly three months.
A small point.
And all the people in
this room whose income ..
Not counting mine, must
aggregate a million dollars a year.
Thought this was a
pretty good little idea.
Right on the beam.
Fits all our proven theories.
Check?
─ Check.
Now you young man, you
don't like our little old idea.
Why?
I challenge you to give me a reason why.
Because, Mr Evans.
A careful examination of the layout
revealed a single disturbing element.
The element to which I refer, Mr Evans.
Is inherently opposed
to the basic qualities ..
To the very essence, of Beautee
Soap's appeal to the millions.
And what is this disturbing
element, Mr Norman?
Well, I'm sure you all know better than
I that Beautee Soap sells for 7 cents.
It goes into the homes of the masses.
Beautee Soap was not meant for
the minority of .. ladies of leisure.
Now then, this picture.
That loose and flossy negligee.
Leg art? Is that Beautee Soap?
A bored and sophisticated
woman in a dubious boudoir?
Oh that disturbs me, Mr Evans.
Beautee Soap is a clean product.
And your advertisement is not clean.
Mister Norman.
I take my hat off to you. You're right.
Mr Evans.
It may interest you to know that
Mr Norman sat up all last night ..
Working out a twist on your
present commercial idea.
If you'd care to hear it,
we have it here on a record.
Play it.
[ Advert playing: ]
"Ha ha, love that soap."
"Yes, Violet. Everybody
loves Beautee Soap."
"As personal maid to glamorous
movie star Wanda Jean .."
"You see how effective the Beautee Soap
treatment is. Do you agree, Miss Jean?"
"Righto. My public simply
demands I use Beautee Soap."
"Why next to the Mocambo,
it's Hollywood's favorite bar."
"Love that soap."
"And not only in Hollywood."
"But Beautee Soap is cleaning
up the whole country."
"West, North, South.
Right, Colonel Raphael?"
"Here in the Deep South sir,
Beautee Soap .."
"Makes the flower of Southern womanhood
lovelier than magnolias and honeysuckle."
"Love that soap."
"And up North in Yankee Vermont?"
"Yep, love that soap."
─ "Anything more to say?"
"Nope. Just love that soap."
"And so, it's Beautee Soap everywhere."
"Not just in the cities,
but on the farm."
"Correct, Barbara Hascombe?"
─ "Not much time for talking."
"Got to get sonny cleaned
up with Beautee Soap."
"Sonny, hold still! You're
getting it in your mouth."
"I know it, Ma. I just love that soap."
"There you have it, folks."
"Beautee Soap is
cleaning up the country."
"For Beautee is, as Beautee does."
"So don't forget .."
"Ha ha .. love that soap!"
Hmm.
I like it. I like it, Mr Norman.
Love that soap. Love that soap.
They'll all be saying it.
It's on the beam.
Only cut that line about it being
Hollywood's favorite bar ..
Next to the Mocambo.
Mr Norman, Beautee Soap
is second best to nothing.
Hollywood's favorite bar.
And don't you forget it.
Right?
─ Right.
Mr Kimberly.
I dare say you've an idea of absorbing
Mr Norman in your organization.
Yes, sir. I thought we might start
him out as Mr Cooke's assistant.
Salary?
Well, I thought an expense account for
a while. Let him draw what he needs.
Excellent.
I see Mr Norman, you have your teeth.
In our province.
My felicitations, Mr Norman.
You are very kind, Mr Evans.
Very, very, kind.
Dinner tonight. My house.
Truffles and champagne.
Get yourself a girl. We'll celebrate.
Check.
Hello?
Oh, yes.
Vic.
It's like this, Kay.
First, the boss wants me to dine with him
and his wife tonight at his apartment.
Second.
The deal is mixed up with the way you'd
have looked in the transparent negligee.
Yes, I .. I guess I would have looked ..
Awful alright.
I mean, it's not exactly the
sort of thing I should wear.
It's just the sort of
thing you should wear.
The only thing is it would have
been much too good for Evans.
Now, about tonight?
I wish you could see the eager
expression on my face right now.
If you'd only come.
Kimberly is on the left side.
─ Thank you.
Oh, I'm losing my earring.
I wish we were going someplace else.
Alone.
Why? Don't you like the Kimberlys?
This was a mistake,
my bringing you here.
Kim will talk business all the time.
Aren't we a little late as it is?
First, the Stork Club.
I haven't been there in 4 years.
Table in the corner.
I might even order some wine.
You are very persuasive.
─ Good.
You know what you are, Kay?
You're an honest person.
You say what's on your mind.
I haven't much experience with honest
people and I'm not sure I like them.
How can you tell what
they're going to do next?
Good evening.
─ That's what I mean.
You can't trust an honest person.
Down?
Sorry, chum.
Yes, sir?
─ Kimberly?
Yes, sir.
─ I'm Victor Norman.
Just a minute, sir. I'll tell
Mrs Kimberly you're here.
I still think we should have
gone somewhere else.
I think the butler does, too.
Good evening.
Good evening, Mrs Kimberly.
I'm Victor Norman.
How do you do.
─ And this is Mrs Dorrance.
Mrs Kimberly, Kay.
─ How do you do.
How do you do.
Please come in.
It's awfully nice of you
to drop in like this.
Do you two live near here?
Oh, I live a few blocks away.
Vic asked me to join him for
dinner. I do hope it was alright.
Oh .. oh how nice. I'm so glad.
Maybe Kim didn't tell you?
He did ask us.
As a matter of fact,
he didn't mention it.
He just said we were
going out to dinner.
But that's perfectly alright.
Really, it is.
Do sit down.
Martinis, Conrad.
Lots of times he doesn't tell me.
He came home a little bit ..
He was celebrating something.
Are you in business with him?
In a manner of speaking.
I gather they had a busy day with ..
Is his name "Evans", Vic?
Oh, if today was Evans' day,
that explains everything.
Whenever Kim sees Evans he
either has to celebrate or forget.
I gather that today was a celebration.
Yes, today we came out the winners.
Just luck.
I'm so glad.
His life really belong to that
Mr Evans and his other clients.
They are all that way in the
advertizing business. Or most of them.
Isn't Mr Norman?
I .. don't think so.
Are you, Vic?
Don't tell Kim, but the answer is "no".
I'm not that sincere.
Whoa ..
Well, well .. our dinner guests.
Good evening. Good evening.
─ Kim, this is Mrs Dorrance.
Whoo .. oomph ..
"Oomph" .. it sounds
like yogi or something.
Oh, he doesn't mean
any harm, Mrs Norman.
Oh .. Mrs Dorrance.
Oh I'm so sorry. Mrs Dorrance.
Whenever he's had a couple of drinks
he thinks that all women are "oomph".
All women. Anybody.
Oh my, I didn't mean ..
I know just what you meant.
I do seem to be off on the
wrong foot this evening.
Well I guess I did it again, lover.
I forgot to tell you who we
were having for dinner.
But Vicky here, wrote the
most beautiful commercial.
"Love that soap."
I'm sorry. I'm afraid now it
is going to be business talk.
The two subjects: business and "oomph".
Well, what else is there?
─ There's always Mah Jong.
Kim, we're going out to dinner you know.
Sure. Where would you like to go, Vic?
─ Wherever you say, Kim.
Well, I thought of some
quiet restaurant, but ..
Now that I see how
"oomph" Mrs Dorrance is, I ..
Do I have to say thank you
every time you say that?
No, it isn't necessary.
Say, I've got an idea.
I know a gay, noisy place where we
can get some wonderful steaks but ..
Maybe Vicky-boy wouldn't
want to go there.
Why not?
─ El Scirocco.
That singer friend of yours
is pretty "oomphy" herself.
And a man can have too much
"oomph" in the same room.
It doesn't matter to me where we go.
Why not let the girls decide?
Where would you like
to go, Mrs Dorrance?
Oh.
El Scirocco by all means.
My shoes and socks, Conrad.
My shoes and socks.
You got to wear shoes
and socks at El Scirocco.
[ Singing: ]
"Why do we talk with our eyes
as we sit across the table?"
"Why do we walk arm-in-arm
whenever we are able?"
"Feet on the ground."
"Ground spinning round."
"Please tell me why my happy
heart keeps repeating .."
"That it's so .. "
"No, don't tell me .."
"Don't say you're mine."
"Don't tell me."
"It's just a lie."
"Why whisper words I have never known."
"Or speak your heart
whenever we're alone."
"No, don't tell me."
"It isn't fair."
"For I'm foolish."
"I'll start to care."
"Why are angels singing high above?"
"Oh don't tell me I'm .."
"In love .."
She is very attractive.
─ Yes, she is.
She's better than that. She's "oomph".
Shush, darling.
You're attracting attention.
I think Kim, maybe we'd better ..
Hello Vic, my honey.
─ Hello, Jean.
What are you drinking?
─ Why Vic, don't you remember?
Always straight Scotch,
right after my number.
This is Mrs Dorrance and Mrs Kimberly.
Miss Ogilvie.           ─ How do you do.
Mr Kimberly you've met.
─ Yes.         ─ How do you do.
One straight Scotch with a water chaser.
─ Yes, sir.
I enjoyed your song, Miss Ogilvie.
I really enjoyed it very much.
Why, thanks.
You know, I close here tomorrow night.
─ Then what?
Then I'm off to Hollywood.
They're giving me a screen-test.
Why, Hollywood? Why
aren't you on the radio?
Why isn't somebody as
terrific as her on the radio?
Just show me how.
It must be great fun being a singer.
It's alright.
What do you do?
─ I ..?
Oh nothing.
─ She has two fine kids.
They'd keep anyone busy.
Oh, you're married!
Oh now, that's wonderful.
That's the racket to be in.
Marriage and kids.
You know, someday I'm going to
get married and have a dozen.
Please don't get married.
All that oomph ought
to stay in circulation.
I think it's time to go home now, Kim.
─ Well, I don't.
Why don't you be nice to Vicky-boy?
And other radio people. People
who will get you a radio spot.
If Vic can do me a favor,
I'm sure he will.
Wont you, honey?
─ I'll see what I can do.
Oh, they're calling me now. I have to
go back and do a number with the band.
I'll phone you.
─ When?          ─ Tomorrow.
Alright, goodnight.
─ Goodnight.
Goodnight everybody.
Now there is the kind of a girl
a man would like to get a job for.
If you know what I mean.
She's a great girl.
And a very good friend of mine.
Ah, friendship ..
Nobody is anybody's friend.
I haven't got any.
Kim has had one too many. He has
lots of fine friends. Lots of them.
Of course.
Sure. That's right, lover. Name one.
Name one.
Why Kim, there are hundreds.
─ Name one.
Well Kim, just at this moment, I ..
I know exactly how you feel,
Mrs Kimberly. I get the same way.
While one is accustomed ..
─ She can't name one.
Not one. You see, Vic?
I don't see what it proves.
I'm telling you how to be
a success in this business.
I started as a dumb kid out of Princeton
with maybe fifty bucks to my name.
An old friend of my father’s out
of the goodness of his heart ..
Gave me a job with his
advertizing agency.
Old Harley Adler.
You ever know him, Vic?
No, I never knew him.
Well he had a nice little agency, old
Harley Adler did. A nice little agency.
All based on the Beautee Soap
account. That's what he had.
Excuse me Kim, they're playing a foxtrot.
It's the only thing I know how to dance.
Want to hear the rest of it?
You're the hostess, lover.
Make them sit down.
Want to hear the secret of my success?
You always ask to talk of my business.
Alright, Kim. What is it?
What is the secret of your success?
I've never told anybody.
Not even my psychoanalyst.
Old Harley Adler was doing fine.
Until he got involved in some tax
difficulty and bribed his way out of it.
But just somehow or other,
the FBI heard about it.
They arrested old Harley Adler
and they carried him away.
Put him in a big, black jail.
People have always
wondered who told the FBI.
Because if somebody hadn't
have told the FBI ..
They wouldn't have carried
old Harley Adler away.
And I wouldn't have had the Beautee Soap
account to start a business of my own.
Who could have told?
Who could have told ..?
Kay.
I'm sorry.
Don't be silly.
It was a very ..
Interesting evening. Thank you so much.
We must be sure to
exchange Christmas cards.
I beg your pardon?
You've never met people
like that, have you?
I'm glad I met them.
They might be from Mars for
all they have to do with you.
That goes for me too, doesn't it.
I don't understand you, Vic.
Who are you? What are you?
It is very simple.
I came from the middle-west,
a town called Ford Madison.
I went back once to bury my mother.
I have no roots, no past, no future.
But that goes for almost
all the people in my world.
I would say you had
a great deal of future.
Oh sure. A series of nightclubs
like the one we've just left.
Maybe someday, if I'm very lucky,
I'll have a life like Kimberly.
Even the house in Connecticut,
I'll never have time to visit.
Knowing you, you'll find time.
You are not like Kimberly.
No, I'm not.
We're almost there.
Driver, it's just on the right.
Past that lamp-post.
Vic, thanks for everything.
A fascinating evening. That testimonial.
And the negligee business. Everything.
No. Please, please don't get out.
Kay.
Get back in the cab.
Get in, Kay.
Driver. Go to the corner
of 54th and 2nd Avenue.
What's there?
A garage where they'll rent me a car.
Where are we going?
I don't know.
Out of the city.
Have you ever seen dawn from a beach?
No.
We'll go out on Long Island.
Jones Beach.
Somewhere.
Yes, Vic.
You know, it's funny.
Every time I get all set to
give you a big sales talk.
You've already made
up your mind to give in.
That testimonial.
Dinner tonight.
─ Yes.
Why?
I don't know. I really don't.
You frighten me a little, but ..
It's funny that you of all people, would
think to go for a drive in the country.
Kay .. whatever there is between us.
It has nothing to do with the
advertizing business or New York.
Isn't that true?
─ Yes.
Vic, I want you to understand something.
It's just this.
I'm not an unhappy woman.
I like my life, my home and my children.
I'm not lonely.
It's the same with me.
I don't want anything from you.
Except you.
Vic.
Hmm?
You know, when I first met you.
I wasn't sure I even liked you.
That seems so long ago.
Oh, I didn't know
life could be like this.
I feel ten years old.
I wish I had known you
when you were ten.
I was always too tall.
As a young girl I was taller
than most of the boys.
So I pretended to be critical of
them. I must have been hateful.
I know I was hateful. I was told.
I was the biggest smart-alec that
ever whistled in front of a pool-room.
Darling, don't run yourself down.
Alright.
Kay, I was right wasn't I?
About coming out here?
You are, too.
There are too many things
in the way in a town.
Yes.
Kay.
I know a pleasant little inn. Up on
the Connecticut coast near Clayport.
What?
It's called The Blue Penguin Inn.
Vic .. I like you.
I find you very ..
Well, I like you.
But if you think that means
I'd go off to a hotel with you ..
Why .. it's just out of the question.
What?
We must be talking
about different things.
You didn't think that was
a proposition, did you?
Yes .. yes, I did.
Well look honey, you got me all wrong.
Oh look.
Look, here's my room over here.
And then way over there on the other
side of the hotel, that's your room.
Why, I mean we might be on a
boat or a train or something.
That wouldn't worry you, would it?
No.
─ Well then.
Oh look honey, we'd have fun.
Do you like to sail?
Yes. Very much.
They have three of four of the neatest,
whitest little cat-boats you ever saw.
We'll have them put us up in a lodge,
get a boat, and hove for the open sound.
Oh, we can lie on the beach, go fishing.
Dine on the terrace by moonlight.
You know it.
We can watch the dawn
come up on the beach again.
All of that is for us.
That's for us, isn't it, Kay?
Yes Vic, I guess that's for us.
Look. The inn is only seven minutes
from Clayport Station by taxi.
You ask for me at the desk.
But why say that now? Are you
going to leave me to walk home?
No. But I'm not going
to mention it again.
It's five o'clock on a Saturday morning.
I'm leaving right after lunch.
There is a later train that
gets to Clayport at four.
You? You'll come or you'll not come.
I'm not going to phone you, I'm not going
to huckster you into coming out there.
But all day long, I'll be using
a little huckster telepathy.
I'll be saying to myself.
Kay .. please come to
The Blue Penguin Inn.
I don't think I'm going to be much use
to the Kimberly Advertizing Agency.
My mind won't be on soap.
Get me The Blue Penguin Inn,
Clayport, Connecticut.
That's right, Blue Penguin Inn.
Oh Mr Norman, it's 10:31.
I'm awfully sorry.
What is so upsetting about 10:31?
Mr Cooke said that while he was away
you were to handle all his business.
And 10:30 is "Wife In Name Only."
[ Radio broadcast: ]
"By actual survey."
"More doctors use Beautee Soap
on their babies than any other brand."
"Want to learn how to spell?"
"Well."
[ Singing: ]
"B. E. A. U. T. double E."
"B. E. A. U. T. E. E.."
"Spells: Beautee Soap!"
"And now: Wife In Name Only."
"The story of a man's disaster and
a brave woman's shining hour."
"Wife In Name Only is brought to
you by the makers of Beautee Soap."
"Yesterday we left .."
Oh Mr Norman, you'd better listen today.
This is the day the hero loses his leg.
Miss Hammer. Take a memorandum.
Mr Kimberly. Dear Kim.
For four years I haven't been
listening to the radio much.
Paragraph.
Kim.
In that time, it's gotten worse.
If possible .. more irritating.
More commercials per minute.
More spelling words as if no-one in the
audience has got past the first grade.
Paragraph.
I know how tough Evans is and ..
Some of the other sponsors.
But I think we make a great mistake
in letting them have their own way.
We're paid to advise them.
Why can't we advise them ..
That people are grateful for what free
entertainment they get on the air.
Grateful enough to buy the
product that provides good shows.
But.
They have some rights, Kim.
It is their homes we go into.
They're not grateful to people
who get one foot in the door ..
By pretending to offer
them music and drama ..
And then take too much
time in corny sales talk.
Paragraph.
I want to go on record as saying that I
think radio has to turn over a new leaf.
We've pushed and badgered the listeners.
We've sung to them and screamed at them.
We've insulted them, cheated
them and angered them.
Turned their homes into a
combination grocery store ..
Crap game and Midway.
Kim.
Someday, 50 million people are going to
reach out and turn off their radios.
Snap!
Just like that.
And that's the end of the gravy.
For you and me ..
And Evans.
Sign it "Love and kisses, Vic".
Oh, Mr Norman.
Sir.
What's the matter? You think I'm wrong?
I wouldn't say.
Do you ever listen to the radio?
Yes, sir.
─ And?
Well, I'd get back at it.
How?
It may sound silly, but ..
I make it a point of honor.
A point of honor never to buy
anything that's advertized that way.
Even Beautee Soap?
Particularly Beautee Soap.
Good for you, Miss Hammer. Good for you.
Hello?
Oh hello. Blue Penguin Inn?
Is Mrs Michaels there?
Mrs Michaels, the owner.
She's not here anymore.
My name is Blake. I'm the new owner.
What is it you want?
I always used to have the same rooms
in the back of the second floor.
Number 4.
And then number 37.
Way over on the other side.
Yeah. I'd like them for the weekend.
Yes, it will cost you 20 dollars
a night for them two layouts.
Yeah. Well, how do I know you'll come?
People call up, reserve rooms ..
And then they have a fight or
something and I'm left holding the bag.
I'll be there. No later than three.
Yes. This afternoon.
Now, sir. About the new
testimonial campaign.
Right now, I'm going
away for the weekend.
Now?
Well if anything comes up, I'll call
you at The Blue Penguin Inn.
You do and I'll cut off your ears.
Where you're concerned, you never
heard of The Blue Penguin Inn.
Is that clear?
─ Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. I never heard of
The Blue Penguin Inn.
Clayport 42499.
Goodbye, Miss Hammer.
Goodbye, Mr Norman. Have a nice weekend.
Wherever you're going.
Four years since you've been here, huh?
A long time.
I knew I hadn't seen you with
the regular weekend crowd.
Alright, so we don't keep it so good.
How about sending up a
boy with a new chair?
Mister, we got one boy
and he keeps busy.
Alright. Let’s have a look at 37.
See if it's any better.
Room 37 is rented.
Couldn't hold it for you.
But I got this one for you.
Six.
It's nicer.
Well, here you are.
How is this one?
I asked you for 4 and 37. Why
didn't you save them for me?
What are you, a numerologist?
What difference does it make?
This is the best room we got.
And these connect,
right through that door.
No.
No?
Well, alright.
Maybe if you ask real nice, the folks in
37 would be willing to change with you.
If .. if it matters to you.
No, no. It's alright. Here.
Here's five dollars. How about
some flowers for the rooms?
Oh, sure.
Plenty in the garden.
All you got to do is pick them.
The Blue Penguin Inn, please.
Did you say "The Blue Penguin Inn"?
Yes, do you know where it is?
Oh sure, I know where it is.
It's out on the point.
It's none of my business but maybe
you're one of the old crowd.
Did you used to go there
when Mrs Michaels ran it?
No.
Okay.
So, I shut my mouth and I take
you to The Blue Penguin Inn.
Hey, lady.
Look.
Over there.
That's The Blue Penguin Inn.
Why, it looks charming.
Yeah .. yeah.
Hello. Here is the bellboy.
Hasn't anyone been asking for me?
"A Mrs Dorrance?"
Nope. Nobody come in yet.
Alright. Thank you.
Hey hey, don't bang it so hard.
Let him play, let him play.
It's his funeral, ain't it.
Hey look! Ten, twelve ..
Fifteen.
Excuse me.
─ Twenty-one thousand.
Well, how about it?
I still say you hadn't ought to
bang it so hard. You'll wear it out.
Alright. Me now, huh.
─ Just a minute, just a minute.
Yeah?
Is there something I can do for you?
─ I'm looking for a Mr Norman.
Oh, you're Mrs Dorrance?
Yes.
Right this way, please.
If you need anything, call.
Oh ..
This here connects with room 4.
You want me to unlock it?
Room 4?
Yeah. Mr Norman's room.
Oh.
I see. Thank you.
Hey.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Mr Norman, I'm so sorry
but they made me.
They said they'd fire me if I didn't
call you. Mr Kimberly himself phoned.
Why did they put you to the torture?
It's something about Mr Evans.
It's something critical.
There is to be a big meeting
about it in Mr Evans' office.
Tomorrow morning at 11.
But tomorrow is Sunday.
Oh well, alright.
They'll miss me in the
choir, but I'll be there.
Goodbye.
Well, you sure cut things thin.
11 o'clock means 11 o'clock.
I know. But I hoped to go
over some things with you.
What?
─ Well, the first thing ..
The last time I noticed you neglected
to answer Evans' rhetorical questions.
I mean those "rights" and "checks".
I know it seems childish, but he
likes to have them answered.
Anyway, it doesn't cost anything.
Incidentally, Vic.
I'm sorry about the way I
behaved the other night.
Oh, forget it.
In front of Mrs Dorrance and all.
She's quite a lady, Vic.
Who?
─ Mrs Dorrance.
Oh .. her.
Now, about today's crisis.
Yesterday, the old man heard a comedian
named Buddy Hare, do a guest appearance.
He was on some program which originated
in Hollywood. Do you know him?
Sure. An ex-burlesque comedian.
He does comedy bits and B movies.
But the old man is nuts about him. He
talks about writing a new show for him.
Yeah, I see .. you want a rough
estimate of our chances?
Go ahead.
─ Well.
Get the biggest Hollywood
stars you can to support him.
Buy the most expensive time
available on a big network.
Hire America's top-name
band, get the best writers.
And you've probably got a flop.
Fine, fine.
And if we refuse to do the job,
Evans will get another agency.
If we do the job and flunk, he'll hold
us responsible and get another agency.
Happy Sabbath, friend.
Here is Mr Evans.
Sit.
Due to the fact that nobody but me does
any talent scouting for this company.
I am forced to work on Sunday.
We'll let that pass, at this moment.
I think Buddy Hare is great.
A sort-of Bob Hope and Jack Benny
combined in one. Check?
Check.
─ Check.
Mr Norman.
You'd better make him pretty good.
Well, he is.
And it seems to me we ought
to give the compass a whirl.
And see if this chap Buddy Hare
is headed in our direction.
I don't want you fellows
to miss the last bus.
Let's not be like straws in the wind.
See what I mean?
Now you're in at the
beginning of this, Mr Norman.
I shall expect you to carry the ball
right down the field for a touchdown.
It's your baby now.
Well sir, I don't mean to forget
that you thought of using Hare.
I wouldn't want any
credit I didn't deserve.
Let's get this clear, Mr Norman.
You fellows at the agency are just as
enthusiastic about him as I am. Right?
Right.
I therefore consider that you,
representing the agency ..
Recommend him just as
much as I do. Check?
Check.
Now, Mr Norman is new here. I'd like
to talk to him alone for a few minutes.
Mr Buddy Hare.
While you and Kimberly were
enjoying your holiday yesterday.
I had my personal staff
gather a little information.
It seems that his agent is a
Mr David Lash from Hollywood.
I know Dave.
─ Do you?
Did you know Mr Lash was in New York?
No.
I took the trouble to discover that.
Mr Norman, it has been my experience.
That somehow or other, whenever I want
a man like Buddy Hare the price goes up.
I don't like that.
I understand.
Mr David Lash has reservations
to go back to Hollywood ..
Today on the Centurion Chief.
I'll be aboard and set the deal before he
has a chance to hear you want Buddy Hare.
Excellent.
Now, one other point of business.
Last night a change in the commercial
was not teletyped to the coast.
I am told that the tele-typist
in your office was at fault.
Fire her.
She's a nice girl.
Doesn't make many mistakes.
I can't fire her just for that.
What's her name?
I don't think I'll tell you, Mr Evans.
No doubt Mr Norman,
you have your good reasons.
For treating me in
this cavalier fashion.
You've only a few hours in
which to catch your train.
I can only say that if you want
a permanent job with me.
You'd better come back from Hollywood ..
With Buddy Hare and
a very funny radio show.
Very funny.
Driver .. we've got a few
minutes before train time.
Let's go over toward Sutton Place.
22 Barton Lane.
─ Yes, sir.
Yes, sir?
─ Mr Norman to see Mrs Dorrance.
I'll call her.
─ It's important. I haven't much time.
Good afternoon, Vic.
You would have a gardener.
It's a very small garden.
Does that make it any better?
I don't know why I
bother to see you at all.
Except that I'm not
used to being stood up.
It gets me sore. Very sore.
I'm sorry.
Cigarette?
What gets me is, you didn't trust me.
You didn't trust me to come up there and
see yourself that it was on the level.
Was it on the level, Vic?
No .. no, it wasn't.
Rooms 4 and 6. Connecting door.
You didn't even bother with
appearances, did you.
It was all pretty obvious.
You may not believe it,
but I didn't plan it that way.
I admit that once it had happened, I ..
Well, I figured it might be convenient.
You'll say anything to win
your point, won't you.
Make any promise.
That's the kind of a guy I am.
I haven't kidded you about that.
Well, I didn't believe you.
I thought you were more than that.
Now you know.
─ Now I know.
And I guess it's like I
told you once before.
We must be sure and
exchange Christmas cards.
We're just different kinds
of people, that's all.
I can't change, Vic.
─ Neither can I.
If we forgot this, it would
just be a little while ..
Until I'd be inviting you to a Blue
Penguin Inn again someplace.
And I'd do that same
thing I did yesterday.
I'm going to Hollywood.
I'm on my way to the train now.
Oh.
For how long?
A week or two.
Have a nice trip, Vic.
Goodbye, Kay.
Well, he's my agent and he should know.
He said, listen honey, a girl's got
to have at least one mink coat ..
Or she won't have any respect in
Hollywood. So, I took the coat.
Jean!
I don't believe it. Vic! Vic, baby.
Hello, honey.
I thought you were already out there.
─ I'm glad I'm not.
Oh, so am I.
Oh Jean, you look good. Awful good.
Have you gotten prettier
since I last saw you?
I don't know. Does it
seem that way to you?
Luscious-er and luscious-er.
Oh that's good, huh?
─ That's very good.
How'd you find me?
Were you going through the cars
shopping to see what you could pick up?
Believe it or not,
I was looking for a man.
Dave Lash.
Oh the agent. He's up in the Club Car.
Or at least he was a few minutes ago.
Club Car?
─ Club Car.
Wait a minute.
I see him down there.
There is only one thing.
When there's a break in the
conversation, mention Buddy Hare.
Mention him good, or mention him bad?
Bad. You hate him as bad as
if he were another singer.
I get it.
Hello Dave.
─ Oh, hello Vic.
Jean Ogilvie. Well well.
Sit down, won't you.
You two know my new assistant.
Freddy Callahan.
How do you do.
─ Have something to drink?
It seems like we always meet
on planes or trains, Dave.
Yeah. I haven't seen you since
before you went into the Army.
Glad to see you back.
There's a smart operator, Freddy.
I'm trying to teach Freddy the business.
So far all he's taught me is how
to lose to him at Gin Rummy.
What's cooking, Vic?
Why are you on the way to the coast?
Oh, the scenery.
Take a look. Isn't the Hudson beautiful?
Yeah, lovely. Lovely isn't it.
That's typical .. of all of us.
What's American to us?
A blank space between New York and
Hollywood where people buy soap.
That Freddy, is lesson number one.
When a guy like Vic won't tell an agent
why he's on his way to the coast.
It means that he intends
to buy some talent.
And he's afraid we're going to raise
the price on him. Isn't that right, Vic?
You are the teacher.
Whoever you'll buy, you may just as
well buy him from us.            ─ Why?
We handle everybody. Everybody good.
The boy is right.
You know what?
People are beginning
to say I'm a monopoly.
Hmm. You even handle me.
Since when, Jean?
─ Oh, a couple of months ago.
Your office is getting
a screen-test for me.
There you are, Vic. Nothing but
the best. That's Lash Incorporated.
Oh don't give me that.
You'll handle anybody.
Why I hear you even handle Buddy Hare.
That's right.
What are we doing with him?
─ Trying to get him a radio show.
Boy, this is where I turn in my
radio for a vacuum cleaner.
No Jean, I think you're too hard on him.
Buddy isn't that bad.
Not nearly that bad.
And between us, she's right. You know
Dave, we ought to get rid of that guy.
We get him any work
since he's been with us?
One guest spot.
─ Oh, that's not enough.
When we've gotten him a good
job and he's eating regular.
Then we'll drop him. Not until.
Jean, let's go to Marvin in the diner.
Wait a minute. You haven't told
me who you're buying from us.
So far you haven't mentioned
anybody but Buddy Hare.
And I'm not going to buy him
just to get Dave off the hook.
We'll see you around.
─ Goodbye.
See you later.
Dave.
You've never seen me sell, have you?
─ No, I haven't.
Well before I got to the back of
a desk I used to be pretty good.
I know that.
That Vic is a smart boy.
And Buddy Hare is a lemon.
But I'll bet you five bucks
I sell Buddy Hare to Vic.
I'll take that bet.
─ Sucker.
Mr David Lash, David Lash.
Telegram for Mr David Lash.
Here.
Mr Lash?
No, but I'm traveling with him.
I'll take it for him.
Sign there, sir.
You wouldn't want to take one for a
Mr Valentine too, would you, sir?
No, I'm afraid not.
Thank you, sir.
You know, this brings up an interesting
question of comparative morals.
To deliver this or not?
You mean someone might be telegraphing
him that you really want Buddy Hare?
Exactly.
You know, when I was
a little girl in Brooklyn.
We had a party-line phone.
It seems that a racehorse named
Honey Lamb paid nine dollars for two.
Thanks, Jean.
─ I enjoyed it.
You could be a lot of help to
a girl like me, couldn't you.
In what way?
In a business way, naturally.
Want a secretary, Mr Norman?
How's your shorthand?
─ Some people like it.
I'll bet you were a tough little girl.
I still am, for the wrong guy.
And for the right guy?
For the right guy.
For the right guy Vic, I'm not so tough.
You know, I never much
liked train trips before, but ..
This one is going to be just dandy.
Isn't it?
I don't know.
What do you mean, you don't know?
You're .. you're trying awfully hard to
sell yourself on me, aren't you, Vic.
What are you talking about?
─ I know you.
I know you like a book, honey.
You're on the rebound aren't you,
from that Mrs Dorrance?
I haven't got anybody
on my mind but you.
Maybe you'll convince me of that.
That's all I ask, Vic.
Just make me believe that and
everything else will be just dandy.
America's first hucksters.
Mister, you like to buy Indian suit?
Never wear them.
No. Children's suit.
Your Missy not got children?
Want to make something of it?
Mister. Maybe you know some children?
Little boy, little girl children.
No, no. I guess not.
Oh yes, come to think of it. Mister does
know a little girl and a little boy.
I'd almost forgotten about
Mister and his love for children.
Special price.
Ten dollars with full feathers.
Come on, honey. Let's take a walk.
─ No. I'll go buy some magazines.
I'd hate to come between two
kids and their Indian suits.
All aboard!
Three.
Well, you got me with ten.
That's the game.
Well, I think I'll go to bed. I want to
be fresh when I get in in the morning.
Yeah, one more game
and I'll throw you all out.
Vic, I wish you'd give more thought to
Buddy Hare. Then I'll drop the subject.
Dave, I told you once. I don't think
Buddy Hare has a change of the big time.
Anybody can put on a good
show with a good comedian.
Why don't you do it the hard way?
Oh no. I'm an easy-way boy.
I'd make my living
lying down if I could.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll give him to you
at his bottom salary.
Put him in a cheap
show with good writing.
Why don't you try it?
Well Dave, I'll tell you.
─ Yes?
You convince me. I'll buy Buddy Hare.
─ You'll what?
On condition that you give me
an option letter right now.
We'll write it out ourselves. I don't
want lawyers complicating things.
Anything you say.
─ Deal?              ─ It's a deal.
Well, kid.
─ I don't know how you did it.
I'm going to frame this.
It proves that my hand
hasn't lost its skill.
I sold the biggest lemon in our stable.
I sold Buddy Hare to a
smart guy like Vic Norman.
How's that for salesmanship?
─ Oh, it’s fine. Just fine.
Only one thing is ..
─ What?
Can I tell him now, Vic?
He's bound to hear in the morning.
Well, that lemon of yours.
That's the man that Vic was sent out
here to buy. For Evan Llewellyn Evans.
Well you're a smart businessman, Vic.
You're a good sport.
And Freddy, here is
your five dollars back.
And there is mine. Because I
didn't sell anything. I was had.
You can keep a secret, can't you?
─ Oh, sure.
You do and I have an idea
you'll have a rise in salary.
Hey, I'm beginning to
like this business.
[ Buzzer ]
Who is it?
─ Freddy. Freddy Callahan.
I got Buddy Hare with me.
Morning Vic, old man. Well, here he is.
Buddy Hare!
Hiya, chum.
Just call me Buddy.
Hiya. Most folks call me Vic.
You can call me Victor.
Oh the boy is sharp and fast.
Buddy's all excited about the show. He's
got a lot of good ideas for you. Really.
Yeah, I got material that will lay them
in the aisles. It will fracture them.
Don't worry about a thing. Not a thing.
Right now I'm getting cleaned up.
So if you'll just ..
[ Buzzer ]
Somebody send for a
couple of hot writers?
Herman and Gaver.
Scripts made while you wait.
How is Norman, the white
hope of radio and ..
The fair-haired man of American go.
George, you've been collaborating too
long. You finish each other's sentences.
You know George, I think ..
─ He's got something there.
So do I.
Wait a minute, I'm the
comic around here.
I guess you know Buddy Hare.
─ Yeah. We know him.
Hey, what are you doing here, Buddy?
─ He's your comedian.
Swell.
Buddy. Your writers.
Writers? Who needs them?
Look Vic, you ..
You guys start thinking up a character
for Buddy to play. I'll finish shaving.
Why, that's okay by me.
I can work any place.
And he wants a character.
─ He's got one.
Oh now Vicky, forget about
them writers, will you.
I've forgot more jokes than
those guys ever knew.
Hey listen, what kind a program are we
going to give this character Evans, huh?
What's the matter? Cigar bother you?
─ Oh no.
I wouldn't miss a morning without it.
─ Oh, swell.
Any kind of a program you want I can
give you. Without no help from nobody.
I ain't one of them baggy-pants
slap-shoot comics. You know what I mean?
I work strictly class.
Everyday clothes, just like I've
got on. See what I mean?
Yeah, I think I see what you
mean. A man of distinction.
You've got it. Class with a capital "K".
Whatever kind of a program
you want, I got it .. hey.
You want a hotel routine?
I've got a swell one.
This one is murder.
I live in a swell hotel.
I got a nice 2-dollar room and hot
and cold running chambermaids.
The rooms are so small.
You must go in the hall
to change your mind.
Yeah. All the mice walk
around hunchbacked.
Then the dining room. Say,
the dining room ceiling is so low ..
All they can serve is flounder.
Alright. Now, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Here's one I made up out of my own mind.
He has a mind?
Look, you say to me ..
─ Hold it.
Where did you dig up this crock of corn?
Oh, I've been around.
Round the burlesque houses?
Oh, I was sort of an Emcee.
An Emcee in a burlesque house?
Merchandiser of candy.
I see .. a candy butcher.
Say, maybe we can work out something
where you do sort-of a gag commercial.
Kid with the announcer.
What sort of spiel did you give?
Well ..
The acoustics in here
ain't so hot but ..
It used to go something like this.
I used to walk out on
the stage and I'd say:
Alright, before the show starts, I've an
announcement for the patrons here.
Those of you who are regular
patrons of the Getty Theater.
Are well acquainted with
our fine selection of candy.
Now I represent the
Beautiful Sky Candy Company.
Makers of those delicious
chocolate-covered California fruits.
I .. I guess I'll be gone.
Yeah.
You have a chance to win.
A genuine water watch
of Warner Massachusetts.
I heard what you said, young man!
You said this was not a genuine
water watch of Warner Massachusetts.
Well now, to be sure, it's not
a hundred-dollar watch.
It is not a fifty dollar watch.
But it is ..
A genuine ten-dollar water watch
of Warner Massachusetts.
My confederates ..
My confederates and myself
will pass through the audience.
Our one purpose is for
the program to sell soap.
See what I mean? Soap.
Hey, I got it.
It came to me like a flash.
Get a load of this.
Now. I walk out onto
the stage like this, see.
I slip.
The announcer comes out,
holds the microphone over my face.
I say .. "Hiya folks".
"You got to fall for the Beautee Soap."
No.
No?
I think I have it. I think I
know what to do with him.
We know what to do with him. First, take
a little strychnine, add some cyanide ..
Boys, this is serious.
We have to work with this guy.
We have to get something out of him.
I got it!
I got it.
The "painter" routine.
I go to the door like this, see.
Good.
I am painting the door with black paint.
You are furious.
─ Right.
You say to me: go!
And never darken my door again.
Great, huh?
─ Oh, great. Only do it.
Never darken my doorstep again.
I like it. I like it.
Never darken my doorstep again ..
I'm sorry Buddy, but I want to
talk to the boys for a while.
Listen. Would you
like a peephole routine?
Of the peephole, by the
peephole, for the peephole.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Now this is it.
We'll make this dope a
sideshow barker, the thing he is.
A carnival, circus kind of a guy.
Yeah. That he could play.
Not bad. Not bad. Might be alright.
─ [ Buzzer ]
Oh no, not again.
Hey, now ..
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Yes?
I'm from the office, Mr Norman.
Oh. Oh, come in.
─ Thank you.          ─ Sit down.
Hi, fellahs.
─ Hi, Gloria.
I tried phoning you, but the hotel
operator said she couldn't ring you.
Yeah. I hate being
disturbed in the morning.
An urgent message came by teletype
from Mr Kimberly in New York.
"Mr Norman from Mr Kimberly."
"Evans wants to know what kind of a
show you are planning for Buddy Hare."
"He says shoot him general descriptions
so we can chat-chat about it here."
"Let me have answer immediately."
Here is the answer.
Ready?
Tell him it's to go
chat-chat in the lake.
I'm making this
audition record. Not him.
Check.
Sign it "Vic".
Are you really that sure of yourself?
I don't know. I try to act like I am.
Thank you, Mr Norman.
Goodbye, boys.
─ Goodbye, Gloria.
Goodbye, Mr Norman.
Goodbye.
How are you fixed for dates out here?
Okay, I have a girl.
─ You mean, you got one already?
Yeah, she's cooking me dinner
tonight. Now listen ..
The way I see this show is a normal gag
comedy format with a band for support.
The main thing is to get new,
fresh material for Buddy.
Now, in making him
into a sideshow barker.
We could ..
[ Radio broadcast: ]
"Have you provided for your loved one?"
"Remember, sorrow comes
when you least expect it."
"At Meadow Mill Mortuary there
are beautiful shady plots."
"Overlooking serenely
peaceful Fairwood."
"Restful, refined, dignified
surroundings for ever."
[ Radio: ]
"Want to learn how to spell? Well."
[ Singing: ]
"B.E.A.U.T.E.E - B.E.A.U.T.E.E.."
"B.E.A.U.T.E.E spells: "
"Beautee Soap!"
[ Radio: ]
"Oh boy, wow!"
"King of the breakfast foods."
Hello.
You're just what a guy needs, Jean.
Am I, Vic?
You're an awful pretty girl.
You really mean it, don't you.
Oh I'm so glad, Vic.
I thought I'd lost you to that
Mrs .. whatever her name is.
Hey, come on. You've got
to help me with dinner.
The cocktails are in the icebox.
You've been here a whole day and
no suntan yet. What's the matter?
Been standing over a hot script.
Working with the writers.
Is the show going to be good?
─ It might. It just might.
And we can use a singer.
─ Hey.
Jean, if that screen-test deal
of yours doesn't work out ..
Will you promise to
sing the way I tell you?
Oh Vic, that would be wonderful.
Yes.
But will you sing the way I tell you?
Well, that depends on what you tell me.
Evan Llewellyn Evans is a little deaf.
He likes people that sing loud.
Loud and on the beat.
"Over there, da da da."
He likes the kind of singers
his father used to like."
But Vic.
That's old-fashioned. Modern
singing is soft, not loud.
And off the beat.
That's what the public want.
Unfortunately, what the public
wants has nothing to do with radio.
It's what the sponsor wants that counts.
You know I'd be a big fool not to take
the advice of a hip character like you.
Hmm.
Vic.
Isn't it nice we're both
in the same business?
It makes everything so much
cozier, don't you think so?
Yes, Jean.
Everything just as cozy as it can be.
Hey, Ogilvie.
Come here.
─ In a minute.
First, I want to get you
some after-dinner brandy.
I should have brought my house slippers.
You know, I like doing
things for you, Vic.
I like having you around the house.
I'm what you might call a
"Vic Norman" kind of a gal.
You know, I think you are at that.
And as for me, Jean honey?
Whoever's apartment this is
must be crazy for penguins.
What's the matter? Are you
allergic to them or something?
You might put it that way.
What is it, honey?
Oh nothing, Jean. Nothing at all.
Now where we? What witty
thing was I trying to say?
Oh yes: Jean.
─ It's her, isn't it?
Something just reminded you of her.
I was right, wasn't I?
Let's skip it, Jean.
And stop interrupting me when ..
─ I was right.
I haven't got a chance, have I.
Oh Vic, you're in love with her.
Look, Jean. Why don't
we go out to a movie?
Sure.
Why not.
Maybe we can find a western
with a lot of shooting in it.
I don't feel much like sitting through
a mushy love story, do you?
Vic.
Who's there?
It's Kay.
Honey, you're what was missing.
You are what I missed.
Oh, me too.
I missed you.
I missed you so much.
You're a long ways from home, darling.
I suppose I ought to pretend I had
sudden urgent business in California.
I do, actually.
You know what, Mr Norman?
You're pretty.
Do you know what?
You're crazy.
I guess I am.
I just couldn't stand it any longer.
I simply got on a plane.
It's like I once said.
You're an honest woman.
I suppose you're used
to this sort of thing.
Having women chase you.
I hate to tell you this.
But hardly anyone ever chases me.
Chasing me is a sure sign of insanity.
Now that I'm here ..
I don't know what to say.
Nothing has really changed since
we had that fight in New York.
Yes, it has.
A lot has changed.
─ What?
I don't know.
When I heard your
voice a minute ago, I ..
Honey .. do you have a place to stay?
I have a reservation on a plane back.
I've got two hours.
I just wanted to see you again.
Why not stick around a while?
It's a nice country.
Alright.
I just wanted to be asked.
I know the ropes, like you.
Maybe I can get you a room.
Way over there.
Good morning, good morning.
Oh Mr Norman, we've been
looking all over for you.
They want you at the teletype right now.
─ Take it easy, honey. Haven't you heard?
All is right with the world.
Oh Mr Norman, they've been trying to
get you all morning on the teletype.
Send two, no three dozen roses
to Mrs Frances Dorrance ..
At the Sunset Hills Hotel.
Yes, sir.
Oh Mr Norman, they're
going crazy in New York.
I'll tell them you're here.
Trouble, huh? Trouble is
not what I want this morning.
What does it seem to be about?
Mr Norman, we've lost Buddy Hare.
After all that time you've spent on him.
What? We can't lose him.
Here it is.
"Kim to Vic."
"This is serious."
"Lash gave Keeves Agency .."
"Option on Hare."
"Prior to yours."
"Dave has left us holding the bag."
Oh that Mr Lash, he's so dishonest.
No he's not.
There must be a mistake.
Dave Lash is an honest man.
Call him. Tell him I'm on my way over.
Tell Mr Kimberly this:
Relax, Kim. I'll fix it someway.
Love and kisses, Vic.
Hello, Vic.
─ Hello, Dave.
Meet the legal battery.
This is Harry Spooner and Joe Lawrensön.
─ How do you do.
Vic, the Keeves people called
me up a month or so ago.
And said no dice on Buddy Hare.
Unconsciously, I wrote it off.
But Keeves, legally,
still have the paper.
And Keeves, legally, have Buddy Hare.
You don't.
It's like he said, Mr Norman.
Keeves owns Hare. You don't.
Besides, I've examined the
option you wrote on the train.
Any good lawyer could break it in court.
─ Uhuh.
Since when did your office
start going in for legal cuties?
Harry, you know I don't
go for that kind of stuff.
Dave, I have one little idea.
It will satisfy Keeves,
and it will satisfy me.
But it would cost Dave Lash
quite a bit of money.
Well, how much?
─ The idea is this.
You tell Keeves you'll get
them a top comedy name.
And you get them the top name at the
price they would have paid Buddy Hare.
You pay the difference.
Why, that would run in to ..
Why, that would cost us .. that
would cost us a thousand a week.
For more than a year.
─ It might, Dave.
Mr Lash, let us take this into court.
We'll win, and it will only cost you a
hundred dollars or so in court fees.
You have us on retainer anyway.
Dave, can I see you alone for a minute?
─ Yeah. You heard him, boys.
We won't go far. I think
you're going to need us.
Dave.
This is important to me.
─ I can see that.
Do you remember one night on
a plane four or five years ago?
What night?
We happened to be
traveling East together.
I was getting ready to go into the Army.
And you were going back to New York
to attend a certain luncheon.
Remember?
─ Luncheon?
I'm not much of man for luncheons.
You were in a talkative mood.
You said when you were a kid
on New York's East side ..
That you were arrested for stealing
some pennies and sent to reform school.
Remember?
Sometimes I talk too much.
Well, that's nothing to be ashamed of.
Later you told me you were
going back to New York ..
To be awarded a scroll by some kind
of civic benevolent organization.
The kid who'd gone straight.
Something about setting a fine example
for underprivileged kids like you were.
Dave.
I think that's something to be proud of.
─ Well I am proud of it.
I give quite a bit of money each year to
run boys' clubs in my old neighborhood.
Decent clubs where
kids can get together.
Without drifting around the
streets or sitting in pool rooms.
Why .. they're a great bunch of kids.
They've got my picture on the
wall of each one of the clubs ..
As if I was something terrific.
And you're going to let those kids down.
Let them down?
What are you talking about?
─ Dave, think a minute.
When this thing about
Buddy Hare gets talked around.
And it's bound to get around, Dave.
You know there are a lot of people
who hate to see a guy like you ..
A guy from the wrong side
of the tracks, get ahead.
What do you think those
people are going to say?
That an agent made a mistake?
No .. you know better than that, Dave.
They're going to say it
was crooked. Dishonest.
They're going to say you can never
trust a guy with any kind of a record.
Now, how do you think that's going to
look to the kids you're trying to help?
How do you think it'll
look to those kids ..
Who think you've done it the
hard way and look up to you?
Dave, I hit you where you live.
And I didn't mean to.
The next thing I know, I'll be ..
Beating women and kicking children.
Dave, I'd consider it a favor
if you'd forget I ever said it.
What you said is true.
Go ahead with your Buddy Hare show.
I'll work it out some way.
Maybe even the way you suggest.
Dave, I've done a rotten thing.
And I want to ask you to forgive me.
You've got your Buddy Hare. You won.
I ask you to forgive me.
I have respect for you, Vic.
You got what you came for.
This is one time I'd rather
be forgiven than respected.
Like I said, I have respect for you.
And I wish I could say
the same thing for myself.
About myself.
So now you know.
Now you know what a heel I am.
Come on, darling. Don't worry about it.
Everyone has done things
they're ashamed of.
I can't imagine you
doing anything like that.
I rather like being on a
pedestal but don't overdo it.
Oh we're so lucky, darling.
Aren't we?
Come on, Kay .. let's walk.
Beautiful, isn't it.
They call it poetic inspiration.
─ They should.
You didn't answer my question.
I said aren't you we lucky.
That we have each other.
Nothing else matters.
A lot else matters.
A lot.
Kay.
I want you to go back to New York.
The first plane we can get you on.
Alright, Vic.
Don't be like that.
That isn't what I mean.
I mean I don't want
any Blue Penguin Inn.
I want everything to be right about us.
You know if I bring off this Buddy Hare
show, I'll be a man with a good job.
A man who can afford to support
a house near Sutton Place.
Oh .. Vic.
Vic, darling.
And I used to say that
money is only money.
Why, it's clothes for you,
school for the kids.
Stop being a breadwinner and kiss me.
I can't think.
─ Want some more coffee?
No no, it's no use. I'm dead.
I got to go home.
─ Sit down.
You know I had a wife once.
Bet she's gone to Mexico by now.
If you stop beating, finish the
script, maybe you'll see her again.
Thanks, pal.
You know this is the best work you two
have done. One more day and we're in.
I'll tell you what.
─ What?
Maybe it will give us an idea.
Read the script aloud again.
Oh no, Vic. Not that.
If you read those
jokes just once more ..
So help me, I'll kill myself.
Let's hope Evans doesn't feel the same
when I get to New York with the record.
On the other hand, let's hope he does.
Hello, Vic.
Do you ever go to bed?
─ Come, get into my car. We must hurry.
What for?
─ Evans. A meeting in 20 minutes.
At two o'clock in the morning?
─ Well, you know Evans.
Tell me, what happened?
Did everything go alright?
It was a good audition.
Buddy Hare was as funny
as can be expected.
I've got the record here.
─ Where are you going?
I've got to make a phone
call. Evans can wait.
Can't you make your
phone call later, Vic?
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Vic.
My darling, where are you?
I'm in La Guardia Field.
Oh, you sound so warm and sleepy.
"I've missed you, darling."
"Do you love me?"
I adore you.
I'll throw on some clothes and
you come over here right away.
I can't. Meet me at Evans' office.
Stay in your car. Park
on the Wall Street side.
When you get there,
blow the horn three times.
"To say hello."
"This is it, honey."
"This is where I take them
for our year's income."
I have to go now.
The man who is about to
pay our grocery bill awaits.
Remember honey.
Three times.
Let's go. Why take a chance on
irritating the old man at this time?
I wouldn't think of irritating
him at a time like this.
It's too important to me now.
─ Then come on, come on.
Kim. I'm in love. I'm engaged.
Well that's fine, Vic. That's fine.
But I'll congratulate you in the car.
It's Kay. Kay Dorrance.
No kidding. That's wonderful, Vic.
─ She has two children.
I know. I saw their pictures. Remember?
You can tell me all about it in the car.
Children cost money.
Nurses and cereals and things.
Kim, make it thirty-five
thousand instead of twenty-five.
Now look here, Vic. If you
think you can get away with ..
Okay.
Thirty-five thousand dollars
a year if Evans okays you.
Plus bonuses.
─ Okay, Chum.
Now let's go take care
of Evan Llewellyn Evans.
This place feels like a morgue.
Vic, I wish you wouldn't
say things like that.
It's locked.
The trañscription, please.
Mr Evans wants to hear it first.
Without you.
Give her the records.
You are both to wait here.
Welcome home, Mr Norman.
He's building up to something.
I'm worried.
You're always worried.
Are those records alright?
Is the show alright?
In my opinion it will make people laugh.
If they happen to want to laugh.
As for Evans, how do I know?
And the singer? How did
the drummer girl turn out?
I didn't use a drummer girl.
─ You didn't?
I think we get a brand-new
singing star, Kim.
Who?
─ You know her.
A girl named Jean Ogilvie.
─ Jean Ogilvie?
Vic! A nightclub singer. A nobody!
Everybody was a nobody once.
─ Yeah, but lots of them stay nobodies.
Take it easy, Kim.
─ Take it easy? Something is cooking.
There has been ever since you refused to
send an outline of the Buddy Hare show.
He hasn't mentioned it since, Vic. I say
he's setting the stage for something.
Oh look, Kim. We can't lose.
─ Why can't we lose?
I told you. Because I'm in
love now. And I can use him.
I'm not going to let him tie a can on
our tails just the minute I need him.
I won't let the old goat do that to us.
─ Shush. Vic, not so loud.
He may have the place wired.
I think I'm going to be sick.
Hey, cut it out, will you.
You're beginning to me Evans- happy.
─ Well, it's about time.
You may come in, now.
Good morning, Mr Norman.
─ Good morning, sir.
Good morning, Kimberly.
─ Good morning, Mr Evans.
Allison, bring me the letter I
wrote earlier this evening.
I take the position that a man either
knows where he's going or he doesn't.
Right?
─ Right.
Right.
This letter is to my youngest son.
Evan Llewellyn Evans the 3rd.
Dear son, you've been overseas
in the army of occupation ..
For seven months and three
days at this time of writing.
My son, I detect a profound note of
discouragement in your letters to me.
My dear Captain Evan
Llewellyn Evans the 3rd.
I take the position that a man knows
where he's going or he doesn't.
And if he doesn't he must chat-chat
with himself and his associates.
Not to go off half-cocked
on his own. Check?
Check.
─ Check.
That son, is what I call organization.
As it applies to an individual
as well as a group.
The rest of the letter is personal.
I wonder if my son will get the point.
It's a beautifully made point, Mr Evans.
Excellent. Makes me wish
I had a son to write to.
The letter has a bearing
on that province.
Mr Norman, you chose to go off on
your own and make an audition record.
You chose to ignore our
normal procedure of chat-chat.
Chat-chat, and double chat-chat.
You went off by yourself and
did things your own way.
Tonight we heard the records.
Tangible proof of what comes
of your going off on your own.
The proof of the pudding
is in the eating, right?
Right.
─ Right.
After hearing those
records, I can only say ..
That you, as an individual ..
Are well organized.
Your program is excellent, Mr Norman.
Excellent .. right?
Right.
Frankly, I wouldn't have
been surprised if it wasn't.
But it was. It was good.
And that singer!
That Jean Ogilvie. Now, that's a voice.
[ Singing: ]
"Over there .. over there!"
"Rat tat de ta dat dah dah!"
Ha ha. Mr Norman ..
I congratulate you.
You wear the mantle of Beautee Soap now.
Mr Kimberly, have you discussed
salary with Mr Norman?
Well, we've talked about
$35,000 a year plus bonuses.
Well, Mr Norman.
Is that satisfactory to you?
Thirty-five thousand dollars
a year is a lot of money.
A lot of money.
Right?
─ Right.
And right now, I'm a
man who needs money.
Mr Evans.
Tonight, you had a little sport with me.
A little sadistic sport.
A childish thing of no importance.
You got me to say "right"
when you wanted me to.
And you succeeded in introducing
me to your general manager.
Your foreman.
─ My foreman?
Your foreman: fear.
Your overseer: fear.
The thing that keeps these
people in line for you.
I didn't know about "fear"
before, but I do now.
I know what it is to be so
worried about your job ..
That you'll kick around a perfectly
nice guy like David Lash.
A guy who's never
been anything but kind.
A guy who does a lot of
good for a lot of people.
I'll tell you something.
I don't like being made to feel afraid.
Mr Evans, there isn't enough money
in the world to make me work for you.
Vic, Vic!
Heaven knows Mr Evans, you're a big one.
The big, rich, successful one.
But there are others. Tyrants, despots.
You and your kind,
wherever you do business.
I think that for a man like you ..
To control so much of what goes over
the air into the homes of America is ..
Well, it's all wet.
See what I mean?
Darling.
What's the matter?
Oh darling, they didn't like
your show? Oh, I'm sorry.
They did like the show.
They liked it fine.
Then what in the world has ..?
─ Kay.
I've got something to tell
you you're not going to like.
Get in the car ready.
Let's drive up to your house.
Darling, what is this? Where are we?
Bolton market.
They start early down here.
Vic, I can't stand it any longer.
What is it that's wrong?
Honey, it's bad news.
I want to get you firmly seated in your
own living room before I tell you.
No. Now, Vic.
Please, I'm really quite a big girl.
You are going to tell me now.
Darling, I see you troubled too often
with what you've been doing, What is it?
What is it?
I just threw away my job. I got fed up.
You and I are going to have to wait a
long time before we can be married.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
So, if you want out, Kay ..
I see.
It's a matter of self-respect.
Just getting out of the Army and all, I
don't know. Things look different to me.
I was becoming ..
Like that guy over there.
Aye, aye, aye! Step right down here
friends and get your fountain pens.
You can't afford to be without one.
Now here they are.
You understand, Kay?
Of course I understand.
You're such a child, darling.
You've come to hate the business you're
in and you just want to drop it and ..
Go and live on a beach
in Tahiti or something.
That's an idea.
Yes. But Vic, you're too good for that.
Why don't you sell
things you believe in?
And sell them with dignity and taste?
That's a career for any man. A career
to be proud of. What's wrong with that?
Nothing .. nothing at all.
Except.
This is all I have in the world.
It'll take a long time and all that time
no dough for clothes for you, for nurses.
That's it, isn't it.
When you say money, you mean big money.
And that just doesn't matter, Vic.
That's not something you base a life on.
If you do, then you're Kimberly.
But us ..?
Oh, Vic.
You wonderful dope.
You and I are going to get married
just as soon as we can get a license.
And then you're going to
do what you want to do.
And that's what matters.
Doing what you want to. Not money.
You mean that, don't you.
─ Yes, I do.
Well, you asked for it.
Who's going to have the next one?
What did you do that for?
Now we're starting out with exactly
an even nothing in the world.
It's neater that way.
T-G