- What are they doing?
- Get her.
- What's wrong?
- What is it?
What are you doing?
- Let me go.
- Why are you doing this?
Let go!
Soo Jin!
Hey!
That's enough.
Don't mind us and be on your way, Sir.
These jerks are waking
up the beast inside me.
(The morality of our partner
very important to us.)
The morality of our partner
very important to us.
(TQ lost its credit with us.)
TQ lost its credit with us.
I'm sorry, Sir.
The rumors you heard were
made up by our competitors.
(That means you don't have...)
(good relationships with other companies.)
(We think of relationships
as very important.)
That's crazy talk.
So what does he want?
This is an important meeting.
Watch what you say.
(What would you like to say?)
(I was going to withdraw my investment...)
(but I changed my mind.)
Why did he change his mind?
(Why did you change your mind?)
(I'll tell you why later.
First, there are terms.)
I'll tell you why later.
First, there are terms.
What are the terms?
(We can't trust your finance director, )
(so we'll randomly choose
one of your subsidiaries.)
(Then we'll go in and
do a thorough review.)
We'll go in and do a thorough review.
(After the review, we'll
decide whether we'll invest.)
They can't trust our accounting,
so they'll review us.
I'm sorry, but your term
is crossing the line.
(If that's what you think, )
(we'll return to China.)
Okay.
Sit down.
Tell them we'll accept.
Mr. Seo, if we accept
their terms too easily...
If you don't have a solution, shut...
Be quiet. You aren't helping.
(Yes, we'll accept your terms.)
(There is one more important term.)
There is one more important term.
You jerks, how dare you forcefully...
drag women?
We're private bodyguards.
We only do as we're told.
As you're told?
How can you use violence toward women...
just because you were told?
You should be ashamed!
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm...
Gosh. Wait a minute.
What is it?
I'm okay.
You're not okay.
You look like you have
ketchup on your lips.
Hello?
Yes, Sir.
Take him away.
Take who away?
- Hey.
- Come with us.
You jerks! Let go!
Let me go!
Soo Jin, wait here.
Okay.
Let go!
Where are you taking me?
(Yes! That's him!)
- What is he saying?
- Let me go.
I have to go in.
Goodness. Who's in here?
He's here. Tell him to
say the important term.
(We brought him, so tell
us the important term.)
(Include him in the due
diligence preparation team.)
They want him in the due
diligence preparation team.
Do they even know him?
(Do you know him?)
(We do. Seong Ryong.)
(He's the chief of Business Operations, )
(and a righteous man.)
(I saw it on social media.)
He's the chief of Business Operations,
and a righteous man.
They saw him on social media.
You're a global celebrity now.
Why does he have to be
included in the team?
(He threw his body to save a person.)
(That means he's honest and dedicated.)
(He won't let his personal feelings...)
(get in the way of assessing his company.)
(I'm sure he'll give a
hard-headed assessment.)
(Because he is a righteous man.)
He threw his body to save a person.
That means he's honest and dedicated.
He won't let his personal feelings...
get in the way of assessing his company.
I'm sure he'll give a
hard-headed assessment.
Because he's a righteous man.
He's a righteous man!
- He's a righteous man!
- A righteous man!
- Mr. Righteous!
I keep hearing things.
What the heck is he talking about?
Which subsidiary will they choose?
(It's TQ Delivery.)
It's TQ Delivery.
All right.
I'll report to the chairman first.
Then we'll arrange the date.
(He'll report to the chairman first.)
(Then he'll arrange the date.)
I can't do it.
(He says he can't do it.)
(No, he must do it.)
She says he must do it.
He just said he couldn't do it.
The job is too big for me.
Someone who's better than
me should do the job.
Excuse me.
(Why is he leaving?)
I don't think you can leave like this.
That looked really important.
I have a plan.
What plan?
You want them to drop the
charges on Soo Jin, right?
What?
Then wait in the office for a bit.
I'll go back into the waiting room.
He says he doesn't want to do it.
He's not good enough to take that job.
What kind of nonsense are they saying?
No.
I persuaded the executives.
If Chief Kim won't do the job,
this negotiation will be nullified.
This is awkward.
Mr. Seo, from now on,
please use refined language.
That was an unexpected
request, including Chief Kim.
We might find an evidence
during the preparation.
That's possible, but the chances are low.
Instead of doctoring the account books...
I think they're planning
to show the deficit as is.
But just in case,
you should be in the preparation team.
Me?
How can I get in the preparation...
I'll take care of it...
without anyone noticing.
Okay.
What do they want?
If it was like our plan, we had to...
prepare for the company's
settlement of accounts.
Why did they single out TQ Delivery?
It's a subsidiary which looks
like it is losing money.
They just want to see...
if we will forge its account.
But we have a problem.
TQ Delivery's union is on a
strike since this morning.
They are in front of TQ
Delivery's headquarters.
Then move them before Seoahn
Jangryong Funds sees them.
They will use that to our disadvantage.
We cannot do that right away.
It will take some time for
us to negotiate with them.
Those darned unions.
I will take care of the union
strike as soon as I can.
What should I do with the
chief of Business Operations?
I will persuade Chief Kim one more time.
He threw his life to save a person,
and he wasn't afraid to
hit the chairman's son.
Will he be easily persuaded by you?
Come to think about it, you hired him.
Yes, I did.
You should have controlled him well.
It's about time someone called. Four.
Two, one.
What a perfect timing.
How perfect is this?
Hello?
Yes.
Okay.
Why are you saying no?
It's not something that
a mere chief can do.
What do you want?
- Pardon?
- Be honest.
I am not at my own interest here, Chairman.
I won't get angry.
Tell me.
With all due respect, may I make a request?
You should have brought it up already!
You said you wouldn't get angry.
Yes. I am not angry. Okay.
Speak.
I believe my predecessor,
Lee Eun Seok's wife is...
facing a lawsuit...
about how our investment was foundered.
- So what?
- I will do my best...
as a part of the preparation
team, so please...
drop the lawsuit.
Is that all you want?
Though it is something small,
I do have one more request.
I will personally...
make that request to Director Seo.
Tell Ms. Cho...
to drop the lawsuit.
I never want to hear a word...
about Mr. Lee's wife from this day on.
Yes, Sir.
Mr. Seo, if what he asks isn't too much,
make sure you let him have it.
Yes, Sir.
Thank you, Sir.
I will do my best.
Arrange a DF team...
and prepare for due diligence
starting tomorrow.
Everything about this investment is...
in your hands, Mr. Seo.
Are you insane?
I thought I made myself clear.
You should learn to be afraid.
I've been living as a huge coward.
But I felt so bad for Mr. Lee's wife.
She had to sell her house...
to pay for her husband's hospital fee.
She was in a huge debt, too.
My goodness.
Are you her brother or something?
I'm not,
but I just felt so bad for her.
Tell me what your other request is.
I know that's your real request.
Can you destroy...
the books you have?
Destroy what?
My books from Deokpo Enterprise.
If you destroy just that,
I am prepared to do everything for you...
without any burden...
on my heart.
I really mean it.
What if I say no?
If you say no, what can I do? I'm a nobody.
But you are in charge of
this investment case.
I could tell the chairman
was counting on you.
I really hope you succeed.
I mean, 78 million dollars are at stake.
Darn you, idiot.
I am just really worried.
You're hurting my armpits.
Fine.
Let's make this work.
Let's make it work for
both of our benefits.
That's what I wanted, too.
Okay, we'll talk more tomorrow.
I have to prepare for the due diligence.
I really hope you can
take care of this today.
I can work at my best
when my heart is at rest.
I have never had...
such a crazy day since I
started working here.
Seong Ryong is about to be fired,
Mr. Lee's wife is in a trouble,
and Seoahn Jangryong is talking nonsense.
It's as if I'm watching an
Olympics opening ceremony.
World Cup opening ceremonies are better.
You're right.
Why isn't Seong Ryong coming?
He said he has to stop by somewhere.
You know what? It's really awesome...
they dropped the lawsuit against Mr.
Lee's wife.
If you think about it, Chief is...
very smart in a way. He's like...
- Sherlock.
- Like Brad Pitt?
What do you mean, Brad Pitt?
Chief isn't smart. He's
just good at using tricks.
Come on, at this point,
he does deserve some credit.
Of course. He took care of
the case without spending...
a dine when it could've cost
her thousands of dollars.
- That's amazing.
- And...
he joined the due diligence
preparation team, too.
Shouldn't he be considered
as our department's pride?
He's not our pride.
Chief is a lucky man.
He's not our pride. He's just lucky.
He is our pride.
I mean, has anyone here been...
on the due diligence preparation team?
- I...
- What?
Have never been on one, either.
I've been offered the position once,
but my appendix burst at that time.
Didn't you say it burst
during your promotion exam?
You said that's why you failed.
That's the other appendix.
Do you have two appendices?
These aren't kidneys.
Stop asking questions.
It's embarrassing to have two appendices.
It's a very rare case.
- Here, Gi Ok.
- Pardon?
Oh, I'm fine.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Gi Ok, what's wrong? Eat up.
No, I'm really fine.
Come on. I was the only one who ate.
You should eat. Why won't you eat?
No, I'm really fine.
- That's nonsense.
- Yes, Soo Jin.
There is no way you aren't eating. Eat.
Oh, yes. Okay.
I'm really fine.
I just received a message
from our legal team.
The company will...
drop the lawsuit.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
It's nothing.
I was wondering what you were up to.
You had a big picture in your mind.
This is barely a big picture.
It's just a tiny picture frame.
I thought...
the world was crashing down on me.
Tell it to crash down.
We will find a way to escape.
At first, it wasn't comfortable
for me to see you...
because you are my husband's replacement.
But that's not the case anymore.
To me and Seung Won,
you are a savior.
I wouldn't say I'm a savior. We are here...
to help each other.
Arrange a DF team...
and prepare for due diligence
starting tomorrow.
Everything about this investment is...
in your hands, Mr. Seo.
It's me.
Bring Kim Seong Ryong's books immediately.
I want to thank you, too.
You fought for us,
and you dropped the lawsuit, too.
Don't be thankful.
I only fought because...
I just needed a place
to vent out my stress.
What about the lawsuit?
The lawsuit is...
Did you do that to let off steam?
Well, I had many reasons.
Come to think of it, I think
you are a righteous man.
Righteous man!
Mr. Righteous!
- Mr. Righteous!
- Can't you hear that?
Please don't call me Mr. Righteous.
I'm sick of hearing that.
Mr. Chair.
- Mr. Medical insurance.
- Stop it.
- Mr. Doubt.
- Don't do it.
Mr. Righteous!
Don't call me Mr. Righteous!
What's up with Seoahn Jangryong?
When Chinese people get
stuck on something...
they think is important,
they don't back down.
I think...
it'll be a huge problem if
we can't get the investment.
I'd hate to have Director
Seo get all the credit...
though.
Still,
we can't let them be.
We need to find an alternative.
An alternative.
Inhumane working environment!
TQ must awaken!
- Wake up!
No more irrational charges and penalties!
TQ must reform!
- Reform!
Of course, I ate.
Yes, I brought heat packs.
If there's going to be a
conflict, don't go in front.
Stay back.
Okay. Don't worry. Go do your work.
You should take care of yourself.
Don't forget your dinner.
Okay, Father.
Chief!
"Mr. Righteous" is lasting a long time.
People might still call
you that until you're 60.
Gosh, that nickname. I
feel like throwing up.
You can't throw up.
It's like a badge of honor.
After you went to the waiting room,
I couldn't eat anything.
Gosh, that's nasty. What's that smell?
That's meat and kimchi.
You ate too much chicken for lunch,
so you took digestive medicine.
You even had red bean porridge for dessert.
I had that yesterday.
It was around noon today.
Why do you lie?
By the way, after conducting due diligence,
TQ Delivery will be fine, right?
What about TQ Delivery?
Well... A friend of mine works there.
It'll be fine.
They're just checking our integrity.
I see.
You didn't eat lunch. You look down.
Is something wrong?
You didn't eat lunch?
It's nothing.
Hello.
How can I help you?
I'm from General Affairs Department.
I heard Chief Kim is preparing
for the due diligence.
- He's here.
- That's me.
I'm sorry, but please
check the attendance...
and remaining vacation day data.
My department has so many errors,
so please check them.
I'm only one person.
How can I check all that?
It's an order from upstairs.
I'll go with him.
Thank you.
- I can go, right?
- She can go, right?
Don't talk to me like that.
Go ahead.
They always ask things when we're busy.
I checked your wife's call history.
I didn't find anyone unusual.
She could be using two phones.
I checked where she's been since yesterday.
Nothing unusual there, either.
My wife is much more thorough...
and clever than you think.
She must have planted someone.
So you better dig deeper.
Yes, Sir.
Assistant Manager Kang,
Chief Kim, and I will be...
in the DF team.
Good.
It's a simple job. We
don't need a big team.
Also, Assistant Manager
Yoon will be in the team.
Who put her in the team?
The General Affairs Department asked for...
attendance and vacation day data check.
Chief Kim can't do it
alone, so she'll help out.
Should I exclude her?
No, keep her in the team.
Did you bring it?
(Deokpo Enterprise)
Are you happy?
Director.
This isn't all of them.
I only brought half.
Why did you bring only half?
Don't you know the basic rule?
You'll get the rest when the deal is done.
Can't you pay all up front...
like how you pay the toll fee up front?
- Forget it then.
- No.
All right.
As long as you keep your promise, I'm good.
I'll keep my promise.
I'm sure you will.
Let me take a moment to say goodbye.
Director.
I'm asking you...
just to be sure.
You didn't make copies, did you?
What?
Well, only the jerks of the jerks...
who's nasty, shameless, deceitful,
dirty, and cheap would do such a thing.
Right?
Gosh. Wait.
Don't get me wrong.
I forgot to give this to you.
Get you wrong? No.
I respect you.
- I'm leaving.
- Sir.
After I finish the work,
give me the other half.
Do your work right first.
There it goes.
It's going.
It's gone!
At least I got half of it.
After the work, I'll be free.
Where is this pub?
How much are the drinks here?
"Don't get me wrong."
"I forgot to give this to you."
Seo Yul is so cute.
How dare he lie to me?
What about dropping the lawsuit?
Did you do that to let off steam?
I couldn't answer her right away.
Was dropping the lawsuit
your first priority...
or was getting the books?
Dropping the lawsuit.
What? That's weird.
It's weird, right?
I don't help people. You know that.
Of course you don't. You're
like a poisonous snake.
I'm like a cobra.
Maybe you're really becoming...
a righteous man.
That's nonsense.
Look what you've been doing.
You've been punishing bad guys.
You're so cool.
It's because they were
doing really mean things.
A righteous man gets angry
at injustice, Chief.
My knee. My leg.
Gwang Sook, don't call me a righteous man.
Do you want to ruin my life?
Chief. Think about it.
Do you want to put on a mask,
wear a cape,
or do you want to wear...
underwear over tights?
Gosh, I'm picturing you in tights!
Goodness.
I'm hanging up. Good night.
That's nonsense.
Be quiet!
Is this true?
Yes.
Mr. Kim requested them
to drop the lawsuit...
in exchange for him to join the DF team.
What should I make of this?
It looks like there is
no problem with them...
preparing for due diligence of TQ Delivery.
If it wasn't for this incident,
they would've begun the
accounting fraud already.
It was the perfect moment
to catch an evidence.
However, Mr. Kim has been
showing a different side...
compared to the information I had.
He would reject unacceptable
expense reports,
and he beat up the chairman's son, too.
He is putting on some kind of a show.
I don't think so.
It seemed too real...
for it to be a show.
Too real?
My goodness!
- I'm sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
I will continue to keep my eyes on him.
- Goodbye.
- Hey!
So Mr. Kim had a go with Myung Seok.
Yes. He was almost fired for that.
Myung Seok probably never
faced anything like it.
At this point, I'm confused about Mr.
Kim, too.
He's been doing the things we couldn't do.
I'm sure Mr. Seo hired him...
to use him like his puppet.
But I still haven't caught...
Mr. Seo using him in any way.
Do you think I'm mistaken?
Let me sleep! Okay? Darn it.
Oh my goodness.
Okay.
Seong Ryong, get a grip...
and live like your old cold-blooded self.
Do not get shaken.
Do not be shaken.
Do not...
What is this? What?
What's going on?
What is this?
What's happening?
What do you mean, you need more money?
It's already hard enough
to pay for the tuition,
rent, and living expenses.
And now you want lesson fees?
No, I'm not frustrated.
It's because I woke up from my sleep.
It's pretty late here.
Okay, then.
Oh, will you come home
during your vacation?
Spending money on airfare isn't a waste.
If you won't come during the vacation,
when can you come?
I mean, we should live like a family.
What is this?
Okay.
And tell Ha Rin to call.
How can she never call me?
Okay, then. Goodbye.
My gosh. I'm losing money again.
Goodness.
How did I make a living
before my promotion?
Okay.
Let's go to sleep.
Whatever.
(Chief Kim)
Why is rent so expensive?
Where can I go?
I can't live anywhere in...
My gosh, this world just won't let me be.
Will you look at where... What?
Why are you so surprised?
My gosh, you smell like alcohol.
Did you drink a lot yesterday?
How is your arm?
I'm fine, really.
No, you're not okay.
You should've been more demanding...
to your father about firing me.
I decided to let this pass.
Let what pass?
Guard. Guard? Guard.
Mr. Go.
You should know your enemy
before you pick a fight.
Let's not greet each other anymore.
I won't say anything even if you ignore me.
Greetings?
My goodness, Kid.
There was no use in pulling that kid's arm.
Yes. Yes. I'd like to
take a look at the room.
I'll see you on Saturday.
Hello?
Is the ceiling solid?
Yes, okay.
This is 20,000 deposit with 1,200 for rent.
This one is 20,000 deposit
with 1,000 as monthly rent.
You should live in this 1,800
deposit and 1,800 rent.
Who could live in this mess?
Are you moving?
You startled me.
Oh, yes. I can't live there anymore.
You wouldn't believe it,
but the ceiling fell down.
How can this be?
What kind of a house is that?
Wasn't the water supply
cut off the last time?
Exactly.
I'm looking for a place around work,
but everything is just too expensive.
While we're on the subject, Seong Ryong.
Just hear me out first without any burdens.
Yes, I'm listening.
I have an empty room in my apartment.
- So what?
- Well.
The rest of my family lives abroad.
My wife and daughter are in Canada.
That's why you looked like a beggar...
I mean, you always looked tired.
I guess sometimes...
I do look like a beggar.
It's okay. I don't mind.
So, anyway.
Why don't you pay me the monthly rent...
and come live with me?
I don't think that's right.
Even if I do pay,
I don't want to be a burden.
What are you talking about?
It's not a burden.
It's not like we're strangers.
But still, it's weird.
Feel free to come and live with me.
Think of it as your own home.
You don't have to be burdened.
How is 450 dollars per month?
- What?
- Take off 50.
No, this is pretty much
like a charity work.
Take 50 off.
Let's call it off.
I'd rather not do something
that'll be a burden to us.
What a cheap guy.
Did you think I am cheap?
No, you are a smart man, Seong Ryong.
- He has good ears.
- Do I have good ears?
Stop bickering with him,
and let's get ready.
Yes. Let's go.
Financial materials are already
here, so just check it.
We need reasons for our
deficit, how we'll overcome it.
What Seoahn Jangryong wants
is an honest analysis.
I guess that's nothing to worry about.
We have Mr. Righteous with us.
This is an easy task. Let's
finish it within the day.
Let's go.
Don't you have a bag?
- Reform!
Delivery men are human, too.
No more penalties!
- No more!
Inhumane working environment!
TQ must awaken!
I don't see any police forces.
We'll report them when things get violent.
No more irrational charges and penalties!
TQ must reform!
Inhumane working environment!
TQ must awaken!
I think I've seen that guy before.
- Wake up!
No more irrational charges and penalties!
Sir, they want you to
revise the penalty policy.
What is that?
When a courier misplaces
or damages a parcel...
Look it up yourself.
TQ Delivery fees are often
mentioned on the news.
How do you plan to...
Why is everyone else wearing black...
- when one person...
- Chief Kim!
- Come here.
- The guy in red.
- Is he head of the union?
- Be quiet.
Ha Gyeong.
Is the man in red the
head of the labor union?
We'll go ahead and set things up.
Okay.
The Seoahn Jangryong people
will be here tomorrow.
Why are the protesters still there?
I want it to end as well,
but the negotiations are going nowhere.
You should've taken charge from the start.
Don't you know you lose the
upper-hand if you can't?
- End negotiations immediately.
- Pardon?
I'm in charge of this from here on.
Whatever happens now is
none of your business.
(Final Accounts)
Check the accounts of each sales office...
then view the financial statements.
Write up a report based on your findings.
(Final Accounts)
Can't they have given us a nicer PC?
Even the power button's stuck.
What's wrong?
What are all these plugs?
What happened?
What's wrong?
Who doesn't mark which plug is for what?
Get out.
- Where to?
- Anywhere but here!
I'm here as a member of the team.
- I...
- Shut your mouth and get out!
I'll be outside.
Call when you're done.
Director.
I can't do all this work alone.
Get out.
Go. Now. Run.
What a horrid temper.
Did I do something that terrible?
Did I pull the plug...
when he was fighting the final boss?
(Unite and fight)
Are you...
Hey.
Aren't you Chief Kim?
Aren't you Joon Kwon from
Flower Wagon in Gunsan?
That's me. I'm Joon Kwon.
We meet again.
It's great to see you after so long.
What are you doing here?
It's been so long!
(Work environment and charges!)
(TQ is killing its employees!)
Seeing you again is
bringing back old memories.
You used to give all us waiters...
some extra pocket money.
Because I knew how much
your boss bugged you.
I see you got promoted.
You're head of the union.
Goodness, no. It's no promotion.
The head of any labor union's
a great job in Gunsan.
It's different here. I don't
have that much power.
Do you remember the head of
the port transport union?
His name was Ja Bok.
Everyone in Gunsan knew him.
I thought he was so cool.
I asked if I could wear his uniform,
and he slapped me.
Your jacket looks really cool.
Is it a luxury brand?
It's lined with plaid.
Why do I like things like this?
Do you want to try it on?
- No.
- Try it on.
No.
Come on, try it on.
This is how it feels.
I suddenly feel so powerful.
People and honor
Even no names are left behind
You haven't changed one bit.
People and honor
Gi Ok.
Yes, Sir.
Are you watching porn?
No, I'm not.
What's wrong? You've been
weird since yesterday.
Nothing's wrong, Sir.
I didn't mean to eavesdrop,
but I heard you talk on the phone.
Is your family having a tough time?
You don't have to tell
me if you don't want to.
I won't be of any help anyway.
No, Sir, it's...
I'm your boss, but I can't
do anything to show for it.
The thing is...
It's about my father.
He works at TQ Delivery.
Does he? What about it?
They've been in the red since 2013. Why?
I think it's because
they increased the fees.
Despite that, they maintained
the shipping costs...
without re-negotiating with
large business clients.
The shopping malls refused.
The couriers are demanding
we raise their fees.
If we do, the company will go belly-up.
Why are they so selfish?
I don't think it's just
because of the fees.
We only increased their fees by 12 cents...
since 2013.
In 2014, we stopped covering...
their cell phone bills and gas expense.
The increase in fees...
is much smaller than the
reduction of costs.
If they're still in the red...
Shouldn't you be working on something else?
Why are you on this?
I just had a look.
Don't. Stick to what you're told to.
Put the fee increase as the
main cause of profit loss.
Yes, Sir.
(Unite and fight)
They blame the company's loss on our fees.
That their operations are spotless.
No entrepreneur in Korea would
admit their wrongdoing.
What works is all down to their strategy.
What doesn't is the employees' fault.
Phone bills, gas, compensation
for losses and damages.
We have to pay for all that.
We work 14 hours a day
and make almost nothing.
- 14 hours?
- During peak season,
we even work 18 hours a day.
You must get sick or
injured working that long.
It's physically draining.
They need to try doing what we do.
Only then will they see how absurd this is.
What?
Just a moment.
What do you mean?
What?
Where are you?
Come and tell me face-to-face.
Our lives are almost not worth living.
We're practically delivering machines.
During peak seasons, we
have no time to pee.
Some end up with bladder infections.
Cystitis can be really painful.
Machines get oiled and tweaked.
Even working cattle...
rest at night...
and get to see a vet when they're sick.
We're human beings,
but we get nothing, nothing at all.
The worst days for us...
are Children's Day and Christmas.
We deliver expensive dolls
and robots all day...
and then go home.
We can't afford to buy a toy at all.
We're practically penniless.
My daughter...
waits at home for her present.
How could the rich businessmen
treat us like this?
We couriers are employees, too.
Why don't they care about us one bit?
It's not just the couriers
they don't care about.
They don't care about human beings, period.
Let's take a break.
Where is he? Why isn't he back yet?
Why don't they care?
It's hard, I know.
Unbelievable.
What are you doing here?
Have a seat.
- Take a seat.
- Sure, thanks.
Hello.
You look like a fisherman.
I do not.
I might make a labor union
in the headquarters.
I could lead it.
Over 10 people...
lost their jobs trying to do just that.
Just say the word "union" and
the Evil Witch lists you.
- There's a list?
- Apparently.
A blacklist of employees.
I didn't get to say so earlier,
but my son works at TQ headquarters.
Does he? At which department?
He said it was a financial position.
Financial Management? Accounting?
They're both very respectable departments.
Seeing you both makes me feel extra proud.
My son gets to work in...
an office and not out in the field like me.
- I should get back to work.
- Just a moment.
When you get back,
please tell your superiors
about our plight.
Yes, I will.
Call me when you're done.
I have to get my things.
I will. Give the man his jacket.
No. I'll keep it on until we're done.
Bye, then.
- Bye.
- Take care.
- I will, thanks.
- Ha Gyeong.
- What?
Fight.
Prosecutor Han's investigator?
We aren't sure about that.
It could be an investigator,
but we could have an employee
leaking information.
What's positive is that there is a mole.
Prosecutor Han must be behind this.
Someone else seems to be
targeting the chairman.
Who? Do you mean the chairman's wife?
Were you aware of that?
He was a target ever since
he stole her company.
Whoever the leak is,
it's someone very close to home.
I say it's Accounting
or Business Operations.
Screen everyone in both departments.
Yes, Sir.
I should go inside.
I'm just a nuisance here.
I'll come by when the negotiations end.
You do that. Let's have
marinated shrimp with soju.
Sure.
Go, go.
Quick march.
- Who are they?
- Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Who are you? What do you want?
We're from a security company.
Gather round.
Why should we gather round?
Get out of here.
Joon Kwon.
I can tell right away that...
they fight for a living.
What? No, that can't be.
They're experts. Look in their eyes.
They don't care for women,
kids, or the elderly.
They punch anyone. Let's get out of here.
Even if that's the case,
I won't run away.
Attack!
(Reduce work hours and labor intensity!)
Let go! Let go of me!
Who do you think you are?
You can't do this!
Leave us alone!
Let go of me!
(Final Accounts)
(Chief Kim Seong Ryong)
(Calling)
Don't come closer. Stay away.
Don't follow me!
Out of my way!
Stay there!
Why are you following me?
Don't come any closer!
What do you want from me? Leave me alone!
Wait, stop! Timeout!
Stop.
I have the report, Sir.
Send it to General Affairs.
Check again tomorrow
before printing it out,
and tell them to check
the Chinese translation.
Yes, Sir.
Good job, everyone.
Great job.
- What's wrong?
- We have a problem outside.
What problem?
(Work environment and charges!)
Stop! What do you think you're doing?
Help me.
Let go of me!
Let me go! Get your hands off me!
Leave us alone!
Get out of here! Get out!
You can't do this to us!
Why are you after me?
What do you want me for?
Am I your type? Is that it?
Who are you?
Do you like me, too?
Wait.
I'm not going anywhere!
What do you want?
I have nothing! Let me go!
Where are you taking me?
Put me down!
Someone call the police!
I don't work at TQ Delivery!
Do you know who I am?
I'm Mr. Righteous!
Cho Min Young, you've lost your mind.
Who are those people?
They're from a private firm.
Whoever they are, they can't do this.
This is their fight. They'll deal with it.
Chief.
Don't go. It's dangerous.
I have to go.
Chief Kim's among them.
Let go! Let go of me, you fools!
How dare you.
What are you doing? Let go!
- Stop this!
- Shoot.
Who are you?
Freeze!
How dare you glare at me.
Who do you think you are?
Stop!
Fall back!
Come back here!
- My back...
- Are you okay?
Don't touch me.
Can you get up?
- Yes.
- I hurt all over.
- Can you walk?
- Are you okay?
- Yes, thanks.
Good.
Are you okay?
I can't do this.
(Couriers are humans! We
want to live like one!)
(Enforcers)
Get this thing off me! It stinks!
I'm dying here!
It smells like it was stuck
up someone's bottom!
Where are you taking me?
That's too bright.
Who are you?
I'm glad you made it, Mr. Labor Union.
Mister what?
You're the head of TQ
Delivery's labor union.
I'm what?
(Let me go, jerks!)
(I'm really scared.)
(Hello, Mr. Labor Union. Welcome.)
(I'm what? No way.)
(Chief Kim)
This is a trial of the utmost difficulty.
- Life is an adventure.
- Chief!
Take the money and run.
TQ must apologize!
We paid off the head of the labor union.
He took the money and denied it.
Did you stab us in the back?
Is this how you both will keep doing this?
If it weren't for you,
I wouldn't have been disgraced!
Where did he go?
Stop hiring thugs and messing things up!
I have to get somewhere in a hurry.