Still not done with the glasses ?
Get a move on !
No, put it further back
so everything will fit !
Good !
Let's make it quick.
Leaving already ?
Piss off, Saman ! I clocked in an hour
before everyone else.
See you Monday, payday.
We'll see...
We'll see, my ass !
HUMAN CAPITAL
SIX MONTHS EARLIER
- Here is fine.
- The gate's open.
Leave me here.
- Just stop.
- What's the problem, honey ?
- I'll drop you off.
- No.
What a pain. I knew it !
Look at this.
Not too bad, Bernaschi !
- How many acres do you think this is ?
- Who cares !
CHAPTER 1
DINO
- All right, bye.
- Bye.
- Morning.
- Good morning, Carla.
- Is Massimiliano inside '?
- He has a surprise for you.
- Hello. - Is that your dad ?
- Yes, but he's leaving.
I'd like to meet him.
But I'm rushing off,
I have a hectic day ahead of me.
I'm Serena's dad,
she asked me to drop her off...
We've probably crossed paths
at our kids' school !
Dino Ossola, nice to meet you.
You know, all of us here
adore Serena !
She always talks about you too,
I'm somewhat jealous !
I'd better go,
I have an urgent meeting,
- otherwise we could've had coffee
with Giovanni too. - No worries.
I have a "hardcore"
day ahead of me too ! No of fence...
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Let's go, we're late.
- It went long !
- Hello !
I'm Serena's dad,
I just dropped her off.
- This place is stunning.
- Do you play ?
- We need a fourth.
- I've hit a few balls.
I could go home and get my things.
You'll find what you need
in the locker room, interested ?
Yes !
- A wicked serve !
- You're a whiz at the net.
They won't win a single game.
Dino!
Let's kill them !
All right!
So... is it true what they say about
the Bernaschi hedge fund ?
Depends on what they're saying.
There's talk of 40-50% return...
He had us sell America
and buy Brazil
six months before everyone else.
- But you didn't hear that from me.
- Of course.
- Some game !
- Giovanni, blame it on doping !
It's all in the legs.
We danced on the court.
The racket I used wasn't bad either.
You've got a good serve.
You've played professionally ?
I was a semi-pro,
but 20 years and 22 pounds ago.
- You work in real estate ?
- Yes. - The market's booming.
- Lucky you.
- I can't complain.
My father said:
"Homes and coffins are always needed".
It's true, anyone can make
a living this way.
I'm almost tempted to take
a risk on something more... no ?
Otherwise life is a drag.
Dino, you realize
you've gotten yourself into a fix ?
- Why, did I say something wrong ?
- You and I are top dogs !
- You'll have to come every Friday.
- Right, we're a team.
We complete each other:
I serve, you close.
Merciless !
- Bye, see you soon.
- Hey, I was wondering...
now might not be the right time
but seeing there's a good vibe
between us... - Yes ?
Not to mention the kids...
Aren't they adorable together ?
You want to buy into our fund.
Wow, you can read my mind !
Yes, I was thinking about
a small share.
- Our minimum is 500.
- 500,000 ?
- Yes.
- That's fine.
Even 600,000 or 700,000.
Think it over and let me know.
Come see me at the Milan office.
- Thursday at 8:30 ?
- Thursday at 8:30, perfect !
My man, Giovanni !
You and I are a powerhouse.
Hello dear,
the big boss is expecting me.
Why that face ?
- Did you read the business plan ?
Read it ! - I read it.
You want to expand,
hire, buy land...
And you're certain you'll have
a 30% return within a year.
30-40%, Giampiero,
it's a conservative estimate.
It's not exactly a gift, you know...
You'll give me 700,000
but I'm using my house as collateral,
it's worth at least 900.
Your house ?
You put it in Serena's name
during the divorce.
Yes, of course, but Serena agrees.
We need her signature. I have
to convince the general managers.
You're awesome !
I'll leave this for you.
What does Roberta think ?
Dino, you did tell her ?
Of course ! She agrees too.
Roby, honey ?
In here.
Come here, sit down.
Are you upset with me ?
What have I done ?
I couldn't believe it was positive,
so I did the blood test.
I just got the results.
My beta levels are sky-high.
Rm Pregnant !
That's great news, isn't it ?
- Some enthusiasm !
- It's the last thing I expected to hear.
You're telling me ! Isn't it crazy ?
- We have space, right ?
- We more or less have money...
We do.
Serena can stay in your study,
since you never use it.
- Her room will become the baby's room.
- You've got it all planned.
Serena came to the clinic...
I wanted to tell her but...
I thought it was best you told her.
Yes, I'll tell her.
Honey!
The investor must acknowledge
he's aware of the high risk
and illiquidity of the product.
Perrier? Fiji? Evian?
Oh, water !
You decide, I trust you.
My pal Bernaschi isn't here today ?
Giovanni's in a meeting right now.
I'm sure he'll come say hello.
Now, onto the next point
which clearly states that
the amount invested
must represent a percentage
that doesn't exceed
20% of your patrimony.
Sorry for the pedantry, but we must
verbalize it before you sign.
Fair enough.
And now... can I sign ?
Go ahead.
Sign by the X's.
Oh, what the hell !
Just kidding !
Here he is ! My man, Giovanni !
- How's everything ? I'm signing.
- Hello.
Sorry to bail out,
but I fly to London in 30 minutes.
Get ready for Friday !
- Malesani's a beast at the net.
- No worries, we'll bust his ass !
Have a good day, fellows.
Where were we ?
SIX MONTHS LATER
OSSOLA REAL ESTATE
- Hey !
- Ester, what a nice surprise.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
- Okay...
- Well ?
Nothing, I wanted to say...
since they asked me many times...
Allied Property is interested
in collaborating with you.
I'm sure they are,
but I'm not interested in them.
Want to answer ?
They'll call back, no worries.
Forgive me for saying this,
but given the recession...
...think twice before saying no.
- All right.
- Why aren't you answering my calls ?
- My man, Giampiero !
- You're not answering emails either !
- Relax with these emails...
- Let's go, I'm really late.
- Wait !
I can't. I'm going to a charity gala
at Serena's school.
Who gives a shit !
I'm risking my job because of you.
- Oh please ! - You haven't made one
payment yet, you bullshitted me.
You fired everyone
and set up office in a broom closet !
It's called optimizing.
You always say resources must be...
Look, I can't be late.
Know where we'll be sitting
at the school gala ?
At the Bernaschi's table,
the table of honor !
- 5,000 euro a head minimum...
- Who ? - You heard me.
Bernaschi invited me
and Roberta to his table.
He and I are buddies now,
we're tennis partners too.
Didn't expect that, did you ?
You used that 700,000
for Bernaschi's fund ?
Upset '_>
Not those measly things
you offer me with 2-3% returns.
Don't bust my balls,
I had to lie to get the money.
- I should punch you.
- You won't, you're too smart.
You know this is a rare opportunity.
This stuff is tops.
We're talking
about 40% returns, get my drift ?
Why did Bernaschi
let a guy like you buy in ?
You've always underestimated me.
I've got to go.
Evening, Mr. Ossola.
- Enjoy.
- Thanks, darling.
Crotti !
Not now... after.
Excuse me.
Attorney...
- My man, Massimiliano,
you'll win the prize tonight ! - Hope so.
...kids who are made to feel like losers
end up in therapy with me.
- The gravida is already on the pulpit ?
- Your wife says
all this competition
isn't good for the kids.
No such thing !
Look at Massimiliano,
- he's ready to pummel his opponents.
- We'll see.
I think it's harmful at this age.
It causes insecurity and anxiety.
Consider it a good thing for you,
given your line of work !
Look, I work in a public clinic.
Forgive him, he's a business lawyer,
he tends to only focus on profits.
You had to get on your soapbox...
We were just chatting.
- Where the hell is Serena ?
- Relax, she'll show up.
I am relaxed.
This salami looks appetizing,
let me give it a try...
Before I forget, we need to meet up.
- Sure, for a tennis match ?
- I wish.
- Tomorrow ?
- No, tomorrow I won't be free till noon.
- Okay, I'll come by at noon.
- I'll call you and confirm.
- Carla, you look fantastic !
- Sorry, I got stuck in traffic.
- Mom, it's about time.
- You look great. - Thanks.
That theater project of yours
is doing you a world of good.
- Serena?
- She's on her way.
- Yes.
- How are things ?
- Just fine.
- Well, I am a bit tired tonight.
They probably want to stay inside,
nice and warm together.
They're twins.
- How lovely, congratulations !
- Thanks.
Finally.
Good evening, sorry.
- What did I miss ?
- The string quartet. - Good.
Folks, it's time for the highlight
of the evening:
the awarding
of the Cottafavi Prize.
As you know,
each year a jury comprised of
both teachers and students,
selects a student who has stood out
in academics, sports, and friendship.
It is with great pleasure
that I call to the stage
an illustrious alumnus of this school,
our dear friend,
Giancarlo Busdraghi !
Imagine that, Busdraghi is here !
Impressive.
- I don't feel well.
- Not now, please.
You didn't eat a thing,
maybe you're just hungry.
Contractions, I'm worried.
Don't get worked up,
drink some water.
- Do you need help ?
- She'll be fine, just low blood pressure.
- Let's not focus on it.
- Some sugar ?
No, I'm not okay,
take me to the hospital.
- Sorry.
- I'm really sorry.
Take care.
- We'll meet tomorrow anyway.
- Don't worry.
- Drive my car home please.
- No problem.
The three Cottafavi Prize finalists.
He hadn't invited me
to anything in a while...
Better now ? Shall we go ?
Didn't you hear what the doctor said ?
To wait here for him and I will wait !
- It's almost 1:00 AM.
- Then leave. - Come on...
- Who hadn't invited you ?
- Giovanni Bernaschi to play tennis !
- He said to come over tomorrow at noon.
- Please...
We used to play on Fridays,
guess he's changed the schedule.
All the better...
Meaning I ruined
the evening for nothing ?
You didn't ruin it...
Hurry !
- Morning.
- Is your wife okay ?
Yes, false alarm.
She just got worked up.
Can you tell Serena to call me ?
Sorry, gotta run.
Where the hell is everyone ?
Excuse me.
Sorry, I totally forgot
about out appointment.
- I'm in a meeting.
- No problem.
I'll wait on the court,
warm up my serve.
Easy, I don't think
today's a day to play.
Since you're here let's have a talk.
- What is it ?
- Essentially...
some markets are proving
more volatile than we anticipated.
Everywhere we're active
is staying way overvalued.
Isn't that good ?
We can cash in and get out.
No, you don't get it:
we bet these markets would fall
but that hasn't happened.
It hasn't...
What I'm saying is your placement
has gone down substantially.
Substantially ? How much ?
- Right now it's at about 90.
- Percent ?
So that leaves me with 70,000...
These numbers are insignificant now,
unless you plan on pulling out
which is not advisable now.
At least you're covered
by your real estate business.
Of course.
- False alarm for Luciana last night ?
- Roberta... everything's fine with her.
Sorry, I have to go,
we'll talk again another time.
So no game today, my man ?
- Excuse me, can I have minute ?
- Sorry, we're a bit busy.
I know, just a minute.
Pardon me.
Sorry.
Look, I think there's been
a lack of communication.
- What does that mean ?
- It was my fault.
I can't afford to lose that money,
I should've told you.
- Like I said, it's temporary.
- Yes, but maybe we can make a deal.
- Meaning '?
- All I want to do is break even.
- Do you think this is a card game ?
- I've got a great idea,
tell me what you think...
You give me back my initial investment
and when the fund bounces back,
because you said it would,
you can keep it all,
even if it skyrockets. - Relax.
An agreement between me and you,
in the name of our friendship.
- That's not how it works.
- Listen...
that money is all I have.
Actually, I don't even have that,
understand ?
What are you saying ?
Where'd you get that 700,000 ?
I borrowed it from the bank.
Are you nuts ?
Didn't they read the terms to you ?
If you fabricated numbers,
that would be called fraud.
Fraud, come on !
With me and you ?
With all the respect
and genuine affection, might I say.
- Not to mention the kids...
- The kids, what '?
You know what, let's end
this unpleasant conversation.
Tomorrow I'll out you a check
for the balance of your placement.
Giovanni, my pal,
what'll I do with 70,000 euro ?
"Last night a cyclist was found
seriously wounded and in shock.
He's a 40-50 year old man,
and was found in a ditch
by the road."
Honey, I didn't wait for you.
You must be hungry.
- There's some pasta, it's cold...
- That's fine.
You already showered ?
I went to see Martini,
we did another ultrasound.
- And everything's good.
- Great.
I just need to rest,
so I start maternity leave tomorrow.
- Perfect !
- Aren't they lovely ?
Yes, so lovely.
Did you see Serena at Massimiliano's ?
- Great...
- Great, what '? Did you see her ?
Who, Serena ?
No, I didn't see her.
- Why ?
- She didn't come home last night.
She didn't drive my car home
so I had to take a cab today.
You did good.
- Are you okay ?
- I'm just peachy.
Can I use your glass ?
The keys.
What's going on ?
- Why ?
- Dunno...
- Sweetie, are you all right ?
- Not now, dad.
You should let me know
when you stay over Massimiliano's.
- Just a phone call, is it that hard ?
- By the way...
- His morn told me to tell you...
- Tell me what ?
- To call her.
- I'm going there now.
- Want me to drive you ?
- No, I'll take my scooter.
Your dad gets worried...
I have a feeling
she and Massimiliano had a fight.
"Allied Property,
how can I help you ?"
Dearest Ester, it's me...
"Hello !"
I figured I would come in and see
what those rascals at Allied Property
have to say.
- Just... out of curiosity.
- "Good."
- Right ?
- "I'm glad to hear that".
- "Shall I book an appointment".
- Listen...
Hope they're not just looking
for my contacts
and want to send me out waiting
for clients like I did 2O years ago
because that wouldn't be suitable.
"No... if you're available
next week we could...
- ls Miss Serena Ossola at home '?
- What happened '?
- Are you her father ?
- Yes.
We need to speak to your daughter.
CHAPTER 2
CARLA
- Serena ! Good morning, darling.
- Is Massimiliano inside ?
- He has a surprise for you.
- I already know.
- Pretend you don't.
- All right.
- Is that your dad ?
- Yes, but he's leaving.
I'd like to meet him.
But I'm rushing off,
I have a hectic day ahead of me.
- Why did you stop ?
- For your manicure appointment, ma'am.
And you have a Shiatsu
massage at 3:00.
Sorry, I changed my mind.
Let's go, please.
Where?
- I need a pair of shoes,
let's go to Baldoni.. - Yes, ma'am.
Actually, let's go to Crozer
so I can finally pick the fabric
for the parlor curtains.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Sorry.
Or maybe we could go
to Adriana Crosetti's antique shop.
She said some new items
from India have just arrived.
And I wouldn't want to miss out.
Look who's here !
- Am I interrupting ?
- What a surprise !
- How are you, darling ?
- Fine.
I'm glad you came to visit.
I have some new treasures.
I wonder if Giovanni will like it.
Could you pull over please ?
Careful, ma'am. It's dangerous.
What's going on here ?
The eaves are detaching
and the stucco is crumbling off.
But the main problem
is the roof beams inside.
- How sad.
- Want to take a look ?
- May I ?
- Come.
Tino Buazzelli debuted here
with an Arthur Miller play.
So did Giorgio Strehler
with "The Chioggia Scuffles".
Full-house every night.
- Can't it be restored ?
- Many have contacted me...
but to turn it into apartments,
a supermarket, or a bank.
A bank ?
In a civilized country,
the city would get involved to help.
I'm outraged.
I'll go turn on the lights
and make a quick phone call.
Let it be clear,
you're in here at your own risk.
- Who gave you this estimate ?
- Too expensive ?
No.
The company wasn't exactly planning
on buying a theater...
Gerard says we'll get a tax break
if we create a foundation.
I don't understand much
about these things...
Do you realize there isn't
one theater in the whole province ?
Is that a horrible thing, honey '?
- You'd be giving a wonderful gift
to everyone. - Come here.
Honey,
I'd gladly give this gift to you,
but will you have time
to manage it ?
You need to have
a board of directors.
I know, look.
I've written down a few names.
You' re Carla Bernaschi,
Bertoncelli, Russomanno...
Honey, I have no idea
who these people are
but if you've chosen them
then I'm sure they're valid.
Thanks, Giovanni.
Thanks.
Seems like an interesting lineup.
Naturally, this is just a proposal
but I think it's essential
to consider the both an audience
that likes the latest trends...
That's me.
Ugo, I'm in a meeting.
Be good, I'll call you later.
The needs of an audience
that likes the latest trends...
as well as an audience that prefers
a more traditional repertory.
Enough of Pirandello, please !
We should just hand out Valium
at the door.
I find it to be a very balanced lineup,
it leaves room for us to
present something experimental too.
- Indeed. - Rosanna,
still defaming 18th century talents ?
Pirandello is Pirandello, get over it.
Speaking of Maestro Pirandello,
I had the honor of shaking his hand
in 1934.
What exactly do you mean
by "experimental" ?
On the draft
I listed a few things like...
- ..Soc'letas Raffaella Sanzio...
- Raffaello Sanzio !
Their Hamlet is from 1992...
Darling, we all read with enthusiasm
your severe critiques in the paper.
- Real enthusiasm !
- We're wondering if there's
anything you do like ?
To get an idea...
What do I like,
asks Professor Russomanno ?
Nothing, theater is dead.
- Aren't you aware of that ?
- I suppose it is.
Good to know,
since I'm wasting time teaching it.
- How about dance theater...
- Excuse me
for interrupting you intellectuals...
As a simple man,
I say working people are tired.
Tired of complex things
that give them a headache.
- True... people are tired.
- We, of the City Council,
believe we need to promote
local traditions.
Nearby in Valcuvia
there's the Po Valley choir,
very talented and I think they deserve
to perform on opening night.
- On the derriere.
- You mean premiere.
That's my input,
you're free to do as you wish.
Would anybody like
some tea, coffee...
or cookies ?
- Thanks.
- Ma'am, well done.
Maestro, thanks.
Thanks, miss.
Mr. De Marchis.
- Well, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- What a mess, this won't work.
- Don't worry.
- They acted out today
but will soon calm down. - Hope so.
I've yet to thank you
for all you're doing.
Politeama Theater shouldn't just die.
I was thinking about suggesting you
as Artistic Director.
Why are you smiling ?
"And when he shall die, take him
and cut him out in little stars
and he will make
the face of heaven so fine
that all the world
will be in love with night...
- I recall your Juliet fondly.
- Oh please, I was just an amateur.
There are amateurs, third-rate actors,
and then actors.
Sorry to contradict you,
but you're an actress.
What do you think
about my theater proposal ?
It's a pity you quit,
you were delightful.
That was a different life,
I'm not even sure it was mine.
- See you soon, Professor.
- Goodbye, Carla.
Massimiliano...
Remember... tear them up !
- Will you come home to change ?
- You two are stressing me out,
- it's not the Nobel prize !
- Give me a kiss.
- Serena will be at our table,
did you know ? - Yes.
- I think it's a shitty idea...
- What?
Inviting him and his wife
to our table... it's a shitty idea !
It's important for Massimiliano
to have Serena there.
He's just unpleasant,
that's how I see it.
I thought you liked him,
you always invite him to play tennis !
"Invited", past tense.
I'll be forced to explain
his placement in the fund too...
Yes.
Tomorrow at 7:00.
No, I go to Milan tonight,
I'll sleep there, if I can sleep.
Nothing, nobody knows.
Call you later, bye.
- Problems ?
- No, I'll sort it all out.
- Hello '?
- "Morning, do you have a second?"
- Sure.
- "I finally found it"
I'll give you a few clues: 1968,
midway between cinema and theater...
- ..awarded in Venice. - "Our Lady
of the Turks" by Carmelo Bene.
Well done !
For the theater project, remember ?
Of course,
when can we watch it ?
Monday, as usual ?
Sure, or even tonight,
later on at my place.
I have dinner plans
but I can call you when I'm done and...
Are you sure it won't be too late ?
"All right, call me when you're done."
- it was the Artistic Director.
- Director of what ?
The theater, he's very nice.
By the way, we'll have to see
about all that...
- See what ? - Gerard says
the restoration can't start now.
What ? But everything's set !
Carla, at this rate
we might have to sell it.
Sell it ?
We got an attractive offer
to turn it into apartments.
Why didn't you tell me ?
I was going to tell you,
and I just did, take it easy.
- We need liquid assets.
- Apartments ?
We promised De Marchis
it would remain a theater.
The contract we signed
didn't include that clause.
Honey, I know it meant a lot to you,
I'm really sorry,
but I have no other choice.
Bye, have a good day.
NEW POLITEAMA THEATER
Mrs. Bernaschi, hello.
- Enjoy !
- Thanks.
Carla, what a wonderful
thing you're doing.
We'll be the first
season-ticket holders !
My boys planned a party for after,
Massimiliano's coming.
Come over, we old folks
will be relegated to the kitchen.
Thanks, but Giovanni's
leaving for Milan tonight.
I would've loved to,
but I'm exhausted.
Thanks.
- Carla, you look fantastic !
- Sorry, I got stuck in traffic.
Mom, it's about time.
Good evening !
I told you not to invite them.
And now I'm being told it's time
to announce the three finalists:
Francesco Alberici from class 5 C.
- What a dickhead.
- Massimiliano Bernaschi, 5 A.
And lastly, Marie Rose Bertolazzi
from 5 B.
The Blackie...
The winner
of the 2010 Cottafavi Prize...
Marie Rose Bertolazzi!
Oh Well...
- I need to get going.
- Talk to him.
Hey, bye.
Let it go.
- Rice with grouper and peas ?
- No, thanks.
- Hi, Donato.
- You all right? - Yes.
- You look solemn.
- No.
It was a rough day,
shall we go watch it ?
- Nobody is home ?
- No, come on.
"I forgive you."
ls someone home ?
Wait here.
- When did you get back ?
- Shut that fucking light !
Just now.
- Is dad here ?
- No, he's in Milan.
- Tell me you didn't drive in the state
you're in ? - Everything's fine.
- No, you drank.
- A few beers, don't bust my chops.
You threw up.
- They called and you didn't fucking answer.
- Did you drive in the state you're in ?
Serena gave me a ride in her car.
Honey, you must not
play around with alcohol.
Did you take drugs too ?
- Did he notice anything ?
- No, definitely not.
- Is everything okay ?
- Yes, just go.
Go on.
- Call me tomorrow ?
- Yes.
"You have a new voice-mail."
"Carla, are you there ?
It's Adriana."
"Sorry for calling so late,
but please call me back."
"it's about your son. I think it's best
someone come pick him up"
"Kids, not on the carpet, goodness !"
Gerard, take them
to the meeting room,
I'll be right in.
Gerard told you that ?
Quit bullshitting me !
I'm fucking fed up !
Listen to what ? Give me a break.
Yes, I spoke to dad.
You need to grow up
and realize
this regards you too
and that idiot sister of yours,
of ours, all right?
I can't handle it all alone !
You expect me to listen to your shit
while everything is collapsing ?
Don't say you're busy
or you'll make me see red !
You never have shit to do, never !
What does your sister do ?
Yoga ? In India ?
But when she's in Milan
she wants a posh apartment.
Go to hell, just go to tell !
You're back early ?
Sorry Carla,
there was a change of plans.
What's going on ?
Nothing,
Milan was full of pesky reporters.
We came here
so we could have some peace.
What time is it ?
I have a meeting now, I'm not
to be disturbed for the next two hours.
Tell the staff to not disturb us.
- What's going on ?
- What's going on...
It's hard to explain right now.
Don't worry, I will handle it all...
All right, I'll handle it all,
it's all under control...
Don't ask questions,
you can't understand anyway.
You're too stupid, Carla,
too dumb !
The spreads are all wrong.
So we'll have to start selling things
that we don't want to sell,
but we're running out of capital
so the only...
the only way out is to keep investing.
Now I have to go convince
those men in there
otherwise, I'm done for,
I'm finished.
Finished ?
Should I be afraid ?
I mean, for us ? For Massimiliano ?
Should we be afraid ?
Maybe the three of us can have dinner
and talk about it.
- It's good to talk things over...
it brings us closer... - Bye.
I have something to tell you too...
- Good morning.
- Is your wife okay ?
Yes, false alarm.
She just got worked up.
- Massimiliano ?
- He's fine.
- Can you tell Serena to call me ?
- Okay.
Sorry, gotta run !
What's he so cheery about...
Idiot.
Donate '?
Just let me finish this dialogue.
I've been writing all night,
I can't stop !
Thanks to you.
I was a coward last night.
What ?
You're an amazing women,
- last night was beautiful.
- I had news about the theater.
I had news about the theater.
It's not happening,
my husband's selling it,
they'll turn it into apartments.
I'm sorry, I never imagined things would
take such a turn for the worse.
I see.
But I'm not surprised.
I'm sorry for you,
I know it was important to you.
As for me, no big deal,
thanks to this,
I was able to meet you.
Donate.
Let's be realistic,
this just doesn't make sense.
Why not?
And all these months ?
Everything we did together ?
I wrote 180 pages of my book
because you inspire me.
How can the care and the love
we gave each not make sense ?
I brought Carmelo Bene back,
you forgot it.
- I truly am sorry, because I also...
- Are you leaving ?
Can I say one last thing ?
You're an amateur !
I thought you were serious last night
but I was wrong.
You appear as a walk-on
and when things get dangerous
you run back to your hilltop mansion.
- You're right.
You think you never have to face
the consequences
because you're still an amateur.
Like when you did theater.
It was easier to marry Giovanni
Bernaschi, but he's not enough.
So you sleep with this poor idiot !
When you realize your betrayal
is a risk, you send me packing.
You're just an amateur.
Don't you forget, just an amateur !
- And a shitty actress.
- Morning, Professor.
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas, ma'am.
Dai, muoviti! Muoviti, cogliona!
Move it. Go, you asshole !
Fuck you, bitch !
FUCK you I
Sorry !
Sorry, I didn't mean it !
Sorry.
- Serena !
- Don't bust her chops too !
- Serena, sweetie. - Sorry,
my dad told me to call you...
- Thanks for last night.
- Sure.
You drove Massimiliano home ?
Yes, sorry Carla, but I have to go.
- Want my driver to take you home ?
- No, thanks.
- What did you do last night ?
- Fuck off.
Massimiliano !
Or do you prefer to talk to dad ?
He's back ?
- And he's not in a good mood.
Look at me.
- Did you drive drunk ?
- Are you deaf ?
- I told you Serena drove me.
- Please don't talk that way to me.
- Did your car drive itself?
- Spare me the dumb joke.
It wasn't a joke.
- Why so uptight ?
- Where were you last night ?
If you were so worried,
why didn't you come get me ?
No, shit !
You didn't answer me:
who drove your car home ?
- One of the Crosettis.
- Which ?
I don't fucking know,
I gave Serena the keys.
Please don't talk that way to me !
Understand ?
Tonight, the three of us
will have dinner and talk. Okay ?
What a joy !
- Who is it ?
- Mrs. Carla,
the police is here.
- The police ? What ?
- They're outside.
So you're not sure
whom Serena gave the keys to ?
- No. - You told your mom Serena
gave them to the Crosetti twins.
Attorney, thanks...
- And Serena is your girlfriend ?
- What does that matter ?
Maybe she wanted to help you,
life can be strange...
A guy told us
he heard about the accident on TV,
I think people watch too much TV...
He also said he was on that road
around the same time
and saw an SUV similar to yours.
Not to mention the dent on your car
that was sloppily covered up with paint.
- That scratch ? I covered it up.
- Really ? - I thought someone
scratched it on purpose.
- How much sugar, Detective ?
- Two spoons, thanks.
Massimiliano you're a bright kid,
if we find out
that you left that party drunk
with your friends,
drove your SUV
and ran that poor devil over
but didn't stop to help him,
you'll be in big trouble.
- No need to use scare tactics.
- In fact...
- Massimiliano is more than willing
to collaborate. - Collaborate with what ?
It wasn't me, understand ?
That'll be all for now.
You'll be called in for questioning.
We'll impound the car
and check for prints, goodbye.
Goodbye, Detective.
Why did it have to be my car
to hit that loser ?
Giovanni!
Have you lost your mind ?
Don't you realize
what that idiot has done ?
- You can't think he did it!
- Dickhead.
Give me Adriana Crosetti's number.
Under C.
Honey ...
I didn't run anyone over, I swear.
Alessandro and Fabiano
said they didn't drive your car home.
Then someone else did,
I was in the car with Serena !
What the fuck do you want from me ?
I saw Serena's face today,
she barely looked at me...
Maybe she's trying to cover for you.
- That girl loves you...
- Serena doesn't love me.
Then why was she here
with you today ?
- Why have you been so uptight
since last night ? - Never mind.
- I'm trying to understand.
- I saw you last night.
What ?
I saw you when
I went up to my room.
I looked out to see if my car was back
and saw you kissing a guy.
Who the fuck is he, mom ?
Just Donato Russomanno...
the theater's Artistic Director,
I was just talking to him about...
I did a dumb thing, I'm sorry...
Dumb...
In 20 years, you might understand
why these things happen.
You'll think I'm pathetic
but you'll understand.
Sickening...
Why are you here ?
- I came to say sorry.
- Sorry ? Don't bother.
Shame on you for blaming my kids
to protect your son !
We're just trying to understand...
Understand what ?
Never set foot in here again !
- Got that ?
- Ma'am...
Never again: you, your husband,
and your rotten drunken son.
Let go of me.
Sorry.
Then why did you drive him home ?
Massimiliano
was in no condition to drive.
Whenever he went out at night
you drove him home ?
Yes, it's happened before.
- He got into your Fiat.
- Not mine.
- Right, your father's wife's,
Dr. Morelli. - Wife...
Who drove Massimiliano's car
all the way back home ?
His car was blocking others
at the party,
so I took the keys from Massimiliano
and left them there.
- There, where ?
- On the thing... the dashboard.
Your boyfriend...
- He's not my boyfriend.
- He claims his car was driven home
by one of the Crosettis,
but they swear they didn't go out.
I told him that, because I thought
it might've happened.
Then who drove the car ?
Did St. Christopher come down
and drive it ?
CHAPTER 3
SERENA
No worries, I have a "hardcore"
day ahead of me too !
Here is my beast.
What do you think ?
- Nice... typical asshole car.
- Right ?
Get in, smell the leather seats.
I'm crazy about it.
Listen to her purr.
Fantastic ! Shut her off
or we'll both die in here.
Not a bad idea...
Don't be ridiculous. We agreed...
I can't bear not seeing you.
We'll still see each other,
we're still friends.
My mom will be bummed
when she finds out.
She doesn't need to know.
Right, we don't have to tell anyone,
- so you can think it over.
- Stop, I already thought it over.
Maybe you'll be miserable
without me,
you'll miss me.
Let's fuck !
- I'll lick your nipples.
- Come on, you're always so violent.
Don't touch me !
Isn't that your dad ?
No... what's he doing here ?
He's crazy.
Embarrassing !
He's my dad's tennis partner now,
you can't break up with me anymore !
- First time seeing Roberta ?
- I've been seeing her for four years,
every day-
You must be as messed up as me.
I've never seen you here before...
I know it doesn't look much like you...
I tend to make things uglier...
Take care
What brings you here ?
Sorry Roberta, I forgot my keys
and dad's not answering.
I'll give you mine. Come in, honey.
Nice, Luca made it.
- Do you know him ? - He's famous...
the kid who got arrested last year
...for dealing at the Art Academy.
- Poor kid wasn't dealing.
- They just found some hash
in his home. - Some ? A pound...
See you at home.
Come here.
Sorry, I'm in high spirits today.
- I love you, bye.
- Okay... bye.
Hi!
- Remember me ?
- Right, this summer.
- Decorating for Christmas ?
- A bit early because I'm slow.
- I wanted to apologize.
- What for ?
I mistook you for a psycho like me,
- I didn't know Roberta was your mom.
- She's not my mom.
- She's with my dad.
- She's pregnant...
I got assigned to a new boring doctor.
Sorry, I have to go now,
happy painting.
Luca, no more bats !
Make something cheery for the holidays.
I think they're cheery,
if this isn't cheery...
May Massimiliano
win the Cottafavi Prize !
- Easy guys, I'm not going to win.
- Who else would ?
Alberici's a brain
but he's a pansy.
Alberici's a pansy,
the other's a Blackie.
- Guys, we are truly sickening.
- Yeah, enough.
- Look who it is !
- Ambrosini the junkie.
Wonder what he's selling.
Good stuff, that's for sure.
- Serena, hop in.
- No, I'll take my scooter.
See you there.
That portrait of me was really crude,
but precise.
I hung it in my room,
I look at it every day
and remember what a bitch I am.
That's all I wanted to say, bye.
Your dad ran off when you were 3
and your mom died.
When ?
4 years ago.
She was fine, then one day
they found a growth in her lungs
and within 3 weeks
she was gone.
I'm sorry,
I lost my morn when I was 11.
Your mom died too ?
No, she ditched my dad
because he was cheating on her
and then ran off
with her high school sweetheart.
Now they live in Romania
where he has a shoe factory.
- Cool. Do you see her much ?
- We talk on my birthday,
- memorable conversations.
- I'm sure.
You got lucky with Roberta then.
She seems cool.
She's uneasy with me,
I think she's afraid I won't like her.
I like talking to her.
My new doctor
makes me talk about
the one problem I don't have...
Meaning, the hash
they found in my house wasn't mine.
I didn't want to narc out the guy,
I'm not a rat !
- In that case, you're a hero.
- Please, I was scared shitless.
A night in jail was all it took
to convince me to piss in a cup
and go to therapy every week
till I turn 18
I'm almost done.
It's probably best
you're not seen with me,
people consider me
a socially dangerous character.
I was in even on the front page
of the local paper.
You don't seem dangerous to me.
They'll worry about you
if they see you with me.
- Well, then I'll go.
- Good, no more hanging out...
- Never seen you before in my life.
- Never !
You're Serena, right ? Hi.
Come here.
Luca's told me all about you,
I'm Davide.
- You've heard about me ?
- His uncle.
Uncle's an understatement, I'm his
sub-dad since Luca never met his.
And a his morn too,
but I'm sure Luca already told you.
- Want coffee ?
- No, thanks.
Luca and I are buddies,
business partners.
We have big plans,
has he told you about them ?
About my sister Betta's insurance ?
A hefty sum...
We're not some poor losers.
We've been living off the monthly
payouts hat I managed close-fistedly,
but he always had what he needed.
Have a seat, take a load off.
And I give him a lift
to the psychologist...
I can't fucking stand her !
Did Luca mention that to you ?
She's a ballbreaker.
Luca turns 18 in March, and bye-bye.
- Bye-bye" meaning...
- Meaning: goodbye and good riddance,
we'll cash it all in.
- Didn't Luca tell you ?
- No.
What do you two fucking talk about ?
I have a good friend in Formentera,
he's like a brother.
He proposed we go 50-50
on buying a chiringuito.
Luca and I have just enough money,
it'll be wicked cool.
Right on Playa de Migjorn,
- are you familiar with it ?
- No, I've never been there.
You should come visit us then !
Maybe after we've settled.
You'll be our guest,
Luca will be thrilled.
- That'd be nice, thanks.
- My pleasure, go wake him up.
He's fucking comatose.
Tell him I'm going out,
I've got a little meeting.
What the fuck ?
Didn't you have plans ?
Yes, it's just a quick hello.
I met your uncle.
Jesus, bet he talked your ear off.
No, he's nice ! He said to tell you
he left for a meeting.
Yes, a meeting with a pint at the pub.
The plan about Formentera sound nice,
you never told me.
- I didn't? Oh... - There'll be
no danger of us hanging out.
- What's that ?
- A cool band.
Have a listen,
but first
we'll take a picture together.
- Ready ?
- Yes.
I'll use it for a drawing.
Make a serious face now.
You made a silly face,
we have to take another.
No, I have to go to that damn gala.
Can I change in your bathroom ?
Listen to this, you probably know it...
Getting dolled up
like a prep school girl ?
Kind of...
Looking at me ?
- I don't want to go to Formentera.
- Why ? it should be beautiful.
- You're beautiful.
- Knock it off.
You're the most beautiful thing
I've ever had.
So are you.
Don't go, don't go to that gala.
...Marie Rose Bertolazzi!
- Talk to him.
- Okay.
Let it go, Massi. Who gives a shit.
- Rice with grouper and peas ?
- No, thanks.
Come with me
to the Crosettis party tonight.
- I'm going to bed early.
- You're not coming ?
- No way !
- I'm tired.
Fuck you, you're a drag,
acting all high and mighty,
who the fuck do you think you are ?
It was horrible,
I thought about you the whole time.
- Oh God...
- Damn!
Why didn't you take this off ?
I don't want to.
Embarrassed ?
- Aren't you going to answer ?
- Now what ?
Ale, was sleeping,
what do you want ?
- Massi is tanked.
- Why is that my problem ?
Why don't you call his mom ?
Fine, what a pain.
Sorry, I have to go.
- Because of Massimiliano ?
- I'm so fed up...
I'll come with you.
- What the fuck is this ?
- Like it ?
Super cool.
- Do they live here '?
- Yes.
Poor things.
Real poor...
You'd better stay here,
Damn, I'd like to see a rich house.
It's a kick-ass party !
Where's Massimiliano ?
- Drink ?
- Are you nuts ? Where is he ?
In there.
Serena, darling, finally.
I called Carla but she didn't pick up.
He asked for you. He puked
his guts out on my Persian rug
Disgusting !
I'm finally meeting Massimiliano.
What a pleasure.
- Put him in the car.
- Don't worry, we'll drive you home.
- We need to move his car first.
- Which ?
- The big one.
- Damn, the SUV! I'll do it.
- Can you drive it ?
- Of course.
- Does he live far ?
- In Ornate. Why ?
- I'll drop it off at his house.
- Are you kidding ? Luca !
My dad can stick
the Cottafavi Prize up his ass.
I'm so glad, I am so glad!
He's an asshole.
I want to be an orphan.
That bastard needs to die.
I want that asshole to die.
Sit up, please.
I hate his finance bullshit.
Have you noticed that my life sucks ?
Have you ?
Only you understand me, Serena.
Come on.
Stand up.
Massimiliano,
can you make it to your room ?
I'll try. Give me a kiss.
No way, go !
- We did it.
- Wait.
- Did you see that guy ?
- Who ?
He just suddenly appeared
in front of me.
I tried to swerve but I think
I hit him. He was on a bike.
Let's leave, help must be on the way.
I need to see.
- What happened ?
- He was run over.
- I think he hit his head.
- They're here.
- Is he dead ?
- No, let's go.
He's dead.
- I'm screwed, fucking hell !
- Maybe it's not serious.
Come on.
Fuck!
TRY TO BEHAVE...
Sono qui nella stanza con lui.
I'm with him, the doctor says
there's nothing they can do.
He's hemorrhaging too much,
they can't operate now.
Yes, they're moving him
to a regular patient room.
No, not the kids.
They shouldn't see him like this.
They're at grandma's,
I haven't told them anything.
Michele, thanks for coming !
The keys.
Hello to you...
Pick up, damn it!
Pick up.
- "Hello ?"
- Are you awake ?
We need to talk, I'm coming over.
Sweetie,
- are you all right?
- Not now, dad.
You should let me know
when you stay over Massimiliano's.
Just a phone call, is it that hard ?
- His morn told me to tell you...
- Tell me what? - To call her.
Are you still fucking asleep ?
Wake up.
- Open your eyes, look at me.
- I have a killer headache.
Get drunk all you want
but leave me out of it,
- I'm not your girlfriend anymore.
- Why are you so pissed ?
Don't you remember last night ?
Yes, I'm sorry.
What do you remember ?
You drove me home, right ?
My SUV ? Who brought it back ?
I left the keys on the dashboard
maybe the Crosettis drove it back.
- You're awesome, come here.
- Quit it. - Sorry.
- I have to go. - Wait !
I need to talk to you.
When you found out your mom
was with that other guy...
- How did you feel ?
- How do you think ?
Where are you going ?
- Not answering your phone ?
- I chucked it.
Why '2
Massimiliano doesn't know a thing.
Why did this fucking happen ?
I'll be locked up for life.
Nobody will know
you were driving, relax.
I always end up in the shit,
no matter what !
- Why me '? Fuck !
- Stop.
I'm sorry. I'm not mad at you,
I just don't want to drag you
into my shit.
- I went to the hospital.
- Why ?
To see how he was.
They took him out of ICU.
But you need to stay calm.
- Is that your daughter ?
- Yes.
Damn Giampiero,
I told you I'm in a jam.
I don't have that money now anyway.
I have bigger issues right now.
You want to take my house ?
Take it then and fuck off !
Sorry.
Know what I think ?
Since the SUV was there
when he got back,
I think Massimiliano drove it home.
And since you're a good girl
who cares about him,
and you realize he's in hot water...
you're covering for him.
I drove Massimiliano home
in Roberta's car.
Serena, honey...
I'm going to see the judge now.
I have to keep you here 2 days
till you admit Massimiliano drove.
Don't force me to be a jerk,
I don't like that.
Keep me here as long as you want,
I'm not going to say that
because it's not true.
FINAL CHAPTER
Mrs. Bernaschi!
- Hear about the cyclist's death ?
- When '?
- Last night.
- How is your son reacting ?
- I'm sorry !
- Tell us about your son.
I'm sorry !
- What the fuck ?
- I need to see Luca.
He told me everything,
just leave him alone.
- The police don't suspect him.
- I'll tell him,
no one must find out
you know each other.
- Listen up...
- I want him to rest assured.
Luca's in the shit,
he's screwed if he gets arrested again.
Go home and keep your mouth shut,
I'll take care of Luca.
- Like when he got arrested
covering for you ! - What ?
That pound of hash was yours.
You convinced him to take the blame
since he's underage.
- Did Luca tell you this bullshit ?
- You're hurting me.
No, he's still covering for you.
Damn straight, I raised him like a son
and I'll save him from this shit.
Right, with the money his mom
left to him !
Watch what you say and do,
I know where you live.
No go home, you little shit. Go !
Little shit !
Luca, my love...
Fuck off, damn Allied Property !
"Cyclist dead from hit-and-run."
Son of a...
Did you see this ?
Serena, honey ?
...no need to worry,
the police suspect Massimiliano...
...and I'll never tell anyone
it was you.
YOURS FOREVER
Dino Ossola called.
He wants to make a deal
that'll supposedly clear Massimiliano.
- What deal ?
- Dunno, I hung up right away.
Are you insane ?
Why didn't you let him explain ?
I don't want to be in cahoots
with that worm
to conceal our son's guilt, got it ?
Let's go in or you'll catch a cold.
On here is the proof
of who was driving the car that night:
first and last name.
If someone else was driving,
the police will find him.
Well, the police are convinced
Massimiliano did it.
And only my daughter knows the truth
and she'll never fess up.
Plus, this guy might vanish.
What do you want in return ?
- Nine hunfred...
- What?
980,000.
700,000 I invested
plus the 40% return I was promised.
Seems only fair to me.
And a kiss.
- What do you mean, a kiss ?
- A kiss.
- Do you want it in cash ?
- No!
Wire it to an account
I just opened in Switzerland.
As soon as the money comes through,
I'll give this to the police.
Write down your account number.
Thanks.
You think I'm coming undone,
don't you ?
You're wrong,
I've never been better in my life.
- I don't think anything, just hurry.
- Good, it's best not to think.
I have better things to do.
Here.
And the kiss ?
No, a real kiss.
You're a jackass.
Serena, enough,
you've been in there for 2 days !
Don't piss me off, open up.
- Food.
- I'm not hungry.
Well, if you change your mind...
I'll leave it here.
- Tell dad not to bother me.
- He'll be back tomorrow.
He left, he was jolly and happy...
I don't understand him anymore.
Guess I'm a shitty psychologist.
I know you don't feel like talking,
but I'll tell you what I think anyway.
If this carries on,
we'll have to hire a lawyer.
They can't keep hounding you like this.
If you say that you drove Massimiliano
home, they have to believe you.
I believe you.
Understand ?
I'll leave you alone.
Don't worry about Massimiliano.
His parents will defend him.
It's not about Massimiliano.
- But Luca.
- Who is Luca?
You're the only one who knows him.
He's not what everyone thinks he is.
Luca Ambrosini ?
Yes, he's a great kid, I know.
What does he have to do with it ?
Right here, turn left here.
Relax.
Oh my God !
- What is going on ?
- Why are they here ?
- I need to go see.
- Stay here, I'll go.
It's best they don't see you. I'll go.
- He wouldn't open up so they
bashed in the door. - Oh my God !
- Adriana, darling, how are you ?
- Hello, handsome !
- Carla?
- She'll be right out.
- You look great.
- Thanks.
- Matteo, third time's a charm.
- You look run down.
- Hi, son.
- Hello, dad.
- Your siblings are here.
- What an honor !
Your Majesty...
I even brought our little sister
straight from Goa.
- But I'm leaving right away.
- Relax, they won't bite you.
Honey ? Aren't you coming down ?
Can you keep an eye on catering,
they don't seem up to par.
Even if you served
your guests dog food
they would still love you.
- Look how happy they are !
- Why, should they be sad ?
Of course not.
Things are going so well for them.
You bet on the downfall of this country
and you won.
"We" won.
You're part of it too, honey.
My mom and dad are here.
Even those two morons
have graced us with their presence.
I'll be right down.
Thank you.
You look beautiful.
Having been convicted of manslaughter
and criminal negligence,
Luca will complete his sentence
next fall.
Massimiliano's insurance
company negotiated
with the family of the victim,
Fabrizio Lupi,
for a settlement of 218,976 euro.
Sums like this are calculated
based on specific parameters:
the person's life expectancy,
earning capacity,
quantity and quality
of emotional bonds.
Insurance companies call this
human capital