Everything you need to know about
Young & Hungry in 30 seconds.
Gabi's a chef who was hired by Josh
who's a rich tech mogul who
wanted to marry Caroline.
But when Josh got dumped, he and
Gabi got drunk and slept together.
Awkward.
The next day, Josh got engaged to Caroline
leaving Gabi with unresolved feelings.
More awkward.
When Gabi recreated Josh's
favorite childhood blanket
for his 30th birthday, Josh
caught mad feelings for her,
called off his wedding, ran over
to her place to profess his love
on her fire escape, only
to find her kissing Cooper.
Who she dated, but then wasn't dating,
but now is apparently dating again.
You are now ready to board Season Two.
Oh my God!
You're on time for work!
What's wrong?
What are you talking about?
I'm always on time for work.
I couldn't say that with a
straight face. (Laughs) Sit.
Ohhh. So, late last night
I came to check on Josh.
I sat there as that boy
poured his heart out.
Until I finally convinced him to go over
to Gabi's and to tell her how he felt.
Go big or go home!
That's what I said.
So what happened?
That's what I'm going to find out. She
could be up there with him right now.
(Giggles)
Both: Oh my God, oh my God!
Oh, I knew it! I said go for
it. Now all is well with...
Hey, good morning, everybody.
What the...
How'd you do that?
My hair?
What do you think? It's
an updo for the "I do."
Well, now it's an "I
don't." The wedding's off.
What? What do you mean "the wedding's off"?
You didn't know?
Uh, Josh didn't "talk" to you last night?
No, no! I had no idea! What happened?
He found out that blanket
was from you, not Caroline.
I don't know how.
What?
No! No, no, no! No, no, no, no, no!
He was not supposed to find that out.
I mean, I mean, for a minute
I wanted him to find out,
but then I realized I shouldn't tell him
and I couldn't tell him and
I was finally okay with that.
You know, everything was
good. And everybody was happy.
Oh, God! Josh, he must be beside himself.
He's beside something, all right.
He must hate me. God, I have to
tell him why I did what I did.
Gabi, wait!
Josh.
God, what is it with that guy?
Every time he breaks up with Caroline,
he ends up in bed with a blonde.
(Theme music playing)
Sync & corrections by PetaG
- www.addic7ed.com -
♪ She's in the spotlight ♪
♪ and she turned my head ♪
♪ she'd run a red light ♪
♪ 'cause she's bad like that ♪
♪ I like that ooh, baby, ooh, baby ♪
♪ baby ♪
♪ I like that ooh, baby ooh, baby ♪
What do you make for the guy
that calls off his wedding
and then has sex with
another girl 30 seconds later.
I mean, not that I care.
You know, why would I
care? What I'm saying is
what am I doing here? What is happening?
(Laughs) You know?
What is happening?
I'll tell you what's happening.
I was canceling the flowers
from Andre, the super hot florist
with the jawline of a Greek statue.
And he asked me out for drinks.
Look at me rising from the
ashes of this wedding disaster,
like a flaming phoenix.
Which is coincidentally the name of
the bar we're having drinks at tonight.
Morning.
Oh my God. Josh, I'm so sorry
about all this. I just need you to know
the only reason I didn't
tell you about the blanket...
No, Gabi, please. Stop.
You did me a favor.
Without you, I never
would have realized that
Caroline wasn't the right girl
for me. But enough about me.
What did you gals get into last night?
Yolanda? Nothing. Gabi?
Did you do anything, ah...
Crazy last night?
Uh... nope.
Totally uneventful.
Really?
'Cause, I mean...
Totally uneventful would
mean that nothing happened.
Something must have happened.
You're an exciting young person.
Fine. Um...
Cooper flew in from China and
surprised me in the middle of the night.
Both: Cooper?
What?
Cooper from China? With
the glasses? Last night?
Do you believe this, Yolanda? Neither do I.
So...
(Stutters) Are you guys in
love? Do you love him? Yes?
No? I mean, should I be happy for you? I
need to know if I should be happy for you.
You now what, I think it's
important to know who to be happy for
and who's just gonna be alone.
Why did Cooper fly in last night?
Why? Why?
Uh... well he bought me a
present and he couldn't wait
to see my face when I opened it.
Oh ma God!
Are you hearing this, Yolanda?
Chills. I have chills.
This is just the most
romantic thing I've ever heard.
Yeah.
The only thing that would
have been more romantic
is if he climbed up my fire escape
with roses in the pouring rain.
(Laughs)
Yeah.
Who does that?
Well,
sounds like we both had, ah,
wildly romantic nights last night.
Now I know this is gonna sound
crazy, but you know that feeling you
get when you meet someone and
you have that instant connection?
I had that with Laura.
It's Lauren.
I know that.
I call her Laura for short.
Yeah.
I believe this one's
definitely gonna go somewhere.
- Is she staying for breakfast?
- Nope.
Oh my God, oh my God, oh my God, oh my God.
Is Cooper here?
Nope.
Josh called off his wedding.
What?
Yeah.
He found out the blanket was from me.
Uh, how?
Who cares? Do you know what this means?
When Josh found out that I was the one
that spent all those weeks recreating
his special childhood blanket,
he realized I was the
one that knows his heart,
which means I'm the reason he called
off the wedding! Now what am I gonna do?
Hm, what do you mean what are you gonna do?
Sofia, last night I was freaking out
that Josh was getting married
because I had feelings for him.
Yeah, and then Cooper came in
and swept you off your feet,
and now you're back together with Cooper.
(Sighs) I know, I know.
But then Josh, he called off
his wedding because of me!
Which means he has feelings for me!
For me!
Oh, no, no, no. No, no,
no, no. No, it doesn't.
Oh, really? Then explain to me why
last night he had sex with a girl
who looks exactly like me.
Do you hear yourself?
I do.
What is happening? You
know? What is happening?
Okay.
Look, I know you're confused.
You had feelings for Josh.
And if Josh had come here
last night declaring his love
for you, it would be a different story.
But he didn't.
- Yeah.
- Who did?
Cooper. Yeah, I know. I
know, you're so right, Sofia.
You're so smart.
Well, we are who we are.
(Sighs)
I just wish I had a sign.
- (Knocking)
- (Gasps)
I'm done. Nice tux.
Thank you.
Never been to a black tie wedding before.
Finley.
Cooper Finley.
- I have a huge surprise for you.
- Sit down.
So you know how I'm supposed
to go back to China tonight?
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, I traded in my first class ticket
for two coach tickets.
Two what-what?
I know, first class for a
programmer. Pretty sweet, right?
Anyway, I figured while Josh
was away on his honeymoon,
you could spend three
weeks with me in China!
It's such an amazing place.
Everything in this apartment is from there.
Mmm, I don't know.
I mean, what if she gets lost...
do they have any signs there?
Cooper... Wow! I mean,
that's the sweetest thing I've
ever heard, but I-I-I can't go.
Josh called off his wedding.
What? Why?
- Oh, don't ask.
- It's complicated.
Um... so, you know, I can't
really ask for three weeks off.
But since Josh was gonna give you the
time off anyway, maybe he'll let you go.
Plus it's not like you're the
reason he called off the wedding.
Oh. Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's a really good point.
Great.
Now, if I leave before I wrinkle
maybe I can get a refund on this tux.
Okay.
Gabi, please ask Josh. It will
be the best time you've ever had.
That we've ever had.
Bye.
Well...
Cooper gave me my sign.
Well, thank God.
Yeah, now all I need is a sign from Josh.
What?
I'm gonna ask Josh if I
can go to China with Cooper,
and if he lets me, it means he
doesn't have feelings for me.
But if he says no, it means
he does have feelings for me.
Okay, and then what? What
if Josh has feelings for you?
And then I w... I don't know.
Oh, hey, baby. How are you feeling?
How am I feeling?
I want to go on a bike ride
and I can't find my other glove.
Okay, well let me help you.
When's the last time you saw it?
This is all your fault.
I didn't lose your damn glove.
Your fault that I went
over to Gabi's like a fool.
"Go big or go home," you said.
That doesn't make sense! I was home!
May I remind you that I told
you to go tell Gabi how you feel.
Not to creep outside around
her apartment and then run away.
I did not run away.
I snuck away.
What was I supposed to do?
She was making out with Cooper.
(Scoffs) Trust me, that
didn't mean anything.
That girl has feelings for you.
Hey, guys. Um...
Josh, can I talk to you for a minute?
Alone.
So, what's up?
I wanted to ask you something.
But first, how are you doing?
Good!
Good.
How are you?
Good!
Good.
I'm gonna go.
Wait, Gabi. Um...
I needed to talk to you
about something, too.
You did?
Yeah.
I-I want you to know that girl
from last night was just a...
oh, rebound. Yeah, I know.
You know, I mean, today was
supposed to be your wedding day.
But it's not.
Because I called it off.
Right.
Which is, um...
It's kind of what I wanted
to talk to you about.
- Should we sit?
- I can sit.
- Let's sit.
- I need to sit.
Josh, um...
I wanted to ask you something, but...
First I want you to know no matter
what you say, I'm totally gonna be fine.
So no pressure. You know.
- Just say...
- I'm good. Don't stop, you're doing great.
Okay. Um...
I was wondering...
Um...
Now that you called off the wedding...
Yeah?
How you feel about me...
How I feel about you?
Taking three weeks off and
going to China with Cooper?
Gabi, I feel the same way.
- What?
- Hmm?
About... China (Scoffs)
As Cooper does.
I love China.
(Chuckles)
I mean, yeah, you...
don't miss the-that wall.
It's, uh... it's great.
Oh, okay. Well I just thought maybe
since you're not going on your honeymoon,
that maybe you wanted
me to stay here with you
and not go away with Cooper.
No! No, no, no.
Go to China. You should go.
Go with Cooper.
Go! And you know what?
China gets cold, so why
don't you take that with ya.
Thanks.
Well, I got my sign.
Uh, final sign? Or you-still-
need-three-more-signs sign.
I asked Josh if I could
go to China with Cooper,
and he said it was fine, which means
that he doesn't have feelings for me.
Which is actually kind of a relief.
You know, it means I'm
meant to be with Cooper.
Well, are you okay with that?
So...
Are you going to China?
Does that answer your question?
Not sure. Tell me one more time.
Okay.
- Hey, baby...
- Not now, Yolanda.
I'm writing code.
You know, keeping the money flowing so I
can continue to pay you to give me advice.
Look, Josh, I know that...
remember when you told
me "go big or go home"?
Well, now I'm telling you,
"go home."
Okay.
- (Sighs)
- (Door closes)
So...
Will I make Andre happy?
Very!
'Cause you're not going.
You're staying with Josh tonight.
No, I'm not.
I'm meeting Andre.
Not tonight.
Yes, tonight.
Andre is riding the "E" train.
That's me.
You stay with Josh.
I would, but he doesn't want me to.
Josh needs you.
Ugh...
Everybody wants a piece of me.
Hey, buddy.
How's it going?
You don't need me here tonight, right?
My life sucks.
Oh...
Oh, I know!
Maybe you need to get out.
You know, go to a bar.
Get your drink on.
Take your mind off things.
No way.
The last thing I want to do is
be anywhere where there's women.
You stay right here.
And let all the nice boys buy you drinks.
Oh, there's my date.
Andre!
Hey, handsome!
Elliot told me everything.
I'm a florist, that practically makes
me a licensed psychologist. Spill.
I'm good.
Yeah, he's good.
You sure?
He's sure.
It all started when Gabi
began working for me.
So...
How are you feeling?
Amazing. Like everything's
the way it's supposed to be.
Uber is here.
You got everything?
I got everything I need right here.
Aw... Can you have it out there?
Okay, bye.
- See you later!
- Bye, have so much fun!
- Bye!
♪ I love to live alone ♪
♪ I love to live...
before you take off your
bra and start singing...
Oh.
Too late.
(Chuckles)
- I just wanted to thank you.
- Aw.
I really appreciate you
getting me through this.
What are best friends for?
Okay. All right, bye.
- Bye!
- Love you, see you later.
- See ya, bye!
- Ah, China!
♪ And I love to live alone ♪
Oh!
Passport.
Gabi.
Gabi! Gabi!
Your passport.
Gabi: Yeah, it's right here in my hand.
You mean my hand? Catch!
Gabi: Thank you!
Bye!
Oh, Cooper!
You forgot your glove.
Cooper: I wear mittens!
Oh!
Okay.
Bye!
"JXK"?
Josh, something weird, Kaminski.
Oh my God!
So I'm running, right?
I get all the way up the fire
escape in the pouring rain
with roses.
Oh my God, just like Pretty Woman.
More like pretty boring.
Shh!
And then I look inside,
- and I see...
- Josh.
Is that Gabi?
(Crowd gasps)
No, it's her roommate, Sofia.
Oh.
What are you doing here?
Well, you didn't answer your phone so I
called Elliot, he said that you were here,
and that your middle name is
Xander, with an "X," aka JXK.
My glove! Where'd you find this?
On our fire escape.
Nope, that's not my glove.
Definitely not my glove.
He's lying, it is his...
Big glove.
Big hands.
Anyway, he was there last night on
the fire escape in the rain with roses.
Did you just out me?
I'm sorry, but I'd like a happy ending.
Duly noted.
Okay, so you did come over last night?
(Stammers)
Technically, I wouldn't call standing
outside in the rain "coming over."
(Sighs)
I just needed to talk to Gabi.
Why?
Have you not seen Pretty
Woman?  He loves her.
I don't know if it's love. I...
Well then what the hell is it?
She's getting on a plane
with Cooper right now
because I told her that if
you had feelings for her,
you would have come over last night.
And you did.
(Gasps)
Wait.
Are you saying that
Gabi has feelings for me?
Come on, Josh. You had no idea?
The pretty ones are never smart.
(Chuckles)
I don't believe... I've got to call her.
No!
Go to her!
Leave your tab open and go to her.
No, yeah, Josh. He's-he's right.
She has to know everything.
And if she still wants to go with
Cooper... fine, but... She needs to know.
Run! Run like the wind to that airport.
Get out of here now.
Good luck.
You too.
Josh: Excuse me.
Pardon me. I'm sorry, this
is a matter of life and death.
Yeah, he has to tell a
girl he might like her.
Hi.
Can you tell me if Gabi Diamond has
checked in to flight YL125 to Beijing?
I'm sorry sir, but I can't
give out that information.
All right, fine. I get that.
But have you seen Pretty Woman?
Gabi. China. Ticket. Buy a ticket!
I'm sorry, you're too late.
That flight's already boarding.
(Sighs) Okay. Well, now
you have to call her.
Gabi!
- Josh?
- Yeah?
- On the phone.
- Yes.
Pretty ones are never smart.
This is Jin Mao Tower.
Wow.
Oh, and remember the sneezing
panda from the Internet?
- Yeah.
- Here he is all grown up.
(Gasps) Oh, cute.
Attendant: Final boarding call
for flight YL125 to Beijing.
Oh, hey, we should put our
phones on airplane mode.
Oh, right. Yeah, we should do that.
How would one do that?
It's ringing.
I got her voicemail. What do I say?
Say everything.
Hey, Gabi.
Um...
I'm calling you from...
The airport, actually.
I'm sure you're wondering
why I'm at the airport.
Good question.
You-You always ask good questions.
It's because...
Last night, after I called off my wedding.
You're the person that I wanted to see.
I even ran up your fire escape with roses.
Um...
I didn't know what I was
going to say, but I knew that
I needed to see you, and
then I saw Cooper and you.
And look, if you're happy with Cooper,
just disregard this whole message.
But...
I-If you think you might,
like, be happier with me...
Call me back.
This is Josh, by the way.
I can't believe I'm in China.
If six-year-old Gabi digging a hole
could see me now...(Chuckles)
Oh, don't turn your phone on.
Why? How am I supposed
to check my messages?
Well, if you don't have
an international data plan,
it will cost you thousands of dollars.
Oh, I don't have those.
Who's gonna call me anyway?
You know, in China they always kiss twice.
Oh. Okay.
Sync & corrections by PetaG
- www.addic7ed.com -