***subtitles by youwish@subscene.com***
***Please don't use without credit***
I truly don't even know
why I'm here, Doctor.
Well, of course, it's difficult
running a large household by oneself,
and raising four children is exacting,
but they're wonderful, wonderful children,
and my husband,
he's a good man;
a very hard worker.
Uh...
There was just... one thing.
Sometimes at night,
and he comes to me,
I imagine myself
splitting his fat, bald head
with a great, large axe.
It's just a feeling that comes
over me many, many times a day.
A feeling of, um,
expectation.
Hungering.
How do you bear it,
this English weather?
I cannot sing from the sadness.
I open my mouth...
You see?
Nothing.
Well, and with my dear Allister gone,
it's two years now I...
I should have thought I'm far,
far too old for these kinds of feelings,
but, well, there they are.
Nurse,
I asked you to clean this wound
and put on fresh bandages.
Dr. Richardson told me
not to waste supplies.
Is he mad?
No, we must keep the wound
clean to prevent sepsis.
- What 'sis'?
- Sepsis.
Infection. It's caused by
germs entering the wound.
Germs. They're tiny creatures
that invade the body,
causing pain, fever, infections.
I don't think I have those.
You can't see them.
They're invisible.
Please, just fetch me a beaker of carbolic
acid solution and a fresh bandage.
Yes, Doctor.
Honestly...
If that oaf Richardson
had this way,
we'd perform surgery in the
sewer using rusty saws,
and it would be Beekman's
pills for everybody,
no matter the ailment...
- Granville.
Are you aware I specifically told the nurse
not to change these bandages?
Soiled bandages are
a haven for germs.
Germ theory is
poppycock, Granville.
Now, stop speaking of it.
You're frightening the patients.
Poppycock? But Lister has proved it.
All the latest journals...
- Pipe, Granville.
No, we won't be needing those.
Thank you very much.
A steady air of calm reassurance
and regular bleeding.
These are the keys
to modern medicine.
Will you remain calm, when the leg
putrefies and become gangrenous?
When you amputate?
When the rot spreads
to her blood and kills her?
I've had quite
enough of your impertinence.
Put back that bandage
and bleed a pint.
Look... look at her, man!
You'll get more blood out of a turnip.
Do as you're told,
and give her Beekman's pills
for insurance.
Beekman's pills are rubbish.
They will do nothing but
bring on stomach cramps.
I won't stand here and watch
you murder your patients,
just because you can't be bothered
to read the latest science.
(laughing)
At long last,
we agree, Granville.
Bloody dinosaur.
Whoa!
Good day, Mrs. Copeland.
Is Edmund in?
I wouldn't know, sir.
Guests at all hours. Mad parties.
Deliveries day and night.
If I didn't love his parents so,
I would never stay.
I'd pack my bags, and all
this electrical equipment.
It's a fire hazard, that's what it is.
I'll try the study.
You. Why have you stopped?
Ow!
Now, that is not what
you're supposed to do.
Hello.
Ahhh...
Oh no.
You haven't been sacked
again, have you?
I tell you, Edmund. The healing arts
in England are positively lethal.
It's no coincidence that the morgues
are placed adjacent to the hospitals.
I mean, this is the 1880s.
We're meant to be in the midst
of a medical revolution.
Is it asking too much to use just
a bit of what science has provided,
rather than go about,
indiscriminately killing people?
Well, if you put it like that.
What's all the fuss outside?
My new generator.
You purchased a generator
just last year.
Obsolete. This one is half the size
and delivers double the power.
I never thought I'd say this, but,
I've lost hope.
Since I was a boy, all I wanted
was to practice medicine,
and to help people that
actually needed it,
but I'm beginning to fear
that the world is set against me.
Well, what are you going to do?
Private practice, I suppose.
I shall harness myself
to some greedy pill pusher,
shut my mouth, and pray that
it nets me a steady income.
Or, I could give you
ten thousand pounds,
and you could do
whatever you wish.
I've told you a thousand
times, Edmund.
You and your family have done
quite enough for me already.
Oh, come on, Mortimer.
I'd hardly miss it.
That's not the point.
I simply must make
my own way in the world.
You are so wonderfully middle-class.
Thank you.
Oh, by the way, there
seems to be a young man
asleep on your stairs.
Really?
Ha!
Good morning.
Mortimer Granville to see
Dr. Dalrymple. I have an appointment.
He's with someone now.
I see. Very well,
I shall wait, then.
Ladies.
Umm...
Ahh...
It's lovely.
Japanese, I think.
You're a charlatan,
with no idea
of a woman's wants or needs than
of... of the moon's atmosphere!
Charlotte, I simply
want you to behave...
You may be unaware, but there is
a social revolution afoot!
Women will no longer
be denied our rightful place.
Try, as you might, to keep us in
the kitchen and the drawing room.
We will not rest
until we are welcomed
in the universities,
in the professions, and
in the voting booth.
What are you staring at?
Yes, I can see the wheels turning.
Pity I can't stay for the pronouncement.
Charlotte!
That woman was...
Hysterical.
Yes, quite.
It's a very difficult case,
that one.
Huh...
I have worked at a number
of hospitals in the past...
year.
Guy's, of course. Charing Cross.
The Westminster Hospital,
most recently,
Excellent.
- St. Thomas's,
Old St. Thomas's,
the Poplar and Stepney Sick Asylum...
Good. Impressive.
Brompton Hospital for Consumption
and Diseases of the Chest,
The Royal Sea Bathing
Infirmary...
Fine. Fine.
It's... It's a variety of experiences,
but, tell me, Doctor,
what do you know of hysteria?
Ah...
Nothing.
Nothing?
But it's a plague of our time.
I would venture to say that
half the women in London are affected.
It stems from an overactive uterus.
In its most severe forms,
it demands drastic measures.
Institutionalization. Surgery, even,
but in its milder manifestations:
nymphomania, frigidity,
melancholia, anxiety,
it's eminently treatable.
Interesting.
Look. I'll come straight
to the point, Doctor.
I'm keen for help.
Oh, you saw my waiting room.
Not enough hands to do
the work, so to speak.
Sir, I would be enormously grateful
for any position that allowed me
to offer relieve to my patients
with little chance of killing them.
I've treated thousands of cases,
and I've not lost a single patient,
but I won't lie to you, Granville.
It's tedious, tiring work.
Are you fit?
I have never shirked
from hard work
in the pursuit of helping
the most needy among us.
Jolly good.
Shall we say, umm...
three pounds a week?
Three pounds?
Four.
Plus board and lodging.
I accept.
We're going to do great things
together, Granville.
Good God, man.
What a grip.
So, breakfast at eight,
dinner at six.
Your room is up... Oh...
Emily.
I want you to meet my new assistant.
Dr. Mortimer Granville.
My daughter, Emily Dalrymple.
Your servant, ma'am.
So pleased to meet you, Dr. Granville.
Emily is the angel of the house.
Since my dear wife, Melodia, passed away,
Emily has run things in proper order.
Oh, and she's also quite
a scientist in her own right.
Don't boast, Father.
Let me guess.
Geology?
Botany?
Lepidopterology?
Phrenology.
(laughing)
- Phrenology, yes.
I can assure you, phrenology
is an accurate science, Doctor.
Yes, the size and relation of the bumps
on one's head's are a veritable
road map to the personality,
if one is properly trained
to read them.
I didn't mean to imply that--
I think a demonstration is in
order for our young skeptic.
It would be most convivial.
Please.
Why,
Dr. Granville, you have the most
perfectly-formed nimbus I've ever felt.
Nimbus?
He is a man of great wisdom.
I knew it. I knew it.
And your mastoid is...
is very well-pronounced.
Doctor, you're quite
sympathetic, aren't you?
Umm... well...
What else? What else?
Oh!
- Oh, I'm so sorry!
- What?
It's just...
Well, your... your
thrombus is so... rigid;
so jutting and prominent.
It startled me.
Rigid thrombus?
Sorry? Rigid thrombus?
It augurs fame.
No, no, no...
While I have the utmost respect
for your method, Miss Dalrymple,
I must complain that you've misread me.
I am but a simple doctor.
I have no ambition for notoriety.
And I can assure you, your
thrombus is the key to your future.
Whether you seek it or not,
Dr. Granville,
you are destined for fame.
Ahoy?
Who is this?
Who is this, please?
Mr. Stanton, huh?
Can you hear me?
Can you hear me now?
Yes.
This is Edmund St. John Smythe.
No, I don't work at
the telephone exchange. You see,
I've installed this telephone
and I wanted to test it.
You're the only person
they could connect me to.
How are things going over there?
Sounds thrilling. Very well,
carry on, then. Goodbye.
Do you realize?
I have been speaking to a barrister
on the other side of London.
What about?
Nothing. I don't even know the chap.
Nothing to value if you
have nothing to speak about.
Here I am in Grosvenor Square;
he's miles away,
yet we're able to speak
to each other instantaneously.
Do you think they'll catch on?
I have no idea,
but imagine if everyone had one.
Right.
Well,
I have just been
offered a position
by London's leading specialist
in women's medicine.
Oh, God, how ghastly for you.
When do you start?
Tomorrow.
Quite looking forward
to it, actually.
Who is she?
What?
Hmm?
She's his daughter.
Emily Dalrymple.
I only met her briefly, but...
But what?
Oh, Edmund, she is magnificent.
The epitome of English virtue and...
womanliness.
I haven't a hope.
A handsome, young doctor.
What more could a woman ask?
Better income. Social equal.
Overrated.
A few laughs. Stiff prick.
That's all a girl wants.
And you know this, because?
Oh, I've read it in a magazine.
Oh, I see.
A toast, then. To the end of Dr. Mortimer
Granville, once a brilliant student,
most recently a visionary
doctor to the poor,
and now, hand-maid
to anxious, middle-aged women.
Edmund St. John Smythe:
bachelor,
benefactor, miserable student,
sometime drunkard,
full-time sexual deviant,
and supreme waster of time and money.
Especially if it has anything to do
with the science of electricity.
- To the telephone.
- To the Queen.
To calling the Queen
on the telephone.
Morning, Mrs. Parsons.
Oh, good morning, Doctor.
This is Dr. Granville.
He'll be assisting me this morning.
Very pleased to meet you,
Mrs. Parsons.
Doctor.
Notice the general pallor.
And how are we
this morning, Mrs. Parsons?
Still feeling anxious?
Yes, quite anxious, Doctor.
I've been having those distracting
thoughts we discussed all week.
Yes.
Throughout history,
the medical establishment has
offered hysterical women
a veritable smorgasbord of treatments:
warm baths, ice baths, water jets,
mesmerisation,
horseback riding, even,
but I favour a more
direct approach.
Now, I like to begin
with a drop of musk oil,
followed by oil of lilies.
A good dollop.
Now, are you ready, Mrs. Parsons?
Yes. Yes, Doctor. Quite ready.
Ooh...
Now, you begin with
the index finger.
Applying gentle pressure,
and slowly,
slowly in a circular motion,
still pressing gently.
It's a bit like patting your head
and rubbing your tummy at the same time,
but you'll soon
get the hang of it.
Vulvar massage was popularized by
Pieter Van Foreest in the 16th century,
who prescribed it most
especially for widows
and women of religious orders.
- No offense, Mrs. Parsons.
- None taken, Doctor.
But, today, in a clinical
environment with a trained professional
this is the most direct,
most effective treatment we can offer.
Good steady pressure.
That's the key.
Oh... Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you.
Of course, reapply oil as needed.
Notice the effect, Doctor?
Shortness of breath,
blushing of the skin,
a fluttering of the eyelids,
twitching.
Come on! Crimson!
Vocalization.
All perfectly normal.
Merely an involuntary physiological
reaction to the treatment.
Oh... Oh, come on!
Come on, boy!
Up and over!
Steady on, Mrs. Parsons. Steady on.
Good steady pressure.
That's the key to it.
Tally-ho!
Steady as she goes, Mrs. Parsons.
Steady as she goes.
You see, by fierce
external stimulation,
we're able to elicit the
pain/pleasure reaction,
thereby inducing
the hysterical paroxysm,
and coaxing the uterus back
into its normal position.
Amazing.
The female organ is, as you know,
incapable of experiencing any
pleasurable sensation what so ever,
without actual penetration
of the male organ.
Arghhh...
As you can see, Granville,
a very satisfactory paroxysm.
Well, I think we can
judge this treatment
a great success, would
you say, Mrs. Parsons?
Startling, Dr. Dalrymple.
A powerful demonstration.
- And those nagging thoughts?
- Thank you.
Gone, Doctor.
Wonderful.
So, same time next week.
Same time tomorrow, I should say.
Moderation in all things,
Mrs. Parsons.
Moderation in all things.
Is that you, Sarah?
Hello.
Oh! Missed me, Charlie!
Sauce, sir?
It's lovely with the fish.
Thank you.
And my father was Anglican
minister of Mortlake.
Unfortunately, he and mother
perished in the last cholera outbreak
when I was a boy.
After coming to London to volunteer,
they contracted the disease themselves.
Oh, how dreadful.
Oh, terrible.
No doubt, that's where you gained
your interest in medicine.
Lord St. John Smythe knew of my fate,
and without thought of the cost,
brought me into his own home and
provided for my welfare and education.
Just what you'd expect from
a man of his standing.
There is no greater charity
than the gift of education.
You read the book of Samuel Smiles?
Is there anyone more sensible?
More supremely British?
Quite.
Music. Philosophy.
Phrenology.
You're a woman of many
talents, Miss Dalrymple.
It's through generosity,
through compassion,
through simple Christian kindness,
that England's gospel is spread
to all those who hunger for...
Hello, Father.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
Charlotte...
Emily, hello. Love the earrings.
Good evening, Charlotte.
Molly! Hello!
Staying out of trouble, I hope?
Most days, miss. Wine?
Yes, please.
You remember my daughter?
Charlotte Dalrymple.
- Daughter?
- My new assistant, Dr. Mortimer Granville.
Oh, hello. Lovely
to meet you properly.
Careful not to prick
yourself, Doctor.
What... oh!
You are aware that
dinner begins at six.
I'm so sorry.
Lizzie Burke had her
eighth baby today. A little girl.
She was turn the wrong way around,
it took forever to get her out.
It was unbelievable.
Must we speak of such
things at table?
Emily.
Dr. Granville.
How is your fish?
Very fresh and very flaky.
Thank you.
And Emily, are the parsnips
to your liking?
Oh, that's enough, Charlotte.
Only trying to make the
conversation sufficiently benign.
Dr. Granville,
what say you?
Childbirth. Nasty, uncomfortable
topic best avoided at supper,
or miracle of life suited
for any setting?
I believe that serious medical matters,
are best left to those who are trained.
Hear, hear!
The lone doctor in
my neighborhood
can only steady his scalpel
with a quart of gin.
What say you, then?
Charlotte is the mistress
at the East End Settlement,
House of Haven for
the less-fortunate.
Yes, unfortunately, the experience
has left her without a sense of
punctuality or decorum.
Oh, that's probably true.
I suppose I should've said to Lizzie,
"Hold tight, darling,
won't be a minute. Just got to pop home.
Mustn't be late for supper"
I don't know why you bother
coming here at all,
if your sole intention is
to be disruptive.
It isn't my sole intention.
We're out of coal again
and I need ten pounds.
No, no, no, no.
I already told you yesterday,
I'm not giving you any further
support in that regard.
I know you did, but
I didn't think you mean it.
Well, if that what it takes to
bring to your senses, so be it.
I've induldged you too long.
I've allowed you to roam the
streets of London late at night.
Streets that I would be frightened
to go into in broad daylight.
I've taken into my own home
the employ of...
inexperienced maids at
your request, but no more.
Then, Father, please give me my dowry.
Haha...
Why, so you can waste it on
prostitutes and factory workers?
I don't think so.
No, no. Not until you marry.
I would rather offer myself
to a band of ravenous Cossacks.
The parsnips are delicious,
are they not?
I do find they work wonderfully
with the fish. Don't you think?
It's not the Middle Ages. She should
be able to marry whomever she pleases.
No! It's not proper.
Now, you give up this settlement house
and step up to your responsibility,
and until you do so,
I will not give you another penny.
Then I won't come here anymore,
not for charity or for company,
and you may threaten me with
privation, with bankruptcy,
with a life that knows
only hunger and squalor,
but I shall never veer
from what I know
to be my own true path.
And don't slam...
Does she slam every door?
Very difficult case, that one.
Good night, Doctor.
How is it, Miss Dalrymple,
tha you are so much the ideal,
and your sister is so...
so volatile?
well, I'm hardly ideal, Doctor.
And...
Charlotte, she just...
feels everything so strongly.
If you truly knew
her, you would see
she's terribly clever and
wonderfully charitable.
Well, if she's earned
such love and admiration
from one so kind and
gentle as yourself,
I shall never speak poorly of her.
Good night, Doctor.
Good night, Miss Dalrymple.
Go on, Frank.
How are you this morning?
We're doing fine.
He just misses his mum.
You know what? I was thinking
about you this morning.
Do you know what
we going to start with?
Drawing.
Pardon me.
It's quite alright, handsome.
- Molly, is it?
- That's right, sir.
But my friends call me
Molly the Lolly,
and I think that we can be friends.
Molly the Lolly.
That's an unusual nickname.
Fancy a lick?
No, no. Thank you.
Only six buck for
a gentlemen like yourself.
It won't take me a minute.
Well, that's a generous offer, I'm sure,
but I have a very busy day ahead of me,
so... so... so... perhaps
another time, okay?
No, no, no. What I mean to say is...
Well, if you'll excuse me.
Suit yourself.
You alright, Fannie?
Yeah...
It's nothing.
Fannie, what is it? What?
It's George.
Again.
I think he's gonna land us
on the street this time.
- Oh, no, no, miss. I can't.
- No, take it. Take it.
Straight to the landlord.
No stopping.
I'll see you tonight.
Mrs. Bellamy, is it?
I'm Dr. Granville, Dr. Dalrymple's
new associate. Good morning.
Very pleased to meet you, Doctor.
- You've been here before?
- Yes.
So you are aware of the procedure?
Indeed.
Going well?
Yes, quite. Thank you.
As I said before, I'm leaving you
in very good hands, Mrs. Bellamy.
Oh..hahaha...
Thank you, Doctor.
Good day.
Shall we begin?
Sorry about that.
- You alright, Doctor?
- Yes, quite. Thank you.
Here we go, then.
Please let me know
if anything is uncomfortable.
That's very nice, Doctor. Thank you.
Very nice, indeed.
Can't you understand?
It's an emergency.
The situation is desperate.
It's completely impossible, madame.
I'll do anything.
Mille grazie.
You are very welcome, signora.
Next.
You know, they're turning
patients away.
Really? I hadn't noticed.
It's all because of you.
These may be broken.
Something wrong with your hand?
Just a twinge.
Allow me.
You seem to have settled in nicely,
Dr. Granville.
Now, you may have noticed that I'm
not getting any younger,
and with only two daughters,
I have no one
to carry on the practice.
I was wondering whether
you might like to consider
becoming a partner.
Father, that's a wonderful idea.
I...I'm speechless.
And, who knows, if things go well,
this practice may end up yours.
Since my dear wife Melodia,
passed away,
God rest her soul,
Emily has diligently and
professionally managed the household.
I've no doubt that one day
she would make a fine doctor's wife,
with that experience.
Lovely.
I do hope I'm not expected to stay
here until after supper everyday.
I'm very sorry, Miss Smalley. I'll
be on schedule tomorrow. I promise.
I do hope so.
Righto. Just in here.
We'll set you down.
Miss Dalrymple, what a surprise.
I'm afraid that your father isn't here.
Good.
Well, in that case I must tell you
that we work only to appointment.
Fannie has broken her ankle. I was
hoping to persuade you to treat it?
I'll have the fish 'n' chips.
That's the rum talking.
It's all I had to ease the pain.
Normally I don't recommend
extreme drunkenness,
but it's probably a
very good choice.
Let have a look at it.
I should tell you, we've no money.
Good night, Miss Smalley.
Oh... Good night.
- Let's take her inside.
- Thank you.
I'm not wearing any knickers.
Well, I'm sure it's
an honest mistake.
Want a look?
- What are these for?
- I'll explain later.
- There we go.
- Lie back.
Very good.
- Now, Fannie...
- Yes.
I want you to count to three for me.
Can you do that?
Yes, I think so.
One,
two,
Ow!
You said three! Bloody hell!
She's out, I think.
Forgive me. I wanted
her thoughts elsewhere.
I need some plaster
for her ankle.
I didn't know my father had any proper
medical supplies in here anymore.
Crimean War surplus, I imagine.
Is your hand alright?
A bit stiff actually.
Why are you so opposed
to your father?
My father.
You know, he's never been
to the settlement house.
I simply wish he helped people
like Fannie who really need it,
instead of the trivial
work he does here.
It's hardly trivial.
That one is a little bit sloppy.
Thank you, nurse.
I apologize.
Hysteria is a disabling condition
suffered by half the women in this city.
Keeps you busy, I see.
Does wonders for
disagreeable personalities.
Do you find me disagreeable?
I've only ever seen you shout
at people and slam doors.
At least I've got the
courage of my convictions.
And few friends, I would imagine?
Good.
Well, I'll need to see you
again in six weeks, Fannie,
to remove the cast.
Thank you, Doctor.
Yes, you've been a great help.
You're both very welcome.
If you ever get bored
of nervous housewives,
feel free to pay us a visit.
Hello, Mortimer.
Please, sit down.
Emily...
I've been... Oh, Emily...
I've been thinking.
Should things progress
as your father suggested,
and I one day
inherit the practice,
what would your
feelings be, about...
well, an arrangement?
Mortimer...
I should be honoured.
Most especially as it will
make father so happy.
Right... right.
Umm...
Oh, that's settled.
Duty first, as always, Emily.
Life is of little value unless
it be consecrated by duty.
Oh, quite, yes.
Granville.
A word?
I must insist that you give Charlotte
no further assistance of any sort.
It merely prolongs her relationship
with those people and that place.
The woman had a broken ankle.
Well, I admire your dedication, Doctor,
but we can't have day-labourers
traipsing through the office.
This is a very exclusive,
and, I might add, lucrative practice.
Appearances matter.
I have taken a solemn oath, sir.
I thought we had an
understanding, you and I,
about your future here.
That's the last of it, Miss.
Oh, Jack, thank you.
Now, then.
It's two hundred late today,
plus what's on account...
three, carry the one...
seven and six, I think.
Yes, that looks right.
May I pay you Friday next?
I'm sorry, miss,
but the gov was very clear.
Cash only, he said,
and get the balance.
Would you tell your employer,
that my father, Dr. Dalrymple,
has absolutely promised
a very large donation
to the settlement house
this coming Friday,
and I will bring him the money myself?
I'll make it stick, miss.
Nobody appreciates more
than me what you've done here.
My boy Frank says you're the
strawberries and the cream.
- Shush... Friday, then.
- Ta!
Mortimer, must you wear
that ghastly hand brace?
I must find some way to attend
to these women properly.
I believe the French have quite
a bit of luck using their tongues.
Please be serious.
We're speaking of my patients.
They need me.
Perhaps for the first time, I feel...
truly useful.
Aren't you a rainy day?
- Oh, don't worry, something will come along, simply...
- Oww!!
I wish I could
share your optimism.
Oh... Excuse me.
Just... just...
- Dr. Granville.
- Oh...
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I think so.
Thank you.
Are you quite finished, Doctor?
Edmund, this is Emily's
sister, Charlotte.
Charlotte Dalrymple,
Edmund St. John Smythe.
Oh, Edmund Smythe from the papers.
Overblown, I assure you.
I attended that party only as
a favour to a dear friend,
and I can swear that I never met
that horse before in my life.
Sounds as if you had a jolly good time.
Well, actually I did, rather.
What brings you
to the West End, Miss Dalrymple?
Begging for money,
unsuccessfully 'til now.
Ah, yes. Miss Dalrymple runs a
settlement house in the East End.
How fascinating.
I must be going.
Oh, it seems that
your hand is no better.
It must be difficult pleasuring
half the women in the city.
Madame, pleasure has nothing
to do with it. I can assure you.
Well, I suppose that depends on whether
you're over the table or on it.
Bye!
Isn't she a Chinese firecracker?
You know how much we admire
your spirit, Charlotte,
and we're lifelong
friends of your father,
but this element you work with
are nothing more than
the draught horses of society.
I don't see how charity will help.
If not charity, perhaps a loan.
A loan? How much?
Two hundred pounds.
Generally, a loan has
some security, dear.
They were my mother's.
They should cover the balance and more.
We will give you two hundred
pounds at eight percent interest.
Thank you.
Now I want you to be sure you understand
this is strictly business, Charlotte.
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
We won't hesitate to collect.
I understand.
Thank you.
Mr. Huddleston.
Thank you. Thank you for your
time and your generosity...
Mrs. Huddleston, thank you.
It means a great deal
to so many people.
Thank you! Thank you!
Scandalous.
Hello?
Dr. Granville.
Trawling for patients?
I'm afraid you'll find no
cases of hysteria here.
Women are all too busy trying
to find enough to eat.
Ah, Miss Dalrymple.
Always speaking out of turn.
No. I came to enquire about
Miss Fannie's broken ankle.
A house call?
Surely there's no harm in
following up with a patient?
None at all.
No pain?
No. Nothing.
I was going to take her
to see you on Friday.
There's no bother.
I was in the neighbourhood.
I was...
I was near the neighbourhood.
- How's that feel?
- Fine. Thank you, Doctor.
Would you like a cup of tea, Doctor?
Oh, no, thank you.
Dr. Granville, it's
the least we can offer.
Yes, alright, then.
A cup of tea would be lovely.
- Take it easy on that for a few days.
- Yes, Doctor.
Very good. I won't be a moment.
You can wait just through there.
Hello.
Hang on.
Just getting to the good bit.
Thank you. I wouldn't
have been able to sleep,
without knowing how
that turned out.
- Milk, Doctor?
- Please.
We use this room
mostly as a nursery.
We do fit in the odd
bit of teaching, now and then.
Promoting some aggressive
political agenda, no doubt.
Sums and letters mostly.
Occasionally, we sneak in
something slightly progressive.
Oh, you might like this.
Actually, look. For example,
this is where
the children wash their hands.
We use soap and boiled water.
We do our best to keep
the settlement sanitary,
but, you can't imagine
the filth and the germs.
You know about germs?
I do read, Doctor.
I spent years trying to convince
the medical establishment
that hand-washing
prevents disease,
unsuccessfully, and then here you
are teaching it to the children.
And with great success.
I know. With the parents
it's another story,
but, eventually, the children
will teach them themselves.
Bravo.
For the women, we're
trying to provide services
that will offer the
most direct result:
Good hot meal. Safe place for
their children and communal laundry.
I think that if we can ease
their work-load a bit,
we could get on to the important
work of changing their minds.
You, Madame, are a socialist.
A socialist?
What if I am?
Are there not eight oarsmen and crew?
Socialism, at its heart,
is nothing more than
a group pulling together.
If women pulled together,
if they weren't so frightened,
there's no telling what
we could accomplish.
And this revolution that you're planning,
will you achieve it all from here?
Drop a stone in a pond,
and it will make ripples.
It is a bit like a pond. It is true. I noticed.
- Yes.
The building adjacent,
and the one behind, are both
for sale for two thousand pounds.
Put them together, and we're
not just a classroom and a kitchen.
We're a centre for the
neighbourhood, with a garden,
a proper school;
maybe even a medical clinic.
Two thousand pounds is aiming
quite high, don't you think?
No, I don't think so.
I know, by the time I'm gone,
women will have the vote,
they'll have equal education
and rights over their own bodies,
and I'd like to play some small
part in making that happen.
Absolutely, and then,
you should teach them how to fly.
I would.
You just wait and see, Doctor.
I'd like to see your face.
Your passion, your devotion
to this work is admirable.
Honestly,
I get much more
out of it than they do.
They only get food and laundry,
and I'm given a useful life,
and I set my own hours.
You know,
I could really use the help of
an able doctor on a more regular basis.
Broken ankles are the least of it.
All the children suffer from
malnutrition, rickets, scurvy,
even cholera and typhus.
All preventable, as you know,
with knowledge and resources.
I'm afraid my patients
keep me very busy.
I only mean...
I only mean a weekend a month.
I don't believe
I would have the time.
Or even a few hours on a Sunday.
Anything would help.
I'm sorry.
- Please. Please.
- Miss Dalrymple.
I'm afraid I can't help.
You can't,
or you won't?
It's a bit more complex than that.
I know, I know. It's...
It's my father.
He wouldn't allow it, would he?
Is that why you came here?
To keep me from bringing Fannie
back to his posh little practice?
Thank you for the tea.
Run along, Doctor. Back to your...
silly, comfortable life.
Mrs. Castellari, Doctor.
- Send her in, Nurse.
- Mrs. Castellari?
Mrs. Castellari, how are you?
Sad, Dottore.
Very sad today.
Good, good.
Lie back, please.
Aii!!!
Your hand is so cold, Dottore.
I'm so sorry, Mrs. Castellari.
I forgot.
Yes.
Is that better?
I think that's enough
for today, Dottore.
Feeling better, then?
Mrs. Castellari!
I assure you Mrs. Castellari,
this has never happened to me before.
You have discredited
my entire practice.
I'm very sorry.
Sorry will hardly suffice.
Your disability is clearly far more
serious than you led me to believe.
Mrs. Castellari tells me you failed
to complete the treatment,
and now,
I discovered that Mrs. Parsons
has stopped coming altogether.
If you could only see your way
towards giving me one more chance,
I can assure you...
No.
I thought you were someone
I could trust,
with my business, my family,
my reputation,
but, clearly I was mistaken.
You're dismissed.
- Doctor...
- Dismissed!
I'm terribly sorry.
I'm finished, Edmund.
Completely buggered.
I had the perfect life within
reach, and I lost it.
All due to hand cramps.
God!
Someone is telephoning!
Ahoy!
I didn't know you had a telephone.
I'm very, very flattered. Yeah.
Oh, yes, indeed.
I'm in my studio. Studio!
My God!
No, I'm inventing a new cleaning tool.
Yes. Very good.
Yes.
Well, yes, do that. Stay...
Got to rush, actually, now.
Goodbye.
Don't stop.
I think you're enjoying
yourself too much.
It makes your hand feel all...
all warm and tingly.
I feel it right down to the bone.
Oh, really?
Turn it back on.
Please.
That's bloody marvelous!
Well, that's what I call
good, steady pressure!
Does it go any higher?
Go on!
That's it! That's the spot!
My feathers!
That is the spot, indeed!
Bugger.
Do you smell burning?
But, you said yourself that you could feel
the vibration deep inside your hand.
I know what I said,
but this is crude,
and rough, and inexact,
and nothing at all like
the motion and pressure that I use.
Well, it didn't seem that much at the time.
Well, I grant you.
If this works,
it could put you back in good
standing with Dr. Dalrymple and Emily.
Edmund, let me be perfectly
clear about this.
We are not going to take
a dangerous, explosive, and
untried electrical device
and press it against
a lady's most gentle areas.
That's it, then.
I believe I shall regret this
to the very end of my days.
Now, who should we try it on?
Ordinarily, for five pounds, I
wouldn't ask questions.
That's with a man.
This is a different kettle of fish.
I don't believe it will involve
any pain, but if it does,
we will stop immediately.
Think of it this way, Molly.
For one brief moment, you can be
a pioneer of technology,
a voyage of the British Empire,
and, quite possibly, the
vanguard of modern medical science.
And we pay up front.
Why not?
Ol.
Do your worst.
- Ooh!
- Are you hurt?
No.
No, it just gave me a fright, that's all.
Never felt nothing like that before.
Shall I stop?
No, no. We'll try again.
I'll be ready this time.
Oh, right there, love.
Oh, that's lovely.
How do you feel, Molly?
Bloody marvellous. How do you think?
Would you say you had a paroxysm?
I'd say I had three from counting, boy.
It got a bit muddy in the middle.
It's astonishing.
What you call that little thing?
Well, I was calling
it the feather duster.
Well, then, think
of something quick,
so a girl knows what to ask for.
Horsefeathers.
I give you my word
as a gentleman, sir.
Three paroxysms in five minutes.
No harm came to the girl?
She was completely satisfied
with the result.
Yes, well, I can hardly take
the word of a trollop.
That's why we must try it here.
Medical science demands
a thorough investigation,
and what better place to
start than with these women,
whom we know suffer
so from hysteria?
Yes, well, in my opinion,
change is rarely beneficial.
I believe we are on the verge
of something revolutionary, sir.
If we achieve half
as much of your patients,
all credit goes to you.
Not just money, fame.
Three paroxysms
in five minutes, you say?
Very well.
One test case,
but if she comes to harm,
on your head be it.
The Rubby-Nubby.
- The Vibratorium.
Jiggly-Wiggly?
- Paroxysmator.
Oh! The Sorcerer's Apprentice.
- The Excitetator.
- Mr. Wobble-neck.
What about "The Squealer"?
You're going to need
a bigger appointment book.
Electric massage?
I don't know.
I have full confidence that the
machine will equal, if not better,
any treatment you've had before,
and, since you were so
unsatisfied last time,
I'm prepared to offer
you this gratis.
I'll trust you, Dottore.
This is Mr. Edmund St...
That is, my electrical assistant.
He'll be attending, as well,
if that's alright?
It's a little surprising at first,
Mrs. Castellari, but don't be alarmed,
you'll soon get used to it.
Everything all right,
Mrs. Castellari?
Bravo!
Well done.
So, don't forget to chain the gate,
and, oh, I left a candle
lit in the kitchen.
Go, and have a lovely evening.
Do you know? I think I will.
Bye.
Dr. Mortimer Granville.
Oh, I'm sorry. We're closing.
Get her out of there.
Two hundred pounds, plus interest,
or we lock the gate.
But I don't have it!
Right. I'm locking the gate.
Get of me!
- No doubt, you're the luckiest man in all of London.
- Miss Dalrymple.
Miss Charlotte Dalrymple.
Will you excuse me, ladies?
Miss Dalrymple.
Dr. Granville, good evening.
Congratulations. I'm sure you'll
make my sister very happy.
Something wrong?
No, no.
I just never seen you so...
Formally attired?
I was going to say...
clean.
Dr. Granville, I can assure you
that women enjoy physical pleasure
just as much as men,
even if it can be
long to come by.
Physical pleasure has
nothing to do with it.
It is strictly a medical treatment
that stimulates the nervous system.
Indeed it does, and it's
a bargain at a guinea,
but my point is,
according to your diagnosis,
hysteria seems to cover everything,
from insomnia to toothache.
- It's not my...
- It's nothing more than a catch-all
for dissatisfied women.
Women, forced to spend
their lives on domestic chores,
and their prudish and
selfish husbands who are unwilling
or unable to make love to them
properly, or often enough.
You seem to have strong opinions on
husbands for a woman who doesn't have one.
Look, if you don't believe me,
ask your patients.
Faintly ironic, don't you think,
to use my engagement party
as an opportunity to deliver
your opinion on marriage?
Yes, yes, and I apologize
for that, but you must admit,
you men really did get the
best side of the bargain.
Bargain?
For us, it's mindless housework
and doting on some halfwit.
You can make some halfwit very happy.
It's simply not enough for me,
or for most women.
Would it be enough for you?
Oh, I'm not most women.
Won't you be lonely?
I would take a partner,
an equal,
but, not for me a life of darning
socks, and doing chores
until my mental faculties
become Sunday pudding.
Does someone say Sunday pudding?
Lord and Lady St. John Smythe,
may I present Miss Dalrymple.
Miss Dalrymple, my guardians.
Lord and Lady St. John Smythe.
Charlotte "Sunday pudding" Dalrymple.
So pleased to meet you, my dear.
I love a good Sunday pudding.
We cannot be happier
for you, Mortimer.
You make us proud
each and every day.
Thank you.
What lovely earrings.
Oh, thank you. They were my mother's.
And will your mother be
joining us this evening?
No, my mother is, in
fact, dead, my Lord.
I trust we didn't waste
an invitation on her.
What about your father?
Will he be here or
is he dead, as well?
No, my father is quite well,
thank you.
I've not seen him, but I'm sure
he'll be here soon.
Oh, hurry up. Damn you.
Get a move on!
Don't want to keep the love of
your life waiting, my dear.
A toast to the happy couple.
You'll soon find that the key
to a happy marriage
- is the ability to enjoy a good argument.
- Yes.
Do remember to let him win
once in a while, my dear.
Oh... Oh... no, no.
There's a misunderstanding.
I would rather marry Edmund
than Dr. Granville.
Marry Edmund?
By Jove, she's a live one.
Who is this man?
That's my father.
I thought he was dead.
May I present,
Dr. Robert Dalrymple.
My Lord.
And this is my fiance,
Emily Dalrymple.
Fiance? But I thought...
Never mind, dear.
- How very nice to meet you, Doctor.
- My Lady
Miss Dalrymple.
I do apologize for being so late.
That's quite alright.
Your hair is most
adventurous, Emily.
Oh, do you think so?
It took ever so long
to get it up there.
Shall we do the once-around?
- Oh, yes!
- Excuse us.
Port, Doctor?
Delightful.
And tell me how you met
our young Mortimer.
Lovely party.
Yes. Yes, it is.
What are your interests?
Music, I enjoy reading,
- Phrenology.
- My!
Mortimer was so modest.
He failed to tell us how widely
accomplished you are.
Phrenology is a treasure
map to the personality,
if one is properly trained.
We are licensing this machine
to doctors all over London.
For a very generous royalty,
of course.
I despise business.
So do I.
Oh, Mr. And Mrs. Huddleston!
Come, let me introduce you.
Good evening, Mr. Huddleston.
Mrs. Huddleston,
do you know Dr. Granville?
Not personally.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Charmed.
Looks as though you are going to be
getting these earrings, after all.
You'll have to excuse us.
I'm sorry.
That was a little odd.
These earrings are security against
a loan for the settlement house
which is due tomorrow.
So this is my last
night with them.
They were your mother's.
Yes, they were.
You do what you must.
I'm sure she would have approved.
Bugger.
Throughout history,
great English families
have gathered in halls such as these,
to celebrate the impending nuptials...
Lord save us.
- Charlotte! Miss Charlotte!
- Stop! You can't go in there!
Arrest her!
Tell me! What happened?
They came for the money.
I told them that I didn't have it...
Mr. Huddleston, what's the meaning of this?
You gave us until Monday.
I no longer hold the note, Charlotte.
Your father does.
Father?
Charlotte, calm down.
I'm simply doing what's best for you.
What are you doing?
I purchased the note
from Mr. Huddleston,
and I'm closing down the settlement house.
You no longer have any debt...
These are the actions of a villain.
- Charlotte.
- Of a villain!
This is your sister's
engagement party.
Party? She's bruised and bleeding.
You want me to consider a party?
Make way, please.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Coming through.
- Leave her.
- This is a private party.
Do not manhandle her!
Let me handle this.
We've got this under control.
I'm a doctor. I believe
this woman needs medical attention.
I don't know that, sir, but I
do know she's not staying.
I haven't done anything wrong.
Please stop. She's hurt.
Please, Charlotte!
If we could just discuss
this like civilized men.
Let me by!
I said, let me by!
Damn!
Did I miss something?
I would never have imagined
it would come to this.
But we have to help her.
I've done nothing but, Emily.
I've tried indulging her.
I've tried a firm hand.
I'm at my wit's end.
Mortimer.
Please, she's my sister.
What would you have me do?
You must testify on her behalf.
- And say what?
- The truth.
That she's hysterical.
Sir, they will send her
to a sanatorium.
That is the only thing that
will keep her out of prison.
Order!
This court will come to order.
The facts are these, Your Honour.
One fortnight ago,
the defendant, Charlotte Dalrymple,
in full view of witnesses,
assaulted a police constable
carrying out his duty.
If this were a first offense,
then a short prison sentence
might suffice, but
this isn't a first offence,
is it, Miss Dalrymple?
You were arrested last April
on public nuisance,
and resisting arrest.
Your Honour, I was handing out
suffragette leaflets
in Trafalgar Square
when two officers arrested me.
The officers' sworn statements read:
"Miss Dalrymple was asked
to leave the square,
whereupon she started
to shout and jump about."
"When finally we did try
to place her in handcuffs,
she resisted most violently."
No. That is not true.
You will speak only when
questioned, Miss Dalrymple.
Well, how am I to defend myself against
his accusation if you won't let me speak?
Is there more?
I'm afraid there is, Your Honour.
October 1879, solicitation.
No, that was not me.
My friend, Molly,
she is a prostitute.
She was a prostitute.
She has since found
gainful employment,
as a maid, in my father's house.
Anything else, Mr. Squyers?
No, Your Honour.
No? Nothing else?
What's of the crime
of charity and compassion?
Very admirable I'm sure.
It seems that this help
included prostitution,
resisting arrest, and
assaulting police officers.
One could only imagine
the cost to England,
should we extend a university
education to all her women.
Yes, it's very easy, isn't it,
to make fun of women's lives?
I would like to see you walk
for one mile in our shoes.
I imagine that your
mirth would turn first
to sympathy and then to despair.
Careful, Miss Dalrymple.
Your symptoms are showing.
Until England fully recognizes
the worth and contributions of women,
will she be anything other
than a second-class country
despite all her wealth.
That's enough, Miss Dalrymple.
Your Honour, Charlotte
Dalrymple clearly suffers from
erratic, aggressive,
and violent emotions
that are best described
as incurable hysteria.
To buttress my opinion,
I would like to call
an expert witness, Your Honour.
Proceed, Mr. Squyers.
I would like to call
Dr. Mortimer Granville,
if it please the court.
Mortimer Granville, please.
Dr. Mortimer Granville.
Your Honour.
The evidence you shall give
shall be the truth,
the whole truth, and nothing
but the truth, so help you, God?
It will.
State your name.
Mortimer Granville.
Now, I'm sure we all, are well aware
of your celebrity, Doctor.
But, if you wouldn't
mind just telling us
a little of your
professional experience.
I'm a medical doctor
whose practice consists
of treating women
diagnosed with hysteria.
And in this capacity, how
many women have you treated?
Hundreds, certainly.
And always good results, I trust?
we've had few complaints of late.
Is it true, Dr. Granville, that
incurable cases of hysteria
demand institutionalization
and surgical hysterectomy?
Please answer the question,
Dr. Granville.
Well, yes.
Traditionally, yes,
but only in the most severe,
most persistent cases.
Thank you, Doctor.
We have already addressed the...
the persistence of Miss
Dalrymple's problem.
Now, in your professional opinion, Doctor,
as an expert in the field of hysteria,
how would you describe
Miss Dalrymple's behaviour?
Without a doubt,
Charlotte Dalrymple is...
erratic,
and volatile,
and, at times, physically aggressive.
She is also the most vexing
woman I have ever met.
Thank you, Doctor.
Your Honour, based on this evidence,
I find that I must recommend
that Charlotte
Dalrymple be remanded
to the Chelmsford Institute
for the Criminally Insane,
with a further recommendation
for immediate surgical hysterectomy.
I wasn't quite finished.
Miss Dalrymple is also
the most generous, compassionate,
selfless, and truly Christian
woman that I have ever met.
Doctor, you have just sworn
that she is erratic,
volatile,
even physically aggressive.
Would you not characterize
that as hysterical?
Well, you see,
after consulting with my patients
and considerable reflection,
it is my professional opinion
that hysteria is a fiction.
It's nothing but a...
a catch-all diagnosis
for women without opportunity,
forced to spend their life
tending to domestic chores
and selfish, prudish
husbands who are
unwilling or unable
to make love to them properly.
Or often enough.
I beg your pardon, Doctor...
Your Honour,
the constable suffered
no grave injury,
but great harm may still be done
if Miss Dalrymple is
locked away and butchered,
and England will lose a devoted
and singular woman
she can ill afford to spare.
I grant you, there may
not be room in the world
for more than
one Charlotte Dalrymple.
Fortunately for all of us,
I think they must have
broken the mould.
In the case of Charlotte Dalrymple,
there are no easy answers.
Mr. Squyers,
I find your case for hysteria
wanting.
By your reasoning,
we should lock up every female in
the whimsy in logic
collide, which would
suggest to me most of
the women in England.
My wife included.
On the other matter, however,
I am loathe to offer
precedent where
a policeman's safety
is concerned.
Miss Dalrymple,
for striking a police officer
in the course of his duty,
I sentence you to
thirty days in prison,
and I admonish you
to think most carefully, and act
most cautiously in the future.
Take her.
Miss Dalrymple.
Dr. Granville.
I suppose I now owe you my uterus.
That's an interesting offer.
Something to meditate on while
I consider a new career.
Mortimer Granville, you are a good
doctor, and you should remain one,
instead of leeching and bleeding
people, and cutting them up to no purpose.
You have invented a machine
that does harm to no one,
and makes anyone had comes into
contact with it feel better.
I should think there are
very few doctors in history
that could lay claim to
such an accomplishment.
Come on, miss.
You are a confounding woman.
You're all fire and
brimstone one minute,
compliments and common
sense the next.
I am a woman like any other.
No, no. You're quite unlike
any women I've ever met.
Will you be alright?
I'm fine. I've got
lots of friends in prison.
Mortimer.
I thought I might find you here.
I've been thinking
a lot about my future.
And, well, actually,
I was wondering if you might
give me a reading.
I'm sorry. I've giving up phrenology.
Oh, Emily, I'm...
I'm so sorry.
Don't be.
Charlotte's trial was
a revelation for me as well.
I realized I haven't been
living my life at all.
I've been living my father's
idea of what my life should be
Phrenology, Chopin,
even you, Mortimer.
You seem happy.
I am.
After all, life will always
be, to a large extent,
what we ourselves make it.
The inimitable Mr. Smiles.
I shall miss him.
And I shall miss you.
God, you're naughty.
I should never send you anything.
No, no. Not even for Christmas.
You must go out and
purchase one for yourself.
God bless you, Mum.
It is a clever old woman who can
keep up with today's technology.
Alright, then.
Lovely chatting to you.
Ring me anytime.
Goodbye.
Any prospects?
No, my name is mud.
Open this.
I told you before,
I don't want your money.
It's not my money, it's yours.
It's your share of the royalties
from our manufacturers.
The portable electric massager.
The portable electric massager?
Yes, I told you I was working
on something rather exciting.
You see, I made a very small motor,
and it seemed to go really well,
so I showed it to a few firms,
and they simply adored it,
and apparently,
they're selling it directly
to women for home use.
I really have to admit, I never
thought it would go so high,
but, it is a rather ingenious
device, even if I say so myself.
Don't you understand, Mortimer?
You have your fortune now.
You can have anything you want.
Miss Dalrymple.
Dr. Granville.
Hello.
Merry Christmas.
I realize it's a day early, but
I thought you might need it.
I don't know what to say.
Apparently, there is
a first time for everything.
Right.
Oh...
Yes!
May I?
That's lovely.
Oh, that's very kind.
Oh, there's something more.
Think of it as a "getting
out of prison" present.
You once said that with two thousand
pounds, you could change the world.
You're not serious?
Apparently, I'm rich,
and the buildings are yet for sale.
Well, I'm not too late, am I?
You are still interested?
Yes, of course.
More than ever.
Although, I should think
by the time I finished,
a few thousand pounds will
not be nearly enough.
Are you never satisfied, woman?
It might be enough for a clinic.
A clinic?
Would it pay well?
I'm afraid not.
Would the cases be interesting?
Routine, I should think.
Broken bones,
sick children,
needy women.
Sounds revolting.
Perhaps something else.
Perhaps something there.
I wondered if you might
have an opening
for a partner, for an equal,
in a joint venture?
Mortimer, if you think...
Oh, damn it!
Charlotte Dalrymple,
I love you.
Will you marry me?
Please don't make me beg.
Not in the street.
I'll need to kiss you first.
Charlotte, I hardly think
that in the circumstance...
- Did you like it?
- Yes, it was rather nice, actually.
Yourself?
Not bad.
You'll get better.
Who would have thought?
Charlotte and Mortimer, together.
Life often brings together
strange bedfellows.
Yes, quite. Quite.
Well, all's well that ends well.
Ah, fresh air and perambulation.
The key to mental accuity
and long life.
If you say so, Doctor.
Oh, look: ducks.
You alright down there, Colonel?
Patience, Eugenia. Patience.
The empire was not
built in a day.
That's very cagey of you.
What are you wearing?
THE JOLLY MOLLY PORTABLE MASSAGER
WILL POSITIVELY CURE:
BLOOD CIRCULATION PROBLEMS,
MONTHLY DISCOMFORT, THE VAPOURS,
HYSTERIA
***subtitles by youwish@subscene.com***
***Please don't use without credit***