Mother
Have you washed your hair?
Always trying to be Elvis,
Yeah, just fooling around,
don't tease me!
Do you like the kite? Ellen
Take a look! Ellen!
Hey man!
You got the wrong guy,
my husband's innocent!
Frank! Still pissing around?
I'll kill you
Told you to watch out for cops!
And now your dad got arrested!
Mom!
I'm your son!
Dad, quit this sweeping job
When I get a job, you can...
Its destiny, I'm a nobody, its okay
But my son won't be sweeping streets
It's a cruel world, money talks
Without it you're shit!
Remember!
If you get a break, hang on in there!
Workers, joint our strike!
Against oppression, act now
Fight for equality
Come on!
Put a few more up here
Here comes prince Charming, no wonder
Ben
Here for Jane
Treat her well, or you'll regret it
Here's an orange to shut you up!
Don't go, don't go
You too! Work okay?
It's okay!
What the hell? It's sour!
Bastard! Get lost!
Hey stop it!
Wash up those glasses! So slow!
Hey! Watch out!
Hey! What's up!
Hong Kong sucks!
We'll get nowhere in this place
Must go somewhere
I don't want to be a nobody
for the rest of my life
Wherever you go,
count us in!
Yeah, we're just like windflower
Settle down in wherever the wind takes
we're all orphans here
One day, I'll come back in a Mercedes
Let's not wait,
we'll go drive a Mercedes now
Who lose, who treat!
It is a deal!
You'll lose!
You're gonna lose, Paul!
No way, I'm winning!
Don't fall in the sea. Frank!
That's you who will fall
You watch out!
Frank, go get it!
Hang on
Cut the crap, help me up
Punk fell in the gutter...
His girl's gonna cry
His body's so stinky,
she doesn't find it kinky
Smells like ammonia
He's mad that he fell - ah
Gutter smells isn't so swell
The riot is worsening, I'm afraid
I wonder what the future would be like
Let's get married
We're poor. How can we have money
for our wedding?
Poor can marry
No matter what the future would like
Just want to be a bird
And be free to fly around
Go places, see the world
I know there are great
places out there!
I want you to come too
Are you dreaming?
It's not a dream!
It's my ambition!
Many people don't even have that
Pay respect to your in-laws
Ben, mind the knees!
Make room, the bride's here!
Going down, careful
Paul, be careful, mind the shit!
You're great! In this situation...
your wedding is more incredible than
the wedding of third uncle
Don't say that
Frank
What are you doing here?
Is the banquet money okay?
No problem, trust me,
don't worry!
Are you sure?
No problem! Get inside
Frank, remember to change
out of the shit
To inside, go on!
Try and get there early!
Cheers!
Thanks for coming,
help yourselves, drink up
Take photo
The bride and groom, photo time
Mr Kwai, take a seat
Is the money okay?
Your guarantee?
You sure you can repay?
No problem!
I swear with my life!
Right! I trust you
Thanks Mr Kwai
What time is it?
Ten thirty!
Thanks!
Frankie baby
Ringo
You're on my turf!
Really? Sorry, sorry man
Let me through, it's important, please
Son of a bitch
Punk
I know you've been to see Kwai
Give me the cash
That's enough. Ringo
You've made a fool out of me,
if you want more
We'll fight again one day!
But this money is staying with me!
Shithead, you got no choice
No... You can't
No? Come on
Bastard
Give it back
You bastard
Drink up
Mr Shing, show me how to make a buck
You gotta take risks!
Take my word for it
The more chaos, the easier the cash
Vietnam's at war,
there's no law and order
Smuggling, drugs,
anything goes to make a buck
Lots of millionaires started this way
What's bugging you!
Frank's not here,
hope nothing's wrong!
Don't worry, he's always like this
Thanks for coming
Thank you!
Hey, Frank
Here comes Mighty Mouse, Ben, Ben!
You're late, everyone's going!
Scared you shitless, Huh?
Only if you didn't show up!
You can trust me man
The boss is getting impatient, got it?
Yeah, let's go!
Have a drink!
Here's your money, thanks
This drink's been waiting for you
Let's wait for Paul!
Yeah!
Paul!
Exactly three thousand
two hundred plus tips
This one's for you!
It's your wedding, drink to the fool
Let's see the bride
Yeah the bride!
What happened?
Nothing what?
Oh that? Fell in the gutter
I was rushing, fell down!
In a gutter?
Yeah, yeah, Punk in the gutter
His girl's gonna cry
You're terrible
Smelly like stale fish
And his girl's gonna fry
Hey, as your pal, can I kiss the bride?
Come on,
It's late, move!
No sweat, only her hand, she's safe
He's really coming!
Congratulations, all the best
Don't let him kiss you!
I've asked Ben, he said your hand's okay
Right Ben?
Jane, don't let him!
The bastard!
He cheated, he kissed my face!
Guys, stop that
Shut up! You guys are always the boss
What's this boss crap?
We're all just trying to make a buck
We're buddies right?
And buddies are all equal
Punk, spineless worm, piss off!
You got me arrested,
you only know how to fight
Got beaten again
Dad, forget it!
Please making a sense!
So what?
Bastard!
You good for nothing!
Just piss off, don't come back!
Scram!
Get lost!
I don't care! You're not my son!
It's you? What's the matter?
What happened to your head?
Nothing! I fell in a gutter
It's nothing! Only a bit of blood
I'm used to getting beaten up by mom
Nothing new!
Hey
You crazy?
If it's only bruised, it won't hurt so much
You've been bleeding all night,
it must hurt
Now will you tell me who did it?
Ringo
He wanted to take it
I wouldn't let him, so he did this
With what?
A glass bottle
Hey! What are you doing?
Give to the poor, thank you
Okay? Go on!
What are you doing? Stop?
Stop! Get him!
Stop!
Ringo!
Did Frank cross you?
He made me mad!
Go to hell!
Die, die!
Ben...Ben...
Paul, open up!
What happened?
We killed Ringo!
What now?
I don't know, run I guess
Wait a second
Sorry
I really got you screwed,
and Jane too
We owe you so much
Is Ben there?
What's the matter?
He's wanted for murder,
we're looking for him
Ben, Frank, Paul!
Fatso!
I brought you lots of food
Were you followed
No, I was smart this time, here, bread
Change your clothes, change your look,
then no one will recognize you both
Lots of people on your back!
The police, Ringo's boys
And Mr Kwai's out for you Frank
Yeah?
How's Jane?
She's okay, the cops talked to her,
she's scared!
Don't worry,
I'll look after her
I got your passports
Thanks Mr Shing
I've got a friend called Luke over there
He'd help you to solve problem
Take these two boxes of penicillin,
Rolexes
and medicine
To the Saigon coast,
hand it to Mr Y. S. Leong
No tricks,
he's dangerous
I got it, Shing
Overthrow the government, we want liberty
Overthrow the Capitalism;
long live to Communism
Overthrow the British government,
we want liberty
Come back, Jane
It's dangerous. Riot outside. Come back
Be careful
Jane
What are you doing here, go
I want to talk to you!
I don't want to hear!
It is dangerous here, follow me!
Let's go
Feel hard!?
Run,
or you'll be recognized by the police
I have to leave Hong Kong for a while
You do whatever you want to do, as usual
You even killed somebody
in the wedding night
Don't worry, Jane
I'll be back to take you away
Forget it, everywhere is the same
The future cannot be foreseen, God knows
Anyway I'll take care of myself
Take care
No matter what,
the goods come first
It's over lifeline
It's so peaceful,
don't seem to be at war
Who gives a shit, war's their problem
They're killing Vietnamese,
nothing to do with us
We're here to get rich!
Then move on to Thailand!
Will we make it?
No sweat! Smugglers,
they're all millionaires
With a new place there's new hope
And this is our new hope
Guess how I'm gonna spent
my first million!
Buy yourself a Mercedes!
That's obvious!
Dummy! Would I risk my life my
life for a pissing Mercedes?
Either I don't go back,
if I do, I go back loaded!
If I make a fortune, first
I'd buy my mom loads
of embroidered slippers
Then she can't hit me
with her wooden clogs!
I only want to go back for Jane
Then I'll get you your ticket!
You're funny
Wow! What a scene!
Hey! What's a happening
Get out!
Why?
Bomb!
Explosives!
Grab the goods!
Forget it!
Come on! Let's run!
My stuff, Oh no! It's over!
Run!
Officer, run! Run!
Forget it! Let's split! Run!
Don't shoot... Don't shoot!
Don't fire! Don't fire!
Take them away
Run! Let's go! Quickly
Don't be scared! Go in quickly!
Move! Shut the gate! No reporters!
No! I'm Chinese, Chinese!
Move over, over there!
Down! Kneel down!
Look up! Was it you?
Did you plant the bomb?
No!
Denying huh?
It's not him... Look up!
If he gets it wrong, we're in hell!
I won't let him shoot me!
It's gonna be okay!
We're not local!
Shut up! No talking! Don't move!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot...
Did you plant the bomb? Speak up!
No! Sir, I don't!
Look up!
Sir, I'm from Hong Kong!
No! No! I'm from Hong Kong!
No! No Sir, I'm from Hong Kong!
HK people!
We are Chinese...please...
Please! Don't shoot!
Come out!
Are you okay?
We wanna take some pictures
Who are your accomplices?
Pig
Why can't we go in and take pictures?
Move on! No photos!
Bastard! Who's behind it? Come on talk!
Tell me where your
accomplices are hiding?
We have the right to know!
Scram! You can't go inside!
Bastard! So you won't talk!
Right? Well, die!
Go inside!
In our business,
we can't be running scared
With a gun in our hands,
this world is ours
How to say?
Bolero
Hey! Come in
It's the first time I've been
in a place like this!
Well, time to open your mind!
Great!
Get off...get off!
Excuse me! You...aren't you...
Go! Go!
Hi, John!
Hi, Lieu. Nguyen, Lieu. Ko
You should take Mr. Leong as an example!
He's really a big shot,
his nose is in the air!
How come Hong Kong singer is here?
Excuse me, I want...
Are you from Hong Kong?
You're Chinese? Great!
You know a guy called Luke?
I'd like to talk to him!
Hey! That Frenchman?
Is he a foreigner?
He's a Eurasian. Take a seat!
If he knows his friends are coming,
he will look for you!
Thanks!
Oh no...!
Be good!
Mr. Leong, would you please ask
them to behave themselves!
I'm here just to drink with them,
no hanky-panky!
I'm sure you're used to
being caressed by strangers
Are you Sally?
Any problem?
There are tons of girls like her!
Oh my god!
Can I be of any help to you?
Why should you help me?
Because we are Chinese!
Wait for me at the bridge tomorrow!
Promise to come. It's a deal!
Shit, I've got to go!
I told you not to talk to strangers,
go back to your seat!
You're looking for me?
Are you Luke?
I'm so happy to see you!
Take a seat!
I'm tied up with something,
see you later!
Good night, my friend!
Good night!
Habana
Thank you!
Mr. Chan,
Our goods were being held up
by your customs earlier.
Mr. Leong, this goods is
so important to you!
Currently my boss wants
to visit the States
I'd like to buy him a return air-ticket
How much is the ticket?
U.S.$100,000!
So you're a greedy person!
Fine with me - U.S.$100,000!
Have you been waiting long?
It's alright!
Luke, let me introduce!
Have we met?
How are you!
What now? Anything I can help?
We were meant to bring some goods
and exchange with Mr. Leong
Unfortunately we ran into trouble,
everything's gone!
What now?
Get something out of Leong!
But this is not our original plan!
You want to be in jail in HK?
You want me to lead a dog's life forever?
I've forgotten I have a father
who is a sweeper!
What you want? Please don't!
Today I saw some soldiers killed people,
I learned something!
In this world, if you have guns,
you have everything!
Tell me how much does a human life cost?
I'm a bit worried you'll get involved!
Leong is so powerful because he's got weapons
I need gun!
I'm not sure it's right or wrong,
but anyway I'll try my best to help you
Wait! What is going on?
I want to prove something!
Two coke, please!
Two coke!
Yes!
$14
We have no money!
Why?
You must pay me!
Don't mess around!
Hurry up! Give me the money!
Don't do that, you'll hurt somebody!
Let's go!
Pay me right away!
Look, such an easy job!
He was scared to death!
Let's go, we'll be in deep shit
if the policemen's around
Give it to me! Hurry up, you bastard!
Please don't!
Give me the money to get lost!
Don't shoot...don't...!
Oh shit!
Let's go!
Get back! Shit, the soldiers are coming!
Don't shoot!
We get problem! Let's run!
Lie down...
I surrender! What?
Lie down
Oh! Lie down!
Get it! Let's go!
We get it!
Let's get in!
Wow, what a fucking world!
This is really a fucked up world!
You got big robbery and
you get small money pincher
You scared?
Peace no war! Peace no war!
We want the governor respects
our peaceful desire
Stop the war, respect human rights
Peace. No war
Peace no war! Peace no war!
Stop!
Don't worry, Jane
I'll be back to take you away
Forget it, everywhere is the same
The future cannot
Be foreseen
I'm sure I cannot get away!
A year ago, Leong signed me up
to sing in this nightclub
He told me I will make a lot money!
At that time, I was only dreaming...
I arrived Saigon,
he held up my passport
And did not allow me to go away...
He even forced me to deal in drug,
trafficking, and made me a whore
I won't want to see you dead
You're my little money maker
In 10 years time you'll forget everything
Forget you been in Saigon
Forget you were a whore,
won't that be swell?
There's no one to help you?
Yes...
Please get me out of this shit, please...
We sneaked out to see the boats here
We wish one day we can get on one
of these boats and flee away
Let's go!
I want you to kill people only!
I did tell you to take her away
Don't worry! We traveled here by boat!
We'll traveled back by boat too!
Are you sure there will be guns?
Don't worry, just go by the plan
We gotta trust him
Yeah, that's what friends are for!
You need this stuff
I have a permanent supply,
just have to ask
This lot is better than that the last
Check it out!
Habana
Thanks Luke
Still the same song?
Yes!
This contains a list of names
and contacts of CIA agents
You'll make big money
selling guns to North Vietnam for us
Right, no problem,
we'll split the profits
Come in!
Hello, Luke!
Mr. Leong
He is my best friend, Ben
Frank
Mr. Leong
Paul
They're friends of Mr. Shing
Mr. Leong, nice to meet you
Mr. Leong
Well, the youth of today, huh!
Well, what do you have for me?
Penicillin
Great! The North needs that stuff
Check it out
It's okay!
I'll trust you if you're Luke's friends
Relax downstairs, have a drink,
It's okay! Drink and have fun
Help yourself
Go have a drink too
I won't, someone's waiting for me!
Still the Don Juan, huh?
I hope no one get killed
I don't give a damn
I'll kill anyone who gets in my way
Ben
I'm worried
Don't worry
Miss Yen, are you alright?
I like that song you sing Wind Flower
Will you sing it for me?
Windflower, flying in the wind
Sit down, how is it?
Had something to drink?
A bit
A bit isn't enough!
Come, get some more glasses
You're all gotta drink
Do you know her?
You Hong Kong boys are real Romeos!
Got your eyes on my girl
before the deals even done!
Mr. Leong, you got it wrong,
we didn't mean it
We just like her singing
I also heard, you wanted
to take her with you!
She's my trump card,
I spent a lot of time grooming her
Mr. Leong, you got it wrong
We already liked Sally
when we were in Hong Kong
Loved her singing
We were staring at her
because it was strange
She seemed to have changed!
She's not beautiful any more
Ben!
She's lost her innocence
She's not happy anymore
What sort of grooming is that?
Are you accusing me?
No one else dares to
talk to me like that!
Young man, you've got guts!
Bring the booze
Let's empty the bottle
I made the screw up, it's my fault!
I'll drink!
Right! Real buddies!
Since you're buddies,
all three of you drink!
Ben! What are you doing?
You call yourself our pal?
Don't let him step on us!
Aren't you being selfish?
What did you say?
You screwed up,
don't drag me into it!
I did that for all of us
Stop it!
What are you two fighting about?
You hit me?
Serves you bleeding right!
Ben!
You traitors!
Bastard
Watch over Ben
Old shithead! Pull him up!
Run!
Run! Quick!
Go back, quickly!
Let me go, let me go...
Don't come over!
Don't move! Or I'll kill him!
One step more and I'll shoot!
Help! Don't come over!
Kill them!
Let me go or you'll die!
Ben, where are you going?
Ben
Bitch! You're not going any where!
Sally!
Ben, Frank!
Help! Quick!
Don't move. Let me go
Sally, Sally
Will we make it?
Let's go now?
Watch out!
Are you guys crazy?
Stuck with this dame
Do you wanna get us killed?
I promised her I'd take her away
That's your dame business,
leave me out
Stop it Paul!
If we're still buddies
It's not important
Let's get the hell out first!
No way! You'll never leave!
Stop fighting!
Get down
The gold leaves, where is it?
Luke! Where is the gold?
Where's Sally's passport?
I don't know
You said it was here! Where's the gold?
In the safe
Where is Sally's passport?
You'll get it over my dead body
Where the hell is Sally's passport?
Speak up!
You'll have to kill me first!
I bet it's in the safe
Bastards! You won't get of here alive
Sally, don't worry
Ben will help you,
even without your passport
We could be refuges,
sneak over to Hong Kong
Sally
You see! I told you not to worry
We'll get back to Hong Kong, right?
Hey! Release Mr. Leong
Take your clothes off
Not Mr. Leong, he's our brother
Where's my passport?
My passport's gone!
Sally keep cool!
Bitch!
Sally!
Stay away
Help!
Bastards! Don't touch my gold!
How dare you take my gold! My gold!
You can't, give it back...
Let her go!
Okay! I'll let her go
Sally!
Don't move!
Stay away!
Or I'll kill them
Don't move! Wanna die?
This is Vietnam, you won't get out alive!
Come on! You shut up!
Punk, you won't get out of Saigon!
No way!
Shut up!
Drive, just go on!
Go on! Quickly
Come on!
Drive on!
Ben, get in, quick, quick!
Don't let them get away
You must get them
Get in, quick, quick!
You'll be alright! Don't worry!
What do we do?
Don't worry, I used to work for the CIA,
I'll handle it
What are you doing here?
Sorry sir, I have a pass
Sir, what's going on?
We're being attacked by Vietcongs,
it's dangerous here
You better get out of here
One of our friends is seriously hurt
We must move her to another town urgently
Okay, but take care
Thanks
Let them pass
Can't turn back now!
Let's just get through! Quick!
Help me, take me...
What are you doing? Go away, piss off...
Piss off, go, get lost!
They're so pitiful
Move, move! Bastards!
Drive on, faster!
Frank, start from there,
plant a mine every there steps in case
Right!
Quickly!
You okay?
Hang on
You'll be okay
Will we make it?
We'll get away! The boat will
leave soon, don't worry
Really?
Really! Believe me
I told you, once we have
the change to leave
We'll go back to Hong Kong together
Be strong
You'll make it back to Hong Kong
I've got a record of yours at home
Waiting to be autographed
Hey! Luke, is this boat coming?
If those Vietnam bastards get here,
we'll be dead!
Is that boat for real?
Hey! What do you want?
Answer me okay?
Are you human? Spare a thought for us
You only care about your gold,
what about us?
Are you blind? Can't you see?
Frank!
What are you doing?
I feel like shit!
Ben, the boat's here!
Why did it take so long?
Last night there was a Vietcong
attack, it's dangerous
Stop the boat up front first
Up front... Up front...
Sally, the boat! The boat's here!
Hey! Stop the boat! Stop! Stop!
Can't stop! It's too dangerous!
Stop! Wait for me! Wait for me!
I can't wait for you!
Go on! No! come on!
Go on! I'll give you gold!
Help me please!
Come on!
Like this! Okay! Come on, quickly...
Ben, I'll cover you,
get on the boat, quick!
Paul
Ben! Quick! Quick!
Wait!
Sally, Sally...
They're catching up!
Luke, get on the boat! Luke!
Luke, Luke!
Go, Luke
Let her go, let go now!
Get on the boat, Luke!
Shit! Why doesn't the boat move?
God damn!
Hey! Give us a hand now!
If those damn Vietcong get us we're dead!
God damn it! Aren't you guys worried?
The boat's screwed!
Come and help!
Stop sitting there like statues?
Luke, can you fix it?
I know you're upset over Sally's death,
so am I!
But it's better this way?
She won't drag us down!
We're scared shitless
not knowing how much longer we'll die
Isn't that worse?
If this boat sinks,
we'll lose all this gold
Hey! Don't touch my gold!
Hey, Ben, put it back!
Hey! Stop doing that, or I'll shoot!
Come on!
Put the gold down!
Are you crazy?
Go on! If you shoot
I'll blow your head up!
For me I'm already dead,
but I don't want to lose the gold
Frank, put the gun done
Put the gun down!
Are you putting this gold
before your friends?!
Do you still know what friends are?
Do you know what you're doing?
You're pointing your gun
at a buddy of over 10 years!
Do you measure your friendship in gold?
Is this enough?
Over 10 years of friendship...
That friendship is over,
we're not friends anymore
Shoot then!
I've known you for over 10 years
Over 10 years!
If you want you can kill me!
Shoot! Go on shoot...
Please stop throwing it away!
I'm sorry!
That's all I'm asking for
All I want in this life is simple
Just this box of gold, is that too much?
This boat is sinking
We better do something about it?
Do you want to die?
I want my gold!
Let's jump!
Quick jump!
The gold, the gold...
Paul
My gold!
Paul, come on now, Ah!
Come on now!
I found it, I found the gold!
Paul, are you crazy! Paul!
Paul
Help!
Go and help him
I can't make it!
Help me! Help!
Help me... Help!
The gold's too heavy...
The gold...
You wanna die? Forget about the gold!
Let's go!
Don't you wanna live?
You can let me die, but I want my gold!
Damn your gold! Damn, damn it...
If I'd known, I won't have
bothered saving you!
We'll go and find Luke
Come if you want if you
don't you can stay
Move, Frank
Come on!
Grab him, grab him, don't move
Don't kill him yet
Luke
All of you stand there, don't move!
Hands up!
Don't shoot! Vietcong!
Shit! Why did we look for Luke?
Put the guns down, quick...
Today our comrades
found American soldiers on hill 43
Right, tomorrow we attack through the bushes
Wow, all that gold
Ben
Put the gold on the table
What is it?
Open it. Right
Some military map and a name list
It belongs to the 3 outside
Something's wrong!
Those three guys had the
name list and the gold
A G.I. escaped, get him!
A G.I. escaped, shoot him
Run away?
No way, you won't get away!
Speak up!
Is this gold and list of agents?
connected to the CIA?
The gold and name list belongs to them
Ask them
Take him away
Right! Move!
Is this gold yours?
No! Yes... The gold is mine
Don't hit him. Stop it!
Don't say yes! Paul!
He knows nothing!
Don't admit it, Paul
He knows nothing, don't hit him!
Are you working for the CIA?
We're not Vietnamese
We're not with the CIA
We don't know anything
No! He's lying!
We know nothing!
He's lying! I don't know!
Is it form CIA?
We don't know anything,
we don't know if these are connected CIA
We don't know anything!
We're Chinese! We don't know!
Please believe me! Go to hell!
How much information do you have?
We don't know anything
We're not from the CIA,
Ben... Ben
Ben... Tell them not to shoot at us!
Calm down... don't panic...!
Ben...
Frank...Calm down! Calm down...!
It's alright!
It's not easy to get rid of me!
He's staring at me! Calm down!
Staring at me! Clam down!
You!
Get up! Damn it! Run!
Stand still!
You kill him! Kill him!
You kill him!
Shoot him!
He kill him!
He is form the CIA!
Don't kill me! Don't kill me...!
Please spare me
Will you tell the truth now?
We're Chinese
We're not from the CIA
Calm down!
No! No...
You wanna run? Damn you Americans!
No...oh... No...Rupert!
Your turn!
You...
No...I don't kill people...No way...!
Calm down...!
I don't kill people,
tell them to leave me alone!
Alright! Don't be afraid, Frank!
I don't kill people...
Got out!
Come out...quick!
He's going to shoot him!
No...No...! I won't...
Go out! You want to get killed?
Go out!
Listen to me!
We can't die in here,
we have to go back to Hong Kong!
I'm so frightened...
don't force me to kill...!
Get outside, Frank!
We got to get some gun!
Tell them not to take me away!
This is our only chance!
I'm not going out! Go out!
Take the gun with you and get inside!
Get out!
Ben...
Don't panic! Frank, these bastards
are just playing games
Take it, Frank!
Shut up!
Kill him...kill him!
No...Don't kill me!
Shoot him!
Don't just stand there,
they will kill you!
I don't want to kill people...
Save your life, don't cry! Shoot!
Please don't force me to kill people
No...
Stand up, quick, stand up...!
I talk, I talk...
I know CIA, come on!
Come on
Let me go, come on!
Frank, you must be strong! Frank...
I can't...I can't
Frank, don't give a shit,
just keep shooting!
Come on!
Kill him!
You have done a great job! Frank!
Bastards, let's do it!
Shoot him!
Kill him!
I won't kill...!
Keep cool! Frank... Keep cool...!
I won't kill people...
Captain, come over here...
Choose me, let me do it for you!
Let me do it, I hate Americans!
I'll kill him for you, please take me!
Good! You'll do it? Good!
Where is CIA? You tell me, where?
In Saigon
Where...
I killed him, are you happy with it?
Who first?
He? OK
Kill him, fine
Are you happy? Punk!
Are you happy? I'm happy too
You like it? Bloody hell!
Hey! Come on, come on...
What?
I make you more happy and
have more fun... OK?
I'll kill more Americans
Kill him!
Don't move!
Say...I'm not going to make it...
Why not...
No bullet, no bullet...
Give him!
Damn you! OK!
I make you happy! OK?
CIA is here? Sure?
Yes, here...in Town Fook
Whom should we kill?
Frank...I've said that
we are going back to Hong Kong together
If you don't, nobody will!
Go to hell
Don't move
Don't move, I'll shoot
Damn it, I go for it!
Don't move, I'll kill him, don't move!
What?
Frank, where's Paul? Who knows
Take care, Frank!
Let's look for Paul?
Go to find Paul, go!
Go! Go to those buildings!
Force me to kill, isn't it funny?
I'm a man! The hell with you! Damn you...
Apache one, get your ass in here!
Ben, Ben, let go...
Paul, be careful
Paul, let's go to search for Ben!
This far, how can we find him?
Maybe he is dead
Don't take the gold again
I want to take the gold. Leave me alone
Go to find Ben...leave the gold!
We are stuck together
Frank!
When we find Ben, we three will leave
Let me go. Paul...
Stay away from me
Don't leave me alone
Frank!
Luke, did you see Frank?
Let's look for him
The US army are going to
leave in 5 minutes
Paul...
Keep quite! Be patient
I'm in pain!
Just hang on, can you?
Shut up! It hurts...
I don't want to die
Let's look around
Damn!
Let me go
I feel so painful!
Stop making any noise!
Paul, what are you doing?
Don't press my head!
I'm out of breath
It's killing me
I'll kill you if you speak again
I'd rather you die. Don't blame me
Frank, Frank...
Paul
For God's sake
He needs our help!
Get to that side!
You are badly wounded
We have to send him to the base
People will take care of him!
He can be, for sure!
Thanks!
Have trouble, let's get ashore, quick!
See if there is anyone still alive...
Our father...
Don't move! Or I'll beat you up!
Luke!
Everyone has to sacrifice in this war!
We are quite lucky though...
We have a chance to see our
friends again....!
Any news from Frank?
He's still alive!
Really?
I wish I did not bring him back
He's not the same Frank anymore!
He doesn't even know who he is!
I saw Frank shoot him in the head...
He didn't die, it's just a miracle!
Maybe he wants to see his old friends
before he dies!
Give me the money,
and I will kill him for you
Take me to see him...
Frank!
Frank. It's me!
The bullet is still in his head,
even though he has an operation
He will become a vegetable
Frank...Frank...
Stop it!
Frank, Frank!
Frank...
Please don't!
Don't do that...!Give me...
Frank. Stop it!
Frank...Stop it...!
Did your hear? Frank
Don't fight, you will die!
Frank
Why don't you save some for me?
We agreed we'll share everything in life!
We were like brothers since we were kids
We fought together...
We cruised chicks together...
You called me brother all the time
I told you we can just be friends
Friends are all equal
Frank. You get so many scars in your head
Beaten up by your mother, remember?
Because you were so naughty,
she had to beat you up
It rained heavily the night I get married
We did not have enough money
to pay the bill...
If not because of your loan!
We could not afford to get married!
At that night,
Ringo, hit your head with a bottle
But you didn't let me know
You're an introvert!
You keep everything to yourself
I'd like to listen to you,
just a few words...
Just a few words...!
Come on...!
Does it ring a bell?
I'm Ben
I don't mean that!
I can't see you like this!
Didn't you tell me you want
to go to Hong Kong
The world is changing...
I'm used to my own way of life
All of a sudden, I have to make a change
I just can't...
I've got to go back!
That's my home!
It's a long way to go...
I've got to go back!
Take care!
Sugar cane juice...
60 cents pleases...
He's not feeling so well these days...
Be good, eat something...
Be good
Come on
Ben! You're back, great...!
His name is Frank
Boss, Mr King says he's
ready for the meeting!
I think it's time for me to retire
The world belong to the young people
Paul is a very capable person
We made money,
we spent all...!
Even the government could
not lay a finger on us!
Have guts, and friend enough!
I seldom make a wrong choice!
Paul will be the most suitable successor!
Congratulations...
Thank you, Mr. King...
I'll try my best to fulfill my duties...
I won't disappoint you!
I have never disappointed myself...
Congratulations, Paul
Thank you
An old friend of Paul
wants to see him!
Okay...anyway. We're through!
Show him in...!
Yes
Ben, when did you come back?
Let me introduce, Mr. King!
Mr. King, this is Ben,
my old friend
He stickled with me throughout
my time in Vietnam
So thrilled to see you again, really!
I'm so happy to see you...!
Half of mine is yours!
What about Frank?
Frank?
He kept telling us to leave him
behind when he was wounded alone
And go with you to Hong Kong
I wanted to help him,
but I was badly wounded
I was so up set,
yet I have done my best!
When we went to Vietnam
to try our luck!
I promised to bring Frank
back to Hong Kong
I kept my words!
I bring him home!
Ben are you out of your mind
When I saw him in Saigon he was crazy
He lived like animal, he led a dog's life!
You know why?
Because he got a bullet in his head!
Why didn't you shoot straight?
Now he has to suffer more?
Is it worth it to kill a friend
for a box of gold?
There are dead people lying
all over the place in wartime
You can bring back any bone
and said it belongs to Frank!
You want to get a revenge? Damn it!
I never lose in my life...
They did not kill me in Vietnam,
you think you can scare me now?
We are all fugitives in our lives,
see who run out of our luck first!
You're going to lose, Paul
Don't worry, I never lose in my life
Ben, we must die together
Frank, shut up
You bring it yourself, you are a dead man
You dare follow me
You want to rest in peace
Let me help you
I'm going to take the box of gold!
Do you envy?
You don't have a long life to enjoy it
Let me help you to rest in peace
He said he wanted to rest in peace
What shall we do?
Give him one more shoot to help him
Come on, help your friend
Shoot him!
Give him one more shoot!
So that he can rest in peace!
And he can't follow us
Shoot, Ben! Help him to rest in peace!
Then we won't suffer anymore
I can continue to earn money
You can make some new friends
Shoot him!