Are you listening to me?
You must escape from here tonight.
It's your only chance to stay alive.
If you follow my instructions
and make it out of the camp...
...travel when it's dark
to flee Bulgaria so you won't be seen.
They'll be everywhere waiting
to arrest you...
...and unless you're very careful,
you'll be caught.
If you make it across the border,
you must get this envelope to Denmark.
First, head south to Salonika and hide
on a ship that's going to Italy.
When you arrive there,
travel north as far as you can.
Your journey will be long
and it may be impossible...
... but you must get this evelope
to the authorities in Denmark.
You must not open it.
If anyone sees it's contents
before you get there...
...you'll end up back here.
Do you understand?
I know you've lived
in this camp your entire life...
...but there is a world outside it.
However, it's a very dangerous world.
Trust no one.
When the time comes,
get from the barracks to the west fence.
When you see the signal,
you will have 30 seconds
to get over the fence...
...before the current is turned back on.
Shoot me.
Hidden behind the log at the edge
of the field...
...you will find a bunndle filled with
items you will need for your journey.
If you follow my instructions
and make it out of the camp...
...travel when it's dark
to flee Bulgaria so you won't be seen.
You must do everything I just told you
if you want to escape.
They're moving me
to another camp tomorrow...
...and I can no longer watch over you.
Follow your compass south to Salonika.
Travel there by any means possible.
Who did it?
Get out! Get out now!
You want to escape this paradise?
Are you that ungrateful?
The border between Bulgaria
and Greece is heavily gurarded...
...and much of the fence is strung
with alarm wires. Do not touch it.
Stop him! Stop him! Stop, little boy!
Come back here! Come back!
Stop! Where do you think you're going?
You cannot escape!
Stop! We will get you!
Stop!
We will get you!
Follow your compass south to Salonika...
...and hide on a ship
that's going to Italy.
-Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
-Okay. Good work.
Hey! Why isn't this hatch closed?
Johannes...
...am I dead?
No.
I don't think I can make it.
They're going to find me.
Not if you're careful.
You must remain unseen.
And if you are seen,
you must blend in with the people
around you.
How?
You know many languages from
the different men you knew in the camp.
Just listen closely and you'll be able
to speak to people...
...and understand them.
I'm afraid.
There are places where
the world is good.
I've seen them.
A long time ago, but I have seen them.
You will, too.
Why didn't you come with me?
This is your journey.
-I have my own.
-But what am I looking for?
What am I gonna find in Denmark?
Freedom.
But I don't even know who I am.
What are you doing in my spot?
You dind't touch my magazines, did you?
I've got to report all stowaways
to the captain. You're in big trouble.
No, please don't tell him.
I need to get to Italy.
I'll give you this
if you don't turn me in!
Pearl handle.
Pretty nice. It looks Soviet.
Throw in the compass
and you've got a deal.
I can't. Just the knife.
You know, I could take this
and trun you in anyway.
But I'm an honest guy...
...and l'd probably get in trouble
for not turning you in sooner.
Okay, you've got yourself a deal.
Roberto, quit looking
at your magazines and get up here!
Keep your pants on, I'll be right up.
Look, I can't take a chance
on anybody seeing you...
...getting off the ship
when we get into port.
So when we're close to shore,
I'll lower you overboard...
...then you can swim to land.
Don't worry. The current will help you
drift to the coast.
You all set?
Have fun.
Once you arrive in Italy,
travel north until you reach Denmark.
Why do they hate us so much, Johannes?
Because it's easy to hate people
who don't believe
the same things you do.
Did my parents not believe what
the guards believe?
Is that why I'm in here?
I didn't know anything
about your parents, but...
...I would assume so.
I don't remember them.
Do you know what they were like?
What they believed ?
Where we were from?
David...
...I don't know anything about you.
I wish I were dead.
Don't ever say that.
Don't even think it.
Why not? There's nothing good here.
What's the point in even staying alive?
If you're alive, you can change things.
If you're dead, you can't.
Do whatever you can to stay alive,
no matter what. Go.
I know you've lived
in this camp your entire life...
...but there is a world outside it.
However, it's a very dangerous world.
Trust no one.
Beautiful loaves, huh?
Sorry to scare you.
You want to get some bread?
-Yes, please.
-Do you have any money?
No.
I'm afraid my bread is not free.
Where do you live?
I'm in the circus.
In the circus?
Well, it's not going to be here
for another 2 weeks.
I think you are a little early.
Where can I get some money
for some bread, sir?
Just take a look at this kitchen.
It's spotless.
And over there,
that's a traditional wood-burning oven.
You know what Abruzzi
down the street bakes his bread with?
Gas.
And still people buy from him
instead of me! It's unbelievable!
You know,
before I can give you some bread...
...you have to do something for me.
-You have to smile.
-Why?
Why? Because you're about to have
the best bread in Italy.
That's why.
Oh, Saint Elizabeth...
...the boy wants to know why
he should smile.
I don't think he know how to.
Who's that?
That's Saint Elizabeth.
She's the patron saint of bakers.
She takes care of everyone
who needs help.
But especially bakers.
Here, see for yourself.
You keep that...
...and maybe she'll help you
out sometime, too.
I'll tell you what.
Just stay here and I'll pick you
out a nice, fresh loaf.
There is something about his face...
...his eyes.
They are not the eyes of a normal boy.
Come and see for yourselves.
My friends want to talk to you.
They just want to know who you are.
Nothing to worry about.
We need to ask you a few questions.
I'm trying to help you.
You've got to believe me!
Let me go!
Travel north as far as you can.
Good luck to you.
Line up, right now! Line up!
Line up over here right now! Right now!
Who did it?
Which one of you is responsible?
It was him. I know it.
Shoot him!
Saint Elizabeth...
...my name is David...
...and, well, the baker told me that
you help people.
I want to get to Denmark...
...and I need help getting out
of these woods.
I have to get to Denmark...
...and I can't if I'm lost in here.
You must remain unseen.
And if you are seen,
you must blend in with the people
around you.
Oh, Saint Elizabeth,
the boy wants to know why
he should smile.
I don't think he knows how to.
Saint Elizabeth, remember how I said
I wouldn't ask you for anything else?
Go away! Please go away!
I didn't mean to make you mad.
I promise,
I was just trying to blend in.
Gina! Be quiet!
What are you doing in my vineyard?
Were you eating my grapes?
Well, it's a good thing you are here
because I need help. Come along.
Come on.
Thank God Gina caught you.
I'm desperate.
I need you to run this wine over
to the Bertelli's party.
Please be careful.
Now, it's 3 farms up the road
and here's 2 lira for your trouble.
What? I'm not giving you more.
-Do you know which way is north?
-What do I look like, a compass?
I have no idea.
Ask the Bertellis. Now go.
Go, go. Go!
Gina, you bad dog! Come!
Finally!
Where have you been?
You should have been here an hour ago.
Good news, everyone! The wine is here.
3 cheers for the delivery boy!
I don't need any strange-looking
urchins at my party.
Now scat!
What's the matter with you?
You have to go to the toilet
or something?
-l'd like to buy some food, please.
-Well, congratulations.
-You came to the right place.
-l'd like one of those...
...that, and one of those.
You got money?
Why don't I just sell you
the whole store for that?
Yeah, and I'll throw in my wife
and kids, too.
Get lost.
David!
Mother...
If you'd ever listen to me,
this kind of thing wouldn't happen.
Look, just calm down.
We can't be that far from a gas station.
I'm not going to go hiking off
when we don't know where we're going.
I don't even have the right shose on.
Excuse me, young man?
We need some help.
Do you know if there's a gas station
around here?
The kid's not gonna speak English.
Use your Italian.
Right.
My wine shop needs steak.
No?
My wine shop needs steak?
I saw a place back there where
they do that.
Oh, you speak English. Great.
Would you go get us some gas?
I'll give you a tip if you do.
Yes, sir.
Sir...
...l'd like to buy some things.
Hey!
What are you doing on my property?
Think you're gonna steal something?
Come on and fight me!
What's this? Something else you stole?
-Give me that, that's mine.
-Oh, yeah? I think it's mine now.
Go ahead and run, little piggy!
And don't ever come back!
Johannes...
...I want to escape.
You said that if we weren't dead,
we could change things.
But how do we know
they're going to let us live?
We don't.
Then we should leave while we still can.
-They'd kill us if we tried.
-They're going to kill us anyway.
We should do whatever
we can to stay alive.
That's what you said.
You're scared.
Yes.
I am.
I don't want to be scared anymore,
Johannes.
Neither do I.
Garlo! Help!
Help!
Don't breathe!
I love you, David.
Are you awake?
I was watching you.
I wanted to make sure
you were all right.
How long have I been asleep?
Since yesterday.
You must have been tired.
When the doctor came,
you didn't even waske up.
Mother put you under the covers.
Where's my bundle?
What bundle?
Nothing. I was just confused.
You got burned...
...but not very bad.
I got burned, too. See?
Mine weren't bad, either,
but Cecha and Angelo are in trouble.
Papa made them go the bed
without supper...
...because they weren't supposed
to be playing with fire.
What's your name?
-David.
-I'm Maria.
Thank you for saving me, David.
Papa said I could have died.
You could have, too.
You're very brave.
Did I just smile at you?
Yes. How come?
I don't know.
Is it because you think I look funny?
No.
Then myabe you love me.
You're awake.
Maria, did you wake him up?
I told you not to.
His name is David, Mama,
and he woke up on his own.
Didn't you?
Go downstairs and get ready for lunch.
David will be down in a minute.
Yes, Mama.
You saved my Maria.
For this...
...I owe you my life.
Are you feeling okay?
We have to get hold of your parents now
that you're awake.
They must be very worried.
We've been asking around,
but no one knows where you're from.
They won't be worried about me.
I don't live around here.
I'm on my way somewhere.
By yourself?
Where are you going?
Lunch is ready, senora.
Thank you, Julia.
Well...
...if you're away from home...
...then I want you to stay
with us for a few days.
The doctor said you should rest
and let your burns heal.
I have brought you
some of Carlo's old clothes.
Now, get dressed and come downstaris.
We've made a special lunch
in your honor.
Everyone's dying to meet you.
I just wanted to tell you I was sorry.
I didn't mean to beat you up yesterday.
Look, I thought you were one
of the boys who stole Maria's bike.
You probably would have done
the same thing, right?
-No.
-Carlo, come down to lunch!
-I called you 5 minutes ago!
-Coming.
Please don't tell my parents
what happened yesterday, okay?
I didn't mean it, I swear.
All right?
Thanks.
Come on.
David, my name is Giovanni Rescigno
and I'm Maria's father.
It's n honor to hv you here in our home.
David, come over here.
Maria wants you to sit next to her.
Maria, I know it's your turn
to say grace...
...but it you don't mind,
l'd like to say it today.
Dear God, we thank you...
...for this wonderful food
of which we're about to partake...
...and for all the bounty
which you provide for us.
We especially want to thank you
for sending us David...
...whose bravery and selflessness...
...has kept our dearest Maria safe
and well.
Please bless David
and our little family...
...and guide us so that we may continue
to perform your good works.
Thank you so very much.
Amen.
Well, David, I don't know about you,
but I'm starving.
Let's eat.
It's okay, David?
Is it nice to have a family?
I like it...
...but I don't know anyone
who doesn't have one.
Don't you have a family?
I don't know, but l'd like one.
We can be your family.
You can be an honorary memeber.
Do you like your brother Carlo?
Yes, but he makes fun of me a lot.
He calls me "crybaby",
but I don't cry as much as I used to.
Don't you like him?
There's a lot of people I don't like.
Why not?
Becuase the world is filled
with terrible people, Maria...
...and they all do terrible,
evil things.
I've seen them.
You don't think that
we are terrible people, do you?
-No, not at all.
-Not even Carlo?
Let's go inside.
I want to show you something.
My papa has lots of poetry books.
He reads to me from them.
Shakespeare is my favorite.
Do you like Shakespeare's sonnets?
I've never heard them.
You don't know anything good...
...do you?
What's that?
That's the Earth.
I've never seen a map like this before.
Do you know how to read it?
Uh-huh.
That's Italy...
...and there is Russia...
...and there's America.
Where's Denmark?
That's up here.
Switzerland and Germany
are between them and us.
-Have you ever been to Denmark?
-No. Have you?
I'm on my way there now.
You are?
Why are you going to Denmark, David?
You know you're not supposed to be
in here without Papa's permission.
I'm sorry. I just wanted
to read David some poetry.
All right.
Why don't you go and cut some flowers
for the dinner table?
-Can David help me?
-No, let David stay here.
Papa and I want to talk to him.
How's your hand feeling?
Fine.
David, Gianni and I just want
to make sure everything's okay with you.
This morning you said
you're on your way somewhere.
Where are you going?
I'm going to...
...to meet up with the circus.
The circus?
Yes, I'm in the circus.
And what do you do in the circus?
-Lots of thing.
-And that's where your parents are?
Yes.
Why are your parents letting
you travel by yourself?
-It's okay. They don't mind.
-David, are you lying to us?
No.
Are you lying to us?
In this house, lies are not permitted.
-No, I swear!
-Okay.
It's okay, David. It's okay.
We just wanted to make sure everything
was all right.
You don't have to worry.
My goodness, we wouldn't hurt you.
We're sorry to ask you
so many questions.
Why don't you go
and get ready for dinner?
You stole it.
When no one was around,
I went into the man's office.
do you know what they'll do to
you if they find it?
It was in his desk.
Promise me you'll never take something
that's not yours again.
You must promise me that.
Who did it?
Which one of you is responsible?
It was him. I know it.
Shoot him. They must be taught a lesson.
No, it was him.
Take care of her, Saint Elizabeth.
I don't deserve to have
you look after me anymore.
I don't deserve anything good.
Please tell Maria that I'm sorry.
And if you talk to Johannes...
...tell him I'm sorry, too.
-Workers of the world...
-Unite!
That was a big mistake, boy.
It wasn't me! I didn't throw it!
Let me out!
Where do you think you're going?
Come on!
You better stay right there, boy!
Come back!
Come back here!
Where do you think you're going?
Come here!
I'll find you, boy!
Hey, my firiend!
I see you made it to shore. Well done.
Roberto? Why aren't you on the ship?
I quit. It was too boring.
Besides, they caught me
stealing a crate of tomatoes.
You need a ride?
Hop in.
Where are you going to?
-Denmark.
-Denmark?
That's a long way.
I'm only going to Milan.
-That's okay.
-I was in Denmark a few summers ago.
It's pretty nice.
Lots of good-looking girls.
Good-bye, my friend, and good luck.
Say hello to Denmark for me.
Hello.
I thought there was somebody there.
I always know when someone's looking
at me behind my back.
some sort of psychic energy,
don't you think?
Come over and take a look at this,
will you?
I've been trying all morning...
...to capture the essence
of this beautiful place.
Usually when I come up here,
it inspires me...
...but today, nothing seems
to be working for me.
What do you think?
It's very pretty.
Is it?
It all seems a bit lifeless to me.
You've got a very interesting face.
Would you mind if I painted it?
What color do you want to paint
my face?
I like that.
I think you'll make quite
a challenging subject.
That is, if you don't mind
sitting for a bit.
I'm Sophie, by the way.
What's your name?
David.
David? That's too perfect.
Michelangelo had his David,
so you've got to let me have mine.
You're very good at sitting still,
David.
Most aduIts I paint can't sit still
for a minute without fidgeting.
I always tell them the more they move...
...the worse they look in the picture.
But that doesn't mean
you can't move your mouth.
Talking won't ruin the painting.
I'm not that bad.
I don't really have anything to say.
Well, then you don't have
to say anything.
There are an awful lot of people
in this world...
...who have nothing to say,
but seem to spend
all their time talking.
You're right to conserve your words.
It means you'll be a man
with great power.
I don't want to be a man of great power.
Then you don't have to be.
Just be happy that you're the kind
of person who could be if he wanted to.
I'm having such trouble...
...with your eyes.
I've never had to use
so much black paint before.
Such serious eyes.
Such a serious face.
Well, just one or two more finishing
touches and then we're done.
I wish my house was a bit closer.
l'd love to invite you to lunch...
...to repay you for your kindness.
Where do you live?
Just over the border, in Switzerland.
David...
...are you quite sure your parents
won't mind you coming this far?
It's okay. They don't mind.
They don't live around here anyway.
I see.
What's that?
That's just my sketchbook.
All my drawings are in there.
-Can I look at them, please?
-You can if you want to.
But I warn you, they're not very good.
I went to a few art classes
when I was younger...
...but I never really kept up with it.
I only studied painting again
a year ago.
Just for my own amusement.
Who's that?
That's just a boy
I knew a long time ago.
I told you they were not very good.
-I have to get out.
-What?
Is something the matter?
You can do whatever you want.
I thought you want to see Switzerland.
I do.
Well, now...
...they're going to ask us
for identification. Do you have any?
-No.
-Well, it doesn't really matter.
This is an easy border.
It shouldn't be a problem.
Okay?
Okay.
-Good day, ma'am.
-Good morning.
-Your papers, please.
-Yes, of course.
-And for the boy also.
-This is my grandson, officer...
...and we left the house in such
a hurry this morning...
...he forgot
to bring his identification.
I don't know.
Our orders are to check
everyone's papers, even children.
Couldn't you relax the rules for a bit?
All he wants to do is to come
into your country...
...overthrow the government
and then rush right out again.
All right, Mrs. Anderson.
Have a nice day.
And young man...
...see if you can get us pay raises
while you're taking over our country.
There, you see? No problem.
Now we can go and have some lunch.
I'm afraid there's
no escaping my artwork.
But it's less expensive
than buying real paintings.
They look like real paintings to me.
But wait a minute.
We have to add my latest work
to the gallery wall.
Hold it a minute, would you?
Thank you.
Is that what I look like?
To me, yes. It's my impression of you.
That's why
it's called impressionistic painting.
So...
...what do you see when you look at it?
Me?
Well, yes.
That's not quite what I meant.
you have to look
at paintings differently...
...from the way
you look at other things.
More closely...
...to see what it says to you.
Well...
...when I look at the boy
in that painting...
...I see a very intelligent,
very serious person...
...and a good person.
But...
...ther's something about the eyes...
...and the face that seems lost and sad.
But that's as far as I can see...
...because he doesn't want to
let the world see any further.
-Do you really see all that?
-Yes. Yes, I do.
Oops, there's our tea.
I hope there's enough food for you.
I'm a very light eater...
...but I know boys
can pack away quite a lot.
I'm fine. It's very nice. Thank you.
Good.
Hello, Annette.
I thought you might smell our food.
Or have you come to say hello
to our guest?
Do you like cats?
I don't know. I guess so.
Well, if you knew Annette, you would.
She's very sweet and also very funny,
aren't you, pussycat?
What's that?
What?
This?
It's a locket.
I've had it for ages.
It belonged to my mother.
And look, I'll show you.
My father had it inscribed on the back.
He gave it to her on their wedding day.
Is that the same boy that you drew?
Yes.
That's my son, Peter.
Or he was my son.
He died not long after that picture
was taken.
-What happened?
-Pneumonia.
He'd always been a frail child...
...but he was a very sweet,
very loving boy.
Did he live here with you?
No, we all lived in Zurich then. But...
...some other things happened...
...after Peter died and...
...and I decided to move up here.
And besides,
who wouldn't want to live up here?
It's such a beautiful place,
don't you think?
We think so, don't we, pussycat?
Would you like to hold her?
-She won't bite.
-Okay.
She's so soft.
And she's vibrating.
She's purring, David.
Have you never stroked a cat before?
No.
Where do you live, David?
Nowhere.
I'm in the circus.
In the circus?
Oh, my goodness.
That must be very interesting.
Yes, it is. It's very interesting.
If you need a place to stay the night...
-...you're very welcome to stay here.
-No.
I can't. I have to go.
I can't stay anywhere anymore.
David, if there's something
troubling you...
...l'd very much like to help you
if I can.
Please...
-...don't turn me in.
-Turn you in to whom?
To them.
To him, to anyone.
I wouldn't dream of turning you
in to anybody for any reason.
You're quite safe here, David.
You're safe.
From the guards?
From everybody.
I want to tell you everything,
Sophie, but I can't.
I just can't.
You don't have to tell me anything.
I just want you to know that
you're safe here...
...and that everything
will be all right.
Sleep well, David.
Everything's all right.
Good morning, David.
I hope I didn't wake you.
I have to go to the village.
I promised to take some food
to a friend of mine who's sick.
You can come along if you want to.
Why do people do such terrible things?
Like what?
Like beat people and kill them,
and make them prisoners.
Most people don't do that.
My friend Johannes always used
to tell me...
..."trust no one."
Life wouldn't be worth living
if you did that, David.
You can be cautious,
but you have to let people in.
How do you know if they're bad or not?
David, most people are good.
They have families and friends...
...and they just want to live their
lives as happily as they can.
There will always be bad people
in this world...
...and you'll usually know
them when you meet them...
...but sometimes you won't.
But you can't let that stop you from...
...living your life fully and freely...
...and making friends...
...and seeing the goodness in people.
Because if you don't do that,
you'll never find any happiness.
Now this is my friend's house.
But you don't need to come in, David.
Why don't you go exploring?
Look around some of the shops.
I'll meet you in the bookshop
in a little while, okay?
They're nice people, David.
You don't have to worry about anything.
Okay?
Hello.
And hello to you.
You must do everything I just told you
if you want to escape.
They're moving
me to another camp tomorrow...
...and I can no longer watch over you.
This is the only way
you'll ever be safe.
Do you understand?
I know you've lived in this camp
your entire life...
...but there is a world outside it.
However, it's a very dangerous world.
Trust no one.
And...
...I'm sorry about your friend Johannes.
I've seen this bood before.
What is it?
That's a wonderful book, David.
It was written by a woman
who lost her husband and her son...
...in Bulgaria after the war.
The husband came from England.
When he went to Bulgaria
to rouse people against
the communists...
...he took her and the boy with him.
But they were all arrested,
and the man and the boy were killed.
But one of the guards
had known the woman...
...since they were children
and he'd always been in love with her.
So he arranged for forged papers
and helped her to escape.
-Is the woman still alive?
-Yes. She lives in Denmark.
I am David.
I know, David.
I know.