Subtitles by DramaFever
[Final Episode]
There's a clear contrast
between the green and white parts.
Looks good. I'll take these.
Goodness, people will think
you're choosing precious gems.
You examined these green onions
for a solid ten minutes.
My grocery shopping skills
are being tested!
Hey look, what are you doing on the road?
Hey look, what are you doing...
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, hey! You can't turn on
the heat that high.
Stop. That's right. It's right there.
Dried radish slices need to be cooked
in low heat like that.
How many minutes has it been?
Four minutes now.
Sauté it for 20 minutes exactly.
If you go over by even one second,
it won't taste right.
I got it.
If Hyun Suk finds out I taught you
the secret sauce recipe...
Hyun Suk will probably say something.
Hyun Suk told me to never share it
with anyone.
Am I just anyone?
That's why I'm teaching you in secret.
Oh, I need to leave for the audition.
At 2:00, fry the tempura
and throw away the leftover oil.
You know we never re-use oil, right?
You sound like a broken record,
President Yang.
Your Grandma's secret sauce isn't the
only reason this place is successful.
It's all because it was combined
with my business philosophy.
You'll be late to the audition.
This time, I'll make sure to get
a regular role.
- I'll head out now.
- Fighting!
[You & Now Project]
[Generation of Loss -
Finding Lost Time...]
Ha No Ra.
Books and now newspapers...
At this rate, you'll get your doctorate
by studying on your own.
Today's lesson was on the secret sauce?
Yeah.
Don't get me started.
Yang Dong Chul is so picky.
He chides me constantly.
Dong Chul went to the audition?
This time, it's a drama.
Yang Dong Chul, who decided to go after
his dream.
I thought he'd regret giving it up.
He's pretty impressive.
Regret? No, he says it's getting more fun.
What about you?
You don't regret dropping out of college?
Not at all. Learning my Grandma's cooking
is so much fun.
You're crazy. You're crazy!
Why would you quit school?
Even when you knew you were misdiagnosed,
you wanted to stay in school so bad.
Why did you drop out of college?
Back then, I thought I was going to die.
So I just wanted to do things
I never got to do.
Then what about now?
Going to college is now something
you don't want to do?
It's not that I don't want to do it.
I just didn't have any reasons
to keep going.
Do you want to see this?
For four years, the tuition and textbooks
will cost more than 30 million won.
When you add meals and spending money,
it'll be 50 million won.
And if I work those four years instead
I'll be able to make
at least 100 million won.
Is it about money?
There's some money left after you
paid for your place, right?
I'm quitting because there's no reason for
me to spend that money to go to college.
I went to college
because of Min Soo's Dad.
And I went into the Humanities Department
because of him too.
But I'm not interested in any
of the majors in Humanities.
My interest was always dancing.
Studying was never my thing.
How many people go to college and
study because it's their thing?
Even getting a job, everyone does it
to keep up with each other's level.
Can you think it over one more time?
At least for Hyun Suk?
Why do I have to get my college degree
to match Hyun Suk's level?
He's just so successful.
It could look bad to others.
Living my life
by other people's standards...
I won't live like that anymore.
That's meaningless.
And as for Cha Hyun Suk,
I'm going to leave that as my first love.
Ha No Ra.
Are you sure you won't regret it?
I don't know if I'll regret it or not.
But I don't want to depend on Hyun Suk,
or have him protect me.
I'll never find myself that way.
From now on, I'm only going to think about
ways I can live with my own strength.
Will this be enough
for an elementary school kids' snack?
A little more.
I thought you can't have more than five
even with a god-given ballerina body?
What's with you today?
Buying spicy rice cakes for your students?
I was going to have some too.
I no longer have to watch my weight
like I did before.
Ever since I started working here,
you've been eating this way too often.
Oh, right, right. I'm so out of it.
I came here for business.
Business?
On Grandma's birthday this year,
you're going to Okcheon, right?
Let's go together.
You want to go together?
Every time you go,
you have so many bags.
Until last year, you were able
to borrow Min Soo's Dad's car.
You have to take the bus this year, no?
I'll be able to get fresh air,
and say hello to Grandma.
Then, shall we?
I should prepare extra food.
Now that you mention it, that summer
in our junior year of high school
practicing at your place in Okcheon
was our last trip.
Cha Hyun Suk hasn't visited here,
has he?
He's probably busy preparing for his show.
That's not why he isn't coming.
That cold jerk.
Dong Chul told him you're working here,
and he told him not to talk about you.
And not to talk about you in the future.
Isn't he being too much?
What do you mean? It's only natural.
That's what we agreed on.
Is that the best you can do?
Expressing anger like that
isn't realistic.
I'm supposed to be angry,
but you don't want me to show it?
You gave up your dream of being an artist,
and haven't had a job for three years.
The man who stole your girlfriend
is rubbing it in your face.
You want to let it all out,
but you have too much pride.
So, you laugh instead of getting angry.
Then the moment you turn around,
bang!
The anger that you
had suppressed explodes!
And you rip that book.
Try it again.
It's too hard.
Do you think expressing two emotions
is easy?
Okay, let's go again.
Food is here!
You have to come in quietly
during rehearsals.
I... I... I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
Na Soon Nam wants us to take a break.
Why don't we take eat and take a break?
Rookie, how is the job?
Besides Producer Cha yelling
every now and then, everything is good.
Endure it a little longer.
I won't be yelling for much longer.
By the way Producer Cha, you used to
buy spicy rice cakes before.
That really tasty spicy rice cake.
Why haven't we seen it lately?
Because I don't want to eat it.
[Nina by Luise Rinser]
It's been a long...
Did he pretend not to know me?
But you should know this one thing.
There is no forever.
It's time for me to move on now.
I can't hold onto dreams
of my first love forever.
I can't live my life that way.
I want to a reggae party yesterday.
It was so much fun!
A reggae party? That must've been fun.
What were you doing, Mom?
You are doing well, right?
Yes. I was eating rice and
reading the letter you wrote.
What about the work? Isn't it hard?
It's not too bad.
Once I finish at the blueberry farm,
I'm going to Hillstone to look for work.
If it's too difficult, you can come back.
No way! I'm going to finish out the year.
I'm so glad I came, Mom.
I've met people from all over the world,
and made some money.
I feel like my mind is expanding.
I'm relieved. You're amazing.
I have to go somewhere now.
I'll call you again, okay?
Okay, take care of yourself. Be well.
My Min Soo is all grown up now.
[Writing Down Today's Joys]
It's been a long...
[Dear Mom...]
To the person I wanted to watch over...
You said you wanted to watch over me.
Oh, Yoon Young. Are you here?
No Ra, I'm so sorry.
I totally forgot that my mom has an
appointment at 9:00 at the hospital.
Really?
Go on the bus without me.
Since you have lots to carry,
leave it all at the Okcheon Terminal.
Head up to the house first
and start cleaning.
Hey, Ha No Ra.
So it is you, Ha No Ra.
Yeah.
Get in.
Get in. I'll give you a ride.
You don't even know where I'm going.
You have a mountain of stuff to carry.
I can take a taxi.
Really? Okay.
Are you going to Okcheon, by chance?
Grandma passed away in April,
so why are you going now?
It's Grandma's birthday.
Really?
Then I'll give you a ride
to the bus terminal.
Forget it.
I'm only doing it because
you're going to see your grandma.
Get in.
Hello? Hi, Reporter Kim.
Sorry for getting back to you so late.
Yes.
It's been thirty minutes, but he hasn't
asked me how I've been doing.
Hey! You said you're letting me off
at the bus terminal.
I've done too many interviews.
I'll do one after the show.
Okay.
Why are you going this way?
I happen to have the day off,
so I might as well go to Okcheon.
You're going all the way to Okcheon?
Forget it! I'm supposed to meet Yoon Young
at the Okcheon bus terminal.
Yeah, I'll go to the bus terminal there.
Why would you go all the way to Okcheon?
Do you think it's because of you?
I'm going because you said
it's Grandma's birthday.
Because you have food for Grandma.
I do have some stake in Grandma, you know.
Still, it's a burden.
Why am I a burden?
Why are you feeling so uncomfortable?
The whole first love thing is over with.
Just think of it as meeting
your high school classmate.
I don't need it. Turn the car around.
Yeah, Yoon Young.
My mom needs to get a blood test
and a few other tests too.
What should I do?
How will you get up the mountain alone?
Oh, really?
I'll handle it.
Help your mom.
Okay.
Gosh, looks like I'll be going to Okcheon
mountain, not just the bus terminal.
Thank you. You should go.
I should say my greetings to Grandma
before I go.
Why is this rice uncooked?
I always come here and cook it.
Then go ahead and say hello
to your grandma.
If you're going to cook here,
we need to clean this place up.
Where's the broom again?
Grandma, I did go to college
with the money that you saved for me.
But, I quit.
There just wasn't anything more
that I wanted to learn there.
Your granddaughter is so smart.
So I learned everything that I needed.
It's all thanks to you, Seo Woon Hae.
Thank you for being born as my grandma.
Seo Woon Hae...
Thank you so much for loving me.
By the way, Grandma, don't you think
Cha Hyun Suk is being too much?
Let's switch.
It's my turn now.
Are you going to cut the weeds?
Go on and cook.
Okay. Thanks.
He went on and on about being
first loves, and 20 years.
How could he change like that
in just three months?
He was so kind in high school.
Don't you want to do it just the way
we made it without the teachers knowing?
This is the first show we're doing
in front of the public.
Let's take a short break.
I think I'm going to die now.
Okay, let's take a break.
I'll bring the watermelon.
Watermelon.
Hey!
Don't feel down even if the teachers
say something to you.
It's because you're like Seo Taiji.
Seo Taiji?
In about 20 years, you're going to be
the top producer in Korea.
Don't say nonsense.
I mean it though.
I knew that Seo Taiji and Boys
would be a big hit.
What are you going to do
if I'm not successful in 20 years?
And what if you are?
Never mind.
You want to make a bet?
A bet?
We'll bury a time capsule,
and check it in 20 years.
Time capsule?
You were the only one.
The only one who saw that an odd and
sensitive kid like me had talent.
The only one to believe in me.
You were the only one.
You were the one
who made me who I am today.
I don't know what you're talking about.
When did I do that?
You don't even remember?
Ah... this was it.
Hyun Suk remembered it all.
Year 2015, Cha Hyun Suk will have become
the best producer in Korea.
July 30, 1995.
Ha No Ra.
What are you doing?
I don't want to forget where it is
when I come back later.
We'll be back together.
This has been my playground for 11 years,
since I was five years old.
That's true. We'll come together.
Don't forget.
You have to go to your right.
You said it's been your playground
for 11 years.
But you forgot?
To the right?
I don't know exactly where it is.
Three steps forward.
Now I know.
Cha Hyun Suk.
You remembered it.
The time capsule?
Don't you want to see it with me?
I don't want to see it.
You can see it all... both of them.
Year 2015, to Ha No Ra
who is now 38 years old.
I see you're still the same.
You're still bright,
energetic, and pretty.
July 30, 1995. 20 years ago.
Ha No Ra...
I've been happy having you by my side
for 20 years, and thank you.
Let's continue being happy.
From Cha Hyun Suk,
who always wants to be next to Ha No Ra.
Year 2015, Cha Hyun Suk will have become
the best producer in Korea.
July 30, 1995.
From...
The one who is keeping an eye on you.
The one who is keeping an eye on you?
To the person who I hoped
to keep an eye on.
The one who is keeping an eye on you.
Cha Hyun Suk.
Had you... looked at this already?
Yes, I did.
When?
Grandma.
I've been discharged from the army.
No one is here in Korea.
So I'm leaving straight for Russia.
I don't know when I'll be back again.
But... don't be too upset with No Ra.
Year 2015, Cha Hyun Suk will have become
the best producer in Korea.
July 30, 1995.
From...
The one who is keeping an eye on you.
The one who is keeping an eye on you...
You came and the buried it again?
Why didn't you throw it away?
Why did you bury it again?
I don't know why.
Maybe 20 years later, in 2015...
I thought we'd come back here together.
To me, you're that kind of person.
I'm going now.
What does this mean?
Are you asking because you don't know?
Yes.
We've never been the type to hug,
so I don't know what it means.
Tell me in words.
That assignment you gave...
I think that one important moment
in my life is right now.
I don't know what you mean.
I only understand if you tell me directly.
Like the last time.
I don't want you...
by my side anymore.
I want you...
to be by my side.
Why?
Because I like you.
Because I missed you.
Because I can't forget you.
I thought I was going to die
because I wanted to see you.
Tell me one more time.
You haven't forgotten me, have you?
How could I forget you?
You jerk!
What?
What did you say?
How could you...
I always had a drink with Grandma
on her birthdays.
Grandma always loved rice wine.
Don't use her as an excuse.
You've been drinking rice wine since you
were six, getting drunk and dancing.
How did you know that?
You think that's all I know?
Do you know why Grandma likes
red bean paste bread?
Red bean paste bread?
Long long ago, there was this old grandma.
One winter day, she had no food.
Not even a grain of rice.
She went over the mountain to another town
to work on a farm.
But they told her that they had
no money to pay her.
And they gave her
one red bean paste bread.
She took that bread and walked home
for two hours through a mountain path.
She wanted so badly to eat it.
But back home...
that grandma had a five-year-old
granddaughter who had starved all day.
So she endured her hunger, went home,
and gave that bread to her granddaughter.
But she thought to herself
"Gosh, I hope she leaves me
one little piece."
But, that granddaughter said to her,
"Grandma, ah..."
A child that had been starving all day...
held that bread out to Seo Woon Hae first
and told her to eat it.
That's a story about my grandma?
She told me that story.
She said that even if you were not
related to her by blood
you were a child that was impossible
not to love.
That child's name was probably...
Ha No Ra.
Grandma never told me that story.
That's why she liked red bean paste bread.
Grandma's the reason why I liked you
so deeply.
Why aren't you giving me any rice wine?
I should say cheers too.
You have to drive.
Grandma, No Ra has finally
come to her senses.
Are you saying I was crazy before?
You made me wait three months
and ten days.
What about you?
How could you not come looking for me
even one time?
Didn't you want to see me?
Who says I didn't?
Huh?
And Ha No Ra, you came to see me
whenever you pleased.
Did you miss me that much?
You knew that I was watching?
Yesterday, you ate three spicy rice cakes
when Dong Chul wasn't looking.
Here it is. Ha No Ra's first batch
of spicy rice cakes.
It's not the same as Grandma's,
but it's still very good.
It isn't easy.
She dropped out?
I'm telling you
because I thought you should know.
Yesterday, she even came to the store
saying that she wants to learn from me.
What should I do?
From now on, don't tell No Ra
anything about me.
Ever...
What does that mean?
Are you really going to give up on No Ra?
Instead, I want to know everything
about how No Ra is doing.
So you're going to keep an eye on No Ra?
I need to leave No Ra be for now.
Let No Ra do what she wants.
What are you going to do
if No Ra never comes back to you?
Then I can't do anything.
You can't do anything?
Hey Cha, how can you give up so easily?
Does this look easy to you guys?
Dong Chul and Yoon Young
were both in on it?
They weren't in on it.
They were doing me a favor.
Why did you do it?
I wanted to be someone who could
help you gain courage in life.
That way you'd come to me on your own.
Cha Hyun Suk... you are really mean.
I was waiting for you,
until you gained courage.
Do you know how nervous I was?
Were you nervous?
You said you knew I was watching
you secretly.
So why were you nervous?
Because you were doing it secretly.
Watching me secretly meant it was not
serious enough for you to hold onto me.
It meant your heart
wasn't quite there yet.
It meant you didn't trust my feelings yet.
I guess that was true.
What?
It was worth the wait, right?
You've become tougher
since the last time I saw you.
Grandma, I'll be leaving now with No Ra.
Next time, I'll be coming with her.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Grandma is waiting.
You should say,
"I'll be back with Hyun Suk".
Grandma, I'll be going now
and I'll be back.
I'll see how Hyun Suk behaves,
and bring him back if he's good.
What?
[Yoobae University is just a
temporary stop for me.]
[Though I may be tested, I will not fail]
[One who overcome one's fault
is a strong person.]
[Paper Due Date - 7 Days]
People say that mistakes can happen
once in a while.
Kim Woo Chul will not fall like this.
Narcissistic personality disorder.
Those with this disorder believe
they are the most important person.
And they overestimate their talents
and skills.
So, they are very sensitive to the
perceptions of others, and obsess over it.
Another important point is that they
lack empathy towards others.
They are solely focused on succeeding.
They work hard to get attention and
respect from people around them.
You will see impudent and rampant behavior
from them every now and then, as well.
Is there a treatment?
The thing is... it's not easy to treat.
The patient must come forward...
and seek out treatment
for this narcissism.
But there is another symptom
of this disorder.
They will never admit that they have
narcissistic personality disorder.
I knew he'd be living like a loser.
It's been a long time.
Do I know you?
What are you doing here like this?
I said, do I know you?
Yi Jin... Kim Yi Jin!
You knew it was me?
You're wearing the same disguise.
You had to disguise yourself
when you were dating me.
Even after breaking up,
you still have to do this.
I really am a bad person.
I'm relieved that you know.
Can you just not endure
the anger towards me?
It hasn't been easy for me to forget.
You didn't stop me from coming to Yoobae
University, so I thought you'd let it go.
Just hit me.
Were you always this dense? Seriously...
You're not possibly...
Are you here by yourself?
Yes, I've made a very clean break.
I'm alone.
You know I'm going to Yoobae University,
don't you?
I heard from Min Soo.
I thought I should say goodbye.
Yes.
Do you still hate me?
I have no feelings towards you anymore.
I was young back then.
I thought about it,
and I was only 23 years old.
I could only think about
hiding my mistakes.
I was too young.
I was scared of everything that happened.
I thought because of one mistake...
I might have ruined my life.
Now...
it's all in the past.
Don't look back.
Let's live looking forward.
You and I both.
Okay.
If you're done...
What is this?
When I brought you to dinner
with Professor Lindemann...
I bought this to beg for forgiveness.
The situation has changed,
but I did buy it to give it to you.
So, I'd like you to accept it.
Ah, I thought about taking the card out.
But I wanted to say those words to you.
So I left it in there.
For the past 20 years...
Sorry, and thank you.
It's the first gift
I've received from you.
I'll accept it.
Okay.
I want to say sorry again.
And thank you.
The two of you were quite classy.
It's not easy to level-headed
when breaking up.
It was a break up with no regrets.
That was why.
You have to have some feelings left
in order to get angry.
About before... I am very sorry.
I'm the one who caused you
to do something you'd be sorry for.
Being so indecisive,
holding on to two choices.
I tried to turn everything to my advantage
and I was very wrong.
Why are you giving this to me?
You should eat it, Professor Kim.
Honestly, I don't like cutlass fish.
Why didn't you ever say so?
I didn't even know all this time,
and we ate it every week.
It seemed like you liked it,
so I didn't say anything.
How is Yoobae University?
I'm starting from the beginning
and writing my paper.
I'm going get back to Seoul
with my skill alone.
I resigned from Woocheon.
Thanks to Producer Cha,
I could not have just stayed.
What I did was definitely a crime.
After I did something like that...
I shouldn't stand on the lecture platform.
Then what do you plan to do?
I'm going to the United States next week.
The United States?
Are you going to study abroad?
Oh no, not at all.
I'm going on a vacation.
For about a month.
I want to gather my thoughts.
So you won't be gone forever.
I'm not quite sure why...
But... I can't seem to leave Korea yet.
Should we go eat red bean shaved ice
after we finish eating?
You know, actually...
I don't really like red beans.
I only ate it because you like it.
We were a couple that were quite
dishonest with each other.
Let's not do that in the future.
If we like it, say so.
If we don't like it, say so.
Don't live hiding our feelings.
Yes, let's do that.
I think being honest is best.
There is a shaved ice with rice cake
and bean powder. Do you want that?
All right.
Looks pretty.
Where is Soon Nam?
We have to eat a simple dinner
and do the show.
Food delivery is here.
Ha No Ra!
What's going on?
There's spicy rice cakes, sandwiches,
and rice porridge.
Those who can digest well can eat
spicy rice cake and sandwiches.
Nervous people can have the porridge.
I told you that No Ra is tired,
and to keep her from doing these things.
Out of the producer I work part-time for,
and my eternal Noona...
who do you think I'd listen to?
Bingo!
Part-time?
I heard you decided to work in
Production Planning now.
Now tell me again,
is it me or your "Noona"?
I'm going to start eating for now.
What? You said you were taking
the civil servant exam.
Ever since I started your old job,
the production work has been fun.
I also met many musical theater people
through Sang Ye.
I may not be able to be a choreographer,
but I want to go into production planning.
That's great!
I was wondering how a dancer
could sit at a desk all day.
Good job.
Why are the two of you whispering
and leaving me out?
Na Soon Nam, you didn't answer.
Is it me or your "Noona"?
Noona, please help me out
with your boyfriend.
Producer Cha.
Go on and eat.
I even made that porridge that you like.
Hurry.
How did you make all that
and still dress up so well?
Gosh, can the two of you stop being
so cheesy over there and come eat?
Let's go.
Who is it? I'm going to kill myself
because I can't get a job.
Who is Hyun Jae, that said there would
be a suicide party here?
I received a strange invitation.
Is it possible to meet my dead Hye Soo?
Gosh, they said it was the last
Christmas party.
I thought there would be
young people here, but what is this?
These are all people
that are going to die.
I was in a coma for 20 years.
And I woke up one month ago.
I'm sure I was 18 years old...
Take a look at these wrinkles
around my eyes.
They're telling me that I'm 38 years old.
You said you gave up your dreams of art
because you need a job, right?
And you said that the woman you were with
for eight years left you?
So, you dated for eight years?
Oh my!
Have you ever kissed?
I was on my way to confess my feelings
to a boy from my church.
But I got in a car accident.
I feel so sorry for you, Ma'am.
Your daughter died three years ago.
How will you ever forget her?
While I lay dead for 20 years...
they say that my mother lived in the
hospital, as well.
When you lose time...
it means you lose everything.
My name is Hyun Jae.
In English, it means "the present".
Which can also mean "gift".
Hyun Jae, or this moment right now...
It is a gift.
Your play was a huge success.
How do you feel now?
Do you have plans for your next project?
I'll do a detailed interview another time.
- Can you sign this for me?
- Please sign this!
Wow! Cha Hyun Suk really is successful,
isn't he?
He sure is.
Let's give this to him later.
Let's go.
- Picture, picture.
- One moment please.
I have to accept flowers
from my girlfriend first.
What is this, Notting Hill?
Let's go now.
Sang Ye, that was great.
This is for me?
Of course. You were my boss once.
You worked so hard all that time.
What do you mean?
She enjoyed it all.
Now she's no longer
an Assistant Producer.
She already has an idea for her project
after You & Now.
What? That's not true.
Good job.
What are you doing with my noona
standing right there?
To a girl with a boyfriend, at that.
You better not do that
with other guys either.
Soon Nam...
Oh my! They must have something going on.
I'm not sure if I can leave my store
in a part-time worker's hands.
Go on, President Ha.
I'm here.
Why are you here again?
Gosh, we better have a time sheet
for Cha Hyun Suk in the store.
I'm not busy now that the show is over.
Let's go see a movie,
since Dong Chul is here.
No, I can't. I have somewhere to go.
Where are you going?
Hey now. Don't try to know everything.
I'm a mysterious woman.
How long will you take? Where...
I'll be watching your employee here!
Watching you.
You're too much. Too much!
Go home and sleep, man.
I'm watching a movie.
Hyun Suk is still here?
He's here all the time.
No Ra!
Oh, Lawyer Lee. You're here?
Can I have a serving of spicy rice cakes?
Ha No Ra's spicy rice cakes.
Okay. You're eating here, right?
I came by earlier and you weren't here.
So I went back to the office.
He's a lawyer at a law firm
across the street.
He only comes to eat when No Ra's here.
One other thing...
He's 35 years old.
What?
I'm busy. Why don't we talk inside?
Why did you tell me to come outside?
I want to make a wish.
A wish?
A wish for the time capsule.
But I got it right.
I got it right too.
Let's continue being happy.
You're next to me right now.
Okay, okay.
Tell me. What's your wish?
Tell him that you won't sell
spicy rice cakes to him.
Are you saying I shouldn't
run the business?
I was kidding.
But shouldn't you do something about it?
You were all smiling at him.
Of course I should smile at customers.
Should I scowl at them?
Oh, I guess you're right.
Then introduce me. As your boyfriend.
- Why should I?
- What do you mean why?
So that the punk Lawyer Lee
will stop showing interest in you.
Really? I thought he was interested
in our spicy rice cakes.
He seemed like he was interested in me?
Wow, that's crazy.
You seem happy about it.
If someone is interested in me,
isn't that a good thing?
Hey, did you not see those fans at my
show that came at me like a swarm of bees?
I'm totally popular.
But what did I do then?
If you're going to be like this,
don't come here anymore.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Are you guys fighting?
What's even worse is,
he didn't even leave after that.
Cha Hyun Suk, No Ra seems upset.
Most men keep a closer watch
on their girlfriends than this.
Have a seat, will you?
You should go
after you finish eating this.
We're supposed to meet tomorrow, remember?
Let's eat first.
I'm hungry from laughing so much.
Hey, Ha No Ra.
We ordered the same thing,
but the ingredients don't look the same?
Seriously, they are missing in mine too.
Only Cha Hyun Suk gets them?
I won't stand for discrimination.
Hey!
Hurry up and eat and leave already.
Ha No Ra, aren't you playing
way too hard to get?
What if Hyun Suk gets away?
If he gets away, then he gets away.
Do you mean that?
Being overly cautious and being
nice to someone
doesn't make that person like me more.
You can't force someone to like you.
Hyun Suk is important to me,
but my life is also important.
Goodness, so you secretly put a
deep fried seaweed roll in Hyun Suk's?
Ha No Ra, you're more charming
than I thought.
Hey, that's why I also said
he's important to me.
Stop laughing. My goodness.
I'm so embarrassed. What do I do?
[Second Time First Love]
They are really good.
Should we upload it now?
I just drew them for fun.
People look at this amateur forum
for fun too.
- Should I press send?
- Wait, wait.
What should I do?
[It's been posted.]
I won't tell anyone.
Someone just commented.
Really?
"I'm curious why Cha Dol
is being that way."
"I look forward to the next one."
Awesome.
Wow, that's amazing.
Even on a Sunday,
the students look busy as ever.
Oh.
It's supposed to be four guys and girls.
Without you, it won't work.
It's not that I don't want to. I can't.
Didn't you guys break up?
What happened?
Let's go somewhere and talk.
I can't. I have to go to the library.
You know already.
I got 2.5 this semester because of an "F".
I need to study. I'm going now.
Does the kid's girlfriend know
that you're the kid's mom?
Why would I tell her that?
It'll make things uncomfortable.
Then I shouldn't feel uncomfortable
doing this.
If you don't want to answer,
you can leave.
Right now!
He must be truly crazy!
Why don't you stop now, Professor?
First, remove that hand.
Those bodies belong to those girls.
Wow, we have ourselves
a second Joan of Arc.
Ma'am, are you going to look for a job
after you graduate?
Hey!
I've never once seen you dance
on a public stage before.
You're doing something you want to do,
so who cares if you're 20 or 38?
With lecture being canceled,
we get to do things like this. I like it!
What are you thinking about?
Do you want to go to college again
now that you're here?
No.
It was good that I got to experience
going to college.
There are so many unforgettable memories.
Of all those memories,
the best one is me, right?
In some ways.
What do you mean?
I did learn many things because I met you.
Oh, is that right.
Then should we stay here a little longer?
So we can play together?
It's okay.
Didn't you say you have to go over
the script?
Let's go. To our spot.
Let's go.
Do you want to go play over there?
My friend here is sleeping right now.