Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
I don't feel very good
Nothing's looking as it should
Dad, Mom, Grandma, Grandpa don't know
who they brought into the world
I want to be someone
Do what no one else has done
So our sweet name will be
remembered by posterity
I like my own sweet name
I like the touch of fame
Sweden can be really good
Fix things up as they all should
Germans, Russians, Americans
We'll set them a good example
Of social democracy
Of a mixed economy
So Sweden's sweet name will be
remembered by posterity
Reform the world
Just from little Sweden
So we get well-known,you see
For our fine democracy
We'll have the touch of fame
Buy our film!! Buy it!!
The only film in two versions.
One yellow, one blue.
Buy the yellow, buy the blue.
Buy our film, 'cause there are two.
The same picture, yet different.
- Nice and ugly!!
- The yellow film.
- Big and small!!
- The blue film.
This is the blue version.
The blue version...
Madeleine, four, take three.
- What school did you graduate from?
- The Sigtuna private school.
- In the crown prince's class?
- No.
- You seem big-headed. Are you?
- The French Lyceum.
- For how long?
All my life, since I was seven.
- The French Lyceum.
- And after that?
Language studies in Switzerland.
I often go abroad, to France.
- You like France, do you?
- I love France.
- What do you do?
- I study French at the university here.
Look at me.
Now look into the camera.
BEWARE OF MERITOCRACY
Do you happen to know
who the crown prince's girlfriend is?
''Maj Hultén, Teacher, Age 34''
Many women find it difficult
to reach a climax in ordinary coitus.
The position doesn't matter.
On top, on the side,
sitting or whatever.
Just about any position is possible -
well, perhaps not while running.
But there are many ways,
just like for any other
physical activity.
Many people think
it's due to psychological reasons
that younger women
don't reach a climax.
Subconscious or even somewhat
conscious conflicts
cause them to forbid themselves
to reach a climax.
- That it's not ''nice.''
- Exactly.
- That's what I think.
Most girls think like that.
Oh, please!!!
You know how you'll look naked
if you just eat and eat.
''Vilgot Sjöman,
young director, age 42''
''Lena Nyman,
drama student, age 22''
Sex lesson two, camera two.
I AM CURIOUS
A BLUE FI LM
Marie,you had a question?
If homosexual women have sex,
is that also mutual onanism?
Yes, the word onanism, masturbation,
means self-satisfaction.
It's a bit difficult to call something
''mutual self-satisfaction.''
But it does describe what it is.
They caress each other's sex organs
so they both reach a climax.
Before, I hardly dared touch a girl
in case she'd think I was a lesbian.
The word lesbian is clear, then?
It means homosexual woman.
- I've never felt that, but-
- Never?
Do you touch people a lot?
Have you been
to a girls'boarding school
where it's even more
sensitive about homosexuality?
It's not the same at this school.
We go out, we meet boys.
It's not the same.
But take girls at boarding schools
in Switzerland,
with nuns chaperoning them.
- How much, then?
- Five thousand crowns.
Damn good it isn't ten!
We'll have to write an IOU.
- Cheapskate.
- And you'll have to pay it off.
Hey, can we get going?
Damn, he can't hear.
We can't wait for Ahlstedt.
Where the hell is he?
At Sandrew they make films
At Sandrew they make good films
I AM CURIOUS BLUE
Hell's bells!
It's embarrassing! You're making
a film on the Swedish class-system,
but you buy a black-market apartment!
- Look who's talking!
You just want it good for yourself!.
- Honey.
Isn't my place okay, then?
- Yes, but I want my own place.
Why?
- Hi. Am I late?
- Yes, we said ten to.
- Isn't it that now?
- It's a bit later.
Sit down, for Christ's sake.
Screen test : Börje Ahlstedt.
Director : Hortlund.
Action!
- You're the sales director
- Yes, I'm head
of the company's sales and servicing
in Stockholm.
And head of Bergengren Ltd.
Yes!!!
- You have a driver's license?
- Oh, yes!
- It's a basic requirement.
- Of course. I'm a good driver.
Are you interested in cars?
I like sports cars.
All kinds of cars.
How old are you?
- How old are you?
- I'm 28.
You get a love scene with Lena.
A love scene with consequences.
What kind of consequences?
I don't know.
I'll think of something.
- This Madeleine!!!
- An upper-class chick.
You're really hot for her.
Then you have something with Lena.
You think you'll be
a successful salesman?
Yes, I believe in my personality.
Yes. 1200. Then I'll make
350 crowns for every car.
- Can I get paid tax-free?
- No, that's not possible.
The term tax-free doesn't exist
these days, sorry to say.
The film company's fan-mail staff
sorts letters to stars and directors.
''From Lena Nyman's Fan Mail''
SKUNK PUSSY!
''Skunk pussy is your name.
Worse than a whore!
You and Vilgot should be tortured
in some sadistic way!
I hope you and your likes
meet a painful death!
If I were alone, I'd sign this,
but we all hope you go to hell!!''
''Director Vilgot Sjöman
cio Sandrew Films''
''Congrats on finding such a young
yet full-blown whore as Lena Nyman.
You must get good use out ofher,
both privately and for renting out.
We're a bunch of fun-loving guys who want
to hire the whore for some group therapy.
She's well trained for that.
Reply in the Nov. 24 of "Expressen",
stating the price and where
we can pick up the whore. ''
Good morning, Peter Wester.
Has Lena Nyman arrived?
THE NYMAN INSTITUTE
Hey, Lena?
Do you want Freud or Marx?
I want Franco.
Hi.
Take a look.
Imagine that's your mom and dad
and you're very young.
A tiny kid, lying there listening
to them talking about you.
You can't hear what they're saying,
but it's obviously about you.
The radio is on, too.
A popular song.
One your mom liked a lot
and went around humming
before she disappeared.
- But why did she run off?
- I don't know.
She couldn't take it any longer.
- But to leave me like that!
It had to do with her nerves.
Maybe she had a nervous breakdown.
I think she was in a mental hospital
for a while when you were little.
You know, she came from
the country, from Västergötland.
From a little place
called Lundsbrunn.
Her mother was religious,
a nonconformist.
The Pentecostal Revival Church
or something like that.
Oh, I must have hated her!
And longed for her.
May I ask you a few questions
for a survey for the Nyman Institute?
You have to branch out on your own.
Newspapers work too fast
and can't be trusted.
Science works far too slowly
and gets no results.
So you have to branch out
on your own.
Has the leveling of income gone
as far as it can in Sweden?
As far as it can?
No, but I don't think it'll go much
further in the near future.
Did you know that income leveling
here has stood still for 20 years?
No? It's true nevertheless.
Guess how it'll be in 20 years.
The income gap will be even bigger.
But not many believed me.
Especially not among the students.
They thought it was natural as hell
that those with a head for studies
should earn a lot more than others.
No storms yet
in our minds do dwell
BEWARE OF
They didn't fear
MERITOCRACY
an educational welfare state
that rewards the bookworms
and forgets everyone else.
I warn you::
Emphasizing education
will sharpen class boundaries!!
Some people were born
with limited prospects.
They're lost and awkward.
They lack the brains to study.
Others have a very different start.
They have the chance to study.
They have parents who encourage
and push them on.
Should they be rewarded for that?
Should they get better jobs?
Better wages?
A better position in society?
Is that right and fair?
Yes, I suppose so.
It's a question of performance.
Yeah, but you can't help being born
with a less-than-brilliant mind.
He shouldn't have to suffer for it.
But the thing is, does he?
Either I hadn't made myself clear,
or he didn't make any major
demands on justice and equality.
He shouldn't have to suffer for it.
But the thing is, does he?
I got the strangest results
from the workers.
They seemed brainwashed, like they'd
not heard the term ''class society.''
Class society?
How do you answer that?
No, I don't think so.
I think everything's okay.
You can't ask for more.
UNAWARE
No, I don't think so.
- I don't think so.
- You don't?
A guy from the Swedish Labor Federation
said it was due to Per Albin,
a prime minister during my childhood.
He duped the workers with dreams.
They're in a coma and won't wake up
even if the right wing takes power.
THE SWEDISH CLASS SOCI ETY
What gives a really low wage
in Sweden?
Being over 50, with only elementary
school, and doing manual labor.
Preferably a woman,
in a rural area. Then it's tough.
14,000 is enough for a woman,
at least in rural areas.
- Women should earn less than men?
- Absolutely.
CONTEMPT OF WOMEN
SECRET: OPEN:
- Where in Northern Sweden?
- Hammerdal, in Jämtland.
- And what's your occupation?
- Short-order cook.
- What education do you have?
- Elementary school.
Let me try and guess your income.
It must be around 1 1 , 000.
That's right.
- I'm from Blekinge.
- Another short-order cook?
No, I'm a teacher.
- What level?
- Elementary.
I earn 25,000.
Textile worker.
Let me guess.
- Say 16, 17, 18,000?
- Yes, 16-17,000.
- High school teacher.
- A fine profession, isn't it?
- Well, yes, I enjoy it.
- And you make good money too?
Fifty thousand?
- About that, yes.
- An architect.
- From Stockholm?
You make a very good income.
A gross income of about -
About 100,000.
You look energetic. Perhaps you do
a little extra work on the side?
I do. That's another 50,000.
Fifty thousand?
So you're up around 150,000?
Congratulations!
Would you please
stand over there by yourself.
I think we really must
do something here.
Don't the five of you
and the whole public
think we should give
a great big cheer for that
good old Swedish class society.
Swedes are moving away
from the church, thank God.
So why get married and buried in
church and have their kids confirmed?
I did a survey.
42% : need for something solemn.
21% : keeping up with the Joneses.
17% : spellbound.
8% : fear of God.
For Swedes, sufficient reason
to take part in religious ceremonies!!
Goddamn it!!
CHURCH WEDDINGS ARE HYPOCRISY
CONFIRMATION IS HYPOCRISY
CHURCH + BOURGEOISIE =
UNHOLY ALLIANCE
THE ONLY WAY TO GO
INTO CHURCH IS FEET FIRST
- Should we separate church and state?
- Yes, that's a good idea.
- What political party are you?
- I'm a Social Democrat.
- And yet you don't think so?
- No, it's too risky.
The church might really wake up!
Let them stay asleep.
PARISH REGISTRAR'S OFFICE
- Should we separate church and state?
- Yes.
Why?
The state doesn't want
to appear Christian,
so church and state
don't belong together.
For example, this office has
nothing to do with the church.
What's the point in my sitting here
copying birth certificates?
All this talk about reaching people -
it's just nonsense.
A few years ago there was a big fuss
about having female priests.
There still is.
But not among ordinary people.
It's among highly educated
theologians.
This movement within the state church
called ''Rally The Church'':
Have you noticed
what they're yakking about?
Female priests.
Abortion. Sex education.
Aren't they fuck-fixated?
Is it good or bad that the church
is losing its power in Sweden?
Good.
- Don't you believe in God?
- No.
- Have you left the state church?
- Why not?
- Plain laziness.
- Are you confirmed? Baptized?
- Both.
When I was confirmed,
I was religious.
- How did it go?
- Hi, Lena.
- I only got to borrow fifty.
- That's nothing! So what's next?
We'll talk about that later.
Lena, I've got myself a new home.
It's fantastic.
Come over and take a look.
I was embarrassed
that I hadn't recognized Bim.
God, I mean... Bim!!
I often slept in his chair up at
'Stockholms Tidningen' while he wrote.
Sometimes we'd both sleep there
before he went home to Bim.
He'd toiled for the socialist press
all his life, after political training.
For every paper that the
Labor Federation had bought up
and closed down.
Finally the bastards put
'Stockholms Tidningen' to death. Hell!!
- How much did you pay?
- Ten thousand.
- For all of this?
- It was all of my Labor Federation grant.
When I first met Hans,
he was working on a future project.
He wanted to shake
the movement up
and make the May Day demonstration
of 1974 something wholly new.
FRATERNIZATION!!!
SABOTAGE!!! NONCOOPERATION
The May Day demonstration was
a manifestation for nonviolence.
An unusually large crowd
took part or watched.
A sign of renewal within the
labor movement, said the organizers.
Nonviolence! Nonviolence!
Foreign Minister Torsten Nilsson
addressed a crowded stadium::
''We need thorough knowledge
of the techniques of nonviolence,
indoctrination of its 'catechism, '
and transformed military training.
We must not underestimate
the problems,
or make little of the risk
of reprisals by an occupying force.
The fact that loss of life
for us and the enemy
would be much greater
in conventional warfare
motivates our wish to introduce
new defense methods in an era
when society's development makes
military weapons seem antiquated.''
The earth is a pillow
Nice and soft and warm
There will Lena safely sleep
Animals and mankind dream
Silent in the arms of the night
It's the altitude.
I just can't.
Hans, what's the matter?
Why can't you?
Too much going on in my head.
I can't relax.
What are you thinking about then?
Is it Bim?
Yes.
- How strange you've become.
- You think so?
Why did you move out to the boat?
You talk so much about the group,
and about group feelings.
How the hell can you
isolate yourself out there with Bim?
Does it work out?
- Yes, it's so damned good with her.
- But are you happy with Bim?
- Sure. We yell and fight.
Then we make love.
- You yell and fight?
After that, it works fine.
But I'm no sadist.
Hell, that's not it!
Give me a break!
Yeah, but he's been impotent.
You can't play him as a wimp.
He'll end up a whining brat.
There has to be some power in the guy.
There can't be any power
in this scene. He's a total failure.
He's worked on the girl all night!
- All night?
A whole bloody night and he fails.
There's no power there!
He had that power years ago,
like we said!
Hey, he's Lena's intellectual father!
He's given her all the ideas
on nonviolence and the class society.
He's the one who educated her
and got her turned on about this stuff.
You screw up the whole situation!
Why ask me to make him impotent?
That wasn't my idea.
It was your idea.
I didn't go home with Vilgot.
I wandered around,
not knowing where to go.
All of a sudden
I started thinking about Börje,
and all the fun we'd had
in drama school
before Marie got pregnant
and they got married.
Then I just hoped time would fly
so I could phone him.
I was terrified
Marie would answer the phone.
Madeleine!
- Do you come here often?
- No!
- First time?
- Yes.
I go to Cecil's. No, not just go.
I have fun at Cecil's.
- Are you here often?
- I'm a regular.
- Ever been to Lorry?
- No.
-Jambalaya?
- Is Sweden a class society?
- I suppose so, to some extent.
Some people, like here,
see this place as something special,
when perhaps it isn't.
The name scares some off.
Just as well.
- I'm in advertising.
- Is Sweden a class society?
A class society?
No, I don't think so.
- Definitely not.
- So we have total equality?
- Yes, quite shocking.
- A shocking equality?
- So we shouldn't change anything?
- Definitely not.
Do you know who the crown prince's
current girlfriend is?
- I'm not the least interested.
- No?
Is sex the greatest joy in life?
- No, that's very-
What's the word?
- Do you have problems with Swedish?
- Yes, I just arrived yesterday. Sorry.
- Were you abroad?
- I live abroad.
- Where?
- In Switzerland.
Those who don't work
shouldn't live off those who do.
So that's a class society, then?
There's too much welfare support.
People laze around and get lots
of benefits. Those who work pay for it!
Damn it, it's all happening!
They want me and Marie to play the leads!
What kind of play?
An American hit.
Success, money, laughter.
A chance like that, of course -
Exactly. But your film!!!
You mentioned a love scene with Lena.
With consequences.
Yes, a love scene
with consequences.
Of course, a love scene without
consequences would be pointless.
What is a lawyer's annual income?
From almost nothing
to a couple of hundred thousand.
Then he pays 80% in taxes.
It's pretty fair that taxes
are as high as they are.
But a restaurant worker, for instance,
earns so many times less,
though the work is hard.
Is that fair?
No, it's not fair.
When I worked in a mine
or on a farm,
I paid lower income tax.
I worked more then but had less left,
even after lower taxes,
than now, when I work less.
Though people say I work hard.
I have more left over now,
and much more satisfying work.
- Can't we do something about it?
- You can do a lot about things.
It's all dynamics. We always revert
to differences and distinctions.
Madeleine! Hurry up.
We're leaving, Madeleine!
He's changed his mind again!
We're leaving town for two months.
- Hell, no. You and I have to get together.
- I know. But how?
How can I get away?
- Say you're staying with your mom.
I've used that excuse too often.
What the hell will you say, then?
- I have to go in now.
- But two months!
- What do I ask them now?
- Same thing.
- The IOU's fixed. I withdrew 5,000.
- Great.
But your mom will have to co-sign.
Then I have to go and see her.
I'll do it before we leave town.
I haven't seen her for a while.
Happy now you'll be getting
your own place?
Sure.
Go back to sleep now.
Be good for daddy.
I really messed up
on that screen test.
If he says he wants me
in the film, I'll say,
''No, thanks. Not interested.''
He can be sure of that!
- But he's counting on you.
He is?
We talked about our scenes last night.
- Last night? In his bed?
- Yeah, I'm living there.
- You can move.
- If I can borrow the money.
- Money, money, money!
- An apartment costs money.
Damned prostitution everywhere!
- Nice if we had a place we could go.
- Everywhere! We can come here.
I don't like being here.
When will Marie be back?
- Not before 12:00.
- Sure?
- I promise.
I'm hungry.
- Where are you all going?
- Lundsbrunn.
- Where's that?
- In Västergötland, I think.
- What are you going to do there?
- Search for Mom, he said.
- Who?
- Mom.
Suppose I'd got on Mom's trail
that afternoon.
If someone had said,
''She's up there at the new school.
She's a cook.
But the school's closed
for the summer. ''
Wrong trail, of course.
No, she's not working there at all.
She moved to Borås a year ago.
Now we'll go up, up, up
Up on our dawning love's
top, top, top
Come, come, come with me
She lives in Borås, is remarried,
and has a son of eight or nine
that I've never seen.
My halfbrother.
Grandma was a Revivalist,
and Mom tried to leave
the church as a girl.
Difficult to understand
that she had a hard time
leaving the church.
Through lies and deception,
they take Him
and crucify Him,
thus proving
the inherent evil of mankind.
But instead of letting mankind
suffer its just punishment,
Jesus went in His love
and said to his Father,
''Father in Heaven, you know me
and you see the evil of mankind.
Let me go down to earth.
Let me speak to the people,
and let me give my life for theirs,
Father, God in Heaven.''
And this was God's plan.
He told His Son to go.
Thus it happened thatJesus came
unto us bringing His gift of love.
We cannot understand this,
but such is the love of God.
Even if we cannot understand,
through faith we can experience it
and perceive that Jesus
purifies and sanctifies our hearts.
Amen.
We shall close by standing up
and praising the Lord.
Hallelujah!!! hallelujah!!!
Praise be toJesus!
God's blessing on you all.
I hope to see you here again soon.
Many other prophecies
also speak of the Day ofJudgment.
How people are busy with worldly
things and have turned away from God.
And, well!!!
how depravity prevails.
Like in the days of Noah and Lot.
- And depravity prevails now, then?
- Oh, yes. Very much so.
Especially in Sweden.
- In what way?
You only have to listen to what
they say in the news and so on.
What do you mean by depravity?
Immorality, thievishness.
REMEMBRANCE OF SUNDAY SCHOOL
What's immorality?
The Bible says
that all intercourse
outside marriage is immoral.
So you and your fiancée
have never had sex?
No.
You're not going to do it
until you're married?
No, we won't.
- Have you ever?
- No.
- Has your fiancée?
- I hardly think so.
Do you desire her in that way?
Of course. That's normal.
But since the word of God says
that it belongs solely in wedlock,
you comply.
You get the strength to do it.
The two of you
don't indulge in petting?
- No.
- But you kiss and cuddle?
- Yes, we do.
- But that's all?
Will you have children straightaway?
It depends if we can.
Not everyone can.
If you're not going to have children,
how are you going to prevent it?
- I don't think we'll try to prevent it.
- But if you did want to?
You just have to go without.
- Complete abstinence, then?
- Yes, exactly.
- No contraceptives?
- No.
No rhythm? No coitus interruptus?
Abstinence.
Take the population explosion,
for example.
The world's getting overpopulated.
How can we stop that?
Stop it!!!
I don't think
it's a question of stopping it.
As I said before, I don't think
we have a long time left.
The Bible says that
the whole world -
But shouldn't we do something
about starvation due to overpopulation?
- Of course. We'll do what we can.
- Like what?
We can send them contraceptives,
teach them birth control.
What the world needs most
is the gospel.
The gospels don't feed starving
people who have a baby every year.
Think about this:
A man who is saved
goes to heaven when he dies.
One who is not saved goes to hell.
But all those millions
in India and China aren't saved.
Are they going to hell?
The Bible speaks of heaven and hell
and those with no faith in Jesus.
So first they starve to death on earth,
and then they burn in hell!
They're children! ''Suffer the children,
for such is the Kingdom of Heaven.''
Jesus said so.
- First torment on earth -
- ''Suffer the children'', it says.
But!!!
Yes, that's a difficult question.
I was damned upset afterwards
and thought of all kinds of things.
Like the Catholics, they don't give
a damn about social change.
And the religions in India,
the caste system!!
Our own state church, that never
made a move for anything important.
QUESTION TO HUMANITY:
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO
WITH ALL THE RELIGIONS?
I never went to Borås,
though I was sure I'd find Mom there.
Mom, my halfbrother,
and her new man.
I just couldn't do it.
I had some very strange days,
floating around in thin air.
Anything could have happened.
It was frightening.
But nice, too.
They dropped me off
five hours later...
near Örebro.
Welcome to our
maximum-security prison,
built by order of the Swedish people.
''There is a refuge for all eternity
in His arms. Amen.''
I'll have to talk with
the social workers in Strömsund.
And in Gäddede,
to find out if there's any room.
Yes, do they have room?
What will your friends here
at the home say if you move?
- They never talk.
- Don't they?
It's as if they're deaf and dumb.
They're not exactly lively.
I'll have a look at that leg again.
That's the one that hurts, eh?
Like the joints are coming apart.
''Bertil Wikström,
General Practitioner, Age 45''
- The doctor's here.
- Oh, good.
- Sleep well last night?
- Better than in twenty million years!
- You're interested in prison welfare?
- Quite right.
- Do you know Torsten?
- Torsten who?
Torsten Eriksson, prison director.
The one who built Kumla,
''The Desert Fortress''?
May I come with you to Strömsund?
But you've got so much to load.
Torsten was a prison chief
for whom we're very thankful
He built Kumla Desert Fort
upon the plains of Närke
Strong he built the citadel
Everybody thinks he's swell
That's Torsten
Running, running away
Torsten was a radical
even in the '30s
Hens are clucking, roosters crow
''Radicals are ninnies''
Wall was built 'bout seven miles high
Faggots seen by TV-eye
And Torsten
Running, running away
Very gentle are the screws
never using axes
Out of work, they got the news
Now they're paying taxes
Radicals becoming men
Old gods can be used again
By Torsten
Running, running away
This institution here -
we ought to blow
the damn thing to pieces.
- Why?
- I don't believe in prisons.
Not huge ones like this.
- What sort of transport is that?
Prisoner transport
on their way to me. My patients.
What do you think will happen
with prison welfare, then?
In the Medical Journal recently
a colleague of mine, Karl Grünewald,
peeked at the Prison Board's
building plans.
They were scary.
Evidently, from a therapy aspect,
the institute that's to take over
from Långholmen
is worse than Kumla.
And the next prison up
in Härnösand is worse still.
The planners apparently have
no knowledge of behavioral science.
It's only financial considerations
behind the whole system.
They build a factory around it
and think it's the perfect solution.
Who's that?
A newcomer. She rents Svartön.
What a smashing hat.
She reminds me of the actress
Gunnel Broström.
Wait here a minute, please.
Peter, dinner's ready.
Bring Johan up with you.
Tell Daddy dinner's ready.
Okay, Lena, you can come in now.
Women, you know. Why aren't you
allowed women when you're in jail?
Does that seem a crucial problem?
Well, it is in the beginning.
But it dulls off after a while.
- How's your leg, by the way?
- No trouble, really.
Except if I've been carrying
heavy stuff. Then it aches.
- Why are you here today, then?
- I'm being released soon.
You get problems
with your sleep and nerves.
- ''Release fever'' you call it, eh?
- Right.
You brood over such a lot of things.
I asked to stay a while,
and I stayed with Bertil and Anna
for two days.
I asked around about prison welfare.
Nice people. Or stupid, or smart.
I got the feeling that no one thought
about what kind of justice we have here.
They're pampered too much.
So it's just getting worse.
They commit crimes
just to get in here!
What was Ulriksfors
in pre-prison days?
Originally, a wood pulp factory.
Then it became a textile factory.
Does the municipality benefit
from the prison being here?
I think it does.
They employ
a lot of people from this area.
It's unlikely any company
would move here
into those huge premises.
- What's a lawyer's annual income?
- I wouldn't know.
- Can you guess?
- No.
- What do you think?
- They must make quite a bit.
-And a textile worker?
- They don't make much.
-A waitress, then? Annually.
- I don't know.
It depends on
what town she works in,
the type of restaurant, and her age.
But it's a lousy job with lousy pay.
- Do you have lousy pay?
- Not anymore.
Why not anymore?
- Did you go to university?
- Did you?
No, the university's in my pocket.
- You earn a lot with that education?
- Yes. Didn't you know that?
Can you sleep when it never
gets dark at night up here?
Yes. I sleep very well.
If you need anything,
like drinking water,just come up.
- Do you know what a prisoner costs?
- 30,000 a year, on average.
- Do you keep figures in your head?
- Not at the moment.
I've locked them up for vacation.
- Do you have a guilty conscience?
- No, but Swedish society does.
- Really?
- Ask yourself!.
If I had a gun,
I'd knock that chimney down.
And the tower.
The whole bloody system.
Thanks. You forgot noncustodial.
Concentrate!
- I am!
- You're not!
It's pointless just saying
a prisoner costs 30,000 a year.
Compare with noncustodial care,
20,000 people costing 60 a year.
- A retake?
- Yes!
He's crazy.
He demands total
concentration on the picture.
Nothing else is allowed to exist!
I know he's a bastard.
Are you sleeping with him, though?
I said, are you sleeping with him?
Oh, that!!!
If I don't, I might just as well
tell him about us.
You have to stop that!
Impossible till the film's finished.
Grand Hotel, Strömsund.
You can be without a little while!
Do you miss me, Lena?
A lot?
I miss you.
I miss you so.
Bye, then.
We'll have time to fly down
to Stockholm and be back Sunday night.
I think the class society ought
to irritate the Social Democrats.
It itches like hell.
Like scabies.
''The socialist itch.''
Sweden is a boastful country.
Our socialism is just showing off.
Prison welfare is just an example
of how amateurish we are
when it comes to looking
after people.
I must attack the idea
of general prevention,
the groundless thesis that people won't
commit crimes for fear of punishment.
What did Mom say?
Did she send her regards?
- No.
- It would be nice if she did.
- Hey!!!
- Yes?
- When are we finished up here?
- That depends on you.
Why is that?
Depends on how much you're
prepared to put into this job.
You're losing your spirit.
That scene today with Gunnel Broström -
You were so absent.
- How about you, then?
- You just faked everything.
- You've changed a lot, too.
Have I?
But you admit you've changed?
There's something holding you back.
- Not that I know of.
Time to find out, then.
You're accommodating on the surface,
but there's a barrier you never cross.
Is this the way it's going to be?
- No, this is no fun.
But we had it good before.
Didn't we?
Or was that just fake, too?
No.
No, it didn't feel like it.
Lena, what is it you want to do?
- What do you mean?
Finish the film? Stay with me?
Finish the film and then leave me?
Have you thought it through?
Okay, so now I'm not allowed
to touch you!
I'm singing no longer
ofkisses and sweet words
of marriage and rings
Darling and lover
are only small play words
Having no worth
they've lost their meaning
You were the first
the last, and the only
So said my heart
from the very first day
But I've given you back now
the ring that you gave me
Bright rings of gold
are nothing for me
I was so blue-eyed
so young and so lowly
I was a baby
that just couldn't see
You had those others
I wasn't your only
The love that I gave you
you just threw away
But my heart is mourning
And longing and hoping
Longing and hoping
Against all,just for you
That you'll understand me
And then you'll come back, love
My heart is hopeless
It won't learn a thing
But I know I must make
this heart of mine strong
A tough girl is what
the men all long for
Is it good that the girls sit here
and the boys stand over there?
- It looks a bit stiff, but it's okay.
- So it's okay?
Otherwise the guys can't see
us girls if we all just mingle.
- What do the guys do all evening?
- I can't really answer that.
They're mostly driving around.
I mean on a dance night?
Most of those who can dance
are up dancing, but tonight is slow.
- Do you buy booze before the dance?
- Of course you bring a bottle!
Definitely!
- Why?
The broads up here are so shy,
so you have to loosen up a little.
I was in the liquor store and bought
five whole bottles of brandy.
Excuse me. Gosh, you're tall.
How tall are you?
Six-four.
Full-grown.
- Do you go out to pick up a girl?
- Yes.
- Do you usually get one?
- No.
It's a drag.
What do you think of a girl
who sleeps with you the first night?
- Good.
- You like it?
Sure, if she's good in bed.
Otherwise it's a drag.
- Bad.
- You think she's bad, then?
It depends who the guy is.
If you meet a guy who wants to,
do you let him?
I don't think so. It depends.
- On what?
- On the boy and other things.
- I wouldn't.
- How many dates first, then?
More than one, anyway.
- Should girls save sex for after marriage?
- No.
- What do you think?
- Definitely not.
- Oh, so they should get practice?
- Right!
Should the girl or the boy
take precautions?
- Who should take care of that?
- The girl.
Well, the guy.
Both.
Which do you prefer,
a rubber or a diaphragm?
- What?
- Rubber, diaphragm or the pill?
The pill's best.
- Are you on the pill?
- No.
- Too shy to ask a doctor?
Should the boy marry a girl
if he gets her pregnant?
Not necessarily, if they find out
they don't like each other.
Well, that's a damn problem.
But it should be tried in court
and that.
If the guy loves the girl,
he should take care of her.
If he doesn't, he should forget her.
- Do you believe in marriage?
- No.
- Have you been married?
- But don't you want children?
- I already have one.
- How old is it now?
- Thirteen.
Thirteen!
I'm doing a scientific survey.
Can I ask you a few questions?
Sure.
- How old are you?
- Twenty-nine.
So you were how old
when you had your baby?
Just turned 1 7.
- A boy or a girl?
- A girl.
''Lena Explains
Nonviolence to Sonja''
FRATERNIZATION!!!
SABOTAGE!!! NONCOOPERATION
It's just as shallow out here!
Christ, it's muddy.
What a lousy lake bed. Hell!
Are there crabs in here?
- No,just fish.
Come on!
Hurry up! I'll give you
a swimming lesson.
Don't you dare? Come on!
I had dinner with Sonja and Elin
every day for a week.
Cloudberries?
It was the first time that summer
I felt like staying in one place.
- God, that was cold!
- It's so peaceful here.
Not a soul for miles.
- I'm so muddy!
Rinse off before you get dressed.
- Do you know Sonja Lindgren?
- Yes.
Did many condemn her for getting
pregnant when she was only 17?
Goodness, no.
I can't imagine that.
- I hardly think so.
- You don't?
Did you?
No, there's nothing!!!
nothing wrong with that.
- You don't?
- Not me.
That belongs to another century,
judging like that.
- Another century? The 19th?
- Yes.
I don't think people are so strict
nowadays. Not people in general.
When I went into the hospital,
they wanted me to take the elevator.
I refused.
''I'll take the stairs.
You take my bag in the elevator.''
Then, in the labor room,
I refused the bed and everything.
They all seemed to look at me
as if to say, ''What's she doing here?''
I thought, ''You go on laughing.
I'll manage this myself.''
You know how it feels.
Not a soul gives you a kind look.
They all think you're filth,
not being able to keep out of trouble.
Hell, only 1 2:00.
I'd sworn I'd get a few hours'sleep
before Sonja and Elin came to get me.
We were going fishing for trout.
But it was just too light up there.
Damned mosquitoes!
Lena!
MESSAGE TO
THE PRISON BOARD:
YOU HAVE STOPPED
THINKING RADICALLY
PRISON (WELFARE) FACILITY
The earth is a pillow
Nice and soft and warm
There will Lena safely sleep
MARCH AGAINST IMPERIALISM
USA - Murderers!
Franco - Murderer!
Viva Ho Chi Minh!
Here comes the socialist movement's
march against imperialism,
symbolized here by a snake.
Africa :Uhuru means freedom.
Portugal out of Africa!!
Volvo in South Africa::
''Apartheid's value lasts. ''
Fire Wallenberg!
Fire the financiers!
Franco, executioner
of the Spanish people.
Crush the right-wing junta
in Athens.
Spread the revolution in the US.
Indonesia is the CIA's gas chamber.
One million people murdered.
It was awful meeting them all again.
All I wanted to do at that moment
was go into hiding.
Workers of the world unite.
Fight for world peace.
Is there a party here?
No, Lena's going to live here.
-Just for a couple of days.
- It doesn't matter how long.
The thing is, where will you sleep?
That's all arranged. Over there.
Hans!
- What is it?
- She gets the right-hand cabin.
- Stop nagging. She'll be in here.
- No, I said!
Put her to bed yourself, damn it!
Let's see if we can find you
a place to live.
- I can't live at home right now, so -
- That's fine.
I don't want to be any trouble.
Oh, no! Hans often has guests.
He's awfully kind.
Yes, he is, but!!!
- What is it?
- It itches.
A doctor in Strömsund
said I had an allergy.
An allergy? Let's have a look.
Only here?
- No. My armpits and fingers, too.
What is it? Move.
I'm going to put -
Bloody pacifist!
Nonviolence, eh?
You're crazy.
- What the hell. You win anyway.
- Win?
You know very well.
I brought Lena here.
I know her
and I want to help her.
You and your damned pseudo-psychology!
- Go and help her your way, then!
If you can.
I've managed Lena before.
Before, yeah!
- Come here.
- I want to sleep.
I don't want to hit you.
Tired of fighting
Half would be enough
We're turned on and off
like lights
Men and beasts alike
The same damned family
Is the pillow big enough for us?
Let us rest now
Shut up in Babel's Tower
People are all blown about
I am one of them
The samejunk and weed
None of us are good enough
I'm one of them
The samejunk and weed
The wind sends me where it will
- Come here.
- Where's Bim?
Asleep.
Come in and sit down.
I want to talk a bit.
It's so damned difficult
to talk about these things.
Lena!!!
You're so sweet.
It's such a mess!
I can't stand this damned fighting.
- Before you go any further-
- What are you doing here?
- I want to talk to Lena!
- I know, but I want to see something.
Leave Lena alone!
You've got nothing to do with her!
I'm going to look at your allergy.
Give me your hand.
A magnifying glass! You're crazy.
Just what I thought.
You've got scabies.
Scabies! The doctor said
it was an allergy.
That's no allergy. It's scabies.
I wonder if you've infected anyone.
- Infected?
- It's catching, in a warm bed.
I almost think you've made up
this scabies to stop us.
Shut up!
I took the part, then.
The part of a car salesman.
Even though I'd sworn I'd say no
and Marie asked me not to.
Börje.
You sold Mr.Johansson a car,
and he's very angry now.
Hi.
Can we talk somewhere?
I'm off now. I can give you a lift.
The car's in the garage.
- What did you say you have?
- Scabies.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
Thanks for the scabies.
- Have you noticed anything?
- You bet! I itch all over!
So you've got it too.
But I might not have infected you.
- Who else, then?
- Maybe you gave it to me!
- Guys always get it from girls!
I know that much about scabies!
- So it's a girl's disease now, eh?
- You've slept with lots of guys.
- And you with lots of girls!
- Were you with anyone before me?
- Yes. And so were you.
- So what?
- You could have gotten it then.
You gave it to me.
And my kid. Bloody hell!
- You've never talked about your kid before!
- Damn, damn, damn!
Bloody hypocrite.
You disgust me!
You're so disgusting!
No matter. We have to do
something about it.
You just call St. Göran's clinic
for an appointment.
Number 27.
THE SOCIALIST ITCH
''!!!we no longer require
your services!!!''
- Do you work at BMC?
- I've just been fired.
- What will you do now?
- Don't know.
Damned prostitution everywhere.
Your number, please.
Step up, please.
Sit on the paper.
One heel in each.
- A bit further forward.
- Give me her card.
- What are you here for?
- I itch. I think I have scabies.
How long has it been?
Two or three weeks.
Move down a bit.
I thought it was mosquito bites.
I itch and I can't sleep.
Your National Health Card, please.
- Have you been here before?
- No.
- You have any discharge?
- Nothing I've noticed.
- You'd notice if you did.
- Then I don't.
Your name is Börje?
- Occupation?
- Car salesman.
Former.
- Are you married?
No, why?
Depending on the examination,
other family members might
need an examination.
- No, I'm not married.
- Unmarried.
Residence as stated here -
- If I were married, would she!!!?
- The doctor decides that.
- No, I'm not married.
Move down a little more.
A bit more.
I can't examine you unless -
That'll be three crowns.
There, then.
Get up, please.
Wait outside for the results.
No alcohol, sexual intercourse
or petting during the treatment.
Stop!
We should be a bit ahead of them.
Back again.
We need speed.
- We should have started earlier.
- Do it, then.
Reform the world
Just from little Sweden
So we get well-known,you see
for our fine democracy
- What are we doing tomorrow?
- The last scene. Lena meets her mom.
- Who plays her mom?
- Gudrun Östbye.
Now we'll go up, up, up
Up on our dawning love's
top, top, top
Come, come, come with me
and we'll have so much fun
Buy our film!! Buy it!!
The only film in two versions.
- This was the blue version.
- The blue version.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org