Dad, your phone call.
Just wait a moment, who's calling?
The court.
Forgotten.
Calling from the court?
The Medical Association promotes
dad to be the committee member.
To solve the family problems.
Such as divorces, heritages,
arguments, etc.
This is not a easy job.
Dad loves to be a negotiator.
l'm forced to listen to him.
The court starts at 1 :00 today.
To spend the whole afternoon.
l get troubles for myself.
Tokyo Family Court.
Family Problems Migistrates.
You come out here.
You'd know that father-in-law has
been looking after my daughter.
We never have any
unacceptable requests.
My daughter was just born.
You just wait here.
l remind you.
We are from the same hole.
Why do you disturb us?
You are only the son-in-law.
lndifferent from the others.
Although you are not registered.
lt is his blood.
Listen to me.
What is this case relevant to you?
Shut up, listen to me.
l think you need to discuss.
But please listen to me today.
We have to convince dad first.
Otherwise the lawsuit finishes today.
Please stay here for a while.
Wait.
l said it so clearly.
l don't know your relationship
with dad.
We don't mean to ignore you.
Convince dad first.
However.
l am the magistrate here.
l am sorry, excuse me.
Shit.
Dad, don't be angry.
Anyway l must keep it.
l am sorry.
Anyway l don't care.
Can outsiders bother the business?
Sorry, dad is always impulsive.
Yat says something to convince dad.
Dad, in fact.
Bastard.
We have discussed.
We hope dad can accept our requests.
To formally submit the declaration.
Anyway l don't care about your ideas.
This declaration is enforced by law.
Dad you say that.
Means you don't admit that
we are individuals.
Why can you say
some mature words?
You only peep on my assets.
All are not loyal.
How come?
Dad.
We also understand dad.
The whole Japan is also feeling
worried as you are.
Right, but you are too rude dad.
Brother, do you agree?
Does it mean l am mad?
Not that.
So why don't you listen to me?
You have to care of mum.
Go back, we go home.
Mum, please don't cry.
No one want to see this.
We don't want to quarrel.
Do we come to lose face?
Yat, say something.
Don't look like a man.
Too bad.
l am really sorry.
Bothering you.
lt's OK, this is my job.
Here is for solving family problems.
Even the quarrels between couples.
And quarrels between
fathers and sons.
Can see anything.
This is so-called everyone.
Sometimes it needs a third party
to solve the problems.
lf everyone is honest.
There'll be no mistakes.
Our job is to listen.
And try to give advise.
l have a suggestion.
You continue to discuss,
we try to judge.
Tin, get ready.
Please wait at the corridor.
Dad...
Ridiculous, without
my permission to do it.
This quarrel is complicated,
hard for you.
lntroduce first.
The Law Society and the
Medical Association Yuen.
How are you?
How do you do?
Talk about the details of
declaration first.
Time is running late,
let me say it.
lgnore the name and address
of the client.
Say the aim of the declaration first.
The aim of the declaration.
Chung.
ls requested not to use the assets.
The case is.
The victim is Chung's wife.
Chung in June last year.
To the radiation format the bomb.
Feels so frightened.
ls sick of worries.
September in the same year
he needed to leave home.
lgnored the objection of the family.
Bought 480 miles land in Chow.
To build some strange houses.
November the same year.
Knew that the place might be radiated.
To stop the progress.
As a result.
Make the Chung's family
to suffer a loss of 7.4 million.
But to his strange behaviour.
He didn't feel sorry and became mad.
Chung wanted to find a piece
of peace land on earth.
ln South America.
Planned to migrate to Basil.
ln order to implement.
He declared to use all the wealth.
The family therefore applied for
an injunction from the court.
lf it lasts.
Chung's behaviour will destroy
the family life.
So we have this declaration.
This declaration affects us a lot.
This is not kidding.
Dad can't use the assets.
By law the wife is the guardian.
How about our daughters?
Don't worry, Chiu.
Nowadays the young can do.
Please call the victim to come.
Mum...
l don't go in, you make the decision.
No way, mum is the victim.
Must turn up the meeting.
l don't want to quarrel.
Be good, don't waste time.
Are you Ms Chung?
This way please.
The elder son Yat.
Please.
The second son Yeen.
The elder daughter Haa.
l am Haa's husband.
Outsiders can go in.
l don't plan to listen.
Chun.
What?
What do you see the bombs of
radiation and hydrogen?
Why do you ask that?
Answer me first.
Afraid?
So frightened.
Really?
Everyone is frightened.
So why do you look ''don't care''?
Needless to say?
This is not under control.
Ching, give me some rice.
Coming.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
However.
Someone is planning to escape.
Don't joke.
That man must be mad.
l disagree.
He is absolutely not mad.
What is this case?
ls this about the case
in the morning?
What is the result?
Nothing.
For you.
320 for 7 tonnes.
Mrs. please.
ls No 2 Canton Gas?
ls older than our No A1 .
12% coals.
The deferred cheque is OK,
to catch the right time.
How much?
1 7500 for a tonne.
Recently the transportation
fee is increased.
9% coals.
The gas experiment in
Tokyo is finished.
How about the boiling
water yesterday?
No such case.
Deduct 1500 for me.
lmpossible?
Pay cash tomorrow.
You are great.
Yat, be careful of the incinerator
at the workshop.
l said many times already.
We'd collapse for this price.
This is dad's idea.
Brother, don't make Shek proud of it.
Kwai, what did you say?
You are soft to be cheated brother.
You need a guardian.
Children shut up.
We forgot brother is an adult.
Four of you guys.
Went to the court for what?
What?
Just calm down.
l am impulsive.
Stupid.
Stop, don't make unhappy.
Who is that man?
Tung's Kong.
Does it need you to say?
Do you know him brother?
How are you Mrs. Chung?
Make up your mind?
You were worried before.
l was shocked to listen to his plan.
Maybe he was in a hurry.
He might feel regrets.
lt's true when seriouly
thinking about it.
His decision is not easy.
But the world is strange.
Some people quit.
Some people do.
This is my neighbour.
He has a good farm there.
Don't disturb.
l have thought it over.
This is like to examine in person.
l want to let you study first.
But that is a good place.
You look.
That is your house.
Really.
This looks comfortable.
Whose is it?
Please come in.
Why does dad come here so early?
How are you dad?
Lost the lawsuit?
Stupid, don't need your concern.
This pay for this month.
This is not good not for dad
to use the assets.
The decision is not human being.
l want to show you something.
l saw the farm film last night.
lt looks good.
Honestly l feel better.
Better to have seen.
They didn't say anything.
Like this.
You also bring mum's board.
To migrate to Basil.
Dad.
No thanks.
Anyway l am too much.
l don't want to be a burden.
As long as dad can pay
some living costs.
lt's OK for me to stay in Japan.
l don't want to be a burden.
Don't bull shit.
You probably...
However.
You just feel good.
Dad will handle.
Dad...
St. Paul.
Mui.
Studying Geography?
The farm is near the city St. Paul.
Don't be exciting after
seeing the film.
Although dad asked us to go.
But l don't feel so.
This may be disgraced.
Stupid, what are you doing?
Nothing, let me say something.
How much for the
purchasing fees this month?
l want to talk to you.
We have to migrate anyway,
why have to purchase?
Stupid.
However...
Understood.
l'd rather die.
Who said going to Basil?
City St. Paul? No joking.
l don't really understand.
Why are you against me?
l am the host in the family.
How can you criticize my way?
Can't you follow me?
We don't need your concern.
l'm responsible for the family.
Laughing at what?
Dad is funny.
Your bureautic saying
makes people stay.
Don't you want to go?
Really don't go?
That's right.
Why do you do that?
Which one...
The second trail is on the 23rd.
Hold earlier?
The clients ignore the warning
from the court.
To carry out his plan.
His family said they couldn't wait.
That's right.
Please tell Mr. Wat.
Giving you more troubles.
Mr. Chung, express mail.
There'll be a typhoon today.
You are back.
Dad's plan is not thorough.
Although he wanted to buy
a house there.
How to solve the money problem?
lt needs a good reason to migrate.
lt's funny to be afraid
to go abroad.
ln fact we can give him the money.
l directly talked to the Ministry.
This Basil migration plan.
Just can be done silently.
Stupid.
Although we have no money.
We can buy farms in Basil.
What do you mean?
The farm lord wants to go home,
it's simple.
Just do the barter.
This is illegal.
The law doesn't say.
Anyway, this is a clever way.
Found any seller?
Got it.
You say first.
Anyway your dad thinks it over.
Just follow your dad's plan.
Listen to your dad's explanations.
l think it's not bad to migrate.
Many people want to go to Basil.
lt's not easy to buy a cruise ticket.
Excuse for my words.
You don't really understand
our family.
Please think it again.
We are now so good.
Satisfied with the current situation,
do you think so brother.
We were brought up in the workshop.
We don't want to leave.
Can't imagine a day
without workshop.
The workshop is my blood.
lt's painful for me to drop it.
We understand dad.
- SORRY, THE ORIGINAL VOBSUB WAS CORRUPTED HERE -
- - p D i ffig h pi
For our sake to migrate.
We thank dad in heart.
But also need to care about
our feeling.
l teach French, what can
l do in Basil?
The workshop employs workers.
You can't see the danger.
Dad, fate is not under control.
Everyone will die.
What radiation? Can we care?
Brother is right.
l accept the concept of death.
But l don't want to be murdered.
Dad, l have a question.
Only we got o Basil or...
Yeen.
l must ask this.
Recently our relationship is bad.
Still remember the man we met
at the corridor?
l don't want to let them down.
All because of dad.
l need to take care of five people.
Two wives, two children.
And a child of the passed wife.
l certainly want them to go.
lt's so ridiculous.
We can tolerate, it's bull shit.
You'd also talk to mum clearly.
How can you let mum cry?
You should know it dad.
You are so wild.
Selfish and not considerate.
Don't ask us to be the victims.
Just go to Basil alone.
And bring all the wives and kids.
We won't listen to you.
You are a bad son.
Dad, stop.
Miss, thank you.
Where is the boss?
Dad?
Dad went to the court.
lsn't that finished?
Today is the critical moment.
Where is dad?
Has he gone home?
How come?
Let him go.
That means we win.
That's only can stop him from
using the assets.
What do you see Yeun?
Just make it.
Please wait.
l have another thought.
This injunction.
ls only applied to addicts.
Now he's only afraid of radiation.
ln general this is.
But he's abnormal.
Doctors said he's OK.
But his words are abnormal.
This is the quarrel point.
We feel uncomfortable to the bombs.
l believe you have the same feeling.
Am l right?
But we are unlike Chung who
is worried too much.
No underneath house is built.
And no migration to Basil.
lt's not difficult to understand
his feeling.
Everyone is different.
How can we say easily
that he is wrong?
l think the judgment must
be realistic.
Chung has a view.
But his family also has its ideas.
This is human rights.
lf we don't control him.
He must sell the family assets.
The family will lose support,
which causes problems in living.
l just make the judgment in
accordance with the report.
That's right.
To prevent any accident,
we must do that.
We must stop him from
using the assets.
This is reasonable, however...
Your decision is childish.
Chung's words have meaning.
We even don't understand his family.
Only let Chung suffer the fierce.
This is the worries to radiation.
Have we considered other reasons.
Why can't we find
the root of fierce?
Worried?
Can't be observed.
Why do we migrate
to Basil so quickly?
l just want to leave the
disguisting radiation.
lt's worthless to be killed
by this stuff.
So l have to run.
Only chicks use the emu policy.
Sons are a good example.
Emu?
Unfortunate, we all are chicks.
So how should we judge?
lt's hard to do.
Yuen.
How about this suggestion.
Anyway Chung is so impulsive.
Personal effort is so little.
We may not go there.
Now we use the law to stop him.
l think this is the best way.
Tin, please let them in.
This way please.
Dad, it's eleven.
What are you looking?
Death ashes.
Dad, won't you change?
lt's bad if you also want
to go to Basil.
You read it in the viewpoint
of a Japanese.
l think it may cause
a trend to retreat.
Chun.
lt's sorry to think about it.
The lawsuit?
Don't worry.
Does the old man stop?
lf he appeals.
lt will be sent to the High court.
Can dad relax for a while?
The dream of 30 years comes true.
The winter is unique.
l also want to stay here.
Do you want to sell the farm?
You really want to buy this land?
How much for this hill?
Here is about ten yards.
Equal to 20 small towns.
How much?
8.2 million.
Can buy 4000 yards in Basil.
Any deposit?
As soon as possible, there are
other buyers.
How much indeed?
1 .5 million.
Yeen, it's not good to do it?
No other choice.
Don't know if dad has other ideas.
lt's no use even you know the
PlN number of the safety box.
Brother, what to do?
What to do?
We can't do anything.
Give me some water.
What to do?
We are careless.
They don't know dad is injuncted.
They thought it's OK
to give dad credit.
ln total how much?
Really don't know what they think.
How much?
Pei Asso 300 thousands,
Chung lron 430 thuosands.
Ko 160 thousands, Sam 150 thousands,
Hau 200 thousands.
ln total how much?
1 .2 million.
1 .2 million?
Dad is great, he gathers
it within 2 days.
Shit.
Yeen shuts up.
You are stupid.
Can you lend me your
mum's term deposit?
What's wrong with dad?
ln need, lend me first.
No hurry.
l know it earlier.
lf dad wants to appeal.
You can't win the lawsuit easily.
Bull shit, l must win.
l am not optimistic.
Don't you save?
That term deposit is important to me.
The rights of the shop?
Anyway mortgage it for
300 thousands first.
Repay you soon.
No way.
How about Mui's account?
No account, it's bad to mortgage
the house.
Of course to give her an account.
Just let her register first.
Where is the flowers?
l am sorry.
Not hard working.
What?
Have you received a cheque of
200 thousands?
Can you lend me some money?
This is dangerous.
l have no other choice.
A difficult question.
Take it out.
Take what out?
Don't pretend, it's money.
All spent.
Have finished all?
lmpossible to spend 200
thousands in half a day.
You don't look brave.
Really haven't.
Don't pretend.
Only these money?
All spent on women.
Bull shit.
lt will be disclosed soon,
l'll go to check.
To hide to avoid dad.
To save a little every month.
Although it doesn't help much.
lt's not enough, forget it.
How? lt's not dad's temper.
lt's useless for insufficient money.
Although we don't know
what happened.
lt's a man to say the truth.
lf l were him, l'd do it.
You are good, so honest.
l like you this point.
No hurry, l wait for your reply.
l can't just wait here.
l plan to go back in a few days.
You don't worry.
A good man keeps his words.
You just go to visit my farm.
l'll be the host.
You go back tonight.
When my dad said to migrate to Basil,
l seriously objected.
Then there's on fire, the whole
home was burnt.
lt's all fate.
Man is lonely.
The feeling of your son can
be understood.
To repay them these money.
And discuss peacefully.
Anyway you are father and son.
Thanks.
Wait, brother.
The money can't be given to dad.
This is against the court decision.
Don't you understand?
The court ordered that dad
couldn't use the assets.
What do you bull shit about?
Don't be angry, anyway
it's not our fault.
Dad, you deserve the suffer.
Your impulsive action makes
us hard to follow.
We ask for an injunction
from the court.
No one can use the assets
without permission.
Dad is illegal to do it.
Dad's appeal is useless.
But the money is collected by dad.
Dad can't have the money.
Yeen.
Apologize to dad.
Now the traffic is convenient.
lt takes a few days to Basil.
That is a good man.
You should feel OK.
Sorry to disturb.
Are you Mr. Chung?
Still remember me? l am Yuen.
From the Family Migistrate.
Mr. Chung.
What can l do for you?
l am sorry for that, honestly...
Don't waste my time.
l just want to tell you.
And that bastard who
made the decision.
l am not scared of any radiation
or hydrogen bombs.
But you open your eyes
to see clearly.
l am now not feeling good.
All because of you.
You made me like
a bird in a cage.
Just to think about the radiation.
Wait until die.
And felling worser and worser.
But l can't do anything.
lt's the most painful in life.
That judgment is disappointing.
l can't forget it.
But do we have other choice?
lf l were not a magistrate.
To think about it in the
viewpoint of Chung.
He can't avoid the tragedy.
No one should be blamed.
Since there are radiation problems.
And he is more sensitive
than the others.
ln fact that man.
ls very careful.
This time he is stuck.
This boring weather persists a while.
The report says because of the
hydrogen bomb experiment.
Father-in-law should know it.
You should know better about
the effects of radiation.
Better to be in USA and Russia.
The radiation ashes come to Japan.
Because of the weather.
Radiation'd be gathered in Japan.
We are the people.
Don't know what to become.
Hair drops.
Bone deteriorates.
Then is all bad luck.
We saw the nuclear bomb before.
lt's cruel to watch.
Have you seen?
A little child.
Shut up.
Sorry for my words.
You understand everything and
decide to migrate.
However...
Worried to an extent.
lt's useless to worry
if you are broke.
Don't stand on your point.
Let's be good.
lnfact you are fortunate.
lt's not bad to stop you from
using the assets.
Now you are having a quiet life.
Where is the fortune?
Asleep? Thanks.
What? No way.
Haven't slept for a few days.
Murderer.
Japan's become a radiation country.
Only invented this stuff.
Where to go?
Go home.
You also follow me.
We should know what to do?
Doesn't matter. Follow me.
Sorry to disturb.
What does dad ask us to do together?
l beg you all.
Follow me to Basil.
The whole family go there.
Maybe l am mad.
But the radiation pollution is close.
Don't know when the war comes.
ln war times no one can go.
No one can go.
Take the chance now.
lt's not late to go now.
Can't let the children die.
We can't let the radiation
kill our children.
lt doesn't matter me.
lt's useless if you don't care.
But think for the children.
l have thought this way.
But l also love you.
How can l leave you?
Please follow me.
A letter from Basil.
They are kind to invite.
lnvite us to get the living rights.
He is our saviour.
Just go to Basil.
Strangers also care us.
Beg you.
To follow me to Basil.
Please listen to me once.
We go together.
Dad is doing of our future.
l also beg you.
To go with dad.
Dad is the host and alright.
Dad is pro-active.
And he is considerate.
To go with dad, Yat.
Yeen, go together.
Hau, let's go.
What are you silent?
No objection?
Dad, l follow you.
Dad.
He's tired, just give him a rest.
Give him some medicine to sleep.
l don't want to be here.
Solve the account problem first.
ln case dad passes away.
Have hm have a will.
A will?
Did sister take away all the assets
at her marriage?
At that time we need to expand
the workshop, she didn't take much.
We need dad's instructions.
Otherwise it's not lawful.
You always talk about
laws recently.
A will?
What do you say?
They ask dad to have a will.
So disgraced to bless dad.
Wait.
What is relevant?
ls it clear to do that?
Yeen can't be proud.
Tired of her.
Let her sleep in my room.
This way, come on, it's OK.
This way.
Dad calms down today.
However...
We stop here today.
What do you mean?
The family judgement.
Should let us attend the trial?
We are busy at home, busy to talk.
We also don't want to talk it now.
This say makes people feel sorry.
But now it's the time.
Let me talk to dad.
lt's not easy for dad to calm down.
Doctors say it's good for dad.
lt's bad to ask a patient
to have a will.
Really sorry.
Shouldn't come to disturb.
Look mum, the child looks like dad.
Mum, don't you mind?
What are you saying?
Mum is not angry at you indeed.
For the sake of the children.
Stupid children.
You look.
All are your relatives?
Your dad is so unacceptable.
Taken at the beach during
the vacation last year.
We were very happy.
Really very happy.
But it may be too happy.
l think that may cause tragedy.
So we have been very careful.
Now here it is.
Really don't go to Basil?
Don't try to convince me.
Mum and Kwai want to go.
ln term of money...
lt's bad if mum cancels
the injunction.
So what do we do?
How much can we share the assets?
But staying in Japan
to be against dad.
Not having too much.
What to do with the workshop?
l seriously object
to sell the workshop.
We must keep the workshop.
Just get the workshop on hand.
Please.
Where is Chung's workshop?
ln Chuen.
Shit.
lt's really bad.
Please explain it clearly to me.
Why don't you pay attention?
Must be forgetten.
All forgetten?
Dad had reminded you many times.
Check carefully before you quit.
You look why it is so bad.
Boss, l am sorry.
No, l did it.
Dad, it's not the time to save them.
The police are coming to investigate.
l made an arson at the workshop.
lsn't it too exciting?
Mum, you go to take a rest with dad.
You won't leave the workshop.
Not willing to go to Basil.
lt solves the problem if
the workshop is destroyed.
Kwai.
What's happened?
Tell me what's happened?
Why do you remain silent?
What's happened?
Kwai, what?
Kwai found the fire first.
What did you see from the window?
Who left the workshop first?
Tell us.
Kwai.
Don't cry.
lt doesn't matter.
We can build the workshop in Basil.
Boss.
So you don't care about our lives?
Boss, what do we do?
Just leave us?
All bull shit.
What do you plan to do?
Sorry, it's my fault.
You also go to Basil.
l can just consider myself.
l must save everyone.
Please migrate with us.
You go with us.
Where is the money from?
lt's a question if
the workers want to go.
Dad doesn't think of consequences.
The Basil man hurts us.
To pretend a good man.
He only wants to get dad
there to be a victim.
Anyway l won't go.
Understood.
So l refuse him.
We can live in anywhere if
we are hard working.
Even migrating to Amazon.
Even no guarantee of safety in Basil.
There is no absolutely safe place
on the earth.
400 tonnes of hydrogen bombs
can destroy the world.
There are not just 400 tonnes
in the world.
You can lie without responsibilities.
You won't think about it.
Dad is worried about our safety.
You are all selfish.
He burnt his home.
Wanted to get the compensation?
lt's not interesting.
He's really mad.
Please let me calm down.
Hydrogen bomb explosion?
How great is that.
Too worried, stupid.
Just let the minister worry.
Only to drop the earth
to avoid radiation.
To dad this result is not bad.
ls it Mr. Yuen? Thanks for your help.
No worries.
Coming to visit dad?
l can leave him.
l think the judgment was wrong.
lt's our fault.
Should bring this to the court.
Should have sent dad here early.
To all of us it's a good result.
You go to see dad.
Excuse me.
l am down to see the patient.
lt's the first time to come across.
Every mad man is the same.
But when seeing the patient.
The feeling is different.
He makes me feel uncomfortable.
Anyway he's mad.
Or we are really the mad man.
Please come over.
l am Yuen.
Thanks for coming.
Welcome.
lt's safe to stay here, no worries.
How about the earth now?
Human is living?
Life is going on?
lt's not possible.
Regrets if you don't escape.
Why don't they understand?
Must leave this planet ASAP.
Hurry to this planet.
ls it burning?
The earth is burning.
The earth is on fire.
On fire.
Burning.
The earth is destroyed.