Man:
Words are tools.
You use the words
to create,
but that doesn't
necessarily mean to build.
It means sometimes
we use words
to chip away
at ourselves.
Reporter on TV: New data suggests
that global economic recovery
is weakening,
as there will be fraud charges
against six Wall Street...
- Woman: Ronnie?
- Yes, baby?
- Are you okay in there, hon?
- You know I am.
- (laughs nervously)
- Are you sure?
Yeah.
Okay, I don't want you
to miss your flight.
I'm coming out
right now, baby.
- I would like that.
- Okay.
Reporter: In Chicago,
both the NASDAQ and SMP
are thinking of territory
at the close today...
- Hello. How are you?
- I'm in pain.
So you...
you need something?
Yes...
I do.
Shh.
Please concentrate
on what you're doing.
Remember
your train of thought,
the flow of ideas
from your brain
down to your pencil,
onto the paper,
into your eyes,
back into your brain,
and around again.
Boom, boom!
- Daddy!
- Hi, Daddy.
Team Princess!
Richard: A tingling sensation.
Is anyone paying attention?
- I'm proud of you.
- I wasn't scared.
I know.
I can see that.
(school bell rings)
Richard: Go enjoy your week
of freedom, people.
And remember, every time you crack
open that "Farewell to Arms,"
I have impinged upon
your freedom
and I am resolutely
not sorry.
- Dad, I need some money.
- Ron: Yes, yes.
Money, money, money.
Here we go.
Woman:
Miles!
Bye, Dad.
(speaking indistinctly)
- Bye. I love you guys.
- Girls: Bye.
I love you.
Timothy, this, my friend,
is your friend Richard.
We'll be celebrating
your birthday
on this holiday, yes?
See?
I did not forget you.
Big Sur, sir.
You have all the info.
Just look for the balloons
on the gate.
Meow, meow, meow, meow.
(rock music playing)
♪ There's no point in asking,
you'll get no reply ♪
♪ Oh, just remember
I don't decide ♪
♪ I got no reason,
it's all too much ♪
♪ You'll always find us ♪
♪ Out to lunch ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Don't ask us to attend
'cause we're not all there ♪
♪ Oh, don't pretend
'cause I don't care ♪
♪ I don't believe illusions
'cause too much is real ♪
♪ Stop your cheap comment ♪
♪ 'Cause we know
what we feel ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty, oh, so pretty ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Oh, vacant ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ But now ♪
♪ We don't care ♪
♪ There's no point in asking,
you'll get no reply ♪
♪ Oh, just remember
I can't decide ♪
♪ I've got no reason,
it's all too much ♪
♪ You'll always find me ♪
♪ Out to lunch ♪
♪ We're out on lunch ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty. ♪
(turns down volume)
Richard?
Richard:
Who could that be?
I wonder.
First thing he does...
turn my fuckin' music down.
- Richard, come here.
- Uh-huh.
- Uh-huh!
- (both laughing)
Yes.
God, you don't age.
What is up with that?
What, have you got a painting of
yourself in an attic somewhere?
Come on,
what's the secret?
For old times' sake?
Huh? Huh?
Maybe a drink.
To start, anyway.
Love the car,
by the way.
Very you.
Yeah, I bought it
from some guy
on the way
from the airport.
You know, just saw the sign,
and, pow... impulse buy.
I intend to destroy it
in the next four days.
Some things
never change, Richard.
What is it?
Timmy?
Jill's.
I've been
wearing it again.
Five years ago
this month.
God, has it really been
that long? Jesus.
I'm so sorry.
Every time I see you,
you say those words,
and I always believe you.
And you never try
to tell me to forget.
But, per usual,
it is my job
to remind you
that this week is about
forgetting all that,
if only for the moment.
Hmm? Mm-hmm.
(sniffs)
Oh!
He lives.
He lives!
Look, you cannot
be cynical
and expect to have
any kind of success
in this world
or any other,
especially if you
claim to be an artist.
I'm tired... sick and tired
of cynical artists.
(cell phone rings)
Ronaldo's here.
Uh-oh, my liver
just had a heart attack.
Richard:
Hey, if you need anything else,
I'd be happy to pick it up
for you in the morning.
This is her.
God, so pretty.
- She's all grown up, Ron.
- It's crazy, huh?
Hey, um, is she
getting cock yet?
I pray for your soul,
Richard.
You cannot pray
for a soulless man.
Oh, yeah? Ronaldo,
let me ask you this.
Yeah.
When your 16-year-old daughter's
hot friends come by,
do you ever think about
what it might be like
to fuck 'em in the ass
till they're cross-eyed?
- I told you! See? See?
- Shut the fuck up.
- Pass the blow.
- Told you.
Jesus, some things
never change, huh?
Hey, hey, I merely say
what others think...
- Mm-hmm.
...but fear to say.
You want some, honey?
No, don't tell Mommy.
(all laugh)
(snorting)
Oh, my God, look at this.
It's the first time in the history of
Internet real estate photography
the place is as big
in real life
as it was online, huh?
It's beautiful, Ron.
Perfect.
Let me know when you
want to settle up.
Ron:
It's already settled.
The rich are different
from you and me, Timothy.
Thank you, Ron.
We've always
been different.
I love you.
Ron:
You're welcome, by the way.
(laughing)
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
- Tim: I was there!
- Ron: You were not there.
- You weren't there.
- Of course I was there.
- I popped my head out...
- I'm the guy that gets busted.
- You get busted...
- I'm the guy.
I pop my head out...
'cause all I wanted...
- I ran off.
...to let you know,
'cause I was gonna
bail you out,
so I said,
"How much for bail?"
And he looks at me
and he goes, "That's him.
- That's him right there."
- "That's the guy!"
- Well, he was the guy.
- The cops fuckin' bust me, and...
You weren't there.
I don't remember...
- Of course I was there! I ran off.
- You weren't fuckin' there.
- No, you weren't there.
- (overlapping voices)
- The doctor is in!
- Hey, Doc.
- He certainly is.
- Richard: Yes!
- What and how much?
- Enough to treat the illnesses at hand.
- Welcome, my friend.
- My man, Ron!
Look at him.
He's beautiful.
Ron:
He can't afford a razor.
Someone get me a drink
while I urinate.
- All right.
- (rock music playing)
♪ This is an announcement
for the transcendental run ♪
♪ The train now standing
leaves for higher planes ♪
♪ Due to a derailment,
there will be no other trains ♪
♪ So why not hop
on this one? ♪
♪ Hear the porter's
glad refrain... ♪
So Amanda,
during her pregnancy,
is getting incredibly...
(clears throat)
Nauseous.
- And what do you think it was from?
- Do tell! I'm dying to know.
- It was me.
- Of course it was.
It was my scent.
No, seriously.
Four months
of her pregnancy,
I have to sleep
in the other room, okay?
But... but I have become
a professional masturbator.
- No, no, no...
- What the fuck is this shit?
What are we talking about?
I see you guys
once a fuckin' year.
- It's my life.
- Doc...
how's the world
of dating, pal?
- It is what it is.
- Oh, come on.
You sedate them, and then it's your
right and your privilege
to take what's
rightfully yours, correct?
- Oh, my God.
- Ron: I hope you're doing that.
Really.
Why don't you tell us about
what you told me about...
the 20-year-old woman?
Thanks, Richard.
Tim:
I don't think I can stay here for this.
- Come on.
- Amongst friends.
Tim:
I don't think I can stay here.
When you told me,
it just sounded like
you should fucking
get it off your chest, you know.
- I mean, you...
- Ron: What?
It was a one-time-only
thing.
And the girl came in
late in the day.
She was pretty,
to say the least,
and it had been
a while for me.
And I... used
anesthesia on her.
Yeah. Let's skip
to the part
where you sent
the receptionist home.
I did things.
I mean, I basically
lost control.
And looking back on it,
I really feel that
I shouldn't have...
- Oh, you fucker! Fuck you!
- (all laughing)
Alley-oop!
Slam dunk,
motherfucker!
(rock music playing)
♪ The man said childhood ♪
♪ It's in his childhood... ♪
Hey, fuckin' Scarface, how about
a little on this end of the table?
- Come on.
- ♪ It was out of control ♪
♪ I had the opinion
it was out of control ♪
♪ Oh, oh... ♪
It was that girl Emily.
She lived in the house
next to us.
Yeah, yeah.
And who was the guy?
- It was Simon... Simon Tuller.
- No, no, no, it wasn't.
You know, I actually
fucked Emily, just... and who else?
- Guilty as charged.
- Tim: I didn't.
- She gave me crabs.
- Ron: She gave you the crabs?
I fucked her boyfriend
Jeff Snyder.
Ron:
Oh, great. Well played.
- That's so fucking funny...
- What?
...because when
I fucked Emily, I gave her crabs,
which basically means
I gave you the crabs!
- Hey, fuck off!
- (laughter)
I banged her...
when I banged her,
I knew that I had
the fucking crabs.
- There you go, mac.
- (mock shrieking)
Here, take them back.
Here are your crabs back,
you fuck.
The gift that keeps giving, huh?
You still have 'em, sir?
You know how to get rid of 'em?
By the way, this is true.
You take a really good,
good lighter,
and you shave
one testicle,
and you light
the other testicle on fire.
- The critters run from...
- Critters!
...the burning testicle
onto the shaved one.
Okay, and then
you take an ice pick,
and you just jam it
into the fuckers!
Aah, aah!
True.
Is it possible
to have a conversation
that's a little
more serious?
- No, no!
- No!
- Come on.
- Fuck that.
That's what
I fuckin' hate, man.
Is people... we...
we can no longer
do and say the things
that make us feel good.
Yeah, that's what
I'm talking about.
Are you saying
that doing and saying
stupid things
makes you feel good?
Richard: You know what
I'm talking about.
Like, when we get
past 40,
we can no longer be honest
about what makes us laugh.
And if you're
a father, forget it.
You show any immaturity,
you lose all credibility.
Oh, come on.
Blah, blah, blah.
- Come on, that's pathetic.
- You are pathetic, Ron, because...
- What?
- You don't need to participate
in a conversation
that might be illuminating
because you're such
a powerful man.
Oh, no, that's not
fucking it, by the way.
I am here to talk
about Volvos...
- vulvas.
- Volvos!
(laughter)
- I got one of those.
- And schlongs.
Richard: ♪ Happy birthday
to you, Timothy! ♪
- Happy birthday!
- (voices overlapping)
Yeah!
Happy birthday, baby.
Happy birthday,
Timmy.
- Look at that.
- She's got a beard.
Of course she does.
Look it, she's got
a man-gina.
- See? I didn't forget about you.
- You never do.
I love you, pal. Happy birthday.
(kisses)
I guess I can die now.
Richard: Do it when no one else
is around, please.
- Thanks, guys.
- We're all glad you were born.
- Happy birthday.
- Timmy!
- (yelling)
- Here's to us.
- Us band of brothers!
- Jonathan: Yeah!
- Whoo!
- (rock music playing)
♪ I wanna be adored ♪
♪ I wanna,
I wanna ♪
♪ I wanna be adored ♪
♪ I wanna,
I wanna ♪
♪ I wanna be adored ♪
♪ I wanna,
I wanna ♪
♪ I gotta be adored ♪
♪ I wanna be adored. ♪
(wind whistling)
Man: Why do you dislike
rock 'n' roll so much?
Man #2: These days, it's a disease.
It's a plague.
It's been going on
for too long.
It's history.
It's not achieving anything.
It's just digression.
They play rock 'n' roll
at airports.
It's about as, like,
advanced as it can possibly get.
Man: But there was a time
when you didn't feel that way.
Man #2: It is too much like
a structure, a church...
- Man: Yeah, but there was a...
- Man #2:a religion, a farce.
Man: A time when you
did not feel that way.
- What made you change...
- Man #2: No, I've always felt this way.
Man: Even when you were working
with the Sex Pistols?
Man #2: I wondered when
you'd get round to that one.
- Ahh.
- Man #2: Yes, even then,
because the Sex Pistols
was going to be
the absolute end
of rock 'n' roll,
which I thought it was.
Unfortunately,
the majority of the public,
being the senile animals that they are,
got that wrong.
Man: Where did the name
the Sex Pistols come from?
Who thought
that name up?
Man #2: Some animal.
I can't remember.
It doesn't matter.
It's history.
Well, I think history
matters a little bit.
When you say "some animal,"
was this a member of the band...
History does not matter.
I mean, your program
is called "Tomorrow."
There must be a reason
behind that.
Man: Well, unless we remember
our yesterdays,
there will be no tomorrows.
Man #2: Getting back
to the public image...
(screeching)
(screeching continues)
(rock music playing)
(volume increases)
♪ Charlie don't surf,
and we think he should ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf ♪
♪ And you know
that it ain't no good ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf
for his hamburger mama ♪
♪ Charlie's gonna be
a napalm star ♪
♪ The reign of the superpowers
must be over ♪
♪ So many armies
can't free the earth ♪
♪ So, soon the rock
will roll over ♪
♪ Africa is choking
on their Coca-Cola ♪
♪ It's a one-way street
in a one-horse town ♪
♪ One-way people
starting to brag around ♪
♪ You can laugh,
put them down ♪
♪ These one-way people
gonna blow us down ♪
♪ 'Cause Charlie don't surf,
and we think he should ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf ♪
♪ And you know
that it ain't no good ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf
for his hamburger mama ♪
♪ Charlie's gonna be
a napalm star... ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf,
he'll never learn ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf
though he's got a gun ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf,
think that he should ♪
- ♪ Charlie don't surf... ♪
- (yelling)
♪ We really think
that he should ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf ♪
♪ Charlie don't surf. ♪
(laughing)
- Whoo!
- (laughing)
(voices overlapping)
- That was mine!
- Fuck you.
- English Beat.
- "Twist and Crawl."
- Whoo!
- Depeche Mode.
- Uh, "Personal Jesus."
- The Cure.
- "Boys Don't Cry."
- "Killing an Arab."
- X.
- Uh, "Johnny Hit and Run Paulene."
And I win, 'cause I got
15 points.
(others mocking)
(seagulls screeching)
(screeching)
Timmy, you all right
down there?
Wanna go for a ride?
- (engine roaring)
- Now!
Come on.
Whoo!
Come on, Timmy.
More, more!
- Gotta get a hard-on.
- I can't! This is so bad!
Fuck, yeah!
Fuck you!
- (Tim laughing)
- Whoo!
Whoo!
(laughing)
Come on, faster!
Let's go faster.
Yeah!
Whoa, whoa!
Whoo-hoo!
Richard: Ho ho!
This is really hard.
Whoa, whoa! No!
(both laughing)
- Are you dead?
- Oh.
- Fuck!
- Oh, fuck.
Fuck.
- Come on.
- Hold on, how do I...
Come on.
I'll radio for help.
- To the dunes, man.
- (both laughing)
- Richard: How are they gonna find us?
- They'll find us.
(hip hop music playing)
The best swimsuit
of all time...
- Cheryl Tiegs in the...
- The big areolas, like ka-kaw!
- Yeah, exactly.
- Fuckin' ka-kaw!
- She's wearing a hammock.
- Here's what I miss, okay.
- Yes.
- I miss pussy hair.
Yeah?
- Is that so fucking wrong?
- No.
Everybody looks like
a fucking Barbie doll.
You know, you don't want
to have a fucking machete
and get in there and just...
night vision goggles and shit.
You want a clean runway.
- Richard: Oh, yeah.
- Tim: Oh, my God.
Look at this.
(laughs)
(seagulls screeching)
- Oh, wow.
- This is the best I've felt all year,
- being here with you guys.
- Yes, indeed. Yes.
But I know it's because
I can't feel anything.
- Drugs.
- Maybe it's not.
Maybe it's... it's us,
being together.
- Don't just rule that out.
- That's why we do this.
That's right.
The question, Rich,
is that why we do this?
I love it.
I think it's fantastic.
I mean,
I look forward to it.
I plan for it.
I need it.
I mean, it's like
Christmas for me.
Or if you're
a non-Christian,
it's like your birthday.
Yeah, or if you're
a Jehovah's Witness,
don't celebrate birthdays,
then it's like the day you get married.
You know, it's slightly
less subdued than I imagine
the typical Jehovah's Witness
wedding to be.
But at your wedding?
(laughs)
My wedding.
Oh, man.
We are marooned.
We are stuck, man.
Why don't you have
a woman, Rich?
I mean, I know
you have women...
but, like, the woman.
Why?
Why do I need the woman?
Why? Why?
You know, you know...
to tame you,
to train you.
I'm... I'm trained.
I'm house-trained, you know.
(sniffing)
Untamed, maybe,
but I don't piss
on the carpets.
It's okay, man,
to let a girl love you.
Who... who wants this?
Hmm?
My mother?
She's...
You fuck lots of women.
Have you ever
truly loved one?
(sighs)
I love 'em all.
Can't love 'em all
if you only love one.
If that's true,
that's interesting.
Yeah.
You want to know
what I think, Timothy?
When they really
get to see me...
they don't like
what they see.
You make sure of that.
Maybe.
(horn honking)
- Richard: Whoa ho!
- There they...
- Whoa ho!
- Hey!
- Up here!
Hey, you guys!
Well played.
Porsches are known
for taking up sand dunes.
(grunting)
Not gonna work.
We've got your energy.
Richard:
Oh, help is here!
(rock music playing)
- ♪ It's easy to... ♪
- Here we go.
♪ Lay down and hide ♪
♪ Where's a warrior
without his pride? ♪
- ♪ We're gonna move real good ♪
- ♪ Yeah, right ♪
- ♪ We're gonna dress so fine ♪
- ♪ Okay ♪
♪ It's dog eat dog eat dog eat dog eat
dog eat dog eat dog eat dog ♪
♪ Leapfrog the dog
and brush me, daddy-o ♪
(men vocalizing)
♪ Makes me proud,
so proud of you ♪
♪ I see innocence
shining through ♪
♪ Makes me proud,
so proud of you. ♪
(slow rock music playing)
♪ Thinkin'
of blue thunder now ♪
♪ Singin' to myself ♪
♪ Thinkin' how fast
it moves... ♪
Wow.
♪ I was singin'
something ♪
♪ Out on Route 128 ♪
- ♪ Thinkin' how blue it looks... ♪
- A little artist.
♪ Singin' out loud... ♪
(man speaking indistinctly
over phone)
The SEC
and a government subpoena?
Jesus Christ.
- A subpoena and...
- (cell phone beeps)
(sighs)
(Ron groans)
- Need a drink?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Recognize anyone here?
(Ron laughs)
Oh, jeez.
Who the fuck
are those people?
(sniffles)
I don't even
recognize that guy.
Do you ever get scared?
What are you asking me?
I guess I'm asking you if your life
turned out the way you thought it would.
Look, I just want to have
a good time, man, okay?
I just... all that...
that dreamy shit,
it's not... it's just...
it ain't for me, man.
- Not now, not now.
- Very hunter and gatherer of you.
Well, you've always been more
evolved than me, Tim... always.
But being part girl
will do that to you...
help you to develop
your sensitivity, you know?
I get it.
Look, I just...
Richard:
Eyes closed, mouth open.
- Dilaudid.
- (laughs)
A morphine derivative.
I had a patient
who offered me money
for a prescription.
It changed the landscape
of my practice.
She had a lot of friends.
And this became
your practice
rather than the one that you imagined
you would have.
I remember
in college saying,
"You can write
about people,
and I can save lives."
Man: Mother Earth is pregnant
for the third time,
for y'all have
knocked her up.
I have tasted the maggots
in the mind of the universe.
I was not offended,
for I knew I had
to rise above it all,
or drown
in my own shit...
- How you feeling, big fellow?
- Fuck off!
(laughter)
- Tim: Oh, just...
- Great. This is great.
- Come on, the air, the birds.
- Oh, I love it. You kiddin'?
Are you kiddin'?
The best.
- (vomiting)
- (guys laughing)
Jonathan:
You okay, man?
Ron:
Hey, man,
it's a brilliant idea,
coming out here.
- Yeah.
- Oh, yeah.
(mocking)
"I got an idea, let's go fishing.
Let's go fishing.
Argh argh!"
Ron:
And the best news is,
we're gonna
be here all day.
- (Tim laughing)
- Jonathan: "It sounds fun!"
- Fuck you guys!
- We're having a reunion.
Give me a pole!
Let's do it.
What you got for me?
No, wait.
I'll take his place.
Hey, Timmy,
I think I got one!
(laughing)
Oh, shit.
So... this is
a reunion, huh?
We all went
to college together.
Jonathan and Richard have known
each other since grade school.
We meet every year
somewhere.
That's nice.
It's... it's nice.
- It's good to catch up.
- Sure is.
I left school
when I was 14.
The sea kept me
moving,
so I never had
any reunions,
except for
with my wife
after long
fishing trips.
She died 11 years ago.
Cancer.
So I spend
most of my days
out here
just drifting around,
trying to
figure things out.
I realize I was...
I was lucky
to have felt
something that looked
or smelled or...
resembled real love.
Most folks
never taste that.
I tasted it,
and it made
every day anointed.
Nothing mattered
when we were together.
And when we were apart...
I felt him.
I felt him
like my own breath.
Do you believe
in heaven?
I wish I did.
♪ All righty, boy,
all righty, boy. ♪
- Are you still writing?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I write.
I write all the time, Ron.
I write report cards.
I write
on chalkboards.
I write to the school board
and ask for more money.
And sometimes I write,
"Dear God,
when You get a chance,
can You tell me why I've got
nothing to write about?"
What does that
gibberish mean, man?
- (snorting)
- I'm a...
I'm an English teacher now.
For now,
I'm a teacher of English.
How is Amanda?
I tell you,
Rich, man,
sometimes I can't believe
that I chose so well.
I wake up with that warm body
next to mine,
and I just...
Yeah,
you're a lucky man.
She doesn't push me
or question me, you know?
We respect what we both do,
and it's defined.
I know my role.
But I still don't know
why I've done the things
that I've done.
I'm in trouble, Rich.
I'm in deep,
over-my-head,
drowning,
motherfucking...
trouble.
- You want me to go get the food?
- All right, yeah.
Sounds good, man.
(sniffles)
(blues music playing)
(whistling along)
Did you have
the large order to go?
Yeah, well, is there
anyone else here
who might have
my order?
- Just one.
- God damn, I bet you that's mine.
- (clicks tongue)
- Would you like to pay now?
Oh, yeah, ahem,
of course.
Would you like to go home
with my order?
(laughs)
I'm working.
And you should probably
work on your lines.
If I work on my lines,
would you consider my offer?
No.
(snaps fingers)
Yeah.
She likes me.
Looks like you're
feeding an army there.
(clears throat)
- Walk out with me.
- What?
I want you to take
that apron off,
throw it on the floor,
walk around the bar,
and leave with me
right now.
You're really high,
aren't you?
You say that
like you like it.
I'm gonna give you
my number.
I'm in town
for three days.
I got three friends.
We're harmless and fun.
Maybe you've got
three friends,
you want to come over,
it's up to you.
But, hey,
if you're planning
on throwing that away
and not calling me...
wait till I'm about
10 minutes away, okay?
'Cause I'm sensitive
like that.
Richard, I'm moist.
(screeching)
(hip-hop music playing)
You are a very sick man.
♪ Bass ♪
♪ Ooh, white, white ♪
♪ Ooh, white lines ♪
♪ Vision dreams
of passion ♪
♪ Blowin' through my mind ♪
♪ And all the while
I think of you... ♪
I don't think I've ever heard
anything like this.
It's one
for the record books.
♪ The more I see,
the more I do ♪
- ♪ Something like a phenomenon ♪
- ♪ Baby ♪
♪ Telling your body
to come along ♪
♪ But white lines ♪
♪ Blow away... ♪
All right,
you motherfuckers.
I can be reached
on my pager.
- Ron: Fair enough.
- (cell phone beeping)
Oh, ladies
will be here in five.
- ♪ Bass ♪
- ♪ Blow ♪
♪ Ticket to ride,
white line highway ♪
♪ Tell all your friends
they can go my way ♪
♪ Pay your toll,
sell your soul ♪
♪ Pound for pound,
costs more than gold ♪
♪ The longer you stay,
the more you pay ♪
♪ My white lines
go a long way ♪
♪ Either up your nose
or through your vein ♪
♪ With nothin' to gain
except killin' your brain ♪
- ♪ Freeze... ♪
- (yelling)
♪ Rock ♪
♪ Freeze ♪
♪ Rock, blow ♪
♪ Higher, baby ♪
♪ Get higher, baby,
get higher, baby ♪
♪ And don't ever
come down ♪
- ♪ Freebase! ♪
- I couldn't be more married.
- Do you still have sex with your wife?
- That's private, Randolph.
(laughs)
That means you don't.
I actually... I do.
He does, I know.
I know he does, a lot.
How the fuck
would you know that?
She's always
too tired to fuck me.
(laughter)
How do you have sex
with the same person
over and over again,
year in and year out?
So, versus what, like, having sex
with random people
over a long period
of time, huh?
I fucking love
that you just said that.
You know what...
the first time that I ever saw
my father have sex
with my mother,
I thought that
he was killing her.
How did they
explain themselves?
My father soothes
a seven-year-old's mind...
he got down on one knee,
and he said to me very gently,
he said, "Son, I was not
hurting your mother.
I was simply fucking
her brains out."
(rock music playing)
♪ Tear your hair
for your aggression ♪
♪ Fight in London,
risk detention ♪
♪ Master race
or masturbation ♪
♪ Causes natural
good sensation ♪
♪ Who am I to say
to the IRA ♪
♪ To the UDA ♪
♪ Soldier boy
from the UK? ♪
♪ Am I just a hypocrite ♪
♪ Another piece
of your bullshit? ♪
♪ Am I the dog that bit
the hand of man... ♪
Your garden variety
MX missile.
M for mushrooms,
and X for... X.
They're better
when you're sober
with an empty stomach
and no other drugs.
You sound like a doctor.
I'm studying to be one.
♪ I ain't never
comin' back ♪
♪ Baby, baby ♪
♪ Won't you hear
my plea? ♪
♪ Yeah, come on,
sugar... ♪
Holy shit, man.
You're letting
your demon out.
I'm on vacation.
Aah!
Turn it up!
(shouting)
(all shouting)
♪ Baby, baby, drove up
in a Cadillac... ♪
- Whoo-hoo!
- ♪ I said, "Jesus Christ" ♪
♪ "Where'd you get
that Cadillac?" ♪
♪ She said,
"Balls to you, Daddy." ♪
♪ I don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation ♪
♪ You're living in the past,
it's a new generation ♪
♪ And I only feel good
when I've got no pain ♪
♪ And that's how
I'm gonna stay ♪
♪ And I don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation ♪
- ♪ Oh, no ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
- ♪ Not me ♪
- ♪ Me, me, me, me, me, me ♪
- ♪ Oh, no ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
- ♪ Not me ♪
- ♪ Me, me, me, me, me, me ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no ♪
- ♪ Not me! ♪
Anyway, this rich guy Greenberg
moves into town,
and he's building
this ugly 25,000-foot mansion
right on the ocean
in front of my mom's house.
Here, hit this.
She's tried
to stop him legally,
but he just crushes her
with his money.
Fucker's putting in
a helicopter pad.
Hey, you know,
if the guy can live
like a king,
why the fuck not?
Why is total excess
equated with living like a king?
I mean, why do people
need all that shit?
'Cause the shit
is there.
That's crazy.
You... you actually
believe that?
Mm-mm.
I don't believe it, I know it.
No, you can't know something
if it's a choice.
Where did you learn
that college bullshit,
from your
philosophy professor?
I'm just saying people
don't need certain things,
even though they might
think they do.
How the fuck would you know
what people need?
Who pays your tuition, huh?
Who pays
your fucking rent?
Mom and Dad.
You're a little fucking infant in
diapers, you fucking bitch.
Why don't you come
and talk to me
when the naiveté
wears off, all right?
(glass clinking)
(slow rock music
playing)
♪ Walking back to you ♪
♪ Is the hardest thing that ♪
♪ I can do... ♪
Jane.
Jonathan, do you have
any idea what time it is?
- Um...
- 5:30 in the morning.
Miles is sleeping.
I just want to hear
his voice.
And you know
that Daniel works late.
Yeah, so he can control
the fucking world's oil markets.
How does he make
so much money
when the rest
of the country is so broke?
Are you drunk?
No, I'm fuckin' high.
I'm high as fuckin' shit.
You get together
with your old friends,
and you can't even pretend
that you're grownups.
I'm pretending
that you still love me.
Jonathan, stop.
I'm hanging up.
Jane, just...
just tell me again
how it went from you loving me
to not loving me.
♪ Just like honey ♪
♪ Just like honey... ♪
(phone beeps)
♪ Just like honey ♪
- ♪ Just like honey ♪
- ♪ Just like honey. ♪
Richard:
Hope, 'cause that's what a...
that's what paper is.
And you gotta stay
on top of it.
What kind of shit
do you write?
I just write stories, things that mean
something to me.
Ah, the personal stuff.
Oh, God, no,
he's so great.
I mean, he's...
he's really amazing.
And then so you...
you submit them, right,
to... to quarterlies,
crap like that?
My last one actually ran
in the "New Yorker."
We were all so proud.
Oh.
And then you'll write
another one,
and then you'll get
the heat behind you,
and then you...
that will...
that will push you through
to write the novel,
to type "The end."
And then
fucking what?
I don't understand.
I mean...
is there something
wrong with that?
You published a book.
I'd love to be able
to do that.
I was...
I was like that.
I was so fucking
excited about this,
and... and about that,
but you just...
you think it's gonna
be so fucking rosy,
so fucking rosy...
- Well, Jonah's not like that.
- No?
He doesn't think anything's gonna be
some certain way.
- He just loves to write.
- You don't have to speak...
You... you live in some
sort of disillusionment,
because it's easier
than being honest.
- Jonah: Wow.
- What are you hiding from, old man?
(laughs)
You think that he's gonna be like you
when he's older...
'cause it makes you
feel better about yourself.
I still love it.
♪ Factory towns ♪
(vocalizing)
♪ Oh, to be ♪
♪ The cream ♪
♪ The cream. ♪
Let me see your heart.
Tim:
You look...
you look just like
my sister Jill.
You should ask her
to come over.
- Then I can judge for myself.
- That's impossible.
She's dead.
She's gone.
How'd she die?
I know it hurts,
but you can tell me.
I killed her.
I killed her...
I killed my boyfriend.
I killed...
I killed them in a car.
(crying)
This place we live,
this is a state,
a stop on the way.
True nirvana only happens
when you die.
They were lucky.
Death is something
to attain.
Do you see them alive
when you close your eyes
to go to sleep?
Let me be her.
(wheels rattling)
(vacuum humming)
(humming continues)
- (razor buzzing)
- (faucet running)
(buzzing stops)
(seagulls screeching)
(shower running)
(shower continues)
(knocking)
No!
God, Tim!
Rich! Richard!
Ron, Richard!
No!
Help!
Help, help, help!
Oh, God!
Timmy! Timmy!
God, help me!
Get him down!
Help, Ron! Ron!
Ron! Ron!
Get him down.
- There shouldn't be blood.
- Help me out.
Hold his head!
Ron!
- Timmy! Tim!
- Let's go.
- Tim!
- Ron!
- Come on. Tim, Tim.
Come on.
Tim, come on!
- (grunting)
- Come on, do it!
Get it!
- Tim, Tim, Tim.
- (Jonathan crying)
Timmy, Timmy!
Wake up, Tim.
- Rich.
- Oh, God.
- Hey, hey.
- He's dead.
- What?
- Ron: What's going on?
- He's fuckin' dead!
- What's going on?
He's gone!
Would you fucking listen to me?
- What are you fuckin'...
- He's fuckin' gone!
- Ron: What happened?
- He's gone!
Our fucking friend is gone.
Let him be, let him be.
(sobbing)
- Tim.
- Okay.
He even shaved.
"25 years from now..."
(muttering)
What are we
supposed to do?
What are we supposed to...?
(paper rustling)
Motherfucker beat me
to the punch.
Somebody help me,
because I'm...
I'm lost here.
I'm not.
(scoffs)
I remember everything.
Senior year,
the room upstairs,
the green couch,
the slanted walls,
the Joy Division posters
all over the walls
- like it was yesterday.
- It was Timmy's idea.
He said, "Will we ever
remember this moment?
Will we ever have
friends like this?"
"Will we ever
feel this way again?
This alive, this free,
this possible again?"
Oh, God, I...
I'll never forget it,
and yet...
I forgot it.
We all did.
We all forgot it.
Tim didn't.
Look, we all said
a lot of things
when we were young.
- (laughing)
- Okay.
Okay, so this... this means
nothing to you?
Your word's no good.
Look, we're gonna call
the police now, right?
And say what?
That we signed an oath,
and now our friend is dead?
"Please come
pick up the body"?
Who gives
a fucking shit?
Fuck.
Timmy obviously did.
You know, he remembered
what we wanted to be,
and... so do I.
You're... this is insane,
by the way.
We're high.
We are high as shit.
Which is why we need
to just think this through.
Ron: Look, we just need
to come down, all right?
- Sleep it off, all right?
- I can't come down, okay?
Now, well, hold...
okay, okay, I'm confused...
shut the fuck up.
I'm confused.
Are we talking about
not calling the cops?
All our names
are on that note.
That piece of fucking shit
scrawl signified
means nothing!
I'm not the same
fucking fool who signed that.
Neither are you,
all right?
Things change.
No, you certainly are not
the same person, Ron.
What the fuck
does that mean?
Okay, so our bond
is no good to you,
a promise we made...
none of that
means anything.
Your dead friend...
(whistles)
It means we fucking
think about it.
It means that I am not
the same person.
None of us are.
You're not
the same person?
You're not the same
fucking friend?
- Fuck you.
- Fuck you. I'm a father.
- And? And?
- And so are you!
Jonathan sees his son
once every two weeks,
and his son calls
his stepfather "Dad."
You write your name
in blood,
and... and it means what?
Your blood means
hooey to you.
So, you go home, Ron.
Go to your mother.
Go to your wife,
who you love,
and you go explain to her
how badly you fucked up, okay?
You failed.
You disappointed.
And how badly
did you fuck up, huh?
You greedy cocksucker.
What did you do?
You a bank robber?
Hmm? Steal people's money?
A bank robber now?
Bang, bang, bang!
Ronnie the bank robber!
Tell us!
Did you go bad on us?
Are you like the hideous men
we read... Jonathan,
did our little Ronnie
go bad on us?
Yeah, hello, we have
an emergency.
What the fuck
are you doing?
Listen, someone
has committed suicide.
We have to call the cops.
We have to report this.
- That's...
- This is who we are.
If, when we wrote it,
we were not that...
Let me just
get this straight...
you want me to sign off
on some 25-year-old
idealistic
piece of bullshit
that I don't
even remember?
Richard, are you
kidding me with this?
This is not a reality.
This has nothing
to do with now.
- Tim is dead.
- No, Timmy died for his reasons.
That's right.
You know, guilt...
I know he could never
live with himself,
but he did it.
- He was weak.
- That was...
that was his choice, pal.
That was his life.
You know what...
you never followed through
on a motherfucking thing
in your entire life, not even then.
You know what we used to call you
behind your back, buddy?
"Rat Ron."
Rat Ron.
Because you were
a fucking rodent.
You were selling us tickets to concerts
that you got for free.
You were trying to fuck
Jonathan's girlfriend.
Rat fucking Ron...
always had to be the man,
the man with the plan.
Well, you tell me...
tell me, Rat Ron,
is that why you're
in so much trouble now?
You fucking loser.
Where are all
your best-sellers, huh?
Where are all your fucking best-sellers,
you fucking hack?
Did you forget when Rat Ron bailed you
out of jail when we were seniors?
You forget about that? Because your
mommy didn't have any fucking money?
Arty little Richard
with no fucking money.
And Ron had
all the money,
'cause that was
my fucking role.
You were art, I was commerce...
that's what you said.
- You remember that?
- Yes.
And you... how much money
did I make for you over the years,
you fucking
zombie quack fuck?
Richard:
Let me... let me try to lay this out
for you in a language
that you can understand, okay?
The way I see it,
you got two choices.
One: You can stay here.
Two: You can die there.
'Cause I got a feeling
no matter what kind of bullshit
you wrapped yourself up into, man,
you are in it so deep,
it is going to
fuck you in the ass
and swallow you whole.
This is insane.
This is fucking insane.
Oh, my God.
Fucking Timmy.
I think you
should leave, Ron.
I think it's best.
All right, I'm gonna go
pack up my stuff, all right?
I'm gonna take off. I'm going home.
(sniffles)
I just want
to make it clear that I left
before any of this
happened, all right?
All right.
(acoustic guitar music playing)
We should do
something about Timmy.
Amanda: Hey, Ron, it's me.
The police are here...
♪ The courage
of the coward ♪
♪ Is greater than ♪
♪ All others... ♪
Amanda: Now the fuckin' FBI
is here, so please get here.
I need you to call me,
please, please.
I have no idea
what's going on.
♪ A scaredy-cat
will scratch you ♪
♪ If you back him
in a... in a corner ♪
♪ But I ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ Am ♪
♪ A coward ♪
♪ I, I ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ Am ♪
♪ A coward ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ Am ♪
♪ A coward. ♪
This is all Timmy's.
That's good.
It's really beautiful,
Richard.
(wind howling)
Hey, fellas.
Captain Bob.
It's good to see you.
You, too.
Where's your buddy Tim?
He, uh...
Yeah, he... he had
some other plans...
- Ron: Yeah.
- Pretty sudden.
- Had to take off.
- Yep.
Gee, he must have
been disappointed to have to leave.
Guys: Yeah.
Captain Bob:
Guess he went home sour
'cause he didn't
catch any fish.
- (laughs) Probably.
- Probably.
Got so embarrassed,
he just took off.
Yeah, he said he had
some important business.
Hmm.
All right, well,
you boys take care.
- Ron: All right.
- See you around.
- Man: Oh!
- Woman: Oh, my God!
- Oh! Oh!
- Man #2: Jesus!
- Man #3: Somebody call 9-1-1!
- Oh, my God!
- Call 9-1-1!
- I got him.
- They're on their way.
Jonathan:
Come on.
Let's go. Live.
Let's go, live.
Live.
Woman:
What happened?
Captain Bob: Larry McCauley
had a heart attack.
- Is he okay?
- One of those guys saved his life.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I know 'em. They've been out
on the boat with me.
And they've been
hitting it real hard.
They are a motley crew.
Not from around here.
- Hi.
I'm Laura Boyd.
Sorry to bother you.
No bother.
What's up?
The Athertons
sometimes have me
pass by and check in.
I was in the area.
So there's just
the four of you here?
No, one guy took off.
But who's counting?
(chuckles)
Nobody.
Yeah, he, uh... our buddy had to go back
to Portland for business.
- Are you the doctor?
- No, no.
He's sleeping
after the heroics.
- Yes, and it was heroic.
- Yeah.
You know, I've seen
that Porsche somewhere.
Oh, uh, yeah,
my buddy,
he bought it off a local,
so probably...
- Right, yeah.
...seen it around.
And the other one's mine.
It's a rental.
That one?
That one there? That's yours?
- What's your name?
- Ron.
Why?
Something wrong?
No, no, Ron,
there's nothing wrong.
(engine starts)
You look like shit,
Jonathan.
I'm making a salad.
How long has
he been sleeping?
Hours.
Yo, Ronaldo.
Hey, man, um,
we got something.
You gotta try this.
I'm so scared.
Of what?
You mean Timmy?
- That cop that was here?
- What we're doing here.
Yeah.
Amanda left
some messages, man.
The feds are at my home.
I robbed clients,
but I never
cheated on Amanda.
I never cheated
on her ever.
- All right.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Never.
And, you know,
in the beginning,
I was trying
to help people, man.
I'm trying, you know,
to enrich them.
And then...
(sighs)
...something gets inside you,
some... some rationale,
you know.
And then you just take
a little for yourself,
just a little bit,
and then...
you know, one zero
turns into two and three
and more and more and more
and more and more, man.
More.
You can't...
it's just...
it's just a drug, man.
You just... you get high
and you drift.
Why'd you need so much?
I love taking care
of my family, man.
I was the man.
I was the man
for a while, Rich.
I wish you
coulda seen me.
I really wish
you coulda seen me.
Amanda... will...
will she forgive you?
No one will.
Will you do it?
- Fuck you, Ron.
- Please.
- Please. Do it.
- No.
- I can't do it.
- Don't... don't...
I have to do it.
I have to.
You don't have to.
You... you can go home.
You can face it.
I've tried, man.
I tried. I can't.
I tried to think
of myself going home
and s-s-seeing her
and having her
look into me...
in my eyes, and I...
I can't face it.
I can't.
You have to do it.
Please.
Come on.
Please do it.
I remember
when I met you.
You were
such an asshole...
- (both chuckle)
...but you were cool.
Yeah, you were
this dark guy
with his dead dad,
and I thought you were...
you were so cool.
You turned me on
to "Holiday in Cambodia".
Remember that?
You remember?
And I turned you on
to The Pretenders.
(laughs)
"You arrived like a day
and passed like a cloud.
I made a wish.
I said it out loud.
Everybody heard.
It was the talk
of the town."
Shh, shh, shh.
Stop talking now.
Okay?
- (groans)
- Okay.
There you go.
(groans)
- (groaning louder)
- There you go.
(muffled screaming)
(slow panting)
(razor tapping glass)
(sighs)
Is he awake?
(rock music playing)
Okay, I feel better.
What the fuck
are we doing here anyway?
We're not even here.
Fuck.
I fuckin' told him
to go home, you know.
I told him, "Go home."
Ronnie never listened
to anybody.
♪ I could've saved
some face ♪
♪ They think that
your early ending ♪
♪ Was all wrong ♪
♪ For the most part,
they're right ♪
♪ But look how
they all got strong... ♪
I fuckin' hate pool.
♪ That's why I say,
hey, man, nice shot... ♪
Pool's for assholes.
- (glass breaks)
- Can't handle your beer, huh, faggot?
(laughing)
♪ That's why I say,
hey, man, nice shot... ♪
Hey. Hey, man!
That's our drink,
asshole.
You made fun
of my misfortune,
and you made a gay slur.
Oh...
I drank your drinks.
Who the fuck are you?
How can that
possibly matter?
You're gonna buy us
two more fuckin' drinks, brother.
Or you're gonna buy
yourself a taxicab to the hospital.
I'm not buying you
anything.
My friend's a physician,
so I get treatment
right here
should I require it.
You're barking up
the wrong tree, asshole.
I'm your worst
fucking nightmare!
Wow, you need
new material, my friend.
"Barking up
the wrong tree"?
"Worst fucking nightmare"?
This guy.
You're joking, right?
Here, here, I'll give you one.
I'll give you one.
I fucked your girlfriend
so hard in the ass,
she cried... for more.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Dude, dude, I'm sorry.
That's been
used before, too...
(burps)
By all the motherfuckers
who fucked your cock-sucking
whore girlfriend
in the ass.
♪ That's why I say,
hey, man, nice shot... ♪
Punish me
for what I have done.
♪ A good shot, man ♪
♪ That's why I say,
hey, man, nice shot ♪
♪ What a good shot, man ♪
♪ A man ♪
♪ Has gun ♪
♪ Hey, man ♪
- ♪ Have... ♪
- (music stops)
(knocking)
(groans)
(knocking continues)
(unlocking)
- Yes?
- Mind if I have a word with you?
- Yes.
- I heard about the fight last night.
Bartender said
you got hit pretty hard.
Oh, yeah.
I deserved it.
See, I've got a problem
that I need to solve.
Yeah?
Yeah, your...
your buddy Ron
said that the rental
in the driveway was his,
but I checked it out,
and it belongs to a Tim Arthurs.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- That car there?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, that's Tim's.
Hmm.
We're gonna return it
for him, because he...
yeah, I don't know why
Ron would say that.
Right.
May I speak to him?
- Who?
- Ron.
Um...
no.
No, he... he had to go.
Hmm.
Yeah, he left
early this morning.
- How'd he leave?
- I don't know.
Taxi.
Ah.
I don't know.
I was sleeping.
Passed out.
You mind
if I look around?
You...
you really don't have a lot to do
around here, do you...
in the way
of stuff to do?
Oh, that's funny.
(clears throat)
Oh, excuse me, I got...
I got a question
about that old guy
from the diner...
how's he holding up?
His granddaughter Emily
says he's doing just fine.
Yeah? Glad to hear
he's hanging in there.
- Yeah.
- Jonathan: Hey.
- Richard: Hey.
- Jonathan: Is there a problem?
Just had a question
about your cars.
I was hoping I could talk
to your friend Ron.
- Ron...
- Ron took off early, yep.
Why are you here?
Cars, right?
Can I see your eyes?
Glasses.
Scotch, right?
So, how long you guys
thinking of staying?
We're leaving soon.
Tomorrow.
That's a good idea.
Fuck!
- Fuck!
- (glass shatters)
Richard!
We're out of drugs.
Oh, no.
- (cell phone rings)
- (sighs)
(engine roaring)
You know, I remembered,
but Timmy fucking did it.
He didn't forget.
He never fucking forgot.
I wanted to be the one.
I wanted to be the reason.
(seagulls screeching)
Go in there,
you give them this.
Don't say anything,
but if they ask,
you had a knee operation.
But they won't ask.
(echoing loudly)
(loud scraping)
Richard.
(quacking)
Oh.
Is that what
you're looking for?
Fuck 'em.
(toy quacking)
Here, I got you
something.
Is that a comment
on my chosen profession?
Let's go home.
- (touch tones beeping)
- (ringing)
Jane: Hello?
- Hey, Jane.
- Hi, Jonathan.
He's right here.
Miles: Hi.
(laughing)
Hey, buddy.
- Miles, how are you?
- Good.
Daddy took me
on a helicopter yesterday
because he had to meet
someone for lunch.
I was only
a little scared.
Miles,
I'm your daddy.
You know that.
We could see
the whole city.
Miles, Daniel
is your stepfather.
- I'm your father.
- What?
Promise me
you'll remember that.
Jane: Miles, come on.
We need to go.
Miles:
Oh. I have to go.
Miles... Miles...
- Mommy and Daddy said.
- Miles...
promise me you'll remember
I'm your daddy.
Bye.
(grunts)
(sighs)
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You're in my arms ♪
♪ Till there's ♪
♪ No tears ♪
♪ Your love is here ♪
♪ Your love is here... ♪
Miles:
I love you, Daddy.
♪ In this dark ♪
♪ You'll free me... ♪
Miles:
Don't pretend, Daddy.
♪ No pain ♪
♪ It has washed away... ♪
Jane:
I love you, Jonathan.
♪ And the world,
how amazing ♪
I love you, Daddy.
♪ Your love is here ♪
♪ Your love... ♪
(knocking)
(sighs)
I came to tell you
I can't do this.
Man:
We have main engine start...
four, three, two, one,
and liftoff.
Liftoff of the 25th
space shuttle mission,
and it has cleared
the tower.
Man #2: Houston, Challenger.
Roll program.
Man #3:
Roger roll, Challenger.
(indistinct radio chatter)
Man #2:
Challenger now heading down range.
(indistinct radio chatter)
Man #2:
Three good APUs.
Velocity 2,257 feet
per second.
Altitude 4.3
nautical miles.
Man #3:
Challenger, go at throttle up.
(voices overlapping) "If we can't
remember what this feels like...
(echoing)
What this feels like..."
- "One we want to live..."
- "We'll die..."
(echoing)
"As one..."
(screeching)
No, it's not right.
I gotta get in that house.
I need a warrant.
- Was it drugs?
- Yeah.
It's out of control.
I mean, it's not recreational,
I'll tell you that.
(police radio chatter)
(rock music playing
over stereo)
(music blaring)
(turns off stereo)
Ah!
It's okay.
(groans)
Are you here to save me?
(laughing)
I need you to tell me
where your friends are.
(laughing)
Oh, God.
You like it?
Do you like it?
Good?
Do you think
it can keep me alive
all by itself?
Can you?
I'm here.
I love my friends.
I... I thought about them
when I was weak.
But you know what?
It only made
me feel weaker.
You know why?
Because...
because you... you can't
have the past back.
No, no.
Every time
we were together,
we're not...
we were not present.
We weren't here!
We were wasted!
We were always
fuckin' wasted, okay?
And we didn't do
what we said we would.
So, maybe...
all this
was a way of saying...
we remembered.
We remembered
what we used to feel.
Where are your friends,
Richard?
You want to know
where my friends are?
I need to know.
Tell me.
- They're dead.
- What?
They're buried
in the back,
in the rocks,
in the sand.
They're dead.
Oh, my...
oh, my God.
You went back there.
What kind of cop are you?
You went back there,
remember?
Richard?
Richard!
(siren wailing)
- ♪ Shake me... ♪
- Richard!
♪ Shake me ♪
♪ Skyscraper ♪
♪ Skyscraper. ♪
Oh, God.
It's me.
Richard,
look at me.
You don't have to do this.
I...
you know where we are?
It's so fuckin' beautiful!
Come here.
- But I am so goddamn scared.
- Hey.
Why?
Why are we doing this?
You don't
have to do this.
I'd miss my friends
too much.
(screaming)
Tim's voice:
"25 years from now,
if we can't remember
what this feels like,
then we have forgotten
this beautiful moment."
Ron's voice: "Who we said we'd become,
our promise to each other,
swearing to and by our friends,
we will never forget."
Richard's voice: "See, this life,
our life, the one we want to live,
and the men we want to be
and will be."
Jonathan's voice:
"To forget this feeling is to fail.
And if we forget..."
All:
"We will die as one."
(rock music playing)
♪ There's no point in asking,
you'll get no reply ♪
♪ Oh, just remember
I don't decide ♪
♪ I got no reason,
it's all too much ♪
♪ You'll always find us ♪
♪ Out to lunch ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ We're vacant ♪
♪ Oh, we're so pretty,
oh, so pretty ♪
♪ But now ♪
♪ We don't care ♪
♪ We're pretty ♪
♪ We're pretty vacant ♪
♪ And we don't care. ♪
- (ambient music playing)
- ♪ Moving forwards ♪
♪ Using all my breath ♪
♪ Making love to you ♪
♪ Was never second best ♪
♪ I saw the world crashing ♪
♪ All around your face ♪
♪ Never really knowing ♪
♪ It was always ♪
♪ Mesh and lace ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
and melt with you ♪
♪ You've seen
the difference ♪
♪ And it's getting better
all the time ♪
♪ There's nothing
you and I won't do ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
and melt with you ♪
♪ Dream of better lives ♪
♪ The kind
which never hate ♪
♪ Trapped in a state
of imaginary grace ♪
♪ I made a pilgrimage ♪
♪ To save
this humans' race ♪
♪ Never comprehending
the race ♪
♪ Had long gone by ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
and melt with you ♪
♪ You've seen
the difference ♪
♪ And it's getting better
all the time ♪
♪ There's nothing
you and I won't do ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
and melt with you ♪
♪ The future's open wide ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
and melt with you ♪
♪ I've seen some changes ♪
♪ But it's getting better
all the time ♪
♪ There's nothing
you and I won't do ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
and melt with you. ♪