THE WAY HE LOOKS
What is your level of laziness
right now?
- Six. What about you?
- Eight. And a half.
And a half? All that?
The sun, the summer vacation,
this pool. . .
It makes me lazy just to think
it will come to an end.
- I'm tired of doing nothing.
- I'm quite happy doing nothing.
We never do anything on summer vacation!
Nothing happens.
- What do you want to happen?
- I don't know.
But the best dramas and great romances
never happen during our vacation.
Who do you imagine
having this great romance with?
You always say there are
only frogs in our class.
Well, it doesn't have to be a prince!
- Don't you worry about this?
- About what?
That you'll go through life
without ever kissing anyone, Leo.
- Giovana!
- It's true!
You won't change that by listening
to Beethoven your entire vacation!
You should kiss any girl
and get it over with!
Why don't I kiss you, then?
But I don't want my first kiss
to be like that.
You will never kiss anyone, then.
And who would want to kiss me?
I bet that witch Karina
would kiss you.
- You might turn into a frog, though!
- Silly!
She's always checking you out.
But it's depressing to think that Karina
is the only one who would kiss me.
Besides, she only talks bullshit.
She's so annoying!
What if we kiss
and she gets stuck on me?
Do you think she's that kind of girl?
Giovana? Giovana? Giovana!
- Hey! Did you say something?
- Weren't you listening?
No!
Get in the water, Leonardo!
Stop being boring!
No one calls me boring!
Are you sure
you don't want to come in?
No. I still have to organise my stuff.
Give me the keys, Leo!
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye.
- Mum. I'm home.
- Hi, Leo! Come and have a snack.
I'm coming.
- So, Leo. How was your day?
- It was good.
- Just good?
- It was cool.
Leo, you're burned.
Did you wear sunscreen?
I did. But the sun was too strong.
Are you sure?
C'mon! You know
I hate wearing sunscreen!
My skin gets icky.
I'd rather not sunbathe at all!
Good! That's what
will happen next time!
- Relax, Mum!
- Relax. Have you packed your things?
No, laziness overtook me.
But I'll do it today.
- What's up, Leo?
- Hi, Dad!
- Tanned, huh? Where were you?
- At Giovana's.
I saw Giovana the other day
and was surprised.
- Why?
- She's grown, she's a woman now.
What do you mean, Dad?
A while back, you were just kids.
Now you're growing up,
becoming real people.
The chair, Leo!
I must have super powers!
I've always done this
and I've never fallen down.
Funny boy!
Leo, I've talked to your grandma
and she has a doctor's appointment
this Wednesday. . .
- Fine, I'll come back home.
- You'll be all by yourself.
- So?
- What will you eat?
I'll eat something at the school
cafeteria or I'll make a sandwich.
- No, no. I'd be worried.
- Mum!
What kind of tragedy
could possibly happen?
OK, OK.
But you call us as soon as
you step inside the house.
- Alright.
- And keep your phone charged.
OK!
Elevator going up!
- What's so funny, Mr Guilherme?
- It's nothing, teacher.
Sorry, but I can't take the pair of you
for another year!
Fabio, please sit at the empty chair
behind Leo.
- Oh, no, teacher!
- Oh, yes, Fabio!
It's impossible to sit behind Leo,
listening to that annoying machine
all day!
- You are such a jerk!
- Shut up, you human walking stick!
How can you go so low, Fabio?
I'll show you something lower later,
guide dog!
- Shut up, jerk!
- Hey, guys, where do you think you are?
If I sit behind Leo, I'm going to have
to help him out all the time.
He can't do anything on his own!
Enough! You won't have to help anyone
at the Principal's office.
Get your stuff.
Gee, teacher! This sucks!
Isn't Giovana going
to the Principal's office, too?
Do you want to join him there?
- No, thanks.
- Go on, Fabio!
- Is this room 21 1 ?
- Yes. What's your name?
- Gabriel.
- Come on in.
Can I sit in that empty seat?
Guys!
It's free. Go sit down.
Welcome, Gabriel.
Any more jokes?
- Well?
- No.
The keys, Leo.
- Bye, Gi.
- Bye.
Don't let that jackass Fabio
ruin your day, OK?
OK.
Let me tell you,
this new guy is really cute!
Maybe this year
things will be better, right?
- Yeah, right!
- Maybe he's my Prince Charming!
C'mon! Get a grip.
He's just arrived.
You don't even know him!
- Are you jealous, Leo?
- Yeah, I'm dying of jealousy.
- I can't believe this! What a nerve!
- What is it?
- Karina hits on everyone!
- What are you talking about, Gi?
She just sat next to Gabriel
and is flirting with him.
It's not enough she hits on you.
The minute a new guy comes,
she goes for it.
Very well. Cells can be divided
into two basic types.
Eukaryotic and prokaryotic.
Do you have an eraser I can borrow?
Gee. . . I don't use erasers.
- I'm sorry.
- That's OK.
Wait a minute.
- Thanks!
- You're welcome.
If I were Pluto and someone told me,
"Hey, you're not a planet any more,"
I'd be very upset!
Give me the key, Leo.
Here.
- Bye!
- Bye.
- Bye, Leo.
- Bye, Gabriel.
- Well, see you, then.
- Don't you go that way?
No, I actually live two blocks back.
I always bring Leo home.
- OK. See you tomorrow.
- Bye.
I'm home, Mum.
Safe and sound in my room.
OK. Of course I'm going to eat.
Kisses, Mum. Bye!
Have you ever thought
about doing an exchange programme?
What do you mean?
An exchange programme. Live abroad.
Not really, I'm lazy. Why?
I've been thinking about it.
- Maybe going to the US.
- Not the States, Leo!
France would be nice!
Can you imagine a vacation in Paris?
I'm not talking about vacations.
Besides, United States, France,
anywhere is good enough!
I just want to leave!
Why now, Leo?
It's not a new thing.
I've been thinking about it for a while.
Imagine how cool it'd be to go somewhere
where no one knows you,
where no one knows who you are.
You could even create a new personality!
- Don't you like your personality?
- Yes, I do!
I'm not the problem.
Excuse me. Gi.
- Will you stay for dinner?
- Please.
- I'll call you guys when it's ready.
- Thank you, Laura.
- What about your mum?
- What about her?
- What does she think about this?
- She doesn't know, obviously.
You plan to move to another country
without telling your parents?
Who knows?
You're cuckoo, Leo!
Where's yours?
- At home.
- At home?
- Hey, let's go.
- Let's!
I'm not going with you guys.
I'm having lunch at my grandma's.
Yes, today is Wednesday! I'm sorry.
I'm taking Leo to his grandma's, OK?
No, you don't have to. I'll go alone.
- It's so close, I can take you.
- Yeah, it's close, I can go alone.
- Are you sure, Leo?
- I am.
OK, OK. It's up to you.
So, guys, we'll talk later, OK?
- Alright. Call me, OK?
- OK.
Hi, Mum.
Yes, I'm at school.
I'm going to Grandma's.
I'll let you know when I get there.
Kiss. Bye.
Leo, Leo, are you OK?
Get off me!
- Leo, are you OK?
- Yep.
- Are you sure? I can take you. . .
- I'm fine, Karina.
You guys are fucked up, huh?
Hello? Hi, Mum. . .
No, nothing yet.
Are you sure he didn't tell you
where he was going?
No, Giovana doesn't know either.
No, stay there in case he goes back
to your place and there's no one there.
OK, OK. It's better this way.
I'm going to hang up now.
Maybe he'll try to call.
Bye, kisses.
She doesn't know anything.
- Leonardo!
- Gee, Mum, what is it?
Where have you been, Leo?
- Around. . .
- Around?
How about letting your mother
know you weren't coming home?
- Oh, Mum, relax!
- Do you know what time it is?
You out there, alone in the dark.
It's always dark for me!
There's no need for all this fuss!
- Leo, why didn't you answer your phone?
- Sorry, Mum. It was in my backpack!
And I'm old enough
to not have to explain everything I do!
You still have
a lot of explaining to do!
You too, Dad? Can't I take a step
without you watching over me?
Watching over you?
You were gone for hours
and want us to be cool about it?
Ask anyone in my class if their parents
would freak out over being a bit late.
- Leo, you know it's different!
- Why does it have to be different, Mum?
Why don't you try to make it normal?
Leonardo, your grandma said
you'd been hurt.
It was nothing, Mum!
It was just a scratch.
Can I take a shower?
Or do you want to bath me too?
- Leonardo!
- Let it be.
- Leo?
- Laura!
Hey, guys, how can I help you?
I'm interested in doing
an exchange programme
and I wanted more information.
OK. So, I need your parents
to come here and talk to us
so we can explain
how everything works, OK?
OK. Thank you.
So we don't have a wasted visit,
could you tell us a little bit
about what we'll need?
Do you want to do
an exchange programme too?
Yeah, I guess.
OK. I'll get some flyers.
That way, when your parents come,
they will be well informed.
I'll just be a minute.
- Here it is.
- Thanks.
We'll come back with our parents.
- You're welcome!
One last question. . .
Do you think I'd have a problem doing
the exchange programme, being blind?
I'll be honest.
We have never had a blind person
go on an exchange programme.
But it's only a matter of finding
a family prepared to accommodate you.
Here's an idea.
Give me your number and I'll do some
research, then I'll contact you. OK?
- What's your number?
- It's 94 837. . . 9.
- So, that's it, kids!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Come on, Leo.
Would you like anything else?
Dessert? Some coffee?
No, thanks, Grandma.
Grandma, how old was my mum
when she had me?
22. . . 23. She got married young.
You were born right after that.
- Did she date anyone before my dad?
- No, he was her first boyfriend.
But they got into so much trouble!
She drove your grandpa crazy!
But she only moved out
after getting married?
Yeah.
Why?
I was thinking about that.
- About having kids?
- No!
I want to move out.
How do you plan to support yourself?
I'll get a job. Everybody works.
There's a kid at school who's a waiter
at his father's restaurant.
Isn't it a bit early for that, Leo?
OK. Kisses.
- Who was that? A girlfriend?
- It was my dad.
Gee, do your parents worry like Leo's?
Hey!
Actually, it's just my dad.
My mum died when I was a kid.
- So it's just the two of you?
- I've got an older brother, too.
- Does he live with you?
- No. He stayed where I used to live.
- Do you get along well?
- Sort of. . .
- Why sort of?
- We're very different.
He's the engineer type.
Only thinks in terms of numbers.
I like to read, he hates it. But when
it comes to music, we are the same.
Did you know that Leo
only listens to classical music?
Really?
Yeah.
I've always wanted
to like classical music,
but I've never had the patience for it.
Why not? It's the best kind
of music there is!
- Gee, Leo.
- Don't exaggerate.
- But it is.
- And why do you like it so much?
Because of my grandma Maria.
She'd always say
that to understand anything,
you first need to start
with the classics.
The problem is that Leo started
with the classics and got stuck there!
Silly!
- You can give me some lessons, Leo.
- OK.
That's all I need!
Beethoven and Mozart together.
Guys, it's kind of late. I have to go.
- Already?
- I've gotta go, too.
Wait, I'll get changed
and I'll take you home, Leo.
If you want, I can take him, so you
don't need to go and come back.
It's not a problem. It's so close.
My house is on the way to Gabriel's.
- It's easier.
- Yeah, way easier.
- It's up to you.
- Let's go, then.
It's about an hour and a half from here.
So it's actually relatively close.
Oh, I'm sorry. I forgot the step.
Don't worry. No problem.
Next time you'll warn me.
My bad!
The Hellenic was a period. . .
. .of great expansion.
Guys, since we're studying Greece,
I want you to pair up for an assignment.
But the pair has to be of boys or girls.
The girls will write about Athens
and the boys about Sparta, OK?
Pair up and give me your names.
Teacher, does it have to be
a pair of two?
Ask the maths teacher.
- Can I be your pair?
- Yes.
Have you seen that video
with the cat getting into the toilet?
- Oh, sorry.
- No problem.
Do people ask you
these silly things a lot?
Sometimes.
- Have you always been like this, Leo?
- Always. I was born this way.
So, you've never seen Giovana's face?
No, never.
Man, I don't feel
like doing this assignment.
Tell me about it.
- We should go to the movies.
- The movies?
I'm sorry. I promise
I'll get used to this.
What happened?
The giant robot destroyed the church.
And now?
Now he is carrying the bride
and the groom, one in each hand.
And that?
He's just smashed the groom.
- Did he die?
- I think so.
What?
The bride has just thrown
the bouquet at the robot's face.
- Bye, Gabriel.
- Bye, Leo.
So, won't you ever talk to us again?
- Leo?
- Yes?
Leonardo, you know
you should have warned us.
Do you know you overreacted?
- We were worried, Leo.
- Dad, you're always worried!
If school had a camping trip,
I bet you wouldn't let me go.
- What do you mean?
- What camping trip?
There's going to be a camping trip,
but I've been avoiding asking you
because I know you'll complain.
We just have to call the school
and get the info.
See, everything here is a huge drama!
Son, it's a camping trip.
We can't let you go with no information!
It's not just about the camping trip,
OK?
It's about not being able
to be home alone,
having to tell you every step I take.
- We've agreed you can be home alone!
- OK, but even so.
Do you know how embarrassing it is
to be treated like this?
If you call the school,
everyone will know about it.
What do you suggest?
- That you say yes, period!
- Sorry, Leo. It's not that easy.
So embarrassing!
It's as though I'm five years old.
Well, Leo. I'm sorry.
I will call the school.
If there's no other way.
Did you do the assignment yesterday?
Did Gabriel say anything about me?
No. He didn't say anything, Gi.
And we ended up not doing
the assignment. We went to the movies.
Come again?
Yeah, Gabriel wanted to go
to the movies, so we went.
Get up, Leo. My legs hurt.
I can't believe you guys went
to the movies without me!
- But we never go!
- Why didn't you invite me?
I'm sorry.
I didn't think about it at the time.
We just decided and went.
What is that, Gabriel?
Belle and Sebastian.
It's a band I like.
- Do you know it?
- No.
My brother likes this song.
Back in my town we shared a room,
and he always played this album
at night,
but he'd always fall asleep
in the middle,
so I'd listen to it alone.
It's not Tchaikovsky, but it's good.
Hi. How are things at the library, Gi?
Weren't you going to do
the assignment with Larissa?
We are.
OK. You got it. I'll call.
Kisses. Bye!
If we get tired,
we can go swimming at Giovana's.
And we can also get a zero
for the assignment!
That's weird!
Hello?
Hello, Vivaldi?
Silly!
Why did you call me, Gabriel?
I wanted to know what my ringtone was.
You got it wrong!
It's not Vivaldi, it's Bach!
I don't want to be Bach.
What do you want to be?
- Can it be Belle and Sebastian?
- Yes.
Now you can even dance when I call you.
Way more upbeat than Bach!
- Come dance, Leo.
- No, I don't know how to dance.
No? Your fingers seem to know how to.
But I don't know how to dance.
Some people are good dancers,
others aren't. But everyone can dance.
- Maybe another time, OK?
- Boring!
Yeah!
You can try to dance.
Feel free to move your feet as well.
This probably looks ridiculous,
Gabriel.
It doesn't! Trust me.
You could even go to a club now.
Shut up, Gabriel!
It's OK for the first lesson.
I can't stand doing this assignment
at the library!
What's your laziness level right now?
Ten! Although I'm past feeling lazy,
I'm feeling homicidal!
Relax, Gi. We'll do
the next one together, OK?
Shall we go?
No! Please, don't go.
Stay a little bit more!
Gi, I'm sorry.
No.
Bye, Gi.
Goodbye, boys!
- It's impossible, seriously.
- Gabriel, it's easy.
The locomotive released one. . .
How do I know
what you're saying is correct?
You're going to have to trust me.
Give me your hand.
Released one stron. . .
This is a hyphen. . .
It's impossible.
Seriously, I give up!
- Gabriel, it's not impossible.
- I'll take a long time to learn this.
What's impossible is me riding a bike,
Gabriel. Not this!
- Hi, Gabriel.
- Hi.
- Do you guys want juice or something?
- No, thank you.
Thanks. We'll get something later.
OK. If you need anything,
I'm in the living room.
Besides, you can read Braille
with your eyes.
It's the same alphabet, but in Braille.
- Here.
- What is that?
- The alphabet in Braille.
- Cool!
Leo, there's going to be an eclipse
today. Should we watch it?
Of course we'll watch the eclipse!
I'm sorry!
My dad said there's a square nearby
that's perfect for watching the eclipse.
I really want to go.
- Let's do it! What time?
- Late, around 1 am.
Never mind, then,
my mum would never let me go.
We could sneak out.
- Let's go, Leo.
- Let's.
Hold on to my shoulder.
Go ahead.
What's so interesting about an eclipse?
It's seeing the moon
vanishing from the sky.
Vanishing how?
It disappears from the sky.
I mean, it stops being illuminated.
Meaning?
Let me think.
You know when you're sunbathing
and you feel the warmth
on one side of your face?
So, that same side is also
being illuminated by the sun.
But what does that have to do
with an eclipse?
Wait up.
Give me your hand.
Here's the sun, the Earth
and the moon.
The sun illuminates the Earth,
the moon,
as well as your face.
An eclipse happens when the three
of them are perfectly aligned,
and that light stops
illuminating the moon.
Since we only see what is illuminated,
we can no longer see the moon.
But it's quick, because the Earth
moves out of the way
and we can see the moon again.
- Got it?
- I think so.
It's weird to try to explain this.
It seems so simple.
See ya.
Leo, I left my hoodie in your room.
Can you bring it to school
tomorrow, please?
- Yes, I will.
- Thanks.
- Bye.
Grandma, how long
have you and Grandpa been together?
It's been a while.
'71 , '81 . . .
Oh my. . . 42 years!
Wow, so long!
Do you still love each other?
Some days more than others.
How did you meet?
It was before we moved to São Paulo.
He was a bus driver on the line
I used to take to go to work.
The truth is, I could take a later bus,
but I always ended up arriving early
at work just so I could ride with him.
One day I was running late
and was so distraught.
I ran to see if I could catch him,
and to my surprise, he was still there.
He refused to leave
before I got there.
Everyone was yelling at him,
it was a mess.
When I got there,
people weren't very happy with me.
Isn't it early for your mum
to be picking you up?
No. It's Gabriel.
We're doing an assignment
and he's come to pick me up.
- I can't believe it!
- It's true!
Hello?
This is Leo.
Really?
Sandra. I don't know if I can stop by
because my parents are travelling
and won't be back until next week.
Would it be OK if I call you
when they get back?
OK, thanks.
Your parents are away?
No. It was the lady from
the exchange programme agency.
She said she found an American agency
that specialises
in the visually impaired.
- And why did you lie?
- I don't know.
- Your mum will never let you go away.
- Gee! Thanks for the support!
- Hey!
- Hi!
Have you guys seen Gabriel around?
- He went to the restroom. Why?
- Nothing much.
I wanted to talk to him about something.
Gabriel is the cutest,
isn't he, Giovana?
And his adorable curls!
He's not from São Paulo.
Where is he from again?
- I think he's from Ita. . .
- He's over there. Kiss.
She's such a slut, isn't she?
There, she's made her move!
She's all friendly!
Talking to him, playing with her hair.
She touched his shoulder, Leo.
And his hand!
She doesn't even know if he's washed it!
She doesn't even try to be discreet!
Leo, I don't think you need
your walking stick any more.
OK.
Did you hear Karina's question
during chemistry class?
She's so dumb!
Poor thing!
Poor thing, but she's also annoying,
right? Or do you think she's cool?
I think she's nice.
She even invited me to her party.
- What party?
- A party she's throwing.
A huge party. She's moving
and the house is empty.
She's inviting the whole class.
- Doesn't sound fun.
- Mind the step.
- I'm going to be the DJ.
- Why?
- I like Karina. Why don't you like her?
- It's not that I don't like her.
But the last place I want to go to
is a party with our classmates!
But it might be fun.
People act differently outside school.
- I doubt it.
- Aren't you different?
Should I leave the door open, Leo?
No. You can close it.
Hi, Gi.
Yes.
Giovana wants to talk to you.
Hi, Gi.
Sorry! My cellphone
must be in my backpack.
I'm home. We're doing the assignment.
Weren't you doing the assignment
in the library?
I'm sorry, Gi.
Giovana?
What happened?
Giovana got pissed
because we didn't wait for her.
Wasn't she staying in the library
with Larissa?
Apparently not.
Let's go, Leo.
Without Giovana?
No way, Gabriel. She'll kill us.
She just walked by
without saying goodbye.
- For real?
- For real.
Let's go, then.
What's up, Leonardo?
New boyfriend?
Ignore it, Leo.
The new guy is doing you good.
You're becoming more manly.
- It's hot.
- Thanks.
I was thinking about going on an
exchange programme. What do you think?
- You want to do what, Leo?
- Exchange programme.
Some kids at school
talked about it and I got interested.
- Do you mean live in another country?
- Yeah!
- You've got to be kidding!
- Oh, no. Here we go!
Go where? This discussion
isn't going anywhere!
- Explain this to us. . .
- Explain what?
Are you insane? Leonardo isn't going
to live abroad by himself. Period!
- Why not?
- Why not, Leo?
Other people do it.
What's the problem?
Well, even if we said yes, tell me,
who's going to take in a blind kid?
Leo!
Carlos!
Carlos?
- Where did you get this?
- At an exchange programme agency.
There's one in Los Angeles
for blind people.
Do you want to call them
to see who'll take care of me?
- Is your English any good?
- You're not going. Period!
Leonardo, Leonardo. . .
It must be because I swim. I used
to swim a lot back in my hometown.
Gabriel?
I used to lift weights sometimes.
That must be it.
What are you doing here?
Yeah, it really shows.
Karina?
We should go swimming together.
I don't have my swimming trunks.
Gabriel?
Who said we need them?
You got it, babe!
Gabriel, answer me.
You've got my number, right?
Dad!
What's up, son? Are you OK?
Can you help me shave?
Take this.
Give me this.
Take the foam.
Gee, son. That's too much.
I'll throw some away.
OK. Put it on your face.
It's me.
- Careful with your mouth, OK?
- OK.
Let me see.
Wash your hands.
Put the razor in the hot water,
it's easier.
Here.
I was thinking about
the exchange programme you mentioned.
- Really?
- Really.
- But don't talk while you're shaving.
- Sorry.
I'm trying to understand
your desire to go so far away.
I think it's natural,
especially at your age, . . .
. .to want to see other places,
meet new people, make other friends.
I think it's normal.
But I also think it's natural
to fight with your parents.
I was like that, too.
But leaving the country to run away
from fights is a bit extreme.
You know. . .
I'm thinking about talking
to your mother about the programme.
But first I need to make sure that
you want to go for the right reasons.
Do you agree, Leo?
- Do you agree?
- Can I talk now?
I agree, Dad.
- How is it?
- Let me see.
Hi!
- Are you having fun?
- Yeah!
- What's his name?
- Cupcake!
- Cupcake, have a drink, man.
- No, he's a baby!
Hey, girl!
Have you met Cupcake?
Cupcake, this is Giovana.
Hi, Cupcake!
Get up and dance. Don't just sit there.
- What's up?
- Are you looking for someone?
- D'you know who's here?
It's true. Go for it.
- Hi, DJ.
- Hey.
Cupcake wants to ask for a song.
Can you put him in his bed, please?
- Are you sleepy, Cupcake?
- He's a baby. He goes to bed early.
Hi, Leo. Go dance. You look
like Giovana, just sitting there.
I'll go dance in a little bit, Karina.
Hi. What are you guys hiding over here?
It's nothing.
Carlinhos!
Vodka and whiskey.
Do you want some?
Straight?
Be careful!
- Cheers!
Leo, come dance.
I made a playlist.
It's going to play for a while, OK?
Of course. Enjoy yourself!
- Leo, you on the dance floor? Finally!
- Who'd have guessed?
Feel free to move your feet.
I'll go get a drink.
You guys want anything?
I'll come with you.
No way! Now that you're dancing,
you can stay and dance with me.
I'll be right back.
Leo, I actually wanted to talk to you
about something.
- Now?
- It's better now that we're alone!
OK.
Has Gabriel ever talked to you about me?
- What do you mean?
- About whether he's into me.
No.
- What's up, Gigi?
- What?
Want to pick up where we left off
at the last killer party?
Fabio, if we do, this time,
the party won't be the only killer.
- Is that how it's going to be?
- Yes.
Fine!
What's up, Rodrigo?
- What's up, Gi? What are you drinking?
- I don't know.
How can you not know?
- Vodka, whiskey. . .
- Can I taste it?
Vodka.
Could you help me?
Maybe give him some hints?
Sure.
Thanks, Leo! You are a sweetheart.
Well, I'm going to check
how the party's going, OK?
It's time to play spin the bottle!
Make a circle, everyone.
- Come with us, Leo.
- No, thanks.
- Stay, Leo! It's going to be fun.
- No, I'm not in the mood.
C'mon, Leo!
Don't you ever want to be kissed?
Douche! I don't have a problem
with the game!
- So, prove it and stay!
- Fine, I'll stay!
Let's go sit over there.
Dimitri, move over.
Turn, turn. You can sit.
OK, let's start with me.
I'll spin the bottle and whoever
it points to has to kiss me. OK?
Sweet.
Shouldn't you be taking care
of your dear friend?
He's fine.
In fact, you should go talk to him.
About what?
He doesn't like me any more!
That's ridiculous, Giovana!
It's true. Besides,
he doesn't want to talk to me.
Aren't you the one
that didn't answer his call?
He thinks you don't want to talk to him.
- This is all your fault.
- My fault? Why?
Things were great before you got here.
Now, I'm not even talking
to my best friend.
Your turn, Matheus.
Go, Matheus!
You also went to the movies
and didn't invite me.
Gi, it wasn't on purpose!
Leo didn't mean to.
Of course he did!
Now he doesn't even want me
to take him home. Didn't you notice?
It's all you, you, you. . .
See? You don't have an answer.
- I'm sorry.
- Bitch.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the moment you've all been
waiting for has arrived.
I believe many of you
are here just because of her.
- Am I right or not, Marta?
- Me?
No, some other Marta!
You're such a douche!
Leonardo!
You hit the jackpot!
For real, man.
C'mon, stand up, Marta!
- C'mon, Gui, get him up.
- Get up, get up.
I'm sorry for getting between
you and Leo.
- It's too late, don't you think?
- I'm still sorry.
I just wanted to understand him.
This whole exchange programme thing,
for example.
He didn't care that he would
leave me here by myself.
How can your best friend leave
without even thinking about you?
What exchange programme thing?
Leonardo wants to go on an exchange
programme. Didn't he tell you?
No.
Wait up, everyone!
Since this is a special moment
in Leo's life,
it's only fair
that we put some music on.
- What do you think?
- Of course.
So. . .
What really matters
is that he doesn't care about me.
He chose you over me in ten seconds!
And he doesn't even realise it.
- It's not like that, Gi.
- Yes, it is!
You have no idea what we were like
before you got here.
Why don't you tell him that?
You need to share how you feel.
There's no point bottling it up.
Right?
Get ready.
Are you people insane?
- C'mon, Leo.
- Giovana, what are you doing?
Cupcake is such a cutie!
- Giovana, are you crazy?
- C'mon, Leo, let's get out of here!
I can't believe
you're jealous of Marta, too!
Weren't you the one saying
I should kiss someone?
I was so sad that we've kind of
been apart, but you've changed.
I don't even know
if I can trust you any more!
Fuck you, Leonardo!
- Where's Giovana?
- She left.
- I think we should go too, Leo.
- Why? The party is great!
Or are you going to be like Giovana?
Why don't you go after Karina?
Seriously, Leo. Let's go, it's late.
Gabriel! I don't get it!
First, you drag me to the party
and now you drag me out of it.
What's going on?
- Answer me, Gabriel!
- Why are you so angry at me?
Because everyone wants to control me
and won't let me kiss anyone!
No new calls.
Leo, I'm going to the supermarket.
Do you want anything?
- I'll go with you, Mum.
- Oh, my!
Get out of this room for a while.
743.
C'mon, guys, come inside!
C'mon, we're late!
Hurry. C'mon, class. Get on the bus.
We're late.
743.
What's up, Leo?
You're the only one missing!
- Want me to help you?
- Thanks, teacher.
Do you always have to be last?
Guys, get on the bus!
Take pictures there. . . Let's go!
Four, six, eight, ten, 1 2. . .
Class, class! Silence please!
I'm going to have to check you by name
because we're missing two people.
Well, well!
They're not missing any more!
Guys, you've got dirty minds! Come on,
Gabriel. There's a seat at the back.
Guys, attention! Let's go over
the rules and instructions for the trip.
People who brought tents. . .
Leo! I collected the sample for you.
Keep this vial with you.
- Thanks.
- We'll analyse it in the lab later.
Teacher!
There's a form that must be filled in.
Ask a classmate
to help you with that later.
OK.
If you need anything, I'll be around.
Just call me.
Hey.
Do we have to fill in this form again?
No, it's on the other side
of the pond. . .
- Good morning, Leonardo.
- Good morning.
So, how is the assignment going?
- It's good.
- Let me see.
Dude, I think your zooplankton
is kind of down.
What about yours, how is it?
Mine is hungover, for sure!
Karina's party was crazy, right?
- I can't remember anything.
- How so?
I was totally drunk.
The only thing I remember is being
in the bathroom arguing with Giovana.
- Did you drink that much?
- I guess.
- Gabriel, where are your curls?
- Wait till it's dry.
There you go!
- Wanna go and sit down, Leo?
- Yeah.
- Don't you wear sunscreen?
- No, I hate it.
Really? Not even on your face?
Alright. . .
There's some here.
What about on your body?
You sound like my mum, Gabriel!
Wow! The relationship is getting hot!
- Mind your own business, jackass!
- He's so hysterical!
So, Leo, can we go now?
- I think we've waited long enough.
- We haven't.
I'm not going to shower
with a bunch of other people.
Don't be so fussy!
I'm not being fussy! It's embarrassing.
Well, Leo. Get over it,
because I'm going.
OK, Gabriel. Wait!
Silly!
There's no one else here.
Someone left the shower on.
Get undressed
and I'll help you get in the shower.
I'm ready.
Are you going to shower
with your shorts on?
- Yes.
- Leonardo, you're a funny guy.
C'mon let's go.
Put your stuff here.
- The sunscreen won't wash out.
- Use more soap.
I was thinking about
having a drink tonight.
Look at that!
There's always a first time.
We could have a drink together.
Are you going to have a drink?
I guess so.
So, Leo. I'm done here, OK?
- Already?
- Yeah.
- Is your zooplankton still hungover?
- Yes.
- Hi, Gabs! Hi, Leo!
- Hi!
- I love that shirt, Gabriel.
- Thanks.
- So, are you guys pumped up?
- I'm kind of sleepy.
But the party hasn't even started.
We're going to watch the sunrise!
Speak for yourself!
I'm not going to watch anything!
I'm sorry.
Weren't you going
to have a drink tonight, Leo?
That was earlier! I'm tired now.
No. Seriously,
tonight we're going to have a drink.
Is Giovana around?
She's up ahead,
pretending she can't see us.
Are you not talking to Giovana, Leo?
- I don't know. . .
- You should talk to her.
About what? If she's pretending not to
see us, what am I going to say to her?
- Did you call me?
- Sit with us!
- What for?
- C'mon, sit with us.
Karina and I will get
something to drink, right?
- Will we?
- Yes! We'll be right back.
I'm sorry.
For what? For being a coward
and asking Gabriel to call me here?
- No, Gi!
- Then what?
I don't know. . . so many things.
Then start from the beginning.
Sorry I spoke to you that way
at Karina's party.
Leo, they were going
to make you kiss a dog!
- What?
- What, what?
What dog, Gi?
- Oh, Leo!
- Giovana, what dog?
When I dragged you out of the party,
Fabio was holding a dog in front of you.
Thanks for getting me out of there.
Forgive me, too.
I overreacted when we had that fight.
- But you chose Gabriel over me so fast.
- I'm never going to leave you!
Imagine an eclipse.
The Earth is in front of the sun,
and the moon disappears from the sky,
but it's still there.
At some point, the Earth moves and
we can see the moon again. Just like us!
I don't follow.
What does that have to do with us?
In our eclipse, Gabriel would be
the Earth and you, the moon, get it?
- And you are the sun, hot stuff?
- Yes.
It depends. If it were a solar eclipse,
then you would be the sun, hot stuff!
- Where do you think Earth is?
- With the meteor named Karina.
Let's go have a drink with them.
Let's go.
- So, can you see them?
- No.
Are you sure
you can't see them anywhere?
No, Leo.
- They're probably making out.
- You think?
They've been really close lately.
You know what?
Let's have a drink without them.
Where can we get some vodka?
What's up, Carlinhos?
Do you have vodka?
Giovana? Karina's party
was good for you, huh?
- Yeah, maybe I'm an alcoholic.
- Come on in.
Wait, Leo's here.
Come. Go down.
Sit in that corner.
- Excuse me.
- OK.
Welcome to my headquarters.
- Are you going to have a drink, too?
- Yes.
Cool.
Thanks. Carlinhos,
have you seen Gabriel?
I saw him with Karina.
But that was a while ago.
Those two are always together, right?
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
- Gi, am I handsome?
- What do you mean?
Do you think people
consider me attractive?
I find you attractive.
You don't count, Gi! Do you think
other people find me attractive?
I don't know, Leo.
I never notice other people's reactions.
You should ask Karina!
No. She thinks Gabriel is handsome.
Would you miss me
if I did the exchange programme?
A lot.
Me too.
Do you think
we'd still be friends if you went?
Of course.
- I need to tell you something.
- Wow! You look so serious!
- It's not that simple.
- Just spit it out, Leo!
Is there anyone around?
No, everyone's far away.
I think I'm in love with Gabriel.
Gi?
Hey!
- What do you mean, in love?
- Like a boyfriend in love.
Aren't you going to say something?
My cup is empty, Leo.
I'll get another drink.
Giovana?
Leo, get in the water!
C'mon, Leo! It's so good!
Thanks, guys. But I'm looking
for Giovana. Have you seen her?
She's probably asleep by now.
Leo, get in the water!
Seriously, it's great!
And we'll watch the sunrise!
- Karina!
- Sorry. I always forget.
I can't, I don't have
my swimming trunks on.
We don't either.
Who said we need them?
Come in, already!
Jeez, Leo. You're so warm.
Here's the thermometer, son.
I can't believe you got sick.
Aren't you the responsible adult?
- It's just a cold, Mum!
- Just a cold?
Your teacher told me
you were swimming at night, Leo!
Drink your tea.
And we're supposed to let you go abroad
after you pull something like this?
- Like you've never done anything wrong.
- But that's different.
- Why?
- Because you're my son, Leo!
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you.
- It doesn't matter the way you are.
- Yeah, right.
One day you'll have a son
and you'll understand.
- Not me! I don't want kids.
- No? Why?
- There are enough people in the world.
- You can adopt one.
One day you will meet someone
and start dating. Then, who knows?
- I doubt it!
- Doubt what?
That you'll start dating
or that you'll want kids?
Both.
You're still very young.
There's no point in forcing things.
So much is going to happen in your life.
So much will change.
You're still going to get
a lot of flu and colds!
And you should know that I'll keep
trying to prevent you from getting sick.
- I'll call you for lunch in a while.
- Alright.
- Hi.
- Hi, Gi.
- How are you?
- Fine, and you?
Sort of. . .
Got it.
I heard you got sick.
Yes, I did.
Do you think
you'll go to school tomorrow?
I don't know.
So, you like Gabriel, right?
Silly!
Do you forgive me for ignoring the news?
I guess I never thought of you that way.
But then again,
I never thought we would ever fight.
Weren't you the one
who wanted a great drama?
No, I wanted a great romance!
Just like you do!
In my case, it is also a great drama.
Because my great romance
is probably kissing Karina!
- You think?
- It's obvious. You said it yourself.
We never know with these things, right?
Look at you, for instance.
I think you guys
would make a cute couple.
- Have you talked to Leo recently?
- He texted me saying he was sick.
You should stop by his house.
Today's Wednesday. He's there alone.
- Who is it?
- It's Gabriel.
- I'm the only one who got sick, right?
- Poor thing.
But Karina said the pool
was bad for her hair. Too much chlorine.
- Did you make out with Karina?
- No. Why?
You two disappeared at the camp,
and everyone was saying
you were together.
So, remember when you
were talking to Giovana?
I thought you guys should be alone.
So I killed some time with Karina,
looking for something to drink.
When we got there, she tried to kiss me.
- But I turned my face away.
- Jeez! What about her?
She asked me
why I didn't want to kiss her.
What did you tell her?
That I had a girlfriend back in Itapira.
After I told her
about my fake girlfriend,
she decided to tell me stories
about her ex-boyfriends.
And I was making up stories
about my fake girlfriend.
The more we talked, the more we drank.
And we ended up in the pool.
That's when you found us.
You must have drunk a hell of a lot
at Karina's party.
What do you mean?
If you drank the whole night at the camp
and still remember everything,
imagine how much you drank
at Karina's party
for you to black out like that!
But why didn't you kiss her?
Well. . .
I actually like someone else.
Do I know this person?
Yes.
And does this person like you back?
Not in the same way, I don't think.
The truth is that
I've kissed this person.
But it was just a peck, you know?
Really fast.
I was embarrassed
and didn't say anything,
and the person
never said anything either,
so I decided to back off.
Leo, if you had ever
stolen a kiss from someone,
how would you give it back?
Spartan society was divided into
Spartiates, Perioeci and Helots.
The Spartiate boys
were sent to the army. . .
Is this room 21 1 ?
- Are you William?
- Yes.
Come in.
- Is that seat empty?
- Yeah.
- Is this backpack yours?
- Yes, it's mine.
Go on. . .
The men were dedicated to the army
and would become free
after they reached 60.
Look at that, Leonardo!
The relationship is going strong, huh?
There you go, douche!
THE WAY HE LOOKS
It's clear. Go on.
Go, go!