Thanks, Cuma.
She's a bit shy but...
Really?
She's very cute.
See you then.
Don't run away, Kado!
Don't run away!
What the hell are you doing
with pansies like that?
Who was that guy?
Where did you find that queen?
There's no place for pansies
in our family!
Get up!
Move it!
Mamo! How come you dumped this stu_?
Where did you go?
Kado must never leave this room.
l caught him outside
with a bunch of pansies.
He'll end up making a murderer of me.
l don't understand that boy.
Dad?
Yes.
l don't trust these guys at all.
Captain! Come on!
They should get ready!
Come on! Get ready!
We're going ashore. Move!
Necip! Flash the light.
Do it again!
Come on! Move!
That's it from us.
There's a new life waiting for you.
Good luck and all the best to you.
Close her up now! Come on!
There we go.
Ramo, if they operate on me,
who will look after the kids?
l will. Don't worry.
Just get yourself well.
Ramo... If it weren't for Serhat,
would you have taken a second wife?
Mother of my kids! Sunshine of my life!
l have eyes for nobody but you.
Mum, we're going out to play.
Should Zelal come with us?
OK. But keep close to the house.
All right, mum.
Slow down, girls.
Havar, it's your operation today.
Stop working. Come on. Let's go.
OK.
Take good care of the kids.
OK, Havar.
Doctor, l entrust my wife
first to God, then to you.
Don't worry, Ramazan Bey.
Open the door! Open the door!
Open the door!
We're going to die in here!
Come on, you bastards!
Open the door!
We're about to su_ocate!
Delal...
You're a big girl now.
You're 1 1.
You're the mother in this house
until your mum gets back.
OK, niece?
OK.
Lori Lori Lori...
You said 30 minutes
and it's been an hour!
Look, my uncle wouldn't lie.
He's coming for sure.
Something must have
happened on the way.
We're running late, my friend.
Look, he'll be here soon enough!
- Isn't he here yet, son?
- No.
ls this Nomay?
No, it's Denmark.
Uncle Nedim is taking us to Nomay.
- Where on earth is he?
- He's not here yet, dad. Honestly.
Hey! Uncle Nedim's here!
Welcome, nephew!
Where have you been, Nedim?
Welcome, Davut. Welcome!
That's it from us then.
- Goodbye.
- Thanks.
Dad, l'll get the bags.
OK, son.
Nephew...
Welcome, uncle.
Nedim, thatjourney did us in.
We came all that way
and there wasn't one police search!
That's because Schengen countries
have lifted their borders.
ln other words, everyone is free
to go to any country they want.
What?
Are you serious, Nedim?
We'd get searched a dozen times
just going from the village into town.
Uncle, what are those whirly things
in the water there?
They convert wind energy
into electricity.
So Davut, what's new back home?
Nothing but poverty.
Nothing but fighting and bloodshed.
Well, if the guys at the
top are always fighting...
...you can't expect the
people to live in peace.
There used to be a saying, remember?
lf the imam farts,
what can the congregation do?
Yes.
The guys at the top are only worried
about their seats in parliament.
What have the people
who die in Turkey done wrong?
Some 40 to 45,OOO people have died.
Who are these people
for goodness sake?
We're the people who die.
And we're the people that kill.
You know, l've given up hope, Nedim.
Whatever l say, no one can understand
without living there.
Don't l know it, Davut?
Where else has there been
torture like the torture we faced...
...in DiyarbakIrjail back in 1980?
The day l ran from the fascist coup
l was 26.
lt's easy to say
but that was 28 years ago.
And nothing has changed.
lt won't change either.
As long as those imperialist countries
continue acting as they do...
...as long as people keep
making money out of war...
...nothing will change,
nor will the war ever end.
No one thinks of the mothers
or the fathers.
God damn them all!
My handsome son...
Delal, if Serhat cries,
give him his dummy.
Dad, l know how to make his food.
Good for you, my love.
Delal, don't go out whatever you do.
lf you get bored, turn on the TV.
OK?
OK.
OK, l'm going.
Come home early, dad.
OK.
Come on, dad.
Mamo, we're leaving.
l'll be right there.
Kado, keep an eye on the kids!
Fuck it!
You miserable shit!
Wow, uncle.
Those mountains are so beautiful.
Could they ever take the place
of our snowy mountains?
You like it, nephew?
Yes, a lot, uncle.
There, Nomay's fjords for you...
Don't stay another minute.
Leave the house right now!
Please go away!
Don't let them see you.
Carry on like this
and you'll ruin your life.
They'll kill you.
Look, you have my number, right?
Call whenever you need to. OK?
My brother will kill me
if he finds out l've seen you.
Please go!
We're not in the backwoods here!
Call me!
Uncle, why is this milk all thick?
Give it here. It's gone o_.
What are you doing there?
It's not a toy.
lt's like this 300 days out of 365.
Overcast and rainy.
People here miss the sun.
You rarely ever see the sun here.
'Politi'.
What?
The police. The police.
Don't be alarmed, Davut.
Look, thousands of villages
in the region have been evacuated.
Hundreds of thousands of people
have been forced to migrate.
Try to understand these people.
That's Turkey's problem.
There's nothing we can do.
We'll have to send you to Oslo.
Go and see Cuma, son.
Ask him for help.
Go to the police station.
Do something.
OK, dad.
ButterFlies.
That's what we are.
Life is a tightrope for us.
You turn one way,
Iose your footing and whoops...!
You find yourself o_ the bridge.
Don't be a bug or a butterFly.
Get yourself a properjob.
l can't work.
l'm not like my brothers.
l've killed the man inside me.
Ooh! There's a man in there?!
Where?
Bring him out!
l want to see him!
Tansu...
Don't be a bitch!
You must earn your own living
like everyone else, girl.
What did you call me?
l called you ''girl''.
Hey! Where on earth
did you find this newbie?
Dad, didn't mum send
us any messages?
Of course she did!
What did she say, dad?
You know what she said?
Say hello to all my little doves.
And tell them l really miss them.
Dad, take us to the hospital too.
To the hospital?
When your mum's a bit better, my love,
l'm going to take you all!
The children won't sit still, son.
They're in tears all the time.
Don't run around, my love.
Don't make grandpa angry, OK?
Come on, Ramo. We'll be late.
Son, check again
with the police station.
OK, dad.
See you this evening.
Twenty horse mackerel...
And eight bonito.
Delal, let's go and play.
OK. Sure.
Sweet Serhat.
My beautiful baby.
Zelal, Serhat's pooed in his nappy.
Shall we give him a wash?
Don't cry, Serhat.
You'll soon be clean, sweet Serhat.
Come, Come.
Open the door!
ln the name of God...
What's going on, children?
Why have you got the
machine working?
Grandpa, we put Serhat in the
machine to wash him.
What?!
You put him in the machine?
Take him out! Take him out!
Delal!
Hazal!
We can't accept
everyone who comes here.
We're going to have to deport you.
lt was so very hard
for us to come all this way.
Please don't.
Don't send us back.
We have to send you back.
There's no alternative.
Sir, can you describe
how the incident happened?
We've been caught
bemeen the mo sides for 25 years.
Even my own children are divided.
One joined the guerrillas and
took to the mountains.
The other is a soldier.
Our situation speaks for itself.
Why did you come to Nomay?
Where we lived used to be the
most beautiful place on earth.
But they turned it into a living hell.
l lost the son
who became a guerrilla.
Do you know what it means
to lose a son?
What cause can be more
important than human life?
What war can be greater than peace?
l came here because l want to
live like a human being...
...and not keep losing my sons.
You see, my youngest son...
...stepped on a mine.
Show them your leg, Azat.
Put this down for the record.
The court rules as follows.
One: that Haydar Altun
and Ramazan Altun be acquitted...
...given insu_icient grounds
for sentencing...
...under article 2216
of the Turkish Penal Code.
Two: that the five children
in their charge be put in the care...
...of the Social Senrices
and Child Protection Agency.
l don't understand.
We're taking your children away
so the state can look after them.
The state?
So yes, the state is paying you
10,600 Kroner every month.
ln Turkish money that works out
at something like 2000-2500 Lira.
Paying us?
Why are they paying us
when we're not even working?
Only God gives without taking.
Are you sure
there's no catch involved?
We're talking about
a welfare state here, Davut.
l've spoken to the asylum o_icer.
As far as Azat's concerned
they've promised to help.
So yes, once we're out of here
all that's left to do is...
...find a house first, then some work.
Tell me, Gülistan,
what sort of house shall we look at?
Gülistan, what's happened to you?
Why won't you speak?
None of your sister's wounds
have ever healed.
She's been like this for seven years,
ever since the mine exploded.
All she thinks about is Azat.
About the children.
l didn't see. l didn't see
what the children were doing.
What a wave of disasters
we've been hit by!
May God keep you
from anything worse.
lt's best to leave
everything to time.
How many times did l tell you
not to take me away!
Patience, Haydar. Patience!
He's right.
There's surely a solution to everything.
lt's God that gave you the boy,
and God that took him away.
lt wasn't your fault, my love.
It was the machine's fault.
Now my little doves...
...you're starting school tomorrow.
From now on
you'll all be sleeping there.
l've spoken to the headmistress.
They'll be coming to fetch you.
All of us, dad?
Yes, all of you.
l'm not going!
l'm not going either, dad.
l'm staying with you.
But my love, it was so hard
to get you in there.
There's lots of kids at the school.
Don't be like this.
There are toys.
They play games...
...they go on trips, they learn.
Now don't cry, my little doves.
No more tears. Don't make me sad.
Like l said stick together
once you're there.
Work hard at your studies. OK?
Now kiss your grandpa's hand.
My little partridges...
My geraniums,
my hyacinths, my violets...
Work hard at your studies.
All right?
Let me take the baby.
Let me have him.
Dad, come with us.
Don't be like this, my doves.
You're going to school and
crying at the same time.
O_ you go now. Go on.
Come on, kids.
Let's get in the van.
The boy's making progress every day.
So is his sister.
Welcome, children.
Well, l was expecting you.
l'm your head-mother here.
Girls...
Shall we have a wander round?
And you know what?
We have a playroom too.
OK. Let's all go together.
All right?
Come on then.
Thank heavens for that!
She's opened her eyes.
isa, you go.
You've got things to do.
Ramo, she'll soon get better.
lf she doesn't get better,
we'll move to Istanbul too.
Zehra and mum will look after Havar.
They'll look after the kids too.
How will we get the kids back?
We should think about that.
lf they don't let us have them,
we'll steal them away.
Come on.
Go my beautifuls.
Ramo.
Are you allright my sun shine?
Everywhere aches. Ramo.
What?
How are my children?
Very good.
May God presenre from evil.
- Really?
- Yes.
Bring my children to me.
Children, your head-mother's here!
How are you, children?
We're fine, head-mother.
Children, aren't you going to welcome
your new friends?
Welcome!
Now has everyone brushed
their teeth?
Yes!
Well done!
Hayriye, take the girls o_
so they can get settled.
These are your beds, girls.
Everything happens to the poor.
Foist them on the rich again.
Take from us.
Embellishment is an excuse.
You know this stu_ right?
Fairy tale!
- Hello.
- Hello, Cuma.
There was a lad living round here.
A bit e_eminate.
Do you know where he's moved?
No idea.
Where can we find him then?
Those losers generally hang out
at transvestite bars in Beyoglu.
And sometimes they go out to work
in Harbiye.
What work is that?
Prostitution. You know?
- OK. Good night then.
- Good night.
Come on. Let's go, Mamo.
There's something dodgy there.
Hey, come on! Come on!
Run, run.
Good evening.
Good evening, hubby.
We're looking for someone called
Can who lives in TarlabaqI.
- Can?
- Can.
What's this Can like, hubby?
A butterFly or a bug?
He's just plain Can.
Are you up for it, hubby?
Buy one, get one free!
Fuck o_!
Just fuck o_!
Mamo..!
Mamo!
Life brings su_ering
as well as happiness, Davut.
Don't let it get you down.
Haydar will get over this too.
How's work?
Do you have an easy time there?
lt's great, thanks, uncle.
Uncle, there's something
l can't figure out, you know.
Why haven't you been able to
adjust to life here?
Well, nephew. Wherever it is,
no place far from home is bearable.
Not even if it were paradise.
Do you know what Cahit SItkI said?
''l long for a homeland''
''With skies of blue,
branches of green, fields of gold''
''A land of birds and flowers''
''l long for a homeland''
''Where life, like love,
comes from the heart''
''Where if there is cause to complain,
it is because of death''
''l long for a homeland''
''Where there is no grief,
nor cause to yearn''
''Where there is an end
to brothers fighting''
Here, love. The king's for you.
The queen goes to the king.
And here's the jack.
He's for all of us!
Newbie!
lt's time you went to work!
There's no eating for free
without going out on the game!
Tansu! Don't be a bitch.
Don't make me lose it either!
What's going on, Cansu?
Life is hard for all of us.
She has to work
just like all the girls.
Just ignore her, love.
Goodbye, head-mother!
Goodbye! Bye!
Do l look nice, head-mother?
Beautiful. Goodbye!
The girls haven't recovered
psychologically yet.
They'll be seeing their mother
very soon, doctor.
ln all the years l've been here
l've never seen such a devoted father.
Poor thing...
He's been here every night.
Do you know the person in the photo?
Thanks.
Sorry sister, do you know
the person in the photo?
Don't look at me like that, Tansu!
l haven't done anything wrong!
Oh no?! Don't steal my fucks again
or you'll be sorry!
Tansu!
Cansu, keep out of this!
Excuse me...
Excuse me!
Do you have any 'brunost'?
The kind you put on bread.
l guess not.
Berat!
Come and see what the man wants.
l'll be right there, dad.
Hello. Can l help?
l want some 'brunost'.
Brun..?
'Brunost'.
The kind you put on bread.
'Brunost'...
Ha! Brown goat's cheese.
Over there.
Thanks.
Well done, son.
No, dad.
It's a tricky language.
Sorry, sister.
Do you know this person?
There, over there!
This way! Come on!
So was that Kadri we were chasing?
Let's ask that camp fellow in the bar.
He'll know.
Think carefully. Don't do anything
you regret when you find the boy.
ln fact, just forget the whole thing.
We'll take care of it now, Cuma.
Ramo and l will figure
something out.
Remember.
l'm always here for you.
Thanks, Cuma.
Thanks.
Let me talk to him first if that's OK.
And you can examine him aftemards.
Sure.
Nephew...
The doctor will measure you first...
...then they'll operate if necessary.
OK, uncle.
That's my boy!
Now put your leg up here, nephew.
Now lie down nephew.
Well done.
We need to find you
a new place to live.
But l don't have anywhere
to go in Istanbul.
ls this some kind of custom or what?
lt's customary to migrate
but this isn't about customs.
My situation's more serious than that.
My brothers can't bear me
being like this.
They won't rest easy
until they've killed me.
Who gave you that?
Your boyfriend?
No. l brought it from the village.
We call it 'berFin'.
Its Turkish name is 'snowdrop'.
The flower has a story behind it.
Only one living thing on earth
is in love with the sun.
And that's the 'berFin'.
The flower is in love with the sun,
but has never seen it.
You see, it knows that it'll die
the moment it sees the sun.
All 'berFins' look at the sun
knowing that they're going to die...
...and wilt away that very minute.
Nothing can match the bravery
of a 'berFin'.
Ayyy!
Havar!
Are they here, doctor?
Yes.
Come on, dear.
Let's go.
Careful now.
Don't hurry.
Run, girls.
Run!
Look how pretty you are!
l am giong to stay with you Mum.
Mum, don't leave us!
Don't cry now.
Do you think l'd leave you?
Mum...
Mum... Mum...
Darling, my precious!
Where's Serhat?
Dad? Mamo?
Why won't any of you
say anything?
Where is he?
Serhat!
How's that, Azat?
All right, son?
Great, dad.
l'm glad we're here, Nedim.
We're here, but my mind
is always on the family.
On the wretched people
back home.
l can't stop thinking of our
snowy mountains.
Davut, there are contradictions
in those mountains you miss.
Terrible contradictions, too.
You have the guerrillas singing,
''Come up to the mountains!''
Then there's the army song that goes,
''l'll blow you to pieces, mountains.''
But if only the mountains
could be left to themselves...
...left to the birds, to the flowers,
to the bugs and the butterFlies.
lf only they could rest!
How wonderFul that would be, Nedim.
How wonderFul!
We've seen what a nice life
people have here all together.
People are human beings above all,
whatever their language or religion.
Come on now! Tea time!
- Here you are, sweetie.
- Thanks.
Hey, it's your guys.
Come on! Move!
What is this maniac doing?
Sorry, sister.
Do you know this person?
What's his name?
lt's Kadri...
Kadri.
l think l know him.
Why are you looking for him?
Find him for us, sister.
We want to talk to him.
ln that case, come to
the old Galata Bridge at sunrise.
l'll find Kadri and bring him along.
OK then.
Bye.
What happened, sister?
Couldn't you find him?
No. l looked everywhere.
Doesn't he have
an address or anything?
Why are you looking for him?
He's gone his own way,
made his choice.
lt's his life.
What harm is he to you?
His world is one thing,
yours is another.
Don't stay here.
Take your kids
and go back to your village.
Give up looking for Kadri.
Bye-bye!
Kado!
Turn round to face me, Kado!
Ramo, Mamo,
God made me like this.
l know you're going to kill me.
When l die, l'll stand before God
and ask him just one thing.
l'll say,
''Why didn't you make me a woman?''
Go on Mamo...
Shoot me. l'm ready.
Mamo...
Just let him go.
Come on, Mamo.
Mamo, you know l'm a woman.
Mamo, let him go!
l've done everything you can imagine.
On the floor, standing up, in bed.
l've had all kinds of sex.
Your brother's a woman!
Accept it!
Shut up!
l told you.
You didn't listen.
lt's beneath us, Kado.
Mamo.
Kado...
Brother!
Come on, nephew.
Walk for your mother.
But with your head held high.
Mum!
Azat!
Dear head-mother
This is Ramazan Alt_n.
l'm very grateful to you
for looking after my children.
My wife, the sunshine of my life,
got better in the state hospital.
Thanks to the mother state.
But then there's also a father state
that made a big mistake with us.
We were pitched into a foreign land
where we couldn't adjust.
We decided to come back.
l'm going to carry on raising
my kids in the midst of the fighting.
But how wonderFul it would be...
...if people who sing the same songs
people who support the same teams...
...and are brothers in the same land
could embrace one another for once.
lt's us men who want war
and the mothers who weep.
lt's my belief that only mothers
can put an end to this business.
We look fomard to seeing you
if you're ever this way, head-mother.
With my greetings and regards...
lN 25 YEARS OF CIVIL WAR IN TURKEY...
US_ 350 billion have been spent...
32,OOO guerrillas have been killed...
6,OOO members of the security forces
have been killed...
5600 people have gone missing...
3200 villages have been evacuated...
2 million people have been
forced to migrate.