Fixed & Synced by bozxphd
Enjoy The Flick
Here we go.
Whoa-ho-ho! Whoa-ho-ho!
Rise and shine, beautiful.
Here you go, buddy.
Oh, thank you.
I still use these.
What took you so long?
They forgot the Mu Shu pork,
and it's your favorite.
Kids, come on!
Food's ready, let's go, inside!
Susan, you hungry?
- Bruce's book...
- Hmm.
Hedging Your Bet Against
God By Bruce Brooks.
That's a great fucking title.
What's the book about?
Well, the way I see it,
was there's a Bible
for the afterlife.
I wrote the Bible
for the here and now.
I'm actually not kidding.
And people can say
all they want about insurance,
and guys like me,
but you know what?
At the end of the day,
having good insurance
is the most important thing
you can do while you're alive.
Every time you up it,
you're just hedging your bet against God,
am I right?
What are you doing?
Come on sit back down, Laney.
Everyone's enjoying the food.
The ribs are sour.
How would you know?
You didn't even eat them.
Laney, come on, sit down.
Daddy...
Where'd you get that dog?
We rescued him from the pound.
Janey, Bingo was supposed
to be a surprise for mommy.
Mommy, I think he needs you.
We talked about this.
No, you talked about this.
We didn't talk about anything.
Can you just give it a try?
Can you trust me?
Fuck you, Bruce.
Boom! Perfect!
Mom, can we keep her?
I don't know,
E. It's just one more thing to worry about.
E.
E, wake up.
You're having a nightmare.
What is it baby?
You have another bad dream?
Come here.
We were walking down the
street to go see Dad
and you were listening
to your headphones...
It's okay, take a deep breath.
Tell me.
I was trying to tell you,
but you wouldn't listen to me.
You couldn't hear me 'cause you
were listening to your headphones.
And there were all these cars.
And then I got trapped,
and I couldn't grab you.
And then the car just hit you.
You were dead.
That will never happen.
How do you know?
'Cause I don't have an iPod.
Oh, funny, Mom.
It will never happen because
I would never let it happen.
Okay? Go to sleep, Mommy's here.
I'll stay with you till
you fall asleep, okay?
Rise and shine, beautiful.
Thought I was gonna
have to wake you up.
No, I don't want to get up.
Come back to bed.
I wish.
Hey, Bingo.
Only school buses
allowed here, Lady.
Since when?
You must not be reading your emails.
Mom! It's okay, E.
Um, is Frank here?
Frank always lets me double park.
I'm sorry.
What's it say, Mom?
It says we have to park.
Come on, Come on.
Susan, what is this?
Oh, it's to check
the parent IDs.
They sent them in the mail.
Part of that whole new security thing?
I don't... Don't worry.
I'll vouch for you.
Okay, thank you.
ID?
I had a crazy morning.
I forgot it.
I will bring it tomorrow,
I promise.
Parent IDs are mandatory now.
We mailed them out last
week and sent an email.
I'll vouch for her. Thank you.
Mom? It's okay, E.
I've been walking him
to class for two years,
surely you can make
an exception for one day.
If I make an exception
for you, Mrs. Brooks.
Then I'm gonna have to
make one for everyone.
Is that how we want to teach our children?
I wouldn't think so.
At this point in the year,
Eli is familiar enough to
get to his own classroom.
He'll be fine. I'll take Janey?
Okay.
I'm okay, Mom. Are you sure?
Wait, Janey, give me a kiss!
Bye, baby.
Ooh.
I'll see you later!
Teach my kids,
you fucking bitch.
"Is that how you want
to raise your kids?"
Yeah, that's how I
want to raise my kids.
Thanks for the help,
you fucking condescending...
Yeah? Yeah.
I'm gonna take a shower.
Mmm-mmm.
It's early, stay with me.
No, I've got
to pick up the kids.
Nah!
Oh, God. I love you.
No, you don't.
What?
Why do you say that?
Because you're married.
And because no man can love a
girl whose ass he just fucked.
Jesus, Laney.
You're crazy, you know that?
I told you I'd leave Sue soon.
I love you.
That's what's so funny.
You could love me, fine.
I could love you. It doesn't matter.
It means nothing.
Fuck. Fuck!
You can't park here, ma'am.
We've been all through this, haven't we?
I was hoping you
wouldn't remember.
No, I remember.
Hey, Laney!
Oh.
Hey! Is everything okay?
Did Henry have a bad day?
No, I can't find Donny.
His cell phone has been off all day.
He hasn't been to the office.
I'm sure he's in
a meeting or something.
Lady, you gotta move it!
I'm moving!
Look, I'm sure,
I'm sure Donny is fine.
All right, thank you.
I'll call you later.
Okay, thanks. Okay.
Oh! Those are my kids!
Those are my kids!
Hurry, kids.
Kids, get in the car!
How was your day?
Good! How was yours?
It was good. How about you, E?
E, how was your day?
It was fine.
Mommy, your phone!
I know, Sweetie.
Did you miss me? Yes.
Did you cry?
How much do you love me?
Oh, good! Oh, good,
oh, good, oh, good.
Promise you'll never leave me.
Mommy, stop!
- I'm teasing, muffin!
- I'm just teasing.
Why aren't you eating?
Not hungry.
You need to eat more food.
Real food. Not lollipops.
Jesus, what are you,
the food police?
All that sugar
isn't good for you.
Empty calories, right guys?
Not...
Energy food. That's right!
Energy food.
And I know, if you eat too much sugar,
you can, um...
You can be very
tired and it can...
It can wear down your body.
That's right.
And you'll lose
some of your energy.
Mmm!
Did you that the pilgrims actually stole
America from the Native Americans?
They had the Native Americans teach
them how to grow corn and stuff.
And then they stole their land.
Is that, right?
Yeah, so we gave them casinos.
Mrs. Zeldis told you this?
No, John Frye did.
His mom told him.
She also said Thanksgiving is a lie.
John Frye's mother is a pig.
Lane.
All right.
You kids want to play basketball?
Really? Yeah!
As long as you promise to
take it easy on me. Let's go.
Okay! All right.
That's good. Yes!
Yeah!
That was high.
Eli, soap.
I already did.
Oh, you did?
Did you practice piano today?
E, you've got a piano recital coming up.
Did you practice?
Yeah. How much?
You done? All set?
Mmm-hmm. Great.
Whoa-oh!
Mom?
I can't breathe.
E, put on your T-shirt.
Ooh, dry your balls.
Mom!
You'll get a rash.
What's up?
I'm just thinking.
About?
Your balls.
What? Your balls!
Like do you worry
about drying them?
Do I worry?
Like when you were a little boy,
did your mother
teach you how to dry your balls,
or you just knew instinctively?
Like should I be teaching Eli?
Honey, you dry them like any
other part of your body.
Oh.
But if you don't dry it,
could you get a rash?
I guess you could,
but whatever you don't get
will just dry in your underwear.
What's going on, Laney?
Oh, your underwear!
Of course,
I don't know why I didn't think of that.
You know,
all this talk about balls...
You're so beautiful.
I feel like my dad
dried and powdered.
Christ, Laney,
can we change the subject?
We got to get rid of Bingo.
I'm serious. We can't keep him.
It's just a dog, Laney.
All kids get a dog.
Why does it have to
be such a big deal?
Why does everything
have to be such a big deal?
Because dogs get old and die!
I mean, what does
a dog live? Ten years?
Yes. Ten enjoyable years
our kids can have a dog.
Only you could manage to turn getting
a dog into a fucking negative.
I'm trying to spare
them a negative!
This dog is going to die,
and our kids will be heartbroken.
Yeah, but that's life, Lane.
That's how it works.
Dogs die. Bingo will die too.
The kids can handle it.
I can't handle it.
Well, then why bother
loving anything, hmm?
I mean, why bother loving me?
Yeah, yeah. I don't see why
anybody bothers loving anything.
Oh, come on, Lane.
You don't mean that.
I do mean that.
So what do you suggest?
Don't fall in love.
Don't...
Don't get married.
Don't have kids.
Don't act like everything's gonna be okay,
when nothing's gonna be okay.
Well, thankfully most of us
like to keep fooling ourselves.
You okay? Yeah, I'm okay.
Why wouldn't I be okay?
I don't know.
I just worry about you, that's all.
I got to go check on the kids.
Hello?
Hi, is this Diane? Yes.
I'm so sorry to call so late.
This is Laney Brooks, I'm Eli's mom.
Fine. Actually, I'm not,
that's funny, I'm not fine. I...
Eli came home from school
today with a bunch of stories
about how the Pilgrims
were thieves,
and Thanksgiving
is a lie, and I...
Well, that's fine, I...
Well, you...
Yes, you can teach your kids
anything you want, I just would.
I'm trying to teach my son, uh,
to have gratitude and Thanksgiving...
Okay, now, I didn't call to get into
a debate with you, Diane, I just...
Mmm-hmm.
That's fine. Yeah, no, no, no.
How about this,
why don't you go fuck yourself?
And you can tell
your little brat
to stay the fuck
away from my kid.
Help.
Bruce.
Laney?
Are you okay?
Honey, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Oh, Jesus, Laney.
What did you do?
I don't think I can do this.
It's just a month, Laney.
You'll be home before you know it.
You must be Laney.
Okay. You can keep these.
And you can keep that.
And I need your bra too, honey.
Jesus.
I suggest you try
and get some sleep.
Drink as much water as you can.
We'll check on you
through the night
just to make sure
everything's okay.
Questions?
I need to call my husband.
We'll give him regular updates.
Everybody's anxious
their first time, honey.
You're gonna do great.
I'll check on you later.
When did you
start hating me, Lane?
I don't hate you, Bruce.
Then why did you
stop taking your meds?
They were making me fat.
That's bullshit. It's true.
So, what,
you'd rather be insane?
You promised me
you'd take your medication.
If not for me,
then for the kids.
They're gonna start to notice.
I need to call my husband.
There's been a mistake.
It's honestly just
not the place for me.
Your doctor will help you with
that when you see him, honey.
Okay,
well then I'd like to see the doctor now.
You know,
the first 48 hours are the worst.
Well, is this
a fucking hospital?
'Cause I'd like to
see the doctor now.
This is a fucking
hospital right?
Relax, relax. You need to get
some rest. This is the worst...
Don't fucking touch me!
You're gonna feel better soon.
I just want you to be happy,
Laney, like you used to be.
Don't you want to be happy?
Okay, your blood work shows
cocaine, amphetamines,
Ambien and marijuana,
but there's no trace of lithium.
Do you want to tell me why you
stopped taking the lithium?
Nurse Pauline says that
you're desperate to go home,
and that you feel
you don't belong here.
I don't.
Well then, why are you staying?
Call someone and go.
You're an adult.
Why not?
Because I have a family. So?
So, I can't just go home
and do this again.
So, uh, where would
you like to start?
Really?
Really.
What's more interesting for you,
the daddy issues or the drugs?
Well, uh, I'd like to start
with the daddy issues
because it's a very organic
segue into the drugs.
Well, mine's boring.
My dad left when I was nine.
That's the whole story.
He kissed me goodnight,
and that's the last time I saw him.
So, drugs?
Yeah, we'll get to that.
Can you tell me why you
haven't spoken again?
Um, he didn't call me.
Why didn't you call him?
Because I didn't
know where he lived.
Ah.
He's upstate.
My brother told me.
So, your brother talks to him?
He does.
Or he did. I don't know.
We um, we don't talk about
Dad anymore because, um,
it always ends up in a fight.
When he left my mother,
she was devastated.
So, I... I held onto that.
And he
didn't, I guess.
Did she remarry? Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, a few years later.
Why didn't you call him then?
Why don't you ask him
why he didn't call me?
Why do you think
he didn't call you?
Can we talk about the drugs now?
Hello? Hi!
Hey, how's it going?
Good! It's going...
It's going well.
How are you? Good.
The kids are wiped out.
Getting ready for bed.
It was a big day ice skating.
You went ice skating,
without me?
Laney, I...
I just... It's just...
We always go together, I mean,
it's kind of our thing.
Yeah, I know, Laney.
But you're not here.
Would you rather
I didn't take them?
No.
No, I just...
I should've been there.
I know, and you'll
take them next year.
Just focus on getting better,
the kids need you. I need you.
I'm sorry. I got to go.
Can I say
good night to the kids?
I don't want to
upset them before bed.
We'll see you at
the family visit.
I'm sorry, Laney, I...
I have to go. I love you.
We all love you.
We miss you here.
I love you too.
You look good.
Feeling better?
I am.
You seem like
you're making progress.
Yeah.
Why don't you say what you're
really thinking, Bruce?
What?
I don't understand why you're so angry.
I'm not...
What? I'm not angry!
I'm not angry. I'm scared.
What are you scared of?
Everything!
I know you think that if I
take my medication every day,
that everything
will go back to normal.
But it's bigger than that.
What is Eli doing with his eyes?
Have you noticed that?
No.
Is he doing that at school?
I don't know.
No one's called me about it.
You can't wait for someone to
call you about it!
You have to call them. Kids
could be making fun of him.
You've got to call the teacher on Monday.
First thing. You've got to...
Promise me you'll call
the teacher on Monday.
I promise, Laney.
I'll make sure he's okay.
Don't worry about it.
I need to tell you some things.
Some
really fucked up things I did
when I wasn't thinking clearly
and I want you to know them.
So we can start fresh.
I don't want
to do this now, Laney.
It's important for me,
that I, that I... I need to...
Come on kids. That's enough.
Let's go. Sit down.
How many cupcakes did you eat?
One.
One? Liar.
She ate two.
Okay. Bye, Mommy!
Bye, baby!
Oh, it's so good to see you!
It's so good to see you.
I brought you something.
You did?
I made this for you.
Dream catcher!
No more bad dreams.
Thank you. E, thank you. I love it.
I love it. It's beautiful.
Neither of them
will ever know how hard
I tried to not hurt them.
Am I gonna fuck this up?
I don't want to fuck this up.
Well, you're gonna
fuck up sometimes.
You're gonna say things
that you regret,
you're gonna do things
that you're not proud of,
and then you're gonna remember
that you're a human being.
We all have our moments.
But when you came here,
you made a conscious decision.
And that was to live.
Nobody tells you
that it's terrifying,
you know,
to love something so much.
Well, yeah.
You're going to have to find
a way to face your terror.
And, uh, you're going to have
to decide what it is you want.
Right.
What do you want?
I've made really shitty
decisions my whole life.
And I just...
I need to remember
how to be a good wife,
and a good mother,
and a real person.
I want to smile like
I did the first time
I saw Janey walk across a room.
I'd love to smile like
that again. You know?
It might not happen right away.
You might have
to wait for a bit.
Look, everything beautiful,
every moment of beauty,
it goes away. Fades.
But then there's another one,
and another one,
and another one.
And you just have to
be alive to see it.
Keep taking your meds.
Have faith in yourself.
Eli, you want to
help us ice the cake?
No, thanks.
It's not the way I pictured it.
It's not perfect.
What? It is perfect.
What are you talking about?
I don't know why you're crying.
This cake is beautiful.
Isn't it, E?
I like it.
See?
All right, basement's dry.
What's going on?
She doesn't like her cake.
What? Janey,
that's a great cake!
That's the best cake
I've ever seen.
Really? Really.
Hey, can I smell it?
Does it smell as
good as it looks?
Okay.
Mmm.
Daddy! Yeah, that smells good.
Your nose! What?
What's wrong with my nose?
You have something on your nose.
What?
I don't see anything. Your nose!
Right there. What?
I want to smell it! Okay!
Oh, my gosh!
You got a little something.
What? Just a little...
Smell it, Mommy!
I'm want to smell it. Can I smell it?
Oh, my gosh!
That's the best smelling cake
I've ever smelled.
Come on, E.
You want to smell it?
- What?
- Mommy!
- Oh, it's all right, muffin.
- It's just the electricity.
It'll come back
in a few minutes.
Janey, look at this.
This one is just for you.
Are you kidding me?
You can do better than that.
What concerns me
are the rituals.
The eye blinking,
the constant pencil sharpening.
Recently,
he started a pattern with tapping his feet.
These behaviors suggest anxiety.
The rituals are a way for
Eli to stay in control.
It's not unusual,
but the rituals
can become a problem
when they get in
the way of functioning.
When they become all consuming.
So, what do we do?
In my opinion, Eli
needs to see a specialist.
Perhaps start with cognitive
behavioral therapy.
Or, perhaps, he can even
benefit from medication.
Medication?
It's my fault.
He's got my genes.
Stop it.
Did you go to rehab because
you're a drug addict?
No. Why...
Why would you think that?
John Frye said
you're a drug addict?
Mommy, drugs are bad.
That's not why she was there, E.
John Frye is just
trying to get your goat.
Eli doesn't have a goat.
Then why were you there?
I was having some
problems in my mind.
And they were making me do
things I shouldn't have done.
Then why did you do them?
Well, it's complicated. But, um,
but I saw a doctor
who was really, really smart.
And he helped me sort
through my problems.
And now I'm better.
Did Mr. Odesky tell you
to send me to rehab too?
No. No, no, no.
Mom, look at this one.
It's so cool.
Really cool.
Eli! Hey, Henry!
Hey, look who it is. Hey.
Hi, Donny. Hi, Henry.
Hey, it's good to see you back.
Oh, it's good to be...
It's good to be back.
Which one are you getting?
I have to see what I can afford.
I'd get a superhero
if I were you, Eli.
Now,
I don't know about you guys,
but I have always wanted
to be the kind of superhero
that swoops into
the burning building
and then rescues the woman
and flies her off to safety.
Well,
you can't be Batman 'cause he doesn't fly.
Right.
And Spider-Man doesn't really fly.
He swings.
Well, what do you guys
think about Superman?
What do you think, Laney?
I think I could be a good Superman.
I think you're
already a superhero, Donny.
Laney! It's so good to see you.
I've missed you.
I...
I didn't know that
you were pregnant.
You're glowing!
Oh, bullshit. I look like shit.
I feel like shit.
But I'm almost halfway through,
thankfully.
Oh, my gosh! Congratulations!
Thanks. Hey, did you get my
message about my birthday party?
I did. I'm sorry, I did.
It's fine, I just want to make sure
you know, no pressure, really.
I totally understand
if you'd rather skip it.
We're gonna be there.
We're planning on it. Okay.
Can I get this one, Mom? Yes.
Oh, hey, good choice, my man.
Um, we've got to go.
So, we'll see you next weekend!
Yeah! We'll see you soon.
Bye, Henry.
Oh, my big girl.
I have a wish.
You do? What's your wish, baby?
I can't tell you.
Why can't you tell me?
Because it won't come true.
Who told you that?
I don't remember.
Well, whoever told you doesn't
know about the "mommy clause."
You can always
tell Mommy your wish.
I wish you'll love me forever.
You don't have to
worry about that, baby.
I will always love you.
Forever? Forever!
I don't know, I always heard
you're not supposed
to have too much time.
Listen, I cover
all that in the book.
But, to answer your question,
there really is no such thing as
having too much life insurance.
Especially,
if you're planning on having more kids.
No offense, David,
you look like you are in great shape.
Seriously.
But, I'm guessing Katrina
here is going to outlive you.
Yeah. That's the plan
I mean, I plucked her
out of high school.
Stop, I was almost
out of college.
Yeah, the book covers
a lot of unique scenarios.
I see it like this, Dave.
There's a Bible
for the afterlife,
I wrote the Bible
for the here and now.
Yeah. It sounds brilliant.
I mean, especially, that notion of,
uh, hedging your bet against God.
Sure it'll be a bestseller.
You know, I have always
dreamed of writing a book.
But, how did you do it, Bruce?
I mean, did you just sit down
and type everything you were
thinking into a computer?
Or did you pay
someone to help you?
It's sentence by sentence.
Anyone can do it.
Listen, you call me any time,
and I would be
happy to help you.
Thank you.
What do you want to
write a book about?
You know, like,
maybe a children's book?
I'm not sure yet.
I'm thinking
about writing a book.
Really? On what?
Prostitution.
Prostitution? Come on, honey.
You don't know anything
about prostitution.
It's the ultimate hypocrisy.
It's illegal to sell
your body, right?
But if you're rich enough,
it's perfectly acceptable.
They just call it being a wife.
Sorry.
Uh, I would like to make a toast,
uh, to my beautiful wife.
Thank you.
Thank you for putting up
with the restaurant hours,
and thank you for
putting up with me.
Suz, I just want you to know,
that, uh, every morning
when I drive away to work,
and I see you standing there waving,
with Henry by your side,
the only thing
I'm thinking about
is how fast I can
get back to you.
Happy birthday, honey.
Hey. Hey.
God, you look amazing.
Do I? Like a million bucks.
Thank you.
I wanted to... I was gonna call.
But I figured I had done enough,
that I had done enough damage.
No, you... It's not your fault.
You could have been any man.
Wow, really.
That came out wrong.
I just meant
it's not your fault,
you didn't drive me to rehab.
I am here for you.
If you need anything,
you just call me, okay?
Thanks. Thank you, Donny. Yeah.
Not at home.
You can call the restaurant.
If you need anything,
you talk to Jeanine, okay?
I mean, anything at all.
Thank you.
When are you gonna talk to me?
Why would you do that?
Babbling about prostitution?
I was this close to signing
David Blackman as a client.
I know. Do you?
Do you have any idea how hard
I work to keep this all going?
'Cause you act like
it's some big joke.
Like what I do for a living
is somehow beneath you.
We used to be in this together.
Remember?
We used to be on the same team.
I'm sorry. I said I was sorry.
I am, I mean it.
I know how hard
you work. And I...
I don't know
what I was thinking.
Come here. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
She was just, she was such a...
Prostitute?
Yes!
Why don't you come to the
conference with me this weekend?
What if we run into my dad?
We don't ever have
to leave the hotel.
I don't know,
you know how those things are.
It's just people being shitfaced
for three straight days,
and I don't...
Not for us.
Nothing stronger than water for me, either.
Come on, we can lay in bed.
You could get a massage.
What about the kids?
They'll stay with my sister.
They've been
through so much already.
They'll be fine, Lane.
Happy parents make happy kids.
Just think about it, all right?
It's been a long night.
I'll go with you.
Thank you.
I hate Upstate.
You don't hate Upstate,
you just hate your dad.
I think I hate them both.
Can I hate them both?
Yes, you can hate them both.
Rise and shine, beautiful.
No.
Pancakes and coffee.
And bacon? Of course!
I've got to call housekeeping.
I got to get my dress steamed.
Wait, wait.
Wait one second.
What have you done?
Who would have ever thought you'd
be able to afford this ring?
You did.
Tell me the newsstand story.
And I want a massage.
I forgot how high maintenance you are.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, the newsstand story.
Once upon a time,
there was this
incredibly good looking kid.
Awkward kid.
Oh, right, I'm sorry,
that was a different story, my bad.
There was this incredibly
awkward kid in Teaneck,
who used to rack magazines at a store
around the corner from his house,
so he could make
some extra bucks.
He was usually bored out of his skull,
but one day,
this knockout walked in.
Long black hair,
and some really incredible...
You know what I'm saying?
There was just
something about this girl.
So this kid,
started dressing up for work.
Bullshit, he wore a T-shirt.
If you knew how carefully he
selected them for fit and color.
Anyway, the point of the story is
that every day this kid would wait,
wondering when that girl
would come back in.
Mmm.
And then,
one day she came back in
and asked the old man behind the
counter for a pack of smokes.
And, when he turned
around she boosted
a candy bar and
stuck it down her pants.
But before she left,
she turned around
and gave the kid a huge smile.
Blew him away.
He thought,
this chick is hot and crazy.
So he rushed out after her,
desperate to get the nerves up to
talk to her for the first time,
and then she did the thing
that just owned him.
She gave the candy bar to the
homeless guy who lived in the alley.
And right then,
the kid was done.
Whatever it took,
he knew he was gonna marry that girl.
And did he?
I'm gonna go jump in the shower.
I don't want to be late.
Let's fuck first.
Mmm.
You sure you don't
want to come with me?
As much as I love insurance seminars,
I think I might pass.
Funny. All right,
I'm back at 5:00,
cocktails at 6:00,
and the awards at 7:00.
I'll be ready.
Have fun. Thanks.
Oh, I...
- I think I'm at...
- Daisy...
Elaine?
Hi.
What a... What a surprise.
Um...
Daisy, Daisy. This is Elaine.
She's, um...
I knew your dad a long time ago.
You can call me, Laney.
Come in, come in!
And this is Daisy's room.
Did you have a dollhouse
when you were little?
I did. What color?
Yellow with blue shutters.
That's me, that's Mommy,
and that's Daddy.
All right.
Let's snap.
Okay!
Bike helmets, huh?
Yeah, all these laws.
All that P.C. garbage.
Keeping our kids safe.
Helmets, car seats, this, that.
We didn't have any of this stuff
when you were a kid,
and you came through.
You survived just fine.
Um...
I thought...
I thought maybe we would,
uh, come down to the city,
Daisy and me, over the summer.
You know,
maybe meet her niece and nephew?
Janey and Eli are their names.
Janey and Eli, yeah, right.
Uh, I'd like to meet them too.
My grandkids.
And Bruce.
I just, you know, when you're...
When it's the right time.
When you're feeling better.
Who told you?
Your brother calls me from time to time.
He gives me updates.
Why didn't you call me?
You were in the hospital.
It didn't seem the right time.
I mean,
the 30 years before that.
She loves that bike.
Gave it to her for
her last birthday.
When I was her age,
all I cared about was baseball.
I'll never forget when
I hit my first homerun.
Pow!
Brought in three runs.
I was so excited I ran all
the way home from school.
And, "Ma! Ma! Ma!" I shouted, "Ma!"
I couldn't wait to tell her.
I burst right into her bedroom.
Didn't even knock.
And there she was.
Face down on the floor
in a pool of her own vomit.
I never knew that.
No. You were too young.
I don't think your...
your mother even knew.
I felt calling you was wrong.
It was too much for me.
The whole family thing.
I wasn't ready.
I just couldn't do it.
This time, Daisy helps me make her
lunch before she goes to school.
I never knew that would mean something.
Making lunch.
I have to go.
Can I use your bathroom?
Yeah, of course.
I really could have given you
a ride back to your hotel.
Give us more time to catch up.
Next time.
Bye, Daisy.
It was very nice to meet you.
Take good care of
your daddy, okay?
Hey. Can I?
Yeah.
I never stopped
thinking of you, Elaine.
Make it work this time.
Go.
Hi, this is Bruce Brooks.
Please leave a message.
Fuck.
Keep 'em coming.
Not a problem.
Enjoy the company.
Where are you from?
Minnesota.
Dylan, Prince
or The Replacements?
I went to the same high
school Dylan went to.
You're gonna think I'm crazy.
I like crazy.
Forget it.
Tell me.
Do people tell you, you look like Jesus?
Because you look like Jesus.
Bruce, I'm... I'm so sorry.
I fell asleep by the fireplace.
And, um, when I woke up,
it was over.
The ceremony.
And I would have gone over, but I was...
I was nervous because I didn't
want to disappoint you.
But how was it? Were you a hit?
I looked for you there, Laney.
You weren't there.
So, now you don't
believe me, is that it?
Yeah. I don't believe you.
Well, Jesus... No.
Do not try to make me
the bad guy here.
Saying your lie louder
doesn't make it true.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Listen to me, I...
I found a couple Xanax in the
bottom of my purse, and...
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Huh?
Why is it so easy for you to look
me in the eyes and lie to me? Why?
Huh?
Do you even love me, Laney?
Yes, of course I love you!
It's just not enough, huh?
I'm going to Atlanta,
I've got business there for a few days.
I need to clear my head
and figure out
where we go from here.
Well, when are you back?
What about Eli's recital?
I'll be there in time for that.
And they can stay with
my sister until then.
What, you don't
trust them with me?
No. I don't.
Look, I...
I think this was my fault.
I shouldn't have brought you up here.
It was too soon.
No, yeah, it was too soon.
I said it was too soon,
and now you're leaving me here.
You always seem to find
your way home eventually.
I just don't know if I want to
be there this time when you do.
Much has been written
about Beethoven's deafness,
but my favorite
story is this one.
After the first
performance of The Ninth...
Beethoven just stared
blankly at the orchestra.
A thoughtful musician realized that
he couldn't hear the clapping, so...
Daddy! Daddy!
He made Beethoven turn
around to face the audience.
Bruce, please.
Why don't you sit with your family?
This isn't Carnegie Hall.
It was Beethoven's eyes,
not his ears,
that conveyed
the symphony's triumph.
And now let's use
our eyes and ears,
while we welcome
Eli Brooks to the stage.
Eli will be performing the
final movement of The Ninth,
The Ode to Joy.
Come on, Buddy.
Why is Mommy crying?
Oh, they're happy tears, baby.
You were just spectacular.
You were just
so extraordinary, E.
I don't deserve
to be your mother.
All right. Who wants a snack?
I do! I do!
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
See you in a minute.
- Mom?
- Mom!
Laney? God, I...
I can't find my contact. This is crazy.
Because it's clear. It's...
Hi, Pumpkin.
Oh.
Hey. Hey.
I need something to calm down.
What happened?
Um, I don't want
to talk about it.
I just... I need something.
Laney, I can't
give you anything.
What kind of person
would that make me?
Donny, this is not
the time to moralize.
You were just in rehab.
And now I'm not.
So, please...
It's all going to be okay.
Okay?
Not for me. No.
For you though,
you're having a baby!
We'll figure that out.
Suz, what's up?
Okay, I'm on my way.
Honey, everything's
gonna be okay.
Tell him Daddy's on the way.
How many people are you gonna
make everything okay for?
I got to go.
I know. I know.
Beer.
No Springsteen on the Jukebox?
Springsteen fan?
Best musician on the planet.
Put Jersey on the map.
Frank Sinatra would probably
argue with that, and Bon Jovi...
Bon Jovi?
All he ever wanted
was to be Bruce.
We all want to be
something better than we are.
So...
So, what?
Lick it. Lick what?
Lick it. Lick my ass.
I'm not licking
that fucking ass.
No more, fucker.
I'll tell you when it's no more.
Fuck!
That hurt?
I didn't even feel it.
I didn't feel it.
Hope it helped -> bozxphd