A SHOCHIKU FILM
I WILL BUY YOU
Produced by
MASAHARU KOKAJI
Based on the Novel by
MINORU ONO
Screenplay by
ZENZO MATSUYAMA
Cinematography by
YUHARU ATSUTA
Production Design by
SHUKEI HIRATAKA
Sound by
SABURO OHMURA
Music by
CHUJI KINOSHITA
Starring
KEIJI SADA
KEIKO KISHI
MINORU OHKI
YUNOSUKE ITO
MITSUKO MITO
EIJIRO TONO
KOJI MITSUI
JUN TATARA
TATSUYA ISHIGURO, FUJIO SUGA
TAKAMARU SASAKI
KYU SAZANKA, HISAO TOAKE
Directed by
MASAKI KOBAYASHI
Nakaminato.
This is Nakaminato Station.
Train for Katsuta departing now.
Next station is Nakane.
Hey.
They got good players.
They're number one or two
in the prefecture.
Yeah?
First of all, they have a good pitcher.
His fastball's got heat.
Does it?
Care for one?
Wow, thanks.
Is there a batter
who can take him on?
Not a chance.
No one can hit his pitch.
The "Smoke Ball," they call it.
Slides by just like smoke.
Our boss loves baseball.
But he's got a good offer from Mito.
They poached him?
Money talks.
Where in Mito?
Hey, Old Lady Takayama.
You got a visitor.
Thanks.
Are you the mother
of Mitsuo Takayama?
Yes.
Are you from the factory?
No. Where can I find Mitsuo now?
He's sleeping at home.
What?
He's an idiot.
What happened?
He lost a finger at the factory.
What do you want with Mitsuo?
Nothing, not anymore.
Wish him well. Good-bye.
TOYO FLOWERS
I'm back, Boss.
Welcome back.
You don't look happy.
I had to bring this back.
What happened?
I got your telegram.
This is going to cost us a fortune.
Yeah?
Get me Manager Miyazawa.
And get us a taxi.
Yes, sir.
It didn't work out?
Another team got him?
He lost a finger on a lathe.
It's a damn shame, Boss.
Too bad.
We could've gotten him cheap.
Hey.
Welcome back.
There's a reason
we called you back.
Kurita at Syowa University.
What?
Can we get him?
We want him.
Let's go.
We'll tell you in the car.
Ippei Kyuki. His last name is "Ball Spirit"?
Who the hell is he?
We have no idea who he is.
- A leech?
- Could be.
He brought Kurita out to Tokyo
and sent him to college.
His benefactor, I guess.
Watch out!
Idiot!
KURITA
Hit it, slug it, Kurita!
Hit it, Kurita.
Slug it, Kurita.
Batter is uniform number 3,
center fielder, Kurita.
Hooray! Hooray!
Kurita!
He's well built.
No wonder every scout is after him.
Kurita!
Furukawa with the Socks
is over there.
Handen wants him, too.
He didn't need to hit that.
He's raising his price.
Kurita!
Batter is uniform number 4,
first baseman, Ohmura.
Hey, you're here, too?
That's Natsume,
the scout with Kyushu.
Kurita has many suitors.
DAITO TRADING COMPANY
Who is it?
Is Mr. Kyuki here?
Which ball club are you with?
Huh?
You're the third one.
You're a scout, aren't you?
Mr. Kyuki?
No, I'm president here.
Oops, I'm sorry.
I'm Kishimoto
with the Toyo Flowers.
The Toyo Flowers?
Go away.
Besides, you're too late.
Kurita is, mind you, a big deal.
The Handen Lilies and the Osaka Socks
were here a week ago.
Your new manager,
what's his name, Miyazawa?
He's too young.
He hasn't got an eye for players.
Is he?
I've been saying this
since last year.
If you take Kurita,
your team will be twice as strong.
Please help us out.
The Toyo Flowers are anxious to...
Don't be stupid.
I'm anxious for the Flowers.
I'm sweating 'cause
I want you to take him.
Are you a fan of the team?
No, what're you doing?
You creep.
You fool.
Here comes Kyuki.
Kyuki.
This is Kishimoto,
a scout with the Toyo Flowers.
My name is Kishimoto.
Nice to meet you.
He's a piece of work.
They said he was eccentric.
This man is a tough customer.
If it's about Kurita, go away.
No, I won't go away.
I'm asking you to help us.
If Kurita joins our team,
we can win next year.
Every team wants to win.
Please.
I don't like flatterers.
For example, Furukawa
with the Osaka Socks.
You know him?
Really, Kurita is
the hardest hitter in Japan.
You've trained him, Mr. Kyuki.
You're the best coach in Japan.
I hate people like him the most.
On the other hand,
the Handen scout, Shima...
A dog needs a collar. A horse, reins.
A nation, a prime minister.
A good player needs a good coach.
That's the bottom line.
I don't like anyone.
I'm turning you down.
Please don't be hasty.
Didn't you see me
taking medication just now?
Huh?
Listen, he's ill.
Just as well,
I'll take the sake.
Thank you.
I knew he was no ordinary rat.
He's a slimy sewer rat.
I don't like him, Boss.
You're the rat.
You stay on him. Don't let up.
Excuse me.
Here.
They have no common courtesy.
Kuri and I are closer
than father and son.
Kuri won't even meet them
for coffee without me.
Of course he wouldn't.
Have a drink.
The newspaper reporters say
you're like two peas in a pod.
Don't flatter me.
Don't they call me a leech?
Of course not.
They say Kurita owes you his life.
You've made him who he is now.
Must've been hard work.
Nobody acknowledged his talent.
I taught him everything, from A to Z.
He learned so quickly.
I hear you paid for all
of Kurita's college tuition.
It wasn't much to speak of.
But it's four years.
That's a vast sum of money.
I gather Kurita's family
is indebted to you, Mr. Kyuki.
His family is rather complicated.
He's got four brothers.
The two oldest are from a different mother.
The oldest is an ex-con.
With all that,
Kuri must've been feeling Ionely.
He bonded with me
like I'm his father.
What's wrong?
I have a stone.
A gallstone.
Are you seeing a doctor?
I had it checked at a medical school
in Osaka last year.
They said I needed an operation.
You have to take care of yourself.
That's an interesting watch.
May I take a look?
Without this,
I tend to forget to take my medication.
I see.
By the way...
can our team pay some
of Kurita's college tuition?
Let's go.
You want to solve everything with money.
I don't like it.
Excuse me.
Mr. Kyuki, what's wrong?
This is it.
I gotta take advantage of this.
This man has a weakness, too, Boss.
Hello, is anybody here?
Get a doctor.
I was surprised.
I didn't know
you'd writhe in such agony.
It happens whenever
I eat anything greasy.
I see. Our team has a good doctor.
Why don't you let him take a look?
What kind of strings are attached?
What are you talking about?
Pull over.
Please, come on.
- Where are you taking me?
- Don't worry about it.
Good evening.
Hello.
- Mr. Kishimoto.
- Hi.
Welcome, sir.
Show us some fabrics for him.
Mr. Kishimoto, please don't.
Don't worry about it.
Just a token of my goodwill.
You shouldn't do that.
I'm leaving.
Mr. Kyuki.
Don't try a cheap trick.
Taxi!
Please go on.
I'll find a cab.
Then take this.
For the tailor. Might not be enough.
You're doing too much.
Don't worry about it.
Go on.
Good night.
Can I call you tomorrow?
I'm not going to work tomorrow.
But...
Don't come in.
I'm in the bath now.
You can't come in.
Who is it?
It's me.
You're no exception.
You have no manners.
Where have you been?
- Making money.
- Mahjong again?
Lottery. If I win, I win big.
- Want me to join you?
- Idiot.
Kuri's here.
Kurita is?
You're here.
I'm having a rough night.
I took her to Togeki Theater and Hibiya.
Now we're fighting over dinner.
We need to talk.
Fueko, sorry, would you
excuse yourself a moment?
I'm going to change.
Secret conference?
I find Mr. Kyuki creepy.
Don't bad-mouth him
in my presence.
I'm not bad-mouthing him.
He's fooling my sister, too.
He says, "I'll get a divorce," but then
sends money to his wife in Okayama.
You know nothing, Kurita.
Want a little money, Fueko?
I interrupted your fun.
I'm not like my sister.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You gonna make the dorm curfew?
Yes.
Here's the thing.
Kishimoto from the Toyo Flowers
came to see me today.
He said he wanted to see you.
Please turn him down.
I still have the College League fall games.
Swing the bat one more time.
You're opening too early.
Let me have it.
When you take a swing,
you open up this arm too soon.
Like this?
But you met Shima,
the scout from Handen.
It's weird to meet one,
but not the other.
Of course I understand
you're going to college.
You can focus on the College League
until graduation.
They wouldn't like student players
negotiating with pro teams.
I wouldn't like it, either.
But if you...
I'm saying "if'...
If you want to go into
professional baseball,
it's not good to give their scouts
a bad impression.
I'll leave it all to you, Mr. Kyuki.
- Do you trust me with everything?
- Yes.
I can handle all the talks
with the pros?
Yes.
You won't regret it.
Excuse me, now.
It's okay.
You gave me some the other day.
You'd be running out of it.
An empty wallet
makes the bat slow down.
HANDEN LILIES SCHEDULE
"No deals until after the championships."
Kyuki's violating Kurita's human rights.
He wants more money.
The leech invokes his legal right.
That's Japan in a nutshell.
You just need to get to Kurita.
Leave it to me.
Kurita is off on the 16th.
I'm taking him to an all-girl musical.
Boys like him don't go for
sophisticated shows.
Revues are the best.
Those scalpers are parasites.
I said, "Three tickets."
He said, "Five grand."
I said, "No way I can pay five."
He said,
"Give me five, or go away."
I had no choice
but to give him five.
It's just so stupid.
Stop complaining. Ouch.
Get in touch with Kyuki.
Oh, yeah. I gotta work.
Aren't you spending
too much money?
I need to spend money.
He's got a leech.
Don't worry about the money.
Isn't it the job of a scout
to be thrifty?
I know that, Boss,
but we've got to bait the trap.
Kyuki is only sniffing around.
We haven't caught him yet.
I get it.
I'll leave the sumo tickets
with the tea shop.
Okay.
Okay. I see.
The thing is, he's busy on the 16th.
He needs to decline your invitation.
That's his message.
Decline?
I've already got tickets.
I'm so sorry.
Yes, but...
I'm sorry.
What? You don't know where he is?
It's the Flyweight Championship.
He won't see a fight like this
ever again.
You're putting me in a corner.
I paid 5,000 yen to a scalper.
Give them to me.
But you hate boxing.
I can sell them.
Spend the night.
Tonight?
Hello? Hello?
Yes. I'm sorry.
I'll tell him when he's home.
Ouch. That hurts.
You're so mean.
That's what they're saying.
Keep fighting.
Fight, fight.
That's the spirit!
Keep fighting.
Oh, no. I lost again.
Here's your 1,000 yen.
Here you go.
Stop it already, Mr. Kishimoto.
He'll take the shirt off your back.
Then I'll get into
the sumo ring myself.
Let's bet on the next match.
- I feel bad for you. Let's not.
Turning your back on a bet?
Look behind you.
We'd be a bad influence.
Is she Kurita's girlfriend?
I'll go get her.
Hello there.
Everybody's waiting for you.
I've seen you before
at Jingu Stadium.
What a stuck-up...
But the way Kurita
was looking at her...
They're in love, Boss.
I have to win her over.
Put together something
to take home for three.
Mr. Kyuki, welcome.
What's going on?
I haven't seen you in a while.
I'm having a problem getting permission
to import canned pineapples.
Do you know of a good contact?
I don't know of any.
Mr. Kishimoto.
Don't talk to Kuri without me.
I know.
Problem is,
too many people don't.
They want to cut to the chase.
Your Chinese is impressive.
Are you surprised?
I used to teach bayonet fighting
to young Chinese girls.
Sorry I left you.
Care for a drink?
- No, I can't really drink.
Oh, my. I see.
Your only fun is baseball?
- Yeah, sort of.
What are you going to do
after graduation?
Any interest in pro baseball?
I haven't thought that far ahead.
Well...
The world of professional baseball
isn't an easy place to live in.
But it can be a fun place
if you have talent.
You rely on your skills
to earn money.
You can say it's a world
of man-against-man.
Do you like baseball?
I hate it.
Oh, no,
let's not talk about baseball.
- Thank you for waiting.
- Thanks.
Please, eat up.
Now I've hooked Kurita.
Ippei Kyuki has been
pulled into my camp.
I have to babysit these two men
until the fall tournament is over.
But wait.
This girl is trouble.
She's like a chameleon.
What's going on in her mind?
KURITA'S TRIPLE
UPSET VICTORY
THE METEORIC RISE
OF POWER HITTER KURITA
KURITA... MASTER
OF THE EXTRA BASE HIT
Well done, Kurita!
Hello.
Mr. Kyuki.
Hello?
Do you know where he's gone?
He's out?
He's really not there?
Yesterday, we promised to meet here.
I told you I didn't like baseball.
Even if he were here,
I wouldn't get him for you.
Please don't tease me like that.
I've been waiting for him
for two hours.
What's so funny?
Hello?
Damn it.
I don't lie.
He's been out since last night.
Really?
If you really don't believe me,
why don't you come by?
We're at an inn.
You can spend the night.
1,500 yen a night.
- Reach.
- Reach?
Oh, my gosh.
- How about it?
- You're good.
You didn't steal it.
That's 9 wan.
I screwed up.
I should've kept it.
Your time in the birthplace
of mahjong sure paid off.
Don't lose the game
to please me.
What are you saying?
There's money at stake here.
4-8-9-6.
Mr. Kyuki, a phone call for you.
Excuse me.
Watch yourself or you'll lose
your train fare home.
You're gonna pay me
for the day, right?
I've been playing mahjong
all night long.
My back hurts.
Okay, okay.
That's a problem.
I'm busy now, meeting officials
from the Ministry of Agriculture.
Yeah. Yes, yes.
Anyway, I'm busy right now.
Talk to you later.
He's meeting officials from Agriculture,
trying to import chicken droppings.
Chicken what?
Chicken shit.
Filthy.
Maybe he's lying
and meeting Kishimoto.
He can't be.
Wait. We're always fooling him.
He could be fooling us.
Idiot.
"TANl" INN
Hello.
Hello?
- Coming.
Welcome.
You said to come, so I did.
Spending the night?
Miss Fueko...
Don't be so mean.
Let me see Mr. Kyuki.
I told you he was out.
Why do you always
treat me like the enemy?
I'm sorry.
I act this way with everyone.
I guess I'm always on guard.
If you can't stand
seeing me, I'll leave.
Please tell me where he is.
This is a gift for you.
"Be wary of a man
who showers you with gifts."
That's advice
from a women's magazine.
If you don't take it,
I'll leave it here.
I'll mail it back to you.
I can leave the postage.
Go! Faster!
I'm not a good gambler.
Let's call it a day.
What?
Don't lose heart.
Here.
I put money on every horse.
If I don't win now,
I'd rather get stampeded.
I figure it's about time
I met Kurita's family.
What do you think?
You're right.
Let's go together.
I hope I can take time off
from work.
I know you're quite busy.
The Ministry of Industry and Trade
is slow to grant permits.
I've been trying to import
fruit preserves from the US.
But...
Mr. Kyuki.
You know very well
I'm crazy about Kurita.
Can I get Kurita or not?
Signing him
is the challenge of a lifetime.
Mr. Kishimoto.
Will you buy me
along with him?
I will buy you.
I'm back.
Welcome home.
Any phone calls?
Mr. Furukawa and Mr. Shima.
They said they were
going back to Osaka.
They did?
They always call us
at about the same time.
Is it going well?
What?
Don't play dumb.
I'm talking about your "lottery" sales.
I'm going to Shikoku tomorrow.
I'll go with you.
- Now I have a leech of my own?
- I won't let you go.
This is from my team's director.
What is it?
It's not much,
but please use it.
I had no idea
what to bring as gifts.
I see.
I'll hold onto it for you.
Get off!
When the time comes,
please consider our team.
We have no say in the matter.
We'll ask Mr. Kyuki to handle it.
Right?
Is this really for real?
Before, I used to think baseball
was just a children's game.
You'll have an easy life now.
You're lucky to have
such a good son.
All thanks to you, Mr. Kyuki.
Thank you very much
for everything.
Boss, people are so naive
in the countryside.
They're not greedy.
Their souls are as pure
as the country air.
We can point them
in any direction we want.
Been a while, huh?
I got your letter.
I'm afraid I'm on duty today.
You totally look the part.
A first engineer?
A first engineer
with no second engineer.
This is Mr. Kishimoto
with the Toyo Flowers.
Kurita's older brother.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Shiro Kurita.
I hear you've been good to my brother.
Not at all.
A nylon jacket.
It's popular these days.
Wow, great.
Kurita!
- Excuse me.
- It's fine. Go on.
See you.
Kurita trusts him the most
of all his siblings.
I see.
He's a cheerful, pleasant man.
This man is very understanding, Boss.
He's honest and ordinary.
I wish our man Kyuki was like him.
Please.
He can do what he loves
and make a good living at it.
He couldn't be more
fortunate in life.
It paid off to give him up
and put him under your care.
We are half brothers,
though from different mothers.
Goro's got a fighting spirit.
I knew he'd be good at sports.
Stubborn, isn't he?
That made it all the more worth it
for me to train him.
It was hard, though.
Thank you for everything, Mr. Kyuki.
Please watch over him
in the future.
He looks like a good man.
Yes, he's Kurita's
second oldest brother.
Used to be an intellectual.
Easy to talk to.
His real-world smarts?
I'd say, "zero."
Mr. Kyuki, what's wrong?
Come on, Ryoko.
Get a doctor.
Call Dr. Nakayama.
- Mr. Kyuki.
- Dear.
I'm Tamekichi Kurita.
Nice to meet you.
I'm with the Toyo Flowers.
My name is Kishimoto.
Mr. Kyuki was
supposed to come with me.
But he suddenly fell ill, so...
- You want to talk about Goro?
- Yes.
I saw someone else the other day.
He was with the Handen Lilies.
Mr. Shima?
So you want to buy Goro, too?
Yes.
As a matter of fact...
This is whiskey for you.
It's nothing much, but...
I'll take it.
Come watch the dogs fight.
Sure...
He's the one, Boss.
He's gonna cost us money.
Kurita's oldest brother
is no pushover.
Yep. He's like Godzilla.
A real piece of work.
I wish we didn't have to
deal with his kind.
I troubled you with my illness
right at the crucial moment.
But it went well, didn't it?
I think so.
Mr. Kyuki, the Handen team
has already reached Kurita's family.
Handen has?
I see.
Mr. Kishimoto.
I wanna stop by the university hospital.
May I excuse myself in Osaka?
Please go ahead.
If you're going in for surgery,
please contact our Osaka office.
We'll do our best
to accommodate you.
- Hi.
- Welcome, sir.
This way, please.
Please.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm here in Osaka on business.
Well, thank you.
Thank you for your call.
Please accept a handbag.
For me?
A handbag for
a cheap phone call?
I'm borrowing Mr. Kyuki for an hour.
You'll be taken to a fun place.
By a handsome guide.
You're getting quite close
to Kishimoto with the Toyo Flowers.
That's the rumor.
There's no truth to it.
That's a false rumor.
I do hope it's a false rumor.
The Toyo Flowers don't have
the money to get the big boys.
Their director Shiraishi is sharp, but
he's got no credibility within his team.
I know that.
I want to consider
Kurita's future carefully.
All the more reason
to want him on our team.
We're prepared to accept
any terms you propose.
I hear you visited Kurita's family.
Well, no, it's not like
we ignored you.
I just stopped by to say hello.
Let me tell you what we think.
At this point, that is.
Kurita's contract should be
four million yen, up front.
We'd like to pay you
a one-million-yen finder's fee.
Don't worry about me.
I just want...
Of course,
that's not our final offer.
Would you leave Kurita alone
until after the fall tournament?
Good evening.
I just offered him
four million and one million.
That's too little.
I told you five million and 1.5.
I can't budge
even if you said 10 million.
Anyway, please wait
until after the fall tournament.
I understand.
I'm a silly man.
I always want to rush to a conclusion.
Please.
Get some geishas.
Sounds good.
That reminds me.
You know Iwamoto,
from Kumano High? We got him.
That's a big coup.
I gave his leech a taste of candy.
A walk in the park.
Wasn't it?
We'd better tell him soon.
He's a greedy bastard.
If you mean to propose
a million, say 1.1 million.
If you mean 2 million, say 2.2.
Be generous with his finder's fee.
Even one yen more is better.
How about this for Kurita?
You might wanna add
one more finger.
We're talking about an auction here.
Here he comes.
Japan Airlines Flight 102, leaving at 8:00
for Tokyo, is ready for boarding.
- Hello.
- You're late, Mr. Kyuki.
Here are your tickets.
Thank you.
I'm taking advantage of your kindness.
Come off it, aren't we friends?
This way, will you?
Please.
Let's talk about the terms.
I'll be blunt.
1.55 million for you.
6.5 million for Kurita.
I'm just getting started.
If that's not enough, we'll raise it.
They say we Osakans
are quick to add more, right?
Yes. Please consider us.
I'll keep it in mind.
Excuse me.
What?
KURITA HOSPITALIZED
WITH APPENDICITIS
He's just fallen asleep.
It's fine if I don't see him.
I'm relieved to hear
he's doing well.
Thank you very much.
It's a portable radio.
I figure he must be bored.
I'll give it to Kurita later.
Give him my regards.
Mr. Kishimoto.
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
Please stop trying
to lure Kurita into pro baseball.
Why?
He's completely changed from
when he first showed up from Shikoku.
What do you mean by that?
It's because you and Kyuki
are trying to take advantage of him.
You're eager for your own fame.
Kyuki is...
- Wait a moment.
Kurita needs to decide for himself
if he wants to play pro baseball.
Don't accuse me
of taking advantage of him.
What right do you have
to interfere with Kurita's future?
It's because I love him.
Isn't that all the more reason
for you to think about his future?
What's wrong with
professional baseball?
I don't need to explain that to you.
All I'm asking is that
you stop trying to recruit him.
But that's my profession.
I can't stop.
I don't trust Ippei Kyuki.
He's ambitious, so he won't
stay with my company long.
As I said before, he's got
one million yen from Handen.
- Mr. Ohgushi, Mr. Kyuki is...
- He's like that.
You trust people.
That's a very noble virtue these days.
But first you must look at the man.
I can tell you now,
when he was in China, he was a spy.
A spy?
He was working for the enemy.
Hello? Yeah?
It's Kyuki.
Yeah. Yeah.
What? Huh?
Yeah. Fine.
He just got back from Osaka.
He's at the hospital.
Is he coming here?
- He said he wanted to quit.
- Quit your company?
Kishimoto, he wants to start
his own trading company.
Once he's got tons of money.
FROM: MIYOKO KYUKI
KOJIMA, OKAYAMA
I feel so refreshed.
Hot, isn't it?
You got a letter
from someone you like.
- A bill from a bar?
- Yes, from Okayama.
Where is it?
Didn't you see your wife in Osaka?
Don't be silly.
Did I have time?
How the hell should I know?
You always cover your tracks.
Thanks to the war.
It's who you are.
It's in your nature.
You scare me.
You're fine when the gig's going well.
When it's not, you're finished.
What will you do if it goes badly?
- I have no idea.
You don't want to know.
When you start to miss someone,
you just can't take it.
If anything happened to us...
- Don't say it.
You'll miss your wife and kids
in Okayama someday.
It's all in your head.
I know very well
what you're scheming.
Think you can get rich
and leave me? Not a chance!
Come on.
Are you jealous?
You're being ridiculous...
Ouch.
Excuse me. Mr. Kishimoto
with the Toyo Flowers is here.
Show him in.
I'll be right there.
Yes, sir.
I'll do right by you
when I'm rich.
One day you'll appreciate
what a great man I am.
Don't be surprised.
What's the word
from Okayama?
So you do care.
I was lying about the letter.
Huh. You...
So what was the result
of your physical?
They took an X-ray.
They said I had to have an operation.
- Good evening.
- Please.
I got a good medication for you.
I brought it with me.
What is it?
Raccoon liver.
They say it does wonders
for gallstones.
Do me a favor and poison him.
My, you're quite upset.
Can I use your phone?
Go ahead.
It's on the front desk.
Excuse me.
Raccoon liver for a fox like you?
He's so gullible.
He'll be back soon.
"Dear Director Shiraishi.
Kyuki is a trustworthy person.
He is our only ally."
He trusts you completely.
Doesn't feel bad, does it?
He's a sly fox.
Not a bad trick at all.
You did well.
If he's a spy,
I'll have to be a guerrilla.
I'll shoot him down
with a wad of cash.
Under the sky with white clouds
Passionate young men gather
Our battle cry
Rings out
The crown of victory
Always belongs to us
We shall fight...
GAME-ENDING HOME RUN
11th INNING, KURITA
DRAMATIC 11th-INNING HOMER
BY KURITA OF SYOWA UNIVERSITY
OSAKA SOCKS
Mr. Sakata, it's outrageous.
The press is abuzz.
Kishimoto gave Kyuki one million yen.
This sounds like the real deal.
He seems carefree and innocent,
but he's shrewd and cunning.
What's Kurita's schedule?
He's a piece of work, too.
- Kurita's schedule.
- Sure.
It appears Kishimoto outsmarted us.
- What? Outsmarted us?
- Yes.
Something was fishy,
so I went to the trading company.
Turns out Kyuki quit a long time ago.
Right away,
I went to see Kishimoto.
I tried to grill him,
but he was just grinning.
He wouldn't grin like that
unless he was confident.
Idiot. How can you give up
just because of that?
We'll settle this in Shikoku.
Fly to Shikoku now.
Make his family shut out Kyuki.
You've been on a spending spree.
What'll you do if we don't get him?
I don't have a license
to print money.
I don't have a tree
with money growing on it.
My authority has its limits.
I'm prepared to do anything.
You can resign if you want,
but that won't give us
the money we need.
I don't dislike baseball.
I dislike the people around you.
They're greedy and selfish.
Every profession
comes with people like that.
I wonder where you
left behind your old self.
All those headlines
have rewritten your true character.
Remember what
you told me once?
"I'm happy I get to study at college.
I want an ordinary, honest life."
Fueko, come out and tell me
if you don't like me anymore.
"You're a coward."
Isn't that what you want to tell me?
I'm not asking you to be responsible
just because we kissed once or twice.
I love baseball.
You've become famous.
I was an illegitimate child.
It's no use beating yourself up.
While you spoil yourself
now that you've increased in value.
Fueko, you're telling me
to quit baseball.
I'm not telling you to quit.
Just don't become a shark.
Don't accept gifts without reason.
Tell that to Mr. Kyuki.
I'm still a student.
What can I do?
You're using them.
You just pretend you're being used
by Kishimoto and Kyuki.
This week will determine my fate.
Take a look.
Your letter of resignation?
You're really determined.
Tell me if you've gotten final offers
from the other teams.
The Osaka Socks say
100,000 yen a month.
Seven million yen, up front.
The Handen offer
is about the same.
No, I'm asking about your pay.
I think you're essential.
Without you,
Kurita the player wouldn't exist.
Don't worry about me.
Please tell me.
There's a rumor that
I gave you two million.
The Osaka Socks said 2.5 million.
What a bunch of jokers.
- And your business funds?
- They'd consider it a separate item.
That's all?
The Osaka Socks think you're cheap.
I've been thinking
three million for you.
For Kurita, eight million yen.
120,000 yen a month.
The team director
Shiraishi has agreed.
I appreciate that.
Can we sign him in Tokyo?
I think you'd better go
to Shikoku one more time.
When the championship is over,
Kurita will go back to Shikoku.
Then we'll sign him in Shikoku?
Probably.
Mr. Kyuki, you'd better have surgery
once the contract is signed.
Let me make arrangements.
Thank you.
You're the only one
who's concerned about my health.
Seriously.
I got him, Boss.
We have the final offers.
How much?
Eight million up front, three million
to Kyuki, 120,000 yen a month.
- It's gone up, huh?
- It's too late to back down.
- We have him for sure?
- 90%
We're the highest bidder.
Fine. Contact the manager.
When can we sign him?
Let me see. After the fall championship
closing ceremony on the 16th.
I'm leaving for Shikoku now.
Good.
Be very careful around his family.
"Our son Goro's future shall be
determined after due consideration.
Not only I, his father, but
his four siblings will be his counsel.
We request that you not interfere
with Goro ever again."
Ryoko. Ryoko!
KURITA SIGNING WAR
FINAL STAGE
HERO GOES TO WHICH TEAM?
We sent a letter to Kyuki, from our father,
clearly forbidding his involvement.
What do you mean?
Goro's future will be
discussed among ourselves.
I heard what I think is a false rumor.
It's not just a rumor.
What is it?
Kyuki's taking advantage of our brother
and enjoying the honey, they say.
I heard that one, too.
For example, they say Kyuki got
a million yen from the Osaka Socks.
That's completely untrue.
Don't believe the rumors. Poor Kyuki.
I hate to say it, but I heard it
from the editor of the Sports Mirror.
That's completely unethical.
How can the newspaper
talk up a baseless rumor?
There's no proof
the rumors are false.
We country folks
always end up losing out.
Wait a moment.
I've also heard rumors.
His parents decided on the Ticks
so they could build a new house.
His brother got half a million
from Handen.
You gotta be kidding.
What good would it do
if I took money?
How dare you spread falsehoods!
Once the fall championship is over,
I'll pay you another visit.
Please accept a gift.
Where have you been?
I even called the dormitory.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were ill.
Soon you'll be leaving college.
What are you going to do?
Well, I'd like to visit
my family one more time.
Thanks to you, Mr. Kyuki,
I can go out into the world.
I've been lucky
to have a good teacher.
I'm glad to hear that.
I couldn't do much for you.
The best I can do now is select
a good team for your future.
Thank you very much.
I'd like to sign up with a team
with a good manager.
Sounds good.
That reminds me, Mr. Kishimoto
wanted you to meet his team's manager.
Why don't we meet him once
before you go back to Shikoku?
Sure.
That team's manager is young,
but I think he's quite good.
Mr. Kyuki,
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
I had a fight with Fueko.
That's why...
You couldn't come here.
Yes. I came today
because I heard she was out.
What are you going to do?
I think my relationship with her
was a mistake from the beginning.
Am I a coward?
Don't worry about it. Okay?
I've raised you
for the last four years.
Leave everything to me, will you?
Please.
I'd be a peasant in Shikoku now
if you hadn't taken me under your wing.
I'll never forget
how indebted I am to you.
You trust people.
That's a very noble virtue these days.
But first you must look at the man.
I can tell you now,
when he was in China, Kyuki was a spy.
I can't trust people anymore.
I need proof.
What do you want me to do?
Stop conning me.
I've done my sincere best
for you and Kurita.
I'm not complaining.
It's my job.
But, Mr. Kyuki,
you're sly and crafty.
- You calling me a fox?
- A fox can't outsmart humans.
Why did you hide it that Kurita's family
sent you a cease-and-desist letter?
Did you lose their confidence?
If it's over, tell me.
Then why don't you back out?
Don't toy with my weakness.
Let's treat each other
with human decency.
You may find it laughable
to hear me say this.
Of course until today
I've been suspicious of you.
I planned to use you.
But when I went to Shikoku this time,
I got a slap in the face.
Kurita's brothers had changed,
they were without scruple.
I thought about it
on the plane home.
Every person has a moment in his life
when he can't trust anyone.
I thought I'd grown weak.
But now I want to try
to be decent to others.
If it's over, please tell me.
I'll back out right away.
I don't want to think
you were conning me.
My job seems pathetic to me now.
I can't stand it.
We do bring pleasure to the fans
by finding good players.
It's a fine profession in that regard.
But our behavior
towards other people is...
Ugly and lowdown.
You've acknowledged it.
So what?
It's our job to be ruthless
and unaccountable.
Because we see people like Kurita,
not as players, but as commodities.
Because we see people like you
not as human beings, but as leeches.
That's the truth.
So we try to resolve
everything with money.
Mr. Kishimoto.
It's not just greed and money
between Kurita and me.
We've worked together,
drenched in sweat, for four years.
I'm aware of that.
That's why I want to show you
some human decency.
Maybe it's just a cheap sentimentality.
You can go ahead and laugh at me.
Look at this.
It's a pledge
Kurita's parents wrote to me.
"Goro Kurita's future decisions
are entrusted to Mr. Kyuki."
Mr. Kishimoto.
Please trust me.
SYOWA SCORES COMPLETE SHUTOUT
KURITA AGAIN LEADING HITTER
SCOUTS CONVERGE ON KURITA
THE SYOWA U. SLUGGER
TEAMS FIGHT OVER NEW PLAYERS
Congratulations.
Thanks.
The watch, as promised.
Thank you.
We'd like to make
the final decision in Shikoku.
This is what Kurita himself wants.
Don't quit running
when you're in Shikoku.
Yes, Coach.
Now please confirm the terms
of our team's offer.
Eight million yen up front.
160,000 yen a month.
Am I worth that much?
It makes me nervous.
Just focus on hitting those home runs.
Soon you'll say, "This isn't enough."
That's right. Your skill at the bat
drove up these numbers.
I almost forgot
something important.
It's about Mr. Kyuki.
Listen, Kurita.
Let's say you join our team.
We'd like Mr. Kyuki
to work for our team, too.
Is that right?
Of course.
Think about it.
What time is your train tonight?
It's the Seto,
leaving at 10:30.
I can't be seen with you at the station.
Have a safe trip back.
Give my regards to your brothers.
It's not much, but this is for the trip.
It's from my director.
I can't take it.
Take it.
Pull over right there.
Okay.
Take this cab.
You must have baggage.
I'm getting out, too.
I'll meet you at Tokyo Station.
Accept his offer and take this cab.
- I'll see you in Shikoku.
- See you then.
Did you see the nice suit he was wearing?
I bought it for him.
I'm flying to Shikoku
the day after tomorrow.
What about you?
I'll be there a day after you.
I'm not feeling too good.
I hope you're not coming
with another team.
Don't doubt me anymore.
You want to know
what my true intentions are.
And I want to find out
what's in Kurita's heart.
This is my last chance.
You still don't trust me.
I can tell.
Don't worry now.
My fate is bound to yours now.
I believe in you.
Mr. Kishimoto.
I've got one last favor to ask.
Right now,
Fueko is waiting for me.
I promised her
she'd see Kurita today.
You want me to see her?
Please.
As you may know,
Fueko and Kurita are...
In love, aren't they?
He wants to break up with her.
How have you been?
I'm here because
Mr. Kyuki asked me to come.
You don't need to say it.
Kurita is leaving for Shikoku tonight,
isn't he?
He is.
You'd stoop to anything
if it helped you to close the deal.
Fine.
I had only one word to say to Kurita.
"Coward."
May I sit down?
I'm leaving.
Watch out!
Thank you.
You're kind,
as suits your profession.
May I take you somewhere?
Are you trying to console me?
You misjudge me.
No. I shouldn't.
It has nothing to do with you.
You may be right.
Maybe I misjudged you.
Maybe I confused you
with your occupation.
That's enough.
Why are you so upset?
You think Kyuki is a gentleman.
I don't distrust people
from the very start like you do.
You can't understand
until you've been betrayed.
Mr. Kishimoto.
Kyuki is faking his illness.
What? He's faking it?
Sometimes.
Half the time, he's acting.
Why are you staring at me?
'Cause you pity me?
You've resented me.
I don't resent anyone.
It's actually comical.
You mean, I am?
Both you and Kyuki.
What in the hell is baseball anyway?
In your world...
You buy and sell people.
It's socially condoned
human trafficking.
Were you really
in love with Kurita?
A long, long time ago.
Shall we dance?
Why?
Are you bored?
Can't you dance without a reason?
I used to be much more
innocent and sincere.
Mr. Kishimoto.
You know why I fell for Kurita?
There was something pure about him.
Almost like greens
fresh out of the garden.
That's what I adored.
You wanna know why?
My mother was a mistress.
She had two patrons.
That could mean
my sister and I...
Maybe we're not real sisters.
My sister married once,
but it failed.
Then she met Kyuki...
Stop it.
Why are you telling me this?
The blood in my veins is dirty.
I can't bear it.
I pity my mother,
but I can't forgive her.
I only wanted...
a boring, honest marriage
to get away from home.
Fueko.
Stop right there.
You're right.
I'm sorry I went to pieces.
Let's dance.
Thank you.
Mr. Kishimoto not only financed my
business, but also found me a job.
You know what
I've given up for you.
I quit my job and lost income.
Think about it.
I'm well aware of it.
When you get there,
watch out for your brothers.
Why do they want to cut me off?
If there's any other reason
than the rumors, let me know.
I will.
One more thing
to warn you about.
Your interests may clash
with your brothers'.
You may need to pretend
to sever your ties.
This is about my life.
I'll think it through for myself.
That's right.
That's for the best.
Go on, now.
Yes. Good-bye.
Mr. Kyuki.
What's wrong?
I'm fine.
Get on the train.
Are you really okay?
The train is leaving.
Departing from Platform 14,
the Seto for Uno Taisha.
If you're seeing passengers off,
please step behind the white line.
Mr. Kyuki.
I'm taking the next train.
I'll take you home.
Kuri, could you do me a favor
before you leave Tokyo?
Tell me you've decided
on the Toyo Flowers.
I just want to hear those words
from your own mouth.
Okay? Would you promise?
Thank you.
I'll be a few days late.
Hold out until the last moment.
Okay?
The longer you hold out,
even a day or two,
the more valuable you will be.
I know.
The train is leaving.
Go on.
A 10-MILLION-YEN PLAYER
IS BORN?
SIGNING AT FAMILY HOME
IN SHIKOKU?
SCOUTS RUSH TO SHIKOKU
WADS OF CASH START FLYING
A fox. A weasel.
A snake. A worm.
Look at them.
No brawn, all cunning.
Boss, it's the showdown.
Real bullets, real blood.
But when the night is over,
a barely 20-year-old student
will become a millionaire.
What's going on here?
His salary will equal
a government minister's, they say.
Can't thank baseball enough.
Come on, Sports Mirror.
Wait a second.
We're causing you all so much trouble
because we love Goro.
We want to select the team
that's best for him.
We'd like to add half a million
to our proposed signing bonus.
So how about 8.5 million?
Your Handen team is, for now,
the most promising.
You're honest.
We like that.
We'll pay right now
if he signs with us.
We have the cash here.
Come take a look.
What's that?
Furukawa,
with the Osaka Socks.
I see. A gift of a cow.
Great idea.
Perfect for the peasants.
Come on, you cow.
Come here, or you'll end up
in beef stew.
Come on. Come.
Father, where are you going?
You gotta listen to this.
If Handen says 8.5 million,
we can pay up to nine million.
160,000 yen a month.
Isn't that enough?
What about the tax?
The tax is separate.
Tamekichi, let's talk over the details
when Shiro is back.
What?
Is Shiro on the boat?
Yes. He'll be back in the evening.
My director and manager will be here
tomorrow morning. Will you meet them?
We'll meet anyone.
We all have to see
what the manager is like.
I'll see you then.
GOMEN STATION
KOCHI NEWS
KURITA RUNS TO HANDEN?
TEAMS BATTLE
10-MILLION PLAYER GOES WHERE?
BRIBES PAID TO IPPEl KYUKI,
THE FIXER BEHIND KURITA
Mr. Kishimoto.
- Hello.
- He came down with a fever in Itami.
Not a trip for a sick man.
Thank you.
How are you?
It's not that bad.
I've been waiting for you.
I got a hotel for you.
How's it going?
I'm glad you made it early.
Handen. Osaka. Kyushu.
And then Chubu, Shinkyu and the Ticks
all broke their silence and rushed over.
Anybody talked about me?
You know it's a small house.
It's chaos with both friends and foes.
And Kuri?
He hasn't shown up.
It seems his brothers
hid him somewhere.
On top of everything,
look at this.
The Kochi News
has written about you.
That's Kurita hitting a home run.
Mr. Kurita, Mrs. Kurita,
that's your son running.
You fought Dad, Tamekichi,
and cut ties with the family.
How can you act
like Goro's brother now?
What did you say, Shiro?
Say it again.
Don't, Tame.
Shiro, Tame and the others are only
trying to do what's best for Goro.
Since when are you all
such caring brothers?
If you want the best for Goro,
let him do what he wants.
Don't force him.
Shiro, I know about you and
Kishimoto with the Toyo Flowers.
Didn't you take money from him?
I know you met him at the wharf.
Maybe I did.
They say you took half a million
from Handen, Tame.
Shiro, what do you mean to...
Stop it.
What good is it
to fight in here?
Saburo, what about you?
Me? What can I say?
Whatever Goro wants...
Fine by me.
Anyway, we're brothers,
bound by blood ties.
We gotta protect Goro.
Otherwise, he'll get ripped off.
What's wrong?
He's in a lot of pain.
He's just thrown up.
Please come in.
Mr. Kyuki, are you all right?
I haven't eaten anything
since yesterday.
I saw Shiro.
How did it go?
He seemed to favor us.
But he said he didn't know
where Kurita was.
Are you okay, dear?
Shall I get a doctor?
No. It'll be a problem
if they find out I'm here.
Ryoko, give me the shot.
Sure.
Is it okay to do that?
Natsume, the scout from Kyushu,
had a movie show.
He didn't know
they'd turn him down.
Shiro said it was between us,
the Osaka Socks, and Handen.
The oldest brother seems to be
in touch with Handen.
He's fallen asleep.
Then I'm going.
When I find Kurita's whereabouts,
I'll contact you.
Please.
Take care.
Mr. Kishimoto.
Fueko sends you her regards.
One million yen,
for Yoneji and you.
No, no.
If things go wrong,
you'll pay us back.
Wrap them in this.
Your signature, please.
You're the eldest son
of the Kurita family.
You're the one
taking care of your parents.
I don't want Tame
to act like a big man.
You can say that, but...
You don't need to listen to him.
Tell them clearly
how much you want.
Well. Hi.
Come here. This way.
Hello. Yeah.
Would you hold on a second?
Mister, you got Tokyo.
Hello? Kishi...
Kishimoto speaking.
Where? I'm in Kochi.
I'm here to meet
the manager tomorrow.
I'm drunk.
Yeah, I'm completely drunk.
'Cause I can't trust anyone anymore.
Remember you asked me
what baseball was?
What is it?
What?
I don't sound like myself?
Of course I'm not whining.
I'm not bothered
by conscience or doubt.
I'm not afraid of hell or demons.
Sorry, sorry. I'm drunk.
I don't know why, but...
I just wanted to hear your voice.
Mr. Kyuki collapsed.
Whether he's lying or it's for real,
I have no choice
but to believe Mr. Kyuki.
Why aren't you announcing?
I'm going to a team
with a good manager.
Which one is your favorite?
I'm thinking about it.
Which did Kyuki recommend?
He didn't say.
I'm choosing on my own.
Hello.
Meeting your people here?
I'm meeting my president.
The president has to settle it.
Ridiculous.
You can say that again.
A trunk full of cash and bills.
Bowing and begging.
I won't be able to take it
if rejected.
Didn't you talk with Shiro
in the kitchen last night?
How do you know?
I was in the bathroom.
What?
I couldn't come out with you there.
I was hungry and had
a bowl of rice and tea.
Did you like the salt pickles
from Kyoto?
- Did you eat them, too?
- I gave them those as a gift.
Sorry about that.
Did you have the castella sponge cake?
Did you give it to them?
The sushi must've been
from the Osaka Socks.
Local specialties are coming in
from all over the country.
Hello, thanks for coming.
We're here like everybody else.
That's Kawajiri,
the Osaka Socks manager.
- Thank you for flying with us.
- Hello.
So?
If I fail, I'll kill Kurita and Kyuki
and commit suicide.
A scout's suicide in Kochi.
I've never been this eager
to sign a player.
As the manager, I guarantee
he'll be our cleanup hitter.
If we choose you,
be sure to follow through on that.
The Kyushu Tulips people are here.
We're saying no to them.
I may be turned away
at the door tomorrow.
No, you won't be.
Excuse me.
Who is it?
Kuri's here, isn't he?
Kurita. Goro Kurita.
You can't hide him. I know.
Who are you?
- Give this to him.
- He's out now.
Make sure to give it to him
when he's back.
Please, I beg you.
MR. GORO KURITA
IPPEl KYUKI
Goro, let me take a swing.
Sure.
Come on, Teru.
Dad, Mom and everybody
agree on the Handen team.
They'll help them expand the store.
You'll do good by your parents.
Handen's not bad, either.
Yeah.
You got something going
with Handen, don't you?
All your brothers
are looking out for you.
Be a good boy
and do as we tell you.
Mr. Kyuki.
Mr. Kishimoto.
Are you all right?
I hear they rejected
Kyushu and the Ticks.
Shiro said they'd reject Handen.
That would leave the Socks and us.
I had a letter delivered to Kurita.
He should come see me tonight.
Will he come?
I wrote that I was in grave condition.
If he doesn't come,
I'll go see him.
It will be all settled tomorrow.
This war is almost over.
A war with money
in place of bombs.
I really want to see Kurita tonight.
Mr. Kyuki.
- Mr. Kyuki.
- It hurts.
Ouch!
Boss, I believe this man
for the first time.
This is a real illness.
He's not faking it.
Hello.
Is Kuri's father home?
Who the hell are you?
I'm Ippei Kyuki's wife.
Mr. Kyuki?
Don't know him.
You may not,
but your father does.
What do you want?
Shiro, it's me.
You met me with Kyuki before.
Well, I don't know you.
Go home, girlie.
We're busy right now.
All you brothers are in cahoots
to shut out Kyuki.
I told you we don't know Kyuki.
You're lying through your teeth.
Who took Kuri the sniveling kid
and raised him so well?
Nobody.
Who sent him to college?
Goro was playing baseball
when he was three.
Haven't you milked him enough?
We want you to take a hike, already.
You're saying it's your turn.
Kyuki is a leech, isn't he?
I hear he used Goro
to make tons of money.
If Kyuki is a leech,
you bastards are mites or lice.
Kneel down before Kyuki
and thank him.
Shut up!
How is he?
He needs complete bed rest.
If he wants to see anyone,
you'd better call them.
Is it that bad?
- Are you Mr. Kishimoto?
- I am.
There's a telegram for you.
Arriving at Gomen Station at 10:00.
Come get me. Fueko.
Hey, Kurita!
What a surprise.
When did you get here?
Just now.
I didn't come here for you.
I have a lot to tell you, Fueko.
I have nothing to say to you.
It's just...
I'm not asking you to, but I wish
you'd join Mr. Kishimoto's team.
I'll join whatever team I please
without being asked.
It's my life.
Kurita, do you understand?
Would you say yes?
Would you tell me,
"I've decided on the Toyo Flowers"?
Maybe I'm going to die like this.
In a way, I know I will.
I'll never forget how much I owe you
for the rest of my life, Mr. Kyuki.
But I can't give you
the answer you want.
You used to understand me
better than anyone, didn't you?
Right? Or was it all lies?
I've thought it over carefully.
And I've decided on the Osaka Socks.
The Osaka Socks?
No. You can't do that.
Are you betraying me?
Being indebted to you is one thing.
Wanting to join the Socks is another.
Kurita...
- Forgive me.
- Kurita.
Kurita.
It's okay for you to turn us down.
I'm fine.
Of course I'm disappointed.
But how can you betray someone
who has believed in you so deeply?
Don't you have a heart?
Why couldn't you share your feelings
with the one who believed in you?
How many have suffered now
because of your dishonesty?
Why couldn't you tell Mr. Kyuki
you'd go to the Socks?
I wanted to say it many times.
But each time, Mr. Kyuki said,
"Leave it to me."
What're you saying?
You're not a man. You're a monster.
A hypocrite who fooled all the teams.
Whatever you say,
I'm taking my own path.
Please, Kurita,
think it over one more time.
What's wrong
with the Toyo Flowers?
They're offering
the largest signing bonus.
I respect Mr. Kawajiri,
the Osaka Socks manager.
I'll negotiate with Mr. Kawajiri
to get you a large finder's fee.
You'll...
This is from your father and mother.
They wrote this pledge
to entrust your future to me.
I didn't sign it.
What're you saying?
In your heart,
you surely signed it.
Mr. Kyuki, I'm indebted to you,
and I'll repay the obligation.
I'm pursuing my own path.
Kurita.
Dear.
I'm sorry.
I'll come back at another time
to thank you.
Do as you please.
Take care.
Kurita.
You were using them, after all.
You coward.
Hello.
Dear. Dear.
Fueko.
Kurita.
Kurita!
Three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten.
Here you go.
And here...
Your signature and your seal, please.
The family seal, Shiro.
Here you go.
GORO KURITA
You don't have it all?
Shiro.
How much did they give you?
I'm not a petty bastard like you.
Tell me how much they gave you!
Enough is enough.
You want a piece of me?
Tamekichi. Brother.
Don't. Stop it.
Shiro.
Tame.
Tamekichi. Tame.
Ryoko.
I'm here.
I'm not gonna make it.
What're you saying?
You mustn't lose spirit.
My life...
It's my life, so I know.
I hate to betray you, but...
My wife and kids in Okayama.
Would you let me see them?
I'm sorry.
Please.
Now, with the manager.
Shake hands.
Smile.
May I?
Kurita, Mr. Kyuki's condition is critical.
I think you can thank him one last time.
I can't go now. I have interviews
and round-table meetings.
I came to tell you
as a friend of Mr. Kyuki's.
He's not faking it.
It's really bad.
Excuse me, this way.
Could you hold the bat?
Could you swing it?
Thank you.
Kurita, Mr. Kyuki may die.
What's wrong with Mr. Kyuki?
Is he here?
Mr. Kishimoto.
He's so cruel.
He should rot in hell.
Why didn't he just say, "Socks"?
Don't. We lost in our game.
We'll get revenge in our own way.
We'll find a pitcher
to strike out Kurita to death.
- Vita-camphor.
- Right away.
Hurry.
Kurita...
Mr. Kishimoto...
Trust me.
Please.
Believe me.
Flashlight.
He's gone.
10:31.
Mr. Kyuki is...
"Mr. Kishimoto, believe me."
Those were his last words.
Kurita's brother stabbed his own brother
and was arrested by the police.
His mother was crying,
saying Goro was not her son.
The fourth batter,
left fielder, Kurita.
Uniform number 25.
THE END