Mrs. Owen is expecting
a lot of guests.
She chose you.
Welcome to Soldier Island.
Mr. Lombard, you seem
to be under the impression
that I am a particular kind
of woman.
And I assure you that I'm not.
They're the 10 little soldiers...
You know, from the poem.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Who is that?
You are charged
with the following indictments.
Philip Lombard...
That you did murder 21 men.
What the hell
are they playing at?!
Malicious nonsense.
Cyril.
I really tried to save him.
I almost drowned.
Twenty-one men?
I'm the only one telling the
truth in a room full of liars.
Who is it?
We are cut off.
Rats in a barrel.
Almonds.
Almonds be buggered.
Cyanide.
None of you moved them?
- No.
Was it you, Doctor?
No.
How did Mrs. Rogers die?
I have no idea.
Did you give her something?
Yes... a mild sedative.
Did you give her too much?
Miss Claythorne, I warned you
against becoming hysterical.
It's the poem.
Don't you see?
Ten little soldier boys.
One choked himself,
one overslept himself,
and then there were eight.
There were 10 of these
and 10 of us,
and now there's eight.
Oh, General... General,
did you move the figures?
What?
The figures.
Did you move the figures?
No.
Of course not.
Perhaps
it was you, Miss Claythorne.
- You discovered it.
- Of course it wasn't me.
- Why would I do that?
- To be the center of attention.
Do you crave attention,
Miss Claythorne?
Any kind of attention?
- What are you talking about?
- Shall we just have breakfast?
It was dreadful news
about Mrs. Rogers.
She was a wonderful cook.
Such a shame.
This egg is four minutes
precisely, is it?
Yes, madam.
Rogers, did you take away
two of these figures?
No, miss.
Condolences, Mr. Rogers.
When are you expecting Narracott?
Mid-to late morning, sir.
His timekeeping
is somewhat erratic.
Will that be all?
Yes. Thank you, Rogers.
Thank you very much.
Tony Marston was young
and strong.
He didn't die
from some stimulant.
Perhaps he was poisoned.
And... And Mrs. Rogers...
Perhaps she was given too much.
What drugs do you have
in your medical bag, Doctor?
Why did you even bring it?
You are a guest.
It's not work.
Actually, it is work.
I was trying to maintain some
sort of professional discretion.
However, Mrs. Owen suffers
from female neuroses.
My speciality
is women's disorders.
Mr. Owen engaged me
in a professional capacity
to tend to his wife!
Gave up on the surgery, then,
Doctor?
No. People do not just die
out of nowhere for no reason.
They die because something
was done to them by someone.
I'm gonna check your bag.
- Don't you dare touch...
- What have you got to hide?
How about I do it?
I'm not being searched
like some grubby criminal.
Then what if the general
goes with him?
He's an honorable man.
Fine!
But while you're at it,
you might want to search
Judge Wargrave's case as well.
I know where I've seen you before.
Chap who has the clinic
beneath mine in Harley Street,
he's a cancer specialist.
That's where I saw you.
If anyone has strong painkillers
and sedatives in his case,
it's Judge Wargrave.
Is that true, Judge?
I have had health problems, yes.
Then that's very cruel, Doctor.
Don't blame me.
You pushed it.
General, shall we?
Just mild sedatives.
As I said.
Bog-standard.
Nothing special.
My surgery was a success.
This... the house, the island...
Is meant to be my recuperation.
Sea air, peace... and rest.
Very sorry.
I'm... very sorry.
Well, there's an end to it.
Like hell it is.
Why shouldn't she be searched?
Equal rights for women.
Let's see what you've got.
Dr. Armstrong,
control yourself, please.
Who the hell
do you think you are?
I'm a doctor.
You're a secretary.
Somebody moved them.
They did.
Someone did that.
Did you really kill
all those men?
Yes, Miss Claythorne.
I did kill all those men.
And more.
Why?
It seemed like a good idea
at the time.
They had something I wanted.
In this case, it was diamonds.
Worth more than a few lives.
What about you?
What did you want?
I nearly drowned.
I failed to save a little boy
in my care.
And there isn't one minute
of every day
that I am not sorry for that.
Why aren't you?
I know what I am.
I always knew
it would catch up with me.
And here it is.
I love you,
I love you, I love you.
I think about you
and you kissing me
and your hands on me and in me
and your mouth on my body,
and I cannot bear
that you are not with me now.
I wish, I long,
I crave for you, my darling,
and I feel so cruel
to poor, dear John,
but the sun rises and sets
in your eyes, Henry.
I love you.
"I am yours."
The men are all ready
for the whistle, sir.
Morale fairly good.
Here.
Let me.
Henry.
You've been a...
a great friend to my wife and I.
Perhaps you could call me John.
Thank you, John.
Myself and Mrs. Rogers were here
for a week
without seeing another soul
apart from Narracott
with the delivery, sir.
Lombard.
Where are you going?
We're sat around
waiting for Ulick Norman Owen.
What if he's been here
all along?
Plenty of places
he could be hiding.
Wait for me.
Please, please,
please just fucking stop.
Stop.
S-Stop. Stop. Stop.
Oh, this is... this is barmy!
No one could hide down there.
Ever get the feeling
you're being hunted, Tubs?
Now, stop calling me that.
I ain't even fat.
And no, I don't.
Really?
'Cause Mr. Owen, whoever he may
be, knows a lot about us.
Well, not about me.
Edward Lander was a degenerate.
He was a pansy.
He fell down the steps
into his cell.
You never touched him?
I wouldn't want to be near
one of them dirty bastards.
Come on, Tubs!
Keep up!
General?
Is your suitcase ready?
She died.
Spanish influenza,
after the war.
Who?
My wife, Leslie.
After all that...
she died of the Spanish flu.
So many did.
I should have just stepped aside
like a gentleman and...
just let them be happy.
Do come back to the house,
General.
You haven't
brought your case down yet,
and we want to get away as soon
as Mr. Narracott arrives.
He's not coming, Narracott,
you know.
No one's coming for us.
We won't be leaving the island.
This is the end.
It's a relief to come to
the end, to know that it's over.
You won't understand that yet,
but you will...
In time.
I think you're quite mistaken.
The boat will come and we'll all
be waiting for you.
Miss Claythorne.
Good.
Bring a couple of chairs,
would you?
What's going on?
It's a bit early
to be on the sauce.
It's been something
of a morning.
Hey. Hey.
Bastard's down there.
I heard him.
What bastard?
Owen.
I can hear him moving about.
Marston's room.
What are you doing?
Camp bed.
Well, we had to find somewhere
to store it, and...
young men don't look under beds.
But w-what do you need
a camp bed for?
What were you planning?
Well, I can't sleep in my room,
can I?
Me wife.
Yeah. Obviously.
Of course.
I've got to find somewhere else
to set up.
What for?
We're all leaving.
Well, you might be.
This is my job.
I can't go anywhere
until my employer dismisses me.
Your employer?
Your employer is insane.
Be that as it may,
I've got nothing else to go to.
All right, then.
Carry on, Rogers.
Did you know he had a gun?
No.
Do stop.
Mr. Narracott seems
a sensible man.
He'll be here.
I must say, I understand now
why you teach in such
a substandard establishment.
I'm just observing
that most schools
would not want to be associated
with an inquest.
I'm not accusing you.
There's been quite enough
of that already.
Yes, there has.
More than enough.
Apart from the egregious
Mr. Lombard
and the Rogers,
who I find most dubious,
and the depraved Mr. Marston,
it's all nonsense.
Everyone was simply doing
their duty.
As was I.
As were you?
You didn't say anything
last night.
It wasn't for gentlemen's ears.
But Beatrice Taylor was my
maid of all work.
Foundling girl.
An unwanted...
From the war, you know?
I believed her to be a clean,
decent, modest girl.
I taught her needlework skills.
We had quite the little home.
But then she got herself
into trouble.
The family way.
As her own loose mother had
with her.
She begged me for help.
Naturally and quite properly,
I refused.
Miss Brent, please!
I beg you!
What happened to her?
She threw herself under a train.
She killed herself?
Even made the local paper.
And they turned it into some
potboiling sentimental tale.
She asked you for help.
If you had helped her...
It was the weakness
in her character
which drove her actions.
Why should I be reproached?
Ask Rogers for some tea.
Lemon, not milk.
It's a
wild-goose chase if you ask me.
Grown man hiding
and sneaking about.
It's ridiculous.
Marston was given cyanide,
though.
Wasn't he, Tubs?
Cyanide?
I'm pretty sure of it.
I don't know.
You were convinced of it
this morning.
Claythorne for the cyanide.
- I'd put money on it.
- She don't seem the type.
No.
She's exactly the type.
What about the old boy,
the general?
Dangerous men come back,
you know, from over there,
their noggins all scrambled.
Oh. Well,
let's search everybody, then.
God-bothering Miss Brent.
Let's search Wargrave.
What, the judge?
Well known as a hanging judge.
He's infamous
for the black square.
The story goes that he'd watch
every execution he'd ordered.
Tubs, you've been looking
sideways at Armstrong
all morning,
and now everyone's fair game.
You suggested the judge.
I was taking the piss.
Mr. Owen is on the island,
and I'm going to find him.
You don't want to pay attention
to what he said.
He's just stirring the shit pot.
Well, I can stir it right back.
Don't look.
Someone did this?
Well, it weren't
no bleedin' accident.
It's murder.
He said no one was
coming for us.
He said this was the end.
Miss Claythorne?
"Eight little soldier boys
traveling in Devon."
One said he'd stay there,
and then there were seven.
Count them, Judge.
Count them.
Cyril!
Run!
Find help!
A boat!
Run!
Miss Claythorne!
I just want to go!
You'd drown!
Please!
Please.
Come inside.
Come. Come.
I've got you.
Don't worry.
It's all right.
I told you Owen
was on the island.
What made you so sure?
Instinct.
We've got to be rational.
Stick with procedure.
Who is this Owen?
And Mrs. Owen.
I don't think there even is
a Mrs. Owen.
We must all have
something in common,
someone who knows us all.
Well, how can that be possible?
I can imagine crossing paths
with a doctor, a judge,
but someone like Mr. Lombard?
Well, we've crossed paths now,
haven't we?
Mr. Lombard, Blore tells me
that you have a revolver.
Oh, Tubs.
'Why have you got a gun?
He's got a gun?
I carry it everywhere.
And it was implied
that I might need it.
Implied?
By whom?
My client needs a good man
who can handle situations.
Who's your client?
Mr. Owen.
Ulick Norman Owen.
Never heard of him.
But he has heard of you.
Audrey, the box.
It's dangerous, then.
My client believes
that it could become volatile.
I see.
And how would Mr. Owen wish
me to proceed?
He leaves that
to your discretion.
But forewarned is...
ls forearmed.
I understand.
That's who got in touch with me
about the job with Mrs. Owen...
Isaac Morris in Soho.
Soho.
I was invited here by the Owens,
whom I've never heard of,
to join a mutual friend...
Mrs. Culmington.
Perfect place to recover,
it said.
The envelope was postmarked
London, Soho.
A sink of depravity.
A godless desert of vice.
What brings you here,
Miss Brent?
Mrs. Owen wrote to me.
She was interested in my work.
The moral education of girls
of the lower orders.
They have to be taught
modesty and decency
or society will be drowned in a
rising tide of unwanted babies,
all squalling to be fed.
She wanted to contribute
to my cause.
Blore?
I got a letter
from Ulick Norman Owen.
He was impressed
by my standing in the force.
He said if I could see my way
clear to spending some time,
keeping an eye out, that he
would recompense me generously.
Keeping an eye out for what?
He said that someone
was here under false pretenses.
He also supplied
a list of guests.
All of you.
Everyone here.
What he didn't say was that
Lombard would have a gun.
Is it Mr. Owen's voice
on the record?
Does anybody recognize it?
Are we forgetting
about the gun here?
There's a Fenian sat over there
with a bloody gun!
Don't blaspheme.
Hand it over. Come on.
Surrender your weapon,
Mr. Lombard.
- Not a chance.
- I could make you.
You can try.
Is Isaac Morris Mr. Owen?
No.
I'd have found that sweaty
bucket of lard by now.
Jews.
Wherever there's a problem,
there's Jews
at the bottom of it.
Something struck me.
I can't think
why I didn't see it before.
Ulick Norman Owen.
Una Nancy Owen.
Or...
U.N. Owen...
is "unknown."
It's a riddle, perhaps.
What does it mean?
It means that Mr. Lombard
is right to insist
that the killer
is on the island.
And he's getting very wet
out there.
The killer's not out there.
The killer is in here.
It is one of us.
We've never met each other
before now. Why?
How could I possibly be capable?
Oh, anyone is capable,
Miss Brent.
Forty years on the criminal
bench has taught me that.
- Rogers.
- Here we go again.
Lining up the next suspect.
You mark my words.
Rogers.
He's an oily bugger.
Slinking around.
Going back and forth
during dinner.
He would have had time
to put something
in Mr. Marston's drink.
I heard him tell Mrs. Rogers
to shut up.
Well, she's shut up now,
isn't she?
He's the one moving the figures.
But the... the general,
the rest of us,
that record, this house...
Why?
Rogers... He's got
low cunning running though him
like Brighton
through a stick of rock.
We need to watch him.
Any faith I ever had
in the thin blue line
evaporated the second
I met you, Tubs.
You call me that one more time,
mate... one more time...
And you'll what?
We are all being hunted.
There's someone else
on this island,
and when I find him,
I'm gonna make him number 22
with a bullet right there.
Oh, God.
How could you say that...
so easily?
I just open my mouth,
and it comes out.
I'll see what can be done
about supper.
There's some liver and kidneys.
Perhaps a pie
with some good gravy.
That would be delicious, Rogers.
Thank you.
Thank you, Rogers.
Well, I ain't eating a
mouthful of his pie.
Oh.
Well, good night.
Trust in God.
But perhaps also...
we should lock our doors.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures.
He leadeth me
beside the still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the paths of
righteousness for his name's sake.
Yea, though I walk through...
the valley
of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil,
for Thou art with me.
I will fear no evil.
I will...
Thou art with me.
Get up!
I was looking for him.
I wanted a coffee.
Ilooked.
And I found this.
It wasn't me.
I just wanted a damn coffee.
He's been here all night.
Seven little soldiers
chopping up sticks.
One chopped himself in half,
and then there were six.
So she's right.
It is the poem.
But he's fucked,
Mr. Unknown Owen,
because six little solder boys
played with a hive.
A bumblebee stung one,
and then there were five.
And there is no hive here,
and there are no bees,
so what are you gonna do now,
Mr. Unknown Owen?
You're fucked!
You're fuck...
Now get dressed.
We will all get dressed,
and I will make coffee.
Miss Brent, shall we?
Yes.
Shit.
Shit the bed.
We'll need to find
something to wrap him up with
or he's gonna go everywhere.
Coffee.
There's no milk, I'm afraid.
Does this person...
mean to kill us all?
I believe so, yes.
I've lost a ball of wool.
I'm quite ridiculously
distressed about it.
It's only wool.
I'm so very tired.
Drink your coffee, Miss Brent.
I'll bring you a candle
to see by.
Thank you, dear.
I'll make some more.
Judge Wargrave, I feel I owe you
an apology for...
exposing your illness in such
an unforgivable fashion.
We're all feeling
a little ragged, understandably.
What's your opinion
of the others?
I haven't really formed one.
I don't trust any of them.
Blore.
That bastard Lombard.
Claythorne.
Miss Brent
and her religious mania.
But you and I...
we have sharp minds.
Actual intellects.
We should stay together.
Very well.
Oh.
Here.
Thank you.
Dribbling down myself
like a child.
Miss Claythorne's making
the coffee.
She should be watched.
Right.
You do the stairs.
I'm going to wash the guts
out of the wood store.
Can I?
I rather enjoy domestic tasks.
They are soothing.
Normal.
Indeed.
I'll just be a moment.
All right.
Stung by a bee.
And then there were five.
Well, I suppose with no Rogers,
I should think about lunch.
I could eat a scabby horse.
You're actually hungry?
Well, it was heavy work...
dealing with Rogers.
And you're the one
who suggested lunch.
Only because it's what one does
at this time of day.
But I'm not hungry.
How could you possibly
be hungry?
Oi, you.
Don't go implying...
casting aspersions...
I've got... I've got nothing
to do with this.
I've got nothing to do
with any of it.
Just because I said
that I was hungry...
I am hungry.
It doesn't prove a single thing.
I'm going to get dressed.
The whole morning, dragging
Rogers around, clearing up guts,
without so much as a cup of tea
to wet me whistle.
And you...
You look at me like...
Calm down.
You've got some front, love.
You've got
some right brass neck.
Don't go downstairs on your own.
Not with those two.
What, Wargrave and Armstrong?
You wait up here for me.
It was locked, which means
there must be a master key.
Rogers must have had
a master key.
You two dealt with the body!
And you found it.
Or did you?
You shrieking like a woman.
Was that a bit
of amateur dramatics, was it?
I did nothing to Rogers.
I didn't take any master key.
We don't even know if there is
a master key.
And we only have your word
that the gun was stolen!
- You could've taken it!
- Why would I steal my own gun?
I don't know
why you'd do anything, Lombard.
why you killed Rogers
or Miss Brent or MacArthur!
I didn't kill them.
Well, you would say that,
wouldn't you?
Just like you'd say
that your gun was stolen!
You really are a first-class,
five-star,
solid-gold fucking moron.
Please, the lady
Double bluff.
What, Tubs?
Why you would steal
your own gun.
Armstrong's got a point.
It's all riddles and games,
smoke and mirrors.
Double bluff.
You were the last one down.
The last one.
Ages behind everyone else.
What... What took you so long?
I don't care to say.
You killed Rogers.
You took the master key.
You went to bed.
You made sure all of us
were downstairs.
And then you got into my room
and you took my gun.
You have my gun,
you little prick.
Lombard.
For heaven's sake.
I never killed Rogers,
and I ain't got your key
or your sodding gun.
Then what took you so long?
If you weren't in my room
stealing my gun,
then why were you the last down?
I was in the bloody lavvy,
if you must know.
Constipated!
Oh, yes.
Yeah.
Laugh it up.
It's not funny.
I was bound up something rotten.
Sat there in a muck sweat.
So it weren't me.
It could have been any of us.
Any one of us
could have had the key.
could have the gun.
It is the only way to be sure.
It's not like you've been
singled out.
We're all getting the same.
No key.
No gun.
Now... Now you, Miss Claythorne.
Of course.
I'm just being thorough.
You like Uncle Hugo, don't you?
I do.
I'm in love with him.
I love him so much it hurts.
Silly.
Girls are silly.
And I'm going to marry him.
I heard Mummy say he couldn't
afford to get married.
Well, I'll find a way, Cyril.
If you marry Uncle Hugo...
When I marry Hugo.
Will you be my aunt?
I will.
Aunt Vera.
And what fun we'll have.
Christmas and birthdays
and summer holidays.
Picnics, parties, pony rides.
How happy we'll be
when we have everything.
Cyril!
Why isn't Lombard doing this?
Blore and I thought it a
good idea to keep you two apart.
Well, well, Miss Claythorne.
Mr. Lombard.
Philip.
Vera.
Nothing.
We'll search the rest
of the house.
Every room.
We're in hell.
And we're being punished
for what we done.
He refused the hood.
He haunts me still.
Look at them.
There's something going on
between them.
Someone has to come for us soon.
They... They have to.
I reckon we're being watched.
We are.