Stack it there.
Let's put you in a cage.
- Check out Mr. Speedy here!
- Hey, cut the crap.
He's going home...
Sing one for him.
Something special...
A special tune you say...
Yes, go for it.
Chains and fire all around,
God, bring the doors down to the ground.
Set the bloody jail on flames
Let us all run free, no chains.
May the guards all go to hell.
Chiscan!
And let out my dear Fanel...
- Chiscan!
- Over here!
- You've got a visitor!
- Who, me?
Yes, you! Aren't you Chiscan?
Yes, l am,
but who could come to see me?
Come on, move it,
l don't have time to fool around!
Come on, move...
- Do you know who it is?
- l don't know, you'll see.
lF l WANT TO WHISTLE, l WHISTLE
- Hi Silviu.
- Hi!
Good day, boss...
You know who came to see me?
Your brother.
Can l go to the toilet?
Hello!
Move over, man.
- How are you?
- l'm OK.
- What are you doing here?
- l came to see you.
l'll be home in two weeks,
why did you come again?
Yes, l know.
So?
Mother came home.
How could she come home?
She did, l'm telling you,
she is home.
She wants me to go to Italy with her.
And what did you tell her?
l told her
l wanted to talk to you first.
But what do you want?
Answer me!
Chiscan, the visit is over!
What are you talking about?
l just got here.
- That's it, you're done now.
- But it's not right.
Get out of here and shut up.
You've got an appointment
at the doctor's omice.
What doctor? The statutes says l have
the right to a 15 minutes visit...
You got two minutes left.
- How did you get here?
- By bus.
What bus? At this hour?
Go home and wait for me.
l'll get out in 15 days
and l'll take care of it.
OK.
Mother has to leave in a week.
She wants to talk to you
before you get out.
You listen to me, l'll be there
in 15 days.
And l'll take care of everything.
OK, see you.
Boss, can l go to the toilet, please,
l really got to go.
What do you want?
l can't help it,
l got to get to the toilet.
- Get back here in 5 minutes.
- l'll be back in 2 minutes.
Don't you know
you can't go near the fence?
Hey, what are you doing?
Resisting arrest?
Stop it, you'll kill him!
Grab his hand!
- Amariucai Janel!
- Here!
- Aioanei Claudiu lon!
- Androne Liviu!
- Here!
- Apostol Florinel!
- Badescu lonel Cristian!
- Here!
- Banescu Petrisor!
- Catarga Dumitru!
- Here!
- Elefterie Daniel!
Hush...
One word and l'll rip
your fucking eyes out, you hear me?
Shut the fuck up! Shut up!
Easy, Bear, easy. l'll rip your eyes out
if l hear one sound.
On the 12th of April 2009, 4:43PM,
l followed the order
from the watch tower
and l seized the inmate Chiscan Silviu.
The inmate Chiscan Silviu
crossed the demarcation line,
he entered the surveillance area,
he ignored the challenge
and resisted arrest.
What do you think about this?
During the four years you've spent here
you've been a good boy.
You like it in the Hole?
No, sir, l don't.
Then what were you doing there?
Listen to me...
You tell me
exactly what were you doing there.
Come on!
Let's hear it!
lf not, you'll get
two more years in prison, just like that.
l wanted to see
who brought my brother here.
Who brought him?
- A woman
- Who was that woman?
- My mother.
- So?
She wants to take my brother
to Italy with her.
Come again?
She wants to take him
to Italy with her. My brother.
So what? That's OK.
Don't you want her to take him?
No.
Come on, get serious...
For the next 9 days you'll spend here,
no more mistakes!
Understood?
Yes warden.
Come on...
Go!
Yo! Godson!
Godson!
- What's up?
- Come here a second!
What's up, did they let you go?
Yes, warden let me get away
with it.
Listen man, l need to use your phone
It's burning...
They made you
snitch somebody out, right?
No man...
- Get the hell out of here!
- Honestly, l swear he didn't.
Wait!
l swear, l really need to call somebody.
- When?
- Right now.
Hey, Blond!
- What's up, dude, did he let you go?
- Yeah, man, fuck him.
You pulled some strings, right?
He wants to use the phone now.
You know l'm cool.
- Whom do you want to call?
- My brother.
Later, when they take us out to work.
You bring it to him, you hear?
Three packs.
l have no cigarettes now,
but when l'm out of here
l'll send them to you.
How do l know you're not shitting me?
Come on, you know l'm cool.
- OK, seven packs then.
- OK. Thanks man.
Hey, what the fuck got into you?
Hey, give us the ball!
Fucking moron!
Hey, turn om the music!
Apostol Florinel.
Chiscan Silviu.
Parliteanu Stelus.
And Banescu Petrisor
come with me to the interv!iew.
And this one: ''l would like to eat...''
What do you like to eat?
- Next one.
- Silviu Chiscan.
- Hi, l'm Ana.
- Silviu.
l'm here for a week in prison,
l am doing field work and l'll show you
how to fill in this quiz.
Look, you have to fill in the blanks
and finish these sentences here.
l have to complete
the sentences, right?
That's right.
Once we are done,
what shall we do?
We'll interview you.
And in a week's time we'll come
to visit you at home,
that is if you agree.
- Yes... whatever.
- OK.
You want to know what l like best?
What do you mean?
Look, it says right here...
''Most of all l like to... ''
Yes, you have to finish the sentence.
To write it down.
Yes, but l don't want to write,
l want you to ask me.
What's the point in asking you,
if you have to write it down?
l don't want to write,
l'd rather want you ask me.
Fine.
- Do you want to know?
- Yes.
Then ask me.
What do you like the most?
Most of all, l like eating pizza.
Do you like pizza?
l'm here just to help you out
with the quiz and we cannot talk now.
- We can't?
- No.
Why?
- Any more questions?
- Yes, why can't we talk now?
Because we can't, l'm here to help you.
l'm just doing field work.
Thanks, OK then.
- l've got to fill in the quiz, right?
- Yes.
- Who's next?
- George Rotaru.
What table?
And when l'm done with the tests
what should l do?
You'll be interviewed.
The next tine we meet.
Life is like...
Freedom is like...
Hi, how are you?
ls mom there?
Put her on...
Hi mom...
l'm OK.
l heard you wanted to see me.
Tomorrow is visit day,
if you want to come...
Bye.
Come on, move it!
Stop!
All in line, face towards me!
Miss!
Hey, miss!
Come on, why you're ignoring me?
Hello!
Hi!
- Can l tell you something?
- Go ahead!
You're very beautiful.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome, my pleasure.
Hey, stop it!
Hey, cool down!
- What are you doing with the shard?!
- Hey, guys cut it out!
- Put the shard down!
- Come on guys, enough...
Come here if you got the balls...
Let them fight!
For a pack of cigarettes, man...
Hey, guys, cut it out... enough...
Leave us alone!
- Hey, enough is enough!
- Leave me the fuck alone!
Come on, let them be...
- Get your fucking hands om me!
- Cut it out...
You fight
for a lousy pack of cigarettes.
Are you picking on me for nothing?
Give me the cigarettes!
You can suck my dick!
- You're a fucking cunt, or what?
- Hey, enough, that's it.
- Buck, Buck!
- Incoming...
Buck, buck!
- Come on, kid, go!
- Buck buck!
Easy man...
Buck, buck.
Come on, say it!
Come on, already!
Say it!
Two!
Two! Fuck you!
NO!
What's the fucking number?
- What was it?
- What?
- Tell me the number!
- Three.
- It was two.
- It wasn't two.
lt was two.
Sunny, it was three, man...
For this cocksucker, it's any
number l want it to be...
Why are you calling me a cocksucker?
You want to hit me?
Get your hands om me!
Come on, hit me!
Come on, sucker, hit me.
Are you afraid to hit me?
Hit me!
Are you afraid
you won't get out of here no more?
l'm right, ain't l?
You're afraid they won't set you free?
Are you?
You're afraid you're going to rot in jail?
Say it!
- Come on, hit him back!
- He doesn't have the balls.
From now on, you do
only what l tell you to do, got it?
lf you don't, l'll blow you
and your dumb buddy right here
for all to see.
Do you hear me?
l'm talking to you, get it?
Get the fuck out of here!
From now on, he is my slave.
lf anyone wants to spit on his face,
go ahead!
Cluck! Cluck! Cluck!
Do you know what l'm gonna do
when l'll be free?
l'll get out of here and l'll marry
that girl with beautiful lips...
And l'll pick her up from work
and we'll fuck right there in the car...
And we'll fuck, on and on and on...
We'll fuck our brains out man...
What are you doing?
Hurry up! He's getting away!
Fucking son of a bitch!
- How are you, my boy?
- Hi, mom!
How are you?
l'm good.
Sit down.
You've grown so much!
l ate my veggies.
l brought you some cigarettes,
Marius told me you needed some.
Thanks.
How are you?
l'm OK. When did you come back?
A few days ago, but l won't stay long,
l'm leaving the day after tomorrow.
l have to go back to work.
- My baby...
- What work is that?
l work in a hotel, as a receptionist.
l wanted to ask you
to let Marius stay here.
He is not fit for work
and he has to finish school.
You shouldn't carry him around with you,
like you did to me.
l'm not doing so bad over there...
l want to take him with me
and when you'll be free,
you can come as well.
l'll never come to you.
Why?
You came here
to get on my nerves, or what?
Why are you talking to me like that?
What do you mean?
For eight years you...
l talked to your father in hospital
and he signed the papers
to let him come with me.
You'll never ever take him away
with you!
You won't take him away
because l raised him.
For 8 years you didn't care about us,
and now you come to take him away?
You're feeling lonely, right?
You should have taken care of him.
Don't you talk to me like that.
- What do you mean?
- l'm your mother. Yours and his.
What are you?
Come again. What are you?
You've never been a mother to me.
When l was there with you, you sent me
home because l was getting in your way.
Now you want your family back, right?
She came back because
she's all alone there...
She's lonely like shit,
that's why she came back.
Am l right?
Things aren't exactly like that...
Really?
You took me with you
and when you found a new guy,
you got rid of me and sent me home,
like a luggage.
ls it true or not?
And then you came back
and took me with you again
until you found a new guy,
and you sent me home again,
like l was nothing but a bag of shit.
ls this what you want to do with him?
You want to destroy his future
just like you did with me.
This is what you want to do to him.
Because you are a fucking whore.
Your mother is a whore!
You stupid con! Don't you talk to me
like that!
Lady, please.
l didn't come here
to have you talk to me like that.
Why do you hit me?
Do you want to know why?
Because l'm your mother, that's why.
Don't you dare hit me again,
because it was you who destroyed me!
Sit down...
l walked the streets
like a fucking nut,
because l didn't know what else to do.
And now you're coming back
and you hit me
after 8 fucking years?
And you want to take him away?
l'll break your fucking neck!
Shut up, shut up!
Stop hitting me!
Calm down.
Get your hands om me!
You stupid con!
- Leave me alone.
- Sit down!
Who do you think you are to hit me?
You know who l am?
l'm your mother, do you understand?
- Stop yelling!
- Fucking whore!
lf you're not home
when l get there,
l'll fucking kill you all, got it?
lf you're not there when l get home,
l'll destroy you all!
Stop shouting at him!
Shut the fuck up or l'll kill you!
You fucking destroyed me!
- Did you hear what l told you?
- Yes.
- Don't you leave with her!
- Sure...
Take your fucking cigarettes
with you!
- l have to see the warden.
- He's out in the camp.
Sir, have you seen warden?
He went to the dormitories.
Have you seen warden?
l haven't seen
your fucking warden.
- You saw him, guys?
- No.
Have you seen warden?
You want to rat us out?
Just tell me if you've seen him.
Why?
Rat...
Warden! Sir!
l've got something
very important to ask you.
What is it Chiscan?
l'll be released on the 1Tth,
and l was wondering
if l could go on a leave, for...
For one day, sir...
l need to go home for one day.
How come?
Could you?
l can't let you go on a leave.
Once you've been examined
by the Committee
you're not allowed to go on leave.
- Where do you want to go?
- Home.
Won't you go home
when you'll be released?
Yes, but l really have to go now.
Please, sir...
Wait a couple more days.
Please sir, l really have to go.
l gave you one finger and now
you want to grab my whole hand.
l'm begging you sir.
Godson...
Hey Godson...
What?
l really need to make a call.
Get out of here.
Godson!
l need your phone, man, please!
Leave me alone, you queer.
Godson!
Give me the phone,
l need it real bad.
Get the fuck out of here
and let me sleep.
l'll wake the boys up and we'll shit
all over your fucking faggot face...
Godson!
l told you to get the fuck out of here!
You lame ass.
What do you want?
What's up my man?
Hey.
You're OK? Tell me...
You're a real sucker.
How come you got so low?
Tell me.
Godson told me you woke him up
Iast night because you needed the phone.
Yes.
- Why?
- l needed the phone
Who do you think you are?
You're a cocksucker, how come
you go and ask him for the phone?
Wait a bit.
You owe me T packs of cigarettes...
now you owe me 10.
And l want them today,
or l'll be real mad. You hear me?
- Hey, l'm warning you... got it?
- Yes.
Watch it...
- l'm Mihai, their teacher.
- Silviu.
- How are you?
- Good.
Let's start from the beginning.
You'll be released soon
and l'd like you to tell me
what will you do outside.
l'll go home to my brother.
- Do you have a brother?
- Yes
- Older or younger?
- Younger.
- Do you want a cigarette?
- No, thank you.
Where are your parents?
My father is in hospital.
ls he sick?
l don't know.
What do you want from me?
l read your quiz and you did good...
Your writing skills are good.
Why did you read my quiz?
lt's OK, l'll put is aside.
Let's forget about the quiz.
l don't want anyone else reading it.
You can refuse to be interviewed
but since you've took the quiz...
Sit down!
You can kiss your freedom goodbye.
Chiscan, stand up!
Get the hell out of here!
Get out of here...
Get out of here!
Take your hands om me!
You sit here!
Get out of here!
- What's got into you?
- Get out of here...
Blond, get out of here...
Get out of here now...
Blond, get the fuck out of here!
Get warden here now!
Get warden here!
Stay right there!
Get him!
What are you looking at?
Get out of here!
Are you scared?
- You're scared, right?
- Yes.
lf you're a good girl,
l promise l won't hurt you.
lf you make one wrong move,
l'll kill you, got it?
- Do you hear me?
- Yes.
Silviu!
l want you to get my mother here
in an hour, you hear me?
Silviu, what are you doing?
You have my brother's number there.
You call and talk to her, get it?
Take the boys inside!
Silviu, don't do anything stupid,
we'll work things out, OK?
You heard what l told you?
Move your ass and get my mother here now!
l'll call her, l told you, l will...
lf l see any special forces around,
l'll cut her throat!
l won't call them, don't worry.
Put the shard down...
l want everybody to go to the wall!
Do what he says!
Fuck you all and all your shitty police!
Go to the wall.
The other one.
Silviu!
Hey, Silviu!
l talked to your mother!
She'll be here in an hour,
l promise you!
Good.
How is the guard doing?
lf you let the girl go now,
we can still work things out.
We'll say you were provoked
to do this.
You have my word for it.
You have my word for it,
you hear me?
Silviu!
Do you still want to interview me?
No.
Let's do it.
Chiscan Silviu, 18 years old, Braila.
Have you ever been to Braila?
No.
Too bad. We could have met
and l could have taken you out
for a comee.
Do you want to go out with me
for a comee?
- Do you?
- Yes.
- Do you have a boyfriend?
So what? It's just a comee,
There's nothing wrong with that.
Do you want to?
- Do you?
- Yes.
You know it's all on tape now, right?
Yes.
Not anymore.
Give me something to clean him up.
Get om the lawn!
Step back!
Silviu!
Your mother is here!
Send her in.
Let us take the guard out of there.
First get my mother in here.
You wanted me to get your mother here.
Now let us help that man.
l make the rules here!
Send her in! Then we'll see...
Go ahead...
This way?
Send some inmates
to take the guard out of here.
Shut up!
Send in two more to take him out.
Good luck man.
l want you to swear you won't take
Marius to Italy with you.
lf you don't, l'll kill myself
right now. Promise me!
Promise me!
l won't take him.
Swear on your eyes
you won't take him with you.
l said l won't, l won't.
Swear on your mother's grave
and to sear like her.
Swear... l'll slash her throat!
Swear l said!
l swear...
l swear on... my mother's grave and...
sear like her and hope to die...
l won't take Marius to Italy.
What will you do?
Tell me what are you going to do?
Say it!
l'll let him stay home.
What home?
Here, home...
What are you going to do?
Tell me!
l don't know, my boy...
You'll stay here
and make his life miserable?
l don't know, my boy,
l don't know anymore...
l don't know what to do...
l want you to bring Buciumas over here,
get your car here and open the gates.
l want to take this girl out
for a comee.
Do you hear me?
Are you kidding me?
lf you do as l told you,
l won't hurt her.
You really think you'll get out of here?
You wanted me to get your mother here,
l did, That's it!
lt's over when l say so,
you hear me?
lf you don't do it,
l'll fucking cut her throat.
And then l'll kill myself!
We're just going out for a comee.
That's all.
l promise l won't hurt her!
Uncum him.
Now you keep him there
till you bring the car.
Tell the driver to get out of the car
and leave the engine running.
What are you going to do?
l want to take Ana out for a comee.
Now tell him to get out of the car.
And leave the engine running!
Get over here!
Get Bear over here!
You take the shard,
and if she makes a wrong move,
you slash her throat, OK?
Shag her!
Run, man, run! Run Silviu!
You have beautiful lips.
Thanks.
Why don't you drink your comee?
l can't right now.
- Do you like it?
- Yes, it's very good.
When the waitress gets back,
tell her to get me one more comee, OK?
Yes.
Get down on the ground!
Put your hands on your head!
Freeze!