Did you knock?
No, I didn't.
But I did think about it.
And why you didn't?
There was nobody to open.
I was in the cellar.
How did you know?
Do you prefer good company
or the nice view?
I've got the free room upstairs,
next to the Fra's Hubert.
This is really nice monk, really nice.
But there's a view on the wall.
Or this room.
Beautiful view on the yard,
but there's nobody to talk to.
Young foregn girl from next door...
never goes out and never talks with anybody.
The Professor can't see nobody now.
The Professor doesn't receive the patients now.
Let's go to my place.
Can I meet the Professor?
No, it's impossible for now.
I'm sorry.
No, please, understand me. Later.
I had doubts,
if you can handle the situation here.
But dr Barredo commended you much.
Why did you leave his clinic?
Dr Barredo retired.
and his successor wasn't really keen on
accepting my methods of work.
We will try to be convinced by you.
But you are not allowed to teach
the depth perception on your own.
This is due to the safety of the patients.
Do you understand me?
Yes, I do.
Can we come closer?
Why would you like to come closer?
To touch you.
Or smell you.
Yes, to smell.
To smell!
We can smell him!
You can smell.
But stay where you are.
From the distance we can only
recognise that you've been smoking.
And what could you say when being closer?
If you smoke cigarettes or rather a pipe?
Is it worth standing up
just to get to know it?
And without standing up
what else can you tell?
Without standing up? From this place?
You can stand up, if you want.
Somebody's walking on the yard.
A man or a woman?
To my mind it's a woman.
Why?
She's wearing high-heels.
A man can also have heels like that.
The cuban heels.
Like in the 60. or 70.
the disco dancers.
Somebody else?
I think it's a woman.
Because woman's steps are stronger.
I would say it's a man.
Sometimes men can have
stronger steps.
It's a woman.
Yes, it's a woman.
I think so, too.
Because of the shoes?
Is she young or old?
Young.
And what is she doing?
Sweeping the yard.
The young lady smokes shoddy cigarettes
and coughts like a lunger?
Can you imagine her?
She has finished.
She got ashamed.
But we can still hear her heels!
Who will go to see what she's doing?
Me.
Are your hands clean?
Yes.
Go then.
Without my cane?
Why should you use your cane?
You could hurt her ankle with it.
Watch out!
Did you hurt yourself?
Without the finger in the glass...
...I think I won't make it.
Help!
Over?
Yes.
Was it easy or hard?
Hard.
It's hard. It's very hard.
You're shooing the sparrows.
One comes...
This is some kind of strange bird.
I thought it was a sparrow.
Why a sparrow?
Because it's jumping on both legs.
The others walk like people:
left, right...
This one is much too big for a sparrow.
What do you give them?
The seeds.
What kind of seeds?
Sunflower seeds.
Didn't you know
that the birds like them?
She calls the cat.
She gives him some milk.
And now she goes inside.
She went back to the larder.
And the yardman watches the yard.
How do you know he does?
Because he's smoking.
I can smell the cigarette smell.
Maybe he's sitting?
Yes, it's possible.
Something else?
No. No.
You've missed the cat.
He has passed by just in front
of your noses.
Which cat?
How can you hear the cat?
He would have to bump on something.
You can smell it.
Nobody can smell a cat.
You're inventing it.
You all have smelled it.
You've smelled it with the dog's nose.
You've just missed the dog's barking.
He's probably inventing it. Sure, he does!
Really?
So who has drunk the milk?
Wait. Move the cane a bit forward.
No.
Denilson, come and see yourself!
I'm coming...
You're ready?
What do you have for me this time?
Why?
We wanted to try,
if you use the cane when nobody sees you.
How should I know
if nobody sees me?
I'm blind.
So why don't you use the cane?
A blind man doesn't need a cane.
If only he's not lame.
If you had the cane,
you wouldn't have fallen down.
I told you I didn't use the cane.
Some people claim you're lying.
That's why you spread a fly line
to check me?
And if I knocked my teeth out?
So a cane would be useful?
It's useful for hitting in the desk as well...
So maybe you can see?
Watch out, it can break.
It's not your cane...
Nothing is happening.
Nobody's here.
If nobody's here,
who trims the roses?
How do you know
those are roses?
What else can you trim here?
Who would go to find out
what do they trim here?
Me.
Go then.
Be aware of the thorns.
I'm going, too.
Carefully!
I'll go, too.
There's nobody by the roses.
You looked too low.
This man was standing on the ladder.
I pricked myself three times
at least...
Mother Marie!
Yes, sir?
What are you doing down there?
Stop, Antonio...
My God, you're scratched all over.
What are you doing here?
My God, come with me.
Ian, Tom, come closer, please.
Didn't you prick yourself?
Don't cry.
It's alright.
You didn't prick.
What are you doing?
We were tracing the gardener?
It's good he's not here.
You've stomped his roses...
How come? He has to be here!
You need to be blingfolded
to take part in the lesson.
To my office, please.
The outside lessons
need the preparation.
This group requires at least...
... three sighted attendants.
You are not allowed to walk
patients on your own!
Somebody can be hit by the car!
That's right.
But they don't go straight
on the crossroad, do they?
The only thing that can hit them here
is the cat or the dog.
Ambulances drive in here,
as well as the cars with carbon and with the supply.
You are right.
I'll be more careful.
It's not enought thay you'll be more careful!
Look at yourself.
You're stuck in the middle of the room
because you're not able to see even the chair.
Why don't you use the cane?
I do.
Sometimes.
Far too less considering
the condition of your face!
Who should I speak to
in order to take them outside?
To me.
And I will provide the support
respectively to the number of patients.
I'd like to seat with them on the bench
in front of the door tomorrow.
Alright.
Just write the scenario of the lesson, please.
I'm sorry... Good morning...
Why do we all wait here?
Where's this line from?
We are grounded!
What happened?
The doctor didn't receive the scenario
of the lesson.
Have you forgotten?
Where were you supposed to go?
On the yard!
But you know the yard already.
Didn't you want to go somewhere further?
Sure we did!
We want to see new places!
Why don't you just crack open the door?
But we can't go out, right?
You don't need to go out,
crack opening the door is enough.
I'm sorry...
Alright, Serrano, go.
Can you come closer?
Tell me what you see.
The birds.
I can hear some kind of the machine...
... but I don't know what it is used for.
Those are cars.
Can you try a little bit more?
Try harder...
I hear something doing: boom, boom...
What?
I can hear something doing: boom, boom...
This is your heart pounding.
And that's all?
The sky is clear,
but the clouds are coming.
There's going to be a storm.
This is a jet plane.
Are you blindfolded?
No, then I wouldn't be able
to take care of you, right?
So you are not allowed to speak!
And you, Eva?
Me?
I was just passing by...
I saw something...
... but it was impossible.
What was that?
A ship.
What kind of the ship?
What ship?
A big ship.
What?
The one that sails on the ocean.
Can we go out?
We would hear it better.
No, you can't.
We can't.
I can.
But the door looking out the street
are on the other side.
Where is your cane?
Pardon me?
I don't own one.
So you can't join me.
Where is this cane?
I broke it down.
How come?
When I was walking around with a cane
everybody was staring at me...
They offered help...
... they pushed and pulled me.
So you broke it down on purpose?
You are able to walk without one...
Can I do that as well?
It's dangerous.
I'll think about that.
I want to try it now!
Please!
And zou tell me
what I'm doing and when I shoudl turn back,
as if you were walking yourself.
You're walking.
You're walking on the pavement.
lam
How are you walking, moron?!
Come back!
Didn't you notice when the pavement
finished?
It was you who didn't notice!
You could have been run over!
I do hear when tha pavement finishes.
And haven't you heard
that the car was coming?
I have.
It was you who haven't heard
since you told me to be back right over the car.
How can you hear the end of the pavement?
Follow me.
Carefully, the step.
The end of the pavement is always hearable.
It is between the steps and the noise of the wheels.
From here you can hear it
with the two-step accuracy.
But when you come closer,
you can track it more precisely.
Imagine it. Then you will hear it.
Listen how it gets closer!
Three steps. Two.
The last step before kerb
always sounds differently.
Try it.
Some more steps..?
No!
Ok, do you want to come back
to the doors?
No, I want to go further.
Eva... Don't let people push you.
Follow me.
The passer-bys go round the obstacles
which don't get out of their way.
But you have to keep determined direction.
What was that?
I don't know.
So how could you go round it?
I did the same as the woman in front of us.
Can you hear her steps?
I can hear many steps.
She's got the shoes on real thin leather.
She uses good parfume.
She's doing window-shopping.
Has she turned?
She's gone into the shop.
A man with the newspaper behind us.
Let him go.
He has a pin in his sole,
can you hear that?
Aren't we following him?
I prefer the other one.
Can you smell him?
Weird parfume.
The mix of yesterday's night drinks
and the morning beer.
What kind of the tree is that?
Can you reach the leaves?
What is this fruit?
Try it.
A cherry.
I can't reach it.
Yes, you can.
You just don't know where to look for it.
Those are bad. Too shy.
Shy? How is that?
Not good.
Trash.
What?
Those are alright.
Eight out of ten.
Try those.
Walk once more.
Some more steps.
Those are the best shoes in the whole shop.
The chair.
What is the chair doing here?
I don't know.
People are sitting on those chairs.
And what are they doing?
I don't know.
Let's have a sit. We'll see what happens.
This is the wind from the see.
How do you know?
I can smell it.
They play checkers.
And drink home-made wine out of the mugs.
Good morning.
Americans?
No. An English man.
German,
Put your hand out.
What's your name?
Two coffees for us, Mario.
Of course!
He didn't notice that I was blind?
No. But don't hold your menu upside down.
How do you know they drink home-made vine?
They pour it out of the jar.
I'd like to have that vine, too.
I think I can smell the sea.
Is there a harbour somewhere?
Yes.
Can you hear those engines?
It sounds like motorcycle racing.
But those are the motorboats in the harbour.
How do you recognise it?
They don't stop at the traffic lights.
The pumps press the petrol... and the water.
You can hear cranes.
In front of us is the wharf.
By the wharf there is a big ship.
Mario has forgotten about us. Mario!
I think I'm deaf.
And who has seen today a big ship?
Maybe you've heard the whistle
when the shop had entered the harbour?
And you've forgotten about than.
Or you've woken up.
The same ship that is now in the harbour?
Can you hear it now?
I don't know well the sounds of this district.
But the church bells reverberate from a big surface.
Maybe it's only the wall made of houses?
Mario probably sees less than me. Mario!
You call him.
I've just invited her for the party...
And that's the problem!
Mario!
A beautiful foreigner is waiting!
I'm going to grab this vine myself
I think.
Mario is talking with a girl.
Maybe the portugese boys take
too many orders?
And the coffee becomes cold?
I don't take orders.
But if you want...
Do you want to smell that?
It's strong!
Brandy. Portugese.
The local speciality.
Wait. I haven't pour it yet!
Try it.
No, thank you. I ordered a vine.
Oh no!
Being too careful doesn't help.
Are you listening?
We're starting.
It hasn't brimmed.
Sometimes it's better to act...
... quickly and resolutely.
Let's try once more.
What are you doing here?
What's wrong?
You're not blind!
Why do you think so?
I know how you cross the street.
And how do I cross the street?
You have to see the cars well,
to cross like that.
You are wrong.
You can see...
every car...
...every car on the street...
...makes a horrible noise!
And then it passes by...
you know how far is every car...
and how fast it is.
I don't believe you.
It is your problem, then.
You can prove you are not lying.
How?
You've said you didn't have eyes.
I don't.
So you have fake eyes.
Glass ones, right?
Please.
Touch them yourself.
Should I take them out?
No!
Take them! Please!
I don't want them!
Play with them!
And, what are you doing now?
I'm clicking.
What?
And where is your cane?
I don't have it.
You don't have it?
No.
Do you want to fall down?
Knock your teeth out?
I don't want it. That's why I'm clicking.
Ian, show to the doctor how to click.
The doctor doesn't believe me.
What did he say?
Please, show how to click.
Are you here?
Yes.
Will you click for doctor Pedros?
Sure.
Very well.
Clicking.
Show me how you walk without a cane.
With clicking.
My mouth is dry, it's hard to click...
The exercise is about...
hearing the bicycle
which Jose left on the courtyard.
Can you hear it?
Yes.
And can you hear it?
I can't hear bell.
Doesn't matter.
We want to hear the bike when it's not using the bell.
Even then it gives the sounds back.
Clicking, for example.
You can also snap your fingers or
tap with the shoes, the good shoes.
Can I start?
Yes!
Yes, please, show it.
It has a bell.
Impressive!
Do you use the sensor?
What do you mean?
The sensor which you have in your pocket.
I don't use any sensor!
But you do own an electronic gadget...
I saw it it your hand.
Do you mean this one?
Yes.
Do you use it sometimes?
Almost never.
It's ultrasonic range finder.
Is it useful in finding your way?
But you don't use the cane, right?
No, I don't.
So you use the sensor...
I use many things.
But rarely the sensor.
Can I see?
You click so well
that you don't need the cane.
I click rarely.
What you need are good shoes.
Did you hear the motorbike?
Which motorbike?
There is a motorbike on the courtyard, too.
You should have heard it.
It is close.
It surely reflects clicking.
I haven't heard it. Does it stand near the wall?
Or any other objects?
No.
So it stands too far.
Few more meters do make a difference.
Won't you find it without the sensor?
I've told you I don't use the sensor
to find my way.
Clever thing. It vibretes more
when the distance gets smaller.
Show me you don't need a sensor!
Yes, show them!
Show them!
He fell in carbon's chute!
He should use the cane as every blind person.
You are dangerous.
Dangerous for yourself and the other blind people.
I won't let you work
with my patients anymore.
I need to fire you.
I gave you good references.
And you'll get the whole month salary.
If I can't work with blind people anymore...
...maybe I could get another work
in the clinic?
What do you think of?
I don't know...
... we need the library in Braille.
Some blind children...
...are waiting for every free place here.
I can't sacrifice those places...
I can rent a room in the town
and come to work everyday as all the others.
I won't give you any work
in which you had any contact with the patients.
This is a private clinic.
It can maintain due to charity donations...
because it doesn't pay taxes to the order.
One missed step can destroy...
...the haritage of many years of hard work.
I'll think about an office work for you.
But you are forbidden...
...to walk around the clinic
without a cane.
The sensor is coming!
He was given a cane!
Lier!
Can you walk?
Why are you interested if I can walk?
Would you like to go somewhere?
Maybe in the same place as yesterday?
To this bar?
Yes.
I can't.
Did they take the sensor away?
I don't need a sensor!
Why exactly to this bar?
Do you want to be the girl
without a cane?
To be picked up by the guy again?
Which guy?
Mister "Brandy Portugues".
"Local speciality".
I can go.
Where do you want to go?
To this bar on the corner.
I know where it is.
Ready?
Yes.
I'm waiting for you!
A minute or an hour more?
What's wrong?
I don't have a cane.
I do.
Pretend you are leading me.
Come, without the cane you'll be
more sexy.,,
...and I don't mind.
Not so fast!
Watch out!
Please, it's too fast!
Everything's alright?
Yes.
Where are the cherries?
Guincho is the dangerous beach.
...the strong wind is there...
Great beach... for surfing.
I'm sorry, it's my surfboard/
This is an action.
There are no cherries here.
Action?
He says it's an action.
Good morning, my beautiful foreigner!
Good morning, Senhores.
You've made it!
Is it here?
Can't you recognise the smell?
Coffee!
You can have a seat.
Is it the sea breeze?
Yes.
I can't smell the seeweed.
Is it a motorboat?
It sounds like a common motorcycle.
But it can go wherever it wants.
No traffic lights, no police,
no heavy traffic...
...it's not a motorcycle.
Is this ship still here?
You have to wait.
When the church bells ring,
you'll hear an echo.
It's a motorboat!
I'm terribly sorry!
Are you alright?
Did something happen to you?
No, nothing.
The guy almost bite my hand off.
American, right?
From New York.
You?
From Berlin.
Holidays?
Not really...
I've got a week of holidays left...
and I'm just hanging out on the coast...
Are you staying long?
Until it's possible to keep up
on the surfboard.
Do you surf? Really?
A little bit.
Where can you surf here?
Here, in Europe, nowhere, in fact.
Except Guincho.
Is there any club?
I'd need to rent a board.
It won't be easy.
Those are maniacs,
they don't borrow their boards.
Do you really surf?
A little bit.
It's very dangerous place.
Every year the current takes
somebody under the Cabo da Roca.
I'll be careful.
At least I will watch.
Will we meet there after?
Today, in Gincho?
Yes.
I'll get the board.
The wind... The wind is really strong today...
I'm a bit afraid when weather is like that.
We'll keep on the boards somehow.
I don't know...
It's hard for you to keep on the chair...
The bells!
Listen to the bells!
The church bell ring!
There's an echo!
True!
Every single beat can be heard twice!
And what does it mean?
The sound reflects from the ship.
Which ship?
This one here, in the harbour!
What harbour?
Is there any harbour here?
Senhores, how far is to the harbour
from here?
Which harbour?
Alcȃntara?
Yes. How to go there?
It's too far to walk.
Take the tram 28 to Prazeres.
And then the bus to Alcȃntara.
Is there nothing closer?
Santa Apolónia. A bit closer.
Yes! Santa Apolónia.
How to go there?
Take 28 to Martim Moniz Square.
I need something closer.
There is nothinb between
Alcȃntara and Santa Apolónia.
Try it, please.
Very nice!
What's the price?
Give it a try,
Please, try it! It's good!
You're a lier!
You lie to everybody!
Really?
There is no ship!
There is no harbour even!
Who told you that?
The locals from the bar.
Senhores...
They sit in the bar the whole day long...
and watch the street.
But they can't see anything.
How's that?
They watch...
...but they can't see.
In the harbour there is a big ship
and it can be heard clearly.
Senhores can't see it since you can't see
the coast from the bar.
You're lying, because you know
I can't see anything!
You can prove that you're not lying.
No! Give me the cane back!
And how will I walk?
Keep up with me.
Three steps. Two. Now.
Watch the kerb!
Stop.
Before the scooter will the the break.
Do you know how the scooter sounds?
Yes.
Now.
How do you feel?
Perfect!
Everything's alright?
I think so.
I've lost my glasses.
Where's my cane?
Here.
I'd prefer to have a cane.
This cane is too short.
Too short...
How long should it be?
I don't know.
It should keep you further away
from the danger.
All blind people have canes like this.
And still they have...
...accidents.
We are looking for the ship?
Yes.
But it's not here.
Where are we?
What's in front of us?
Throw a stone.
What kind of water is that?
The Atlantic.
The Tag river is on the left.
Fish...
Once more.
It's here.
Where?
Here.
Can't you hear it?
No.
It starts here.
Clap your hands.
Can you hear the difference?
Yes.
Here is where the ship ends.
How big it is?
Not that big.
About 30 meters.
We're not looking for this one.
This is this ship.
Where?
What can you hear?
A wall.
Very high wall.
It is a huge ship.
I can't hear it's a ship!
Yes, you can.
Imagine it is talking to you.
How can I imagine that
if I can't hear it?
Imagine it first
and then it will talk to you.
And the you will hear it!
And what is he saying?
He says...
...that the sun was heating it the whole day.
And now it can cool down in Tag.
It's warmer up.
But it has cooled a bit down.
How can you know it's not
a building or a canal boat?
It is not a canal boat!
One of the engines is working.
It always goes at low revolutions.
For the passenger to light the lamp
and take the cold beer from the fridge.
You can't hear it...
but the whole ship is vibrating
gently.
Really?
Something else?
A razor buzzes up there, on the left.
Golarka brzęczy w górze, po lewej.
Maybe an officer is shaving
before the sentry?
How do you know it's an officer?
I don't know if it's an officer.
Why would the passenger shave
in the middle of the night?
Can you hear his epaulette, too?
And you can't hear nothing?
No!
I'm cold, I'm going back!
Please, take this.
Thank you!
Do you know where are you going?
Wait here!
What were you doing in the harbour?
Three security cameras filmed you
throwing stones.
We were throwing it.
But we weren't pointing anything.
It's hard to point, without eyes.
Why were you throwing them then?
To hear the plop.
Plop means that something has been pointed.
So you wanted to point something!
Point what?
An Atlantic.
Serrano! Didn't I stiched you up last week?
No.
And who pu the stiches on you arm?
Doctor Pedros.
You stiched up my knee.
Here lies the blind man
who used to be my patient.
Such as you.
I'll show you what happened to him.
Wait here.
Why?
He was run over the train.
No breaks.
Good.
Thank you.
And now, pack your things, please...
... and leave immidiately!
Do you understand?
Yes.
Can I say good-bye to my friends?
I know they liked you.
But would it be better to protect them...
...from the sad partying?
Alright.
Those are the seeds.
I'll show you.
And this is your bird.
Thank you.
Do you remember about scrambled eggs?
I do.
Good morning.
Good morning, Mário.
Something to drink?
A bacon in my scrambled eggs?
I'm talking to you!
Why is there a bacon in my scrambled eggs?
I'm terribly sorry!
I can't eat bacon!
Can I move a bit your suitcase?
Something to drink?
More coffee?
Brandy?