UFA Cinematic Art
presents
IMMENSEE
A German Folk Song
Screenplay by
Color photography
Decors
Music
Production management
Featuring
Production
and direction
Philharmonic Orchestra
Hamburg
THE WATER LILY
Lyric Suite
We have about an hour, right?
Drive ahead with the luggage and
wait for me at the gate with my ticket.
- When's the plane to Amsterdam
going?    - At 10:20.
Water lilies, as Mister Torsten
explicitly wished for.
We had put orchids on the table.
Something personal, I suppose.
- Elisabeth.
- Reinhardt.
- That was fast, Reinhardt!
- It has to be fast...
in an hour I will be
on the plane again.
But we don't want to rush
at this very hour, Reinhardt.
When I said I'd have an appointment
with the General Music Director,
they made deep bows
all the way to the floor.
A little of your light is even
shining on me now, Reinhardt.
You've become a great man...
Don't embarrass me, Elisabeth.
It's just the time... the long time
we haven't seen each other.
I thank you for
the water lily, Reinhardt.
The water lily... Elisabeth...
When you played the
suite for me, I thought
it is for me alone, and not
for all the strangers around.
And so it was.
...The water lily.
What would the water lily
be without you, Elisabeth?
It is... it really is
the symbol of our youth.
Yes...
It was beautiful, your concert,
Reinhardt.
I haven't been out
since Erich's death.
"Since Erich's death"...
how that sounds...
I was on the passage
at that time...
when I came to Buenos I got my
father's letter... all was already over.
And I didn't even write to you.
That's how I recognize you, Reinhardt...
you haven't changed at all.
But I have a letter for you.
Actually, I wanted to send it
to you for the concert.
But I'm happy to be able
to give it to you now.
To give it back, that is.
It was painful for me
at the time you sent it to me.
Because...
this is not how our parting
was meant to be.
Look... people are
connected by more things
than just that what we had
to say goodbye to then.
O Lord, how long ago!
To my dear Reinhardt, faithfully
Elisabeth.
Like a thousand years.
And suddenly, at a
fleeting hour...
in between hotel and airport,
everything comes back again.
As if it were today.
The sun is rising.
The sun rises...
...over our entire life.
Yes, Reinhardt...
I was waiting the whole time
for the bird to start singing.
A bullfinch!
Until now I woke you up.
Early in the morning
with my whistle.
And when I'm gone now
he will do it for me.
And every time he whistles,
you should think it's me.
- What's his name?
- No name... just bullfinch!
- But he needs a name...
- Name him Reinhardt!
Reinhardt is your name only.
Nevermind,
we'll find something.
- Haven't your mother heard you?
- She's still asleep.   - Come!
We put the bird down here -
I have to show you something.
I finished it
just the other night.
- You made it yourself?
- Yes.
What a prospective
musician is able to do!
You shall sit here...
...in the evening...
- Marvelous!
- ...or in the morning if you like...
...and then think of me.
If you still want to
think of me, that is.
All right, then.
...in the morning and evening.
And then we will
write each other.
And we'll appoint
a day and an hour...
...and then...
...we'll point out a spot in
the sky, the moon, or Mars...
...or Venus.
Yes...
That one suits best.
Then I will look up
from my music desk...
...and our gazes will meet
each other up there, on Venus.
Our hearts, Reinhardt.
Look over there...
...the sun.
I would like to be there,
where the sun now rises...
And when you'll be there,
where you think the sun rises...
it will go on the same way.
And you'll be saying again:
"I'd like to be where the sun rises..."
That way we'll be
separated more and more.
Do you think I could
stay here, all my life?
That's not for me.
Perhaps for Erich...
...but not for me.
Nah, I have to get out!
Out into the world.
Other countries, other people,
something new all the time.
I don't want to hear this...
You're frightening me -
my mother would say...
Now what would she say?
"That's how gypsies are,"
she'd say.
"Gypsies"?
What you're saying...
I don't say that.
I mean, my mother says that.
Don't make that angry look.
I want to come along
to where you're going.
Be very quiet.
It's so beautiful to look at the
rising sun, and be quiet together.
- You'll get cold, Elisabeth.
- Erich, you scare us.
I didn't mean to. I just
wanted to surprise you.
This is Reinhardt's last free day,
you must make use of that.
I wanted to invite you to the
Immensee estate this afternoon.
- Are you coming?
- Oh.. no, we won't be able to.
I see... well.
Don't be upset Erich, but later,
after Reinhardt is off to the city,
I will have enough time
to come to Immensee.
This afternoon we'll drive past the
lake once more, with Reinhardt's dad
...towards Rehwiese, you know,
the road we always took.
Now kids, you can tell me
whatever you like...
If one wants to enjoy a ride like
this, one shouldn't be in a car.
Of course, a car is nice when
one needs to get somewhere fast
but over here, one should
take time, and look around.
Mr. Torsten, being a violin maker
and Bach friend, you aren't modern.
You rather belong to the old...
I mean to the good old times.
Don't say that, Mrs. Uhl,
I'm quite modern already,
at least I hope so. But...
the haste, you know,
the haste doesn't suit me.
The young people of today
have found a quite distinct,
sometimes rather formal
word for "tempo."
I prefer the word "diligence."
Ah father, one with
a one hundred horse power
gets you much farther
than this carriage.
Yes of course, farther,
but not closer.
You know... not close enough...
so you can have the leaves
of the trees you love
sliding through your fingers,
when one drives by...
Ah, Reinhardt wants to go to
China, or Honolulu, or wherever...
Hear, Reinhardt?
She doesn't agree at all.
But Elisabeth..
people aren't all the same!
One likes to stay in the homeland,
and the other wants to see the world!
Exactly!
Leave it, dear Elisabeth,
he will soon learn otherwise.
I think Elisabeth is more like us,
a homely girl.
Isn't that true, Elisabeth?
I don't know what I am.
Dad, with all due respect
to your coach, but I'm quite glad
we can sit on the meadow
and have a coffee for now.
Where are you going?
We're already at the Rehwiese.
Yes, but shouldn't we
go down to the lake?
No please, it's too humid down there.
One's not getting younger.
Of course. Well then, let's
stay up here where it's dry.
Stop it!
You know I don't like this.
There's climbing plants
underwater all over the place.
It's creeping me out when
you're away for so long.
"Away for long"? You'll soon
have to get used to that.
Come, let's swim
to that drift wood.
Actually, it isn't very nice of us
to swim right in front
of the Immensee estate.
Why not?
If Erich sees us
he'll be sad.
- Don't turn the log around!
- Scaredy cat!
Ah, scaredy cat...
I can't come to the afternoon tea
with my hair all wet.
By the way, we have to go back.
Just leave the old folks
amongst each other.
We're going to swim
into the wide world,
and the first stop
will be water lily island.
No, not  to the water lilies!
I don't want to. They wrap
around one's legs and cling on.
Goodbye!
Don't swim towards
the water lilies!
Do you worry about me?
That's sweet of you. Water lilies
are your favorites, I know,
and today is our last day.
If you don't return immediately
I will swim back.
I will join the others by myself.
Come back already!
Not without a water lily!
Shame on you!
You're mean.
What stupidity!
Stubborn rascal...
Dammit...
I can't... get on...
Yes... they're holding me...
The twines are holding me...
I'm sorry Elisabeth, but I'm
coming without water lily.
Well, Erich,
what are you looking at?
Just at the Rehwiese over there.
What's there to see?
Not much, Dad.
Just Reinhardt and Elizabeth,
celebrating farewell.
And you're not there?
Guess they don't want me there.
They want to be alone.
You're watching them like
knight Toggenburg...
I wouldn't look out for one
who doesn't want me.
One needs to stay proud.
Won't be long till I finally
can put all this behind me...
...then I will be
pushing up the daisies.
- But Dad, sometimes you're...
- Well should I cry?
And then you'll be master
of the Immensee estate.
- Stay proud, Erich.
- But Dad, why talk about dying?
- It is not the time yet.
- Unfortunately it is.
- I really don't want to leave this
beautiful earth.     - But Daddy...
What's the saying again?
People are getting older,
legs are getting colder,
after dying life is dust,
young ones can, old ones must.
I'm angry.
Don't be angry Elisabeth.
We don't have time for that today.
Same time tomorrow I will be
in Hamburg, at the conservatory.
Life begins tomorrow!
Life begins tomorrow...
without me.
I'll take you to the train station.
No Elisabeth, little girls should
still be in bed that early.
I can't stand farewells
at train stations.
Where father, mother and brothers
stand there with their handkerchiefs,
and waving and all that,
"Please write a postcard!",
you know all that...
that's not for me.
We'll say each other
goodbye on our own.
We will say each other
"see you again..."
...don't we?
Don't cry...
you don't have to cry, Elisabeth.
I may, just a little bit...
It eases it.
Thinking that you won't
wake me up tomorrow morning
as always, with your whistle...
As of tomorrow someone
else will do that, Elisabeth.
See, you're already awake, too.
A bird like that doesn't
belong into the bedroom.
His screaming
wakes up everybody.
Don't be sad Elisabeth,
nothing against that bird,
but he has to
go down to the living room.
You don't have to hide Elisabeth,
I know what's the matter.
But believe me,
it is good he's gone.
See, one should not
commit oneself too early.
You don't know much
of the world and of life yet,
and perhaps something
better is awaiting you.
I don't want anything better.
There's nothing better than Reinhardt.
Yes... one always
thinks that.
But believe your mother, such
a separation has its good sides.
First wait what Reinhardt will think
of it when he's back for holidays.
He will come - for Christmas,
or the summer holidays...?
No...
No? He won't come?
But yes... he will come, earlier.
He promised me
he will come on his birthday.
Check...
What is it?
I see my father before me.
He didn't think sadly about dying.
He always looked at me
so... peculiar lately.
Did he actually like me?
I think so.
He just didn't like me looking out
for you all the time, Elisabeth.
Did Reinhardt write to you?
He wants to come
for his birthday.
When we're apart...
and I live without you...
just be content...
you are my other self.
Elisabeth...
Go, oh winds,
and deliver this kiss...
to the beautiful child far away,
who has to wait for me.
Elisabeth...
Kiss her cheeks, is what
my desire tells me...
deliver her my message...
...I will always remain faithful.
Elisabeth...
You are really moving me.
You're only mistaken on the date.
My birthday is tomorrow.
In two minutes it will be "tomorrow".
Good heavens, it's already midnight?
But you are making everyone
rebellious here with your singing.
Don't worry Mr. Torsten. Where people
sing so beautifully no one complains.
And we talked to the porter before.
It was meant to be a surprise.
I thank you.
But I have nothing to offer you now.
That's what we expected. Max!
It's about time.
Heavens - don't miss out on the time!
On your birthday today...
we,  your classmates...
...congratulate you most sincerely .
How sweet you sung.
But tell me, where
did you get the score?
The professor gave it to us.
He used your song as an example!
- See?
- Gosh!
Enough serious talking. It's time to
get terribly drunk, to Elisabeth!
Burnt punch...
...mixed with piquant conversations
about art and love...
that's what I like.
Flames go up!
By the way...
...who, actually, is this Elisabeth?
Please stop about Elisabeth.
You see, he doesn't really like it.
Doesn't mean you have to go now.
I want to put at least
a bath robe on.
Maybe you're so friendly
to let off steam in my absence.
Children, I know who Elisabeth is.
Here, "only to be
opened on birthday."
The cute hostess wanted to give it
tomorrow, but I said today is the day.
Sender: Elisabeth, or rather
Elisabeth Uhl, Immensee.
- But Werner...   - Play a little
louder, so he won't hear us!
Wait...
"Twelve Songs to Elisabeth"...?
- What?
- That's hot...
Even twelve at once?
Cheaper by the Dozen?
"The Wooden Bench at the Lake",
"Elisabeth, a Bullfinch and I",
"When I tried to break the Water Lily"
Rosie, Rosie, Rosie white,
Rosie on the water...
I told you this is hot stuff.
Kids, don't lose your manners,
that's indiscreet. Put it back!
Why indiscrete?
These aren't love letters...
Maybe they are?
Why?
- No need to become jealous, Jesta.
- Keep your hands off.
What a pity.
Play.
Should these songs, love, as they fleet,
Chance again to reach thy hand,
- Give me the album!
- Noooo!
Come 'ere...
Now it's getting hot!
But Reinhardt, take
it good-humouredly!
Damn it, you shouldn't
bite you beast!
Say... is this a fight,
or a love scene?
I think they both take it differently.
For Jesta at least it's a love scene.
But gentlemen, you are
embarrassing me too much.
Mr. Torsten...!
- Let go of the album!
- No!
Hot stuff...!
Stop being silly!
Give me the book!
I think the fun
is getting out of hand.
I think so too.
- Here... better open your package.
- What?
The birthday child has
his solo party next door...
Jesta's crying...
...a birthday celebration
full of atmosphere.
But we won't let our
good mood get disturbed.
Burnt punch...
for everyone!
To our son
To Reinhardt
Dear Reinhardt!
The water lily on the cake
shows you that I assisted
your mother with baking.
Think of me when you're eating it.
Think of our day of farewell.
It is very lonesome here without you.
Why didn't you write me?
The fact that we had to send you
the package shows me
that I must not count on you
to come as you promised.
Greetings, with all my heart
Your Elisabeth.
It is sad, yes...
but don't be sinful,
after all it's just a bird.
No.
It is more.
Anyway, it has to leave.
It's unreasonable.
Furthermore, how's it look like -
we're expecting Erich -
when he comes, and you're still
standing there crying for a dead bird.
But I'm not crying...
Now finally go outside
and bury him.
Or I will do it.
I'm on my way.
Our love's little grave.
She was so sad about the
little bird. She'll be right back.
But I'm happy to have you here
alone with me for a second.
I'll just look for her.
You could do me a
big favor, Mr Jürgens.
I would love to have a picture of
Elisabeth, and you draw so fine...
One could have her
photographed of course...
...but a drawing is more personal -
an artistic adornment for a room.
But sure Mrs. Uhl,
if it gives you pleasure...
I suggest you come over here
once or twice a week.
I'd also appreciate if you'd become
a visiting friend to our house.
That child's too often on her own
in my view.
You mean,
since Reinhardt left.
Oh well you know,
it's only puppy love,
and it's a good thing
you know about it.
But will it be
all right for Elisabeth?
No reason to be modest.
It should be a great joy for her.
You think so?
Now don't hesitate
to speak out, Mr. Jürgens.
And be sure I'll be
a motherly friend to you.
There's not much to say what the
three of us - you, Elisabeth and me -
wouldn't already know.
I'm all by myself down there
at the Immensee estate
since my father passed away.
And I cannot think of any better
partner for my life than Elisabeth.
Is that so?
But I know Reinhardt and Elisabeth
made each other a promise.
I don't think much of it,
to be honest.
Reinhardt's surely a lovely person,
but he is too restless...
...and he certainly
won't make Elisabeth happy.
Reinhardt has no qualities to
built a marriage on.
With me she would have a quiet
happiness, on the Immensee estate.
And no one else in this world
can love her more than I love her.
There she is.
Look, how thoughtful of Erich.
Yes...
I don't understand you, Mama.
Wasn't it right?
Your mother told me you're so sad
about losing the bullfinch, and...
...so I thought it appropriate...
That's very sweet of you Erich, but...
...where's the wooden cage
for my bullfinch?
- Yes, Reinhardt!
- But where is he?
Now where could he be, mother?
Finish off, five o'clock, closing time.
- Now please...
- Wait until they have left.
My boy comes home on his birthday
and doesn't even say Hello to his mom?
Mom, now he's not just your boy
anymore. Some day that's over.
But Papa, I don't get you.
Well it seems so... but it'd be
better for you to understand...
- Even if you don't, it is like that.
- I am apalled.
You're not apalled, you're jealous.
But that's alright, mommy.
Just don't let our boy take notice,
it's his birthday today.
I am so happy you're back now
and that you kept your promise.
But you aren't happy at all.
Something wrong?
I can't stand that yellow bird.
I also did like
the bullfinch more, but...
mother likes the yellow one better.
That's because
of the golden cage.
The Immensee estate.
It's so sad that you have to
leave again so soon.
Now Erich should come visit us
twice a week to draw me.
Mother wishes a portrait
of me so much...
I don't like it...
What is it you don't like?
That someone else gets
to know my face so... by heart.
I often complained to your
father about your unfaithfulness.
What are you telling me now?
Your father thinks you now don't have
no more time for such... childishness.
Why haven't you written me?
I have written you. Often...
..but only in the way I can write.
But that's no letter...
"Twelve Songs for Elisabeth"
"To Elisabeth"...
"Elisabeth, a Bullfinch and I"
Beautiful!
Now I have a birthday wish to you.
Will you sing them tonight?
[Dedication to Elisabeth]
Should these songs, love,
as they fleet,
Chance again to reach thy hand,
At the piano take thy seat
Where thy friend was wont to stand!
Sweep with finger bold the string,
Then the book one moment see:
But read not! do nought but sing!
And each page thine own will be!
Ah, what grief the song imparts
With its letters, black on white,
That, when breath'd by thee,
our hearts
Now can break and now delight!
Nice.
This is for the singer, Elisabeth.
And who is the composer
of the the song?
Ah father, your old organ
doesn't have the range it takes...
At our conservatory
it sounded much better.
Don't be so cheeky, boy.
What was good enough for Johann
Sebastian will be good for you too.
Don't you think so? But you made
that quite nicely! Show it to me...
- What?
- Show me, the sheet music.
These are mine.
I don't want to take them away.
I only want to take a look.
Or should I not
see what's in it?
Yes, but...
I see!
Oh I see.
Well...
And now you think
they belong to you alone?
Well, these are...
- These are Reinhardt's letters to...
- To you, Elisabeth?
Yes.
And...
One doesn't want
anyone else reading it.
I understand that.
Now, put away
your private correspondence...
...and come sit with me.
Elisabeth's mom and Erich
will be there soon too.
Take your time.
How sweet of you, to want my
songs for yourself alone.
Never shall anyone
else have them.
They're our's alone.
When we will be sitting at
the table with the others...
...it will feel almost as if
you're already gone again.
This time I will
bring you to the station.
One more time the two of
us together...
tomorrow morning.
I want to tell you something.
Something important. Our very
future will depend on it, but...
Don't stop. It strikes six o'clock
already. You will be late.
We won't see each
other for a long time.
Will you love me as much as
you do now when I will be back?
- Sure...
- Yes?
- I defended you.
- Me?
Against whom did you need to?
Against my mother.
We talked about you
last night for a long time.
- She said you've changed.
- What?
She thinks, not like
you were before.
You think so too?
No...
Come, we have to go now.
- There's your train!   - So what...
It will hold on for a while.
I wanted to tell you something.
Something very important,
I mean...
...that's important
for our whole life.
I already know it
from your songs!
Yes, you know it
and you should know, but...
one has to say it as well.
And that's what I want,
but only when I have finished.
Only when I have advanced,
when I know where all this leads to.
When I can face your mother
and tell her: I am somebody.
I want to take Elisabeth with me,
out there into the world.
- Ah...?
- Yes...
See, then we won't have to part
at the station.
Then you will come along.
All aboard!
Are you looking forward to that?
Wait, see me at the window.
Oh, I thank you, Elisabeth.
Farewell, Elisabeth.
Farewell, Reinhardt!
In two years!
[To my dear Reinhardt
faithfully, Elisabeth]
Three years went by...
Do you believe it now?
Come...
You don't have think
of the worst, Miss Uhl.
There's not much
more to think.
Well they're artists, and somewhat
more free in how they conceive this.
And I always wondered
why he doesn't write me.
It won't be as bad
as it looks like.
See, yesterday they had
a shindig, as they call it...
...a large party, many people,
it got late, and so she stayed over.
- Not nice.
- No.
If you knew what troubles I already had
with other lodgers about this foolery.
But he won't become reasonable.
"Philistines" is what he says then...
...though he's such a nice person.
It's all the fault of those darned
females who all run after him.
No wonder, he is a handsome boy.
- Is it often like this?
- What?
Don't ask me,
I'm so bad at telling lies.
It's alright.
Where is he now?
He is rehearsing in the conservatory.
For his final exams.
I see...
I want to ask you a favor.
Don't tell Mr. Torsten that I was here.
But... are you leaving
without seeing him?
Of course.
The board of trustees of the
conservatory grants Reinhardt Torsten
after completing his three year studies
the predicate Master Student.
As reward for the best composition, he
will be the first out of three laureates
who are also amongst us,
in acknowledgment
of his special talents
who will be awarded a scholarship
for the conductor's academy in Rome.
Congratulations!
At your age, my dear son
almost every year
still has its own face,
because youth doesn't
let itself be impoverished.
Many a thing has
changed over here, too,
what will probably hurt you
if I understood you well.
But Dad, do you have to tell him
now, after he got his scholarship?
He needs to know.
Imagine him coming home and
learning it from someone else...
Elisabeth would've written him.
But Mama, how do you
think this should go?
Of course Elisabeth did not write him.
Leave it to me, I know what to do.
Yesterday Erich and Elisabeth
had their wedding.
He asked her twice
before, to no avail...
since he became head of the
Immensee estate after his father's died.
As much as I can imagine how much
your work must have captivated you,
you nevertheless shouldn't have
forgotten about Elisabeth entirely.
I'm very proud of the
high award you have received...
Your loving father.
At the Elbe I did write my songs.
Flow, oh songs
I loved so well...
...into the ocean of oblivion.
No enraptured youth
will ever sing you now...
...nor maiden in the time of bloom...
You were the songs
that witnessed of my love...
...but now she holds my
faithfulness to scorn.
You were written on the water...
...now flow away
as the water flows.
How far is it to Immensee?
Not far, five minutes left.
Then I will take
down your suitcase.
Does anyone have an envelope?
Yes.
Want a sheet too?
No!
- What's that about?
- Tcha...
I've made up my mind...
...I will travel on with you.
Gentlemen, now that's hot stuff...
Yesterday you drove us mad, we begged
you to go straight to Italy with us...
...and now suddenly not?
No...!
To Mrs. Elisabeth
...Jürgens
Hey boy... come here.
Here's two mark.
Take this letter, put a stamp on it,
and put it into the mailbox.
- You can keep the change.
- Thank you!
Thank God, we made it,
we're rolling on.
Sit down, leave the window
down, don't be so curious.
Perhaps he did got off.
Nonsense. Suitcase, hat,
and jacket are still here.
Perhaps he's running there,
shouting to drop him his stuff.
I wouldn't put it past him!
Outrageous.
What buildings!
All built with a... zeal of faith.
- We don't have that anymore.
- Why not?
We have our own kind of faith, Werner.
You are right.
I believe in Bach...
...Beethoven...
...in the Ninth,
in the 'Song To Joy'.
And in that tiny bit
that God gave me.
You sang heavenly today.
Today you sang divinely.
My dearest,
my dear blonde boy...
Why didn't you come to my
dressing room this evening?
Why didn't you come
to my dressing room?
It was full of flowers.
- Lots of flowers.
- Yes.
I love you very much. Every hour
without you seems a lost hour to me.
But it's better if you
learn Italian, you know.
The language of my fatherland, and
above all of my heart... understand?
- Yes, yes...
- "Yes yes..."
Not understand.
I wanted to be proud for you.
You should have with
nessed my triumph.
- "witnessed".
- witnessed...
And how they all love me -
much more than you do!
Did you know it?
She really wanted it.
I didn't want to deny...
Your song appears
entirely changed!
It is much more Italian now.
That's no longer you,
that's Verdi!
That she would change it so much,
she didn't tell me anything about it.
That's pretty steep.
But the woman sings fabulous.
But this is not my song anymore.
This is not Elisabeth.
No... that's Loretta.
What's the matter with you?
You seem so nervous.
Nothing so fortunate how I want
to see you, when you're with me.
Not really nervous, just...
if you only had told me earlier
we'd have dinner together.
Earlier?
I wanted to surprise you.
You succeeded in that...
It's... too bad,
I already am meeting some
friends at a German restaurant.
Where are you appointed?
Which restaurant?
Well, at the German restaurant,
near the Spanish Steps...
What a joyful night.
Nicer than in a German restaurant...
The Italian night, the Italian sky.
You are my soul.
I love you.
Yes...
The stars here are lower in the sky.
One thinks one could grasp them.
Venus...
Yes...
Venus... is so beautiful.
So close...
It's hard to believe this is the same
Venus as the one in Germany.
Is not the same. Is another Venus.
Is the star of love.
Well?
Better put on a hood,
or don't come too close.
The bees are angry today,
buckwheat is flowering.
The bees won't do me no harm.
Wherever you are is paradise, no?
You are right. Here the lion
lays down with the lamb.
Well, that's not what I meant.
Something is depressing
me here in my peace.
What is it, Erich?
Whether you... I mean... whether
you are as happy as I am?
But Erich...
Why do you ask this?
See, loosely speaking... You are
doing the household all day long...
...then you give me that
little sisterly glance...
- Still, I often wonder...
- What do you wonder about?
Now what is it?
I want to answer you.
Look, up on the wheel,
some bird stood there yesterday
on one leg, and he pondered
starting to build here.
You're a foreign bird
anyway, I thought...
and then he reconsidered
and moved on,
the long stilted Egyptian.
I ordered the wheel
up there myself.
One day he will stay, if not
this year then the next one.
Mr. Jürgens, I braced it.
I must go to the factory,
are you coming?
Go without me and come back soon.
I've got hands full of work.
I'd expected everything,
but not that...
- Where do you come from?
- I've been here for three days.
What? And you haven't been to
Immensee yet, you unfaithful one?
I'm on my way to you now.
What a fortunate day,
what a joy.
It's been more than three years, no?
You've become a little slender.
- Is it really you?
- Of course, it's you too!
- It's only you who changed.
- Do I?
You look much
more cheerful now.
Oh, I see...
...well...
But we will still stay
good friends, no?
Eh.... and Elisabeth will
be glad, for heaven's sake...
We sold the house... Reinhardt.
My mother lives with us now.
The bench...
I think we've seen
enough photos now.
I think so too.
We've told enough about ourselves -
you don't tell anything about yourself!
Haven't you seen anything, in Italy?!
I could tell you a lot about Italy...
...but we'd need
a whole evening for that.
I think we have to postpone
this for some other time.
I believe I already
stretched my visit quite a bit.
At home they must be waiting
for me for dinner.
But you're not about
to leave already?
That's out of the question!
Elisabeth, say something!
We didn't even
have a toast on his visit.
I will dish you up something
you surely haven't drunk before.
Right, Elisabeth?
Here, try it. That is, first you
have to take a sniff.
Well, you world wandering soul
who nibbled at all wells, what is it?
- A liqueur...
- Yes, but which one, what brand?
I'm no expert... a good
old Benedictine I'd think.
Hear this Elisabeth? Reinhardt
knows what he's talking about.
- Cheers.
Now I will tell you
what you just drank.
- A real Jürgens.    - Jürgens?
- Yes, a real Erich Jürgens.
- Another one?
- No thanks.
Where the old barn used to be,
we're building our new liquor factory.
We already installed
a small distillery.
These are the first tests.
I tell you this good drop has a future,
we will become well-known.
Don't think you're the only
one to become famous.
How eloquent you are,
I haven't known you like this.
Well, in the meantime I hit
the jackpot, but you know that.
How long do you want
to stay at Immensee?
My first concert contracts
start not until fall.
Until then you
will have to bear me...
And until then you're on vacation?
That's great.
No vacation... I have to work!
But for that there's no place better
than here with us!
What nonsense to squat
down there in the crowded town.
Move up here. We will set up the
old surveyors house in the garden,
we'll bring down the piano, you
may compose as much as you like!
No one will bother you.
Very kind of you Erich, but my
parents are around as well.
They can come up here
as often as they want.
See, that's a great idea!
Elisabeth, you say nothing. Now
invite him and ask him to stay with us.
As you think, Erich...
Reinhardt, if you want to stay
with us we would be very happy.
Water lilies... do you remember?
Why do you look
at the water all the time?
Look at me for once.
Our silence is dangerous,
don't you think so too?
These are the bells of Marien, no?
How clear they sound today...
...your wedding bells.
Why did you do this?
Don't ask.
Why don't you knock
before coming in?
I did, but you did not hear.
You were so immersed in
our letters and in the picture?
That image of course doesn't
belong in your album.
Neither does the bullfinch.
Doesn't fit in the golden cage.
To whom belongs my image now?
- I don't know.
- Where's Erich?
- In town.   - And we're
all on our own now, like before?
He has courage...
Can he be so assured, Elisabeth?
We must not do this anymore.
What were you looking for
in my letters?
- I just saw how few they are.
- But what were you looking for?
Our youth.
Not also our love?
- Our youth.
- They are the same.
"In faithfulness, Elisabeth"
Did you want to give me
back the picture?
No.
Over our heads, in the
woodwork of the new building
today the ribbons are crowning
the topping-out ceremony.
And we, who erected these walls...
want today - revered constructor
and revered constructoresse...
...following an old tradition,
recite the topping out speech.
Let me put this down.
Just as it's standing here
now in miniature,
it will once stand there
large and completed -
You may sit down again.
...and it will tower high over the
Immensee as a sign of diligence...
...and development, by giving
to the holy fruits of your fields...
...a new purpose -
I mean the potatoes.
You acknowledged the spirituality
of this fruit! Spirit!
And it's spirit that counts!
And once we get
the machines in here...
...then it's not only a matter of
squeezing the spirit out of the potato...
...no - it will be your duty to carry
out the fruits of our labor...
... in barrels and bottles,
as the machines' real engine.
And, and, very important,
if I may say so...
in refined condition
in the form of brandy!
Bravo!
Also as an engine
for happy people in happy hours!
Bravo!
What do you say about Elisabeth?
I haven't seen her so lively before.
Don't you dance, Erich?
No. I can't dance.
I never danced in my life.
Anything wrong, Erich?
What? ... Why?
No.
I know what I'm doing, Mama.
What are you doing?
See, so lively,
I never can be like that.
Reinhardt is an artist.
He can express his joy very well.
And Elisabeth...
...it seems to suit her well.
So why did you invite him?
- Am I not allowed to?
- Sure, of course.
- Of course...
- See, Mama...
I also think so.
Elisabeth is more beautiful
when she is happy like that.
All people are more beautiful
when they're happy...!
I'm getting dizzy.
Too much turmoil for me here,
I have to prepare some things...
...if we want to go
over there afterwards...
That's alright mama.
You're running away
from me Elisabeth?
I got too warm from dancing.
I'm afraid of getting a cold.
But it's so warm, Elisabeth.
Yes... that's why.
Now, what are you then?
Warm or cold?
- I don't know.   - I think
you don't know lots of things.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Why do you want to go home suddenly?
The others already went ahead.
They'll be waiting!
Let them wait - doesn't matter!
Are you afraid of...
being alone with me?
- You should know if I should be
afraid!    - Oh yes... I do know that.
When I just held you in my arms while
dancing, it all was just like then.
- You must not think of that.
- I have to think of it!
- Let me go  - You think of it too!
- No!
Yes you do. You had wished
for this dance to never end.
It must have an end, Reinhardt.
- Why, Elisabeth?
- Oh, Reinhardt.
Elisabeth, if I would ask you...
Elisabeth, do you
want to come with me?
Out into the world,
just as you once promised me.
I have a right to ask you this.
What would your answer be?
Mother is calling!
Is this how you wanted it?
He always stood between us.
Even when he wasn't here.
Isn't it so?
See...
One cannot enforce
one's own happiness.
But it's not about my happiness...
it's all about yours.
In the last few days I've seen lights
shining in your eyes for the first time.
Because of Reinhardt.
I let you go, Elisabeth.
You can do that?
You can really do that?
Because I love you...
...I want your happiness.
Watching the bees?
Yes... I enjoy it, seeing how...
...they come and go... the hive-bees
of Immensee. [ lit. Bees' Lake ]
There on the lime tree,
there's an entire swarm.
Yes it is time to swarm.
High time of  the bees...
Now the struggle
for the queen begins.
The one who flies highest with her,
the strongest, will conquer her.
To be free for the strongest, that's
the right of the hive-bee queen.
See?
Nature is just!
Can't you be clear about
what you want to say?
Not anymore.
I am not allowed anymore.
- Why didn't you take the yellow coach?
- Madam prefers the black one.
I'm going to town alone.
Shouldn't I ask Madam if
there's anything to do?    - No!
...whether there's anything to get
from the butcher or the grocer?
Nevermind, I'll do it myself.
You can stay here.
I'll be back home
in the evening.
I am free.
Erich let me go, last night.
Forever.
Do you know what you just said?
Oh yes...
Then... you are my Elisabeth?
No.
He is the stronger one.
Now I know.
You want to sacrifice yourself?
Your happiness? Your life?
Me?
Your love?
- But it's not about Jesta.
- But apparently it was...
...at least for you.
Never for me.
- Never?
- Never!
I see...
If I had known that
at that time, then...
What then?
What would have been
if you had known it back then?
Then...
it would have made me
very ... happy, back then.
But Reinhardt, do you think
that in these circles,
among these people, in this kind of
freedom, I could have been living?
I don't want to rise above them,
it all may be very nice, but...
that's not my world!
Do you think I could have lived up
to what you experienced in Italy?
See? I am right, isn't it?
I was on my way home, back then...
...I was on the train coming
from Hamburg...
I was so embarrassed when people
looked at me me because I was crying.
I was saying farewell
to you, Reinhardt.
I was saying goodbye
to what was dearest to me.
See, I realized in everything
that we don't belong together...
that our roads through life
don't match.
See, you belong out into the world.
You have to be in Hamburg today...
...and in Rome tomorrow, and
after that in Athens, or wherever...
...and I...
And you?
I became... rooted... here.
Rooted... here...
I see.
And now?
Yes...
Now I love Erich.
When he let me go yesterday,
letting me go because
he loves me, for you...
I knew that I belong to him,
indissoluble, forever.
And that's why we
have to say farewell.
I'm not sleeping, Elisabeth.
Forgive me.
I love you, Erich.
Do you believe me?
I believe everything you say.
But you're crying.
Even happiness has its tears.
"To my dear Reinhardt -
faithfully, Elisabeth"
No, it is not appropriate
to take the picture back.
But yes, Reinhardt.
We were faithful, both of us...
...you to your work, to the
star that was guiding you...
...to the whole world
you belong to.
And I... to my small world,
where I became rooted in...
...and to my duties that I accepted
since Erich passed away...
...to conserve and expand what
he started to build at Immensee.
So let us remain
faithful, both of us,
even if we don't hear from
each other for years...
...and when the oceans and
continents separate us.
Faithful to our youth,
faithful to ourselves.
I will always remain faithful...
Elisabeth...
End
Subtitles: mysteriousmountain
and Kurosuke for KG.