Subtitles provided by MBC
[Episode 126]
Yes, Sire?
Is it true you put Pisang
in Kwanghae's medicine?
Yes, Sire.
You are relieved of duty.
There was no other option at this point.
Understand that I did
what I did to save him.
Sire, I believe we can trust him.
Your thoughts?
It's not that I don't trust Doctor Heo.
But I fear for the Crown Prince
in his current condition.
Sire, please allow me
to continue treating him.
Doctor, he is getting worse.
Please administer
herbs to neutralize the Pisang.
Doctor, if His Highness dies...
...you will be framed for murder.
We will give him
the same medicine in an hour.
Doctor.
How long? We have to stop him now.
We'll trust him. It's our only choice now.
He's working with
Prince Yeong-chang's side.
How can we trust him?
You saw the poison with your own eyes.
Any improvement?
We have to give it time.
Give it time?
Until you kill him, you mean?
Enough.
He's gotten worse since
the treatment started.
He's getting better.
Don't be fooled by the current symptoms.
The Pisang is working on the malaria.
The changes in temperature indicate
his body is fighting the disease.
Now leave treatment to the professionals.
Well, well, what's all the yelling about?
Something you want?
Something? The Crown Prince is ill.
As loyal subjects
we're naturally concerned.
We heard you yelling.
May we see His Highness for ourselves?
What?
No one may see him.
Oh?
He must be worse than we heard.
If you'll excuse me.
You have a grave responsibility.
We trust you are doing all you can.
Sir.
I hope he's better soon.
Huh? Pisang?
Poison in medicine? Are you kidding?
I just did what I was told.
How is the Crown Prince?
Don't breathe a word of this.
He's gotten worse.
No...
What about Jun?
If the Prince dies...
...he and I are as good as dead.
I can't sleep or nothin'.
There you are!
I've been looking all over for you.
Why? What is it?
A word. Let's take a walk.
- To where?
- Wherever.
Honey-sweetness. Sweetie-honey.
He's here, I brought him.
Oh, it's been forever.
You know my son-in-law?
Well, bow.
Sir.
Great, great. Hey, On-nyeon.
Listen.
Have you heard of another way
into the royal pharmacy?
Another way? Like sneaking in?
No, no, that that.
If Doctor Heo nominates him,
he can be a doctor too.
I've heard of that happening.
But it's for extremely gifted doctors.
Your son-in-law is only good
at gambling and women.
Only?
He's Lord Gambler, Lord Letch.
Are you any good at doctoring at all?
I give great massages.
Massages?
Is that good to know?
Moron. Pressure points are important.
It might just be enough.
Where did you learn it?
From the masters at Unbong Temple.
Is that a fact?
All right. You can show me.
This way.
- Right.
- Good good.
Excellent.
Use my body as you see fit.
If you please.
Oh, right.
Your coloring indicates poor blood flow.
I'll take care of that.
If I may?
- First lower your head.
- And my arms.
Then twist.
Now lower your head again.
And again.
And once more.
Let go!
Get off!
A doctor? Doctor THIS!
Nomination? Dream on!
Wait...
Hong-choon, my arm is broke...
Wait.
You're a stranger to me!
Never call me Father again!
Not all poisons are harmful.
Nor are all herbs beneficial.
Used correctly, poisons can cure.
Morning glory seeds are
not toxic in themselves.
But they can induce abortion.
Correct. Very well said.
So the Pisang Doctor Heo used
may actually help the Prince?
How did you hear about that?
From the herbalists.
It's the nature of the palace.
He's not getting better,
if it's the Pisang...
That's enough.
Watch your mouth.
Now listen to me.
Not another word about the Prince's
deterioration. Understood?
Ma'am.
How is he?
It's too early to tell.
This was unwise.
It will be fine.
Just tend to your duties.
Doctor.
Yes?
Minister Jeong wants a word.
What was that?
You know exactly what.
We know why you put
Pisang in his medicine.
If this works out,
we'll take care of you, don't you worry.
What are you saying?
You call yourselves loyal ministers?
The Pisang isn't poison, it's medicine.
I'll help him, whatever it takes.
If he does recover,
we're back where we started.
My lord.
There's one chance left.
Doctor Heo is still giving him the Pisang.
If we add a little more, it won't be
medicine, it will be poison.
The Crown Prince will die of poison.
And Doctor Heo will pay for it.
Your Highness.
Look after my boys.
Not as their doctor.
But as a friend, a guardian.
Your Highness.
Stay with us.
I know how the Pisang has
increased the pain.
But you can beat it.
Beat it and get better.
You trusted me, believed in me.
And I believe in you.
I know you can fight the pain...
...and beat this.
Your Highness.
Just a little longer.
A little longer.
Your Highness.
Is he improving?
We'll know in a day or two.
Something has come up
and I have to go.
I'm sorry.
No. You go on.
Yes, sir.
Who are you?
What is this?
Come along quietly.
Why...? Let go...!
Awake?
Where am I?
Why am I here?
I'll keep it short.
We have your parents.
Do as we say or they're dead.
What do you want?
Sir, it's me.
Come in.
- Well?
- We're ready.
Ma'am, it's Dol-swe.
- Come in.
- Yes'm.
Well? Did you find out?
Yes'm. His Highness
still hasn't recovered.
And Jun?
He's spent three nights by his side.
He's under such a strain.
It's all anyone is talking about.
Using Pisang as medicine...?
Try not to worry.
He knows what he's doing.
Quite right, quite right.
Ma'am.
Are you ill?
No.
Your color is off.
It's nothing.
Well?
Did you add more Pisang?
Did you?
I couldn't.
What?
Keep this up and I'll go to the police.
They're your parents. Suit yourself.
Time is short. Now do it.
All done.
Thank you.
Doctor Yu will be here in a minute.
Oops, um, excuse me.
Of course.
Thanks.
Ugh, my tummy...
Did she add more Pisang?
Not that I saw, sir.
Well then. You'll have to do it.
M-my lord.
I can't get near it.
Silence.
Do it or die. Whatever it takes.
Where's the pharmacist?
He hasn't been home in days.
I'm helping out.
Is it ready?
Yes, Doctor.
The Crown Prince's medicine?
Doctor Yu took it.
Your Highness.
You're awake?
How am I?
The fever broke.
Like you said.
The medicine did the trick.
Your Highness.
What is it?
His Highness is awake.
Doctor.
I heard he was awake.
Yes. He's resting now.
How is he?
The malaria broke.
You've done well. Thank you.
And his medicine?
Do we keep administering it?
Just to be sure?
Your recovery may be difficult.
His Majesty is ill.
If the King dies, you may die with him.
How dare you?
I said move.
My lord!