Tbilisi - Georgia, 1992
Georgians have always been warlike.
Many keep a sword in the house.
Still.
All Georgians should have a weapon.
But not to rob people.
Hello.
I also copied it.
- Someone knocked.
Did you bring it?
What does he write?
Come on, tell.
- Hold on.
Take your leg away.
- Keep on walking.
No, I was talking to my sister.
Are they nice?
- Taste this.
What took you so long?
Are you already in the queue?
- Yes, come quickly.
Hey, don't jump the queue.
Are you talking to me?
- Yes.
You think I'm stupid?
Say something about it, people.
They are jumping the queue.
Starting tomorrow, I'm going to keep order here.
Take it easy, ma'am. No one is jumping the queue.
She was already here.
What do you mean, she was already here?
She stood there and I was here.
I have seen her, but not you.
Make a little space.
I do not care. In line.
Come on with the bread.
No jumping the queue.
Let that woman with that child pass.
What took you?
We're starving.
I'm here now, aren't I?
You certainly hung out with Eka
on the street.
Shoes off.
What do we eat?
Again beans?
Aren't you fed up with beans yet?
What's wrong with the electricity?
- Call your brother.
Did you not hear me?
Call your brother.
Can I just catch my breath?
Catch your breath...
You must be very tired.
Gio!
Come inside.
Eka, how are you?
You don't talk to me?
- Leave me alone, Kopla.
You can't answer politely?
Get lost. No one says anything to you.
Got that?
What a big mouth.
Hey, you.
Break off a piece. We are hungry.
Give him a piece of bread.
Here. Take it.
Hello, Eka.
- People are jealous so easily.
Do you know what they blazon abroad about me?
What do you want?
- How can you breathe here?
That's fine.
- You know what I'm gonna do to her?
I will help you.
I'll kill the neighbor.
What do you mean, do I wear tight clothes?
I bought bread.
- No, thank you.
Close the door. For the smoke.
Sorry...
Would you like some water?
And you? Water?
Water?
- No, thank you.
What's wrong? Why is no one saying anything?
Did I do something wrong?
I don't get it.
If you're drunk,
I'm not talking to you.
Are you serious?
Don't you love me?
Your mother does not love me anymore.
Fuck off.
What are you doing?
Fantastic. Well done.
Bastard.
- What are you doing? Come here.
Let me go.
- Come here, bitch.
My God.
-Always the same. Shut up.
I won't shut up
and I'm not stopping.
Look at him.
Go wash your hands.
Stop it.
- Wash your hands.
Leave me alone.
- You want a slap?
Mind your own business.
- What a big mouth.
You're dirty.
- Just let him.
He only ​​tastes his food
when there is dirt inside.
Go wash your own hands.
Idiot.
- You're an idiot yourself.
Do you know how many goals
I made, Natela?
A lot.
Do you know?
What do we care?
Then I couldn't care less either.
Listen to that.
They'll end up killing each other.
What happened?
- Get out.
Oh no, What's wrong?
My God.
My wine... But why?
This is no ordinary wine.
What have you done?
Wine gone, and my carafe broken.
It's impossible to live with you.
You guys are crazy.
I can't take it anymore.
Go help your grandmother.
Sit down.
Stop.
Open your notebook.
Silence.
Silence, I said.
- But I...
Shut up.
I'm sorry.
Shanshiashvili graces us with her presence.
A little late, huh?
- I'm sorry, ma'am.
Why are you late? Did you have to
comb your hair or iron your uniform?
Silence.
Last night my father came back from
Sukhumi.
This morning we waved him goodbye.
That's why I'm late.
Your father must have brought presents .
What did you get?
Tell me.
Who knows why these people go to Abkhazia?
And why so many villains
are involved in that war?
That's not true.
- Shut up. And don't tell nonsense.
Excuse me, ma'am?
- Come in. Sit down, you.
Grab your notebook. So tell me?
Can Zaridze come with me for five minutes?
Why?
- Her mother is downstairs.
Zaridze, you can come.
Very kind of you.
- Never mind.
Come back immediately.
Wait .
She is probably telling
stupid things also to herself.
Ketino is worse.
- Absolutely.
See you later.
-You get your notebook back tomorrow.
Give me.
Do the flowers come from Kote, do you think?
- Who else?
What would it mean?
- He likes you.
As if you didn't know already .
- Come on, stop it.
It's ok. Come.
You okay, Natia?
Didn't you like the flowers?
Where are you going?
- None of your business.
Are you coming along for a ride?
- Joker.
I kick the others out
to make space for you.
Okay, guys?
Very nice, but no thanks.
Are you okay?
- Yes. And you?
Does your brother know?
Are you crazy?
- Have you already heard?
Guess.
- No idea.
Is my dress too short?
- No, it looks good on you.
Anita thinks it's too short.
- Not at all, nonsense.
Manana is leaving her husband.
Manana gets a divorce?
- Her husband kicked her out.
A while ago.
Did you know she wasn't virgin when she married?
I thought she was so proper.
Don't gossip.
- Do not start again.
If only she had told her husband the truth.
No man puts up with something like that.
Why would you conceal it?
You guys are so stupid.
In what time do you live?
Come.
Should we close the place with a big lock?
Bunch of silly virgins.
Stop it.
I'll be up all night walking through your street
I'll wait for you all night
life is so short that you can already see the end
I go home and think of you till the morning
you do not know,
you do not know, sweet darling
how my heart is pounding
how my heart beats for you
I'd want to live right in front of your house
and I'd sit until the early morning under your balcony
life is harsh and unfair
if you have a dream it will always break
Sopo, mother's coming.
Shit.
- Quick.
Hurry.
Clean quickly.
Get rid of the fags.
Throw them out.
- Get rid of the smoke.
Hello, madam.
For the umpteenth time:
don't sit in the window.
Continue playing.
Hey, who do we have here?
How are you?
- What do you think? Now you have forgotten about me...
Where have you gone?
-I'm just there.
But I don't want to bother you,
like the rest.
Come on, I want to talk to you.
Why? You can talk to me right here, not?
I want to give you a present.
-But it's not my birthday.
I know. You come with me?
I'll be late for music lessons.
-Five minutes.
What will you give me?
-Patience.
I'm curious.
- Just wait.
What do you want to do here?
- Look, just come.
Sit down.
What is it?
- Close your eyes.
Oh, come on...
- Please, close them.
Can I open them?
- Not yet. Only when I say so.
Open them.
What is that?
- It's for you.
For me?
Take it.
-Is it real?
Don't be afraid. It's not loaded.
You never know what can happen.
This is to protect yourself.
But don't tell anyone.
I'll show you how to load it.
You pull this and take out that.
I only have one bullet.
I'll get you more.
You put it in here.
Now it's loaded.
- Let me hold it.
Just do'nt shoot.
-Don't worry.
How did you get it?
- What does it matter?
Where will I hide it?
Great.
With this in mind, a cease-fire has been
proclaimed in Tskhinvali.
Won't you be in trouble for missing your lesson?
-I'll say that I was sick.
Or you blame me.
- Then she'll forgive you immediately.
Ofcourse.
How are you doing anyways?
Normal. Maybe I'll go and
live with my uncle in Moscow.
But not for long. I won't leave you alone.
- Yes, yes.
I'll come back to marry you.
All okay?
- Hello, Lado.
Where is your uncle?
- In Moscow.
When is he coming?
- Not yet.
Do you know him well?
- He's friends with my uncle.
Do you know him as well?
- At times he visits our downstairs neighbors.
If he's there, they sing.
-You like him?
Quite.
Do you still go to school?
- Sometimes, sometimes not.
Depends on my mood.
Kote, grab that spare tire.
Quick, we're in a hurry.
Kote?
Kote!
What did you want to show me?
Just wait.
Wait. Where are you going?
Please, Natia.
Where are you going?
You'll see in a moment.
Please, Natia. That's enough.
What did you want me to show me?
Don't move.
I have not seen him since.
He's very busy.
He is doing things with his uncle.
Maybe he is already in Moscow.
What does it mean when someone
gives you something like this?
I think he doesn't want anything
to happen to you...
like someone treating you disrespectful
or hurting you.
I think he really loves you.
I think...
He wants you to stay out of trouble.
Yes, I guess you're right.
Now it's my turn...
Where have you been?
You have to come home when it gets dark.
Leave me alone, Natela.
- Leave you alone? I'll break your bones.
Don't cause any more trouble.
Things are already hard enough.
Just take it easy.
- What do you mean, take it easy?
Gio.
Talk to me normally.
- I do.
Gio, open up.
- It's none of your business.
Just get lost.
- Gio, please open.
You're drunk. You're disgusting.
And I love you.
I wish you were dead,
then at least we would have peace.
What did you say? I'll teach you...
What's wrong, Gio?
What has happened?
- I'll kill that bastard again.
Come on, you know how he is...
Hush.
You are still sitting there? Come on out.
What are you doing?
Why do you keep sneaking through my stuff?
I won't steal anything.
You've read them, huh?
I haven't read anything.
You should be ashamed, reading other people's letters.
What were you doing with this?
You know that I am keeping those.
What exactly were you looking for?
I'm talking to you.
I was looking for an address.
I wanted to send dad a letter.
Here you go.
I'm hungry.
Don't we have anything to eat?
We'll find something.
You should have seen what happened last time.
My father was drunk and acted like an idiot.
He smashed a carafe of wine.
Why?
I couldn't care if he would die tomorrow.
-You shouldn't say that.
Really.
- But he's your father.
I couldn't care less.
I don't believe that.
Come on, move it.
- Look at those half-wits.
What's wrong with you? Idiots.
Sorry, did it hurt?
You better watch out, guys.
Come, just let them.
- What? You think this is normal?
Calm down, you.
- You shut up.
Should I come down?
- And then?
Wait and see...
- Let him be. He's not normal.
You put up with all of this?
That's why you are acting so tough.
Just go home, Kopla.
- Your friend has a big mouth.
Get lost or you're in trouble.
- With who? With you?
Yes, with me.
You've seen too many Jackie Chan movies.
-Shut up.
And who are you?
- He's with me. Is that a problem?
Go ahead, stab me, if you think you're so tough.
Go and take your friend with you.
-Oh yeah? Are you afraid?
Afraid? Come here if you dare.
You'll regret it.
- Now we're getting scared.
Come.
Why do you react like that to those guys?
Because you think like that they treat you like dirt.
Let them think what they want.
Let them stew in their juice next time.
So I can't say anything?
Am I your friend or just a classmate?
I did not mean it like that.
-Okay, I'll never stand up for you anymore.
Don't be angry.
If it's a real guy,
he arranges everything with your father.
Is that it?
- Yes.
Is Eka coming?
- No, she's not going.
Ana, get in.
Guram, wait.
Mom, she's really not coming.
Five minutes. I'll be right back.
Will you come with me?
Don't feel like it.
Come on, he'd like to see you.
Get dressed.
No.
You promised.
Come on, please...
What should I tell him?
I don't know.
Just tell him I have a fever.
Take care of yourself.
Hey, watch out.
Let's go to the toilet.
Block the door and don't let anyone in.
I brought this for you.
- What for?
To protect yourself against Kopla.
Take it.
Are you crazy?
A moment, there is a teacher inside.
Stupid bitches.
Put it ​​in your bag.
-I'm not saying you have to shoot him.
Just frighten him.
That'll teach him.
That's ridiculous.
- Then at least the thing has some use.
And then?
-Teach him a lesson, then he'll leave you alone.
How long will you still put up with this?
This is the kind of language those guys understand.
Otherwise they'll never leave you alone.
What nonsense.
And how incredibly stupid to take
that thing to school.
Do you want me to do it?
I think you're just afraid.
Open up.
-A moment.
Can't you wait a moment?
- Did you fall into the crapper?
Imbecile.
I'm not an imbecile.
- Get lost.
Don't you dare to hit me.
Give back.
- Look...
- What a stupid picture.
Give back. Do you hear me?
Look.
Why did you force that thing on me?
- You really don't get it.
Nonsense.
Stop it.
Give it back to her.
He ripped her photo.
- Stupid idiot.
You're a bastard.
- Hey, you...
Are you talking to me?
- Yes. Give me my bag.
You want your bag? Please.
You're crazy.
Zaridze...
Leave the classroom.
You get a zero today.
A zero for throwing bags?
Yes, for throwing bags.
I think I deserve a higher grade.
Silence.
Get out. Immediately.
Quiet now. Open your notebook.
It was Zaridze's fault.
-Sit.
Punish me as well...
if you like.
What? You're not going anywhere.
Back to your place.
- I want to get out of here as well.
Don't you dare.
With your big mouth.
Paichadze!
Open the window.
It's suffocating.
Hey, Zaridze. Wait.
We're coming as well.
Get lost.
- What are you doing, Paichadze?
Are you crazy?
Where are you going?
Have you completely lost...
See you tomorrow.
You'll catch a cold.
None of your business.
Who was that guy with whom I
saw you the other day?
Guy? He has a name.
Why? Are you jealous?
-Wait.
Are you in love with him?
- You know what I love?
My parents and bread with butter.
-Wait.
I want to say something.
Something important.
Will you marry me?
-What?
I'm serious.
I'll ask you only once.
Think about it. You have two weeks.
- I don't need to think about it.
The answer is no.
Why not?
- Because you're an idiot.
I told you to stay away from that car.
Asshole.
Leave him alone.
Put that thing away or I'll put it in your...
Let him go or I'll shoot.
- Calm down.
Didn't you hear what I said?
Get lost. Both of you.
And give him his knife back.
Come on.
Bye.
You're soaked. Is it raining that hard?
Eka, you have cigarettes?
You know I don't smoke?
Sorry.
- You have any money instead?
No.
- That kid is useless.
What did you say you were doing?
-I was reading.
Oh yeah? What book?
Stop. Let's go smoke.
- We don't have any cigarettes.
Then look better.
I have to go. I'll call again later.
You're home, right?
Talk to you soon.
You couldn't wait two seconds?
My god.
Where are you going?
It's like talking to a wall
with that guy.
What?
- Why did you take that cigarette?
Because I felt like it.
I'll buy some new ones.
You're ashamed of nothing.
-Fuck off.
Stupid bitch.
- Don't talk to your big sister like that.
What's wrong with that kid?
Stupid kid. She drives me crazy.
Stupid bitch. My mother was saving it for
when my father was released.
I'll buy new ones.
There are plenty of cigarettes in the world.
Where were we?
Oh yes, he doesn't get it at all.
Doesn't he know that there are demonstrations?
- Apparently not. Or he pretends.
Don't sit there soaking wet. What is it this time?
- Did you cry?
Give me a puff.
Make sure no one jumps the queue.
Everybody queue up.
Eka.
Do you have money for me?
- Yeah, come here.
Just start selling.
Hello.
Give me bread. Ten loaves.
Don't you have to wait in line?
- Quiet.
The queue isn't meant for you?
What are you looking at?
You should be ashamed.
What's wrong with this country?
What are you doing?
Leave her alone.
Let her go.
Natia!
Assholes.
Bunch of cowards.
Assholes. Cowards.
I hope you die.
Bunch of cowards, bastards.
Motherfuckers.
What?
- You heard me. Go to hell.
Stupid bitch.
- What are you doing?
Has he completely lost his mind?
No thanks.
Let's go to the toilet.
I want to give you something.
Go. I'll be there.
Can I pass?
Dear friends.
Attention to the master of ceremonies.
Let's make a toast.
To our amazing women.
To their beauty.
What would our lives be worth
without them?
Blessed are all women.
-Cheers.
Cheers.
- To the women.
All at once:
to our women.
To our women.
You can do better. Cheers.
Eka, it's me.
Good thing you got me out of there.
I can never sit still for a long time.
But it was a beautiful wedding, huh?
Yes.
Check if my dress is closed properly.
What did you want to give me?
No present, though.
I couldn't find anything.
Here you go.
Did you want to present this to me?
How'd it go? Did you seen Kopla?
Did you scare him?
- I haven't seen him.
Come.
-Wait, I want to say something.
What is it?
Do you love that guy?
I think so.
I think I love him.
What are you looking at?
What do you want to know?
He didn't force me.
It just happened.
He's a good man.
Really.
That's sweet of you.
And Lado?
What about Lado?
What does he have to do with anything?
Come.
Just go. I'll be there in a moment.
We sat in the car
and I couldn't see anything.
I had no idea where I was.
-Where did they take you?
Somewhere outside the city.
Then what happened? Tell me.
We went into a house.
- The family album of Kote.
A man told me I was now Kote's wife
and then I had to peel potatoes.
Did you want to stay there?
I guess...
How could I have escaped?
They said that I would fall in love with him.
So I stayed.
Did it hurt, the first time?
Hey, stop it.
They are dancing.
- Even your dad is dancing.
My dad?
- He's drunk.
What's the matter?
Not happy that I got married?
Of course I am..
-You don't look it.
Awake?
Was it a nice wedding?
- Quite.
You'd like a tea?
- Please.
Is it better? Does it still hurt?
No.
Mom?
Is it true that daddy
killed the father of Kopla?
No.
Why?
Has anyone said something about that?
No....
But is it true?
No, it's not true.
I'm going.
Wake Sopo later.
She has an exam.
Sorry. Do you have candles?
Two.
U.S. state that starts with an O and
ends with an O. Four letters.
Ohio.
- Ohio. Very good.
Do you have eggs?
- No.
Coach of the Argentine national team...
- I don't know.
Eka...
I missed you.
Kote's mother baked this.
It is delicious. Taste it.
How's school?
- Normal.
And how are you?
- Well, I guess.
But how's school? Tell.
We have holiday soon.
It's exam week.
They're asking for you.
-Really. Who?
Lela, Paichadze, Achiko...
They are curious how you are doing.
They miss you.
I miss them too.
No more music lessons?
Ah...
- What do you mean?
Kote doesn't want me to go to music lessons.
He doesn't want me to be a pianist.
So now you do everything that he wants?
I don't get it.
I don't only do what he wants.
You do, and you know it.
You think so?
Are you here to interrogate me?
Thanks a lot.
Come on, Natia...
Don't be mad.
I did not mean it like that.
Has something happened?
Come on, tell.
My birthday is soon...
and I wanted to invite some friends.
Jou, Lela, Achiko,
a few guys as well.
But I'm not allowed.
They don't have any money left, they say.
They made debts for the wedding.
I told them that you could bring your own.
But like that I would bring disgrace to the family.
Then we'll simply go to your family?
I can't stand them.
Then we'll celebrate it at your place.
So you don't have to see their faces.
As if my father's face is so much better...
When I go home, he'll be furious.
Hello, Eka.
Are you okay?
- Yes. You too?
Natia, where's my black shirt?
-I do not know
Search for it. I have to go.
I don't have time now.
Help searching. I am in a hurry.
Really?
Can't you see that I have guests?
Calm down, Natia.
Are you crazy?
- Yes.
Get lost with your shirts and socks.
What are you looking at?
I've had it with your socks and shirts.
What's wrong?
Why are you talking so loud? Kote...
What happened?
- Leave me alone.
What is going on?
Come on, I'm asking what is wrong.
Why did you get so crazy?
You're driving me crazy.
There you are, sweetheart.
You're so big.
Congratulations.
Congratulations, darling.
Hi, sweetheart.
- Everything okay with you?
And with you and your mother?
- Fine, thank you.
That smells delicious.
What did you make?
All things that you like.
I missed you terribly.
Can I help?
- No, honey. Everything is ready.
I'm serving.
What is that?
- Hands off.
Hurry, Natela. I'm hungry.
Everything is ready on the balcony.
Wait, come here.
Here's the wine. Delicious wine.
And you take the bread.
Everything is ready. You can already prepare the dishes.
I finish this and I come.
Moment. First this...
Look what I have baked for you.
Enjoy, girls.
There is plenty.
I forgot a knife...
It looks delicious.
- My favorite.
Grandma has really made a feast.
How did you do that, Natela?
Borrowed money?
- Or did you go to the pawnshop.
Come with your glass.
In one gulp.
- Good.
Cheers, Natela.
To your grandmother.
- Cheers.
To your grandmother and all sweet grandmothers of the world.
And to your health.
-And yours.
Completely empty.
Cheers.
How hungry I was.
- Dig in.
There's Lado...
Come.
You do not know, honey, you do not know...
What's up, Natia?
- Good. And you?
Everything okay, Eka?
- Yes.
And I'd sit until the early morning under your balcony
I'd want to live right in front of your house
and I'd sit until the early morning under your balcony
life is harsh and unfair
if you have a dream it will always break
Hello.
What are you doing here?
- Just hanging.
Come home.
- No, I'll stay here.
Come, I said.
- What does he think...
I'll see you tomorrow.
Natia?
Are you here?
Do you come? The food is ready.
Natia, do you hear me?
The food is ready.
We are waiting for you.
Natia, come. Now.
Do you hear me? Come out.
The food is getting cold.
I'm coming.
... bombing in Sukhumi. According to the
latest information no one was hurt.
So that's it: Yura has gone there.
Where?
- Yura's son to Abkhazia.
I know. I do not wanna talk about it.
-You realize what he has done?
He's dead, his family is broken.
Poor people.
Stupid kid. Children
cause nothing but trouble.
Enough. When I heard...
Take some bread.
Here you go.
Hey, you.
- Do you have cigarettes?
I do not smoke.
-Wait.
Don't you recognize me?
Come here.
Do not move.
I'll kill you, motherfucker.
- Do not let him escape.
Come here, asshole.
Where are you running?
Son of a bitch.
Let's go.
Asshole.
Run.
Natia, wait.
Wait.
Open the door.
- Don't.
What's wrong?
Don't.
- Let me go.
Tell me what is going on.
What's going on?
- Eka!
You're driving me crazy.
You'll break the door.
Open up.
-Come on out.
Didn't you hear what I said?
Now listen for a minute...
Give it to me.
- What the hell is going on here?
Have you lost your mind?
What's going on here?
Calm down.
Give it.
Listen to me.
Why are you screaming like that?
Give it.
- Come here, you.
Tell me.
- Didn't you hear me?
Give it.
- No.
I hate you.
- Have you gone crazy?
Get out of the kitchen.
-Stay out of this. That bitch...
You think you're at home?
Shut up.
- Street girl.
I give you a home and this is what I get.
You're crazy.
Do you think she's your daughter?
Where is Kote?
Where's that husband of yours?
I asked where Kote is.
- That son of yours has killed somebody.
Is it clear now?
You got it now?
Is it true what she's saying?
I'm going out.
I'm going to figure out if this is true.
I'm coming along.
- You wait here.
You don't get to decide what I do.
Stop bitching, woman.
You're all crazy.
Eka, give it.
How often do I have to say?
Clear?
It's mine, not yours.
Is that clear?
Give it. It'is mine.
Okay, I'll give it back.
No one will take it away from you.
Take it.
It's yours. Why aren't you taking it?
Kote should die as well?
You know where he is.
Go and kill him.
Come.
Is this the entrance?
- Mom, this right here is the entrance, isn't it?
Yes.
- Thanks.
Where are you going?
The visitors' entrance?
Yes.
Let's see inside.
Okay, yeah, fine. I'm hanging up.
Documents.
First name?
Eka.
Last name?
Khizanishvili.
How old are you?
- Fourteen.
Relation to the prisoner?
He's my father.
Do not put them there, but there.
Dad, do you have the
passports and documents?
No, you have them.
Khizanishvili?
That's me.
- Come on, girl.
Turn right.