(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
There are always two wolves...
fighting within our minds.
One is cold and heartless,
and the other...
is warm and peaceful.
Which one wins?
The one I feed wins.
My father told me the story...
the Indian chief told his grandson.
My father told me...
to be a person...
who feeds the warm wolf.
I'm sorry, Father.
From now on,
I will feed...
the cold and heartless wolf.
(Episode 1)
Ji Yoo...
Ji Yoo.
No.
No. This must not be true.
What's going on?
Ji Yoo!
Kang Ji Yoo!
Kang Woo!
Kang Woo.
Ji Yoo! Ji Yoo.
Move.
Ji Yoo.
Ji Yoo!
Where's Ji Yoo?
Ji Yoo. Ji Yoo.
Where's Ji Yoo? Ji Yoo!
Ji Yoo! Ji Yoo.
Kang Ji Yoo!
Where's Ji Yoo? Bring her here!
Bring Ji Yoo right now! Ji Yoo!
Ji Yoo!
- I only did as I was told... - Wait outside.
(Hong Soon Bok)
Kang Ji Yoo.
You ruined everything.
This dress...
and my wedding.
You always make me miserable.
But do you know this?
I won't go down like this...
because...
I'm no longer Hong Soon Bok,
but Chae Seo Rin.
So you can't die yet.
You need to be...
healthy and alive.
(Year 2011)
- Hey. - Hi.
Are you still making that?
Do you think you're Rodin or something?
What do you think?
Once I add the music, it's done.
Look. Girls don't like those things.
Hard work? Art? They don't want that.
They like small and shiny things.
That's what they like.
She isn't a girl.
What do you mean?
She's beyond human.
My gosh. You lunatic.
Go see Professor Jung.
- He wants you to come to his lab. - Why?
Maybe you came in first again.
Can't you let me have it just once?
Would you like...
my help?
"In Jeopardy".
She's in danger just like the title.
Thank goodness, the gentleman is there.
He won't ignore the woman in distress.
That woman...
won't ask the man for help.
Sorry?
Look. She gathered her skirt.
Would you like my help?
That woman probably doesn't need the help of any man.
Excuse me.
No. She needs the help of the gentleman.
Definitely.
Did you forget me already?
You left nothing but loneliness
Did you forget me?
Did you forget me already?
Who are you?
Who...
Oh, no.
I like you.
Will you go out with me?
I'm such a loser.
It's been a year already.
Gosh.
The next item is by Kim Min Young...
whose work received the highest bid...
in the Hong Kong auction.
"Pink Illusion". We'll start the bidding at 1.5 million dollars.
(VIP Regular Auction)
The items that I marked in the brochure...
are the ones Yoo Kang Woo will be buying.
Whatever happens,
you must gain his attention.
(Pink Illusion)
1.8 million dollars.
We have 1.8 million. Anyone else?
1.85 million.
We have a bid of 1.85 million dollars.
1.86 million.
We have 1.86 million.
Who will give more?
I'll ask three times and close the bid.
1.86 million.
Congratulations.
You've won "Pink Illusion".
The next item is by a 19th century British artist.
It was painted by Arthur Hacker in 1902.
It's "In Jeopardy".
We'll begin at 40,000 dollars.
45,000 dollars.
We have 45,000 dollars.
Just a minute!
I missed both pieces.
I couldn't miss them.
I'm sorry.
I'd like to talk more...
about the woman in distress.
Would you like to have dinner?
I'm sorry, but I don't have time.
I'm meeting my girlfriend.
It's about the project you submitted.
Submit it for the Seoul Ideas Competition in Urban Planning.
- Sorry? - If you revise it a little,
it might win the competition.
Improve the practical parts and make it better.
Yes, Sir. I'll work on it until my body gives out.
Hello?
Yes, I'm Min Sun Ho.
Pardon?
- I'll be right there... - I'm on my way...
I'll be right there.
I'm on my way.
Kang Woo!
You'll fall!
Don't run.
- My goodness. - Good to see you!
What if you get hurt before your performance?
I wasn't going to run,
but my feet jetted to you...
like they had an engine attached.
Still, you should be careful.
(Intensive Care Unit)
Is Min Hye Sun here?
Yes, she's over here.
That man is quite attractive. It's enough for me to fall for.
That's good.
But he has a girlfriend.
So?
- Pardon? - Did you think it would be easy?
But what do you gain if I marry...
into Mosung Group?
Why do you have so many questions?
Just do as you've always done.
I make the orders...
and you follow them.
Yoo Kang Woo's girlfriend has a performance soon.
That's where you should meet him again.
You'll get to see him...
and check out his girlfriend.
(Swan Lake)
(Kang Ji Yoo's Dance Performance)
Ji Yoo?
It can't be.
Is Kang Woo's girlfriend...
No.
It can't be.
Excuse me.
Hey!
I saw you at the auction the other day.
We meet again.
Is this your seat?
You're right. What a coincidence!
It's nice seeing you again like this.
I came because my friend is performing today.
- What about you? - I came to see my girlfriend.
Is your girlfriend...
Please, no.
It can't be. I'm sure it isn't.
Is she a ballerina?
Here.
It's her.
Ma'am.
How was I?
You're doing well.
You started late, but you're just as good as Ji Yoo.
Then will I be able to win...
this coming dance competition?
You haven't heard yet?
Heard what?
(Seoul International Ballet Competition)
Soon Bok.
Is it true...
that you're going alone for this competition?
The thing is...
If only one person can enter,
it should be me, not you.
You don't need this competition.
You don't need money, and you've won every award out there.
You don't have to care about college or scholarship!
Please let me explain.
My life depends on this competition.
If I don't win this,
I have to give up on college and scholarship.
You know better than anyone how hard I worked for this.
How could you do this to me?
Well... Soon Bok...
Well...
I told her to do it.
An American director is coming...
to sit as a judge for this competition.
With Ji Yoo's skills, she'll definitely catch his eye.
Then she'll go to the States.
She's a better dancer than you,
so give her this one.
We'll keep paying your tuition through college.
Aren't you doing this for the scholarship anyway?
(Grand Performance Hall)
Kang Woo is Ji Yoo's boyfriend.
Why? Why?
Why does it have to be her? Why?
Soon Bok.
My gosh.
You have your ear plugged up with this.
No wonder you couldn't hear me.
Ji Yoo left her umbrella.
Bring it to her.
No.
You brat. Get up.
What if she gets wet and catches a cold?
I got wet, too.
You're not the same.
Get up.
You'll be blessed for doing good deeds.
Get up already.
- No. - Hurry up.
Go on. Hurry.
It's always Ji Yoo this and Ji Yoo that.
Whose mum is she anyway?
Why does it have to be Ji Yoo?
I worked so hard to be free of her.
Why again?
After all I did to get here,
I can't go back...
to Hong Soon Bok because of her again.
(Secrets of Women)
Excuse me.
I know Kang Woo's girlfriend.
I don't want to get tangled up with her again.
Do you want to return to the sewer?
Sleeping at a friend's house...
means you're allowed to sleep out.
Please be mine forever.