In THE REALM OF THE SENSES
Written and Directed by
NAGISA OSHIMA
Awake already?
It’s so cold.
It’s too early to get up.
Let's sleep a little longer.
I couldn't sleep all night.
I know.
I had the same problem
when I started here.
You're so stylish and refined.
What are you doing
working as a serving girl?
I took a liking to you
as soon as i saw you yesterday.
Come on...
hold me tight.
That tickles.
You have such
a beautiful body.
Don't you like women?
In that case...
It’s the same every morning
before he goes to the fish market.
- Let's play that association game.
- I'll go first.
Hairy legs.
Crabs.
Chastity.
Men.
What are you kids up to?
Stop it!
Leave the poor man alone!
What are you doing here?
How awful!
What are you doing?
Get out of here,
you little brats!
It’s you!
- What's gotten into you?
- Osaka -
Let her go!
Keep your filthy hands off her!
I can't remember.
What was your name?
Was it in Osaka?
Nagoya? Tokyo?
You were so cheerful and kind.
I was your customer.
Don't you remember me?
I’ve never seen you before.
I want you now!
Look, I have money!
Please, just this once.
You just won't give up.
- You haven't changed at all.
- Hurry up.
You really don't remember me?
Nope.
What's wrong? It’s limp.
Are you cold?
If you just let me see your...
What a pain!
You'll catch cold.
You'd better just forget it.
Go on now.
Don't stand there singing!
Hurry up!
Where have you been?
Stop dawdling
and take this in right away.
You're working in a proper inn.
It’s not as easy as being a whore.
What are you staring at?
Stop it!
- Go to hell!
- Stop it!
I said stop!
- What's all this about?
- Once a whore, always a whore!
I’ll kill her!
Stop it!
So what if i was?
You think you're better than me?
Stop it!
You're to blame too.
Watch what you say!
We all have to work together.
I expect you both to apologize!
Out of my way!
What's going on?
It’s practically a brawl in here.
Who are you?
You new here?
What's your name?
Sada.
Sada Abe.
Lucky you came when you did.
Now i wonder just where you were.
You've got such pretty hands.
Why hold that knife when you
could be holding something else?
What a nice view.
No, don't stop.
Go on working.
Don't play with fire
I like the sway of your hips.
I bet you've broken
many a man's heart.
I will pierce you through
How many hearts
have you broken?
Master...
You're hurting my hand.
That hurts.
Master...
I’m a married woman -
I’ve heard all about it.
Your husband's business failed.
Now you both have to work.
That's right.
Must be hard.
You're...
a woman with a past,
aren't you?
I only came here because i heard
this was an upstanding house.
Is that so?
Well, as you see...
I’m an upstanding man.
Aren't you done yet?
Hurry up!
Bonds
Between friends
Can never be broken
Master,
are you alone tonight?
I stopped drinking out,
so tonight
I’ll be your customer.
Why did you stop drinking out?
So i can do this instead.
Madam sent me.
She said there was a customer.
That's me.
What is this
Narrow path
See how wet you are?
Let's not waste time.
Come on.
That feels so good.
If you go on, I’ll -
What if the geisha comes?
We'll get in trouble.
- You want me to stop?
- No!
It’s driving me mad.
How is it driving you mad?
How?
Good evening.
Thank you for sending for me.
I’m your geisha, Yaeji.
Just a moment, please.
I’m a bit busy right now.
Please take your time.
Come in, Yaeji.
Sorry i kept you waiting.
Good evening.
What a lovely young girl!
In the white snow...
Where are you going?
To the toilet.
I’ll be waiting.
I don't have to go
right this minute.
They say it feels better
with a full bladder.
Take your time.
There's no hurry.
But Master...
last night i -
It’s all right.
I want you to feel good.
Your pleasure is enough.
I’m holding back for you.
You're going to make love
to your wife later, aren't you?
What a slut,
having sex every morning.
So you've seen us?
Have you been watching?
I won't let you go
until you've come.
Don't worry about that.
Let's take our time
and enjoy it.
But It’s already dawn.
Who cares?
You're an unusual woman.
My hair
Is out of place
Only because
Of my pillow
Yet i know
You don't believe me...
Master, I can't play anymore.
You have to keep playing.
I told my wife you'd be playing
the shamisen for me tonight.
If you stop,
she'll get suspicious.
Why don't you sing instead?
Just a little longer.
It’s my job
It’s a prostitute's life
Forgive me
The warbler in the tree
by the shed
On the second branch
from the top
Sprinkled vinegar
with grass held in her beak
And then laid 12 eggs
The first was a nightingale
The second was a kingfisher
The third was a wren
The fourth was a night crow
The fifth was a woodpecker
The sixth was a starling
The seventh was a plover
The eighth was a pheasant
The ninth was a robin
The tenth and eleventh...
Excuse me, ma'am.
I’m sorry to disturb you.
Oh, hello. What is it?
I’m sorry
if this is very sudden,
but i request permission
to leave your employ.
Well, this is quite a surprise.
We can discuss it,
but for now please change this water.
I’m very happy with your work.
And you're very well-behaved.
There's no reason
for you to leave us.
- Oh no.
- What is it?
I just got my period.
I don't mind.
Good morning.
Your guests have arrived.
This is the first time
you'll see me completely naked.
Are you happy?
Yes...
but the man
should undress first.
No, let me undress you first.
Your skin's so youthful.
It’s practically glowing.
You're utterly radiant.
Skin like this could suck
the blood right out of a man.
You can't be serious.
You're the one
who devours women.
I’m old. I want your youth
to rub off on me.
Your skin's so soft.
I feel like sucking on it.
Silly.
I’ve brought your sake, sir.
Master, didn't you say
you'd stopped drinking out?
This isn't out.
This is our home -
yours and mine.
I’m so happy
to hear you say that.
How auspicious
Young pine
Show us tonight
Congratulations!
How your branches flourish
And your leaves grow thick
How auspicious
Your leaves grow thick
What do i do with this?
Don't you know?
I never had
a proper wedding before.
If my bride had already
been properly wed,
that would be quite a letdown.
Indeed, tonight is our wedding.
So please rejoice with us,
all of you.
Keep playing
Let the music play
After the nuptial cups
comes the bridal bed.
Yes, they must consummate
their marriage.
It’s already been consummated.
That was underhanded!
You may have had her before,
but on your wedding night,
she'll be especially delicious.
Is that right?
Really?
Shall we?
Yes, Master.
Stop calling me ‘‘master.''
Call me Kichi-san from now on.
Of course... Kichi-san.
Sada.
Have the plums blossomed
What's this?
You're trembling.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
I’m shaking all over.
If you'll excuse us...
You seem awfully interested.
Come take a closer look.
No, let me go!
Come now.
Surely you've seen it before.
No, don't close your eyes.
Look!
Don't moan
with pleasure like that!
It’s not pleasure.
It’s pain.
Kosome, It’s your turn.
It hurts!
In Kitahama
He came out
Into the cool of the evening
A breeze from the river
Suddenly blew
Through the peonies
He's a wild
And untamed lover
Stay with us
Always
Kichi-san, where are you going
To harvest the rice
in the fields
Take me with you
You'll only get in my way
You wretched little monk!
May I make the bed now?
Give us a little longer.
What time is it?
It’s already noon.
Really?
Kichi-san.
Kichi-san, It’s noon already.
Good morning.
Did you hold it all night?
Yes.
Couldn't you sleep?
I wasn't sleepy.
I was too happy.
Really?
You're so young.
How can you look
so fresh and lovely without sleep?
You're radiant!
I’m glad you're raring to go,
but give me a minute, okay?
- Where are you going?
- To pee.
Why not do it here?
Where?
Inside me.
You're crazy.
I can't do both
at the same time.
Let's try and see.
Can't you just wait
while i pee?
I’ve been waiting so long.
I see. Very well.
Are you ever not wet?
It’s not like
I’m sick or something.
I know.
You're adorable.
I was a little worried once,
so i went to see a doctor.
He said...
I’m acutely sensitive.
Acutely sensitive?
Those are big words.
In any case, I love the fact
you're acutely sensitive.
Kichi-san...
put it in me now.
Not yet.
I said put it in.
What's so funny?
I was thinking
that the only time
my dick can rest
is when i take a piss.
That's right.
But after you're done,
you sure get hard again fast.
See?
Just like i said.
You're right.
It practically belongs to you.
It does belong to me.
Tell me...
why does it get hard
so quickly?
Because...
it knows you want it.
I want it again now.
People can see us.
I don't care.
You sure are full of spunk,
granny.
I am with you two around!
Let's say good-bye here.
No. I’ll walk you home.
Leave it alone.
It hurts when i walk.
What if the servants see us?
It’s hard again.
That's because you're holding it.
Let go.
No, you have to take me
right here and now.
Pardon me,
but I’ve brought your sake.
Come in.
How unusual!
You're not in bed together.
I can't get my young girls
to come in here.
Why's that?
You're always
in the middle of -
Of what?
Of me sucking your pee-pee.
Ma'am, i have
to leave for a while,
but I’ll be back
tomorrow evening.
Please keep an eye on him
so he doesn't go out.
You can count on me.
But what about geisha
coming here?
That's fine.
Really? Why?
Well? Do I look pretty?
You've lost weight.
Makes you even lovelier.
Oh, dear!
Kichi-san, you're still not tired?
It’s cruel to tempt
a woman my age with such a sight.
I know we need the money,
but i get mad with jealousy
when I imagine you with another man.
Are you really jealous?
That makes me happy.
But he's just a school principal
and town alderman.
Very upstanding.
You like 'em upstanding,
don't you?
I really do.
Kichi-san, I’m taking
your kimono with me.
Why?
To make sure
you don't go home.
Am i supposed
to go around naked?
I’ll lend you my robe.
Try it on.
All right.
Well?
More sake, sir?
Shall i pour more, sir?
It isn't healthy
to eat so little.
The two of you never eat.
Sir, why don't you run away
before she gets back?
If you stay,
she'll end up killing you.
What are you doing?
Master, do you mind
hurrying it up?
It’s hard for me
in the afternoon.
I said we didn't have
to do this.
But i want to.
I was up all night
waiting for this.
I see you have yet
to mend your ways.
You promised to try
to sleep alone.
It’s different with you,
because i like
and respect you.
You understand, don't you?
Sir, beat me!
Slap me!
- Sada!
- Slap me!
Harder!
Now pinch me!
Don't stop!
Harder!
Now pull my hair!
More!
Harder!
But Sada...
Kichi-san!
How have you been?
- I’ve got money.
- Really?
Let's go spend it.
I missed you so much.
I’ll never leave
your side again.
Kichi-san,
can I put it in me again?
If you want.
You're so restless -
putting it in, taking it out.
That's good.
Just like that.
Really?
You look so happy,
like a 16-year-old girl.
Watching your thing
go in and out of me
makes me feel so good.
It feels so good.
I feel like I’m drunk.
Kichi-san...
stay just like that.
Sada...
how was it
with your school principal?
Show me exactly
what you did.
That tickles.
Well, that's what i did.
To your principal?
‘‘Sada, I just want you to think
seriously about your future.''
What about in this department?
That?
He couldn't get hard at all.
So what did you do?
Don't get mad.
I suddenly thought of you
and went into hysterics.
I don't know why...
but i asked him to slap me.
And what did
your principal do?
Slap me.
I’m sorry.
Harder.
Harder!
Come and look
In the snow
Even the birds
Stay tucked in their nests
They say true love means eating
food dipped in your lover's juices.
It’s delicious.
Sada...
I’ll do whatever it takes
to make you happy.
That's delicious too.
And now...
let's try this.
A woman's pussy
is her capital city
Guarded by the pubic hair
lined up all around it
Kichi-san, take it out!
Take it out! Hurry!
How can i
when you're sitting like that?
How does a hen lay an egg?
Like this?
That's right.
If you strain too hard, you'll crush it.
Slowly and gently.
Fighting like cats and dogs...
- That's it.
- That wasn't nice!
Sada, we're not alone.
I don't care.
- What's that for?
- To cut it off.
You're crazy.
So you can't use it at home.
I already told you
i wouldn't.
Well, you might.
That's why I’ll cut it off.
Then you won't be able
to use it either.
That's why
I’ll mount you like this
and cut it off inside me.
All right. Go ahead.
It feels good.
If i cut it off,
do you think you'd die?
Probably.
I don't want you to.
Don't worry. I won't.
I promised to stay with you
forever, didn't i?
I’ll set you up in a small inn.
I don't want
to be your mistress.
I don't want to share you
with your wife.
We have to be together
all the time.
Listen, Sada,
if we lived together,
I’d be reduced to a skeleton.
So you don't want
to live together, is that it?
Fine. I’ll live with you,
even if i become a skeleton.
You sure?
Even worn down to a skeleton?
I’m sure.
Now could you stop
threatening me with this?
It’s dangerous.
Now you'll grow a beard.
Are you going to make love
to your wife again?
No.
Say you'll never do it again.
I’ll never do it again.
‘‘You can kill me
if i ever make love to her.''
You can kill me
if i ever make love to her.
Kichi!
- Shall we scare her?
- All right.
I’m a ghost!
- I’m the haunted parasol!
- I have one eye!
And four legs!
Why don't you
make love to her?
She's not my type.
I’m sorry,
but It’s closing time.
Old man,
you want to do it?
You can have me
if you let us drink some more.
Mine's only good
for peeing these days.
Kichi,
don't ever leave me!
I caught a little goblin.
Now It’s your turn.
Come here.
No.
Then I’ll come get you.
Ouch! That hurts!
That hurts.
Could that have been
a burglar, dear?
Don't be silly.
A burglar wouldn't make
all that noise.
Probably just some drunk.
We can clean it up tomorrow.
Do you think...
it could have been her?
Go to sleep.
Going back to her?
You startled me,
appearing out of nowhere like that.
It’s all right.
Come and look
In this snow
Even the birds
Stay tucked in their nests
Lying in bed
I open the lattice window
With my pipe
Come and look
Master, you're wanted
on the phone.
No!
Get off me!
Hello!
Welcome.
Damn you!
Damn you, Kichi!
Tell me the truth!
You fucked her, didn't you?
If you want a reverse grip,
you'll need a thicker blade.
You can't kill anyone like that.
I meant to buy
a thicker blade.
Then how'd you end up
with a carving knife?
There were people watching.
You're crazy!
How would anyone guess
what you wanted it for?
This is all
you ever think about.
Son of a bitch!
You think I’m crazy because
i can't stop thinking about you?
Take off your clothes!
Wearing a kimono like this!
Take it off or -
Wait a minute.
I can't take it off like this.
Help me, will you?
Tell me:
What did you do
in bed with your wife?
Look, he's shaking his head:
‘‘I didn't do anything.''
Apologize.
‘‘I have no reason
to apologize.''
See?
- Bastard.
He's a stubborn one.
I’ll teach him a lesson.
Please do.
Give him a good punishing.
Ouch!
- Does that hurt?
- It sure does.
- What about that?
- Yes.
Does it hurt
but feel good too?
It hurts
but feels good too.
Say, ‘‘Bite me harder.''
Bite me harder.
- Does this feel good too?
- Yes.
Fuck me harder!
You like this?
Yes.
I’ll do whatever you want.
Forgive me for leaving you alone
these past three days.
I thought I’d go mad!
I’m sorry.
Are you crying?
Only because I’m happy.
Look at me.
I’ve never seen you cry before.
Let me see.
- No!
- It’s all right.
Your tears are salty.
Damn you for making me
so happy.
You're awful!
- May i bring in your sake?
- Yes.
Bring it over here.
We're fused together.
- Don't you want anything to eat?
- No.
A full stomach
makes you sleepy.
Shall i clean up
the room a bit?
There's a strange smell.
We like that smell...
don't we?
Kichi,
don't fall asleep on me.
I’ve heard it feels good
to choke each other
when you're making love.
When you clutched
my throat the other day,
it felt really good.
Really?
Okay, then choke me.
All right.
Here goes.
As you tighten up here,
you'll tighten down there too.
Am i hurting you?
- I’m fine.
Squeeze tighter.
How's that?
What's wrong?
Your face is beet-red.
It’s nothing.
Squeeze harder.
You sure?
It’s gonna hurt.
Don't get mad, okay?
How's it feel?
Good?
I guess you have to approach death
to feel the height of ecstasy.
Did you enjoy it?
- Not at all.
You have to squeeze hard.
I’ve had enough.
I don't like watching you suffer.
Then let me try it on you.
Shall i?
Go ahead.
You're tickling me.
You scared?
Not at all.
Go ahead.
Your thing
just jerked inside me.
It keeps on twitching.
I can't breathe.
Go slow, okay?
All right.
It feels so good.
I can't stand it.
- Does it feel good?
- I feel it twitching.
- Feel good?
Yes.
I can't stand it...
It’s moving around.
I can't breathe.
- The geisha won't come in here.
- Why?
Because of your reputation.
What? What are they
saying about us?
- That you're perverts.
- What?
Who cares
what they say, Sada?
I care.
Why are we perverts?
You're constantly
sucking on his thing.
What's perverted about that?
Why shouldn't a woman
adore her lover's body?
Come back here!
- Let her be.
- Who's talking about us?
- Everyone.
Everyone?
You mean you, don't you?
What do you think about us?
Tell me, damn it!
Sada, stop it!
That's enough now.
Leave the poor girl alone.
Look, Sada...
who cares if people
call us perverts?
I want you to fuck her.
Master, please don't.
I’ll never be able to marry.
Get out.
He's too good for you anyway.
Good evening.
My name is Kikuryo.
- Your geisha has arrived.
- Thank you.
My, you certainly
are a virile gentleman!
What shall i play?
Anything.
Just play with spirit.
You treat me
So hatefully
Yet i cannot help
loving you
Do i seem like
a pervert to you?
Why do you ask?
I can't get enough
of his body.
That's natural for a woman.
How old are you?
I’m 68.
Do you find him attractive?
Oh yes, he's very charming.
So you don't mind
watching us do this?
It’s a feast for the eyes.
Would you...
like him to make love to you?
Ma'am, it feels so young.
What's that?
Granny pissed herself.
What a mess.
I hope she's not dead.
You look all pale...
like a corpse.
Don't say that.
It could bring bad luck.
It was awful.
I felt like i was having sex
with my dead mother.
Your mother died?
Yes, when i was a child.
Yours?
Three years ago.
I wasn't there when she died.
The next year,
I spent ten days
taking care of my father
as he was dying.
Once you're dead, that's it.
- Sada.
- What?
Let's be happy
together forever.
Let's say good-bye here.
I must say...
you don't smell
very good today.
Like a dead rat
or something.
Master, could we go away
to the hot springs for a week?
Impossible!
If anyone knew about us,
I’d have to shoot myself.
What's wrong?
Why are you back so soon?
Kichi, where did you go?
You weren't here,
so they cleaned the room!
I went for a haircut.
I didn't think you'd be back so soon.
What? You bastard!
How dare you go for a haircut
while I’m out
earning your keep!
Forgive me.
But you said you love
my neck when It’s shaved.
I love it so much
i want to slice it open.
Please don't.
Strangling me should suffice.
Perhaps that's just what I’ll do.
Sada, that's dangerous.
Want me to strangle you?
No, but if it
gives you pleasure -
Say, ‘‘I want you to strangle me.''
I want you to strangle me.
All right.
Don't pull too hard.
Are you afraid?
Yes.
You say that...
but you're actually happy,
aren't you?
I’m going to strangle you.
Pull tighter.
You can pull tighter.
Is it twitching?
Really?
Good.
Pull as hard as you can.
Harder.
- What's wrong?
- Wait a minute.
It was starting
to really feel good.
I know: I’ll tie you up.
Give me your hands.
Don't you like being choked?
I don't mind.
If you fight it,
I’ll pull even harder.
I said i didn't mind, didn't l?
My body is yours.
Do as you please with it.
Then I’ll start again.
Go as slow as you can.
Does it hurt?
Does it feel good?
Like I’m part of you.
All i see is red.
You're so quiet.
It’s a little scary.
Say something.
You idiot!
How can i talk
when you're choking me?
Don't worry about me.
Just enjoy yourself.
Even if i kill you?
All right.
I’ll kill you.
It feels so good.
Was it good?
If you want it that badly,
get on top of me,
though I might not keep it up.
Are you sure?
Does it hurt?
Watch me while i sleep.
If i fall asleep,
you'll choke me again, won't you?
You want me to choke you?
If you strangle me...
don't stop midway.
It’s too painful afterward.
Kichi-san.
I’m starting now.
Ready?
Not yet.
Kichi-san!
Kichi-san.
SADA AND KlCHl
TOGETHER FOREVER
For the next four days,
Sada carried
his severed organ
from one Tokyo inn to another.
She was still smiling radiantly
when she was arrested.
The story shocked
all of Japan.
The sympathy of the public
made her strangely popular.
These events
took place in 1936.