Hurry.
(Episode 6)
- There they are.
- Wait a minute.
- Grab him!
- What is this?
Run away. Hurry!
Run away from here.
- Grab him.
- Wait.
- Oh, my.
- No.
Why is he like this? Sir.
Yeon Kyung, what happened?
I performed CPR on a
cardiac arrest patient.
CPR? Oh, my. Are you okay?
His pulse and respiration are back.
Move him to intensive care unit
and reserve some check-ups.
Sir, it's me.
I'm Shin Myung Hoon, the
director of Shinhae Hospital.
- Hurry.
- Sir!
- We're moving.
- Oh, my. Sir!
It's me.
It's Shin Myung Hoon.
Open the door.
Be careful.
What did I do wrong?
- I did not...
- Is that Mr. Heo Im?
Follow him and see where he goes.
Yes, sir.
I was going to see you.
I don't think we're close
enough to come see each other.
You said you would contact
me if I turn in my papers.
When should I start?
Do you think that turning in a sheet
of paper will let you work here?
Did you not say that you hire
people based on their skills?
Skills?
Are you that confident?
Please arrange a meeting for me.
I will show you myself.
We don't hire people based on their skills.
- Pardon?
- Do you have a license?
- What is that?
- You don't even have a license,
and got in trouble at the other hospital?
Do you know that Yeon Kyung is in a
difficult situation because of you?
What do you mean?
I'm not sure whether you
know the word "bother".
- Bother.
- I know what it is.
That's good. You're a bother to Yeon Kyung.
Do you understand?
Is he safe?
Yeon Kyung.
I heard you helped that man run away.
You're digging your own grave.
Male, 58 years old, he had
a sudden cardiac arrest...
due to acute myocardial infarction.
According to his angiogram,
here, here, and here,
his coronary arteries
are plugged by plaque.
I think he needs a coronary
artery bypass graft.
Do you know him, by any chance?
Professor,
this patient is the presidential
secretary for economic affairs.
What? Who?
What are you doing? Hurry and
reserve an operation room.
The preparation is done. You can just go.
How will I perform normally
when I'm so nervous?
This is an interesting sight.
Your friend has a very
talented granddaughter.
She was very smart since she was young.
Her affiliation is quite clear.
Why are there patients wherever you go?
Your timing is amazing.
Look. If we were late, it
would have been serious.
Okay.
What?
Where?
To Haeminseo Oriental Medicine Clinic.
The director let him in.
Bong Tak.
Hey, Bong Tak.
I told him to not call me that.
Bong Tak.
Do you need a license to become a doctor?
What happens if you do not have that?
You will get arrested...
for illegal medical practice.
- Get arrested?
- Oh, my.
- What is wrong?
- Wait.
How can you get that license?
What do you mean "get"? You
acquire it by passing the exam.
Exam?
He must be talking about the
medical state examinations.
Can anyone take the exam?
You have to graduate from
oriental medicine school.
- How do I go to that school?
- Go through college admissions.
How do I take college admissions?
You have to study hard, focusing
on Korean, English, and math.
How long should I prepare for that?
If you graduate elementary school,
middle school, and high school,
it'll take 18 years. It'll be 12
if you take qualification exams.
Gosh. Gosh.
Why do you look like that?
Didn't it work out yesterday?
Did they refuse to accept
fake doctors like you?
I am not a fake doctor.
You just do not know who I am.
You should just sweep the floor.
That's the job for you.
I am not a servant.
What else do you have to do?
I am going.
He must have learned something.
When he's upset,
he should move around.
You surprised me. What is this?
I bought milk and bread.
You did not have breakfast, right?
I did.
He didn't even buy me coffee.
Why would he buy milk?
What happened to him this time?
I told him only the truth.
Is he sick again?
This place...
is not so bad.
You're a bother to Yeon Kyung.
She must have tried hard to protect you.
After what she has done for
you, you should disappear.
Why do you keep coming here?
If you get her into trouble,
will you take responsibility?
- So I...
- What is this?
Yeon Kyung...
No.
She should have told me.
I cannot work at the palace,
nor be a doctor here.
The surgery went well.
He will be ready to leave in a week.
Is this what solving the problem
one has made looks like?
We should give her a day off.
As a director I can do that, can't I?
Of course.
You should get some rest, Dr. Choi.
Thank you.
Professor Hwang,
about that thing I told you...
It didn't happen, all right?
Yes, sir.
Choi Yeon Kyung. You're great indeed.
Treat me like an elder.
Yes, ma'am. You are great.
Why?
Is it because I saved a patient or
because it was a Head of Department?
Both?
Jae Ha.
About yesterday...
You weren't at the symposium yesterday.
If you're sorry,
will you have dinner with me?
How would a doctor leave the
hospital and go somewhere?
Have dinner with the woman
you are flirting with.
Bye.
I'd like to.
But she always refuses me.
Doctor.
(Emergency Medical Services)
It's her.
I found her at last.
Are you all right?
Pardon?
A man ran to you like light...
and it pierced into his back.
Is he all right?
You hugged me from behind...
to bring me here.
That is unfair.
You remember me hugging
you, but not my scream?
It hurt a lot. I nearly died.
It must have hurt a lot.
Excuse me.
Hello. Come here.
Why did you come here?
Let me take a look.
What are you doing?
What are you doing here?
You should go and clean up.
Yes, sir.
Gosh, let me take a look.
I should go back.
I should at least wipe her tears
of blood with your throat.
No.
Is this Dongi Pharmaceuticals?
What are you doing?
We've been in contract for a long time.
Gosh.
Warm green tea.
Gosh, you surprised me.
What did you say?
You should prepare that...
instead of milk.
Do you have pueraria lobata
or the root of an arrowroot?
Yes, but why?
She has a bad liver.
- What?
- She will get better if she...
drinks green tea in the morning
and pueraria in the afternoon.
And your relationship will get better too.
Liver?
She has a bad liver?
Is she drinking?
How do you know?
Are you two close?
How can I speak to you nicely?
You told me you'll give us the medicine.
Why are you backing out?
Gosh, we only owe you a little.
Are you looking down at the
clinic because it's small?
What a nerve she has.
I asked you...
if you are close with her.
How do you know that?
I know about this...
- because...
- Gosh.
Are you trying to make
him believe your lies?
I am not.
You should even apply acupuncture on him.
Gosh, what will you do for a living?
I need to think about it.
Be quiet. Hold this and follow me.
Where?
Gosh.
Come here.
Are you two close?
You are so stupid.
(Patient's Chart)
You're taking a day off?
Why would you do that?
- Are you sick?
- Don't make a fuss.
I need to take care of something.
What is it? What is it?
Is it dopamine? Are you going to a club?
What's happening? That patient
has a surgery tomorrow.
Why is she leaving? Something
came up and she has to leave.
The surgery has been cancelled.
Give me her chart.
Gosh, what's the matter again?
She's not your patient.
Would you say that to your family?
Even if it were my family,
how would I stop a patient
that really wishes to leave?
She has unstable angina,
narrow left main coronary artery,
arrhythmia, and diabetes.
She needs surgery as soon as possible.
You're not the only doctor here.
I'm a doctor here.
She has personal issues.
What would a cold person like you know?
Only surgeries matter to you.
She thinks she's the only doctor here.
Don't you agree?
No, I don't.
Jo Mi Young.
If you leave like this, the
coronary artery might get blocked,
and it could cause myocardial infarction.
It can get really dangerous.
Even if there's a problem,
you should get a surgery
as soon as possible.
Thank you for telling me that.
But I can't afford to
be a patient right now.
Is it because of the surgery fees?
Doctors seem to regard
patients as a source of money.
No.
They regard patients as
a life they must save.
And I think one's own life is
the most important reason.
Please come back when you
can stay as a patient here.
Meanwhile, don't forget to
take aspirin and angina drug.
If you feel the symptom
that your heart aches,
put the medicine under your tongue
immediately and come to emergency.
Good bye.
- Do you have beggars in this world?
- Come on.
Gosh.
He might be highly qualified,
but still, how can such a young
man take charge of the VIP ward?
It's because the hospital
director has his back.
That's correct.
It's all thanks to my connections.
I'm so young and inexperienced.
I hope you can give lots of
instruction from now on.
- You're more than welcome.
- You can talk casually to me.
He's so polite. He's also tall.
He just looks like a model.
I also know that I'm here
thanks to my connections.
That's why I'm going to start
with a clean slate now.
Gosh, my tooth aches so much. It's here.
You should have cleaned it.
You little punk. Who are you?
Where's the acupuncture
point for a toothache?
- What?
- Where should I apply the needle?
Nonghyun and the jaw area.
Did you hear that? Give me your hand.
Gosh, you caught a cold
in the middle of summer.
- Hey.
- Hapgok, daechu and gokji.
Pass me the needle.
Come on.
Hand out the drugs to them.
Hey, Mr. Heo!
You'd better go and get some treatment.
You said you had chest pain this morning.
Gosh, how come you're
sleeping so much today?
Who's that silly man you brought here?
Are you going to retire after
putting him in charge of here?
Is it because of the money?
What's this jerk doing here?
Help me, master! Master!
My goodness.
Gosh.
They said it's facial nerve palsy.
He got acupuncture for several days.
However, he hasn't gotten
better and he can't hear well.
He says he hears ringing in the ears.
I don't think it's a
simple facial nerve palsy.
It isn't?
There are many reasons when
a face becomes paralyzed.
We need to take an MRI
scan to know for sure.
Do you want to do that?
Why does he use an MRI scan
for a facial nerve palsy?
We don't use those machines in
the field of oriental medicine.
You once said that oriental medicine
needs to use high technology.
We're done.
Sir.
I don't have anything, so please take this.
What is it?
I got it at the soup kitchen this morning.
You can eat it later. You
don't need to give it to me.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
I appreciate it.
Hey!
- Mr. Heo!
- What's wrong?
- Mr. Heo! Wake up!
- Goodness!
- Gosh, what's the matter?
- Hey! Wake up!
It's just what I thought.
It seems to be an acoustic schwannoma.
What?
Look at this. Here's the auditory nerve.
He got a tumor here. The facial
nerve passes the ear and spreads.
He got a facial palsy
because of the tumor here.
He should get surgery to remove the tumor.
It's necessary to work on facial
palsy before it gets worse.
I can treat it myself.
Thank you.
Hey, come on.
He was talking about his
chest this morning.
What's wrong with him?
It looks like acute indigestion. Let's see.
What's going on? Why are
you holding the needle?
You punk!
Are you going to take him
to the hospital? Come on!
Stay still!
You can go on.
I don't think it's just acute indigestion.
His pulse seems to be different.
Then what's the matter with him?
Well,
I'm not sure...
I knew it.
You're a quack, aren't you?
Be quiet!
Do you know what he ate?
He didn't eat anything. He
drank a lot last night.
He must have had lots of
water as he was thirsty.
His limbs are swollen and cold,
and his stomach feels chilly.
It looks like heoriaemaek.
What is that?
It's when you drink too much water.
It makes your chest feel stuffed
and makes you feel dizzy.
His face is dry and swollen.
It is dark just like he got a bruise.
He breathes raggedly like
he is going to die soon.
That must be Heo Im's method of
treatment that I've only read about.
I'll connect electricity to them to
increase the effect of acupuncture.
Thankfully, the pulse feels better.
His face color has come back to normal.
Gosh, he is alive.
- He's good.
Are you all right?
- He looks better.
- Gosh.
- Thank you.
Are you all right?
Now that I look at him, he's handsome.
What are you doing?
You are so handsome.
Who are you? Why are you doing this?
Me? I'm...
the King of the poor.
- Run!
- Here.
Go.
- Run!
I heard you showed the staffs how
good you are on your first day.
They must have secretly
wanted you to make a mistake.
They must be disappointed.
I didn't do it to show them.
I don't know how you were born to
a useless man like your father.
You must have inherited...
my blood through your mother.
Did you choose the staffs
for the VIP wards?
Yes, I have a plan.
I want to give you something
for saving my father.
But I do not have anything to give you.
So please accept this, Dr. Heo.
You should eat this when you are hungry...
while looking after the patients.
He should have just thanked me with words.
That's a meal for them.
If you don't want that,
why did you act up there?
You were so happy after you saved someone.
When did I...
You were born to be a doctor.
- What?
- Whether it's a palace or a house,
a person who is full or
a person who is hungry,
you feel happy when they live.
It's nice to get them fixed.
That's what doctors do, isn't it?
I need to drop by somewhere.
You should go inside first.
Don't go anywhere else.
Go straight home.
- Yes.
- Go.
Home?
(Haeminseo Oriental Medicine Clinic)
(Haeminseo)
Home.
Gosh.
I did not say I was going to live here.
Heo Bong Tak.
Why are you here at this hour?
Were you thrown out of the
hospital because of me?
I could have been.
But I see that...
you didn't go yet.
Just give me a few days.
Why?
Are you going to come
to the hospital again?
Why did you not tell me beforehand?
If you don't have anywhere to go,
you could stay for a while.
What did you say?
I mean...
Don't go somewhere strange
and cause more problems.
Just stay here instead.
What are these?
It's nothing.
It looks like clothing for people.
Why does it look like this?
- Give it to me.
- I am just curious.
Just let me see.
It's not something you
should be curious about.
What is this for? Just
let me see for a moment.
Choi Yeon Kyung.
Jae Ha, why are you here?
I couldn't get in touch with you.
When I went to the hospital,
they told me you went home.
But I didn't know you would have a guest.
Who is he?
Well,
he's Grandfather's guest.
I came from somewhere far away.
Is he staying here?
Well, for a while?
Did you not say that I could
stay here a few minutes ago?
Why? Does it bother you?
Jae Ha, I'm sorry, but let's
have dinner some other day.
All right.
Bye.
Excuse me.
Go inside.
Why would I be bothered?
He is Heo Im indeed.
I got to see something that
was passed down as a legend.
Come to think of it,
he's not someone I can dare boss around.
Wait a moment, that's Jae Ha.
I thought he was in America.
Did he come to Korea?
Why is his facial expression like that?
He should say hello to me if he came here.
Gosh.
That scum.
Here.
It is meat.
You are here! Please sit down.
We are having meat for dinner.
What did he do to deserve meat?
Dinner's ready. Don't you want to join us?
I'll eat by myself.
Hey.
The woman you were with...
Did she go somewhere?
What are you doing?
I was hungry.
Even after you ate?
I could not eat a lot.
How could you be so awkward
with your grandfather?
I could not eat in such
an awkward situation.
Open the lid.
Put the seasoning in.
Pour water and wait three minutes.
I mean, count to 200.
Is this really noodles?
Go.
All right.
No.
Open the lid and pour water in here.
Plug it in...
and push this button.
Wait after you push the button.
Here. If you do this,
it's tuna ramyeon.
You are trying to send me out
after feeding me this, right?
Eat up.
You should meet him. You don't know...
if you can get something out of him.
Have we...
met somewhere before?
We haven't seen each other before?
Maybe when we were young?
Eat up.
What am I doing?
What am I expecting from someone
who came from 400 years ago?
I feel strangely full.
What is this?
There is a person inside this.
This is...
It is funny.
You should watch and learn.
He went to Seoul Station with the
director to treat the homeless.
He must have been really tired.
You should not judge me...
based on what you heard and saw that day...
to say what kind of life I led.
What is it that I don't know?
Who is he?
The little girl has grown
up and has become a woman.
Time flies.
Does she still like this?
So he met Kyung.
They must be deeply connected.
Bong Tak.
Bong Tak!
What?
I wanted to get some sleep today.
Why is he screaming so loudly?
Heo Bong Tak!
What are you doing?
Hello.
You hair is a little...
But you are the most beautiful
person in the world.
(Most Beautiful Person in the World)
Did you have sweet dreams?
(Sweet Dreams)
The rain sounds so great today.
Is that all he learned?
You should wake up early.
In summer, when it is the most lively,
you need to make sure that the sun
connects well to the energy...
He's even scolding me.
And after you wake up,
you should move your body
to massage its parts...
and wake up your organs.
Let us move our bodies together.
You don't need to clean up when it rains.
Do not say that. You should come out too.
Let us do this together.
Oh, my.
Hey.
Did you forget who you were?
Do you not know that doctors'
hands are like their lives?
What do you think happened overnight?
He must like it here.
Every corner must shine so that
patients would gain strength...
and make doctors feel good.
I did not clean this room.
Oh, my. Hey!
I will do that part.
- I'll do it.
- Gosh.
I am just cleaning up.
That man...
- Was anything strange about him?
- No.
The clinic seems much brighter after
that handsome man has come here.
Brighter? It's gloomy as always.
You were going to go grocery shopping.
Aren't you going?
- I am.
- The room has to shine.
Let me go. Wait.
Everyone likes him now.
Everyone.
Bong Tak.
Bong Tak, Mother is here.
Mother, you are here.
Bong Sik is here too.
Bong Sik.
Bong Tak...
dislikes domestic animals like
chickens and pigs the most.
But look at him now.
He is so talented.
I've never seen her laugh like
that after her son emigrated.
At first, I thought he was useless.
But he seems really nice.
The director scolds him frequently,
but he seems to have
something planned for him.
And you know that he wouldn't take
just anyone to Seoul Station.
Even if he's healthy, he is old.
With Bong Tak by his side, I
feel like I can trust him.
Hey, I brought...
I brought snacks for you.
Snacks?
- Here, Bong Tak.
- Gosh.
- This is...
- Yes?
This is cow bezoar.
This is precious medicine.
Where did you get it?
You should eat it. I have more at home.
When you were young, Bong Tak,
you wanted to have this so much.
How did you...
To give this to my mom...
To save my mom... To save her...
Please give me medicine.
I must save my mom.
Please. Please give me medicine.
Did you steal this from someone?
I did not steal it.
- You little...
- Please give it back.
Will you not stop?
I need to save my mom.
Right.
I know how you feel.
How you feel.
I do know how you feel.
Gosh.
Have this.
I am all right.
No, you have it.
My Bong Tak should have this and cheer up.
Have it.
Good boy.
- Goodness.
- Have this.
It's a bit salty.
Goodness. It's good.
My brother...
must like you.
Bong Sik.
Do you like that woman?
He must really like you.
Bye.
You go that way. I will go this way.
This is my house.
Why would I go that way?
Were you not on your way to somewhere?
Oh, right.
Do you want to go with me?
I need someone to carry stuff for me.
All right.
What does he have in mind?
He cleaned up when I
didn't even ask for it.
Let's see. Will they have...
fresh Korean beef today?
Hey, punk. Where have you been?
Long time no see, Chun Sool.
Try this. It's buy 2 get 1 free.
Let us buy this.
Just one.
Is this all right?
This presses on my acupuncture points.
It releases all my fatigue.
It feels like paradise.
It feels good.
That.
- Do you mean English?
- Yes, the letters.
I have been wondering,
but was this language
created by the descendants?
That's called English.
It's a universal language.
Universal language.
Come to think of it, you
knew how to read Korean.
Who taught you that?
My father taught me the Chinese
letters when I was young.
Then my mother taught me Korean language.
Thanks to my knowledge in Chinese,
I was able to read medical books.
I wondered why I had to learn Korean.
I did not know I would use it in here.
I guess she predicted this to happen.
Don't you think your parents will
be worried about you from there?
They passed away when I was young.
My father passed away on
a road when I was 10.
My mother passed away due to
her illness when I was 12.
The doctor said...
that a cow bezoar would treat her illness.
It seems like cow bezoars
are common in here.
People will not die in
vain like my mother did.
My parents died when I was young too.
Still, you have your grandfather.
He may look ill-tempered on the outside,
but he seems to love his
granddaughter dearly.
I see...
that you have bad feelings
towards your grandfather.
But you have not left that place.
You must still care for...
You've only seen us for a few days.
You should be good to my grandpa.
Don't trouble him.
What?
Are you letting me stay in his house?
I will be good.
(Haeminseo Oriental Medicine Clinic)
You wench, why did you have to
bring me to this shabby place?
Do you want to save your money that bad?
What will you do with the money you saved?
Will you...
be so free and spend all
that money after I die?
Stop complaining.
They say it's well-known
for its treatments.
You wench.
Are you here to visit the oriental clinic?
Oh, my. Well, yes.
Nurse Jung called me.
She heard our circumstances
and recommended this place.
She said I'd meet someone I know there.
It was you.
She's my mother-in-law.
My husband died in an accident,
so I'm taking care of her alone.
She became paraplegic a few years ago.
She can't move an inch without any help.
We've been to hospitals.
She got acupuncture in
several oriental clinics.
But she's not getting any better.
She is old and weak.
I think it will be better to
stick a needle deeply at once.
Do you mind if I try?
Let's wait and see what choice he makes.
Hey.
She's an important patient.
Sir, you can't let him...
Stay still.
She is important.
Please do well.
She's sensing the needle.
Patients feel a twinge when they
sense the needle accurately.
It's like they're electrified.
You did well in enduring the pain.
Here.
- What?
Goodness.
Oh my goodness. Mother.
Oh my goodness. Thank you.
My goodness.
Mother! Mother! Mother!
Mother!
- Oh, no!
- Goodness.
I can't live without her.
Please save my daughter-in-law.
Calm down.
Min Jae.
I think Patient Jo is
suffering a blocked artery.
Thankfully, she's breathing.
Come here with an ambulance.
She told me to get a surgery and
that she could do fine without me.
She insisted so much.
But she fell down while
I was in the hospital.
She hurt her back.
You may think the most important
thing is saving people's lives.
But if something happens
to me during the surgery,
she'll be left alone...
without anyone to rely on.
What? Was there an accident?
- I need to go out.
- What?
- Keep an eye on her.
- Okay.
No...
- My leg...
- Gosh.
My leg.
I think he's really hurt. Are you a doctor?
Yes.
My leg.
Don't move.
Are you okay?
What is wrong?
Is it happening to you again? Look at me!
Someone who appeared in your life recently.
Gosh, you look terrible.
Let us go somewhere so
I can read your pulse.
Whether it is acupuncture or moxa,
I will do everything I can.
It is because of you.
It is all because of you.
After all that I did to get here.
I don't want to see you anymore.
Do not be like this.
Get out of my sight.
Please.
Gosh, that woman.
Get out of my sight.
You'll be staying in
this place if you like.
Why would you...
You mentioned about scouting...
No, recognizing peoples'
talents before, right?
To hire competent people, you
need to offer this much.
Then... Are you saying you will...
You're such a competent person.
You shouldn't be staying in
that shabby oriental clinic.
You came all the way here from Joseon.
Then you should achieve your
goal in a bigger world.
Don't you think so?
Patient Jo's surgery went well.
Okay.
Jae Sook took escorted the
old lady to her house.
I see.
- Well...
- Yes?
What?
Nothing.
I hope he keeps him safe...
and sends him back.
I hope he does.
Get out of my sight, please.
You really don't know?
I don't. He doesn't have a mobile phone.
Can I go home after organizing this?
The director didn't say anything...
and we didn't hear from him for a few days.
Maybe he didn't like this place.
He should have said goodbye
if he was leaving.
- I'm sad.
- You're right.
You feel empty...
when someone leaves.
Were you sad?
Really?
You'll feel sad when I leave.
- Okay.
- How could you feel sad for him?
You only knew him for a few days.
Wait and see when I leave.
Is he here?
(Shinhae Oriental Medicine Hospital)
(The opening ceremony of the VIP ward)
Thank you.
We ambitiously prepared...
the VIP ward of Shinhae
Oriental Medicine Hospital.
Based on our long history
of medical technology...
and excellent personnel,
this ward will become the stepping stone...
of upgrading the level
of oriental medicine,
and become a worldwide
oriental medical center.
Next, Dr. Yoo.
Hello, I'm Yoo Jae Ha.
The players are exceptional here.
Yes.
We still have one more person left.
Really?
He's coming.
I am sorry, I am a little late.
You're just in time.
Okay, introduce yourself.
Nice to meet you.
I am oriental medicine doctor, Heo...
Bong Tak.
(Live Up To Your Name, Dr.
Heo/Deserving of the Name)
Heo Im, you became a different person.
Heo Im came.
What will you do this time?
What does he have to do with you?
I'm getting to know him.
I'm playing games? With whom?
I will walk the path that I could
not walk when I was there.
This must be stress.
Will a strong background win? Or skill?
Why did you let him in
here in the beginning?
I will become a doctor who becomes
happy when he saves lives,
and glad when he heals people.