In The Beginning
Based on a true story
Construction of a hypermarket
This is RPC.
We deal in office equipment.
Could I have the name
of your Logistics Manager
to send a catalogue?
Mr Miller... with 2 Ls.
Philippe Miller.
Can I ask who your supplier is
for equipment rental?
Point P, OK.
Hello.
I work with Philippe Miller from CGI
on the construction
of the hypermarket near Caudry.
Mrs Blondel gave me your name.
We need a tacheometer.
A GTS 239.
You got one?
Your surveyor know this one?
Yeah, I think so.
- When will you return it?
- End of the week.
Can you sign for it?
I'll be right back.
200 for the monitors,
500 for the instrument, OK?
These are a big hit.
I bought 'em
in Slovakia.
They're rolling in it.
Fake pay slips.
I sell 'em to illegal aliens
along with rent slips.
So they can draw benefit.
It sells well.
Hello. This is BBL.
We rent office equipment.
Can I have the name
of your Logistics Manager?
Mr...?
Sorry, it's noisy in my office.
Thank you, ma'am.
Construction of Highway 61a
There were beetles everywhere.
So, the ecologists got
the construction stopped.
They staged demonstrations.
It was pretty scary.
Are you from CGI, too?
A guy from your firm
came last year.
He met with all the people
who'd lost their jobs.
He left and never came back.
I think it scared him.
Where can I buy cigarettes?
It's too late now around here.
I can help you out.
- Thanks. Here...
- It's OK, keep them.
I'm Monika. Goodnight.
You don't need anything else?
Oh, yes, there's a wedding,
so it may be a bit noisy.
That's all he said?
He said he's here
for the road works.
Shit!
Give me a hand here.
Tonight's my night off.
Lots of girls
would jump at the chance.
- Put it back.
- It's gross!
You're the one who cleans the floor!
Go on, get in there.
And don't sulk.
It has nothing to do with the guests.
I don't believe this!
What the hell!
You had stuff stolen, too?
And they've wrecked the door.
Oh, I don't believe it!
What about your car?
Same here.
- Come on.
- I'll join you.
Reception here.
There are 2 people to see you.
Did they say who they are?
I'm not pressing charges.
Should I ask if
it's the police?
I'm coming.
The 2 gentlemen
are in the dining room.
Go straight through.
Hello.
Do you have 5 minutes?
For a coffee.
- What can I get you?
- A coffee.
The manager of this place
is an old friend.
He told us
you arrived last night.
We decided
to come and see you directly.
Patrick and I
run a tool rental company here.
Since the work stopped 2 years ago,
we've had a really rough time.
We thought we had a chance
of getting the contract.
We got into debt
to buy new machines,
hire drivers, mechanics...
And at the last moment,
your predecessor
chose our rivals.
It was a disaster for us, of course.
Later on, we understood.
The site manager
worked in a rather...
He wanted something from us
he didn't get,
so we didn't do business.
He expected a pretty big "'discount"'.
So, if the work does restart,
we don't want to lose out again.
Sure.
We'd be prepared to go
as far as 15%/% "'discount"'.
15%/%?
15%/% of the total amount.
That's a tidy sum in cash.
But it's up to you to tell us...
I see you've met.
We were discussing the beetles.
What a nightmare!
Those little beetles
decimated the whole region.
Thanks.
It's only that big,
but it's wiped out hundreds of jobs.
So, how long are you staying?
A day or two, no more.
You're just...
Just doing a status report.
That's something,
'cause they never cleaned up. See it?
Yeah.
Is your room alright?
Not too much noise last night?
Sorry about your car.
It's only a window.
We'll leave you our card.
I'll add the cell number.
Hi.
I owe you these.
No need.
Time for a coffee?
5 minutes?
You work on Sundays, too?
Sometimes.
Been out and about?
- Coffee, please.
- Same here.
Normally, there are
less people at the fair.
He won't stop crying.
Philippe - Nicolas and Esteban.
Hello.
- Try the carousel.
- Too busy.
- Not seen Corinne?
- No.
I'll go, then.
Go with Mommy.
See you later.
You staying here? Back soon.
Can I sit here?
There were some things
in the car I want back.
The fake phone cards?
Can't even sell 'em.
You tried?
You a cop?
You afraid of cops?
And you?
You're the talk of the town.
That you're here for the highway.
They don't waste any time.
Not with 25%/% unemployment here,
they don't.
I can't find Corinne.
Let's go, then.
To the carousel?
I'll get this.
I owe you that much.
Hello. Mr Miller from CGI here.
We met at the hotel earlier on.
I've thought it over.
Yes, you know, our agreement.
The money in cash...
I have to leave tonight for Lille.
Is tonight not possible?
Tomorrow morning?
OK...
Very well.
Is it working?
Can you hear me?
First of all, some cars
are badly parked.
They're blocking the road.
Please move them as soon as possible.
Hello, everyone.
Thank you for coming...
Thank you, everyone, for coming.
This year, the Town Hall
has joined forces
with the neighboring towns
for the raffle
to raise money for the elderly.
Let's now see
what the children have been up to.
This year, they were asked to create
costumes made entirely
from recyclable materials.
The winner of this competition
who will be known
as the Recycling King - or Queen -
will win a CD player
provided by the Town Hall.
The kids will come up one at a time.
Give them a big hand.
- Some mulled wine.
- Thanks.
It's not great!
Did you reach an agreement?
We'll see.
They're good guys.
You'll come to an understanding.
This is Mr Miller.
You're eagerly awaited, you know.
He arrived last night.
I'm fully aware of that.
I'm Stéphane.
Let's go somewhere quieter.
People look happy, don't they?
If I tell them who you are,
they'll ask you to go on stage.
Should I tell them? No?
They won't eat you!
Let's go to the Town Hall.
I'll tell Michel.
I'll shut the door.
Sit yourself down.
We do weddings here.
Don't be scared!
We're really pleased to see you.
So, you're here to do a status report?
That's right.
OK. And what exactly does that mean?
I meet people...
I see how things are going.
Try to see clearly...
That kinda thing.
They didn't tell us 2 years ago
that work would stop.
Now they don't tell us it might restart.
Very strange.
I understand.
Well, I do what I'm told.
You know, it's...
You mustn't...
What are you told?
To come and see how...
in what condition the site is in...
To meet people...
Have you seen the site?
Of course.
There was the drainage problem.
It's not building land, so that's...
That's nothing to worry about.
It's not a problem.
In any case,
they haven't forgotten us.
That's good.
- No...
- So, there's hope.
I'm afraid I can't stay.
We've had to
provide access for the farmers
who work the land.
Don't forget the farmers.
Could you take
the new plans back with you?
I'll go get the copies.
I'm sorry...
but I really can't stay.
How can we reach you?
Can you leave your card?
I have nothing on me.
Someone broke into my car last night.
I'm very sorry.
We don't know how to contact you.
Are you staying in the area?
Philippe, can't you go after him?
- He's gone?
- Yes.
He just follows orders.
He's not in charge.
He can't say too much, but
he's here for a reason.
They could at least send
someone competent.
Maybe there are things he can't tell us.
The jerk was lost for words.
Don't say that.
You sound like a tribunal.
Where's he come from?
He's from Head Office,
but he does look lost.
He seems very dull,
unable to string a sentence together.
A bit pathetic.
- Got anything else?
- No.
I want to ask you something.
I know it's not done...
It's my résumé.
I thought
you might be hiring people.
Times are hard.
You did 3 years at college?
Yeah, I'm still refunding the loan.
I got a technical sales diploma.
Then, I did some bookkeeping
in a garage.
Why stay in this hole?
It didn't use to be a hole.
And I was born here,
and there's Nicolas and the kid...
I'm not going to move
to go in search of work
or we'll all live in China.
And I work in the sugar refinery
during the beet harvest.
I just do shitty jobs
in shopping malls and such.
That's life.
You coming down for dinner?
No, I have work to do.
I can bring something.
I'm not hungry.
You won't mention my résumé?
Don't worry.
Goodnight.
There'll be more next time.
- How much is there?
- 5,000.
It's all we could get so fast.
Is that OK for now?
That's OK.
Here's a list of our equipment.
It corresponds
to what was needed last time.
We can give you
further info by phone.
I'll phone you.
Sorry about yesterday.
It wasn't very...
But people here suffered.
If every supplier does this,
you'll rake in a small fortune.
Here are details of a friend
who rents vans.
He's open to discussion, too.
Keep in touch.
That guy left this for you.
Why did he give you that?
I don't know.
They didn't charge him...
D'you sleep with him?
We need the money.
No, I didn't.
Not everyone is a slimeball.
Yeah, sure!
Mr Miller?
I was not impressed.
- I...
- Who d'you think you are?
People like you...
think you can judge me!
Listen.
I travel a lot.
I meet a lot of people.
People like you are alone.
You look all alone.
Mr Miller, please don't go.
I'm just a jerk!
- Don't go.
- Ajerk, isn't that right?
He was sleeping.
Thanks, Corinne. I'm sorry.
Is Nicolas home?
He's not back...
I'll stay with you.
Go to sleep now.
One day, the cops
will find him dead somewhere.
He has good shit though!
That's the problem.
Yeah, that's the problem!
Don't worry, we'll build that highway
and get the hell outta here.
To highways!
Initially, I just need to establish
a base to prepare things.
A base?
You mean a platform
at the entrance
to store the machines,
equipment, etc?
Yeah, a platform.
Do you have the plans
or should we use the old ones?
- We should go take a look.
- Sure.
Ah, the coffee!
What's the link between CGI and you?
I know they keep
adding subsidiaries, but...
It all belongs to CGI.
You have agreements
with the holding company.
My associates and I try
to have a structure
that's flexible enough
to let us stay in touch
with grass-roots reality.
You're not GTM?
You're GMT.
GMT R. "'R"' for "'roads"'.
Jamel handles schedules.
CGI has 1,700 subsidiaries
with branches all over the world.
And it keeps changing.
They asked me to do this,
among other things.
It's a tough task.
But we're here to help.
But civil engineering in France
is a headache
for companies like ours.
It's true,
it's so closely monitored nowadays.
In fact, we lose money on it.
Is that right?
We don't know
about that kind of thing.
We're just struggling to survive.
What about your equipment needs?
We'll need a copy
of the schedule asap.
First, I want to see
your estimation.
You must have quotes and plans?
Here you are.
If you need more equipment,
we'll manage.
OK.
But in the meantime,
how do we get in touch with you?
We don't have a thing.
Do you have a card?
Look at the state
it was delivered in.
Let's call Michel -
he'll reprint it in no time.
He'll be interested
in working with you.
He can reuse the logo.
What're you doing
for lunch, Mr Miller?
Call me Philippe.
This is it.
It was a packaging firm.
Now it belongs to the town,
but we can't afford to refurbish it.
The site isn't far. I thought...
I don't know what you need.
It's not too run-down.
Even a kitchen...
We'll help you clean up.
I'll see to the power
and insurance.
Why did they leave?
They relocated to Croatia.
Can't you do anything?
What can we do?
Near here, there was
a textiles factory. 800 jobs.
The boss went to India
with the machines and our subsidies.
We're left with the jobless.
I phoned your office.
They didn't tell me.
They couldn't find you.
I have little contact with them.
I said I was a mayor
concerned by the project.
I just got
one voice mail after another.
Happens all the time.
Especially with me.
We tried in vain
to sue them 2 years ago.
The main thing is, you're back.
You have to give priority
to local firms.
The suppliers, hotels...
I'm counting on you.
Going well, isn't it?
Just fine.
They've suffered.
I know.
You know...
Call me on this number.
There you are.
The CGI's offices were 15 miles away.
We never saw them.
People will be reassured
that you're here.
See you soon.
- Call me, OK?
- Sure.
ACCOUNTS
Hi, how are you?
He hired you?
I don't know. We're helping out
for now, then we'll see.
So, with the drivers,
that makes a team of 34 people.
Here are their résumés.
We could have a global wages contract
with payment at 90 days.
Then, we'll see.
What can you give me on that?
Patrick said your rate is 15%/%.
Can you get it by Friday?
In cash?
The more people you hire,
the higher the commission
for both of us?
Of course.
We need people to direct
heavy vehicles at junctions.
You need to contact
the agency direct.
Sorry...
The Town Hall asked him
to hire locals,
so try your luck.
What do you do?
I'm a driver, but I'm not sure
I want to do it.
Hello, this is GMTR
about the work resuming.
Mr Miller asked me to call you
to draw up the rental contracts.
It's payment at 90 days.
No, not 30 days.
Yes, Mr Miller spoke to them.
Rosemonde here will be helping out.
She's a retired secretary.
I thought she'd be useful.
Have you worked in construction?
Yes, a bit.
Thank you, sir.
This is your desk.
All the papers are here.
- Who's his foreman?
- The one in charge.
- There's just temps.
- That's weird.
I won't give him 10%/% in advance.
Nor me.
I got taken for a ride before.
I'll pick up the contract
from your office.
Nice car...
I've been loaned it for now.
Why for now?
Can you sign these?
And who do I call
to get the company checkbooks?
They'll be here.
Do I call the agency for an advance?
I don't deal with that.
The agency writes the checks.
Thanks.
No need for a tie.
I'm meeting Mr Miller.
Are you the foreman?
- Louis.
- Nicolas.
Is he here?
Over there.
We're better off here
than where they were 2 years ago.
We'll get the Town Hall
to redirect the minor road.
Never worked with GMTR.
Where were you before?
Drop the chitchat, OK?
Whatever you say.
I spent a long time abroad.
Tell us what to do
or I'll make suggestions.
Fine by me.
Hurry up, we're running late.
More champagne!
- Where's the boss?
- He'll be here.
What's going on?
They're getting ready for Monday.
They're giving you a warm welcome.
It's party time!
Speech! Speech!
I'm not very good at making speeches.
A big thank you...
to the suppliers.
And also...
that...
I just want to say thank you
to Mr Miller
for all he's done for us,
for the local firms...
Since work stopped 2 years ago,
things have been hard.
Many of you felt abandoned
and were losing hope.
Now you've found fresh hope
and you feel, as I do,
that there is a path,
a way... a highway!
You get there quicker!
And it'll lead us to a better future.
A road is always the start
of an adventure.
And I hope that this second chance
will be the right one.
To second chances!
Am I disturbing you?
No.
I wanted to thank you,
but I thought it'd embarrass you.
Men like me
are no good at politics.
You do realize that I'm a woman?
My job...
has very little to do with politics.
I just try to help people
as best I can.
This is the road
in cross-section, in slices...
The first stage is the machines
scraping the surface.
The soil...
Then we treat the earth.
And we put asphalt on top.
How many people, in the end? 40?
- About 50.
- Good.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Someone to see you.
Know what they used to write
on old nautical charts?
There was a line
and it said: "'Beyond this limit,
we enter unknown territory"'.
See you soon.
Want a drink?
No, thank you.
- Do I sign everything?
- Yes.
Where's your family?
I have a son and an ex-wife.
Does she work?
Why do you ask?
Don't know.
The problems start
when you lose your job.
Let's just say...
we've drifted apart.
That all you'll say?
Doesn't matter.
Weather forecast?
Stable till tonight.
Start excavation work
over 100 yards.
Get to it before the storm comes.
Construction of Highway 61a
They've made good progress.
The slopes are done and all.
Hi. Alright?
Pascal. Works with me.
Here's the schedule.
2 men didn't come today.
I replaced them,
but I asked Monika to find others.
It's gonna be tight.
Let's take a look.
Louis, is it OK to park there?
The parking lot's back there.
The plans don't correspond to ours.
I suggest we use ours,
'cause if we wait,
the rain will be here by tonight
or tomorrow morning.
It's very slimy clay.
So, the vehicles will get stuck
and we'll have to stop work.
Is that OK?
I'll be right back.
Gaby!
You OK, guys?
Pascal, call the water company.
- What did you do?
- Dunno.
No, it's water, not gas.
Looks like we hit a pipe.
What do we do?
We need pumps.
Got any pumps?
C'mon, men, go get water pumps.
I have a form for you to sign
for the water pumps.
It's urgent. There's a flood.
We need to talk.
- Still no checkbooks?
- Keep giving out order forms.
The small firms can't wait.
Tell 'em to call me.
You're hard to reach.
Hey, guys!
Come eat with us.
I got an appointment.
He didn't say
if he wanted weekly meetings?
No.
Isn't it strange
that no-one's come from CGI?
He said they're coming next week.
Well, we'll see.
Why have you stayed a foreman?
I get paid nice n' regular.
I got enough trouble
with a wife n' kids.
How do I get hired?
Look n' learn. We'll see.
Let's go.
It'll start raining any minute.
It's Louis. We hit a water pipe.
It's like a lake here.
We've lost 2 days.
I've added a pump.
The first was too small.
Do you think
we should go around it?
What do you think?
I think we should.
It's sunny now, but it won't last.
It's gonna pour soon.
We'll do that?
OK, I'll deal with it.
See you.
I left you 3 messages.
The suppliers agreed
to be paid at 90 days.
That's 3 months.
What date's that?
November 28.
So, officially,
we don't owe anything till then.
Should I write it down?
No, it's OK.
What time do you finish?
Around midnight.
It's OK.
I just have to get into the groove.
I'm quitting soon, anyway.
You should've told me.
Don't worry, it's my problem.
Will you give Nicolas a job?
It'd calm him down.
If you're alone at night,
you can call us.
Bye... boss!
Article 215: The spouses
share in their estate.
Lastly, the parents
consult their child
on decisions
which concern him or her.
So, Barbara and Michel,
I wish you every happiness.
You can kiss now!
I went to the site.
They said you had an appointment.
Probably.
Do you go home at weekend?
Rarely.
With all that traveling,
don't you get lonely?
It's only for a while.
You do it to earn money,
then you move on.
If you can...
Are you from here?
Oh, no, my parents are from Lyon.
I came here with my husband.
Actually, I'm a widow.
It's been 5 years now.
My husband was the mayor.
I was in charge of the charities
and I bred horses.
When he died,
people asked me to take over.
My daughter studied far away,
so I did.
You live alone?
Yes, I try to. And you?
No...
No, I...
You like to scare people, don't you?
It's your thing, huh?
Do I scare you?
I don't know. Just enough...
This way.
You can go the other way,
but I like this way.
It's from a Russian icon.
Well, we're not really sure.
We're carrying out research.
Or rather I am,
because no-one else cares.
It's not very valuable,
but it's better here than in a museum.
It makes a change
from neighborhood quarrels.
I like coming here.
It has something.
Who pays for all this?
The local communities.
It doesn't matter.
Why do you always ask
who pays?
Do you like the colors?
I wouldn't know.
I'm supposed to have stopped...
I like to smoke when it's cold.
Do you want to...
There's a bowling alley...
A bowling alley!
You want to take me bowling?!
Isn't that a bit crazy?
You like bowling, do you?
I never go.
I was just saying...
I've never met anyone like you.
Mom?
I'm in my room, honey.
I'm with Denis.
I'm taking the car. Bye.
Bye.
It's all fake...
We'll have to stop tomorrow.
It's not in the estimate
or the schedule.
It's decision time.
I'll tell you tonight, OK?
You said that last time.
It's your responsibility.
It's me.
I wanted to talk to you.
To say I feel good with you.
I won't hurt you.
What's going on?
I tried to repair the car.
I cut my hand.
Then, my cell fell in the water.
It's pissing blood.
What're you doing here?
You asked me to get fencing
to put in front of the office.
It's all in the trunk,
but the car broke down.
Got a cloth?
I'll bleed all over.
- Should I call a doctor?
- No, it's OK.
Thanks.
It's not serious.
Monika's a bit in love with you.
I don't think she is.
Not surprising, with all that's happened
since you came.
Funny thing,
changing people's lives, huh?
Don't you think?
The kid isn't my son.
I love him, but he's not mine.
I don't know
who or where his dad is.
He did a runner
when Monika was pregnant.
I do what I can to help.
My dad
spent his life telling me
I was a useless idiot.
He died
before I could spit in his face.
What do you want to say?
Your scams with the suppliers
are no business of ours.
No-one'll come asking about it.
As long as we get paid,
we don't care.
It's better than nothing.
What do you want?
Dough?
Money?
I don't give a shit about money.
I know where to find it.
What counts is
that we all achieve something.
You understand that?
Or you wouldn't be here.
What're you gonna do?
Get your gun out? Then what?
Where will you go?
Sit down. Let's have a drink...
Sorry about that.
Finally!
Feel better?
We're trying to have a baby.
Think I'd make a good father?
Be honest.
"'Boss"'!
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
A big crowd tonight.
Over 300 people. Thank you
for coming to the grand final.
It shows how interested you are
in handball.
Before we start...
Before we start the game,
I want you to give
a very warm welcome
to the mayors
of tonight's two towns.
Mr Jaudon,
Mayor of Barsac
and Mrs Stéphane Arnaud
of St Berto!
A big hand!
Sports events like these
would not go ahead
without sponsors.
I call on Mr Barracher,
Manager of the Banque Populaire.
Last but not least,
Mr Philippe Miller of GMTR.
As you know,
he has restarted the road works.
He's the man who saved us.
Mr Philippe Miller
of GMTR!
It's now time for the game.
Give a big hand to the two teams!
I'm from the paper.
I keep calling you.
You must give some time
for the article I'm writing.
I didn't think it'd go like this.
It's not what I planned.
What do you mean?
What did you plan?
You don't plan things -
you let them happen.
Did you just need me
for your damn road works?
Is that all this was about?
This feels wrong.
I think you've lived alone too long.
I've wasted so much time.
The guy with the water pump
wants a check or cash.
The order forms won't work anymore.
People are talking.
They don't want
to be conned again.
I won't let 'em down.
What about those damn checkbooks?
Where's Nicolas?
He didn't come home last night.
- I'll call him.
- It doesn't concern you. Enough!
Hello. I'm Mr Barracher
from the Banque Populaire.
OK!
Come with me.
It's quicklime,
to dry out the ground.
Mind your eyes now.
Then, it hardens
and the road rollers can get to work.
Then, the asphalt.
I'll show you.
Your first time?
Yes. I usually visit small farms.
Look at this.
If it rains now,
we have to start over.
I don't understand. Your company
is a subsidiary of a huge group.
Yeah.
I run a little country branch.
I know nothing about all that.
I'm not talking
about the project as a whole.
Just a small temporary problem
of petty cash.
Wait a minute...
Your company
must have a bank, accounts...
There's a whole structure.
Yes, but in the meantime,
I still don't have a checkbook. Sugar?
Can you give me a ballpark figure?
It's not a great deal.
The electricity bill,
office supplies...
Around 25,000 euros.
Yes, proportionally, that's not much.
So, you just want to open an account
to pay your immediate expenses.
It's a cash flow problem.
Exactly.
What about the wages?
No, the agency deals with that.
There's no problem with that
till the 28th.
You saw the site
yet I can't even write checks for fuel!
Indeed.
Like the others, it's in my interest
to do business with you.
And I must admit it's exciting
to be part of such a big adventure.
What do you need
to open an account?
As with any company,
a trade register certificate,
an ID card,
and an initial transfer of funds.
But the transfer is the same problem
as the checkbook.
Well, in the meantime,
as the sums aren't very big,
we can offer invoice discounting.
That just buys you a few weeks.
The legal limit is 2 months, but...
You present us with your bills,
and we'll honor them.
It solves a firm's
cash flow problems.
Not that companies like yours
are strapped for cash!
That's good.
With the gasoline
and lighting, that's the total.
Call me if you need me.
37,000 euros?
Your car costs more than that!
I'll get things started,
but I need your company ID number.
That's very important, OK?
Thank you again.
Have lunch with us... for once.
How long will it take to dry?
2 days, provided it doesn't rain,
but it could well do.
I can't wait 2 days.
I thought of something last night.
If the embankments
are 8 instead of 10,
that's 20,000 cubic yards
less earth to move.
If you can do 50 rotations
instead of 35,
we save a week.
If we use more, won't it dry faster?
We can try.
The 28th!
We have to finish by the 28th.
Come on!
Hello. Philippe Miller here.
No, I have the bill
right in front of me.
A total of 1 1 ,630.
I'll do it as quickly as possible.
You have my word.
2,125 euros.
When it rains,
we can't get anything done.
Hello. This is Mr Miller here.
There's a problem
with the checkbook.
The start of next week
at the latest.
No, it's not
in my own best interest.
We'll do what's necessary.
And I'll handle it myself.
Look what he's just sent.
That's no good, it's not an original.
- Should I call him back?
- Yes, do.
- Did you send his checkbooks?
- Yes.
Look at that.
Isn't it something?
I'll take you. It's worth seeing.
Now you'll stop saying
we're not a regular firm.
You've spent far more than you said.
I still have to pay for fuel.
It's gonna be a problem.
Call Louis, tell him I'm on my way.
Off we go.
- Can you sign this?
- Later.
There's been a mistake.
You were sent a fax.
Yeah, I'll deal with it.
The other thing is, I've just checked
your first statement.
I have it here.
This isn't at all what we agreed.
I can't hear you.
It's too noisy.
I'll call you back.
As soon as you can. Goodbye.
- It's starting to look like something.
- Like a road!
Let's go have coffee.
Excuse me... Hello.
You know they buried the Pharaohs
with a beetle on their chest?
No, I didn't.
One of my men told me today.
I had no idea.
Did you work all night?
I didn't hear you leave.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
I want you.
I think about it all the time.
All the time.
I didn't know
you could feel this way.
Love you.
Come on, guys!
The owner of the scooter
may not press charges.
I didn't even damage it.
Sign here.
Will you ever stop messing up?
Did you give the cops
my number?
They can get that anywhere.
I just said I worked for you.
It was the magic word.
Bunch of jerks!
All that for a stupid scooter...
I don't deal anymore,
just deliver.
I threw it all away
before the cops got me.
I don't know how I'll pay for it.
They say, after prison,
you wanna take on the world.
Maybe that's what I need.
After prison, you're all alone.
You'd shoot yourself
rather than go back inside.
Put that on plates
and spread them out.
Is there a dance?
You lower the blade
to scoop up the earth.
It's called a scraper.
That's the safety. Like that,
it won't start.
Gaby, I want Nicolas
to demonstrate the excavator.
We'll show you how it works.
Thanks, Gaby.
- Esteban, up you go.
- I don't have a license!
Step back, kids.
Give him a big hand!
Nicolas! Nicolas!
The kids have a surprise.
Don't worry, I won't damage it.
Finish practising with Gaby.
Then, you can join the night crew.
How's that?
Day or night's fine by me.
That's OK with me.
How's that, then?
There are things about my life
you don't know.
You can start a new life.
That's what life's for.
I haven't wanted to settle down
in a long time.
It'd make me very happy.
The bank manager rang all day.
To hell with him. He's nobody.
Who'll pay for all this?
He's rejected
our most recent checks.
All the suppliers are yelling at me.
I'm sick of it.
I'm trying to help you.
Look how beautiful it is.
You don't realize what's happening.
If it was going to stop,
we'd know by now.
Why should it stop?
C'mon, guys, c'mon!
DO NOT OPEN
Project Manager of Highway 61a
Come along with me, Nicolas.
Leave a message.
This is Mr Barracher from the bank.
I keep leaving you messages.
I have to say
that unless you sort out
the paperwork,
I'll have to consult my superiors.
I think it's deplorable
that it's come to this.
This cannot continue,
so please call me back very soon.
What about these 2 checks?
What can I do?
He'll only open an account elsewhere.
I believed in this guy.
I believed in him.
C'mon, guys, c'monI
When did this happen?
They took the petty cash.
Why do people do this?
How am I supposed to work now?
The printer's gone.
Don't throw these away.
They're important.
No, we have no idea.
Last month,
they wrecked a school.
So, what now?
Do you need papers?
We've seen the damage.
Now you must come file a complaint.
You're here?
I'm working.
One of your employees
is a familiar face. That boy.
He works for us.
It's not him.
Well, goodbye.
The police said
you won't file a complaint.
Why's that?
I don't have time.
Not anymore.
It's not that bad. Come here.
What is it?
I have to go.
I'll let you know, Mrs Arnaud.
Come with me.
Someone to see you.
Is this a bad time?
The bastards!
They did it last night?
Wow!
You told the insurer?
Yes, but they'll take ages
to pay out.
I can't work without a computer.
Should I call you boss?
I met a lot of locals,
looking for you.
They call you the big boss,
Mr Philippe.
"'Mr"' Philippe...
How did you find me?
Someone saw you on TV,
showing off.
You ain't exactly discreet.
What exactly is all this crap?
What do you want? Money?
Dough!
Bread!
The car and all the rest you took
makes a lot of bread.
You steal a lot of bread
off these folk?
I'm not doing it for the money.
Why do you do it, then?
Why?
You know that Claude left me?
You caused me a lot of trouble.
I won't let you mess things up.
So, you might as well kill me now.
That's what I'm doing.
Here...
I found this little beetle
on your site.
I've got some, but not all of them.
So long.
I heard the news.
Is everything in the box?
Monika can call me.
What's the time?
Forty past ten.
Monika said
you haven't paid for the fuel.
I want to finish before it rains.
Is it going to rain?
We'll run out of gas in a few hours.
34,000.
Hurry it up!
The gas is coming.
What else has to be paid for?
The lighting.
He wants cash.
He won't wait till the 28th.
Give them that for now.
What's going on?
I can sell you another car.
There's 10,000.
Now can you wait a week?
No, Mr Miller,
it's a matter of trust.
What more do you need
to let us work?
Please calm down.
Come into my office.
- I don't have time.
- Mr Miller!
What do I have to do?
I rang his firm, CGI.
They didn't even know
the work had resumed.
I'll call her back and find out.
Does your boss know?
At first, he was so proud
to be a part of it.
Now he's afraid he'll be asked
to explain himself.
Did you call the cops
about the break-in?
He won't file a complaint.
And he's bought new stuff.
He can't write checks.
I don't know
where he gets the money.
We'll soon find out.
I don't want to land in shit again.
- I gotta go to work.
- Now?
I'm working
from 9 PM to 5 AM.
Goodnight.
There's 10,000.
All that for 10,000 shitty euros.
It's all I have left.
What next? You gonna pay 'em back
all the money you stole?
Your project's just hot air.
You'll go down for 10 years
and hang yourself in your cell.
Work is a fool's game,
I always said so.
I'm going to pay a little visit
to your friend, the lady mayor.
It'll give her a shock
when I spill the beans, won't it?
2 days... I'll give you 2 days.
You know where to reach me.
Does it hurt?
I just want to finish my job.
Want to see a doctor?
I've done some bad things in life.
You need to rest.
We'll make it.
I know we will.
You can't carry on like this.
Look at them.
We'll make it.
Stéphane, there are worrying rumors
about the highway.
False and unpaid invoices,
trafficking...
I hope
we haven't been helping a crook.
What does he stand to gain from it?
You were seen with that guy.
People talk.
You were happy to have
your picture taken with "'that guy"'.
C'mon, guys!
It's stopped raining.
We might finish tomorrow night.
Finish what?
The road.
I don't want you to lie to me.
There's nothing more humiliating.
You've never been truly humiliated.
I can't give up now.
It's too late.
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it's real.
Why?
Because it was possible.
With me, too?
We've done something extraordinary.
Known Philippe long?
His real name's Paul.
Been on jobs together?
His name's Paul... Paulo.
I know that.
Hello. Good timing.
I'm with your little protégé!
I've got the cash.
Hang on, I can't hear you.
Where can we meet?
Here. I'm at the Jack Pots.
I don't wanna be seen with you.
There's a sugar refinery nearby.
- Stay a while.
- I'm on the night shift.
Wait.
Can you get me some gear?
I hear you're the man.
You heard wrong.
Hello. Police.
His car is in the parking lot.
No-one cleaned his room?
We didn't want to disturb him.
Should I call the police?
Philippe, it's Monika.
It's Nicolas.
Bring some black coffee.
We looked all over for you.
Looks like you've done that
all your life.
It seems ages ago.
I'll get the coffee
or it'll take hours.
I saw your pal earlier.
He was leaving.
He looked rough.
We need you on site, Philippe.
We can't do anything without you.
Can you stop for a minute?
What's going on?
I'm pregnant.
We've been trying for a long time.
It worked at last.
- We wanted to tell you first.
- We're happy.
Congratulations.
I spoke to the agency
this morning.
Your wages will be paid
as usual on Friday.
Don't listen to gossip.
We have a job to finish.
We'll finish it together.
Well, we'll try.
- The beer's on me.
- Thanks.
- I'll go talk to the night crew.
- Bye.
We'll take his word for it.
We have no choice.
We have to trust him.
There's always rumors flying around.
Rival firms try to mess things up.
We have mouths to feed.
If you work and don't get paid,
they're thieves, not bosses.
We've had a bill for a firm called GMTR.
Heard of them?
What's the bill?
Legrand, plant hire.
83,000 euros.
How much?!
Whose signature is this?
These are the latest plans.
Coffee?
What do you think?
- Well?
- Not good. Rain is forecast.
Let's protect these embankments.
They're the most exposed.
Why don't we protect them to here?
Yeah, we can try.
What if there's heavy rain?
Then, we're dead.
You've reached Legrand.
We're open from 8.;30 to 1 2.;30
and from 1.;30 to 6.
Please leave a message.
This is the Accounts Dept. at CGI.
We have an order form
from GMTR.
It means nothing to us.
Please call me back.
I'm Mr Valais.
The number is 01 75 77 77 77.
Thanks, bye.
Here's another one.
Same signature.
What's he playing at?
Hello, Mr Legrand here.
You left me a message
about an invoice for Highway 61 .
I deal with someone
from your company. Or rather, GMTR.
Yes, that's right. Philippe Miller.
What?
The agency sent the wages.
It's the last time, Philippe.
On Monday,
the bills'll be unpaid.
We'll have finished then.
Try to stall them with that.
Here...
Come on, move it.
Move all this!
C'mon, guys, we gotta finish!
Here, Lionel.
Frédéric.
- Thanks.
- Come with me.
Louis, he'll be in charge
of an excavator tonight.
We must finish tonight.
I just spoke to the people at CGI.
They said
you gave me a false order form,
that there's no construction
in the area.
The work doesn't exist.
So, none of this exists?
I think it does exist.
They're your machines.
So, I don't exist either?
You're talking to no-one!
No-one!
Here, Bernard.
Let's go to your office.
If it doesn't rain,
we'll finish tonight. What do you want?
Want us to stop?
Guys, we gotta finish tonight.
So, who wants to carry on?
We carry on!
There we go, the discussion's over.
Hello. I'm Daniel Barraux,
Operations Manager.
I didn't understand my assistant...
Let me explain.
You're one of our works managers?
Not exactly.
There...
In the beginning,
there was a beetle problem.
A what?
A beetle.
In 90 days, we've managed
to go from here...
to here.
If it doesn't rain,
we should finish tonight.
Finish what?
You've built a section of highway?
It'll be daylight in 3 hours.
You went to CGI today?
What did they say?
They said they trusted us.
It mustn't rain.
It should even end up
costing less than a normal project.
What do you mean, "'normal project"'?
Where's this road?
Where does it go?
I don't know.
Nowhere.
Don't forget your seat belt.
How did you get this paperwork?
I just did.
I'll tell 'em to stop.
We keep going!
- It's too dangerous.
- We keep going!
I just want you to save my team.
Because they trusted me.
And because it's not their fault.
I don't really matter.
I was lucky to have met them.
I was lucky...
- Hang on...
- It hurts!
It's stuck!
There's gasoline!
Don't leave me!
Nicolas!
Over there!
He's upstairs?
We have to call the police.
He's behind all the false order forms.
We must file a complaint.
He came of his own accord.
Are those his papers?
He's done a runner.
What has he left behind?
Thank you, boss
We have to file a complaint.
An unconscious burns victim
for shock treatment.
Sit down.
What'll they do to him?
He shouldn't have been on his own.
He won't die?
Leave us alone.
Miss?
It's alright.
He has extensive burns,
but he'll be OK.
Gaby, don't!
You fucker!
Fucker!
Crook!
Sorry about that, boss.
Why did you do this to us?
Scumbag!
- Sir.
- Well?
He was at the hospital 2 hours ago.
- What name do you know him by?
- Philippe Miller.
- Is he armed?
- No idea.
- Stop him by dawn.
- We'll try.
This is the place, sir.
I think he's long gone.
After his last prison term,
"'Philippe Miller"'disappeared.
No-one knows where he is.
When the "'real"' work resumed,
all the workers and suppliers
were rehired or compensated.
Only the temping agency
filed a complaint.
GMTR's work was deemed
to be in conformity
by the Highways Department.
The beetles were moved
to a nearby forest.