1st night
Excuse me, can I make the room?
Lady?
Excuse me?
Are you from here?
2nd night
Good morning.
It's cheap, 5 euros.
The lighter too.
No.
- The belts, they're cheap.
- No.
Grenadine, mint...
Almond milk?
Lemon. Almond milk.
That wouldn't be bad.
How about with gas?
And water with gas, perhaps.
That way we'll taste it.
Yes, yes!
A passion juice.
Don't you prefer pear?
Yes, pear.
One pear juice.
In Sylvie's city
A wallet.
Cheap.
A lighter? A lion?
It's cheap, 5 euros.
I didn't order that.
I want juice.
This is aggressive.
Isn't sending it back too?
I'd have coffee.
I ordered something else.
Do you realize what
you have ordered?
We've finally decided.
You ordered this, and
I've brought it to you.
No, no.
I have: A juice...
Well...
Yes, well...
Well, leave the coffee,
I think.
Her
them
A passion juice.
No, a beer.
Sorry.
Thanks.
No.
I don't think so.
But I'll think it over.
Give me a coin, please.
Drop dead, you dumb hick!
Sorry.
I picked these this morning.
What?
I picked them this morning.
Thanks.
Want a lighter?
No, thanks. Thank you.
A wallet, 5 euros, 4 euros.
Belts, much cheaper.
Do you have a cigarette, please?
No.
Sylvie.
Sylvie?
What is it?
Don't you remember?
We've met?
"Les Aviateurs", 6 years ago.
What?
"Les Aviateurs".
What's that?
The "Les Aviateurs" bar,
behind the cathedral.
You don't remember?
I still have the map
you drew on a napkin.
You don't remember?
No?
Yes, yes, yes.
The "Les Aviateurs" bar.
Sounds familiar.
You were with 2 friends
from the Conservatory.
The Higher School
of Dramatic Art.
You don't remember?
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
You entered the Conservatory
6 years ago, right?
You're mistaken,
I've been here a year.
But you are Sylvie, aren't you?
No.
But... you're Sylvie, right?
- You aren't Sylvie?
- No, you're mistaken.
What?
Sylvie.
You're mistaken.
What a disaster!
I made a mistake.
That's okay.
You could have asked me sooner.
What?
It's not nice to follow people.
Yes, I know.
To follow women on the street.
I wasn't sure.
That's why you should have asked.
Actually, I called you Sylvie
and thought you answered.
It's not pleasant to be followed.
So you noticed?
Couldn't you tell?
No.
Were you running from me?
I sure was!
I went round and
round trying to lose you.
That itinerary was my fault?
Yes, your fault.
I was convinced...
Not at first.
But later, I was convinced.
It's unpleasant to be
followed on the street.
- Yes, very...
- I wanted to be sure.
Very, very unpleasant.
It was very long, endless.
I didn't know where to go.
I'm sorry.
And the shop I hid in
was closed.
Didn't you notice?
No.
Since when are you following me?
I saw you at the
Conservatory cafe.
From the cafe?
You followed me from the cafe?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
How awful!
What a disaster!
You're so similar...
Sure, 6 years...
You are younger.
She was younger too,
6 years ago.
Now she is older,
but still young.
Yes... sure.
Less younger...
I'm very sorry, really.
I get off here.
I'm sorry.
I hope you don't get off here.
No, don't worry.
I'm getting off.
- I'm really sorry.
- Forget it.
I feel awful.
I have to get off.
Are you on vacation?
Have a nice trip!
Bye, and forgive me.
That's enough!
I hope you find her.
3rd night
Excuse me,
do you have a cigarette?