Upload and Synchronize Subtitles: Alcochino @ [torrent411.com]
- What's the matter ? - Breath not it.
With your greasy hands, you bitches all.
- What about you ? - I have them washed.
Here.
What warmth !
You are-and, merde!
It is good, this powder. Who gave it to you last?
Climax.
Climax! How horrible that name!
He was always stuffed with '' Climax. '' The name stuck.
What is the climax?
Damn, Vanda! You do not know that box?
Me no.
You've never been to the 'Cave' '?
But smoke, damn!
Fume !
You really sucks.
I have not the courage to make coke.
- Pass, I do. - You!
It's coming ?
Have you smoked?
Pango has found a pad.
- Who's Pango? - Nhurro.
Oh.
Nhurro, Pango, Yuran, Chumbito ... Il a des tas de noms.
It seems he has settled into the house of the girl who killed her kid.
I have not fishing.
Doing coke, Vanda.
Smoke it first. It décrassera you.
You're going to drink?
Non.
So not drink at all.
- Gaffe, shit! - It burned.
IN THE ROOM OF VANDA
Move on !
lack of bullshit.
Hurry!
Rub hard, I'm really dirty!
Nhurro!
I'm busy.
It's nice the cabinet.
My God, help me.
Vanda will make the tour.
You got the scissors, Zita?
I knew it.
The old woman had, had, had in his head ...
I too had but I lost my head.
Here.
A second, strawberries have not yet hardened enough.
It breaks me this fucking noise.
- You'll get me more? - You put in more?
- Damn, you saw mine and yours? - So what ?
Whore ! We can not talk to him without it begins to yell!
It's like that.
Shit!
Look at the state of this room!
It's on the bed I'm going to tidy up.
- You never crazy in a ream. - I'm going to tidy up.
I will clean this room, Zita and you too, Vanda.
And you will clean yours.
Come on, each his room. We'll see who finishes first.
One two Three...
Lena !
- Say, Anita. - You cassava?
No. Only Friday.
Only Friday.
Come in.
- Leave that ! - It's yours ?
Boots, futales ...
it really is joy here, everything is '' we ''.
- Mouth not shit! - The poor.
- You're really sad. - The sad thing is you.
- Sad shit. - The sad thing is you.
Mrs da Luz? Salad or cabbage?
Madame da Luz?
Nuno ?
- Cabbages ? - No no.
Bye.
Hey buddy, pay attention to Noah's Ark!
Noah's Ark will happen.
Noah's ark ?
How I'll take the covers? And all this stuff?
It's not much, but it's mostly the covers ...
- Mrs ! - Yes ?
- From the salad or cabbage? - No, I have no money.
Thank you.
You do not want? Thank you.
Madam salad?
Madame !
So there it is, Geny? They shaved your house?
Geny! It will take you to sleep with me.
My poor little girl !
- Vire at that, please. - But where ?
In the trash there.
- Damn, I have to come down? - Come on, be nice.
- Vire me two buckets. - Right now ?
- Do it, be nice. - I go.
But damn, go ahead.
You see that I put, descends- them.
Now ?
Go on, Nando, you may well do that for me! Go down those buckets.
I clean for us to be comfortable. Go ahead. Help me a little whore.
Give me a hand.
- the is put there? - No, outside.
- In the street ? - Yes.
Advanced.
Holy shit.
Vire me those buckets, Nando.
I go. Let me do me a shot.
Look, the guy went to get doses.
In the meantime, you can help me.
Okay, I'm going.
After my shoot, I'll start.
You sit down already? You sit not here.
Go on the couch.
Make the break. Sit on the couch.
- I am good like this. - Sit there.
You do not want to sit down? Can not you see that I put?
Upper !
It's boring!
My arms hurt.
I have to go pee.
Since that's not possible.
What crap!
That's it ?
You're done ?
Attends.
Miranda, Miranda.
Miranda...
You know who lived here, Nando?
The girl,
quite pretty,
one that wanted to sell his kid for 50 balls.
Larousse ? The one that threw her baby in a trash can?
Yes, I see that.
If she threw it in a bin or if she killed him,
this I know.
Pango, the house is great like that, right?
Good work.
Give me a cigarette.
Thank you.
I tell you shit; my brother.
I put all the fruit.
If you are looking for red apples,
they are under the bananas, you've heard?
Mom, did you see?
I found that.
- Or ? - Over there.
Oh, good!
- Oh what? - Why you keep this thing?
It's an antique, andouille.
Someone had to take in someone's home.
It is in good condition.
There is a broken wire. This is not an antique that, Miranda?
Do not you think I can get three hundred francs, down?
Look, there's just this broken wire there.
You had not seen him, Mom? He was behind the crates.
It lacks only son. but it can be replaced.
He is handsome, is not he ? It lacks one, there.
I thought you'd seen.
He was there, I found it by removing a crate.
Meaning ! He feels wax.
Wax or oil.
If Emilia saw him, she would like right away.
Do not put it there, it's dirty.
You have only to wash.
- Take it from off the fruit. - Take it yourself.
Do not put them there, we can not reach the TV.
You had not seen the boat?
- Look, he is in good condition. - He is magnificent.
But it is my boat, damn!
I put it near the crates to clean.
- He was behind the crates. - I forgot to take the fucking.
- It leaves us not even look at him. - I had asked for. He is mine.
It's good, it's yours.
Let us at least look!
It was there, it was me who found him.
It is in good condition. It lacks a thread.
Blankets, I can spin you.
Imagine if I had been in it.
- You'd be released in all ... - Smoked like a herring.
As a herring!
And if they had sprayed gasoline you ...
I who can not walk without my crutches, I had not a chance.
Not one, you grillais.
These kids are worse than ...
This is wickedness, they malice to the body.
They come from Nhurro district.
They are five or six, three black and two white.
There is one that is the type of pad where we slept before, you and me.
Exact.
He is the artist who love this kind of number.
A real crazy.
People believed that the windows I was still in the can.
- While it burned? - Clear !
How sad !
If you were in, you spent there.
- Sure, how would I get out? - In addition, with the covers ...
Logic.
The essence, it does not forgive.
In addition, the reeds were dry around a roaring fire!
You remember an old sofa that was there?
- From sleeper sofa kind? - Yes, with backrest.
They also had to be swinging a match.
It took the fire rose to the reeds, and everything burnt.
My blankets in the can, my saps, all gone up in smoke.
- It really is wickedness. - Pure evil.
Yesterday I was in the can,
and they began to throw stones at me.
I started screaming to believe I was touched, so they stop.
Me, before yesterday I passed by the school.
The artist was there with two black guys.
They put themselves in the head strip me.
- Misery. - They knew...
that I had of the currency, guarantor cars.
They put themselves in the head that I had the money.
''File-nous ton cash,
file-nous ton cash''.
And I '' But I did not. ''
'' So jump, we hear parts or not. ''
And I jumped, you know? Of course I had the parts.
'' Empty your pockets and give '' and I have nothing left.
My luck, it was the arrival of the father of Vanda.
The black, you see?
It saved me.
They had already started the scalp dance and all the stuff.
Vanda's father, he worked with his shovel.
He has forbidden.
I went directly to the excavator.
I jumped into the dumpster.
He descended far, in Fontainhas.
Oh damn!
That way I'll be cold. Cold, cold, cold.
I'm cold, I'm cold. Cold, cold, cold.
In the Mouraria
at the corner of Rua da Palma.
One day,
I left my soul captive.
When passed by my side ...
Oh shit !
... dark-skinned,
the mocking gaze.
Vanda, vanda, vanda ...
Leave me alone.
Nhurro Hello!
You do not have a cigarette?
And I tell you shit a hundred times. See you.
Fatima, a martini please do!
- You want an ice cube? - Yes.
I'm ok thanks.
Vanda!
I heard about your sister Nela. It's sad.
Night is falling.
It is dark.
I should go buy candles.
Well, here Crutches.
Nhurro!
My God...
Father, help me.
Whore...
Fees?
I will die.
Go to sleep Paulo.
Evil never die. It is the innocent who die.
Tomorrow I would have you cut your hair.
Mom will see Nela to visit?
She even phoned.
- Why ? - For the money.
- Get out of here, bitch. - Get out yourself!
- My balls that I'm going out! - Bitch!
You make me crazy, imagine yourself even.
And you, you not imagine the hatred I keep you.
Get out! Just leave the camp of my room.
Can you imagine not hate ...
Do not you have more than me.
Fuck you put on!
Go there yourself. You ever age and a husband. Not me.
'' Find yourself a husband. ''
'' Find yourself a husband. '' Repeats Diogo.
Mom, it's broken tupperwear!
Your cake, Mom, the cops will put you into pieces.
They'll screw up.
They are afraid they stash the drugs.
Bit by bit they will search it.
And we'll see if they let the ham.
- Help me clean this pad. - I have my own store.
Lena, the kid still shit. You have to the exchange.
You're going to go dowdy like that?
With that hair?
- Put me stuff in bags. - I have the disgusting hands.
Zita, put it in bags.
They let the plastic bags.
The tupperwears first.
Put hot on the bottom.
They let the plastic bags.
- No, put that first. - Shut up !
- Did not you hear what she said? - What did she say ?
The warm background.
Hi Zita. You okay, Vanda?
- You bananas, my beautiful? - Who is it ?
You've found a roof, Paulo?
More or less.
Says. Where is it ?
With Ginger. A shack on the side of Venda Nova.
I saw my old today.
She spoke to you?
When I saw it, I had tears in my eyes.
She was in the garden, she was digging. She tended the sprouts.
She looked at me: '' You're so skinny. ''
I put my hand in my pocket and I took everything I had money.
And I gave him.
'' What state are you?
You're all dirty, and your shoes ...
You make me sad.''
And she asked me: '' You have to eat, you feed you well? ''
'' Yes, I eat. ''
'' Sometimes I leave a dish in the oven,
to see if you come looking for him. ''
'' Every time I hope you come and get it. ''
I can not cross my old, it's too much sadness that falls on me.
Yuran, you'll end up killing her.
Do not call misfortune.
Paulo, we have to exchange our pumps.
Leave yours, I'm on it.
No, mine is new.
- I just open it. - Newfoundland, you speak!
We'll share together tonight.
- Do you how here. - Two.
I exchange the trailer.
I just open one and the other there not long ago.
They are not bad.
They are not bad at all.
If you knew the shit that I was already passed on.
I balance everything.
And that cigarette, that's today?
Well, Yuran, I'm going to win.
- And I tell you shit. - Good luck Paulo.
I tell you shit too.
May God our Lord be with me.
What is it ?
This is Crutches silver spoon to eat his yogurt.
Who is it ?
You made me look good, you!
That depresses me.
I entered as a doomed.
- Ah yes ? - Yes, as a convicted ...
They put you right back to the hole, Carla? On leaving the station?
Yes, at five o'clock in the morning they took me to the station.
Immediately in the cage.
What a pain !
Meanwhile, they made ...
I do not know what it's called.
- The prison number, anything. - Paper to put me in jail.
I left the office at nine in the morning.
At eleven o'clock I was in the closet.
You can not wear jeans ...
- Inside? - That cotton trousers.
And you must always wear a blouse.
- Ah yes ? - Blue?
- It depends, there are several colors. - See you. I come again.
Imagine, they must wear a gown.
All for Knorr cubes, whore. This is the jail. It's like that.
Must say she has a past.
Eight years of flight, it counts.
But shit, falling for Knorr cubes!
We never saw that.
It only exists in Lisbon.
But shit, three! Knorr cubes!
Vanda, you did not hear what she said? It is not a beginner.
But she often squeeze and each time trial.
Three times she should have been released three times, a new trial.
I know who left it to them was another thing.
- And immediately they returned there. - That is true. They seek you.
Zeninhas example ...
He goes out and after one week out they come looking for it.
They emerged a conviction. And he did his time.
Of course.
How many ?
This I do not know.
Damn, it's hard.
It's worse than tough.
Falling, I want to think about it.
Ni moi.
Fall,
for Knorr cubes. Jesus. We never saw that!
Arrest someone for bouillon cubes.
I'm sure this is the first that goes to the closet,
with such an accusation.
'' I am in prison for Knorr bouillon flight! ''
It is sad, really sad our country.
It is the poorest and that's the sad part.
So many years of suffering in the hands of my father.
After twenty-four years, he left with nothing.
Sad ! She was hungry for the eating.
I will never forgive him.
Poor mom!
Damn, it's a miracle if my sister Zita is with us.
When Mom was eight months
he crushed his stomach between two chairs.
He almost killed her.
It's a miracle.
Me, it revolts me.
The '' N '' is not very good.
No credit today! Only tomorrow.
Tomorrow. Not today !
The devil take me if I do not display it.
It is your new secret pad where I can go with you?
They say nothing Crutches.
You're getting old.
I'll say, '' Nela, stop your bullshit. If you continue,
you will not see me again, nor I, nor anyone. ''
I could not call. We do not leave me.
Otherwise, I would have done as Nela. I would not stop calling.
She should not ask that!
I would have asked for thirty bullets. Dope, not money.
What would I do with money at the hospital?
Finally, there were at hand.
If I had known earlier, damn it!
Do not you imagine the work to find a piece of aluminum.
I thought as drawers in the house, packed with aluminum ... Hell!
And I, here, with the aluminum, dope and all.
I took the thing thermometers, this iron thing where they are arranged.
I took it, I lit the lighter 'Sauvé, I found something to smoke.' '
I'd even used the pool provided the '' drop '' sink.
'' Vanda, you will not go with it. ''
I had brought the aluminum you, dope and all.
But Miranda took everything from me.
Miranda and I had to put a mask to see you.
After I not get it off. My hair was caught in the knot.
The more I tried, the less I arrived. '' Miranda, remove it to me! ''
He is done...
'' Take me this stuff! I can not do, it chokes me! ''
You see the kind of anguish, pockets stuffed, too.
It's a real fucking pain, what you think.
The real suffering is to know that one can consume.
Exact. Knowing that she will go home and eat.
Damn, what I have not! I tore the perf, and all ...
How many times I went to the window! And I fell.
Skinny as I was, my legs were not me.
Me, I would have escaped.
I'm surrounded by wankers.
No one helps me, that broken arm.
Damn, you're shit.
What do you still want me? You kidding.
Breathe. Let me make my shot and I go out without your garbage problem.
It would go well here with modern wallpaper with flowers.
If you knew what I enjoyed with my bruises.
- Stop whining. - But I was right, man.
If you had paid all the crap I've ever had ...
Seven or eight bruises!
You, you'd live in fear.
I was a walking bruise.
Once the shaking was so violent,
that the pump is blocked by itself.
This one was tough, man. An internal hematoma.
He took all the tendons, all, to block my leg.
It lasted three days and three nights.
It rained and the sun, and even rain. I was shaking in my blanket.
I ended up dying it myself.
I the morning without my 'Serenal' 'I not booted.
Only after it is infected, because I had done wrong ...
Before I walked to '' Serenal '' ...
I have not dressing on weekends,
and neck hematoma swelled, so swollen,
on Monday by going to the hospital and I pressed the pus spurted.
If I was not my '' Serenal '' I could hardly walk.
I was in the emergency and a girl,
injected me with something in the neck,
to make me out the eyes of the orbits.
It was the kind Antral or Antrax.
I think the bruises I had,
it is a side effect of '' Serenal ''.
A hematoma on the left ribs, another on the right ribs.
That of the right ribs, I have already burst.
I have one left foot ...
Show me.
- Two on the coasts. - Ah yes ?
I got a neck, the same time as that of the leg.
You've got a neck?
- Later, the neck popped. - But I'm talking about the neck.
But then I took antibiotics, blood, live.
Let me take a puff, Nando.
That was when I went to the hospital,
after puncturing the hematoma of the leg.
On leaving the hospital, I make a right arm.
What about me? One on each foot. Do you remember ?
One on each foot and an arm.
It's this one.
Finally, the guys who won the championship this year?
C'est Benfica ... no, Porto.
No, I'm talking bruises.
Fuck you, Nhurro!
The little old, I was impressed. It looked Carabosse.
She walked with his cane like that.
A little old jail!
Vanda will make your tour!
Only old there.
But you know, you can walk everywhere.
'' Ouch, bring me drugs!
- If you need money, we bring you, but drugs, not ''.
But I'll bring it next time, a dose or two.
I will do it.
One day, you'll stay there, and I'll not see you.
When I stay, I will stay.
So it hath more there?
There is a bar and all ...
It's not the bars, as it is said.
This is the fence like the one we have for rabbits.
And in his cell either, it's not the bars.
This is glass with wire mesh in it.
This is far from the search and the three flags.
And to find Nela
it is a hassle.
She has a sword to kill: the end of our race.
A sword ?
She did it with the bed roasting
- I assure you. - You speak !
It's crazy. That's jokes.
Next time I bring him.
You have only to tell the guard that's for you.
No, Grandma, I hide in my dentures.
- There instead. - Pile instead.
Go do your tour. Hurry up !
Their machines guess anything except metal.
I can bring anything metal.
Lina, they searched everywhere.
Nela was chatting with a babysitter.
A woman I know. A chance to have met her.
- Who is that ? - One of my clients.
She is the guardian.
As soon as she saw me, she said: '' Ah, the little vegetable seller. ''
On Friday, I go back.
Mrs da Luz? Salad or cabbage?
Excuse me, I'm tired.
- I put you how? - A.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Nuno! Cabbage, salad?
No ? Thank you.
Cabbage, salad? Thank you.
Some salad ?
Shit !
Where are my keys ?
Some salad ?
Fuck, Ginger, do not do that. It's not worth it, leave the table.
It's not worth it.
Please.
I have already said that this table is there. Stopped.
If you are not you taking the table, I take it.
Up to you.
This table is here.
Ginger, where did you stashed the fleet?
She's there.
Stop it, damn. I'm fed up !
You are stubborn to ten.
This chair, it takes him.
We will not let her.
Ginger! Ice, take her?
Shit, Ginger!
Oh, Ginger!
Damn, we will spend one more night here!
We will still freeze.
I plates, cutlery ...
Forget it, forget it.
Pans, plates, forks,
we have everything you need there to eat.
Do not worry.
The mattress is nickel, very hard,
and as I have a bad back ...
The best for you is to sleep on the floor.
The best for me? What are you looking for ?
I tell you that it is nickel,
I have a bad back ...
And you want me to sleep on the floor!
So guys, it bathes? There will be a place for me there?
- No. - Good.
Tu as vu ce naze?
What are we sailed yet? The sneakers ?
You're really stubborn.
They will raze the house.
Not stubborn. Ordered. It's not the same thing.
Being stubborn, that's one thing. Another is to be designed.
Leave me peace. I like things rows, that's all.
On May 13 in Fatima, that's thousands of people.
For sellers, it's mine!
For pickpockets.
For the pros.
I've never been on the thirteenth.
I'm already gone, but not three. Here.
Pass the lighter.
May is the most beautiful month.
He cherries, Notre Dame.
This is the month of Vanda. The class.
I can not stop thinking about Nela
That's why I do not go there.
This is the first time I enter in a prison.
I do not like that.
The hospital is the same. After I stop over thinking people.
Damn, this is serious.
On arrival, she was looking me eyes, she not see me. And I: '' Nela! ''
She took me in his arms and kissed me.
If I came away with the other, Zita,
they would still be looking for me.
I was wrong. I wrote my name instead of hers.
I had not read '' Owned ''
and I put my name.
And '' relationship '' I put '' sister ''.
When I heard the girl in the speaker,
'' There is a Vanda in the pavilion? Vanda Maria Pires Duarte. ''
And I: 'No, no, excuse me! Vanda Maria, it's me. ''
'' She is my sister, Manuela Duarte Fernanda Pires ''.
'' You're wrong. Repeat a listing. ''
She called the three pavilion. Pile where was the '' Duchesse ''.
I did not know there were so many pavilions.
With numbers and this circus.
Without the number, I would have lost.
I can not stop thinking about it.
How sad !
I really dirty hair.
I look like a bum.
In addition, with the dirt they grow faster.
Water and soap.
That would leave all this filth.
We really need me to.
I parked cars ...
I was a thief ...
I was mason ...
I was server ...
And I know more what I can ...
What I can do in this world.
It's incredible !
They came back.
Vanda is how red apples?
- Four or five francs? - Four.
- Five. That's Vanda? - Four.
Where is the aluminum?
Here it is.
Diogo cry!
- Go see Zita! - Go yourself!
Want to buy a silver spoon?
5 francs !
It is in that here? I can get myself a tranquil shot?
You think it is your mother's cunt or what?
- I was just asking. - Get out!
- You're the guy with crutches? - Yes, it's me Crutches.
- You know who I am ? - I know.
- Damn Redhead! What sleeve! - I'm getting not fuck.
Try with this pump.
The needle twists. Your neck is that the wedge.
The wedge?
My luck is great.
I know it's great! It's pumps are damned.
You fired the air?
You think I'm freak or what?
Damn this is long.
- That's it ? - Not yet.
Shit, Paulo, remains quiet.
- Attention not miss the vein. - But no.
Before, I was really addicted to coke ...
You ever look better.
You have perked up. You're so thin.
- But I have trouble breathing. - Me too.
I get tired very quickly.
As soon as I walk a little, I'm exhausted.
The morning is one of those cough ...
I'll give you stuff but it will take them.
I will take them.
- Pedro ! - Juré.
This is what I take when I have trouble breathing.
And if you do not take ...
I swear on the head of my grandmother that I will do anything for you.
I can even get one now.
You do not imagine how it's expensive.
It is tablet for the lack of air. Really good.
- It should not take too much, right? - Oh no!
You know what scared me? I thought I had tuberculosis.
Take care of yourself.
If one eats bad ...
There the food but mainly, Pedro,
must never shoot up with another pump.
I never do. But where I sleep,
Once I stood barefoot
and a needle planted myself in the foot.
Be careful, Pedro.
I'll give you tablets to the lack of air.
I'm scared to go for analysis.
It is to avoid Ventolin.
One can become addicted to Ventolin. You know ?
Where are these tablets crap?
I have trouble breathing, I use the sprayer and all.
- You have asthma then? - Not really. It starts just ...
- But I'm probably. - So, we're all in the same state.
You, me, the guy Paulo Geny, all alike.
- And Geny, you see? From one day to another ! - Yes, the poor.
But when I damn these tablets?
I went avenue of Uruguay ..
To see this lady, Rosa, who used to help me.
She lives on the seventh, you know.
I ring down, the door opens.
I enter. There is disappointment! The elevator down.
T'imagines, climb to 7 th. my crutches!
I have to climb seven floors.
Flat, bloody, dead.
I get up, knock,
'' You alright Rosa? - Very well thank you.
- And your husband too? - He's fine, thank you God.
- You'd have a little something for me?
- I'll see what I can do.''
She comes back and refile me two yogurts.
- It refile you what? - Two yogurts.
Damn, two yogurts! Fuck I was, I was hoping money.
I put yogurt in my bag. And down,
I prayed for them to be strawberry.
I would have killed the old.
I do not expect it
be so mean.
We did not want to be rude but sometimes
circumstances will push you!
Provided there is the strawberry pieces!
Paulo, I had one of those fluke!
I managed to sting a blackbird,
a golden, not a standard black,
a blackbird colorful.
And I went down to the gypsy quarter.
I went to the old well that gets off the birds.
Two sugar packets.
I caused him to see if he bought it, and the old man said no.
It'll be great.
But when I told him it was a golden blackbird ...
... he was hooked.
There must be a spoon there, Redhead.
Be nice, going to get me.
He really flashed.
A great deal. I won six sacks.
There was another ...
It must be in yellow basket.
... but it was not a nice golden brown.
Take the candle, be nice. My leg hurts.
Apart from gold, nothing to bite, it was the only one that was worth it.
C'mon, man, I can not, it hurts too much.
The old man asked me to find canaries.
I fucking hurts. Hurry up ! I have to go do my tour.
I do not know where is your spoon Paulo. We put everything in the bags.
Without my spoon, I can not eat my yogurt.
Damn, is it! You are blind or what?
Here. It will come in search!
But you really have to take them.
We take the how?
Every eight hours.
At seven o'clock, three o'clock in the afternoon,
and eleven at night. It's the best.
When they are finished, come in search. We must take them!
When you return, I will give you the syrup.
On leaving, I take one.
This is to help breathing, right?
Yes and syrup too. Rate not hours!
Geny, she went out to beg like everyday.
She had become so thin, so weak that he had to carry her in his arms.
wear from here to the market. What misery !
That is true.
She is out, too.
In the evening I was told: '' Geny is dead. '' I did not believe it.
Neither do I.
She was the inning with Fragata, right?
I do not know.
She collapsed suddenly. At the foot of Fragata, I think.
It's sad.
He called an ambulance. She did not get on.
Sacred Geny.
Later they called another.
There, it is mounted,
but she arrived died in the hospital.
You realize.
Paulo out more.
It's Geny that would find the twenty bags for his doses of the night.
And he was waiting.
It was not even fucking be fifty balls.
It was cowardly of him.
Yes, it's unbelievable.
He said he could not.
You you have mastered it!
When we really need, we always get there.
Of course.
I told him a thousand times: '' When you're stuck, you get there. ''
It's clear.
Now he makes an effort for her little morning dose.
You clearly see.
It is a combination with cotton. Me and Julio was tired.
It is that guys who fall in and out.
When this is over, he will have to be doing like the others.
Nothing else to do.
And Julio, you see? It was going so well ...
Yes. He relapsed.
He relapsed serious.
And go again. At this time, it should already be well ...
I met him this morning, but not since.
He just passed.
- Sacred Julio. - He really suffered.
He did it to dry. He drank like a beast.
So imagine dry.
- I could not have. - Neither do I.
I am so afraid of missing. That's what makes me most afraid.
To me too.
Do not you want my flowers?
No, I have no money.
- They are not expensive. - I do not have money.
I let them.
- Put them in a vase. - Thank you.
You want to take in the cemetery.
They do not let in the real flowers.
That plastic flowers!
I did not know. In the new cemetery?
Yes.
This is the first time I hear that.
That plastic flowers ... Thank you.
You're welcome. Hello.
Hello. Goods.
I can not send you money for your cigarettes.
I have no money, I have nothing, I can not.
One cartridge, but it's expensive.
I have no money!
You too. Goodbye.
I have no money, I can not.
Ouch, Mom.
Hurry up, it's almost over. And the sun has not disappeared completely.
On television, we see better.
- The sun grows, right? - Yes.
It's time, guys. We abandon the ship.
I'll get you.
Already one week
that you're stashed there.
You're not smart, you're a beef.
I've had. You lost.
The floor is tiled. It lacks the doors.
Top it has windows,
when we sleep, nobody can enter.
Downstairs, the only downside is the doors, but otherwise ...
Well painted walls, a real home,
all clean, nothing is dirty.
Will just do the housework.
I hope I forget anything.
That's all we have to do.
My keys ?
This is the last time I tell you: do not be disrespectful.
Otherwise, it is paid.
In my country, it will not be like this,
This is the Portuguese justice emptiness.
You believe you can do what want.
Every injury, should be fined.
I picked you, you!
In Cape Verde, you should have already received a lesson!
You think you are?
Here, it is not you who make the law.
Here, it still belongs to my father.
In Portugal, you respect nothing.
A girl should never forget respect.
And what else!
- Otherwise it must be severely punished. - Respect, I pat myself.
You do not even respected thyself!
All day on your bed You not working, you're not rise up.
Locked up in your room day and night.
How can you live?
You're never go out.
In my island...
have to get up at three in the morning.
We will work with pick and shovel,
or we will pick herbs.
And we try to get by. Both men and women.
It's like that every day,
of both dying of hunger and thirst.
We must find another way.
You, you have no solution.
When this type drank, he believes any permit.
Ms. Gracinda!
You want a silver spoon? It is five francs.
Zinha!
You want a silver spoon? Four francs.
When we were little girls, we did it all:
'' I want salt, I want salt. ''
And when we arrived, we had forgotten:
'' Madam, my mother would, would ...
Damn, I forgot. ''
And when came the Pitrolino.
And you, in your neighborhood, there was not a man passing?
He sold the oil and everything.
It was a grocery store in a cart, it was the Pitrolino.
I do not remember, I was too small.
- Too small ... But it always happens! - It's called the Pitrolino yet.
Yes, it still happens.
But it sells more oil it sells wine ...
- And the grocery store. - From bleach.
It brings the gas cylinders.
And wine to Anita.
'' Du showers, showers du, du showers ... ''
'' Madam, my mother would, would ...
- Want what, my dear? - I forgot.
- Go ask him '' I returned.. '' My mother would ... I forgot again. ''
I was always head in the air.
So for the way I repeated,
'' You sel, you riz, you frasan,
you sel, you riz, you frasan ... ''
Lord Jesus!
Once at school,
we played ball with a girlfriend, I liked playing ball,
there was a barbed ground ...
I lifted him to get the ball.
She was right behind me, I let go, it tore him the skull!
As she ran, I heard: trrrr.
She always brand.
And I: '' Paula, you're not ready to forget. ''
'' Surely not, I will always have the brand ''.
He always came to me with this stuff!
And the day my godmother
recounted his gossip
and all of a sudden...
a stool tumbles ...
bang, right on his mouth.
Yet that does not forget.
The brand is made to remember.
It was still a nice childhood in this neighborhood.
It's sad to leave.
It hurts me.
Of course we had a nice childhood here.
If ever I pass by here ...
There was no dope once.
There were but ...
It will not see, it was not like now.
Who would have thought ... our Geny Geny was dealing.
Tire not it like that.
You the Crames completely.
- Let me take one last puff. - You already had your turn!
You've already shot a LOT!
It was small!
Ah yes ? And that's why the cigarette has this face there!
- You make the burn. - No.
Whore ! And the other burns the lips.
Just go.
What do you want, Nhurro?
Did not you a little bread, Zita?
- What do you want ? - You're not a little bread, Zita?
I have not, Nhurro.
Thank you Madam.
ARTIFICIAL FLOWERS ARE PROHIBITED
I have my bag,
two pants, a shirt.
My old sneakers and that's it.
You're here, that's a lot ...
I do not sleep, I'm listening.
It's sad, right?
I do not know what I'll do.
That's life we ​​wanted.
I always helped you and I'll help you again.
I've never refused anything. We've known since we were little.
That's why ... I know it's a girl's room.
Yes, you should not have come like this, I could have been stripped.
That is true.
We enter when you are told to enter.
I hit. That, my father taught me.
If you spend no more often it is because you do not want.
I know.
They never told you not.
But I do not like to stick to those who are willing to help me, you know?
There comes a point when they say to you '! You abuses' ''
They never told you that. Till today.
'' It helps, it helps a little, and one day he feels at home. ''
They never told you not. Till today.
Tomorrow I do not know.
Every time I here it is as if I got home.
That's why I came to ask you a shelter, a roof.
And you know you have it. If you have not, is that you do not want.
Here, anyone ever refused to eat.
Neither room or a corner for rest.
That's life we ​​wanted.
No, this is not the life we ​​wanted, that's life we ​​are obliged to live.
You think ?
Yes I think. Looks like a destiny, it is drawn ...
You were going so well. Look at you now.
How many times I saw you go in the neighborhood,
and how many times I said 'you go again.' '
And you '' No I get out of work. '' You see. I was right.
No, when I walked in the neighborhood ...
it was not for dope.
I was out of work, were placed me there.
And you bought.
No, I arrived penniless, I met a drug dealer, I asked him:
'' Lend me a hundred bullets, I go out with a girl, I have not a round.
The boss not pay me. ''
Him instead of giving me a hundred bullets: '' Well that's two hundred. ''
You clearly see ? And you slammed them where? In the dope.
That, that's life we ​​chose. It's like that now.
You know as well as me. What happened to me...
It happened to you, to me, to many others.
Except that thou hast a mother ...
... Who helps me a lot. But I also work hard.
I would do anything for her.
Like her, there are few.
I too have someone like my mother.
A mother, it has only one, fathers were many.
She never refused me anything, she never had anything either ...
But the little she had ...
She gave it to you. When she could not, it was because of your father.
What is certain is that I avoided asking him for money.
I knew that with the little she had it fail him.
Yes.
But I made him much harm.
It's destiny, I think.
I know she has always forgiven.
That's why I left, to stop hurting him.
Imagine a mother who bears four like us.
My mother had me and already it made her mad.
Then imagine four.
And my mother stopped drinking.
You see.
She still suffers from a lack.
It's been three months since she no longer drinks.
And for you it is not important that?
Yes Yes. It is important.
Look where my sister and my brother.
Looks like we will fall, too.
Fall. If it was like that.
One day they will say, 'Enough.' '
They will be so worn.
Being out there every day is not livable.
And your mother will get tired.
It can change that.
But I also work hard.
They must put in mind to slow down.
And win.
There are already two there, we will not add two more, right?
Lift and support.
We did it when we were little.
- No ? - Yes.
I have over my grandmother and you want more you help your mother.
I'm going out. I can not hear you.
- But you let me stay a little here? - Yes of course.
- Some time ? - You know I do.
Well ... thank you.
- Want to buy a mandarin? - I do not have money.
- Look how beautiful it is! - No, I have no money.
Thank you, I have no money.
Put it over. Range our clothes and the mom.
Vanda, you buy me Mandarin?
Vanda!
What do you want him to Vanda?
Anna, you want a salad?
Salad or cabbage?
New funeral parlor Sales
Want cabbage?
Life has despised.
I lived ghost houses that others abandoned.
Houses...
where even a witch would not have wanted to stay.
But sometimes I found a house that was worth it.
All my houses ...
all households were clandestine houses.
They were abandoned.
If we had been good people ...
Yes.
... they would not demolished.
There you go...
house after house.
I paid more for what I have not done ...
for what I did.
- They started to rehouse people? - Yes.
Or ?
Where Carla lives.
The side Boavista?
My God !
It's not so bad. All districts are not like ours.
And now. God knows where it will go?
At the cemetery.
I can not anymore.
And this door, we take it?
Here, Nhurro shot himself.
Nhurro left.
It was too much for him the girls' room.
Where I screwed up my pants?
This room will never row!
It's cold ?
Lend me a pump, my needle is clogged.
I lend you a tip.
But it is the needle is blocked.
Opens it.
Where I have a tip?
Here !
Pours a little water in the mouthpiece.
Pour a little water, Mosquito.
Hurry, before it coagulates.
Do not throw there, there is a bed
- Oh, you sleep here? - Unfortunately yes.
Mom, you go there at what time?
At this rate, it will be the visit at four in the morning!
- Shut up ! - You're sad.
You want to come with me?
They will not let me in.
Come. Just to walk.
And who will take care of the kid?
Well, rest then ...
For sure if he was sleeping ...
Miranda, if you go there, I'm there.
What I will do at the prison?
Hello, hello Lena.
Right away.
I go to coffee with Dad.
It's fake ..
Draws a puff!
Only one ?!
One like me, shit!
Do not mouth!
Shit ! You're going to burn everything.
It's my turn, on the grandmother's head.
Where is she ?
Here it is.
I laugh but you know that it is due to lack.
And you it makes you laugh?
No ? You're the only well.
You're really special.
There is it like to laugh.
There are those who mourn; yea but when not.
And when they do, they laugh. And heartily.
Thou hast ever cried you more than your account.
To cry, I cried! At the hospital, I was doing it.
Whore ! It was not pretty.
But if you are going to see, do not forget your basket.
What cart?
You're so dumb! What basket, Vanda?
But yours.
- Cart? - Yes.
Watch out, you're gonna burn!
What cart?
A basket !
You really are an idiot.
The idiot is you!
You never heard '' If you are going to see,
do not forget your basket? ''
You saw the movie ?
The one where the girl out of her tits a gun like this, like that.
Police Academy. He went there two weeks ago.
- Tires-one and I finished. - Why one?
Because I fired one, this question!
Watch out !
- There is some left. - Watch out !
Women.
You'll make your tour?
You're going to hurt you with that.
You are going to hurt yourself.
Upload and Synchronize Subtitles: Alcochino @ [torrent411.com]