Is my older brother,
Han Gi Tak? I know it
doesn't make sense but,
lately I keep having similar dreams.
With his big hands,
there was someone teaching me how to jab.
Can you explain it more?
When I heard the name Han Gi
Tak, tear sprung to my eye.
When I saw this, it was as if the pieces
of the puzzle was coming together.
But if you are that
person's younger sibling,
then could it be just my fantasy after
hearing about your older brother?
I lived using your name.
Because he wanted to see you,
your brother gave me that name.
Hong Nan...
That's my name?
Han Hong Nan.
Calling me Hong Nan,
he raised me like a real sibling.
He never forgot about you.
You...
But, after this moment, don't
say that name out loud.
Han Hong Nan and Han Gi Tak.
Could it be...
♪ It was as if the sun was covering you ♪
That my older brother, like
everybody's been saying,
he died that way?
Da Hye.
Your brother, remember him
as you see in this picture.
He would want you to.
You not living as Hong Nan.
He would want you to live as Da Hye.
This is all that I can tell you.
Final Episode You were
really surprised right?
I feel like everyone I love are in misery.
This is why I couldn't tell you.
The one who found your older brother,
is Jeong Ji Hoon.
- What?-It seems like he's been
looking for your family for a while.
On the day Kim Yeong Soo died, that's why he met
you at Big Wolf. Han Gi Tak was the chef there.
Jeong Ji Hoon did?
To you, who lost your husband, he couldn't
tell you about your older brother.
You are someone who went through
harder times than any other person.
That isn't your fault. Everyone is worried.
I don't think I have the right to say this
to you, seeing as how you rejected me.
It's laughable, but the
words I want to say...
is that you are a woman who
received a lot of love.
So don't think stupid thoughts.
I lost my husband and older brother.
Weirdly I'm not going crazy over it.
I think I can put up with it
because of the love I received.
Could you please not look at me like that.
With the look that you know everything.
Exactly what are you, Lee Hae Joon?
A friendly person staying at your house.
I am leaving the day
after tomorrow, Ahjumma.
Why? Did you come to congratulate me?
You should have at least
brought cake and some flowers.
You too...
If you met another person instead of
me, would you have been more happy?
We're both killing each other.
No matter how much we hurt, it won't be
as much as someone who's already dead.
It's just so hard now.
Let's just end it here.
What are you talking about?
Let's cut ties and live well.
After I settle matters here, I'm going
to that Yong Chan and go far away.
I came here to tell you that.
Branch Manager.
Branch Manager... no, CEO,
You look really, really,
really, really handsome today.
Department Head Ma.
You calling my name like that
makes me feel fluttered.
If I do weird things from
now on, please understand.
Differently than the other
Branch Managers, you constantly
did do some extremely weird things though.
Let's embrace each other.
-What?-Come now.
It's my first time so it may be awkward.
Oh my. Does this mean, I'm
in Lee Hae Joon's line?
Is it confirmed?
Why are we day drinking?
When will I experience the taste
of soju with you guys again?
When I go back to America, I won't
be able to taste it for a long time.
I'm sad. You're starting
to say those things again.
Is there no soju in America?
You're leaving?
I only came here on vacation briefly. Since
I played around a lot, I need to go back.
You can just play with us.
Protect the restaurant well
between the two of you.
Don't ruin the Big Wolf
that we finally got back.
Especially you.
Stop scolding the kids and you
practice your cooking, okay?
Okay!
Seung Jae, take care of Yi Yeon.
I'll be the one to protect Song Yi
Yeon and Big Wolf, so don't worry.
And the meat soup for our Hyungnim,
I am in charge of it, so don't
worry about that either.
Alright, you're reliable.
Wait a little longer.
Before you leave, I will catch Na
Seok Chul and get him locked up.
Seung Jae.
I know how he moves, I'm close.
- So...-That's not what
Han Gi Tak would want.
The revenge you want, he would
never want you to do that.
Noonim! Sister is going back to America
and I just wanted you to know.
She nagged at us a lot today and left.
Should we try it again?
Yes, let's go.
That's great, Yi Yeon. A little bit more.
Okay! Good!
That's right,
you'll do well on your own.
♪ It was warm, in my heart ♪
Everyone's around right? I'm going
to count to three and take it.
One, two, three! I took it.
One more time. One, two, three!
I took it! One more time!
Should we take a look?
Whoa!
Hey, Sung Jae...
Na Seok Cheol!
Are you the one who killed Gi Tak?
This is so freaking annoying.
Hey you, am I not allowed to
kill Han Gi Tak or something?
I killed him because there
was a reason to kill him!
Get rid of this bastard.
So annoying.
Should we get rid of Han
Gi Tak's sister too?
Yeah, we should let her go on the
rooftop and send her with brother.
You try to stay alive. By
tomorrow, it'll all be over.
Yeah!
Hello?
Yeah, this is the real estate office.
Do you know who Han Gi Tak is?
Excuse me?
Oh, I couldn't get in contact with the
relatives. Do you not know Han Gi Tak?
Yes, I know him.
I have Han Gi Tak's items.
It's been a while and I'm not sure if
I'm supposed to throw it away or what.
Come by quickly and retrieve it. That
way we can put the room up for sale.
Uh, okay.
I'll come.
This is fun.
Hello? Come quick!
[Hong Nan]
I"m sorry. There isn't that
much that I can say to you.
You brat! Where are you?
You left Yi Yeon alone.
Hello?
You...
Don't come...
Choi Sung Jae! What's wrong?
Don't you come! Na Seok Cheol...
Is looking for you.
Are you there? Excuse me.
Hello, ma'am.
[Masked number]
Hello?
Have you met... this person?
The person who used to
live here, Han Gi Tak.
Of course. He lived in this house for
over 10 years so I know him very well.
Hey, listen closely.
If I hit you that hard, the least you
could've done is visit me, isn't it?
You're startling the one who did it.
Na Seok Cheol!
Hurry and bring the secret bank code.
The sister of Han Gi Tak
that you care so much about,
If you want to see her live. Got it?
Hello?!
Da Hye is with Na Seok Cheol!
- What?- This brat...
knows about our secret.
No! He can't know that Da
Hye is my little sister.
Then what do you want me to do?
Leave them be?!
No! It's my fault, I'll take care of it.
I lived under your name.
Because he missed you,
your brother gave me that name.
Oppa...
Clean out slowly. We have lots of time.
Seung Jae...
Seung Jae! Keep it together! Did
Na Seok Cheol do this to you?
How long have you been like this?!
I told you... yesterday.
You brat!
I told you not to!
Go.
Seung Jae!
Help!
Excuse me! Call 911 please!
Seung Jae! Wake up! Choi Seung Jae!!
You packed everything up, I see.
Do you want to ride my car? I
have something to tell you.
It's fine. It's late, I'll leave.
I really don't like repeating myself.
What are you doing?
What do you think?
Han Na's father... Yeong Soo...
Don't!
Manager...
You're finally here!
Are you okay?
But, you Branch Manager.
Did you come empty handed?
Na Seok Cheol!
Do you want to go to hell?!
Yes, I want to go to hell
so I'm living like this.
Come here.
I won't die. I won't die. I won't
die because I've already died once.
Come here!
Come here, I said!
This brat.
Where is the secret bank code?! I don't
have time to plaay with you like this!
I'm the one who has the
least amount of time.
I'm the one who worked for 15
years under a crappy company!
You really don't get what I'm saying.
I don't know about anything else,
but I will protect Da Hye.
Try and protect her.
No! No! Please don't!
Don't touch Da Hye!
This bastard, really...
It came out well.
Hong Nan...
Let's see each other, I'm leaving soon.
Noonim, sister said she was
going to go back to America.
How would I die, leaving
you alone, Song Yi Yeon.
He doesn't resent you. He never has.
Meet a good person.
Like a friend, like family, someone
that can be there for you like that.
Where is the secret bank code?!
You cute pair. I should eat both of you.
Na Seok Cheol!!
Isn't that what you want?
Yes! That's it!
Give it to oppa.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Don't cry.
Give it. Hurry and give it to me.
You, is living like this worth it to you?
Yeah. It's worth living.
Thus, pretty, give it me.
You try and come get it.
How much people are you going to kill?
Wasn't Han Gi Tak enough?
Big Hyungnim, Seung Jae, and now even them. Are you
going to kill all of them just for that money?
What's wrong with money?
Do I have to lose to Han
Gi Tak my whole life?
He should be thankful to
Song Yi Yeon's father.
Because he made the person that my face
like this linger around all this time.
What are you saying?
He's been following me
around my whole life.
Just blocking up my way. That's Han Gi Tak!
- Don't!- Let's stop now.
No!
Don't do it!
It's mine!
No!
Save me! Save me!
This crazy...
No! Let go of his hand!
Don't! I was wrong! I did bad things!
Yeah, let's stop now... Seok Cheol.
No! Let go of his hand!
Be happy.
The people I love.
Don't! You can't leave me!
My sister, until the last moment,
I leave her to you, Brother-in-law.
Don't be like this! No!
Bye, you quack.
Oppa...
No!
No! Please...
Don't go! Please!
No!
Thank you for loving my sister so much.
Among the reasons we came back, there must be a
reason the people up there felt bad for us and
wanted us to know one thing before we left.
To me, I think one of those
things is you, Kim Yeong Soo.
No!
♪ Only tears come out. But this
is what farewells are like ♪
♪ I loved you so much.♪
Hong Nan!
♪ A fool like me ♪
♪ We are separating like this. ♪
♪ I, not even once ♪
♪ I have no regrets of loving you. ♪
♪ One more time, ♪
♪ If I had a chance, I will
never let go of our love ♪
You...
This time,
I'm going to say goodbye.
Don't go.
Don't cry.
♪ The dummy I am for being greedy ♪
♪ We are separating like this. ♪
♪ I have never ♪
♪ I have no regrets of loving you. ♪
♪ One more time. ♪
♪ If I got the chance ♪
♪ I will never let go of our love ♪
Oppa... Don't go.
Where am I going, you brat?
♪ Deep in my heart ♪
You're by my side, right?
♪ The dummy I am for being greedy ♪
♪ We are separating like this. ♪
♪ I never have ♪
♪ I have no regrets of loving you. ♪
♪ Just one more time, ♪
♪ If I had a chance ♪
♪ I will never let go of our love ♪
♪ Like before ♪
♪ If I could see you,
so that I can feel you♪
♪ Even if it's just for one day ♪
♪ Come back to me. ♪
♪ I will empty this spot for you ♪
♪ To me, while I am waiting for you ♪
Yes officer, so Na Seok Chul...
We don't know the details for sure yet.
But we think it was because of a fall.
Nonetheless, thank you
for your cooperation.
Yes, you worked hard.
I told you if you cry everywhere, you're the Ugly One,
right? If someone makes fun of you, what do you do?
One two, one two!
That's right.
That's right, my dongsaeng.
Han Gi Tak's memories disappeared.
I will... I will remember those moments.
Ahjumma, are you okay?
Manager.
Huh?
Hae Joon...
Yes.
Why are you looking at me like that?
I was glad to meet you.
How is it? It's warm, right?
Ahjussi, this is quite...
Winter is in a long time.
Hey! What are you saying.
Here, this is Han Na's first bra!
And this is perfume, rose and, kiss...
Kiss? If you get a boyfriend,
tell it to mom and grandpa.
And you have to make sure it's
someone as good as your dad, okay?
Yes, yes. But, what is this one?
You're not giving it to me?
This is a tiara. This is what
brides wear for their wedding.
Your dad would have liked it if he
saw you wearing a wedding dress.
I'm going to marry you.
- Huh?- Let's practice.
It's nothing you force. It's something that
comes naturally, that's what family is.
He is looking handsome lately.
I'm not going to miss you
father, so you stay here
and watch Han Na get married and have kids
after all of that, let's meet again.
Father, I was happy to be your son.
♪ I close my eyes again and again. ♪
♪ I can't erase the memories. ♪
♪ I keep calling your name ♪
♪ I love you, I love you. ♪
♪ Don't leave. Don't go without me ♪
♪ The days I'm not with you,
I think I'm going to cry ♪
♪ It hurts so much. It seems
like you're going to come ♪
♪ I close my eyes again. ♪
The sister that I abandoned but
didn't take off the family list.
Now I will be the real Hong Nan. This
is the only way to protect that child.
Hold onto this photo for me.
No matter what happens to me, so that
she can move the money with this code.
♪ I think I'm going to cry ♪
This time, no matter what,
I will protect her.
♪ It feels like you'll really
appear, if I close my eyes again ♪
Good work, Han Hyung.♪ If
I close my eyes again ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ I see you ♪
Eat before you leave.
It's curry.
When I first got married, the
me who didn't know how to cook,
only made curry every day.
Even after eating curry for 365
days, he never complained once.
After that person left, it's
my first time making it again.
Yes, I wish for you to become a
little bit more comfortable.
Like you said before, it would be good
if we never saw each other again.
If we see each other by chance, let's
pretend that we don't know each other.
Don't act like you know me because I'm
going to act like I don't know you.
I won't.
Even if I'm rude and say mean
things, don't cry about it.
Insult me like a cool person
and just turn around.
I understand.
Channel managers: pilar_velasquez & tompark
Thank you to The Possessed seggers: pilar_velasquez,
emikodragon, xiennora, dudie, robertases
Thank you to The Possessed seggers cont.:
earsds, kitty100, shms, mihaelagh, wanttogo
cgwm808, bjohnsonwong, laura_garrido, tompark
I thought I would have some soju with
Hyungnim on the train ride to heaven.
It's a relief though that there will be
someone who will remember Han Gi Tak.
He left coolly right?
Refusing the train to heaven, was
there a purpose to your return?
Of course! If I didn't come back,
things would have been really bad!
What is it? Do you still
have lingering attachments?
As I hoped for her not to realize me,
I still hoped for her to realize it was me.
Oh, I thought you had
something you didn't say.
I didn't say my farewells to her.
To say bye.
Today my favorite curry
has appeared once again!
Thank you to The Possessed subbers: dolcehime,
changhuh, itsjoo, sera19_27, paasyk_838
Thank you to The Possessed subbers cont.: joy_yoo_3,
soyummay, geneva68, genevievesee, yiji1997, manaphy
To Han Na's mom that I love. My Da Hye.
For meeting such an incompetent husband,
you're going through a lot aren't you?
I told you I'd make you happy yet all I've been doing
is making you go through hard times. I'm sorry.
But one day, with Han Na and you,
I will become a Kim Yeong Soo
that you won't be embarrassed of.
I'm always thankful and I love you.
Thank you to The Possessed subbers cont.: pikasquirtchar014,
aoh705_vip, dramadramaok, imashl3y, seowoocho_477
You've worked hard, today as well.
You've worked hard today as well.
I worked hard today as well.
Thank you so much to
Translation Editor: Changhuh
Many thanks to our editors:
mirna023_316 - joysprite​
♪ In my two empty eyes ♪
♪ the image of you appears going far away ♪
♪ I waited for you ♪
♪ who were like such a warm spring day. ♪
Goodbye.♪ I waited for you ♪
♪ While knowing everything, the
time you won't come to me ♪
♪ I want and want even more ♪
♪ The person who can't stay with me. ♪
Farewell.
♪ You thought very
occasionally of my name too. ♪
♪ Unable to leave ♪
It's fine. This much is enough.♪
You also like me are crying. ♪
♪ You also like me are crying. ♪
Even after the marriage, you
constantly had projects.
You are playing a role of someone
that has fallen deeply in love.
Do you perhaps have a special
love that you have experienced?
I wonder. I don't know when it started but
from somebody
I get the feelings that I've
received an embarrassing love.
Even during hard times, I
endured with that strength.
I have really became relaxed.
A new road?
Yes, that is the case.
What did you do before coming here?
I held a knife.
I like men who cook.
Noonim. Rather than a cook, what
do you think about a barista?
My son. Mommy really really misses you.
Mommy is almost there so
wait just a little longer.
What do you want to eat? Chicken?
Okay let's go eat that. If my son wants to
eat it then of course Mommy has to buy that.
Of course! Mommy is going to make lots of
money and buy delicious food for Yeong Chan.
Thanks a lot to our Chief Editor: cgwm808
Thanks to Cover Wall and
Thank You Cards: tompark
Thank you to our English
moderators: lupita311 & yiji1997
Thank you for watching with us!
Oh my!
Branch Manager! You're so handsome today!
I heard you got into an accident but it seems
after that, you have gotten even more handsome.
Thanks to the employee resting
room, my back discs are all gone!
It's all better now, Branch Manager.
Excuse me.
But... Isn't that seaweed?
Huh?
Are you talking behind the back
of your superior, Sister Po?
- No!- Never!
Didn't I plead with you?
Because the Branch Manager hurt his
head on a hit and run accident,
even if he does strange things,
let's be his warm co-workers.
-Understand?-Yes!
Please distribute my shares
equally to the employees.
Are you sincere?
I told you.
What about the management rights...
The managing just needs someone who can manage well, and
regardless of who, they are still company employee.
See that they don't make decisions
without the consent of the employees.
To: Lee Hae Joon
If you are reading this letter then
that means that I have left this world.
For the past two months, just like you have
experienced those ordeals like a dream,
I too, experienced a dream like
time here borrowing your name.
In order to protect this department
store, I ruined your plan.
But I don't want to apologize.
In exchange for bringing up this
department store from the bottom,
Would it be selfish of me to say that I gifted
you employees that love and care for you?
Rather than living for revenge, I
hope that you live for happiness.
From: A friend that looks like your twin.
"You're fired from the company, what
are you doing here?" is what he says.
How our Manager Lee is handling
the proxy president role...
I was curious as to whether or not
protecting the Chairman spot well.
Also, my aging father,
I pity seeing him tidying
up the president's messes.
I wanted to be of some help.
What do you want to do,
Chairman, Lee Hae Joon?
Although I did resent you
to death, and I still do...
Hyung.
Hyung?!
Also, Father.
What the hell?
I want to call you that at least once.
Before I die, at least once,
I want to call you that.
Father, and Hyung too.
I don't know!
I don't know what he is trying to say!
Until when do I have to keep doing this?!
Please, have a conversation!
Talk, please!
Stop it. Living once with you is enough.
Let's go eat. I have a
lot of free time lately.
You said you wanted me to act more like a Dad. If I don't do
it now when I have a lot of free time, when will I ever do it?
Since when were you that considerate?
Cha Yeong Chan! Don't go too far away!
Thank you.
Do you know how much I like your dad?
We have some similarities
so it makes me happy.
Your dad was a very successful person.
You can be proud of him.
I wanted to tell you that so I came here.
- Ahjussi...- Yes?
Later on, will you teach me how to dance?
Of course!
♪ Oh I see it all ♪
♪ Oh I see it now. ♪
♪ Let it.♪
♪ One, ♪
♪ Two, ♪
♪ Three,♪
♪ Get set! Go! ♪
♪ Bye bye bye, goodbye! No, no, no! ♪
♪ Oh you tell me more,
just lay it all on me ♪
♪Because, ♪
Excuse me...
I'm on my way to apply for
workers' compensation insurance.
♪ Can't you get a hold of yourself?! ♪
What?
Never mind.
♪ I'm so dizzy. ♪
♪ Maybe I have two faces ♪
♪ I'm falling again ♪
♪ Wait for me ♪
♪ I'm frightened! ♪
♪ I'm scared! ♪
♪ Forget the night I chose ♪
♪ Don't let it go.♪
♪ Thank you to make some noise. ♪
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
♪ I promise you. ♪
♪ I'm wagering my all ♪
But... Have we ever met?
I'm not sure. I haven't
been here for that long.
It's the same for me.
Why are you laughing?
It's nothing.
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
I'm not that kind of woman.
Did I say something?
Why are you still laughing?
I'm sorry.
Thanks for watching Please
Come Back, Mister on Viki!
I'm taking it.
Kimchi! One, two, three!♪ The
road I accidentally was walking ♪
♪ felt familiar and I stopped there ♪
Ahjussi, can you take a picture of us,
please?♪ felt familiar and I stopped there ♪
♪ In the place where I was ♪
♪ Together with beautiful
you that stupid night ♪
One, two, three!♪ Together with
beautiful you that stupid night ♪
♪ Will you give a smile ♪
Father![Kim Yeong Soo]
What are you doing in my car, you brat!
Father, can't I ask you this once?
I have to drive around cars like
this so that I can succeed.
Stop the nonsense and go
home to do your chores!
Go go!
That way I'll be able to
bring home a pretty wife!
You should study well
before thinking about this!
You can't do anything.
Just wait!
♪ Wanna stay up all night ♪
♪ Even though the sleepless
times are too long ♪
♪ I want to experience the
day that will get better ♪
♪ cuz I’m still waiting for you ♪
♪ I am Imprisoned in the pitch darkness ♪
♪ The past memories are sweet ♪
♪ I remember and want you now ♪
♪ I want only you ♪
♪ Moon Light ♪
♪ Thinking about you tonight ♪
Thanks for watching Please
Come Back, Mister on Viki!