[Members gathered for a secret meeting.]
Sixth Man Project.
New member?
Robin, Batman.
[Candidates that fit in well.]
[Elite candidates.]
Even a poisoned Holy Grail
is the Holy Grail.
Go beyond the limit.
Something never experienced before.
Subtitles Ripped By www.vikisubtitle.com
Me.
[Candidates who don't want it?]
Grab him and knock him over.
[Candidates with strong personalities.]
Park Myung Soo?
[Necklaces delivered!]
Who gives the final okay?
[Not a smooth process.]
Think about it carefully.
Among numerous data that's available,
the experts have gathered simple
keywords that describe the candidates.
[Data collection and analysis
of the candidates!]
The long-awaited Sixth Man Project!
[The result of the Sixth Man Project?]
[Wednesday night, the day before
Infinity Challenge taping.]
[Infinity Challenge's emergency
call inviting the candidates.]
Everyone, hello!
Infinity Challenge!
We're missing one.
Another one left?
No.
- Jung Hyung Don is coming later at 10pm.
- He's coming.
Anyways...
[Hyung Don joining after
Cool Kiz On the Block.]
Sixth Man Project.
To the interest of many and
the 21 Sixth Man candidates,
thank you all.
Anyways, speaking of...
Park Myung Soo has ended up at
the edge spot he hates so much.
This was Park Myung Soo's
biggest fear on this show.
A spot at the edge.
It happens with just one missing.
I'm sorry but that can be the edge, too.
Like cliffs over there.
We need a new guest.
- It was 21 people?
- Our members don't even know yet.
Out of the Sixth Man candidates
who expressed interest...
Out of the ones who showed more interest
with big data analysis of viewers' opinions
and through the research of
many producers and writers,
we invited 8 candidates with the
hottest responses out of the total 21.
It was a survival game!
The most important thing
here is their strong will.
That's right.
The candidates will be arriving shortly.
What comes to mind for MBC Yeouido?
Most recently, it's Kevin!
[Will the candidates be as
easily scared as the members?]
Home Alone!
Not as much as Home Alone but
we did prepare some surprises.
[1: Flares after the entrance.]
[2: Honking from an empty car.]
[3: Ghost doll drop.]
[Welcome greeting prepared
with storage supplies.]
Let's meet the first candidate of
the long-awaited Sixth Man Project!
[First candidate's car arrives.]
[Observing the candidate
through the screen.]
The first candidate.
The first for Sixth Man.
[The passionate candidates
narrowed down to eight...]
[The first candidate to take another
step to being the Sixth Man?]
[Arrives with the
Sixth Man necklace + suit.]
[Kwang Hee - ZE:A member,
Big Data 2nd place, Experts' choice 10th place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired: honest,
interesting, jealous, cursing, fits well, new, cute...]
- Hwang Kwang Hee.
- Kwang Hee?
Kwang Hee!
The first candidate is Kwang Hee!
[Entering the welcome greeting course.]
[Announcement: Enter after facial recognition.]
Coincidentally one day...
[Hold on...]
[Facial recognition...]
I think it's done.
He's coming.
[Enters the first stage.]
[How will he respond to the welcome greeting?]
[Welcome present, flares.]
[Original scaredy-cats even more surprised.]
What is that?
[Body frozen but his
mouth is causing a fuss.]
It scared me.
It scared me. So embarrassing.
That flare isn't a big deal.
It's a festival.
[Stage 2: Horn]
The overall mood isn't that scary.
What is that?
[Sharp voice and controlled
snap of the wrist.]
[Properly showing his
remaining reactions.]
What is that?
This is fun.
[I like this move.]
He's so scared.
[Last stage: The ghost doll drop.]
What is this?
[Masterpiece scream is
a delight on the ears.]
[Octave 1.] [Octave 2.] [Octave 3.]
[Reaches 3 octaves while bending
his body in three stages.]
That's good.
Is this physical training?
This is all we've prepared.
It's not even an appetizer.
Still, it's pretty good for
Kwang Hee's first stunt.
[Buffet level reactions
to the small menu.]
Hwang Kwang Hee, congratulations!
[Meeting the captivated audience.]
Hwang Kwang Hee,
thank you for participating.
Please go to the spot that
you would like to be in.
- It's so embarrassing.
- Quickly.
Be greedy! This is really important.
[Taking the advice to be greedy
in selecting his desired spot?]
[Next to Jae Suk in the
central sphere of influence.]
Why did you pick this spot?
I felt like I have to
at least be next to you.
What about being next to us?
It's too senile over there.
[Insistent about the tried
and true spot next to #1.]
Hwang Kwang Hee, I heard
about Star King and Ho Dong.
They said they'll send me off.
Waiting to hear from here.
They said they would send you
off, but you said it wasn't true.
[On SBS Star King last week,
a cool good-bye to Kwang Hee.]
Say your last good-byes.
I can't say good-bye yet!
The order hasn't come through.
They haven't confirmed anything yet!
[Tough position.]
Why do you keep going back and forth?
Then you come here when we call.
I need to keep a foot in a door
in case this doesn't work!
I asked my company to try...
some corruption, some lobbying.
Lobby for what?
Nice, nice.
But they said you didn't
take any of that!
Can't talk to you guys at all.
Yeah, not at all.
So please explain your position.
Really?
I want to do this!
I want to do this! It's crazy right now.
My church made banners for me.
The elder thinks I'm already a member!
The church elder congratulated you?
Full congregation prayer!
It's forty day special prayer time.
What did Si Wan, Park Hyung Shik,
and Dong Jun say?
Im Si Wan got competitive.
Im Si Wan?
He saw it!
He said I'm the kid who
was on Infinity Challenge.
Si Wan?
He's a little nervous now.
You know why?
It seems like I'll make it. Being nice to me.
If you join us, you'll beat
Si Wan and Hyung Shik.
What do you mean?
He wins.
Si Wan signed a movie contract recently!
Kwang Hee, your paths are different!
He has movie contracts piling
up and I have trash piling up!
Movie and commercial contracts piling up!
[Runaway engine of ambition, Kwang Hee.]
Let's sit and wait for the next candidate.
I'll support you.
[Second candidate arrives.]
They're coming!
[Need to beat this person
over Im Si Wan...]
[Second candidate revealed.]
Hello!
[Kang Gyun Sung - Noel member,
Big data 3rd place, Experts' choice 3rd place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired:
Funny, hit, laughter, perverted, shocking, new...]
[Not an easy rival...]
[Long strides forward.]
[Immediately enters stage 1
without facial recognition.]
[Kang Gyun Sung's reaction?]
[Run away.]
It scared me.
[Running without the chance
to see his reaction.]
[The horn. His reaction?]
[The swift scaredy-cat runs again.]
[Stage 3 drop.]
[Reactionless sprinter.]
[Ended with a short scream.]
Why are you running?
I thought I should come quickly.
[Second Sixth Man candidate,
Kang Gyun Sung.]
Gyun Sung.
Go to the spot you want.
- Where?
- Where you want to stand.
Where you would stand
in Infinity Challenge.
[Taking the great spot
he had put dibs on.]
One, two...
Three. Is that it?
I like it here.
[This is my spot.]
- He's nice.
- Why?
He's so different from Kwang Hee.
Come on, man!
Why? Why?
- What?
- Why?
I think it would be easier for the
others to manipulate me in this spot.
Manipulate me in this spot.
[Passive position.] [Leading position.]
In the interview you said no one
but you would be a good fit.
One person who can't be.
Kang Gyun Sung.
Why so sad?
Except for him! What one
person? None of them!
Not you either.
No.
He keeps flip flopping.
[You said that?]
Kwang Hee.
Why were you looking at him like that?
It's a competition now.
Since he came as a candidate.
Did you expect to get an invitation?
Me?
Of course!
[Insolent hoobae.]
To be honest.
- You knew it would come?
- Yes.
They're really so different.
Gyun Sung and Kwang Hee have
completely different personalities.
Different...
- I don't know.
- Excited and calm?
Know-it-all?
Not you either!
Kwang Hee, how do you
think you are different?
He's different because...
instead of being funny with words,
he's funny because of imitating
voices and being bipolar.
Wasn't he so funny that day?
First of all, Kwang Hee
has many strengths.
Like what?
No army service yet.
[A biting comment with his soft voice.]
You're too harsh.
Not you either!
[Battlefield with flying bombs.]
That differs from what you said earlier.
You say hurtful things so calmly.
[Quiet sniper of mean
comments, Kang Gyun Sung.]
[Third candidate arrives.]
[Coming]
I'm curious about the next person.
[What sort of rival is next?]
[A dark shadow falls on the young lambs.]
[Jang Dong Min - Popular comedian,
Big Data 9th place, Experts' choice 1st place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired: Honest,
expectant, funny, cursing, intense, laughter, good...]
Dong Min.
Why did you invite him?
Myung Soo's curses are selfish.
Mine are curses of justice.
[He has finally come...]
Ring the bell... Facial recognition...
Facial recognition?
He's very suspicious.
It's manual.
Recognition, yeah right.
[Flare welcome greeting.]
Oh, my God.
Scared me.
Something wrong?
[Manly man.]
[Stage 2: Horn.]
Oh, my God.
[As aloof as if bitten by a mosquito.]
What's this?
[Final stage for the fearless Dong Min.]
Oh, my goodness.
[Ghost drop.]
What the?
[Identical to Myung Soo.]
[Doppelganger?]
I ought to rip it down!
His reaction is just like Myung Soo's.
How could they be so similar?
He's a young Myung Soo.
I ought to just...
He wasn't very scared.
[Rising star of anger, Jang Dong Min.]
Young potty mouth.
Now...
[Myung Soo hyung.]
[Ignore]
[Infiltrates the center
as smooth as water.]
You naturally went to that spot?
Then where should I go?
[Arrival of a powerful enemy.]
You just swooped into this spot.
Can I not stand here?
He's so similar to Park Myung Soo.
The way we kick is the same.
I was scared.
Have you ever worked
with Myung Soo before?
Yes, I have.
It was his first time working with me.
He would yell at female
idol singers and stuff.
I figured that's just him.
Then he suddenly got mad at me.
So I said, "What!?"
He reacted like this.
Then during the break time,
I clearly remember hearing this.
"I don't think Dong Min fits in."
And then,
I was supposed to be permanent.
But I didn't film anymore after that.
[Two people with a history.]
You talked to the producers
to get Dong Min fired!
That's not it.
I don't remember saying that.
Don't remember or didn't do it?
He was a bit too much.
He yelled more than me.
That's why? Jang Dong Min,
after you aired on Sixth Man,
how was others' responses?
- There was a lot of talk.
- Like what?
That I definitely have to do this.
[Short but heavy response from others.]
Who?
Yoo Sang Moo and Yoo Se Yoon
even said to quit other stuff.
They said I definitely have to do this.
Even your colleagues...
Kwang Hee is so...
He was so bright earlier.
How do you feel meeting him, Dong Min?
He got a lot of mean comments.
He was sad.
So how did he have the
balls to come here?
[Definitely the rising star of anger.]
- He's unexpectedly shy in front of Dong Min.
- Balls, that's good.
Who do you think is the
strongest candidate?
Who?
Gyun Sung's good.
[You're too kind.]
I saw the multiple personalities.
It reeked of acting.
[Reeked of acting...]
Smells travel through TV?
[Flinch]
You do something, too!
I'm not good at fighting.
Things like fighting.
Who's fighting right now?
I'm not good at fighting.
[Fourth candidate arrives!]
They're here!
[The fourth strong
candidate for Sixth Man?]
[Choi Siwon - Super Junior member,
Big data 6th place, Experts' choice 5th place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired: Good fit,
good-looking, positive, let himself go, shocking...]
He has the highest point for passion.
[Guarding himself]
Why did he come here?
[Enters while whistling
with an actor vibe.]
He's got an attitude.
He's fearless, right?
Probably.
[Knock knock.]
[At the facial recognition,
he tries voice recognition.]
[It opened!]
- He came in.
- Let's see his first reaction.
[Flare gift.]
[What... so different from the first three...]
[Like 007 after completing a mission?]
It's like a movie.
[What? Do they want me to do something?]
[Coughing with satisfaction.]
American reaction!
American reaction.
[Fixes his clothes like a
Hollywood secret spy...]
[Entering stage 2!]
[Mommy!]
[Welcome!]
[His agent footwork.]
Did you see that?
[Sad reenactment of the American moves.]
[Continues to maintain his spy charisma.]
[Calmly walks to stage 3!]
Be quiet!
The ghost.
[Boo]
What is this?
[Spy charisma shatters in one blow.]
[American agent reveals his humanness.]
How dare you act cool?
American reaction.
He was surprised.
So cool.
I was so surprised.
- So good-looking.
- You weren't shocked at all.
Except Gyun Sung, everyone looks
like a squid in comparison.
My face?
My face? No way!
Kwang Hee. Come here and look.
No!
Excluding Gyun Sung, everyone
looks like a squid.
You know how much silicone I got?
Be grateful to your silicone.
[Only as bad as a squid
thanks to the silicone.]
Siwon!
[Will his amazing looks be a pro or con?]
He's so good-looking.
Incredible.
Siwon. Please be honest and go to
the spot you would like to be in.
Looking at height, I think I belong here.
For balance.
Why here?
Jun Ha is on the right.
On the left now.
Gyun Sung is on the right.
You're on the left.
Dong Min and Kwang Hee are next to me.
[Lumps of ambition.]
We're very realistic.
Idealistic over here.
All of Siwon's movements are...
slightly Hollywoodesque.
Especially when surprised.
[Fancy footwork.]
[Calm 1, 2 step.]
I felt like Michael Jackson.
It was a new reaction.
Something never seen
before in entertainment.
It was slightly cheesy.
My appeal is that I'm fresh.
[He's good.]
Fresh.
[Was I good?]
I blocked his path to you.
[Going for a high five with Ha Ha.]
[Quick with the other hand.]
[Top at adjusting to new situations.]
Both hands are ready.
Siwon is amazing.
[Jealous...]
Kwang Hee.
You're both idols.
Why are you suddenly...
taking a step back now?
Because he just has so much.
And you just can't beat SM.
Look at him.
Only incredible people are here.
Your boss is going to be so upset.
My dream is to go to SM.
I'll even go to a subsidiary company.
[Asking for trouble...]
Even at Infinity Challenge,
you keep looking to go somewhere else.
I need to go to a good
place. Noblesse oblige.
That's about moral duty,
it's not applicable here.
[Just let complicated things go.]
Take your hands out. You're on air.
Should I just freeze to death?
[Taken aback.]
You have a jacket on.
You're good.
[Stay on your toes.]
We have four Sixth Man candidates here.
As one of our members couldn't
come due to another filming...
Who? Who's missing?
- The fat one.
- Ah, yes.
Ah, yes.
He's good.
It's a new reaction.
[Was I good?]
We have the next candidate.
Please sit.
Hang your jacket.
[Sitting in their places...]
Kwang Hee, come here.
[Kwang Hee standing far away.]
Why are you being so shy?
SM makes me uncomfortable.
[Fifth candidate arrives.]
The next candidate.
It's the fifth candidate.
[A very slim man...]
What is that?
Leon?
[An extraordinary fifth candidate?]
[Hong Jin Kyung - Big data 12th place,
Experts' choice 7th place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired: Positive,
laughter, strong, honest, passion, shocking...]
Why did she come like that?
Why'd she do that?
I thought she was a monkey.
[Entering stage 1!]
[Entrance present!]
[Scared me...]
Scared me.
[Bearded ahjusshi is unfazed.]
[Passing stage 2 like a real man.]
Scared me.
[Fearless manly man.]
She doesn't get scared.
[Last chance, stage 3.]
What is it?
[Boo!]
Oh, my God!
Mommy!
[Got her!]
[The entertainment reaction comes alive.]
[Fully satisfied.]
My goodness.
Why did you draw a beard?
[Completely prepared
to be the Sixth Man.]
Jae Suk hyung!
What are you doing?
What do you mean, hyung?
There were a lot of comments
that said no woman.
[Jin Kyung came dressed as a man.]
They said a woman can't do it.
[They look like brothers.]
[She's unstoppable.]
What are you doing?
It's a hermaphrodite theme today.
[She's a strong rival...]
That's my theme today.
Where did you do your beard?
At home with a sponge.
- You have it at home?
- Yes.
[She gets an A for dedication.]
I'm very prepared.
You look like Lee Yoon Suk.
She looks like Han Ki Bum.
[Exactly the same!]
[So proud.]
Hong Jin Kyung, thank you.
We did this for everyone else.
If you were to join, please
pick where your spot would be.
- Jung Hyung Don is there?
- Yes.
Pick comfortably.
I've seen this man before.
If I join, I'll stay here.
Why?
Here?
You seem easiest to get along with.
This is a really hard spot.
When I talk like this, you have to move.
I can do this.
[Gap attacks possible.]
First of all, her face is just too funny.
[Fitting appearance for gap attacks.]
Her looks fit in with us.
Out of everyone, she's the first
to make us laugh with looks.
- She's too strong.
- Hong Jin Kyung...
- As soon as she arrived...
- First time the appearance cracks me up.
Jin Kyung, the other candidates are here.
What do you think?
I called Kwang Hee during the day.
I heard.
I asked what he's doing
and he said he's taping.
I asked what he was doing later at 9pm.
He said Infinity Challenge.
[The two knew the other was coming.]
I also called Kim Young Chul.
When I asked, he said let's drink.
[He wasn't invited...]
He doesn't know we're filming tonight.
He wanted to drink.
That must be why he called me.
I didn't say anything
but he saw an article.
He said to call Producer Kim Tae Ho.
Say he's making a mistake.
[They said they would call us soon
but why haven't they called me yet?]
Have strength, Super Power!
[The others all arrived by car...]
The sixth candidate walks in on his own.]
Who?
[Who is it...?]
[The petite sixth candidate?]
[Yoo Byung Jae - Writer/Actor -
Big data 1st place, Experts' choice 6th place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired:
Honest, positive, sincere, rejection, charming...]
He said he didn't want it.
He went back and forth.
[Following the directions
for facial recognition.]
I'm curious about his reaction.
[Come on in!]
[Byung Jae falling over with joy.]
[That punk is... impressive...]
[Sending a gaze of resentment.]
His reaction is good.
[Wavering]
[Surprised]
[Nervous without anything happening.]
It really shocked him.
Come out!
Are you there?
I know you're there.
Hmph!
[Bluffing]
[Arriving at stage 2.]
[If that was stage 1...]
[The end of the world.]
[Save me!]
[Blockbuster reaction right
in front of my eyes!]
[I won't let this go...]
[Calms his heart and enters stage 3.]
Ah, s###!
[Exciting dance moves.]
[Amazing]
[Standing ovation.]
I'm sorry.
[If you're sorry, one more time!]
[Stop doing this...]
Yoo Byung Jae!
[High hopes for the rising
star of reactions.]
He's strong.
[Fully satisfied.]
[Oh, my tears.]
[Sixth Sixth Man candidate,
Yoo Byung Jae.]
[A hand's length shorter than Ha Ha.]
You are really small!
[Right into my arms!]
Ha Ha's the happiest to see him.
Why are you laughing at her?
[How can you not laugh?]
Ah, my beard?
- I really like her.
- Really?
What do you like about me?
You're so funny.
- What are you doing?
- He said he likes me.
- Be still.
- Yes.
Your clothes are really nice today.
They said to dress like K*******.
He's like a kindergartener.
Kindergartener!
[His short friend betrayed him.]
How can you say that?
What do you mean kindergartener?
- Byung Jae.
- Yes.
Have you made a decision?
I was very conflicted.
How do you really feel?
I want to do it.
Honestly, it's a sweet offer...
It's a heavy crown to inherit.
So, I don't want to do it.
You just said...
You just said you wanted it.
- Have you decided to do it?
- Yes.
Let's pick your spot.
Just say where you would like to be.
Pretend Hyung Don is here.
- Hyung Don's here.
- Just go where you want to go.
On the very end.
You won't be seen.
I don't need that. Don't
really want the spotlight.
Don't lie!
Then don't come here!
[Logical response instead of curses.]
Why did you come?
For the spotlight.
Film me only! Nowhere else!
[Is he really my doppelganger?]
- He's exactly like Myung Soo.
- Come here.
- He's like a young me.
- So cute!
As you can see, Byung Jae is in his 20s.
- What?
- I didn't know.
- 28.
- He's 28.
Same age as Im Si Wan.
I'm 28, too! How dare you
use Im Si Wan as an example?
[Neurotic about Im Si Wan!]
[Hard to escape from Si Wan's shadow.]
What did you do today?
I came earlier and ate just out front.
What did you eat?
Buckwheat noodles and dumplings.
By yourself?
- You don't have a manager?
- No.
No company?
Why are you talking down?
[Fickle man shuts Kwang Hee up.]
[Let's have some manners...]
[He's not wrong.]
I was asking for you.
How dare you?
Hey!
Why don't you have a company?
I don't. I'm a writer.
He's a writer?
You didn't know?
What's a writer doing here?
Just keep writing.
He came all the way here.
So this is our sixth Sixth Man candidate,
Yoo Byung Jae!
He's got an incredible height.
So funny.
[Waiting for the next candidate.]
You came like this?
Yes.
Not here?
I came from the salon like this.
They're here.
Not the last one but...
[The seventh candidate?]
[The celebrity pose.]
[Seo Jang Hoon - Now a celeb,
Big data 8th place, Experts' choice 9th place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired: Good,
honest, big, uptight, incredible, new, laughter...]
[Folded in half for the facial recognition.]
He's so funny. He gets scared easily.
He gets scared so easily.
The door is open.
Facial recognition?
[Entering stage 1.]
[Boom!]
[Flapping]
[Game begins from stage 1.]
[What is this?]
[Staggering]
So surprised...
He gets scared easily.
Look at him.
[Jang Hoon cowering.]
He was Goliath.
He gets scared very easily.
[The dignity of Goliath
has vanished and now...]
[The master of reactions.]
Seriously!
[Such a celebrity...]
So surprised.
[I'm so scared...]
He has a comedian's face.
I'm so scared of these things.
[Bam]
[Mommy!!!]
[I want to go home!]
[Running away to the entrance.]
- Hurry up.
- It's over, come in.
It's over.
[Something else is going to happen...]
There's nothing else!
So suspicious!
He's a softie.
Our seventh candidate for Sixth Man.
Don't act like you don't want to do it.
He'll say no.
No, that's not it.
I came with different thoughts.
What kind?
[Such a chatty hyung...]
You wore a nice suit!
Looks good.
Different thoughts.
What kind of thoughts?
You will see a new me today.
What will you show us?
The reason I came today
is because it's so unfair.
What's unfair?
I was mentioned from the very
beginning for no reason.
I dealt with so many mean comments.
You did?
Since I dealt with that anyways,
it makes sense to take
that after I've tried it.
[Blabbing on and on.]
So today I'm going to
be different from usual.
If you want it, just say you want it!
I've let it all go.
And really, I'm furious.
Great, anyways. Whether you felt it was
unfair or not, thank you again for coming here.
So seven of the Sixth Man
candidates have gathered here.
One person hasn't come yet.
This person will come after
a pre-scheduled event ends.
They're too busy!
So with the eight Sixth Man candidates
who received invitations,
and with all of you
who have participated,
Infinity Challenge!
[Sixth Man Secret Member]
[Byung Jae enters alone.]
[Empty]
[Enjoying the freedom of the empty room.]
[Gyun Sung enters just in time.]
[The two candidates sit far apart.]
[Hoobae singer Siwon enters.]
Hee Chul's hair is
about as long as yours.
Hee Chul?
[Cheery with their talk.]
[Sitting on pins and needles.]
I didn't know Choi Siwon would come.
Last week, I thought he was just a guest.
He really came.
I wondered if he really wanted to do it.
It's cold.
[Everyone nervous at the
fighting rooster's entrance?]
Byung Jae.
[So happy to just hear his name.]
[Daddy long legs Jang Hoon.]
[Youngest Kwang Hee.]
[All the candidates gather.]
[Eyes sparkling.]
As soon as I saw Jin Kyung,
I thought she'd get it.
I think it's a good opportunity to
add a new aspect of her as a woman.
To be honest, Hong Jin Kyung.
Hong Jin Kyung.
Too funny.
[Her prediction is Kwang Hee!]
Jang Dong Min.
Not sure.
[Not even the candidates can predict.]
Will someone really get picked?
[Out of us?]
It'll really be one of us?
No. It might not be.
If it's not one of us,
Infinity Challenge will be in trouble.
Imagine if it's one of us.
[One of us... maybe me?]
Siwon looks like a work of art.
[Responding with an American reaction.]
And he happens to be next
to Jang Hoon and Dong Min.
A work of art.
My eyes feel refreshed.
Why did you sit here?
[What is it?]
After filming,
you will all vote to pick four people.
We'll let you know the
results afterwards.
The eight Sixth Man
candidates invited today.
The final candidates will
be decided by their votes.
Who will be the final
Sixth Man candidate?
[After the producer's announcement...]
[Thinking...]
[Only half of us will be picked?]
[A silence fills the dressing room.]
Many people just physically can't do it.
Siwon definitely can't.
It's not possible?
You can wrap things up.
I think they want Siwon the most,
but the world won't let him be.
Don't be fooled, Infinity Challenge.
It's up to Siwon.
He could if he stayed in
country. He goes international.
There's too much money involved.
He would be fine without the money.
Come on.
He wants it, why do you
think it won't happen?
Why put up the fences?
[Siwon is the #1 competition.]
Why put up the fences? I'm just grateful.
I've been abroad a lot so I think I could
create some more humorous scenes.
[Sixth Man Secret Member]
[Agent Jung Hyung Don joins in
the Sixth Man headquarters.]
[The candidates enter the
heart of Sixth Man project.]
[Let's see...]
Jin Kyung.
Oh, my God!
[Hyung Don's first time
seeing Jin Kyung.]
What the?
Nice.
Hong Jin Kyung.
- It's cheating.
- Her face is cheating.
[Face clearly cheating.]
She's a girl.
There were so many comments saying
I couldn't do it because I'm a girl.
It's just too funny.
I came because I wanted to show you
that I could play a man and woman.
[Not fair.]
Anyways, everyone.
Thank you all for being here.
The member who couldn't come yet due
to his schedule will arrive soon.
Who's not busy? Why wait
for someone like him?
I changed my flight time.
From when to when?
From evening to day.
[Dedicated enough to return to
Korea because of Sixth Man.]
Subtitles Ripped By www.vikisubtitle.com
Great attitude.
I had a two part shoot today.
I See Your Voice.
But I just didn't film the
second part because of this.
But this guy's working?
How arrogant...
[The last candidate arrives just in time.]
[The final person to join Sixth Man?]
[Huh?]
[Jeon Hyun Moo - Multi-entertainer,
Big data 7th place, Experts choice 2nd place.]
[Related key words after Sixth Man aired:
New, busy, hard, not a good fit, popular, good...]
[Arriving with bananas on his head.]
[Shape of bananas visible from afar.]
Is this it?
Ring the bell and open
after facial recognition.
[Why's it so quiet...]
[Boldly opens the door and enters.]
[Trembling]
Oh, my God!
[Tropical fruit tree shaking
like a poplar tree.]
It scared me.
[One more time.]
What is that?
[Doesn't lose bananas.]
That scared me.
[Looking around.]
[Even the silhouette of the
banana head is strange.]
I'm scared, is this a haunted house?
[Goes closer to the empty
car while on edge.]
[Stage 2: Honking the horn!]
[Hot mess.]
[Offbeat footsteps.]
[Still doesn't lose the bananas.]
[Clear voice that shows his
background as an announcer.]
[Rich reaction at a high decibel!]
Where do I go?
Don't!
[Nothing there yet...]
[Embarrassed...]
Don't!
[Creeping]
[Quickly]
[Sudden roadblock by the ghost doll.]
[A scene created with a powerful
voice and a giant fuss.]
[100% insane.]
[Much more scary looking
than the ghost doll.]
Fine, I won't do it!
[Should I go or not?]
[After screaming one more time.]
[With no one around to watch him.]
[The final candidate completes the course.]
Before he comes,
what did you do today?
Siwon?
I arrived this morning.
From where?
From the US.
[Surprised]
- Who did you meet?
- A Hollywood movie?
Drama and a movie.
Do that!
He's busy even without this.
[Rough voice fits right in.]
For a moment I thought you were a thief.
Aren't you Lee Won Seung?
Pizza please!
I thought she was a thief.
I thought you were a thief.
What did you do, Jin Kyung?
For me, I did my makeup this morning.
[She merely told the truth.]
Yoo Byung Jae, what did you do?
An interview and meeting.
You look so tired.
Right?
No, I'm not really.
Kang Gyun Sung looks very tired.
- Kang Gyun Sung?
- They're so competitive.
- Your eyes always half closed?
- Yes, I have thick double lids.
Then your eyes should be more
open, not halfway closed.
You only curse?
That side is intense.
Overall, there are some
intense people here.
Are you saying that side is weak?
This side is at ease.
[Eyes that don't seem at ease.]
Hong Jin Kyung?
[Intently looking for someone.]
Looking for PD Kim Tae Ho again?
I don't see him.
Where's PD Kim Tae Ho?
[Gaze continuously going to one place...]
You're noticing the
producer's reaction a lot.
I tend to look a lot. If he doesn't seem
pleased, I move on to the next topic.
You keep looking for him.
Look at honeybee producer.
[Just then!]
[Finally, the last candidate.]
[Entrance of magnificent color.]
A commercial.
Everyone here has filmed
a commercial before!
You should have left it,
why did you wear it here?
I wanted to show off.
I'm sorry for being late.
Nice to see you.
[Confused]
Jeon Hyun Moo.
What? We were waiting for Jeon Hyun Moo?
[Feeling of injustice after the long wait.]
Jeon Hyun Moo.
- You have many shows but you know about this, right?
- Of course.
Looking at your jacket, it
seems you don't know at all.
They didn't tell me what to wear at all.
I had no idea I had to wear a suit.
Everyone, thank you again
to all of you participating.
Out of the 21 Sixth Man candidates,
we sent invitations to 8.
And so, we are here today.
- Again, welcome.
- Welcome!
To verify the talents and
qualifications of the Sixth Man,
we will have an Investigative Debate.
[Candidate Investigative Debate.]
Why should you be the Sixth Man?
Please introduce yourself
in the given thirty seconds.
First,
Hwang Kwang Hee.
Why me first?
Please.
Going first is the best!
[Cheers up.]
30 seconds. Start.
Yes, yes.
It started.
Oh, yes.
So I...
Um...
I need a breakthrough, sunbae.
I think it's time to
add some young blood.
I thought Star King would be very
upset to hear I was coming here,
but they said they'll send me off.
If I get cut here, I have
no job on Saturdays.
I must do this.
Oh, no. No time left.
- I would really like it.
- Okay, please sit.
We're strict on time.
To make it fair for all candidates.
Next is Kang Gyun Sung.
I was ahead of myself.
[I was a bit too rash.]
Choi Siwon!
[American style gestures.]
Next is Kang Gyun Sung.
Hello.
I'm Kang Gyun Sung.
I'm...
...crazy.
[Multiple personalities
jumping out without warning.]
If you trust me...
I will become the new psycho.
NP.
Not the same character.
Young.
[Ending like a pretty flower.]
[Perfect timing.]
[So scary.]
Short and sweet!
Wow! In just a few words.
Got it.
Next.
[Finally me?]
Seo Jang Hoon.
- Two each.
- Funny.
As I've said many times,
I had no ambitions in the beginning.
I said I wouldn't do it.
So why did I come today?
The people who said mean things.
I came because of them.
Starting today,
I will relieve all the
resentment in my heart.
[Honestly expressing his competitiveness!]
Great. Next is Choi Siwon.
[Overly good-looking...]
So good-looking.
Start.
What use are words?
[Right...?]
[American reaction only possible by him.]
American expression!
In simpler terms,
Hollywood hand movements.
I am ready to become the...
[Like watching a commercial.]
perfect candidate.
[He's good.]
I am ready to let go.
To let myself go.
You be the judge.
[Okay?]
[Feels like they already lost to
the classy American gestures.]
Every move is a photoshoot.
Next, Jang Dong Min.
[Jang Dong Min has a different vibe.]
Hello, I'm Jang Dong Min.
For the past ten years, Infinity Challenge
gave us a taste of humor.
[Copying Siwon's hands.]
But you know, with taste...
people want something
even stronger and bolder.
If you've sucked it dry for 10 years,
what's left?
[He's... good.]
You need something stronger and bolder
for Infinity Challenge to last 20, 30 years.
- I'll let you be the judge.
- One last curse.
Shut up, %$#@.
[Alarm rings perfectly on time.]
I needed to talk.
Myung Soo's nervous.
[Sense of danger for the old potty mouth.]
And now next,
Lee Won Seung.
[Fits better than her real name.]
Now, our...
Hong Du Kkae.
Oh, my belly button.
Everyone here is talented and
influential in the celebrity world.
Dumplings, please.
You turn on the TV and...
Kimchi dumplings!
these hottest and the most
talented here come on.
However, you cannot
find me on any channel.
That's how it is.
My rarity.
Rarity?
Not scarcity?
[Not enough time to correct them.]
That's it.
[Tearing up.]
Hong Jin Kyung. Time's up.
- I understand.
- I'm sorry, but...
[Same gaze.]
Hong Jin Kyung. Where are you looking?
At the writer.
[A speech with nothing except her face.]
It's scarcity, not rarity.
Yoo Byung Jae.
[Same height standing.]
I love his height.
Hello, I'm Yoo Byung Jae.
Thank you for having me again.
From the beginning and now,
Infinity Challenge has always
been about being less than average.
I think I can fulfill that.
As you mentioned, my height is 5'4".
Same as my mom.
[He fits best with the
Infinity Challenge mentality.]
I am truly below average.
He's funny.
- You're saying, that's me.
- Yes.
Next is the man who wore
a jacket to K*******.
It's kind of small.
[Tight]
Jeon Hyun Moo, please.
It seems you all have one
thing in common excluding me.
Look at the camera.
Ten seconds have passed!
[Even accepts the advice of rivals.]
A lot of time has passed, Jeon Hyun Moo.
[Hehe]
To be honest, I have want for nothing.
I am a multi-celebrity.
I have 9 shows.
But the fact that I still came here
means Infinity Challenge needs me.
- You need me.
- That's it.
[The clock shuts his mouth.]
- Some more time...
- Please sit.
You need to manage it.
In the given time.
[Sweating...]
You started as a KBS announcer.
This is the old MBC meeting room.
I failed an announcer exam here.
- Here?
- Here.
Lost to Oh Sang Jin.
Please stop talking about that.
[Oops]
He's trying hard.
[Depressed...]
[Everyone bring themselves down.]
[Sixth Man Project Endorsements.]
Hello, I'm Park Hyung Shik.
Nice to meet you.
I heard Kwang Hee is
a Sixth Man candidate.
I am an eternal fan of Infinity Challenge
so even if he doesn't become a member,
I will be a viewer forever so...
Kwang Hee, fighting.
Infinity Challenge, fighting!
Honestly...
[He's not sure about his support either.]
[Heo Ji Woong]
Jang Dong Min...
I want to nominate Yoo Sang Moo.
Why wasn't he a candidate?
On TV, I think Gyun Sung
was exceptionally funny.
Dong Min...
Right, I came to talk about Dong Min.
Jang Dong Min is...
[This is hard...]
It could be good.
Try Dong Min out then.
He'll probably have a scandal soon.
[A pro that he could
be easily swapped out.]
What Hyun Moo's best at is dancing.
There aren't a lot of people who can
confidently dance a variety of dances.
If he was on Infinity Challenge,
he could be in charge of dancing.
For Seo Jang Hoon,
in Kevin and Giant of Temptation
he showed that he has good
chemistry with the members.
To be honest, Infinity Challenge has used
a lot of people discovered on Radio Star.
I strongly advocate Seo Jang Hoon.
[From the original voice
imitator to the new.]
Hello, I'm Nam Bo Won.
I think he's quite talented.
He was born with a great voice.
If he works hard, he
can also be number one.
She lies so well.
I've been tricked so many times.
Seriously.
Not just a few times.
[Back to support mode.]
I respect you.
I'm proud of you.
I'm always cheering you on.
Jin Kyung.
Lend me some money.
Hello, I'm Yoo Byung Jae.
I don't have any celeb friends
so I asked a hyung I hang out with.
I'm very worried.
Hello, I'm Yoo Gyu Sun.
Sixth Man means...
[Glimpse]
being a multiplayer...
Just do it.
Just do it?
As the Sixth Man...
Byung Jae doesn't have
a driver's license.
That means it can't get revoked.
Know what I mean?
I recommend candidate Yoo Byung Jae!
[Taiwan's top actor, Peng Yu Yen.]
Hello everyone, I'm Eddie Peng.
He is hilarious, man.
You guys just have to pick him.
You never know.
I could be the seventh if you want.
I mean, him.
I heard Choi Siwon was chosen
as a candidate for Sixth Man.
I'm here to offer words of endorsement.
Choi Siwon is a very dedicated
and sociable young man.
One concern is that...
because this is a show with
many long term projects,
whether Siwon, who spends a lot
of time abroad, could handle it.
I do have this concern,
but that's his problem.
Regardless, Infinity Challenge!
Good evening. This is Adrian Brody.
I am here on the set of
Manhattan Nocturne asking you
for this very serious moment.
Please vote for Siwon!
Korean Adrian Brody!
Please show your support.
[Hehe]
I love you Korea. I hope to see you soon.
[Sixth Man Secret Agent.]
[Solid]
Let's begin part 1.
As you all know, as a celebrity
at times we receive a lot
of compliments and applause,
but there are also times we
receive tough love and criticism.
We will now assess how
you deal with this.
In order to check your coping skills,
we will check your heart rate.
[Famous with international top stars,
Celebs Read Mean Tweets About Themselves.]
[Heated interest about Sixth Man.]
[How will they react to some tough love?]
- They're reading comments?
- Yes.
They say the experienced take it well.
[Pricks his conscience.]
Ask him!
[Why me...]
Among us, the eldest hyung.
He has some great experience
receiving mean comments.
[He won't read them himself.]
We'll see how he handles it.
You can see his heart rate
on the screen, 63 bpm.
He's at a very calm state.
I will now read the comments.
If you've had enough, say stop.
Such a thrill to see Myung Soo
feel nervous about Dong Min.
It's going up.
Just by mentioning Jang Dong Min.
Can I go on?
With just the mention of Dong Min.
Why do you look like such a bird?
[Pretending to be calm
but heart rate rising.]
Shall I go on?
Park Myung Soo! Yoon Jong Shin!
Clothes don't matter, they're so ugly.
[Heart rate dropping at being called ugly.]
It dropped at being called ugly.
Myung Soo found his peace
again after being called ugly.
He's okay with being ugly but not a bird?
It's like a lullaby to him.
We did this as a brief test.
Now, everyone.
Even as you read the numerous mean
comments about yourselves one page at a time,
if you can't take any
more, you can say stop.
- Got it?
- Yes.
First, we'll start with Kang Gyun Sung.
Probably not much.
[Heart rate shown in live time.]
It's showing up.
Low heart rate.
[Fascinating]
[I must control my feelings!]
He just seems crazy.
It went over 100.
It shot up.
His expiration date is up.
He's already run out.
[Oh, really?]
He's very...
[Calm down.]
You can stop if you
don't want to see more.
I won't watch if he gets picked.
How is he funny?
Is he going to imitate voices forever?
You think I will?
You can reply back.
Multiple personalities.
Kang Gyun Sung.
He was quiet as a guest, but he
suddenly wants to be the Sixth Man?
So two-faced.
I never said I wanted it.
It's not true!
Next.
- I'm nervous.
- I just did this.
Yelling with multiple personalities
is typical of one hit wonders.
You just did that!
I'm one hit.
Knock you out in one hit with laughter.
[Goosebumps!]
Nice.
I'm done.
[Unbeatable multiple personalities.]
Kwang Hee.
Read one page at a time.
Kwang Hee seems the type
to get hurt easily.
- You can say stop.
- It's already rising.
He's anticipating it.
Kwang Hee. Ready?
I'll start.
Not funny, noisy, chaotic.
Why the heck is he a candidate?
[Not bad.]
This is fine.
Kwang Hee? He's old news.
He's long been a wallflower
now thanks to Im Si Wan.
Is it going up?
[What'd you say?]
Will you continue?
I can do it.
[Exciting]
It's getting close to 90 bpm.
Kwang Hee has a soft will like tofu.
Isn't it obvious from his whining?
[Shaking...]
It got him.
[Smiling but his heart rate...]
You seem very angry.
- Are you okay?
- Yes, one more.
I'm curious.
[Have strength!]
Can I not read it and just sit?
You can stop.
I'm curious.
My goodness.
Can't you tell he's a one time thing?
He's not good enough to fit.
[Calm]
- Are you okay?
- It's going up.
I make a good living and
I came with a happy heart.
Tell them to show their face.
[Anger explosion in 10 seconds!]
They need to use their real names!
Kwang Hee's not good enough.
You think you're good enough?
You try!
[Hitting the breaking point.]
I came of my own free will!
What a weird person.
Please sit.
[Refreshing blunt response technique.]
Choi Siwon, next.
He has mean comments?
I have a lot.
That person would get in
huge trouble from fans.
These days, the fans do it.
[Smile]
Look at his smile.
[Disgusting imitation.]
When did he laugh like that?
Just now!
How?
[Totally different grins.]
[Disgust]
Like before.
[Wrinkle]
- Like that.
- See!
[Scrunch]
Siwon.
I wouldn't take Siwon's face.
No thanks to that weaselly Chinman.
He sort of looks like him.
Where does this person live?
Mokdong.
Next.
He's too sleazy.
- You can stop.
- I know.
[Wink]
[Entranced...]
Seriously, Siwon.
Do you have a sleazy move?
- Sleazy pose?
- The end to all sleaziness.
Be as cute as possible.
Giving a cocktail to a woman.
Use me as a model.
[Excited Mr. Hong.]
I can't get into character.
[Shall we?]
[Like oil.]
[American reaction.]
[Happy eyes.]
Great.
Even when he laughed by himself.
[King of American reactions.]
By himself!
Great, great.
His life is an exaggeration, especially
him trying to be on Infinity Challenge.
[Rising at the mention of Sixth Man.]
[Heart racing like his passion.]
It went up.
[You feel me?]
They say he's popular in China,
but he's less so in Korea.
I'm popular in China
because I am in Korea.
[Poke]
[Siwon's addicting moves.]
Nice!
I'm sick of his English pronunciations.
I don't wanna be like you.
[Nice, right?]
Should I be stiff then?
When in Rome, do as the Romans do!
Nice, nice.
Next is Hong Jin Kyung.
[Clip clop.]
Hong Jin Kyung.
[What's wrong with you...]
Like my dad.
[Her energy has plummeted
since the beginning.]
Are you already tired?
Slightly.
What is your weakness?
My stamina is very weak.
I get tired very quickly.
Physical strength is very important.
If I do it, I'll just film
the opening and leave.
Just the opening.
[Overcoming her limits past the opening.]
Every time I see her, she
looks like Son Heung Min.
She does look like him!
You do!
[Mr. Hong can't deny it.]
This unni looks like a cucumber.
Please read slowly.
Including the talk about capitals,
she's ignorant but pretends she's smart.
Are you ignorant or smart?
I...
don't think it's a problem of either one.
Ask us one difficult
capital we won't know.
[Thinking]
Maldives.
The capital of Maldives.
Do you know?
What is it?
Mali.
Mali's a country.
Male.
It's right. Mali, Male.
It's right!
[Arguing with her shallow knowledge.]
Let's go with Seo Jang Hoon.
- It's originally high.
- He's always angry.
Seo Jang Hoon?
Is this show for the
middle aged or something?
120!
Next.
Buying any eyes that haven't seen
Seo Jang Hoon's "Up Down" dance.
[What's that?]
Oh, my eyes.
Eyes that haven't seen his dance.
I was wondering what that meant.
[Eyes that haven't been
contaminated by this sight.]
[Slow to understand comments.]
Jang Dong Min.
The mean commenters need to worry.
[Expert in curses of justice.]
You can say whatever you want.
It's already 154 bpm.
[About to explode from anger
even before starting.]
Don't do it!
I already have high blood pressure.
[Assessment ended for the
safety of his health.]
Yoo Byung Jae, start.
It's already starting at 135.
I hate Yoo Byung Jae's pathetic face.
[Curious]
[Sorry...]
It's automatic!
Yoo Byung Jae sucks.
I hate his loser character.
[You hate me that much...?]
[Pitiful face incites sympathy.]
Next is Jeon Hyun Moo starting at 103.
Let's go.
I don't want to imagine it, but
he looks like he's hairy all over.
What is that?
On your back?
Back, stomach, everywhere.
Shoulders, too.
Like seaweed.
Is it all connected?
Must you use your hands like that?
It is connected.
[Safely gets past the
first mean comment.]
Another?
Hyung Moo's face looks like a dog.
It really does!
I look like a dog. A shih tzu.
But you really do.
Shih tzu.
It's slowly going up.
115.
[About to read the next comment.]
Want to stop?
Jeon Hyun Moo is the type of man I'd
hate to meet in person in everyday life.
Want to stop?
- Jeon Hyun Moo.
- No.
[Oh, no.]
- Want to stop?
- I can't respond.
You can stop.
I'll keep going.
He's on every single
channel, so sick of him.
Seems like quantity over quality.
He must be obsessed with money.
This was written by one person?
One person wrote a long one.
One person wrote a continuous one.
The style is similar.
He said quantity over quality.
I came here to go for
quality over quantity.
Next.
He wants to take a part of
God Yoo's hosting, is he crazy?
He must think he's really good.
OMG.
[Heart rate rising.]
It's going up a lot.
Can he continue?
- Stop?
- Keep going.
Great.
[Freeze]
I'll stop here.
One last one.
I just hate him.
[Assessment ends painfully.]
What was the worst?
The type of man I'd hate to meet
in person in everyday life.
It really hurt.
It's okay to not want to see me on TV.
But they hate me in real life, too.
Hate to meet.
Like asking me to leave Korea.
Overall the many sides of you all,
for each one of you...
Hong Jin Kyung!
She has a serious face.
Like a picture.
Hong Jin Kyung!
[Eyes about to close.]
It's like you're at a
parent teacher meeting.
[After ending the simple part 1...]
Everyone.
It's not exactly humiliating but...
we have some impressive
pictures of you all.
[A test of strong mental strength.]
[First, Kwang Hee.]
Kwang Hee.
[Embarrassed x100.]
[Born again thanks to
the almighty doctor.]
[Oh, my stomach.]
[Kwang Hee's pre-surgery picture
where he looks like Baekga.]
[Mr. Hong exhausted from laughing.]
[Undoubtedly Kwang Hee.]
Really?
- It's Kwang Hee.
- There's more?
Let's look at Jang Dong Min.
Why?
[Cheap]
[Why did I do that?]
Jang Dong Min. This is nothing.
The next one.
[Call me Min oppa.]
[Dark past of young fashion courage.]
Are you Gong Gil?
[The King and the Clown.]
Is this Bae Yong Joon?
[Continuous visual attacks.]
[Man]
[Tearing up.]
[What happened back then?]
Next is Choi Siwon.
I have a lot.
[Lightly starting with a
cute picture of his past.]
[Titled "Kim Siwon Fortune Cookie".]
[Embarrassed]
Siwon's aren't very...
[Manly]
[Strong man.]
[I think I look cool.]
[Addicted to Siwon's actions.]
[Follow me!]
[So fun!]
[Different than me.]
I love those kind of pictures.
You know!
[Smooch!]
[Worked up.]
[So cool!]
Get ready to grab your stomachs.
Why?
[Why are you looking at me?]
Hong Jin Kyung.
[Powerful enough to
prevent proper hosting.]
[Nervous]
[Automatic American reaction.]
Seriously.
Your stomachs will hurt.
[Boom]
[Oh, my goodness.]
[Could this be what fairies look like?]
[Escaping reality.]
[Funny no matter how
long you look at it.]
Enough!
[Now bursting just from looking at her.]
Are you her husband?
[The fairy and lumberjack...]
I need to hang this up.
We really need to hang this one up.
Where was that taken?
[Alluring]
[This must be a dream.]
[One more please!]
These two.
[Fiery appearance.]
Are they siblings?
[Noona]
Stop!
[Complete the collection.]
[Save me.]
The triple combo.
[The next person.]
[Seo Jang Hoon!]
[Squinting]
[Back when he couldn't see anything.]
Why didn't you open your eyes?
Where is this from?
[That's not all!]
[Funny screen capture.]
[I'm angry.]
Isn't that a mask?
Like a stretched stocking.
This is nuclear bomb level.
[Hyun Moo frozen in time.]
The face of someone you
don't want to meet.
Someone like that.
[The last card!]
[A particular body part pulls your gaze.]
[Shy]
[Mouth hanging.]
[Rich in furry chest hair, Hyun Moo.]
[Can't believe our eyes.]
[Stop looking.]
Thanks to you all, we
really laughed a lot.
While laughing and chatting with you all,
part 1 has already ended.
We will see you soon for part 2!
[Shall we take a quick breather?]
Now let's begin part 2.
Right away?
We need to start.
We will ask a few questions
to test your character.
Character is very important.
In these few questions, you
can only answer yes or no.
First, we will start with Park Myung Soo.
Park Myung Soo.
Just watch Park Myung Soo
as a systems test.
In the case that you answer with a lie,
we use cutting edge technology
to know immediately.
- A lie detector?
- Yes.
Lies light up red.
The truth will light up blue.
[Amazed]
It's my first time seeing one.
- Ready?
- Yes.
Let's ask some questions.
Is there someone here that you
would like to have as our member?
[Straightforward bomb
for the first question.]
No.
[No?]
[Truth]
[Steady graph doesn't change.]
[I dislike all of you.]
[His confession leaves scars
on the candidates' hearts.]
He means it.
Just as expected.
- You're too much.
- He really means it.
- He sheds no blood or tears.
- He means it.
Then is there a current member who
should be nervous about the new member?
Yes.
[A member should be nervous!]
[Truth]
[Of course there is.]
- Is that person on your right...
- Yes.
I'm the only one on the right!
Yes.
- Yes?
- Yes.
[Truth]
[I'll be nervous...]
[I'll work harder.]
Great.
Then in the past month,
have you kissed anyone?
[Small waves.]
Yes.
Yes?
[Truth. Consistent graph.]
[The Brangelina couple!]
The final question!
In the next life, would
you marry your wife again?
Yes.
Let's see.
[Lie]
[Graph shoots up.]
Subtitles Ripped By www.vikisubtitle.com
[Sigh...]
Park Myung Soo, step out.
[His true feelings revealed.]
This is the test.
It's accurate.
Very accurate.
[Systems test complete.]
Test your character as
a Sixth Man candidate.
I'm better than Jung Hyung Don?
[American reaction.]
[Even in uncomfortable situations...]
[How will they react?]
In the past month,
have you kissed anyone?
[Deadly talents?]
Everyone,
[The fate of these 8 are in their hands!]
we only have the final voting round left.
Do you really want do
become the Sixth Man?
[Who will seize the poisoned Holy Grail?]
[Sixth Man Secret Member]