Innocence
- What's your name?
- Iris.
Good morning, Iris.
These are Nadja, Rose, VeraÉ
É Alice and Selma.
And I am Bianca.
Rose, Vera, come, quick.
Selma, you also.
Hurry.
Change of ribbons.
You see, Iris, each one
has a ribbon color.
The red one is for small ones.
And violet for the one in charge.
No, violet is Natacha's color.
She went away, now I wear the violet one.
Liar.
Don't worry, she'll get over it.
Iris, you will sleep here
and I will sleep over there.
Bianca, where is
my younger brother?
There are no males here.
- Why not?
- Because.
- But, where am I?
- This is our house.
You will also learn to swim.
- Now try yourself
- you see, how fun it is?
- You must also move the legs. That's right.
- Raise your legs. That's right.
And forward, that's right
You also arrived today?
Yes, but I will not remain
for long.
- Laura, come.
- Can I be with Iris?
No, you're not in the same house.
But you will be able to see her tomorrow.
You see, Iris, there are 5 houses in the park,
one for each group of girls.
Laura is in house #1 and you are in
house #3, with us.
This is Madeleine, she is
here to serve us.
If she does not obey us she will be punished.
I want to go back home.
This is your home now.
- But they are going to come to look for to me
- No.
Will my brother be able to visit me?
No, no.
Iris.
Come.
- I am going to show you the house.
- And Bianca, where is she?
Bianca.
- Where are you going?
- I can't tell you.
- Why not?
- Because.
- I want to go with you.
- That is not possible.
- Why not?
- Because.
- Leave her alone, she must go now.
- No.
- Leave her alone.
I promise that when
you wake up tomorrow morning I will be there with you.
It is always so.
At 9 we leave.
- At 10 we go to sleep.
- At 7 we wake up.
- At 8 we have breakfast.
- At 9 we work.
- Work?
- Yes.
Do you know what time it is now?
Here that is very important.
Do you know to count?
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, fiveÉ
É six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
One, two, three,
four, five, sixÉ
É seven, eight, nine,
ten, elevenÉ
É twelve, thirteen, fourteen --
Iris.
Stand up, we're going.
BiancaÉ
Will you stay with me today?
Iris, come.
Come.
It is important to follow the way.
And that you always follow
the lamps.
- Where are we going?
- Down there.
- Good morning.
So long, Iris.
I am Mademoiselle Edith.
I hope you'll be happy here.
We will learn to love all the animals in this park
Come with me.
All beings are fruits
of the same treeÉ
Which is called Life.
Life first started in the seaÉ
and then spread to air and finally to earth.
- What is this?
- A hind.
- And this?
- A rat.
- A fox, a wolf.
And we are here.
We are the most evolved species that exist
and our progress never stops
É and the human infants, within several years,
will have completely different characteristicsÉ
É then you, and in several generations the
progress of evolution will clearly be seen.
Alice, will I have to stay long here?
Yes.
Do we have any visits?
There are no visits, nobody ever comes.
But is there a headmistress?
Yes, she comes every year
in order to see us dance.
However you will not see the headmistress
in the near future.
She only comes once a year to give
the blue ribbon.
And when will I be able to leave
to see my little brother?
You cannot leave, it is prohibited.
But you gou out every afternoon.
I don't go out. I told you
it's prohibited.
What do you do then?
Listen, if you continue with this,
you will be punished.
- Good morning.
Here are your things.
You are going to meet Mademoiselle Eva.
She is very kind.
Welcomes, young ladies.
Come in.
You are lucky of being chosen
to live here.
But you are still just
ugly maggots.
It will be necessary to work hard.
Hurry young lady.
Wait.
I am going to show you something,
and you have to pay attention.
É because you will have
to do it after me.
Seven, eight.
One, two, threeÉ
É four, five, sixÉ
É seven, eight.
Unfortunately not all
maggots transform themselves into butterflies.
But I hope that within a few
years you will all have that honor.
Bianca, where do you go in the afternoons?
- Do you see boys?
- No.
Then what do you do?
Attention, I am counting.
One, two, three, fourÉ
É five, six, sevenÉ
É eight, nine, tenÉ
Hide!
Bianca?
What do we do now?
Iris.
I am here.
Are you crazy? We have been looking everywhere for you.
I wanted to follow Bianca.
You didn't try to leave
the park, did you?
No.
You know what kind of punishment there is for leaving the
park?
No.
You stay here forever and serve the others.
- What is it?
- I don't see anything.
- I see something.
- What?
What do you see?
You see this? This is the wall
that surrounds the whole park.
Iris, I am going to show you
another secret.
Look.
You see, outside there are very strange people,
that's why we musn't go outside.
And Bianca's secret, do you know what it is?
Sure, come with me.
So, what's her secret?
Let's play a game.
You musn't move.
- You lost.
- No, start again.
You are a little spy.
Bianca.
- What do you want?
- I want to sleep with you.
It is prohibited.
What did you do with your legs?
I hurt them when i was playing.
We're finished, young ladies.
Iris, please wait here.
- Tell me, are you happy here?
- Yes.
- Do you get on well with your friends?
Especially with Bianca.
And because you like Bianca so much,
I suppose that you obey her as well.
Yes.
You know, perhaps it is
difficult to understand itÉ
É but obedience is the one and only
way that guarantees us a good life.
What are you doing?
Do you ever ask yourself
if we'll ever get out of here?
Of course i do, but there is a great wall in between
and there are no doors.
Don't worry,
I know how to get out of here.
How?
- Can't you guess?
- No.
Will you come with me?
That is prohibited.
- You won't tell on me?
- No.
- Do you swear?
- I swear.
Can you help me
with untying the rope?
Is is true that Mademoiselle Edith
tried to escape when she was just a little girlÉ
É and that the headmistress punished her by breaking her legs?
Ah, those stories of punishment are just a way of
scaring the children.
They cannot force us to be
here all of our lifeÉ
É if we don't want it ourselves.
Iris?
What are you doing there?
Are you scared of the storms?
Laura left the park, but
I shouldn't have told you that.
Were you with her?
Will she be punished?
Are they also going to punish me?
- Did anybody see you?
- No.
- Did you speak about this with anyone?
Will I be punished?
No, I promise you, you won't be.
Come in.
Laura is no longer among us.
I know that you are sadÉ
É we will organize an incineration ceremony as
soon as possible.
Good afternoon, young ladies.
Good afternoon.
Let's go.
Stephanie don't eat with your fingers.
Use your fork.
Eva.
Eva, calm down.
Calm down.
We're going back now.
- Happy New Year, young ladies.
- Happy New Year.
- Did you make a wish?
- Yes.
- What kind of wish did you make?
- To always be with Bianca.
I want to be chosen as
the headmistress
Those are not dreams.
Well, it all depends on the talent.
I am sure that
she will be chosen.
What means "chosen" ?
Every year, the headmistress comes and
she chooses the one that wears the blue ribbonÉ
É and she takes her away. It's one of the ways to get
out of here faster.
But I'll be afraid of the headmistress
when she comes.
I won't be scared.
Please, please let me be chosen.
Two of them have become very pretty.
This year has been a good year, I think
that she will be very satisfied.
So long
headmistress, so long.
Alice.
What are you doing here?
Today is not your turn.
I want to practise with
Mademoiselle Eva.
Good one.
She asked me to come.
Why do you want so much to be
chosen?
Do you want to distance yourself from the others?
Aren't you happy here?
I am, but I would like to make sure
that they like me.
You know Alice, I don't
believe that they will choose you.
And what do you know you disabled species!
You shouldn't have discouraged Alice
like that.
Anyway, she doesn't know what it means to be chosen.
And what do you know about it?
If they disappoint her, she will suffer.
She will learn.
Learn what?
I don't believe she will become like us.
What do you mean by "like us"?
Hurry, we're only
waiting for you.
Here you are.
Raise your chin. Turn.
Very good. Now give me a beautiful smile.
Come
Turn. Stay like this, please.
Take a look at the nape of the neck .
Very well on
the feet, very well.
Thanks.
Coming?
Don't be scared.
What is that ball?
Push it a little back.
Thanks. The profile.
Stand on your toes. Stay like that.
Very well, thanks.
Coming?
Are we bashful? Of course
we are not. We are very beautiful. See.
The profile.
Wait a second
I want to see something.
A little short.
Turn.
Stay like that,
I need to see something.
Wait, do not move.
Step on your toes.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait a little more.
Now you can descend. Thanks.
Are you coming?
Let's see.
Look at her face.
Raise the chin.
Very well.
What a pretty nape of the neck,
very pretty. Look.
Very pretty. Turn.
She is very pretty, isn't she?
You.
Give me your hand.
Now the other hand.
Show me your teeth.
- This one.
- This one? Sorry.
Congratulations, you worked well with the
students.
Alice.
Lady, take me.
Alice!
You said that I will
be the chosen one.
I never said that.
It she going to die?
Where are you going?
We cannot find her.
Alice did a very big mistake.
We will never see her again.
And we will never speak about her again.
Now you know how the transformation looks like.
First one occurs at the age of 7,
when they lose the milk teeth.
The second one will happen any moment.
This time the entire body
will transform.
From now on, every month,
they will lose a little blood.
Now it must find a companion to assure its descendants.
Hurry, we musn't be late.
I am coming.
Rose, today you will be
in charge of the others.
-  OK.
-  Why?
- Because I am goin with Bianca.
- But that is prohibited.
- As of today she has permission.
- Are you coming?
- And why her?
- Someday you will take her place.
- Good afternoon, young ladies.
- Good afternoon, miss.
Welcome, Nadja.
You are going to see that everything will be fine.
- Good afternoon, Nadja.
- Good afternoon, miss.
Let's go.
- What is that?
- That is your costume.
- Why are there only four?
- You will see.
Leave us alone.
Repeat it all before the audience.
Step up,
step on the chair.
You will have to take care of legs, Nadja.
Ok.
Young ladies.
Here is where we dance.
Repeat.
Very well, Nadja.
Continue, continue.
Continue, Nadja.
What is that noise?
It is absolutely prohibited
to draw the curtains.
- What is on the other side?
- The spectators.
The spectators?
Where are you going?
- Leave me alone.
- Calm down.
Nadja, don't be scared.
When the curtains will unveil
you will not see them.
Ok?
Let's go to the classroom.
Bianca, take care of her.
You are going to see, they always applaud us.
What is wrong?
I cannot return.
Next time
you will be less scared.
I don't want to return.
You have no choice.
Good, this is all for today.
I hope that you will be
more concentrated tonight.
Bianca, come with me please.
It is your turn.
Mademoiselle Edith already told you about the
bleedings that can occur.
When it happens you will use these cloths.
You know Bianca, a complete new
cycle will begin.
You and other violet ribbons are going to leave the school.
And tonight you will dance
for the last time.
Last time?
Bravo, you are the most beautiful.
- I am very proud of you.
- Thank you miss.
Did you all have a good time?
Come, let's go.
Come.
Bianca, come.
What are you doing here?
What is that thing?
- Didn't they find the money?
- Money?
Look.
Do you think the guests will pay for the
expenses of the school?
Who else, if not them?
You?
I am sure that you will use your legs well when
you leave the school.
I do not want to go out.
Bianca.
Bianca, what are you doing there?
Leave me alone.
Is it true that you are leaving?
I do not want you to go, I want you
to stay with me forever.
Iris.
- Iris.
- Leave me alone.
Bianca.
Good bye.
You won't forget me?
- No, and you?
- Never.
- Will we see each other when you come out?
- When i come out?
It is time, Bianca.
Young ladies.
Let's go, young ladies.
Come, let's go.
Step in, young ladies.
MissÉ
Éwhat is going to happen with us?
One thing is certain:
you are going to forget us quickly.
Go.
Translation by Bluesoul