By any chance, did you happen to see...
Eun Gi!
Eun Gi.
Seo Eun Gi!
Wake up, Eun Gi.
Eun Gi... Seo Eun Gi,
Wake up.
What should I do if you come outside without saying anything?
Do you know how worried I was?
Didn't you hear what I said?
If you keep doing these kinds of things...
No. I am sorry.
Let's go inside. You will catch a cold, ok?
Who are you?
Eun Gi, why are you like this?
I asked you who you are.
Hey, Seo Eun Gi!
I am asking you who you are.
Why are you like this?
Step aside now.
Don't play with me!
Yes.
Doctor...
our Director... what should we do about our Director?
Sometimes, due to a sudden shock, the patient may lose all their post memories.
This, too, is the patient's way of protecting herself...
from her fears,
and pain.
Are you saying that there is a possibility that she might not know us again?
Just think of it as a small test to finding her memories again.
If she passes this test, then, like a treasure chest, all her memories will all come out.
Do you... know me?
Subtitles brought to you by The Naughty Team at Viki.com
[Episode 14]
Lies.
Eun Gi!
Let go!
Calm down. Calm down!
Let go of me. Let go.
Calm down. What's wrong?
It's lies!
Lies!  Lies!
Go downstairs.  Now!
Yeah.
Calm down.
It's lies!
Lies!
What should we do?
It's alright. It's alright.
What should we do, Oppa?
Why is Eun Gi unni like this?
I was scared to death.
I was suspicious how everything was going well...
If my suspicions are true...
I want to invalidate Director Seo's claim to the inheritance as an incapacitated beneficiary.
If Director Seo is designated as the heir, she will be the legal heir to the Chairman's estate.
All of the fortune and shares of Taesan,
will be in her possession and control.
Eun Gi, Eun Gi, Get back to your senses. Eun Gi!
-Ma Ru...-Seo Eun Gi!
Ma Ru ...
Get lost.
I told you to get lost.
Subtitles brought to you by The Naughty Team at Viki.com
Yes.
Ma Ru...
Yeah?
Jae Hee Noona is here.
What?
I told her she can't come inside for now, so I told Choco to stall her outside...
What are you going to do... about Eun Gi?
Our Choco has really grown up.
In the past you were just a little baby.
Are you going to keep me standing here like this?
My brother told me not to ever let you inside our house, Jae Hee Unni.
I am not a bad person, Choco.
If you aren't a bad person, did all bad people die?
Traitor.
To you guys,
am I still a traitor?
You abandoned my Oppa, and married a chaebol Chairman.  You got all your wishes. You must be very happy, huh?
I guess, huh?
I thought if all my wishes came true, I would
be very happy, but....
Oppa!
I am not really happy as I thought.
Why? Now you even became a President. You should be happy.
I guess I feel this way because your Oppa is not next to me.
Heol!
Go inside, Choco.
Oppa, this Unni isn't the Unni we knew. She is a totally strange ajumma.
Don't talk for a long time and come inside quickly.
I came here because I worried about our Eun Gi.
Please let me meet her.
Let's go inside.
I told you to get lost.
I am Eun Gi's mom. I have the right to see her.
Move away.
What on earth did you talk with Eun Gi about?
What on earth did you talk to her about that she became nervous like that and even collapsed?
I talked about you.
It isn't even something new.
I don't know what is so frightening and made her fall down.
It is I who wants to ask.
If you try to mess with her again even once,
you will see for once what Kang Maru is capable of doing...
and how far he can go.
Love is not about loyalty.
It isn't about sympathy either.
Just because you want to return everything back to normal,
doesn't mean you're in love. That is just your conscience.
Love is...
what you gave me.
That was love, right?
After I lost that, I realized how important it was.
The reason why, now, I'm here in regret...
Regardless of what happens, the determination to have it again...
that is love.
With the title of being Eun Gi's "fiance",
Even though I don't know with what mind you came back and play with me like that.
Truthfully, I...
don't hate it.
To tell you honestly,
I was happy because I saw you again.
The world without you is boring, not fun....
and really nothing special.
I'll leave. Let's meet again.
Subtitles brought to you by The Naughty Team @viki.com
Yes, Director Ahn.
I have gathered Seo Eun Gi's MRI records and brain scans.
How?
After following her down to the hospital, I was able to get it.
It looks like she is still receiving treatment from a neurologist in our country,  Professor Seo Min Hyuk.
I will prepare for the motion to incapacitate Seo Eun Gi's claim to the inheritance due to incapability.
Don't worry, Eun Gi.
I will take care of you till you die.
I won't ever kick you out without a penny, just like somebody else (Chairman).
As long as you know where you stand,
as long as you stay stupid, pretty and nice...
like now,
then I won't hate you.
Why would I hate you?
Because of Maru and I, your life became a mess.
You're the biggest victim.
I am sorry.
I am sorry with my sincere heart.
Let's go down to eat. Choco made a delicious bean paste soup.
Then drink tomato juice.
I will bring it again.
Will she be okay?
Yes.
I will bring it again.
If you hate tomato juice, should I bring some milk?
Okay.
Don't ask her and give it to her when she wants to eat later.
Yeah, she will eat it when she is hungry.
Please stop getting mad at Maru and drink some milk, Eun Gi.
Please drink it, Unni.
Stop it. I won't eat it.
That Unni is really too much. Is she the only one having hard time?
She thinks my brother isn't having a hard time?
This can't keep happening.
I need to go tell her what I need to say.
What will you tell her?
You stay still. It isn't something for you to get involved.
Didn't you hear what I said?  I told you I won't eat it.
What will you do if you don't eat? You have to eat and live.
This is really too much.
Hey, let's go watch a movie together.
Okay. Let's do it for once.
Milk is still left in the fridge. And there is another box of tomatoes.
In our neighborhood, there are 3 markets.
And I still have lots of energy. And because I backed off from work, I have a lot of time.
Subtitles brought to you by The Naughty Team @viki.com
You, getting mad, breaking everything and being like this after collapsing....
It actually makes me happy.
In this situation, it is normal to get angry and furious.
Because Seo Eun Gi, you seemed always too bright and happy.
I was worried about that.
Because I thought, maybe, you were just hurting inside.
Maybe, if it's possible,
I want to see you scream and cry.
What conversation did you have with Han Jae Hee?
Are you having a hard time because of me?
Did I make you have a hard time like this?
If you are having a hard time because of memories about me,
because of those memories, because you want to hide those memories,
if you are being hurt like this,
don't hide and let it out.
Stop hurting (stabbing) yourself and
hurt me, Eun Gi.
Stop inflicting pain on yourself, and
hurt (stab) me like this.
You need to live properly in order for me to leave.
You need to get up properly...
so I can, without worries,
disppear from your side.
I will bring you milk.
Subtitles Brought to You by The Naughty Team @ Viki.com.
Did you sleep well?
Yes. Did you sleep well?
Yes.
Thanks to you, Maru, I slept for a very long time.
And....
I dreamed a really long dream.
During that long dream, I dreamt about you, Maru.
But in my dream, you, Maru,....
is different from the Maru I know.
How?
Tricking me, hurting me, and overly-confident...a bad person.
When you get back all your memories later,
what will you do if I am really that kind of person?
Huh?
I asked you what will you do if I am the bad guy who came out in your dream.
I won't be able to forgive him.
He is the person I chose after abandoning even my father.
Why are you laughing?
Why are you laughing?!
Because I am relieved.
Huh?
You must do it like that, okay?
Don't forget, don't have a weak mind and never ever let him off.
You must do it like that, Seo Eun Gi.
What did you hear from the President that you collapsed like that?
I remember that Han Jae Hee came to find me and talk with me.
I remember I was having a really hard time.
But I don't remember our conversation very well.
They're like small broken pieces of glass.
I heard your memories came back.
Just a random small event.
What is that?
What is it?
Lawyer Park Joon Ha, you, told me
that Kang Maru approached me with the intent of getting revenge on someone.
He and second Madame have been in a close relationship for a long time.
You said that earlier.
He is a person who still harbors deep feelings for second Madam, and he approached you with ulterior motives!
What did you mean by that?
You said clearly what that is and who that is.
I don't remember until then.
That person is in a close relationship with Kang Maru and
for that person, he approached me.
Lawyer Park Joon Ha said that to me.
I did?
Yes.
Who is that person?
Kang Ma Ru... what kind of person is he?
Of the side of Kang Maru I don't know...
by any chance, do you know?
I heard you called me.
Have a seat.
I will talk to you standing.
Then let's stand together and talk.
I was childish.
It was childish of me to frame you as a corporate spy earlier.
I'm sorry.
Forget everything and let's get along well in the future.
What should I do if I don't want to accept that apology?
Shall I kneel down?
I can kneel down.
In front of you, I can kneel a thousand, or even ten thousand times.
Should I really kneel down?
It's disgusting.
I think I'm going to throw up.
Are you sure that's what I said?
Yes, you did.
That Kang Maru is trying to fool me.
Not someone else?
Yes.
You weren't dreaming, right?
Are you sure you didn't make up this memory?
I have never said anything like that to you.
It's the first time I've heard this.
Really?
Yes.
I heard that there are a lot of people in the world who trick themselves by making up their own memories.
That 30% of their stored memories,
are actually memories that they've forgotten then recreated themselves.
Then I guess I thought it wrong.
Do you have any other things to say to me?
I want to find my memories quickly.
Yes.
I'm not going to hide anymore and be scared.
I am planning to do everything I can.
If it is something that will help me recover my memory, I'll do anything.
I've gathered all of the documents you need.
Now, all we need is a way to prove Seo Eun Gi's incompetence and inability to manage business,
and expose her true state as soon as possible.
Of course, it won't be easy.
Until she has full clarity and recovery, she will continue to hide behind Kang Maru.
Let's break them apart. Kang Maru and Seo Eun Gi.
And, let's keep Kang Maru.
The bastard's talent is too valuable to give to someone else.
I want him. I want all of him.
Yes.
Hello.
I thought you were sick...
What makes you visit here without notice?
I came to formally pay my respects and check in.
Pay respects?
Today I have officially started reporting back to the company.
I feel like I've been too weighed down by
my minor health issues recently.
After all, it is my company, and my people here.
I might as well recover and learn through directly interacting with them.
As we'll be seeing each other more often, please wish me the best.
Are you seriously going to officially start going back to work?
This is where I belonged before.
This is where I want to begin
That way, I'll regain my memory sooner.
I hate to do this to someone who just came back to the office, but
there's something urgent I need your help with, Director Seo.
You remember the Tae Yang Cosmetics deal that you started last year but didn't get to finish?
We're in the midst of revisiting that deal again
and you know how your relationship with their CEO Min is strong.
So? What do you want?
We finally were able to squeeze in a meeting with him today
but something's come up with our lead contact.
It's tough to cancel the meeting, as we're already in competition with others that are eyeing this deal.
Why don't you go ahead and meet CEO Min today,
and set it up relationally so that the key members can meet again tomorrow?
I'll need you to hurry there, as I'm hearing that he's already waiting at the promised meeting location.
It's a Korean restaurant called Han Gang, room 11.
I'm counting on you, Director Seo.
Is something wrong?
You said it was CEO Min from Tae Yang Cosmetics, yes?
Anything you know about him?
Yes. He was very fond of Director Seo, and even wanted to have her as a daughter-in-law; they had a great relationship.
I don't remember.
At the time, Secretary Kim had assisted you on this deal.
Why don't I talk to Secretary Kim and find out more about him.
Yeah.
Don't over-exert yourself. Let's just tell them that something urgent has come up and you can't make it.
Let's do that.
No, I'll do it.
Eun Gi.
If I suddenly say I can't make it, they'll be suspicious.
It's certainly better than overexerting yourself.
I do not want to say I can't do it.
I don't want to say that anymore. I don't want to.
I am confident that I can memorize/ I'll just memorize everything.
The kind of person he is, who his family is, what his hobbies are... I can just memorize it all. Right?
His son married last year.
And you were also present at the wedding.
Not too long ago, his grandson was born and he was very happy. So, point this out first, and slowly, and naturally,
flow on with the conversation.
Should we go in together?
No. I can go alone.
Don't worry.
Have you been well all this time?
Last year I saw you and
this is the first time this year.
I attended your anniversary ceremony with my father
and this is the first time we've met since then.
Did it seem that way?
I think it was that way.
I am forgetful these days.
I heard the news about your son.
Then, is Director Seo now....
with President Nam, thinking that he is Representative Min?
With what thought did you do that?
What if this causes problems, and causes CEO Nam to pull out of the deal?
That's what I want.
The more Seo Eun Gi's mistakes are bigger,
the more the image of which the other Directors look at her...
will be more special and deeper.
It just seems like yesterday that I've heard about your son geting married,
and is living happily now.
And you even saw your grandson, right?
Since I saw you at the wedding,
your daughter-in-law seems like a very wonderful person.
You are very blessed, Chairman.
Are you drunk?
How dare you come here drunk!
Why, a sprouting little wrench like you!
My son is what and what?!
He said that he's not Tae Han Cosmetic's Representative Min.
People have been switched.
This person is...
CEO Nam from Moh Sung Chemical corporation
His son died due to a car accident 5 months ago.
But to a person who just lost his son, I....
Han Jae Hee
What are you?
Why did you come back to Tae San?
What is the reason why you're back?!
Tae San...did you come back to ruin it?
Because you couldn't believe that Han Jae Hee is the Chairman!
Ruining what is already done....
Starting a fire...
Is that why you came back?!
You can't possibly do this if that is not the case.
To the person who lost his only son not too long ago,
you said what?!
Isn't something wrong with your brain?
Chairman Nam who got hurt because of you ....
He pulled back from investing in Tae San resort.
How will you take responsibility?
How will you take the responsibility!?
You told me wrong.
You
told me to go meet Tae An Cosmetics Representative Min....
Why did you hang up?
I have something to say to her.
GIve it to me.
I think we fell into a trap, Eun Gi.
It seems as though news of the investment deal that Seo Eun Gi has ruined is spreading quickly throughout the organization.
Even the directors have started murmuring amongst themselves about it.
Why don't you reference this incident in next week's board of directors meeting
and I'll prepare the documents to remove her rights to the company.
This ended this more easily than I thought. Concerning Seo Eun Gi.
Shall we celebrate?
Do you want to do that?
This is no fun.
It was fun when it wasn't this easy.
Since it is too easy,
it is no fun.
I am embarrassed. I am really embarrassed.
I should have listened to you, Maru, and
listened to you say not to go.
What did I think I could do like this?
Eun Gi.
Without another person's help,
I can't even stand up.
What did I think I could do? Seriously.
Don't pull yourself down. It'll be better next time.
If you wait, you'll find your memories again.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Because I want to remember you quickly.
Maru...
how much he knows me and loves me...
because I want to remember quickly.
But what is this?
What do I do?
What can I do now?
I shouldn't have come back.
Let's give up.
Let's just give up everything.
Wake up. There is a place you need to go.
Wake up.
You have to deal with the situation you started.
I told you let's drop it.
I told you I would give up Tae San.
Don't be ridiculous.
You don't even have a right to give up on Tae San.
Maru.
What have you done to give up?
Later on when your memories come back and
you reclaim the position you deserve,
if you don't want to have Tae San at that time...
if you feel that it doesn't matter to abandon it, then abandon it then.
I can't do it. How can I?
You saw everything yesterday. You saw how I became a laughingstock
and crumbled down like an idiot.
Didn't you already see all of that, Maru
You can do it.
I can't do it. I can't do anything.
I am the evidence of that.
Where are you going? I got off alone and where are you going?
Team Leader Kang's words were right.
Han Jae Hee's side...
seems to have gotten all the CT and MRI scan records.
They know every truth and
they tested Director Seo like that.
It seems that they only have one objective.
To take away Director Seo's rights to own the corporation.
What should we do now?
Subtitles brought to you by The Naughty Team @ViKi.com
Eun Seok!
Mom!
My son, today I'm feeling really happy,
so I'll buy you a present. What do you want?
Present?
Tell me everything.
I'll buy you the best thing in the world.
Eun Gi noona!
Huh?
Eun Gi noona. I want Eun Gi noona.
Something other than Eun Gi noona.
Eun Gi noona...why, why doesn't she come back home again?
Not Eun Gi Noona but another thing.
Then, ice cream and Eun Gi Noona.
Is there not anything else you want beside Eun Gi Noona?
This world has lots of luxurious and wonderful things,
but all you can think of is your sister Eun Gi?
Guns, cars, robots, clothes.
There's a lot of things in the world.
I said I'll buy you everything, that I'll do everything. But that's all you can think of?
Take Eun Seok upstairs.
Yes.
I hate you, Mom.
How long are you planning to be here?
This isn't going to change anything. Just go home.
President...
I had a reason.
I am dealing with amnesia.
Because I wanted to escape from danger,
I pretended to know you on our first meet.
Because I could only think of protecting Tae San,
I used you, tricked you, and by bringing up your son, I hurt you.
Scorn me as much as you want, till all your anger is gone.
This happening...I really want to ask for forgiveness.
You lost your memories?
I just didn't lose my memories.
My brain was also damaged.
No matter what you say, I'm not reversing my decision to pull out of the investment.
Furthermore, why would I entrust and invest in someone who has brain damage?
I didn't come here to ask you to reverse your investment decision.
I wanted to do whatever I could to
take back the pain I may have caused you.
Why would you divulge such information about yourself that would leave you vulnerable as a businesswoman?
I believe I will recover.
And it will get better.
How do you trust me? What if I spread the news? Then what were you going to do?
I came here, risking everything.
Even if you spread the news, I can't do anything.
And...
I did wrong.
I've prepared the documents summarizing the failure to secure the investment deal with CEO Nam
We should hold a board of directors meeting and specifically address this issue.
CEO Nam Dae Young is on the line for you.
Put him through.
You are connected now.
Hello CEO Nam
I actually meant to reach out to you myself.
Regarding Director Seo Eun Gi...
I really am at a loss for words on what happened with that deal
I am sorry.
Director Seo is still learning and very inexperienced with business, and I should not have sent her
As soon as possible, I'd like to hold those talks again.
Excuse me?
Oh, and one more thing.
I'd like to make the counterpart for this new investment deal
Director Seo Eun Gi please.
Excuse me?
But... I heard that you had to endure an unpleasant encounter with her last time...
Unpleasant encounter? Hmmm...
I don't remember that.
What?
The late Chairman Seo really raised his daughter well.
With Director Seo,  whom I feel I have a connection with,
I would like to start this deal again.
Please bring the Board of Directors together.
Let's disclose all of the documents
about Seo Eun Gi.
We will now adjourn the discussion about parameters for the new Jeju Premium project.
Please reference the attached documents for further detailed information.
So then we'll move forward on the Jeju Resort project as discussed.
Next,
I wanted to discuss with all of you directors an issue of critical importance
It is about the position of Director Seo Eun Gi.
Let's talk about your previous plans to murder Seo Eun Gi. Right now.
Chairman?
I'm sorry.
Let's take a break for a moment and then continue on.
We even lived in the same neighborhood, man. We are brothers, yeah, brothers!
Hey, Jae Hee!
Been a long time.
Wow, after not having seen you for so long, your face looks rather rough.
Why don't you go in for a facial massage?
I told Maru everything.
About how you asked me to make sure pretty little Seo Eun Gi
completely dissappeared forever so she couldn't come back.
Maru tells me
that as long as I go into that conference room
and explain everything you asked me to do
Maru said he'd set me up for the rest of my life.
You know, it's not like I love the guy to death or anything
but at the very least, that man keeps his promises.
He is cut from a totally different cloth than you.
He lacks a bit of style, sure, but
he follows through with everything he says he will do.
I mean, you know that better than me,
Right?
Maru paid the consequence for the murder
that you committed
and didn't say a peep since then.
By the way, this isn't something that I know because Maru told me
but because so many things are telling from just one thing
and this is exactly the kind of thing you would do.
Isn't that right?
Chairman Han?
What was it that you were about to say earlier?
I'm thinking about announcing a promotion...
to make Director Seo Eun Gi
Tae San group's public CEO.
Director Seo Eun Gi has built much business experience now
and I believe that her business philosophy and vision is
something that we need to provide an apt opportunity and space
so that it can grow and be cultivated.
Will you accept my offer, Director Seo Eun Gi?
Thank you for watching with usSee you next week