Jim, line one, please.
Jim, line one.
All right, load him up.
Load him up.
Come on, he's not the only
flyer in town today.
Get him up. Transport him.
- A lot of paperwork.
- Careful.
I got him.
Ready? Up.
Right there. I'm going in.
Easy. Easy. Okay.
I got it.
Okay, gentlemen, what do we got?
This man jumped out of a building
and landed on a car.
- Did you get his blood pressure?
- Eighty over something.
Jumped out of a building.
Why? What do you mean,
it was another suicide?
I need another--
Boy, look at the X-rays on that kid.
He is so messed up.
How did it happen?
Does anyone know?
Jumped out of a ten-story window.
Ten-story window?
You're kidding.
- Was he on drugs?
- I don't think he was light at all.
- Toxic screen was negative?
- I heard it was attempted suicide.
Take a deep breath, Roary.
Okay, Roary.
That's it.
Looks like a nice, clean wound.
He's been here eight months or more.
I've been here before.
- I've been here--
- Can you hear me, Roary?
Sure. I can hear you.
My mom's maiden name.
I don't know.
Remember Peggy...
Peggy...
What was her name?
She was the first one to have a bike.
I loved her for her bike.
All the neighbors wanted a bulldog...
Collision Corner.
475 North Columbus.
M-l-C-K-E-Y...
Why? Why?
- That's silly.
- But it's true.
Only to drive Chevys.
Excuse me.
You know where I can
get a beer around here?
Yeah, around the corner. Max's.
You go out here to the right.
A lot of guys from the hospital go there.
Hey. Hey, want some company?
- It's just $25. That's all.
- No.
No. No.
$20?
You look like you could use it.
I'll have a draft.
Right here.
Put the money up.
First one's on the house.
- First time in here, right?
- Yeah.
My name's Jerry.
Roary.
Hey, Jerry, give me another beer,
will you please?
Yeah, that's a 3.
Trust me. It's 3.
Benny, you got a queen, you got a 1 0,
you got two 4s.
- 7, 6...
- 6...
- 4...
- And a 2.
- Possible straight.
- But that's good for me, man.
- Queens.
- You got caught--
- Oh, no! No!
God damn. No.
- Burt is at it.
- Hey, listen, I can't--
...out of the state,
but that he will be on SFO
as soon as he gets back to California.
We just hope we're still
on the air in 1 983...
- Hey!
- when he gets back to California.
Don't touch the set, man.
People ask me what SFO is, you know?
What the show is all about...
- Sorry.
- and what we're trying to do.
Let me say, ladies and gentlemen,
what we're trying to do
is not get canceled.
And you can help
with those postcards and letters.
I think part of our problem is that
we're going to be covering
a lot of different territory.
In broadcasting terminology,
I would say that in that vast waste--
Shoot!
Here. To me.
All right.
Hey, hey, hey.
You're the jerk.
Who's the jerk? Bullshit.
Go, go, go!
That was beautiful!
Get busy with this game.
- Take this.
- Hey! Hey!
Yeah!
Man, that white boy can shoot good.
Come on. Goddamn it.
- Wings?
- Yeah, yeah.
Wings, did you see
the Dillinger movie last night?
- No. No.
- It was really good.
It was one of them art films
with a whole lot of slow motion.
They probably didn't have
the real ending, though, did they?
What real ending?
The man dies in the alley.
Dillinger's pecker's
in a jar at the Smithsonian.
His schlong. It's in a jar.
What is it doing in a jar?
Well, it's 16 inches long,
for Christ sake.
It's in there with the Spirit of St. Louis
and everything.
It's like a national treasure.
What kind of jar did they use?
'Cause if they use a mayonnaise jar,
something like that,
they'd have to bend it
in order to get it in there.
Can they do that?
Look, Blue, if they put
a man's pecker in a museum,
they're going to take the time
to find the right size jar.
Of course they're going
to get the right size jar.
Yeah.
I heard that story.
When I was a kid, I was down there.
At the Smithsonian?
Did you see it?
The guard said it wasn't there.
- See?
- It's probably on tour.
You know, like the King Tut stuff.
They do that.
You know, if they put that thing on tour,
it'll do a hell of a lot more business
than the King Tut thing, huh?
Good morning, Blue, fellas.
- Come in.
- Play cards.
Right, Blue. Right.
They ain't putting my pecker in no jar.
I'll tell you that much, Stinky.
And in no Smithsonian lnstitute, either.
I'm gonna take mine with me,
'cause there are a lot of things
I want to do with it.
- We're ready to go.
- Morning, fellas.
Hey, Books.
How are you?
- Play some cards.
- Wings.
That's right.
Hey, who the hell left this chair over here?
Hey, Jerry, how'd the game go?
Good. Hey, what do you say, Max?
All right, he's okay.
Stinky's okay. He's doing all right.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Come on, guys. Get over here.
Roary, right?
Jerry, right?
Good to see you back.
Did you meet Max yet?
Max, that's Roary.
Looks like another one on the cuff, huh?
Here's your enchiladas.
How you doing, Roary?
Glad to have you.
- What'll you have?
- Enchiladas!
I have some free time.
I just thought I'd get a beer.
- Draft?
- Draft.
Jerry, Burt, how about
some beer over here?
- We're thirsty.
- All right. They're coming.
Hey, I got them, Jer.
What's wrong with your leg?
What's wrong with yours?
Hey, you play cards?
I played a lot in the hospital.
Hey, can you use another hand over there?
Another hand? Yeah.
I can use two of them.
What's this...
Goddamn, that's funny.
Every time I hear it, it's still funny.
Grab your beer.
I'll introduce you to the guys.
Here we go.
Wet and cold.
I will have one of those
wet and colds, buddy.
Hey, Roary.
Okay, everybody,
I'd like you to meet Roary.
Roary, this is Stinky,
that's Wings,
and this is Blue Lewis.
What's wrong with him?
He walks funny, and his head
sort of tilts to one side.
Which side?
The right side.
Then put him over here.
I don't want him looking at my cards.
Watch out for him. He cheats.
So you're a friend of Jerry's, huh?
Yeah.
- He's a hell of a guy.
- The best.
Well, he's not that good.
What's your name?
- Roary. R-O-A-R-Y.
- Stinky, let's deal the cards out
and get the game going, huh?
- Okay, just a second.
- Okay.
Everybody ready?
Look at--
- Oh, wow.
- I'm all in with 3 of clubs.
Hey, man!
- Hey, kid, you're all right.
- Hey, you're okay, kid.
I'll drink to you.
Hey.
Look at that ass.
Come here.
Let me see it.
- That's not--
- Yeah.
Fifty-five.
$55? You told him $50.
Goes up, man.
- Goes up since from here to there?
- lnflation.
Don't look away for a second.
Know what I mean?
Bad sneeze, eyes closed and--
But anyway, I'm going to bet a dime.
A dime more.
You better take a look at your hold cards.
I think you read them wrong.
No, no, no.
I know what I got. Let's go.
Say, so what happened to you?
I've been in the hospital for a while.
So?
I jumped off a building
and tried to commit suicide.
You asshole.
You got it all backwards.
First you get crippled,
then you try to commit suicide.
Roary, I'm sorry I called you an asshole.
- It's all right.
- Yeah.
That's the most depressing thing
I've ever heard.
Hey.
Okay, let's play some cards.
A little distributing company.
Max, you're two weeks behind on this one.
Not while I'm eating, okay?
Well, let's try this one.
Hey, Jerry, you got a friend down there.
Hey, Mouse!
Let me see.
That's an 8 of hearts.
What are you doing up with the sunshine?
Phone rang this morning.
It was the wrong number.
Got another Coke?
Okay, so, then bet.
- I did already.
- You gonna raise?
Well, I may do that, too.
Is this a deuce-- this card?
- Yeah.
- Hey, that's Jerry's girl.
I'm gonna take yours.
Poor kid's a junkie, and, you know,
she whores it so she can buy junk.
Promise? On my ass.
Does Jerry know that?
Yeah, he knows it,
but he thinks he loves her.
Hey, here's the last card.
Down and dirty.
- Cover me, Burt?
- You got it, Jerry.
- Come on.
- Where are we going?
Outside. I don't want
to talk in here, Mouse.
Where the hell's the money?
The money's right there--
- Where the hell is it?
- Right there.
Don't get excited.
Right there in front of you.
Max, this is ridiculous.
You got to stop buying these things.
Jeez, Max. Here's one for electric.
Eight hundred bucks!
- lmpossible.
- Possible!
So what the hell you want me to do,
Burt, raise prices?
Everybody in the damn neighborhood
is on a fixed income.
You keep it up, you're going to be
the one who's on a fixed income.
- Gil.
- Yeah?
- You want to go to the game tonight?
- Nah.
- Come on. This will be a great game.
- Jerry, you go too early.
Look, I got an extra ticket.
Hey, I'm sorry, man.
I can't make it.
Roary, how you doing?
Good.
Listen, I got an extra ticket
to the Warriors game tonight.
My lady's out of town.
You want to go?
Yeah. Good.
Game starts at 8:00.
I like to be there about an hour early,
so I'll meet you here at 6:30.
Okay with you? Good.
How's your beer doing?
Give me that.
I'm going to buy you one.
Hey, Clifford!
If you can catch the ball,
maybe you can pull up a lay-up.
They're looking at you, Jerry...
Don't worry about it.
They never come up in the stands.
Hey, hey.
There he is.
That's Alvin Martin.
Which one is Martin?
The one that says "Martin" on his back.
Right.
Hey, Alvin!
Work on the 3-pointers!
You look good!
Hey, shut up, Mouth!
Hey!
They love it.
Hey, those two girls next to you--
do they come to all the games?
I don't know.
Why don't you ask her?
He wants to ask you something.
What?
He's just shy.
Can we get a beer?
Stop the ball!
Get on Westphal, get on Westphal.
Come on, Jo Jo!
Stay on that man!
Let's go. Get back there!
Get back!
Get on Westphal!
- Run the play!
- Yeah!
Run the play!
Get the rebound!
- No, you bum!
- Get up!
- Abernathy, pass off!
- Pass it off!
Come on!
Screen him!
Yes! All right!
All right!
Let's go!
Come on!
Get out of here.
- Yes, yes!
- Yeah! Yeah! All right!
Move it! Get down there!
Get down there!
The key, Roary--
The key is Alvin Martin.
Shoot it!
Martin, shoot the ball!
Shoot it! Shoot it!
Alvin--
Two points.
Shit!
He choked!
Martin-- Come on, Roary.
Final score--
Phoenix Suns: 94,
Golden State Warriors: 93.
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen,
and be sure to drive home safely.
Al, you got a couple of seconds?
I just got two questions
that I want to ask you.
Real short, okay?
Tough luck, huh?
Look, tight shot just on his face, all right?
Are you rolling on this thing?
We're ready? Okay, good.
Al, a great ball game
for you individually tonight,
but what about the last two seconds?
Well, I came off the pick,
and I got the pass from Abernathy.
I had the shot,
but I saw him cutting down--
- That's a lie, man! You panicked!
- Shut it down, okay?
- We can't use this thing.
- Who let that guy in here?
I'll talk to you later, Al.
Let's see if we can talk to him.
- It's The Mouth, sideline know-it-all.
- He's not worth it, man!
You didn't play so hard either, Clifford.
Al, you gotta remember that panic is dumb.
You made that shot thousands of times.
Just relax, man.
Alvin, why don't you take care
of that jerk once and for all?
Why don't you get out of here, man?
You don't know what the hell
you're talking about!
I don't? I can beat you
any day of the week.
Why don't you be cool?
You're making a fool out of yourself.
Why not?
Why don't we go one-on-one?
- We'll see just how big a fool I am.
- Let's go.
Wait a minute.
Okay, man. Okay.
We'll do it.
I got practice tomorrow at 1 1 :00.
You meet me at the arena at 1 0:30.
- And be on time.
- I'll be there.
- We'll do it.
- All right.
Okay, guys. Come on.
If you got the balls, you'll be there.
What? Get out of there.
- I was talking to him.
- Okay. Take off. That way.
- Yeah, we'll see.
- That way.
Here you are.
You hurt yourself?
- No, I didn't.
- No.
What's the matter with your leg?
Nothing.
Nothing that's going to bother you.
What's wrong with your hand?
Hey, look, man, I don't want to play you
if you got something wrong.
- There's nothing wrong with my leg.
- Nothing wrong with his leg.
Let's just play.
That's exactly why I'm here, man.
I'm going to shut you up once and for all.
I mean, we love you when we're winning.
We love you out there yelling
and screaming when we're hot.
But, man, you come down on us
so hard when we get behind.
Why don't you give us a break?
Let's play.
Wait a minute.
Last chance.
I got nothing to prove.
You want to forget it?
You want to take it out?
You take it out.
Don't you want to warm up first?
No need.
That's one.
Come on. Put it up.
Put it up.
Damn it!
What is this?
That's two.
Not bad, Maxwell.
Three.
That's three, Jerry. Not bad.
Damn it!
That's four, Jerry.
Stay with it.
Come on!
That's five! That's five!
That's a foul.
You hurt yourself.
Time, time, time.
- Take it easy.
- That was a foul.
5-1.
You got one, Alvin.
You got one.
Come on, Jerry.
5-2. 5-2.
Look out!
Oh, repeat after me.
"That was a nice block, Alvin."
Foul-mouth. Get off.
- Watch him now, Jerry.
- Get off.
- Watch the feet. Stay with him.
- Look out!
Attaboy!
All right.
- 7-7.
- Sweet!
7 -7, Jerry.
All right!
9-7.
It's 9-7, Jerry.
You only got one to beat him.
- One to beat him!
- Look out, look out!
Stay with him, Jerry!
- Aw, Jerry!
- How are you? What happened?
9-8.
That was a foul!
One to beat him, Jerry.
One to beat him.
- Block!
- Roll in!
- Got him!
- All the way!
Damn!
Swish!
1 0-9.
- 1 0-9. Game.
- No, man.
You gotta win by two.
Two. Hey...
That'll shut you up, Mouth.
No, man. I wasn't ready.
- Bullshit!
- Hey! Come on, Alvin!
Look, man, I don't play that hard
against cripples, you know?
I could've beat you with his hands.
You're a half-court showboat, Charlie.
- That's all you'll ever be.
- No, he's not.
He's great, and you know it.
No, come on.
Shut up, Roary.
Hey, man, look, get out of my gym,
and take that other freak with you.
Yeah.
Un-fucking-believable!
Unbelievable!
Two points!
It was so close!
You're fantastic! All right!
You're unbelievable!
I was there.
I'm your witness.
- All right. I'm good.
- I saw it.
- I'm good, aren't l?
- "Good," Jerry?
- You're fantastic!
- And it's not a dream, is it?
- A dream? No.
- All right, Roary!
- 9-1 1 --
- 9-1 0.
He cheated on the last one.
- I'm going to buy you a beer.
- All right!
You don't want any cookies or anything?
- No, I don't want cookies.
- All right. Let me get this.
- Listen, Roary...
- You keep that.
don't tell the guys what happened.
- What do you mean don't tell the guys?
- They won't believe it.
Jerry, you almost beat the guy.
I surprised him.
Hey, Roary, nobody is ready
for me the first time.
- Besides, he had a bad hand.
- Hi, Jerry.
- Hi, Georgie. How you feeling?
- Fine.
But you almost beat him.
Oh, Jer.
Look, about your leg--
I know it's none of my business,
but you're sure there's nothing
could be done?
Roary, I had an operation
on my bread and butter.
- Bread and butter?
- When I was 1 6.
I went through the physical therapy.
I went through everything.
Nothing happened, nothing changed.
But they know a lot more now.
I know, Roary.
I've been to the doctors.
Listen, I bet they could
do something for you.
It'll cost a million bucks.
Who's going to pay for it? You?
I thought you said we were taking a shortcut.
This is a shortcut.
That's a shortcut-- those steps?
I'll race you.
Sheesh. What does that mean--
that, uh, "bread and butter"?
It means good luck.
You want to come up for another beer?
Sure.
Is it all right?
Anne's gone to Richmond for a while.
Come on.
Aw, sh--
Hey.
That's Anne.
Not so rough!
You're hurting me!
Roary, go around the back.
You said you wanted it, man!
- You wanted it, right?
- Take it easy!
Okay, that's how you're going to get it.
Oh, shit!
Get out of here, Jerry.
- Hey, beat it, huh?
- This is my house.
And that's my girl you're fooling with.
Whatever you paid her,
I'll see you get it back.
Now, please, get out.
Christ!
Look, she came on to us.
Anne?
Yes, honey?
Where's the money?
They didn't give me any money.
Listen, man, she took 25 bucks,
and I want to see it.
- Or what?
- Or this.
Mistake.
I'll give you five seconds to get out,
or me and my friend there
are going to hurt you.
I'm not even going to count.
You figure it out.
Starting right now.
Okay.
Relax. Relax.
What's 25 bucks among friends, huh?
Oh, Jerry.
Anne, what happened?
I met this guy.
Jerry, he had such incredible stuff.
Jerry, it was heaven.
Listen to me, Anne.
I can't handle this anymore.
Do you understand?
I can't take care of you anymore.
I can't do it.
Hey, come on, honey.
When I get back here...
I want you gone.
Hey, baby, I'm pretty screwed up right now.
What are you talking about?
Just leave, Anne.
Jerry, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
It just didn't work out.
Don't leave, Jerry.
"Her huge melons
glistened in the moonlight.
"She smiled, taunting him,
"then slowly, ever so slowly,
she began to undu-- undu--"
- "Undulate"?
- "Undulate"!
- Undulate what? Her hips?
- Yes, yes, her hips.
- Go ahead, go ahead.
- "As her breasts moved toward him,
"bubbling in the night air,
he couldn't help but notice
"how she had grown from that small child
from whom he had once babysat."
"He reached out..."
Go ahead, go ahead.
"and gently touched
her large, brown aur--"
A-U-R-E-O-L-E-S.
"Aureoles"?
You're killing the story.
"Her large, brown aureoles"?
What? He touched her cookies?
Hey, guys, let's go to lunch, huh?
- I'm hungry.
- Okay, good.
Here's your hat.
Here's his coat.
- Oh, good.
- Blue, block that in the book, will you?
- Yeah.
- You guys still reading that dirty book?
No, no, no.
We don't read dirty books.
Hey, Max, I'm going out to eat.
You don't read those dirty books anymore?
- Roary, come on to lunch with us.
- I'm coming.
Roary, don't bring me
those chili burritos, okay?
What's the matter?
I got heartburn or something.
Get me a couple
bologna sandwiches instead.
With?
- Mayonnaise--
- Mayonnaise on white?
- White bread and--
- No pickles.
- How about a Bromo?
Hey, Benny.
How you doing, Benny?
- All right.
- How's it going, huh?
- Coming along.
- Hey, Blue!
Blue, when you coming to see me again?
No, no. Move, brother Stinky.
Hey, Roary, when you see Jerry,
tell him his old lady took up
with a pimp in San Francisco.
I'm not going to tell him anything.
There's no need to tell him that.
Don't tell him. Right.
We don't have to tell him anything, okay?
- Right, right.
- Come on. Let's go.
- I dropped the book.
- What?
Wait a minute.
I dropped the book. Pull me back.
Don't lose the place.
Blue, don't lose the place.
We're going to lose more than that
if we don't get out of the way!
- Get out of the street!
- Oh, my God!
Folks, keep clear.
This man's a big one here.
Let them through, please.
- Let's get him up.
- Okay, let's go.
All right, there.
You'll be all right, man.
Roary.
Jer, how's Max?
- He had a heart attack.
- I know. How is he?
He's resting.
He hasn't been looking right, you know?
I know.
He's worried about the bar.
He just got a foreclosure notice.
He hasn't closed the bar
for one night since he opened it,
and he owes $1 1,000.
Eleven thousand. Jesus.
Let's get something to eat.
- So what's going to happen?
- Happen to what?
What are you going to do about the bar?
I don't know. What can I do?
Someone comes through with $1 1,000,
or we find another bar.
We could buy it, Jerry.
Come on-- Roary, we could buy it?
No, listen. I was going to tell you.
I got some money put away.
My mother, when she died--
they put it in a trust fund.
I was going to loan it
to you for your operation.
How much?
Bread and butter.
$1 0,000.
That'd be enough to get
a half interest from Max.
$1 0,000?
I did it for-- I did it for you.
But with that money,
we could buy half interest in Max's.
Are you kidding?
$1 0,000, Roary?
You have ten--
You've got $1 0,000?
Roary, with my--
I've got money saved.
I can get my operation!
- But Max's.
- No. Come on!
- Jerry--
- Max's? No. Roary, that's a bad investment.
Look, places like Max's,
they go under all the time.
No. Jerry, you and me.
We can make it work.
No, Roary. Please?
I want that operation.
You'll get it.
I guarantee you.
Roary!
It is just a bar!
I'm talking about my life!
It's not just a bar.
Jerry, it's family.
You're right.
There you go.
Here you go.
- Jerry--
- You're right.
You mean you believe me?
Jerry?
You freak show, I told you you're right.
- We'll get rich.
- Yeah, you and me, rich.
What a sight.
If it doesn't work out,
Jerry, I'll do it myself.
- I'll fix your leg. Hold still.
- No, no.
I'm gonna fix his leg.
I'm a doctor, really.
- He's a lunatic.
- Come on.
- What, again?
- Cottage cheese.
- Hi, Max.
- It's good for you.
Hi.
Where are my four beers?
Jerry's working on 'em.
How you doing?
Here you go, Louise.
Excuse me.
Thank you so much.
- How's your tips?
- Oh, great.
- Just run a tab on them.
- Okay.
Now, is there anything else
I can get for you guys here?
Hey, chef.
Ordering a tuna fish with Swiss cheese
and a roast beef on rye.
Tuna fish, cheese, roast beef, rye.
It's a good idea, the sandwiches, Roary.
We're doing a hell of a business back there.
Yeah. I've been having trouble
with the ordering, though.
Some days I don't get enough cheese,
some days I get too much bread,
and today I forgot--
I forgot...
I'll wait till somebody orders it.
- Then I'll remember.
- You're doing beautiful, baby.
Don't forget these.
Hey, Jerry.
- You want a sandwich?
- Nope.
Hey, Jerry, you read today's sports page?
It named Alvin Martin Rookie of the Year.
Jerry, he's been getting 3 million a year.
Hey, what's this?
That's Scotch.
I want two bourbons.
You get it, Burt, okay?
Hey, Burt, do you think he deserves
this kind of money?
Hey, Burt.
- I'll be right back.
- All right.
- Louise.
- Yeah.
Come here.
See, I got--
I got two cheeseburgers going there.
Just make sure they're rare.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. I'm just tired.
Your leg giving you pain?
A little.
It's nothing new.
Yeah. It won't be long
before your operation.
It'll be forever.
Sh--
Hey, Jerry.
I threw it away.
I threw away thousands!
Thousands of dollars on that bitch,
and she's off in some
stinkhole in San Francisco.
You'll make it back.
I wasted it!
I'm breaking my back.
I'm working two jobs.
I'm no better off than when I first met her.
And she's worse.
I don't know what the hell I'm doing.
Hey, Jer.
You know how you're always talking
about how we have to forget our past.
Oh, bullshit!
Shit, Roary, I don't know shit.
Everything I touch
turns to shit.
I didn't turn to shit.
Well, that's because
you're already shit, Roary.
I didn't have to do a thing.
Hey, what's going on?
I'm alone behind the bar.
Louise is screwing up--
I'm sorry. I forgot.
Come on, get out there and help her.
Hey, Jerry.
Hi, Roary. How are you?
Hi, Anne.
When did you get back?
- I got back--
- She got back this morning.
I called her.
I wanted her back.
You want a hamburger?
Thanks. I have to go back to the bar.
Hey, Jerry tells me that you're
doing great business there.
Yeah, we're doing good.
I just wanted to ask you
if maybe you could leave
your other job a little earlier.
Burt's going to see
his cousin Joan in Marin, and--
Sure, I can come any time he wants.
Good.
You don't--
You don't have to leave too early.
I mean, a half hour would be good.
No, it's okay.
I'm gonna quit that job, anyways.
You're gonna quit?
Why?
You need the money.
No, I need more time with Anne.
Okay. I'll see you down there.
All right.
You want a beer?
- I'll go get it.
- No.
Thanks.
You sure you want to quit your other job?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Okay.
Have a good one.
All right.
And oil thyself, squeaky.
Hey, Roary.
I'll see you in a while.
Yeah, Jerry.
Yeah, I'll see you later, Jerry.
See you later.
Please and thank you very much.
I appreciate it.
I think we got trouble.
What do you mean?
It's up your alley.
No. A family--
No, I wouldn't enjoy that.
Go with the man.
- What is it?
- Stinky, shut up.
Benny, who's that?
Lucius Porter.
How do you do?
Mr. Maxwell.
I'm Lucius Porter,
a friend of Anne's from the city.
Anne has a ring of mine,
one that I place a great value on.
Now, if you would be kind enough
to tell me where she is,
I would be deeply appreciative.
I didn't know that ring was real.
It is of infinite worth, and I want it back.
Well, then, I'll get it for you.
I think she's probably already hawked it.
But if she hasn't, I'll get it for you.
If you don't, I will kill you.
I wish you hadn't said that.
I mean, that kind of thing--
that's not allowed in Max's.
I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to ask you to leave.
I mean, I'm sorry,
but you can understand that.
You are a fool.
Get out of here.
It's been a pleasure meeting you.
Perhaps we'll get together again,
sometime in the not-too-distant future.
What's with the suitcase?
Look, I'm not staying here anymore.
It was a mistake.
What are you talking about?
Look, Jerry, I don't think
you should be here right now.
I don't understand.
Lucius is gonna be here any minute.
I'm going back with him.
That's crazy, Anne.
We're doing all right this time.
I've got money.
Yeah, but not enough.
I'm not hustling for Lucius.
He's just taken real good care of me.
I love you.
I am in trouble.
Right?
Damn it!
- You look a little thin.
- Please, no.
Have you lost some weight?
- Look, just--
- I think you just need a little rest, hmm?
Wait--
God, Lucius, don't hurt him anymore.
Honey, he's gonna be all right.
- All right. All right.
- Why don't you go on down to the car?
We're through here.
It's--
It's-- It's enough, okay?
Please, please.
It's-- I've had enough.
Where the hell is Jerry?
Never been late before.
He should have been here
over an hour ago.
It's just not like him.
I wish he had a phone.
He gets his calls from somewhere.
I don't know, maybe--
maybe you ought to go over there.
I think somebody should.
You want me to go?
- Hey, Max!
- One minute.
No. I'll go.
Louise, can you get down
by that green table?
I got to go.
Here's a guy doing figure eights.
Hey, hold it right there, pal.
I'm Roary, the chef from Max's bar.
Oh, yeah, that kid.
See ya, Roary.
See you later.
Jerry.
Why don't you get a telephone, Jerry?
Hey, what did you leave the door open for?
Hey, Jerry.
Jerry.
Jerry, sit up.
Jerry, I'll go get some help.
I'll go get some help.
Oh, Christ, Jerry.
Roary.
Your face.
Jerry, you're hurt bad.
Jerry, I'm gonna get a doctor.
No.
- Jerry--
- No.
- I'll call an ambulance.
- No. No ambulances.
Why can't I call an ambulance?
No doctor.
Nobody.
Roary.
Oh, shit.
No, don't take any off the top, Louise.
I like it just the way it is on the top.
Just take a little off the side, okay?
- Okay, just keep your hands down.
- Okay.
Hey, leave her alone.
She knows what she's doing.
What do you mean?
- Oh, hi, there.
- Hi.
How's he doing today?
Same as always, sleeping.
That's what he needs.
Yeah, but two weeks?
Does he talk about what happened?
He doesn't talk about anything.
Well, you know, you would think
Jerry would want to get better
so he can bust those guys up.
He doesn't get angry,
he doesn't do anything.
The other day I'm giving him a bath,
you know, massaging his leg
like the doctor says,
and I dunk him.
Roary, you don't do that.
It was just a joke.
He didn't fight back.
He would have let me drown him.
Okey-dokey, Blue, I think you are done.
You're gonna leave him like that?
- What do you mean, leave him like that?
- This is for you.
- For me, Louise?
- Yes.
A red lollipop.
Yes, you were a very good little boy.
Oh, wow.
- You look great, Lewis.
- Thanks, Roary.
Why don't you let me cut your hair, hmm?
No, I've got bad hair.
It doesn't cut--
Oh, no, you don't.
You have nice hair.
- Whoa-ho, there's gonna be sex.
- I can tell.
Maybe some other time, Louise.
- Some other time.
I meant my hair.
Yeah, we know what you mean.
Okay, if you're all done up here,
I'll go set up the sandwich stuff, okay?
- Yeah, I've got to do some reordering.
- Reordering!
We know where you're going.
We know where you're going
- Hey, Louise.
- We know where you're going
- We hear you!
- Shame, shame, double shame
It might not be a bad idea someday
to take a little bit off.
- Everybody knows your name
- Whatever. You are the worst.
Hey, Jerry.
How's the water? Still hot?
It's fine.
I forgot to show you something.
Wait till you see this.
This is terrific.
Let me see.
Where the hell is it?
I hate that, when you know
where something is, and you don't--
you don't know--
Look at this.
Alvin Martin, $3 million.
$3 million.
Makes you about 2.7 or 2.6.
Give me your leg.
Come on.
Lift.
That thing getting a boner?
Whoops, sorry.
Didn't mean to make you smile.
You gotta start feeling better soon.
You gonna try to get back
at that guy Lucius?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Think about it.
I don't know.
Stop being such a basket case, man.
- Where's your balls?
- I got no balls, Roary.
What are you gonna do,
give up on your operation, too?
That's right.
Why don't you make some bubbles?
You'll feel better, you'll see.
You'll see.
Hey, Roary, you sure
you ain't bullshitting us
just to get me to take you guys for a ride?
Hey, Roary don't bullshit.
If he said Jerry played
Alvin Martin one on one
and almost beat him, I believe him.
We had bets down.
We had major bets.
Lewis, where's the book?
I didn't bring the book.
What, are you crazy?
You never know when you're gonna bet.
If you had your book, I'd lay odds
that we don't find Alvin Martin's house.
Yeah, well, you'd lose.
There it is, right on the other side
of this shrub here.
- It's the white house.
- Hey, let's see the magazine.
- Stop. Stop, Benny.
- There it is. There it is.
No, no, that's not the house, man,
'cause Alvin Martin's house has got--
well, you know all them
white houses look alike to me.
- Okay, let's go, let's go.
- You're right, anyway.
His number's 1 4458. That's it.
Right. Yeah, okay.
This is fantastic.
I almost moved into a neighborhood like this.
- Benny.
- Baloney.
- Let me have that magazine, Roary.
- Here you go.
This is a tough neighborhood.
Hey, this is the house right up here.
Right up here.
Hold it, hold it.
That's it. That's it.
Look, that's the house.
- What's the number?
- Look at that house, man.
- 1 4458, that's it.
- Boy, look at that house.
I don't believe it.
Are you kidding?
So what's it gonna be?
You gonna ask Alvin Martin for the money
for Jerry's operation?
- I didn't say--
- Yeah, what are you gonna say to Martin?
- Excuse me, Mr. Martin--
- Excuse me, Mr. Martin.
Perfect, go ahead.
- Give me the magazine.
- Oh, okay.
- All right.
- Great.
Looking good.
What's the place look like?
Stinky, it's beautiful.
It's all in white, and it's modern.
And Alvin Martin has got two
Japanese gardeners working on the lawn.
- Japanese?
- Yeah.
I thought Martin was a spade.
Don't use that word when there's
another spade in the car.
What? There's a Negro in this car?
There are several Negroes in this car.
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
You know,
I never thought about it before,
but it must be tough
being a bigot if you're blind.
I know. I had to give it up.
Yeah.
Excuse me. Mr. Martin?
Well, I guess Roary was wrong.
You don't want to die, do you?
I'm going to loan you
the money for your operation.
Now, it's not charity, it's just a loan.
I don't want your money.
Wait a minute.
Look, you little bastard.
I'm not finished.
I'll be honest with you.
If you hadn't almost kicked my ass
that day we played,
I wouldn't be here now.
I mean, your whole story
is sad and all that,
but I know stories that make yours
sound like a picnic.
I don't want your charity.
I told you, man.
No charity.
Are you listening to me?
Call it curiosity.
Curiosity?
Listen, Jerry,
I know you're good enough
to play semi-pro ball.
Can you understand that?
I mean, a hot shot
little white boy like you?
Man, if you can pass like you can shoot,
you might just go all the way.
Hey, look, I know it sounds unreal,
but that's what makes it so good.
That's exactly what makes it so good.
What do you say?
Hey, look.
I'll send a car for you tomorrow.
Bitch.
Fetch, fetch.
Alvin's got you in the best hospital,
at Stanford Hospital.
The doctor for the Warriors
is going to be taking care of you.
- He's not bad, huh?
- Yeah.
He lives right nearby,
so he'll be conditioning with you
or working on your thing
while you're there, and--
I guess you'll be there three,
four months or something.
I wonder how they can do that
with their mouths open
- without taking a lot of water in.
- I don't know.
You'd think they'd get sick,
or get a headache or something.
- Come on! Here, boy!
- Looks like they're choking.
- I'm going to need you.
- What for?
For the operation.
You don't need me.
You got the best people
in the world around you.
I'd just like you to be there.
I've been working so hard at the place
and taking care of you, I'm wiped out.
- I need a rest.
- Please?
Sure. I'll ride up with you.
No. I think it's better if you come by
and you're on your own.
Kind of make it look like it's a surprise.
Wait a minute.
What, are you ashamed
to let people know that l--
that you need me?
- What the hell does that mean?
- I just thought it'd be better this way.
Nothing. I'll be there.
So long, Jerry.
Hey, so long, you guys.
I'll see you sooner than you think.
Hey, you guys take care of Max.
Jerry, good luck to you.
All right, Roary.
He's your responsibility.
It's all on your shoulders.
Sprint!
- Bye, Jerry.
- Good luck, Jerry.
All right, fellas, drinks are on Max.
- What?
- Hey!
Three cheers!
Hey, let's go!
Bread and butter.
Hey, Louise, "apparently"--
L-Y or L-E-Y?
L-Y.
That's what I got.
Hey, Roary.
I think we have to increase
our order on draft beer,
maybe two, three kegs a week.
- That okay?
- Good. Make it three.
Hey, Herrada!
Yo!
Here are your two
ham sandwiches with chips.
- No?
- I got better things to do with my money.
Hey, I got a new one for you guys.
Okay, go ahead.
- This ain't no Polish joke, is it?
- No, no, Mr. Wilkowski, never.
No Polish jokes.
Roary, who are you writing to?
What?
- You writing to Jerry?
- Jerry.
We haven't heard from him in months.
Why don't you call him?
Call him?
I don't want to be pushy,
I just want to bug him a little bit.
Listen to this.
Tell me how it sounds.
Okay.
"Dear Jerry..."
Yeah?
I just wanted to get your impression
- about the opening there.
- Okay.
"ln case you've forgotten,
my name is Roary.
"How are you?
I used to be your best friend,
so you said--"
Now that's not too angry, is it?
- No, no. That's fine.
- All right.
Go ahead.
"I'm sure you're working very hard,
and apparently, you're very busy,
"but I would appreciate hearing from you,
hearing about your recuperation,
"and how life is treating you.
"Stinky says hello.
So does Wings.
"So does Blue Lewis.
"And Stinky has
a girlfriend named Claire.
"She looks like Shirley Temple, but older.
"l think mainly she and Stinky
have a good thing going, sexually, but--
"Blue Lewis doesn't have to read him
porno anymore, she does.
Louise is..."
What? What'd you say?
The rest of this stuff is just guy talk.
- Is that more titty talk, there?
- No.
Let me see that.
I tell him that you're doing a good job
and how pretty you are.
Thank you.
No problem.
Okay. "Burt and I went to Tijuana,
"saw a lousy bull fight.
"They had this old cow
that could hardly walk.
"A guy comes out, stabs it.
"Blah, blah, blah. Big deal.
So why don't you come by?
Love, Roary."
I just wanted to write a friendly letter.
It's beautiful.
Do you really think he'll come back?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, he'll come back.
I know what he's doing now.
This is a dream come true for him.
And he has to spend
some time with his dream.
Yeah.
But what's your dream?
I don't know.
Well, why don't you spend
a little time finding out?
Yeah.
Why don't you go wash the dishes?
- Oh, no. Must l?
- No.
I'm only kidding.
Come on, we'll do it together.
All right, I'll be right over.
I'll wash, you dry.
No, you wash and dry.
Yo, Benny, the girls are all alone.
Dance with them.
One, two, go dance.
Hey, Roary, take this to the back table.
Down there, to the right.
Thanks.
- Bread and butter.
- Merry Christmas.
Hey, Roary!
Where the hell is Jerry, huh?
He'll be here.
Hey, if he isn't here at Christmas,
when is he coming, huh?
He's coming, he's coming.
Come on, baby. Let's go!
Come on, honey.
It's still pouring out.
Oh, boy.
Hey, dance with Roary.
Jingle your bell.
Hey, Roary.
Come on, Roary.
Let's go.
Come on, baby.
Let's dance.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
- A couple beers.
- What's going on over there?
Roary and Louise are dancing together.
What? To that music?
Where the hell is that jukebox?
Here. Here, Stinky.
Watch the stick.
Stinky!
Where are you going, Stinky?
Where are you going?
Hey, come on.
That's my favorite song.
What?
Hey, you cut my song, Stinky!
Hey, hey, Stink!
I'm playing the piano.
What the hell do you think I'm doing?
Hey, Roary! Roary!
What is this, a woman with a beard?
Where's Louise. Louise!
- Where are you?
- I'm right here.
Here, here.
Dance to some real music.
That's it.
Okay.
Hey, where's Claire?
Here I am, Stinky.
- Hey.
- Hey, man.
Merry Christmas.
Ain't no drug dog, is it?
Hey, Louisie!
Oh, no.
- Oh, boy.
- Merry Christmas.
Burt's kissed her.
Hey, Roary.
Mistletoe, come on--
Hey, not me, the lady!
Jesus. Come on.
Come on.
Kiss her.
Mistletoe! Mistletoe!
Burt's making--
Burt's making Roary kiss her.
Louise, come on.
With your lips, your lips!
Come on, now.
On the lips.
Roary, on the lips.
On the lips. On the lips.
Come on, on the lips.
What are you waiting for?
On the lips! Come on!
Lay it on her!
Go ahead, Roary!
He's kissing her!
He's kissing her.
All right, Louise.
Hey, all right!
Hey, Max, we need a bunch of water!
Look at that!
Hey, Roary, come up for some air.
Come on, hey.
Oh, what fun it is to ride
In a one-horse open sleigh, hey
Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way
Oh, what fun it is to ride
In a one-horse open sleigh
We're going home.
The party's over.
Party's over, huh?
Did Jerry come?
Didn't show, he didn't show.
Let's go home.
Can we wait--
We're going home.
Blue, it's late.
But we should wait
for ten minutes for him, at least.
I'm wondering what
happened to him, too.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, it's Christmas.
You can't expect everybody
with the traffic...
Let's go home and have our own party.
To hell with Jerry.
Santy Claus sees this mess,
he ain't gonna bring you guys no presents.
- Hey, Burt.
- Yeah.
Thank you again for the cheap tie.
I didn't buy it. I stole it.
Goodnight, Max.
Those guys were really disappointed,
weren't they?
Yeah, well, they love Jerry.
He's like family.
Maybe that's the problem.
- No more.
- What?
Let's forget all this
and take care of it tomorrow morning.
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
What do you mean by that?
What?
It's a problem?
Oh, he's well.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe he just doesn't really want
to come back anymore.
You mean, like, he feels
he doesn't fit in anymore.
- Yeah, maybe.
- Here.
I don't know.
Just-- I don't know.
Can I pull your collar up?
Oh, thanks.
I had a great time.
- You were terrific.
- It was so much fun.
And I also want to thank you
for the present.
- Present?
- My kiss.
You'd better get home.
- I'll tell you what you can do.
- What?
You can sleep late tomorrow.
Oh, may l?
You get some rest, too.
- Yeah, have a merry Christmas.
- You do, too.
- Goodnight, Louise.
- Merry Christmas. Bye.
Shit.
"Don't worry, Roary.
I'll get it."
Yeah, it's Max's, it's Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
It's very late.
Do you believe Christmas Eve,
you drive for five hours,
only get three dollars in tips in this rain?
Some Christmas spirit, huh?
Have a good time, pal.
All right.
Here you go, pal.
Keep the change.
Hey, Merry Christmas.
Hey, Jerry!
Hey, Roary!
No, stay there, Roary.
I want to show you something.
Yeah.
Look at this knee.
Just look at it.
- Beautiful.
- Oh, it's good to see you.
- You look terrific.
Well, let's get out of the rain.
All right.
Them boys really
missed you tonight, man.
Well, I got hung up, you know?
- You could've called.
- I did call. I called you.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, I got a present for you.
These are for the guys.
- Terrific.
- Let's get a beer.
My doctor says the leg is pretty strong.
Should be okay if I don't push too hard.
You know, kind of pace myself.
I've really gone along pretty fast.
Alvin works out with me every day.
Ah, that's great.
No.
This is great.
I tried out for a semi-pro team
in San Jose last week.
And?
And they want me.
Jer, that's terrific.
This is Christmas.
So...
when do you start?
Thursday night.
Sorry, guys. Last call.
- Want another beer?
- Yeah.
- Two?
- Two.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
San Jose Thursday night.
Can you make it?
Can I make it?
Are you kidding?
I'll be there on Wednesday.
I'll bring the guys.
My fault.
My fault, I'm sorry.
I almost had a heart attack.
No.
Hold off on the guys for a little bit.
I don't know how I'm going to do.
I think I'd be too nervous.
Yeah.
Good.
Can I bring Louise?
Louise?
- The waitress?
- Waitress.
It's a shame you didn't
get a chance to know her.
She's really doing good.
She's-- She's something.
The guys love her.
Gee, I hardly remember her.
She's kind of pretty, isn't she?
Jerry, she's beautiful.
You really like her.
No, I mean, we're just friends.
She's a good waitress.
Sure, bring her.
Merry Christmas.
He didn't even call or nothing.
His first game, he didn't even invite us.
Who does he think we are,
people he used to know?
Hey, I happen to know
you guys are wrong.
He wants to see you bad.
It is his first game, you know?
I mean, he's tense.
He's under a lot of pressure.
He did send you gifts.
Roary, you and Louise
are going to the game,
and we knew Jerry before you did.
Shut up, Blue.
If the man doesn't care,
he just doesn't care.
He does care.
It's just that you got to give him some time.
Look, if you don't
want me to go, I won't go.
Well, the point is,
somebody's got to go.
- Go ahead.
- Hey, Roary, you ready?
It's getting a little late.
- Go. I'll see you.
- Go on, it's all right.
See you when I get back.
Yeah, we'll be here.
All right. You got the camera?
Yeah, I got the camera,
got the bulbs, got supper--
I'm not hungry.
Hell, I'm going to eat.
What's on my plate, Wings?
You got a potato at 6:00,
you got succotash at 9:00,
and you got a steak at high-noon.
I don't like succotash at 9:00.
- All right!
- Move, move!
Come on, man, me!
Coming down!
I thought The Mouth would be out there
hot dogging his way to overnight star.
What does that mean, "hot dogging"?
Hot dogging, that's like--
When a white player tries
to play like a black player.
Yeah.
Jerry, shoot it!
Oh, God.
Now that's a foul.
That's a foul.
You okay?
Oh, no.
Walk it off.
Come on, Jerry.
Easy, easy.
All right!
Okay, gentlemen, line up.
We got two shots.
Two shots.
That scared me.
Get it down.
Hey, that's my boy!
Hey, you know what?
Kind of reminds me of what
it must be like to watch me.
I'm serious.
Hey. Thanks, Alvin.
Hey, man.
It's all right.
Skin that!
All right!
Yeah!
Wasn't he terrific?
Yes, he was.
- lncredible.
- Let's see, where are my keys?
Here we go.
You got your keys, Louise?
Louise has got her keys.
Yes, I have them.
Look at that fire.
It's incredible.
You know, I think I like basketball now.
I really liked those guys
in those little shorts.
Alvin says Jerry could go
all the way if he wants.
You know, I think he could, too.
Yoo-hoo, anybody in here?
You know, he looks different.
Yes, he did look different.
He looked very good.
- He looks like a gazelle--
- He did look rather gazelle-like.
- You little spider monkey, you.
- He looked like a gazelle.
Oh, no.
Hey, watch the oranges.
- This is the greatest night of my life.
- It was really fun.
I think I had a pretty good time,
too, you know?
Thank you. It was great.
I had a great time.
Excellent.
Louise?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Could you just go away?
I'm going.
Louise...
Come on, we've got to talk.
There's nothing to talk about.
Bullshit.
I know what it is.
It's because I am the way I am.
That's it, isn't it?
- Roary, please don't.
- It's all right.
I'm not going to mope around
wounded for the rest of my life.
I love you as a friend.
I got carried away.
So we won't be lovers.
Big deal.
I'm sorry.
When I kissed you,
it's because, you know, I'm--
I'm happy about Jerry,
and all he's doing,
and the kissing, the rest of it
was stupid.
It's not like I lie awake, horny for you.
I don't.
It was just a moment.
A big moment.
No big deal.
Are we still going to have a cup of coffee?
But, of course.
Come on in.
Pick up the oranges.
Yeah.
All right.
All of them.
I want them up...
- I got them.
- and in the kitchen.
I'll clean everything up.
I got it all.
I'll clean it all up.
Oh, boy.
Wow.
All these oranges.
Do you know how many
oranges we bought here?
I love you.
What?
I said, "l love you."
Oh, good.
I love you, too.
Let's be friends
and forget all that other crap.
All that other stuff.
Wait. I don't think
you really understand.
See, I do...
want to be your lover.
And there's nothing
that I would like better,
do you know, than to be your lover.
It's...
You're afraid.
I think so. Yeah.
Of what it would be like with a cripple.
Yeah. Yeah. And...
I'm-- I know it's all inside my head.
Do you know?
And it doesn't make any sense to me.
And I hate that part of me.
But if we did try, do you know, and it--
and, I mean, let's say
that it didn't work out--
I couldn't forgive myself.
I couldn't.
And I couldn't hurt you that way.
You're right.
It would hurt.
So let's not push for anything.
Let's just be friends, okay?
Thank you.
Thanks so much.
Now, Jerry scored 426 points
in 1 5 games.
1 5 in the 426th
gives me 28.4 points average per game.
- Please.
- Huh?
Huh?
Does that sound right to you?
Sounds right to me.
That's absolutely right.
Does what sound right to me?
28.4.
No, it doesn't sound right to me.
What do you mean?
I got it right here, Stink,
in black and white.
In black and white?
Black and white.
Yes, I got it right here
in black and white.
The National Hockey League
has announced it plans to crack down
on the violence
that's been plaguing the game.
Hey, I thought that Jerry's going to be
on the Gil Stratton show.
Relax, relax, Blue.
If Jerry told Roary he's going to be on,
he's going to be on.
That the right station, Max?
That's Gil Stratton.
That's what they said.
Hey, Max, make it
a little clearer, will you?
Damn you, Stinky.
In the NBA, the Warriors announced
the signing of Jerry Maxwell
to the club today.
Hey.
Jerry looks good in that.
--where during his short
but dazzling career,
he was averaging 26 points a game.
28 points, you dodo!
Listen to Blue Lewis.
28 points.
Hey, Max, drinks on the house.
In addition to everything else,
there was a lot of damaged
cartilage in my knee,
which had to be removed,
which means they had to replace it.
I don't think I've heard of that.
Well, it's a pretty new operation.
Anyways, there was this guy there
who had to get a nose job,
you know, get it reduced.
Well, they took the cartilage
from his nose...
- From his nose.
- and it ended up in my knee.
In his knee.
There's even nose donors.
That's right. People who want
to make extra money.
Make bucks on the side.
That's great.
She got it right away.
Oh, no.
I got to admit, he had me going.
I'm thinking, "Hell, that's a great idea."
Oh, boy.
Roary, you are beautiful.
Can I help you with that?
- No, thanks.
- Is there anything else?
Louise?
No, thanks.
- Roary?
- I'm all right.
- Well, I hope you've had a nice dinner.
- Roary.
No, Roary.
Wine in my water?
She's cute.
She is cute.
I can't get over how beautiful Louise is.
Well, thank you.
Told you, didn't l?
Yeah.
Why don't you come by Max's
and see the guys?
I mean, you know, they love you.
It hurts them.
You're never around,
- you never come by--
- I will, Roary.
Just not now.
- Just come by Max's.
- I said I will.
- To Max's.
All right, to Max's.
And to your nose.
Okay. Strong fingers.
- Get a good head massage.
- I love it.
Boy, I'm cold.
Okay.
Wait.
There.
Thanks.
Well, you're welcome.
It's cold.
Why don't you go
dry your hair on the porch?
- Okay.
- So it'll bring out all the little
golden highlights in your hair.
Come on out.
Yeah, I'll be out in just a minute.
I wish I was a fish
I wish
- Floating in your bathtub
- Oh, wow.
It's great out here.
Yes, you are getting
blonder as we speak.
Swimming 'round your drain
I've been meaning to tell you,
you look very good.
- You have been looking very good lately.
- Yeah?
Oh, my God.
Roary, you shaved your beard off.
You finally shaved it off.
- No handle.
- God, look at you.
God, you have a mouth now.
Does it look okay?
It's beautiful.
I feel good, too.
I think my moves are getting better.
Watch this. I'm going to make a sharp turn.
You tell me if it's
precise enough, all right?
Okay.
Dashing figure.
See that?
It's very good.
Wow.
Is there a need
for that particular move?
- Maybe.
- Yeah?
I might have to defend you someday.
By turning left.
Yeah.
You want to go to a movie
this afternoon?
Well, I can't.
I got other plans later.
Okay.
Roary...
I have been seeing Jerry.
Since when?
A couple of weeks.
Since the night at the restaurant.
Wasn't I supposed to know?
Jerry thought it would be better,
you know, for the time being
if we just didn't say anything.
Jerry said that?
I got to go.
Thank you.
Shampoo and everything.
Roary.
Hey, come on.
It's not like there's some
wild love affair going on.
Roary, please.
- See you guys later.
- You got some speed there.
Hey.
Jerry.
Roary.
Hey.
Great news.
Tomorrow night's the night.
I play pro-ball.
Yeah.
Well, I don't think tomorrow night's
a good night for me, Jerry.
I don't think I can get
a mascot uniform in time.
What?
A mascot uniform.
You know, for your dog.
I'm your best friend, aren't l, Jerry?
Isn't a man's best friend his dog?
Isn't that what I am?
Hey.
What's going on?
I'm your dog, Jer.
You know, your little companion,
trails along,
follows you wherever you go.
Your dog?
Is this a joke?
Come on, Roary, what the hell
are you talking about?
I'm talking about friendship, Jerry.
Of course, you're not
too good at that, are you?
Only when it's good for you.
But you know what you are?
You know what you are, Jer?
You're a thankless shithead.
And I had it over my head,
and I'm choking on all the shit
you dumped on me.
And no more. No more.
Look, Roary, if you're
talking about Louise--
I'm not talking about Louise.
Don't mention her name.
You don't talk.
You-- I'm feeling good.
I'm mad.
You know? I think I maybe
should be grateful
for all the shit you dumped on me
because all my life,
I felt like I was dumped on.
This is the first time
I feel like I'm fighting back.
The first time I feel like
I'm doing something right, Jer.
Thank you, Jerry Maxwell!
Thank you!
You want to hear something funny?
I couldn't even kill myself.
What a joke.
I jump off the tenth floor of a building,
and I can't even die.
A joke suicide, like a cartoon.
I fell on a fucking Pontiac,
for Christ's sake.
Roary, please, I never knew--
No, you stay where you are.
You stay where you are.
You know, you never even asked me
why I tried to kill myself, Jer.
Nobody. Nobody asked me why.
Well, I'm going to tell you.
Nothing like...
the girl I loved being
stolen by my best friend.
Nothing that romantic.
Nothing that dramatic, Jerry.
It was just because of nothing.
I just felt like nothing.
You wouldn't understand that,
would you, Jer?
You've always had people like me
to tell you you were something.
But I'm not nothing, Jerry.
I'm something.
I'm big, Jer.
I'm big.
Bigger than you.
But that's not hard to be.
That's not hard to be.
That's not hard to be, Jer.
Hey, about the guys,
you don't have to come by
Max's anymore, Jerry.
We don't need your kind of cripple there.
Have a good game, Jer.
Have a good game.
My heiny!
It's open.
Hi.
Hello.
Well...
it kind of looks like we both done it.
What?
I saw Jerry tonight.
So?
I didn't know you'd seen him this afternoon.
I didn't figure you had to know.
I wish I had known.
I told him I wasn't
going to see him anymore.
- You did?
- Yeah.
I don't think he had too good of a day.
So?
And I told him I was in love with you.
- You said that?
- Yes.
I told him that you and I were lovers.
We're gonna be, aren't we?
Roary! Roary.
I mean, I went over there
and I told Jerry that l--
Have you heard anything
that I've been saying?
It was something that was...
Roary!
Roary, listen!
I want you.
Roary, hold me.
Well, you gonna play or what?
I want to tell you guys
why I never came back here.
I didn't come back here...
because I was afraid
something was gonna rub off on me.
Come on, Jerry.
Wings, I was afraid...
that I would be...
a cripple again or something.
But Roary, he told me I'm still a cripple.
He's right.
In fact, I am the only
real cripple in this room.
Did you know that Alvin
was looking for you?
That's too bad.
I really feel badly about that.
But I'm not playing tonight.
You wanna know why?
Because I forgot
something very important.
I can't do anything alone.
I'm afraid to be alone.
That's a good one, huh?
The great Jerry Maxwell.
I was so into what I wanted
that I lost everyone I loved along the way.
Blue, let's break out your book.
I'm giving 3 to 1 odds
that Maxwell plays tonight.
You lose, Stinky.
Hey, you got any tickets
for tonight's game?
Why?
Because you're not gonna
fuck around with our dream.
Your dream?
Yeah.
You've taken an awful lot
from everyone here, Jerry.
Don't take any more.
This is our dream, too.
Jerry, if you blow this,
we've all been robbed.
Don't blow it.
Don't blow it, Jerry.
Yeah.
Blue's got 38 points on you.
He's gonna lose his shirt.
Hey.
Jerry!
Hey! Jerry!
Look at you. You shaved.
Hey, guess what? Jerry's on!
This afternoon,
before Warrior practice,
we caught up with the newest
member of the ball club,
- rookie Jerry Maxwell.
- Yay, Jerry!
Can I say something
before you ask me anything?
Sure, go ahead.
I would like to say "Hi"
to all the guys at Max's.
- Especially Roary.
- Roary.
This is a basketball, you got that?
Hey, Alvin, lighten up.
Listen, seriously, look over here.
- I bet he's nervous.
- Yeah, he is.
How does it feel to come out
of semi-pros right to the NBA?
I feel super.
I dreamt about this all my life.
Dreams! Dreams!
- Hey, Roary! Roary!
- Yo.
Tell Jerry when he comes back
to bring the rest of the team with him.
Drinks on the house.
Is that all right with you?
Hey, I think that's terrific.
You have a good time.
Tell Jerry we love him, huh?
- Hey, Max? Max?
- What?
Can I go to the game?
Come on.
I ain't paying you to go
to no damn basketball game.
Aw, come on.
Have a heart.
My buddy Burt'll cover for me,
won't you, Burt?
"My buddy, Burt'll--"
I wanna go to the game, too!
I want to go to the game, too.
What do you want me to do? Lock up?
- Yeah!
- I ain't been closed in 25 years
and I ain't closing to go
to no damn basketball game.
Hold the bus! Hold the bus!
Max's is closed
for the first time in 25 years.
Burt didn't want to go,
but I talked him into it.
I said Jerry needed us.
Jerry'll be surprised.
We're partners in the bar, not my girl.
Did you lock up?
I don't know. Did you?
I thought you did.
I'll do it. It's all right.
Stay here.
Don't anybody leave without me.
Got a light?
Hey.
Hey, want some company?
Anne. Do you remember me?
I'm Roary, from Max's.
Roary.
Roary!
Shit.
I know you.
I didn't recognize you.
You look great.
What did you do?
You did something.
What's different?
You lost weight or something like that?
You look great.
All right, well,
I could do something for you.
No.
What? You gay or something like that?
No. I've got a girlfriend.
Okay, then.
Roary!
You do me a favor?
You lend me 50 bucks?
For junk?
For old times' sake.
25, Roary?
Please?
For old times' sake?
Don't you want to know about Jerry?
You think I don't know about Jerry?
I don't know. Do you?
Well, of course I do.
That-- That gimp!
He's gonna limp around
that fucking freak house
for the rest of his life
'cause he's nothing.
And you're a sucker.
And I'm a whore.
That's the way it is.
Oh, God! My behind has gotten--
Come on, boy!
Hey, don't let him leave without me!
Hey, hey, Roary, come on!
Sir, could you wait
just one second, please?
- Come on!
- I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
Will you move your bun, boy?
Get over here!
What are you--
What are you doin'?
- Roary, move your ass!
- All right!
Move 'em out!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Golden State Warriors!
And introducing the newest Warrior,
Jerry Maxwell!
There he is!
Jerry!
Holy shit!
What happened?
Three guys fell down the stairs.
- Sir, are you okay?
- You all right?
Sir? Sir, you okay?
I broke my arm.
- It's Lucius.
- Lucius!
Who? Who?
Roary!
What did you do?
- You got him!
- Way to go!
Roary, I love you, baby,
but I'm movin' to L.A.
Sir, you all right?
Lucius.
Hey!
Jerry!
Hey! Roary!