- Very good, Mr. Hermil
- Thank you.
- Your carriage is here, sir.
- We'll continue tomorrow...
I'm sorry.
- It's late. I must go.
- All right. Until tomorrow.
Goodbye.
You were saying?
It's a myth that
English men are cold.
Isn't La Sperati singing?
- No, next Tuesday.
- Pity, I won't be here.
- They say she's admirable.
- As a singer or a woman?
I know nothing about opera.
If our Princess knew
how few of guests
come for the music.
She knows full well.
It's her way of inflicting
penance for our sins.
You come hereto court
Countess Teresa Raffo,
you get 1 Mozart, 2 Schuberts
and 4 Liszts as penance.
- Pity you're so late.
- It's my fault, Princess...
entirely mine.
I have no doubt.
You've missed a Mozart
and a beautiful Liszt.
- I'm sorry.
- Come and sit with me.
Thank you, Princess.
I'm afraid I can't stay
to the end.
It's a pity you're leaving
so soon.
She is an extraordinary
pianist.
Yes, I think so too.
Goodbye.
Where are you going?
I won't stay if she's here.
- I didn't know you'd come.
- Yes, I know.
Goodbye.
Enjoy yourselves.
- Teresa... please.
- Will you leave with me?
You know I can't.
Either you leave
with me now
or you'll never see me again,
I mean that.
My dear Tullio,
you can't let our most
beautiful guest leave.
It doesn't depend on me,
Prince.
But my evening
has just begun.
Tell Count Egano
I'm waiting for him.
Never mind, here he is.
Dear Stefano.
Shall we go?
Let's go in before that
fanatic starts another piece.
My wife takes offense
if I'm not in the room.
After all, it takes
so little to please her.
- I'll come for you later.
- What?
No, I'll send the carriage.
I won't be back.
I'm not feeling well.
- I'll come with you.
- Don't complicate matters.
Come in.
As you can see,
I know you quite well.
I was sure you'd come.
Before going out again
I chose to wait for you
rather that risk
finding you here
when I got back.
Give me back my keys.
Be reasonable.
I couldn't leave with you.
For once my wife asked
me to accompany her.
Why didn't you tell me
you'd be there?
I went because
I knew you'd be there.
It's time we faced this situation.
Don't you agree?
For months you've skilfully
succeeded, like a conjurer,
in preventing me from
seeing how things really are.
- So I took the initiative.
- Initiative?
Seeing what?
That I'm married?
You've always known that.
- Of course.
- So?
From what you say,
your rapport with your wife
is only a formal one.
- Precisely.
- That's not true.
And it's obvious
when you're together.
You're like all
the bourgeois husbands
of this world, my dear.
They swear to their lovers
they've rejected their wives
and do the same
with their wives.
I won't accept
such pettiness.
You know I'm a free,
liberated woman
and not only in word,
like you.
You're jealous of her.
I won't share a man
with another woman.
Not even with his wife.
You're not sharing me
and you know that.
All I think of is you.
You're always inside me.
I feel your presence
constantly. It's persistent...
even hostile.
I'm going outwith Egano.
Run along to your wife.
Leave me.
I won't leave you.
You're staying with me.
You're still awake?
You said you weren't
feeling well, so...
how silly of me...
I became anxious.
I waited by the window
for your return.
You know what I was doing?
Writing to you.
But since you're here...
I'm going to Florence.
I don't know for how long.
This time it's serious.
I had to tell you.
You're leaving forever?
Well... forever...
What big words.
Listen, Giuliana,
even though...
even though I've never
spoken to you about it,
I'm sure that
at some stage,
some compassionate soul
must have informed
you of my infidelities.
I didn't tell you myself
because they were
insignificant affairs,
and because of our pact,
from the time
you agreed to marry me.
Love is there while it lasts
then it's replaced by respect,
affection, friendship,
common interests...
if all that is possible,
of course.
But I must assume
that it's our case,
since you've accepted,
without reacting,
the situation between us
for quite some time.
As you said, they were
insignificant affairs.
That's why I tried
to ignore them.
Marriage...
Yes, our marriage was to
be defended at all costs...
even from our own
resentment. Correct?
And you were right.
You're been wonderful.
Because, even if
my love for you...
has waned,
as inevitably happens,
my affection and respect
have but increased.
I'm fond of you
and respect you...
like a beloved sister
without whom I could
no longer live.
I'd suffer greatly
but naturally you'd have
every right to leave me.
Will you stay with me
and help me?
H ow?
By Putting up with me.
By facing a situation
which, by society's standards.
Would certainly
be criticized.
- The woman I love...
- Teresa Raffo?
- Yes, Teresa.
- She's a widow, she's free.
What prevents you
going to her?
I didn't mention
marrying her.
She's a beautiful
sensual woman.
I desire her.
No woman has ever
possessed me
as she has.
What is this? I arrive
and they're leaving?
Anyone home?
Federico.
You're all leaving when
I have 3 day's furlough?
No, only me.
Where are you going?
- How long do you have?
- Three days.
Actually, three and a half.
Listen... I'm up to my neck
in problems,
or good fortune,
if you like.
I'm leaving Giuliana
by herself...
not that I want to impose,
but I'll feel better
knowing you're with her.
Wait. I'd like to spend
my three days in Rome,
not with my sister-in-law.
- She's adorable, but...
- No, do as you please.
I only need to know
you're around.
I mean,
if before going out,
you tell her your plans
for the evening,
Giuliana will be happy.
This is a very delicate
time for her.
Does anyone else live here?
The house looks so big.
Or she'll be
so disappointed.
I promised to show her
one of Rome's finest homes...
It is beautiful, but...
No, it's not.
This villa was built for my mother.
She wanted lots of
greenery even in the city.
My father did his best
to please her
but when he died,
she returned to the country
where it's much greener.
Then my brother married
and came to live here.
I kept these rooms
to be more independent.
- So it's not the main part.
- Yes, it is. I assure you.
Federico.
What's wrong?
What's wrong with you?
Giuliana!
That's it. Help me.
- Call the governess.
- Right away, sir.
She hasn't fainted.
She's taken something.
Are you alone in the house?
No. They've gone to bed.
I was too...
Forgive me.
I was depressed and took
something to help me sleep.
Instead of relaxing
I've become terribly anxious.
Terribly afraid.
I didn't want to be alone.
I'm here.
How are you feeling?
It's nothing.
Such a silly thing.
- Do you feel better now?
- Yes.
I'm sorry to inconvenience you.
Lie down a bit longer.
This is Filippo d'Arborio,
the writer.
See what important
friends I have?
Ulderico Guinigi
and Miss Elviretta.
My sister-in-law, Giuliana.
- Hello.
- My apologies.
I've ruined your dinner.
Do continue.
You mustn't be alone
tonight.
Come on.
Tell us when you're ready
for bed.
Or go to sleep here
lulled by our voices.
- When we were boarders...
- Which school?
I was poor.
My parents couldn't afford
my studies.
I paid my way by tutoring
the younger pupils.
Federico was one of them.
And I always fell asleep.
That's right.
As soon as I started
talking, he'd doze off.
He says the tone of my voice
was to blame.
I would be very pleased
if you
managed to sleep, too.
Breakfast is sewed.
What a beautiful scent.
Are they tuberoses?
At this time of year!
How did you find them?
You're so sweet.
"I await you.
Stefano Egano. "
The idiot. How dare he?
You shouldn't read
other people's letters.
You really are silly.
If I've slighted anyone,
it's him, not you.
I promised Egano
I'd watch his horse's race.
But I'm here with you.
What are you complaining
about?
I was hoping to see you
at the races yesterday.
My horses distinguished
themselves.
There are too many people.
I'm afraid of crowds.
They're racing in
the steeplechase tomorrow.
I can get you seats
at the finishing line.
I'm afraid I can't go.
In case you change
your mind...
I assure you
the countess won't.
- I'd like her to tell me.
- I'm telling you.
If you change your mind...
I'm at your disposal.
Very well.
Egano's friend say
he's left for Rome
and so has she, apparently.
She's broken off with Tullio.
You did well to come.
Let the tongues wag.
Don't let them pity you.
Never accept the role
of the poor abandoned wife.
You're hereto disprove that.
I didn't want you here
because Teresa's coming.
My train was late.
While I dueled with that
fool in Florence, she left.
I must see her again.
She's treacherous,
elusive and a liar.
The moment you think
she's all yours,
she escapes you.
She's already pursuing
other desires.
I must find the strength
to break off with her.
- And you must help me.
- What can I do?
I don't know. Many things.
Convince me
not to see her again.
No one can convince you...
least of all me.
That's not true.
You see, the most
dangerous thing for me
is that my frustration
makes me feel so unhappy
but at the same time
I feel alive, vital...
It's the first time
I'm in such a situation.
One does sell one's soul
in exchange for youth
and one is defenseless
in love.
You talk as if
I'd never existed.
You're right,
I'm being unfair.
I'm sorry.
Be patient with me.
As you would with
a sick person.
Someone who indulges
in his illness.
- Was that you singing?
- Yes.
You're going out?
- Where are you going?
- To Di Castro's auction.
I can't pin my veil.
Will you help me please?
You have a new perfume.
What is it?
Crab-apple.
It's an English perfume.
"The Flame".
“To Giuliana Hermil,
Turns Eburnea,
"I humbly dedicate...
Filippo D'Arborio. "
- Aren't you going out?
- You know D'Arborio?
- When did you meet him?
- When your brother was here.
- Have you read it?
- Yes.
I skimmed through it
at the Club.
A mediocre writer,
don't you agree?
No.
His style is so pompous,
so emphatic.
It's quite unbearable.
How can you say that?
His style is extraordinary.
It's like music.
You can't judge
a man like him
by just skimming through
his book.
You take it to heart.
He may be a great writer
but he's ill-mannered.
You must give me that.
The dedication he wrote you
is not only stilted
but also uncalled for,
if one considers
it's addressed to a
lady he only met ones.
I saw him again
after our first meeting.
Are you taking the carriage?
No, I'd rather walk.
I'll see you later.
Now as you've all seen
4500 lire. Congratulations,
Countess Raffo.
Thank you.
Now there's a fabulous
dove-shaped brooch
in diamonds and rubies,
valued at 5 or 6000.
But I'll start at 1000.
Things are warming up.
Good evening, Mr. Hermil.
- Good evening, Madam.
- Good evening, Emilio.
- Is Mr Tullio in?
- No, Madame, he went out.
Tell the kitchen I've eaten.
Good night.
I've spent endless nights
outside here
looking up
at your windows.
I know.
I saw you once.
And you didn't call me?
Why are you so cruel
to me?
You're one of those men
who make women suffer.
You're selfish.
Proud.
Despotic.
The domineering lover.
If you knew how hard
it's been
to resist calling you,
but I succeeded.
And you had to come
looking for me today.
But I didn't come
looking for you today.
I went there by chance.
- That's not true.
- It is. I swear.
I hadn't left the house
for days on end.
My wife said she was
going to the auction, so...
Your wife was there?
No, she wasn't.
I assure you.
I had nothing to do either,
and I got there early.
And I'm usually late
wherever I go.
I saw every single person
who walked in.
Oh God, I'm ruined.
So your wife lies to you.
She deceives you.
Maybe she has a lover.
I'm sorry. I'm only joking.
I only saw those
who were already there.
I didn't see the people
who arrived later.
I didn't even see you.
- Good evening, sir.
- Is my wife back?
Yes, an hour ago
but then she left again.
She went to catch
the 8.30 p. m. train.
She said she was going
to visit your mother.
I think she left you
a note in the study.
I'll be with you shortly.
You're the only punctual
man in Rome.
This is Mr Filippo d'Arborio.
I'm Tullio Hermil.
- An academic match?
- With pleasure.
Tell me if I've done well.
Who do you want next to you
at dinner?
On your right the Princess
of Fondi. And on your left?
It's up to you.
- Do you like that book?
- No.
I do, very much.
I also like the author.
I invited him tonight
but he's not at Rome.
D'Arborio?
He'll get in touch
as soon as he gets back.
I'll organize another dinner.
I'd like you to meet him.
- I've met him, thank you.
- What's wrong with you?
- Are you in a bad mood?
- Not at all.
Then will you approve
my seating arrangements?
Remember we must give
the Dampierres
an answer tonight.
Shall we go to Paris
or not?
You're the one
who's been invited.
I'll go if you come too.
What else
do you want to do?
D'Arborio's dinner, trips...
You're a bachelor again,
and I'm taking advantage
of it.
I'm sitting here.
The Ambassador on my right,
and I've put Dampierre
on my left.
All right?
Yes, it's all right.
Dampierre is next to me
so I can tell him we'll
be going to Paris next week.
All right.
Thank you.
- How are you, Giuseppe?
- Well, thank you.
Tullio! My dear Tullio.
Mama, how are you?
You're all alike.
You tum up unexpectedly.
- Giuliana?
- She was expecting you.
- Elvira, where's Madam?
- In the garden.
Go and tell her
Mr Tullio is here.
What does Giuliana
usually do?
She has some friends, so...
Friends?
Yes, friends from Rome
staying with the Torrigianis.
Giuliana says
they're very nice.
At least she occupies
her time.
You see, I never go out.
I told her invite
whoever she likes
but she'd rather go out.
It'll be a nice surprise
for her to see you here.
Here's Giuliana.
- You look very well.
- We weren't expecting you.
To be honest, I wasn't
planning on coming.
I was at station
with a ticket to Paris
then I saw a train for here
and changed my plans.
I knew Tullio was crazy
but not to this extent.
Wait.
Do you mind if we occupy
a room in the left wing too?
Tullio reads at night
and I wake up very early
so we'd rather have
separate rooms.
As you wish.
There are plenty of rooms.
Go to the other wing.
- Would you like some?
- No, thank you.
- Been to Villa Lilla?
- No, I haven't.
- Why is that?
- I haven't been there.
We should discuss
Villa Lilla.
There's an Englishman,
an ex-diplomat,
who'd like to buy it.
I'm told I could get
an excellent price.
I'm against selling,
but we could rent it.
With all the money spent
to renovate it
when, as newlyweds,
you said you'd spend
six months a year there.
I never believed you.
If we rent it we could
pay for its upkeep,
if nothing else.
Uninhabited houses suffer
and deteriorate
before their time.
Well, think it over.
It's not for the money.
To me, that will always be
your home.
Mother is right.
We should at least
go and see it.
If you're free tomorrow
shall we go to Villa Lilla?
Welcome, Mr Tullio.
My respects, Madam.
Hello, Callisto.
Water the horse
and feed him.
I've been airing the house
for two weeks.
I knew you were at
the Badiola.
I've been waiting
or the weather to improve.
Very good, sir.
You should listen to
your mother and rent it.
Yes.
It would be most
reasonable thing to do.
The English diplomat
would look after it well.
But the idea upsets me.
Doesn't it you?
You seem just as
hesitant and fearful
as when we came here
for the first time.
There were the same flowers.
The same perfume.
That's right, it was
the same season.
Let's try to be
two new people
who meet here
for the first time.
It's up to us to try.
If we don't succeed,
we'll sink back into
unhappiness and misery.
That's not possible.
Don't torment me.
Why not?
You've been my wife,
my sister,
But you've never been
my mistress.
It's different, you know.
Very different.
Without embarrassment,
with no false modesty,
without holding back.
Love is that too.
Especially that.
And I've never
taught you.
It's been my fault.
I was wrong.
Tell me you want
to make love with me.
Tell me you want to.
Ask me.
Ask me, my love.
I was getting worried.
I wanted to send someone.
- How are you?
- Well.
- Shall I accompany you?
- No, thank you.
Giuliana wasn't very well.
I wanted to sleep at
Villa Lilla but she didn't.
- What was wrong with her?
- Nothing serious.
Perhaps she caught cold.
You're so right. It's a shame
to leave Villa Lilla empty.
But no English diplomats.
We'll go and live there,
at least a few months
of the year.
Yes, I know you don't
believe me, but you'll see.
The smell of the lilacs...
Maybe that's why
Giuliana took ill.
It was such a heavy
perfume.
I'll tell her to stay in bed.
It would be wiser.
And I'll call the doctor.
I wanted to last week
but Giuliana refused.
Tell Giuseppe to get the gig
and go to Dr Milani.
I'd be most grateful
if he came tonight.
Calm down,
Giuliana is better now.
It was nothing serious.
There's no need to worry.
She forbade me to tell you
until she was sure
but, as there's no doubt now,
I'll tell you,
so you won't be
as silly as you were today
by taking her out
in the gig.
Giuliana is pregnant.
- Pregnant?
- Yes.
- Did she tell you?
- No, but I know.
She's had quite a few
turns like today's.
Nausea, dizzy spells...
you know.
So I asked her and she
said she hoped she was.
But she wanted to be sure
before telling you
so as not to disappoint
you, of course.
I've begged her
to see the doctor
because she won't listen
to my advice.
She should be in her
third month.
But don't betray me.
Wait for her to tell you.
She made me promise.
I'm so happy.
You've made me wait
so long for this moment.
Now she must be careful.
The first months are the
most dangerous for her.
She's so frail,
our dear, dear child.
Good night, Mama.
I'm going upstairs so if
she wakes up I'll hear her.
You'll wait for the doctor?
If Giuseppe had found him
he'd be here by now.
- If you need anything...
- No, thank you. Good night.
Tullio.
Don't leave.
I'm afraid of being alone.
What have you taken?
A sleeping draught?
Tullio.
Did you sleep here?
What happened?
You said not to
leave you alone.
I did? When?
Don't you remember?
I took a sleeping draught
last night.
Maybe I took more
than usual.
You take sleeping droughts?
Does the doctor know?
Yes.
Show me what you take.
I can't remember
where I put it.
Wait.
I think...
I must have finished it,
and thrown out the bottle.
Is what my mother
told me true?
That you're pregnant?
Yes, it's true.
I wanted to tell you.
I tried to yesterday.
- Is that why you left Rome?
- Yes.
- But I didn't know then.
- And he followed you.
Followed me? Who?
It was all over
before I came here.
Before I knew I was...
like this.
I had found the strength
to overcome my confusion.
I was very lonely.
Very sad.
I'm not justifying myself
or accusing you.
I'm in despair.
In despair.
But I come last.
What about you?
The same right applied
to you as to me.
We were two friends.
Two free people.
- You could too.
- I wasn't to claim a right.
I never felt I had one.
I swore before God
to be your wife forever.
It was different for you.
But I...
There's one thing
I want to know.
The only really
important thing.
I'm no longer interested
in our past live together.
But I've changed a lot
in these last few days.
And yesterday...
no, let me finish.
Yesterday I found you again.
And I believed you'd like
to start from scratch.
For a moment I left
that all I'd been through
was nothing but
a dream, a nightmare.
We were there, you and I,
just like after our marriage.
Are you being sincere?
No one must suspect
anything.
Why? Do you want me
to stay with you?
Yes.
Seeing you're awake...
I've signed up for
the championship.
I need some lessons so I
won't discredit the family.
- Coming down?
- I'll join you shortly.
- Hello, Giuliana.
- Hello, Federico.
Touche. Bravo.
You should sign up
instead of me.
Now I'll try harder.
Watch out.
Careful, boys.
Don't hurt yourselves.
Stop it.
Are you crazy?
We're off the board.
I want a return match.
- Not now. I'm tired.
- That's enough, boys.
The doctor is here.
You'd better see him.
Everything's all right,
but he wants Giuliana to
stay in bed for a few days.
Anyway, he'll tell you.
Go up.
No, I'm sweaty.
I want to change.
I'd keep him waiting.
Apologize for me.
It's no use pretending
I don't know anything.
As you can imagine.
Mama told me right away.
I'm really pleased.
That way she'll stop
nagging me to marry.
The heir is guaranteed.
Congratulations.
May I congratulate
Giuliana too?
No, leave it for now.
Mama should've kept quite.
Giuliana isn't well.
- She may lose the child.
- But the doctor said...
Even last time
Giuliana fell pregnant
the doctor said all was well
but it wasn't.
If you left now against
the doctor's orders.
Mama would be so upset.
So you'd better stay
a few more days.
I'll go to Rome to make
arrangements with Dr Magli.
I'll have to give him
some details.
How many months are you?
I finished my second one
a few days ago.
I don't think there's any
danger at this stage...
if one takes
the necessary precautions.
I don't understand.
You're not thinking of
keeping it, are you?
Last time you lost it
through natural causes
and that will help cover up
for this one.
I'm referring to the family
who know you're pregnant.
I know what to say
to Dr Magli.
But I can't.
- What can't you?
- I can't.
Why not? Are you afraid
or don't you want to?
I can't because it's a crime.
A crime.
How could you think I'd...
But you're quite happy
to give my name
and my family's affection
to a stranger.
Isn't that a crime?
Why won't you answer me?
I said I want to help you.
I love you and bear no grudge
for what you've done.
I'm very grateful to you,
but...
But what?
You said it's all over.
That you want to
put it behind you.
So it's not true.
Because if it were so,
how could you and I...
Yes, I admit it's impossible.
I must leave you.
It's over between us.
Listen, Giuliana,
the real crime is the one
you want to commit.
First you torment yourself
with remorse
but then you absolve
yourself from that sin
and torment yourself
about the consequences
and this time the absolution
is a life sentence...
not only for you.
Can't you see how absurd
your behavior is?
I'm an atheist.
But that doesn't mean
I don't have moral problems.
On the contrary, I'm aware
of their consequences.
I don't delegate God to
decide what's right or wrong.
I assume
my responsibilities.
You see, I know that
my sins,
if I've committed any,
can't be redeemed
through repentance
or by punishing myself.
I'm a free man.
Earth is my only country.
I have no other destination.
My story begins
and ends here.
I don't have a hell to fear
or a heaven to hope for.
I believe we can only
count on ourselves.
What I'm proposing
isn't an easy way out.
My solution faces
the truth of existence.
It doesn't seek refuge
in faith
or in a god created
by our imagination
who, in another life,
grants rewards or penances.
If I could think like you,
have your self-assurance...
You could live your life
freely, to the full,
without fear.
Think it over carefully.
It's entirely up to you.
Anyway I'll go to Rome
to make the arrangements.
You'll join me as soon
as possible.
I need a favour.
That I meet your friend,
Filippo d'Arborio.
Do I have to come to Rome
for that?
Send him an invitation.
He'll be delighted to come.
We're good friends.
Besides, he'll rush here
to see Giuliana again.
He was smitten by her
when I introduced them.
I teased him so much.
I don't want to invite him.
It must be a chance meeting.
You invite him
and I'll just tum up.
It's a delicate matter.
I can't explain.
It's also my fault.
We didn't expect you
in this heat.
And since the house
needed a thorough cleaning,
and the carpets
were stained.
I thought...
Put the house in order.
My wife will be arriving
next week.
- Who's in the house?
- The cook, Virginia,
and Alfredo.
Any further orders, sir?
What is it?
Yes, I need someone
to deliver a letter.
I'll send for the coachman
or I can go myself,
if you like.
You may leave.
I'll call when I'm ready.
Well?
I'd have joined you,
as I said in my letter.
I never thought for one
moment you'd return.
You're contradicting yourself.
You knew I would.
Today you send you butler
to my home, not to Paris.
I hadn't heard from you,
so before leaving...
Did you expect me to believe
you'd join me in Paris?
You see? I did well
to come here.
Contrary to common belief.
I believe truth is never
said to one's face.
There are too many factors
which intervene in
our intimacy, so...
one usually ends up
not understanding anything.
Understanding what?
That you've got over it,
my dear.
Quickly, in fact.
Very quickly.
It's not pleasant
for a woman...
to be abandoned.
There are those
ready to pity her
and I don't like that.
There are those who
question her charm
and I don't like that either.
You send me a note
when I'm on the train
saying that serious
family matters...
Oh, come now,
not even a mere clerk
would resort to that.
I really believed
a catastrophe had occurred.
I wanted to go to Paris.
Yes, to have fun.
And when I got there
I didn't even unpack.
I came straight back,
thinking that, if you had
such serious problems,
you might want me
by you side.
My friends will surely laugh
when I tell them the story
of my fall.
What do you say?
Shall we still dine together?
As you wish.
No standing on ceremony.
Please, Teresa,
you're the only person
to whom I may tell my story
one day,
I hope this will be
our last day.
Good evening. Excuse me.
My brother Federico.
Countess Raffo.
Osvaldo said you were here.
I'm terribly upset about...
I mean, rather...
I looked into that matter
but couldn't find my friend.
I last saw him before
going to camp.
I didn't even know
he'd gone to Africa.
Why go to Africa, anyway?
Right now he's in hospital
in the isolation ward.
His condition is very serious.
A disease he caught there.
Perhaps, Countess, you know
this friend of mine, too.
- D'Arborio, the writer.
- I've met him.
I'm an admirer of his.
He's between
life and death.
The truth is they know
nothing about tropical diseases,
and they don't know
how to treat him.
Too much sad news tonight.
I'm sorry I'm the bearer
of some of it.
I'm truly sorry.
Drop in when you get home.
I'm staying out late.
- Never mind, I'll wait.
- Very well.
You know what?
I'm suffering less
than I thought.
One day I might listen
to what you have to say.
What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
- The door was open.
You told me to come
at any hour.
Yes, I wanted...
I wanted to know which
hospital d'Arborio is in.
The Policlinic, in isolation.
No one is allowed near him.
Now you must tell me
what you want from him.
When you asked to meet him,
I thought you suspected
something between him
and Teresa Raffo.
It's plausible, since
all the ladies in Rome
are in love with him.
Besides, your lovely Teresa,
no of fence meant, of course,
isn't the type to
deny herself a whim.
But no, I found out
they barely know each other.
You saw it yourself.
She didn't know he was ill.
So, what's all the mystery?
I can't tell you anything.
It's a matter which concerns...
a friend.
Well, I'm going to bed.
It's dawn.
Can you at least tell me
when d'Arborio
left for Africa?
I'll find out,
but tell your friend
to leave him in peace.
D'Arborio is ill.
Very ill.
He's a man
who warrants respect.
He's not only a great writer
but also an angel.
He's the only person
who makes me feel ashamed...
or almost.
Why?
If you think about it,
you might realize why.
We're so intelligent,
we're educated.
We've travelled,
we enjoy ourselves so much,
we're so rich...
and then?
- What's all this nonsense?
- I don't know. Good night.
When are we going to the Club?
You owe me a return match.
I don't know.
I don't know
what will happen tomorrow.
- It depends.
- Good night.
Good morning.
Madam send me
for her lighter clothes.
It's hot at the Badiola
now too.
Didn't she say she was
coming to Rome?
No, sir.
I'm sorry, I almost forgot.
W s from Madam.
I also have to do a few
things for your mother.
I hope I'll be able
to leave tonight.
If you have any orders...
No, I'll get there before you.
I can't do what you asked.
I'd rather leave.
Get out of your life.
I can't commit murder.
- I spoke to...
- Whom?
My confessor.
- Did he tell you to leave?
- No, but he agrees.
I hope my family will
give the child their name.
- Why not his father?
- No, he must never know.
Do you really mean that?
Do you realize what will
happen if you leave me?
It's not the scandal
I'm worried about.
But your situation
as a single mother
who, to save her child
deprives it of a father.
If I were convinced
your decision
stemmed only from your moral
and religious convictions,
if I felt you were mine
and mine alone,
I could stand anything.
Children belong to whoever
educates and raises them.
FILIPPO D'ARBORIO IS DEAD
Maria, did my wife call?
No, sir, but she asked me
to wake her at 9 o'clock.
Wait a moment.
You may go.
May I? Good morning, Madam.
It's 9 o'clock.
Come in.
Have you seen it?
I heard he was
seriously ill.
I told you, didn't I?
That's strange.
I could have sworn
I told you.
A tropical disease
he contracted in Africa.
Why won't you look at me?
Who are you thinking about?
Why torture yourself?
The doctor.
I'll show him in.
- Hello. Is the midwife here?
- Yes.
This way, doctor.
- Is the doctor here?
- I'm here.
- Come quickly.
- Excuse me, doctor.
I have something to tell you.
And I'll do so
in my mother's presence.
Last time you examined
my wife,
you said we may
be faced with a choice.
Let it be clear, and I
take full responsibility,
that, should this unfortunate
situation arise,
we want the mother saved.
I sincerely hope we won't
be faced with this choice.
But I'm grateful to you for
taking full responsibility.
As you know, Catholicism...
I know. It's an immoral
and criminal precept.
It doesn't concern me.
Let's go, doctor.
Mr Tullio.
Here's the young master.
He's already opened his eyes.
They're both safe and sound.
We made it.
Congratulations,
he's a beautiful baby.
- Everything went well, sir.
- You may go in now.
But no one else. She's going
through a brief crisis.
- She's well but very weak.
- It's nothing, sir.
Don't worry about it.
Yes, she's had a strange
psychological reaction.
She won't see the child.
She's crying.
Isn't he beautiful?
God bless him.
Raimondo.
Grandma's Raimondo.
Isn't he the world's
most beautiful baby?
Look at his eyes.
Don't cry in front of Uncle,
my treasure.
He's so good.
He just eats and sleeps.
Look at his hands.
He'll be tall.
- Isn't he gorgeous?
- Like all babies.
Foals are different.
You should see Zara's.
He's a splendid silvery gray.
But babies...
You're just baiting me.
What do you know about babies?
You were red and wrinkled
when you were born.
You weren't like him.
He's beautiful.
Instead of being silly,
tell Tullio his son
is a little ray of sunshine.
- Must I be the one?
- Yes.
Nurse, shut the windows.
It's cold today.
Are you scared I'll say
the foal is better?
Come now, Mama.
I'll tell them I've never
seen such beauty
and that I'll be proud
to be his godfather.
What's wrong?
You joke about it,
but I'm desperate.
Desperate.
- What are you saying?
- You've no idea!
I'm not upset with Giuliana.
Even the doctor said
it's a reaction to stress.
But your brother...
He's so strange.
Before he was worried for her,
and that's understandable,
but now that
all's gone well...
They never see the child.
As if he didn't exist.
They don't even mention him.
The only thing your brother
said to me is
if we want a baptism,
it must be private.
No reception. Nothing.
You had me scared
for a moment. Is that all?
Tullio isn't religious.
He has his own ideas.
We'll celebrate
some other time.
- Is that what upsets you?
- Yes, very much.
With everything else.
They keep to their room.
They're hostile.
But this is all good news.
We won't have
the bother of the party,
and Tullio and Giuliana
are so in love
they forget they have a son.
Perk up, all will go well
and Tullio will go to church
as he did for his wedding.
And Raimondo?
Are they calling him that?
You're crazy husband is
driving mother to distraction.
It would have been better if
you'd not come to the church.
I told Mama and the nurse
to have champagne with us
to calm her down.
It's champagne,
not holy water!
Come in.
Good! Come in.
Not here. In the other room.
Giuliana mustn't get tired.
You may go.
Let's go, Federico.
Do you really
not want us here?
Why don't you come?
The doctor said you can
move a bit.
It would do you good.
Come on, make an effort.
- Hurry up.
- For me.
I'll see you later.
Let's have a nice Christmas
to please Mama too.
Try to come up with something.
Don't count on me.
I'm leaving.
You're not staying for
Christmas? Mama said...
I'm sorry to disappoint her
but I've changed my mind.
I just can't do it.
I'm sorry but I don't like
the atmosphere here.
I love you all, but I
have my problems, too.
And I want to spend
my leave in peace.
I'll go and find some joy
elsewhere.
Has he eaten?
I hoped he'd be awake.
Will he be warm enough?
His little hands feel cold.
- Shall we put his mittens on?
- No, Madam, don't worry.
He's nice and warm.
Don't worry, he won't wake up.
Besides, babies like
hearing voices,
hearing they're not alone.
You go to bed too, Nurse.
Good night.
Good night, Madam.
I've been watching you
coddle him at night.
Why don't you tell the world
how much you love him?
Don't lie. Have the courage
to speak the truth.
I went in because
I thought someone called.
It's happened before.
As if something was wrong.
That's not true.
I've seen you sneak out
in the dark before.
What's wrong with that?
You do the same thing.
Nurse told me.
It's true.
But it's not the same thing.
By watching him, I try to discover your secret.
I try to force myself
to forget,
but I can't... I can't.
And I damn the day
I accepted this torture.
And you've changed.
You're happy now.
That's why I can't stop
looking at him.
And you don't care
that I'm suffering.
You love him.
And by loving him,
you're loving him father.
You know that's not true.
I even wanted him to die
when he was born.
It's awful, but it's true.
His presence
distresses me, too.
Yes, I hate him for
the pain he's causing you.
I can't see you like this.
Why won't you believe me?
I swear I hate him.
Is that how you feel?
Yes.
Because he's come
between us.
I would like you and I to...
Take me away. We'll be
happy far from here.
We'll leave after Christmas.
I promise.
Mama's waiting downstairs.
We're going to Mass.
Your cape, Madam.
No, you may go.
Won't you wear my present?
I think hot.
It's so extravagant.
Nonsense.
The peasants always like
to see their masters...
well-dressed.
The bell has rung twice.
We must hurry.
Very well.
You may go to Mass, Nurse.
I'll stay here.
Thank you, sir.
The baby is asleep anyway.
Good night, Mr Tullio
and Merry Christmas.
Good night.
- Have dinner sewed.
- Yes, Madam, right away.
Yet another Christmas
has gone by.
And we'll be leaving.
You promised...
After Christmas.
When are we leaving?
Whenever you like.
Tomorrow, if you like.
The baby isn't breathing!
Doctor, hurry!
He's not breathing.
He's stopped breathing, doctor.
Don't go in there.
Why not?
Stay with me. I'm afraid.
I'm so afraid.
Come with me.
Come.
Mr Hermil.
No, it can't be.
It can't be.
Dead?
Yes.
Get away. Don't touch me.
I'm not your accomplice.
Be quiet, Giuliana.
I beg you.
- You did it.
- Quiet. You knew all along.
It's your fault.
I hate you.
No, you've always said
you hated him.
No, I wanted to save him
from you.
- I did my utmost to save him.
- What are you saying?
Yes, everything I did
with you was to save him.
Only to save him.
And now, for the rest
of my days,
I will have to live with
this mark on my soul.
Help me, God.
May you be
as unhappy as I am.
You're lying to yourself.
You wanted him to die.
Not for one moment
did I want to get rid
of him.
Because I loved him,
my poor baby...
denied a thousand times.
You must know that
so you'll understand
that it's truly over.
I loved and always will
love that baby's father.
To the end of my days,
I can but hate you.
Hate you.
Despise you.
Women have the
extraordinary capacity
to adapt reality
to the romantic ideals
of the worst literature.
My wife's affair
with Filippo d'Arborio,
lasted but a fleeting moment.
Just like many
of your friends
who fell for the
fashionable scribe,
who had the misfortune
to contract a disease
which sent him back
to his maker.
That's all.
I'm only sorry
that I helped to contribute
to this appalling
second rate novel.
You don't really believe
you caused the death
of that innocent?
You see, it's strange,
but newborn babies have
an extraordinary resistance.
The cold didn't kill it.
So don't feel any remorse.
He must have died because...
No, that doesn't matter.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's the intention that counts.
And there are so no doubts
about my intentions.
I knew full well
what I was doing.
I feel no remorse
and I'm not justifying myself.
I'm not touched
by man's justice because...
no court on earth
could sit in judgment on me.
Have I bored you?
I'm sorry.
It's early. We can still
spend some time together.
That would give me
great pleasure.
I like your home.
I've tried to picture it
so many times...
but never succeeded.
It's strange, you know,
because it resembles you.
It really does.
- With all your beauty...
- And my ugliness.
What is there that's ugly?
Let's hear it.
Slow down. There's no rush.
I have to look carefully...
and think it over.
- Will you offer me a drink?
- Of course.
Well?
Have you decided?
What is there in me
that's ugly?
Now I'll tell you.
Let me drink first.
I shouldn't. I drank
so much at dinner.
But you've plunged me...
into such melancholy.
One step at a time.
You asked me before
what I thought
about what you told me.
Now I'll tell you.
I believe you're even more
in love with your wife.
So much in love
that you're pitiful.
That's not so, my love.
I admit that my experiences
with her, of late...
have been intoxicating.
But murky and morbid,
if you like.
Only the pure are capable
of such excess.
Think of the hair-shirts
worn by ascetics.
You're in love with her.
And for the first time
you feel defeated.
Your two rivals
cannot be vanquished
because they're dead.
Poor Tullio.
What nonsense
are you saying?
If there's a loser
in this mournful story,
it's my wife.
She, who has decided
to live
among the ghosts
of the graveyards,
instead of living
her life freely.
And who obstinately
refuses to believe
that our problems should
be solved here on earth
and not in a hypothetical
hereafter.
Whereas I'm here with myself
without illusions,
without regrets.
The day I no longer
had a taste for life...
felt no curiosity...
I would end it all.
Those are things one says.
But there comes a time
when one ceases to live
and begins merely to exist.
But we don't realize it
and if we are unfortunate
enough to do so,
our hopes tum to
eternal life.
That's not my case, I swear.
How do you know?
You're always so sure
of yourself.
But no one knows
what the future holds.
Not even you.
Less than a year ago
you spend your nights
beneath my windows
crazed with desire
and jealousy.
And I...
committed all kinds of follies
to smother my love for you.
I wonder why you men
raise us up with one hand
and drag us down
with the other.
Why won't you let us
walk by your side...
as one being
next to another?
Woman next to man.
Nothing more, nothing less.
Of course...
if I decided to live
by your side.
Live by my side?
But I don't love you,
my treasure.
You're a monster.
Not because of what
you've told me.
After all,
that's just the natural
conclusion to everything.
You're the most
attractive man
I've ever held in my arms.
But...
if I ever decided I was
the sole arbiter of my life,
I wouldn't want to feel
unworthy of it.
Leave me alone now.
What will happen
if I go to sleep here?
Are you tired?
Maybe I had too much
to drink.
Please don't go to sleep.
I can't help it.
I'm tired.
Please don't go to sleep.
I want to show you
my conclusion.