Will.
Hey. I asked
if you were okay.
Sorry.
You know, we don't
have to do this.
We can just go home.
I'll be fine.
God, this thing is so...
Thick...
Official.
Maybe they're
overcompensating.
It's kind of hard
to call everybody up
out of the blue
after two years.
Nobody's seen her?
I ran into her and David
at a supermarket,
and a little bit
after that, I heard
they disappeared.
And they met
in the grief group?
Mm-hmm, while we
were still married.
Yeah, I guess you
could have put odds
on our divorce.
No, people
don't think like that.
Yes, they do.
No, they don't.
Yes, they--
oh, my god.
Jesus.
What was that?
A coyote, I think.
Just stay here.
Oh, man.
You should go
back in the car.
Okay, okay.
Oh, my god.
Jesus.
This was your house?
A lot of money
in Eden's family.
Wasn't ever mine.
Come on, Ty.
Dinner's ready.
Hey,
you're here.
Fucking a.
I win, see? Hi!
Was there
a betting pool?
Uh, for entertainment
purposes only.
- Hey.
- Hey, buddy.
I am Gina.
We met at their--
- yes.
- Nice to see you.
- Good to see you.
- God, Kira,
you look
so fucking hot
right now.
Will you bear
a child for us,
like, right now?
We're not kidding.
And, you, I see
you've almost shed
that dirty dishrag look
that's so concerning.
What? I have
a dirty dishrag look?
Mm, less so now.
- It's just--
- what? Come on.
He did look
like a dishrag.
How are you?
Eh...
Is this Kira?
- That's me.
- Hi. I'm Claire.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Hey, will, I'm Ben.
Remember me?
We drove a thriving
business into
the ground together.
Never thrived.
It was thriving
like a motherfucker
for three months,
and you know it.
Hey, wait.
Where's choi?
Late as usual,
and I can't get
any reception
up here either.
Is Eden and, uh--
I'm here.
Oh.
Let me look at you, will.
Mm, I missed you.
You, too.
House doesn't look
very different, does it?
No, not--not really.
Well, we're glad
you're here.
Oh.
You're a mess.
And you must be Kira.
Hi.
Thank you
for having me.
Will, you remember David.
Of course. Sure.
Will, come here.
Hey.
I'm so glad you're here.
I'm really glad, man.
Hey, how--how are you?
Oh, I'm brilliant.
I mean, we've got
a lot to talk about,
so much
to celebrate tonight.
Kira.
Yes.
Ah.
Oh. Okay.
Beautiful.
What can
i get you to drink?
No, i-I'm good.
Uh, I'd go
with the wine.
It's an '85 rothschild.
Are you
shitting me?
Uh, okay,
what does that mean?
Oh, will,
you're adorable.
It's, like, $8 million
a bottle, cro-mag.
Well,
this night is special.
We shouldn't save
these things.
We shouldn't
put off enjoying...
What we have.
You sure?
I'm good.
Yes. Thank you.
Well, since
everybody's here--
except choi.
Oh, fucking choi,
man.
- Fucking choi.
- All right.
Except choi, but, you know,
I guess we'll just have
to start without him.
Um, first of all,
welcome to our
little reunion of sorts.
You guys are all
very special to Eden,
which--which means
you're very special to me,
and we really missed you,
and we love you.
You know, each and every one
of us is on a journey,
and we feel
that it's important
to be on that journey
with the people you love,
and it's something
we really, really
have good here.
We want to open up
the house again,
give it and us
a new start, so...
Let's raise this
ridiculously expensive
glass of wine
to new beginnings.
Yeah.
- To new beginnings.
- Cheers.
- Salud.
Hey! Save a glass for me.
This is Sadie.
Sadie,
meet my friends.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Hi.
So, um...
How do you guys
know each other?
Um...
Just friends
in common, I guess.
We met
in Mexico.
Sadie's
staying here with us
and helping us out.
Yeah.
It's fun. We have fun.
Hope you don't mind me
crashing the party.
It's awesome.
Huh.
They've told me
so much about you.
We hit a coyote
on the way up here.
- What?
It just came
out of nowhere.
I mean, there was
nothing we could do.
It was
in horrible shape.
He had to kill it.
What? How did you
not tell us this,
like, immediately?
You killed it
with, like, what?
Tire iron.
Oh, god. What?
I don't know
how you did it, man.
That's pretty butch.
No, it was
a good thing.
That was mercy.
Mm-hmm.
Would you mind
if I looked around
for a little bit?
Of course not.
Thank you.
See you in a bit.
Can't believe it.
A tire iron
requires a lot of...
- Wow.
- I know.
No, you don't. No, you don't.
No, you don't.
No. No. No!
- Will.
Jesus.
Sorry.
You scared me.
No harm done.
You're so handsome
tonight.
You're shining.
And, Kira,
you're both
really beautiful.
Thank you.
Heh.
Could you help me
get those glasses, please?
Bars on windows are new.
Well, I was here
alone for a while.
It's security,
safer.
It's nice.
Thank you.
We got them
in Mexico.
Is that where you've been
for the last two years?
Some of the time.
Did you
worry about me?
Did you think
about me?
Yeah.
I did.
Well, I'm fantastic.
I've never
been better.
You don't have to worry
about me anymore.
You don't find it hard
to be in this house again?
No, not at all.
It doesn't
have to be.
That's what's
so incredible.
You look different, Edie.
I am different.
I'm free.
All that useless pain,
it's gone.
It's something
anyone can have, will,
and I want you
to have it, too.
Eden looks hot.
I can say that,
right?
We're all
consenting adults.
It's good to see you
again, Ben.
You, too.
It's been
way too long.
Heh.
I'm just here
for the food.
What were you guys
talking about?
Not my business.
I was just
telling will
that pain
is optional.
It is?
Why didn't anyone
tell me that before now?
I know.
But it's actually
really simple.
All those
negative emotions,
grief, anger,
depression,
is all just
chemical reactions.
It's entirely physical,
and it's completely
changeable.
Kind of sound like
a pamphlet there, Eden.
You can actually expel
those emotions
from your body
and live the life
you want to live.
So you're
shitting out your pain?
I can see you're
not interested.
I'm sorry, Eden.
It just sounds
fucking crazy.
Eden, what the fuck?
Until you
stop making a joke
out of everything,
you'll never
learn a thing.
That's why nobody
cares what you think.
Um...
Yeah. Okay.
Heh.
She fucking
gored me, man.
That was loud.
- Oh, it's not--
- for the vegetarians.
Has she been acting
like this all night?
Yeah. David, too.
Look, I'm all for whatever
you gotta do to get by,
especially you two,
with what you went through,
but you didn't lose
your mind.
Oh, I didn't?
Not like that.
How are you?
I don't know.
I don't really know
how to act.
Well, it's not like
the good old days
anymore, you know.
No.
No, it isn't.
Wait. Where's Amanda?
Home with the kids.
- Yeah?
- Pissed.
What? What's up?
Think we hate
each other.
That's not good.
Yeah. I know.
But the sex is--
it's so...
- Angry.
I can't get away
from it, man.
Um, it's good to see you.
You, too.
Mm.
Hey, no one cares
what I think?
No.
Come on? Really?
Ben, have
a glass of wine.
I've let it go
already, and
so should you.
I'll always
have a drink.
See?
It's gone already.
We'll be here.
Come.
Sit with me.
Ask me a question.
Okay.
Seriously,
ask me a question.
Okay. Sorry.
Um--hey, wait.
You're up for tenure,
aren't you?
Yeah. I got it.
Come on.
A year ago.
Year ago? Really?
I had a party
and everything.
I'm... sorry.
You don't have
to be sorry.
You're here now.
It's weird to be here,
isn't it?
Mm.
Maybe that's choi,
our hero.
Fucking choi.
- Hey.
Aha.
Yeah, look.
I'm finally here.
Yeah.
Who's that?
Hey.
Um, everybody...
It's you.
Oh, darlin'.
Oh, I can't believe
you're really here.
This is
my friend pruitt.
- Hey.
Evening.
Eden.
How are you?
Mm.
Hey. I'm Ben.
Nice to meet you.
I'm gonna grab
a whiskey. Did you
want anything?
Ah, anything diet
is fine, thanks.
Okay.
Hey. I'm Tommy.
Miguel, Kira, Gina.
Nice to meet you.
I have no idea.
I'm glad
you're here,
but frankly where
the hell is choi?
Choi?
Is my asshole boyfriend.
Said he was gonna be
early for once.
He didn't call you guys,
say he was gonna be late?
No. Come on.
I thought he was
gonna come with you.
- Yeah, i--
- we haven't seen him.
All right, that's it.
I'm gonna try again.
Heh. Do you guys
have service up here?
Sorry.
Horrible.
And the bills fell
through the cracks
while we were away.
We have to get
them up here
and reconnect
the landline.
I'm sorry, Gina.
Well, he usually calls
at least once.
You know what?
Your best bet
is gonna be
in the back actually.
Good luck, though.
Is everything okay,
will?
Yeah. Yeah, why didn't
you leave the key
in the door, though?
There was a home invasion
up in the canyon
about a month ago.
- Oh.
- This couple got terrorized.
It was really sick.
Just kinda
freaked us out.
I didn't hear about it.
Then I'm sure
it never happened.
Yeah, come on,
will.
Can't a man
put himself
in lockdown
if he wants?
This is America.
Okay, what if
there was a fire?
Okay.
There you go.
Better?
I just keep
the house a little
differently.
That's all.
It's my house.
Will, could you
do me a favor
and go get
some more
firewood?
You know
where we keep it.
Has he been
like this a lot,
so agitated?
Sometimes.
Well, I'm glad
he has you.
It comforts me.
I know he wants
the best for you, too.
I'm glad
you're here, Kira.
I think
it's important.
Can I ask you
something?
How has he been
handling things?
He can be
self-destructive.
I think he's doing
the best he can.
You're it.
You're it! Come on!
Come back to us
when you're ready.
I'm telling you.
Why are you doing it?
Because it's--
you're very dirty here.
- Am I?
- Yes.
And it's
attention to detail
that is
incredibly important.
It's my credo.
It's your credo?
It's a new--
i came up with it
last night. Hey.
Why don't you go
back to bed, okay?
We'll keep--
we'll keep it down.
- Okay.
Okay. I love you.
Good night, baby.
Good night.
I love you, too. Night.
Good night, hon.
Mm.
And that'll be
the time he saw
his gross parents
having sex.
We are gross.
Mmm.
Do you think
he needs a brother?
No! Oh, my--
they're in a cult.
No, no, stop.
We're not in a cult.
I know plenty of people
who do the invitation.
- You do?
- Yeah, yeah.
Eden, you guys
really in this?
We are.
So that's why
you were in Mexico?
Did you get
all naked down there
in the jungle?
Sometimes.
Well, I did.
Yeah, you did.
But, you know,
it's just--
it's just
a group of people
coming together.
You know, they all
have lost someone,
and then they--
they help each other.
You know,
it's really a science
rather than, like,
some weird religious cult
or anything.
You know,
it's smart people
like--like us,
here in L.A.,
New York,
thousands of people.
You'd be surprised.
Yeah, my boss
is into it.
It's like a new est
or something, right?
Yeah, no--
I think
it's a little more
grounded than that,
you know,
more practical.
And at the same time,
it's very spiritual,
you know,
however you define that.
Seriously,
what goes on down there?
I mean, is it
like a self-help group
thing or...
Well...
Since you asked,
we have something
that we'd like
to show you.
- David.
- Oh, no.
- Yes, yes.
No, no.
- Perfect. Just perfect.
- Oh, no. Now I understand
- why the doors are locked.
- My bad.
You're gonna
convert us.
This is
a conversion thing,
right?
Oh, my god.
No, this is
the real reason?
I know it sounds
a little weird,
but it's actually--
it's pretty amazing stuff.
Indulge us, okay.
Is this some kind
of a recruitment video?
I really
don't want to--
I do. Convert me.
I am weak.
Yeah, you are.
It's nothing like that.
Promise.
All right, let's do this.
This is our home
in sonora, Mexico,
and it is your home, too,
if you choose it to be.
Our home and our family
is open to anyone
with the desire
to help themselves.
The human brain has
a remarkable ability to heal.
My life's work
has been to discover
new ways to rewire,
to rewrite
our experiences with trauma.
I mean, trauma has visited...
All of us.
We invite you
to a conscious existence,
to a connected existence.
But we take this journey,
all journeys side by side.
You are not alone.
Wherever you are,
we--we transcend, hmm?
How do you feel, Annie?
I feel loved.
You are loved.
You are deeply loved.
Who are you
going to see, dear?
My husband...
James...
My father.
It's all right.
They will
all be there.
I--
soon, Annie.
Soon.
Over soon.
All of the pain and
all of the grief,
you renounced it,
haven't you?
You've made a choice.
You're ready to go,
aren't you, honey?
Come.
Come. Breathe in.
Breathe in.
Breathe deeply.
You feel
her spirit?
I can feel it.
She's with
all of us now...
And your father...
And your wife...
And your son.
Don't cry.
There's no darkness,
just reunion.
Annie is safe now.
This is
what it's about.
We did not just
watch somebody die.
That was real?
- Yes, it was.
- Yeah.
Why would anyone
want to watch that?
She just wanted
to show everyone
that there's nothing
to be afraid of.
That was the point.
She was very sick.
With what?
She barely looked 30.
Cancer.
Look, I get it.
If you
gotta go at 30,
it's not a bad way,
surrounded by people
who love you.
On video?
It's beautiful.
It's
a little grim.
She looked
at peace to me.
- I'm not judging her.
- No, I know, babe.
Yeah, no one's
judging her.
I just don't understand
why you'd show
something like that at
a dinner party, David.
- You don't get it?
- Mm-mmm.
I guess this is
not really being taken
the way we meant it.
I mean, it is
a pretty heavy thing
to drop on us, David.
But it's not heavy.
For us, it's not.
- No.
- It's okay.
Not everybody gets it.
It's not about the fact
that she died. We all die.
What's it about?
It's about communion.
Right,
like Eden said,
she's just
trying to show you
that there's nothing
to be afraid of.
Look at me. My pain
had turned me into
some walking cliché.
I was a coked-up,
out-of-control
record producer,
for god's sake.
I was a slave
to my own grief,
but not anymore.
Dr. Joseph
freed me from that.
I just...
Phew!
He gave me back
my center, you know?
I don't have to be
afraid anymore.
Amen, brother.
You know, we've all been
through horrible things,
but those things
don't have to define us.
What happened
to Eden and will--
no, don't. Don't!
David, don't.
Finding this
saved my life.
I almost died after.
I almost
couldn't keep on living.
You know that, will.
But look at me now.
I'm great. I'm happy.
I'm not angry anymore.
And if anyone is
gonna try to take that
away from me...
My god, look at the way
you're looking at me.
If anyone is gonna try
to say that this isn't--
Edie, i--Edie--
it's just you
don't think I know?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
- I know!
- Let's get a drink.
It's just
that easy for you?
Come on.
Come on. Let's
get a drink.
Yeah, we all are lost.
We can agree
on that, right?
It's just...
It's too big.
It's too big
for any of us alone.
You got to...
That better be--
no, I've got it.
I've got it. I got it.
David.
Oh, sorry.
Excuse me for a second.
Hi there.
- Hey.
Are you okay?
I-I'm sorry.
No, not you.
I mean, I knew it was
gonna be heavy, but...
I was just--why choi and i
were supposed to be
here together for you.
We have to make
a better effort.
It's on us,
and I was trying
to give you space,
and I don't know
if that came across
like I was checked out.
It's...
I think
you should probably...
Okay, hello.
I don't--
you haven't heard
a word I said, have you?
I-I'm sorry, Gina.
Just a couple people
looking for a party on foot.
Good luck. They'll die
of dehydration.
Yeah.
Anyway, um,
we can talk later.
I just--i wanted you
to know that...
I have been
thinking about you.
- Yeah.
- All right?
- I love you...
- I love you, too.
And I miss you.
I miss you, too.
I'm gonna get a refill.
Get a--get a drink.
I feel like you guys
have to come to my house.
I--that's all I do.
Get ice cream and...
Are you gonna
come and join us
at some point?
Will?
Can you tell me
what that is?
It is a pill, will.
I found a bunch of it
in Eden's bedroom
- unlabeled--
- wait. What are you--
please just look at it.
It's phenobarbital,
i think.
Is that dangerous?
Anything is dangerous if
you take too much of it.
It's a barbiturate.
I mean, it's old-school,
but it's...
Not unusual to find it
if you're rifling
through somebody's
medicine cabinet.
Hey, hey, break up
your little clique.
Come talk to us.
Come on. Let's go.
Apparently
v.I.P. Room
is in the kitchen.
Guys,
guys, guys,
join us, please.
Just opened
another bottle.
Oh, yes.
Probably needs
a little more air.
I mean it, Miguel.
Just keep it
between us.
Okay, snoopy.
Ah, man.
Can you give this one
to Miguel?
- Yeah.
- Gracias.
De nada.
Ah, smell that.
Okay.
Salud.
Will thinks
you guys are on pills.
Figuratively.
You think we're crazy?
I never said that.
That's okay.
I'm not offended.
A lot of people
think we're crazy.
But I doubt they're
as happy as we are.
Where's the diet
again?
Why?
No comprendo inglés.
- Thank you.
- De nada.
Or don't you guys think
this is a little bit weird?
Look, will,
there is no way
that tonight
wasn't gonna feel
a little strange...
Or sad.
Look, this is just
a long-overdue reunion
between old friends
with a couple
of totally frickin'
friend weirdoes.
They're a little mansony.
- "Mansonian"?
- And that skinny girl--
look, I'm not kidding.
Come on.
Hey, I got you.
Look at me.
Yeah, they're
a little weird,
but this is L.A.
They're harmless.
Let's just get
through this night,
give them a break.
Let's steal some more
of this wine.
Oh, now that is
something I can
get behind. Come on.
Hey, guys, listen!
I realize that some of you
might have found that video
a little disturbing
or off-putting,
and I apologize for that.
It's cool.
Nah, Gina, it's not.
Last thing I want
you guys to think
is that I'm trying
to force my ideas on you.
- Welcome back.
- Hey.
You know,
it's just I want
you guys to know me.
There's this game we
used to play in Mexico
at the end of group,
and I think
we should try it.
What kind of game
are we talking about?
Like charades
or something?
Ah, it'll be fun,
and it'll give you a sense
of what we learned, right?
I'm in.
What is it?
Okay, it's kind of
like that game
we played in college,
"i never."
- Oh, yeah.
- I always lose that game.
Oh, I never do.
Except this time,
it's "i want,"
so we take turns,
and everybody gets
to say what they want.
I want to hear
what Gina did in college.
You mean
who she did.
The point is
to be honest.
All right? To admit
your desires.
You know,
because anything
is possible
once you strip away
social constraints
and embarrassment
and those negative emotions
that, you know--
the things
that hold us down.
So honesty, okay?
That's what it's about.
Want to give it a shot?
I'll go first.
Wonderful.
Okay. I want...
To tell you,
Eden, and David...
Will and Kira
and Gina,
Miguel...
Pack a lunch.
And Tommy--
there are so many.
Ben, Claire, pruitt...
I want to tell you all
that I love you.
I know I haven't known
some of you for very long,
but tonight I feel love.
I do.
And a lot of people
don't say that.
They're afraid.
But--so, I love you.
- Oh.
- Mm.
- Oh, shit.
- Oh, my.
Oh, my gosh.
This is...
Wow.
Hi there.
You got it?
Uh-huh.
All right.
Um...
I want...
Some of that coke
you used to do.
Done. I think
i might have some more.
You keep it
in the house?
You're
the worst rehabber
in the world.
No, David, don't.
I was kidding.
No, you weren't.
That's okay.
That's the point
of the game.
Okay.
I wasn't kidding.
Bust that shit out.
There you go.
I like
this game.
I want to tell you
about my wife
Margaret.
We were married
eight years,
would have been 15
next month.
She was a painter, oils.
First saw her work
at this artists retreat
in Minneapolis.
I was in love with her
before I even met her.
These abstract,
energetic landscapes...
And then I saw her.
Wow. It was like
I'd hit the jackpot.
She was the most generous
spirit I'd ever seen,
and she was as bright
and gorgeous as...
The morning.
When you surprised her,
she had this--this laugh,
this joyous,
guttural rumble
that came from
way down deep inside.
You knew you'd done
something good.
She was all light,
all light.
During times
like this, um,
nights like
this night...
I think of her
quite a bit.
Did she, uh,
pass away?
Yes, she did.
We had
been drinking.
I had been drinking.
We had
just come home
from a dinner,
and we were
in the kitchen.
We'd fell into one
of those arguments,
you know,
one of those
stupid fights
that last
your whole marriage.
It was
about the dishes.
Somebody
started yelling.
I don't
remember who.
I went to pour myself
another drink.
She tried to stop me,
and...
Something just gave.
I turned and hit her
as hard as I could.
Her knees buckled.
She hit her head.
Think she was trying
to get back up.
You know, she had
her hand out,
was staring at me.
And then
she collapsed,
and she was gone.
What the fuck?
It was a terrible,
terrible mistake.
It was seven years ago.
I went to prison.
I paid that way,
but I was still
the same person.
Finally, by accepting
the invitation...
And looking only ahead,
destroying that
horrible part of me
that made
that moment possible...
I'm cured.
And I miss her.
Not a day goes by
i don't think of her.
But I don't grieve,
and I don't
feel guilty anymore.
I've chosen
to let that go.
Those emotions
are useless,
because I'm gonna be
seeing her again
in a better place
than this.
That's what we believe.
That's what most people
have believed
for centuries.
I, for one,
can't wait to get there.
But forgiveness
doesn't have to wait.
I'm free
to forgive myself,
and so are you.
It's a beautiful thing.
It really is.
What's more honorable,
facing the truth or
hiding it to be accepted?
And people change.
I don't know.
This...
Doesn't seem
very honest.
It feels like you're
selling us something.
No, we aren't.
I want...
Are we really
gonna keep
doing this?
- I want--
- this better be good.
I want to kiss Ben.
I always have.
Why the hell not?
Bring it, sister.
Oh, my god.
I want
to kiss Ben.
One per party.
- Um, no.
- Boom. No?
- Whoo!
- Oh!
- Oh, yeah!
- Get it, girl!
- Ah!
- Get it, girl.
Go!
Jeez.
I don't know
if I approve that.
And nobody
tells Amanda.
Uh, I want a blow job...
Oh, you're
ridiculous.
From somebody.
Oh, I know.
What?
I'm not joking.
I have to go.
No, come on.
We're just having fun.
It's all right.
This is all making me
a little uncomfortable.
I'm sorry.
Come on. I'll--
have a seat.
I'll get you a drink.
We'll do
something else.
No, no, no.
I don't want
to spoil
anyone's fun.
This just
isn't my thing.
- Claire, please.
- Hey, just--
just let her go, David.
Why can't she just leave?
Will, I just
want her to stay
and have a good time,
and Eden has
planned this night
for a long time.
We'll be
very disappointed.
Yeah, well, just let her
do what she wants, okay?
I'm gonna leave.
Of course.
- Bye.
I'm sorry
if I've made you
feel uncomfortable.
It's--it's okay.
I'm tired.
Claire,
why don't you just stay
a little longer?
I'll see you again
soon, okay?
I'm really sorry.
Okay, Claire.
Eden, it's okay.
I know.
Do you want me
to walk you to your car?
It's, like,
40 feet, will.
Bye.
- Bye, Claire.
- Bye.
- Nice meeting you.
Are you
in the prius?
Yeah.
I parked
behind you.
Bye. Thank you, guys.
- What?
- Why did she leave?
Hey, will,
come over here,
and talk to me.
Just give me a sec.
So what do you do?
- Okay.
- Well, I'm a nurse's assistant.
Careful on the right.
Okay.
Straight out.
You're all set.
Oh, uh, Claire.
- Miguel.
- I save lives.
Stop.
Will, come on.
Can you and I talk
alone for a minute?
It's important.
Yeah. Yeah.
Come on.
I'm very happy
you're here.
It's so important
to Eden and me.
I mean, we chose you
because you matter to us.
You chose me?
To be here tonight.
But I don't know, man.
Y-you've been acting so...
Suspicious
of our hospitality.
Frankly,
it upsets me a little.
I lock the door,
and you have a fit about it.
Just now, my friend
wants to move his car,
and you're standing
by the window
like you're gonna catch him
stealing something.
You seem very distant,
very...
Just off somehow.
I'm sorry.
Maybe I wasn't prepared
to be here tonight.
Okay.
I appreciate your honesty.
Look, i--i understand
that you feel
like you have to be
on the lookout.
I know, because
that's how I felt.
The world is unsafe
and chaotic,
and, you know,
it happened before.
It can always
happen again.
David, please.
I don't pretend to know
what you went through
with your wife,
and you don't know me.
You can't.
Hey.
Hi.
I tried to convince
Claire to stay.
I felt bad about,
uh, my story
scaring her.
She seemed
to understand.
No, I swear to god,
every day.
Every day I get an email,
and it's just I'm going,
you know, "what is this?
Is this, like, gonna
kill my hard drive?"
And it's usually some stupid
fricking video of, like--
how many cat videos
has Claire sent you?
- Oh, my god.
- Claire has sent me cat videos
so--every day,
it's a cat video.
I mean,
i got a cat video.
I got a penguin video.
Oh, my god, penguins.
Penguins are overrated.
- Overrated?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- They are.
- Here we go.
- Penguins?
- Yeah, they're happy,
and they're always like,
"oh, my god.
They're so adorable."
You're it.
Kira.
I need help, Tommy.
Oh, what?
So things aren't great
with Kira, huh?
Heh. What--
why would you say that?
Just seems
like that to me.
Seems like
she's real distant.
No.
No, she's great.
Should we go
back inside?
No. I'm gonna
make a call.
Oh, good luck.
There's no service
up here.
No, it goes in and out.
I could hang with you.
You could fuck me
right here.
What?
Why should we
deny ourselves ever?
It's what it was like
in Mexico.
Man, everyone was
just going for it.
It was awesome.
I think you need
to go back inside.
You don't like me?
I don't know you.
I could make you
like me so much.
I could
make you beg me.
Could do it
without even
touching you...
Just with
my voice...
My breath.
S-Sadie.
You can hurt me
if you want.
I don't want
to hurt you.
I don't believe you.
Hey. What are you
doing out here?
I needed a break.
Oh, really?
Heh heh. From what?
Tommy, there's
something wrong here.
Will--
something bad
is happening here.
You're wrong.
Look, and I know
what you're gonna say,
but Claire left
because that poor girl
is sexually awkward.
Choi is the most
unreliable Korean
in Los Angeles.
He could be anywhere.
And Eden...
I haven't seen her
for two years.
It's crazy.
But we're all
trying to figure out
how to go on,
you know.
This is how they do it.
Something doesn't
feel safe here.
Of course
it doesn't feel safe.
Took a lot of courage
for you to come here tonight,
but you're letting your mind
run away with things.
Hey...
I love you, will.
But you gotta stop acting
so fucking weird.
It's freaking people out.
You're safe, okay?
I'll see you back inside.
Will, choi.
What's up?
Listen,
it's about 7:00,
and I'm pulling up
to Eden's house.
I forgot to pick up
dessert like I said
I would,
and I can't
get ahold of Gina.
Could you get some
on your way? I--
look,
I'm early, dude.
I'm actually early,
but honestly
I don't want to go
back down the hill
and look
for a fucking
patisserie.
I hope
you get this.
See you here
in a few, I guess.
I'm goin' in.
Okay, bye.
There he is.
- See?
- Hey, buddy.
All right, I want
to play "i want."
- I want--
- no more blow jobs.
I like this game.
Was it obvious that
i like the game?
I have room.
I could do it.
We both enjoyed
that game.
We did. Heh.
- Oh.
- Ooh.
I think
this is a new game.
- I'm scared.
- This is the next game.
Maybe this is one
of those guess who...
So pretty.
- So purty.
- Nice.
It is lovely.
Stop it right now.
What is going on here?
Happy birthday.
What is this about?
It's not for another week.
It's close enough. Mwah.
- Okay, please, please.
- Come on.
But no singing.
- Oh, come on.
- Come on.
Please? Please? Thank you.
- It's wish time.
- All right.
Make it good.
Yeah.
You attacked
that one.
- Bastard.
- Well done.
Where's choi?
Excuse me?
I mean, where the fuck
is choi, hmm?
What are you
talking about, will?
I just got
a message from him.
He said he was here, that he
had gotten here at 7:00.
- What?
- He said he was here.
Eden,
is that true?
I haven't
seen choi tonight.
Edie, where is he?
Will, stop, please.
Just--
no. No. I just
got a message from him.
He said he was here.
He made the call
from right outside.
- We haven't seen him.
- Don't fucking lie to me.
He called
from right outside
your front door.
David is not
lying to you.
Choi never got here.
Maybe he
turned around, man.
Look, he might
have forgotten
something, will.
You never know.
Yeah, why is everyone
acting so fucking polite?
Where's choi?
Hey, Eden,
what's going on?
I have not seen
choi tonight,
Gina, I swear.
Something
isn't right here.
There is something
very strange going on here,
and no one
is saying anything.
What do you think
is happening, will?
Hey, who are you? Hmm?
See, see, I don't get
why you two are here.
Hey, these are
my guests.
Yeah. Hmm.
Two years. We don't
see you for two years,
and then all of a sudden,
we get invited
to this lavish dinner.
You're all smiles,
spewing out all this jargon
with these two in tow.
Don't tell me
that this is normal,
- the invitation.
- It helps people.
Will, everybody's
allowed to have--
no, it's a fucking cult,
Miguel!
It's a fucking cult!
Will, sit down!
No! No, look at
the video, okay?
It's not about communion.
It's not about family.
It's about fucking denial.
You are
out of line.
All right, no,
it's about denial.
Oh, you know what it is?
It's a fucking brainwash.
Our son died, Edie,
and you're trying to ignore it.
It meant something
when he died,
and don't you try
to erase that.
Ty was real. It was rea--
it is real.
Please, please, Edie.
Where's choi?
Will, she said
she doesn't know.
I think
this is just a big
misunderstanding.
Don't fucking
patronize me, David.
Hey, why don't you
tell me something?
Why are all the doors
locked, huh?
Oh, my god.
Okay, why are all the bars
on the windows, hmm?
Why is there
a big fucking bottle
of phenobarbital
stashed in your bedroom?
Jesus Christ, will.
Did you go through
our things?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
We should go.
- No. No. No.
- We should go.
Something very dangerous
is going on here,
and nobody's
talking about it.
We're all
just ignoring it
because David brought out
some good wine!
We are going, will.
We are going.
No, I'm not
going anywhere!
We are going
right now, will.
It's all right.
All right.
What's up?
Choi?
I'm so sorry.
I was right here,
and then work called,
and it's so fucked up,
'cause they can't do
anything without me.
I called you.
I didn't get it.
You okay?
Hi, love.
Did I miss dinner?
You missed more
than that, bud.
We have plenty.
I'll get you something.
I'll fix him
a plate.
Thank you, pruitt.
What's going on?
David...
It's okay.
We really should
go now, will.
Just give him
a minute, Kira.
I'm--I'm sorry, Eden.
I know it's hard, will,
but you
can't criticize us
for finding our own way
through this.
I've never done that
to you.
I know. I know.
It's none of my business.
I know,
and I'm very sorry.
It's okay.
You're part
of our family, will.
All of you are.
Will you--will you
excuse me for a second?
Choi, eat.
You--you got
any more of that wine?
Just gotta lather it up.
Keep washing.
10 seconds,
at least.
We should go.
Let's go, then.
Let's just--
let's just
get out of here.
I can't.
Kira, I'm not okay.
My son is dead.
Where do I put that?
I don't know.
It's like a scream
trapped inside me.
And nothing
changes the fact
that I should have--
I should have
been watching
more closely that day.
Now, look, you couldn't
have known, will.
You could not have been
looking out for that.
It's another kid.
And Ty loved him.
And they were
just playing.
They were
just messing around.
I shouldn't have
let them have the bat.
What happened to your son
wasn't anything
that could be predicted
or changed or...
I've been waiting to die
since the moment
it happened.
Moving forward
is not a betrayal, will.
Look at Eden.
That's what
letting go looks like.
You're not
letting go of him.
I would never ask you to.
You know that.
We can help
each other, will.
That's the only way.
I love you, Kira...
But I don't think
you can help me.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, you are.
Mmm. Red velvet.
Miguel, you get
the first piece.
I'm excited.
Hi, will.
Can I see his room?
Of course.
I know you have doubts.
Skepticism
can be contagious.
I wouldn't
have known either
before I saw the new truth
and shared it with you.
I wouldn't have believed,
but it was revealed
so clearly.
Remember the reward.
This beautiful moment
is upon us.
Tonight is the night
our faith is made real.
The hardest thing
is to start.
Just take the step.
Believe,
and give yourself over.
Will, let's go.
Everybody's waiting.
I love you.
I love you so much,
my heart is breaking.
I'm waiting for you.
Okay.
Kira.
Look at these people.
They're so happy
to be here with you.
I think
we should take a moment
to look at each other
and really look.
Please raise your glass.
To a better world.
To peace.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
Don't drink it!
Don't fucking touch it!
- No! No!
- Will!
- No, don't drink!
- Don't drink!
- Calm down, will.
No. No.
We are leaving now!
- Control yourself.
- Will, you do not
want to go this way.
Let's go, Kira.
We're leaving
right now!
- Calm down.
- No, we are leaving now!
You ruined it!
You ruined everything!
Oh, my god.
Sadie.
- Sadie.
- Oh, my god, will.
What did you do?
Don't move her.
Sadie.
Somebody call 911.
- I'm on it.
- Sadie.
Sadie, can you hear me?
Do you have
a first-aid kit?
Sadie,
can you hear me?
It's okay, Sadie.
- She's not breathing.
- No, she's breathing.
- Not Sadie, Gina.
- What?
Gina?
All right, get her
to the floor.
Gina.
What's going on? Gina!
- Baby?
- Gina.
- Can you hear me?
- Baby?
Starting cpr.
Baby, it's gonna be okay.
- What's happening, Miguel?
- Somebody get 911?
I'm not getting
any reception.
a pulse, Miguel.
Fucking door's locked.
- Gina, can you hear me?
- Gina.
- Come on, Gina.
- Okay, baby.
Come on.
Go. Go. Go. Go. Go.
- Tommy. Tom--Tommy.
Come on! Let's go!
Tommy!
- Come on!
- Kira! Kira!
- This way.
- What?!
Ben, this way!
- Oh, my god.
- Go left. Left!
Oh. It's locked.
Will, it's locked.
Okay, okay.
This way. This way.
Will! Will!
The door. The door.
Fuck. It's locked.
We're gonna have
to break it.
Shh. Kira.
- No.
- - Please, no.
Will, why is
this happening?
Listen to me.
We are gonna get ready.
We're gonna do
whatever it takes.
Do you hear me?
- They are just people.
- Right.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Come on.
Okay.
You weren't
supposed to hurt
anybody like that.
I know.
- Oh, god.
- How could you do that?
- Why would you do that?
- Don't do this.
We were supposed
to just go to sleep
and go there together.
It was supposed
to be beautiful.
It's gonna be quiet
in a minute.
We'll be there soon.
It wasn't supposed
to be like this.
- That's not what he said.
- No, I know. It's just...
We just have
to finish now. Hey.
Listen to me.
We take it
one step at a time.
We finish.
- No. I can't.
- It'll be quiet,
and we can rest.
Yes, you can.
Eden,
you gotta help me.
You have to help me.
You can't leave me.
No, this is wrong.
Dr. Joseph said it
was gonna be hard,
but we'll have
to finish it now.
This is wrong.
We were chosen,
remember?
We were chosen.
This is the only way
we can leave
this hurting.
This is right.
This is the only way
we can stop hurting.
We can
leave all this,
all this pain,
all this shit
behind.
You can do this.
Hey...
We can still
get there.
Come on.
There's a door
- to the garage upstairs.
- Okay.
We're going there.
Okay.
Shh. Shh.
Dr. Joseph...
Oh, my god.
Choi.
Oh, god.
No.
What?
- No.
- What?
No. No. There was
a door here.
Oh, fuck.
We had a door here
when we lived here.
Fuck. Okay.
Okay, maybe--
maybe we can signal
someone outside.
Maybe I can signal
Come on.
Kira.
Shh.
Don't be afraid.
There is a plan
for us, man.
Will.
Just let go. Just--
we'll be there soon.
I promise.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Eden.
I'm sorry, will.
I'm sorry.
Eden.
Stop it. Stop it.
Stop it.
Okay.
Will.
We are not
gonna die like this.
Hey, lis--
I'm okay.
Eden?
Get the gun.
She shot herself, David.
That's good.
She's with them now.
It's empty.
We have a gun.
That's okay.
It's time.
Don't do this,
David.
Will.
I miss him.
I miss him so much.
I wanted to leave.
I'm sorry.
Will you
take me outside?
I hope...
I hope we...
I, uh...
I gotta go
get Miguel.
Tommy.
Okay.
Oh, my god.
Kira.