Mandela, Mandela, Mandela
Who is sir?  It's that terrorist
Mandela, they let him out
Remember this day boys, it's the
day our country went to the dogs
come, let's go, come
I'm now in a position
to announce
The Lord Nelson Mandela will be released
at the prison
on Sunday,the eleventh of
February at about 3 pm
There's Mr. Nelson Mandela
Mr. Mandela a free man
Taking his first steps
into a new South Africa
This is the moment the world
has been waiting for
...and the top news of the day
here in South Africa and around the world
The recent release of Nelson Mandela
from prison
has triggered a power struggle
between the ANC and their rivals
there are reports the government
is secretly providing
arms to these groups
contributing to violence
that has erupted across the country
South Africa seems to be
on the verge of civil war
Mr. Mandela has traveled to Durban
in an effort to persuade 100,000
angry young ANC supporters
to make peace
Take your knives and your guns
and throw them into the sea
After 4 years of talks
the day black South Africans have been
fighting for has finally arrived
for the first time they are free
to cast their vote
along side whites
And an estimated 23 million people
went to the polls today
I Nelson Mandela
do hearby swear to be faithful
to the Rebublic of South Africa
Never, never
And never again
shall it be that
this beautiful land
will again experience the oppression
of one by another
and suffer the indignity
of being the skunk of the world
there he is,
like clockwork
that makes him such
an easy target
yes, good morning
morning morning
how are you?
how's your mother?
she's much better thanks-you
good, very good
Watch your left
Mandela, Mandela
alright
What does it say?
it says he can win an election,
but can he run a country
not even one day on the job,
and they are after you
It's a legitimate question
Today marks the beginning of a
new era in South Africa
as President Mandela
takes office in Pretoria
facing issues that range from ecomomic
stagnation, unemployment and crime
While at the same time balancing
black aspirations
With white fears
yeah, I never thought I'd see the day
I feel sorry for you son, you've
got your whole life ahead of you
what's it going to be like now?
ah, don't be so gloomy
now I added vitamins
There is a horrible flu bug going around
tell me when you get home
Thanks mom
now I'm telling you Francois
Look at Angola, Mozambique
look at Zimbabwe
we're next, they're going to take
our jobs and drive us into the sea
just you wait
Good morning.
- Good morning
Good morning
Good morning everyone
Ah Brenda, you've had your hair done
I like it
thank-you, we need to talk about
your cabinet appointments and ministers
Give me one moment please
- Okay
After you comrade President
Thank-you sir
Brenda
please assemble all the staff
for me
all those who haven't
already left
"Right now? All of them?
- Yes please
Yes, Mr. President
Ladies and gentlemen if would
like to follow me please
The president would like
to speak with you
here he comes
yeah
wants the satisfaction of
firing us himself
I'd like you to stay out here
Yes, but we...
I cannot talk to them hiding
behind men with guns
Good morning
Good morning, how are you
this morning?
Good to see you
Thank-you for coming
on such short notice
Some of you may know who I am
I could not help noticing
the empty offices
as I came to work this morning
And all of the packing boxes
Now, of course, if you
want to leave
that is your right
and if you feel in your heart
that you cannot work with
your new government
Then it is better that
you do leave, right away
But if you are packing up
because you fear
that, your language,
or the color of your skin
Or who you worked for before
Disqualifies you from working here
I am here to tell you
have no such fear
What remains remains
the past is the past
we look to the future now
We need your help
We want your help
if you would like to stay
you would be doing your country
a great service
All I ask
is that you do your work to
the best of your abiities
And with good heart
I promise to do the same
If we can manage that
Our country will be a
shining light in the world
good morning
is it still morning?
yeah, when you get a chance, can I
get the schedule for the month?
yeah
we need to plan security
Office of the President good morning
Yes sir
we will have that ready for you
We need more men
- Did you talk to Brenda?
- Yes, yesterday
that must be Jason with the schedule
come in beautiful
What is this?
Mr Jason Shabalala
That's me
Am I under arrest?
Capt. Fader and team
reporting for duty, sir
what duty?
With the presidential bodyguards
we've been assigned to this office
Here are our orders
you're special branch, right?
you'll see that they have
been signed
we'll OK the assinment
just wait here
Good morning sir, sorry
You look agitated Jason
that's because there are four
special branch cops in my office
oh, what did you do?
nothing
they say they are the presidential body
guards, have orders signed by you
Yes, yes
These men were
specially trained by the SAS
they have lots of experience
they protected deClerk
- Yes, sir, but that does not mean -
You asked for some more men
- Yes sir
When people see me in public
see my bodyguard
you represent me directly
The rainbow nation
starts here
Reconciliation, start here
Reconciliation sir?
yes, reconciliation Jason
Comrade President...
Not long ago these
guys tried to kill us
Maybe even these 4 guys in my office
tried, and often succeded
yes, I know
Forgiveness starts here too
Forgiveness liberates the soul
it remove fear
that is why it is such
a powerful weapon
please Jason
try
Sorry to disturb you sir
Just a minute
2 copies of the schedule
Thanks
Jason, can we get rid of
these guys now?
here's the schedule for the month
Let's look them over
for assignments
Right.
What?
Jason, can I talk to you
How can we trust them?
we can't
that's what Mandela wants, OK?
Let's go
are  there any special orders
or conditions?
no, oh yes
Mandela  does not like when you don't
smile when you push people away
seriously?
Yes, seriously
it's the new South Africa
"Mandela?
it's the president's name
that's what we call him
We'll call him Mr. President
can we go through
the schedule now?
can you gentlemen come closer?
Yeah, me too
What are our orders
how is going to do all this, huh?
when does he take a break?
he says he rested enough,
in prison
here's a headache
what?
the rugby match
England against Springboks
at the stadium
Will be a headache for
England that's for sure
I don't care about the game
all I care about is that
the president will be exposed
2000 drunken football...
sports fans, mmm?
yes, sports fans
who didn't vote for him,
who probably hate him
who came out of the womb
with guns in their hands
What?
OK guys, I want your
eyes on the crowd at all times
he's taking the middle of the field
going to walk in, shake hands,
and walk off, that's it
Got it
OK, let's go
Ladies and gentlemen, it is our
pleasure today
to introduce our newly
elected president
Mr. Nelson Mandela
Good luck captain
Thank-you Mr. President
Good luck son
good luck
Good luck Chester
yes sir
Good luck
- Thanks.
stop him
no, stay with him
Thank you for honoring our new flag
it's a pleasure sir
Thank-you
how are you?
Good to see
Mandela, Mandela
you are delaying the rugby sir
Yes, yes of course
why didn't you stop him?
you try next time
does he do that sort of thing
all of the time?
that's my answers
good thing it was just a cup
and good thing he never saw it
oh he saw it, he sees everything
I hate rugby
Fuck man
these english mean business
we need to focus...
FOCUS FOCUS
Let
why don't we do a little work
while we watch
we have a lot of promises to keep
yes we do
It's not too late
if the boys can pick up their game
if they don't
heads will roll
c'mon you bloody bastards
where do you want to go first
for foreign investment?
where the money is.
America, England...
Saudi Arabia
How long before the world cup?
about a year
now is time enough for improvement
Mr. President
don't get your hopes up
we're a damn disgrace
did you see all those old
aparthied flicks?
they're a disgrace
but it's also the constitution
along with the aparthied
anthem, I know
But it's time people moved on
look at this
all of the whites are
cheering for the Springboks
all of the blacks are cheering
for England
I used to do that
on the island
we would cheer for anyone
but the 'boks
it made the wardens
very angry
of course it did
sorry I'm late, how's it going?
very badly
maybe it's just as well
why?
I've just been at a meeting
of the national sports executive
there's a strong support to drop
the Springbok emblem and colors
if they play badly
maybe it's a good time
to make a change
this could be the last time we
have to look at the green and gold
Francois' team came to the stadium
this afternoon
unprepared and arrogant
They left 80 minutes with their
tales between their legs
like whipped mongorels
and I for one,
am glad
not because they lost
but because there is
now no way
to ignore the fact that we are
completely and utterly unprepared
To re-enter the world of
top-notch international rugby
The Rugby World Cup is
now less than a year away
and I for one am relieved that
we are the host nation
and there for qualify
automatically for the tournament
somebody gets the axe
because I'm not sure we can get
in on merit alone
who's it gonna be?
team played without discipline
Without strategy
And without courage
and there for...
he's trying to get them to drop me
he's just bitter because the Springboks
were boycotted when he played
Maybe
But people listen to
what he says
They brought shame upon our nation
and I for one can say without
fear of contradiction
that today, these 15
so called, men
did not deserve to wear
the hallowed green and gold
Here's your tea, Mr. Mandela
I warmed the milk tonight
ahh, you are too good to me Mary
your daughter called to cancel her
visit this weekend
Did she say why?
No, she didn't
she said to tell you
she was sorry
I see
do you need anything else tonight?
ahh, no Mary thank you,
I'll go to bed
good evening
good evening Mary
some nice pants for you
God bless you
there you go
you're a very lucky boy
it's a real Springbok
practice jersey
I know it's a bit big, but it's
warm and it will last forever
c'mon, take it, it's yours
why won't he take it?
if he wears it, the others
will beat him up
because the Springboks are so bad?
no
because for them, Springboks still
represent aparthied
and now, for the next
item on our agenda
the embassy executive proposes
a vote on the following motion
that, as a permanent symbol
of the aparthied era
The colors emblem
and the name of Springboks
Be eliminated immediately
and that all sports teams
representing South Africa
shall be known,
as the Proteos
Comrades, we will submit this
motion to a hand vote
and in the event of a close count
will go to a written ballot
all of those in favor of
eliminating the Springboks
Raise your hands
Viva Proteos Viva
Viva
both units to their cars, right now
what do I tell the
Japanese trade delegation?
I delegate that decision to you
do you want me to inform the VP?
No
we should at least include
the minister of sport
No
I strongly advise against doing this,
especially on your own
it gives the impression of
autocratic leadership
you risk alienating your cabinet
and your party
your advice is duley noted
Dear Mandela, the
people want this
they hate the Springboks, they don't
want to be represented by them
yes I know, but in this
instance, the people are wrong
and as their leader, it is
my job to show them that
you are risking your political capitol
you're risking your future
as our leader
the day I am afraid to do that, is
the day I am no longer fit to lead
at least, risk it for something
more important than rugby
tell the boys I want to go
very fast
we, the executives
would like to applaud you
for your diligence
and your courage
please, join us in
our anthem
Comrades, comrades
members of the choir, we would
only interupt such beautiful music
For something truly important
Please, welcome,
President Mandela
Thank-you
I thank you, please
Smile
Brothers
sisters
Comrades
I am here because I believe
you have made a decision
with insufficient information
and foresight
I am aware of your earlier vote
I am aware that it was,
unanimous
none the less, I believe we should
restore the Springboks
Restore their name
their emblem, and their colors,
Immediately
let me tell you why
on Rogha lsland
In prison
all of my jailers were
Afrikaners
For 27 years
I studied them
I learned their language
Read their books
their poetry
I had to know my enemy before
I could prevail against him
and we did prevail,
did we not?
all of us here
we prevailed
Our enemy is no longer
the Afrikaner
they are our fellow
South Africans
Our partners
in democracy
and they treasure
Springbok Rugby
if we take that away,
we lose them
we prove that we are what
they feared we would be
We have to be better than that
We have to surprise them
With compassion
With restraint
And  generosity
I know,
all of the things they denied us
but this is no time to
celebrate petty revenge
this is the time to
build our nation
using every single brick
available to us
even if that brick comes wrapped
in green and gold
you elected me your leader
let me lead you now
Who is with me on this?
Who is with me?
12 votes,
a luxury
we only needed one more
yes than no
what if you hadn't got it?
Well you know
that is the parties decision
Sorry Mandela
but we've got problems
everywhere we look
Housing, food, jobs, crime
our currency
you can't keep interupting affairs
of state to placate a minority
I must, that minority
Still controls the police, the army
And the economy
if we lose them, we cannot
address the other issues
so, this rugby
Is it just a political calculation?
It is a human calculation
if we take away, what
they cherish
The Springboks
Their national anthem
we just reinforce the cycle
of fear between us
I will do what I must
to end that cycle
or it will destroy us
this tastes like shit man
it's not the beer
take another
everybody take one
I'd like to propose a toast
to the taste of defeat
drink it
remember this
and promise yourself,
never to taste it again
You're right, it tastes like shit
here's the schedule for
the overseas trip
(speaking Afrikans)
What did he just say?
he asked when we were supposed to sleep
as well as other basic human functions
If Mandela could do it
we can do it
in a common struggle
that has brought about our emancipation
and pushed back the frontier
Of racism
the millions of our people
say thank you and thank you again
I come here with a message
people of the
United States of America
open your markets to us
and come invest in our country
and in Japan, President Mandela
met with Japanese officials
as he concluded a grueling
trip to the far east
and in related news, it was announced
that Mandela will visit South Africa
stop it old man
It's cold man
- Good morning Mandela
- How are you?
- Well thank you sir
- Good morning sir
How is your family Hendrick?
top shape sir, how about yours?
I have a very large family
42 million
I don't think I'll walk today
we never, never ask him about
his family
but he asks about ours
all the time
Think, think of it
Separated from his wife,
his children
How often do you see them here?
He's not a saint,
he's a man
with a man's problems, he doesn't
need us reminding him of them
Good morning Mandela.
- Good morning
Thank you very much.
- Enjoy it
Very good
ahh Brenda, good morning
Good morning Mandela
I like that dress
Thank you
This is for you
What is it?
Your pay checks
you haven't been collecting them
what's wrong?
This is terrible
It's what deClerk got
plus an increase for inflation
Today President Mandela
announced, that in his opinion
his salary is too high
He's right, they're all overpaid
he has decided to donate a third
of his monthly income to charity
give me the houses and cars they give him
and I'll donate a third to charity too
Hello
hang on a minute please
yes, of course
they're lining their pockets
as fast as they can
must be his girl friend eh
Oh, he knows I'll bloody
well kill him
what?
Who was that?
well...
I told you it was his girl friend
I've been invited to tea
with who?
the President
The president of the SA rugby?
Count your fingers after he shakes
your hand boy
The President
he wants me over for tea,
week after next
you must tell Mandela that the
pass service is very bad
and too expensive
he must do something about it.
Good night everybody
Good night
What the hell does he want with you?
I don't know
you've met him before
I shook his hand on the rugby field
and you didn't even vote
c'mon, he's still the president
I play rugby, what am I
going to say to the guy
say to him, thank-you for
inviting me
what if I pull something
stupid in front of him
you won't
go ahead, I'll pick you up right here
bye
Mr. Francois
a picture please
They can not pass
see who's coming for tea?
if you want me to get his
autograph
who?
Francois Penaar
call him in
I will
No autographs, OK?
I know how to do my job, OK?
Who is Francois Penaar?
you can't be serious,
he's the captain of the Springboks
I like soccer myself
you know what they say about soccer
it's a gentlemans game,
played by hooligans
On the other hand
Rugby is a hooligans game,
played by gentlemen
ya ya ya, I've heard that one before
And it wasn't funny the first time
Can I ask you a question lieutenant?
yeah, of course
what's he like?
when I worked for the previous president,
it was my job to be invisible
This president, when he found out
I liked english toffee
he brought me some back from
his visit in England
to him, no one's invisible
That's where you wait
One of his assistants will come for you
and the bathroom's over there
if you need it
uh, OK, thanks
What are our chances
in the world cup?
I mean, for real
We'll do our best, that
I can guarantee
Office of the President
so, what is he like?
well he's not as big as he
looks on TV
and we don't stand a bloody chance
in the world cup
Mr. Penaar
right this way please
Francois
what an honor
I am so excited
Thank-you for coming to see me
thank-you for inviting me Mr President
so, tell me Francois,
how is your ankle?
my ankle?
I was told it was hurt
has it healed?
the truth is sir, you never really
play at 100%, no matter what
ahh, yes
in sports as in life, yes?
yes sir
Please, sit
take this one
looking into the light hurts my eyes
Mrs. Dreis
you are a shining light in my day
Yes sir
this is Francois Penaar
captain of the Springboks
(speaking Afrikans)
shall I pour sir?
no, no, Iwould prefer to
do it myself
Thank-you very much Mrs. Dreis
how do you like your tea Francois?
just milk, please
the English have given us many things
including brandy
But afternoon tea
That is the greatest
Here we are
Thank you sir
You have a very difficult job
I do?
I have a trading business
Captain of the Springboks
a very difficult job
well not compared to yours, Mr. President
well, no one is trying to tear my head off
while I'm doing mine
Yes sir
tell me Francois
What is your philosophy on leadership
How do you inspire your team
to do their best?
by example, I've always thought
to lead by example sir
well that is right
that is exactly right
but how to get them to be better than
they think they can be
That is very difficult I find
inspiration perhaps
how do we inspire ourselves
to greatness
When nothing less will do?
how do we inspire everyone around us?
I sometimes think it is by using
the work of others
on Robben lsland
When things got very bad
I found inspiration in a poem
a poem?
a Victorian poem
just words
but they helped me to stand, when
all I wanted to do was to lie down
But you didn't come to hear an old
man talk about things that make no sense
No, please, Mr. President
it makes complete sense to me
On the day of a big match
Say, a test
In the bus, on the
way to the stadium
Nobody talks
ah yes, they are all preparing
right
but when I think we're ready
I have the bus driver put a song
something I've chosen,
one we all know
and we listen to the words together
and it helps
I remember when I was invited
to the 1992 Olympics in Barcelona
Everyone in the stadium
greeted me with a song
at the time, the future
Our future
seemed very bleak
But to hear that song
And the voices of people all
over our planet
made me proud to be South African
it inspired me to come home and do better
It allowed me to expect more of myself
may I ask, what was the song sir?
Well, it  was Ozisikilili Africa
a very inspiring song
We need inspiration Francois
Because in order to build
our nation
we must all exceed our own
expectations
so what's he like?
he's not like anyone I've ever met before
what did he want?
what did he talk about?
Francois, it's like talking to a brick wall
what did he say?
I think he wants us to
win the World Cup
Excuse me
What do you think?
it doesn't matter what I think
Yes, it does
I think he looks like one of the policemen
who forced us out of our house
I don't like seeing you shake his hand
And I'm not the only one
you criticise without understanding
you seek only to address your
own personal feelings
That is selfish thinking
it does not serve the nation
wait please
here
Give this to your mother for me please
What is it?
It's a bracelet I found unpacking
why don't you just throw it away?
I don't have the right,
doesn't belong to me
if she left it, she meant
to throw it away
"Mrs. said you finished with the paper
ya, of course
Here we go
The World Cup is played every 4 years
16 teams qualify from around the world
4 pools of 4 teams
each playing in 90 foreign venues
around the country
2 teams will advance from
each pool to the quarterfinals
Ivory Coast qualifies
that's wonderful
According to the experts, we'll reach
the quarter finals and no further
According to the experts
you and I should still be in jail
you make a personal appearance
in the finals
and at the opening match
between Australia and Springboks
the finals will be broadcast to over
a billion people around the world live
A billion people
watching us?
This is a great opportunity
I reckon you've knocked the stuffing
out of him today
I haven't even begun
they may not be the most talented
team in the world
but sure as hell going to be the fittest
let's go again guys
Brenda
yes sir
please get the head of South African
rugby for me
right away
thank-you
Dr. Ledges wants a few words please
afternoon men
good to see you all working so hard
I have a short announcement
as part of the build up
to the world cup
you will be conducting coaching
clinics in townships all over the country
I know, I know, you've plenty
on your plates already
But this is a request from the top
the very top
Thank-you
This is complete crap man
What is this? Are we some sort
of circus act now?
they expect us to play our best
give our bloody all, then
they add to our bloody work load
What do you think about this Chester?
well, I try not to think, cause
it interferes with my rugby
See?
Talk to the Captain
you gotta make them understand that
don't have the time for this
I'm not going to talk to them
Why not?
we've become more than just a rugby team
and we might as well get used to it
this is you speaking?
Or Mandela?
you know me better than that
you know times change
and we need to change as well
Shit
ya
glad I don't live here
don't forget, we've got cameras
on us at all times
what a bloody joke
CHESTER CHESTER CHESTER
Chester, I reckon you're up
what am I supposed to do?
what you do best
lets roll
Who wants to play Rugby?
Who here knows the rules of rugby?
me
What is it? You hit another player
when the ref isn't looking
No, no, no
The first rule of Rugby
It can only pass the ball
backwards or sideways
do we practice today?
yeah
Form a line
Have fun, pasalo
Hands up
like this
I'm here so I
make it like this
Now you run
so I want you in groups of 3, OK?
And in addition to the
nationwide RP campaign
We propose that that all retail
outlets charge a fee for plastic bags
ahh, excuse me
Mr. Minister
if you'll forgive me
this sounds excellent, we'll return to it
please indulge me for one moment
while soccer is usually their
favorite sport here...
But things changed today
When a group of local kids reall took
to the Springboks in a surprise visit...
See that?
That picture is worth any number
of speeches
this is Johan Revelius
Reporting live from Cape Town airport
Where the Sprinboks' flight
has just landed
the green and gold have just one week
to put the finishing touches
to their grueling training program
And I for one, must admit
to being cautiosly optimistic
I say cautiosly because
in my humble opinion
The Springbok team has
been over practised
on the field, and over committed
off it
which makes beating a bower house
Austrailian side in next weeks opener
a tall order
Especially as this is an
inexperienced team
with a history of coming up short
in big matches
This is Live in Cape Town
returning you to the
studio in Johannesburg
around the world
objectively
What are they saying about our
chances to beat  Australia?
Everyone thinks they'll beat us
And if they do we will have to go
through England and the rest
just to get to the final
so, it is very important
that we beat Australia?
Thank-you
Mandela, the cabinet
ministers are here
to brief you on the trip to
Taiwan
Yes, I'll be right out
one week boys
want snipers on top of the stadium
and the surrounding buildings here
No problem
want those 2 approaches
completely sanitized
2 approaches  -will decide where
he comes in at the last moment
We want uniforms
plain clothes
sharp shooters
And sniffer dogs
And if you need more men, we have
an army unit on standby
we are not going to take chances
gentlemen
The President is going
to be exposed
much too exposed
Brenda
I have been studying
for the summit in Taiwan?
good
ahh, no, not exactly
test me
look like...
block out their names, see if
I can recognize them
Andre Joviur
Kevin Johnson
did I get them right?
yes Mandela
that's the way I used
to study in law school
Unfortunately
Chester is far too easy
to identify
But that will change
it must
team meeting, after dinner
gather round
what's this Francois,
homework?
make sure everyone has got one
What is this?
We need to learn this song
we can't just mouth the
words anymore
nobody cares, as long as we're
winning the matches
you're wrong, they do care
it's their bloody song,
not ours
flippin' terrorist song
they used to arrest you for singing it
now it's one of our anthems
I can't even read it or
pronounce the words
It's optional, take it if you want to
It means, God bless Africa
which, you have to admit,
we could use
Tell us, Mr. President
Have you always been a rugby fan?
ahh, people don't realize that I played
rugby myself when I was a student
it's a very rough game, almost as
rough as politics
How do you think the Springboks
will do?
I think they will do very well
Their level of commitment is tremendous
now it's been said, you used to support
any team that played against the 'boks
yes, well obviously that is no longer true
I am 100 % behind our boys
After all, if I can not change
when circumstances demand it
How can I expect others to?
Francois
Welcome, Mr. President
Gentlemen, forgive me for
interupting your work
the day before such an
important match
but I just wanted to come and wish
good luck in person
Sometimes, very seldom, as president
I'm allowed to do what I want
Mr. President, this is...
Oh I  know who this is
Andre, good luck
Brendan, good luck to you
Kevin, good luck
James, good luck
Yapi, good luck
did you ever imagine this?
how could I?
Thank-you, good luck
Good luck
Good luck to you
Good luck son
but uh, where is Chester?
he's injured sir, his hamstring
we're trying to keep it quiet
Well, will he be out
for the entire tournament?
with hamstrings, who knows
we'll miss him
the whole country will miss him
- Well gentlemen...
- Mr President
this is for you, from us
I am honored gentlemen,
truley honored
and you must know that your
country supports you completely
Good luck to you all
Thank-you sir
Francois, walk with me
I have something for you
It has helped me through the years,
I hope it helps you
Thank you Mr. President
Thank-you
it's time for bed Dada
ah, I'm going to stay  up for a while
The country is excited tonight
you need to sleep
The doctor said
the doctor has no sense of vocation
Thank-you
Do you know what's the best
thing about you being the captain?
um, the honor?
No, we don't have to share a room
no no no, I can't, I can't
I need to be really angry...
I know, it's working
What is this?
A poem
from the President
how does a poem help?
the same way your visit does,
inspiration
what happened?
we scored
We won!
we did?
Very good
What do you think?
Great, that was fantastic
you must be very happy.
Any man would be happy dancing
with a beautiful lady like you
Mr. President, you're
exaggerating
not at all, my father was
a polygamist
As you know, I am not
but when I look at you,
I envy my father
coaches room, 6 AM
6, drink up
Jones, coaches room 6, 6 AM
hey guys, I hope you're not going
to be this slow next week
what's going on?
change of place
that's what they used to do, smuggle
gravel in from the yard
throw it across the floor so they
could hear the wardens come in
can we see the President's cell?
yes, of course
Can you believe this?
the number on the door, 46664
means he was the 466th prisioner
here in 1964
we've done it up just the way it was
Come with me
Out of the night that covers me
Black as the Pit from pole to pole
I thank whatever gods may be
for my unconquerable soul
In the fell clutch of circumstance
I have not winced nor cried aloud
Under the bludgeonings of chance
My head is bloody, but unbowed
Beyond this place of wrath and tears
Looms but the Horror of the shade
And yet the menace of the years
Finds
and shall find, me unafraid
It matters not how strait the gate
How charged with punishments the scroll
I am the master of my fate
I am the captain of my soul
Dada?
sir?
What happened?
simple exhaustion, but it will
lead to worse if it's not treated
he needs a complete rest
and I don't mean simply shifting
the affairs of state to his bedroom
No phone calls, no meetings,
no visitors, no politics
you know him, he won't do that
then I'm going to put him into hospital,
in isolation
no, not yet, I'll threaten him with
hopital if he doesn't behave
I'll cancel everything
and I'll come back tonight to make
sure he's not waking
Don't cancel the trip to Taiwan,
not yet
Chester's back
Point for Green
Mandela, this is the delegation who...
I know who this is
Welcome, thank-you for
coming so far to see me
thank-you
how do you do?
I'm fine, welcome
Thank you very much
Ladies and gentlemen,
the game is delayed
this is it, let's go
International business alliances
strong industries have
developed in shipping...
um, please excuse me
yes Mr. President, of course
Gentlemen, let us continue
in ten minutes
This is good, very good
so, who is our
next opponent?
All Blacks play England tomorrow
then we'll know
I see, you will make sure that my
schedule is free for the entire match
oh yes Dada
This is good
This is very good
Why do not we do a
little work while we're here?
Just enjoy the rugby.
so let me understand this
the All Blacks are killing a team
that trashed us last year
Thanks for reminding me.
we're gonna really have to tackle
against the English
are those the judicial appointments
for the free states?
they'll keep until after the match
Here's the kick
I am the president, you know
And the conversion is good
are you watching this guy?
he's about your size
how much you suppose he weighs?
120 kilos -  Shit
same as me
Ya, but you're slow
he looks or contact every time
he gets the ball
yup
It's good for us
I will break my arm, my leg, my neck,
but I will not let that guy go
Well said
...when you pass it
grab this
Run!
still think I'm wasting my
time with the rugby?
he's in the clear
and he will...
tell the minister of sport I would
like a full report on the All Blacks
this rugby, it's still strictly
political?
oh yes, oh yes
of course
hello, hello
Francois...
don't lose them, I won't
be able to get more
thanks Francois
Wait, there is a forth
who's that for?
the All Blacks beat lreland 43 to 19
I see
they beat Wales  34 to 9
they beat Japan 145 to 17
145 points in one match?
It is a new international record
they beat Scotland 48 to 13
in the quarter finals
you saw the match with England
yes
45 to 29, and it was
not that close
They seem unstoppable
If the opposing team plays them face up,
Lomo runs wild
if they focus on Lomo, that leaves
others free. And then there's Hacca
a Maori war mask, yes,
it is very powerful
sources say half of the All Black matches
are won before the start because of it
How can we beat them?
I have the coaches number,
maybe you can call him and ask
no no, I don't want to distract their
focus, even for one minute
But how can we win?
Maybe we won't, they're favored 2 to 1
we've already exceeded all expectations
on and off the field
It is not enough, not now.
Not so close.
This country is hungry for greatness.
brought one of your Mom's
protien shakes
thinking about tomorrow?
no
tomorrow is taken care of
one way or another
I was thinking about how you
spend 30 years in a tiny cell
and come out ready to forgive the
people who put you in
Go home man, there's nothing
more you can do today
ever mentioned to you I hate the rugby?
once or twice, yes
I just want to get him through tomorrow
safely, that's all
we all do
the tickets sold out long before
the team became popular
there's not exactly going to be
the rainbow nation out there
and that's the reality
now all it takes is one idiot
trying to make a statement
Or one fool who thinks god is speaking
to him through the radio
and it's happened before but not today
Not on our watch,
and not today
We are on the spot
on this historic day
where even this early, crowd
expectation is at fever pitch
because there beloved green and gold
has managed to defy all expectations
but now they come up against a team
unlike any they have faced before
these All Blacks are possibly one of
the greates international sides ever
with a player as dominant as any
this correspondant has ever seen
final approach captain
let it be noted that I'm taking
control of the aircraft
duly noted
I take full responsibility for
what happens from now on
Do you see that jet to the east?
did they get clearance for this?
not from us
Where is he?
VIP box
get him out of there, NOW
- No time
What the hell was that?
- A win
- Yes!
Come on!
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome the
President of the Republic of South Africa
Mr. Nelson Mandela
Dr. Nelson Mandela, the
President of South Africa
...in a rugby jersey with the
number 6 on his back...
Francois, your country is very
proud of you
- Thank you sir
- Good luck
Good luck son
(radio broadcast)
Chester I want you to know your whole
country is supporting you
Good luck
Thank you sir
Good luck son
...dramatic moments, I don't think I've
ever seen so many flags in one stadium
Hi
their captain
honored sir
It is a pleasure
Nice to see you
I'm a little afraid of you
you all be careful now
thank-you
NELSON NELSON NELSON
...Dr. Mandela just lifting his cap
to the 62 thousand people...
...wonderful aerial shot of...
(anthem singing)
The national anthem of South Africa
South Africa national anthems
(anthem singing)
...what an unbelievable spectacular
year in Johannesburg
(anthem continues)
Are you okay?
Here we go.
Maybe we should
make a little wager
All your gold,
for all our sheep
I was thinking more along the lines
of a case of wine
The celebrations over, we now
come to the big game...
Come on!
(chanting)
...that's the Maori challenge, laid
down before going into battle...
Hey, get out of here
...knocked him down and stole the ball...
...put into play by New Zealand,
here's a chance on the outside...
huddle
what the heck are we doing?
Lomo is killing us
Foreward,
we must start scrumming
we must disrupt them at the first phase
we cannot allow Lomo the ball in space
he's freeking killing us,
but listen, if Lomo gets the ball...
Whoever is there, James, Yust,
hit the fucking guy, hold on to him
help will come,
help will be there
(whistles)
...they want to get the ball...
...most of the opportunities
have gone New Zealands way...
GO GO GO
listen up
first blood to New Zealand...
...an important kick for
New Zealand...
score for New Zealand
...score now New Zealand 6
South Africa 3
Come on!
BOOT IT
...South Africa in the lead
for the first time in the match...
Advantage for South Africa 9-6...
Scoring New Zealand
Half time
unsuccessful kick, the score
remains 9 - 9
that's the closing score 9 all,
there will now be a 5 minute break...
so, what does this mean?
extra time, 20 minutes
I don't think I can take it
...be a test of great character...
who's the greatest team on this field?
New Zealand 12
South Africa 9
penalty against green
too many guys off their feet
speak to your team
Heads up,
look in my eyes
Do you hear?
listen to the country
7 minutes, 7 minutes
Defense, defense, defense
This is it!
This is our destiny,
Go!
How long?
7 minutes
...an important kick...
YEAH!
tie score
Now, now!
...can hear the big man coming...
Now!
...has he got 'em?
...great play there...
(whistle)
Chester, will you lead us
in a prayer?
thanks god, for getting us into this final
thanks for no serious injuries, and
most of all, thanks for the win
Amen
Francois
a few words?
Great game, but you couldn't have done
it without the support of the 63,000 here
Ya, we didn't need the support of
60 thousand South Africans
we had the support of 43 million
South Africans
I have to thank-you for what
you have done for our country
No Mr. President, thank you
for what you have done for our country
this route is crowded
let's change to conceal
There's no hurry
No hurry at all
Mandela says there's no need to hurry
I thank whatever gods may be
for my unconquerable soul
I am the master my fate
I'm the captain of my soul.