- Hi Wilmar. How are you?
- Everything's just great.
- You're looking healthy again.
- Yes.
- Hi.
It's been ages. You're so skinny.
I've still got my love handles.
- Hi. Happy birthday, Lola.
- Thanks. Welcome.
Hi, and welcome.
- Happy birthday.
- Oh, how nice. Thank you.
- Isn't that pretty.
- Come and say hi.
I'll put it down here for now.
Wilmar's daughter?
Last time we met, you were this big.
You were out back, completely naked,
in love with a guy at the grocer's.
- Remember? The man in the deli.
- Oh, right.
- Time flies...
- He must be my age by now.
Shall we go in and...
have a drink?
Do you recognize them?
Charlotte's parents.
The girl who was so hen-pecked
in school.
Hi.
- Let's see, it's... Hanna?
- No, Mia.
That's right. How are you?
I haven't seen you in ages.
- Don't you look nice.
- I thought I'd dress up a little.
Welcome. Very nice to meet you.
My name is Lola.
- Give her the present.
- Here, happy birthday.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
- You speak Swedish?
- I speak only little Swedish.
- We speak Swedish at home.
- How long have you been in Sweden?
- Six month only.
- So you've been here in winter.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
I'd like one too, please.
- That was my husband Wilmar.
He'll say hello to you later;, he's
busy. - Thanks. Can you take this?
- Did you like the snow?
- Yes.
- There wasn't much snow.
- No, but she got to play in it.
- Everything okay with the kids?
- Just great.
- You've got two teenagers now.
- Yes, I know.
- How does that feel?
- It's fun.
It's going great.
That was a nice one.
Happy birthday, Lola.
- Come and give me a hand.
That was beautiful.
- We're awfully close.
- You're not afraid, are you?
- Eh?
- No...
Now I just need
a match that works...
Don't get too close.
Watch out. Watch out.
Watch out.
Nothing happened.
Too bad Wilmar. Next year
the grandkids will be in charge.
Aren't you funny...
Give me the flashlight.
Hang on...
- Don't get too close, Wilmar.
- I'm just going to look.
Remember, you're not sober.
Be careful, Dad.
- BANG.
- This is your day to be funny, eh?
- I knew it. I knew it.
- Dad. Dad. Are you okay?
- Dad...
- I can't look. I can't look.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
- I'm all right.
- Dad...
Mother. I'm all right.
Come here. Come on.
Emily, get over here.
Listen up, everyone.
Time for coffee and birthday cake.
- Dad, what are you doing?
- It hit you right in the eye.
INVOLUNTARY
I saw "Dear Writer, Dear Actress",
that Chekhov play you were in.
I really liked it.
I saw it twice.
- And you were so good.
- That's nice to hear.
Overall. You're so good.
I've seen a lot that you've done.
Revues, that Christmas special
where you were a constable...
- It was so funny.
- Yes, it was...
And lots of films too,
serious and funny.
And you have four kids.
How do you manage?
I don't always,
but most of the time I get by.
- Well, I'm impressed. You go, girl.
- Thank you.
- Have you heard from Hollywood?
- No, I don't think...
- Are you hoping to?
- No, I'm happy as I am.
It's a shock being on a coach with
you. I'd have thought you'd fly.
No... no, this was... the best
alternative for getting home today.
- Well, I'll see you on the trip.
- That'll be fun...
- Would you like a mint?
- Oh, thanks.
- This is my husband.
- Hi.
- Oh, I took too much.
- Don’t worry about it.
- So, how old are you, about 22?
- No, I'm 19.
- Whoa.
- But thanks for the compliment.
I didn't mean you looked old...
- Mint?
- Please.
- How old do you think I am?
- I don't know, maybe... 42?
- 42? No, actually I'm 35.
- Oh. Sorry.
That's okay. Most people
think I look younger than 35.
- If I'm wearing a sweatshirt.
- I can see that.
That's how I usually dress.
More youthful than this, anyway.
So you've got your whole life ahead
of you. What do you want to do?
I don't know, I only know
I want to really live, you know?
I want to try out
whatever I feel like doing.
Right now, I want to travel.
To Peru or Brazil...
I like horseback riding.
A friend and I, a girl I went to
school with, I thought we might...
- ...go riding somewhere.
- Do you take the horse with you?
- Right - take a horse on a plane.
- Well, it can't be easy to find one.
I'm sure we can rent them there.
- It's barely visible.
- Isn't it? Yes it is.
Good.
Show off the lace.
Yeah.
I'll raise the camera a little.
Check this out.
- I'm like, "Ooo."
- Look at that.
Get ready, get ready...
That's cute.
Let's try this.
- Like a doll...
- You or me?
You.
- My hair looks so dark.
- Your hair is not dark.
- Here, compare here and here.
- That's 'cause it's on your skin.
That's all it is.
My eyelids are shiny.
- It's cute.
- No, it's not cute.
- Why do you look good and not me?
- I don't look good.
Yes, you do.
Great that they're all
turning out so nice...
It's nice when the pictures are so
good. Hear how positive I am?
- You're a real pessimist.
- What's that?
- You're negative all the time.
- I just wish I photographed well.
- But you do.
- No, I don't.
You do too.
I'll hit you if you say it again.
I don't... OW. Brat.
You're like, "I'm so ugly.'. '
It's your attitude that's ugly.
- What should I say?
- You're pretty. You are.
- Mum taught me not to lie.
- But you are pretty.
- No I'm not, no I'm not.
- You are, you are.
Does everyone understand?
No questions?
Then I'll bring her in.
You can come in now.
There...
Can you stand here?
We're going to do an exercise.
I'm going to show you some pictures.
Each picture has two lines. Point
to the one you think is longest.
Which line
do you think is the longest here?
That one?
What does the class say?
What do you say?
- This one.
- That's the longest?
- Does everyone think so?
- Yeees.
It's not easy to see.
Try this one.
That one?
No?... What do you say?
This one.
- Do you all think so?
- Yeees.
Okay now, take your time.
Look closely.
Which line is longest?
- Do you think that's the longest?
- Not really.
You think the other one is longer,
but you picked this one. Why?
- Because everyone else does.
- That's right. Take your seat.
Do you know what we did
when you were outside?
We decided
to disagree with you.
You can go in now.
So now we're all happy.
All happy in the back of the coach.
We're having fun
in the back of the coach
What? What do you mean don't laugh?
You're laughing.
Are you wrong in the head?
- Seriously, go get it.
- "Seriously, go get it..."
- I mean it, go get it.
- "I mean it..."
Jeez, don't get
your knickers in a twist.
- Rile him up.
- Take it.
Screw that.
There it is.
What the hell is with you?
- Now now, chill out.
- What? You're the one who...
- Sit down.
- Wrestling in the aisles...
- Yeah, but you took it.
- Hey, you took my cap first.
- Surfing. I want to learn to surf.
- Yes, that would be nice.
Hang out on the beach all day
and party all night.
Get out of here
and away from boring people.
Me too. I want to get away
and have new experiences.
- Where to?
- Just away.
I've just been through a grueling
divorce;, I'd like to get away.
I understand.
It was really something.
It was like two weeks ago.
- Wow, that's recent.
- It feels like a long time.
I get home from work
and the house is practically empty.
She took almost everything.
In the kitchen
I find a note from my wife;
"I'm taking the children,
we're leaving you"...bla bla bla.
So she met someone else
and just left.
I was completely... It was the worst
thing that's ever happened to me.
I spent a week in bed - at least.
I couldn't get up, just kept crying.
Lucky for me I had my brother.
He lives close by.
So I could go there and eat and be
with his family. I even slept there.
So after that first week
I got back on my feet.
- And now I'm here, two weeks later.
- Hard to believe.
- And I don't show it, do I?
- No, not at all.
Do you have a boyfriend?
- Would you break up in a note?
- No, never.
- You just don't do that.
- No, it's immature behavior.
Yeah... I thought so too.
It's so incomprehensible. We've
known each other for eight years.
You'd think the least she could do
is talk about it if she's not happy.
That's true of any relationship.
Just leaving a note is unbelievable.
I think so, anyway.
I have it here;, I'll show you.
Look at the last sentence. I don't
even get it. Do you, as a girl?
It doesn't even fit
with the previous sentence.
It's as if she wasn't in her right
mind when she wrote it.
I... I don't know, maybe she...
Maybe you understand how she thinks?
Maybe girls think differently.
D'you think?
- I wouldn't treat anyone like this.
- No, but maybe you...
- Maybe you can interpret it?
- I...
- Shouldn't you call and ask?
- The medical hotline?
- I can't call the medical hotline.
- Why not?
If I say, "My husband was hit by a
rocket" they'll say to bring him in.
- Then he has to go in.
- He refuses.
- It's not possible.
- Of course it is.
What do we do,
drag him into the car?
Mother and I were sick one week,
stayed home from work and school
We rented lots of films, I got tons
of candy, and she drank rum and cola
We had fun all day
while others toiled away
When father came home from his shift
we innocently coughed and sniffed
That was really nice.
And funny.
- It was very good.
- And now you know the whole story.
- Here I thought you drank the rum.
- He's blamed you all along.
- You're blamed for Mum's sins.
- You're blamed for everything.
- I don't mind.
- Oh, that's good.
Damn you're hot.
- Come on, let's dance.
- No.
Ow. What are you doing.
Knock it off. Ow.
Look at them instead.
Come on, hottie.
Oo, porn stars.
- Come on now.
- No.
Come on, dance.
Shit.
Turn the music off.
Turn it off. You moron.
All over the rug. Mum's going
to kill me when she sees this.
- Damn you...
- You know I laugh when I'm upset.
You're so stupid.
- Look at this bloody big stain.
- It's not that bad.
What do we do?
What's in the drink? I bet it
tastes just as awful as last time.
- Sorry, Sara, you suck at drinks.
- No, this is the best ever.
- Thanks. Gimme five.
- Why are you making faces?
- That's disgusting.
- No, it's great.
- Don't break the window.
- I'm leaving.
- With my witch's brew?
- I'm going with your "witch".
Bye bye.
Oops, I dropped the "witch".
- What are you doing?
- I'm speaking Swinglish.
What is it?
- Johnny.
- Johnny boy.
Hottie.
Roger. Ha, his name is Roger.
Roger, you listen to me.
- Rogerrr.
- Roger rocks.
Hey.
Lars. Lasse. Lasse.
Hey, Lasse.
- Is your name Lasse?
- No.
So what is your name?
I just wondered.
It would be nice to know.
Can't you tell us?
- Say your name, say your name...
- Kenneth.
- His name is Kenneth.
- Wazzup, Kenneth.
- Can we call you Kenta?
- Kent Agent.
We'll just have to call him that.
So, Kenta. Having fun?
- Mmm.
- There now, cheer up.
- What are you doing? Did he answer?
- I'm sitting here.
- What are you doing?
- We're fucking, can't you tell?
- We're just...
- Is that a new mobile phone?
It's nice. You can use it
to take pictures of us beauties.
Lovely phone, lovely view,
and lovely girls - babes.
Loverly babes,
izzat somefink for you?
Take our picture, then.
Kenta, Kenta, Kenta...
Come on, K...
Woohoo.
I'm sure it will be gorgeous.
- What did it cost, Kenta?
- Let me take a picture of you two.
- Here, take this.
- Pose for us, Kenta.
- Pose with the hottie.
- Let's be models.
Smile now, look happy.
Smile now, open up.
That's better.
- And smiiile.
- Gorgeous.
- Move your flab.
- What flab?
- So, Kenta, young man...
- "Young man"?
Old man.
Can't you buy us some alcohol?
Of course you can.
Suit and all. Nice.
- I put one ball under my tie.
- I have it out under the suit...
- ...so it pops out when I stand up.
- You've got it all planned, Leffe.
- How is your wife doing?
- She's just fine.
- And the kids?
- Everything's fine.
- You lease your car, Leffe?
- Yes.
- I could switch to a new one today.
- You've got a 2005?
- 2005 or 2006, I'm not sure.
- You don't even know?
- Estate car?
- Estate racing car.
You know the 307 I had before
the car I had before this one?
- A sporty silver one?
- Yeah. It handles the same way.
The suit goes with the car, but the
car doesn't suit you. A family car.
Where you going, Leffe?
You can't drive - you're drunk, man.
- Let's go join the others.
- Why don't we stay and talk?
- What do you want to talk about?
- I just wanna give you a hug, man.
Now you're pushing me again.
What is it?
Why can't we stand here?
You're on top.
What the... Leffe?
Cool down now...
- Straight up the crack.
- Don't you like that?
It's all dry now.
The pants sucked it all up.
So your pants are wet?
Mine are always wet, but in front.
- Come on.
- Hang on a second...
I was thinking before...
Ugh, you're being a pain.
- Can’t we just stand and breathe?
- I don't know what you're...
Just let me go down the stairs...
- Promise you'll stay and talk.
- Of course.
What I wanted to say is,
you're so genuine.
- Come off it now.
- What, you don't believe me?
Of everyone I know, the people
I know best, my best friends.
- You're the truly genuine one.
- So are you.
I promise you,
I'll say the same thing tomorrow.
- If that will make you believe me.
- I believe you, but...
- What are you getting at?
- I mean, I'm a little drunk now.
Trying to distract me
by grabbing my balls?
- Don't you believe me?
- Yes...
- I don't know.
- What the heck was it called?
There's a priest with a grown-up
daughter who comes to him...
...and he didn't know she existed...
- Do you know it?
- No, not really.
What was the name of that film
we saw when we were in Stockholm?
- Not this time, but last time.
- What film was that?
- We saw it in Stockholm.
- A Swedish film?
- Not "A Second Chance"?
- No.
There's an actor
with a northern dialect.
- Dark, handsome... Andree.
- You mean Leif Andree.
That's the one.
Only it's not him.
He plays a priest,
who has a grown-up daughter-
- and one day
she comes into his house...
He's remarried, has three kids and
one on the way... she comes...
...and...
You don't know the one I mean?
It was really good, you'd like it.
It has a meaning, a message.
Sounds good...
Hi again.
Have you all had enough to eat?
I think we’re all here. If your
seatmate is missing, tell me now.
We don't want to leave anyone
behind. No one? Good.
We'll be leaving soon, but first
our coach driver has a few words.
I just want to say that every time
I make a stop at this lay-by...
...I inspect the coach.
Today I discovered something sad.
You're welcome to play music
and make noise-
- but I can't accept that
passengers damage the coach.
What's happened, then?
It's something in the toilet.
Something's been broken in
the toilet. It doesn't matter what.
I don't know how you act at home,
but on my coach there are rules.
- Have any of us been to the toilet?
- No.
- What's broken?
- Just a curtain rod.
It doesn't really matter what.
This is a little family business.
- Losses affect us personally.
- I see, but we didn't do anything.
I'm sorry for your family,
but I didn't break your coach.
No, no, I'm not accusing anyone.
I just think it's common courtesy...
- ...to admit having done something.
- You approached us. I'm insulted.
- Be that as it may, it's poor form.
- Bloody poor form.
- Your job is driving.
- It's pointless talking.
He's a total dumbass.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I think this is poor form. I think
whoever did it should confess.
I don't think I feel like driving on
until I find out who did it.
Next time it might be something
affecting the safety of the coach.
That's why we're going to stay here
until someone comes forward.
He can't be serious.
Drive the coach.
- Mo-ron.
- Start the coach, you arsehole.
Dad...?
Yes?
- Dad?
- Yes...
- What are you doing?
- I realized...
I realized we had... Grappa
that we bought in Italy last summer.
Dad, why don't you sit down?
You look kind of dizzy.
- Ow.
- Oh, Dad...
I'm OK. Have you seen all the space
since we put in geothermal heating.
- Careful now...
- You should have been here.
They just cut the furnace into bits.
Zip, zip. Really efficient.
- If you lay a banger in your hand.
- Why would I do that?
Listen. If you lay it in your hand
and set it off, guess what happens.
Nothing. There's a little heat,
maybe a tiny mark, but that's all.
But if you hold it like this,
then you're in trouble.
- What's that got to do with...
- Thomas, explain.
This "explosion" isn't even an
explosion; it has no force at all.
- Those rockets fly high.
- It's flash powder, it's harmless.
- What is this flash powder?
- It looks like more than it is.
- What...
- It has no explosive...
- It's like a sparkler.
- I've never heard of flash powder.
- It gives off light, that's all.
- It's like a sparkler.
It's not as explosive
as it looks.
Rockets fly way up high.
How can there be no force in them?
- It exploded on the ground.
- But it had the same force.
It's a burning force,
not a propulsive force.
- If it hits you in the head...
- Eva, listen now.
- ...it's completely harmless?
- You get so scared of everything.
And you lose your objectivity.
- Objectivity? I don't think...
- Darling...
I've been doing this since I was
a kid. It's not dangerous at all.
- Axel, stop. Slow down, what is it?
- I'll deal with this.
You calm down now.
Stay there now.
Take it easy.
- Ulf, go easy on him.
- I said I'd deal with this.
What kind of nonsense is this.
I said I wanted no trouble.
No. I said calm down.
A historic moment.
Shit, he's nervous.
Don't do it.
Good one.
Did you forget
to hold your nose, Leif?
- You work with natural medicine?
- Yeah, and I have a new method.
- You suck toxins out of the body.
- Sounds environmentally friendly.
Either you use the old-fashioned
scraper, or you suck it out.
- It's fantastic.
- The false chocolate inspector...
No, really.
I'm going to do some suction.
You want some suction?
It's perfect, you've got it out.
Get off now. Shit.
I'll piss on you.
Leffe, for god's sake.
- I've sucked on all these guys.
- Oh, great.
Doctor Dick takes the instrument...
he sucks...
My trousers fell down.
- Are you okay?
- I pulled a muscle in my groin.
Great, guys...
- Leffe runs like a dog.
- Or a Duracell bunny.
I have no energy.
- You're going to get sucked.
- What are you doing?
Olle, come on now.
Just lie down.
- Come on, guys...
- Don't leave before the bell.
- No tickling.
- Okay, okay.
Down with the fly.
I swear, I'm going to hurt you.
Knock it off.
Let go of me, damn it.
Leave my dick alone.
If you touch me once more,
you're going to regret it.
You fucking sicko.
There.
Olle, come on...
It was just a joke, Olle.
Olle, come on, it's just saliva.
Olle.
You can't be pissed off about that,
we've done... Hey...
Olle, wait.
- What the...
- He was laughing, wasn't he?
You were next to him,
he was laughing, right?
Hey...
Exactly what are your plans now?
- What do you mean?
- You stop the engine and get out?
- Are we meant to just sit here?
- What part don't you understand?
- We stay until someone confesses.
- How long do you plan to wait?
That's up to whoever did this.
- I don't get this...
- What exactly don't you get?
I think you're overreacting,
considering what actually happened.
I know exactly what's happened,
but I have to put my foot down.
- "Put your foot down" - absurd.
- Next time, say the toilet floods.
You understand, don't you?
Is it really so much to ask? Is it?
There's nothing strange about it.
Hmph. I don't know.
Normally I'd care about a ferry
timetable, but my hands are tied.
Isn't it your responsibility
to get us there on time?
Normally,
unless a situation occurs.
- So you take responsibility?
- This is silly. Can't you...
What's your name?
I want to speak to your boss.
It won't help you. I'm Henrik and
my brother and I own this company.
He's out of the country,
so you'll have to talk to me.
- So you're the boss?
- You can say that.
I'll pay you for the curtain rod,
say 300 kronor, and let's drop this.
It probably costs more,
but this isn't about money.
Great. If it's not about money,
call a cab so I can make my ferry.
Should I pay
for all the passengers then?
- I can't just drop this now.
- You've blown it out of proportion.
I understand you're frustrated.
So am I. I'm sorry.
This is how it's going to be.
Come on...
- Nooo...
- Yeees.
Come on, honey.
I don't feel great either, but you
don't see me lying on the ground -
- and being sick all over.
Come on now. I mean it.
It's no fun for me to stand here
watching you feel sick.
Do you think I'm enjoying this?
- Hello. Wake up.
- Leave me alone.
Come ON.
- Do you want me to drag you?
- Nooo...
- Come on, take my arm.
- Ow ow. I'm coming.
Now.
You smell awful.
Come. Sit down.
...now I'm just wondering
what happened...
...my son came home
bleeding from the ear...
...he was goofing off...
...with the woodworking teacher...
...are there any witnesses...
...why didn't this teacher
come and talk to me about this...
We need privacy to talk about this.
I suggest we go to another room...
Do you know how old she is?
- 45?
- 37. She looks 50.
But it's hardly strange.
- She has Axel and the twins.
- And she's all alone.
- Oh, poor woman.
- It's harsh.
I had them for two years, the twins.
It was horrible.
That's where I got my grey hairs.
God, they were a pain.
One day I sent one of them out.
And she called me that night.
Absolutely furious.
She hollered so much.
Practically hysterical. I'd only
had him sit in the hall a half-hour.
You know what Axel did last week?
He refused to do orienteering.
I spoke sharply to him, and he ran
off and ruined all the checkpoints.
I still haven't found them.
When I called her that night,
she said, "Not my boy.'. '
- "Not my boy.'. '
- Is she on disability?
- I think she worked in healthcare.
- I heard she did piercing.
Isn't it kind of beside the point to
talk about what the mother does?
There's a pupil in trouble;
shouldn't we talk about that?
We're only saying
the mother has her hands full.
That's beside the point.
A child has been hurt at our school.
Isn't it up to us to find out why?
He shouldn't feel vulnerable here.
Ulf. I don't get it.
I saw what happened in the corridor.
What you did crossed every line.
You should never do that to a pupil.
I'm talking about abuse and you're
babbling about the mother's work.
I don't understand.
I forgot my calendar,
may I see yours?
Let's see...
What's your problem?
- I want an apology.
- You keep saying that.
You want an apology?
What should I say?
Think about what you did.
Ulf. What I did was because
you mistreated a pupil.
- In your opinion.
- Even if he's a troublemaker...
...you talk to the deputy headmaster
or the other teachers.
Taking it upon yourself
to punish a pupil is not acceptable.
It wasn’t punishment, it was a
reprimand for not following orders.
Do you think
such "reprimands" are okay?
Yes, I do.
Axel is a little terrorist.
He's a danger to himself,
his friends and his environment.
He has no concept
of self-control.
This is woodworking, do you know
how many dangerous things there are?
Do you know what a hammer can do?
A knife? A saw? They're dangerous.
Axel is a danger to himself
and others.
You can't mean that.
There must be ways to keep him...
You can talk to him. Maybe he should
take sewing instead.
Right, put a needle
in that boy's hand...
No, look, we're not going to get
anywhere with this discussion.
- No, we're not, but...
- I think you need to do something.
Either you report me, or you drop it
and apologize and we forget it.
And let me deal with the staff,
so you don't have problems.
You will have problems with this
staff if you don't straighten up.
You can't just
hang someone out to dry like that.
It doesn't work that way.
Unless you set an example first.
If I blow up because I can't handle
a situation, it's my responsibility.
But you talk to me.
- You're not taking responsibility.
- Well, report me, then.
- I will.
- I only gave him a reprimand.
I showed him physically
that there are boundaries.
- A boy needs that.
- That means you crossed the line.
- I did not.
- You did.
If so, I want to hear it
from my superiors.
Fine. If you need that lesson,
then I'll just have to report you.
- Do that. And apologize.
- No.
Then there's nothing more to say.
Is there?
- This is absurd...
- Good luck. And watch your back.
Who the hell is that?
- It's a babe, right?
- You think?
She rocks a little when she walks.
- Why is she coming this way?
- Isn't that Vera?
- Isn't it?
- Is it?
Yeah, that's Vera... Olle's wife.
I'm 100% sure.
No, hang on...
- Is that really Vera?
- Yes, it's Vera.
Goddammit.
- Are you disappointed?
- Disappointed? It's weird.
You call in the middle of the night,
in tears, asking me to come.
I drove for two hours to get you,
and now you want to stay.
- It's very strange.
- I know.
- If we don't talk now we never will.
- There's no discussion. It's sick.
They held you down
and sucked your dick.
How can you feel okay
about them being down there?
- It's not okay.
- No, it's not.
And you want to stay with them
at the chalet.
- Okay. Drive.
- Don't do this for me.
You've changed your mind
because of what I've been saying.
I haven't changed my mind.
Well, once...
At least three times.
First when you called me-
- then you wanted to stay, and now
you want to go home. Three times.
Look there.
Mama's little girl,
what happened?
Her mother is going to freak out.
She's totally wasted.
- Mama's little girl.
- Linnea, wake up and join the fun.
That's it, smile for the camera.
- There.
- Let's see.
"Lay down, bitch,
and everything will be all right."
- She's doing push-ups.
- How about a dance?
- Linnea, I want to dance with you.
- "I want to dance with you, too."
This is so sick. Come on.
- Take a picture.
- Look at her.
Hey, put her down,
can't you see she's sick?
- She didn't say anything.
- Well she is.
- Don't be such a grouch.
- I'm happy as a lark.
Killjoy.
Let's see...
Watch this car.
Stupid.
You just had to do it...
What happened?
- Here he comes.
- What happened?
- You're in for it now.
- Shut up now.
Will you shut up.
Which one of you arseholes
threw something on my car?
- Did you throw something? I didn't.
- Oh, don't play dumb.
- I don't underst...
- I've got a huge dent in my roof.
- I don't know what you mean.
- We'd tell you if we’d done it.
Who else could it be?
Someone threw something on my car.
- Right, someone...
- Maybe it was one of your cans.
- Arseholes...
- I'm sorry if something happened...
You threw something on my car.
I want compensation.
You're in deep shit
if I find one of your cans here.
But we didn't do anything.
Why should we compensate him?
Shit.
Damn kids.
Let go of me.
What have I done?
- Let me go, you perv.
- Let go of her, damn it.
Hello? Are you all right?
- So what, is he gay or something?
- Eh? Leffe? Hell no.
No, no, he's married.
It's not that.
It... it's like... we did stuff like
that... or we didn't do stuff...
- Stuff like that happened before.
- When?
I don't know...
like, ten years ago...
- I mean, it wasn’t all the time...
- So you blew each other?
"Blew each other"...
that sounds so harsh.
We were just drunk. It happened,
once, that Leffe wanted to suck...
- I know how this sounds...
- It sounds freaky.
- But this was different...
- And so... you did it...
- Did you do it every time?
- No.
- Were you doing it when we met?
- No, it was ages ago.
We met much later.
- So you gave it up?
- I never did anything like that.
- I've never sucked Leffe's dick.
- I certainly hope not.
- Oh my god...
- You laugh and I feel like shit.
I'm sorry. It makes me
feel like shit to hear it.
Wouldn't you freak if I said Hanna,
Karin and I held each other down...
- That's not the same.
- What's the difference?
I... I don't know.
No, there is no difference.
You can forget your trip
to the amusement park.
That's out.
I'm here now,
can't you be happy about that?
Of course I am. But I wonder
if you realize how lucky you were.
That man could have taken
you wherever he wanted.
He could have been a sicko,
a pedophile, anything.
What if he'd dragged you into some
cellar or done something in the car?
Every day I read about awful things
that happen, kids getting drunk...
...crashing their mopeds or
meeting older men. Horrible things.
Just open the newspaper.
- Are you listening?
- Yes, but don't yell at me.
Then what should I do, Linnea?
I'm reaching out to you.
Do your parents
know about this, Sara?
- They don't know what happened?
- No, but I'm going to tell them.
- I'll be talking to them, too.
- Go ahead.
- Isn't it enough if she tells them?
- No, it isn't.
- Gee, thanks a lot...
- Linnea...
Don’t think you can do whatever you
want and that I'll be fine with it.
I don't know what you do.
Maybe you're on drugs - are you?
- No.
- Have you tried drugs? Ecstasy?
- You have to trust us.
- I can't trust you anymore.
Oh please...
What were you doing, Sara,
when Linnea was lying there?
- Were you in the park?
- Yes, I was in the park.
Didn't you see her?
- Yes...
- Why didn't you do something?
- I don't know...
- You don't know.
I don't understand. If a friend is
unconscious, you do something.
- Shouldn't you?
- Yes...
So why didn't you? Or someone else?
Weren't there were several of you?
I don't know...
Leffe, Leffe, that's you,
that's me, that's us
The little problems
that Leffe's got...
...are right for Leffe
Leffe, Leffe, that's you,
that's me, that's us
The little problems
that Leffe's got...
...are right for Leffe
Don't stop. Yes. Come on.
- Yup, one ball...
- Einstein.
- Is it that long?
- He was pulling on it.
Careful, careful.
- Olle. Take a picture.
- Just a second.
- RELAX. RELAX.
- Careful, Per.
One more time.
- Like hell.
- Man, that's scary.
Olle, smell this.
No pictures, Olle.
- No goddamn pictures.
- I've put it away.
No goddamn pictures.
- Come on.
- I said I'm sorry.
- Put the camera away.
- I've already done it.
- Olle. Olle.
- Cool it, it's gone.
- Gunilla...
- Oh my gosh, I'm late.
- Where were you on Friday?
- Working on my boat.
Thanks.
I've heard that
if there are worms in apples...
- ...it's actually good for you.
- Gross.
- It's extra protein.
- I was going to say fiber.
- Is it the worms or the wormholes?
- It's the worms that are healthy.
If you have a wormy apple,
with lots of little holes -
- and just eat it
without looking for the worms...
- ...I don't think they taste bad.
- They just melt into the apple.
- Were you fed worms as a kid?
- I ate them willingly.
- I even ate a slow-worm once.
- No. Why?
- To impress three girls.
- But they're this thick.
I put it in my mouth, and the tail
came off when I went to take it out.
No. You're kidding.
- You can't chew on a slow-worm.
- No, I just...
Excuse me, could you please
look at me as well as Ylva?
- What?
- I mean...
I... I just think that if three
people are in a room, it's...
...important to look at them.
I try to do that.
In a situation like that, to look
at both people and not just...
...shut someone out. If I just sit
here and talk like this to Ylva...
- ...it's uncomfortable for Josef.
- Definitely.
- I just thought I'd mention it.
- Sure.
I don't think Josef meant to shut
you out. I asked him a question.
I don't think so either.
- But it's something to think about.
- Absolutely.
- Is that... okay?
- Sure.
I can...
- So, I put it in my mouth...
- Right.
- I didn't actually eat it. I...
- Chewed on it?
No, no. I just had it in my mouth
for a moment.
And when I went to take it out,
the tail broke off.
Eww.
- I don't want to.
- We have to.
Come on.
It's okay.
It's best to tell the truth.
Edvin... stop that now.
Hi. I'm very sorry, but I think
we have something to tell you.
My son Edvin
was alone in the toilet before.
He doesn't usually go alone,
but my wife and I think...
- Were you in the toilet, Edvin?
- Uh-huh.
- Did you break the curtain rod?
- I don't know.
- Edvin, tell the truth.
- I promise, no one will be angry.
I don't think
you did it on purpose.
You just accidentally
pulled it down. Is that it?
- Edvin, was it you?
- Uh-huh.
- It was.
- How nice that you came forward.
- Next time, what will you do?
- Tell my dad.
He knows that.
I apologize.
That's okay.
- Oh, and we'll pay for any costs...
- Oh, don't worry about it.
Good job, Edvin.
Don't you feel better now?
- That was good of him.
- Yes, it was.
It's not an easy thing to do.
Okay then,
we're on our way.
People might think it's a piece of
cake to drive a coach.
That it's not hard at all.
I need to stay focused. Otherwise we
might end up in a ditch, or worse.
- No one wants that to happen.
- No, of course not.
And I'm fully responsible,
as opposed to a pilot, for example.
He's got a co-pilot watching things,
and a control tower.
And a computer that essentially
controls the whole flight.
He just pushes a button
and he can go for coffee.
I think so.
I think he does a little.
Pull a lever, raise the landing gear
and that's it.
The system takes care of itself.
But here,
I have to keep an eye on...
...everything.
On other drivers...
Here comes a loony.
You see a lot of them at night.
- He could be drunk.
- Or on drugs, or...
...or anything.
You see it more and more.
Translation: Jennifer Evans
Corrections: audio