Iris_(2001) ,WEB_MKV_H264_AC3[5.1](BBCFilms,Eng,Sub) 1280x718
I want you to come quick.
Don't go!
- Iris!
Iris, w-wait for me!
Just keep tight hold of me,
and it'll be all right!
You won't keep still!
I can't keep still!
I can't catch up
with you!
Speed up!
Oh!
Whoo!
Iris, you've got bicycle oil
on your ankle.
- I don't care, John.
- Oh.
- Those of you,
our guests
on whose magnificent
generosity we depend...
we really are most
frightfully grateful...
will need no introduction
to one of our most
distinguished graduates
and an honorary fellow,
Dame Iris Murdoch.
She's a noted philosopher
as well as author
of some 26 novels,
and we are honored
to have her with us today,
as well as the distinguished
Wharton professor of literature,
who has the great good fortune
of being married to her.
I need to say no more about her
for good wine needs no bush.
But she will not
mind comparison
with, say, a really fine
vintage Claret.
Dame Iris will speak to you
about the importance
of education.
Education doesn't
make you happy,
and nor does freedom.
We don't become happy just
because we're free, if we are,
or because we've been educated,
if we have,
but because education
may be the means
by which we realize
we are happy.
It opens our eyes,
our ears...
tells us where delights
are lurking...
convinces us that there
is only one freedom
of any importance whatsoever...
that of the mind...
and gives us the assurance,
the confidence,
to walk the path our mind...
our educated mind... offers.
I shall tell him
all my love
All my soul's adoration
And I think he will hear me
And will not say me nay
It is this
that gives my soul
All its joyous elation
As I hear
the sweet lark sing
In the clear air
of the day
- Yes, of course,
there's something fishy
about describing
people's feelings.
You try hard to be accurate,
but as soon as you
start to define such and such a
feeling, language lets you down.
It's really a machine
for making falsehoods.
When we really speak the truth,
words are insufficient.
Almost everything except
things like "pass the gravy"
is a lie of a sort.
And that being the case,
I shall shut up.
Oh, and... pass the gravy.
But love,
which is unsatisfying...
and real love... extreme
love... once it's recognized...
has the stamp
of the indubitable...
Ah, John. I may call
you John, mayn't I?
Meet Miss Murdoch.
Iris, my dear, John Bayley,
one of the more promising
young lecturers
in the English school.
Though I caught him out
over old-English grammar,
his weaker side, I fear,
a minor question of
Anglo-Saxon syntax.
Wine.
I mean, went down
the wrong way.
Yes, I like that.
There is a right way down,
of course.
Amazing how most of us find it
without even thinking about it.
Oh, I-I r-rarely think.
If you think about it,
you'll never find it.
Best thing to do is hang on
and trust the body.
I do.
- Human beings
love each other...
in sex, in friendship,
and when they're in love.
And they cherish
other beings...
humans, animals, plants,
even stones.
The quest for happiness
and the promotion of happiness
is in all of this
and the power
of our imagination.
I'm writing a n-novel.
I don't suppose you have
the time or the inclination
to even r-r-read
a n-novel.
I've written one.
It's going to be published.
And I'm writing another.
Oh. C-C-Can I...
can I read it?
No one has read it.
None of my friends.
What's it about?
About?
It has something
for everyone.
A b-bit like Shakespeare.
Perhaps, yes.
Please don't talk
to anyone about it.
N-n-n-no.
Of c-course not.
I-I-I w-won't
t-tell a soul.
Every human soul has seen,
perhaps even before
their birth,
pure forms such as justice,
temperance, beauty,
and all the great
moral qualities
which we hold in honor.
We are moved towards
what is good
by the faint memory
of these forms,
simple and calm and blessed,
which we saw once
in a pure, clear light
being pure ourselves.
Whole grain.
Do we have whole grain
or something other?
What is "whole"?
Is it something in itself
or does it have parts?
Oh, spaghetti.
If you have a whole,
you have a whole.
Ooh, sausages.
You and me is a whole.
If you toddle off, there's a
hole in the whole, or if I do.
But a whole can't be broken.
It just forms another whole.
- Baked beans.
- Baked beans!
Do you want premium points?
Do we deserve them?
Do you want bags?
Bags, yes. You know,
it's all around us...
people like you
and me talking nonsense.
I know.
Bag for life?
For life?
That's what it says.
We have to ask...
give you the choice.
Ooh, rather.
You just have to listen...
that's the job.
You call it a job, but it's
like music, what you do.
You live with the angels,
speak their language...
the music of the spheres.
Nowadays, the only language
anyone really understands
is pictures.
Paint the picture.
See,
now I'm bagged for life.
Love's the only language
everyone understands.
Ooh, love, yes.
I can read it,
but I can't speak it.
Mmm! Ooh.
My coat's
caught on your chair.
Mnh!
And the captain said
to the two weevils,
"Which would you
rather have, Mr. Smith?"
"The bigger one, sir."
"Wrong, Mr. Smith, wrong.
"In the Navy,
you should always choose
the lesser of
the two 'weevils.'"
Patrick O'Brian...
"Between two evils,
always choose the one
you haven't tried before."
Mae West..." Oh, my vest! I tore
my vest again this morning."
You must get
some new vests.
Jolly good.
You must get
some new vests.
I just said that.
You're always saying that...
that you just said something.
Me too.
Good job. You reminded me
I had two lectures today.
You remembered.
No, but I remembered to
apologize for the one I forgot.
They were very sweet
about it.
Glad not to have to listen
to you, I expect.
Oh, I'm sure.
They'd have been delighted
to have listened to you.
I always have been.
Iris.
John.
Oh!
Thank you.
Janet! Janet!
Oh, my God, Iris!
Am I late?
Don't be silly.
Oh, no, it's the Hokeycokey.
Everything'll be over.
John, wait.
Oh, dear.
Oops. Sorry.
Cha-cha-cha.
Cha-cha-cha!
Ch... ooh!
Cha-cha-cha.
- Thank you!
- You too!
That was my husband.
Cha-cha-cha.
Are you with Iris?
H-H-Hoping so.
- You know, we have...
- I-I thought we had.
- Nearly met.
- A-Are you a friend of Iris?
Yes.
She seems
to have a lot of...
Do do do-do do do
Janet Stone, John Bayley.
How do you do?
H-How do you do?
Shall we?
What are your rooms like?
A-Adequate, thank you.
- I'd like to see them.
- Oh.
Do you... do you have
a lot of friends?
Is a list of my friends
necessary?
I-I just wondered
if you had many.
There aren't many people that
one wants to know one. Do you...
Whoop!
Ahhhhhh!
Iris!
Y-You might fall.
W-Would you like some
more c-champagne?
That would be nice.
I-I've had some
s-since Christmas.
It does keep, doesn't it?
I-I s-s-shouldn't
be doing this.
- What?
- H-Having women
in my r-room.
It's...
it's not p-permitted.
I wouldn't say
you "had me" exactly.
Have you danced before?
It was a-all right,
wasn't it?
Oh, I think so.
I-It b-b-broke the ice,
so to speak.
- Ice.
- What?
Oh! Oh, it'll do.
Aren't you particular
about words at your college?
I-I-I'm only here on
a s-s-sufferance, really,
as a-a tutor and guide.
I-I get all the Americans
and Frenchmen to m-mother.
You love words,
don't you?
If one doesn't have words,
how does one think?
S-Shall I do that?
W-what... What is your
n-n-n-novel about?
About?
How to be free.
How to be good.
Ooh!
And how to love.
Well, that's all...
a-all there is, I'd say.
Well, l-language is all
v-very well, you know,
but it's not the only way of
understanding each other.
There's...
t-there's sight and...
and smell and... and...
a-and touch, of course.
I-I l-love your nose.
It's snub.
Snubby.
S-Snubby, snubby.
Snubby, snubby, snubby.
Let me do that to you.
Take off your jacket.
I-If we were, a-as it were,
m-married,
w-we could d-do this
all the time... perhaps.
We should be doing it
nearly all the time.
Yes, but i-if...
Thank you.
Look.
Ah!
You stopped
with your working.
Yes, well, I don't mind.
How's it coming along?
It's harder to write than
all the others... much.
Have you noticed?
Just that you've seemed...
puzzled every now and again.
That's it, yes.
Puzzled.
Puzz... pu...
It's a funny word.
All words are like that when
you take them by surprise,
aren't they?
Have you got a title?
A lot of trees
seem near.
We must stop it.
What to do?
The window, John.
The window!
We must stop it!
No, see?
It's gone.
We all worry about going mad,
don't we?
How would we know...
those of us who live
in our minds anyway?
Other people would tell us.
Would they, John?
Sorry.
I don't want to set
the world on fire
John Bayley.
I just want to start
a flame in your heart
In my heart
I have but one desire...
I haven't seen her
for ages.
Oh, j-jolly good.
Nice.
Takes all sorts.
N-Not that I...
We're all... we're all
m- men at St. Anthony's.
Do... do you like women?
I-I mean, do...
do w-w-women like you?
You mean lesbians?
Yes.
Would it bother you
if they did?
Oh, the s-same thing
happens with me...
with h-h-homosexuals,
I mean.
And do you
go to bed with them?
Lord, no.
At the college,
somebody once said to me,
"Old-fashioned lesbians
of the very highest type."
And... and d-do...
do you go to bed with them?
Tsk. Wh...
Dame Iris.
It's this way.
- She's written philosophy
and plays and poetry,
but her novels are her
lasting literary legacy.
Iris Murdoch is acknowledged
as the foremost English novelist
of her generation.
A little excessive,
don't you think?
What do you reckon?
Shall I take that again?
Her novels embrace
the subjects of freedom
and what it means to be good.
Dame Iris?
...in the successes
and failures of love.
She's written philosophy
and plays and poetry,
but her novels are her
lasting literary legacy.
People, of course,
are very secretive.
And, for many reasons, want to
appear what we call ordinary.
Everybody has thoughts
they want to conceal.
Perhaps even quite simple
aspects of their lives.
People have obsessions
and fears and passions
which they don't admit to.
I think any character is
interesting and has extremes.
It's the novelist's privilege
to see how odd everyone is.
- In your novels,
you yourself are very exact
in your use of language.
But in general terms,
do you think the language
is becoming debased?
Reading and writing
and the preservation
of language and its forms
and the kind of eloquence
and the kind of beauty
that language is capable of
is something terribly
important to human beings
because... this is connected
to thought.
If children are not taught...
W-What did you say?
D-Did you ask...
I was asking about
the importance of language.
- John!
John!
- John? John?
- Iris?
John?
- Oh, you're there.
- What is it?
I'm back.
M-Much earlier
than I thought.
Yes, I came straight back.
I didn't know why I was there.
You were going to do
an interview.
- What interview?
- I don't know.
So, um...
And see your publisher?
Was it your publisher?
So I came back.
I didn't expect you back
for ages.
- Has she rung?
- I didn't answer.
It was Nora!
Iris, Nora's dead.
Oh, so she is.
Oh, that is sad.
Oh, well, never mind.
Must have been Ed.
What for?
Oh, yes, my book.
Oh, so I came back.
- What is, uh...
the name
of the prime minister?
Oh, me? Are you asking me?
Yes, I am.
I know.
Okay, what is the name
of the prime minister?
I don't know. Ask John.
Surely it doesn't matter.
Okay, well,
no, not really.
Someone will know.
Who would you like
to see?
I mean,
is there anyone...
I don't know.
Shall I look up some names?
Talk to someone?
I've got a lot of ideas,
but they won't come together.
It happens all the time...
forgetting names.
So, does it happen
all the time?
I mean, you know, does
she mean writer's block?
I suppose she does, but...
Iris can always write,
doctor. This is...
- Oh, I know.
- Iris is a person...
Yes, yes, but
it doesn't work like...
Surely in
her case... a- a woman
with a f-first-class mind.
We will
have to be certain.
There'll have to be
tests, scans.
I don't think I can...
I mean, it's a little
beyond my competence.
Iris finds her new book
v- very tiring and difficult.
Basically, I'll
arrange something.
Iris has
a very clear mind.
Mine's a muddle,
but not hers.
She does everything...
always has.
Food, shopping,
tickets for things.
I-I never know
how she m-m-manages
and does her b-books
as well.
Well, they can
get you help.
N-no, no, no, no,
n-nobody would suit.
There's
a very good place...
a specialist nursing home...
Vale House.
- Not necessary.
- Not yet.
- I'm sorry.
- N-N-Not your fault.
Well, uh... take care.
Goodbye, doctor.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Iris?
I'm sure the country
won't go to the dogs.
Not knowing the prime minister's
name's not a capital offense.
Absolutely.
I know the names
that matter.
You'll be all right.
Well, I will be
if you stop worrying.
I've got a book
to finish.
Oh, Tony Blair...
so there.
Iris, are you
comfortable?
I'm going to start
the scan now.
Just keep
nice and still.
Try to relax.
It'll take
about 15 minutes.
John.
I'm very sorry.
Is Iris still...
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I don't know what's
going to happen, Janet.
I've left the car outside.
The engine's running.
- Won't be a mo.
- Right.
- See you out there.
- Yes.
John, I'm frightened.
Everyone's doing
their best.
Janet's got the car.
It'll be...
- It's done.
- You're finished?
I thought
you were c-close.
So far, but it hasn't made
any difference.
Here's to it.
Just try
and keep working.
- You must.
- I will.
And here's
to the next one.
Just keep working,
keep talking,
keep the words coming.
K-Keep at it.
I shall come more like
a deprived animal
if I can't write...
be like a starved dog.
No. Keep at it.
I'll keep you at it.
I feel...
as if I'm sailing
into darkness.
A...sinuituis.
An...i...mal.
Toothbrush.
Uh...
Uh, no.
Yes.
Por...
P... no.
Tennis thing.
God.
Iris is getting t-tired,
I'm afraid.
John.
Can we have the blinds?
Dame Iris,
thank you very much.
Thank you.
Well done.
Dame Iris,
thank you very much indeed.
It was so kind of you
to come, Dame Iris.
Thank you. I like it.
Thank you very much.
Is it any help?
What, to us?
Yes.
It's... implacable.
What does that mean?
It means inexorable.
I know
what the word means...
Um, to me... to us.
You see, words have meant
everything to her.
They will still mean
something... some thought.
It can't just be
dead b-birds dropping.
I know what it means,
and it doesn't surprise me.
It frightens me, but...
and then sometimes,
it doesn't frighten me,
and that's just as bad,
because that's it winning,
isn't it?
N-n-no, no.
No, it's n-not.
It won't win.
It will win.
There.
That's very kind.
- Whoo!
Young - Iris!
Iris, wait for me!
Just keep tight hold of me,
and it'll be all right!
You won't keep still!
I can't keep still!
I can't catch up
with you!
Speed up!
Oh!
Whoo!
Oh, good morning.
Oh. No.
Uh... I...
I think it's the...
person who brings
the post, John.
Yes, it is.
Yes.
John? So sorry.
Thank you
very much indeed.
Thank you.
So sorry.
There. There.
Go on.
Go on, go on,
go on, go on, go on.
It's only the postman.
Don't repeat everything,
puss.
It's only the postman.
It's for you!
It's your book!
What's that?
Your book!
It's only the postman.
It's your book!
Isn't it
perfectly splendid?
Well, why don't you
look at it?
It's only the postman.
Damn.
Stop nudging up to me
like a water buffalo.
I have a lot to do.
Lots to do, Iris.
See what I've done now?
It's not your fault.
Not your fault.
Sorry. Sorry.
It's only the postman.
Yes, all right!
It's only the postman!
Sorry. So sorry.
There's lots to do.
Which side do I go?
-
Ask me my three main priorities
for government,
and I tell you... education,
education, and education.
John! John! Why does
he keep saying that?
- What does he mean?
- By what?
"Education, education,
education."
H-He means learning.
Everyone g-getting
enough of it.
Why does he
keep saying it?
Politicians have to
keep repeating things
to make themselves heard.
They have to be
like travelers
eating sheep's eyes
with B-Bedouins.
They have to do anything
to make themselves liked.
Why does he want to eat
a sheep's ear?
- Shall I turn it off?
- No.
We could go for a swim tomorrow
if it's n-not raining.
- No.
- Yes. You love water.
When you swim,
you love it.
Swim...
swim is good for you.
When are we leaving?
Not today.
Are we going to London?
No, we're going
for a swim.
When are we leaving?
Not today.
Iris...
Iris, wait for me.
You dirty old man.
Hello!
There we go.
No, Iris,
not with your socks on.
Your socks!
Whoa!
Look. Look. Look.
Come along.
Come on, come on,
come along.
Go on.
Ooh.
Oh.
Oh, yeah?
Ah!
Give me your hand.
That's it. Give me your hand.
No, no, don't...
don't pull me in!
You're all right.
I won't let you go.
Let's get you dry.
You're all right.
Come on. Here.
Up your hands.
Let's get you warm.
That's it.
Come on. That's it.
No, Iris. Iris!
Just put your...
like this, up high. Up.
- Let's go now.
- Let's get your head
through.
- As soon as you got
your head in.
- Let's go now!
- Iris, as soon as we've
got your head in!
- No. No.
Iris! As soon as
you've got... Come on.
- Let's go now!
- Come on, put your head down.
Where's my petticoat?
- Here.
- Ah.
Are you sure
he's expecting me?
Maurice.
I brought John.
You said I might.
Did I? And did
you say you would?
Yes.
Well, come in.
- Maurice Charlton.
- J-John Bayley.
Isn't it hot?
Yes, it is.
I've got just the thing
will cool.
I imagine
your friend Maurice
is hoping to have
his wicked will, is he?
Not today is he.
You and I are much the same age,
aren't we, John?
Yeah, I-I think so.
Does it matter?
No.
This is not important,
i- is it?
What Maurice means
is that most of my real...
my other friends
are older than me.
Much older.
Yes, and there's
a very good reason for that,
isn't there?
Is there? What?
She likes people
with a bit of a past.
She uses them...
don't you?
No, I don't.
For your novel.
Don't you, Iris?
- I-I haven't read it.
- Haven't you?
Neither have you, Maurice,
so don't play games.
Nobody has read it.
The gentle lady hasn't yet
bestowed her favor on anyone.
I-Iris doesn't like
to talk about it.
I know that, too, Iris.
That's because it's full
of people she knows...
all these masters of thought
you're so chummy with.
Bound to be.
We all know.
Isn't it, Iris?
No, it isn't, but you can
think what you like.
You know nothing about it.
Nobody knows but me.
And... I'm not telling.
I thought
it was a secret.
I mean, I know Iris
doesn't want it talked about.
Come on, Iris.
I'm sure we'll all
recognize ourselves.
I don't see how you...
anyone... can.
They won't.
T-T-They won't.
I hate that sort of thing.
I won't ever do it.
I don't see the point of
writing a novel that's
autobiography.
There's no fun in that.
T-They won't see
themselves, you know?
D-Don't people
w-written about in novels
always s-see themselves
differently?
I'm sure they do.
W-Who was it who said,
"You can use anyone
you like in a novel
"as long as you
drop it in somewhere
that they're good in bed
"e-even though...
...they might not be"?
Evelyn Waugh.
"And so to bed"...
Samuel Pepys.
So, have you granted your favor
to John?
Told him
who's in the novel?
We h-have other things
to talk about.
No one has read
my novel...
no one but the publisher.
It doesn't matter.
Well, it does matter.
I-I f-feel let down.
Am I not a part,
s-some s-small p-part
of your life?
You were very gallant.
V-Very stupid.
No, John.
Will you come in?
Have you been
e- entertaining?
Yes.
All these people.
And to think
I chose you, well...
obvious lack of...
I mean, I thought that
I fought no competition.
What's this?
A friend made it.
Oh, is she a c-cook,
your friend?
No, he's a philosopher,
but his real interests
are cooking and telephones.
I'd like you
to read this.
I was rather afraid
you might not like it.
T-Thank you.
I value your opinion.
Perhaps it's time
we made love.
Yes?
Yes.
That's what I thought.
Have you got
a French letter?
A rubber thingy.
Oh.
Lord, no.
Well.
We'll just have to be
careful.
I-I don't...
don't exactly...
It will be easier
if you take your trousers off.
Yes.
Yes, of course.
I've never...
I'm a r-rather
late s-starter.
My brother used to have to
t- tie my shoelaces for me
till I was 7.
I-I-I don't know if...
I do.
It'll all go...
...swimmingly.
- Oh!
- Jump!
- Aah! Help!
- No! No! No!
No, no, no, no!
No, Iris!
Iris! Iris! Iris!
No! No!
No! No! No!
No! No, help!
Help!
I'm trying to help you!
S-S-S-So sorry.
Please, don't, Iris.
You have n-nothing
to be sorry about.
It would be unfair,
and I couldn't bear it.
We should be saying
s-sorry to you...
and n-not just sorry,
but...
S-Shall I read to you?
Shall I?
"Occupied in observing
Mr. Bingley's attentions
to her sister,
"Elizabeth was far
from suspecting
"that she was herself b-becoming
an object of some interest
"in the eyes
of his friend.
"Mr. Darcy had at first
scarcely allowed her
to be pretty. "
I... wrote.
Yes, my darling,
clever cat.
You wrote books.
Books... I wrote.
You wrote novels...
wonderful novels.
I wrote.
Such things you wrote...
special things...
secret things.
Do you know
many secrets now, Iris?
You have shown me a map
of Iris' b-brain world, empty,
and tell me that
its hidden mysteries
and all the unknown life
in there has gone,
has been wiped.
How, then, can she say things
of such a terrible lucidity?
Which bitterly empty jungle
does that come from?
We don't know.
Not we.
You... you don't know.
D-Don't hide, please.
Is it not
r-remotely possible
that what Iris says is
of some c-consequence, yes?
Yes, perhaps.
So, perhaps, we ought to
l-learn her language
before the lights
go out.
The lights will go out.
Yes, of course,
they will.
You all keep telling me...
us... that.
I know that. She may
even know that herself.
Iris!
I'm sure
you could write it.
Just get one word down.
Persevere.
Iris, your notebook!
No, wait!
No, no, no, no.
Come. Come.
That's it. There.
Come on. Come on.
You walk...
you read...
paddle in the sea...
...then you'll write.
Be just like
the old days.
John!
Iris... Mama.
- Look who's here,
Iris.
Look who's here.
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Shhhhh.
Yes, Iris... sea.
I thought we'd walk
to calm her down a bit.
She has an idea
for a novel.
Hello, Iris.
- Hello, Iris.
Talk to her,
Janet.
Hello, Iris.
Sea's a bit cold
for swimming.
Stay as long as you like.
There's plenty of room.
You're not to worry.
Oh, we don't want to be
a nui...
No, you're not.
She's as much of a mom
as anyone.
Give her
a bit of a rest.
Can't rush around
these days, John...
tummy trouble.
- Is she ill?
- She gets tired easily.
She's really not...
what do we do?
We just talk to her,
say things to her
that she can write...
she can, you know?
It's all right,
is it, John?
You know,
it'll get better
as you get to know
each other better.
I-Iris has got
more than one world
going on inside her head...
a secret world.
Until another book
comes out.
I'm the only friend
that knows of her secret world.
Oh, John.
No, no. It's like living
in a fairy story.
I'm the young man in love
with a beautiful maiden
who disappears into
an unknown and mysterious world
every now and again,
who always comes back.
- Iris! Look!
Iris!
Look! He's got
his clothes on!
He's got his clothes on!
- He's got his clothes on.
He's got his clothes on.
Seems very sensible
to me.
Janet,
are you all right?
I'm absolutely fine, John.
I'm fine.
I thought I'd get her
to sign this.
Anything...
anything is fine.
Just get her to write.
Does she know anything
about her past...
her career, work,
friends?
S-Something
of a c-closed book,
but it's there.
I know it.
- Oh, they look
wonderful.
Well done, puss.
Good to see your book
so well received, Iris.
Yes, wasn't it?
You thought you'd never
finish it, didn't you?
I read her the reviews.
I read you the reviews,
Iris.
You hated me doing it
before.
Would you sign your new book
for me, Iris?
Like postcards, do it at once,
or you don't.
Please.
I see an angel.
I think it's you.
- De nos amours
Que reste-t-il...
They're under water now.
There are some drugs,
aren't there, Iris?
They don't last long.
When the f-friendly f-fog
disperses,
there yawns the precipice
before you, doesn't it, puss?
They're beautiful.
Horrible, isn't it?
Horrible.
Horrible thing,
you there with your toes
at the edge of the precipice.
You can say
anything you like
as long as you m-make it
sound like a j-joke.
Oh, don't, John.
That's cruel.
That's where you're wrong.
It's not cruel, it's nothing,
because it's not understood.
She's in her own world now.
It's perhaps
what she's always wanted.
... et dans un nuage
le cher visage
De mon passe
Come on.
Let's go in.
Que reste-t-il
de nos amours
de ces beaux jours
Une photo, vieille photo
De ma jeunesse
Que reste-t-il
des billets doux
When do we go?
Des mois d'avril,
des rendez-vous
Un souvenir
qui me poursuit
Sans cesse
Bonheur fane,
cheveux au vent
Baisers voles,
reves mouvants
Que reste-t-il
de tout cela
Dites-le-moi
Un petit village,
un vieux clocher
Un paysage si bien cache
Et dans un nuage
le cher visage...
Chin up, John.
Janet.
Yes, puss. Yes.
Going, going.
Now you go.
Soon.
We'll... we'll go soon.
Now. Now.
Who is it?
Hello? Hello?
Are you there?
Where this?
Soars, enchanted
I hear
the sweet lark sing...
How much is that doggie
in the window?
The one
with the waggly tail
How much is that doggie
in the window?
I do hope that doggie's
for sale
Bravo! Bravo!
Another! Another!
Sing your mother's song!
Sing your mother's song.
My soul's adoration
And I think you hear me
Soars, enchanted
I hear
the sweet lark sing
Da-da-dee-dee
of the day
It is this
that gives my soul
All its joyous elation
As I hear
the sweet lark sing
In the clear air
of the day...
Dear thoughts
are in my mind
And my soul soars,
enchanted
As I hear
the sweet lark sing
In the clear air
of the day
For a tender
beaming smile
To my hope
has been granted
And tomorrow
he shall hear
All my fond heart
can say...
I hear the sweet lark
sing in the...
Come, gentlemen.
You shall have to do
better than this.
Aren't you a bad cat?
- And tomorrow
he shall hear
All my fond heart
can say
- Teletubbies!
Morning.
Good morning.
Oh, thank you.
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
It's only the postman.
- Time...
...for Teletubbies.
- Tinky Winky
- Eh-oh.
- Eh-oh
Eh-oh.
It's only the postman.
Teletubbies
Tinky Winky
Dipsy
Laa-Laa
Po
Teletubbies...
- Uh-oh!
- Where have
the Teletubbies gone?
Remember Proteus!
- What about Proteus?
- I'm like Proteus.
You've got to keep hold
of me the way Hercules
kept hold of him,
even though he changed into
a lion... and a fish...
and a snake.
Whoo!
- I-I-I'm worried
about the r-river.
We swim.
You never know, sir.
I have, of c-course, looked
everywhere here already.
Young -
Everything you do...
everything you say,
write...
you do it superbly...
and you're always going to,
all your life...
Whatever you turn
your hand to. I-I know it.
A-And I know you must feel
that I d-don't belong
in your world.
I don't.
Ahh! Ahh!
Where?
Between the soup
and the baked beans.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you so much.
I caught her
before she got to the checkout.
She's been g-gone for hours.
I thought I'd never see
her again... n-never.
Well, all is well, then.
Please,
d-do tell me your name.
I'm Maurice, John.
Iris's friend.
I was a witness
at your wedding.
Oh.
Well,
I'm late for a meeting.
M-Maurice.
S-So sorry.
So sorry.
W-Were you trying
to get away from me?
D-Did you want
to leave me, Iris?
Please.
Young -
I-I f-feel as if I don't
know anything about you!
- When you
know everything about me,
then I'll be dead.
He's a professor
of ancient history.
They have
a m-malign influence
on you, I think.
They all have...
all your friends.
He's a teacher.
A master of thought.
Oh, you two talk, do you?
Y-you master thoughts together?
We make love,
yes, but that's not
the important thing.
Then he goes home
to his wife in London.
Does it frighten you?
I f-feel that I'm just
s-standing in a long line
of suitors
waiting for a kind word.
I always give you
a kind word.
You must accept me
as I am.
And I'm to be kept in my box
o-or not kept at all?
Nothing matters
except loving what is good.
Am I good?
Just...
keep tight hold of me,
and it'll be all right.
Who are you with
now, Iris?!
Who is it?!
We're lost!
We're lost! We're lost!
There's no reason for this!
And if there is,
I don't know it!
I hate you, Iris,
you stupid cow!
I bloody loathe you...
every bloody inch of you!
All your friends
are finished with you!
I've got you now!
Nobody else has you anymore
except your fucking best friend,
Dr. Fucking Alzheimer
with all his fucking gifts!
I've got you now,
and I don't want you!
I've never known anything
about you at all,
and now I don't care!
Ohh. Ohh.
- I think
it's time I told you
about
some of my friends...
the people in my past,
of my heart and...
and not.
Oh, dear.
Ought I to t-take notes?
There was a friend
who was a student with me.
No, he can wait.
He was not the first person
I went to bed with.
That was Harry.
Then there was Roger,
who wanted to marry me.
And Oscar, who said
he couldn't live without me.
And Tom...
who far too clearly could,
but...
so, the student friend I had
resisted going to bed with
joined the army
during the war
and promptly asked me
to marry him for...
he was certain
he was going to be killed
and wanted me to have
the widow's pension.
Yes, I know.
They all said that.
Anyway...
I didn't want
to marry him...
but I did go to bed
with him.
I... I thought that best
before he went off to fight
because you never know.
Anyway, he w... he was killed,
my student friend,
and we weren't married...
so no pension.
There.
I-It wouldn't have been much,
anyway, I know,
because I had friends killed.
Their wives got very little...
get v-very little.
Is that all...
I-I mean, roughly?
What about the f-friends
in your other world?
You know more about me
than anyone on Earth.
You are my world.
Thank you.
A-After all that,
I r-rather hoped
it might be time for me
to get my kind word.
-You don't need to do it
on your own.
Vale House is very good.
No, no, no, no, no.
You're exhausted,
you know that.
Of course I am!
It's something that we share!
We're in
a s-state of g-grace.
I think
we understand each other.
What do you think?
I don't know.
There's always help
if you need it.
Isn't there any help
for her?
What? Sorry?
- Sorry?
- Nothing.
Janet's dead, Iris.
They want me to say a few words,
but I can't think of any.
No, no. No, Janet...
Janet's dead, Iris.
I m-miss Janet very much.
I m-miss Janet
because I used to store up
funny things to tell her
had happened to us...
things I could no longer
tell Iris.
Another friend visited us
in Oxford overnight, recently,
and I found her
cleaning the bath.
I said, " Oh, please,
T-T-There's no need."
She said, " Oh, yes, there is.
I want to take a bath."
I was hoping to be able
to tell Janet that story.
S-She would have enjoyed it.
S-She would've laughed...
I mean, I think.
Anna Karenina...
Tolstoy, you know...
went on her way
to the station
to throw herself
under a train...
sees something funny
which she thinks to tell
Vronsky, her lover, about.
We all do it.
I do it with Iris and Janet...
all our friends.
But then, Anna thought,
that she wouldn't be seeing
Vronsky again
because she was
about to kill herself.
Y-You don't want to hear this.
Janet didn't kill herself.
But if there's one thing
that would have prevented Anna
from t-throwing herself
under a train,
that would be it...
the... the thought
of t-telling something funny
to t-the man she loves.
Well, t-the love is over.
Oh...
Life will...
soon be over.
That's all.
Goodbye, Janet.
No! No! Janet!
Jan... Janet!
Janet!
It's all right, Iris.
Janet! Janet!
Help! Help! Help me!
Help me!
Calm down. Calm down.
Calm down.
Janet!
Wrong! Wrong!
No, Iris! Stop it, Iris!
Wrong driving!
Stop it, Iris!
No! Not house!
No! No!
Them! Them!
Iris!
Puss!
My old mouse!
My old cat-mouse!
Where are you?!
Oh!
Ohh!
I...
love...
you.
Oh, little mouse!
I know you do.
I used to be so afraid
of being alone with you.
Now I can't be without you.
Let's get us home.
And then there will be
tomorrow...
and the next day...
and the next...
and on we go.
Easy.
Closer and closest
together.
Oh, your ring.
It's so worn now.
Where did you get it?
From a pawn broker's.
I like things
that are worn down...
just wear, wear, wear...
until they go.
- We've, uh,
had a bit of luck.
The usual thing, I'm afraid...
somebody's died.
Iris...
D-D-Do you have a smile
for Dr. Gudgeon?
No?
No.
So...
the time has come.
You knew it would,
Professor Bayley.
Yes.
She d-didn't have a smile
for you today.
Yes.
Well,
we must make a start.
- What d-do I do?
- Nothing anymore.
Vale House
is a very friendly place.
I was surprised...
well, I mean,
this is one of the best...
more difficult to get
into than, well, Eton.
Taxi for Vale House.
Yes.
The lady's on the s-stairs,
but I can't get her down.
Shall I?
Y'all right, my love?
We're goin'
for a little drive.
That's all right,
isn't it?
What's your name, then?
Iris.
Yes, it's Iris.
All right, then, Iris.
You'll be all right,
my love.
Come on, upsy-daisy.
There you go.
Lovely.
- Human beings
love each other...
in sex, in friendship,
and when they're in love.
And they cherish
other beings...
humans, animals, plants,
even stones.
She'll be fine, now,
won't ya, Iris?
You can visit
any time you like.
Come all day
if you want to.
Stay the night.
That's all right.
We can make arrangements
for you to do that any time.
It was s-so q-quiet...
when she died.
Do you know, I-I thought,
"I wouldn't mind doing that
myself"?
I h-had a joke to tell her.
It wasn't a very good one,
but she'd have laughed.
- We need to believe
in something divine
without the need for God,
something we might call love
or goodness.
As the psalm says,
"Whither shall I go
from thy spirit?
"Whither shall I flee
from thy presence?
"If I ascend unto heaven,
thou art there:
"If I make my bed in hell,
behold, thou art there.
"If I take the wings
of the morning,
"And dwell in the uttermost
parts of the sea;
"Even there shall thy hand
lead me,
and thy right hand
shall hold me."
- Dear thoughts
are in my mind
And my soul soars,
enchanted
And tomorrow he shall hear
All my fond heart can say