In the name of God
Wait.
IRON ISLAND
It's old,
but it's in good shape.
The rent is reasonable too.
It comes with everything.
See.
It stands like a rock.
Meraj!
Give me that megaphone.
Here you go, Captain.
Meraj!
Where the hell are you?
Lower the lift!
Hey, Meraj!
Let go!
What's the matter?
What's wrong with you assholes?
Fighting like animals.
This bastard wrote to my sister.
He's lying, I didn't.
You've fucked up... and you too.
Haven't I told you
to stay away from this girl?
If I catch you fighting
one more time
I'll throw you in the sea.
Go home.
Get to your work!
Hurry up. Let's go!
Meraj, I've told you
not to leave the lift!
Go get the people down there.
Tell the guy to use the ladder. Hurry.
What is it?
Put your shoes on.
Make some tea.
Kid, I've told you a hundred times
that girl isn't right for you.
You don't have anyone.
God knows where
you would've ended up
if I hadn't brought you here.
I put you to work
to earn some money.
To make something of yourself.
She's engaged.
Her dad's very protective.
When he gets back from the sea,
he'll put you in your place.
He wants to marry off his daughter
to have one less mouth to feed,
not to add another one.
I have a job... an income.
You call this a job?
An income?
- Who's her fiance?
- Never you mind.
- She wants to marry me.
- You both fucked up!
Captain Nemat, they're here.
Hurry up and get this phone working.
People are waiting.
- Hello, Captain.
- Hello there.
- How many children do you have?
- Six, Captain.
Great. May God protect them.
Big family.
- That's life, Captain.
- Stay here.
Look out, girl. Be careful.
- Hello, Captain.
- Hello there.
- Stay here with us.
- Yes, yes.
I'll give you a job
here on the ship.
You'll go to work in the morning,
come home after sunset. How's that?
Hello, Captain.
Hello, Haj Khanoom.
You got rid of the bakery?
- I don't have any flour.
- What do you do with it all?
You keep bringing in new tenants.
So, I bake more.
That's fine, stop whining.
I'll get you more flour.
Thank you, Captain.
No more payments due.
We're even now.
Hey, kid, look out.
Watch your step.
All your kids are girls too.
You have to find husbands for them.
If you stay here
I'll find them good husbands.
Not those penniless punks.
Suitable husbands!
I'll get good prices for you.
Everything's in order here.
They'll live a happy life together.
How much is the rent, Captain?
No rent, my dear sir.
Anything we charge
is spent on the ship and
it's deducted from your salary.
I'll show you what you need to do
and teach you how to do it.
- Hi, Uncle Sadegh.
- Hi there, Captain.
- How are you, Uncle?
- I'm fine.
What do all animals need
in order to breathe?
They need air.
Second graders, be quiet.
First graders, tell me
how many syllables.
Two syllables.
- The first syllable?
- Dosh...
- The second syllable?
- Man.
Read it.
D... o... sh...
ma... n.
(enemy)
Uncle,
I'd like to go to war
and fight the enemy.
Pay attention.
The war has long ended.
You mean there'll be no more wars?
Pay attention, students.
War isn't a good thing.
May there never be a war
anywhere in the world.
My dad told me
we have to kill the enemy.
Uncle, where is the world?
Where we are now
is part of the world.
So, we're in the world.
Uncle, but this is an oil tanker.
Pay attention, students.
We're inside the ship,
the ship is in the sea,
and the sea is in the world.
So, we're all in the world.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Uncle, my dad lost his leg in the war.
Uncle, who's the enemy?
You can relax.
Everything's at hand.
- Hello, Captain.
- Hello there.
Hello, teacher.
Please.
This is the classroom.
The kids can start right away.
Education is more necessary
to them than food.
I've brought you
four wonderful students.
Here's the paper.
Thanks, but the school
is getting very crowded.
Praise the Lord.
Thank God for that.
This teacher is truly kind.
A hard worker.
You're kind. Thank you.
So, I'll leave these
students with you.
These are old newspapers again.
Abdolkarim, what's the difference?
Just read it for fun.
Let's go, my dear sir.
Bye for now.
- I need to talk to you, Captain.
- Okay, fine.
- It's important.
- Do come and see me.
I'll come to see you.
- It's important. I have to see you.
- Okay, fine.
Can you read or write?
How about you?
And you?
You?
I need to speak to Private Mohammad.
Yes, his wife wants to speak to him.
Hi, Mohammad, how are you?
Hold on, hold on.
Hi. How are you?
She's fine too.
I'm holding her.
Your mom's fine too.
Everyone says hello.
I've got you some dates.
When are you coming?
The Captain looks after us.
Okay, okay.
I'm waiting for you.
Bye.
Thank you.
- Should I put it on your account?
- Yes.
Next.
Dial this number for me.
Make up your mind.
I only have this one room.
It belonged to a guy
who used to work here.
He made good money,
set up his own house.
Now he's living a comfortable life.
- Here you go. This is it.
- Thank you.
I'll have them give you
a large carton,
so you can make a divider.
Clean it up,
put a carpet here
and live a lifetime of comfort.
Hello there.
How are you?
Here are your new neighbors.
They can give you anything
you need for the cleaning.
They're good people.
They look out for each other.
I'll take care of your job right away.
Now get on with your life.
Send some money.
I have no money.
I got cut off. Dial again.
He got the message.
He has to send money.
- Put it on my account.
- I can't.
You owe me money.
I don't have any.
I don't care. You owe a lot.
I have no money.
- What'll I tell the Captain?
- I'll talk to him.
- Right, you talk to him.
- Yes, yes.
Next person.
Dial this number.
Hi.
Is this Captain Abdallah's raft?
I want to speak to Issah.
I'm his son.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi there.
- I need to change the oil.
- So, do it.
- We have no oil.
- I'll send you some.
Hello there.
God bless you.
Hi, Bibi Khanoom.
How are you?
In pain.
Is it your knee?
Use this ointment every night.
It'll take care of it.
- Here you go. Bye.
- Thank you.
God willing, you'll get better.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi there.
Do something, Captain.
We have no oil.
- Oil?
- We have no lamps.
I'll have them bring you some
from the reservoir.
Thanks.
Bye.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi.
These burkas are ready.
- How many are there?
- Eight.
- Should I put it on your account?
- Yes, please.
Fine, eight burkas
for Mrs. Ommalbani.
Hi, Captain.
Hi there.
Does she still have a fever?
- Is she feeling any better?
- No, Captain.
- How about yourself?
- Thank you. I'm okay.
- Any news from your husband?
- No news.
It's been eight months now.
I'll give you to your mom.
Calm down.
God willing, he'll come back
one of these days with good news.
Thank you.
Be careful,
you're about to give birth.
Give her one of these pills
every morning
and a spoon of this syrup every night
before she goes to sleep.
Good. She's quiet now.
Thanks, you've calmed her down.
I'll put it on your account.
I'm so grateful.
Bye.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
- Kid, why aren't you at school?
- He's sick.
Sick? Kids have to go to school.
- God willing, he'll go tomorrow.
- Make sure he does.
- Hi, Captain Nemat.
- Hi, Uncle Abdolkarim.
Wait, Captain.
I need to talk to you.
You've probably
invented something again.
You better see it up close.
Come with me, Captain.
- What's this?
- The machine I've designed.
One end of this rope's tied
to a float in the sea.
The other end is tied to this weight.
As the float rises,
the weight will drop.
When does it rise?
When the ship sinks in the water.
The ship's sunk this much
over the last two months.
What do you think?
You've said for years
the ship's sinking.
We haven't seen a thing.
Thank God, this ship is
still standing like a rock.
It's sunk two meters
since a few years ago,
but it can't be seen
with the naked eye.
Give me a break.
When the tide is low, eight meters
of the ship is out of the water.
You say it's sunk two meters
in the last few years.
Who cares what happens
in a hundred years?
Captain Nemat,
if this continues, the ship will sink.
Instead of having
these negative thoughts
and the nonsense that you put
in poor children's heads,
you should think of
something useful,
something that would make
them successful in the future.
Captain Nemat
to the Phone Company.
- Captain, they're calling you.
- Who is it?
Hello there.
You shouldn't have called me here.
I told you that I'd
contact you myself.
What do you mean
it doesn't concern me?
No, I can't do this.
What do you mean?
Where the hell should I tell them to go?
You're forcing me.
I said this six months ago,
I said it two months ago,
and I'm telling you now.
What's in it for these people?
Will you give them a place to sleep?
A piece of land?
Do you have any idea
what will happen to them?
No, sir. I can't.
No, it can't be done.
Then go and talk to the people
you bought it from.
You don't care what
will happen to these people?
All you think of
is your end of the deal.
I won't do this.
I won't evacuate this ship.
And you can't do anything about it.
Do whatever you want.
Akbar!
Where are you?
Get over here.
How's it going?
We're having a problem.
The steel's too thick.
Hurry up.
You're wasting time.
Move the ones you've
already taken apart on deck.
Here, this is for the guys.
It's for this week.
I've deducted what they owed.
Sign here.
Hurry up. There's no time.
Hurry. Let's go.
Move it. Hurry!
Akbar!
Uncle Sadegh, what do you see
in the sun? I can't see a thing.
I've been looking for years in vain.
And you want to see
something in five minutes!
Don't move away
from the lift, understood?
From sunrise to sunset.
Men use the ladder.
Women and children use the lift.
Got it?
Good.
Have you told them
to shut off the generator?
Yes, Captain. I have.
Lower the lift. Go ahead.
At 9:30 p.m.,
the generator will be shut off.
Get your IDs ready.
IDs. Get them ready.
Hurry, get your IDs ready.
- What for?
- The Captain needs them.
- To get green cards.
We already have ours.
The Captain knows people.
He can get as many as he wants.
He'll sell them and deduct it
from your rent, okay?
- Maybe he should get it himself.
- Okay, wait.
IDs. Get them ready.
Get your IDs ready.
It'll get there.
Just wait a bit.
Okay, okay.
It'll be there in one or two days.
All right, okay.
It was the asphalt makers.
Hurry up.
Yes, Captain.
I'll tell Akbar.
- Counted them?
- Yes.
I got the new neighbors' IDs, too.
Go and hide yourself somewhere.
If he finds you, he'll kill you.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi there.
Welcome back.
How was the sea?
I had a phone call.
Was there a problem here?
They probably just wanted to say hi.
Hi. How are you?
Bye, Captain.
How are you, Baby Fish?
There are no fish here.
From the sea. They come in
through that hole in the corner
and they can't get back...
to the sea.
Ah, it got away.
Give me your net, I'll help you.
Here you go.
Father,
please forgive me!
Let her go!
My honor's at stake. Go inside.
I didn't raise my daughter
to dishonor me.
Let her go.
Have mercy on her.
Leave me alone.
What is it to you?
She's my daughter!
I'll kill her if I want to!
You bastard!
Come out, you filthy bastard!
I'll find you!
We listen to everything you say.
You know that, Captain.
I come here once
every two weeks.
I'm at sea all the time,
working like a slave.
Take these away.
I told you not to leave her like this.
Marry her off.
The guy I'm telling you about
is a decent man.
It's true that she'll be away,
but at least you'll know she's safe.
She's taken care of.
This guy has money.
He's dependable.
I'll get you something too.
Whatever you say.
I say, let her go.
This guy's a good man.
What do you say?
- Do you agree?
- Whatever's the will of God.
Shall I proceed?
You know best. I trust you.
But I'm leaving on a raft tomorrow.
I have to go to sea.
I want no embarrassment later on.
I want to be proud.
I guarantee that you'll be proud.
And your daughter
will be settled down.
You can relax.
Don't worry a bit.
When you get back,
there's one less mouth to feed
and God willing,
you'll even gain something.
Meraj!
Go and rest assured.
Hey, Meraj!
Come and lower the lift.
It's 9:30 p.m.
The generator will be shut off.
Should I hand you over to her father?
Should I?
Or maybe I should beat
the hell out of you myself!
This is the end, Ahmad.
Yesterday when he left,
he asked me to look after her
in his absence.
I swear to God,
if you mess things up one more time
or set your foot
where it shouldn't go,
I'll kill you, and the seagulls
will fly over your grave.
Understood?
The key.
Now go downstairs.
Tell Akbar that
the Captain has sent you.
He knows what to do,
and you'll obey him.
Go!
You can't come aboard, sir.
I'm responsible. I just can't.
Go call the Captain.
He's not here.
Look, we have an official notice.
You shouldn't resist.
I don't know.
Come back tomorrow
When the Captain is here.
Let us come up.
We'll do our job and then leave.
And what is your job?
- Are you Captain Nemat?
- Yes, I am.
- Hello.
- Hello there.
We have an official
evacuation notice for the ship.
Evacuation?
You think you can just throw us out?
Where do you think you're going?
I'll explain to you
when I get up there.
Wait. I won't allow this.
Hey, people!
They Want to throw you
out of your home!
Come and defend yourselves!
The sea
is beautiful
and spectacular.
The ship
is in the sea.
The ship...
sinks more...
in the sea every day.
Life...
in the ship...
is beautiful.
- Did you write it down?
- Yes.
I've already told you.
No, it can't be done.
What?
You're going to use force?
Go ahead. Do it.
Listen, listen.
You can bring a tank.
You can use a rocket if you want.
Look, these people need homes.
They want a life.
Their children were born here,
they grew up here.
You expect them to leave just
like that? No rights, no nothing.
That's fine. You're welcome.
We have nothing to talk about.
Listen, they can call a meeting
when they have something to discuss.
We have nothing to discuss.
Okay, I'll come.
We can have a cup of tea.
But tea won't resolve our problem.
Okay, okay. I'll come.
I'll definitely come.
Good-bye.
Get closer to the lift.
I'm watering my flower,
my dear flower.
I'll teach it patience.
No one has watered it.
That's why it's gone dry.
Hi, Uncle Jalal.
Hi, Baby Fish.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- How many fish have you got?
- I don't know. Probably 10 or 20.
Your goat given birth yet?
No, she hasn't. One of these days.
Hi, Uncle Sadegh.
Hi, Baby Fish.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Seen what you wanted to see?
- I haven't found anything yet.
God willing, I'll soon find it.
What's up, Akbar?
Stop, stop!
The damn thing
has broken the drill.
But I think it'll work.
I hope it's the right place.
Go, pour some water.
More.
Akbar!
- What happened?
- It's done, Captain.
Hassan, switch on the pump.
Switch it on!
Switch the pump on.
It's working, Akbar. It's working.
Move it. Let's get the barrels.
"The aggressive nature
of the enemy and our duties.
Our world is a world of phenomena
and in facing any phenomena,
we have to get to know it first.
Meaning we have to know
the key elements
of its nature and its goals."
That's good.
Give it to the next person.
"We then have to discover
ways of resisting it,
based on a precise methed..."
Not "methed" - "method".
Give it to the next person. Next.
"Floods are one of
the destructive phenomena
which have to be handled."
All rise.
- Hi.
Sorry, teacher, we have to
end the class. Kids, follow me.
They have a class, lessons to learn.
Where are they going?
This is a class.
Fill the barrels half way.
Half way!
No more, no less.
That's enough. That's half.
Pull it up!
Everyone ready.
Parviz.
Hurry up, kids. Quick.
Let's go.
Do something!
I can't deliver the baby!
We have to take her to a hospital!
Ali Mansour,
turn on the generator!
Wait, her husband's not here.
Put the burka on her face.
God, please help me.
God, do you hear my cry?
What is this?
What are you doing?
You worthless losers!
You have no shame?
The ship is in the sea.
The sea is vast.
The sea is beautiful
and spectacular.
Did you write it down?
- Hi.
- Hello.
I want to see Mr. Razequinia.
Which one?
I don't know. The one who's
in the ship scrapping business.
They're all in that business.
You probably need to see someone
in charge of acquisitions.
Go and make a U-turn,
take the coastal road
and after 20 kilometers, make a right.
There you can ask anyone
for the breaker's yard.
You can find him there.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I'm looking for Mr. Razequinia.
Over there.
Be careful, careful.
Go ahead, move.
When you're done here,
go and cut up that pipe too.
Hey Parviz.
Hey, Moslem.
Be careful with the steel parts.
Don't play around.
How many times must I tell you
not to drop them in the water?
- Hi.
- Is Captain Nemat here?
- No. Can I help you?
I've got some stuff for him.
Right. He told me something about it.
Wait here.
No problem.
Ali, Ahmad, take the stuff
from the pickup truck and put it
in the boat.
What's all this stuff for?
A wedding.
But this is a classroom,
the students will be here.
There's no room for them.
Where should I put 'em?
I can't put 'em in the cabins.
Meraj, lower the lift.
Hi, Captain.
Hi there.
Anything else, Captain?
Thanks.
I hope I can return your kindness.
Good-bye, Captain.
Let me know
if you need anything.
Is this what I get
for all my kindness?
You steal my boat.
Where in the sea did you want to go?
Say you've fucked up.
Forgive him. He's young.
Let him go.
If I let him go,
there'll be chaos on this ship.
I fucked up!
I'm sorry, Captain!
For God's sake!
I fucked up!
Please, Captain!
I'm sorry.
We'll give the ship
so we can get ourselves some land.
We want to live on dry land.
As the teacher says,
this ship's sinking every day.
We have to leave as
quickly as possible.
I Want you to help each other
so We can build a town on dry land.
A town...
With a house
for each one of you.
We Won't let go of each other.
We're used to one another.
You all have to give me
power of attorney,
so I can take care of the land.
There are still some problems,
but they can be solved.
They just need following up.
As long as I'm With you,
you needn't Worry.
- What's your name?
- Bahram.
You can go.
Attention, residents!
If you haven't signed the power
of attorney papers, please do so.
Dear residents, please sign
your power of attorney papers.
Next.
Ameneh.
Good job, Ameneh.
Can I read it?
Just sign here, Abdolkarim.
You can read it later
when we have our land.
Can I sign in my husband's name?
Your husband? Sure, go ahead.
What's his name?
Abbas.
I'm going to get it
notarized immediately.
Yes, sir.
They can come
tomorrow morning at 10:00
to collect it completely.
Yes.
Everybody has agreed.
All of them, yes.
Uncle Sadegh, come down.
I won't! What do you want?
You're wasting our time.
Come down!
I won't come down.
You can leave if you want.
We're all going on a pilgrimage
to Shah-e-Shahid.
There's a sun over there too.
Women and children, use the lift.
Men, use the ladder.
Amoo Jalal, where are you
taking that goat? Take it back.
The boats that are full can leave.
What are you doing here, kid?
Come on up.
Why didn't you leave with the rest?
- I was fishing.
- Fishing?
What are these?
Why did you do that?
Poor fish.
Let them grow bigger, and then
we'll catch them and eat them.
Attend the pilgrimage.
Gather for the pilgrimage.
Pray for the lands.
Attend the pilgrimage.
Please go ahead.
Welcome.
Isn't Mr. Hachemnia coming?
No. We're here to collect the ship.
What about the check and the rest?
We have it. We'll inspect the ship.
After drafting an inventory,
we'll be at your service.
Are there any people here?
No, they're all gone, evacuated.
Here are the official
power of attorney papers.
It's all in order.
Give him the check.
- There you go.
- Good-bye.
Take care.
Come here, kid. Come.
I hope
all your prayers are heard.
Keep the faith.
Come on, let's go see the lands.
Hurry up, kid.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi there.
Go on, kid. Hurry, we're late.
Hey, wait!
Where are you going,
you little rascal?
Let's go, we have no time.
Take her to the shrine.
- Hi, Captain.
- Hi there.
Hi there.
I'm so very sorry to keep
you all waiting for so long.
Listen, listen.
I took the money for you.
Thank God,
all the problems are solved.
This land that you're standing on
will be yours one day.
It'll belong to all of you.
We'll build a town here.
You know what kind of town?
Come along.
Come and I'll show you.
Come, come.
Hi, Uncle Sadegh.
How are you?
We'll build a park here,
a big park
for the kids to play in.
We'll build a school here,
a school for our dear teacher
to teach our children.
I'll wait until you're done
with your pilgrimage.
Written and directed by
MOHAMMAD RASSOULOF
Executive Producer
BITA MANSOURI
Cinematography
REZA JALLALI
Sound
MOHAMMAD MOKHTARI
Makeup
REZA RADMANESH
Film Editing
BAHRAM DEHGHANI
Music
MOHAMMAD REZA ALIGHOLI
Sound Mixer
MAHMOUD MOUSSAVI NEJAD
Producer
ABOLHASSAN DAVOUDI
Cast
ALI NASSI RIAN
HOSSEl N FARZIZADEH
NEDA PAKDEL
DIDAR RAZEGHI
MEHDI BADELEH
RAHBON NADALI
ABDOLKARIM GHANI
AREF ZAKERI