Oh, God, it's too
damn cold out here.
Hey, Francis.
Hey, Pee Wee.
Get back in town?
Yeah. Have you seen
Helen around?
No, I haven't seen her
in a couple of days.
Well, I'll catch up
with her.
Hey, bum.
Hey.
You're looking good.
Where'd you get
them shoes?
The hospital.
I got the...
I got the whole outfit
up at the hospital.
Oh.
Doc says I got cancer.
First thing I ever got.
Cancer?
No shit.
He says, "You're gonna
die in six months. "
I said, "Well,
I'm gonna wine myself
to death. "
He said, "Man,
it don't make no difference
whether you wine or you dine.
You're going. "
Shit.
Well, Grandma...
Too bad.
Got a jug?
I got a dollar.
Nurse Hopper...
Nurse Hopper
gave a dollar.
You're in business.
Want to work
with me today,
get some money?
I had some last night
but I blew it.
Get us a jug,
a place to flop.
Could be cold tonight.
Work where?
Up at the cemetery,
shoveling dirt.
A fella told me
they was hiring.
Do they pay you money
or do they give you a free grave
when you croak?
If it ain't money,
forget it.
I ain't shoveling out
my own goddamn grave.
Little streams
of alcohol
Come a-trickling down
the rocks...
I knew that guy Grogan
when I was a kid.
He used to own all the electricity
in this town.
Well, he ain't got
much of it now.
Don't bet on it.
Them kind of guys
never give up
on a good thing.
Say, Franny...
you looking for anybody
special up there?
Might be.
You want to be buried
under a stone like that?
I never knew no bum
buried under a gravestone.
I don't need me
no stone.
This soldier is gonna
have to die alone.
If you die first
I'll send out the invites.
Hey, Gerald.
How are you doing, kid?
Kind of nice up here.
Pretty across the creek.
I don't know
if you know it or not,
but you're up here
with the rest
of the family.
Your grandfather's
just four graves down.
Oh, Jesus God.
I'm sorry, boy.
It wasn't
because I was drunk
that I dropped you.
All's I had
was four beers
after I come home
from work.
You slipped out
of that diaper
and your mother...
"Sweet Jesus!"...
crouched down
and snatched you up.
And I didn't touch you
because of the way
you looked.
Your brother...
Billy comes in and says,
"Why is Gerald
so crooked?"
Jesus Christ,
I remember everything.
I even remember
the red and yellow squares
on the linoleum...
when you fell.
Hey, Franny.
Hey, Franny,
the truck's here
to take us back down.
Yeah.
You know somebody
that's buried up there?
Yeah, a little kid.
A little kid?
What did he do,
die young?
Pretty young, yeah.
Damn.
What happened?
He fell.
Fell where?
On the floor.
Fell on the floor?
Well, I fall on the floor
about twice a day.
I ain't dead yet.
That's what you think.
Well, where are we
headed now?
What do you care
where we're headed?
Got an appointment?
No.
You got tickets
to the opera?
No.
Go ahead, sweetheart.
I just like to know
where I'm headed, that's all.
You ain't known where you've been headed
for 20 years.
You got a point there.
Go by the mission and see if anybody
knows where Helen is.
What is Helen's name?
Helen.
No, what's her
other name?
She's only got one name.
You don't want to tell me,
that's all right.
Damn right
it's all right.
You gonna eat over
at the mission tonight?
That preacher puts out
a pretty good spread.
I had a bowl of soup
over there yesterday
'cause I was starving,
but, God, it was sour.
Them old bums
are just hungry.
They don't believe
in nothing.
I used to live
around here
when I was married...
that house
right there.
Oh, yeah?
When was the last time
you were here?
22 years ago.
Who lives there now?
Some people
I used to know.
Still got the diamond.
I used to play there
when I was a kid.
I had a pretty good
throwing arm.
What year was that?
I don't know, 1901.
Yeah, I was
five years old.
How old are you now,
eight?
We had a trolley strike
that year.
- Hey, wait up.
- Hey, come on.
Hey, you old grumpy,
give us some candy.
Hey, give us
some candy.
Scabs.
Come on, you scabs.
Lousy scabs.
You see
what's up ahead?
I don't want
to hit anybody.
Keep the speed.
Scabs! Scabs!
You don't belong here.
Go on home.
Scabs off that car!
Get that scab
off that car!
- He's got no right to run it.
- Yeah!
You get off the tracks.
You take this car
back to the barns.
You won't
get through here!
They busted his head.
At the ready!
Fire!
I think you killed him,
Francis.
You'd better run.
Why did you kill me?
I didn't mean
to kill you.
Was that why you threw that stone
that broke open my skull?
My brains float out
and I die.
Scabs get
what they ask for.
Then you feel
no remorse.
You dirty bastards,
taking our jobs,
keeping us
from feeding our families.
Odd logic
coming from a man
who abandoned
his own family.
You haven't been home
in 22 years.
I dropped my baby son.
He died.
I couldn't face that.
A coward... he'll run.
You have no arguments
to justify what you did.
I got arguments!
What do you got
arguments about?
I ain't gonna sit here and argue
with some goddamn dead scab, see?
See?
Why don't you please
sit down?
I ain't no dead scab.
Well, you look like one.
Blessed be the name
Blessed be
the name
Blessed be the name
Of the Lord
He breaks the power
of canceled sin
He sets
the prisoner free
His blood can make
the foulest clean
His blood
availed for me...
Never mind the blood.
Just pass the soup.
Blessed be the name
Blessed be
the name
Blessed be the name
Of the Lord
Blessed be
the name
Blessed be the name
Of the Lord.
Now I'd like to ask all you lost
and hopeless men,
who will give you
a ride
on the turnpike
to salvation?
Jesus will.
Jesus delivers.
Is there a man here
who wants a different life?
God says,
"Come unto Me. "
Take Him at His word.
Come down front now
and kneel
and be saved.
All right then.
Mmm.
- Amen, brothers.
- Amen.
Wake up, bum.
The soup's on.
Hey, Pee Wee,
Helen still didn't come in?
No, and I've been
here all day.
Glad to see you
staying straight, Franny.
I believe that I've got
a job for you.
I worked today
up at the cemetery.
Splendid.
Well, shoveling dirt
ain't all that splendid.
Well, maybe this one's
a better one.
It's old man Rosskam,
the rag picker.
He needs a helper.
If you're serious about
staying off the hooch
he might put together
a decent pay.
Well, I'm gonna
talk to him.
- I appreciate it.
- Fine.
I'll tell you what else
I'd appreciate
is a pair of socks
if you could spare 'em.
The ones I got's
all rotted out.
Hey, God damn it,
where'd you grow up, in a barn?
Close the door.
It's cold in here.
Where have you
been hiding?
Oh, a fat lot you care
where anybody is or isn't.
I could have been dead in the street
three times over.
You wouldn't have known
a thing about it.
How the hell could I, with you walking away
like a goddamn crazy woman?
Oh, who wouldn't be
crazy around you?
Spending every penny we get
and drinking whisky.
- Stop that screaming.
- God, Francis,
you're bad enough on wine,
but on whisky...
oh, you're a devil.
I got six bucks.
Yeah?
Where did you get it?
Working all the damn day
out at the cemetery,
shoveling graves.
Wonderful.
Splendid.
Hmm?
And you're sober.
And you're eating.
Yeah, and I ain't
drinking tonight either.
Oh, that's so lovely.
I'm very proud
of my good boy.
Try these on for size.
They're good and warm.
Just what I needed.
I thank you for them,
Chester.
It's fine
you're off the drink.
You've got a strong look
about you today.
Oh, just a false face
for Halloween.
Don't run
yourself down.
How are you, little lady?
I see you're doing well.
I'm perfectly
delightful.
Good.
He says I'm doing well.
I'm doing just fine
and I don't need any Methodists
telling me...
Don't fight him.
He'll just take the socks away.
Oh, Franny, with $6
we could rent a room and get our suitcase
and phonograph back, huh?
Hey, you see who's
in town, Francis?
Oscar Reo.
Oscar Reo that used
to sing on the radio?
That's the fellow.
He blew the big time
on booze, but he dried out
and tends bar now
at the Gilded Cage.
Ooh, I was in love
with his voice, you know.
I wrote him fan letters.
Well, we threw a drunk with him
down in New York,
didn't we, Pee?
Two, three days, wasn't it?
The most musical drunk
I ever seen.
Yeah.
Okay, folks,
time to close up.
Francis,
where do you plan to sleep tonight,
do you know?
The weeds.
Where did you sleep
last night,
Finny's car?
No, not in Finny's car.
I will absolutely not
stay in that car another night.
I was at Jack's.
I thought you didn't like
Jack no more,
and Clara neither.
They're not
my favorite people,
but they gave me a bed
when I needed one.
Look at this.
Is she dead?
Hey, Sandra,
it's me, Rudy.
Are you dead
or just drunk?
She's just drunk.
She can't hold it
no more.
She's a goddamn
Eskimo.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Whether she's an Eskimo
or whether she ain't,
she'll freeze
out here.
Then dogs will come along
and eat her ass up.
Is she a bum
or just plain drunk?
She's been a bum
all her life.
Oh, nobody has been a bum
all their life.
She had to be something else
before she was a bum.
Well, she was a whore,
you know, in Alaska.
What about
before that?
Well, I don't know.
I guess maybe she was
just a little kid.
Well, that's something.
A little kid's something.
It ain't a bum.
It ain't a whore.
Come on.
Let's get her up.
Yeah yeah yeah.
You're gonna freeze
to death tonight.
I slept outside
last night.
It was cold.
I'm gonna get you
a bowl of hot soup
and you won't
freeze up so fast.
Who are you?
Just a bum.
But I can get you some soup.
Get me a drink.
No, I don't have money
for that.
Ooh, she can't
come in here.
Chester won't let her.
What are we supposed
to do with her, let her freeze?
You know him.
All right, God damn it.
Get her a bowl
of hot soup
and a blanket.
Franny, the ambulance
this morning wouldn't take her anymore
when she was
bleeding to death.
Slit her throat.
Maybe they'll take her.
She doesn't want
an ambulance.
She just wants
to sleep it all away.
I'll bet she doesn't
even feel cold.
She's a cake of ice.
Just 'cause you're drunk
don't mean you don't feel cold.
Here's soup.
Soup.
- You got soup.
- Got soup, yeah.
Here, have it.
See? She don't
even want it.
She wants it.
She's just pissed it ain't wine.
She told me she wanted
to be a nurse up in Alaska.
- A doctor.
- She wanted to be a doctor.
No.
A doctor wanted me
to be a nurse.
You didn't want that?
I did,
but he died.
Ah, love.
Love.
I can't look at her
no more.
Watch yourself there.
Hold your horses there.
We're walking here.
But what I dreamed
Of thee
I love you
As I never
Loved before
When first I met you
On the village green
Come to me
For my dream of love
Is all
I love you
As I loved you
When you were sweet
When you were
sweet
16.
Wonderful.
Oh, that's just won...
- God bless your voice.
- Yeah.
Why thank you, miss.
Can I get you a drink?
That beer looks
a tad light.
- You said you wouldn't drink.
- I said wine.
Thank you so much.
I think I know
you two Turks.
Well, you'll be
thinking right,
except you wasn't sporting that
pussy-tickler
last time I seen you.
You guys got me drunk
in New York.
And vice versa.
Francis Phelan,
Oscar.
- And this here is Rudy the Kraut.
- Francis.
He's okay
but he's nuts.
My kind of fella.
- Pee Wee Packer. Good to see you.
- Pee Wee.
- Introduce me.
- And this here is Helen Archer.
She hangs out with me.
I'll be goddamned if I know why.
Have one of those
yourself, Oscar.
No, I don't drink
anymore.
- Me neither.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
Well, I haven't managed
to turn it off yet.
I'm gonna wait
till I retire.
- Still getting rich.
- You're a sport.
Can't tell you from
those swells over there.
A flower.
Thank you.
Swells and bums...
ain't no difference.
Except that swells
want to look like swells
and bums want
to look like bums.
- Am I right?
- You're a smart fellow.
That was such a wonderful
song you just sang.
I remember when you
sang that on the radio.
Oh, I used to sing
that song myself.
A singer?
Where was that?
Oh, everywhere...
concerts,
and then I sang
every night on the air.
- You should do us a tune.
- Yeah.
No, I couldn't,
the way I look.
You look as good
as anybody in here.
- Oh, stop it.
- Come on, huh?
- Flowers?
- Yeah.
Now if you're gonna
get up there and sing,
you're gonna have to
put on the dog a little.
Oh, Francis.
He'd get a little money
and the first thing
he'd do would be
to buy me roses.
Wouldn't you, Fran?
- Sure would.
- Yeah, we were lovebirds then.
We had
a beautiful apartment
up on Hamilton Street
there.
Goddamn dead men,
traveling around
together...
wearing flowers.
- Yeah.
- When was that?
I don't remember
you living anyplace that long.
Oh, sure.
'35. We was here six weeks
or something like that.
No, it was more.
Months. We were here
almost a year.
Well, Helen would know.
- I can't call one day different from the next.
- Francis wouldn't stop drinking
and then we couldn't
pay the rent, you see,
so we had to give up
my old Steinway piano
and the Havilland china,
the very best
you could buy.
When you buy,
buy the best.
My father
taught me that.
Why don't you
sing us a tune, Helen?
- No.
- Sing us a tune.
- No no.
- Yeah yeah, come on.
- Sing us a tune.
- Well...
Just a little one, huh?
- Yeah.
- Come on, Helen.
- Come on.
- Oh, well...
Listen, does your friend know
"He's Me Pal"?
He knows everything.
Huh?
Yeah.
Well, people used to like
the way I sang that.
A real old-time trouper
will now sing us a song...
the lovely Miss...
Helen Archer.
...Helen Archer.
I would like to sing this
for my man Francis.
I know a lad
And when I feel bad
He scares
all my troubles away
When he's your friend
He's yours
till the end
No matter
what others may say
He don't tell me
How I ought to be
He likes me
just as I am
And when I feel blue
He's the one
I go to
'Cause his heart
is as big
As a ham
He's me pal,
he's me pal
There ain't nobody else
I can see
I know he's dead tough,
but his love is no bluff
He'd share his last dollar
with me
I'd rather have him
and his 15 a week
Than be some old
millionaire's gal
He's the best ever was
and I loves him because
He's me pal,
he's me pal...
My pal is poor
But I am dead sure
He's better than
most millionaires...
Am I right?
I'm satisfied
When he's by my side
The joys and the sorrow
we share
I'd give my arm
To keep him from harm
He'd do the same thing
for me
He'll always be there
Stormy weather or fair
That's the reason
I likes him,
you see
He's me pal,
he's me pal
There ain't nobody else
I can see
I know he's dead tough,
but his love is no bluff
He'd share his last dollar
with me...
Wouldn't ya?
I'd rather be his
with his 15 a week
Than be some old
millionaire's gal
He's the best
And I loves him
He's me pal
He's me pal.
By God, Helen,
that's as good as it gets.
You were born
to be a star.
Oh, you think so,
honey?
He's the best
ever was
And I loves him
because
He's me pal
He's me pal.
Nice tune.
Thanks.
Mighty nice,
old gal.
Not bad at all.
Have a glass on me.
It's a nice night,
isn't it, Fran?
Oh, yeah, nice.
Yeah.
Hey!
Get out!
Damn it,
get out of there!
Those animals
are always here.
Damn them.
Jesus Christ.
The worms crawl in,
the worms crawl out
They crawl all over
your nose and mouth
They eat the puss
between your toes...
Get away from me.
I got the money!
He got my money.
He got my money. Oh!
Little bastards!
Oh, gee.
- What's wrong with you?
- $15.
They got away.
$15!
$15, Francis.
Forget about the money.
We'll get more money
tomorrow.
- Oh, Jeez.
- Don't worry about the money.
$15, Francis.
Where'd you get $15?
$15 that Billy gave me
to get you out of jail.
God damn you, woman,
and your sneaky ways!
Hey! Hey!
Sandra's dead.
I'll bet
she prayed to die.
Her life wasn't
human anymore.
I want to go to church
in the morning.
Good.
What am I gonna
do with you now?
Hey, you can
stay here.
The beds are full but you can sleep
on a bench.
- I'd rather not.
- Sounds good to me, Pee.
Listen, we can go up to Jack's.
He told me I could come back.
- He said that?
- Yeah, "Come back anytime," he said.
Well, let's shag then.
You'll take care
of Sandra, Pee Wee?
- Yeah.
- What was her last name?
Never heard it.
It don't matter now.
Never did.
Rudy.
I went to Gerald's
grave today.
Gerald's?
You did?
That was the first time,
wasn't it?
Right.
Yeah, you've been thinking
about him these days. I know.
I never stopped
thinking about him.
I went to his grave
and talked to him.
You talked to him, huh?
How did you talk to him?
I stood there
and talked to the grass.
Boy, I'm getting
nutsier than Rudy.
Oh, you're not nutsy,
Francis.
You're back
in this town.
No, that ain't it.
Something Billy said...
I never told you that.
He says
Annie never
told anybody
about me
dropping the kid.
She never told who,
the police?
Nobody,
not Billy, not Peggy...
nobody in the family.
Ain't that something?
I can't believe
a woman
going through
all that stuff
and not telling
nobody.
Oh, you got these people
on your mind lately.
Maybe you ought
to go see them.
That wouldn't help nothing.
Get it
out of your system.
Dead sons of bitches...
being friendly.
What ails you now?
Everything ails me.
Oh, come on. At least you got
to sing a song.
Yeah, I did.
I sang.
I sang while Sandra
was dying over there.
Oh, come on, she was gonna die anyway.
Her time was up.
Oh, well,
I don't believe that.
I believe you die
when you can't
stand it anymore.
Take as much as you can,
then you...
you die when you can.
Well, that's as good a saying
as there is...
die when you can.
Yeah, well, I'm glad
that we agree
on something for once.
We get along all right...
not a penny,
with no place to flop.
- We're on the bum.
- No, that's for sure.
Come on, let's get over
to Jack's
before he turns
the lights out on us.
Hey, Jack.
We've come by
to see you.
What's the chances
of a bum getting a drink?
Oh, it's cold for October.
They're calling for snow.
Feel my hands.
This is my home.
I ain't about
to feel your hands,
your head either.
I don't see
any snow.
I had a bowl of soup at 6:00
but it disappeared.
I gotta get
something to eat.
I don't care whether
you eat or not.
How about a soda pop,
Helen?
What?
Sure, Jack.
What kind of soda?
Come here.
You feel any better,
Clara?
No.
What's wrong
with your shoe?
I have a piece
of twine in it.
I got a shoelace
but I didn't put it in yet.
Then put it in.
Well, it's a new sweater
or something.
- Do you know where it is?
- Don't ask me.
Find it
and put it in.
I'm reneging.
You're what?
I don't like to do that.
Can I ask you
a question?
No.
She said no.
What do you mean, no?
What's he gonna ask?
Find out what's he gonna ask.
How's everything
been going?
I always thought you were
an intelligent man, Franny.
But you can't be,
the way you drink.
- You could be a charming man.
- That's right.
You could have $20 in your pocket
at all times.
Yeah, I told him that.
If I had $20
I'd spend it all on her.
Oh, sure.
I don't want her
sleeping down in the weeds.
The weeds?
I never have gone that far down.
- It's not that far to go.
- Oh, pfft.
You slept in Finny's car
last night.
No, it was two nights ago
and that was the last time.
If it comes to that again I will simply
get in touch with my people.
My people are very high class.
You really ought
to get in touch
with them, deary.
You ought to get
straight, Franny.
They need
men like you.
You can get yourself
a Victrola like that one.
Eh? Eh?
I had all that shit.
If you don't shape up
you'll die.
Maybe you're right,
Jack.
May I use
your bathroom?
Help yourself.
Remember that tune,
hotshot?
Poor little lamb
Now his fleece
has gone cold
Wakes up
in the morning alone
Poor little lamb
knows what's coming
Life is an empty cup
So let's go on a bummer
this summer...
Hold it right there!
Stop, damn it.
Get 'em!
Come on!
Help.
Give me your hand.
Come on.
You got him.
Who was the guy
that didn't make it?
Some Guinea horse thief.
What are they chasing
you for, buddy?
I forgot to shine
my shoes this morning.
So let's go on a bummer
this summer
Where we won't have
to be afraid
Where the world
will be
On a hummer, boys
And we'll laugh
And we'll drink
lemonade.
Lemonade.
I used to sell it
out at the ballpark
when I was a kid.
That's when
I first started
hanging out with those
older fellows,
playing ball.
Windy Evans used to play
in his jockstrap
and catch flies
behind his back...
a great ballplayer.
Hey, where did you get
them shoes?
I found them.
God damn it,
them's nice shoes.
That's why I wear 'em.
I'm gonna cut off
your goddamn feet.
Well,
I'm real sorry
that I hurt your head
so bad.
But I had good reasons
'cause, you know,
I almost lost
a finger.
I couldn't do
anything right-handed
for a long time.
But I don't
hold grudges
for more
than five years.
See ya.
Thanks for
what you did.
Francis,
are you all right in there?
Who are you talking to?
Huh?
Yeah.
It broke.
Who are you
talking to?
Just thinking about
some of them old bums
that froze.
Foxy Phil Tooker...
the little guy froze
all scrunched up
with a red icicle
coming out of his nose.
Yeah.
Didn't even bother
to straighten him out.
Just buried him
in a half a coffin.
Yeah.
Hey, bum,
how about a bum
getting a drink?
I ain't no bum.
I know you ain't,
God damn it.
You're a good man...
a working man.
I knew
a fellow once
looked a lot
like Francis.
Oh, I had
the hots for him.
I'll bet you did.
Clara never lacked
for boyfriends.
She's pretty sick.
That's why
you can't stay.
I'm gonna tell you
something...
I always thought
a lot of Clara.
You're drunk, Francis.
You just stay drunk
for the rest of your life.
I'm really
leaving you now.
What am I gonna do
with this woman?
Oh, it's late.
Yeah, people.
Gotta hit the hay.
Fix me a sandwich...
to go.
No!
You forget
when you were hungry
you came to my place
begging for food.
- I never begged!
- He only asked you for a sandwich.
- Women.
- I'll go and make him a sandwich.
Jeez, Fran.
Sharp cheese...
you like sharp cheese?
It's my favorite.
Good night, pal.
Best of luck.
See you around.
Toodle-oo.
Now where in the hell
are you gonna sleep?
I wouldn't stay there
if they gave me mink pillows
and silk sheets.
That's right.
I remember her
when she was whoring
and always broke.
I had to speak my mind,
that's all.
Yeah, well, it didn't
accomplish anything.
Here, have a piece
of sandwich.
I don't want that.
It'll choke me.
It won't choke you.
You'll be glad for it.
I'm not a phony.
- I'm not a phony either.
- Oh, you're not, eh?
Hey, I'll kill you...
what I'm gonna do!
I'm gonna knock you
across the goddamn street.
Now be a goddamn woman.
That's why you can't find
nowhere to flop.
I asked for a sandwich.
Did I get it?
Yeah, you're stupendous
and colossal.
Don't you squint
your eyes at me
or I'll knock you across
a goddamn automobile.
You've been a pain in the ass
for nine years!
Jack told me
that I could stay,
but you can't because you're a pain
in the ass!
They don't want you.
Now I'm gonna eat
that sandwich.
Go head, eat it.
And I'm gonna be thankful
for everything.
Well, you're
a perfect saint.
Jesus wept.
You are a woman
for abuse.
I won't eat it.
It's rat food.
I'm gonna kill you.
Don't drive me insane.
Be a goddamn woman
and go and find a bed
somewhere.
Get off, Fran!
I'm gonna call my brother.
Good.
Why don't you
call him twice
so he can hang up
on you again, huh?
And where are you gonna
get a nickel for the call?
That's my business.
God, Francis,
you were all right till you started
on the wine.
Wine wine wine.
Now we're gonna get
some cardboard
and we're gonna go down
to that old building.
No, I'm going
down below.
Who are you kidding?
You got nowheres to go.
You want to get knocked
over the head, huh?
It wouldn't be the worst
that ever happened to me.
Are you gonna
hit me now?
I'm not gonna hit you.
Shh.
I love you, soul mate.
Now don't go
walking away from me.
You'd be lost
in the world.
Yeah yeah yeah.
- Are you awful cold?
- Yeah.
I couldn't stay outside
tonight, Francis.
I would die.
Here.
Finny, you got visitors.
Who the hell is it?
It's Francis.
Move over.
Make room for Helen.
I'll get you a jug
for this, buddy.
Yeah, sure.
- Don't be afraid.
- No, it's not that.
She knows.
She's been here before.
I'll see you here in the AM
or I'll meet you
up at the mission.
Why don't you
just get in too?
There's no legroom.
Keep the faith.
Now I lay me down
to sleep,
I pray the Lord
my soul to keep.
If I die
before I wake
I pray the Lord
my soul to take.
Oh, ow ow.
Don't touch me here, Finny.
It hurts too much.
Sands of the desert,
salt of the sea.
Oh, forgive me.
Forgive me
for I have sinned.
If you must
call them sins,
you know,
I call them decisions.
I'm not a drunk
and I'm not a whore.
And I never let a man
use me for money.
You know, I went Dutch
lots of times and I...
well, I would let them
buy the drinks,
but that's because
it's a man's place
to buy the drinks.
But I never
ever betrayed anybody.
And that's
what counts with me.
Of course
I know
living with Francis
was sinful
in the eyes of some people
and I took a certain
amount of liberty
with the Commandments
of the Church.
But nobody's gonna
compel me ever...
I couldn't declare to anybody,
not even you, St. Joseph,
that loving Francis
was sinful.
Because it was
probably...
the greatest thing
in my life.
That's...
that's all.
Thank you, St. Joseph.
Oh, thank you.
Preacher said you was looking
for a strong back.
Could be.
And you've got one
maybe?
Pick up that barrel.
You pick up
stuff like this yourself?
Do you?
I do a lifetime
of lifting.
I pay you $7
and work till dark.
Back work ought to be
$8, $9.
Families eat
for a whole week on $7.
$7.50.
$7.
All right, what the hell
is the difference?
Get up the wagon.
In Albany, Dr. Benjamin Boss,
director of Dudley Observatory,
a noted astronomer,
said he did believe
life exists on Mars
but that he could not imagine
Martian spaceships reaching the Earth.
Orson Welles, the director
of the radio program
that paralyzed
the nation in fear
said he regretted
the terror he'd created
and that the whole thing
seems like a dream.
Now back to
the Swingtime Hour.
Yours for the second half
of our morning program...
this sparkling
little ditty.
Here,
would you like
the rest of this toast?
It's good toast,
but I can't eat
a thing now.
A friend wanted to give me
a cheese sandwich last night...
not a chance.
Come on, get up.
So how do you like it?
Like what?
Sex business,
woman stuff.
I don't think about it
that much anymore.
To tell you the truth,
I'm over the hill.
Over the hill?
How old are you, 62?
Not that old.
7 1 here.
I don't go over no hills.
Four, five times
a night
I get it
with the old woman
and in the daylight
I go house to house,
I get offers.
I never went
house to house.
Listen, half my life
I go house to house
and I know how it is.
You get offers.
Boy oh boy,
you get offers.
Dregs!
I'm sorry.
My dear, you may stay
as long as you read.
We don't allow sleeping.
I wasn't sleeping.
I was waiting
for the fire
to die there.
Helen.
Helen Archer.
Yes.
Nora, Helen.
Nora Lawlor.
I haven't seen you
in 20 years.
Nora.
Of course.
Well, how are you?
I used to hear you
on the radio,
but the I lost track.
What have you been doing?
Well, I went
on concert tour
as a pianist.
And then I was abroad
for years...
Oh.
...living in Paris
and Vienna and everywhere.
How exciting.
What an exciting life.
I envy you, Helen,
I really do.
I never go anywhere.
Are you staying with your brother
while you're here?
Well, I suppose.
We're very close.
I saw him in church
only last week.
- In church?
- Mm-hmm.
Imagine that.
I go past his home
all the time.
- It's so...
- Hypocrite.
What's he doing in church
after what he did to me?
What?
Well, you know,
he and my mother...
- they stole all the money my father left me.
- No.
- Oh, yes.
- Shh!
- For 15 years, you see, they hid the will.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
- 11 of those years I knew...
- I'm sorry, but you have to leave.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I always knew.
- You're making much too much noise.
- I wanted to be free
even if I had
to suffer for it.
Oh, I got even. I left her with
the peacock there.
Thieves they were.
Thieves.
They were thieves.
Thieves they were,
thieves.
Common thieves.
Thieves.
On account of the will,
you know,
she just laughed at me.
That's right.
Well, after I left
your loving son
took care of you,
didn't he, Mother?
Mm-hmm, the poorhouse...
that's where the peacock put you.
And where did your
plumage go then, Mother?
You old cripple,
where did your plumage
go then, huh?
Where did your plu...?
Dregs!
Yoo-hoo!
Dregs man!
Whoa.
On the back porch...
papers,
a washtub
and some old clothes.
I don't want to go in.
I know her.
So what's that?
Mrs. Dillon.
I was born on this street.
I don't want people I know
seeing me looking like a bum.
But you are a bum.
You and me know that,
but they don't.
I'll carry anything you want
next time we stop.
Sensitive bum.
Sensitive bum
I got working for me.
Miss Dougherty,
are you all right?
I'm going downtown,
Francis.
Shouldn't you
put on some clothes?
Clothes?
Do you think
I'm crazy, Francis?
Not exactly, ma'am.
To whom have you
mentioned my spell?
No one, ma'am.
No one?
May I ask why?
Well, people
with no clothes
ain't what you call
regular business, ma'am.
Please don't
call me ma'am.
Makes you sound
like a servant.
Call me Katrina.
I couldn't.
I couldn't get it out.
But it's my name.
Say it.
Say Katrina.
Katrina.
So there.
You've gotten it out.
You know,
a great poet once said
that love enters
through the eyes.
You must be very careful
not to see too much.
Have you ever seen
anyone faint?
Faint?
No.
Then I shall faint
for you,
dear Francis.
You've done that
pretty good.
You can get up now.
Hey, bum, come here.
I'm sorry.
I'd like to buy this shirt from you.
Will you take two bits for it?
Why does a bum need
a clean shirt?
Clothes make the man,
they say.
Tidy bum.
Sensitive, tidy bum
I got on my wagon.
Pfft.
You love music, don't you?
It's the greatest thing
there is in this life, you know.
We ought to be willing
to die for our music.
What does she mean,
Mommy?
She means it's nice to be able to play
the latest tunes, dear,
just like you're doing.
Easy.
Whoa.
Get up.
Dregs!
I think I'm gonna
get off up ahead.
I'm gonna see some people I haven't seen
in a long time.
Of course I want
my pay now.
You quit before dark?
I've worked seven hours,
must be, no lunch.
Take a dollar off
for that.
That'd be fair.
25 cents
for the shirt...
$5.75.
Half a day's work...
you get half pay.
$3.50.
I am the boss.
Yeah, you're the boss
and you're one strong
fellow too,
but I know when
I'm getting skinned.
This hand's
seen it all.
Whoa.
Threats, eh?
Threats I don't like.
$5.25,
that's all I pay.
$5.75 is fair.
You gotta be fair
in this life.
$5.75.
A bum is a bum.
You I don't like.
Well, I sort of
liked you.
And I ain't half bad
once you get to know me.
Get up.
Excuse me, lady,
do you know where I can get
a nice little turkey?
What did you say
to my wife?
I asked her where
I could get a turkey.
What for?
Well,
my duck died.
Just keep moving, bud.
Got you.
Ain't seen you much.
Francis got a job.
It's possible we'll take
an apartment soon.
- You're back in the chips.
- Oh, yeah.
Francis coming in
tonight?
He might be
and he might not be.
It all depends
on his work
and how busy he might
or might not be.
I get it.
Oh.
Right on the bed there,
Donovan.
$6 for the bags
and $1 for the room.
Oh, yeah.
Same room, same bed.
I'm gonna pay you
for two days
in case I don't
die tonight.
You want to eat something?
I'm making coffee.
No no, no coffee.
Thank you, Donovan.
Yes?
Howdy.
I brought you
a turkey.
A turkey?
It's a 1 2 1/2 pounder.
Billy said to drop by
every Sunday
and I know
it ain't Sunday,
but I...
I come by anyway.
Is that you, Fran?
It ain't one of those
men from Mars.
Oh my God.
My God.
Hi, Annie.
How are you doing?
You're looking good.
This is a surprise.
Yeah.
Here, take this critter.
It's freezing me up.
You'll stay
while I fix it?
Come in.
Come on,
come in.
Sit while I get it
in the oven.
Danny can go
get cranberries.
- Who's Danny?
- Peg's boy.
He's in
the fourth grade.
He's smart as a cracker.
Gerald would be 22.
I...
well, I saw his grave
yesterday.
I talked to him.
I told him
a lot of stuff.
I'll bet he was glad
to hear from you.
Maybe.
Tell me about Bill.
How's he doing?
He's a gambler,
not a very good one.
He told me that you
never told nobody
about how I lost
my grip on Gerald.
Not till the other day.
There's nothing to be gained by
talking about it.
It wasn't your fault
any more than it was
my fault.
There's no way that I can thank you
for that, Annie.
- Oh, please.
- Thanks don't touch something like that.
Never mind that.
Tell me, what is it
made you come see us?
Well, I'd like to say
that it was
Billy invited me
to come by.
I never thought
I'd get invited.
Billy said
you had a wife.
No, not a wife.
I only ever had
one wife.
one husband.
I only had one man.
It's religion.
It wasn't
only religion.
Hmm.
I never could
marry again.
But I did live
with Helen
nine years
on and off.
She nursed me when
I was sick as a pup.
She's a damn good woman.
Where is she now?
Downtown somewheres,
you know.
She's like a little kid.
She...
she's gonna drop dead
in the street someday
if she keeps
wandering off like that.
She needs you.
And what do you need,
Fran?
I think I need
a shoelace.
I'm so awful sorry,
Annie.
There's things to say,
you know.
They're...
lousy things,
lousy lousy things.
I never stopped
loving you and the kids.
I know that don't entitle me
to nothing, you know.
I don't want nothing.
I went my whole life
just remembering
things here...
whatever was
on the table.
I want nothing,
just a cup of tea,
a sandwich.
You still make
that Irish breakfast tea?
Yeah.
Danny,
this is your grandfather.
He came to see us
and he's staying for dinner.
- Hi.
- Hello.
You come from school?
Are you Grandpa Phelan
or Grandpa Quinn?
Phelan.
Francis Aloysius Phelan.
You're the Big Leaguer.
You played with
the Washington Senators.
Billy says you taught him
how to throw an inshoot.
Oh, he remembers that,
does he?
Will you teach me?
Yeah, sure. Get a baseball.
I'll show you.
Yeah,
you put your fingers
across the seams
like that.
See?
And you snap...
snap your wrist.
Like this.
That's right.
It'll do a nice little
jig for you.
Yeah.
Let's go out
and try it.
I'll get
another glove.
A glove?
Annie,
you wouldn't by a fluke
have my old glove around,
would you?
There's a whole trunk
of your things
up in the attic.
Maybe you'd want
to have a look at them.
You saved my stuff?
No point
throwing things away.
Get up, Billy.
Grandpa's here.
Hey, Bill.
How have you been
getting on?
You made it.
I'd have bet
against it happening.
Well, you'd have lost.
I brought a turkey.
We're having it
for dinner.
You like turkey?
Who the hell
don't like turkey?
Listen, you can use
my razor
in the bathroom
if you want to shave.
Don't be telling people
what to do.
Brother,
most of my life
is in this picture.
Half the neighborhood
turned out for that ballgame.
There's your
great-grandfather,
old Iron Joe.
And that's me.
Handsome devil, eh?
Some people thought so.
Some didn't.
Here,
look at this
in the light
and you'll see
where Ty Cobb signed it...
1911, the year
he hit 420.
He was a mean guy, Cobb,
come at me many times
with his spikes up.
But he was the best.
Better than Babe Ruth?
Better and tougher
and meaner and faster.
Couldn't hit home runs
like Babe, though.
Would you like to have
that ball?
Sure I would, sure.
Who wouldn't?
Then have it.
But you'd better look Cobb up.
See?
I remember this suit.
You wore it for dress up.
I wonder if it'd still fit me.
I'll take it downstairs
and press it.
I'll carry the glove.
All right.
That's Danny's room.
It's a nice, big room.
It gets
the morning light.
It's nice.
And what if I did
drink too much wine?
Whose business
is that anyway?
Who knows how much
I didn't drink, huh?
Do you have a place
to stay tonight?
Sure.
I always got
a place to stay.
Do you want
to come home permanent?
I thought about it.
I admit that.
But I see
it wouldn't work out.
Stranger things
have happened.
Name one.
You at the cemetery
talking to Gerald.
Nice out there
where he is.
There's a grave there
for you
right by that stone...
one for me
and two for the children.
You bought me a grave
after I ran off?
You're part of the family.
Uh, Peg...
well, she's
kind of bitter
about you
staying away.
I was too
for years,
but that's all
done with.
I don't want
no fight with Peg.
I can't say nothing
that means anything.
I know it's hard
what you're doing,
but it's something Danny will always
know about.
And Billy... he was
so glad to help you,
but he'd never say it.
Yeah, he got a bum
out of jail.
You're so mean
to yourself.
Hell, I'm mean to everything
and everybody.
You goddamn spooks.
You ain't real.
You're dead.
Of if you ain't,
you ought to be.
I'd rather be dying
out in the weeds
than standing here
watching you pining away.
I'm the one that's living.
I'm the one that put you
on the map.
You don't know nothing
that I don't know.
See?
So get your asses gone.
I'm sick to death of looking at the bunch
of youse anyway.
Fran, Fran.
Annie,
I'd eat all the dirt
in this yard for you
and all the weeds
and all the dog bones too
if you asked me.
I think you probably
ate all that already.
How are you doing,
Margaret?
I'm doing fine.
No thanks to you.
Yep.
Let's give the man a break, for chrissake.
He just got here.
What break did he
ever give me
or you?
You don't just pop up here one day
and all is forgiven.
I ain't expecting
to be forgiven.
I'm way past that.
Oh.
So why have you come back here
like a ghost
to force this scrawny
turkey on us?
That's 1 2 1/2 pounds.
Why did you come here,
is what I want to know.
This is a home
you didn't build.
I built you.
I built Bill...
helped to.
- I wish you never did.
- Shut up!
Rotten tongue
of yours...
shut it the hell up.
He only came
to visit.
That's all.
I asked if he wanted to stay
and he said no.
Oh.
Then it's all decided.
Nothing to decide.
Like your mother says,
I'll be going on.
Mm, fine.
That's good.
That's it! You've got the feelings
of a goddamn rattlesnake.
Would you pardon me?
Pardon me for having
any feelings at all.
Tough lady.
She'll calm down.
How about the boy?
Did he hear that?
No, he's out playing with the ball
and the glove that you gave him.
I gave him the ball,
not the glove.
The glove is yours.
It ain't much of a glove
compared to today, but...
You want to give it
to him... go ahead,
but I always thought,
"I want to give
that old glove to Bill
so's he could say he had something
from the Bigs around the house. "
That turkey smells nice.
I bought you
this plum pudding.
Mama said that you
liked it for dessert.
Thank you.
That's nice that she
remembered that.
I got a letter here
that come to me
up in Canada.
I was playing ball
with Toronto.
Maybe you'd all
like to hear it.
"Dear Poppy,
I suppose
you never think
you have a daughter
waiting for a letter.
I was so mad
that I was gonna
join the circus.
I hope you have
good luck with the team.
Mama has 14 new little
chickens out
and there's a Wild West
show coming.
Won't you come home
and see it?
Billy is just
going to bed
and Mama's watching me.
Do not let me find you
with another girl
or I will
pull her hair.
Yours truly,
Peggy. "
You know, it's funny...
I don't remember
writing that.
Well,
probably a lot
you don't remember
about them days,
you know.
You were only
nine years old.
Yeah.
I remember Toronto,
191 3.
We had one ump
named Bates.
The game was getting dark
and he won't call the game
because he's in
with the other club
and we're winning.
So Pudge Howard
who was catching for us
has a three-way confab
on the mound
with me and
High Pockets Wilson
who's pitching for us.
And Pudge squats down
behind the plate
and High Pockets lets go
with a blazer... boom!
right down
the pipe... pow!
"Ball," says the ump.
"Well, if that's a ball I'm gonna eat it,"
Pudge tells him.
And the ump said,
"Well, then get eatin'."
Pudge takes the ball
and takes a bit out of it like this.
Of course
it ain't a ball at all.
It's a yellow apple like this that I give him
out on the mound.
Bates goes down in history
as Old Blindy Bates
that can't tell a baseball
from a yellow apple.
Great stuff happening
in them days.
Yeah.
Great stuff happening
all the time.
I do believe that turkey
should be ready.
Hey.
Wake up, you crazy kraut.
That you, Franny?
No, it's Buffalo Bill.
I'm looking
for the Indians.
The Indians?
Oh, God.
You seen Helen?
No.
Where did you get
the new suit, Fran?
- Up a tree.
- Up a tree?
You don't tell me
nothing that's true, man.
Every lousy
goddamn thing
you can think of
is true.
Look at you...
a new suit.
Look at me...
I look like
a goddamn bum.
You are a bum.
You know why...
you know why people
call you a bum?
Because it makes them feel better
when they say it.
The truth can't hurt you.
If you're a bum,
you're a bum.
Oh my God, Franny,
there must be a God
that protects
some bums.
Look at me.
Franny,
I'm gonna
kill myself.
You ain't
intelligent enough
to kill yourself.
- Hey.
How are you doing, Andy?
The hotel open?
Okay, Francis.
You strike it rich?
Oh, yeah.
Here,
lubricate your soul.
All right.
This here is Rudy the Cootie.
Rudy.
He says he's gonna
kill himself.
I got me
a form of cancer.
Ain't nothing
wrong with you
a little work ain't
gonna cure, buddy.
Cops was in here tonight,
shining in their lights...
didn't come in.
Cops want to do something...
they ought to fix
those goddamn houses
down there, eh?
I fell through the floor
last week,
could have broke
my neck.
Did you break it?
If I broke my neck
I'd be dead,
wouldn't I?
Oh, and you're alive,
is that it?
You ain't dead?
You wise guy.
Well, Charles Darwin...
he's dead,
master of botany,
died in 1936
and born
of two midwives.
What the fuck
is he talking about?
He ain't talking
about nothing.
He's just talking.
Hey,
then give us a sip
of that hooch.
My leg
is killing me.
I got TB.
Wow, TB.
Jesus Christ.
I'm sorry for anybody
who got TB.
You know that
Sir Isaac Newton...
you know what he done
with that apple?
I know that.
He discovered gravity.
And you know
when that was?
1936.
- Oh, Christ.
- Born of two midwives.
Driving me nuts
with all this jabber.
Hey,
you giving orders
around here?
In the Big Rock
Candy Mountains
All the cops
have wooden legs
Bulldogs all have
rubber teeth
And the hens lay
soft-boiled eggs...
Oh, shut up,
you goddamn idiot.
Shut the fuck up!
God damn, you got me, buddy.
You got me.
I don't like it
when anybody
gets in an uproar.
Gotta be nice.
- Hey, you all right there?
- I'm all right, Franny.
- You like your spot?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
When I leave this earth,
I want it to be with a blessing
to everybody.
Mockingbirds will sing
when you die, Francis.
What's that?
The guy over there behind this shed
has got a baby.
A baby?
Yeah.
I had a little kid.
He broke his neck
and died,
1 3 days old.
I'm the one
that dropped him...
22 years ago.
My wife never told a soul
that I did it.
22 years
she kept a secret,
protecting
a bum like me.
You can't figure women.
My old lady told me I was the only man
that ever touched her.
I came home one day
and she was banging
two guys at once.
I'm talking
about a real woman,
not some
trash-barrel whore.
My wife was
good-looking, though.
She had a terrific
personality.
Yeah,
all in her ass.
Screw you, guys.
I told you nothing.
Hey, Franny...
you know where
that Milky Way is?
It's right up
over there.
You know,
on the outskirts
I'm a restless person.
I'm a traveler, really.
On the Big Rock
Candy Mountain
You never change
your socks
Little streams
of alcohol
Come a-trickling
down the rocks
Oh, I'm bound to go
Where the wind
don't blow
On the Big Rock
Candy Mountain
There's a land
that's fair and bright
Handouts grow
on bushes
And you sleep out
every night
Oh, I want to go
Where the wind
don't blow...
Get the hell out of here!
Raiders!
Get out!
Wake up, wake up.
Raiders!
Raiders! Raiders!
Bastards, get out
of this car!
You bum!
Move it, move it!
Oh, Jeez. Jesus.
There.
How are you
making it, pal?
Goodbye.
He's dead, sir.
What was his name?
Sir, sir,
what was his name?
Rudy.
His name was Rudy.
Rudy what?
Rudy Newton.
He new where
the Milky Way was.
That's what he knew.
Hey, sweetie.
Hey.
I have to run now, baby.
I...
Looks nice.
You've found
all our stuff.
Looks nice.
Pretty.
Mighty pretty,
old gal.
Mighty pretty.
I'm gonna come back
sooner or later.
I'm gonna get you
that gravestone
that you always wanted.
You know what I want
to put on it?
"Helen Marie Archer,
a great soul. "
What do you need, Fran?
Oh, I ain't fussy.
A turkey sandwich
will do me just fine.
I always want that tea.
That's Danny's room.
It's a nice, big room.
It gets
the morning light.
It's nice.
The room's got
some space to it.
We could set up
an extra cot.
It's a mighty nice room.
It's the morning light.