Earphones?
- Are you alone?
- My mom's in the washroom.
Can I have a pair for her?
- Earphones?
- Yes, please.
Earphones?
Ladies and gentlemen,
next station: Barcelona sanka.
Renie thanks you
for using our services
and hopes to see you
on board again soon.
Please do not forget
any personal items.
Have the ﬂowers arrived?
Leyre, I told you to call first thing.
Tell the sommellier to move his ass
or I won't call him
for the next wedding.
I'll leave the papers for the bank.
Really! I can't be away
for even one morning.
Have they arrived?
Why haven't you called?
Hang up and call right now.
I don't want to buy anything
or donate anything.
Does Felix ambrés live here?
- There's no one here with that name.
- It says here that there is.
- Why are you looking for him?
- I want to see him.
- Yes, but why?
- Does he live here or not?
First tell me why you want to see him.
He's my father.
Then you've got the wrong ambrés.
I seem to remember
that the ambrés who lived here
is very young and white.
Hey! That's my letter! Give it back!
Hey! Hey!
This is félix ambrés,
my son.
Neh-br
may I continue?
Thank you.
Chino, your cell. Thank you.
The idea is that the volunteers
talk about their lives.
- What for?
- To record them.
One of the project's aims
is historical.
They're creating an archive. In the
future, when people want to know...
What do I get out of it
if a moron studies me in 100 years?
- Who'd study you, bighead?
- This smells of cops.
Yeah, have they got anything
to do with it?
- No, they haven't.
- Swear by all you hold sacred.
They want to keep an eye on us.
I haven't sold grass
for at least two hours.
You're like a crowd of five-year-old.
It's an ok project, really.
It's a my to change
the image shown of you
on the TV, in the papers,
in the media...
I'd like to be public enemy no. 1.
I want you to have the chance
to show what you're really like,
how you live...
Yeah, and then we all end up
in the slammer. It's dangerous.
If I bring a camera into the house
my dad'll string me up!
And then he'll sell the camera
to fix your face.
Do we get paid? What?
- Do we get paid?
- This isn't Hollywood.
- It's a project by the ministry.
- Only nutter gets paid.
Idiot!
All nutter needs is a bit of love.
- I love you too, guys.
- V\iho'll put it together?
You think you're almodévar?
- They can do what they want with it.
- Why not give us the cameras?
- 'Cos they want them back!
- Right!
Don't say I didn't try.
Screw the project.
No, come on!
I'll still get my millionaire salary
and we'll go back to...
Hey, how do I know
what they'll do with what I do?
I have to explain everything.
They'll wipe their asses.
What do you think they'll do?
They can show us
any fucking way they want.
I don't like to look scary
but I don't want to look pathetic.
He's right.
- Here.
- What the fuck do I do with this?
I don't know.
Treat it like a girlfriend.
I'll go screw it.
A threesome!
Do whatever you want.
That way, you'll understand it.
Surprise us!
Knock everyone on their asses
when they see it.
You're not the worst guys,
and you're not pathetic.
Surprise us, chino,
with something
no one expects from you.
Hi, this is Felix.
Leave a message
and h! Call you back.
- It was it your idea to run away?
- Yes.
- Your mother didn't send you?
- No.
So she knows nothing about this?
No.
- May I?
- Yes.
Would you like something to eat?
Call your mother.
When she finds out you've gone
she'll get an awful fright.
Is that what you want,
to frighten her?
I just want to meet my father.
Isma, 'what's wrong?
Hello, I'm Nora salmerdn,
félix ambr6s's mother.
I'm calling from Barcelona.
Ismael is with me.
Fe'lix's mother?
What are you doing with my son?
Excuse me, I'm not doing anything.
He came on his own.
He had this address
but félix hasn't lived here for years.
I want to speak to my son.
She's very angry,
very sad and very worried,
so take a deep breath
and speak very calmly.
Love, what are you doing there?
- I want to meet my father.
- You don? Know what you're saying.
- Yes, I do know.
- You can? Go off on your awn.
Anything could have happened
to you.
- You should have done it with me.
- I asked you a thousand times
- but you never listened.
- Isma,
this isn't the way.
You're in Barcelona with a stranger.
She isn't a stranger.
She's my grandmother.
What matters now
is that my son, a minor,
is 400 Miles from my house
and against my wishes.
He came by himself.
What should I do?
Put him out on the street?
I want him back here
as soon as possible.
Well,
I can put him on a train
in a few hours.
Will we risk
that he'll run away again?
I don't want to go home.
- What do you want me to do?
- Take me to see him.
I know I'm going to regret this,
but I think it's best if I take him
- to meet félix.
- What are you saying?
The boy ran away.
This obviously means a lot to him.
If he goes home without seeing Felix,
how long will it be
before he tries again?
- Does félix live on his own?
- Yes.
Well, I think so.
Don't you know'?
- Has he got children?
- No.
Well, I don't think so.
We don't see each other much.
We both work a lot.
What does he do?
Why not ask him all those questions
when you see him?
What if he doesn't want to see me?
How could he not want to see you?
Wait here, ok?
- Those table centers are horrible.
- They're ten Euros cheaper.
420 of them, do the math.
Really tacky.
- Will we take them off?
- No, not now. Let's see in here.
Good. Good. Good. Good.
And the puff pastries?
You'd no time?
- How long has he been here?
- I told him not to make them.
It would take too long.
We didn't hire an assistant and...
Look, we're gambling our survival.
Where are the chair covers?
- They're on their way.
- The wedding's today, not tomorrow!
- We're not used to weddings.
- The covers are here.
Great. Get moving.
I'm going to kill the sommelier.
Well, they arrived in time.
Hey you! What are you doing?
Who let him in?
- If Nora sees him, she'll kill us.
- Leyre...
- What's this wine?
- The washroom is for customers.
This isn't the wine I ordered.
We're throwing him out.
Wait in the car.
You'll have to take charge
for the next four hours.
- I have to take charge?
- Yes, I've something important to do.
- What about the wedding?
- I'll be here before the meal starts.
No, you can't go!
I can't cope with all this...
You can cope perfectly.
Four hours, probably less.
- The contract depends on this...
- Foul
felixambrose
biographyand life history
saves woman's life in accident...
What happened?
Why did ismael run away?
Did you have a row'?
No.
Hurry up and we'll get there early.
I can go on my own.
Take me to barajas and...
And what?
You get to Barcelona, hire a car,
drive to God knows where...
I'll go with you,
we can manage better together.
It's all arranged.
Berta will see my patients,
we've canceled your appointments.
Thank you.
I wonder how he found him.
He's not the only félix in Barcelona.
Félix.
- What is it?
- I'd forgotten that was his name.
How do you get on with your mother?
Fine, I think. Normal.
And what does "normal" mean?
She scolds me when I'm bad
and she's happy
when I get good grades.
It's him.
Mom, I hope it's an emergency.
I don't want to spend the recess...
Do you know the name
alike thou?
What do you know about alika?
Wen,
I've got a little boy called ismael
who says he's the son
of you and alika tchou.
- Do you think that's true?
- She called him ismael?
So it's true.
- And her?
- Who?
Who do you think? Alika!
Is she with you?
Nutter,
I've got something to tell you.
No, but the boy and I
are on our way to you now.
- What do you mean?
- We're on our way to you.
- You feeling rough?
- No, I'm fine, go away.
- I wanted...
- Get out!
What did he say?
- Does he want to see me?
- Of course he does!
Why wouldn't he?
You look very pretty
he made that trip on his own
and he's so young...
He's not that young.
Isn't he young
to take a train on his own?
- Well, he did it.
- Are you justifying it?
He just wants to meet his father.
You're his father.
I'm trying to understand it.
I know.
It'll be all right, you'll see.
Ismael adores you.
I was coming out of my house...
Hey, you brute,
stop thumping the machine!
It swallowed my euro!
If I got a euro every time
I heard that... get out of here.
I want my juice, or my money!
So, I was coming out of my house
the other day...
I want my juice, or my money.
Don't you understand, kid?
Get out, don't be such a pain.
Are you deaf? The boy said
he wants his money or his juice.
Hey, these women have monkeys now
instead of poodles.
I bet you wish
you'd a monkey's intelligence.
What an idiot. Come on.
It was a miracle he survived.
The worst thing is I didn't want
to buy him the damn bike.
The doctors said he'd be fine
if he looked after himself, but...
He didn't.
You know the first thing he did?
He gave up architecture
even though he was doing well.
Then he went traveling
and when he came back
he wanted to sell
the apartment his father had left him
because he'd seen
a magnificent house.
Of course, I said absolutely not,
the apartment belonged to the family.
But he insisted so much
that in the end
I bought the apartment
and moved there because
my house was too big for just me.
And then he comes and says
he wants to go into education.
Be a teacher.
A good my to ruin his life.
- Why do you keep taking photos?
- When I'm grown up,
I want to remember everything
that happens today. Today is my day.
You came out very pretty.
Take my bag, please,
and look in a black diary
for Fe'lix's address.
Have you never been to his house?
Every time I threaten to visit
he makes an excuse.
He's got a lot of work,
he's going to Barcelona soon...
Passeig de pau casals, number 8.
We're in passeig de pau casals,
but I don't see number 8.
- There!
- Where?
You're right!
Excuse me,
is this 8, passeig de pau casals?
Yes, but we're closed.
Does Felix ambrés live here?
I'm his mother, Nora salmerén.
- Salmer6n?
- Yes, félix ambrés salmerén.
That's what his I.D. Says.
I'm ismael Gonzalez,
félix ambr6s's son.
His son? Apleasure. I'm jordi.
This was the address I had.
Do you live with him?
No. He gives this address
to get his mail.
Driving to his house is complicated
but it's just along the beach.
I can take you there.
- Nutter, I have to talk to you.
- I've got no time today, chino.
- We'll talk tomorrow.
- It's urgent.
The cops are after bonobo.
Again?
They've got it in for him.
But this time he's innocent, I swear.
He hasn't dealt in ages.
You have to tell them
- to leave him alone.
- Yeah, and they'll listen to me.
You can convince them
with those smart things you say.
Give me a break, chino. I can't today.
Tell bonobo to lie low till tomorrow.
You tell him,
you're the only one he listens to.
If he listened to me,
he wouldn't always be in trouble.
They're out to get him.
Fuck...
He's to hide today
and tomorrow we'll see what we can do.
I can't do it today, really.
I've got a life too.
- Is anything wrong?
- No, nothing.
You looked rough in the washroom.
Even if nothing's wrong, you know...
Yes, I know.
I know.
Hwy
what would you get for a kid mo's...
Eight years old.
Ismael, you'll get wet!
Let him enjoy it.
He's thrilled with the sea.
- H ave you known Felix for long?
- Yes, it's been a few years now.
When he decided to settle here
I was delighted.
There aren't many
good conversationalists,
and he's a great listener too.
Are you sure
we're talking about my son?
Does my son live there?
In a cave?
Come on.
I'll check the fridge.
This kid must be hungry.
Calm down.
It's all right, you know that.
Look in my eyes.
Look in my eyes. Look in my eyes.
Ismael, look in my eyes.
Look in my eyes.
Ismael, the problem isn't
in your lungs. It's in your head,
it's playing tricks on you.
Look, you don't need this.
Look in my eyes. Look in my eyes.
Look at me.
Forget about the air in your chest.
Think of something nice.
Something you really like.
A song? A film? Look at me, love.
W“?
Is there a girl at school
that you like?
Yes! We got that right.
Very good. Now, think about her,
and all you'll have to tell her
when you see her.
That's it. Good.
Good. All right.
Come on, love.
You're going to sit here.
Sit down.
I'll be right back.
I'll make him an infusion.
Or whatever I find.
How did you calm him down?
Félix had the same thing.
The ambréss' defective genes.
You're good with kids.
He was hypnotized.
Am I like he says I am?
I don't know what you mean.
My son must have said
something about me.
He never talked about me?
Mom?
Ismael?
I'm félix.
"Sapere... aude."
It's Latin.
- And what does it mean?
- "Dare to know."
You don't look after yourself.
You're...
Thinner and more...
More mature. When he gets
some grey hair he'll be irresistible.
Won't he, ismael?
I don't know.
I didn't know him before.
Leyre, I won't get there sooner
just because you keep calling.
If everything's ok, that's great.
Don't get rattled,
show them you're in control.
Yes, I'm on my way. Ok, so long.
It's a pity you're leaving so soon.
Tell Felix that if they want to eat
I'll see them at the hotel.
There's nothing here.
Why are you looking at me like that?
- Like what?
- Like that.
I can't close my business
when I feel like it
- or stop working for three months.
- I didn't say anything.
The world doesn't stop when...
When your son needs you?
Is it true you ran away?
And does...
Your mother know mere you are?
- Do they hurt?
- Do what hurt?
Your legs?
No. Well, at times they hurt a bit.
- I guessed...
- What did...
- Sony, you first.
- It doesn't matter.
What did your mother
tell you about me?
Nothing. Well, that your name
was félix and you lived in Barcelona.
Is that all?
Where do you live?
- In Madrid.
And how...
How is your mother?
Today she's really angry with me.
You're in for it when you get home.
Yes, but when she gets like that
Luis defends me.
- Luis?
- My father. I mean, my other father.
My mother's husband.
I have a deal with him.
Every month
Luis buys me a new video game.
My mother doesn't like them
but Luis thinks they're ok.
Your mother's right.
Video games are shit.
A lot of people criticize them
but they're very useful.
They improve your reﬂexes,
your concentration,
and they teach you strategy.
Luis says I'm much better at math
- because of video games.
- Hell of a theory.
No one advances a level
without discipline.
That's ridiculous.
For God's sake!
Mom!
- Sit there.
- Ok, ok.
Go to the kitchen and get some ice.
And a cloth. They're in the drawer
under the cutlery.
If you wanted to scare off the child
you're doing a great job.
- That hurt!
- Don't tell me how to talk to him.
You've never known how to talk to me.
- In 'which drawer?
- Under the cutlery.
Do as you wish,
but this way you'll never
connect with him in 30 minutes,
which is the time you have
before alika arrives.
What?
Alika's coming?
Of course, to pick him up.
I'd stay, but...
I've only got the restaurant staff
and they're all useless.
If you want, I'll take him to
Barcelona and give him to her there.
But now that I think about it,
I won't be able to drive.
- I can't find them.
- I'm coming.
My ankle is swelling, I can't leave.
It's not swelling.
I miss you...
Like people miss
starless nights,
like they miss
beautiful mornings.
No! Being with you
is hurting me so.
Oh, I miss you
when I'm walking, when I'm crying,
when..
Why did you turn it off'?
That slushy stuff makes me sleepy.
But if you want I'll leave it on.
I think we should
spend the night in Barcelona.
Driving straight back would be hard
on ismael. And on us.
I just want to go home,
put him in his bed
and forget about today.
Dr. Joan torrents
gen general practitioner er
- mom, you hardly let him touch you.
- Did you see his hands?
- He was more like a vet than a doctor.
- Here.
- What did he say?
- That it won't kill me.
No, he said that she's fine.
It was just a little knock
and she should walk carefully
that I'm fine! What would he know
with those big hands...
Can you go a bit slower, please?
That's it, gasp for air.
Is there a lot of crime here?
You stay here.
- H hey, nutter! Look 'who's here!
- What's up, guys?
We thought we'd get
some images of the town.
Yes, but think before you shoot,
I know you lot.
Where's bonobo?
He's looking for a place to lie low.
This is my mother, Nora.
Mom, these are chino, mogollén
and Aziz, friends of mine.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello.
So it was for him...
This is ismael. Ismael is my son.
Shit, a lot of people
thought he was...
I can leave you the camera
so you can film the kid and...
No, you're working.
There'll be other chances to film us,
right, ismael?
- All right, see you tomorrow.
- Sure.
- Take care.
- So long.
Will we go to the development?
No, I'm going to the mmorehouse!
His mother's expecting me.
Wait.
Ismael!
- Ismael!
- Let him go.
Come on!
What are you teaching them?
To love themselves a bit.
I don't have it easy.
I teach in a center
for kids with problems.
Delinquents.
No, kids with problems.
So now you're a social worker.
I teach drawing and an in general.
Didn't I tell you?
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
- N nothing?
It's jordi. Yes?
- Jordi?
- I've had an accident, leyre.
No, it's not serious,
but I won't be able to drive.
Of course you can do it on your own.
Call me 'amen you need to, ok?
All right, bye.
- Jordi, where are you?
- Hello!
Why don't you go to the cellar
and pick the wine you like most?
The one I like most, really?
So, I can't leave you on your own.
- What's that noise?
- It's my heart.
The boiler.
You'll have to call the cardiologist.
- Lamb?
- Yes, don't you like lamb?
But when are we going to eat?
It takes ages to cook.
- This is dry and tasteless!
- What do you mean?
My lamb is always delicious.
Have you any meat stock, bay leaves
or honey? Something to liven it up...
- Lamb with honey?
- Jordi, is this one good?
- Holy shit, I'll say it is.
- Give me that.
There's honey and all you want
in that cupboard.
Let's go out to the table.
I'll leave the lamb to you.
Try to leave one bit without honey,
if you can.
- He doesn't look at me.
- What do you mean?
Félix doesn't look at me.
Of course he looks at you.
Not in the eye.
- Come and sit beside félix.
- Let him sit where he wants.
Don't you want to sit here?
Ismael, you'll have to sit with me,
those two will drive you crazy.
Here.
Thank you.
So, do you eat everything
or are you the kind
who lives on hamburgers?
Everything.
Spinach too?
My mother says it's good
but I think it's disgusting.
There are things we don't like in life
but they're good.
How often have I heard that?
Do you like any sport?
I play basketball in the school team.
Really? You know félix played
basketball at school?
Volleyball. I never played basketball.
- It's almost the same.
- Almost the same?
Yes, it's with a ball and it's not
soccer which is what most kids play.
Why can you never be quiet
when you've got nothing to say?
The lamb won't be ready for a while.
What if I show you my secret room?
Vvn, psp, Xbox...
- You've got all that?
- It's the only way I can play sports.
- May I?
- Come on.
Can I leave you on your own?
Keep an eye on the lamb,
and if you feel like it
make the salad.
Come on.
Are you going to tell me?
- How is he your child?
- Do I really have to explain?
You have an eight year old child,
who's black...
We can act civilized.
I don't care, but he is black.
Get to the point.
Why did you keep it from me?
Since when do you care what I do?
Yes, leyre.
Even now, you can't forget
your fucking restaurant.
Hang on.
This fucking restaurant
has kept us all our lives
because if had been
up to your father...
Leyre,
you'll have to sort it out yourself,
I can't talk now.
'Bye.
Why didn't you tell me?
Tell you what?
That I'd fallen madly in love?
No. You wouldn't have understood.
Why do you think that?
Because you have no idea
what it means to love someone.
You ruined my father's life...
And you'd have ruined mine
if I'd let you.
Pay attention.
This is only for the chosen few.
Why doesn't félix look me in the eye?
Do I scare him?
I guess...
I should thank you
for bringing ismael.
Alika was the physiotherapist mom...
Looked after me when I came home,
after the accident.
Remember her?
We were together three months.
The best in my life,
despite the pain.
I felt really good.
The rehabilitation was working
and I was making plans
for when it was over.
But some things scared me.
The idea of telling you,
among others.
But I wanted to try to stay with her.
I was in love.
I'd never been in love.
Then alika told me she was pregnant.
I don't know...
I'd never thought
about having a child.
I got scared.
I panicked.
And I acted the way you'd taught me.
I said that the best thing
was to get rid of it.
That's normal. You were young.
Alika didn't want anything.
At most, an embrace.
That I wouldn't make her feel
more alone than she already was.
But all I wanted was to get away.
She realized and never came back.
I went to the house where she lived.
They said she'd moved
and left no address.
I even thought about
going to the police but...
Alika was illegal here.
She disappeared without a trace,
like she'd never existed.
And you never heard any more?
I didn't even mow the baby
had been born, until today.
I beat him at everything!
Jordi's a fierce opponent,
you must have played well.
No one can beat him.
- It smells of honey!
- There's honey in it.
- And that salad?
- What's wrong with my salad?
Instead of slicing the tomatoes
you crushed them.
Careful, or you'll get no dessert.
Just wait,
you'll end up licking your fingers...
This is delicious!
It's good, isn't it?
And I won't give you the recipe.
Don't you like it?
Neither do I.
I want to take a photo. May I?
- Not now, afterward.
- Yes, now.
- Go over there.
- All right.
If you get félix
to look good in the photo,
- I'll give you a super-prize.
- Really?
My mother always thought
she was a good photographer.
When I was little like you,
she put me facing the sun,
and I'd keep my eyes open
as long as I could,
and when I couldn't do it anymore...
Just like that.
This one's good.
- Now you go over there.
- Come here.
Sit here.
Attention. Let's see.
A bit closer together, please.
Félix, move a bit closer.
Let's see. Big smile.
Look natural!
- Very good!
- That's it.
Is that from ismael?
He keeps sending me photos.
It's his way of apologizing.
What's this?
- This is a piano.
- Right! And the key?
It got lost.
- Have you always been in catering?
- No.
I was a musician, in another life.
And why are you running a hotel
in this life?
Because one day I decided to change
and I changed.
Simple as that? Just because?
Simple as that and just because.
Why don't I believe it?
Because you never believe anything,
do you?
- Are you a good friend of my son?
- Hands up.
The interrogation is starting.
Why don't you ask
what you really want to ask?
In another life
were you a psychoanalyst?
I had asthma too.
Nora got rid of it. I don't know
what she did, but she got rid of it.
- I don't need the inhaler now.
- I know her methods.
It's cool having
a grandmother like that.
You know what I'd like now?
To be like a computer,
connect the USB to you,
and know absolutely everything
about you.
When I grow up,
I want to be the captain of a ship.
- You like the sea?
- To look for treasure.
You know there are lots of ships
at the bottom of the sea?
I wanted to build cities,
in the desert or on other planets.
That would be neat!
- Have you got a girlfriend?
- Have you?
I asked first.
I don't know. Her name's Kim.
Sometimes I think she likes me,
other times I don't.
It's a muddle.
Awhile ago,
if I did this in front of her,
I was the neatest guy.
But if I do it now
she looks at me like I'm a moron.
Shit, this is some place!
Are you all right?
- Have you got a toothbrush?
- No.
A breath mint?
You go.
Tell them I don't feel well
and I'm waiting here.
Are you sure?
All right...
- Would you rather I waited here?
- No.
I can't do it on my own.
Ok.
There he is.
You go into the hotel.
I'll get ismael.
Ismael!
Don't ever do that to me again!
Luis is inside, go and say hello.
We had to ask directions
at one point...
Luis!
You really stirred it up.
- Were you angry?
- A bit.
- And her?
- Loads. We'll try to sort it out.
You've changed a lot.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I looked for you.
It isn't easy to explain
all that's built up inside...
We come for my son. Nothing else.
All I care about is ismael.
I don't want you to promise him
anything you won't keep.
A child
understands promises differently.
It's better to say "no" now
than disappoint him later,
when everything is more complicated.
- He knows you now, that's what he...
- Let me speak, please!
- You can't accuse me of...
- He's my son.
He has a life.
Maybe that means nothing to you.
- I want to get to know him.
- Why??
Because he came looking for me.
He's my son too,
in case you didn't realize.
You have no right to say that.
I was all alone until he was three.
You know what it's like
to rear a child on your own,
without papers,
living in shared apartments,
not knowing
if you'll be able to manage?
No, I don't know.
No.
You don't know.
Of course you don't.
If you don't want to drive,
a friend of mine
has an hotel near here.
Thank you, but we have to go.
Don't leave anything behind.
Hello, I'm Nora, Fe'lix's mother.
A pleasure.
Thank you for looking after ismael.
Hello, I'm jordi.
- Can I get you a drink...?
- No, thank you. We're leaving now.
But you've just arrived.
We came to get ismael,
it's not a vacation.
Apparently
there's a hotel near here...
To save you
driving to Barcelona at night.
I don't want to leave.
- Or you can stay here.
- No, we'd better not.
- Ismael, we have to go.
- That's not true.
We're closed to the public,
but you're Fe'lix's family
and this is like Fe'lix's home.
Good evening.
Félix,
this is Luis, alika's husband.
- Hello.
- A pleasure.
Can I sleep in your house?
But you've seen what it's like.
I can sleep in the armchair.
I think your mother has other plans.
She can change them.
We already changed them a lot,
because of you.
What you did
was irresponsible and dangerous.
- Anything could have...
- Nothing happened!
Get your things, please.
Go on.
We'll talk calmly
when we get to Madrid.
I don't want to leave!
Luis!
Ismael!
- Why did you lie to me?
- When did I lie to you?
All my life.
- Lie about what?
- About félix.
I never said anything.
That's lying.
I did it to protect you.
Wait!
I was wrong. It's obvious.
I thought you weren't ready.
- I'm not a child.
- I'll tell you what.
We'll stay tonight
and tomorrow morning we'll go home.
No.
I want to stay and live with félix.
You've got Luis but he's got nobody.
- What are you saying?
- I want to know my father.
- Luis is your father.
- Yes, he is too, but I know him.
We won't talk about this now.
Let's go home, please.
Why do you hate him so much?
Ismael!
You should go home.
It's the only place he knows.
I'll take the path down to the town.
- I'll go with you.
- You can't walk.
Of course I can!
You two stay in the hotel
in case he comes back.
No, I can't just sit here.
Come with me, if you want.
I'll wait here.
Ismael!
Where can he be?
- Ismael!
- Nora, this way.
It was her, obviously, because...
The child was fine until she arrived.
You saw that, didn't you?
Ismael!
This is ismael.
If I don? Answer! 'M in class
or very busy.
Ismael,
I'm in the hotel, waiting for you.
The others are out looking for you.
Stop messing, you'll regret it later.
Mom's worried.
You know her, she always thinks...
Shit!
- Ismael!
Ismael!
Hey!
If he went the other way,
the town isn't far.
He'll see the lights.
Every time you come into my life...
Chino,
I said I can't do anything today.
Really?
I'm a disaster,
I can't give you advice.
Lots of times
I just did what my friends did...
And I'd get beaten up
or reported to the police.
It was shit.
Once, nutter... I mean, your father,
told me something
I've never forgotten.
Rage is like a hand grenade
for a one-armed man. Understand?
He can activate it with his mouth,
but he cant throw it.
He can only run. Can you imagine it?
The one-armed man running
and suddenly, boom!
The grenade blows up in his face.
You've got a great father.
Hey, don't cry on me.
You want me to start crying too?
Luis, they found him.
He's with one of Fe'lix's pupils.
Yes, I'm fine.
We're going back now.
You still use it.
It's the one you gave me.
You gave up the rehabilitation.
I couldn't let anyone else touch me.
That's stupid...
I looked for you.
I looked desperately for you
for three years.
I went to all the places
you ever mentioned.
I even went to Nigeria,
I showed everyone
the photos I had of you.
I never moved from here.
When I was starting to forget you,
you started pursuing me.
You'd appear everywhere,
in the reﬂection of a store window,
in the puddle in a train station,
in a shadow in the forest.
You never let up.
- You pursued me like a curse.
- Don't go on.
I didn't come for an explanation.
Call your mother.
Tell her we found ismael.
She was very worried.
- Why do you call him "n utter"?
- Because he's nuts.
He's not like the other teachers.
He's always direct.
Go on.
I'm sorry.
Thanks.
- You'd do it for me.
- Did bonobo find somewhere to hide?
Yeah, no one will find him.
- We hid him in the school.
- In the school? Are you crazy?
- What's wrong?
- You guys never learn.
Take it easy. It'll be all right.
Good luck, pal.
- Sort it out, chino.
- Don't worry.
Can I sleep over with félix?
You go with him.
I'll go back to the hotel.
- On your own?
- I know the my.
But it's easy to get lost.
Chino!
Nutter met my father at the court and
told him to withdraw the complaint,
to leave me in peace,
that I could have a future too,
that I was intelligent...
No one had ever told me
I was intelligent!
- I'm sure you are.
- It doesn't matter
but nutter thinks I am,
and that's neat.
It's like I love myself more.
Nutter's been great to me.
Well, to me and to others.
He gets involved in every mess,
he's not afraid of anything.
- Thanks for seeing me back.
- You're welcome.
Hey...
You're a real looker, I'm not
surprised he's in love with you.
No offense meant.
Are you staying?
Nutter seems really lonely.
No girlfriends or anything.
We even thought he was a faggot.
- Good night.
Where's ismael?
He's staying with félix.
He won.
You never told me
they were a posh crowd.
- I'm going to shower.
- Ok.
It wasn't a good idea
to leave him there.
We have to leave very early.
You go back now,
I'll take the train tomorrow
I thought you couldn't
do it on your own.
What happened?
What have I missed?
I'm not always like this.
- Like what?
- Like the one-armed man's grenade.
But this is a weird day.
Yesterday I didn't even know
I had a grandmother,
and today I like Nora.
Why do you two always fight?
I don't know.
Because she wanted me
to be what I'm not.
And I blame her
for the things in me I don't like.
Your house is cool.
Did you imagine
I'd have a house like that?
- No.
- And me?
- Am I like you imagined?
- No.
Is that good or bad?
It's good.
I was afraid I wouldn't like you.
Anytime you want to go to bed,
just tell me.
Pick the room you like best,
there are loads.
You don't have one with padded walls,
do you?
- Hello.
- Hi, there.
We prepared
something for you to eat.
Does your husband like beer or wine?
I don't think he'll come down.
He needs to rest.
He drove the whole way.
You can't eat on your own.
I'll sit with you.
Yes, well, good night.
If you need anything, let me know.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Ismael has been very good.
And he must have been really tired.
You have a very well behaved child.
What are you getting at?
I want to talk about ismael
and what will happen now.
Nothing will happen.
That's impossible. He knows us now.
My son has a life,
and he'll continue
to live it as before.
And félix?
Are you going to stop him
seeing his father?
My son has a father...
Who gave him his name and helped me
rear him. And that father isn't félix.
Don't you care what ismael thinks?
I'm going to protect him. Nothing
matters more to me than he does,
that he's well and grows up happy.
I'm sure félix thinks the same.
If it had been up to Felix,
ismael would never have been born.
I don't have much experience
as a father.
I should have got you a video game
or something like that.
- It doesn't matter. I'll teach you.
- Teach me what?
To be a father.
Where did you get that cigarette?
I always have a pack to hand.
In the practice, in the car.
I rarely touch them,
but from time to time...
When you said you'd stopped smoking,
I thought that...
That I was telling the truth?
I wasn't.
So now you know
you're not the only one with secrets.
What do you mean?
You always said that félix
wasn't important in your life.
It lasted three months.
I saw how you looked at him.
I'm tired.
This wasn't
one of the best days of my life.
I saw how you looked at him.
Félix is lsmael's biological father.
He'll always be part of
the most wonderful thing in my life.
I know.
You'll have to live with that,
because otherwise...
Otherwise, what?
I can't change what happened.
Félix is lsmael's father.
Until a few hours ago he was our son.
Now you talk as if
he had nothing to do with me.
He's got my surname.
That's not going to change.
But now he knows félix...
And what at?
What do you want me to do?
Stand aside?
See how they take away
the only thing I care about?
Please, alika, say something.
- I don't want to talk about this now.
- But I do!
What?
I didn't put ismael on the train.
Don't blame me
for 'what's happening.
And what is happening?
Because I don't understand.
Since I arrived here
I've become like...
A piece of furniture.
Is that my place in this story?
Look...
Until today I've been your husband
and lsmael's dad.
You have to decide
if you want that to continue.
You scared me!
What are you doing?
You're covered in grease.
I couldn't sleep so I thought
I'd do something useful.
I didn't think it would make
so much noise when I turned it off.
- Do you know about boilers?
- No,
but there's nothing you can't fix
with a bit of lubrication.
Or with a hammer blow
in the right place.
No offense,
but I'd rather an expert saw it.
Right.
Are we talking about the boiler?
- Is this your room?
- We'll have a whiskey
and you can relax a bit, all right?
With those grease stains,
you're even more attractive.
What?
How long since you last screwed?
If you think I accepted a drink
to get into your bed, no.
Ok, it was just a question.
Let's go back to traumas,
they seem to interest you
more than sex.
- Excuse me, but I love sex.
- Really?
Let's analyze what happened today.
You USS an excuse
to tum up at your son's house,
a son you rarely see.
No, ismael is not an excuse.
You pretend to have a sprain
'which no one believes.
- But it really hurts...
- And at night, instead of sleeping,
you go down to the basement
to smear yourself
with lubricant.
Why don't you just admit
that you find me irresistible?
What do you feel like?
I don't have much.
- My house isn't like jordi's.
- What do you have?
I don't think you'll like it.
Quince jelly.
Really? I love it!
- Have you no more games?
- Yes, there's a file,
but they're old games
so don't criticize me.
You 're beautiful.
You can? Be asleep!
What?
- You really want me to read to you?
- Yes.
Bu! R's so long.
We've got all the time in the world.
We're going to be here
for five days.
Hi stay.
Let's see.
“Call me ismael.
Some years ago,
having we or no money
in my purse
and nothing particular
to interest me on shore,
I thought
I would sail about a little
and see the watery part
of the world. '
I loved her very much.
- And her?
- I think she loved me.
Why did you split up?
It was my fault.
Why did you never look for me?
Because I'm a fool.
Luckily you don't
take after me in that.
I'm worried about félix.
He really suffered over alika.
Come on!
At 20 you die and revive all the time.
He can't punish himself all his life
because once
he was carried away by fear.
I blame movies.
They've done a lot of harm.
Love isn't that...
Slushy, clingy thing
that ends with a stupid kiss
and violins in the background.
No, you can live without love
but not without food and a roof.
And if you fall, you get up.
It's happened to me 1,000 times
and look, here I am.
That's why I brought him up
to be independent.
Hey!
- What's wrong?
- With me, you needn't pretend
to be strong, insensitive, all that.
If you go on like that, I get bored.
I see.
When did I last smoke one of these?
When was it?
He says that
I mined his father's life.
What does he kmow'?
And that I was never in love.
He doesn't know vimat it's like
living with a depressive who...
Pulls you down day after day,
while you try to hide it
from your son.
If I hadn't loved him...
Here, this is poison.
I feel dizzy.
All right,
we'll leave the sex for another day.
- If you want, I'll put on some music.
- And we'll dance.
Did I say we'll dance? No, no, no.
No, no, no.
Yes, please. You can't refuse.
You asked for it.
Didn't you sprain your ankle?
Stop, alika.
I don't want to.
We shouldn't have stayed.
I behaved like an idiot.
I mow 'what's x-wrong with you.
You don't. Even I don't know.
Why don't you go upstairs?
Get some sleep.
I'll get ismael and as soon
as we come back, we'll leave.
- Is that what you want?
- Yes.
I want to go back to our home
and forget about all this.
Are you sure?
Yes.
I was scared.
Couldn't you sleep?
I'm a sleepwalker.
- Does it scare you?
- Being a sleepwalker?
The piano.
Why not throw it out the window'?
- What an idea!
- Out with the piano!
Why do you want a piano
if you don't play it?
Well?
- Are you going to tell me?
- Tell you what?
What?
You know all my family secrets,
I should know something about you.
The truth is, a bit of sex
would have done wonders for us.
I'll answer
all the questions you can ask
- in one minute.
- One minute?
Why do you live alone?
What happened to you with the piano?
And why do you always
look at my cleavage?
And there are 30 seconds left.
Why do I live alone?
Isn't it more than demonstrated
that the couple
is a factory
for making unhappy people?
Touche'. And the piano?
The piano...
This piano...
Knows I'm the worst musician
in the world.
Know howl composed my big success?
In a London pub after drinking
eight pints of beer.
I'd gone to an audition
for the philharmonic orchestra.
I'd been preparing for two years
and they didn't even take me
as a substitute.
So, at the bar in the pub, drunk,
I took a ballpoint and a napkin
and started to minute the first thing
that came into my head to show
my scorn for music.
I vaguely remember that I was humming
and some hooligans repeated it,
like at a concert.
Pablo, a friend who was with me,
recorded it without telling me,
and sent it everywhere.
And, fuck me,
three months later
the song was playing
- on radios in half the world.
- Good lord!
Even the pope in Rome knew it.
And, then,
you wouldn't believe the money I made.
And I could buy the hotel.
A napkin,
a lousy napkin with a couple of notes,
was my big success.
I liked the idea
and I wanted to do it again.
I went back to London,
back to the same pub,
I got drunk the same way,
smudged thousands of napkins,
I even hired some hooligans,
but, you know,
every time I tried
to write a new success,
it became a new failure.
And, well,
your cleavage
isn't the best I've seen but...
It has its charm.
'Can you play?
- Can you?
- Me?
- Play something.
Go on, even if it's
"Happy Birthday to you".
I don't know at what moment
I decided to love you,
if k was the day you appeared
with your hair soaked by the rain,
when I saw you
lying on my bed for the first time.
What you see in me,
no one saw before.
Mas bum with you.
'(Our disabled prince.
I've come for ismael.
We're leaving now.
You kept it all this time?
Don't do this to me.
I have to go.
I'm thirsty.
Isma, love, we're leaving now.
Already?
Hurry, get a glass of water
and put on your shoes.
I've never stopped loving you.
I know you still love me.
I know it.
I'll never forget your expression
when I said I was pregnant.
I was scared to see you again,
of what could happen to me if I did.
Tell me nothing happened to you
- and I'll leave right now.
- Yes, it happened.
We been obsessed with you
all these years,
but I hated the idea of being
unfaithful to Luis with your memory.
Because he loves me too, truly,
and with the kind of love I need.
Now I'm going back home
to carry on
with the life I left yesterday.
Ismael had a right to meet you,
and he's done that.
If you want to be in touch with him
we can try it.
I won't stop him getting to know you.
He has that right.
But don't think for a minute
that ismael will be
your way of having me again.
Every time I look at him
I'll be seeing you.
Forget me. I don't exist anymore.
Then I'll have to think
that ismael was never born.
Mom, let's go.
- Ismael, say goodbye to félix.
- I don't want to, let's go!
Ismael!
He didn't mean what he said,
he was talking about me, not you.
You must show me
something you've mitten.
Ismael... ismael!
- What happened?
- We're leaving.
Luis!
It'll be hard
to beat your pinball record.
I'd have liked you
to be my grandmother.
I am your grandmother.
I don't know
what félix did or said to you.
At times he's a bit awkward
with these things,
- but I'm sure he loves you.
- I don't want to see him again.
Go on, away you go-
go and see félix.
He must be heartbroken.
- No, I'm not going.
- Why?
He's got a mother
who can look after him.
I saw him pass by a while ago,
going to the school.
What a fucking scene!
Shit, it's crazy.
- What happened?
- Same old thing.
It's a real fuck-up.
They came to arrest bonobo and when
he tried to escape they beat him up.
- Go away, come back tomorrow.
- Excuse me...
- Girls, where are you going?
- Excuse me,
- I'm looking for félix ambrés.
- He's causing bother, like always.
- What happened?
- Come back another day.
Go home! Go home!
You've got no right
to do what you're doing!
You hit a minor in school!
- Are you ok?
- Get the fuck out of here!
Show me the court order
and your badge number!
Go to hell!
- Chino, film his face!
- Get out of the fucking way!
Ambrés, get out
and let them take him.
Look what they did to his face!
We should report them!
- Film them!
- That's enough!
Chino, keep filming!
- You animal!
- I'm sorry.
No, not you.This animal!
I pay your wages with my taxes!
- And you treat us like this?
- Don't be fucking stupid.
What are you doing?
This has nothing to do with you.
- You think not?
- No, no, kids!
Don't be provoked, kids!
Raise your hands!
Don't play along with them!
Not you, chino! You keep filming!
Let him go!
- Felix, no!
- Let him go!
I told you to let him go!
- Film him, chino.
- I said, let him go!
Are you going
to tell me what you did?
What do I have to tell you?
No one asked you to interfere.
If you hadn't insulted them
they wouldn't have arrested you.
- He was an animal...
- Shut up!
You've got no right.
Don't you see those kids adore you?
Of course they do.
I'm teaching them
they've got the same rights as you.
- That's why we're all going to jail...
- Shut up.
You've got no right to deprive
ismael of a father like you.
Since when do you care about my life?
- I've always cared.
- You should have shown it.
We're not talking about us.
We're talking about your son
and about you.
What happened, nutter?
- What did you do to ismael?
- I fucked it up.
Well, go... and un-fuck it.
I can't.
Félix,
once you lost the thing you loved most
out of fear.
Are you going to let fear
choose for you again?
- You've told me that a million times.
- Don't you understand "shut up"?
I can't, really.
What I did was terrible.
He'll never want to see me again.
Look in my eyes.
You're getting on that train
because if you don't I swear
that I'll kick you on to it
so you can go after him.
Mom...
Ismael!
If you walk that fast
I'll never catch up with you.