You know it looks
more suspicious if you
stand outside, right?
떰
Shh.
Come on. Just touch it.
No.
It's not gonna bite.
Come here.
No.
Stop.
떰
Oh, in your pasta
I be gettin' rad
that's focaccia, doctor
Betty Crocker
I spin it proper
laryngitis be
the only obstacle
gotta have ya keep quiet
inspire
get a basket of bread
you got traffic ahead, word 떰
call me
when you get home.
All right.
Like the second you
walk through the door.
Okay.
Please exit
through the rear door.
He's too cute.
Yeah.
He, uh, went down on me
for the first time last week.
He did?
Yeah. It was good, but he
definitely needs practice.
Yeah. I hate it
when they need practice.
떰
If you're not gonna
feed the dog,
neither am I.
We don't even have dog food.
You know where the money is.
You go to the store,
you buy things
for yourself.
What's in there, coffee?
Anything good?
Should we euthanize her?
Let's do it. For fun.
Much easier than fighting.
Why are you still wearing
your bathing suit?
It's summer. It's hot.
Let's play a game.
I thought you wanted
to watch TV.
I did, but now I'm bored.
Dare.
Like truth or dare?
Like what?
It could be anything.
Come on.
Use your imagination.
It's just not the kind of game
you play with two people.
It's just more fun
with a group, you know?
How 'bout checkers?
Come on.
Come on. Please.
Please. Please.
Come on. Come on.
I love how dark I get
during the summer.
Sometimes I get so dark
people actually
think I'm black.
Shut up.
It's true.
Do you have any tampons?
No.
Nothing?
I'm kind of irregular,
so I don't need them
that much.
That's gonna be a big problem
once you start having sex.
Hey, chiara!
Oh, hey, Sammy.
How's your summer been?
- It's going good. You?
- Fine.
Do you still work
at hall of fame?
Yeah. You should stop by
sometime and say hi.
Okay.
All right.
See ya.
No. He's just
some guy I know
from my neighborhood.
You sure
you never dated him?
No. He's a douche.
He'd fuck anything.
Who was that?
Just some girl
I was hanging out with.
Who?
Just some girl.
What's her name?
Jessica.
Is she in your grade?
She's in sixth,
going into seventh.
We made out.
You did?
Yeah.
It was all her idea.
I met a guy.
Cool. Where?
At the beach.
He went down on me.
All right.
It was good,
but he needs practice.
So, what are you doing later?
Probably going out.
All right. So, I'll just
come over after dinner.
떰
Wanna help?
No.
What else do you
have to do today?
Stuff.
Like?
You used to like to help.
Please exit
through the rear door.
You can't get her
or whatever.
I was, like,
"all right. Watch me."
I walk over to introduce myself.
Bro, this girl is 35 years old.
Thirty-five?
Thirty-five.
How'd that go?
I didn't think
I was gonna get it.
Talked to her
about five minutes.
Next thing you know,
boom, got her number,
and that was it.
Maybe that's cause there
was no more alcohol left.
I took a walk to mobil.
And, like, this guy is
standing at the window,
and he's taking mad long.
And I'm, like,
"hurry the fuck up.
I'm trying to get my beer."
He's like,
"oh, shut up."
Did you hit him?
Yeah. This hand
is killing me.
Yeah?
Yeah. I knocked him out.
Hi.
Hey.
How's it going?
Good.
Cool, uh, I was just
in the neighborhood.
Shopping.
Where do you live?
Gravesend.
And you were shopping
around here?
Yeah.
Mmm.
How do I know you again?
The beach.
That's right.
You look different.
Yeah.
So, do you go to murrow
with chiara?
Yeah.
That's a nerdy school, right?
Like, it is and it isn't.
Mm-hmm.
What school do you go to?
Kingsborough.
High school or college?
College.
Um, I should get back to work.
Yeah. Uh, do you
have matches?
You know that's
bad for you, right?
Yeah.
Lila, you're
late again.
Class started 15 minutes ago.
Hurry up and get in there.
떰
I am the motherfucker
rookie of the year
mykki blanco, young Castro
chill
we on that chill tip,
real high
we feelin' real loose,
real fly
we on that chill tip,
real high
we feelin' real loose,
real fly
welcome to hell bitches,
this is mykki blanco
new world order motherfucker,
follow pronto
get in line, nigga
your soul is mine, nigga
your scaredy cat pussy
motherfuckers can't deliver
maybe she born with it
maybe it was maybelline
all white blanco give your
heathen ass a christening
nigga's so greasy in the
daylight, he glistening
"this fag can rap" yeah, they
saying that they listening
pissing in the wind
at the 4:00 A.M. spot
blazed off the indica
a bottle of ciroc
a mouth full of pop
chug it in the pay phone
1-800-loco, motherfuckers
y'all can go home
I'm the new rufio
y'all ain't know
I pimp slap you bitch niggas
with my limp wrist, bro
what the fuck I gotta prove
to a room full of dudes
who ain't listening
to my words
'cuz they staring
at my shoes
we, we, we make love tonight
in the back of the club,
yeah, we feeling all right
lights, lights low
this shit feel crazy
low-key loose niggas know
we getting wavvy
we getting wavvy, yeah,
wavvy, yeah, wavvy
yeah, wavvy,
yeah, wavvy, yeah, wavvy
yeah, wavvy, yeah, wavvy,
yeah, wavvy
yeah, wavvy, huh,
we getting wavvy 떰
떰
When I walk through
'hoods, 'cause
I like your hair as it is.
It gets so light in the summer.
It's pretty.
I hate it.
Yeah, that's why I'm
tryin' to go global
yeah, that's why I'm
tryin' to be a mogul
and I'm hopeful that me
spittin' it soulful
will have me
in the daily postal
flyin' coastal, eatin tofu
like I told you, I know some
who trash rappin'
worried 'bout
the trendin' fashions 떰
So, what's
your favorite way
to masturbate?
What?
What's your favorite
way to masturbate?
What? Just tell me.
All right.
So, show me.
No.
Just show me.
Come on.
Nope.
No.
Have you ever
made out with lila?
I've made out with all
my girlfriends but lila.
I think you should
make out with lila.
Lila?
No. Thanks.
Why not?
'Cause you could have
herpes or something.
Thanks.
I'd rather have herpes
than rabies.
Oh.
You've reached the offices
of the president
of the United States.
Nah. I'm playing.
This is Sammy.
If I call you back, I call you.
If I don't, then, oh well.
It feels so nice.
Nice?
Really nice.
I really wanna be with you.
Keep going.
Like, I wanna be with you,
be with you.
I don't know.
Why?
'Cause you've been
with other guys.
Three.
Three's a lot
when you think about it.
You know, one, two, three.
Is it?
Don't stop.
Why does it bother you?
It doesn't.
Just forget it.
Yo.
Hey, Sammy?
Yeah.
It's lila,
chiara's friend.
You forgot your shit here.
Yeah, I... I kind
of need them back.
I'm at work. You can
swing by and grab them.
Um, can I maybe meet you
after work tomorrow?
Look what Patrick got me.
Shh.
Stick your finger in there.
They'll suck on it.
No.
They don't have teeth.
You do it and tell me
what it feels like.
You're scared of everything.
I'm not, but think
what you want.
Get on.
Do you get dizzy easy?
No.
Uh-huh.
Boo!
Sorry. I was just
taking a piss.
Come on.
This way.
Do you have a boyfriend?
No.
Chiara's always got boyfriends.
Well, that's different.
Why?
'Cause she's needy.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Do you want something from me?
What would I want anyways?
Oh, fuck.
Fuck.
Fuck. Shit.
What's chiara doing tonight?
Out with her new boyfriend.
Who's her new boyfriend?
This guy, Patrick.
It's kind of serious.
He gave her a promise ring.
It won't last.
It might.
It won't.
You're so pessimistic.
I'm not pessimistic,
but, trust me,
it won't last.
They're in love, so it might.
They're not in love.
Yes. They are.
Oh.
No. No.
That's right.
Discipline the animal.
Hear? Try spanking him.
Like this.
Stop.
떰
Yo, does your dog
like to get high?
I don't know.
What's the dog's name?
Coffee.
What kind of name is that?
You named your dog
after a hot
fucking beverage?
Ignore them.
They're just
being dicks.
She's so hot.
So hot.
Gross. Why is she
rubbing herself like that?
'Cause it gets her off.
Looks painful.
Her titties are kind of perky.
She's got peach titties.
She's got a nice ass.
I remember one time
I made a porn.
My ex-girl
found the video.
She didn't like it so much.
Punched me in my face.
I still got to keep
the porno, though.
I've thought about doing that.
Doing what?
Like, as a career option.
Really?
Yeah, totally.
Like, the hours are really good
and so is the pay.
And I like sex, a lot.
Like, a lot, a lot.
She's not very good.
I've seen better.
What's your name again?
Lila.
Lila, why don't you
come and put your ass
right here?
So I can smack your ass
with this paddle...
Till it turns sore.
Turn that white ass red.
I should go.
I have to get up early.
It's the weekend.
Yeah, but, my mom's
in the hospital.
Get me a 40.
It's the best rap
you never heard
that's why I got you
hangin' onto every word
I'm just savin' up,
imagine the stack
they said our boy Barnes
is the savage on the track
that's 'cause it sound like
I'm in a battle when I rap
I got a head full of money,
pocket full of dreams
Biggs said it best, things
ain't always what they seem
in this fake world we live in,
things spinnin' it real
show me nice fuckin'...
where do you live?
Either way, don't matter,
still spinnin'...
25th ave.
Between what and what?
What and what?
Well, we can't
drive up and down
your block all night.
Hmm.
Witnesses can't believe
how your mom's,
like, I can't believe
they ain't even my plan,
that'd kill my seed
please, livin' in the fast
Lane, I keep my Lane... 떰
under, over, drop.
Drop. Out and...
Out, to the side.
Left.
Okay.
Under, over, drop,
around, drop, up.
Out, in, left, right, left.
One, two, drop, three
and get lower.
Out, in, one, two, three.
And then you jump
into line, right.
Can you look at something?
No.
Just look.
I'm sure you're fine.
What am I looking for exactly?
Does it look red or irritated?
I-I don't know.
I would do this for you.
I really don't know.
It looks like you've
been scratching it.
I have. That's why
you're checking if
there's anything there.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
What do you think
about, you know,
keeping things open?
Why?
'Cause you've had
all these other experiences.
I'm older.
A little, anyway.
Look, I know
I want to be with you.
But I can't commit
until we're even.
Even?
You know what I mean.
No. Say it.
Don't make me say it.
You need some help?
You look like
you're coming apart.
Okay.
Olivia, levia,
Rita and Aiden,
please come help light candles
16 through 10.
떰 realize she's on her way
she's sweet 16 today
You never get mad...
Except when I miss my curfew.
You are a pair of angels
that supports me in
everything I pursue.
You threw me this party
in such a spectacular venue,
and you even let me pick
the tasty dessert menu.
To say we're always happy
would be untrue,
but we stick together
and don't need
family therapy or glue.
Mom and dad, come help me light
candles number three and two.
And I'm on that road today
we are finally on the way,
16 today
You are so close to my heart,
and I'm totally smitten.
When I see you,
my heart pounds
and my eyes brighten.
So handsome and gentle,
in your arms,
my knees weaken.
I hope this moment lasts
and never comes undone.
Zach, please help me light
the most special on my cake,
candle number one.
떰
Is everything okay?
Can I cut in?
Um, I didn't get a chance
to talk to you.
My hands are kind of full.
When did you
and Patrick break up?
I don't really want
to talk about that here.
Can you hold onto this for me?
Wow. You really
cleaned up.
I know.
What are you doing later?
Writing
thank-you cards.
Do you wanna come
to a party with me?
No.
Please.
- Why?
- See ya.
Bye.
'Cause I would do it
for you.
Seaweed flow,
must be from that weed smoke
eyes Chinese 'cause
we smokin' sour diesel
blunts siamese, two of these,
you be me, yo
fuck the police though,
we smoke it like it legal
seaweed flow,
must be from that weed smoke
eyes Chinese
'cause we smokin'...
Bored yet?
It's better than a lot
of parties we've
been to this summer.
Fuck the police,
though...
hey, what's up?
I remember you.
You girls need a drink?
It's a party, not a funeral.
It's okay. I'll get it.
What's your name?
Chiara.
Devon.
Nice to meet you.
I like the way you sparkle.
You look like a pink disco ball.
You see Mr. young bone,
ak, I'm so gone
hoes love me, Jerome,
hoes love me, Jerome
sit back, get smacked
get stoned...
yo.
Hey.
Every time I see you,
you look different.
Yeah, I just came from a thing.
Chiara's thing.
Right, right, right. Fun?
Yeah.
Mmm. Um.
It doesn't work that way.
Whoa. Look at that.
What's that about?
I don't want to lose it.
No?
It's kind of over,
but I'm just holding onto it.
That's too bad. Um...
here.
Seaweed flow,
must be from that weed smoke
eyes Chinese 'cause
we smokin' sour diesel...
'scuse me, America,
I don't do the taxes
I make my money flip stretch,
we call it gymnastics
it's fuckin' Friday,
I need a nia long
with a nice set of tits
and a green thong
me and juicy always smokin',
we like cheech Chong
a French bitch pussy,
sweet honey dijon
she love the paper,
everywhere the cash be
cha-ching!
Now baby girl, pop that pussy
like some acne
I must be ballin' 'cause
she only fuck with athletes
I'm that d, smokin' purple
in a black tee
I love weed, nigga,
I got a green thumb
she fuck me, nigga,
until she bleed cum
your favorite crew
will be on milk carton soon
I'm busting off in the ocean
like a harpoon, yeah...
I'm on a road, so alone
you left me cold,
hard on the floor
hard to endure
Hardy and pure
how are you sure
the love was so pure
the sex was outrageous,
the way we made love
straight bangin',
wakin' up the neighbors
we fucked on weed,
we fucked on speed
missionary, baby, scratch
my back till it bleed
and you're a beauty,
and I'm a beast
but we didn't make
Disney rated movie
we made magic, we made havoc
you were my prodigy,
the love was my beep status
you were the baddest,
above average
the bedroom was a young
jizzy ad-lib, yeah
one kiss, I was hammered,
yeah
hormones doing backflips
you were down South
for so long...
just do it.
I hate being sick.
It'll sober you up.
Ew, it smells so bad.
Oh, gross.
I'm gonna call a car service.
Why? It's early.
I'm not drunk.
I'm just hot.
I-I can't.
Open your mouth.
Why?
I'll do it.
Open your mouth.
There's puke in your hair.
Get it off me.
No. Do it yourself.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh, you wanna go again? Like...
I don't understand, man.
Bro, what the fuck?
What about your dick?
Thanks a lot, Devon.
Thanks a lot, man.
I always got you, bro.
떰
I gotta, gotta be up
at 6:00 A.M.
Can you set my alarm?
Am I your mother?
This is outer space
pump up the bass
this is outer space
떰
Hi.
Where are you going?
Work.
Sucks.
Yeah.
- Please don't do that.
- I don't mind.
It's my fucking mess.
I said stop it.
I spent the night
with this guy last night.
Who?
He's a friend
of a friend.
Is he your boyfriend?
No, but it's kind of
better than a boyfriend,
you know?
No.
It's kind of
more exciting.
That sounds too exciting.
It's hard to describe.
Are you just getting home?
My dad's gonna kill me.
Maybe you should go.
I will.
What're you gonna tell him?
I don't think I can lie.
That would just make it worse.
If you hear screaming,
call the cops.
Shut up.
I'm serious.
Just tell him you were
at chiara's, or something.
You're really late.
It's really early.
Don't bullshit me.
What are you gonna do,
punish me?
No. If you don't
give a shit,
I don't give a shit.
Don't you wanna know
where I was?
No.
Stop trying
to pique my interest.
Chiara's? Nate's?
I was with
this guy.
Who?
You don't know him.
You don't have a guy
that I don't know about.
If you did,
believe me, I would know.
Hang that up
when you take it off.
I don't want to see it
crumpled up in the corner
of your room.
Please.
Fine.
You've reached the offices
of the president
of the United States.
No, I'm playing.
This is Sammy.
If I call you back, I call you.
If I don't, then, oh well.
- Hi.
- Yo.
I...
what do you want?
I called you before.
I'm working.
I figured.
What's up?
You know.
What? Look, I'd love to hang,
but I'm kind of busy.
My dad freaked
that I came home so early.
He'll get over it.
I hope so.
He will.
Do you mind
if I hang here?
That's not such a good idea.
떰
I really don't think
I could be high
enough to pass out,
then fuck you,
and not remember it.
We were really drunk.
Do you get
what I'm saying?
But you have had
that happen before, right?
Hi.
Sorry about the other night.
I just didn't want you
to do something stupid.
I know.
Did you do something stupid?
I don't know.
It's kind of a blur.
How blurry?
Did you sleep with him?
I don't know. Maybe.
Is everything okay?
I'm gonna see
if I can get you
an appointment.
Please don't.
No. This is not okay.
You don't know
where he's been.
Please don't.
I'm sure it's fine.
I'm gonna take out
the speculum now,
so I need you
to take a deep breath.
It's a bit early
for the first pap smear.
We usually don't do them until
the patient is sexually active,
or until after
the patient turns 21.
At your age,
I would recommend...
Um, an hpv vaccine.
Your gown is on backwards.
Can I ask you
a few questions?
Sure.
Do you smoke?
At parties.
How many alcoholic beverages
do you consume in a week?
Like 60 ounces a week.
Do you remember
to wear your seat belt...
Every time you get
into a car or taxi?
I try.
And how often
do you menstruate?
I don't know.
Monthly?
Maybe.
Every two months?
Sounds right.
Would you like to be tested
for stds?
No.
Do you have any history
of high blood pressure,
cancer or heart disease
in your family?
Yes.
Which?
Cancer.
Who, and what kind?
Mom. Breast cancer.
At what age
was she diagnosed?
I don't remember.
Alive or deceased?
Deceased.
I would like you
to consider participating...
In a surveillance program
at some point in
the next few years.
Are there any questions
I can answer for you today...
About your personal
or sexual health?
Lila, is there a reason
you came in today...
For emergency contraception?
I think the nurse
made a mistake.
You've reached the offices
of the president
of the United States.
No, I'm playing.
This is Sammy.
If I call you back, I call you.
If I don't, then, oh well.
What are you doing here?
What do you think
she's doing here?
Your mom let me in.
I think she's here
'cause she wants your dick.
She can suck my dick.
You never shower.
She don't want...
Your smelly little stinky dick.
I think she wants
to suck all our dicks.
She only likes
to pretend to
suck your dick.
I'll do it.
It's gonna be a little hard
to do standing up.
Go on.
Come on, puppy, sit. Sit.
Did you decide
who you're gonna do first?
Pick me.
Do you like it?
Do you like my dick?
It doesn't like you.
What do you want?
What's wrong?
Oh, come on.
떰
I'm the motherfuckin'
rookie of the year
mykki blanco, young Castro
killer
we on that chill tip,
real high
we feelin' real loose,
real fly
we on that chill tip,
real high
we feelin' real loose,
real fly
welcome to hell, bitches,
this is mykki blanco
new world order motherfucker,
follow pronto
get in line, nigga,
your soul is mine, nigga
you scaredy cat pussy
motherfuckers can't deliver
maybe she born with it,
maybe it was maybelline
all white blanco give your
heathen ass a christening
nigga's so greasy in
the daylight, he glistenin'
"oh, this fag can rap,"
yeah, they saying
that they listening
pissing in the wind
at the 4:00 A.M. spot
blazed off the indica,
a bottle of ciroc,
a mouth full of pop
chug it in the pay phone,
1-800-loco
motherfuckers y'all can
go home, I'm the new rufio
y'all ain't know
I pimp slap you bitch niggas
with my limp wrist, bro
what the fuck I gotta prove
to a room full of dudes
who ain't listening to my
words 'cause they staring
at my shoes
we-we-we make love
to the night
in the back of the club,
yeah, we feeling all right
the lights, the lights low,
this shit feel crazy
low-key loose niggas know
we gettin' wavvy
we getting wavvy,
yeah, wavvy, yeah, wavvy
we getting wavvy, yeah, wavvy
yeah, wavvy
we getting wavvy,
yeah wavvy, yeah, wavvy
yeah, wavvy 떰
떰
Yeah.
Yeah, you remember
back in the days
when we used to rock waves
and shit?
when, like, yo, I had
the fucking 360, my nigga
like, nobody in the hood
was fucking with my shit
and that's real shit
uh, since nine five,
mama been working nine five
and I know the landlord
fed up with our lies
so we pray to the gods,
the jahs and the allahs
to keep us safe
and watch our lives
'cause all we tryin' to do
is do good
put on my hood
when I walk through hoods
'cause these niggas
these days is loco
you'll get it in ya vocals
if you ain't a local
yeah, that's why I'm tryin'
to go global
to be a mogul
and I'm hopeful
that me spittin' it soulful
will have me
in the daily postal
flying coastal, eatin' tofu
like I told you, I know
niggas who trash rappin'
worried about
the trendin' fashions
rather than
descendin' passion
they want me send 'em tracks,
but I just send 'em laughin'
right after I start laughin'
they start askin'
what happened
I'm back to the chapter
mama told me follow dreams
and never have to answer to
so that's what I do,
became an mc master
since then
it's been a disaster
for you
and your favorite rapper
go ahead, ask 'em
"who is Joey bad?"
watch 'em gasp, asthma,
damn, it's so sad
he paused the chatter 'cause
he know he rather back up
than to admit the kid
is hotter than magma
but fuck it, you gotta
give credit where it's due
'cause you ain't gon'
like the karma
when it's set up on you, it
can get you on your medical
fuck you up in the decimals
or get you two to three
for residue found
in your retinal
uh, and they told me
not to be so complex
dumb it down to accomplish
articles in complex
and the source,
Alfredo, of course
there I go again, steppin' out
of line, runnin' off course
I heard reports that
it's like sexual intercourse
with your thoughts
when I talk
about the shoes
in which I walk
for it is not faux nor false
that this kid from the north
speaks with forced supports
of reinforced assaults
I'm sure by now you can assume
he never lost
unless it was some form
of divorce, or a corpse
born boss, no days off,
child labor
let me see those in favor
to spin that back
like tornadoes
Yeah. Go ahead
what rap audience ain't
ready for is a real person
you know what I wanna say,
a real n-I-g-g-a
I'm comin' at 'em
a hundred percent real
I ain't compromisin' nothin'
anybody that talk about me
got problems
you know what I'm sayin'?
I'm comin' straight up
like if I'm a street person
that's how I'm comin'
at the whole world
and I'm bein' real about it
and I'm gon' grow
wit' my music
Yeah, but
it's far from over
won't stop till I meet hova
and my mama's in a rover
till I'm an owner
of the world's finest motors
I blow like supernovas in your
daughter room on a poster
known as history's
biggest musical composer
no disrespect to Bob mar,
yeah, another stoner
marijuana my odor,
and when I get older
hope my spermatozoa from my
scrotum meets a sexy ovum
like three times,
have three kids
I hope me and my wife
can show 'em
not to make the same mistakes
you know that we did
I hope they acknowledge
the knowledge
'cause yeah,
they gon' need it
'cause when my family
tried to tell me
I just wouldn't receive it,
couldn't believe it
till I saw
with my own pupils
felt bad when I learned that
the advice was truly useful
but fuck it, only made us
as human beings more mutual
even though over time
our punishments,
they grew more crucial
so use the word "brutal,"
'cause my parents mad strict
hope one day I'll attract
the likes of even madlib
go call the mansion
and hear my songs mastered
until then,
all I can do is imagine
imagine
I'm gon' make it all happen 떰
yeah. It's all right.