No crystal or china.
I hate white-picket-fence stuff.
Great shirt.
Where'd you get your sense of style?
When I met him, he was wearing polyester
and dating women.
- I didn't know who Jackson Pollock was.
- Thanks for helping, Monty.
So, guys, you've been together two years?
What's the appropriate gift
for this anniversary?
Tupperware?
Hair weaves? Tummy tucks?
Come on, Brandon, get up and dance.
Are you crazy?
Oh, God.
- Who's hungry? We just made it.
- Spanakopitas!
- No, thanks.
- No?
Quit smoking. It'll kill you.
That's a nice haircut.
It's much, much better.
Go to the kitchen.
- What'd your aunt say?
- You don't wanna know.
Why'd you pull away from me like that?
- I feel awkward around your mother.
- She doesn't care, Brandon.
She's not like your mother.
He's Jewish?
Half-Jewish, half-Greek.
We thought this would go great
in the living room. What about here?
You're not putting that here.
This always happens to me.
Quick, go get a broom.
The clock can't stay.
It won't stay. Trust me.
I'm not myself since I stopped smoking...
sixteen years ago.
You stopped smoking 16 years ago?
Are you joking?
Ready?
Happy birthday, Brandon.
- I don't believe it.
- That's Patrick...
here, and that's Violet.
- God, they're beautiful.
- I got one more surprise.
- What?
- Come on.
Look who's here.
Surprise!
Brandon, how old are you?
You are so bad.
- Happy birthday.
- Did you know?
No.
- Brandon.
- Rodney.
I got him.
You kidding?
- Fantastic.
- The whole family's here. Andrew.
- Can I push the dog off the raft?
- No, that's not a nice thing to do.
- It would be fun though.
- Fun for you, not for the dog.
Nick!
I'm off to England. Financing came through.
What's wrong?
You better get a test.
- Why?
- That flu...
wasn't the flu.
I got it.
You tested positive?
Yep.
How?
Dave said it happened before we met.
- You won't leave me, will you?
- No.
I won't leave you.
Better not use my razor
if you want to stay negative.
- Look at yourself.
- "Look at yourself."
- What do you see, girl?
- "What do you see, girl?"
- Do you see the body of a woman?
- "Body of a woman?"
- The temple of creation and motherhood?
- Your lunch is served.
The flesh of Eve that man,
since Adam, has profaned?
That body was meant for begetting children.
It was not meant for the lust of men.
- "The lust of men."
- Want more children, Lilith?
"I want more children.
"A lot more children."
There's a really good scene coming up.
If you won't kill him, I will.
I got a meeting I've got to get to.
He joked about them.
Said if we ran into dinosaurs on Mars,
Renee should take care of them.
If nothing else works, maybe gas?
Are you crazy? You should be in bed.
Come on back to the house.
Why? So you can leave again?
Do you want to get sick again?
Dave said that your T-cells are up, so just...
come on back.
Nicky, Brandon's here.
I thought you weren't due back
until tomorrow.
Obviously.
Miss Texas-at-Large,
meet Brandon Theis, famous director.
My pleasure.
He's just returned from another one of his...
business trips.
Outside.
Hello, Brandon.
- Nick, come on in. The water's good.
- I'll be in later.
- What's with all these freaks?
- You never liked my friends.
Tony is practically living here in my house.
It's my house, too.
- What?
- Who negotiated the deal?
Who designed it?
You stayed eight years without paying for...
Stayed here?
My financial planning saved your ass
and this house. You owe me.
- You're out of control.
- Yeah, really?
Really?
Fine, we'll divide it in half.
I'll take this side...
with the freaks.
Don't park there.
Who's this?
- Zack. He's helping me on my film.
- And you're helping him with his homework.
- Knock it off.
- Are you due for a midlife crisis?
Excuse me, your car
is blocking my side of the drive.
So either move it, or I'll have it towed.
That does it. I want you out.
Hey, wait.
Stop!
Where is he taking them?
I sold them.
- To who?
- "Whom." It was an auction. I don't know.
- You get them back.
- I can't.
Opala. Hi, baby.
Fucking asshole, you are not taking Opala.
She is my dog. You gave her to me.
I don't care. You're not taking her.
Fine.
You know, you should never cross a Greek.
We're fair, but we are merciless.
Oh, no!
Sorry, Houdini.
Oh, man.
Houdini, sit.
Stay. Good boy.
Oh, man. Damn it.
Shoot.
Christmas season is usually big
box-office season for the film industry.
But storms across the nation
have literally frozen ticket sales.
Captive audiences across the nation have...
Donald, what's happening?
Tony, sorry I'm late.
Third time this week.
You do it again, you'll get off a week.
- Hey, Nick.
- Hey, Chad, what's happening?
It's Chuck, not Chad.
Well at least it isn't Chip.
All right, don't bust a gut.
Go to a lighter weight.
Fuck!
- Now will you do it?
- Do what?
Nick, you're dropping things.
You're forgetting things.
Listen to Dave. Do the scan.
You look like you caught your balls
in your zipper, Dr. Dave.
I've fought everything else off
for three years.
It's PML?
Yes.
Let's see these little fuckers.
There's a lesion here and here.
They're advanced.
I have 10 days till I croak, right?
- But it could also be several months.
- We've had this conversation.
How long before I become a rutabaga?
Any vision problems?
My right eye
is like I'm looking through a tampon.
So...
it will be like Jim?
Yes. It will be like Jim.
Do you know what I always said
I'd do if I got PML?
I remember.
Time for Plan B.
My driving days is over.
- Sure about this?
- I thought about it a long time.
I'm not going to die blind,
demented and lying in my own shit.
I'm here for you, no matter what.
I know.
Hello, this is Nick.
Can I speak to my mother?
- What can I do?
- You're doing it.
Amalia? I need you to meet me at my place.
Yeah. Now.
- Find your passport?
- Right here.
We're going to the airport from work, right?
Okay, let me see.
Hello.
Nick?
Good guess.
What's up?
My headaches won't go away.
Yes?
And I've lost my keys for the tenth time.
You called Dave?
He wants me to take more tests.
He's given me pills.
- You taking them?
- Yes.
Maybe you should try a sleeping pill.
Right.
Feel like dropping by?
- I can't.
- Why not?
I'm going out of town.
Jesus, you haven't called in a year.
Right, and you have?
I don't need this right now.
You haven't changed a bit.
Have a safe trip.
Who was that?
Was it Nick?
What did he want?
Nothing.
I can't believe you even talk to him.
He'd only call if he were extremely upset.
After what he did, why would you care?
You know why.
Bet you're happy the blue screen's over.
That dog's a nightmare.
That trainer's useless.
We should've used the guy from
West Hollywood Dog Training Academy.
Nope.
Dead.
Dull.
Never.
Dead.
Might as well be dead. Dead.
Christ, Monty.
Now we're in trouble.
- Hi, Tony.
- Hey, sweetie.
- Where is he?
- He's in the office.
- Hello, doomed one.
- Monty Tipton, please.
You are wearing black.
It's a fiesta, not a funeral.
You taught me black was slimming,
but whatever. One fat pig coming right up.
You're looking good, girl.
We needed a party animal
to liven things up. Monty!
- Nick.
- Drop everything.
- Now?
- Yeah.
- I gotta go.
- It's a command performance. Now!
I got him.
Good month.
You look great.
- I can't believe you're sick.
- Who knew?
You should see my headshot.
Now you can get me a Tylenol commercial.
So, who can I call?
We're doing okay, right, Tim?
We'll probably need a bouncer.
A few single straight men are coming.
Single and straight, in this house?
Johnny.
Get the hair out of your face.
- You called your father?
- Next.
- Call him.
- The jerk would never come.
Tim Bergen, Nick's partner.
You did call Brandon?
Fuck, no. I'll pretend you didn't say that,
so we can stay friends.
- You've got to.
- No, forget it. End of story.
This won't be an unhappy occasion.
You haven't said a word.
What's up?
Good morning, Danielle.
I'll get you some coffee.
- Anybody seen the animal trainer?
- Stuck on the freeway. He's on his way.
So what do we think of Samantha Frank?
She's a vacuum with nipples.
- Amalia, let me help you.
- I can do it.
- I'll take one.
What's all that?
You said a lot of people were coming.
My God, she dropped the groceries all over.
Look at this.
Let's clean it up. Come on.
There must be something.
Chemotherapy, something?
Take this. Nothing works.
It's the same thing Jim had.
There's nothing they can do.
I need you to be strong for me.
I'm counting on you. Come on.
Amalia.
- We knew this day was coming.
- No, not today.
Please, not today.
- I'm in shock.
- We all are.
- Shouldn't somebody tell Brandon?
- No.
Nick's got enough problems.
Excuse me.
Yes, he called.
Get here as...
Fifteen minutes would be great.
That's the other line.
What is this huge oatmeal for?
Who's gonna eat this?
And you got two, just to be sure?
Nick.
There's a limousine outside.
It's the Harts. Don't worry about that.
Bill, how are you? Good to see you.
- Sara.
- We heard on the way to the airport.
- That house. I wish I was going with you.
- So do we.
Since you're the first people here,
you'll know everybody who's here.
- Are you feeding this dog?
- Of course.
I know you want to keep it small and cute.
This is my mother.
Anybody home?
Mrs. Bingham and son.
So glad you could make it.
- Oh, you.
- You don't look sick.
- Missed you.
- You do.
- How you doing?
- Hi.
Come on. Let's meet everybody.
Okay.
Nick, how about Matt in New York?
Definitely. Lina, Andrew. Bill, Sara.
To put everyone's mind at ease...
I've transferred all my accounts to Amalia.
But I've got some bad news.
There's no money in them.
Why give your mother such a hard time?
You must be tough on kids these days.
I'm just teasing, Ma.
This is my party.
So...
there'll be no wake and no funeral.
So grab the free booze while it lasts.
Come on.
- Uncle Nick?
- What's with the hair?
It's for a show.
- You're a dancer now.
- Yeah, and Dad's not doing leaps.
I thought he'd be in bed...
not joking and pouring champagne.
Amalia.
- Where's Brandon?
- Who cares?
- Nick hasn't told Brandon?
- Nick couldn't handle it.
You lost so much weight.
I thought your ass was Jodie Foster's chin.
Babe, you know me,
I never miss an opening...
or a closing.
You look fantastic.
This a tan, or Ava Gardner's
Show Boat make-up?
"I always look well when I'm near death."
Greta Garbo in Camille.
And we move on to Double Jeopardy.
What is this? The Big Chill, or what?
More like The Deep Freeze.
I want an unbiased opinion.
You.
Which of us is tanner?
Yes. Monty,
have you met my mother, Amalia?
Wanted to see if you're paying attention.
I'm going to fix the music.
Why don't we sing Christmas carols?
What do they sing in Australia?
"We Three Kangaroos"?
Oh, man.
Quincy.
Don't mind the car. Sit. Speak.
I'm sorry. We're very busy right now.
Don't you have a paper route or something?
Brandon.
Charlene.
It's been a while. What are you doing here?
I tried calling you. Nick's sick.
He's having a gathering.
We're heading out of town this afternoon.
And he doesn't want me there.
Brandon, it's a farewell party.
They did a brain scan.
He has a few days before
his mind's completely gone.
No.
Why does this have to happen now?
Of course, he planned this whole thing
to annoy you.
Maybe I can fly back.
There won't be time. Do what you want.
What's going on?
- I'm going over to Nick's house.
- For what?
He's very sick.
Again? Who'll finish directing the scene?
Who cares?
It's not directing, it's animal training.
Stan, take over, will you?
When will you do it?
This Friday night.
Not gonna end up like Jim and Jack,
unable to take care of myself.
You'll still be alive.
You call this living?
I'm too weak to work.
The pain is unbearable.
Look at me. I'm ready.
Sounds like a good idea to me.
- Some champagne, dear?
- Sounds simply marvelous.
Here goes my diet.
Hi, Brandon.
- My best piece, so far.
- She's beautiful.
That's Liz.
Happy birthday.
Joe wants us here Saturday
to arrange his body.
Arrange?
Tony says the Seconals
can cause convulsions.
I wouldn't want my family to find me
wearing these crepes.
I'll miss you, Joey.
That's nice of you, darling.
This might not be a pretty picture.
You know that?
Come on, Nick, that's enough.
- You sure you can handle this?
- Yes.
Oh, no. What do we do?
The pillow.
Are you nuts?
Can you imagine waking up after this?
He could be a vegetable.
Oh, God.
I read in The Final Exit
you should use a plastic bag. I'll get one.
What's Final Exit?
It's a book.
You wouldn't know it,
because no one's filmed it.
I found one.
Much better.
Juan, hi. Look, we...
- He's still alive.
- No, he's not. No.
Give him time. The pills haven't taken effect.
Come on. Call Tony.
Calm down, Juan. Come on.
Is he gone?
Yeah.
Who's got a camera?
Joe.
Anybody home?
Elvis has left the building.
Come on.
I'm going to miss Joe.
Is this a girl?
- Yes.
- So I'm not the only bitch in the room.
Nikko.
Nikko, we're here.
Baby sister.
You only call if it's a matter of life or death.
- I always call you.
- Do not.
Do, too.
Thanks for coming, doll face.
Hi, Aunt Fanny.
You still tailgating semis?
They kept losing us, trying to change lanes.
Not easy.
- We have to go.
- I thought the plane waited for you.
Yeah, but we'll lose our take-off spot.
We'll be thinking of you.
Bill.
- Goodbye, Nick.
- Take care.
Goodbye, Nick.
You know...
I love Sara and Bill, but that dog...
Come on, let's go inside.
You made it.
Can't stay long.
Hello, Amalia.
- I think dementia is setting in.
- What is the Snow Queen doing here?
What a surprise.
Charlene told me.
You look great.
Live fast, die young,
leave a good-looking corpse.
How's Opala?
Fine.
I was just heading to the airport.
And where are we whisking off to
this holiday season?
Australia.
We're shooting the rest of the film there.
You and Junior?
You called this morning.
I thought you might want to see me.
He's seen you, and it's not a pretty picture.
When's your plane?
Soon.
We were going to say goodbye
to the boys at the firehouse.
- You got nerve showing up here.
- Get used to me.
Why don't you say goodbye and go?
I'll go when I'm good and ready.
You know how to do that so well.
- Don't make me run at this wake.
- Let's get a drink or two, or six.
Are you okay, hon?
"He has every characteristic of a dog,
except loyalty."
Henry Fonda in The Best Man.
Vodka rocks.
He looks better than ever.
He's got four, maybe five days.
I always figured there'd be time
to talk things through.
Uncle Brandon,
I thought you weren't coming.
God, you look so tall.
Tony, make him leave.
He's upsetting Nick,
and my mother's nervous enough.
- It's okay. I'll handle it.
- Okay?
- Is your father coming?
- He called. He'll be here any minute.
Will you excuse us?
Nick's family needs to say goodbye
in the time left.
What'll happen to him?
- You don't want to know.
- What will happen to him?
It's Progressive Multifocal
Leukoencephalopathy.
It moves fast.
He's already losing his peripheral vision.
And you're here to help?
Brandon...
your being here, it's just adding
a lot of stress and confusion.
Do us a favor.
Catch your plane before he gets back.
I've a right to be here.
You lost that right...
- when you kicked him out.
- Who are you to judge?
- This is between me and Nick.
- What's this?
Looks like one of Nick's art pieces.
My God.
It's our friends who have died of AIDS.
There's so many of them.
Jim Bixby was first.
He and Carl were together for...
- How did you stay together for so long?
- Wasn't easy.
Two male egos aren't easy to mesh.
He died in the hospital...
tubes coming out of everywhere.
You're a doctor, right?
Ran the AIDS Unit at County
until I couldn't take it anymore.
Now I teach.
There's different types of AIDS?
No.
Different infections
attack a weak immune system.
With Jack, it was toxoplasmosis.
He decided to die at home.
- Can we go outside?
- No, I'm staying here.
And Joey had skin lesions.
He took pills,
but he didn't get the dosage right.
Jeez, what happened?
He needed some help.
You?
I entered medicine to help people.
How soon?
Please, just don't make this any harder.
- I'm not leaving till I talk to him.
- He needs his tranquility.
Houdini's licking his balls, and Jim says:
"I wish I could do that."
I said, "Better pet him first."
So much for tranquility.
I thought you had Australia to go to.
- Can we go somewhere to talk?
- Go ahead, talk.
What's the plan?
Everything's taken care of.
Someone will show you the storyboards.
How soon?
- It was going to be tonight.
- Tonight?
But some friends are coming tomorrow.
I wanted to wait,
but I've got do it before I get too gaga.
I could drag a few days as a vegetable.
Guacamole for brains.
- Actually, I think avocado's a fruit.
- So am I.
- You still have your sense of tumor.
- Only working part of my immune system.
Excuse me.
You're going to kill yourself?
Andy...
I decided to end it before I become a mess.
- How?
- I been storing up Seconals in the safe.
Why'd you tell us?
Why didn't you just do it?
I wanted you to know
while I'm still working on all cylinders.
Almost all.
I think that sucks.
You're pissed off, so you drag us into it.
- It's not fair.
- Come back.
Andrew.
Was it something I said?
I'm sorry.
- He just loves you so much.
- And I love him, and I love you.
Didn't you bring me something?
- Yes.
- Go and get it for me.
I know how you love getting presents.
How's it going with Rodney?
Not good.
He doesn't know how to deal with Andrew.
Things are not great with us.
Then divorce him.
We have three kids.
Staying together won't help anybody.
What will I do without you to turn to?
You'll be fine.
What is this?
- My favorite color.
- It's for your ski suit.
So...
is it me?
It's perfect.
Nick Stark, coming down the slopes.
That's it, Brandon.
Good. Left. Right. You're getting it.
That's it.
I can't turn in this manner!
Shoulder down the fall line, Brandon.
Come on.
Uncle Brandon.
You're doing great. It's the intermediate run.
- But not on my skis.
- Are you all right, Brandon?
Race you guys to the bottom.
You're doing fine. Come on now, follow me.
No. You're such a sadist.
Look to your left. Good, now to your right.
Relax, you tense guy, you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Come on, let's sit down.
What will it take for you two to talk?
Time heals all wounds.
Why is everyone treating him
like he's a goddamn saint?
He acts like it's a joke, like he doesn't care.
It seems that way, I know.
You don't care either. You used to call.
We used to hang out.
It felt weird calling after Nick and I broke up.
He's so close to your mom.
Uncle Brandon, why'd you break up?
It's complicated.
When he got sick, I guess...
I got scared.
Mom said you didn't get it.
But you did, didn't you?
You're gonna die, too.
I'm okay.
Sometimes one person gets it,
and not the other.
They don't know why.
So, what've you been up to lately?
I'm dancing...
in this performance piece
with my boyfriend's band.
What do you do in it exactly?
Most of the time, I'm suspended from wires.
- Has your father seen this?
- No.
I don't think he'd like it.
Why not?
I'm not wearing very much.
Levon.
Daph?
I want to make sure
that Mom is taken care of.
Tony knows,
but I'm telling you, just in case.
It's important...
I'm cremated quickly,
otherwise the insurance won't...
No, don't talk about it.
I can't get over how brave you are.
What's the choice, Brandon?
It ain't going away.
I can't read the fucking numbers.
I don't even remember
how to dial this thing.
Relax.
There are people here to help you.
I might as well have a cigarette.
It's not going to kill me, right?
Why did you come?
We were a big part of each other's lives.
But you ended that.
It's time for him to be with his family.
- You don't know what happened.
- It doesn't matter.
Can't you see, you upset him?
He wants me here.
He's acting like he doesn't, but he does.
I've known my brother longer than you have.
And he wants you to go.
I disagree.
What do dildos and soy beans
have in common?
What?
They're both meat substitutes.
What is a dildo?
Nikko, does all your humor
have to be gross?
Lighten up, Aunt Fanny.
I'm operating on a single T-cell.
Would you like my car?
I need another car
like I need a hole in the head.
Champagne.
Announcing the arrival of Air Brazil.
- Soli's here.
- And not in drag, for once.
- Are those your real eyebrows?
- They're fake, like your tan.
And this from someone
with Betty Boop spit curls.
So, is it true?
Yeah.
Sit.
Rodney.
How are you? So good to see you.
Let me get you a drink.
He looks fine.
He isn't.
Those are for you, drink...
Darling, look who I brought to your party.
Claudette Colbert and Leslie Gore.
- This is for you.
- Both for me?
No.
Cheers.
Give me one of those.
Making yourself at home?
It isn't easy.
Nick's a very loyal person.
Don't smoke the cigarette.
I know that my being here is hard for you.
I'm sorry.
I love him, too.
Prove that. Go in there and tell him.
Don't give her cigarettes.
I don't display my feelings in public.
I doubt if you display them in private.
So cute.
There's Yiayia.
Yeah, that was taken after Grandpa died.
No, it wasn't.
Doll face, the black dress.
You're right.
Imagine having to wear a black dress,
every day in the Greek sun.
Forget about it.
- Why is that one torn in half?
- Dad was in the shot.
The ancient past.
I think it's time to hand out presents.
Monty, for you.
Nick.
It's Macaulay Culkin
throwing up a soft-shell crab.
- Were you on acid when you did this?
- No drug talk in front of Mama.
I took acid once...
when I was pregnant with you.
Mama...
this one is for you.
- Open it, Amalia, let's see.
- No.
Charlene...
- for you.
- Finally. Thank you.
Aunt Fanny, it's small but expensive.
I made this for you, Mom.
I'll never take it off.
I should have the Chinese food.
Lina, it's breakable.
Thank you.
"Don we now our gay apparel."
That's sweet. I'm never gonna fit into this.
That's why God invented shoehorns.
Why don't you just die already?
And this one is for you.
It's an original Mitoraj.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome. I love you.
- It's very beautiful.
- You know, I got that in Italy.
Which reminds me,
I have 50,000 frequent-flyer miles.
Let's go to lbiza.
Your father's here.
Paul?
You are the last person
I expected to show up.
Hi, Dad.
Next to last.
How's your girlfriend?
She's fine.
We sent you a Christmas card
last year, remember?
I got it.
"Love, Paul and DeeDee,"
in her handwriting.
Amalia, aren't you going to say hi?
Hello, Amalia.
What are you doing here?
He's my son, too.
Mr. Stark, I'm Charlene Lee.
Let's get you a drink.
Did you see the latest house Nick designed?
It's gonna be in a magazine.
What're we waiting for?
Let's get out the good stuff.
What a good idea.
He didn't come over to me.
I didn't even shake his hand.
Give it time. I know he's happy to see you.
Greg, you made it.
What can I get you?
Just water, please. I don't drink.
- Alex. Hi.
- This is Nick, and this is Tony.
Come on, you guys,
we're bringing out the good stuff. Help us.
Let's get some caviar.
Does Le Dome deliver?
I think we could talk them into it.
Cool, let's work on that.
- Who needs a drink?
- I do.
Just beer for me.
- Not too much for Nick.
- Look out, it's Nurse Ratched.
- You need a nap.
- A nap? Tony...
I'll be sleeping soon enough.
Easy.
He's my brother.
I'm her brother.
This is my drink.
- Who elected him God?
- Where'd you guys meet?
- We met at 30,000 feet.
- 30,000 feet?
You're not members
of the Mile High Club, are you?
I can't believe you're still smoking.
It's the only thing that calms me down.
But you should really stop, Mom.
Greg, Santa Claus came early,
and dropped off something...
- to stuff your stocking?
- Little?
Do you think it's my fault?
No, I don't want...
Is it some kind of punishment?
You've been a great mother.
Take the whole pack.
- It's Ken and Ken.
- Something tells me you want to be Barbie.
I have been calling the wrong 976 numbers.
Why don't you try 976-HAIR?
Paramedic vans to look at
emergency hairstylists.
Okay, let's play the quiet game.
Monty, you start.
Who is that man?
- Monty Tipton, he's an agent.
- Does he handle any stars?
Once Tony and I were houseguests
at Nick and Brandon's...
and you know how some hotels
put a chocolate on your pillow?
We looked at it and said, "How thoughtful."
We had a closer look and
it turned out that a dog had taken a dump.
Dad, how come everybody's acting normal?
That's what Nick wants.
This is the first time
you've seen me drink beer.
Yeah.
Is it okay?
You're asking me about beer?
Damian Knowles. He's a theater producer.
This is Tony Zamara.
- Hello.
Is he really going to go through with this?
- It is not right.
- Don't start up here.
Someone must talk him out of it.
- Don't you dare fucking try.
- There you are. Nick wants you.
Excuse me.
How are you doing?
It's my worst nightmare.
Do me a favor. Don't make a scene, okay?
Once Damian gets going, he's relentless.
Can't let him loose in the house.
He gets a bowl of dry food in the morning,
and a bowl of dry food at night.
Tony, are you going to remember this?
Yeah.
Grab a pen, and write this down.
Tony isn't living here?
Earth to Brandon,
Nick's been living alone for the past year.
He and the dog next door love each other.
They always fight.
Can't let them be left alone with each other.
Give me a kiss.
Good boy.
How do you know Nick?
I'm his father.
I'm so sorry.
What I meant was,
it's a pleasure to meet you.
- Hey, Marshall.
- How you doing?
- What's that?
- Remember that?
God, I'd forgotten I was your best man.
I'm fine. Nice to meet you, then.
You lost it from the hip,
and gained it in the soul.
You'll be battling the body fat,
which is one of your charms.
I like your shirt though.
Yeah, it's got that '70s look.
I'm worried that he's in danger.
And I don't want him to be in danger.
- You want him to practice safe sex.
- Yes, I do.
Do you know that he's not
practicing safe sex?
We don't talk about that.
If I mention something like that...
I would say, commercials. You know...
He could be the personification
of Cottonelle toilet paper.
Fluffy, soft.
- You liked the idea of commercials?
- Or some kind of fabric softener.
Have you seen Leo, or whatever this kid is
he's been hanging around with?
- I don't know anything about it.
- He's got purple hair, and looks like he...
rolled home through the gutter.
Anyway, I don't know what he's doing.
I can't talk to him.
No, thanks.
Birds and bees are fine,
but bees and bees, I don't know.
Rodney.
You want me to talk to him, Rodney?
It would mean a lot, coming from you.
I rushed over,
because I heard it's going to be tonight.
Now he's extending another day.
Brandon.
- Everybody here knows.
- Yes.
I'll have to discuss this in confession.
So I can't take the sacrament
without confessing that I was here...
knew what was going on,
and didn't try to do something.
Do I have to escort you out of here?
You're not too bright.
I like that in a man.
My mother has drapes in that fabric.
How're you getting along
with your folks these days?
Okay.
They think I don't know
they're splitting up.
Dad sends me to church,
hoping I'll become straight.
Catholic church? Good luck.
I mean, your Dad'll come around.
He will.
Didn't Brandon give you this?
Yeah. Here, you want it?
Looks great. Red, blond hair, can't beat it.
What happened with you guys?
You've heard how opposites attract?
They also repel.
Ever since I was a little kid,
I remember how much you loved each other.
Really?
People grow at different paces.
It's hard to tell who's in the right,
or who's in the wrong.
Sometimes you just...
got to go with your instincts,
you know what I mean?
Look at this. I never even wore these.
So, I hear you have a boyfriend.
- His name is Lion.
- He's cute.
He's in a band.
Excrement Sacrament.
Dad hates the name.
He's right.
You guys are using condoms, aren't you?
- Yeah.
- Sure?
Good. Very important.
I'm out of here, and so...
I'm going to give you these.
Now, these are $300 shirts.
This one is.
You're being a good girl
for Grandma, honey?
Yeah.
We will all be there for Christmas.
Nice gift for the Lion.
When you need somebody to talk to...
I want you to call Brandon.
He loves you very much, and he'll help you.
Don't do it, Uncle Nick.
I have to.
Stay a few more days.
In a few more days...
I won't be me.
I hear you're leaving for Australia.
I'm scheduled to fly tonight.
My sister wants me in the kitchen.
- Andrew, you're going to come with...
- Excuse me?
We went through this. He's drinking now.
Just leave him alone.
We're leaving at 10:30 p.m.,
to see your grandmother, in Philadelphia.
- I'm staying with Mom.
- No, you're not.
- More water.
- What can I do?
- Why don't you relax in the living room?
- Yes, Paul.
So it's okay if we take your credit cards
on a shopping spree?
That's a good idea.
- We'll come and pick them up tomorrow.
- Okay, Greg.
- What time does the party resume?
- Same time, same station.
Right. Nice meeting you, Tony.
- See you, Alex.
- All right, see you.
Greg, drive carefully. You've been drinking.
- You're not going with them?
- No.
- I'm staying.
- I wanna stay, too.
Andrew...
your grandmother's expecting you.
Don't let her down.
I want you to take care of yourself.
Do it for me, okay?
And you.
You're really going to do this?
Rodney, I wouldn't do it if I didn't have to.
I don't want to give you my cold.
- Take care.
- Okay.
Let's go party.
Let's go.
It's the '60s.
I, myself, am too young to remember.
I was such a big fat pig,
before he got on my case.
You weren't that bad.
Come on. I was a fat fag-hag...
afraid nobody would go out with me.
Nick taught me self-respect.
I just flashed
on what life will be like without him.
Will he go through with it?
You ever known Nick
to back out of anything?
Does it take the whole Nile
to quench your thirst?
Drunkenness is...
- temporary suicide.
- Hear, hear.
The Greeks said:
"It's not horrible to die.
It is horrible to die alone."
In the gay community...
you get to choose your family.
And he chose us.
Nick always had good taste.
Just remember, kiddies, "no matter where
you go, or what you do, you're gonna die."
Moonstruck.
Maybe dying's like waking up from a dream.
So you believe in suicide?
No.
I believe in choice.
I was raised a Catholic.
I wouldn't take my own life.
Dying in agony, stuck everywhere with
tubes, is something you'd put up with?
I know I'd rather not.
But I wouldn't take my life.
What's going on?
The man wrapped in newspaper
is reading a newspaper.
I don't get it. What is that again?
- It's conceptual art.
- Conceptual art. Please.
Try hiding your peepee inside of a dress
for Mardi Gras. That is art.
How anyone can support suicide
is beyond me.
You'd be surprised how many people
are helping behind the scenes.
Even doctors.
- Wasn't this in Santorini?
- Yes.
This thing's expensive.
Don't ever call it a paper plate.
I'm sorry, I had a little too much.
What is that? Where'd you get that from?
The secret clubhouse.
Where's Spanky and Buckwheat?
- What's this?
- Already they're planning your retrospective.
That old junk.
- It's brilliant.
- Knock off the modesty bullshit.
I remember when you used to practice
your signature, in case you became famous.
That's one less worry.
Why don't you just sign everything quick?
Death is a great career move for an artist.
Nick, are you sure
you're doing the right thing?
- Hello, Damian.
- Hi.
About what?
It's God's decision when we die.
I told you to leave him...
No, it's okay, let him talk. Go ahead.
Have you...
Have you thought of the significance
of what you're doing?
Why, I hadn't.
I really appreciate your reminding me.
I really needed a moral crisis about now.
If I buy your pamphlet, will you fuck off?
No, stop.
Who is this guy?
- I'm only trying to help.
- It's best to shut up.
I appreciate your concern,
but don't worry about me. I am fine.
I just can't find my keys.
So, you and me, we go find the keys.
Come on.
I want you to leave him alone.
I wonder which is braver.
Taking a life, or not taking it.
Get the hell out of here, Damian.
Thank you, Dr. Kevorkian.
- Damian, I'm sorry, but I warned you.
- I just hate what...
I just hate to see him go.
It's the most comfortable bed in the world.
You'll see it folds out really nicely.
This'll give you a little privacy.
Paul.
So...
- when's the last time you were together?
- The day he walked out on me.
- I didn't walk out on you.
- Now you're back.
- You're pretending to be his father?
- I am his father.
You haven't been his father for 20 years.
If you had been his father,
none of this would have happened.
Would you ever think of that?
Maybe he wouldn't have turned gay.
Maybe he wouldn't be so sick.
Did you ever think of that?
- I think Nick's lucky.
- Lucky?
He's wrapping up unfinished business
with everyone he loves.
Will you be here tomorrow?
Nick and I need to work things out.
Honey...
it would take years...
years for you to work things out.
He's got hours.
Why don't you leave him with people
who really care?
Fuck you. I care about him.
How about you?
Doting on him...
- treating him like he's a mama's boy...
- Stop with all your arguing.
Christ.
Haven't you heard?
It's in the genes.
Designer genes.
You want to take this...
and you want to turn it into a star turn.
The lover returns.
Let me tell you something, honey.
It's been done. And better.
You're pathetic.
Monty, that was a bit harsh.
"Way down deep, I'm very superficial."
Anyone?
Julia.
I won't do it.
I won't spend a night
in the same house with him.
Fanny's already called a cab.
Here it is, Ma.
Good night, Daphne.
Good night, Amalia.
Come on, let's go.
You've been drinking.
You've always hated
the smell of alcohol on my breath.
- Fanny!
- Be careful, Paul.
- It's difficult.
- Yes, we all understand.
Now you see why.
I didn't know how to...
stop being mad at you, Nick.
At me?
You kicked me out,
and you left me to die alone...
away from the home I built,
even away from my dog.
Don't be a prick. I didn't dump you.
It was a shock for me, too.
I needed time to adjust.
And you really tried.
I did.
We stopped making love,
but I stayed with you.
I think you were jealous of me,
for not being sick.
You were jealous
of anyone who came near me.
I wasn't jealous.
You're Greek, you can't help it.
I'm dying.
Why should I care what you say?
You pushed me away...
because you were afraid
that I would abandon you.
I wouldn't have left you.
We'll never really know now, will we?
Do you want me...
to cancel my flight
and come back tomorrow?
What?
Do what you want.
You'll either be here, or not.
Like always.
No.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
You're going to love going to court.
I am not walking off into the sunset,
leaving my mother empty-handed.
I guess this is it.
I can't do it.
I can't leave.
It's for the best.
We tried to make it work, but we just...
We just can't.
This is my home.
Your new place will become your home.
Can I come back here to die?
Good morning, Amalia.
What's all this?
You used to say,
"I don't believe in that religious crap."
Couldn't hurt.
You know what you ought to do?
You ought to go back to making
that kind of jewelry you used to make.
God, it was good.
Remember not to look down all the time.
Keep your eyes up. Okay?
Okay?
Nikko, please don't leave me.
I can't make it without you.
You're going to have to.
Do I smell hot onion bagels,
or did you sleep in that shirt?
Yes, it's me, Monty. I'm at Nick's house.
I want you to bring me a fresh shirt
and a new tongue.
No, just come over as soon as you can.
You look pretty hung-over
for someone who doesn't drink.
I'm having little problems with my vision.
Pieces are missing, like blank spots.
You give me some of that?
Who are you?
You're my dad.
This is richness worth a second cup,
Charlene. How do you do it?
Nick never asked for a second cup
of my coffee.
How are you doing?
Come on, Opala.
Lina and I almost made it once.
What?
We had this electric moment
when you said to me:
"Why'd you have to be gay?"
I said to you:
"Me? Why do you have to be a woman?"
Here's some Thai food.
You can always use more with this crowd.
You're staying?
Yeah.
He always loved this dog.
He's out in the back yard.
Thanks.
I had an electric moment with her.
She's not a woman.
Who's that?
- Brandon.
- Oh, God, he's back.
And Opala.
Come on, Houdini.
Opala. You met Houdini, haven't you?
Sure she has.
Hi.
You showed up.
- How do you like my brand new shoes?
- Nice.
They were expensive, too. I thought...
I should use them.
What kind of a name is Opala?
"Opala" means "trash" in Hawaiian.
They found her in a garbage bag
by the roadside.
- For you.
- Thanks.
Don't you miss them?
I miss a lot of things.
When Opala was a puppy,
she used to sleep in between them.
Lucky bitch.
I got this for you a while back.
A sundial watch?
So is this out of one of your catalogs?
What do you think?
This'll come in handy
for the next seven hours.
- Nick, listen...
- Nick.
Matt.
How are you, man? Good to see you.
Thanks for coming.
- For you.
- That's a pathetic poinsettia.
Babe, welcome to Christmas in LA...
where Santa has sweat stains.
How's New York?
- Brandon's here?
- Sure.
You want to see the finishing touches
at the site?
You mean, the latest house he designed.
I'd love to see it.
Could we go?
Wait now, we can't take a whole group.
Can I come?
If you want.
Why don't I take you some other time?
- Oh, sure.
- Let's go.
This needs water. You take this.
- I'll be back.
- Should I do the kitchen?
- I guess we didn't make the A-list.
- For this I flew five hours?
Let's get a drink.
Does my hair look like one of the seagulls
from the Exxon Valdez oil spill?
I meant to tell you that.
Nick, we've done some great work together.
It ain't over for you.
I get to walk away,
but you gotta keep on slaving.
I've always been amazed...
at the way you see things.
Does the client know
I'm checking out today?
No.
When he finds out I've kicked...
you should jack up the price
based on the sympathy factor.
Here we are.
They're finishing up the kitchen today.
Come on.
I'll be right back.
This is unbelievable.
This reminds me of Santorini.
Do you like it?
Yeah.
So...
- you and Tony aren't living together?
- No, we're just friends.
For a while now.
What about you?
You were...
very perceptive about Zack.
I was just thinking about
that trip to Lake Tahoe.
Remember?
You were teaching me how to ski.
I was giving you such a hard time.
You were so patient with me.
You remember when I finally got it...
and we skied down the hill together...
just...
swirling through the powder...
laughing and shouting?
Nobody connects like we did.
Switch gyms, you'll find somebody.
Stop it, Nick. Stop it.
We're running out of time.
It's not my fault.
We better get going.
They'll be pissed at me for taking him away.
Hi, honey.
Brandon, you've met my wife, Pat.
My favorite cousin.
Excuse me.
What's the idea of leaving the party
without telling me?
So sorry, Mommy. I'll never do it again.
Don't wander.
Awake at the wake.
You're wearing the same thing
you had on yesterday?
I stayed.
Holding a torch on the porch.
Didn't you spend the night with Alex?
Feeling vibrant near his hydrant.
Didn't you think he was cute?
- You two aren't really serious?
- Hardly.
- How's Nick?
- Doing okay.
- Are you holding up?
- I'm glad to see you.
- Who are all these people?
- Nick's friends.
I've never seen them before.
I want you to get them to go.
- He invited...
- Every single one of them.
- I'll see what I can do.
- Don't see.
Get them the hell out of this house.
My son is going to die.
I want to have time with him.
Yes.
Roast beef.
Got to have an empty stomach.
An empty stomach?
For the pills.
Was the spanakopita that bad?
The sun...
keeps going down.
I can't believe this is his last afternoon.
How'd it go?
I can't get through to him.
I don't know if it's...
the sickness or the drugs...
No, it's just him.
Keep trying.
We have to spread the word.
Nick's family wants everyone
to leave by sunset.
We're all supposed to go?
It's my party, and I'll die if I want to
Die if I want to
You would die, too, if it happened to you
Lighten up, please.
It's not a funeral...
yet.
- I want a picture.
- Good, Aunt Fanny, here we go.
All right. Here, Nick. Come on.
Look at me. Smile.
I want an 8 x 10.
Everyone, out of the kitchen.
Let me see your face, Nick.
Here we go. Great.
- One with Matt.
- Matt, sit down.
Squeeze together, guys.
Would you like to have a picture taken
with Nikko?
No, thank you.
I have one at home that I really love.
Let's go.
Everybody, get together. Get tight.
Wait, wait, wait.
That'll be nice.
Where's Dad? Dad, get in there.
All right, squeeze together.
I hope these come out.
Pretty, okay.
One more, one more.
No, I'll go over here.
Yeah, good. Look this way.
And smile.
Now, just me and the children.
Pretty. That's a good one.
Mom, all right, one with you.
I do hope these come out.
Nick's taken his father's place.
Greek sons
always watch out for their mothers.
How about one with Brandon?
Sure. Brandon, come, get in there.
All right. Good, guys. Great.
- That'll be nice to have.
- Who's next?
Do one with us and the baby.
I was thinking about that.
Don't forget. You have to help me
get everybody out before sunset.
That's great, thanks.
Can we go someplace and talk?
Why didn't you tell me you had AIDS?
'Cause I knew you'd be ashamed.
How do you think I feel, being left out?
Facing it all now?
You've been ashamed of me
ever since you found out I was gay.
I've always had a lot of prejudices.
No shit.
I thought a lot about this.
When I dated your mother...
her family rejected me,
because I was Jewish.
I know exactly how you feel.
I'm sure you do.
Watching you with your friends
has made me see things differently.
They care about you so much.
I'm sorry I wasn't a good father to you.
You were a good father when I was a kid.
You gave me my first watercolor set
that got me interested in art.
I did?
It was a deluxe set. It had 42 colors.
I did my first paintings with it, Dad.
I'm so proud
of how you're handling yourself.
Excuse me.
Your family is at our house,
driving me crazy. I can't do it anymore.
He's my business partner for years.
What do you want?
I want you to come home.
- It's what I want.
- You gotta give me more time.
- It's just so sad, Charlie.
- I know.
Get help. Help me.
- It's a paper plate with paint on it.
- It's a Lichtenstein.
It makes me dizzy.
Tony, Stuart's a mess.
He's been drinking non-stop
since he got here.
I'll see if Tim can drive him home.
- You've got to get everybody out of here.
- All right. Excuse me.
Know the phone number for Yellow Cab?
I'll take you to the airport.
- No, that's okay.
- No, I'd like to.
I can't stand the idea
of you being in a cab all by yourself.
Thanks. You're such a doll.
Every cloud has a silver lining,
even a storm cloud.
Is he coming?
No.
You'll tell me if he comes?
Metaxa, right?
Thanks.
What's the picture?
It's a picture of Nikko and Daphne
when they were kids.
Is there anything that I can do?
No, Nikko left...
written instructions for afterwards.
He has a prepaid work order...
for the Neptune Society.
Is there going to be a funeral?
No funeral, no services.
That's what he wants.
He wants me
to scatter his ashes in Santorini.
That's where we met.
I know.
Tony said that...
everyone has to leave, except for the family.
I wanted to ask you if I could stay.
When you came back,
it meant a lot to Nikko.
It did?
He didn't say so...
but I know he would want you to stay.
Thank you.
Douglas?
- Uncle Paul?
- Yeah.
It's good to see you.
It's been a...
You gave up your trip?
Yes.
Listen...
I may have gone...
overboard last night.
May have?
"God always has another custard pie
up his sleeve."
Georgy Girl.
My plane leaves in about an hour.
The family's going to have dinner.
"Not moussaka again."
Melina Mercouri in Never on Sunday.
Do I have something for you.
- The ultimate LA bad-taste jacket.
- You made fun of me when I bought it.
Now it's yours.
Wear it with enthusiasm, Matt.
- I love you.
- I love you, too, babe.
Promise me...
you'll make the choices
that'll make you happy.
I promise.
Remember...
if you need anything though...
call.
I mean, not me. I won't be here.
Funny to the end, aren't I?
You think we could change the music?
Why? You don't like it?
It's been playing over and over.
If you don't change it,
I am going to break that CD in half.
You know...
I always hated mushy music, but now...
I kind of like it.
"Tears?
"When you have been bathed
in scented wine...
- "your limbs caressed by sweet oils..."
- Give it a rest.
"When your hair's...
- "been combed with sandalwood."
- "My hair."
You mean, my hair?
"There will be no time for tears."
The Ten Commandments,
or a Vidal Sassoon commercial.
Will you call me tomorrow
and tell me if he went through with it?
Yeah, sure.
Did you say goodbye?
I can't.
- Here, Monty's leaving.
- Okay.
Babe...
I'd love to stay,
but I gotta go home and sort my socks.
This is for you.
- For good luck?
- You always wanted me to give you head.
Come on, I'll walk you out.
So...
just don't do us any favors and sing
"I Did It My Way."
I won't.
I got drunk last night,
and I was really mean to Brandon.
It's in your nature. He'll live.
He's with Monty.
- You doing anything tomorrow?
- No.
Me, neither.
I really...
miss Jack.
I thought about going with you tonight.
Monty...
you've been positive for eight years,
you haven't shown a sign of a problem.
Even if you do get sick,
you gotta stay strong.
Keep fighting.
You could get lucky.
The next time we see each other,
my tan's going to be darker.
I'll be closer to the sun.
Pastitsio is ready.
Come on, let's go over here.
Eat something, Mr. Stark.
Time for the help to leave,
Mr. Eddie's Father.
- Stay for dinner.
- No.
It's family time.
Come outside and say goodbye to me.
- Okay. Sorry about my dad.
- Nikko, should I make you a plate?
I'll get one in a minute.
I feel like a stewardess.
"Bye-bye, so nice having you, bye.
"Nice having you,
bye-bye, please come back."
Don't you get morbid on me.
This won't be morbid, asshole.
I'll always be looking out for you.
Every once in a while,
just flash me that big Nikko smile.
Every day.
Do you own a pair of scissors?
I want you to go home right now...
and cut these bangs.
Promise?
You're a beautiful woman, Charlene.
How is Mr. Right going to find you
hiding behind this?
Look at that face.
It's a beautiful face.
I want you to stay off Ding Dongs.
I gotta go back inside.
I know.
Goodbye.
Houdini. Come on.
Lie there. That's it.
When I was a little girl, I was so mad...
when you threw out my favorite toy.
- How old was I?
- 10.
But you love me now, don't you?
Yes. I love you now.
This is special sauce.
The sauce is good?
It's from a can.
Really good.
Look, all right.
First off, we've got to keep him
from drinking more.
He's gotta keep his head clear
to say goodbye to his family.
What's all this yip-yapping?
And what's with these sad faces?
- You know, we gotta take a walk.
- Nick.
I'm not losing my mind yet.
- Nurse Ratched.
- I don't want you wandering off again.
I won't be long.
Just don't put me in this position.
- How long have I got after I take them?
- You've got 20 minutes.
Thirty, max.
All right. I gotta do this, Tony.
I got to.
Don't be long.
What's going on?
I don't know. Nick wants to talk to Brandon.
Come on, Opala.
Listen...
I want you to go back to making
the kind of films you made in college.
Okay.
You made such a difference in my life, Nick.
You brought me out of my shell.
- The years that we spent together...
- Yeah.
We had great times.
Come on.
Hey, Violet. Hi, honey.
- Mr. Stark.
- Howdy, neighbor.
I see him every day,
and I can't remember his name.
I am going out of town. Can you feed them?
Sure.
Actually, my friend here can feed them.
Brandon.
Good. Thank you.
They've been here all this time.
I need you to be strong for me.
I don't want you crying.
You know...
I can barely see.
It's like looking down a long tube,
what I see.
Come on, I'll take you back.
Bye-bye, Violet.
Would you take Opala?
You can't let her loose in the house,
or she'll rip everything to shit.
She gets one cup of dry food in the morning
and one cup at night.
Her name's Hawaiian for "trash."
Brandon found her in...
I told him to make sure
that he got a hold of everything...
that I told him he needed...
because I have to keep some distance.
Hi.
Can't a guy take a leak around here?
Sorry.
God, that was the best.
That was the Christmas
we spent in Switzerland.
And then New Year's Eve in St. Moritz.
We took the chair lift up the mountain,
and skied down to the Niarchos party.
We were like James Bond.
We step out of our ski suits,
and had black tie on underneath.
Inside this mansion...
were all these rich 20-year-olds,
lying around, passed out.
And this huge vat of caviar,
with cigarette butts put out in it.
Dad sure is taking this well.
Which reminds me,
when I was 16 years old...
Dad takes Daphne and me
on a camping trip in January.
The ground is frozen solid.
Tony always gave me a hard time
about the Winnebago.
He called it "Cleopatra's Barge."
Excuse me.
I'm going to do a line.
That's that.
We were good together.
I'm going to miss you so much.
You'll find somebody.
I want you.
I'll still be around.
You always said you were an atheist.
Agnostic.
That just means I haven't had proof yet.
But I have a strong feeling I'm not leaving.
Will you send me some kind of sign?
Yes.
- We're close.
- How close?
Pretty close. He already took the pills.
Thanks for staying.
Your mother needs you.
Need anything, Amalia?
No, thank you very much. I'm fine.
Come on.
Sit on my lap.
I want you to promise me one thing.
Promise...
you will stop smoking.
I can't.
Okay.
Then promise me you won't wear black.
Always remember...
I took care of you.
You did.
Nick.
Come here, I want to show you something.
Come on. Come sit over here.
This is our...
trip to Europe last year.
This is you arriving in Amsterdam.
Check out your eyes.
- Not a pretty sight.
See, this is the next day.
Can I talk to you a minute?
Excuse me.
Shouldn't he be spending these moments
with his family?
I don't want him to nod off in front of them.
We have to get him into his bed soon.
Okay.
Remember this?
It's a train station
where we dropped off your French friends.
Where are my keys?
You don't need your keys.
Remember the view from our room?
It's time for us to leave, you guys.
He's starting to go.
Mother...
I love art.
This is us back at the hotel.
It's okay, Nick.
I'm so sleepy.
This is it.
Don't be scared, Nikko.
It's me, Brandon.
- This is it.
- Just lie back and relax.
That's it. Just think about...
us going up the chair lift together.
That sun feels warm.
And with that icy wind
blowing on your face...
it's a weird feeling, isn't it?
We're almost at the top of the mountain.
We're gliding off the lift.
We're stopping up at the top.
Now we're pushing off.
We're flying down.
Ski with me, through powder.