Subtitles downloaded from
www.OpenSubtitles.org.
Last night...
I had a terrible pain.
So hard pain I ate all the
pills I found in the house.
But the pills did not help.
The pain did not relax.
I tried to see some picture in front of me.
Who would have forgotten the pains.
But that's just the ignorance.
I did not come up with anything rational.
Emergency Phone.
- It's a matter of screaming at our doorstep...
Finnish: Arja Meski
www.undertext.se.
He was found in the morning from the floor.
He did the resistance. Overdose.
We found cocaine, alcohol,
all but syringes.
She does not breathe.
Quietly. What is your name?
Call the breathing apparatus.
Give 100 mg Celocurine.
Give tracheotomy equipment.
Has the ventilator become?
Oh God!
Media Talent Agency. Good morning.
Can I have Ivan Beckman's office?
Here's lvan Beckman's office.
Leave the message to Beckman or Lucy
Laurens after an acoustic signal.
This is Rosemary Kramer.
This is about lvan Beckman.
Here in Lloyd Hall.
I have played many times.
Please ask me to
call me right away.
What?
Ivan tirii perfectly.
Lloyd licked her up.
Has Lloyd called 8 times?
Yes, I can not contact you.
Wait.
Is that Lloyd again? What now?
Do you produce any message?
You would not go there.
This is an emergency.
What do you want?
We need to reach consensus.
That's what I try!
There is a faxed list...
Is it suitable for everyone?
Judy?
What now?
Here reads that leva died in the morning.
What?
I'll call and check.
What does that say?
He was in the hospital.
I saw him just recently and
he was not in hospital.
How did he die? With overdose?
He used hard drugs.
- Wait a minute. There is no need to speculate.
Last week he drove a bad crash.
Listen now. Has anyone
seen him lately?
He pulled drugs at the party.
- I do not want to hear any more about it, Joe.
Waiting Now. Barry?
I talked to Cedars.
The body is there.
Nobody knew anything.
Not parents or friends.
According to them he died of cancer.
But the reason could be whatever.
What do you mean by that?
We probably knew about the illness.
Take a moment's silence.
He has not answered the
phone calls for many days.
Many customers can become
embarrassed by Don West.
Then get ruined right away.
I saw Don West yesterday
with another agent.
I can talk to Don. I know him.
Hey, Brad. Hey. Nice to see you.
I'm sending Brutus to their trips.
I'm leaving for that.
How are you?
Good. That's the lvan's case.
Really bad. Spacious house.
Don has nice things to do.
I heard he died of drugs.
Not just lung cancer.
Don does not believe that.
It's cocaine use. I always
wondered where she got her energy.
Ivan was a good
friend of all of us.
He died tragically
and it is not funny.
Do you have something?
No thanks. I look forward to Donia.
She'll be back in five minutes.
Hands up or shoot!
Close the door. I left the keys in the car.
Yolanda! I thought there
were already banned ads.
Yolanda! But what about it?
Now I take the gun!
Hello, Don! How are you?
A few days have been seen.
- It's tragic.
- He is dead.
Yeah, a terrible case.
Was she crazy on her face?
Lava running the head on
fire manuscript waving...
"Help, help!" No one would have
helped the agent. Do not get mad.
Of course not. He died
long-suffering lung cancer.
It's a cover book.
She was cancerous.
Be known for a long time...
He was a drug and vulturist
and he died of cancer?
He was a good friend,
I do not know.
Who is there going down the stairs?
Johnny!
Brad, do something for these kids.
I do not want Danny McTeague
to direct the movie.
Danny's script is good.
Is required an impartial instructor.
I want to be Constanza Veron.
Constanza is good.
She knows the camera.
I can tell what
Danny irritates me.
I can not resist the teenagers
coming from young film schools.
I'm not going to make a status coma.
I want to make a scene at a time.
The instructor guides
and moves forward.
I understand well. Would you
like to believe in Constanta?
I'm sorry for the
national anthem, huh?
I said I want to film
with Constanza Vero.
He knows the camera, he's a lesbian,
and with them I'm gonna be kidding.
See all emails about
my family's writing.
And that's not all. Look at this.
I'll show you something.
Speak Sharon's fax to Fernando
for the terrible messages.
They've got them home too. If anyone
comes here... Look at her, Brad.
Yolanda!
Do not get kids in the bedroom.
Show him, Bradsky.
The thing for me is obvious,
the snout is for digging.
I agree.
If someone comes here to spit...
the reception is compliant.
Who would come here...
I'm not playing with me, Fernando.
I am Barry.
I want the film to be
controlled by Constanza Vero.
Great thanks for the help, Brad.
It was nice to meet you.
If you can speak for us, I
would be very grateful.
I'm on your side.
I appreciate your help.
You know movie stars.
The one does not handle it better.
Thank you. It was nice to see you.
Who is calling?
Danny. I've been calling all day.
You're on a cell phone, I know.
I've heard about lvan.
Awful business. Really bad.
Has Lloyd kicked me in the movie?
Is it true?
I have not been kicked before. Hand-
the script is mine. You are my agent!
Do you hear what I say? Hello?
Yeah, yeah, what do you say.
Barry? Barry? Deuce!
Call her again. Agent Barry.
Man is like a breath.
His life is like a shadow.
In the morning a man flourishes, in
the evening he is cut like a grass.
Teach us to use our day
properly and give us wisdom.
Look honest and be righteous.
For the future is for men of peace.
Who can better express
the farewell words?
Than the beloved sister of the deceased.
Marcia Beckman. Please, Marcia.
Thank you for being here.
It means a lot to our family.
And lvan would have been happy
to see how he was loved.
Don has not come yet.
He promised to come.
Do you see Charlotte?
Good looking to be sure.
- Good clumps.
- Olet vulgaari!
He was a good friend, a loving
family member and a great support.
I remember when I was small...
Deuce!
Danny does not look happy.
Danny is certainly not happy.
Do not look at her.
Hey! Are you having fun?
Be quiet!
It is not right now.
I know what you did. Sell me.
I cared your manuscript.
It was just fine.
Do not bury funerals!
Don was supposed to come.
I know it is always difficult
to lose a close one.
But I have to be
patient, and all of us.
We could not leave
goodbyes to Lance.
Thanks for coming.
- Don West...
- Oh God...
- Great actor...
- Come on, Danny!
Be silent, Barry. The dispute is
completely us! Hiber funeral!
- I swear I am...
- Get up.
Great actor!
Steal a Thief to play my movie!
Ivan Beckman's office. She just...
Wait a minute. I'm connecting.
Ivan. Here, Lucy.
Danny McTeague is calling.
How's it going, Danny? Great!
The studios are still fighting you.
I can see your name already in the letters!
"Weeds" is a great project!
I think so too. I wrote it.
Blood pressure is normal.
The script is really profound.
You should do it and not
do something terrible.
Wait a little.
Your weight has fallen.
I've been training. Do I look good?
I'm so thin to my taste.
Could not you talk about this?
I do not want Bonnie to know.
Forget Bonnie! I'm not talking about this.
I like it as a secret.
Stop it already.
Try to stop, Danny.
Iso moiskaus! It's a great job, Danny!
Come on!
Give it up here.
Do not make calls, Lucy.
Give me here. Give it here!
I mean, lvan.
Why are you so tight?
Three, three... I'll be up to you soon.
The temperature is normal.
Now the lung cancer is taken.
Why? Insurance.
I have to go.
The insurance company wants Xrays.
Have you ever burned?
X-rays must be taken. Come on.
All in the car.
Now get outta here. A timid pass.
Ladies, ladies.
It is terribly tense.
I do not understand L.A. I do not want
to be fucked and I do not lick my face.
My wife is a beautiful Italian lady. She has
a tussle and I want to dive in the throat.
You have a tropical flavor.
Where else is he?
Yolanda has not been in the
premiere of ten years.
As a wise woman she cares
for children at home.
And I can celebrate.
Does he trust you?
Let's go, Brady's company.
Have you ever been unfaithful
to your wife, Don?
Yolanda? Never.
I heard of little else.
You hold me perverted. Correct.
Is the pervert to smack in
two months from your punch?
Not for me.
Fantastic. Really heavenly.
I do not want to mess up your suit.
Do not mess.
It did good!
Naama's basic reading, Brad.
- Nice to see.
- Hey.
- Have you seen it?
- Real movie.
Ime him all the mokom but
what do you do in my limo?
I get the price from that replica.
Good evening!
So that's... Good creature. The man
is like he did not have a week.
Not in public.
Can you imagine them in bed?
Bring that fuck out there trying to
get my client out in the afternoon.
I'm being sawn in my persian all the time.
But you do not like it.
I would not be so sure... What?
I know how to starve
my neck and see me.
You're so silent.
What's wrong?
You're a murderer, Madeleine.
Sorry. Everything is my fault.
Your shows were amazing.
Is it true? Thank you.
Can you meet next week? I guess.
I'll call you.
Hey. Take care of yourself.
Goodbye.
Hello, lvan. What have you held up for?
I was in that satyr.
Margaret and lwan.
You have not met each other.
- Hey.
- Margaret and Joe.
- What's up, lvan?
- Not bad.
Do you make money for us, lvan?
I'll do my best. Good night.
Ivan. Did you avoid me?
Hey! Nice to see you.
What did you like about the movie?
I thought it was great.
Really? I thought it was disgusting.
You can be proud.
I can not. And I brought it.
There is one great
director, Danny McTeague.
Who is it? Angelic convulsions.
He was an Oscar nominee for
manuscript and guidance.
He has written a
manuscript called Weeds.
It's dark-colored, shimmery.
She could agree to Don.
Could not you show a manuscript?
I can not show it.
Bonnie is her agent.
I do not know.
Send a script to me.
Please send it to me.
Thank you. It was nice to see you.
Bonnie!
Do you want to thank me? Whence?
You might not want to make Weeds.
It's a pig.
Don is a full share...
Look for me in this matter.
What do you mean? Explain now.
I will be back soon.
I do not understand anything! I've
been together for a long time.
Do not care. The most important thing
is that Don wants to make Weeds.
Want to meet her?
Nytkö? And advertise?
I do not really control these patterns...
You're fine, Danny.
That's fine.
Are you ready? Let's go.
Did he lock it for sure?
Did he ask about it?
Let me introduce you: Danny McTeague.
Danny McTeague?
If Danny McTeague!
I'm a big fan.
No cards to the table.
What is the rule number one?
No gays!
What about rule number two?
You are gays.
What about the third?
That is not.
Come down.
That's great! Sit down.
He has written the script for Weeds.
Take it.
Tsau, lvan. Do not get tired of anything!
Ivan!
Charlotte? Are there any problems?
Is not.
The script is creepy.
Listen now.
I'd better write
ten times better.
"He is not afraid of ignorance.
He just bends and raises the ball."
"The man yells, 'Get out of here!'
The woman does not grow old."
"She looks at the
muscular shape of a man"
"and his gaze stops
in the swollen eye."
"Frightened, angry, in tears .."
Time is wrong.
Really horrible.
What is this soo?
Why are you trying to sell it?
What do you do not like?
Have you read it? You go first.
You have not read it.
You do not know what it says.
Say what does it say?
Rikkaruohosta.
It winds along the slope.
Deadly weed.
Just like Jaakko and the bean wand.
I would write much better.
A fussy thing.
I'm serious.
Do not think about it, honey.
I can not stand that you sell one.
What is missing from the
script is seen on the canvas.
Danny McTeague knows
how to make big money.
Believe me.
Even though I am young and
beautiful, I'm not stupid.
Who said so?
I print my own script to Don.
It was already spoken of.
He was all interested in it.
It should be.
Please be here and stay here.
- I do not have time to. There are many things to do.
Gold. Do not blow it down now.
Stay here.
Seksi does not like to amuse now.
Do you think Donia?
You're so paranoid, lvan!
If that were the case, I would
love you and think of him.
I'm not sour. There is so much to do.
I'm terribly busy.
I'm sure you understand.
You do not believe me.
Hello, hi, darling.
Hey, dog. How are you?
Good morning!
Hey, Lucy. Take the papers.
The phone is hot. Who has fired?
Everyone is furious.
Has Verite been called?
Lloyd Hall on the twin lane.
I'm playing the manuscript you sent.
It got bad reviews.
I have good reviews about it.
Send them to me.
Danny McTeague on the second line.
Ivan. I want to explain something.
Did you hear? That's my opinion
about Don West. I do not want her.
Don West finances your movie!
Larry Barton does it for free.
And he is not worth it anymore!
Peru's Don West Agreement.
And he probably would not agree.
Say it's a lesbian... I do not remember
the name... Constanza, it's Italian.
Don can not stand gay and
get away right away.
- Constanza True?
- Any True.
Guess what? You Are amazing.
Thank you.
Nobody likes it, lvan.
Have you posted reviews?
I am, but I have not read Weed.
Say it's good that McTeague
guides it and recommends it.
As you like.
I'm talking to Barry.
Hey, Phil. What does Barry do?
Is on the phone.
I go there.
I talked to the studio in the afternoon.
I agree. It should be an interest
rate on what they pay for.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
Rough day...
You have good customers.
The biggest is Constanza.
He has Oscar access but...
He is too old or lesbian,
and now he wants to guide.
Is he free?
Something is planned.
Danny McTeague
wants him to Weed.
- What part?
- Bethin. Don West.
Is it true? Have you heard of them?
Love is remarkable.
- Hello?
- Constanza. How are you?
Could you read the Weeds and
certainly the right version?
Do you want Weeds, Amanda?
It's on the desk.
Is it located in Alabama?
My version of my version
happened to be in L.A.
Then you have the wrong version.
You're Don West's counter-actress.
You will love the good...
with Don West in Alabama.
Listen. I'll read it again.
I keep in mind what you
said and call you soon.
Mission accomplished.
Do you think he plays?
Lucy. Connect to Tarzan's office.
I would have been on my knees...
Because we're bothering you.
Hello?
- You.
- Take the speaker.
What's up, lvan?
Good, Don. And for you?
Congratulations, you've
got a full moon.
Want to do Weeds?
I want to weed the weeds with
Constanza Vero for four months.
What about Ted?
What do I care about Ted?
Ted is out, you're in.
Ladies and gentlemen, Don
West belongs to ours!
Congratulations!
- What did Don say?
- She agrees.
Awesome, nicely trained!
Here are the calls. Beyond belief!
Who is Jackie?
The most immediate thing about insurance.
Alright. Thank you.
Congratulations!
Jackie? Hey, here's Lenny Beckman.
The doctor wants to meet you.
What is it about?
She wants you to come here.
Is that something special?
She just wants you to come.
It's a bit busy, I do not
know when I'll get it.
You have to come today.
Can not you say anything?
He asked me to call.
She is late at the reception.
At your convenience?
I do not really know.
Could you come with someone?
Any friend though?
Let's see, Jackie.
Take someone with you if you can.
It's a deal. Thank you.
See you later.
- Hey!
- Beckman!
- You Are amazing!
- Thank you.
Everyone loves you.
With this day.
Are you going to celebrate? Have fun.
Great job!
What are you doing?
I can not leave all these jobs.
Go have fun.
You're so kind, Lucy.
Go already!
Has Charlotte called?
Oh yeah. He regretted yesterday's
premenstrual irritation.
Why did not you tell it?
I forgot it. Sorry.
Thank you.
Have fun. You can play.
Oh God!
Hey, here's Charlotte.
Leave the message so I call.
Hey, here's lvan. Can you call?
This is important. I'm in the car.
Ivan? Come on in.
Well...
This is not worrying.
Here in the left lung...
This area seems suspicious.
Is it cancerous?
I would like to ask you:
Do you have dyspnoea?
Sometimes it happens, sometimes...
Do you feel uncomfortable
pain in your chest or back?
If I'm in a bad position,
I can get chest pain.
Did you cough a lot?
Mornings. Who does not cough you?
It is true.
Does the blood sometimes spit?
Ivan! How's it going?
Very. What about you?
Finely. Watch the beautiful.
There's Bobby.
Melanie.
Jessie. Nice to meet you.
Francesca. Being met.
Little...? You know the place.
Enthusiastic feeling.
Could you wait for a minute?
Well small. You know how much
fun there are for three girls.
You're a good man, Bobby.
Always nice to see you, lvan.
You're a knight.
I'll make sure that I love them.
Thank you, Bobby.
I guess that's enough. Take it yourself too.
- Thank you.
- Which girls lost?
- Tylsää.
Did you find your phone?
Hemmetin tiput!
- Hello?
- Hey, Francesca.
Hey, where are you?
In an upstairs penthouse.
Penthouse...
Go ahead and find out.
- Now, let's have fun.
- Ivan!
Danny-boy! How did you find me?
How's it going?
Who dared to act as an actress?
How are you doing?
A little man does not pull you.
I want you to represent me!
Weeds become a movie!
- Bobby!
- Koko urani...
Do you want to be an actress?
I'm a teen actor but!
Do you get a taxi?
We have the money and Don West!
Please son!
This man will take you home.
Do not just get in the door.
It would be my love.
Do not be shy.
- Who is it?
- Beckman.
Ivan Beckman?
That mischievous cheerleader?
It's a pricey, bald
head, a sucker...
It is my understanding of you.
Love a show!
My mother is Irish.
Maybe I could use accents.
Maybe in this movie.
My friend Bobby.
Hey, Bobby.
She's got to arrange what.
I do not need anything.
Definitely nothing.
Danny McTeague just left.
I picked him up in the elevator.
Was he in good shape?
In a slightly moved state of mind.
You should close the door, Bobby.
I would nipple her cheeks.
Do you want to pinch his nipples?
- Look now. Pinch.
- But a little.
I get heart ache soon.
Now I can not go home.
You're so tanned.
Where did you get the color?
Now continue.
It's just getting bored.
We were already naked and put on again.
Speak for your own, Don.
The secrets have already been told.
I'm saying, Don.
Have you slept or do you want to
have my girlfriend Charlotte?
I can not take this...
You are horrible.
Answer the question, Don.
What am I against?
You tugged his throat in front of my nose.
Would I like to fuck her...?
She... Guess what? Charlotte
has a bad duckweed syndrome.
He has ambition. Unlike you.
He's a traitor.
I want to fuck her: I want to.
- Did I fuck her?
- Are you?
Have I bitten?
What do you care about it?
Why not care?
She does not even wear panties.
He gave my sniff to his head.
Forget it.
You're a kitty, lwan.
He only thinks of himself.
Like all. If I had a
chance to fuck him,
I would have snatched him in every
hole and hung him on the flagpole.
I could fuck all these women.
Bobby made me a little worried.
Bobby talked about his own
girlfriend and was worried...
- lme him.
- What?
Ime him. And no name!
Otherwise, you'll get off.
There are rules.
Ime now, my name.
Do not be a cheerleader.
Do it or go out.
Do you want to leave or leave?
I will not leave.
You will not leave. Do not spill
the vodka on my shoulder.
Can I have a silence for a moment?
I'll pay for these Kettles.
Allright then.
Are you going to do it? Good.
Good girl.
I'm a big girl, and parts.
- Well...
- You guys...
But not to play...
Speaking of lmemes...
You will not be allowed to watch! It
does not matter. Listen to lurps.
You do not have to.
Healthy, doggy. Bye.
Hello?
This is Lucy. The meeting has begun.
All right, I will come soon. Lucy?
Won you to call the repair service?
Did you run the crash?
I'm not. The ring broke out.
Alright. I will call.
Thank you. Hey.
Oh God.
Hey. Are you lvan Beckman?
I see that the ring is empty.
I'll handle it in ten minutes, but
I'll look at your membership card.
Hey! What are you doing here?
Come on.
You have the chance to have a party.
Have you seen the leaves?
"Western Tail East.
From Symbolist to Beckman."
And so write Verite!
Hello, I'm Ira Reuter. But rather.
Can I tell you a lover?
Could you sit there?
I'm sitting at the desk.
I would like to ask a few questions.
How have you been sleeping lately?
I'm fine. Usually.
What about having sex
or masturbating...
Does everything work like it should?
Yes, yes.
I'm not writing anything here.
May I smoke? I nikotinisti.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
Dependence... Do you use
drugs and in what case?
I do not use more than anyone else.
What does it mean in your circles?
It is said that we sometimes
get a little strong.
What substances do you use?
A little one and repeat...
cocaine and little pills.
Do you use cocaine once
a week or once a year?
Depends on the little life situation.
If there is a lot going on and the
customers are in the party, I'll go.
What about alcohol?
Ryyppy periods sometimes.
Seasonal drinking... Once
a week or once a month?
Once a week.
I might be an alcoholic weekend.
Thank you. Why did you come here?
As I said, my doctor urged
me to talk to someone.
Whence?
Recently...
I got a diagnosis of " cancer ".
I do not know what that means.
I found a shadow in my lungs.
I had to call an oncologist.
I'm going to poke a cigar.
Have you called oncologist?
I do not.
- It may seem frightening.
- So.
- Are you worried?
- I am.
I notice your mother is dead.
Where did he die?
He died of cancer.
Do you have the number of
theologian with you, lvan?
I suppose so. Should we call?
Do you want me to play for you?
That would be good.
Sorry.
HOMEOPATIA
Well, but hey! Days.
What is the feeling today?
Good. What about you?
Better than ever.
Hello?
Did you read my manuscript?
What? Sorry, sweetheart.
Are you still angry?
I do not, of course.
Is not that why?
No no. It was just
such a busy week.
What are you doing tonight?
I'm having dinner with my dad.
Hey, all right. You will come soon.
Why did not you party?
It was such a tough week.
- Is it?
- Is.
That's where I have a scapegoat.
Martin was there.
Or was Martin there?
Our dear friend Martin.
This will spice up. No more than you take.
What did you have?
The wound has been tough.
To sleep with. Don Westin agent.
It's really great!
Everyone is talking about it.
Maybe we should not
take more but...
This helps to withstand
the diner at dinner.
Thanks for coming.
You look gorgeous.
I am a little lost.
You do not have to lose weight.
Do not try to fatten me.
How have you been?
I've missed you.
So do you too.
Maybe I should have
gone home after all.
I got that in it.
Hi dad.
Is this yours? Would not it?
It's nice. Lots of color.
This is great.
Is not this your job here?
Well, but... sister.
Hey, lvan. How are you?
- How are you?
- Good.
Here is my girlfriend Charlotte.
Do not I live in New York?
Nice to meet you.
What are you doing?
She is an artist.
What kind of artist?
I'm currently studying the human body.
Nude models.
Marcia was just about to show her drawings.
Do you want to see?
Here's my job. What do you like, dad?
Samant like before.
This is something new.
Show it first.
It starts to be the right one.
Is that true?
I'll show you something, lvan.
Is not he beautiful?
There was something in it.
Thank you for showing them.
Manny said you've succeeded.
So. I am happy about it.
Tarzana was very pleased.
He's been kind of friendly.
She's only interested in money.
She's an agent.
It is difficult to maintain some
kind of regulation in this work.
It's my life, dad. It's my
milieu, I get my bread.
Talent Seeker-son.
I do not know where your girlfriend is.
Charlotte? Charlotte!
I went a little bit embarrassing.
What did you talk about?
- Of course.
- Kind of.
Quiet how seriously you take it.
You have not got almost anything.
I gave you a solid lunch.
Strong lunch?
The clock is half past ten.
I was out in the happy
hour and ate little heat.
I did not want to eat,
I just came along.
I know what the question is. Ivan is
again tangled with the cocaine launcher.
- Could you be silent!
- I do not!
He has been kidding all the time
since he came from the bathroom bar!
I can tell you I'm eating
antidepressant medicines.
It makes me influence a little...
What?
Nothing. It was just fun.
It was hysterical fun.
I eat antidepressant drugs, and
that's why I'm a little nervous.
You do not have to explain.
He accused me of using cocaine.
- It certainly is not.
- What?
That's enough.
You always have a small reel.
Can not we just enjoy it together?
This is a nice family dinner.
So you think.
If I'm not honest for
you, who would be?
Regarding what?
Is Charlotte honest?
- Then be honest.
- Yes I am.
What kind of perversion
do you want me to mess?
I'm not messing you with anything.
I know you already enough.
That's enough. You are
very dear to us, lvan.
Now at least went to appetite.
But you do not like what I do.
Yes, that's true.
You're still drowning, lwan!
That's enough!
If your mom was here.
Mom is not here. Mother is dead!
Charlotte? What? Tell me, lvan?
Do not you see how embarrassing it was?
Should I just leave?
Hey, here's Charlotte.
Leave the message so I call.
Hey, lvan here.
Could you call? This is important.
I want to tell you something.
I'm sorry, koiruus.
Have I missed you? Am I?
Sorry, my dog.
Hey, here's Charlotte.
Leave a message...
- Hello?
- Hey. Someone needs you.
Francesca. Hey! Hi, how are you?
Good. How about you? Come here.
The same thing as the last one?
It sounds good.
Does Jessie come in?
Hello? Hey, Charlotte.
What are you doing? You're breathless.
I listened to music.
Nice to call.
- You do not mind?
- I do not.
What did you have to tell?
The car was terrible.
- I am so sorry.
- I too am.
I was a bit wretched too.
The wind is too crowded.
What was the matter with you?
Can you chat in the morning?
Does your doorstep?
It can not be me.
It's yours. Who is there?
I do not expect anyone.
See who it is and come back.
I'd rather talk in the morning.
I'm so tired.
Will I come there?
No, no, no. Eat breakfast.
Do you agree? Charlotte?
Go to the door to open it!
Hey!
Whose turn? Truth or Dare.
Good!
Well, lvan. Truth or Dare?
Truth. I'm boring.
How many different drugs did you take?
How many? Please list.
- 200 grams of cocoa.
- At least.
- EXtaCY.
- It's already seen.
There was more. Hepoa? Heroin?
No. That's the limit.
Is it true?
I do not like heroin.
Maybe I could try it out?
You could.
- Maybe I'll try.
- Next time.
What do people have against heroin?
Now I have decided.
There was something else, too.
You're not as cloudy as me.
You did not say you love me.
Yeah, there is more.
What do you know about us?
Tell the truth.
- Recipe Taboos?
- Good stuff.
This is my dog's medicine.
- My mom ate these.
- Söikö?
- Is it true?
- He died of cancer.
Cancer drugs.
I have cancer.
Tummy lungs.
It takes my breath.
Do you know what? Last night...
I had a terrible pain.
So hard pains that I took all the
pills I found out of the house.
But the pills did not help.
The pain did not relax.
I tried to see some picture in front of me.
Who would have forgotten the pains.
But that's just the ignorance.
I did not come up with anything rational.
I just remember...
when I was three or four years old.
I remember when my mom liked me.
He had a knit shirt on top.
I sat down on her chest.
She smelled so sweet.
And what about it...
What's going on with my dog?
Do you think the Animal Protection
Association will take it?
Is it given somewhere?
Do not pity me.
Why hurt?
Once...
Once again you too.
Your time will come.
This is a concern for us.
We hear the screams.
Quietly. Do not be afraid.
Everything will be allright. Be calm.
Turn you over. Just calm down.
How much cocaine did you take?
Talk to me.
Send the ambulance.
Good morning.
He was found on the floor.
He did the resistance.
Probably an overdose.
Cocaine, alcohol,
everything except syringes.
Do you know him?
She does not breathe.
What is your name?
LMU!
Call the breathing apparatus.
Give 100 mg Celocurine.
Give tracheotomy equipment.
Did the breathing apparatus come in?
Where does all the blood come from? LMU.
Do you have a hose?
Knife.
Oh God!
Hey.
She hears. He can not just talk.
To whom would we call?
Could you type a number?
I do not think he wants
to contact anybody.
Do you want to say something?
Hi God God.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher
from www.OpenSubtitles.org