ALARM RINGS
THIS FILM CONTAINS VERY
STRONG LANGUAGE.
DULL RING
MURMUR OF RADIO
Rise and shine cos it is ti-ime!
Davey! Davey!
Come on, you great swinging dick!
Wake up! We're gonna dance
on Charlie the Tuna's grave!
David! I see you.
Open up, man!
Davey.
Dave!
David, some loudmouth is
yelling for you. Come on, get up.
Get up, David. Let's go. Get up.
Yeeeaaah!
Davey?
Heeeey!
Oh, no!
Hey, you always go golfing in PJs?
Huh? What?
You got mud cleats in them slippers?
Huh?
Joseph Megessey. Call me Megs.
Megs?
That's my name. Don't wear it out.
It's ridiculous.
I don't know you.
I feel like I know you.
Your brother talked about you a lot.
Said you were swell.
Davey! What's goin' on?
Davey! Come on,
you great swinging dick, let's go!
Quiet. Shhhh!
We'll be out fishin' very soon.
You're mad. It's still dark.
Yeah.
Davey!
Megessey. Who do you think you are?
Your room, huh?
How dare you! Mr Megessey, I was
up until 2am grading papers.
Nice bed.
Oh... I'll count to ten,
then I call the police. One...
This you?
..two, three...
You've changed. You're pretty.
Mr Megessey.
Where do you think you're going?
Davey?
Fuck!
Mr Megessey, will you wait?
Forget it, it ain't your fault.
I'm sure my brother just forgot...
Hey, I covered ground. I called
long distance. "It's me," I say.
"Right, how are you?" All that.
He says let's get together.
I just called to let him know
I'm back, I'm not pushing.
He says, "Let's get together."
At 6am?
Hey, I'm talking.
"Great," I say. "When?"
"Whenever." "Openin' Day?" I ask.
"Openin' Day," he says.
So, here I am, 2,500 miles later.
Who is to blame? Me or 'Mr Busy'?
And when was this call?
A couple of weeks ago.
Maybe five.
Oh, five weeks.
Did you call to confirm?
Who needs this shit?
Mr Megessey? Joseph!
David has had hangovers before.
(LAUGHS)
What the hell? Martha, what...?
Megs, what are you doing here?
Jesus, I'm all wet.
Move your butt, David.
It's Opening Day.
Oh, Jesus Christ...
We're gonna catch Martha a trout.
Get outta here!
Come on, David, catch me a trout.
Someone's lost their mind.
It's Openin' Day. Rainbows this long.
I ain't up to it.
Sure you are.
HE RETCHES
See, you just need
a bit of perking up.
What?
You talked him into comin'.
Didn't talk him into anything.
Martha, instant's fine.
My stomach's already freeze-dried.
What're you doing?
Got any milk?
Course I've got milk.
Thank God. I hate that powdered cream
shit. Tastes like mouse balls.
Wait!
What d'you want for breakfast?
Beer.
Beer for breakfast? Horrible!
Breakfast beer. You never had it?
One sip of breakfast beer,
the cobwebs go, your voice rises,
and hey, the sun rises inside you.
Y'know, I got a case in the car.
Well, I hardly think that...
Um...
He leave?
He went to the car to get beer.
Good.
I could use one.
How can you stomach it
after all you had last night?
I work hard all week, I'm entitled
to cut loose at weekends.
You should try it. It'd do you good.
Fine, I'll come along tonight.
Forget it.
You might enjoy a woman's company.
Women, sure. Not a sister.
Besides, I date.
Yeah, I've seen those kind of women.
They snap gum for conversation.
Don't you want a point of view?
I want that I got the news.
David, piss up a rope!
What did I say?
Oh, just drink your coffee. >
Your friend seems... nice.
He's not my friend.
He's just someone I know.
We were in Vietnam together.
# Hey, hey, Opening Day!
Look out, trout, we're on our way. #
Careful, Martha, it's so cold
your tongue'll stick to the can.
Oh, Martha don't drink beer.
< Well, hey, it's early.
David.
< Thanks.
To Opening Day.
SHE LAUGHS
Oh, to trout.
To trout.
Trout.
Well, I like breakfast beer.
That's beautiful.
I'll crack you another.
I gotta go change if I'm coming too.
You coming?
Fish won't know what hit 'em.
Right, they'll jump into my lap,
to hear a woman's opinion.
OK, what'll it be?
Coffee.
And?
Ma'am, what's your name, ma'am?
Shirley.
May I be permitted
to call you Shirley, Shirley?
Be my guest.
Shirley, give this young lady
a pile of pancakes.
That's on me. Lady don't buy.
Pancakes. And for you, Sir Galahad?
Well, let's see.
I'll have...pancakes, too.
Pancakes.
Bacon.
Eggs over easy.
Bacon, eggs and pancakes.
Grapefruit,
bagel with cream cheese...
..and some cornflakes with banana.
Hungry?
If my eyes were basketballs, they
wouldn't be bigger than my stomach.
And, Shirley, can I have a
sardine sandwich while I'm waiting?
Thanks, Shirley.
Hey, it's Opening Day.
Anyone need to bleed the monster?
No facilities out there.
If you want to use the john, go now.
Excuse me.
Hey, old buddy.
You think your sister likes me?
Are you serious?
You two are from different planets.
She's just along to bust my ass.
Hey, I was gonna do that for you.
I'm a biology teacher.
I think I can bait a hook.
How ya doin', ya big swingin' dick?
They bitin', huh? Huh?
Nothin'?
Nothin'. >
Do you ever catch fish, Joseph?
Martha, the only way
I'll ever do that is to drain a pond.
< We'll see.
Hey, stud.
You ain't said nothin' about the hat.
I wear it for luck.
Bad luck?
No way, Jose. It's Bobby's.
Didn't help Bobby much.
It's helpin' me.
They hide under rocks. Trout.
Goddam speckled bastards,
hide under rocks.
What kind of a life is that?
< Let's catch some fish.
< Hey, Martha, how we doin'?
Joseph...
I know they're out there, Martha.
I know they're there.
Oh! Aaah. Oh! I have one!
I have one, Joseph. I have a trout!
Shit! Reel him in.
I got one. There he is.
He's a rainbow. Reel him in.
What do I do now?
Did I lose... Where is he?
You got him. You got him. Here he is.
Look at him!
He's cousin to the Loch Ness Monster.
Joseph! Aaah! Joseph, no...!
Joseph, wait! Ah...!
HE LAUGHS
Perfect.
Good thing he threw the hook, Martha.
That baby was ready to take your leg.
Shit!
Oh, this fishing is
a wonderful time(!)
Hey, Martha! >
There you go.
My wits are weak
but my back is strong.
Who said fishing would be easy?
Martha? You OK? >
< MUMBLING
I don't forget.
Jacknife's like an elephant.
Short on smarts, long on memory.
You sleep. Jacknife's on watch.
You sleep. >
Would you have him give me a buzz?
I started working at this garage.
If he wants, he can call or come by.
Shouldn't you give those a rest?
Jacknife! You gonna drive again?
No. I'm after Dave Flanagan.
He's up front.
This way?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. No, I got no problem.
Oh, no. Hold on a second.
Be on time tomorrow.
Hey, Davey! Davey! How you doin'?
I suck.
Let's grab a beer.
Look, Megs...
Come on. Since when
ain't you thirsty? Since when?
What you doing here?
Seeing how you are. I got my car,
came over. It's about to fall apart.
So then she moved to Florida.
She thought Connecticut
was too cold or somethin'.
Maybe too many memories
of your old man here, huh?
It must've been tough, comin' back
on crutches to find your dad's dead.
Yeah, I was pissed.
His gung-ho vet shit
got me to enlist.
I'd been fantasizing about
decking that son of a bitch.
Boom!
Yeah, man, I felt cheated.
Boom, boom!
Boom, boom! You're outta here!
Y'know what I hated? Waitin'.
Yeah. Knowin' it was only time
till somethin' bad happened.
Fuck, yeah.
The only way I could handle it was
to get up for it. Know what I mean?
It was like something set in,
you know?
And not just me.
For a lot of us, maybe.
I was never there, Megs.
I don't follow that.
It never happened.
It's done with. >
Understand?
HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRR
Go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
We're hot at ten o'clock. Dead hot!
< Bobby, please!
Come on, Dave.
Come on.
Bobby, no!
< Get him outta here!
Bobby, don't! Please! Nooooooo!
(SCREAMS)
Ow! Ow! Owwwwwww!
Help me!
Help me! Come on!
Got my piece?
Got it. You OK, Davey?
My fucking leg!
Bobby?
GUNFIRE
HORN BEEPS
How long you been back?
A month, maybe.
Well... Yeah... I hooked up
with an old buddy of mine.
A vet?
Trying to give him a hand?
Shit, I got all I can do
to help me, man!
Ever wonder if
you get enough distance?
< Every damn day.
I dunno if I want to think about
what this guy makes me think about.
Makes me feel good
when my friends come to me.
Makes me know I'm not alone.
It's important that you know that.
< People alone,
they just waste away slow.
That's all people, not just vets.
Jake, this uh...
..this guy, he's got a sister.
Mm-hmm. Tell me about her.
What time d'you get in last night?
< Don't start!
Mother called.
Great.
How's Florida?
She wanted to talk to you.
Why? So you could get on
the extension and gang up on me?
Forget it.
Have a nice day.
Oh, your friend left you a number.
Who?
Joseph. I mean, Megs.
He's not my friend, Martha.
He wants you to call him.
He's not my friend.
SCHOOL BELL RINGS
Quiet, please.
CHATTER CONTINUES
Take your seats, everybody.
Would this entire class like to stay
after school with me for a month?
Thank you. Now, people,
open your books to page 550.
Bone structure.
Let's look at the Haversian canal.
What is bone tissue? Is it alive?
< (David. Oh, David.)
OK, start this sucker up.
There you go.
Zippety-do-dah!
How are you with foreign jobs?
If it's got wheels and an engine,
I'm your man.
What'll it be?
Oh, yes, um...
Is Joseph Megessey around?
Oh, Megs. Yeah.
Why don't you park over there?
Hey, Megs!
Yeah?
You got a visitor.
He's over there.
Hello, Joseph.
Oh, goddam, look what...
LAUGHTER
Shall we adjourn to the office?
Yes.
Right this way.
(Goons!)
Nice of you to stop by, Martha.
Wanna take a walk in the parking lot?
Yes.
Allow me.
Thank you.
This your car?
Yes.
Well, it's reliable.
You could use a little air.
Oh...
If you move to the pump I'll fix it.
Joseph, would you let me
buy you a coffee?
I'll be right back.
It's on me.
A lady don't buy if I'm around.
Clean up, Megs.
I gotta date with a lady!
You jealous dogs!
You dirty, jealous dogs!
QUIET CONVERSATION
Do you come here often?
Uh?
Oh, yeah. I pass it.
It's nice.
It's all right? It's OK?
It's lovely. Yes.
I'm not dressed right,
I should be dressed up.
You're fine.
I don't eat out much and stuff.
Do, er, your girlfriends
come and cook for you?
Is that like a real question
or are you just jerking my chain?
What?
No, I just...
I'm nervous. It's just conversation.
You're nervous?
Yes.
Me too.
Cocktails?
We were gonna have...
How about it, Martha?
I'll have a cocktail if you will.
Oh, sure.
Cocktails are good.
What kind, sir? Something elegant?
Elegant is good. Also.
How about a Bud, Martha?
Two Buds.
How about you, Martha? Boyfriends?
I bet you gotta fight 'em off.
No, I've given up the fight.
You? Come on. You're built
like a brick shithouse!
That's ridiculous.
I noticed right off...
Shh! No!
You've got the biggest...
Stop contradicting me!
I know what I am.
< Yeah? What's that?
Martha, some people get awful ugly
the minute they open their mouths.
Other people, like you, Martha,
they grow on ya.
You know 'em better, they get
better looking. Or so I think.
I'm gonna need another one of these.
David said you were
in Vietnam together.
Yeah, basic right through we were.
He never talks about it.
No? I talk about it all the time.
To myself if no-one wants to listen.
Did you know his friend Bobby?
You like to drive? Hop in the car,
head off, just for the hell of it?
Sometimes.
How about Saturday?
Sure.
Martha, it's up ahead.
Hey, Bob. >
We were some trio,
Bobby, your brother and me.
They said I was the lucky one.
I ain't fooling. They used to say
"Lucky Megs". "Lucky Megs".
That all sort of ended
when we lost old Bobby.
You wouldn't have liked me
when I got home. I was crazy.
Always getting in fights. Dumb ones.
Gettin' the piss kicked out of me,
five against one. Not a nice time.
What it all got down to is, er...
..well, one night I was starin'
at the ceiling rafters, wondering
if they'd take my weight...
Don't laugh, or anything.
I prayed.
I felt better.
What was done was done,
I couldn't change it...
..but for some reason
we lost Bobby...
..and I had to make
that reason a good one...
..cos Bobby, he deserved it.
Right, Bob?
RADIO: FOOTBALL COMMENTARY
Thank you, sir.
< Sir, your change.
Martha.
Becoming quite a social butterfly,
aren't we, Sis?
Fishing trips, dinner dates...
..more parents' meetings?
He was a truck driver!
So are you,
I don't hold it against you.
He's crazy!
He was crazy before I knew him.
'Nam made him crazier.
He's spent more time in the can
than you could believe.
You wanna date? I'll set you up.
Plenty of guys owe me favours.
Fuck you, David!
What did I say?
What d'you care? Why this interest?
You're my sister.
Oh, I thought I was a housekeeper!
I can't remember the last time you
said, "Martha, how was your day?"
Or "Let's go out to eat somewhere.
Want to come to a party?"
I don't go to parties.
That's not the point!
All right, I'll take more interest.
We'll go to a movie, OK?
Martha!
Martha, he's bad news. He is!
(Fuck!)
TAPPING ON DOOR
Is it really so bad around here?
No, it's not so bad.
I love this place.
Every good memory I have is...
Maybe that's why I...
Sis, I'm gonna be more
appreciative from now on.
I promise.
You'll see.
David...
..the things I want,
you can't give me.
You're gonna leave?
Someday.
Keep her on the road, Flanagan.
Uh? Uh? Where've you been, stud?
Spanking the monkey
in the john? Uh?
Come on, let's go. Come on, Davey.
Come on. Get in.
Driving, huh? Yeah...!
Buyin' guys beers
you don't even know...
..money in the jukebox
so strange babes can dance.
Hardly anyone knows
when you come or go.
I ain't complainin'
Am I? Hey, keeps you occupied.
You ain't occupied,
you're like an empty house. Useless.
Me, I did so many whites, I was like,
hotter than sunshine, I was insane.
A madman. I'm seein' trolls
and leprechauns in the road.
< It was V did that. You know that.
I came back from 'Nam
a first-class head.
Now, I don't touch a thing.
Megs, don't talk.
Hey, all right!
Hey, awright!
Hey, how about some hoop?
Come on, I know you was
a stud ball player. Come on.
I'll take a look.
Yeah, I'll park this pig for you.
All right. Up!
Come on!
All right, over here, over here.
It's too much for me. You want in?
Right, I'm with you, you?
Yeah, the big guys.
OK, thanks, man!
Get in there!
OTHERS CHEER
< Aw, shit!
< Nail his ass!
You see that, huh?
Your buddy's got two already.
Hey, Jacknife. Come on, pal.
Megs, you playin'? Right.
You're with him, him and him.
Whoa!
Come on, Megs. Get off me!
< Two points!
God!
Back here.
Aaaaargghhh!
Shit. You OK?
David, let me help you.
NO!
OK, let me help you.
I said, just, NO!
Let's get outta here.
< Is he OK?
COME ON, LET'S GO! >
Sorry, guys.
How's it feeling?
It's OK.
Sorry I yelled.
Yelled? Shit! I been yelled at by
queers and ladies worse than that!
Nice sky, uh? Real pretty.
Yeah.
Remember the sunsets?
Over there? Beauties, huh?
Remember what Bobby said?
Without the helicopters
it could almost be Hawaii.
Remember him saying that? I do.
Remember when the three of us...
I don't want you seeing my sister.
Ain't that her decision?
No. Martha don't know
shit about guys.
She'd have trouble with a
perfect guy, let alone one like you.
What kind of a guy am I, Davey? Uh?
Hold out your hand.
Look at your hand.
Your fucking hand!
I ain't punched no glass
in a long time.
Yeah, I heard that before.
Look at me. Fat and happy. You never
seen me looking so good. Huh, guy?
You look the same as before... guy.
Yeah, and you look real good, too.
Fate's a funny thing. >
Slow down.
Think this is fast?
Slow down, Megs!
What the fuck's wrong?
I'm just a crazy bastard.
Don't care who I take with me.
Got something to live for lately?
Whoooo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoooo!
HE WHOOPS AND YELPS
Ahoooo! Ahooooo, ahooooo!
I got someplace to go.
You're coming with me.
I don't know, I don't know anymore.
You get fuck all from
looking over your shoulder, right?
Things would've changed
if people did. >
I know that... >
..but I'm not able to put it aside.
How long has it been?
My wife wants to know
what's my, er...
.."Hey, what's your problem?"
What do I tell her?
What do I tell my kids?
That at 10am I was there,
and at 10pm I was in California
trying to hitch home?
And nobody picked me up. >
I was in uniform
and nobody would pick me up.
Hey, now come on, stay.
You can just listen.
Davey! Davey! >
What can it hurt? Davey!
Davey!
Megs, don't let him pull you down.
Don't you let him do it to you!
Davey! Davey!
KNOCKING
Joseph!
Hi.
Davey stop home?
No. Why, what's happened?
Uh, OK.
Joseph, wait! Are you hungry?
There are pangs.
Well, would you like some soup?
Soup is good.
Split pea with ham.
Home-made. I like to cook.
Hey, we're a team, cos I like to eat.
Hmm, china. They match, too.
I almost got a set once.
You got a plate for buying groceries,
but I didn't shop enough.
Go ahead and start.
I'll wait for you. I hate
to eat alone. You eat alone much?
Sometimes I eat with David,
but he eats alone.
I often correct papers while I eat.
I think you give too much homework.
Smells good. Good as Campbell's.
I ain't even tasted it and I like it.
Well, now you can.
I started too soon?
No, please, start.
Please. Oh, please.
No, don't. Don't, Joseph.
Joseph, please, don't...
Just get your hands off me, Joseph!
Martha. That's the thing
about shy people, Martha.
They think somebody's lookin',
but nobody is.
Except me and I like what I see.
For God's sake, shut up for once.
You're damn right. Yeah.
(Fuck!)
I'll pay for it. Don't worry, I will.
No...
I'll pay...
Shhh. Joseph, I liked the kiss.
Joseph, I liked the kiss.
I liked the kiss, Joseph.
I'm sorry, I'll pay for it.
Hush, now. I liked the kiss, Joseph.
Hello, Ed.
Why, Davey.
Can I...?
Please. Of course, yes.
Who is it, dear?
Pru and I were watching the news.
Pru, it's, er...
Why, Davey.
Sorry it's so late, Pru.
Nonsense.
Come in and sit with us.
Something to drink, Dave? Beer?
Yeah, please. >
Well, it's been quite a while.
Not so long. Dave shovelled the walk
for us after the snow in February.
< Oh, that's right.
If you want any help
I could come back again.
Mow the lawn, maybe.
Rake some leaves.
Oh, we have a service for that.
We'd appreciate that, Dave.
Do I really... look well?
Dave, is everything all right?
I doubt it. >
Thank you for your concern.
I'd like to come
and clean your yard again.
You've done that before. Why?
Why? I don't know why, Martha.
Well...
Come inside. We'll...
..we'll go upstairs.
Come on. Get... get...
Oh, my Go...
Jesus!
Come here.
William Green.
And we were such an unlikely pair.
He was tall and skinny...
..and I was, well, me.
You was pretty good.
We didn't know what we were doing.
Like two cars that hooked bumpers,
pushing and pulling at wrong times.
I shouldn't laugh, it was horrible.
We went to a cheap hotel.
He kept apologizing.
"I'm sorry, I'm so terribly sorry."
I think he hoped I'd change my mind.
And then he asked me to marry him.
He'd been to bed with me
so he thought he should.
But, you know, you didn't want to?
Well, I didn't sleep with him
so he'd marry me.
We would've
made each other miserable.
Um... it's getting late,
We better think about hitting it.
Martha, I can see myself out, y'know.
Oh, I can walk you to the door.
Well...
Hey.
Joseph?
Yeah?
The seniors' prom is on Saturday.
Will you take me?
Me?
You. I missed my own prom,
no-one asked me to go.
No? Huh.
I crashed mine. I wore a motor cycle
jacket, steel-toed boots, shades.
Stood there grinnin' at them tuxedos,
hopin' they'd try and throw me out.
Will you take me?
I don't know, Martha.
Hmm. Yeah, OK.
OK, I'm ready. Pass it up.
Oh, it's great.
Forty-two, regular.
Thirty-four.
Thirty.
May I help you, sir?
I'd like a, uh...
Something for a prom.
A prom. I have some suggestions.
Here's one. It's a wristlet.
Worn on the lady's wrist.
Martha!
Martha! I'm home!
Joseph is taking me to a prom.
HE LAUGHS
Shall I put a TV dinner on for you?
Dad wouldn't let
that guy on the porch!
What, someone gentle and kind?
Turkey or Salisbury steak?
I've had it with him
hanging round you!
You listening to me?
Oh, I hear you!
Call him and say something came up.
The PTA.
The fucking Board of Education.
What's the matter with you?
He's a loser!
Go out and get drunk!
No way!
Then shut up! A loser?
You're a loser!
You're like a mould here.
You eat what's there then grunt
instead of speak. Shit.
Shit! >
I'd be better off with a dog.
I wouldn't have to worry
about a dog killing itself.
What's it like to want
only to get drunk at night?
I just want to be left alone.
By what? By life? You asshole!
You want me here so the house
isn't empty if you come home.
And I've been afraid for you.
Me? What about you?
OK, yes! I have been afraid for me.
But I've done it. I have stayed.
Well, no more. I am leaving.
Just like Mama.
She cried. Did you think
she was crying for Papa?
It was for you. Because you
might as well have been dead, too.
Martha? Martha...?
DOORBELL RINGS
Joseph, I'm sorry. I'm not ready.
Yeah, it's me.
I said I'm a knight going to meet
a fair damsel, so do your best.
Just a mad seducer. That's me.
What? You OK?
Yes, I'm wonderful.
CHEERING
You. You, in the pants.
Why you wearing those pants?
You a soldier?
Answer me. A kid like you,
you know how to fight?
No. Kids don't know how to fight.
They don't know nothin' about it.
Take those off. You can't wear 'em.
TAKE OFF THE FUCKIN' PANTS!
Hey, mister.
We're not looking for any trouble.
Nobody ever really is, Joe College.
Tell your friend to take those
pants off, or I'll do it for you.
Dave, why not leave it and go home?
What do you say? They're just kids.
CAR HORN HONKS
Hi, Mrs Flanagan.
(ALL) Hi, Mrs Flanagan.
Oh, Martha. You look enchanting.
Thank you. Joseph, this is...
William Green.
Geology and space science.
Joseph Megessey. Cars.
Um, you'll excuse us.
Oh, sure.
That's him, huh? Bee-bee-beep.
DISCO MUSIC
Click your heels three times -
you'll get to Kansas.
Give me another.
Maybe you oughtta slow down, Dave.
Joseph, this is Tanya and Frank.
Hello, Tanya. Hi.
Frank teaches Phys Ed.
You like sports?
Me? Love 'em.
< Which ones?
When I was a kid, we used to have
horse-shit fights. Those road apples
would fly. I excelled at that.
And I like demolishing trucks.
HELICOPTERS WHIRR
'No!'
Go on, Dave.
You got five seconds!
Come on, we gotta go!
NO!
Come on, out!
HE SCREAMS
DISCO MUSIC
Hello!
Oh, hi. Hi.
You wanna dance, Martha?
No. Do you?
Come on.
Oh, I don't know how...
HELICOPTERS WHIRR
Megs!
Help me, man.
Let's get the fuck outta here.
Come on!
Megs!
Let's get the fuck outta here!
You OK, Dave? I'm goin' for Megs.
Don't go back, Bobby. Don't, man!
DON'T GO BACK, BOBBY!
JACKNIFE'S DEAD! >
JACKNIFE'S DEAD!
JACKNIFE'S DEAAAAAAD!
NOOOOOOOOOO!
# One way or another
We're gonna be lovers
# I don't care what you say
# One way or another
We're gonna be lovers... #
CAR RADIO
APPLAUSE
SLOW MUSIC
Joseph, do you know who
the queen of this prom is?
Who?
Me.
Bullshit! Bullshit!
High School bullshit!
It's cos of you! It's your fault. >
We should've stayed put. We were
twenty feet up, being shot to hell.
But no. Gotta get some.
Get some, get some, get some.
Ow, ow, ow. Hooowwwooo!
You gonna be lucky for her?
Like you were for me and Bobby?
I was drafted. You enlisted.
Fuckin' jock! Think those
motherfuckers would tackle you?
You chickenshit asshole!
Fuck.
I heard you! I heard you!
You landed wrong, your ankles broke.
We came for you and I got hit!
I lay there, blood pumpin' out
and I heard you!
"Don't go back!
Jacknife's dead, don't go!"
He's dead! Jacknife's dead!"
But Bobby did go back, huh, Davey?
Bobby did!
You can't keep running from that!
Bobby did! He did!
Go on! Go inside now. Please.
You hoped he'd be home, didn't you?
He's not your friend, Joseph.
I'm his friend.
We'll be more comfortable
in the living room.
I know, we'll have
some of your brandy.
Shall I tell you what brandy is?
Yeah. Please.
If beer for breakfast is sunrise,
then brandy is sundown.
Well, I can hardly get
a word in edgewise!
Sorry.
I don't want you sorry, Joseph.
I was just teasing, Joseph. >
You always tease me,
but can't tell you're being teased.
Teasing shows you're cared for,
don't you think?
I think so.
Let's go look for him, Martha.
Please, let's have our brandy.
Martha.
Ain't you the sight, stud?
Martha, I'm sorry.
Come on, sit down. Sit down.
Let's clean you up some. It's clean.
You know me -
I wipe my nose, I use my sleeve.
Oh...
Ow!
How could she understand, huh?
She wasn't there.
Jacknife?
That's my name.
That's what Bobby called me.
Cos you crashed trucks.
Have you told Martha
what your nickname was?
Come on. What'd Bobby call you?
David? What was your nickname?
I'd... I'd like to know.
"High School", cos he was all-league.
Bobby had nicknames for everything.
Bobby's was Red Sock,
cos he loved the Red Sox.
He was gonna take us to Fenway Park.
We were gonna cheer.
Aw, Bobby.
If he'd stayed he would've lived.
How many nights did I think that?
He didn't. He couldn't leave me
any more than he could leave you.
What were we gonna do
when we got back, huh?
Come on, help me, no matter what?
Come on. Tell me. You know.
Fuck, Davey, come on!
I don't know. Go to Fenway Park.
Best seats in the house, huh?
Yeah. Hot dogs and beer.
Green grass, fresh mowed.
Take off our shirts.
Soak up a few rays.
We were gonna cheer, huh?
We were gonna cheer
till they cheered us back.
And then?
Then we were gonna...
What, Davey? What?
David? >
What were you going to do?
We were gonna go fishing.
Opening Day.
Yeah...
Martha.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so so sorry.
I know you are, David.
You're leaving?
Thought I would.
Mission accomplished, right?
Martha, who are we kiddin'?
You, me, just ourselves.
We were having a wonderful time.
It doesn't have to end. If I fooled
myself I can do it a while longer.
I can't, Martha.
'I blame people.
I've been blaming people so much.'
And I've been hurting people.
That sucks.
'They're people that cared about me,
but I didn't... I thought...'
'No, I think, I think I don't
deserve them caring about me...
'..because...
..I don't like me very much.
'But hey, it's time.'
'If not for me, then for the people
that didn't stop loving me.'
'There was a guy, Bobby.'
There was another guy, Megs...
..and us three were friends.
I loved those guys like brothers. >
'Bobby was the smart one.'
'Megs was the crazy one.'
Me... >
..I was the scared one.
Bobby talked to you.
'He talked to you, sports...
'..books, girls.'
Bobby said that certain girls...
..they glowed.
And that when they touched you,
you weren't scared...
..or tired.
When they just stood next to you,
you weren't confused.
Bobby said we'd all
find girls like that.
'Then things would make sense,
just because you were with them.
'He said it would
happen to us all.'
Because we, er...
..because we all of us,
we deserved it.
HORN BEEPS
I bet we'd have had
a horrible time at that prom.
And we would've left early.
Gone someplace fancy for dinner.
No, we wouldn't have been hungry.
Maybe we would've driven someplace.
Someplace quiet and parked.
And then...
..who knows?
Who knows?