Örn. I'll get fired
if you don't get out of here.
Hold on.
Just give me a minute.
Sorry. I was applying
to the data protection committee.
Now?
Yes.
I think you'd be more useful here with her
and let the doctors do their jobs.
What are the doctors doing?
See you tomorrow.
I'll come in early tomorrow morning.
Goodbye, Kola darling.
Try to get some rest.
Daddy, where's Mommy?
- she's gone home.
- For Christmas?
No. We're saving Christmas
until you get back.
When will that be?
Try to sleep, darling.
But I can't close my eyes.
Shall I sing a lullaby for you?
Yes.
Sleep my lovely little one...
JAR ClTY
Where are you?
Arnar, what are you doing?
Arnar.
What have you done?
Arnar, Arnar.
The chief asked for you
to handle the case.
- Isn't he off work sick?
- No, not today.
It's in Northmarsh.
- Just round the corner?
- Yeah.
Sigurdur Óli's already there. He's
watching out they don't touch anything.
They'd do better to watch out
for Sigurdur Óli.
- Who found the body?
- some boys in the neighborhood.
What a shitty smell.
A typical Icelandic murder.
Messy and pointless.
And with no attempt
to conceal the evidence.
- How long has he been lying here?
- About two days, I would say.
Smells more like two months.
"Holberg."
An unusual name.
Excuse me.
Can I have a word?
- It's about the murder in the basement.
- I didn't know the man at all.
Regarding Holberg.
I only spoke to him a couple of times.
About the bloody stink in the basement.
Has it been like that for long?
It was worse in the summer.
The house is built on a marsh.
Did you notice any visitors recently?
No, he kept to himself. I saw
a shady-looking character the other day.
- Can you describe him?
- No. I was drunk.
- I have a plane to fly.
- Where to?
- Ever been to Stockholm?
- No.
Awful place.
"Aude."
Good Lord, bring peace to the dead,
comfort to those who live.
Good morning.
Or maybe not so good.
Erlendur?
I think it's shot on a Holga,
an old Russian camera.
Aude was only four when she died.
Has my daughter called?
No.
Holberg lived in Keflavik,
born in 1937.
He was a truck driver
for the past few years.
What about his family?
No family.
He had a sister who died young.
- How old?
- six.
His flat looked like
he was a lonely old fart.
- Destined to live alone.
- What?
- Anything from Pathology or Forensics?
- No, not yet.
Did Holberg have any children?
Not according to the report.
Don't you find it abnormal,
photographing a headstone?
There's nothing normal
about losing a child.
Dad.
- Hello, Eva.
- Hi, Dad.
- I haven't got any money.
- Two hundred.
That's not much. Give me 200.
Are you ill?
Eva. What's wrong?
Give me the money and I'll tell you.
Did something happen?
OK, 100?
Don't tell me you're pregnant.
- How?
- What do you mean, how?
Do you want the details?
- I can't talk to you in this state.
- I don't know what happened. It just did.
- Where are you living now?
- I'm between apartments.
- Do you want to go clean?
- I can't. I've told you everything.
- You owe me 200. Give me the money.
- To get your baby drugged?
How can you call this a baby?
It isn't a fucking baby yet.
Who's the father?
The idea for the database
is to gather genetic data
on the entire population of Iceland
and use the findings to create
new medical cures,
to relieve suffering and prevent diseases.
But is it ethical to use
personal information this way?
That's a difficult question,
but in many ways I think that
if there is any justification
for using personal information,
it must be to ease and treat diseases.
Data on genetic diseases
isn't necessarily personal.
It is information on diseases
passed on between generations.
It's a social problem.
Örn.
Örn, a letter just came
from the data protection committee.
Thanks.
I'm positive there is no trace of it
on my side of the family.
No one's even heard of this disease.
What does your wife say?
She doesn't think it matters.
Says it won't bring our daughter back.
Talk to your mother.
She refuses to discuss it.
I'm off to the harbor.
I'm worried about your father.
It's as if he can't face his retirement.
He's restless around the house and hangs
around at the harbor day in, day out.
I wonder if he ever felt at ease at home.
This is the only Aude
who died aged 4 in 1974.
It says here the cause of death
was a malignant brain tumor.
I looked up the mother.
Her name was Kolbrun.
She committed suicide.
- What about the father?
- I couldn't find anything about the father.
In such cases, that generally
means incest, rape or a foreigner.
The only living relative is Elín,
Aude's aunt.
Elín.
Can you find her address?
Was there any friction
between him and other workers?
I don't think so.
He kept to himself.
- Did Holberg ever talk about his family?
- I don't think he had one.
You have to be joking.
Is that a goat?
No, it's a sheep.
Hello?
Elín? My name's Erlendur.
I called you this morning.
Would you please come to the door?
I need to talk to you about Kolbrun.
I don't want anything to do with the police
after what you did to her.
What did we do to her?
Leave me alone.
Aude, Kolbrun's daughter Arnar.
"Preserve my life
from fear of the enemy."
Leave her alone.
Where did you get that photo?
From Holberg's basement.
Did you know him?
- I hope he rots in hell.
- It looks like he will.
Is Holberg Aude's father?
Ask Rúnar Arnar.
- Rúnar?
- That sleazy cop.
Sergeant Rúnar Gislason?
Do you know that scum?
He was the local policeman.
Lived here the last I knew.
What did we do to her?
Ask sergeant Rúnar, if he's still alive.
That piece of filth.
Sergeant Rúnar.
How come Elín won't talk to me?
How the hell should I know?
I'm investigating the murder
of a man called Holberg.
What the hell
has that got to do with me?
Fuck off, or I'll call the police.
I am the police.
Perhaps you've forgotten that, too?
Tell me about Kolbrun,
Elín's sister.
What did we do to her?
She was a whore.
Accused the man of rape.
It was no fucking rape.
They said she was hitting on all of them.
All ofthem?
Yes, the whole trio.
- The trio?
- Yes.
- What men are you talking about?
- You know.
So you just sent her back home?
I was simply showing her
what to expect if she pressed charges.
Is that what police should be doing?
She'd have been laughed
right out of court.
They should have fired you years ago,
you lousy piece of shit.
The sergeant told her
to forget about it,
then hid the blood-stained panties,
the only evidence.
- Did Holberg know he was Aude's father?
- He flatly denied it.
- His mates testified against Kolbrun.
- What mates?
Gretar and Ellidi.
Scumbags from Keflavik.
Ellidi?
They told everyone she was a whore.
Said she sold herself
to the Americans at the base
and that she wasn't too good
for an Icelander.
Kolbrun didn't leave the house for months.
Then she committed suicide.
Do you have children?
Yes.
There's nothing as terrible
as losing a child.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- The usual?
- Yeah. I'll have a sheep head.
- Enjoy.
- Thanks.
Eva.
"Preserve my life from fear..."
"Hear my voice, O God, in my prayer."
"Preserve my life
from fear of the enemy."
"Hide me from the secret counsel
of the wicked,"
"from the insurrection
of the workers of iniquity"
"who bend their bows
to shoot bitter words"
"that they may shoot in secret
at the perfect."
"They search out iniquities."
"They encourage themselves
in an evil matter."
"They commune of laying snares privily."
I've made a decision.
I'm going to make you a grandfather.
Grandpa Erlendur.
Thanks.
Can I stay with you
until I find myself a new place?
Can I stay?
As long as you want.
You know that.
Smuggling of liquor and narcotics,
insurance fraud, manslaughter.
He sank a fishing boat.
Set fire to it.
Three survived.
The fourth was locked in the engine room
and went down with the boat.
Anything there
about assaulting a young man
and cutting up his face
with a broken bottle?
Do you know this guy?
Ellidi is one of the most
notorious maniacs in Iceland.
The trio. Drug addicts and scum
fucking everywhere.
Would you mind
putting out that cigarette?
You're killing me with your smoking.
You haven't stopped
Since we left town.
Stop whining like a sissy.
Ellidi just came out of solitary.
I'd treat him carefully.
What was he in solitary for?
He didn't show up in time
after a weekend leave.
Are you saying Ellidi was out
when Holberg was murdered?
I suppose so. They brought him
back here two days ago.
What's going on? I had no information
about that. Why weren't we told?
The yellow press has been
all over us about prison conditions.
We're not giving out
any unnecessary information.
Unnecessary?
This means that Ellidi
is a murder suspect.
It's not my responsibility.
I wasn't even on duty.
I'll be calm.
Holberg was found murdered.
- Holberg was murdered last weekend.
- I'm not talking to you while they're in here.
What can you tell us
about your friend Holberg?
Send them out.
It's all right.
Where were you saturday night?
- How is she doing down there?
- she?
- Your cunt.
- Cut it out.
Howwas he killed?
A blow to the head Arnar.
- With a hammer?
- No, with an ashtray.
An ashtray.
What became of Gretar?
Gretar?
Your friend and Holberg's.
Why are you asking about Gretar?
- Gretar disappeared in the early '70s.
- What should I know about it?
Holberg raped a woman
a few years before Gretar disappeared.
That was no fucking rape.
Where were you last weekend?
- Getting nice and wet?
- Why cover up for Holberg?
- How are your panties?
- Cut the crap.
He asked her what kind of panties
She was wearing.
- How her husband liked fucking her.
- Her husband?
What husband?
- What do I get out of this?
- Nothing.
Except talking dirty to us.
I want smokes, a TV in my cell
and a whore - one a month.
His daughter, for example.
They say Eva's pussy
is as pink as a pig's.
Cheapest fuck in town.
What woman were you talking about?
What other woman
were you talking about?
That fucking stupid moron.
Is he playing games with us?
Or does he know about another woman
that Holberg raped?
Do you think it's broken?
Don't be a pussy.
Erlendur,
Ellidi wants to talk to you.
I'll tell you what I know,
if you just get me out of here.
Solitary is driving me crazy.
They treat me like a beast.
Who do you think you are?
Nelson Mandela?
You're the worst kind of a moron
I've ever come across.
I hope they keep you locked up forever.
I'll tell you everything you want to know
if you just get me out of here.
Why did you testify against Kolbrun?
I don't know what woman
you're talking about.
Who said I testified against this Kolbrun?
Sergeant Rúnar.
I'll kill that jerk when I get out of here.
If you don't know Kolbrun,
then what woman were you talking about?
Will you help me get out?
I'll see what I can do.
I can't remember her name,
but she lived in Grindavík.
She was about the same age
as Holberg.
Gretar was in on it.
He took the photos.
- What photos?
- I've told you all I know.
What happened to Gretar?
Ask sergeant Rúnar Arnar.
Why him?
You promised to help me get out.
And you promised your mother
you'd always be a good boy.
You think he's misleading us
with this other woman?
He's not that clever.
We caught him off guard.
How on earth are you going to find
this other woman?
Who said I was going to do it?
- Erlendur, my friend.
- My friend?
I'm having trouble breathing. Would you
mind putting that cigarette out?
Just open the window.
Eva.
Hi.
I went out to buy carrots.
- Who taught you to make meat soup?
- Mom.
Once when she wasn't talking too badly
about you, she told me it was your favorite
and that you were a loser.
Have you found the killer yet?
- Ellidi sends his regards.
- Ellidi?
Isn't he in prison?
The scum I deal with
Sometime mention your name.
It's their way of getting at me.
Does it work?
How do you know Ellidi?
I don't know him.
Has it ever crossed your mind
that they all know that I'm your daughter?
I get bugged about that, too.
I'm Erlendur,
a police investigator.
I'm blind, not deaf.
Sorry.
I wanted to have a word with you
about your son Gretar.
Have you found him, then?
No, but a friend of his was found
murdered recently. Holberg.
I wouldn't know about that.
Really?
Was he bumped off?
The last I saw of my son Gretar
was when he came to my house
in the summer of 1974.
He stole money from my purse.
Then he disappeared himself.
Like he'd been stolen.
Why have you got a picture
of JFK above your bed?
I always had a soft spot for him,
you know.
Did you know
Gretar took photographs?
Yes.
He was always taking those photos.
He told me once
that photos were...
the mirrors of time.
But I didn't have a clue
what he was talking about.
No.
Do you think you'll find my boy?
I never knewwhat Gretar was up to.
I told him that at the time.
- Him?
- sergeant Rúnar.
He led the investigation
of Gretar's disappearance.
Rúnar Gislason?
And he seemed to be in quite a hurry
to close the case.
- There was something rotten in the air.
- What?
It stank.
The whole business stank.
- Got anything vegetarian?
- No guacamole bullshit here, buddy.
- I'll have a latte, then.
- Latte? The coffee's over there.
Right.
Holberg's autopsy confirms that he died
from a blow to the head.
It cracked his skull, hit an artery
and led to hemorrhaging of the brain.
The murderer was most likely
a right-handed male.
So it wasn't a crazy old woman
from Grindavík
taking revenge after all these years.
- Hardly Kolbrun's sister, Elín.
- Ellidi?
Can't we just extend his sentence
and close the case? End of story.
Is that what they taught you
in America?
They found a benign tumor
in Holberg's brain
and skin discoloration linked to it.
- Aude died from a malignant tumor.
- Yes.
You said Holberg's sister
also died young.
I'll try to find the cause.
We have to find out if Aude
is definitely Holberg's daughter.
How?
There's only one option.
Careful, now.
Body snatchers.
Grave robbers.
Grave robbers. Grave robbers.
Body snatchers.
Grave robbers.
Hold her back.
I'll never forgive you for this.
Never. Mark my words.
I understand that, but the investigation
into Holberg's murder must go on.
Is that monster going to torment us
beyond the grave?
Can't you see what you've done?
You're no better than sergeant Rúnar,
that filth of a cop.
I should never have spoken to you.
Never.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Ellidi sends his regards from prison.
He told me to ask you
what happened to his friend Gretar.
I don't know.
He said he is going to kill you
when he gets out.
I hope he won't be too late.
This is ridiculous.
- How many women are on the list?
- 105 women.
Plus another 61
who've moved away from Grindavík.
That makes 166 oldies.
What are we supposed to do?
Knock on the door and ask all these
grannies if they were raped 30 years ago?
Abitharsh, don'tyouthink?
I don't see
how we can do it differently.
"Excuse me, but were you raped
when you were younger?
"No? sorry to bother you."
And then what?
If she's kept quiet all this time,
why should she want to talk now?
- Play it by ear. Question of psychology.
- Psychology?
Yes. Try to get invited in,
Sit down,
have a coffee and a chat.
Just be a bit of a pussy.
- Have you ever been raped?
- What?
I was asking
if you've ever been raped.
Raped.
Have you ever been raped?
No, thank you.
What can I do for you, my dear?
I'm sigurdur Óli, a crime
police investigator from Reykjavik.
- lsn't that something?
- I'm investigating a rape.
A rape? Here in Grindavík?
When? Last night?
No, back in the '70s.
I don't know how to put this,
but were you raped back then?
- You don't fool me that easily.
- What?
I've had it.
What?
Did she recognize me?
No, she thought she was
on Candid Camera.
Do come in.
She stopped giving off scent long ago,
but her body's still in good shape.
What?
I need to get a new card.
The blow would have killed him
almost instantly.
He'll have seen the tunnel,
the bright light.
Didn't he just go the other way?
I can't see
whether men were good or bad.
But I can see he suffered from constipation,
which is not uncommon at his age.
This could just as easily be
the heart of a saint.
Right. A constipated saint.
What about the brain tumor?
I found a small benign tumor
in the brain
and skin discolorations,
especially under his arms.
What about Aude?
- Aude?
- The girl we dug up.
She's supposed to have died
from a brain tumor.
Have you heard the story
about Albert Einstein?
Albert Einstein?
What about Thomas Harvey,
the pathologist?
No, I've never heard of him.
He was on duty when Einstein died.
A curious chap.
He performed the autopsy.
Because it was Einstein,
he couldn't resist the temptation
of opening the skull and taking a look
at the brain. But that wasn't all.
He stole the brain and took it home.
Lost his job, of course,
when the theft was discovered.
But he became a living legend.
He kept the brain on his mantelpiece.
- ls this true?
- True as daylight.
Why are you telling me this?
Her brain's missing.
What? Aude's brain?
If they took the brain
to investigate the tumor,
they would not have had time
to put it back before the funeral.
It had to be fixated in formaldehyde.
And where do they keep brains
these days?
Jar City.
Jar City?
If we find the brain, we'll establish
more quickly the cause of Aude's death.
- Now watch this.
- Good luck.
I'm Elínborg, a police...
- Are you investigating the murder?
- Yes, how did you guess?
Everyone's talking about it.
My neighbor filled me in.
- Yes, we talked to her earlier.
- Do come in and tell me more.
Thank you.
- ls that you?
- Yes, I wasn't such a bad-looker.
Ever hear the name Holberg?
- Yes.
- Really? How?
My neighbor told me about him
this morning.
Of course.
He gets a bit excited around strangers.
We're looking for a woman who knew
Holberg and lived in Grindavík in the '70s.
It's rather a sensitive matter.
He raped her.
And how is it connected
with his murder decades later?
Unfortunately I can't tell you.
Well, then I don't know
how I can help you.
Sorry to have to ask you this,
but have you ever been raped?
No, unfortunately.
I mean, unfortunately
I can't help you there.
And you've never heard
of Holberg before?
Believe me,
I'd remember if I'd been raped.
So you're looking for Jar City.
I understand you look after
the remains of the organ collection.
Is this to do with Aude?
Do you know her?
What do you know about Aude?
Has it got something to do
with the Northmarsh murder?
The coroner's report
mentions only a brain tumor.
There are no further details.
I saw that report.
It's very unprofessional.
It's a hereditary disease -
neurofibromatosis.
Some people live normal lives
without it ever surfacing.
They are symptom-free carriers.
But it's much more common for
the symptoms to appear at an early age
in the form of body marks
and skin tumors.
Where is she?
Who?
Aude.
You mean Aude's brain.
Eva.
Is Eva in?
No, but perhaps you could tell me
where she is.
- Are you trying to be funny?
- I'm not the funny type.
Shut up, you old fag.
Let us in.
We know the slut is in here.
- What?
- Your daughter's a slut.
Get the fuck out of here.
And don't ever dare come back
I need an ambulance
to Ljósheimar 14.
A young man fell down the stairs.
No, I don't have a clue
about his name.
Hi.
I'm looking for Eddie.
Did you think Eva would get special
treatment because you're a cop?
- How much does she owe you?
- Two thousand.
- Can we make a deal on that?
- If you like.
You'll get more next week.
I'd try to find Eva before Ellidi does.
How does Ellidi come into this?
Ellidi broke out of prison last night.
And he's mad at you.
Where is she?
Eva.
Dad.
Evening.
Sorry.
Fuck.
Hello. Anybody there?
Open up the fucking door.
Don't I have to have an abortion?
I'm so scared
I may have harmed the baby.
The old girl was right.
It stinks.
The area is all one fucking marshland,
Slowly going down.
Look.
The floor's been broken up.
Probably to repair the pipes.
Are you saying it's hollow underneath?
A perfect place
to hide your nearest and dearest.
It's a sunday,
but I'll see if I can still get a crew.
If Gretar was buried in the '70s,
rotting away ever since,
don't you think he'll be here tomorrow?
- Ellidi sends his regards.
- What do you mean?
He's looking for you.
- Did he break out again?
- Yes.
- Why wasn't I informed?
- Call the prison.
If they work sundays, that is.
But I suspect sergeant Rúnar's
in for a little social call.
No need to wait up for me, love.
I'm on a stakeout.
No, in Sandgerdi.
You should have left us alone,
you bastard,
instead of turning Gretar
against me and Holberg.
No wonder you were scared shitless
when we killed him.
You didn't want to be connected
to a murder, did you?
This is sigurdur Óli.
I need backup. I'm on a stakeout.
Just look at you.
An old dirtbag with shit
halfway up your back.
Who's going to wipe your ass now when
you can't misuse the police force anymore?
Well, Gretar.
So that's where you've been hiding.
I think we've found
our mystery woman from Grindavík.
What?
What have you discovered?
We have no secrets anymore.
Did he rape you, Mother?
You have to tell me the truth.
Why do you think
Ellidi and Holberg killed Gretar?
Rúnar dropped
Kolbrun's rape charges,
but kept the evidence
So he could use the trio for dirty jobs.
Gretar pushed the others too hard,
So they killed Gretar to get him
and the sergeant off their backs.
What kind of dirty jobs?
Maybe she can tell.
It would at least explain why
the sergeant assigned himself
the case of Gretar's disappearance.
How?
So he could close the case
and avoid being connected to a murder.
Do come in.
I recognized him right away
from the photos in the papers.
Maybe I should have...
What are you trying to say?
You've been looking for the woman
Holberg raped in Grindavík.
It's me.
You call this rape?
My husband spent
half our marriage at sea.
I was lonely
and drank a lot at the time.
But why the photos?
I had no idea
I was being photographed
until Gretar turned up and threatened
to show them to my husband.
Blackmail.
Why didn't you go to the police?
Everyone knew that sergeant Rúnar,
the head of the district police,
manipulated the trio.
It was a setup,
and they were being used by him.
It was made very clear to me
that if I didn't pay up,
I'd be denounced as a whore.
You make one mistake in life,
and it haunts you forever.
When was he born,
your youngest son?
Did you ever consider abortion?
All the time
Until it was too late.
But the child could also
have been my husband's.
Your son Örn has been researching
the death of a girl in 1974,
who was most likely his half-sister.
Her name was Aude.
How did he find out
that Holberg was his father?
After our little angel died -
his daughter Kola -
Örn, my son,
became obsessed with...
Hold on.
What did she die of?
She was only five.
The doctors said
it was a genetic brain disease.
Neurofibromatosis.
My God.
What have I done?
I killed Kola.
Holberg and I killed the little angel.
Stay away from me.
- What a bloody stench.
- Get out of here.
I have every right to be here.
I'm your son. Your prodigal son.
Looking for new victims?
Can I ask you a question, Dad?
Dad. Did you rape any other women
aside from Mom?
- I'm calling the police.
- lt's about time.
They could search your computer
while they're here.
What do you want from me?
You haven't got a clue
about what happened.
You couldn't care less.
Right?
I've never raped anyone in my life.
It's all a fucking lie.
They said I had a daughter.
Her mother, Kolbrun,
charged me with rape but couldn't prove it.
I was never convicted.
The disease
Should have died out with you.
You should have been the last carrier.
You were the last in line.
Unmarried, childless.
No family.
But you're a rapist.
A lousy fucking rapist.
- What do you mean, "a carrier"?
- Aude got the disease from you.
I got the disease from you.
There hasn't been an incident
of the disease in Iceland
Since Aude died,
apart from my daughter, Kola.
Now we're the last two standing.
I didn't rape your mother.
She was a fucking slut.
She cheated on your father
while he was at sea.
Gretar photographed her in action.
Why do you think
She never told anyone?
Get out of here,
you son of a whore.
Don't ever let me see you again.
No one here.
What a mess.
Nobody here.
Disgusting.
Icelandic paternity.
I AM HlM!
Does it worry you?
People always said
I didn't look like either of my parents.
- I've always had that feeling, too.
- What?
That you were a bastard.
Got your sense of humor back.
What sense of humor?
Call me if you find anything,
and declare him wanted.
We suspected unauthorized access
of the database.
Why didn't you notify the police?
It's a sensitive matter
because of data privacy.
Personal data must only be used
for research purposes,
and of course we didn't suspect a link
to the Northmarsh murder.
How did he do it?
He set up an unauthorized
research project.
He forged signatures, pretended we were
researching the genetic transmission
of a brain tumor disease
found in several families.
He tricked the data protection committee,
the ethics committee and us.
The process so far has been...
- Hello.
- I found a sawn-off shotgun barrel
under his bed.
Shotgun?
- He's hardly going to use it to kill.
- Why not?
Then he would have shot Holberg.
- Alert all departments that he's wanted.
- sure.
So that's how Örn got hold
of the names and ID numbers
of all the people with family histories
of this disease?
Can you please let us in?
That's how he discovered that Holberg
was his father and Aude his half-sister.
This could be extremely embarrassing
for the company.
We prefer to regard it
as a personal tragedy.
You keep all these secrets
carefully categorized on computer.
Old family secrets.
Tragic stories, sorrow and death.
In the hope
there'll be less in the future.
Is that the girl you dug up?
There was a break-in
at the morgue.
Hello?
- someone's broken in.
- shit.
- ls there anything but bodies there?
- No. I'll meet you.
Call the pathologist.
What's going on?
- He broke the window and climbed in.
- Who breaks into a morgue?
Where are Holberg
and Aude's remains?
- ls it linked to Holberg's murder?
- Could be. Hurry.
In here.
You keep this door unlocked?
The girl's not here.
Her bones are gone.
Say, did you ever find her brain?
Hello.
- Hello.
- He's here.
- What?
- Who are you talking about?
- He's outside, staring through my window.
Stay inside, I'll...
Shit.
- Are you OK?
- He's in the cemetery.
- Who?
- Örn, Aude's brother.
Stop him before it's too late.
I'll do my best.
Go inside and lock the doors.
He saw you digging up Aude.
You shouldn't have done it.
You should have
let her rest in peace.
I had no choice.
I'm sure you'll want this.
The disease.
Hand me the gun.
You know what the geneticists
call us, me and Aude?
Deviations.
We're called deviations.
My daughter once asked me
in the hospital:
"Why do we have eyes?"
"To see with," I said.
"No," she corrected me.
"To cry with."
What are you if you're not yourself?
Easy now.
Who are you then?
- lt'll be all right.
- I didn't plan it this way.
- lt'll be fine.
- Now it's too late.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be mad at you.
But when I see the way you live,
the way you waste your life...
then watch a tiny coffin
come up from the ground...
nothing really makes sense anymore.
I don't know what's going on,
and I want to...
Beat the hell out of me?
You think you can put on armor
and defend yourself against it.
That you can watch the filth
around you from a distance...
Iike it's none of your business.
But all this repulsion
haunts you like an evil spirit.
In the end...
you even forget
how ordinary people live their lives.