- What do you think?
- What do you want to eat?
- Hell, I don't care.
- Let's get some salmon patties.
Well, shit.
- Man: When do we want it?
- Crowd: Now!
No more war! No more war!
- Man: When do we want it?
- Now!
- What do we want?
- Peace.
- When do we want it?
- Now.
- What do we want?
- Peace.
- When do we want it?
- Now.
Assholes.
Man: You should be ashamed
of yourself, Caldwell.
- My cousin's over there now.
- Come on, come on.
We don't want your fucking war.
- Hey, smile for the camera.
- One, two, three, four.
We don't want your fucking war.
One, two, three, four.
Let's go.
I hear Tate Scott
might run for Sheriff
if Orville Allen retires.
Goddamn Tate Scott.
The whole damn bunch
is Yankees
got nothing running through
their veins but Cincinnati blood
from Ohio. They're from Ohio.
You ought to have
to be from here
to run for office,
the way I see it.
Well, they've been here
some 40-odd years though, Jim.
I don't give a shit.
- Born and bred a Yankee.
- Man: Okay.
- And plus...
- Yeah, yeah, bye.
...he got the grin of a queer.
Jim, there's a riot going on
down the street.
The police force has arrested
a bunch of hippies.
Your boy's the ringleader.
Oh.
Would you do the same thing
if we were the Klan?
You think the Klan would let
a bunch of dopeheads
like y'all in?
Seriously, man.
That's not what I'm saying.
What in God's name's
going on here?
You, get up. Come on.
Get up. Get up here.
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on. Come on.
What the hell do you think
you're doing?
Get up here.
God damn it.
You're making me look bad.
You un-American son of a bitch,
you're making me look bad
- out there on the street.
- That's bullshit, Daddy.
No, it's not bullshit. Hey.
Hey.
Well, that's real brave,
hitting me when I'm handcuffed.
Yeah? Well, I'll un-handcuff
you, you little bastard,
then I'll beat the living
dogshit out of you.
I'm tired of getting you bailed
out of all your monkey business.
Now you go to the jailhouse,
act like a human being
and apologize.
And I'll come post your bail and
I'll try to straighten it out,
if that's possible.
All right?
- You're a sad old man.
- Yeah? Oh.
- I'll bail myself out.
- All right.
You go your way
and I'll go mine.
Right. Then you go your way
right to the jail.
- Take him away.
- Come on, Carroll.
- Let's go.
Go on, arrest his ass.
Bastard.
What's up, baby?
What's up?
Hey. Daddy feed you all right?
Daddy feed you?
Daddy feed you, huh?
Did Daddy feed you?
Come on. Come on.
What's the word, Jimbo?
Jimbo: Shit, I don't know.
Where's Daddy?
Shit, I don't know.
He took off in his truck.
He's been acting weird lately
like everybody else
in this fucking family.
Skip,
the salad dressing's mixed.
Oh, Skip, if you're gonna be
up all night,
you're gonna have to
cut down the radio.
I've been listening
to underground music.
Carroll got me
to doing it, yeah.
It's real different kind of
music.
But the program don't start
till midnight,
so that's how come
I had to be listening so late.
Well, it don't sound
like it's underground.
It sounds like it's right
in the room with me.
Carroll says if you listen
to underground music,
it'll open your mind up.
That means just take LSD...
opening your mind.
Goddamn Carroll.
That's all this town needs...
a damn hippie peace march.
A bunch of filth lying around
the park in their own shit.
Carroll says we got no business
being in Vietnam.
He says it's in vain
or something.
That's easy for Carroll to say.
He ain't fighting
the little bastards.
Somebody's got to fight
the bastards.
You know, Carroll actually did
his fighting, Jimbo.
What's that supposed to mean?
Tell me, Skip.
Uncle Carroll says that he's
fighting for freedom and peace.
Shut up.
In a peaceful way.
Jimbo, come on, honey.
You ain't one to talk.
You're 50 years old,
still living at home,
driving up and down the road
in them sports cars
like a damn teenager.
You got no kind of life,
no kind of job,
chasing after any old wore-out
whore who will talk to you.
You're nearly 50
and you live here too, Dad.
I thought I told you
to shut up.
Take it easy, honey.
Jimbo:
At least I didn't turn out to be
some freak like you
and him did.
Why don't you go live with him,
polish each other's medals...
while you're protesting
the damn war?
They say Tate Scott
might run for Sheriff.
If that damn Yankee gets in,
we're all screwed.
We'll be eating Cincinnati chili
full of cinnamon in it.
- How would you like that?
- A phone call, Mr. Caldwell.
Well, I'm eating my supper.
Tell them I'll call them back.
It's long-distance
from England.
- From where?
- England.
England?
Hmm.
Uh-huh. England?
Hello.
Man: Mr. James Caldwell?
Yeah. Yeah, this is
Jim Caldwell.
This is Phillip Bedford,
Mr. Caldwell.
Well...
that was Phillip Bedford...
that son of a bitch's son.
Jimbo:
What the hell did he want?
Your mama's dead, son.
Died today of cancer.
Yeah.
Wants to be buried here
with her people,
so they're bringing her back.
Who's bringing her back?
That English bastard
and his kids.
Well, they can't come here.
They ain't welcome.
Well, I ain't happy
about it neither,
but we got to put up with it.
She deserves to be
with her people.
It don't matter
what she done to us.
So...
I believe
the funeral's on Saturday.
All right?
Tell your brothers
and call your sister.
Yeah.
Jimbo: Yes, sir.
Lord have mercy.
Yeah. Yeah.
Dorothy:
Poor Miss Naomi,
dying all the way over there
in England.
I only met her that one time
when I was little.
She was a free-spirited woman.
How come her to leave
Mr. Caldwell like that?
I love Jim Caldwell,
but he ain't
the most romantic man
in the world.
And Miss Naomi...
she wanted to travel,
see new things.
And he wouldn't take her.
So one time she just
up and went by herself.
Met that man over there.
Then she come back over here,
divorced Mr. Caldwell,
went back over there
and married Mr. Bedford.
I think he thought
she'd come back to him
one day.
Not like this.
JD, JD.
Mm. Yeah, bud?
I had some strawberry mescaline
go missing.
It wouldn't happen to be
in your brain now, would it?
- JD: Got to be.
- Hang on, hang on.
Mm-hmm, I got all that good shit
traveling around my brain.
Just play nice next time,
partner, and ask.
- What, baby? What?
- Look.
♪ You will bear someone else's ♪
♪ Fertile seed... ♪
Well, okay.
♪ Evil woman, don't play ♪
♪ your games with me... ♪
Hey, buddy.
What's going on?
Are you okay, buddy?
When did Mama
visit us last time?
Was it last 4th of July?
No. No, it was, like,
six, seven years ago
when Aunt Mary Beth died.
Remember,
she brought you that hat...
that Scottish hat?
Mama died, Carroll.
They called from England.
Mama's name is gonna say
"Bedford" on her grave.
Yeah.
Do you have any medicine,
Carroll?
Yeah, buddy.
I got some medicine.
Are you all right, Father?
Yes, yes, I'm all right.
Please stop asking me
if I'm all right.
- Bloody fool.
- Good damn it, Neal.
One of these days
your luck is gonna run out.
Hey, girls,
before my luck runs out,
why don't y'all hand me
one of those beers back there?
- There you go, Daddy.
- Thank you, baby.
That's just what you need.
Y'all got another one?
Well, this looks like
it will do fine.
Now everybody stay here
and I'll go and register.
- Hello.
- Hi. Can I help you?
Yes, yes.
Uh, I have a reservation.
The name's Bedford.
Dispatch: We got an accident
on 271, one vehicle.
Looks like there's
one fatality...
one more car...
Let's go see that wreck before
we head to the house, all right?
Grandpa, I got to shit
pretty bad.
You can shit after a while.
Man:
it don't look good, does it?
Well, looky here.
There's Jim Caldwell.
I reckon that son of a bitch
shows up
at every wreck there is.
Officer: Rich folks ain't never
got nothing else to do.
- Officer #2: Hey, Jim.
- Hey.
- Officer: Jim.
- Hey, Peyton, what happened?
Hey, Jim. I guess he just
didn't make that curve,
hit that concrete mile marker,
I figure...
- Yeah.
- ...as far as I can tell.
Yeah, he's dead all right.
Nothing we can do till
the coroner gets here,
but he's over
at the steakhouse.
All right, let's take a look.
Peyton:
They're down there now
trying to figure ways
prize him out.
- Peyton: Jim, watch your step.
- Deputy: Look right here.
You think you can get in there?
Man #2:
Come on, Jim.
Let me take a look.
Yeah, you see, if you could just
go to the other side
and we could wedge
his foot out.
If he was a smaller man.
Move over a minute.
Move over.
Let me in there.
O Lord.
Yep.
Broke his neck, looks like.
Probably didn't know
what was going on.
Deader than Woodrow Wilson.
Grandpa, I gotta go.
I'm serious.
Well, go shit in the woods.
They're all around here.
All right? I'm trying to
figure this wreck out here.
He might have been headed
to get some pussy or something,
maybe looked up at the trees
for just a second too long.
Yeah.
There was a soul in this
Volkswagen a little while ago
thinking about something.
Now there ain't nothing more
than a voice-thrower's dummy
laying there.
Now it's trying to figure out...
...why he didn't make it.
Carroll: I want you to enroll
in college next semester.
Mickey: I don't want
to go to college, Dad.
It's a waste of time.
You gotta get that
student deferment, son.
They're drafting guys
left and right your age.
- Hello.
- Carroll.
Hey, Donna, what's up?
When did you get in?
Donna: Now come on
over here and eat.
Daddy's having a cookout.
No, Daddy don't want me
out there.
Donna:
Don't be stupid.
- I got arrested.
- Are you shitting me?
- Yeah.
-  Oh my God.
I'll tell you about it when I...
Donna: Come on.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Okay, yeah.
- I'll see you later.
- Bye.
That was your Aunt Donna.
They just got in.
Neal wants us to come out to
the house and eat with them.
Do I have to go?
Yeah, you do.
Skip. Hey.
Hey, buddy.
Hey, come on, Skip.
- God damn.
- Get up, buddy.
Why don't they just get all
of it while they're in there?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
How are you doing, buddy?
- Oh, hi, man.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
- All right, all right.
We're heading over to the house
to get something to eat, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay, so get yourself good.
- All right.
- Okay.
Yeah, looks like we're gonna set
another sales record
- this year.
- Donna: All right.
Of course we set sales records
every year.
Donna:
Bye.
It looked like
we weren't last year,
and then in that fourth quarter
we just started moving
Cadillacs off that lot, man.
- I'm telling you...
- Phillip Bedford just called.
- What did he want?
- He just wanted to let us know
they're here. They're staying
at the Pines Motel.
They're coming over
to eat with us.
I don't believe my goddamn ears.
You invited them bastards
over to our house?
Neal: Damn, Donna,
what's the matter with you?
They took your mama
away from you.
Ls this your goddamn
business, Neal?
What's going on?
Jimbo: Donna invited them
English people over here.
Now she's gonna call them back
and un-invite them.
Donna: Like hell I will.
This isn't just about you,
Jimbo.
Mama's dead.
She's got another family
and we gotta deal with that.
The world don't revolve
around you.
Vicky: Oh, I guess it's too busy
revolving around you,
ain't it, Donna?
Oh, go make a doily, Vicky.
I wish Donna hadn't
shot off her mouth,
but now we're stuck with it.
Hard to believe
I'm fixing to meet that man
face to face.
I'm furious with you, Phillip.
You put me
in an impossible situation.
We're actually going to go
to this man's house?
I'm sorry, Father.
She took me by surprise.
She was very insistent and I
thought it very rude to say no.
You know how much
I detest excuses.
I wasn't making an excuse.
What if he attacks me?
Oh, please.
Naomi told me
some terrible stories
about his mood swings,
temper... violent temper.
Hello. I've come to compare
notes on the bug situation.
I found the most enormous bug
racing around the loo.
You must come and see it.
We've been invited
to the Caldwell ranch, Camilla,
for a cookout.
I wonder if I've brought
the proper clothes.
What does one wear
to a cookout?
it is so dreadfully hot.
I feel as though
I'm swimming in treacle.
Are we just gonna have to
sit here all day?
April: Yeah, can we go
swimming or something?
Donna:
Well, why don't y'all wait
for Uncle Carroll and Mickey
to get here?
Uncle Carroll always loves
to swim with y'all.
- Hey, y'all.
- Hey, baby.
Hey.
They're here.
Fantastic.
It's like "Gone with the Wind."
Hi, everybody.
Are you Phillip?
Yes, yes. Donna?
That's right.
And this is my brother Skip.
God damn, he's
a good-looking son of a bitch.
You have any trouble
finding the place?
Oh, no. No, no, no.
Your directions were impeccable.
Well, y'all come on in,
meet everybody.
Hi, guys.
Come on.
This is my brother Jim, Junior...
everybody calls him Jimbo...
his wife Vicky,
my husband Neal,
our daughters Autumn and April.
And, let's see, Jimbo's son Alan
is somewhere around here.
My son too... me and Jimbo.
Yep, came right out of me.
Well, I suppose it's my turn.
My name is Phillip.
This is my father Kingsley
and my sister Camilla.
Where'd Daddy go?
This is Daddy...
well, Jim, Senior.
Daddy, this is Kingsley...
I mean, Mr. Bedford.
Mm-hmm.
How do you do, Mr. Caldwell?
Fine. Just fine.
Kingsley: Well...
you have a lovely house.
Donna:
Oh, hi, guys.
This is my brother Carroll
and his son Mickey.
- Jim: Yeah. Yeah.
- How are y'all doing?
A good picture
of you in the paper...
a nice, big picture, front page.
Hey there.
Phillip, isn't it?
Yes. And you're Neal,
Donna's husband.
Neal Baron.
I'm Donna's husband.
She's the daughter,
Jim and Mrs. Caldwell's
daughter...
or Belford, I guess it is,
or was.
Boy, it's a shame
about her moving on.
She's in a better place now,
better than England anyway,
from what I know of it.
I'm just fucking with you, son.
But not really. God damn,
it's miserable over there.
I went over there once
on business and, God damn,
I don't see how y'all do it.
You can't get so much
as one good meal over there.
They wouldn't know a grill
if one bit them on the ass.
And musty, God damn,
cold, shitty.
Boil everything.
They boil a goddamn Clark Bar.
Anyway, I don't mean to be
running your place down.
Well, that's quite all right.
The...
the food can be a challenge.
I'd rather live
in West Virginia as there.
Well, listen,
pleasure talking to you.
I'm gonna grab a drink,
if you'll excuse me.
Hell yeah,
let's get a cocktail.
I'm in the car business.
I got six lots in the greater
Atlanta area, new and used.
Of course, I don't know
what they've told you about me.
Nothing actually,
but you're doing a fine job.
I'm a two-time pro baller,
defensive end.
I played six seasons
with the Lions.
I got drafted by Baltimore,
but when I got traded,
I come into my own
with the Lions.
I had two pretty bad
knee injuries.
That's what did me in.
I'll show you
the operation scars later.
They're monster.
Hey, Neal, don't you
talk poor Phillip's ear off.
Now Donna was Miss Alabama
back in the day.
Boy, you ought to have seen her.
She looked real good back then.
Donna:
Are you doing all right?
Of course she had the kids,
and that's hard on them...
childbirth.
Yeah, I robbed the cradle.
I got her barefoot and pregnant
right off the bat.
- That gave her something to do.
- Well, she's lovely.
Yeah, she's a good gal
sometimes... Donna.
Hey, listen, me and the girls
are headed back
after the funeral.
Donna's gonna stick around
for a couple of days.
But there's a big Falcons
pre-season game on Sunday.
I know everybody
in the organization,
being an ex-player, and I'm
kind of a big deal around there.
Do you want to go?
40-yard line. You want to?
I'm not really familiar
with American football,
but thank you.
Oh, that's right, y'all call
kickball "football" over there.
Well, you ought to come with me,
watch some real football
where people don't wear
short britches.
I'm told that you are
quite the expert
of the barbecue grill.
What did you do to your hoof?
My hoof?
Yeah. You're on
that walking stick.
Oh. Yes.
It's been my constant companion
since the Great War.
- I was wounded in France.
- Oh.
I fixed up a lot of soldiers
in France.
Some of them just got
a snort of whisky
and a prayer though.
So...
I was a medic over there,
served under Pershing.
Yes, well, you all did.
Yes, sir, we all did, yeah.
Grandpa, can we go swimming?
Do what?
Can we go swimming?
Just so you don't go half-naked.
Eh? Eh?
Whoo!
What are you doing?
Eating corn?
- Mm-hmm.
-  Yeah.
I'm Skip, the one that met you
on the porch a while ago.
I remember.
- I got three airplanes.
-  Really?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Wow.
I got a GTO, a Corvette
and a Chevelle.
Got a lot of lung cancer
and gall bladder trouble
in England, is what I read.
Your thoughts are so random.
I am a thinker,
always have been.
Funny. Very funny.
- Do you want to go see my cars?
- Absolutely.
Alan: There you go, brother.
Camilla:
Mm. Oh, it's lovely.
Shit, somebody's
in my damn shop.
- Camilla: Hmm?
- I hear music in there.
- Somebody's in my damn shop.
- Oh.
Hi. What are y'all doing?
Smoking?
- Smoking a little reefer?
- Yeah.
Sorry, Uncle Skip.
We'll get out of here.
We ain't messing
with nothing.
Just, you know, take your time,
have fun.
Just don't let Jimbo and Daddy
catch you, all right?
- All right?
- You got it.
- Skip: All right.
- Camilla: Ciao.
Maybe turn the music down
or something.
- All right.
- Camilla: Not too much.
Can you turn
the music down?
Oh, man,
Grandpa would kill us
if he caught us.
I mean, really kill us probably.
Yeah, your old man and Grandpa
are both real uptight.
One time Grandpa
sees me lighting up
is when he's dragging my ass off
to a car wreck
or a drowning.
That's some weird shit, man.
He brought me out to see when...
when Floyd Carver
shot that guy
from the employment office
in the belly.
Oh, yeah.
Did he die?
I can't remember.
The dude killed
the shit out of him.
I saw his guts
and everything.
Daddy says Grandpa
needs a trip.
He says it might
loosen him up some.
He don't even know
what acid is probably.
Imagine that... Grandpa tripping?
That's some funny shit
right there.
You know, I got some acid,
you know.
If you want some,
if you want to try.
Okay.
Yeah.
Here we are.
Oh!
I feel as if I went
to an art opening
for automobile lovers.
Oh.
Automobile lovers?
I like the way that sounds.
The fact of the business,
I like the way
everything you say sounds.
I wish I could speak English.
Anyhow, this here
is the Wildcat,
United States Navy.
That's what I flew in the war.
The car's name is GTO,
nicknamed Goat.
Why do you compare your cars
to airplanes?
Oh, I cook up missions
all over the county...
keeps my head in the clouds.
Anyhow, the Wildcat...
the thing about this plane was,
it was the very first American
fighter in the Pacific,
which is where I fought
in the war.
Oh.
Anyhow, right here...
step on over here.
- Camilla: Oh, look at this one.
- Oh, yeah.
That's your Hellcat.
The car's name is Chevelle.
You see it right there.
Chevelle's a little quicker
than GTO,
handles better too.
And the grand finale
over here...
Oh, I love this one. Oh.
It's something.
- Does it go fast?
- Yeah, it does.
- I bet it does.
- They all do.
Mm.
Now the Corsair had
11:1 kill ratio.
- This... don't sit on it.
- Oh.
- Don't sit on it.
- Terribly sorry.
It's okay.
Anyhow, the Corsair had
11: 1 kill ratio
and the Corvette...
11: 1 compression ratio.
- Isn't that something else?
- Lt is. it really is.
It's a beautiful,
beautiful machine.
I'll tell you what:
I love this thing.
Now see, notice how
the hood's so long,
that pretty hood, longer than
the ass end so much, see?
Well, in a Corsair, from
the cockpit to the propeller...
14 feet.
See there?
I do. Do you know
you're like a little child
when you talk about them?
What do you mean?
A kid can't fly these things.
Well, it's just not any son
of a bitch that can handle them.
I mean, you can make a mistake
pretty easy, believe me.
Have I upset you?
They're beautiful.
Yes, they are.
I feel real strange about Mama.
Dear Naomi...
what an eccentric creature
she was.
I wonder why she didn't tell us
she was sick.
She just didn't want you
to worry.
There was nothing
you could do.
Your accent sure is pretty.
I could listen to you talk
all day long.
I need to smoke a reefer with my
nephews. You want to go with me?
Yes, I do. Thank you.
I noticed you didn't eat much.
You don't like Daddy's cooking?
Oh, no, no, no.
It's... it's not that.
Um, I'm sure it's wonderful,
but I can only eat
a very bland diet.
How come?
I was a prisoner during the war,
of the Japanese.
The culinary skills of the Jap
cooks left a lot to be desired.
My insides were left
a bit of a wreck.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be nosy.
No, that's quite all right.
All three of my brothers
were in the war.
Carroll was in the marines.
He was a medic.
Skip was a pilot in the navy.
They both got decorated.
Jimbo was in the army,
but he don't talk about it much.
He ran the laundry
at Fort Polk.
He's so damn jealous
of the other boys' medals,
you'd think
he was in high school.
Well, he shouldn't feel
that way. He did his bit.
Yeah, try telling Jimbo that.
Try telling Jimbo anything.
He's Daddy's boy all right.
Families can be difficult.
They sure can.
So are you married?
Divorced.
Oh.
You got any kids?
No.
Is she pestering the shit
out of you, Phil?
No, no, no, not at all.
Neal, get me a beer.
Well, shit, you got legs.
Well, may I thank you for your
hospitality, Mr. Caldwell?
The barbecue was superb.
Yeah, well, see you tomorrow.
Hey, sweet ass.
Hey, come here a minute.
Come here a minute. Yeah.
Camilla:
Hey, you're blotto.
Hey, listen, there's something
I was thinking about.
I just want to ask you...
This English accent of yours...
there's something about it.
There's just something about it.
Now,
uh, I know we don't know
each other that good yet.
And I'm sure
that you're not gonna just
actually do it
with me yet, but...
But I was wondering
sometime can we just slip off
and you get naked
and talk English
and recite something,
I don't know,
and just let me
beat off to you?
Beat off?
Um...
beat... beat off.
What, have a wank?
See? That's what I'm talking
about... that damned English.
Makes me hornier
than Frank Sinatra.
"Have a wank?"
You're mad as a March hare.
I ain't mad.
I just get real focused
on things.
- Think about it.
- Okay.
Goodbye.
Skip:
Hey, think about it.
Dispatch:
S.O. to 44A.
Man over radio:
44A. Go ahead.
Dispatch: Sheriff, are you
still out at Good Frank's?
Give me a 10-84 to Mr. Meyer's.
Jim:
Mm-hmm, yeah.
He's making threatening phone
calls to neighbors, telling them
he's gonna kill their cat.
Caller advised
of a possible 10-96.
Sheriff: All right.
Dispatch:
Unit 59, 10-20?
- Hey.
- Hey, Daddy.
- How are you holding up?
Well...
all right so far.
- Yeah.
it's all kind of hard
to think about, huh?
What?
Are you gonna be okay tomorrow,
you think?
Tomorrow? Well,
what about it?
The funeral.
Dispatch: All units,
we have a three-car accident
- up on Lance highway...
- Yeah.
- Four fatalities confirmed,
several injuries,
not real sure how many.
It's a shame about
ol' Naomi, you know,
it really is.
Yeah.
You ain't fooling me.
Yeah? I gotta go.
There's a big wreck
right down the road.
- See you later.
- Okay, Daddy.
Man over radio:
In five minutes. Lance highway
- and Scott Ranch Road. Over.
- Dispatch: 10-4.
Let's bring in that new
mystery challenger.
Woman: God bless you.
Go on in. There you go.
Well, yeah.
Yeah. There you go.
Dorothy: Mr. Caldwell.
- How are you doing, Pops?
- Please.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
Naomi.
I forgive you this time.
Bye-bye.
There you go, Mama.
Go on, buddy.
Mama?
- Da... Daddy?
- Hey, buddy, hey.
- Daddy?
- Hey, it's okay. it's okay.
Go on.
Go get with Dad.
Phillip: Father.
- Camilla: Father. Oh my God.
- Phillip: Okay.
Donna: What...?
- Carroll: Yeah, loosen his tie.
- Father. Somebody get a doctor.
- Give him some air.
- Donna: Where's your phone?
Camilla: Father.
Carroll:
Hey, get some water.
Man: There you go.
Donna: Well, somebody
ought to go with them.
They're in a strange town.
They don't know anybody.
Donna, we're all headed
over to the church now
for your mama's funeral.
All right?
Carroll: She's right, Daddy.
Somebody ought to go with them.
Yeah.
Donna: Oh my God,
I hope he's all right.
What if he's dead?
Thank you.
Neal: Broken teeth and bones
and hair and shit...
I mean, it's the hardest fought
game...
He's gonna pinch my last nerve.
Neal: We got one point
with one second to go
- and you know what happens?
- L-l don't know.
They missed the dang
extra point!
Oh, hey, babe, did they
get your mama buried all right?
- Yeah.
- Hey, listen, I gotta get
something else to eat.
This thing tastes like shit.
- How's your daddy doing?
- He's doing well. Thank you.
He had a heart attack
about three years ago,
so of course we were worried
about that.
But the doctor said
he just fainted
because of the stress
and exhaustion.
He's resting now.
And Camilla's with him.
Oh, thank God.
How long
are they gonna keep him?
They said they'd release him
in... in... in a bit.
But they don't want him
to travel for a day or two,
which means we...
we won't be leaving tomorrow.
Well, he can't stay
at the Pines Motel.
I mean, none of y'all should
be there in the first place.
That ain't nothing but
an after-prom fuck joint.
No telling whose jizz
y'all are sleeping on.
Y'all are staying at Daddy's.
That's very kind,
but we couldn't possibly.
Oh, yes,
you could possibly.
I think it's a great idea.
Daddy would insist.
Neal: All right, girls,
let's go.
We got shit to do.
Phillip: Neal, thank you so much
for your help at the hospital.
Neal:
Hey, no sweat, slick.
Take care of yourself,
all right?
Donna: Y'all drive safe.
Call me when you get there.
Hey, Neal,
keep it on the road.
Bye, babies.
Neal: Hand me one of
those beers back there.
- Aunt Donna.
- Yeah?
Uh, Connell's band's
playing tonight.
Really?
Yeah, at the main dollar store
parking lot.
And I'm doing the sound
and the lights.
Uh, you ought to come.
- All right.
- All right?
- Okay, I'll see you later then.
- I'll see you there.
Okay.
I feel like dancing anyway.
Let's go dance.
I should stay here
with my father.
You need to relax.
There's a whole house
full of people
to take care of your daddy.
Well, I'm not really a dancer.
Well, you will be
when I get through with you.
Hey, what's going on?
Any gruesome car crashes?
Any homicides?
No, doesn't appear to be, no.
Too bad.
Hey, let me ask you a question.
How cold can it be in there?
Is it really that dark
and cold inside you
that you can't even hug
your own son
on the day
of his mama's funeral?
You're drunk. Go home.
Yeah. Hey,
let me ask you
another question.
You remember when I was
wounded on Saipan,
I was in the hospital
for three months?
Jim: Of course I do.
Yeah, I wrote you a letter
from that hospital.
I spilled my guts out to you.
I told you everything
you ever meant to me,
about how when I signed up,
I became a medic 'cause you were
a medic in World War I
and... and...
and how I didn't mind
getting shot because...
'cause I figured that you was
finally, you know, proud of me
and how I admired you more
than anybody else in the world,
even President Roosevelt.
And you never wrote me back.
I mean, you never said
one word about that letter,
not to this day.
I never got a letter like that.
You're lying, Pops.
Donna told me
she saw you reading that letter.
Your sister must be
mixed up or something.
Your letter must have got lost,
lost in the mail.
You know,
I used to think
that you were seven feet tall.
I spent my whole childhood
just trying to be
just... just like you.
God damn, I'm glad
I didn't succeed.
Hmm.
Yeah.
You turned out real good.
Man: ♪ I came ♪
♪ I saw ♪
♪ He said ♪
♪ He fled... ♪
"'Forward, the Light Brigade!
Charge for the guns!' he said:
Into the valley of Death
Rode the six hundred."
"Cannons to the right of them,
Cannons to the left of them,
Cannons in front of them
Volley'd and thunder'd;
Storm'd at with shot and shell,
Boldly..."
I'm glad you came
and loosened up a little.
Me too.
I actually had fun.
"Cossack and Russian
Reel'd from the sabre-stroke
Shatter'd and sunder'd."
"Then they rode back,
but not the six hundred."
Connell: Man, I gotta
tell you something,
but you can't tell a soul,
especially my grandmother.
Mickey: All right, man.
Connell: I got a problem, man.
What is it?
I mean, I really got a problem
right now.
All right.
I got this in the mail today,
thought you should
check it out.
Well, shit, man.
What are you gonna do?
What do you think
I'm gonna do?
Yeah.
Come in.
May I?
Oh, Mr. Caldwell.
Yeah.
I just
wanted to see
how you were feeling.
A great deal better,
thank you.
Well, that's...
that's good.
Good to hear.
Yeah.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Caldwell.
Uh...
I got a question for you.
Yes?
How did y'all meet...
you and Naomi?
Well...
I was taking my dog Molly
for a walk in Hyde Park
one morning...
a border terrier,
a wonderful dog.
And my wife had died
a year previously.
Molly had become
my constant companion,
always trying
to lift my spirits.
I noticed...
a very attractive woman
standing by the bronze statue
of St. George
slaying the dragon.
And she had a camera,
obviously a tourist.
And she spotted me
and she asked me
in a very attractive
Southern American accent
if I'd care to take her picture.
Of course
I said I'd be delighted.
So she gave me the camera.
And I was expecting her
to stand in front of the statue
and smile.
I'd take a snapshot of her,
I'd give her the camera back
and we'd go our separate ways,
but not a bit of it.
Not a bit of it.
No, instead she absolutely
astonished me
by climbing on the back
of the horse,
sitting astride it
behind St. George
as quickly...
and as nimbly as a monkey.
Sounds like her, yeah.
I was laughing so much,
I had difficulty in taking
the picture properly.
Anyway...
that's how I met
Naomi.
I just always
wondered about it.
Always wondered.
Yeah.
Hey, kid. What's up?
Just going outside
for a smoke. You?
Just having my cereal.
You're up early.
Not really.
I ain't been to bed yet.
How come?
Connell and me
were up all night talking.
Connell got drafted.
Shit.
Does Dorothy know yet?
No, he ain't told her yet.
Man.
Poor thing.
She loves that kid to death.
It's weird, Daddy.
How can government just come and
tell you what to do like that?
He was gonna go to California,
get in the music scene.
- It's fucked up.
- I know. it ain't right.
I mean, that's why I'm telling
you you gotta get in college.
That's why I'm against it,
you know?
So a kid like Connell
that has a dream
gets a chance to live it.
But, you know,
there is something cool
about it though...
Connell being a soldier.
No, son.
There's nothing cool about it.
Jimbo: Well, looky there.
Here we go.
Nobody else is going to church.
Why do we have to?
'Cause we always go to church.
Because we love the Lord.
Well, we went to church
yesterday.
No, we didn't, God damn it.
We went to a funeral.
It's different.
Hello.
Hello. Good morning.
♪ And then the hydrogen atom, ♪
♪ and good things are gone... ♪
- Hi.
- What are you doing?
Getting the car on?
I'm just fiddling
around in here.
What are you doing?
Oh.
It's hot.
- Skip: Yeah.
- Very hot.
So when are you gonna get naked
and recite something to me
in your accent, hmm?
Come on, tit for tat.
No is not
an acceptable response.
- Listen, uh...
- Hmm?
Yes?
- Hop in.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Kingsley,
you heard of Jayne Mansfield?
- Jayne Mansfield?
- Yeah.
Yeah, the film star,
blonde with those...
Titties. That's right.
That's right.
Well, she was killed
a couple of years back
in a car wreck in Louisiana.
And a friend of mine
just called from town.
They have the very car
she was killed in
out at the discount store.
And they're selling tickets.
And it's a big deal.
And I darn near forgot
it was today.
Would you like to come with me?
Come on. All right?
- Oh.
- Let's go.
All right.
How grotesque.
it's a good spot.
I come out here
to do my thinking.
I used to bring
Patty Overton out here
and just wear her ass out.
That was before the war.
She married
a Primitive Baptist preacher.
She was hare-lipped
and you needed Grandpa's
bifocals to see her titties,
but, you know,
she had a $900 ass
and, God damn, she could take it
right up to the gills
without so much
as a hiccup.
Oh, I think she sounds
like a lovely girl.
Yeah.
Right, enough
beating about the bush.
Let's get on with it, fly boy.
I think a little
Tennessee Williams
would be appropriate.
Do you know
"A Streetcar Named Desire"?
You hear that?
No. I don't.
Birds?
Silence.
That's what was hard
to get used to.
It still is sometimes.
It's kind of like floating
on a peaceful lake
with a tornado in your head
or something.
I never did want to see wrecks.
I didn't want to know
what somebody's last thought was
before they died.
I never wanted to see dead faces
looking at nothing.
I just wanted to fly.
When I was a kid,
I read books on it.
Once in a blue moon
one would fly over
and I'd watch it
till it disappeared.
So that's how come
I joined in 1940.
We weren't even in the war
at that point.
I just wanted to fly up there
in the quiet and the still.
I was a navy pilot.
How about that?
It wasn't quiet and still
though.
It was loud and crazy
and scary.
But you went up
every time you were supposed to,
did what you were
supposed to do.
And I went up
with three minds.
One mind was always thinking,
"One way or the other,
I'm gonna get back.
I'm gonna make it back."
And then another mind
was always thinking,
"This is probably gonna be
the last day of my life."
And then your third mind
was right down the middle
and didn't think
about anything.
It wouldn't
let the other two in.
You know, people say they don't
like to talk about war
because it brings up
the bad memories
and the nightmares
and everything.
I don't believe that. I believe
they don't talk about it
because nobody wants
to hear it.
See, in the early part
of the war
the Japanese were good pilots,
better than we were really.
Later on we got better, but...
I made a mistake that day.
It was a clear blue day
and he got in behind me
and I got hit right here
and back up there
in the back.
And I couldn't believe
I'd been shot.
And at the same time I'd been
expecting it all the time,
you know?
I... one way or another...
I bailed out.
I didn't want to.
I was scared to.
But I didn't want to burn
to death.
That's what we were mostly
worried about up there.
Yeah.
You know how lucky I am?
No.
I landed right in the middle
of the goddamn US marines.
It knocked me out.
I broke my right leg,
collarbone, a few ribs, pelvis,
both hands.
I don't remember a lot about it,
to tell you the truth.
November the 12th, 1942,
Guadalcanal.
I woke up in a hospital,
had both my hands in casts
and my right leg,
just tore to pieces.
And...
the hospital got hit.
And I nearly burned to death.
I saw a guy coming at me
with a big ol' wet blanket
or something and he threw it
over my head.
I thought he was trying
to kill me.
But he saved my face,
as Jimbo says,
for what that's worth,
and got me out of there.
Carroll got to come visit me
a couple of times.
That's real special.
And that was the end
of the war for me.
I mean, God damn, honey, you
can't get out of your own skin
no matter what it is.
Anyhow, it takes
five kills
to become an ace.
And I got six.
I'm an ace.
Skip.
Uh, I didn't
beat off.
Come on, I know a place.
Jim: Her and her boyfriend
and her chauffeur...
they all got killed in Louisiana
in the middle of the night.
The kids was in the back seat,
didn't hardly even get hurt.
A little ol' dog of hers...
...deader than Rin Tin Tin.
Kingsley: Yes, I can remember
when it happened.
It's always shocking
when the rich and famous die.
There's no reason for us
to believe
that they should have immunity,
- but we seem to.
- Yeah. Yeah.
You reckon how many people
would live to ripe old age
if we didn't go anywhere,
'cause transportation
kills a lot of people.
Yeah. What if the last thought
in the world was,
"God damn it, here comes a car
across the center line
about to kill me, 'cause I had
to get out at 10:00 at night
for a roll of toilet paper.
Well, I wish I would have
just wiped my ass
with a sweetgum leaf."
Yes, I've been thinking a lot
about last thoughts recently.
I hope I don't have one.
Yeah?
I'd rather go in my sleep
so there wouldn't be
any conscious thoughts...
- Oh, that's good.
- ...just a dream instead...
Yeah.
- ...hopefully a good one.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Three, please.
Whew.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Move over, son,
so we get a better look.
Yeah.
Mm.
There it is. Whew.
Yeah.
What they said was, there was...
the car was headed through
a road in the swamps.
And there was a mosquito truck
on the road spraying pesticide.
And it comes drifting
across the road like a cloud,
just this fog of poison.
And this tractor trailer rig
slowed down
when it hit the fog.
And Jayne Mansfield's car
slid right under it.
That was it.
That was all she wrote.
Yeah. Mm.
She was decapitated,
wasn't she?
A lot of people think that,
but it wasn't the whole head.
No, it was just the top of it.
Yeah. Mm.
Kingsley, you spend
a lot of your time
figuring things out?
You know, Jim,
these days I think
I spend more time
accepting things.
Not me.
I spend all of my time
figuring things out.
Yeah.
Boy:
That ain't her real head.
Shit, don't you think
I know that?
My daddy says it's probably
not even really her car.
Ain't you got anything better
to do than to pester me?
Huh? Huh?
That's right. Yeah.
- I'll be in the truck.
- Yeah.
Well, mm,
seen enough?
Just about. Just about.
Whew. Mm.
Mm.
Jim: Yeah.
A dead man's stare
ain't any different than
that plastic head's stare.
Ain't nothing
in either one of them.
I saw it on the battlefield
many times.
I'm sure you did too.
Yes, I'm afraid I did.
The fact is
we all have a crash
of some sort awaiting us.
Yeah. Hey, you hear that?
Yeah. Yeah.
I put pieces together
all the time
and they all fall apart.
Before I can ever get it all
put together,
they all fall apart.
Jim: That's it exactly.
Everything's been turned
upside down.
Yeah.
Listen,
I love my boys,
but for the life of me
I can't figure them out.
Jimbo is a good hand
around here,
turned out normal,
didn't even see combat.
The other two
was out-and-out heroes,
turned out to be hardly naught
but hobos.
You think it'd be
the other way around.
Yeah.
Yes, well, I have to say
that Phillip has been a bit
of a disappointment to me too.
Yeah, well, times are changing.
Good life's disappearing.
Sometimes I pray
I'm not here to see it go.
Oh my God, do you believe them?
They're acting like
long-lost buddies.
I know. I'm amazed.
Jim: Let's go sit down a bit,
all right?
Kingsley:
it's really quite a storm.
Jim:
Rest your bones.
Vicky:
Look at them.
No telling what they was up to
while we was at church.
Jim: Yeah.
Phillip:
I'm gonna go freshen up.
Donna:
Well, hey, sister Vicky.
Let's take a walk.
Donna:
We had fun riding.
It's about my sister.
- Jim: You what?
- Donna: We had fun riding.
You need to leave her
the fuck alone.
Well, now, see here, I don't
know what you're getting at.
No, no, no, no, I'm...
I'm not pissed off at you.
I don't even like you.
I only get pissed off
at people I like.
There's nothing in this for me.
This is for your own damn good.
Don't get mixed up with her.
The power's out!
Jim:
See what I got to put up with?
Like I was fixing to tell you,
she ain't a bad gal sometimes.
But she can suck you down
in the hole
you'll never be able
to crawl out of.
Neal used to be
a slim, muscular,
good-looking,
humble guy.
Now he runs his mouth off
like a threshing machine
just so he doesn't have to
hear himself think.
And if you look at him,
he can't even hardly squeeze
into a damn leisure suit,
eats whatever you put
in front of him,
drinks two cases of beer a day.
Donna:
Like all the shit you done.
Jimbo: You want to have some
spending money in your pocket...
- Jim: Careful, careful.
- ...and not to have to work
like a slave,
keep your sanity, let her be.
She's tricky.
She's as whiny
as a two-week-old cat.
Jimbo: I ain't even sure
them's his daughters.
Jim: ...stop and see
what's going on now.
- Jimbo: Get me?
- Jim: Hippies, dope, laziness.
Jim: They call it free love.
It's a free ride is what it is.
Kingsley: What astounds me
is the lack of respect.
You know, the people
that we fought
and that died next to us...
if they were to see
what was going on today,
they would literally
spin in their graves.
It's just a crying shame.
While our boys are fighting
in the jungle, the hippies are...
they're singing songs
and pissing on our flag.
Well, don't they realize
that there is a rising tide
of communism
that's going to sweep up onto
our shores and overwhelm us
if it's not stopped in places
like Southeast Asia.
Exactly what I've been telling
Carroll, word for word.
Phillip: This war is not
about communism.
It's about nationalism.
The Vietnamese people
just want to be free
of foreign domination...
first the French,
and now the Americans.
Jim: We ain't trying
to dominate anybody.
We're just trying to bring
freedom.
Phillip:
At the point of a gun?
Kingsley: Yeah, well, sometimes
violence is a necessary evil.
That's right. That's right.
It was my turn in '17.
And then Carroll and Skip had to
go off after Pearl Harbor.
And pretty soon, well,
it's gonna be Alan's turn.
We need to keep Alan
around here.
We gotta groom him
to take over one of these days.
Jim: Well, now there's
plenty of time for that.
What, you want him to come home
with a chest full of medals too,
or get killed?
Or both. Hey.
Well, I'm just glad
I got girls and not boys.
Phillip: Don't you think
you've had enough, Father?
I mean, you're just a day
out of hospital.
I've had quite enough of you
hectoring me about my drinking.
It's one of the few pleasures
that I have left.
And also
I've had quite enough
of you posing as some sort
of military expert.
Well, I'm no expert,
but I do know something
about war.
I was a soldier too.
Oh, yes.
I'd forgot.
Yes, you fought in the glorious
battle of Singapore.
- The Nips surprised us.
- Yeah?
Our heavy artillery
was pointed seaward
and they came up behind us
through the jungle.
And we surrendered to a force
a third the size of ours...
the most disgraceful defeat
in British history.
And Phillip was a part of it.
It was a botched business,
I admit.
Yes, well, coward Percival
should have been
court-marshaled, short.
General Percival was a brave
and honorable man.
The situation was hopeless.
The fact is, Phillip,
you spent the war as a prisoner,
as a mere slave of the Japs,
not as a soldier.
But I survived
when a great many of us didn't.
I think I should receive
some credit for that.
Kingsley: Oh, the will to live
is very powerful
even among
the lower animals, insects...
mere instinct.
I surrendered because
I was ordered to surrender.
You didn't have to surrender!
You could have
gone off into the jungle
and fought as a guerilla.
You haven't the faintest bloody
idea what you're talking about!
Yeah.
I am astonished.
What makes you think that you
can speak to me in this fashion?
What makes you think you can sit
there and spout drunken nonsense
and not be called upon it?
Well, face the truth, Phillip.
You're lazy
and you drift through life
and then you blame
everything on the war.
You're insane.
I've never blamed the war
for anything.
Kingsley: You really do live
in a fantasy land.
Fantasy?
You are a pompous old dinosaur
that's outlived his time.
I think those Japanese guards
kicked you too many times
in the head.
I really must apologize.
I have behaved very poorly.
Don't worry about it.
I have busted a few glasses
in my day.
Jim: Yeah.
Whatever happened
to stiff upper lip?
Yeah.
What are you doing, Skip?
I came to see you.
Just go put a shirt on, get you
some ice cream or something
and go to bed.
Yeah.
You remember me being a kid?
Well, hell yes, you was good
one time, so I remember.
Yeah.
You remember when I was
a little bitty kid?
I just said, yes, I do.
Now you're my damn kid
but, God damn it, I'm going
through some business papers.
Just get you an ice cream now.
Go to bed.
You remember any stories
about me when I was little?
You remember anything,
like one time when you and me
had a conversation sometime,
something like that?
Anything?
I mean, just some story
about me when I was
a little kid, you know?
'Cause, you know,
Mama told me one or two
last time I saw her.
What did she tell you?
Well...
she told me one
about a cousin of hers
that was so wild,
they used to tie him to a tree
while they fed the chickens
and put the wash up.
Jim: Mm-hmm.
They called him Precious.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
The power's back up.
Put your shirt on.
Go find something to do.
Yeah.
All right.
Turn that music down!
Donna.
♪ Please, fantasy ♪
♪ Please stay with me... ♪
I put a shirt on, Daddy.
Boy, you sure did, didn't you?
Mm-hmm.
♪ My reality ♪
♪ Stay close to me ♪
♪ Stay, fantasy ♪
♪ Please stay... ♪
Boy, I must have been
something else when I was a kid.
Yeah.
Donna: What are you
thinking about?
Phillip: I'm not sure.
Well, there's no way
it wasn't gonna happen.
Doesn't it feel good to live?
Yes. Yes, it feels good to live.
Well, you don't seem
too happy about it.
Don't get all English
on me again.
I mean, you can't tell me
that wasn't good.
No. No, I can't tell you that.
Quit being so weird.
You are thinking something bad,
aren't you?
It's not fair to be acting
so weird
and not tell me what it is.
Talk to me.
I'm just tired, just very tired.
Don't make excuses.
Tell me.
Okay.
Those things my father was
saying about me, about the war...
I was a prisoner, a slave,
but I was still a soldier.
God.
That's what you were
thinking about?
Not about me
or about just now...
you know, about us?
You wanted to know.
Well, the war's over.
And daddies are daddies.
They're always yelling
and saying shit.
I don't want you to think about
anything else tonight but me.
I'm sorry, but you insisted.
No way you could
really understand anyway,
there's really not.
Hey,
don't treat me like that.
I'm not some idiot.
Did you really spend
the whole war as a prisoner?
You didn't ever fight?
It depends on what you mean
by fighting.
Fighting the enemy, shooting,
jumping from foxhole to
foxhole...
not too much.
Fighting to survive
every crawling,
filthy, miserable,
horror-filled minute...
yes. Yes, I fought.
Where are you going?
I just want a cigarette.
The storm didn't last long.
They never do.
Probably way off
in the next county by now.
Camilla:
My father's a monster.
Skip: Yeah,
Daddy's a monster too.
- Skip: You watch much TV?
-  No.
- Hey, Daddy.
- Hey.
I heard you and Kingsley
are going hunting.
Yeah.
We're gonna go out...
out around Ten Mile Creek.
But it ain't hunting season.
In my places
it's always hunting season.
I'm proud of you.
How come? Wha...?
Because of how nice
you've been to Kingsley.
Yeah, well,
I hated that man for 20 years,
blamed him for ruining my life.
Yeah.
- What changed?
- Well...
it started at the funeral home
when they rolled him out
to the ambulance.
I looked at him
on that stretcher...
a strange town,
a long way from home,
just... his wife just died,
he's thinking maybe
he's fixing to die too...
and I just thought, "Well..."
"...that poor devil."
it was like
I wasn't mad no more.
What is that?
Ice tea, hon.
I made some for your grandpa.
He and Sir Kingsley
are going hunting.
Made some hot tea
for Sir Kingsley.
Want a sip of tea? Eh?
Not yet. Not yet.
I'm thirsty.
There was a Civil War battle
fought not far from here,
called the Battle of Ten Mile
Creek.
- Really?
- Yeah.
See, the Yankees
come swooping down
off the high ground,
killed just about all our boys.
You haven't brought
your dogs with you.
No. We don't need any dogs.
- Daddy.
- What, Mickey?
I'm trying to meditate.
That was Alan. He's been
tripping since last night
and this morning put some
in Grandpa's ice tea.
Why would he do that?
'Cause I told him.
I said it'd be a good idea.
Fucking dude.
Actually I've got a very funny
hunting story
about Phillip
when he was a small...
Hold on, hold on.
Hold on.
- Sorry? Beg your pardon?
- Hold on. What's...?
What's happening?
Kingsley:
How do you mean?
Yeah.
Everything feels funny.
A little wiggly.
Do you feel a little wiggly?
Jim, are you all right?
Everything's changing...
the ground,
the trees, the sky.
The leaves
like a wave.
And...
I don't have any balance.
Please tell me
that you see
that parade of trees,
the one with waving leaves
up yonder, see?
'Cause I don't know what...
I don't know what's going on
or where I'm at.
Look, look, we've got to get you
back home.
Yeah.
No, no, no, don't.
Whew.
Look, we've got to get you home.
- Let me help you up.
- No, no.
- You can kiss my ass.
- Eh?
You'll have to kill me first.
Yeah? How did you get behind...
behind our lines?
I got a whole company of men
right behind that curtain
over there, you sorry
sack of Hun shit.
Drop that weapon!
Jim, have you... have you
gone completely mad?
- Jim: Yeah.
- What?
I'm not a German, Jim.
It's Kingsley.
German Jim Kingsley...
good alias.
Is that how you got back here,
Mr. Alias?
Let me see your orders now.
Your orders.
Who won the 1916 World Series?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Boston Red Sox in six.
Ja, ja!
All right, all right. All right.
- Yeah.
- Jim, calm down. Calm down.
Who do you think you's fooling,
you cabbage head?
Open your mouth.
No, I'm... I'm English.
We fought on the same side.
But it's not the Great War now.
It's 1969.
So please, please,
please put the gun down.
Oh my God.
Kingsley: Heavens.
Jim!
Where's Daddy?
Is he back yet?
He's hunting
with the old man Bedford.
What's going on?
Alan put LSD
in Daddy's ice tea.
- He fucking what?
- Donna: Where did Alan get LSD?
Did he say
where he was going?
Yeah, they're out
along Ten Mile Creek.
Okay, come on, come on.
Let's go. Let's go.
- Get your truck.
- Lord have mercy.
Jim!
Daddy!
Hey, Daddy!
Daddy! Hey, Daddy!
- Daddy!
- Carroll: Hey, Daddy!
- Father!
- Daddy!
Y'all, shut up.
It ain't kindergarten.
Daddy!
All right, Carroll,
you go this way.
You go that way.
Carroll: Daddy!
Donna, you get your ass
over here.
- Beautiful!
- Kingsley: Jim.
I never knew it was so
beautiful.
God, it's so beautiful.
We really have to return
to the truck.
Phillip: Father!
Phillip!
- I found him!
- Jimbo: Looky here.
Hey! Come on!
Come on, Kingsley.
Jim: Get your skinny
little ass in here!
- Thank God. Are you all right?
- Yes, yes, I'm all right.
Poor Jim has completely
lost his mind.
Jim:
Uh-oh, here comes the police.
What are y'all looking at?
Phillip: What on earth
happened?
Kingsley:
I've been worried about Jim
for the last hour and a half.
Jim: Come on in.
I love it. I love it.
Jimbo: You got a 70-some-odd
year old man out there!
He could have hurt himself!
Alan: I didn't know
he was gonna be going hunting.
Jimbo: Son, he's out there
running around the woods
with a gun!
He could have killed
that goddamn Englishman!
Alan: Yeah, but he didn't, Dad.
It's okay. God.
Jimbo: Boy, it ain't about
what he didn't do!
It's about
what it could have been!
Kingsley: Oh, well.
Jimbo: What the hell
has gotten into you?
I raised you
better than this, boy.
Did you think of me?
Did you think of your mama?
What do you think
your mama's gonna think of this?
How is he?
Alan:
Exactly what I was thinking.
- About the same.
- ...you had to live with you.
According to Carroll,
it could take a long time
for the drug to wear off.
Alan: You don't ever care
about nobody but what you want.
Jimbo: Son, I'm gonna
tell you right now,
I would never do that
to my father!
I'm glad you're safe though,
Father.
Jimbo: I would never do that
to my father!
I was worried about you.
Jimbo:
How the hell could you do that?
Nothing to worry about.
I've been in tighter spots.
Jimbo: You're disrespecting me
right now!
You're gonna be
grounded forever!
- You understand?
- Phillip...
- Alan: You can't ground me.
- Jimbo: I sure as shit can!
- Last night I...
- Alan: I'll just run away!
I think I said some things
I didn't really mean.
- I didn't either, Father.
- Alan: You ain't gonna hit me!
Alan: You ain't gonna hit me!
Jimbo: You ain't too big
to spank, you understand me?
Alan: I'm going away
to Carroll's.
Let's just put it behind us
and go on.
Jimbo: You get your ass up
to that room.
Get your ass up to that...
Alan: You can't tell me
what to do!
- Kingsley: Oh, yes.
- Jimbo: I sure as shit can.
As long as you're
in this house...
- Go on.
- ...you're mine!
Alan: Well, I hate this house!
And I fucking hate you!
Jimbo: Better don't come out
till I tell you to come out!
My billfold got wet in the
creek.
Take all the stuff out,
spread it all out and dry it.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- See?
- Where is it?
It were in there.
Yeah. Just dry everything...
my license and whatnot...
and that damn letter of yours.
- I don't understand.
- What?
All these years you've been
carrying this around.
Why not say
it meant something to you?
it's not gonna kill you
to talk to your kids, Pops.
You might be surprised
what happens.
What's the matter
with your head?
Huh?
I can't!
I can't breathe!
- Daddy, Daddy.
- I can't breathe.
Daddy, it's Jimbo.
I'm right here.
- I can't breathe.
- I'm right here.
Let's get you up.
Come on.
I can't breathe.
Skip, don't just stand there.
- It's swelling me up!
- Get over here and help me.
- I can't breathe!
- Let's take him outside.
Come on.
It's pretty to look at,
but it ain't good fire though!
I can't breathe!
Motherfucker!
I can't breathe! Hey!
I can't breathe!
- Come on, Daddy.
- I can't breathe!
- Come on.
- No! I can't! I can't breathe!
- I can't breathe!
Watch that step, Daddy.
- You steady him, Skip.
- What's that?
I'm gonna go make
some more coffee.
All right.
Did you need me
to hold you up, Daddy?
Uh, hold yourself up.
Skip.
Yeah. Yeah.
You know, there was a...
there was a time
when everybody I looked at
looked like pigs
with hollowed out eyes.
And everything
was kind of yellow.
Yeah.
Is that when you was
in the war?
No, about 10 minutes ago,
or maybe it was yesterday.
I'll be darned.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hey,
you see down there
where that fence goes along
with the driveway,
looks like a big rubber band,
you know? Huh?
No, sir. I can hardly see
anything out there,
to tell you the truth.
Well, I was putting barbed wire
up along there.
You must have been
about seven or eight.
And I had you helping me.
And I got all tangled up.
I ended up falling,
getting all rolled up in it.
And it was all stuck
in my hair even,
my shirt and my pants.
And I asked you to help me
get out of it.
And you started bawling
and run off.
I said, "Why, you little shit."
And in a minute or two
you come back just hauling ass,
still crying,
with a pair of wire cutters.
I said, "God damn, Skip, I done
got wire cutters right here.
I just need you to help me
get out of this."
You...
you always...
you always panicked
when somebody got hurt.
You never could see anything
get hurt, you never did.
Yeah.
You said I was about
seven or eight?
Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- Huh?
What are you doing?
I was just kind of putting
my arm around you a little.
Well,
huh.
Feels strange.
- Yeah.
- All right.
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Are you wet?
- Wet?
- Yeah.
No, sir. I'm...
Do you feel wet?
Jimbo: if we was
Old West outlaws...
I was thinking about this
the other day...
I'd be Jesse James,
Carroll would be Pat Garrett...
Skip, you'd be Billy the Kid.
Carroll:
Pat Garrett wasn't an outlaw.
Jimbo: Yeah, he was.
He changed his mind
and he switched over.
How come I'd have to be
Billy the Kid?
Jimbo: 'Cause.
Because he was just a dumb-ass
who got lucky and killed a few.
There's this one picture of him.
I saw it.
He's lopsided.
Looks like he's licking the snot
off his nose.
What if I throw a low, hard one
down there,
bounce it up in your nuts?
How would you like that?
Jimbo: I don't think
I'd like that too much.
I was just kidding.
I'm just fucking with you.
Shit.
Carroll:
Hey, can we take a break?
'Cause I'm tired
of just standing here.
I don't know about you.
Hey.
- What?
- Hey.
Oh. One of the dogs has been
shitting on the porch.
I think it's this
damn Penelope.
Where did everybody go?
Well, Jimbo's out back
someplace there.
No, I mean,
where's the Bedfords?
Well, they left already
about an hour ago. Yeah.
- They left?
- Yeah.
Well, why didn't anybody
wake me up?
I reckon nobody
thought about it.
Good girl.
Well, what did they say?
They said, "Bye.
We had a good time,"
you know, stuff like that.
Dorothy gave them some chicken
and biscuits to eat on the road.
- Well...
- Good girl.
Did anybody say,
"Tell Donna goodbye"
- or something?
- Not that I remember, no.
No.
Well...
You're a good girl
most of the time.
Don't shit over there now.
Uh, I'd better see
what Jimbo's up to.
Okay.
Jim: Yeah.
It'll be good to get home, hmm?
Yes, Father.
Well, Skip, you finally got
some decent pussy, didn't you?
Well, maybe
I'm in love with her.
What do you think of that?
- What?
- I'm sorry, buddy.
I'm sorry, that's just funny
for some reason.
Hey...
- Nah.
- Shit, man, Daddy did acid.
- No.
- He said he figured out
everything he ever
wondered about.
Then he said that when he puked
he forgot all of it.
Hey, Jimbo,
what did you put
in Mama's casket?
I saw you put something
in there.
It's just something
between me and her.
Come on, man, what was it?
It was a letter I wrote her
and never sent her.
Boy, this shit's strong.
What?
What, you don't think
I never smoked dope before?
What do you think I am,
a caveman?
Shit.
I just don't like it.
It ain't good for me.
I start thinking
the FBI is chasing after me.
My heart starts racing so fast,
I'm worried it's not gonna stop
till I'm dead.
Hey, Jimbo, me and Carroll...
we don't care
that you never did see combat,
just so you know.
We really don't.
I mean, you're our brother
and we love you to death
and you're our flesh and blood,
you know.
And we're glad you didn't.
There ain't no reason
to be jealous about it.
You don't have any idea.
So, um...
you ought to be happy
about it.
I mean, me and Carroll's proud
of what we did and everything,
but it's a goddamn
nightmare, Jimbo.
So you ought to just let it go.
See, you can work
and sleep and be thought of
as normal.
Me and him can't, you know.
I mean, you see
how Daddy treats us.
What little sleep I get,
I wake up
thinking I'm on fire.
Now how would you like that?
God damn, buddy,
I love you to death,
but sometimes, man, you can
really fuck up a free meal.
Now what did you have
to say that for?
I mean, he was actually smoking
with us and talking to us.
Now why did you have to
say that, man?
It just felt right.
Here.
Put this on your face.
Now that's why
you'd be Billy the Kid.
He got shot when he was 21
for being too big for his
britches and not thinking.
You just need to think sometimes
before you open your mouth.
I do think, Jimbo.
No, you don't.
I try not to.
Hey, hey,
let's go get some cheeseburgers
and go hang out at my place.
Let's go.
All right.
You drive.
You shitting me?
No. Go ahead.
Carroll:
Are you sure, buddy?
Yeah.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Let's do it.
Skip: Jimbo, stop. Stop the car.
Stop the car.
God damn it.
I c... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Jimbo,
it just don't feel right.
Jimbo:
Well, God damn it, Skip.
Daddy.
Hey.
What's up?
I went to the recruiting office
yesterday
when you were over
at Grandpa's
and I joined the army.
The sergeant said they'll keep
me and Connell together.
Everybody in the family
did it, Daddy.
I saw this picture
of some guys in 'Nam
hanging out
with some palm trees,
with their shirts off
and guns slung
over their shoulders.
Looked so fucking rock 'n' roll.
I want to do
something cool, Daddy.
I don't want to rot here.
I'm 18.
I don't need your permission.