[Episode 23]
What is this...?
Have you lost your mind? Why
won't you listen to me?
What are you going to do now?
What should I do...?
I know what you want to say. Don't worry...
This is fact. Nothing about it is wrong.
Everything is now in its rightful place.
When you do the news, do it like this.
Go home first...
Ah, it's embarrassing. Embarrassing.
Ah, so embarrassing.
Ah, seriously. I'm crazy.
I'm really crazy. I'm crazy.
♪ Slowly fall a thousand stars ♪
♪ And everything, all goes by ♪
♪ Wasting all I loved ♪
Where is he going instead of going home?
♪ In a good night ♪
♪ Never ever say ♪
Mom, I can't have dinner today.
Let's do it next time.
Hey, your crazy bastard. You won't
be able to get married now.
The girl you said you're dating
right now, don't let her go.
The one who knew from the
getgo that you were sick
and stayed with you at the
hospital, don't let her go.
If you lose her, you will never...
be able to get married...
and will have to live as a bachelor...
Mom, stop it now. Don't cry.
Stop crying now.
If you break up with her, what woman would
ever agree to an arranged date with a man
who had breast cancer surgery for
a second opportunity for you?
Women would never even consider dating you.
They won't even look at
you twice as a man...
Because the whole nation knows...
so what will become of our Hwa Shin?
Mom, stop crying.
My poor pitiful child. What do I do...?
What if my son can't get married?
Who cares if I can't? I just
won't get married then.
So... stop crying, Mom.
♪ Sometimes I need you near me ♪
♪ Keep me right, keep my breath ♪
♪ Till the end of story ♪
♪ Let me wait, if you’re late ♪
♪ Till my words find your ears ♪
♪ Someday you color me anew ♪
[ Running Away While Dating Is Prohibited]
♪ Somewhere underneath the sky ♪
Look where you're going.
Hasn't Lee Hwa Shin come yet?
Ah, seriously...
It's a mess. A mess...! Ah, this kid...
What's this?
[Request for a Leave of Absence]
When did he put this here?
Oh, good. Have you contacted Hwa Shin?
You can't get a hold of him?
He disappeared without
saying a word to you?
Yes, Chief...
Okay. Go on out.
- Gosh...
♪ Everything passes ♪
♪ Although it may be a bit slow ♪
♪ I'm still at the time ♪
He told me to go home first...
Before the final college entrance exam,
part of the terminology
questions has been leaked.
With the exams right around the corner,
this comes as a shock to all the students.
Here's Reporter Kim Sung Bae.
♪ The season too which
was dazzlingly bright ♪
The customer's phone has
been turned off, so...
♪ Like a scene outside the window there ♪
I'm sorry. I thought maybe you'd know as his
friend... Is there some place he might have gone to?
I've been looking for him, too.
I'll make sure he comes back safely.
Don't worry.
Because I lost to Hwa Shin...
♪ Like the sunlight that shines on me ♪
♪ While keeping that place and shining ♪
Mr. Reporter.
♪ So that someday you can find me ♪
♪ Everything flows away ♪
♪ Maybe it will take some time ♪
♪ Like the lights outside the window ♪
♪ They keep fading away ♪
♪ They have to fade away ♪
How could you help him out with the interview
like that just because he asked you to?
He disappeared after his
broadcast was done.
He doesn't answer his calls either. Whether
he's dead or alive... Nobody knows...
Really...?
Because he was too embarrassed to keep working
as an anchor... to some place I don't know...
I think he ran away.
That day... the test results...
they all came out okay, right?
Of course, they did.
The day the results came out, did
Reporter come by himself later?
Yeah. Yeah... I told you
everything is fine.
I hope that ours is a country where
minorities can be happy, too.
Let's... break up.
The China government has decided to give about 20 million
yuan to help with Noth Korea's damage from the flood.
About 34 million won has
been offered as aid.
Due to the flood caused by Typhoon Ryan in
the North Hamgyong Province in North Korea,
over 130 people have died and nearly
400 people are currently missing.
Reporter Kim Seon Yeong
is giving you the report.
Typhoon Ryan caused considerable
damage late last month
and the river has over flown into...
Ah, that crazy punk!
Seems like you were waiting for me.
I was waiting. I was
burning up inside waiting.
Hey, grab this punk. Grab him.
This hateful kid.
You love him and hate him every 10 minutes,
this punk. Get out. Get out, you punk.
- Get out, you punk.
What the? What are we going to do with you?
Just concentrate. Don't worry about him.
This punk, get in here.
Omo, you've come back, Reporter Lee? Where
have you been and what were you doing?
- How is your health?
- No need for small talk. If you're here, do the broadcast right away.
- Huh?
- What?
- I don't want to.
- If you're not going to do the broadcast, then why did you crawl out here?
Am I not receiving a warning? I didn't come to work for
a week without saying anything. Give me a warning.
I came here to get a warning. And I don't even want
to stand in front of a camera for the time being.
So it's been a week.
- Let's break up
- Let's... break... not break up.
- Yeah.
- You've been well?
How could I have been?
Where were you and what did you do?
Just...
Of course. "Just"?
- Why aren't you eating? Come on, eat.
- Where were you and what did you do?
What were you thinking that
you disappeared like that?
I was embarrassed.
- But why did you return?
- Should I leave again?
- I like it there.
- Didn't you think about me?
- I did.
- And that's how you act?
That's why I returned after a week.
If it weren't for you, because I felt like I was going
crazy from feeling like the world was looking at my chest,
I would've gone back to Thailand already.
- Why did you keep your phone turned off?
- Isn't that the basics when it comes to disappearing?
- You must have done it a lot.
- It was my first time.
So, what's the decision you
made after disappearing?
Let's break up. [Let's break up.]
- Let's not break up.
Have you been watching me do the news?
No, I couldn't. There was no TV.
Where did you go?
Let's break up.
Let's not break up.
Of course.
What's with your hand?
It's okay. It's nothing to worry about.
Show me. Why is your hand...?
Let's break up!!!
Let's break up! Let's break up! Break up with
me! Come on, break up! Break up with me!
This selfish bastard...
Selfish bastard...
Ah, I'm glad I ran into you.
I was going to call you to my office.
You've been picked as the special
correspondent for Kenya.
- Oh, Chief!
- Stop whining.
The company's ordering you to. Hey,
You'll be able to drink Kenya AA coffee
so it's nice. It's for a year. A year.
Chief! Ah, this is crazy!
The coffee tastes good here, too...
Seriously...
Stop looking at my chest, it isn't yours.
Is that so?
So. Is it doing alright?
It's not that side.
Is that so?
Ahhh... Gosh..
You seem just fine. The
way you're acting up.
I heard you asked for a warning from Chief.
You told him you want to get a warning
- and step down from the anchor chair?
- Yes.
You have no idea that while you've been away, the viewers
have been flooding the comment boards and have been
calling the broadcasting station looking
for you and waiting for you, right?
They weren't looking for you out of curiosity and
they weren't waiting for you out of pity either.
They say they want to see you every day in that chair.
Where you've gone to, whether you've been fired,
complaint calls are still flooding in. Not only
that, the pure love between you and Pyo Na Ri,
and Reporter Lee Hwa Shin is
doing well without relapsing.
They want to see that you're healthy every single day. Do
you want to run away like a pubescent student that much?
- No way.
- Everyone is only talking about you two.
Didn't you see the placard hanging
per the president's orders?
I'm sure that very soon, the president will
properly get his money's worth out of you two.
I'm giving you up, Sunbae. It's over.
I'm not going to like you anymore.
Did a better guy appear?
I still think your chest is sexy.
And I want to work alongside you while
sitting here for a long time to come.
So be healthy.
Many companies have been found to be using Sophora instead
of the most costly lingzhi mushrooms, to make supplementary
health food containing red ginseng and Tian Ma, which can
affect the digestive system and hinder consciousness.
Let's not break up.
Let's break... not break up. Let's
not break up. Let's not break up.
Let's break up.
For a whole week, where the hell did
you go and what did you do? Here.
Mom.
What?
Let's break up.
Let us break up.
This punk, I will just...! Hey, how
can a mother and son break up, huh?!
We can't break up!
I can say it so easily to Mom.
Why can't I say it..?
Are you done with work?
No.
- Yeah.
Do you want to have dinner?
I don't want to.
- Let's.
What should we eat?
Thank you.
I said we should have some rice. Why Udon?
Oh, it's tasty. I've been craving Udon.
Can I have a glass of soju?
Since when did you ask me before you drank?
Aunty, could I have a bottle of soju, please?
Yes.
Mr. Reporter.
When Chi Yeol is done with his college
entrance exam, let's have dinner together.
But Chi Yeol doesn't like me.
That's right, he doesn't... But then
again, no matter whom I bring home,
he'll act like a father-in-law. No,
no, he'll act like a mother-in-law.
He thinks his sister is the
best in the world, so...
- Next time...
- Next time?
What next time are you talking about? You live next
door, so just treat him like your brother-in-law, okay?
Should we get together on the day he's
done with the college entrance exam?
Why? Is it because you're afraid
of Chi Yeol? But you know what?
In the scope of things, he's
still a brother-in-law.
Na Ri.
Let's break up...
- Let's break up.
Is it because you're scared
of a brother-in-law?
Why?
Is it because of you are sterile?
Is that it?
You knew about it?
Since when did you know it?
You've known but as though you didn't, you've been
watching me while having me in your palm, is that it?
Not long after you disappeared...
Slow down!
Move.
How ridiculous I must have looked...
That's good then. Let's break up.
- I don't want to.
- Let's end this.
Mr. Reporter, I'm okay even
if we don't have kids.
I'm really okay.
I only need you. And... I don't even have
the confidence to raise kids well and...
You're really good at lying.
No, I'm telling you I'm fine.
You're making a person
pitiful in an instant.
- Did you feel sorry for me?
- Don't be sorry, Reporter.
Did you pity me? Is that why you
didn't say anything and just watched?
I wanted to give you time. I figured you
would tell me in time, comfortably,
so I just waited.
I can cope with not having kids, but I can't
be without you. I can't break up with you.
I said I'm not okay with it!
This is not a problem that can be resolved
just because you say you're okay.
As long as you're understanding, is that
supposed to put me at ease? Is that it?
I... am confident I will
love you a whole lifetime,
but... whether I can make you
happy for a whole lifetime...
I keep questioning it thousands of times.
- So...
- I can't break up with you.
Let's break up.
That day, he said he was on his way to get the test results
but that it got pushed back because you had a seminar.
Huh? Right. Ah, that's what happened.
Right. That's right.
Why... are you lying to me, Doctor?
He said that you told him to come by later
because you had a surgery scheduled suddenly.
Is there... something wrong with Mr.
Reporter?
Did he relapse?
♪ Look in my eyes ♪
Right now, he probably feels very uneasy.
Just watch him from afar. He'll
probably act crazy for a while.
Don't get caught up in it and let him be.
He will overcome it. The war in his heart.
♪ Hush, you can find your stars ♪
♪ Someday in your dream ♪
♪ Yes, I know it’s not so easy ♪
♪ Yeah, but don’t you ever let go ♪
♪ I know it’s all or nothing ♪
♪ But we’ll make it all right ♪
♪ Oh, so live your life
shining like a star ♪
♪ And I’ll be your moonlight ♪
♪ Look in my eyes ♪
♪ Can you see my heartbeat? ♪
♪ Swirling everywhere I go ♪
♪ Look in my eyes ♪
♪ I’ll be right here by your side ♪
♪ So don’t you ever let go ♪
♪ Step, step, where do we go now? ♪
I have some family problems in England.
I have to go to there for a week.
Hey, what about the 9 o'clock news?
Have you lost your mind?
Hey. Do all broadcasters have to keep doing
the news even when their mother is ill?
If I'm not there when my mother passes, I don't think I'll be
able to swallow even a spoonful of food for the rest of my life.
How could I possibly eat when I'm
not even a human being?! How?!
Oh, is your mom that ill?
Ahh... Seriously...
Hey, hey. For just a week, just for a week,
couldn't we put Lee Hwa Shin in the anchor seat?
Hwa Shin?
Hey, you could get your seat permanently taken away by
Hwa Shin that way. You never know about these things.
Hey, if Hwa Shin gets a good response, do you
think the president will give you the seat back?
Please help me, Jong Hwan.
Oh, Jeez. I'm going crazy...
Tell the president about it yourself, then.
Yes. Yes. Pardon?
What do you mean, Pyo Na Ri? President...
Yes, Yes. Yes, I hear what you are saying.
But it's too soon for Pyo Na Ri, and there
are too many risks we have to watch out for.
Well, anyway, I'm against the idea of having the
two of them doing the 9 o'clock news together.
Think about it the other way around... If I couldn't
have children, you'd still ask to break up with me?
- Would you?
- Get lost.
To be honest, a marriage without
children... Yeah, I can imagine.
We could get sick of each other
with just the two of us.
Looking at a child who looks like us will
keep us going even when things get hard.
And we'll make up quickly when we
argue for the sake of the child.
We'll smile while looking at the child and
overcome our worries. It would be nice.
That's it, then.
But Reporter... I can't
even imagine a marriage
where you're not there.
When you disappeared,
everything the doctor said about us not being
able to have a child seemed pointless.
When I couldn't find you, I realized that there's
nothing more I want than just to have you by my side.
So please, Mr. Reporter... if it
isn't because you dislike me...
If it's not because you're tired of me already,
please don't ask me to break up with you.
- If you say let's break up once more...
- Let's break up.
Let's break up.
- Are you even human?
- Let's break up.
- Won't you close your mouth?
- I said, let's break up.
- That bad mouth of yours, I'll sew it up!
How can you say that so easily?
It's an easy thing for me to say.
Let's break up.
Geez... You're really a bad guy...
Reporter, it's not over. People say nothing is 100%
impossible because of advances made in medical science.
Let's just do it every day. Let's sleep
together whenever we get a chance,
and eat whatever is good for us and sleep together,
take care our bodies and sleep together,
without any burden to you, let's just
think of it as taking a really great nap.
If we don't give up,
they say it's possible.
You want just keep sleeping
together every day?
Let's make an effort together.
Ah, so pitiful... Hurry up and go home.
I will be good to you.
What if it doesn't happen even then?
- Those kinds of things, say that after we sleep together a hundred times.
- And what if it still doesn't happen?
Then... let's take a nap every time we eat one
of the noodles at my place you bought me.
- And if it still doesn't happen?
- We'll buy some more noodles.
Don't look at me like that...
I'm not marrying you. Do you
know how many noodles there are?
It's not quite a thousand.
- I'm not marrying you.
- Marry me.
Let's break up.
Let's break up!
Go.
- You're dumping me?
- Yes.
- I've been dumped?
- You're not going to regret it, right?
- Yeah.
Fine. Let's end it all.
Yeah, fine, fine. Just end it.
Let's break up. Break up.
(Let's break up.)
Hurry up and go back to your home!
Ah, I don't know.
Ah, Reporter, you're really something.
Your pride is really amazing. Geez...
You're tops in stubbornness.
You're so great.
With this, I've really
done as much as I can.
Don't feel hurt by me.
Trying to hold onto you this much,
I've really done all I can.
Don't say that you've been hurt by me
behind my back. Don't even criticize me!
- Oh, fine, let's just forget it. Forget it.
- I told you to leave.
- Just forget it.
- You'll freeze to death.
Just forget everything!
Mr. Reporter, since it's the last
time, do you want to have some ramen?
- Last time?
- Yeah.
- No thanks.
- Do you not like that it's the last time or that it's ramen or do you not like the nap?
Okay, let's forget this.
Forget it. Just forget it. Forget
everything. Forget it all!
Aren't you going already?!
We broke up, so don't worry about me.
Just go in and sleep.
Noona.
What are you doing there?
You saw, didn't you? Your sister was drinking
and creating a scene and clinging onto me.
Get rid of your sister from here.
What did you say?
How dare you say "get
rid of" about a woman?
Hey!
Get over here already!
Are you off to work?
Are you... going somewhere?
Yes, I have some matters to attend to so...
Ah, then see you at the
hotel in the evening.
What are you doing at a
hotel in the evening?
We'll have to see...
Going to hotels already...
Be careful that people don't start talking.
You just need to keep your mouth shut.
Seems like you'll have to eat dinner alone.
I figured, so I made you your
favorite dish, codfish soup.
Don't eat just whatever just because
you are alone. Eat properly, hmm?
Heat it up before you eat. You
know how to heat it up, right?
I don't know!
I hate that you're dating. I'm bored.
I feel like you're being
taken away from me, by Chef.
Hey... how can you say such a thing?
I'm not going to reheat it and eat it. I
don't know how to reheat it. I'm not eating!
How can someone change!?
Hey, I'm finally starting to date after
500 years. Help me out, would you?
Hey, Hwa Sin and Pyo Na Ri, you
two do the 9 o'clock news.
Why? I don't want to work with her.
It's the president's orders.
Just do well for a week.
Reporter Gye probably won't let it happen.
The president said to try putting the two
of you together as temporary replacements.
Recently you two made news, so he thought we might
get good ratings. Happy now? You want me to go on?
We can't.
I'm not asking you, this is an order.
How come you only think about yourself?
It's a good opportunity for Pyo Na Ri.
This is a good chance for her to recover
after ruining the election broadcast.
Also, Reporter Gye said she doesn't want to do it
with you. She said she's taking a break for a week.
I will try my best. Thank you
for giving me the opportunity.
I said we can't do this, Chief.
Leave.
You won't be able to get
married at this rate.
Why?
If you do the 9 o'clock news with me,
people who didn't know will find
out about our relationship.
Nothing good can come out of this. The
broadcasting company is just using us.
To get more viewers.
It's not because you think I'm still not good
enough even for a week as temporary replacements?
I'm going to do my very best
even if it's for a week.
I'm sure you will.
It's too soon for you.
If you're in a too visible of a place,
you'll get even more arrows flying at you.
What I'm saying is, it could
be dangerous for you.
Maybe because I've never been in a safe position before,
I don't feel that afraid when you say it's dangerous.
- It's not a joke.
- The same goes for me.
We broke up.
You act like it's for my sake that
you don't want to get married.
And you're telling me not to be
the 9 o'clock anchor either?
Why did you become such a scaredy-cat?
Why are you such a coward?
Me having breast cancer, being sterile...
Don't forget it.
Are you stupid? Think about it again.
Why have you turned into a scaredy-cat?
Why have you become a coward?
I won't ever be your replacement.
You know I'm doing the morning news, right? You can't
come back since I won't give you the seat back.
Good luck.
Okay. Thank you all. Geez.
It's unlike you to act so pitiful.
Do you know why I'm not doing
the 9 o'clock news with you?
You met me first when I was a high schooler, so you'll
always see me as a high schooler, Sister-in-law.
Correct.
How can I do the 9 o'clock
news with a high schooler?
Oh, don't be so down.
Do you think I don't
know what you're up to?
Not just for a week, but
forever, here, in this spot,
you're trying to take over the seat, right?
You think it's a good opportunity, right?
Isn't that obvious?
Not just me but for anyone else, through
this kind of opportunity a star is born.
Ah, don't worry. My sister
can't win against me.
Oh... Can I... go to the
bathroom for a bit...?
Yeah. Yes, go ahead.
Hey, it's the first broadcast
so keep the tension.
[SBC 9 pm Hotline News]
10 seconds left.
9, 8, 7, 6...
Opening line, cue!
Though the world can't change the news,
the news can change the world.
This is SBC News Hotline. I am Lee Hwa Sin.
I am Pyo Na Ri.
- It's to the point.
- Yeah. Okay. Okay.
What kind of woman could
have cured your asexuality?
I'm so excited and curious
that I ran all the way here.
She's younger, right?
Yes, she is. She's younger than you.
Sunbae.
Hey, Bang Ja Yeong! What
are you doing here?
Sister, say hello to her. To me, she's
the sexiest woman in this world.
It's been estimated that the daily wage of
former CEO of the "D" Group, Kang Yong Jae,
who went to jail over tax evasion
and refusing to pay fines
is 4,000,000.
Every time he works 7 hours,
from 38,000,000 of fine,
4,000,000 won is written off each time.
- A normal wage...
- Could he be digging up diamonds at his labor house?
Hey, hey, Hwa Shin! What is he
trying to add on now? Don't do it!
Even if he doesn't work on weekends and
on national holidays, he still gets paid.
At this rate, it looks to be a
very lucrative part-time job.
Hey, Pyo Na Ri! Step in! Step in!
A normal wage for labor
for a criminal is 30,000.
So if you're to pay off 38,000,000 in fines,
it'll take more than a hundred years.
At the very least in consideration for our citizens
who work hard every day while paying their taxes,
former CEO, Kang Yong Jae,
- please keep folding those shopping bags diligently.
- Hey, Hwa Shin! Are you crazy! Why are you doing this?!
Your department stores' bags
should be an exception, no?
This concludes the SBC News Hotline.
Why do you always do this when I'm PD?
Do this to other PDs on another
live show, you bastard!
Have a restful night.
Thank you for your efforts.
You still think I'm a scaredy-cat?
Should I be punished?
Hey. Although it's refreshing,
go easy, would you?
While scratching that itch,
you could bleed instead.
Hey, Hwa Shin, at this rate, D Group's
department store will pull out all their ads.
Aish, you're asking to get fired
on your first day, you bastard.
If I get fired, I'll just
go fold some shopping bags.
Well done. Good job.
This is new bedding.
Yes, it's new, but you have to wash
them still, right? I'll be going now.
- Yes, goodbye.
- Yes.
Why are you following me?
Oh, it arrived.
What's all this?
This is the rice cooker we picked together.
This is the iron I bought that
time to iron your shirts.
And this is our bedding.
It's brand new but it's been laundered,
so we can use it right away. Right away.
You said forget it. You said you
were going to forget it all.
I'm leaving.
You didn't buy the rice
cooker for yourself?
No. Our rice cooker's lid is a little loose, but I
can't throw it away because it was my mother's.
I think I can use it for
another ten years or so.
Let's break up.
These are all things you don't have at
home. You came without a winter blanket.
Let's use it as we live together.
This is all of my dowry.
Don't expect anything more.
I won't marry you.
You won't?
Really? Then forget it. I'm going.
Ah, then what am I
supposed to do with this!?
So, I told you I'd make rice for you
with this, and iron your shirts,
and use this to nap with you!
Are you a tick?
Mr. Reporter, I'm a woman who had
a crush on you for three years.
On top of that, while liking each other
I've even accepted your marriage proposal
and I just got notified to break up.
To break up... I think it'll take
me at least... thirty years.
I'll break up with you
after thirty years, okay?
Why are you being so foolish? Seriously.
Boo Yoo Group's President Choi Jeong Goo has been
charged with 1,700,000,000 won worth of charges.
Under the Additional Punishment
Law on Specific Crimes...
Alright, let's do the closing!
Booyoo Group fired most of its permanent workers
in this past year citing an operating deficit.
Right now, they're only hiring
temporary workers. This situa...
"Boo Yoo Group will be with you until
the day you are rich in mind and body."
Hey, hey. There he goes again. Stop. Stop!
Stop! Lee Hwa Sin, stop!
I guess it was only up to the day in which President
Choi became wealthier rather than the citizens.
This concludes the News Hotline.
Thank you for tuning in.
The news itself is fun to watch, but Hwa
Shin's position is becoming unstable...
Am I still cowardly now?
[Thank you everyone for watching.]
Why do you keep butting in without a warning? I feel like
I'm going to die from a heart attack because of you.
Hey, is it anything new that a Korean
Chaebol is found guilty of tax evasion?
I told you clearly before
we started, didn't I?
When you talk about Boo Yoo
Group's President Choi's arrest,
I told you to do it dryly without any emotion and
just deliver the facts. Did I or didn't I, you punk?!
What? Dryly? Let go.
Am I a dryer?
Without emotion... Am I a robot? Do I
have to just read it like some parrot?
- You said you'd let me say what I wanted in closing!
- Right.
Seeing President Choi's conduct, I just can't only deliver
the facts dryly like a robot! What do you want me to do?!
You didn't have me sit here just to
behave like a tongue inside a mouth!
You know I'm not telling you to
I'm saying not to act like a thorn
stuck inside a mouth, you punk!
You'll get your tongue pulled out at that
rate. Are you dying to have it pulled out?
Are you happy that you got to spew out whatever you
want? You think the viewership will go up? Who cares?
Tomorrow morning, everyone will create chaos while pulling
out their ads! Who's going to take the responsibility?!
If you keep this up... Hwa Shin... You...
A little... Ah, seriously...
Beom.
Give me a bite of that bun.
Just one bite.
Wow, you're so stingy.
Brother-in-law,
Brother-in-law, just one bite of your bun.
Thanks.
You're not even saying hello. Huh?
Reporter, I'm really curious. Where
did you go during that week?
What did you eat that you
say only what you want to?
[Lee Joong Shin]
How did you know?
You think I came knowing you'd be here?
I looked everywhere,
and just barely found you here.
I guess... I like you more than Pyo Na Ri.
Are you confessing your love to me?
I...
used to think that I was a pretty lonely guy. But after
seeing you from behind leaving the broadcasting station,
I realized that you're lonelier than me.
I realized you're not the person
I thought you were anymore.
How big your love is... How
sincere it is, I saw it.
You taught me what it means to give up.
I'm going to see you as if I were meeting
a new friend. I can do that, can't I?
I hung out with my brother and a friend.
A friend, who?
A new friend.
Mr. Reporter, though we're doing the 9 o'clock
news together we haven't had a company dinner yet.
Let's have a get-together, the two of us.
Didn't we break up?
Yeah, exactly. So let's do it
as 9 o'clock news partners.
Because we haven't even had one
get-together, we're out of sync and a mess!
- Who said it's a mess?
- I did!
There's a lot I have pent up because
of you. Let's have a get-together.
You haven't had dinner yet. If you want
some stew, then let's go to my place, huh?
Forget it.
Oh, really.
[Chief's office]
It's the president.
Ah, yes, President.
What are you doing?
What are you doing!?
How much advertising did Reporter
Lee Hwa Shin lose up to now?
Stop him from doing any more broadcasting and send him to the
employees' children's kindergarten as a maintenance staff!
Let's eat, Mr. Reporter.
It's delicious.
A compliment? Let's see.
Whenever it's bland to me, you say it tastes good. Okay,
I got it, I'll make it like this for you in the future.
Reporter, you know what? We don't
need a child. There's already one.
Hwa Shin will be raised by Pyo Na Ri.
Shut your mouth.
- If I shut my mouth how am I supposed to eat?
- Then open it only when you're eating.
Are we really breaking up over this?
Yeah.
You really don't change your mind...
Also, when you do the news, watch your expressions
and stop being so cautious because of me.
But you make me that way! Please
watch how you say things!
Did you hear that that department store pulled
their ads? At this rate, you'll get fired soon!
Got it. Got it. Got it. Alright. Just eat.
Let's talk about work after we're
done eating. That's enough.
Don't you ever forget it. Anchors
should only care about the viewers.
If you care about anyone else, then viewers won't trust
you. It's the end for an anchor if you have no trust.
Ah, so unlucky, seriously. Always
around the dinner table...
- Before, you used to say that I was cool whenever I said things like this.
- I did?
You didn't mean what you said? Huh?
It was written all over your eyes, nose, mouth,
and forehead that you thought I was cool.
But now what? Unlucky?
I did? Was I that blind?
Ah, this... Seriously...
I guess you don't like being called
unlucky even though we're breaking up.
Have some anju. (snacks eaten with alcohol)
The things I hate the most
in this world are anchovies.
Even if you hate it, have some.
It's good for your breast.
I don't want to.
You really don't listen, do you?
Why should I listen to you when
I don't even listen to my mom?
Listen to your mom and
me too from now on then!
- What?
- When you're doing news, too,
how you can you butt in without a
signal whenever I read my lines?
Do you know how much it shocks
me everytime it happens?
- That is...
- Are you a reckless driver? A newbie driver?
You would be the newbie and
I'd be the reckless one.
Whether a newbie or reckless,
they're equally dangerous.
A reckless driver will probably get into a huge accident
over his ego while trusting his own driving skills.
A newbie would be better. They'd be more
careful and wouldn't cause a big accident.
If you look at it this way, you're
way worse than Reporter Park!
What's? How dare you compare
me to that bastard?!
What? I am worse? Where am I worse? How am
I worse? Does that make sense right now?
Even if Reporter Park
disrespects his partner...
at least he didn't butt in every time I do
my lines and say whatever was on his mind.
Every time I'm on with you I'm so nervous that
I feel like I'm going to get a heart attack.
I told you not to do it in the first place!
Because I didn't think you could handle it, I
told you not to do it. Did I or didn't I?!
Why should I not do it?! You (informally) should be
thinking about how to work well with your partner instead!
- You?
- Are you a dictator?!
- Shut your mouth.
- Are you a tyrant?!
- Hey, shut it!
- Do you think being a reckless driver makes you cool?!
♪ Kiss... Kiss... ♪
Noona~
What to do? This is terrible!
It's Chi Yeol. Chi Yeol...
You're scared of Chi Yeol, right?
Hurry up. Hide. Hide!
Why... Why should I hide?
It's not working. Why isn't it opening?
I said we should fix it. Ah, seriously.
Noona!
You're drinking by yourself?
Huh? Yeah...
Hey, you said you were going to the library
with Dae Goo. Why are you home already?
I left the library key.
How can you forget that?
Get your act together.
- Hurry up and go to bed!
- Okay.
I want to be alone, really.
I've been having a hard time these days...
- I'm going.
- Fighting!
Mr. Reporter, sorry. Sorry.
Are you alright? Huh?
Sorry. Sorry.
Hold on, look at me. Why
did you kiss me earlier?
Because you were driving me
crazy, to shut you up I...
We can kiss even though we're breaking up?
I don't know.
Do you want to sleep with me?
Sleep with me...
Really... Are you really okay?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Is it... okay that we can't have children?
I said it's okay!
No...
Just trust me.
No, no!
I'll be responsible for you.
- No, no, no, no...
♪ Why don't you think about ♪
Why do you keep saying no!? Geez... ♪ Me
and you and me and you, What about us? ♪
Wait. Mr. Reporter, help me with this.
Why did you wear something like this?
Why is it so tight?
♪ Why don't you think about me? ♪
♪ Me and you and me and you ♪
♪ What about us? (What about us?) ♪
♪ Why don't you think about ♪
No, no, no...
Are you going to keep saying no?
♪ You're all mine ♪
- Could I... really make you happy?
♪ That's all mine (That's all mine) ♪
Quit playing so hard to get.
♪ You're all mine (You're all mine) ♪
- Marrying... I'm not going to marry you...
- Lee Hwa Shin, raise your arms.
♪ You're all mine (You're all mine) ♪
- Huh?
- Raise your arms like you're cheering for Korea's independence, I said.
♪ Mon, Tue, Wed, Thur,
Fri, Sat, Sun, everyday ♪
♪ You're all mine (You're all mine) ♪
I'm not going to marry you...
I'm not marrying you...
Don't be ridiculous. Hurry
up and take this off.
- Do something!
- I'll, I'll take it off.
♪ You're all mine, yes, all mine ♪
♪ That's all mine ♪
♪ You're all mine (You're all mine) ♪
- It's embarrassing! So embarrassing! Embarrassing!
♪ That's all mine (That's all mine) ♪
Don't wear turtlenecks. I won't either.
It's too hard to take off.
Did you win or did I lose?
We're even...
♪ You who have waited stubbornly forever ♪
♪ You who have endured
for a very long time ♪
♪ Now you are the person within me ♪
♪ Loving for part of a minute and ♪
♪ Receiving love for part of a day ♪
You can't disappear anymore.
♪ Will I like it like this? ♪
♪ Will if be as good as I want? ♪
And you have to eat anchovies well.
♪ The feeling is gradually intensifying ♪
♪ And there are many things I want to do ♪
And we have to sleep well, too...
♪ Shall we delay romance a little? ♪
♪ In the fall, warm coffee ♪
♪ In the winter, oh a romantic Christmas ♪
♪ I want to be together with you ♪
♪ as we are today ♪
♪ Oh! Wish of wish of wish ♪
♪ Just as we are today ♪
♪ We who have ended only
jealousy and envy ♪
♪ Hope we won't become that way ♪
♪ Because it's too nice now ♪
♪ We are becoming more and more alike ♪
♪ We are gradually learning
about each other ♪
♪ Love everyday everyday ♪
[Jealousy Incarnate Preview]
You really want to get married?
I want to live with you
as soon as possible.
You're here, Brother-in-law?
If you act carelessly with
my sister, I'll kill you!
Do you have any money saved up?
Have you ever presided before?
Did you hear he's being sent to be a
maintenance staff at the kindergarten?
Why aren't you letting me resign?
You must be happy.
You really don't think you can
work at the kindergarten?
♪ Just as we are today ♪