THE JEW SÜSS
A Film by Veit Harlan
Script by Veit Harlan, Wolfgang
Eberhard Möller and Ludwig Metzger
Production Design:
Otto Hunte, Karl Vollbrecht
Cinematography: Bruno Mondi
Sound: Gustav Bellers
Starring:
The events in this film
are based on historical facts.
Following the tragic demise
of my father, Duke Eberhard Ludwig,
the rule of this blessed land
has passed into my hands.
At this time, I wish to commit myself
to my people by oath.
I ask the Council
to read out the oath.
As a sign of my vow, I place my hand
upon the constitution of this land.
"We, Prince Karl Alexander,
Duke of Württemberg,
Imperial Field Marshall
and former Governor of Serbia,
swear by God Almighty
to care for our subjects „well-being
with the utmost devotion.
We promise, by this solemn oath,
to ensure that our rule shall,
in all manner and true form,
adhere to the honesty and faith
that are Württemberg custom.
We solemnly vow
to uphold the constitution,
and, true to the constitution,
together with the Council,
to maintain the leadership
of the Dukedom."
I swear it!
All of my thoughts
They are with you
You, my one and only
Never leave me
For you, you, you
To be thinking of me
That would be my greatest wish
Darling
I wish to never leave you
Thank you.
Dorle!
Father!
Come on, Dorothea,
to the dinner table! Quick!
I have to be in the castle
in an hour.
Anew notebook?
"All of my thoughts..."
That’s lovely!
"To my dear bride Dorothea Sturm
on the day of our beloved
Duke Karl Alexander’s coronation
from her loving and loyal Faber."
The goose will be burnt.
We’ve waited for you for too long.
Don’t complain, Dorothea.
It was a stirring ceremony.
Our little household
can wait a bit on this occasion.
Give your bridegroom a leg.
Give me a leg.
Lovely crisp skin!
This is my favorite Sunday dinner.
So, to whom do we drink?
To Faber? May I?
Faber? Faber is not so important.
None of us are that important.
So, to whom do we drink today?
Dorothea, today...?
To our Duke.
Karl Alexander.
May God guide him safely.
My Duchess!
You get your present later.
Come, your people are calling for you.
My people! My land!
Württemberg, the most blessed land
among the Germans.
COINS AND JEWELRY
Go. I don’t want you to be seen
in the Jewish Quarter.
Yes.
I’m looking for Mister Oppenheimer.
He’s expecting Your Excellency.
What’s that goyish-looking prig
doing at Oppenheimer's?
What a question!
You mean he needs money?
No.
But he won’t give him any.
Yes, he will, and plenty.
He should give it to him,
so we can take, take, take.
Put something on, Rebecca.
I think Württemberg is rich.
Württemberg is, but not its Duke.
Well, I’ll see.
Fabulous!
Fabulous, really fabulous!
But too much for us.
Too much for a duchess?
Fabulous! Wonderful!
I don’t even dare ask
how much it costs.
50,000 talers.
As I said, my Duke doesn’t have
that much money.
Fine. Ten?
What about the remaining 40,000?
We’ll make a deal.
What about the 40,000?
We’ll settle it somehow.
When? Where?
In Stuttgart.
You know well enough
that no Jews may enter Stuttgart.
Tell your Duke that if he needs me,
he should arrange a permit
for me to come to him.
When you come to Stuttgart,
perhaps I could help you,
but you cannot enter the city gates
with your papers.
Then lift the ban on Jews.
Me?
Not even the Duke may do that.
He could, but only
with the Council’s agreement,
and they won’t let in any Jews.
If His Highness
wants to do business with me,
Your Excellency will find ways
and means to arrange my papers
so that I shall have
no difficulties at the border.
Say, I send you such a passport.
Anyone could tell you’re a Jew.
By the side curls and clothes,
you mean?
Don’t worry, I’d fix my appearance.
Send the papers,
and the Duke gets his jewels.
But only if I deliver them
to him in person.
All right.
But it’s urgent.
The Duke needs the jewels.
Rely on Süss Oppenheimer,
Your Excellency. Good-bye.
Are you mad, Joseph?
You want to cut your beard and side
curls and change your clothing.
Have you no fear of our Rabbi?
I shall open the door for all of you!
You’ll wear velvet and silks,
tomorrow or the day after.
That day will surely come.
That’s what I was afraid of
the whole time!
What a road!
Hell!
Don’t swear.
I must get to Stuttgart tonight.
If we had only gone a bit slower,
you would be there!
Is anyone hurt?
Thank goodness, no.
But you did take a spill.
The road is in bad condition.
How long does it take to get
to Stuttgart from here?
An hour.
An hour?
Would it be terribly impolite
to ask you to take me part of the way?
Why does the Duke need a ballet,
an opera house?
And for God’s sake, what is the need
for a bodyguard? He’s safe here.
Gentlemen, I agree with you
that our Duke’s demands
from our State Council
are exorbitant.
I am also of the opinion
that we are used to simple living,
and that our constituents
would not understand us
if we consent to our Duke’s demands.
But, gentlemen,
nor do we want to be petty.
The Duke was a great general
and needs soldiers around him.
Let him have his bodyguard.
All right, let him keep his guards.
But no opera or ballet.
I’d like to emphasize
that we’re bowing to him,
contrary to our convictions.
As we saw yesterday, he presented
new and even higher demands.
We only make it harder
on ourselves if we consent.
Even the guard should be refused him.
You don’t have a sense of humor.
All right, Faber. Count the votes.
You know my stand.
Mister Oppenheimer? Of Frankfurt?
- Mister Oppenheimer?
- Oppenheimer.
Your papers are in order.
If I could, I’d like to travel
all over the world.
You have surely traveled.
Have you been to Paris? Versailles?
I envy you. Where else?
London, Vienna, Rome,
Madrid, Lisbon.
My goodness!
That’s almost the whole world.
Which one was the nicest place?
I mean, where did you feel
most at home?
At home?
Everywhere.
Everywhere?
Have you no homeland?
I do. The world.
Nonsense. You must have felt
happiest somewhere.
As happy as I am here now
in Stuttgart, sitting next to you,
as happy as now,
I have never felt in my entire life.
Rejected?
Yes, Your Highness.
Seven votes to four.
I get no opera?
No, Highness.
Nor any ballet.
What? No ballet?
And no guard either?
No, Your Highness.
I think I was treated better
even in Belgrade, as governor.
Oh, the Councilmen!
The Councilmen think
that Your Highness" ancestors
didn’t need a bodyguard, either.
- In the Constitution...
- The Constitution is none of...
Perhaps another discussion
with the Councilmen is called for.
The Councilmen! I’d rather be bound
to a golden jackass.
That’s a Jew, that
Mister Oppenheimer of Frankfurt.
If I can ever be of service to you,
I’d be delighted to reciprocate
the kindness of your gentle daughter.
They let him through the city gates
without question.
I was right. He is a Jew!
Sir, I would advise you
not to miss the next coach.
Why? I am in no hurry.
I have business in Stuttgart.
On the contrary,
could you recommend a good inn?
There are no inns for Jews
within Stuttgart’s city limits.
I compliment your awareness.
But I am so obliged to the damsel,
she would understand
if I don’t comment.
Ask him already how much
the necklace costs.
Your Highness shouldn’t trouble
himself about business matters.
I am delighted to be of service
to Your Highness.
- Yes, but everything has a price.
- The Jew is waiting.
So? Yes, should a Jew be more
generous than my Councilmen?
They apparently don’t know
how to treat a great personality.
And you do?
I think I do.
For example, I don’t understand
why the Council denies you a ballet.
I just cannot grasp it.
With Your Highness" permission,
I’d consider myself fortunate
were an arrangement reached
whereby Your Highness
would actually... The ballet, I mean,
I’d consider myself fortunate
to be allowed to say
that I am Your Highness"
loyal servant.
Remchingen, interrupt the rehearsal
and bring me the little
black-haired one.
Süss, I need some small trinket.
I have nothing else on me right now
but this little...
- One day you’ll present your bill.
- Why the aggravation, sir?
Württemberg is such a blessed land,
and you sound as if not one taler
could be squeezed of the state.
Asia’s riches would pale
when the authorities realize
what sources lie in Württemberg.
But, my God, they do not!
Who does not what?
- I think...
- So what?
With your permission, Your Highness,
I can’t understand
how out of 400 villages and 70 cities
that no more money can be had.
Money? How?
For you or perhaps for me?
Highness, do you want to know
what you owe the Jew?
352,000 talers. Exactly.
So what?
Should I pay that?
Your Highness,
I did not demand a thing.
Your demands shall be fully met.
I don’t take gifts from Jews.
Of course not.
I know civilized people pay debts.
You could seize what I have.
Seize? No!
Oh, Your Highness!
Pardon?
What does Your Highness possess?
How rude! I possess Württemberg.
Not bad. Württemberg.
Do you want to have Württemberg,
and I should take it seriously?
That was only a joke.
I ask of Your Highness,
only if you want to pay...
Your Highness could also hang me.
I am only a Jew.
What? What should I give you?
Give me the roads of Württemberg.
The roads of Württemberg?
What for?
Lease me the roads of Württemberg
for 10 years.
Let me manage them.
They are in terrible condition.
It’s high time they be repaired.
I'll keep the road and bridge taxes
and give Your Highness
the tolls collected at the town gates
through which the roads go.
Slow down.
In this way, Your Highness meets
his promises, I make money,
and no one gets hurt.
The roads!
And what will my Swabians
say to that?
What should they say?
Should they transport
their grain free of charge
on the roads and over the bridges?
Every bridge and road has cost much
and should produce income.
If this were no Jew...
Why? Does not the Kaiser Leopold
in Vienna have a money-making Jew?
Does he not have his Isaac
Oppenheimer? Is he not strong?
Power is money.
This is crazy!
I've paid in four villages already!
I’ve paid in four villages already!
At two bridges,
that makes six talers tax.
Now you want one more.
The whole load is worth only 20!
Here comes the tax collector.
Complain to him.
What happened?
They’re all complaining.
What about?
If I have to pay seven more talers...!
Don’t shout. You don’t know
how to make calculations.
How much do you take for your grain?
Fifteen per hundred.
Fifteen per hundred?
Speak German! Fifteen percent.
Listen, till now you made a 15 percent
profit on 20 talers. How much?
Three talers.
Today you may make 15 percent
on 27 talers. That’s?
4.25! That’s plus 1.25 for yourself.
Right? For each taler the Duke takes,
you make a profit!
If tomorrow bread prices double,
you make double the profit.
So, go thank the Duke.
- But...
- No buts!
Pay! Pay! Learn how to reckon!
Father, meat prices have gone up,
vegetables, everything!
I used to pay one coin.
Now I pay three.
First the meat, now bread.
Oh, children, children!
And eggs! it’s not the end.
And the one to blame for all this,
you brought into town!
Don’t speak so harshly to me.
The Duke has exceeded his authority.
He’s collecting by force the guard
funds that we refused him.
I like the Duke,
but there’s a limit to everything!
It won’t turn out well.
That’s frightening,
what you’re saying!
Are you afraid of Jews, Dorothea?
Yesterday I saw a Jew, Levy,
riding from gate to gate,
and from bridge to bridge,
and inspecting every post,
collecting the Württemberg
farmers" money
and sticking it in his filthy bag!
Calm down.
This is pointless.
The Jew did, in fact,
buy the Duke his guard,
and that is stronger than you,
my child. We must be wise.
We’ll never be as wise as the Jews.
Much wiser!
The Jews aren’t wise.
They’re just clever.
So, you don’t want to pay
the 80 talers?
Get the wife and kid away from here.
I don’t have 80 talers.
But the road is mine.
I bought it from the Duke,
paid for it.
The house is not on the road.
The road circles the house.
That’s right!
Excuse me, may I?
The road circles here,
but it goes in a circle,
because people used to circle it.
Originally, it was straight.
Is there a stream or hill there
forcing the road to circle them?
No! But your house is there.
That’s why the road is crooked.
Why is your house in the road?
The smith shop always...
By the road, not in it.
All right, let it be in it,
but then this bit of the road
must belong to you, as well.
If it doesn’t, you must buy it.
All right, Levy, all right.
But I won’t sell to the blacksmith.
I just wanted to be nice to him.
But the idea of possession
was misunderstood.
Possession?
Blacksmith, whatever stands
on your land is yours, no?
Of course.
And whatever stands on mine,
whose is it?
- What is that supposed to mean?
- A part of your house is mine.
And I'll tear that part down
because I don’t want it there.
I don’t want a house on my road.
But half of the house is on the ground
that your secretary marked.
It’s our smith shop! It’s our living!
Your rebel should have thought
of that before, dear Madame.
Half a house, cute as a toy!
It looks like a doll’s house!
It will stand there like that
for a whole year,
so people will start to think
whether they can afford
to resist the Financial Advisor,
even if his name is Oppenheimer.
You’re so clever! But evil!
Look at the Jew!
Just look at this exploiter of people!
Keep going!
- There are people in the way!
- Drive over them!
Arrest him! Arrest this man
immediately! He’s a murderer!
Get going!
To simply order the officials
to send in their daughters...
Isn’t it an honor?
Honor? It’s a scandal!
But I’m no longer a child.
I know how to behave properly.
Shut up! Don’t give me
such answers, know-it-all!
Don’t spoil their fun. They aren’t
always invited by the Duke.
By the Duke?
It’s the Jew who invited them.
Once again, the Jew has organized
a meat-market,
and our daughters are good enough
to be the merchandise.
Gentlemen to the left,
ladies forward!
Primitive natures would think this is
fun, but for me it’s too conservative.
I didn’t send my wife away
to Ludwigsburg for this.
Where is your fantasy, Jew?
Note the order, Your Highness.
In the back are the old ladies,
in front, the juicy ones,
and the tender things, opposite
your bodyguard, Your Highness.
Patience, Your Highness.
Don’t spoil our surprise.
Close off this section, jackass!
We should make a room here.
I thought that, instead of
the court thistles, just once
you’d enjoy the spring blossoms
on your own.
What this devil thinks up!
Like a shepherd tending sheep,
I separate daughters
from their parents.
Control yourself, Faber!
We’re at court!
This is no court!
It’s a pigsty!
Faber, you’ll get in trouble.
Many young ones.
A thousand niceties.
Frederika and Mina Fibelkorn.
Both just under 18.
Real wild roses...
But, maiden, why so shy?
Show the Duke your nice legs.
She’s crying.
Don’t cry, maiden.
Why should you cry?
Would you teach your old master
to dance?
May I invite the Damsel?
I don’t dance, Financial Advisor.
Would you not obey your Duke?
My Duke?
Who else?
Stay outside the door.
Surely you didn’t expect
to see me here so soon.
I wouldn’t have wanted to.
Why is this pretty mouth so serious?
Actually I had hoped to see you
laughing, as you did on the road.
This is no dance!
Hot lips, cold heart.
Isn’t that so?
Or can your heart fulfill
what your mouth promises?
Don’t!
Would the damsel care to dance?
Not anymore!
Where are you going?
I’m looking for my father.
- Dance with me!
- Pardon!
Will the damsel care
to dine with me?
No, she won’t.
My child is going home.
I see.
Are impertinences accepted,
or won’t she be allowed some fun?
Excuse me, if you please.
What’s your name, little one?
Mina Fibelkorn.
Are you afraid of me?
No.
Come on, don’t be a bore.
I go along.
Queen.
King wins!
I bring you luck, my angel.
I could use some,
with this money monger.
You’re throwing a lot of money
away here. Honest earnings?
What is that to you, brother?
- I’m no brother of yours!
- Ace! I go along.
Jack is trump.
That lovely money!
You are so at ease with it,
as if you don’t know
how hard it is to earn it.
Money has no smell.
Even the ancient Romans knew that.
Should I be holier
than the Roman emperor?
Jack, Queen, King!
Three times!
Nice sound.
A nice lot, you are!
Choking in money!
It’s all blood money!
Blood money?
And a Jew plays with it?
He gambles for Württemberg!
A Jew plays for your daughters,
and the Duke holds the bank!
You insult the Duke!
That will cost you your life!
- You must catch me first, Jew!
- You rebel!
Unmask yourselves! Hebrews!
The ass!
My heart is pounding like crazy!
Whoever insults me insults the Duke!
There is still some difference.
Don’t make such a fuss.
- Pour me a drink!
- Your Highness...
Please consider that as long
as Jews are forbidden entry,
any vagabond is free
to insult your minister.
All right, then, have your wish.
I allow Jews to enter Stuttgart.
Is this law?
If I say it, it is law.
Thank you, Your Highness.
But if I am Your Highness"
loyal servant...
Is this not enough for you?
Not me, Your Highness.
If I am to be successful,
Your Highness,
I must have a document
ensuring our safety.
- A document?
- Yes.
One stating that all my actions
are on behalf of Your Highness
and wished by Your Highness,
and that in any case
I have Your Highness" protection.
Really, this is the worst impudence
I have ever encountered.
So Your Highness thinks a Stuttgart
citizen should go unpunished
after attacking your Financial Advisor
with a hammer?
Who did this?
The blacksmith Hans Bogner.
The blacksmith Hans Bogner
shall be hung.
Don’t you feel ill, Süss?
Have no fear.
I have the Duke’s letter
ensuring our safe conduct.
Jews'whore!
Did you hear that, Joseph?
Watch out, Jew! You’re next!
Arrest him!
You have enough enemies, Joseph.
They can’t hang me
higher than that Hans Bogner.
You think so,
Mister Financial Advisor?
Jews are moving into town
by the hundreds. People are wild.
They’re coming in like locusts.
Oppenheimer levies all taxes.
The Jew has got his hand
on money, on salt, on beer,
on wine, even on grain.
Also our wives and daughters.
Get a hold on yourselves.
Has the complaint been lodged?
The Duke has outlawed
any written complaint.
He can’t. He took an oath
under the constitution.
You’ll scorch your mouths,
honored sirs.
We’d rather do that
than feel our blood boil!
Our mouths are our own,
but our blood is our children’s blood!
- Announce me to the Duke!
- Now?
- Announce me.
- He’s asleep!
Then wake him up.
- Your Excellency.
- I must see His Highness.
It’s impossible.
I saved his life once.
Don’t act so important.
I’m sure the Duke hasn’t forgotten
his great debt, Your Excellency.
That’s right.
Brothers!
It’s good that you came.
Bring us wine.
Let’s have a drink.
Well, what is it then?
My Duke, I come in the name
of the Council, about the Jews.
Well? What do my people want?
All of Württemberg is furious,
Your Highness.
And what do you suggest?
My General, I have stood by you
under fire on the battlefield,
and I am used to marching straight
and saying what I think.
And what I think is this:
Send away the Jew and stick to us.
- Are you on their side?
- With all my heart, sir.
He is on their side
and has access to His Highness!
- That’s impossible!
- He’s right in the room.
I’ve got to see for myself.
Words, words, words!
Once and for all!
The Councilmen aren’t
supposed to terrorize their Duke
or contradict his wishes.
If Your Highness doesn’t act
according to the constitution,
you should at least
adhere to Luther’s advice.
And he says,
"Know, thou faithful Christian,
that after the Devil thou hast
no worse enemy than a real Jew.
At best, one should set their schools
and synagogues afire,
take away their prayer books
and Talmud study matter,
forbid them money-lending, and..."
Your Luther is nothing to me!
I mean it as an old soldier,
if the Jew wants to contaminate
our women with his filth,
that would be your doing, my Duke!
What? Are you accusing me?
I shall have you arrested!
Then you should arrest
all of Württemberg, Your Highness!
I just might! Rebels!
I could really forget myself
if I go on listening to you.
Out! Get out, I say!
Servant, my robe!
Call my Financial Advisor
Oppenheimer!
The Lord said the people of Israel
would be destroyed by fire and sword.
His Highness calls Your Excellency.
Hear, Oh, Israel, the Lord our God...
You have cooked me a real mess
with your Jews.
What should I do
about my Councilmen now?
If Your Highness designs to ask me,
I would advise him to destroy them
with fire and sword!
Destroy them? How?
Dissolve the Council, establish
a cabinet of trusted persons,
and silence the main screamers,
especially this Sturm.
Süss, Süss!
You show me dangerous paths!
One must believe in one’s stars,
Your Highness.
You know about the stars?
I know someone who does.
Just wish it, and he’ll show you
the constellation,
and Your Highness
will be reassured, I know it.
The ascendants are favorable now.
The ascendants are favorable, Rabbi.
Because they must be.
Can one say they must be?
Can one order them at will?
One cannot order
the stars in their orbits,
but can one not order
the orbits of men,
if one makes them believe
that God orders the stars" orbits?
My son Joseph,
the Lord sees you and how you’ve
grown vain and proud as a peacock.
Heavy is the Lord’s blow
when Jews forget who they are.
What should I do, Rabbi?
Don’t you live in a palace
like King Solomon’s?
Don’t you sleep in a golden bed?
Don’t you have walls covered
with books that you’ll never read?
This damask costs 12 tallers!
But, Rabbi!
The Lord wants His people in ashes,
dispersed all over the world.
He rules in mysterious ways
over the peoples of this earth.
How can I rule if I don’t show myself
to the people?
If you want to rule the goyim,
rule their money.
But keep your hands
out of the quarrels of princes.
If I rule the prince,
I rule his people.
The prince will be forgiven,
the Jew hung.
God’s will shall not be disturbed
if I turn Württemberg
into Israel’s promised land.
It is already near.
I have only to grasp it!
I can already see the milk and honey
flowing for the people of Israel.
Dare I not reach over Jordan
by God’s will?
Can He not will it?
You interpret His word
at your own convenience.
His word should be understood
in Israel’s favor.
That is God’s will, Rabbi.
What should I do? Should I lie?
No need to lie.
Tell him the second truth,
the truth in our way.
Sound him his motto "Attento".
What does "Attento" mean?
"He who dares."
The Duke.
Remain seated.
Well, what do you see?
The sky, of course.
This man...
Sun.
Square to Jupiter.
Jupiter in favorable transit
to ascendant...
God is great,
and wondrous are His signs.
How does the future look?
How can my eyes unfold
what the Lord hides?
He makes the stars and moon revolve,
friends and foes,
but only He knows their meaning.
Let me see my stars.
Blessed be the eye which the Lord
allows to see among the myriad...
Can you see?
What is the name of my star?
The Duke’s star is Mars.
And what is this fiery one called,
there on the horizon?
That one is Venus,
in opposition to Mars.
It shimmers right in my eye.
So tell me, short and clear,
should I dare or not?
Or are the stars against it?
The stars are neither in favor
nor opposed.
But it is written,
they shall obey he who dares.
Here it is, in writing.
He who dares...
That is my motto. Attento.
All right, I’ll take the chance.
Süss, set up your cabinet.
You may come in.
My dear friend,
thank you, indeed, for coming!
Please be seated. We meet in private.
Let us lay aside all formalities.
You trust me, and I shall act
to deserve your trust.
Our Honored Sovereign
has nursed the intention
to surround himself
with men whom he trusts,
and his attention
has directed itself to you.
- I wouldn’t know why.
- That is why I summoned you.
The Duke intends to create
a new cabinet with you in charge.
I cannot accept this.
I am sworn in loyalty to the Council.
You are also sworn in faith
to the Duke.
I do my duty.
So does the Duke, my friend.
Don’t you want to help him?
I mistrust his advisor.
I know that from reliable sources.
Do you understand?
But why should we be foes
when we could be more than friends?
You have a charming daughter.
How is she involved in this?
You’ll understand if I tell you
that I am set on marrying her.
My daughter?
In every way, Councilman.
It is impossible.
No, I am sorry, no.
You will not say no.
You will say yes and yes again.
If you contemplate the matter
at any length.
No contemplation is needed.
My daughter is betrothed.
Really? You have time to reconsider
until tomorrow.
See you tomorrow, then.
I join your hands
before the Lord’s eyes.
Pure as gold shall your love remain.
Endless like this ring
will you remain faithful.
You shall always look back
upon this very day
and know nothing is great
that is not good.
Nothing is true that does not exist.
Be man and wife,
united before God in heaven
until death do you part.
I have the honor, Mister Chairman.
Mister Financial Advisor.
Your time is up.
I stand by my decision.
It hasn’t changed overnight.
You know very well that my daughter
and my Secretary,
Mister Faber, are betrothed.
You have a father’s right
to change your decision.
Even if I can, I will not.
My daughter will not bear
Jewish children.
So...
I see we understand each other.
It could be dangerous
to defy a man in my position.
- Please consider this.
- I have nothing to consider.
My daughter is already married.
Since when?
Since last night.
Where do you get your impudence?
For heaven’s sake,
I am the Chairman of the Council!
And as such, I ask you, where
do you actually get the impudence
to disturb the peace of my family,
of this land,
to advise the Duke
against his own Council?
Where do you get your impudence,
you filthy dog,
to sow discord between
the Duke and his people?
I thank the Councilman for his sincere
and brave opinions.
Fresh air!
Write!
What is it, Joseph?
Why shout at me like this?
Write: On grounds of evidence
of sworn, responsible witnesses,
he is charged with rebellious
and dishonorable intentions,
and is instrumental in a conspiracy
against His Highness, the Duke.
The Finance Ministry
will handle this affair immediately.
Who is charged?
Councilman Sturm.
Where is the answer?
I do not acknowledge your right to
judge nor this place as a courtroom.
Mister Councilman, we act
under the instructions of the Duke.
It’s useless! If Jews sit in judgment
over citizens here,
it is in defiance
of Württemberg law and honor.
Sturm, I am convinced you have
no debts to your name.
Really? Convinced?
Come on, get to the point.
Did you not, on Sunday
the 27th of last month,
prepare an assault against
our most honored Duke?
This is becoming ridiculous!
Let’s hear more!
Did you not on that Sunday,
in the presence of witnesses,
namely in the home
of Councilman Weissensee,
say, "Hans Bogner, the blacksmith,
was murdered"?
Did you or did you not say that?
Yes, I did! So?
Don’t joke with me.
If a murder was committed,
who is then the murderer?
Of course,
he who brought him to trial.
And who brought him to trial?
Who signed the death sentence?
The Duke, of course.
So, the murderer, in your opinion,
is the Duke.
- Oh, so that’s the idea!
- Yes, sir.
There is no doubt as to the fate
that awaits murderers,
even in the case
of the worthiest of dukes.
I’d bring to court the Kaiser himself
if he offended the law.
Even His Majesty the Kaiser
is not held holy by this man!
I’m going mad!
So do you still think that the charges
of treason are not just?
If the names of the Kaiser
and the Duke have been defiled,
it is by your own filth!
Sturm, Sturm, you entangle
yourself more and more!
Councilman Metz, don’t you see
how things are twisted here
only to destroy me?
Will you take a part in the plot
that this Talmudic Jew-mind
has cooked up?
I forbid you any form of insult,
Councilman!
He will no longer have the opportunity
to insult you.
We shall know how to protect you
from such riff-raff.
Come in. Are you afraid?
Tonight you sleep in my bed,
and I’ll sleep downstairs.
But, Dorle, you don’t even know
whether your father approves.
Come in already, and help me.
I can’t do this by myself.
Why should he mind?
We are husband and wife.
He has to get used to that.
Oh, Dorle.
You’re sighing already!
I am already used to the idea.
I have looked forward to this.
But I imagined
a different wedding for us.
Me too.
I think Father is very grieved.
Because of the Jew?
Especially the haste in which
everything had to be done.
Karli, in all my years,
I’ve never dined without Father.
And today of all days,
our wedding day, he left us alone.
But believe me, Karli,
even so we may be happy.
Now you are my husband,
my protector, and my happiness.
You always come
at the wrong moment.
Master Roeder is here,
and is looking for Miss...
for Madame...
Did he ask for me,
or for my father as well?
No, for you, and for Mister Faber.
Good evening, Master von Roeder.
You’ve come to congratulate us?
It’s not the right moment.
Your father is held
at the castle by force.
Why?
I don’t know.
The Jew?
I bring him the summons
to the Council meeting
because I didn’t want anyone else
to break the news to you.
In one hour, a meeting will be held
at the Council House.
- Councilman Weissensee?
- Here!
- Mayor of Tübingen?
- Mayor of Kronstadt?
- Here!
- Mayor of Ludwigsburg?
- Mayor of Weinsberg?
- Here!
- And Brankenheim?
Master blacksmith
Peter Eugen Penter?
Here!
All here, save for one.
And where that one is,
everyone in this room knows.
Well, free him!
Patience. It’s not that simple.
You know as well as I do
who got him arrested,
and he is higher ranking than ever.
As long as our Duke listens to him,
the Council could soon have no say
here in Württemberg.
What would that mean?
That the Duke defies the constitution.
He wants to set up a cabinet
and dissolve the Council.
And that is in defiance
of the constitution.
He wouldn’t!
It would not be the first time.
It has happened before,
that the constitution was overlooked.
Scandalous!
I move we prevent
this act of his with force.
And demand the release
of Councilman Sturm.
All in favor, raise your hands.
On the charge of outrageous acts
against the government
and my own person,
I’ve decided to call you, gentlemen,
in special assembly
chaired solely by myself.
It has been brought to my attention
that last night a special meeting
of the Council took place,
in which, as my advisor
Mister Oppenheimer informs me,
it was suggested that I’d be arrested.
In case this arrest were met
with resistance, I was to be executed.
Therefore, for my safety,
I have decided to dissolve
the Council immediately.
The appropriate edict is in the hands
of Mister Oppenheimer.
Thank you, gentlemen.
I want to know everything
the Jew and the Duke discuss.
Yes, Your Excellency.
His Highness invites Your Excellency
to his study.
Excuse me, Your Highness,
for interfering.
The Councilmen have sent me...
I know, Master von Roeder.
I don’t need
to be informed of it by you.
You can see then, Your Highness,
how greatly we care for you.
Your well-being is endangered,
but it’s not too late.
Not too late?
People are rebelling
against their Duke,
plotting with such traitors as Sturm,
resolutions are declared,
armed threats are made!
- What do you call that?
- Open rage.
So? What do you say about this?
The same again, my Duke.
Away with the Jew!
Your Highness, if I have become
the stumbling-block...
I want to tell you something,
Master von Roeder.
Your Councilmen are a nuisance!
The best soldier
has no more notion of government
than an ox has in playing the fiddle.
But my Financial Advisor is a genius!
He earns me money,
power, and good counsel!
- He wins me...
- Enemies.
Nothing but enemies.
I shall crush you, Master von Roeder.
I have nothing further to say to you.
Out! Out!
That man is right, unfortunately.
You arouse resistance to me,
more than I can handle.
Sovereigns have been known
to deal with resistance
if they have reliable friends.
I have no friends.
I shall make you some,
Your Highness. Strong friends.
I shall make the contacts.
- How do you mean to do this?
- I have already started.
With the court at Würzburg.
The solidarity of sovereigns
should not be underestimated.
The Würzburg Duke has soldiers
that could be borrowed.
Borrow soldiers?
Soldiers to be borrowed?
This is really a Jew’s way
of thinking, out of the book.
But it is a good thought,
Your Highness.
Remchingen, come here.
What’s he suggesting, Remchingen?
Should an open feud break out
between me and my Swabians?
You yourself are a Swabian,
Remchingen.
Your Duke is a Swabian himself,
The Swabians
don’t mean anything to the Jew.
Are you aggravated, Karl Alexander?
Eavesdropping?
You spoke so loudly,
there was no need to eavesdrop.
Do what he says.
What do you know about politics,
my child?
Nothing at all.
But I know something about men.
Trust your Financial Advisor.
Do you love me?
Yes. I’d love you even more
if you were as clever as...
As your friend Oppenheimer?
The way you were
before Belgrade and Peternardein.
I was young then.
You could still be.
Just do what your friend advises.
Is he my friend?
I think so.
Remchingen, leave me with her.
No, I leave you, gentlemen.
I cross my fingers for you,
Karl Alexander.
I’m not free to decide.
But, Your Highness, why not?
You think I have followed your advice
so I should continue.
Whether I want to or not.
You’ve won the Duchess" heart.
- Only her heart?
- I don’t understand.
- Is it only her heart you’ve won?
- What do you mean?
I mean that nothing is holy to you,
not even your Duke’s wife, Jew.
Only your own interests,
your profits.
Your Highness seems to mistrust me.
Yes, I mistrust you.
Sturm! Sturm! Sturm!
This is how revolutions break out.
If one shot is fired,
everyone will panic.
The palace guard
consists of a thousand men.
There will be a terrible bloodbath
if Your Highness decides to wait.
The people must be confronted
by a force they won’t dare resist.
Is it true that in Pfalzneuburg
the Würzburg Duke offered military aid
to hold things in line?
Sure, Your Highness.
Mister von Remchingen will agree.
Is that true?
Certainly, Your Highness.
That’s a military takeover.
Your Highness would become
an absolute sovereign.
Like the Sun King in Versailles.
How much would it cost?
To bring in foreign troops?
How many are needed?
At least four or five thousand men.
Four or five thousand men?
At least...
We’d have to hold the position
at least three to four months.
Well...
But the Jews whom Your Highness
granted entry to Stuttgart
owe Your Highness money.
I’ll see to it that
this operation succeeds.
Rabbi!
You interrupt a holy service.
Can’t you wait?
No, Rabbi. There is no time.
You must speak to the congregation.
So what’s the hurry?
He who has no peace to pray
will go astray and lose his way.
Peace is fine, Rabbi,
where it belongs,
but now I need five times
100,000 talers from the Jews.
From the congregation?
Are you mad?
I came to the synagogue
because they are all gathered here.
The Councilmen want the Jews
out of Stuttgart again.
But the Duke is willing
to counter them in one blow.
I’ve convinced him of that.
He should become absolute ruler,
and then he’ll protect us Jews.
So should the Jews
become soldiers?
No, just pay.
Soldiers cost money.
You want to wage war with goyim,
want to become a Mordechai
who raised 75,000 for Esther,
then you must take off your
goy clothes first. Dress Jewish.
Rabbi, Rabbi,
you don’t realize this is serious.
But I know,
because I sit at the source,
if the Jews give 500,000 talers today,
I will see to it
that the Duke never forgets
it was the Jews" money
that helped him to his throne.
But if today the Jews are stingy
and hide behind nice Talmudic
sayings, then they will all lose.
Even their lives.
Come, sing with us.
The Lord’s will be done,
with you and your thoughts,
and our brothers should see
that you stand by me.
Later we’ll speak with them.
All of my thoughts
They are with you
You, my one and only...
Dorothea, you sit so...
What can I say?
I went to church.
I ran through the streets.
I went to the grave.
I prayed, and nothing helps.
Please...
It’s already the third night
and still nothing from Father.
And my husband
has also been away a while now.
Dorothea!
I can’t stand up, you startled me so.
It’s good you’re here, Faber.
Don’t ever leave me alone.
Never leave me alone again.
They were here again this afternoon,
searched everywhere.
They search, but they won’t find
a thing against your father.
- But I can’t stay with you, Dorothea.
- Where will you go?
Don’t ask me where I was,
nor where I’m going.
Are you going away again?
To the Council House?
The Council House is closed.
The Duke’s guard
is posted in front of it.
Why?
Revolution has broken out
quite openly.
And Father?
We’ll get him out,
you can be sure.
God be with you, Dorle.
Must you go already?
I only came to let you know
that nothing has happened to me.
And if I don’t see you again, Faber,
if this is the last time
I hold you in my arms...
- But, Dorle, I’m sure that...
- Don’t say a thing.
I want to listen
to the beating of your heart.
Papers indicating high treason
were found in your home,
inside your desk,
in your own handwriting.
How many times do I have to tell you?
It’s all forged by that malicious Jew.
The Councilman had better be careful.
There are dungeons
in Hohenneuffen, in Asberg,
where he’ll see neither the sun
nor the moon.
- Asberg won’t help you silence me.
- My pen moves, and you’re hanged.
I have no fear of dying.
So you’re a hero, what?
One never learns. Well, then...
I want to stay alone.
Send the guards away.
Sturm, my intentions are good.
I won’t touch a hair on your head
and release you tonight.
You only have to be willing
to become minister.
So, in your stead, I would also
be glad to have such an offer.
I’d rather hang than break my oath.
I don’t understand you, Sturm.
I offer you position, power, title,
honor, as much as you want.
What do you know about honor?
Don’t be so stubborn.
I need your good name
for my ministry.
You and your name would guarantee
the bond of opposites.
- Is that such a big deal?
- Your deal, not mine.
- Is this your final word?
- Absolutely.
Good. But then
the responsibility is yours.
I advise you, for your own sake,
and for the sake of your daughter.
Leave my daughter
out of this dirty business.
Why? Why should she be left out?
Why shouldn’t I ask her?
Perhaps she’ll take pity
on her suffering father.
Gentlemen, the Duke
has called for foreign troops!
No! This is civil war!
- He wouldn’t dare!
- I know it for sure.
The Duke’s Turk told me.
The Jew has spun it all.
The Jews fund the Duke’s war
against his own people.
- Lf we don’t beat them to it...
- They’ll be here in three days!
- In three days?
- We have two days.
Everyone should be armed.
The orders have to go out tonight!
The gates are doubly guarded!
Try going through
as the Duke’s messenger.
Not so hasty!
You need the right password.
The password now
is "Karl Alexander."
Duke’s messenger! Open up!
- Password!
- Karl Alexander.
In the Duke’s name, I arrest you.
Why is that?
Tonight’s password is "Attento."
He is no messenger!
Take him to the Financial Advisor.
These are the secret orders
we found.
This is Dorothea Sturm's husband.
Herso-very-Christian husband.
Whose orders are these?
Turn around!
- Will you speak?
- At Württemberg!
At Württemberg? Really?
You’ll name your companions.
Who will be ready in two days?
Who should prepare for fighting?
Will you open your mouth?
Well, who are the rebels?
Who seeks civil war?
You do!
Me? How interesting!
You want a military takeover.
You suggested this to the Duke,
didn’t you?
I ask the questions here, not you.
And it will hurt you
no less than it will me.
Take him to the torture chamber.
Show him no mercy until he speaks.
What does this say?
It says the Councilmen
mean to attack in two days.
And what about us?
If we don’t want defeat,
Your Highness, we must hurry.
It depends on carrying out the plan
quickly tomorrow night.
What now, then?
I won’t have Wirzburg's forces
by tomorrow.
We’ll act with our own troops.
That’s a filthy Jew!
What are you telling me to do?
Citizens shooting each other?
Your Highness need not be present.
No, I shall not have it!
Very well, Your Highness wishes
to stay the Council’s lackey.
Shut up, you rascal!
I beg to resign.
See, now you want to pressure me.
Slink out the back door!
Take care, my boy!
Remchingen, see to it
that the Jew stays near me.
Does Your Highness
still wish to hear my advice?
Speak.
The ball you’ll give for the Kaiser’s
messenger will be the proper scene.
Tomorrow you go to Ludwigsburg
and come back a day later
as absolute sovereign.
Absolute sovereign?
In one day and one night?
That would mean a takeover!
Military takeover, Your Highness.
All right, I’ll go to Ludwigsburg.
Inform the Duchess!
Right away.
To the chair with him.
But wait for the signal.
This is where the fingers go.
Shall we remove the ring?
- It’s a wedding ring.
- Keep it on.
It’s shaped like a horseshoe.
For luck.
Only the Duke may grant
the traitor a pardon, you know that.
But the Duke is in Ludwigsburg.
Excellency, I beg you to help me.
I’ve written everything down.
Here is the application.
What would the Duke want
with your application?
He’ll tear it up, just as I am doing.
He will have the traitor shot.
Mercy!
Have you no heart?
I had a heart.
I was merciful.
Always, Miss.
Pardon me, Madame.
Nice ring. From your husband?
In this case,
it is really difficult to help.
Would you like the ring?
The gem is real.
Such a little ring
on such a little finger.
Do you want to see a real ring?
Come with me.
Well, come on.
Come on. Are you afraid?
Just look at it.
Do you still think I’d be tempted
with your little ring?
Me? Do you want it?
You want to free your father
and husband, don’t you?
This is how you go about it!
If a bird catcher lets one go,
he should catch another instead,
isn’t that so?
The cloth is out! Go!
So, are you enjoying this?
- You recognize the voice, don’t you?
- Great God!
Take the kerchief away!
What does this mean?
Do you hear anything?
That’s what it means.
Then remove it, my child.
Now give me back my kerchief.
- No!
- No?
All right, keep it. But...
- My Father in heaven...
- What?
Pray, pray to your God.
Go ahead and pray.
But not only Christians have a god.
We Jews have one, too.
An avenging God. An eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth.
- Thank your Father in Heaven.
- Let me out.
Don’t you want me to keep
the traitor from being shot?
Don’t touch me!
Don’t fret. Later you can have
your Secretary back.
Stop! Stop!
The Secretary is to be released.
I don’t understand it. Why?
The Financial Advisor has ordered
to free him immediately.
How do I understand this?
Get out!
- Where to?
- Go home.
Home.
To whom do I owe this?
Your pretty young wife asked
the Financial Advisor in person.
- That is not true.
- Yes, it is.
Is Councilman Sturm’s daughter here?
Not with me.
Wait!
Lots of people knock on this door.
I don’t bother what they do.
They all seem the same to me.
- But she was here?
- The girl that cried?
Where did she go?
Go after her. That way.
Jew!
The Jew has this
on his conscience.
Let go!
- Attack!
- What are you waiting for?
The Jew must go!
I’m here to see the Duke!
Commander von Roeder!
In the Duke’s name!
Now!
Don’t shoot!
He deserves it, Jews" lackey!
We don’t want a civil war, but if you
shoot now, it will be unavoidable.
On behalf of the Council,
I demand that you open the gate now!
Open the gate.
Well, Oppenheimer? Sit down.
Whom were you looking for?
The Duke, Your Highness.
Excuse me, Your Excellency.
I’m afraid he’s drunk too much.
Go look for him.
Tell him everyone is waiting for him.
It’s not serious, Süss.
I just don’t feel so well.
Get me a doctor.
Still no messenger.
- Tomorrow, Your Highness.
- When? When?
- Tomorrow morning at the latest.
- What’s that?
I thought he should be here
any minute now!
Just joking, Your Highness.
No more damn jokes!
I’m not up to them.
I don’t understand any of this.
I don’t know where they are.
I feel so weird.
I haven’t felt ill like this
since Peternardein.
Champagne!
This is the best medicine.
Anew glass!
To your health, Your Highness.
Why throw it away?
Throw it into your belly, Jew.
Wouldn’t it be better, Your Highness,
to join the ball?
Fireworks, rockets, lights, and women.
It’s always the same.
What is there behind
the whole mess?
What do you expect there to be?
Always the same, Süss.
Yes, I’ve seen people
in many different forms.
On the battlefield,
on the dance floor,
even in bed.
But today it seems to me
it’s always the same.
Why are you looking at me like that?
A physician’s gaze...
- What, me?
- Unmask yourself, my friend.
- What mask?
- The last one.
I wonder how you look.
How should I look?
A joke! If you dare make jokes with
me, you should appreciate mine, too.
- Couriers for the Duke.
- Let them in.
They don’t want to come up.
What is this?
My wig!
In the name of the Council,
Your Highness,
here are the demands of your people.
Demands? Demands! Who is
brazen enough to make demands?
- Alexander!
- Go away!
This isn’t for women!
Stop the music.
We know of your plans, Highness,
and the proposals of the Jew.
That’s why we demand...
You demand? I think I’m the one
who should be making demands.
- Nothing has changed, Highness!
- Not yet!
The oath you took
for Württemberg still holds.
And we ask you,
do you want to keep this oath,
or does the Jew mean more to you
than your own people?
I myself choose my advisors!
No one else!
- Your advisor is a murderer!
- Lies!
He sent my wife to her death!
Slander! Sheer slander!
What, you dare to fight
in my noble presence?
I shall have you hanged, dogs,
hanged!
Alexander! Alexander!
Call a doctor!
Alexander! What are you doing?
He’s dead.
Stop, Mister Oppenheimer!
Following the Duke’s death,
the Council has authority
until a new Duke is chosen.
In the name of the Council,
I arrest you.
Sitting here is a wretched Jew who
for months brought nothing but lies.
His whole policy rests
on a letter of the Duke’s
which releases him
of any responsibility.
The things you
have accused me of,
I only did upon the wish
and whim of my Duke!
The document says so.
You can read it clearly.
I was nothing more than
a true servant of my master!
Are you stating that letter
you swindled out of the Duke
can erase the list of your evil deeds?
We adjourn to consult.
Jew! This is the master blacksmith
speaking to you.
Doesn’t that stir your conscience?
Leave him alone.
You said you won’t be hanged higher
than our colleague Hans Bogner.
Silence. Wait for the sentence.
After a month of careful study,
we find the charges justified:
Blackmail, profiteering, corruption,
illicit sex, procuration,
and high treason.
But far greater seems the Jew’s guilt
of the scandals
that have brought so much
suffering upon our people.
Therefore, we shall listen to him
who has been most offended.
Gentlemen, I seek not revenge,
only punishment by law.
Speak freely, Sturm.
You suffered the most,
and yours is the right
to set things justly.
Suffering does not breed justice.
An eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth.
That is not our custom.
Our legal code states,
for all eternity:
"Whenever a Jew mingles
his flesh with a Christian woman...
He should be hanged at the gallows."
"Whenever a Jew mingles
his flesh with a Christian woman,
he should be hanged at the gallows,
as well-deserved punishment
and an example to the people."
I was nothing but a loyal servant
to my master!
How could I help it
if your Duke was a traitor?
I want to set everything right.
I swear it! Take my house,
take my money, but let me live!
I am not guilty!
I am only a poor Jew!
Give me my life!
I want to live! I want to live!
I speak for the Council in the name
of the people of Württemberg.
All Jews must leave Württemberg
within three days.
No entry for Jews in the entire realm
of Württemberg.
Decreed in Stuttgart
on the 4th of February, 1738.
May our descendants
adhere to this decree,
and thereby be spared suffering
for their own well-being
and for the sake of their children
and their children’s children.
THE END