Subs By:robster38
Very well.
I will release the Goguryeoans.
But remember.
If Yingzhou falls into the hands of Tang,
your people won`t be safe whever they turn.
I know that you`re gathering them back together
to establish an autonomous state like we did.
Yingzhou must be protected
if only to make that happen.
You and I must join hands and work together.
If you`re concerned about us betraying you,
I assure you that will never happen.
It`s Geumland.
Come on in.
Khitan soldiers are coming.
Khitan soldiers?
It`s General Li Kaigu.
Li Kaigu?
I`ve come for the King.
Clear the way.
He has been informed,
so wait here.
This is our country and we will do as we please!
Don`t tell us what to do!
Be quiet, you blasted fool.
Stop yelling in the middle of the night.
What? "Blasted fool"?
Who do you think you`re talking to?
I`m a general now....
a general of the Khitan mobile forces!
What? A general?
That`s right, a general!
Do you know who I am?
I`m the Wolf, the Wolf of Mt. Madu!
What, a wolf?
You look more like a dog.
What?
It`s funny you should say that
because you look like a dog.
You must be that thief from Mt.Madu that I heard about.
What? A Thief?
You punk!
Darn!Tungso.
We are the brave Turkic warriers!
Silence!
Be quiet you countryless bastards!
That`s it.
You pushed us too far!
I`ll show you what these "countryless" soldiers can do!
what`s this commotion?
What are you doing here?
If I may ask  you that question,
Your Majesty, why are you here?
We`ll part for now.
i will see you at the palace.
General, we can send the displaced citizens
to Mt.Dongmo at last.
Was the negotiation with Li Jinzhong successful?
-Congratulations, Joyoung!
-Congratulations!
-Where is my father right now?
-He is in his quarters.
He and my uncle will handle te relocation of the refugees.
We will be joining the Khitans in their war against Tang.
Aye!
-Father!
-I heard the news.
Good work!
When can we take the refugees back?
The soner the better.
start preparing the refugees for departure immediately.
~Dae Jungsang~
-We will leave with in the next ten days.
-Yes, general.
But the fall harvest is coming up,
and they will want to leave thereafther.
~Bang Gae~
we can`t take all of them at once.
-Start with those who able to leave now.
-Yes, sir.
Xue Rengui at your service, Your Majesty.
Welcome, General Xue.
did you select the warriors that will serve under you?
I`d like to speak to you about that if I may.
Go on.
It`s about General Zhang Xuanyu and Ma Renjie
who fled from Li Kaigu.
~Xue Rengui~
Permit me to put them to important service.
They have been removed from service
for failing to carry out my order.
~Emperor Wu Zetian~
Your Majesty, they are veteran warriors
who fought countless battles in the frontier.
And they know Li Kaigu better than anyone other warrior
having served under him for many years,
Very well.
-You may put them back to service if you wish.
-Tank you, Your majesty.
And Your Majesty,
-General Li Wen is heing held behind bars...
-And?
You wish to utilize Li Wen as well?
-I would be thrilled if you would allow it.
-the answer is no.
Your Majesty....
He is the man responsible for this crisis
having failed to suppress the rebellion in Yingzhou.
I can`t forgive him and absolve him from punishment
even befor he is brought to trial.
Your Majesty.
Li Wen  may have failed to accomplish his mission,
but he is an exceptional warrior.
-There are plenty of other exceptional warriors in Tang.
-But Li Wen is the only warrior
that ever defeated Dae Joyoung.
This may be a war against Tang,
but it`s a fight against Dae Joyoung and Li Kaigu.
Zhang Xuanyu and Ma Renjie knows Li Kaigu,
and Li Wen knows Dae Joyoung.
So their service will be vital in this war.
Li wen as well?
Very well.
Do as you wish.
Thank you, Your Majesty!
General!
Have you forgotten everything Li Wen has done to us?
You should let him rot in jail.
Why are you saving him?
My trysted friend have become enemies overnight.
at least I know that Li Wen won`t betray me.
Bring him to me at once.
Yes, general.
Let`s go!
General!!
Go take a bath first.
What`s your real agenda?
What are you talking about?
What are you trying to do to me
calling me to serve under you?
~Li Wen~
You made a mess of Yingzhou
so you have to clean it up!
I`d rahter rot in jail than join this conquest.
You`d rahter die than serve me.
Is that it?
-I`m done here.
-Li wen!
I told you once that
I would let out my last roar someday.
Do you recall?
Everyone who is anyone has jumped into this war.
Li Jinzhong, sun Wanrong and Li Kaigiu of Khitan,
and Dae Joyoung and dae Jungsang as well.
That`s the reason why I gave up my cushy life
and jumped into this.
To crush all of the major players come out on top
as the final victor!
Xue Rengui is stretching his arms
to let out his last roar to the world!
Do you understand?
~Mt.Dongmo, Goguryeoan Settlement~
-Father, welcome back.
-Grandfather....
Dan and Jeak, you`re back!
Look how much you`ve grown!
You`ve accomplished a monumental task
bringing back the refugees.
Please come inside.
There is so much we want to know about.
Send a message to Joyoung about our arrival.
Our delay probably has him worried.
Yes, sir.
Please come inside.
Yes, shall we?
Tang army is to attack Yingzhou?
Our intent was to get all of the displaced Goguryeoans out
before the war but that may not be possible.
I`d like to go to Yingzhou
and help father.
I can`t let you do that.
-Mother!
-Dan, I can`t allow that either.
You`re too young for the battlefield.
But fahter was only about my age
when he fought his first battle.
~Dan:Dae Joyoung`s son~
Please give me your permission.
If you really wish to help your father,
help the newly arrived refugees to get settled here.
~Sukyoung:King Bojan`s nice~
But Mother!
That`s the best way to help your father.
Dan has disappeared.
What do you mean?
Where could he be?
Father?
He must`ve gone to his father.
But the road is so long and so rough!
He`s just like his father!
Joyoung traveled from Pyongyang Fort
to Goryeo Fort to find me at his age.
What? Xue Rengui?
~Li Jinzhong:King of Khitan~
Xue Rengui is the commanding the Tang punitive expedition?
Yes, Your Majesty.
That`s the report from our informants in Chang`an.
Unbelievable!
I never dreamed we would have to fight Xue Rengui!
That`s not all.
There are 28 subordinate generals
including Zhang Xuanyu, Ma Renjie and Li Wen.
-Zhang Xuanyu, and Ma Renjie?
-And Li Wen?
Li Wen is coming back?
~Sun Wanrong~
There are indications that
Tang court wants us completely destroyes
~Shin Hong~
We may be up against a stronger army than we
anticpated but the Khitan army is strong as well.
~Chulin~
That`s right, father.
~Li Geom~
Neighboring tribes have sent
considerable reinforcements as well.
How about Dae Joyoung?
Why isn`t he here?
Your Majesty,
Dae Joyoung`s army is small compared to the
reinforcements troops we have from neighboring tribes.
Dae Joyoung`s army may not be large,
but they are powerfull!
-You saw them driving out the Tang army
from Yingzhou with your own eye!
-But Your Majesty.
we have General Li Kaigu`s fifty thousand soldiers.
Please don`t rely so heavily on Dae Joyoung.
Xue Rengui recruited his most despised enemy
Li Wen to win this war!
It is divine fortune that Dae Joyoung is with us at this time
when the fate of our newfound country hangs in the balance!
Send for him at once!
We joined this fight for two reasons.
One,
to protect tje lives of the remaining
Goguryeoans in Yingzhou,
and two,
because peace in Yingzhou is directly linked
to peace in the entire northern region.
Let me make it very clear that
we are entering this war as your ally.
And I ask that you keep your agreement
to release the remaining Goguryeoans
once this war is over.
You have my word your request will be granted.
We have a request as well.
We may be an allied force
but an army requires order and discipline.
Therefore, General Li Kaigu will be the commander
in chief of the allied force, and all of the tactics
and directions will come directly from us.
We have no objections about General Li commanding this war.
But if we must receive tactics and directions from you,
it wouldn`t be a relationship of allies but of master and servent.
A two headed horse gets nowhere.
We can`t prevail with two different strategies
and two sifferent directions.
-So you`re telling us to take orders from you?
-That`s absurd.
This is not an allience!
Forget this!
-Call this whole thing off and let`s get out of here.
-Do you think we`re just going to let you walk out of here?
Are you bastard threatening us?
What? Bastards?
-What?
-That`s enough!
You`re before the King!
Your Majesty.
we can`t defeat the enemy with this kind of alliance.
I`ve granted all of your requests, General Dae.
Likewise, you must cooperate and
give the right of command to the Khitans.
Is that agreed?
Otherwise I can`t release the refugees either.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty,
Tang army has reached Shanhai PAss!
Shanhai Pass?
Any report on their size?
It`s a massive army of two hundred thousand soldiers!
two hundred thousand?
Two hundred thousand soldiers are assembled at Shanhai Pass....
Princess Im Yugwan
~Tang Army Headquarters, Shanhai Pass~
There are two forces disturbing order
and creating confusion in the northern region!
One is the Turks of the northwest region,
and the other is the Khitans of Yingzhou.
~Xue Rengui~
that took up arms against Tang!
We will establish our headquarters here at Shanhai
and advance to Yingzhou.
These are your assignments,
so listen closely.
-Hongpei,
-Yes, sir.
I will announce the commanders of the 28 armies.
In command of the First army, Li Wen!
In command of the second army Zhang Xuanyu!
Loyalty!
In command of the Third army is Li Duoja!
In command of the Fourth Army, Ma Renjie!
In command of the Fifth Army, Zhao Renshi!
In command of the sixth....
This is where Tang headquarters is locarted.
~Khitan Army Headquarters, Yingzhou~
They will divide up their troops
and attack Yingzhou from all sides.
As all of you know Yingzhou is not
an ideal location for siege warfare.
Thus our best option is to go out there
and cut off their advance before they reach Yingzhou.
They`re advancing from different directions
so they could split us up.
~Mimosa~
You`d give them what they want?
You`re right.
~Shin Hong~
Division would weaken us
more than it would weaken them.
But we can`t leave the paths wide open for them
to advance just to stay uni8ted.
The Tang soldiers are exhausted from long travel.
And we have greater knowledge
about the lay of the land than they do.
If we take full use of these advantages,
we can still defeat them even if we have to split up.
Take a closer look.
The neighboring tribes will defend
the east bound path north of Yingzhou for us.
This southwest path,
wich is most likely to be their main route of attack,
will be guarded by General Li Kaigu.
General Sun Wanrong will take the southeast route,
and general Xue Jitou,
Mogae and Doyeop will take the east and west side.
If each of us do our jobs,
Yingzhou will be completely protected.
~Li Kaigu~
You haven`t told us what to do.
You and your men will guard the city gates of Yingzhou.
What did you say?
You called us to be gatekeepers?
This is unbelievable!
You`re unfamiliar with the lay of the land in Yingzhou.
We can`t assign you to important tasks.
If that`s the way you feel,
this war will be over before we fight a single battle.
Don`t worry.
You will have your chance to fight in due time.
I have a suggestion
if you`re that hungrry for honors.
Disband your army and come under me.
How about it?
Will you fight with us?
Guarding the gate is a very important task as well.
We will comply.
Li Kaigu will not give us a chance to render any worthy service.
If we fail to do significant work,
we will face difficulty taking the remaining refugees back.
Any news from Mt.Dongmo about my father`s arrival?
No, not yet.
I`m sure we will hear from him very soon.
We must render considerable service in this war
in order to save the rest of the refugees.
But we will accomplish nothing being gatekeepers.
Let`s think harder about this.
There has got to be a way.
We need every last able bodied man we can get, Father.
Why won`t you let General Dae Joyoung fight with us?
-It`s already been discussed and decided by the tactician and myself.
-But the fate of the nation is at stake.
We don`t need Dae Joyoung to win this war.
Let us believe in ourselves, Geom.
Is it the refugees?
Are you holding Dae Joyoung back
because you don`t want to lose the refugees?
Goguryeoan refugees are ou people, too.
Why are we fighting this war?
Isn`t it to protect our land and our people?
Losing our people is
just as detrimental as losing a war.
We can`t lose anymore of our people
to Dae Joyoung than we already have.
It`s in the best interest of the state,
so we will not discuss this any further.
Don`t worry.
We don`t need Dae Joyoung`s help
to protect Yingzhou.
~Tang Army Headquarters, Shanhai Pass~
Darn!
-I just can`t figure it out!
-Figure out what, sir?
I know what we have to do to win this war
but I just don`t know how.
What do you mean by that?
Think about it.
Winning this war is very simple.
All I have to do is to turn Li Kaigu and Dae Joyoung
against each other.
I see, but how will you manage to do that?
~Hongpie~
that`s what I said I can`t figure out!
General!
General, we`re prepare to move out.
How large is Li Kaigu`s army?
He has fifty thousand troops, sir.
Fifty thousand....
They couldn`t have recruited more than twenty thousand troops
from the neighboring tribes.
And there`s only about another tweenty thousand troops
in the Khitan Army.
How about Dae Joyoun?
How many men does Dae Joyoun have?
There were a little over five thousand men
when he attacked Yingzhou.
~Li Wen~
That`s less than half our size
even if you put them all together.
So why are you worried?
Deom weapons to soldiers,
we are by far superior to the enemy.
I guess you`re becoming anxious with your old age.
Watch your language, General Li Wen!
Yes, I am old.
My days are numbered,
so I want no regrets.
I`ve tasted countless victories on the battlefied.
But if I lose what is likely to be my last fight.
I would have faild at life.
That`s why I can`t fail.
I will stay here and observe the developments for now.
The rest of you will advance to Yingzhou
at first light tomorrow!
Yes, general!
How can you fall asleep at a time like this?
Go splash some cold water on you face!
Yes....
There is one thin we can do.
Disband the troops like Li Kaigu said.
We will split up and join the Khitan army.
Disband the troops?
Are you out of your mind?
Mimosa.
perhaps you need some cold water on your face, too.
What we need right now is to distinguish ourselves in this war.
It doesn`t matter where it is done as long as it`s done.
Our enemy in this war is Tang,
but we are competing against the Khitans
for distinguished services.
In other words,
our enemy is both Tang and the Khitan.
How can we defeat them both?
Defeat them both?
How are we going to do that?
Gaepils, you have any ideas?
Huh?
Oh, the general will tell us.
Gulsabiwu, get out there and start making the raven flags.
-The raven flags? For what?
-There is no time.
Make as many as you can
and hand them out to the soldiers.
Yes, general.
Not you too, Joyoung.
Don`t do this to us.
Mimosa, go to Li Kaigu at once.
tell him we will disband the troops to serve in his army.
Yes, sir.
That`s it!
This is the only way to defeat the Tang
Chinese and outshine the Khitans.
General, General Dae Joyoung sent a messenger.
It`s Mimosa.
Mimosa?
-What does he want with me at this time of the night?
-I`ll go see what he wants.
-You will disband the troops?
Yes,
we will spit our men up and incorporate
them into the Khitan army.
I`m glad to hear that.
But I`m very suprised that
General Dae would make such a decision.
He cares deeply about his men.
You are amazing man
for making him come to this decision.
If this is a ploy of some sort,
I suggest you stop immediately.
General Dae is going to disband his army,
and give his position and power to serve this war.
What kind of ploy could there be?
Then you can you can serve under me.
We could come up with some awesome ideas
if we put our heads together.
How about it?
Will you help me?
How could I refuse such a
valuable opportunity for learning?
We are prepared.
I regreat having to split you up like this.
Remember.
We came together under one flag and fought our enemys.
But now each of you is an army of one
fighting your own enemies.
Wherever you are assigned,
whomever you serve,
always spearhead the fight.
And if you kill enemy officer or capture ground,
take out the raven flag and mark your feat.
Each of your achievements will be all of our achievements.
-Is that understood?
-Yes, sir!
Geumlan and I were assigned under Sun Wanrong.
Then you will be in the mountains.
It will be a fight to capture grounds,
so prepare large flags.
We already have, sir.
Sudol!
I`m going under Xue Jitou with Gaepil and Tungso.
You`ll be on flat land.
Focus on takin out the enemy leader.
I`m not good at a whole lot of things,
but no one can kill like me on horseback!
Don`t worry about us, general!
I will be going under Li Kaigu with Mapa.
Why does it have to be that rotten bastard?
Don`t worry about me.
Once our achievements are recognized
after the first battle,
chances are we will be back together.
And when we do,
we will be fighting together again.
It is our duty to stay alive until then.
-Is that clear?
-Yes, general!
Your Majesty,
all preparations are complete!
Command us to march to battle!
Command us to march to battle, Your Majesty!
Is it true you disbanded Dae Joyoung`s army?
Yes, YourMajesty.
Did you consider whether this action
would help us or hurt us?
I have considered long and hard, Your Majesty.
If it helps us we will win this war,
but if it hurts us we will be defeated.
And you, Li Kaigu,
will be held responsible for the outcome!
Your Majesty,
I, Li Kaigu, will never be defeated!
I will bring you only victory!
Very well.
I am counting on you and the brave Khitan warriors!
March out to battle!
Crush those who dare to threaten our new state!
Go!
Brave soldiers of Khitan,
go out there and fight!
Yes, Your Majesty!
Loyalty!Loyalty! Loyalty!
In AD 696 the same year Khitan declared autonomty,
Tang court dispatched 28 generals
including Zhang Xuanyu, Ma Renjie, Li Duoja,
and Zhao Renshi to Shanhai Pass
and begand a massive punitive campaign against the Khitans.
In response,
Khitans rallied their neighboring forces
including the former Goguryeoan forces,
to fight the Tang army.
This was the start of an importand war
that would decide the subsequent fate
and mastery of nothern China.
General,
this is where Li Kaigu`s main force is located.
Sun Wanrong`s army is here,
and Xue Jitou is right over here.
Honpei, don`t you find something very odd?
Odd? What`s odd?
Where is Dae Joyoung?
Dae Joyoung is....
Dae Joyoung is one of the men that caused this war.
He would never turn around and leave
when the battle is about to begin.
I found nothing about Dae Joyoung
in the report from our informants.
That`s why I`m puzzled.
Perhaps he and Li Kaigu separated.
"Separated"?
What are they, lovers?
-Hongpei,
-Yes, general.
Can you do me a favor and take that curtain off?
This is a cape,
and I happen to think it make me look dashing.
Just take it off!
This is not a matter to be over looked.
Where did Dae Joyoung disappeared to?
Now there is no telling
when he will show up and blindside us!
I`ll send an alert to each army
to watch for Dae Joyoung.
Yes, that might make me feel a little better.
I just don`t feel at ease....
~Khitan Camp, Yingzhou~
General!!
The Tang army has reached the ten mile mark
from the front line.
How many of them are there?
There are at least thirty thousand of them.
If my guess is right,
LiWen is their leader.
Send the advance guards to advance base at once.
I want a detail report of their every move.
I will go to the advance base.
You could be the first to die once the battle begins.
I could also be the first to kill the enemy commander
once the battle begins.
General Dae Joyoung will lead the advance guards.
The war has now begun!
Take your positions,
and keep a tight reign on the soldiers!
Yes, general!
Did you wish to see me?
I`d like you to go with the advance guards.
Advance base is very important place.
We can`t trust it to Dae Joyoung alone.
Observe the enemy,
but watch Dae Joyoung very closely as well.
I just don`t understand.
Why are you and my father
so distrustful of General Dae Joyoung?
There is not a whole lot you can trust in this world....
especially not during war.
There is only one man you can trust in this world
and that`s your father.
You have to remember that.
Li Kaigu?
Are you sure it`s Li Kaigu?
Yes, general.
-How about our other fronts?
-The`re studying the enemy
like we are checked on their advance.
And Dae Joyoung?
We have yet to receive any report about him.
I want a report on Zhang Xuanyu, Ma Remjie
and Li Duoja`s current position as well.
We`ll get on it, sir.
I`m sure he is in this war...
But Dae Joyoung and his entire army have disappeared!
You should be tending to your weapon and not your face
if you want to survive out there.
Why are you painting your face anyway?
To forget that I`m a woman.
You should be tending to your weapon,
not staring at me if you want to survive out there.
If you want to paint your face, do it right.
You don`t want the enemy to laugh at you.
I`m starving.
Tungso!
We have to eat well
if we`re going to collect the enemy`s heads.
Tungso, couldn`t you get us any meat?
-I took everything I could find.
-Be thankful we have this.
Eat up.
You!
You bastard!!
What are you doing here?
So you`re the three fat rats in this camp that I heard about.
Food is life!
How dare you lay your hands on military property
during war time!
Don`t you know the punishment for this kind of crime?
Sometimes you can judge a book by its cover.
You look like thieves and you are thieves!
Blasted bastard!
You spat on General Xue Jitou`s face!
I`m sorry.
I always earn my keep.
Cut us some slack this time.
Tungso, clean that off for him.
Get your filthy hands off of me!
I`m a general!
A General of the Khitan mobile forces!
What is that, general?
Isn`t that the old Goguryeoan military flag?
Have you seen this flag before?
I`ve seen a few Goguryeoan refugees
who had this flag.
This flag used to make the Tang Chinese run away in fear.
What are you going to do with it?
I`m going to display it at the frontline
when the battle begins.
But Goguryeo has long been destroyed and gone.
Yes, but the sons of Goguryeo are still alive and fighting.
Goguryeo is in our blood.
We can`t change who we are
or where we come from.
We can`t locate Geom.
Do you know where he is?
He wouldn`t go anywhere without telling us.
We are worried sick.
Geom is at the advance base.
The advance base?
You mean he`s with Dae Joyoung?
I asked him to go
so he can keep an eye on Dae Joyoung for us.
No!
He has to stay away from Dae Joyoung!
General, what`s wrong?
Could you give me this flag?
I would like to display this flag
when the battle begins.
I could,
but you`re a prince of Khitan now.
It won`t be appropriate.
Why do you want to display the flag anyway?
I just like it.
The way it looks, how it feels....
I just like it for no particulare reason.
Subs By:robster38