[Episode 20 End]
Shin Young Il claims all the
evidence you submitted along with...
the Jung Geun Moo list are fabricated.
What is your response?
Jung Geun Moo's testimony...
and the evidence I submitted
will be proven...
to be authentic and true after a
proper investigation and analysis.
However, Shin Young Il...
must admit to his crimes...
and withdraw from his position...
if he has any decency as a human being.
Why did Chairman Jung confess
to his son's crime...
and testify at the confirmation hearing?
You should ask him yourself.
But I'd like to thank him...
from the bottom of my heart...
for taking courage and testifying.
That is all.
- Wait a minute.
- One more question.
- Excuse me.
- Is that blood on you?
Please tell us where that came from!
I got a nosebleed!
Wow. That was straight out of a movie.
How did you get Chairman
Jung to take the stand?
Where did you get those videos?
What a blow.
We were worried because we
couldn't reach you this morning.
The Minister position is gone now, right?
With all that evidence,
- he can't stand a chance.
- That's right.
There's one thing left.
Ae Ra, please call Detective Song.
Speak of the devil. Hi, Detective Song.
Detective Song.
What is it? What's up?
Mr Joe Deul Ho called out
of the blue this morning.
He asked me to catch a killer.
What?
So I went to Incheon
airport as Mr Joe asked,
and he came right in.
Choi Hyun Tae?
Choi Hyun Tae.
You are under arrest for the
murder of Kang Il Goo and...
the attempted murder of Joe Deul Ho.
Take him in.
Wait.
I can't believe you went
all the way there...
just because Mr Joe told you to.
He's peculiar,
but he doesn't lie.
He's never wrong.
Did you get proof?
It was all in here.
He's here. He's here.
Would you like to say something
about Joe Deul Ho's accusations?
It is an insult to me.
I have led a pure and transparent
career for 30 years.
It is an attack on prosecutors as a whole.
I will follow the law and make
sure he pays for his actions.
What about the video that
Joe Deul Ho submitted?
It was a fabrication made
with malicious intent.
I will investigate thoroughly
and uncover the truth.
Sir.
Please answer one more question.
Get people to analyse the evidence
from the confirmation hearing.
Don't worry, Sir. We'll prove
that they were fabricated.
You'll get past this. Stay strong, Sir.
(Minister)
Hello, Sir.
This is a disgrace.
- What's going on?
- My apologies, Sir.
I'll take care of it.
I'm going to discuss what
to do with the general,
so you think of something as well.
I will. But Sir,
I need your help.
Thank you.
Was everything presented
at the hearing true?
- Does it matter if they were true?
- Father!
Everything is about to collapse!
We must stop it!
A person has died.
How will you stop it this time?
I don't know whether I
can help you any more!
Then stay out of it.
Yes!
I will stay out of it from now on.
Joe Deul Ho, who appeared as a witness...
at Shin Young Il's confirmation hearing,
testified that Chairman Jung
Geun Moo of Daehwa Group...
bribed Shin and requested that
he cover up his son's crime.
Joe Deul Ho submitted incriminating
videos to back up his accusations.
Congressman Kim, the presiding officer,
said they would investigate
thoroughly to uncover the truth.
The Shin Young Il, who
had been advocating...
cleaning up corruption, may lose
his nomination for Minister.
Is this your office?
I was about to leave.
What will you do?
If Shin Young Il crumbles,
you'll be left with nothing and nobody.
You never know.
They say the evidence may
have been fabricated.
Plus,
it's not like I'm affiliated with Mr Shin.
You're not?
I heard you went around telling
the partners at the firm...
that since you're close
with the future minister,
you must become the managing
partner of Geum San.
I was just saying that.
Since Mr Jang was found guilty,
we'll have to get a new
managing partner anyway.
You're his daughter,
so it won't help restore the firm's image.
So,
I'll take good care of Geum San.
I'll say just one thing.
Don't even think about
taking over Geum San.
It's not a place that a kiss-up
who wags his tail at anyone...
can dare even covet.
And if you come into this office again,
I won't let it go.
Get out.
You said you'd find a way,
and you really did.
I told you, I'm Superman.
What? Kim Tae Jung?
That bat. Don't mind him.
Once we take care of Mr Shin,
he'll drop off on his own.
Don't worry about him. It's really okay.
Why did you say that at
the confirmation hearing?
Do you want me to go to prison?
Do you want me to die?
Father, please call the reporters
and hold a press conference.
Tell them I never killed anyone.
The chairman is not well.
He needs to rest, so please leave.
Why you...
What's wrong with you?
He fell for Joe Deul Ho's
tricks and sold me out!
What were you doing?
Call the reporters. I'll
hold the press conference.
I'll say his mind wasn't all there
because of his brain surgery.
I'll tell them, so call the reporters.
I'm here. Happy?
Joe Deul Ho, you jerk.
- Do you want to do an interview?
- What did you say to my father?
You must be crazy.
Don't come closer.
The first blow was what your father wanted.
The second was for the
people that you hurt.
Do you know why I hit you?
I don't know anything.
I'll need to hit you about 100 times.
Get over here.
For every question you can't answer,
it's an additional 30 punches.
- Get over here.
- I know.
Do you know why your father told
of your crimes at the hearing?
What do you know?
- I know! I know!
- What do you know?
Because you're his son.
You may be a loser, but
you're still his son.
That's why he wanted to get you out...
even if it meant he had
to bribe someone for it,
but you became more and more despicable.
That's why he realised that wasn't
the right way to love his child.
Should we ask him?
Am I right?
He says I'm right. Come here.
Come here.
Turn yourself in.
Turn yourself in and find redemption.
If you keep running,
your time in prison will only get longer.
Forget it. You need to be
beat up more before you go.
Get over here. Get over here.
- Come here.
- No.
Chairman Jung.
We started off on the wrong foot...
and fought the entire way here,
but I hope you recover completely...
and let me see you scream again.
When you make your return,
please become a respected businessman.
And please ask for forgiveness...
from Il Goo.
Thank you again...
for being brave...
and testifying.
Are you here?
What are you doing? Why
aren't you here yet?
Hurry up!
Michael Jung, you are under arrest
for the murder of Noh Gwang Soo.
What do you mean?
- Ji Wook.
- I told you not to call me that.
- Take him away.
- Wait!
I have something to say. Wait!
Mr Shin!
Please!
Chairman Jung Geun Moo's son,
Michael Jung, was arrested today...
for hitting Noh Gwang Soo
with his car and killing him,
destroying the body and
obstructing justice.
(Choi Hyun Tae)
I told you to leave the country.
Why are you calling?
Couldn't you do that one thing right?
It's me,
Joe Deul Ho.
Thank you.
You left me another piece of evidence.
The recording is great.
Choi Hyun Tae...
was arrested for attempted murder...
along with the murder of Kang Il Goo.
I wanted to ask you...
why you killed...
Kang Il Goo.
Was that necessary?
Tell me.
Don't you feel sorry...
for Kang Il Goo?
Please tell me.
Did you want to kill me...
and become the minister?
Was the appointment as Minister...
that important?
Didn't I tell you...
that I considered you my big brother?
But...
you wanted to kill me...
just for that piece of paper
with the appointment.
Stop babbling and get out.
(Play)
I need you to kill someone
in a car accident.
Yes, Sir.
If it all goes well,
I'll make sure you're not dragged into it.
Don't make any mistakes.
Yes, Sir.
I took care of Joe Deul Ho.
Good job.
Leave the country for a while.
How untrustworthy were you?
Choi Hyun Tae...
recorded your conversations as insurance.
He already confessed to the police.
I told you, didn't I?
Submit yourself...
to the judgment of the law.
Ji Wook.
You say you detest crimes,
so I have no choice but to
cheer on that conviction.
I hope...
that conviction will be fair to everyone.
Even if it is your own father.
Come in.
This is everything Mr Joe submitted
during the confirmation hearing.
The audio files of Mr Shin
ordering the murders...
of Mr Joe and Kang Il
Goo are also in there.
He told me to tell you that what
you use this for is up to you.
You can either expose or bury
Mr Shin's crimes with this.
Is that what Deul Ho said?
He wants me...
to prosecute my own father?
Rather than another prosecutor
putting the handcuffs on him,
wouldn't you doing it...
protect his pride just a little bit?
That's what Mr Joe said.
Thank goodness it wasn't worse.
You are incredible.
You wore a sack of sand knowing
it was going to happen.
That kept me alive,
but it was so heavy that I almost drowned.
I don't know whether to laugh or not.
How long will you risk your
life for your job like that?
What if something bad happens?
You don't have nine lives, you know.
Dae Soo.
Can you believe...
Mr Shin tried to kill me?
He's completely lost his mind...
because of that minister position.
Even so,
how could he go so far?
When people lose their minds,
they can't think straight.
There were times when people I trusted...
took off with my money, and
I wanted to kill them.
But you didn't kill them.
The only explanation is that
he completely lost his mind.
That's why we need to do whatever
it takes to lock him up.
Who knows what he'll do next?
I'll have to stop him.
I'll stop him.
Let's drink together.
How did you find me?
Did Deul Ho send you?
No.
I came on my own.
I never properly thanked you
for finding my bag last time.
So I thought I'd buy drinks.
If it were you,
could you...
prosecute your own father?
It wouldn't be easy.
No matter what anyone says,
my father...
led a straight life as a good prosecutor.
I became a prosecutor...
to be like him.
But...
it stopped at some point.
He was no longer the father that I knew.
It'll be hard to stand
by his side right now.
But if you do stay by his side,
maybe he'll come back to being
the father that you respected.
I think it's something that
only you, his son, can do.
Why am I saying this...
to you?
You don't have friends, do you?
I heard you were too busy
studying in school...
and catching criminals as a prosecutor.
I also heard that you never
had a real girlfriend.
Who said that?
Mr Joe.
Let's stop talking about this.
You asked...
if I could prosecute my own father, right?
No.
I couldn't do it.
But you can do it.
That is what I think.
Did you want to kill me...
and become the minister?
Are you that short on money...
in becoming the minister?
You act calm on the outside,
but you seem to be losing it on the inside.
Lawyers defend,
and prosecutors investigate.
I took the GED...
and have no money or connections,
so no one will eat with me.
Shall I make you someone
with money and connections?
It's more honourable than you,
who follows Chairman
Jung like a puppy dog...
and cleans up after him.
Left!
Hello, Sir.
Did you go with the police again?
We uprooted them completely this time.
Why didn't you just become a detective?
I should've, right?
Why don't you go with me
next time if you are free?
Good work.
Didn't I tell you...
that I considered you my big brother?
Did you want to become Minister that badly?
Did you want to climb that high that badly?
Why didn't you know that those that fall...
don't have wings?
As of today,
I will...
withdraw as a candidate for Minister.
Whereas a nominee for Minister must be...
cleaner than anyone else,
I am accused of corruption,
and thus am not qualified.
Hence, I've decided to withdraw.
I apologise sincerely...
to the people of this great nation.
I promise...
to undergo a thorough
investigation of the charges...
made against me.
Shin Young Il, the minister nominee,
has withdrawn his candidacy.
He held a press conference and
went to the prosecutor's office.
He is expected to be investigated
for the claims made against him.
Chief Justice Choi Dong Wook has
been nominated as the next minister.
The public's attention is on how far...
Shin Young Il's corruption charges go.
Gosh. Nothing lasts forever.
He looked omnipotent, but he's gone.
Just like that.
I don't know how to feel.
Come to think of it, you
started empty-handed...
- but took them all down.
- That's right.
And we added just a little bit...
- and helped, right?
- A little.
Thanks.
Thank you. Thank you.
Okay, it's time to go back to
being the neighbourhood lawyer.
That way, I can pay rent.
I'm glad you brought that up.
While we're on the topic,
can you raise the rent just a little bit?
Now that I've lowered my interest
rate, it's hard to pay the bills.
What are you talking about?
You can bring that up next year.
I'm busy right now.
What? What did you just say?
Don't be like that.
- Just a little bit.
- I'm busy.
We won't be able to afford instant noodles.
Poor Dae Soo.
Will we finally have peace?
I think there will be some aftershocks.
What will happen to Geum San?
- What do you think?
- I think...
I'm sure they'll take a hit.
Chairman Jung and Mr Shin
are all getting locked up.
Even their managing partner was locked up.
Come in.
What is it?
We had been misinformed.
What do you mean?
We didn't know Shin Young Il was like that.
We were fooled...
by Kim Tae Jung.
When Kim Tae Jung went around
saying he was close to Mr Shin,
you were all on his side.
Now that Mr Shin has taken a fall,
you want to come back to me, is that it?
That's not it.
We agree with you.
We think Geum San must
change in order to survive.
Mr Park. Mr Choi. Let's talk.
I was instructed...
to finish your investigation
during my term.
Wouldn't it be best for all...
to bury what must be buried and
admit what must be admitted?
There's no need to bury anything.
If you're going to admit it anyway,
you must not leave any doubt.
If it looks like you are going easy on me,
it will not help you become...
the Minister of Justice.
Why did you have to...
I've served you for so long.
I can't become a stumbling block.
Please let me be investigated fairly.
Fine.
But...
I have a favour to ask.
Go ahead.
Please let Shin Ji Wook handle...
all investigations and trials for my case.
Do you mean your son?
Please, Sir.
It won't look good.
How can a son be impartial in
investigating his own father?
He is capable of following the rules.
Even still,
it's not like he'd investigate
you just because I tell him to.
He'll do it.
Please permit it.
Yes.
I understand.
I'll take on the case. Yes.
I'm sure it'll be tough,
but we're counting on you.
No.
I'll go in alone.
(Chief Prosecutor, Shin Young Il)
Come in.
I came to escort you.
Okay. Let's go.
(Shin Young Il, Chief Prosecutor)
Do you need anything?
No.
I'm a bit tired, but I'm fine.
You should call a lawyer.
Later.
I'm fine by myself for now.
The evidence is solid,
so you won't be able to avoid serving time.
If I had planned to bury it,
I wouldn't have asked for you.
Dig as much as you want.
Don't let people say you
went easy on your father.
That...
won't happen.
Good.
Let's begin with the most recent matters.
On April 6, 2016,
Jung Geun Moo...
Father,
why did you do it?
Why?
Why did you go so far?
I believed that was the
way to protect myself...
and our organisation.
Father!
Power is...
difficult to let go of
once it's in your hands.
The higher you climb, the
higher you want to climb.
Did you have to climb high
even if it meant doing that?
You could've made it
even without doing that.
Really?
I wonder.
Life...
isn't that easy.
Ji Wook.
Step on me to climb up.
It may hurt you,
being the son of a corrupt prosecutor.
However,
if you're a prosecutor who
locked up such a father,
you'll make people trust you
to be impartial with any case.
- Father.
- So,
work your way to become
the chief prosecutor,
the minister...
and the general.
I will be your cornerstone.
That's why I asked for you.
Okay. Let's begin.
Shin Young Il, the past chief
prosecutor, is being investigated...
for inciting murder, taking
bribes and abusing his power.
Shin Young Il is said to have
voluntarily confessed to the crimes.
People wonder why he incited the murders...
and just how much he received in bribes...
from Chairman Jung Geun
Moo of Daehwa Group.
(Shin Young Il Is Sentenced to Prison.)
The imprisonment of the
past chief prosecutor,
who had represented the prosecutors,
has left everyone wondering...
how harmoniously the court and
prosecutors will work together.
Shin Ji Wook, the prosecutor who
initiated this investigation,
is Shin Young Il's son.
This has caused a stir.
The suspicions regarding
Shin Young Il's corruption,
which was brought to
light by Joe Deul Ho...
during Shin Young Il's
confirmation hearing,
will hopefully be clarified at trial.
It's finally over.
Do you feel relieved?
I'm not sure.
It'll be tough for Shin Ji Wook.
I'm sure.
(Law Firm Geum San)
The partners have come to
a unanimous decision...
to elect Jang Hae Kyung...
as the new managing partner of Geum San.
Thank you.
Geum San will no longer be...
a law firm which speaks only
for large corporations,
but a firm that takes the side of
the weak, who need legal services.
We must become a law firm
loved by the people.
I also believe...
you should become people of
the law who value ethics...
and be reborn as such.
(Managing Partner, Jang Hae Kyung)
I...
Ma'am.
I'm sorry for everything.
Geum San will change.
So,
you'll need to help.
I'll work hard with a new heart.
Ask anything. I'll do my best.
Please,
leave Geum San.
What was that?
Are you kicking me out?
I played a part in making
Geum San what it is today.
Do you think I'll leave voluntarily?
I'm not asking you to leave voluntarily.
Kim Tae Jung,
you're fired.
Ma'am.
You want to fire people
at your whim, is that it?
This is a violation of the labour law!
Labour law? Give me a break.
It's natural that she
fire a criminal like you.
Watch your mouth! What
do you mean, a criminal?
Kim Tae Jung.
I have a gift for you.
Gosh.
Do you remember this?
The USB drive that you hired
someone to steal from my office.
I suffered quite a bit because of this.
I don't know what that is.
I saw you pay...
your supposed friend for that.
We have a witness, too.
Inciting burglary.
Money-laundering Daehwa Group's
slush fund is an added bonus.
Is that sufficient grounds
for termination now?
I've made plenty of copies,
so don't get any stupid ideas.
Why are you giving that
to me behind your back?
I wanted...
to get you cookies or something,
but she said I needed to bring you these.
Congratulations on becoming
the managing partner.
It suits you.
Thanks.
Enjoy your time together.
I'll leave you two alone.
And congratulations.
Where are you going?
You can't even eat that.
Thanks.
If it weren't for you,
I never could've done it.
Your name was outside on your door.
It looked good.
I'm going to visit my dad.
Will you come with me?
Sure.
How is your health? Are you doing okay?
Yes.
Since I no longer drink
and exercise regularly,
I've been well.
I'm glad to hear that.
Hae Kyung...
was appointed as the managing
partner at Geum San today.
Congratulations, Ms Jang.
Hae Kyung plans...
to change Geum San from now on.
That is up to Ms Jang.
And Mr Shin...
has been arrested.
I heard about that.
Please take a good care of...
Hae Kyung.
Don't worry, Sir.
If you're planning to get back together,
do so while I'm in here.
I may not approve of it once I'm out.
There's no need.
We'd like to stay as friends as we are now.
I feel like fighting against
loneliness with a glass of alcohol.
- Ta-da!
- What is it?
You need to put this on your face.
There's plenty of serum on this face mask.
You need to keep caring for your skin...
so that Dae Soo will like you.
Why would I do this for Dae Soo?
I'll do it for my own sake.
Besides, there's nothing
between me and Dae Soo.
What do you mean?
I know everything about...
you two.
Goodness. Don't be ridiculous.
I don't think you know what's going on.
When there's no one else in the office,
he flirts with me like a peacock.
Besides, why would I
meet such an old geezer?
I like someone else.
I like Song Joong Ki.
Is that so?
- I find Mr Shin amazing.
- What about him?
I get that he's a prosecutor,
but it must be distressing
to prosecute his own father.
- Why are you worried about Mr Shin?
- What?
Now that I think about it,
- you two look great together.
- What?
Is there something going
on between you two?
What on earth are you talking about?
We just met...
as an attorney and a prosecutor
at court a few times.
We had drinks a couple of times.
That's all.
You had drinks with him? That says it all.
Gosh, there's nothing going on.
What do you mean, nothing?
There's definitely something.
Other than the fact that we are
not on good terms with Mr Shin,
as a man, he is tall and good looking.
He seems strong and manly.
When he smiles, it's like
looking at a sunflower.
He seems like a great guy.
He's never been in a relationship before.
How do you know so much about him?
- Ms Hwang!
- What?
Would you like me to help you out?
What brings you here?
I'd like...
to defend you.
You want to defend me?
I'd like to give you...
a chance to atone for your deeds.
I already found a lawyer.
I know.
Will you try to prove my innocence?
No.
I'd like you to be...
judged by the law...
for the crimes you have committed.
It's an interesting suggestion,
but I'm going to decline.
Mr Shin,
take my hand.
You offered me...
your hand...
when I had no money or connections.
I think...
it's my turn to offer you my hand.
I was...
going to kill you.
That's the truth.
I'm willing to pay for that...
for as long as you wish.
I really appreciate your offer.
I do.
Thanks for coming.
(Trial for Shin Young Il for
bribery and inciting murder)
Prosecution.
State the charges.
Defendant.
Defendant Shin Young Il...
abused his title as Chief Prosecutor...
to incite the murder of Mr Joe.
Furthermore, he accepted bribes...
from Chairman Jung Geun
Moo of Daehwa Group.
The prosecution charges the
defendant in accordance with...
Article 31 of the Criminal
Code for murder instigation,
Article 120 for bribery...
and Article 123 for
abusing one's authority.
Everything is over now.
In the end, Mr Shin...
didn't take my hand.
You punk. You asked for this.
Gosh, you stink!
Let go. You smell horrible.
Stop it!
People don't change easily.
When Mr Shin serves out his sentence,
he might become a scarier monster.
But I saw.
I saw him struggle...
when I offered him my hand.
That will suffice.
All I need is hope that the
world and the people in it...
can change.
That is the reason why...
I live on...
as a neighborhood lawyer.
(One year later)
(Court Room 305)
Plaintiff, you were wrongfully
dismissed without...
- any reason, correct?
- Yes.
Please tell us how the company treated you.
It started from petty little things.
First, they bullied me.
Then, they threatened me to
turn in my vacation days.
When I complained, they hired a
new employee and moved my desk.
Where did they move your desk to?
Beside the water purifier.
Everyone must have looked
at you while passing by.
Everyone laughed at me.
Your Honour,
the plaintiff has been...
a loyal employee for the past seven years.
She was wrongfully dismissed...
from her company for one reason.
It was because she applied
for maternity leave.
The labour law states everyone has
the right to take maternity leave.
Nonetheless, the plaintiff was dismissed...
without a proper reason.
Does that mean...
that she shouldn't have given
birth in the first place?
I request your wise decision.
No more questions.
Ms Lee.
You were impressive today.
Thank you for the compliment.
My client wants to settle.
What do you say?
If the conditions are
right, we'll consider.
Mr Joe, the other party asked to settle.
Settle?
That's great. We won't need
to continue with the trial.
I'm heading to Geum San.
You should head over, too.
You take care of it.
Me?
Do you want me to decide
on the settlement amount?
You don't want to?
No, it's not that I don't want to...
You can't complain later.
You can't nag and complain...
that I didn't ask for more, or that
the conditions aren't good enough.
I'm not a nag.
This case is yours, so you finish it.
You're sure, right? This is my case, right?
That's what I said.
Then naturally, I should decide.
Yes.
Okay.
Let's proceed with this.
Ms Lee. You've become a
real pro in just a year.
It's all thanks to Mr Joe.
I've experienced all sorts of battles...
while working with him.
It must be fun.
Pardon?
So much that it doesn't compare
with your time here at Geum San.
Yes. That's true.
How are things in your office?
We're swamped as usual.
He's so famous in the area as you know.
What are you doing? No, no.
- That's not right.
- Come on.
It's almost done.
Word got out that consultations are free,
so people come from afar, too.
If you search online,
it also shows up as "Free
consultation law office".
Are you getting paid regularly?
Of course.
At least I don't have to work odd jobs now.
How's Ms Hwang doing?
Get what? A divorce?
Why didn't you do anything...
when I said I was getting married?
You should've stopped me.
You were so in love.
You said you had to get married
because you were pregnant.
Did I?
I must have had lost my mind.
I can't live with him.
My gosh. I'm going crazy.
Why are you fighting?
Our personalities and everything clash.
We're too different.
What about the baby?
I'm taking custody of my baby.
Not a chance!
Over my dead body.
Mr Joe, divorce is one thing,
but I need to have full
custody over the baby.
Have you lost your mind?
- Yes, I have!
- It's in my belly.
I won't give you a cent in alimony.
- You have to give her half.
- Right.
I earned all of that before we got married.
- It doesn't matter.
- Mr Joe.
You'll represent me, right?
He's my lawyer.
I worked with him longer.
We're like brothers.
He's closer than my real brother!
See? She's always starting up with me.
She's always starting fights.
You have no right to say that!
Why don't I?
Have you once cooked for
me since we got married?
You always feed me instant noodles.
That's not a decent meal.
- Hey.
- Noodles?
Why are you picking on noodles?
I don't believe this.
You said you love noodles so much
that you could eat them every day.
- When did I say that?
- You said my love is all you need.
And that woman!
Ask that woman to cook for you.
He has another woman.
- Do you have another woman?
- It's a misunderstanding.
She's a childhood friend.
Who texts their childhood
friend every day and giggles?
- It wasn't every day. It was once.
- It was every day.
- You giggled?
- No, I wrote "laughing out loud".
- Don't lie.
- Forget it!
Goodness.
Fine! Let's get a divorce!
Get a divorce.
What?
Split your assets down the middle,
and cut the baby in half, too.
I misjudged you.
- How could you say that?
- What?
How could you say that?
That's what you do when you get a divorce.
I'm so disappointed.
How could you say that?
I'd do the same even if it were me.
Oh my gosh.
What's wrong? What... What's wrong?
What's wrong? Is it the baby?
It's coming.
- How can you cut the baby in half?
- Come here.
- Are you having your baby?
- We'll be back.
- It's your fault!
- Okay, okay.
Is she having her baby?
I think so.
I'm having my baby.
Hold on.
Wait.
Are you serious?
Are you?
Hi, Jin Young.
Where else would I be? I'm home.
Beer?
You should've called sooner.
Okay, okay. I'm coming.
Where is she?
Ms Lee?
Mr Shin.
Hello.
Are you meeting someone here?
Yes. What about you?
Yes. I'm meeting a fellow lawyer friend.
And you?
I... Well...
Seeing how you can't answer me
makes me think it's a blind date.
Yes.
Who set it up?
A lawyer friend...
- The public defender...
- Oh Jin Young?
Goodness.
Soo Bin.
- Daddy's here.
- Daddy!
You look so pretty.
You look like a princess.
It smells great.
- Hi.
- It smells great.
I made kimchi stew.
Did Mummy make all of this?
Yes.
Really? Wow. I'm impressed.
Actually, we bought it.
See? I knew it.
Hey.
Soo Bin. Here.
- Ta-da!
- It looks like you.
It tastes good.
It's spicy.
- Front legs out, hind legs out
- Leaping, leaping, it became a frog
The law is not fair to everyone.
It is a time for solitude
and reflection for some.
Hi.
Goodness.
Thanks. Sit.
How have you been?
I've been well.
- Is everything okay?
- To some people's families,
You can't get sick, okay?
It can be a painful wait.
Some have...
a personal lawyer who
visits them every day.
Of course, you must pay a very high fee.
We recommend...
one year in prison.
Defense, make your closing statement.
And here,
there is a person who was detained...
for stealing an eight-dollar candy.
Your Honour,
the defendant is here...
on a charge of theft.
She stole one bag of candy...
from a local supermarket.
The cost of that bag of candy...
is eight dollars.
Because of that eight dollars,
the owner handed her over to the police,
and the police sent her to
the prosecutor because...
it was not her first offense.
The defendant stole the
same bag of candy...
from the same supermarket three times.
The total price of candy that she
stole thus far is 24 dollars.
The wholesale price of the candy...
is half of that,
which is 12 dollars.
Defendant is being detained
at a detention centre...
for 24 dollars.
It was wrong to steal the candy...
I am a neighbourhood lawyer.
Most consultations are free,
and no matter how small the case,
if the client was wronged,
I defend them regardless of the fee.
I am not a warrior of justice.
I am not Superman,
as Soo Bin thinks.
However,
if I see someone who is wronged,
I can't just walk on by.
As long as...
there are people who are wronged in
my neighbourhood and in this land,
I will continue to do my job.
Regardless of how petty the crime,
the punishment was escalated...
because it was her third offense.
Don't you think this is wrong?
(My Lawyer, Mr Joe)