I'm really excited
to be here.
We have something really special
to share with you today.
In total, between iMac
and PowerBook lines,
we have sold over
3 million units this year.
Okay. That's it.
Well, maybe there's
one more thing.
I'm about to show you
something that's amazing.
Something that no one else
in the world has seen yet.
Now, Jony, myself
and a small team
have been working really
hard on a secret project,
which is something
I've been known to do
from time to time.
The device I'm about
to introduce to you
is gonna revolutionize
an entire industry.
It's a music playing device.
Okay
We'll get to that in a minute.
Because what it represents is
as important as what it is.
It's a tool for the heart.
And when you can
touch someone's heart,
that's limitless.
If I do say so myself,
it's insanely cool.
It's a music player.
It's a thousand songs
in your pocket.
I'd like to introduce you
to the iPod.
Hey, Jobs.
Get up, man. Wake up.
I'm up.
Steve.
Hey, Daniel.
Hey, what's going on?
Are you reading Be Here Now?
Yeah, it's amazing.
I'm reading that right now.
It's unbelievable.
It's the next level.
Hey, speaking of Be Here,
what happened to you last night?
Where'd you go?
I had to study.
I know, I know.
You know, I'm not dismissing
the value of higher education,
I'm just saying it comes at
the expense of experience.
The system can
only produce the system.
I don't want to be a part of that.
Neither should you.
I agree with you. It takes balls
to drop out like you did.
That's why you should.
I mean...
Steven.
Might I borrow
you for a moment?
I'll see you in, see you later.
Sure.
Thank you. Thanks. I hope
I'm not interrupting.
What about your classes?
I'm not a student
anymore, Jack.
Well, you're here,
and you're learning.
Sure sounds like
a student to me.
If you want me gone...
Why would I want
you gone, Steven?
I'm glad that
you're here.
Whether you're
paying or not.
Now, you're always carrying
this notebook around.
You obviously fancy
yourself as an artist.
Why don't you sit in
on some design classes?
No. Well, I like the idea of art the beauty.
But only in the right context.
Just not as a career. I don't
have the necessary talents.
But aren't you interested in electronics?
What about engineering?
There's a growing market for qualified
technicians. What about that?
I don't want to spend
my parents' money
to get a degree
and become something
as forgettable
as an electrician.
Excuse me, what, a degree is
a waste of time now? So...
For some. For others it offers validation.
Job security.
Steve...
I'll see you around.
Steven. To be continued.
What are you working on?
Nothing, really. It's homework
for calligraphy class.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, the teacher's
this monk, or something.
A monk?
Yeah. Robert Palladino.
He's totally inspiring.
My name's Julie.
Are you leaving?
Yeah. I have to go.
You want a hit?
Yes.
Yes, I do.
Can I take a couple?
Sure.
For my friends.
Well, my friend,
and my girlfriend.
It's so beautiful.
Like a window to the world.
What do you think
it's like in space?
It's...
beyond understanding.
Yeah.
Who has a baby,
and then just throws it
away like it's nothing?
You talking about
your birth parents?
Oh, no,
no, no, no, no.
That's bad. Yeah. That's
making me really sad. I...
Sorry that my life
is ruining your high.
It's okay.
I miss you when
you're not around.
I love you, Steve.
I love you.
Space. The endless black deep.
What was it that
that guru used to tell us?
There is no time to waste.
Do you hear that?
What?
There he goes again.
Calligraphy is the artful and
visual expression of communication.
Take Garamond, for example.
A typeface specifically designed
to make the very act of reading
more natural.
Computers are inherently
designed to make your lives easier.
Theoretically there's no limit
to what computers can do.
It is not who you were
at birth that matters
but what you do with
the time you are given.
The moment of
your death is fixed.
Life is but a journey to
serenity, to its completion.
Be as simple
as you can be.
You'll be astonished
to see how uncomplicated
and happy your
life can become.
I don't even know what I'm
gonna do when I go back home.
What about you?
What are you gonna do when
you get back to The Valley?
Steve?
Steve? You okay?
No. No, no! No. It's
still black and white.
People want color.
Pong didn't have color.
So?
Let's do something better.
It can't do color.
Says who?
Okay, you refuse
to do anything
that vaguely escapes
your comfort zone.
You're not even my boss.
Well, I damn sure
should be.
Hey, Jobs!
What're you doing, Steve?
He's an idiot.
You know, and half
the people around here
don't know how
to design shit.
People are complaining
about your behavior.
Okay? And, yeah.
About mine?
And your odor.
Are you showering
like we discussed?
I'm wearing shoes.
You asked me
to wear shoes,
and I've got them on.
That's not part
of the deal, Steve.
You've gotta learn how to
work well with other people.
I'm just trying
to do it right, Al.
I know you are.
Then let me.
Listen, Steve!
You're good.
You're damn good.
But you're an asshole.
Well, that...
Hey. Let me finish.
I want you here.
I really do.
Somethings gotta change.
Give me my own project.
What?
I'll do it on my own.
And I'll make the best damn
game you have ever seen.
You're serious.
Okay, Steve.
I need someone to reprogram
a troublesome game.
But I'm on
a tight deadline.
So if you can deliver,
we'll pay you
up to $5,000.
$5,000?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
And as for your personal issues,
I think I may have a solution.
So many circuits.
Woz? Hey, it's Steve.
Thanks for saving my ass.
Of course. We're friends.
That's, that's what friends do.
I just can't work
for other people.
I guess I need my independence.
If that makes any sense.
Uh-huh.
That makes perfect sense.
I'm sorry for ruining
your Friday night.
Are you kidding me?
This is great.
I'd do this for free.
I really would.
But just out of curiosity,
how much are we getting paid?
$700.
Some big bucks there.
Shit.
This is good. Really good.
I know.
Wow. 4 days.
You aren't kidding around.
I'll have to show it to Nolan,
but this is, this is good.
Woz?
Hi. Hi.
Woz!
Hi! Yeah, I'm
in the living room.
Hey. Good news.
Huh? Let me guess, your
bosses liked the video game.
They loved it!
Ooh.
$350. Whew! That's not bad.
Not bad? It's great.
What are you working on?
I'm writing jokes for
my dial-a-joke machine.
I've got some really good funny Polish
jokes, which work because I'm Polish.
Hang out and tell me what
you think of this one.
Ready? Ready?
What is long, and hard, that a Polish
bride gets on her wedding night?
A new last name.
That's hilarious.
Pretty good, isn't it?
What do you call a beautiful
Polish girl? Lucky.
What's that?
Hmm?
Oh.
That. Now that
is gonna be cool.
It's a computer terminal board
I'm working on.
Hooks up to the TV
for the display.
What is it like, a kit?
What do you mean?
Well, well...
The code is still buggy,
but in theory it'll display
whatever you're working on. Like...
Show me.
Show you. Okay.
Wow.
I don't care if HP
didn't like it. It matters.
Yeah.
It's got potential.
No, the Sex Pistols have potential.
This is the wheel.
It's the
Industrial Revolution.
No more decks,
no more mainframes.
That changes everything.
It's pretty cool, I guess.
Hi, Charlene. Hello.
Hey.
Cool. It's profound. How could you
not tell me about this before?
I don't know. I was just working on it for my own.
It, it was a hobby.
Exactly. Exactly.
For your own. For you.
It's what you wanted. It's what
your gut' your instinct wanted.
Your big evolved brain wanted
something that didn't exist,
so you just willed it
into existence.
It's, what do you
call the system?
The operating system?
The operating, and it just shows you...
That's what I call it.
Yeah, it's just a real time
display of current operations.
You can see what you're working
on while you're working on it.
Okay. Look...
Don't you get this?
This is freedom.
This is freedom to create,
and to do, and to build,
as artists, as individuals.
Look, look, look.
But look,
you're overreacting.
Even if you were developing this for
freaks like us, and I doubt you are,
nobody wants to buy
a computer. Nobody.
How does somebody know what they
want if they've never even seen it?
Huh?
We're going to Homebrew.
No...
I am not presenting
anything at Homebrew.
I'm. No.
Why do people drive so slow?
Get out! Move!
I'm telling you right now,
I've been to Homebrew.
I understand the caliber
of people who speak there.
I'm not one of those people.
I'm telling you this thing is amazing.
I'm not...
You're gonna be great, Woz.
Steve, could you do me a
favor, could you just please
slow down a little bit
so that I feel like
there's a chance we might
actually get there alive.
I want to get there first
so we present first.
You know if we're
gonna do this thing,
we need to come up
with a name.
Yeah, I know. Something catchy.
Something...
I've been
thinking about it.
...electric.
It needs to feel like...
I don't know.
What about
Enterprise Computers?
No.
No Star Trek names.
I swear.
What about Kirk Enterprises?
I will drive this car
right off this road.
Fine, fine, fine, fine, fine!
I will run the car
right off the road.
Jesus! Calm down! Seriously.
Okay. Nothing Trekkie. Jesus.
It just needs to be, like, something
that people will relate to, you know?
Like, it needs to be
something that you see,
and you're just, like,
"Man, I just gotta have it."
Apple.
Excuse me?
Apple, like the fruit?
The fruit of creation. Apple.
It's simple but sophisticated.
It comes before Atari
in the phone book, too.
That is so much better
than Phaser Beam Computers.
It's naming it
after a fruit.
Apple. Apple Computer.
But, what about
Apple Records?
The Beatles' label, stu...
What, they own
the word "apple"?
Why do you always
hate The Beatles?
Well, I do not
hale The Beatles.
Yes, you do. You always...
I do not hate The Beatles.
They're just, they're not
Dylan, and you know that.
Okay, and that's a comparison
that you always make.
Well, I...
'Cause it's obvious.
And I don't think it's fair.
Apple. Really? Apple?
Right, listen. If we come up with
something better, we'll change it.
Let's just go with it
and see if it sticks.
It will display
up to 192 memory locations
on the monitor simultaneously.
Allow me to explain because it's
quite fascinating, actually.
The logic board is rather complex,
especially compared to some of
the other boards here,
including of course,
the Altair.
And as you can see...
it's much smaller, and cheaper
to manufacture and build...
which, by using
dynamic RAM, I was able...
We were able to shrink the size
of the board substantially.
So, it works with
your television?
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
It will work on any
television, or video monitor.
All you need is
a radio frequency converter
to display the images
from your microprocessor
to your set output device.
And it'll run BASIC.
It will also run BASIC, which
I think could be a great...
So I guess that wraps it up. Thank
you very much for your time.
This was terrific. Fuck.
Tough crowd.
Good evening, gentlemen.
I'm Frank.
I'm Lutz.
And we're here with reduced
instruction set computing CPU.
Excuse me.
Name is Paul Terrell.
Saw your presentation.
And?
And I'd like
to talk business.
What can I do for you?
Well...
I own a local computer parts
store, in Mountainview.
The Byte Shop?
You buy computer parts.
Yeah. We sell transistors, boards,
soldering equipment, monitors.
You know, hobbyist types.
Like Radio Shack?
No.
Listen, why don't you stop
by and talk to me sometime.
There's my card.
Give me a call.
Great..
It was nice meeting you.
Steve Jobs.
Steve Jobs. All right.
Who was that?
It's Paul Terrell.
Oh.
Who?
So what kind of investment
are we talking about here?
Jesus, Steve. I said I was
interested, not buying.
I know. But you're also not
the only interested party.
Oh, really? I'm not?
No.
You're not.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Because it sure seemed that way
the other night at Homebrew.
You think that's the
first stop that we made?
We've been
all over The Valley.
Oh, well, then you
already have a retailer.
I got offers.
Look, Paul. My middle name's Paul.
My dad's name is Paul.
Bunch of Pauls. I'm...
I think we're
kindred spirits here.
We're both businessmen
that operate from our gut.
And my gut tells me to
give you this opportunity.
I'm thinking $400 per machine, for 50
units, paid at the time of delivery.
$400 for a hundred units,
a third up front.
We're not negotiating.
Yes, we are.
Okay. I'll pay $450
per machine. $450.
On delivery, nothing up front. I
know it's asking a lot, Steve.
But it's a big payoff
if you deliver.
When I deliver.
$500 per unit and
you've got a deal.
All right.
You got 90 days.
I'll have it in 60.
Daniel and I just didn't have
room at our place, so...
No, no.
I'm glad you asked.
We could move some things around,
give it a good cleaning.
I could move most of
my tools to the shed.
Maybe get you boys
a fan when it gets hot.
Ooh.
What do you think?
It's great, Dad.
Yes. It is.
This is perfect.
Good. Well, it'll be good to
see you building something.
Good. Hey, keep it neat.
Inside and out.
Thanks, Mr. J.
Mmm.
We got a shop.
Yes, we do.
How's it going?
And voila.
It's gotta be straighter. These
have to be more symmetrical.
We have 60 days to
complete 50 of these,
and you're worried
about the symmetry?
Sieve, nobody cares
about the look of the board.
I care.
Well, that's just great.
But we were out of time the minute
you made that stupid promise.
You're right.
Need help.
Woz.
Huh?
We got a problem.
We got to figure out what to
do with all these employees.
You know Bill?
Bill.
Too long, Woz.
How are you?
Good to see you.
How is everyone?
Oh, this is my friend
Daniel Kottke.
Hey. I've heard a lot about you.
How're you doing?
Kottke?
Kottke from India, of course.
I've heard a lot
about you, too.
Don't touch that.
That's Chris Espinosa. Kid down the
street I was telling you about?
Nice to meet you, fella.
This is gonna be so cool.
Great. I'm so glad
that you're excited
about this thing
we're doing here.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Yeah.
Excuse me, just please stop.
And go over there.
Just out of the way,
over there.
We can't afford to pay
3 people right now.
ourselves, unless we deliver.
And don't worry about Chris. He's just a kid.
So he just wants to help.
You're just a kid.
Cheese!
Thanks, Mom.
So embarrassing.
All right.
As promised.
Nice board.
Where's the rest?
The rest?
This is all of them.
I asked
for 50 computers.
That's keyboards, cases,
monitors, and power included.
Not just boards.
Just boards? Excuse me? Just boards?
These are state-of-the-art.
The logic boards alone are...
Nobody's making anything like this.
They're, what, how dare you!
How dare you!
I think what my colleague
is saying is that...
You're not seeing
the possibilities here.
That is indeed one unbelievably
kick ass computer.
Not to the consumer.
Well, then maybe
your consumer
should start to
learn how to...
How to even work that,
don't you think?
Listen, boys.
You sold me on a home computer.
That's a keyboard and monitor.
This is a board.
Now, I'm sure this makes
a very capable starter kit,
but the everyday person,
the kind of person
that's not an engineer,
or in a computer club like you,
they're not gonna know
what the hell this is.
The average Joe doesn't want
to build their own computer.
They just want to buy it.
They want to take it out
of the box, plug it in,
and have it work.
Steve.
Are you listening to me?
Yeah. These are your boards.
And they will sell.
I can promise you that.
You saw our demo
at Homebrew.
You know what it's capable of
with the right components,
which, by the way,
all of which you sell.
So, demo it to the consumer.
And market
the components separately.
You show them your keyboards,
and your monitors.
You'll move more
inventory that way,
and you'll make a hell
of a lot more cash.
You got me.
All right, Steve.
I'll try to sell them.
But if I don't, I'm not
making another order.
Okay. That's fine.
But I think that you might be really
interested in our second model.
What's the second model?
What are
you talking about?
All-in-one.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm Rod Holt.
The technician.
We talked on the phone.
Of course. It's Rod.
Glad you could stop by.
Welcome to Apple Computer.
All right.
Show me this
revolutionary piece of shit.
The Apple ll.
It's the first ever all-in-one
personal home computer.
And you called
me because?
We need a heat efficient power supply.
In the case.
That's impossible,
but don't mind me.
I'm just, you know,
an engineer.
What's the wattage?
40 watts. And quiet.
What the hell do you mean, quiet?
I mean silent.
There's no such thing.
These things run hot.
They need fans in them.
Those bitches
ain't quiet.
That's exactly
why we need you.
To redesign it.
Redesign what?
The power supply.
From scratch.
It can't have a fan,
it can't overheat.
And ii needs to fit
inside a box this size.
Don't do that.
Please, don't do...
Whatever.
Do whatever you want.
My rate is $200 a day.
And if I ever think things
aren't working out, I walk.
Mmm-hmm.
Are we clear?
We're clear.
We're talking
about the future.
We're working in a market
that doesn't even exist yet.
What Intel has done
for the microprocessor,
we are gonna do for
the home computer.
How can you not know
what I'm talking about?
No, ma'am. But it
runs on a TV monitor.
Yes, like a television set.
Exactly.
I don't think you understand. It's not a TV.
It's a personal computer.
Okay, do you own
a typewriter?
Great. Okay, now do you use it?
Perfect.
So imagine combining your typewriter
with your television set.
No. Don't... Wait. Wait!
Wait. Please, sir,
don't, don't hang up.
Yes. We are small
right now, but we...
How do you know we're
working out of our garage?
Who told you that?
Ahhh!
Yes. Yes.
Well, thank you
for taking the time.
Yes, sir. Apple Computer.
Apple? Yes, like the fruit.
Who's that?
No. No. All I'm asking is
that you come visit us.
One meeting and I promise
you'll be on board.
Around $50,000
would be my guess.
Hello?
What did they say?
What the hell is
the matter with people?
Take it the call went well.
I would say I hope you choke, but that
burrito is gonna kill you either way.
Oh, come on, Steve.
Cool your jets, man.
Excuse you?
Just, you know, you're
so stressed, you know?
It's, like,
relax for a change.
For a change... Why? Why? So I can
be more like you two assholes?
Hey. I'm studying integrated
circuit design here, man.
Are you?
We each do our part.
Really? Then why do I suddenly
feel like your part is expendable?
Out here smokin' up like we're in India.
Well, wake up! We're not.
What happened to you?
You used to be...
What? I used to be what?
Motivated.
l am motivated.
Really? Then show me.
This is a business, Daniel.
And I can't help you
if you don't help yourself.
I'm in there making
a hundred phone calls.
Rod is slaving away.
The kid always finds
something to do,
and God knows Woz
pulls his weight.
Thank you.
And that's
a whole lot of weight.
That really... That kind
of hurts my feelings.
Whoa.
Is this the right...
Apple Computer?
Yeah, this is us.
Yeah.
You expecting something else?
Uh, no. Well, yeah, maybe something
a little less Manson Family.
It's a startup.
Yeah.
I'm Mike Markkula.
Steve. Jobs.
Steve. I heard
a lot about you.
You spoke to Don Valentine
on the phone.
He and I are old
colleagues of sorts.
The VC from Atari.
Yeah, Valentine. He said
you called him 150 times.
Jesus.
He practically begged me to come
and look at your outfit here.
Called in
a personal favor.
Well, Mark.
Mike.
Welcome to Apple Computer.
Thank you.
Yeah, is this...
This is everything?
Yes.
No.
No. We're, we're in 6 stores
in the greater area.
We'll be launching the
Apple ll in about a month.
In a few months.
It's close.
Gentlemen, is there
some place we can talk?
Here you are, fellas.
For you.
Steve's a fruitarian.
He will only eat fruit.
Okay, boys. I'll leave
you to your business.
Thank you.
Thanks, Mom.
Thanks, Mrs. J.
You're the best.
Yeah. So where were we?
I'm sorry, don't take this the
wrong way, but what's your angle?
Uh...
What my colleague is
trying to say is...
Where was your
last employment?
Intel.
So how much are we
talking about here?
What, the investment? That's
what you came here for.
Foreplay is not
Steve's strong suit.
Isn't it?
Yeah, well,
I've been looking for something
to really sink my teeth into.
Look, Steve. I'm willing
to take the risk.
And, this
certainly qualifies.
But risk disguised
as promise.
And you've shown promise.
I've seen it in your eye,
and I know that look
because I've had it myself.
Tells me you're
onto something big.
Yeah. Okay. To the point.
I think we should start
with around 90 grand,
see where that takes us.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Could you repeat that?
I'm sorry.
$90,000 isn't
gonna get it done.
Oh, whoa, whoa. Wait.
Steve, one second.
I don't see anybody else coming
in your garage with a checkbook.
Oh, no, no.
90 grand
gets it done for us.
I just don't think it
gets it done for you.
We'll do the
$90,000 investment.
At a $300,000 valuation.
But I also want you to kick
in a $250,000 credit line
with 10% interest to
be paid back in full
once we meet
net revenue positive.
Okay.
What I mean is, okay.
Yeah.
Now, the first thing
you need to do
is incorporate, so that you two as
owners can protect your interest.
And that is, of course,
if you'll have me aboard.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Markkula.
Of course. Mike. Yeah.
How're you doing?
Yeah, put her there.
- Bill.
- Bill?
- Fernandez.
- Yeah.
Oh. Thanks, Mike.
Yeah.
Steve. Here's to you, pal.
Are you
even listening to me?
I'm pregnant.
Steve, you have
to talk to me.
This is your
responsibility, too.
Don't you dare
blame this on me.
I'm not.
Mmm-mmm.
We both had
our moments of...
What? What the hell
are you talking about?
You.
When I was in India,
you were with, you know.
Steve? Are you crazy? You
cannot put this all on me.
You can't do this to me
right now. Not now.
Well, I'm sorry this
isn't part of your plan.
I'm sorry you
have a problem.
But it's not
happening to me.
But this is your...
No!
Get out of my house.
What?
Now!
Oh, Jesus. Here we go.
Hey. ls everything
okay out here?
Steven, he's kicking me out.
He doesn't want
anything to do with me.
Maybe
it's for the best.
You don't deserve to be treated
the way he treats you.
I'm pregnant, Daniel.
What? You're...
He says it's not his,
but I would never...
What did I do wrong?
You didn't do
anything wrong.
It's Steve.
That's just him.
He changed.
Hook them right
to your television.
It is, yeah.
What do you think, J?
Ready?
Ladies and gentlemen,
my name is Steve Jobs.
When I founded
this company,
I had one goal in mind.
And that was to do what nobody
else considered possible.
To put the power
and the beauty
of the world's most
advanced technology
in the hands and homes of
people just like you and me.
And I can promise you
that after today,
you will never look at
computers the same way again.
So I am proud to introduce
to you, and the world,
the future of
personal computing.
The revolutionary Apple II.
Gotta just start over.
It has to be intuitive.
Precognitive. I mean, I want
it to know what you want to do
before you even know
you want to do it.
Wait, are we still talking
about the command prompts?
Bill, we're talking about everything.
The whole thing.
Lisa. Guys, it's the future.
I'm telling you right now.
I mean, Lisa's
gonna do for the next 10 years
what the Apple ll
did for the last 3.
I can tell you
that right now.
Do you know why
people buy an Apple?
Why do they buy an Apple,
not the competitor?
Because it's got bravado.
It's social status.
No, you know what?
It's even more than that.
It's social currency.
We've raised the bar.
And if we want to stay there,
we gotta risk everything.
Great artists, Dylan, Picasso,
Newton, they risk failure.
And if we want to be great,
we've gotta risk it, too.
On the command bar?
On everything.
What...
And it starts with the little things.
There's over 20
different functions
tied to even single variation
of the command bar,
which by the way,
takes weeks to program.
We're not doing anything that
IBM's not already doing.
And I would rather
gamble on our vision
than make a me-too product.
We got to make the small
things just unforgettable.
Let's just start with something simple.
Lisa Write.
What happens if I click
on one of these tabs?
You get a drop-down menu,
and then there's preferences,
and page options.
Okay. Exactly.
Now, which tab do I click on
to get different font styles?
How many custom typefaces
are there on Lisa Write?
That's actually something that I wanted
to talk to you about, Steve, is...
I've been asking for
the fonts for months.
But everything we're talking
about is conceptual.
And I'm sorry, but typeface, it isn't
exactly a pressing issue right now.
Everything is
a pressing issue.
If we want to make the
vision for Lisa a reality,
we gotta put in the hours
and make something great.
Yeah, but we have a hard
date on this software,
and I'm sorry, but adding pretty
fonts is not gonna change that.
Well, Bill?
If you don't share
our enthusiasm,
and care for the vision
of this company...
No, no, no, no. I just,
I'm not understanding...
Get out.
What?
Get your shit and get out.
What, wait...
You're done.
What, you...
What, are you gonna,
you're gonna fire me?
No!
I already fired you!
Why are you still here?
Steve, he was our best
programmer in the division.
He's the best programmer that
doesn't care about our vision.
Okay. Look, I know it's not
my place to say it, but...
Then shut
the hell up, Bill!
Yeah.
So sorry to interrupt
you, Mr. Jobs,
but your attorney is
here for your 8:00.
All right.
I want to see samples
this afternoon.
Somehow we managed to design a word
processor that doesn't have fonts.
And it can't happen again.
So fix it!
2:00 to 3:00. And
your 10:00 is waiting for you.
Steve. Steve, hey.
Daniel. Hey.
Do you have
a second to talk?
I thought we rescheduled.
It'll only take a second.
That's what everyone says.
Steve.
Fine.
I don't have a lunch, so' meet
me at Good Earth at noon.
Okay. Cool.
Okay.
What are you
working on these days?
Oh, um.
Apple ll Plus repairs, mainly.
Right.
I need you to sign this.
It legally preserves
your visitation rights.
I don't want them.
Lisa Brennan is not my child.
The courts disagree.
Chris-Ann is a lunatic. It's impossible.
At the very least, improbable.
You knew going into this
the paternity test could prove
that you were the father.
There are 24 million
people in California.
That test has a 5
percent margin of error.
That's 1.2 million people that
could be the father of that child.
It's not me.
You don't need to convince me.
But you do need to sign this.
Miss Brennan is entitled
to your child support
regardless of whether
you sign it or not.
Do you really want to give
up the rights to see your...
To see her child
in the future?
I don't have time.
Not now.
Steven, as a father, I
implore you to sign this.
Regardless of whether you think
Lisa is your daughter or not.
There's no risk in signing.
Only the regret
if you don't.
Frederick Rodney Holt,
he recently made
an additional
preferred purchase
of 106,656 shares
at 19 cents a share.
Right, and to be clear,
this new purchase,
it does not affect
Mr. Holt's entitlement to
founder stock.
No, not at all. Steve?
No, no, no.
Rod gets his due.
Daniel Kottke,
engineering technician, founding employee.
Now, at our last meeting I,
I don't believe that
we meta consensus
as to Mr. Kottke's entitlement
to founder stock.
Well, in all honesty,
to be rewarding Daniel
with the same amount
of stock as Rod seems
a bit unfair.
Doesn't it?
Yes. Daniel gets nothing.
Nothing?
Don't you think
you should
think about what you're
doing, for a second?
I have thought about it.
Daniel gets nothing.
Yes, sir.
It's noted.
What?
Any low grade technician
could do his job.
I've been feeding him for years.
It's not personal.
Don't give me that bullshit, Steve.
Of course it's personal.
He can barely do his job.
If we give Daniel
preferred stock,
some engineer with 10 times
his talent gets nothing.
Then what happens?
Then we just draw this line
right here, right now, okay?
So you, what are you talking about?
Management, or...
Management and engineers.
Yeah, this means...
I know what it means, Mike.
Thanks.
No, he's...
You know what, I don't...
Okay then.
Shall we continue?
We can assume
that Bill Fernandez,
Randy Wiggington
and Chris Espinosa will not
be receiving
any options?
Drinking a beer, huh?
Tomorrow's
a big day for you.
For us.
Mike told me about what
happened with Bill and Dan
and Chris. And, Steve...
Why'd you do it?
The company outgrew them.
They're not management.
They're not project leads.
It's not my job to
be nice to people.
It's my job to
make them better.
They don't deserve it.
Then who the hell does?
Do you know how
this company works?
Do you want to know?
I'd be happy to teach you,
if you want to know.
Do you know why I started
this company with you?
Why I left the safety
of HP for this?
I doubt you do.
You never asked.
I left because
this was my thing.
And you guys thought
it was cool.
I just wanted to be
one of the guys.
And of all the guys I knew,
you were the coolest.
You were smart,
quick-witted.
And this was my chance
to do what I loved.
And to do it for fun.
That's all, that's
all I ever wanted.
I thought that's what
you wanted, too.
Somethings happened
to you, Steve.
I'm grown up, Woz.
No. No, you're not.
And now, turning to
big news in business,
Apple Incorporated is making
headlines once again.
On Wall Street
the tech titan Apple
went public this morning,
to incredible market interest,
as four point six million
shares of its IPO
were sold within an hour
of the opening bell.
Wall Street executives
had forecast the big clay
for the growing
technology company,
but experts now
say Apple's day
exceeded the market's
wildest expectations.
It was the most over...
Hey, hey. Here he is!
Yeah. Yeah. Oh, terrific.
Yeah, you did it.
Let's help
them move that stock.
Hey, pal.
Oh, hey, thank you.
Business as usual, guys.
There's work to
be done, people.
Thank you.
I had some fun ideas.
This is it for me, Bill.
I'll see you when I see you.
I'm gonna get out of here.
I'll call you later.
All right.
Hi. Could you please tell
Mr. Markkula we're here. Thank you.
Yes, sir, Mr. Rock.
Gentlemen.
Mike. Please.
Have a seat.
There's something we
need to talk about,
and I don't think
you're gonna like it.
It's Steve.
He's hemorrhaging
the company's dollar
on fantasies that simply are not
possible with the Lisa computer.
Yeah, but Steve's been
doing the impossible
ever since this company
was in a garage.
Mike, I love everything
Steve represents. You know that.
But he's like a kid in a candy
store, and we've given him the keys.
Yeah.
But, it's his candy store.
You're never gonna see
a personal computer
where the keyboard is attached
to the machine again.
Mike, it's a problem.
The bigger problem is that
he is ridiculing IBM.
Jobs took out a full page ad
in The Wall Street Journal
taunting the biggest computer
company on the planet.
"Congratulations on your
first personal computer."
He's trying to start
a war with IB fucking M!
I'm fully aware of the ad.
Then do something
about it!
Listen, Arthur,
you know he's right.
3 years ago IBM had no
interest in the personal computer
and now look at 'em!
They followed us.
Think about it.
We have, Mike.
And I'm sorry, but the
Board is unanimous.
Steve will no longer be involved
in Lisa's development. Period.
What is this, Arthur?
Some sort of power play?
For 18 months now you've
offered nothing but support.
And now you want to try and
take Jobs off of his own team?
I don't want
any of this, Mike.
But you have to
try to look at it
from the shareholder's
perspective.
Steve is great.
He's great.
Yeah, he's great.
But he's a time bomb.
And it's our job
to diffuse him.
So take care of it.
I don't give a shit
what the Board thinks.
It's the time you're taking. Your perfectionism.
It's, it's, it...
They're looking at
losses in the millions
before this thing
even gets off the ground.
They're not seeing
the big picture.
That's right. The shareholders
don't see past their own shadows.
They're only concerned
about the here and the now.
And the Board has
got blinders on.
If they could see you
they'd take them off,
they'd see you
the way I see you.
The way your
employees see you.
Lisa is my project.
It's mine.
And they're taking
it away from me?
You're letting them
take it away from me.
Bullshit, Steve.
You know that's not true.
Shit.
There are more
Apple II's teaching more subjects
in more schools than
any other computer...
Everything from alphabet
lessons for preschool,
to science programs
for graduate school.
So whatever Brian wants to be,
an Apple personal computer
can help him be it.
The Apple II. There's no telling
how far it can take you.
Now that doesn't
make any sense.
Well, you haven't seen as
much of murder as I have, Mr. Cross.
I'd rather have a judge give me the
works than have to do n' myself.
Right here in solitary.
So what?
So you go right on punishing yourself.
You can't get away with it.
Hi, I'm Gabe Kaplan.
Take the Pepsi Challenge. Let your
taste decide.
Right, guys? Okay, now
why don't you tell me
which one you chose.
Pepsi Cola.
Yeah?
Hey, Steve. It's Mike.
Hey.
Hey. Um, I think I may have
found a project for you.
It's more of an R&D
outcast than anything,
but it's actually a project
you approved some time back.
Why don't you look into it?
So this is
the Macintosh team.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, Jesus.
Nope. It's just Steve.
It's really good
to see you, Steve.
Bill Atkinson. It's good to see
they got A players over here.
Mmm-hmm. Hey. Get up.
Hi, Steve Jobs.
What's your name?
Burr...
Burrell Smith.
Oh, sorry for the mess.
We're just a bunch
of degenerates. So...
It's okay.
I like degenerates.
Yeah.
Who's your project lead?
Uh, Jef Raskin...
I don't know where he is.
Jef Raskin.
Okay. I'll deal with that one.
I'll be taking over now.
Um... Sorry, taking over, like,
the entire Macintosh project?
Yeah.
Awesome.
Where's your design team?
Team? I don't...
Show me
your current build.
Well, obviously ease
of use is a big feature here.
We're trying to develop
a simpler interface
that's geared towards
the real layman end user.
But, we're kind of struggling with
the interface, and, to be frank...
The results have been.
Shit.
Yeah.
What's it got
under the hood?
Standard kick ass stuff.
64K RAM...
Two 56 bitmap
display, Motorola 6809.
We're gonna run the 68000.
But dude,
that's Lisa's processor.
That's correct. Dude.
I don't care what the budget is.
Give me their processor.
Done.
Hey, Steve.
How are you, man?
Chris, it has been a...
Yep.
You're working on the Macintosh?
Yeah.
Good.
Good, this is
gonna be fun.
Okay. Let's go back to what
you were saying before.
This thing is for
the everyman. Right?
That's our end user.
It's the school teacher.
It's the garbage man.
It's the kid. it's some grandma
out in Nebraska. Right?
So we need to make
this thing simple.
It's gotta work like...
like an appliance.
Hey, Jef.
Steve Jobs is here.
Since you weren't around...
Some of the project leads were
having a meeting with Motorola.
Why exactly are you here?
I'm here to help
build the Macintosh.
Ah. I'm not sure that
that's practical for us.
We're actually trying
to avoid this project
becoming another
over bloated disaster.
Okay, Jef.
You got my attention.
Look, Steve.
You didn't want to be involved
back when we started this thing,
and that was fine by me.
I just wanted you
to cut the checks.
Be involved,
just don't tum Macintosh
into a measure of
revenge for you.
Everyone knows about your
fallout with Team Lisa.
So trust me when I say,
we're doing fine.
Okay, Jef.
Let's get
a couple things straight.
We don't do fine.
And we don't accept things
the way that they are,
and we don't
stop innovating.
Now, your machine lacks power.
And your little interface,
it needs work.
And I'm here
to help with that.
Now, I'm not trying to take
Macintosh away from you.
I want you on this team.
But you can either get on board,
or you can get the fuck out.
Okay. Now, we've got a lot of work to do.
So, let's get to it.
Bill, you come with me.
Okay. Where are we going?
Recruiting.
Shit.
Hey, Steve.
Hold these for a second
Yeah.
Thanks.
What, what's going on?
What are you doing?
Steve? You're on the
Macintosh Team now.
What, Ste...
What's a Macintosh?
Andy Hertzfeld.
Are you good?
I only want good people
working on Macintosh,
and I'm not sure
if you're good enough.
Excuse me?
Bill Atkinson says
that you're good.
I... Yes.
I think I'm pretty good.
Are you creative?
I... I think so.
Welcome to the Macintosh Team.
I'm tired of saving
your ass, kid.
You love saving my ass.
I want my own
engineering team.
You can pick them yourself.
And I am done
working under the gun
of your ridiculous
deadline bullshit.
You might as well be asking
for a date with her.
I want that, too.
Done.
Serious, Steve.
So what is this, Steve? Some
sort of performance review?
How are things
going on the IIE?
Things are great.
Really great.
You're bored to death,
aren't you?
Yes. Yes I am.
You want to come work
with me on the Mac Team?
You're trying to recruit me
for the Mac Team, aren't you?
Okay, I'm in.
You've gotta have a problem
that you want to solve.
A wrong that
you want to right.
And it's gotta be something
that you're passionate about,
because otherwise you won't have the
perseverance to see it through.
I don't ever want to hear you tell
me that you can't make it faster.
I mean, millions of people
are gonna buy this machine.
And we can't look
at the competition
and say we're
gonna do it better.
We have to look at the competition and
say we're gonna do it differently.
We have an opportunity to build
a revolutionary machine.
And in your life you only
get to do so many things.
Right now we've
chosen to do this.
So let's make it great.
It's great.
No. It's not.
It's insanely great.
We should try to get more
memory into it if we can.
We can still hit the timeline.
Take a look at it.
This little Macintosh side project
has gotten out of hand, Steve.
Way beyond the pale.
First you created a $10,000
monstrosity with Lisa,
and now you've
poured millions
into what was supposed
to be a minor diversion.
You've missed
multiple ship dates,
and meanwhile, IBM is
just purring along.
Steve...
People don't use computers
the way you think they do.
How are we even supposed
to market the Macintosh?
We don't
You give me 5 candidates for CEO.
You're gonna let me choose.
I say we choose someone
with a marketing background
to help us sell
what's never been sold.
Now, while I would like
to run my own company,
Mike has helped me understand
that you don't think I'm ready.
Yes, because you're not.
Okay.
I want John Sculley.
John Sculley?
President of Pepsi Cola.
The Pepsi Challenge guy.
He's smart,
he's a marketing genius
and he'll do whatever
it takes to succeed.
Steve, Sculley
is a tough get.
Maybe the toughest
on our list.
What the hell makes you
think you can get him?
Why would he
ever leave Pepsi?
Nobody remembers the world's
best soda salesman.
I need somebody I can trust.
You can
make a great product.
But you have to
convince people
that what you're
selling is greater.
We're not selling computers.
We're selling what they can do
with a computer.
A tool for the mind.
And that,
ladies and gentlemen,
is limitless.
Because people will
never stop believing
that they could get
more out of something,
whether it be their jobs,
their marriage, their money,
their lives.
That's what you have
to do with the Mac.
It's the belief
in the limitless.
The impossible.
That no matter what you
dream, you can do it.
And Mac will
help you get there.
A few months ago, when Steve
was visiting me in Manhattan,
he asked me a very important question.
He said,
"Do you want to sell sugar water
for the rest of your life,
"or come with me,
and change the world?"
Well,
here I am. Thank you.
It is now 1984.
It appears IBM wants it all.
Apple is perceived
to be the only hope
to offer IBM
a run for its money.
Will Big Blue dominate the
entire computer industry?
No!
The entire information age?
Was George Orwell
right about 1984?
No!
Today
we celebrate the first
glorious anniversary of the
Information Purification Directives.
For the first time
in all history,
a garden of pure ideology,
where each worker may bloom,
secure from the pests.
Our enemies shall
talk themselves to death.
First time in all history.
We shall...
prevail.
On January 24th, Apple
Computer will introduce Macintosh
and you'll see why 1984
won't be like 1984.
Good work.
Some response, huh?
I can't believe it.
It's a revolution.
The thing's
a game changer.
You really outdid
yourself, Steve.
Hey. Why don't you
give me a call?
Grab some dinner or something.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'd like that.
Steve.
Arthur.
Great job up there.
Thank you.
Steve, I want you to know
that we believe in you.
I hope you know that.
Thank you, Arthur.
Hey.
What was that?
What...
Rock. He just...
Said something,
"we believe in you."
What's going on?
It's the Macintosh.
You know, we had
them run the numbers
100 different ways,
100 times over...
- You're marking up the Macintosh.
- Yep'
If we keep it as is, we'll be
hemorrhaging money by launch date.
You're gonna price out
the consumer.
Well, we can't take the risk
of flattening our profits.
No.
We can't have it both ways.
I mean, you insisted on the
most expensive hardware.
The Mac was originally
much cheaper.
Jef Raskin
designed a $1,000 box.
I made it great.
If you want the company
to remain profitable...
Whose idea was this?
It's a group decision.
It was mine. Not Michael's,
not the Board. It was me.
We don't do this, John.
IBM does this shit.
Steve...
Not Apple. Not me.
Look, don't make me
the villain because
I'm looking out for our
company's best interests.
Steve.
Some things have to change.
If you keep heading
down this path,
I will not be able
to protect you.
They got to you.
They?
How'd you get this?
Arrived yesterday. It's pre-beta,
obviously, but it's all...
It's a blatant rip-off.
Get me Bill Gates
on the phone.
Let me make this
perfectly clear, Bill.
So that when I'm finished, you
can still see through those
thick pretentious glasses, you
psychopathic, unimaginative criminal.
You stole my software,
and I can prove it in court.
And I'm gonna sue you for every
cent that you have ever made.
And I will make it my life's mission
to see to it that you never,
never,
ever make another dollar that
I don't first take 90 cents.
I can only assume that you
are all as irate as I am,
and you're simply
too dumbfounded to speak.
Mr. Jobs promised
us a million units.
We have yet to reach
a quarter of that.
Something has to change.
With two failed projects,
overextended R&Ds,
and that Microsoft fiasco,
we're about to experience the first
quarterly loss in company history.
IBM beat us to market
by 2 years
with a better product
and better sales.
The Macintosh is not even a toy.
It's a joke.
IBM has now moved
on to mini decks.
And so should we.
What are you
getting at, Arthur?
Gentlemen, I believe
it's time to reconsider
the viability of
the personal computer.
Steve, anything to say?
What would you
have me say, Arthur?
You raised our price.
Don't put that on me.
The problem is not the price, Steve.
It's your product.
You over-hyped the Mac.
You told people to wait. You sold
the future of the Macintosh.
And as a result we lost
2 years of sales.
It's not my fault.
Well, it sure as shit
is somebody's fault.
Well, I'm not
receiving any support.
You're stripping
me of my resources,
and dumping millions
into the Apple ll.
Do you know why we keep dumping
millions into the Apple II?
Because it sells. It's 70% of our revenue.
How's the Mac doing?
I made my opinion
perfectly clear.
If you want to keep sucking on the
tailpipe of IBM, then I can't stop you.
But I will not take the blame for
the failures of some court jester.
All right,
this is crazy, Steve...
No. No, no. To whom are
you referring, Steve?
I don't know, Arthur.
You tell me.
John, you're awfully quiet.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
I guess I'm just
at a loss for words.
Head of marketing.
Pepsi genius.
Loss for words.
It's him. Not the Mac.
But the cost
of that process...
$10,000 price tag.
That price tag...
Goes against him,
and not against Mac.
It's ironic, isn't it?
You chose Dylan, I chose,
I chose The Beatles.
Seems so backward now.
Woz.
What are you doing here?
Good to see you,
too, Steve.
I'm... I'm a little bit busy.
Just, do you mind
if we talk later?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. This'll
only take a minute.
I, uh...
I'm leaving, Steve.
Okay.
No. No, Steve.
I'm leaving Apple.
For good. Actually,
I already did. I just...
I thought I should come
back and tell you first.
Why?
We both knew this was coming
for some time. I don't even...
I don't even remember
the last time we talked.
What do you want
from me, then?
Not everyone has
an agenda, Steve.
Right.
You know, I can still remember
when we were just kids,
back in your dads garage.
And we just wanted to
create cool toys for people like us.
You remember that?
Yeah.
Now it's not about
people anymore for you.
No, it's about the product.
Worst of all, it's...
It's about yourself.
You're the beginning and end
of your own world, Steve.
And it's so small. So sad.
And it's...it's
gotta be lonely.
And I know you're gonna say
that the product
and the person
need to be connected
and all that,
but it will never be
what you think it will.
It just won't.
No, not' not for
a long time at least.
I don't know what you think
is going on, Steve, but I do.
And it doesn't
end well for you.
And I'm not...
I'm not sticking
around to watch.
It's been a journey.
And for the record,
I love what we did.
Hi. You've reached John Sculley.
Please leave a message.
Hey, John. It's Steve.
Uh...
I just...
We're still partners,
John, you and I.
We are, we're in
this together.
And I, um...
You just give me a call back?
That'd be great. Um...
Hey, Mike. It's Steve.
Would you give
me a callback?
Please?
John, you have
to take control now.
Do you have any idea how close
our shareholders are to a panic?
The implications
of your inaction?
Forget your job, the entire
company is at stake here.
This could ruin everyone.
I know, Arthur, but I still
think that we can salvage this.
Can't salvage anything.
I doubt...
Steve.
Mike.
John.
Steve.
Arthur.
What the hell are you
doing here so early?
I could ask you
the same question.
This is good.
Steve, why don't you join us this time?
Have a seat.
This time?
Steve, have a seat.
John?
Arthur, I don't want to. Yes.
You do. Say it.
Tell him what
you've told me.
I find it increasingly
difficult to do my job
when the greatest
obstacle in my path
casts a looming shadow over
everything I try to do.
What did you say?
Steve...
You are your own worst enemy.
And this company's.
This... It's unbelievable.
Who do you think you are?
I'm CEO of Apple Computer.
Hiring you
was the worst mistake
I have ever made.
Steve, it doesn't
have to be this way.
Okay. That's done.
Boards
don't run companies.
The people who create the
product run the company.
He has the nerve to tell me
we should have used the 512.
We told them that
it needed a 512.
We said not to use the 128.
We knew 128 kilobytes wasn't gonna
get it done when we built it.
Sculley is leaving
for China tonight.
He's gonna be there for
a week, so we got time.
We just gotta recruit.
Sieve, Sculley's
gonna find out.
And then what happens,
you know?
He's the CEO of
the company now.
Well, for now.
But we have the people
who make Apple.
Oh, hey, Mike.
We're just getting started.
Guys, give us a second.
John's canceled his trip.
He's having an executive staff
meeting first thing tomorrow.
So I didn't come to join your revolution.
I came to warn you.
He wants to make
absolutely sure
you're nothing more
than a figurehead.
No power, no title.
No team.
I remember thinking when we first
met, um, that you were remarkable.
You wanted to do
something truly great.
And I did, too.
I still do.
Raise the white flag. Concede to Sculley.
I'm begging you.
No.
You can't win this one.
Whose side are
you on, Mike?
Because there are sides now.
And you're either with me
or you're against me.
Are you with me, Mike?
Yes, Steve. I'm with you.
Okay.
Those in favor
of John Sculley.
All in favor
of Steve Jobs.
Mike.
Every Board member's vote
must be accounted for.
Mike?
Sculley.
I vote for Sculley.
So, now what do we do?
Apple's market value has
eroded in the past several years,
which led to the ousting of former
chief John Sculley in 1993.
Ed Woolard,
former CEO of DuPont,
has joined Apple as
Chairman of the Board.
New CEO Gil Amelio says
sweeping changes are necessary.
Jobs' computer software company
NEXT, has entered into buyout talks
with his former company,
Apple Computer.
Hey, will you wake up Lisa and
see if she wants breakfast?
Yeah.
Lisa?
Lisa? Come on.
Are you gonna
sleep all day, huh?
Oh, go away.
Why? I say all day
because it's 10:00.
Laurene made you breakfast.
I'm not hungry.
Well, you can't sleep
all winter break.
Yes, I can.
Reed! Reed!
Can we not run in the garden?
Please?
Thank you.
Were you able
to get Lisa up?
Well, how can a human
being sleep that much?
She... I don't know
if she's coming or not.
I'm going to the farmer's market today.
Just gonna get a few things.
You have any plans?
You want to come with me?
Hmm?
I said do you have plans?
Today?
Well, Gil Amelio
is gonna stop by.
They're transitioning in
some of our software.
Okay.
I'm... I'm just helping them out.
They just need a little help.
Oh, boy.
I'm in trouble,
aren't I?
Steve, what can I do to
convince you to come back?
What can you do
to convince me
I wouldn't be boarding
the Titanic, Gil?
Because I know how you feel about Apple.
What NEXT could never be.
Plus, you know, considering
that you now own
a million and a half
shares of Apple,
I mean, that's
a tangible investment, too.
You guys must be
pretty desperate.
We're not desperate.
How are things going
with the Newton?
Look, don't blame me for the
failures of the last regime.
It's not as bad
as you think.
You're overseeing
massive layoffs.
Apple stock just set
another record low.
And you're 4 months
from insolvency, Gil.
I'd say that's pretty bad.
Well, yeah. In order
to fix what's broken,
some sacrifices
are necessary. All right?
Steve, what do you need?
Name it.
Steve.
Gil.
Mike.
It's nice to see you.
Come on,
I'll show you around.
No, Gil, don't worry about it.
I'll give him the tour.
You sure?
Yeah, sure.
No problem. Come on.
That's great.
You guys go ahead. I'll...
I'll catch up.
There's something I
always wanted you to know, Steve.
It was never my call.
Let's not do this, Mike.
No, this is important.
You know, I tried.
I wanted you here.
I always did.
It's too bad it took me
so long to get you back.
Oh, I'm not back.
Yeah.
You will be.
We'll see about that
You know, I'm gonna show myself around.
I'll take it from here.
Son of a bitch.
Who did these?
I did, sir.
Who are you?
Jonathan Ive. I'm Director
of Industrial Design.
Why are you still here?
It's 11:00 a.m.
on a Monday.
No.
Why are you
still here at Apple?
This isn't
the company I built.
There's no taste, no style.
No design.
So unless they're shackling
you here, why do you stay?
Well, sir, I guess I would
say there are still
those of us that believe
in what Apple stood for.
What you stood for.
What do you think
I stood for?
I think...
I think you believe
that the computer,
or the Walkman,
or whatever it may be,
should be a natural extension
of the individual.
And it's that mission,
that devotion to quality,
and ideals, and heart...
That's what keeps us here.
That we might do it once more.
Okay. Whatever
you're working on,
the rest of the day
I want you to forget it.
I want everyone to
design something new.
I don't care what it is, I
don't care if it's technology,
just create something.
Something useful.
Something you care about.
Steve.
We're glad you're back.
I'm not back.
Yet.
Steve.
Ugh!
Junk.
Steve, you met
our Chairman, Ed Woolard.
Steve.
Hi.
Look, um...
I know all about the bad
blood you must taste.
And I understand your hesitation to trust me.
But I just want you to know
l am not Arthur Rock.
I'm your friend.
Okay.
So, can we take
a minute to talk?
Apparently.
Today's Paper-
I'm sure you've
seen the news.
I'm sorry, Ed, you're gonna
have to be more specific.
Our shares dropped
7.5% overnight.
It's the lowest
it's been in 10 years.
Last week
an unidentified investor
dropped one point
5 million shares.
Put a real scare into
the marketplace, Steve.
1.5 million shares? Wow.
I guess the stockholders
must be getting restless.
We want
you here, Steve.
I'm here.
As a consultant.
As CEO.
CEO?
Yeah.
At least in the interim.
And Gil?
Yeah, well,
Gil's halfway out the door.
He has to see
the writing on the wall.
At least if he's not
too proud to admit it.
Oh, he's going to try to force you
out, and make a case against you.
Where have I
seen this before?
Gil's on the ledge. He
doesn't have a play here.
All we need is
a little push from you.
If you want to get back what
you lost, this is the time.
I never lost it.
It was stolen from me.
There's no sex left in computers.
No curves.
Now, if computers are
for art, and beauty,
and global interconnectivity,
why are they so ugly?
You know, it should be artful.
But no one cares.
The world may mistakenly see
computers only in black and white,
but we live, and we dream
and we paint in color.
And we think
the computer should, too.
What do you think?
Jony, I always want you
to be honest with me.
No matter what.
Just be brutally honest
Understand?
Understand.
What do you think?
I think, I think the blue,
it's not quite right.
Here's a dopey idea. What if
we put the speakers inside?
Yeah, Steve,
Gil Amelio and the board
are not gonna allow that.
No way.
We're not gonna
ask for permission.
Steve's done an admirable
job assisting me
as an advisor during
this, this period.
And while I commend his
actions, and his initiatives,
I believe it's now in our
best interest to move on,
and relieve Steve of his
advisory role in this company.
I agree, Gil.
You do?
I do think it's time Steve step
out of his current role, yes.
Steve?
Thank you, Ed.
I'd like to present the Board my
vision for the future of Apple.
We're not Microsoft or Dell.
So we need to stop
trying to be that.
We need to go back to who we
are, and what we do best,
and throw away
everything else.
Here's how
we're gonna do it.
We're gonna build
a new line of computers
for the home,
and for the office.
We're gonna build a new operating
system on the backbone of NEXT.
The next generation
of Macintosh.
And we're gonna kill
every other project.
Everything.
This company will not
make shit anymore.
We're also gonna double down
on the advertising budget.
Chiat Day will be the only
advertising agency we use.
Just like back
in the old days.
In short,
we're gonna make
Apple cool again.
But I will not be
able to move forward
without the Board's permission to
operate under complete autonomy.
I'll be made a full voting member
of the Board. And lastly...
Interim CEO.
Now, hold on.
I'm the CEO, and this is...
Look, you put me
in this position.
Apple is like a ship with a hole in
the bottom, and it's leaking water.
And it's my job
to make sure that
we point the ship
in the right direction.
So why don't you
let me do my job?
All right, let's
put this to a vote.
Those in favor?
What the hell?
Ed?
Mike?
Sorry, Gil.
Nothing personal.
When you grow up,
you tend to get told
the world is
the way that it is,
your life is just to live
your life inside the world
and try not to bash
into the walls too much.
But that's a very
limited life.
Life can be much broader,
once you discover one simple fact.
And that is that
everything around you
that you call life
was made up by people that
are no smarter than you.
And you can change it.
You can influence it.
You can build your own things,
that other people can use.
It's to shake off
this erroneous notion
that life is just there,
and you're just gonna live
in it, versus embrace it.
Change it' Improve it.
Make your mark upon it.
And once you learn that, you'll
never be the same again.
But in our cash position...
Mr. CEO.
Mike.
You wanted
to talk to me?
Welcome. Please.
Have a seat.
Ed. Hey, Gareth.
Mike.
What's this?
It's an opportunity.
I haven't seen Bernard
around for a few days.
Wheres Katherine,
Delano?
Mr. Lewis and Mrs. Hudson made
a difficult decision easier
by agreeing to step
down from the Board.
Really?
They both agreed to accept incredibly
generous golden parachutes.
The same opportunity is
detailed inside that envelope.
So you're forcing us out?
With good reason.
And what's that?
The current arrangement is
inhibiting.
I can't hold everyone's hand
while we cross the street, Mike.
And so your next big move
is to eradicate your Board?
And you think you
can just do that?
I'm sorry, Mike.
But it's time.
Take the parachute.
It's more than fair.
20 years.
You know, I told myself
I'd be out of here
while I was still
in my thirties.
And now look at me.
I'm practically an old man.
Gentlemen.
Thanks, Mike.
So...
What are we gonna do now?
We're gonna put
a dent in the universe.
Here's to the crazy ones.
The misfits,
the rebels,
the troublemakers,
the round pegs
in the square holes,
the ones who see
things differently.
They're not fond of rules,
and they have no respect
for the status quo.
You can quote them,
disagree with them,
glorify or vilify them.
About the only thing
you can't do
is ignore them.
Because they change things.
They push
the human race forward.
And while some may see
them as the crazy ones,
we see genius.
Because the people
who are crazy enough
to think they can
change the world
are the ones who do.
How was that?