Don't make us worry, Cemal. Write soon.
Yes. And don't wait too long yourself.
How did you get a Swiss visa?
The man said it does not matter.
But is he reliable?
Without a risk
you can't even cross a river.
Mama Papa!
The children are running to the train!
Mehmet Ali went to the train!
Come away! - No, you go away!
You call this looking after each other?
And you look at your mother!
What's going on, scaring us like that!
Papa, did you bring us something?
Give the horse some water.
You yell at the children too often.
The man said it's better
if I take you along.
Already now?
Apparently they accept families easier.
So we will all go.
Are you crazy? How can we afford that?
Should we leave the children here alone?
Why alone? Mustafa is almost grown up,
Fatma is old enough to get married,
and then there are still my parents.
But when can we let them come?
How do I know?
Maybe soon or a little later.
I'm not leaving the children behind.
And what will I do there all alone?
You'll work, like Miisliim's wife.
The children here, me there?
No, I won't come with you.
You always throw stones on the path!
Papa, look what arrived!
A postcard
from Uncle Cemal.
Well, read it.
"Dear Ali Haydar. We have arrived safely.
Miisliim and his wife have found work.
We still have to wait.
It's true, this really is paradise.
Butter would flow from the udders
of your goats. The yoghurt would be firm
like ice cream from Maras. Once you've
crossed the mountain, everything's okay.
God be with you. Cemal."
Did he find work?
They will start soon.
Is his wife working, too?
Sure, why not? Give the horse some water.
She works with
her big belly?
Don't I work
with a big belly?
Working in a factory makes you dead tired
and grow old before your time.
And how do you know?
I see their faces when they come back.
But they come back as rich people.
With cars.
You're putting that into your
children's heads, and about going away...
They can see it for themselves.
Are we missing anything?
Nothing and everything.
Papa, are we going away?
No one is going anywhere.
And anyway.
With what money do you want to leave?
I would sell the horse and the cows.
And put your sons before the thresher?
If it works there, who needs a thresher!
You think it's all that easy.
Is it easy
anywhere for people like us?
Even grass comes out with all its roots.
Once you've sold everything,
you're worth less than this grass.
You'll be without roots, a nothing.
My father will be going there. If you eat
this grass, butter will flow from your
udder, says Uncle Cemal. Maybe that will
be your stable. Nice, isn't it?
What are you up to? Nothing but nonsense
in your head. What's to become of you?
You're a good for nothing.
At least don't sell too cheap, son.
How much is the Swiss chocolate?
20,000. We also have this one here.
I would like 150 gr. of this one here.
Be a good substitute for your mother.
Thank you, Papa.
Look after your brothers and sisters.
Leave the goat alone! Let it go!
Leave her here, mind your own business.
That's enough! I have visitors.
Welcome, Haydar.
So you've brought your wife. Well done.
Is everything ready?
Everyone is going abroad.
If this goes on, for whom will
our government reign? - We're still here.
Certainly.
How much did you bring?
Two million, as you said.
I believe you.
We must trust each other.
They've turned out fine.
Are there no political problems?
No, nothing. - That's fine then.
This man will give you passports and
tickets. He'll take you aboard the ship.
He will also exchange your money.
Our money is worthless there.
Take care of this piece of paper.
Don't worry, he's a reliable man.
In 2 weeks you will be in Istanbul.
He will expect you at dawn.
Have a good trip. - Thank you.
May God reward you.
Oh, before I forget.
If I were you, I'd take along more money.
One or two million.
Prices got higher there.
As if it were different here.
Anyway, good luck.
The man did not look very reliable.
Cemal said he is reliable.
Why keep the bad news for the end?
It's not his fault.
Do things get cheaper here?
I don't know how we're going to manage.
Suggest something instead of complaining.
I want you to buy this field.
Too small. What could I do with it?
There won't be enough money for the trip.
All right, I will buy it. For your sake.
You're my neighbor.
Thank you. - You're welcome.
I hope my money will bring you luck.
What's wrong?
I won't come.
But everything is ready.
I won't leave the children behind.
Again?! We can't take any
children along. We've decided
and that's it.
Without the children I won't move.
I'll also take the baby.
How can you work
if you take the baby?
They have day care for babies.
They have what?
It's better to leave our children here
with my parents.
They aren't registered in our passports.
A baby doesn't need a passport.
Meryem, be realistic.
Everything is arranged, we're going.
We gave our savings for this journey.
All you speak about
is money.
We sold everything.
Now we only have
this house and this money.
The daughter-in-law is right.
You have already sold everything,
at least take a boy with you.
Send him to school, let him become a man.
You have pulled out your roots. Now we
need a boy who can grow new roots.
Maybe then he will save the family.
Whom should I choose?
They all mean the same to me.
I'm old and with one foot in the grave.
You are not too young anymore yourself.
Kids get accustomed easier.
Only they can change things, not us.
Slowly, slowly.
Slowly, or it will spill over.
Mama, buy me a Pepsi too.
That man is staring at me. Who can he be?
What are you up to?
Let me have some too.
No, no.
You can't drink all of it alone.
What will the man say about Mehmet Ali?
I hope he won't make any trouble.
"We are three, understand?" I'll say.
That's what I'll tell him. After all,
we pay for the trip, don't we?
I have to pee.
Wait. He will stop soon.
But I - What can I do? Wait.
I have to pee now.
He has to pee. What shall we do?
He has to hold it back.
I have to now!
Now is not the right moment.
You must have drunk a whole barrel.
Papa, is that the sea? - No.
If you continue it will become the sea.
There, my So...
that is the sea.
How nice.
Let's go and find Yasar.
I'm looking for Yasar.
He's inside.
The passports are ready.
Where is your wife?
Outside. There is something else.
Your tickets are also ready,
and the 1,000 marks.
No Swiss francs?
Aren't you happy
with marks? That's 1.5 million liras.
1 million, lthought.
The mark has become more expensive.
Do you want them?
All right, I want them.
Here, one million.
Something else
You get good seats.
When you get to Milan,
go to the train station and do exactly
what it says on this paper.
Then throw it away, that's important.
Do you see the boat over there?
That's where you'll go on board.
Okay have a good trip.
Are we leaving now?
Who's he? Are you taking him along?
How can he go on board without a ticket
or a passport? That's impossible!
You idiots!
Didn't you tell him?
The boy has to stay behind.
Then I'll stay too.
The boat is about to leave, it won't wait
Think of something. It's your fault
that things are the way they are.
My God!
You were afraid to tell him.
God, give me patience.
It's your decision.
Maybe there is a way,
but it's a risk.
Are you aware of that?
We cannot go back any more.
All right, let's try.
Thank you, Yasar.
Good luck and have a good trip.
I hope they won't forget us in here.
They won't forget us.
Hurry up Hurry!
Come, this is my cabin.
It's warm here, and you are safe.
Sit down here.
We can sit here.
No, no. Here. Me, there.
Thank you for saving our lives.
We're not used to being locked in.
In two days we will be in Naples.
O Kay?
I want to look out at the sea.
Take off your shoes.
Wait for me here.
Wait here. I will look for someone
who will bring you to Milan.
Come and sit down here.
We've made it.
This is where a new life starts for us.
Papa, it's so nice here.
100? Forget it! 100 each.
300 for the three of them.
200, okay? 200.
300. We don't argue about prices.
Switzerland is expensive.
Do you have 300 marks?
Don't be rude.
That's okay. That's all right.
That's right. Milan. Schaffhausen.
Me, Schaffhausen, Switzerland.
You? From where in Turkey? From where?
Yes, Turkey.
Yes, but from where?
Not bad.
Stop, another one for me.
Let me see.
Did you see how nice? See?
Madam, did you see how nice you are?
How much? - Two, 10,000 lire.
Now three. 15,000 lire.
Here, my family. My women.
Oh, yours.
7 children.
Exactly seven.
Don't you have any condoms?
Bravo. Me two, and that's it.
What, Switzerland? That's Switzerland.
Me Switzerland.
No. Me Switzerland, you Maras.
Me, mother, father, Switzerland.
You you .. you Switzerland?
We go to Switzerland.
Into paradise behind the mountain.
Me Switzerland, you Switzerland.
So you want to go to Switzerland.
Well, then come with me.
You, with me to Switzerland.
Yes, Switzerland. Do you have a passport?
Switzerland over there.
Paradise they say.
Is something wrong?
No idea.
Why police?
They have no right to enter our country.
You want to make them enter illegally.
And you know you are not allowed
to carry more than 3 people.
That's not my fault.
I don't want any trouble
because of them.
Hey, friend,
let's send them back to Italy,
to Milan.
And we take care of the rest together.
All right?
I'm a Swiss customs officer,
not a businessman. Understand?
There, central station Como.
Como. There.
Then direction Milan.
Here, that's for the train.
For the train.
I'm sorry. All the best. Bye.
Thank you.
Maybe we'll meet again.
Show them the way to the station, please.
Bye-bye.
What does it say?
In the big bar in the main hall
a man will come up to you.
Over there is something like that.
Get out, hurry!
What about our suitcases?
Leave them in the car. Come on, hurry.
Look, I'll tell you the real price.
Amongst friends, of course.
1.5 times 3 is 4.5.
That is 4,500 marks.
Let's say that you have 2,200,
so you still need 2,300.
How are you going to find that money?
Not even two people can travel with that.
I got them hooked,
leave them to me.
Well did you find a solution?
That's all we own.
A lot of money, but with that
you can start your trip back home.
We can't go back impossible.
Do you have passports?
Yes, two.
They bring something. Not much, but
What's that?
From my cousin. He's over there.
What happened to it?
The goat chewed on it.
Goats are clever animals.
Listen, your cousin Cemal,
can't he send you something?
We don't know where he lives.
He was with you - at least I thought.
I Will find him.
Here. Take this and go.
Come back tomorrow.
Till then I'll have found him.
Haydar, take the passports.
Go on. Don't worry, nothing will happen
to your money. Leave it here.
Go now and come back tomorrow.
Bring them back to the station.
Find a way to get the money.
Shit, we are not fit for this world.
If my father could see us now
There must be a solution.
Those men seemed reliable to me.
Them? Reliable?
We mustn't give up hope.
Look who's coming.
Haydar, look who's coming.
Hello.
Are we on the same route, heading north?
One gets closer in foreign countries.
You are still missing 2,100.
In marks.
And what about Cemal?
We've found him, he's fine.
He's in a home for refugees.
He doesn't have a work permit,
but he's fine.
But he wrote he would start to work soon.
If not today, then tomorrow or later.
Just a moment.
Thank you.
Bravo.
Our people are like that.
In difficult situations we help each
other out, isn't that so?
Aldo, bring them to the villa.
I'm not thirsty, thank you.
I don't want to drink either.
It's not to drink, but for washing.
It's time to pray.
Let's not waste drinking water.
Waste'?! What do you mean, waste'!?
When traveling, praying is not mandatory.
What? God should forgive.
Have you become unfaithful, just because
we are in the country of the unfaithful?
God have mercy and stand by us.
In which direction is Mekka?
God forgive us!
Anybody not happy can get out, okay?
Who else has something to fuss about?
You want to start a new life
and carry your whole past with you.
You can't cross the mountain with that.
Do I look weak?
What's wrong? - Just a moment.
Since Istanbul
you've been making trouble for us.
You have a healthy son,
but life doesn't consist only of that.
One has to earn money.
I also have a wife and three children.
I have seven.
I found a job for you.
Soon you will earn lots of money over
there where the chocolate factories are.
You like that, don't you?
You only have to sign here that you will
give us a part of your salary
in exchange for our help.
How much? - Half of it.
I have a family, it won't be enough.
Half is enough. Do you have a pen?
Come on.
Sign here. Sign.
You will start a new life.
Don't make such a face Come on.
Now listen, everyone.
If anything goes wrong
and the immigration officers catch you,
then you know what to say, don't you?
Everything about me, nothing about you.
And what will you tell the police?
When you're over there
you have to ask for the Polizei.
If you turn yourself in,
they will keep you.
If you get caught, they'll send you back.
When registering
at the police station
ask for "political asylum".
You are all political cases.
Do you understand?
How do they distinguish
between real refugees and others?
For God's sake. I'm not a refugee
nor a political case.
They will realize that I'm not
so unfaithful as you all are.
You are incredible, Uncle Haci.
What? - You're incredible.
The weather is against us.
Don't worry, these people are not
looked for, they are country folks.
That may be so,
but that doesn't change the weather.
Come on, get ready. Come on
Hurry up, grandfather. Hurry up!
How do you want to carry all this stuff?
There is no sense. This is pure suicide.
With all this stuff, I'm not going.
What do you mean?
The weather is against us.
I can't change it. Ciao.
What's happening?
Massimo doesn't want to do it.
They must cross the mountain today,
tomorrow there will be others.
If you want to stay alive,
get rid of these people quickly.
But the weather
It's great. The immigration officers
will stay inside warming their asses.
I can't take the responsibility.
Leave the responsibility to us.
If you don't like the weather,
they will find the way by themselves.
The group is too large.
We'll divide them.
Tell them where to go, and they'll go.
They don't have to follow each other.
Go over there. You too.
My son is coming with me.
Okay, take him and go over there.
Why is this man not coming with us?
Didn't we bring you here comfortably?
You can go the rest of the way alone.
Shall we carry you on our backs?
Take the path Massimo described to you.
Keep together. At the first deviation
split up. One group to the right,
one to the left of the mountain.
As long as you walk up, you're in Italy.
When it goes down, you're in Switzerland.
I'll wait for you over there.
If nothing happens, I'll find you.
If something goes wrong,
you'll have to look for yourselves.
You were supposed to take us to paradise.
You're supposed not to cause any trouble
and not to be weak. Come on, come on.
Hurry up, don't leave the path.
If he lies this way he won't suffocate.
He will regain consciousness soon.
You will get us into trouble!
I think this is the place the man said.
According to the sign this must be it.
Mama, like the ice cream from Maras.
This way or that way?
Didn't you hear what the man said?
I don't care about the man.
God is my only leader.
I'll go where I want to.
Does anyone want to join me?
Don't you think you could endanger us?
How should we know the right way?
Let's go the way Haci Baba said.
Sit down here. Don't move.
Leave that suitcase.
Why do you always walk downwards?
There are important things in there.
Main thing is, we get over the mountain.
Forget the suitcase! Go on!
Meryem, forget the suitcase! Go on!
I told you he was nothing but trouble.
What's wrong, Haci Baba?
A cramp in your legs?
Fetch water. - I'll give him a massage.
What are you carrying around?
Are you smuggling gold? - Books, books.
Books?! Do you think I'll carry
your goddamn books over the mountain?
Stop! Stop, don't sin! Stop!
Leave the books
and drink this.
Down there. Looks like a tunnel.
Eat something. Here, have this.
It will be over soon, my son.
Mehmet Ali, eat. - No.
Friends, let's go on.
Othenlvise we'll freeze here.
We'd better split up.
Who goes first?
Me.
Are you serious? - Yes.
Till now we have helped each other
as much as possible.
Our goal is right over there. I'm going.
Is anyone coming with me?
Ekrem, go with him, take care of him.
The men and I will take the steep path,
Haydar and the women go on the easy path.
I'll leave these goddamn things here.
We'll wait for you across the border.
Good luck.
Tasso, keep quiet!
Have you finished?
Yes. And are you going to work all night?
I will close soon.
Let's go inside, Tasso. Come on.
Grazer, come on out, somethings wrong!
Disperse!
Where is Mama?
We'll find her.
Hurry, Meryem fell.
My leg
Calm yourself. - Easy
Stop! Stand still!
Political asylum! Political
We will take a look at that tomorrow.
You come with us now. Go on, walk!
Is my leg broken? My shoe!
Wait here. I'll go and look for Mama.
Be very quiet and don't go away, okay?
Maybe it's Haydar. - No, be quiet.
What happened?
It's Ekrem.
Did you see Haydar and my son?
Didn't they come with you?
Go on, hurry up.
Hurry come on, hold on to me.
Hurry, othenlvise we will be caught.
Papa, did you find Mama?
Be quiet.
Papa, I'm so cold.
I am freezing.
Scratch your head, you'll be warm.
Will we visit Ramser in Switzerland?
This is not the right moment.
Slowly. There is something.
It's closed.
Don't talk nonsense.
Not even I would find the right way.
Tell us with whom you came.
He said there was nobody else with him.
That's bullshit.
How did he find the way?
Allah showed him.
What? Him, too?
He lied, I knew it right away.
Where are they?
Back there at the pool.
I'll get dressed first.
Sound an alarm for a search on the pass.
The border control calls up too.
Another six persons are in the border
area, one of them a child.
Probably their lives are in danger.
I understood that, over.
Resist a bit more, my son.
It won't take much longer.
You are strong.
Your mother is waiting for us.
Move a little.
My twig has fallen down.
It's lost in the snow.
Attention, attention! I repeat.
Your lives are in danger.
You might get lost any second.
Don't be afraid, we will help you.
Approach the lights.
I repeat.
Ivan to Charly, come in, please.
What's up?
Did something happen?
Up to now, nothing.
We are moving towards the old Roman path.
The dogs have not reacted.
Will call as soon as we notice something.
They are looking for us.
They speak Turkish.
Do you understand what they are saying?
They are looking for us.
It's a trap. Someone has betrayed us.
But they won't find us.
Wait. Let's try to understand them.
I know what they're saying.
They are offering help,
but I don't believe them.
I did not come all this way
to get caught here.
Don't give up!
I have no energy left.
We are here!
Damn it!
Why this punishment, God?
In Ali's name, please see me!
Here we are!
God, I am at the end.
Papa, where are we?
We'll be there soon, I promise.
Pull yourself together, all right?
Tea? Coffee?
Tea, please.
Any news?
I'm afraid not. They're still searching.
Any news from my son and Hayden'?
No, but don't worry, they'll be alright.
Did you get their personal data?
Personal data!
You can't talk with them!
I won't register uninvited guests.
Wake them and register them properly.
No one will be awakened and registered.
I won't let you mess them up again.
These people need our help. I don't care
what they are called and where they go.
But I care. If everyone thought
he could come, where would we be?
Many more will be coming,
whether you like it or not.
The water is up to our necks.
So you better learn to swim.
And you better learn Turkish, so that
you can talk with your new clients.
Aldemir is a good teacher.
Jealous?
We don't register people
according to swollen feet,
but according to name and origin.
Whether they like it or not.
Help! We want to go to the police.
I am not a police officer.
Come on, get in.
Renato, this is Bruno.
Suitcases in the back. In the back.
I just picked up two madmen.
They ask for the police.
Finally - we are rescued.
Help! Help!
Wait for us help!
This is Switzerland?
I guess this is Switzerland.
Is this Switzerland?
He doesn't understand.
He doesn't answer Look!
Help! Help us!
Help! Help my son and me!
We'll do an ECG.
Wait outside.
Who are these people? - No idea.
Can you stay with him?
Yes. You have a blanket for him?
Outside in the closet.
We are happy that they found you.
Please, Haydar, these men
would like to ask you a few questions.
And what about my son?
I'm not leaving without my son.
He's in good hands.
I'm not leaving without him.
Don't worry, he's in good hands.
They will only ask a few questions.
I didn't harm anybody.
Your son is dead!
Dear Haydar. We have arrived safely.
Miisliim and his wife have found work.
We still have to wait.
It's true, this really is paradise.
Butter would flow from the udders
of your goats. The yoghurt would
be firm like ice cream from Maras.
Once you've crossed the mountain,
everything's okay. God be with you.
Is he Cemal?
Looks like a Turk, doesn't he?
Sometimes we all look like Turks.
I'm sorry. He needs to be put
in custody.
What are the charges?
Illegal crossing of the border.
In our eyes he remains responsible
for his son's death. He stays here
until we can clear this matter.
Exhaustion and exposure as the doctor
found out is not enough proof?
He did not expect as much coldness here.
Not even here is there only sunshine.
We both know very well
that other facts are involved.
We would like to know
what and who brought them here.
Haydar, what made you come her?
Hope.
My condolences.
I am so sorry.
I brought you something.
Thank you.
What's happening with the boy?
Mehmet Ali will be buried at home
so that he can give us new energy
and so that we won't lose hope in future.
And you can also tell him that
I would like to join in on the burial,
on the expenses, I mean
And if he needs anything else
I would have liked to become your friend.