♪ A game of broken hearts...
♪ When I woke up
this morning, the... ♪
♪ This world
is not my home ♪
is not my home... ♪
You have mail.
Ghost.
Password accepted.
Lisa, I'm for real.
Are you?
There's a price to pay.
Close and send.
Jesus.
Didn't mean to scare you.
That's OK.
Um, well, you here for...
A room.
I have a reservation.
OK. Well, let's go
to the office.
Your girlfriend?
Uh... No, no.
She's just a guest.
Nice place you got here.
Thank you.
I do my best.
Go in the other door over there.
So, uh...
How long you here?
Passing through.
OK. Miss...
Ms.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Ms. Smith, right?
Yeah. Well, um...
I'm J.T. Welcome to
the Lone Star Motel.
And if I can do anything
for you, just, uh...
Hi.
The key.
Oh, yes.
You are number seven.
Lucky seven.
And is that your car?
'Cause if that's your car,
you can just, uh... You can
leave it right there.
Don't touch it.
Don't go anywhere near it.
Sorry. Did I
interrupt something?
Oh, no, no. She was
just checking in.
Hey, I was wondering
if y'all had some magazines.
What kind of magazines
you looking for?
You know, like Cosmo or Vogue or, you
know, like, some fashion magazines.
'Cause I'm going
to be a model, and
I need to keep up
with the latest trends.
You're going to be a model?
Yeah.
Wow. Yeah, you could be a model.
I think so.
I'm Tanya.
- I'm J.T.
- J.T.!
Where the hell did you put
that Crescent wrench?
Now, how am I
supposed to fix the...
I'll see you later,
J.T.
Anytime.
What was that for?
That's a warning.
Where's the wrench?
It's on top of the file cabinet.
Yeah. Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm not too sure about this.
Well...
Who's that?
Tanya.
You boning her?
Not yet, I'm not.
But you're planning on it?
You couldn't get the Beamer?
I hate the Hyundai.
Well, it's more than you've got.
She looks trashy.
I know.
I love that.
Sorry.
Asshole!
Jerk. Hey, hey!
Watch it, fag boy.
Oh, my god. I hate
this fucking town.
What? What did you just say?
Did you say that you
wanted to suck his cock?
Get off me!
I can help with that.
Come here. Come here.
Get off!
Put him on his knees!
Want to give a little suck
in front of us all, huh?
Save your boyfriend!
Come on, James!
Come here, you little shit!
I know where you live, man!
Stupid fuck! I can't believe
that cross-breeding...
Just drink your beer.
Relax.
Fucking asshole.
Don't you want to
just fucking kill him?
Yeah. Cut his fucking dick off?
I absolutely would love
to do that.
I'd love to shove it
right down his throat.
But you know what? It isn't
going to do any good.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about wherever I
go, for the rest of my life,
I'm going to run
into redneck Joey
at the 7-Eleven, at the
Wal-Mart, at the K...
I know you're not
planning on spending
the rest of your life here.
I mean, that's insane.
We're getting out of here.
Who's going to run the motel?
Have your father hire someone.
We're getting out of here.
Yeah, maybe you are.
You are, too.
I don't think so.
I'm not quite sure
what goes on over there.
Me, neither.
It must be a party or something.
You know, I bet the woman next
door, she gets pissed off.
What woman? What woman?
Well, there's some chick
in number seven.
She drives a cutlass.
Nice car.
Yeah.
Very nice car.
Oh, god. Oh, god.
I'm too drunk
to talk to anybody.
That's OK. You don't
have to say a word.
Hi.
How you doing?
What are you boys doing?
Well, uh, we're hanging,
having a good time.
We're going
to go skinny dipping.
Yeah. Y'all are drunk.
A little drunk, yeah.
You got any beer left?
I got this one.
You can have it.
Thanks.
Uh-huh.
Me and James were, uh...
Were brawling earlier
with this big crowd of guys.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
They were all...
Cowboy boots and...
yeah. Tough guys.
Oh, yeah.
I like tough guys.
Well, I like naked women.
How sweet.
You want to go swimming?
I would love to,
but there's
no lifeguard on duty.
Well, that's not a problem,
because I can save you.
Do you think you could?
Absolutely.
See, I read this manual
and I learned how to do
mouth-to-mouth and
that heart-pumping thing.
Heart-pumping thing?
Yeah. That's right.
Yeah, I feel safe now.
You're really scared?
Not about drowning.
Listen...
I'll make you a deal.
Wait.
What are you doing?
Well, I'm getting naked,
you're getting naked,
and then, my friend,
she is getting naked.
Uh, no. That's my cue to leave.
Oh, James. Come on.
Huh?
OK. Go.
I'm going. I'm going.
I just ain't never seen a
model get naked before.
Me, neither.
I'm talking about you.
Oh.
OK. Go.
Let's go.
I'm going. I'm going.
I don't know why
you're sitting down,
'cause you're going in,
like, 2.2,
you know what I'm saying?
All right.
Right. I know.
I know you know.
Nice.
Yeah.
You have a great body.
Thank you.
For a farm boy.
OK. Let's see it.
Let's do it.
OK. Go.
All or nothing.
We're playing a game here.
We're having fun.
Right.
All or nothing.
Or nothing.
You are brave.
Thank you.
It's your turn.
To what?
To come in the pool.
Come on.
Please.
It's not fair, really.
I'm not very fair.
Seriously. Please,
will you get in the pool?
Come on.
I need some beauty in my life.
Tanya, honey?
Tanya?
Whoo! All right!
Was it worth it?
Absolutely.
100% worth it.
100%?
Uh-huh.
Absolutely.
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- J.T. Hello!
- Hi!
Look who it is, hey!
Hey!
Come on in!
Great.
Party town.
♪ This world
is not my home ♪
is not my home... ♪
Tanya.
Tanya, honey, I'm leaving.
Tanya. You up?
Tanya!
Morning, Tanya.
Tanya. Honey,
what's wrong?
Tanya, what's wrong?
Tanya.
Tanya, wake up!
Jesus. Drunk?
Daddy, go away. I don't
have any clothes on.
So fucking what? You
scared the shit out of me.
Go away.
Come on.
Pull yourself together
before tonight.
We got more people coming.
Daddy, you said we could go to
Paris and I would be a model.
Right.
That's just what
we're going to do.
A couple more gigs, Paris.
Uh-huh.
Par-ee.
You have to be 20.
I'm already... 20.
A model? Right.
Daddy's going to make sure
that never happens.
Concentrate.
Clear.
I'm keeping
my clothes on tonight.
Yes, me, too. Unless, of
course, she just begs.
Oh. Well, yeah.
Right.
In your dreams.
You know? I think that
I'm going to go get her.
But I mean... why don't
we just, you know,
hang out for a while,
the two of us?
Fine. If you're going
to pout, just go.
I'm not pouting at all.
Just go. Well, that's
what I'm doing, man.
Relax! Lighten up.
Have fun.
Tanya?
Hi.
Hello.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
Good. Well, um,
you want to come out?
Can't.
We got some beer.
Thanks. All right.
I'll see you later, OK?
Can I help you, son?
Uh, no. No. I was just seeing
if Tanya wanted to come...
Did you get my little
girl drunk last night?
No.
You know, I'm hoping
you can respect
our right to privacy.
I'd hate to tell
your old man that...
we were leaving this...
really fine hotel for another
'cause you was harassing
my daughter.
Harassing?
Run along, junior.
What was that all about?
Let me tell you something.
I cannot believe that he
just put his hand on me.
I mean, all these fuckers
telling me what to do...
first, that chick, and now him?
Wait. What chick?
Come on. The chick in number seven.
The one who has the car.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, exactly. Well, first
her, and then this dickhead.
Hey. Fuck you!
Fuck 'em.
Yeah. I mean, fuck 'em.
They don't have
to live here. We do.
Oh, man. Motherfucker.
I mean, this is going to
be mine one day, right?
Oh, yeah. So you're a
prince among thieves.
No. I am a king.
Well, long live the king.
Thank you very much.
Hi.
What's that?
Having trouble finding the key?
I don't...
The office key,
the one with
the black rubber on it.
Listen. If you're from the police,
I told them everything...
Why don't we go inside?
After you.
OK. Great.
Listen, do you mind if...
Why don't we just go and
come back for her later?
She'll be out in a minute.
You said that a half hour ago.
I know, but if we just give
her a couple more minutes...
You're totally stuck
on her, huh?
No.
Just because you saw her naked?
Yeah, just because
I saw her naked.
I mean, I got a thing
for a beautiful girl
who gets naked with me.
Don't you ever get
a hard-on for a girl?
Sure.
Yeah. Sure.
Wait, what is that
supposed to mean?
Oh, forget it.
Come on. We'll go...
No, I'm serious.
No, come on. We'll...
I mean, just because
I care about my hair
and my clothes...
Forget it.
I said that I'm sorry.
No. As a matter
of fact, you didn't.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Well, I actually
want you to say it.
Look at this. Oh, my god.
I love this car.
What's the problem?
I don't know.
It won't start.
Are you kidding me?
This is ridiculous.
We're stranded here
on a Friday night?
Damn it! Fuck.
Oh, my gosh.
Wait a minute.
Wait, you're not thinking...
Just do me a favor and
don't... Don't touch the car.
Well, then,
how are we going to get it?
Oh, man, is she stacked!
All right.
This is perfect.
Look. She's showering.
You get up there.
No!
No, you're going
to keep an eye out.
I can't believe that you drilled
a hole to spy on people.
Well, it's a boring fucking town.
What can I say?
Get out!
Man, muffled: Hey!
What the fuck is this?
Fucking blackmail scheme?
You middle-aged punk!
Yeah!
Hey!
Hey, Tanya.
- OK. Come on. Go!
- Let's go. Let's go.
Tanya, come on.
Is that your dad?
Is she coming? Yeah.
Sure, she's coming.
He's over there.
Come on. I don't think
this is a good idea.
No, it's a very good idea.
I don't have any shoes.
That's OK. We're going
to take care of everything.
She's going to know about this.
Shh. No, she's not going to know.
We're going to have the car back.
Now, listen. Don't touch the car,
'cause I'm going to hit the alarm.
- This is your car?
- Yes, it is my car...
Not exactly.
For tonight, it is.
Look, go hit neutral.
Go hit neutral.
We're going to push the car
away from the building...
Are you serious?
So no one hears it.
OK. Here we go. Shh.
Hit it in neutral.
Excellent.
Excellent. OK.
Push. Push.
Push. Push. Push. Push.
Come on. Come on.
Let's go. Get in!
Oh! God damn it!
Where's my car?
Where's my fucking car?
Shit!
Over-fucking-confident
shit!
♪ Come on, boy
♪ I want to dance now
♪ Line by line
♪ We talk all night, yeah
♪ Hold me down,
I think I'm flying ♪
Whoo!
♪ Everybody's eyes
are shining... ♪
I have to say,
I'm getting quite fond of
the little machine myself.
It's too bad you can't keep it.
I know. It's just
not a chick's car.
You know what I'm saying?
What are you talking about?
Well, you know, this car...
it's just built for a man,
like a man.
It is a man's machine.
Well, maybe it belongs
to her husband.
You should...
Oh, yeah.
You shouldn't be driving
it either, then.
I'm going to check
the glove compartment.
Assneck.
What's an assneck?
Total assneck. You don't even
know what an assneck is?
No. What's an assneck?
Nothing. Hey, give me
the keys to the trunk.
I'm going to open it.
What's an assneck?
No. Not "what's
an assneck?"
"Where's
Exactly.
Where's your assneck?
You want to know
where my assneck is?
Well, I'm going
to guess on my ass.
Nope.
The ass part of your ass?
Uh, yeah.
Could you be more specific?
J.T.?
What do you think that is?
I don't know, but it stinks.
Yeah, it does.
OK. Let me explain it
to you.
Your assneck...
You guys are so stupid...
is between your
scrotum and your...
That's Dr. Brewer.
Oh, my god.
Do you think she killed him?
Somebody put bullet
holes in his head.
This is so beautiful.
I swear to god. This means
that I can keep the car.
I can't believe it.
What?
Absolutely! Because
if she killed him,
then she's not going
to report the car stolen!
Do you see?
Am I right?
If she killed him,
she would have no
problem killing you.
You know what? I'm so not
worried about that, because...
Oh, my god.
And this so beautiful.
But she doesn't know
I have the car.
I'm just some kid, like,
who gave her a key
and, you know, took a
piece of paper from her.
I love this.
That's true.
No! There's...
That's a good point.
There's no fucking way
we're keeping this car.
We have to call the cops.
You know what? It's a
fucking dead body.
You can't leave it in the trunk.
Um...
Yeah, that is a problem.
That is
the problem, J.T.!
I can't even believe
we're discussing this.
You put it in the lake.
Yeah. I was thinking that.
That's a good idea.
We can weight it down
with something.
We'll probably find
some rocks or something.
This woman killed this man!
That happens to be
against the law!
Oh, you're such an assneck!
Total assneck!
Yeah, right?
Here. Help me...
Help me get him out.
This is great.
See it?
Don't spill my beer.
I'm begging you, as a
friend, not to do this.
One, two, three.
It's totally heavy.
Will you listen
to me for a second?
All right?
This is my only chance.
I'm never going to own a car,
not even a shitty one
like your Hyundai.
We do not have the money.
We're never going to have the money.
Do you understand?
This is not the way.
There are other ways
to get a fucking car.
Well, this is my only shot
and I have to take it.
It's wrong!
It's not like we killed him.
Shut up.
We're helping. She's not
going to get away now.
Hell, where's she going
to go without her car?
Exactly.
I can't even believe that
we're having this discussion.
Something's leaking.
Oh. Ugh.
Oh, my god.
Oh, god.
Put it back.
Will you help me bring it
into the lake, please?
No. I said no.
Please, James?
Just come over here and help
me bring it into the lake.
Fuck you, J.T.
Where are you going?
I'm going home.
All right.
Let's hurry.
You ready?
We should put some rocks in
the thing to weigh it down.
Yeah.
Close his eyes. Jesus.
All right.
All righty.
Is that it?
Yeah.
Want to go for a swim?
Not really.
Where's James?
He went up, uh...
Up there.
Should we go get him?
Probably thinks
he can walk home.
Shit.
I cannot believe this.
Look at this!
I haven't even had
the car a day,
and already, I fuck it up.
Come on!
I'm cold.
Go.
Hey, big boy.
You want a ride?
You're in my seat.
I'll move.
So did you finish?
Are you coming or not?
I wasn't there, all right?
All right.
It's wet.
It will be fine.
What did we do, man?
We didn't do anything.
Just don't think about it.
It's better that way.
Hey, faggot.
Where did a couple of
pole-smokers like yourselves
get a fine-lookin'
piece of ass like that?
I didn't know you were
looking at my ass, Joey.
What?
What did you say, you little...
Pull over!
Pull over, you little fuck!
Pull over! Hey!
Hey, pull over,
you little ass licker! Huh?
Pull over so I can fuck
your girlfriend!
Yeah, fuck your girlfriend!
Pull over.
I don't think that's
such a good idea...
Pull over. Let's give
him what he wants.
If they try to drive
off, block them.
Yeah.
Well, well, well.
Where did
a couple of fags like you
get a fine-looking machine
like this? Huh?
Is there a problem, huh?
Problem?
Don't worry.
You and your lover there, you
can have a little fun later on,
screwing in a new light bulb.
You swing a pretty mean bat.
Whoo-ee! Ha ha!
How did you get all wet?
You want to know?
Can I hold your bat?
Uh, I don't, uh...
Can I hold it in my mouth?
You fucking pig!
You had to call me faggot?
That's right, mother!
Last out! Aah!
Fag! It's a fucking faggot
kicking your fucking ass!
You stupid shit! Son of a bitch!
Stupid shit!
Piece of dumb ass! Ugh!
Freakin' hick!
Oh, you stupid,
ugly dumb-ass shit-faced...
Let's go.
Where are we going?
I know a hiding place.
So, you're really going
to keep the car?
Yes. I cannot exactly return
it looking like this.
She'd kill you.
All right.
What next?
I don't know. Maybe
we should rob a bank,
rape somebody.
I don't know.
Shut the fuck up.
It's a long walk back.
Let's go.
I'm this way.
See you later.
Hey. Shouldn't we kiss
or something?
Some other time.
Well, sir, what do we got?
Well, it's him, all right.
He's real goddamn dead.
Yeah.
You been by the house?
They're still taking photos.
It's all mixed-up,
you know?
Who are they?
Are those the guys...
Yeah, those are
the guys that found him.
Found him. Yeah.
They were fishing, and, uh...
He was floating near the shore.
They thought he was an alligator.
They were going to shoot him.
Yeah. This is all
screwy, you know.
This is all screwy, you know.
Yeah. What's screwy
about it is...
There's something screwy?
Have you been to the house?
Well, yeah.
Well, it's pretty neat
in there, right?
And then you come here, and
it's all out in the open...
A floater, everything. The victim
is floating right here, you know.
It looks like two people did it.
It looks like, uh, one was a
pro and the other an idiot.
Well, you know many professional
killers working in town?
'Cause I don't. No, this was
done by somebody's boyfriend,
somebody's husband,
one of the women that got him indicted.
I don't know.
Got it.
Yeah. This guy was assaulting
his female patients.
Eight of them banded together
and got him indicted.
You seen the paper?
No.
Hey, Neal, quit fuckin' around.
Come here, give me that paper.
Hmm.
Says here you have
him in custody.
Well, I guess I do now.
You got a problem.
Yeah, no shit.
But I knew the guy,
he was going to
turn himself in today.
He didn't want a big,
uh, production
with reporters and
handcuffs and everything.
I screwed up.
Yeah.
You killed him.
Hey, don't even joke about that.
My wife's been crying ever since
she found out he was missing,
so, uh, I don't even know
what that's about.
But don't scratch me off
your list of suspects.
Hmm. God bless
the women.
Whoever did this was no woman.
Ordinary woman, a housewife,
or anything like that,
it was an expert.
Do you think
they're still around?
No.
I think the guy who
dumped them in the lake,
he's still around.
Police believe
Dr. Brewer was already dead
when he arrived here at the
shores of our own lake Coleman.
And then he was thrown
into the lake
by his killer, or killers.
I spoke with
detective Lopez earlier,
and he told me that several
clues found at the scene...
They dumped the body?
Jesus, what the fuck
is going on?
Who could be that stupid?
Stars shine bright on the lone
star motel, this is Arthur.
Oh, hello, James.
No, he's out somewheres.
Yeah, your car
is still here. Why?
No, he is supposed
to be back, but he ain't.
All right,
I'll tell him. Bye.
James just called for you.
He did?
Yeah, he's coming over.
Are you fixing his car?
Yeah.
Seemed awful concerned about it.
Yeah, well, you know how he is.
Yeah? Well, I don't want
to know how he is, J.T.
Now get in there.
Dad?
Yeah?
Did you clean up number seven?
No.
The lady said
not to be disturbed.
She did?
Yeah.
Did she say anything else?
What else?
She wants to marry me.
No, really.
Really.
Hey.
Yeah.
What you got?
Tell you what we got.
We got paint chip over here.
From a tree,
could be our vehicle.
Um, we got footprints,
tennis shoes, bare feet.
That's a beach.
So what?
So what, yeah.
We got tire tracks.
It's probably our best lead.
I'm waiting on the make.
Tire tracks?
Our best lead is tire tracks?
Well...
Jesus Christ.
Someday you'll grow up
to be a detective like me.
Well, the title "detective"
infers that you would be
able to detect something.
That's the best you can do?
Neal, give me that list.
I'll tell you what
we're going to do.
We're going to go by
every hotel and motel.
Here you go.
I don't give a shit what you do.
Just give me something.
Yeah.
We'll look for somebody that
looks suspicious, you know?
I think this guy is probably
a Joe salesman-looking
kind of guy.
Nobody to look at.
Oh, Jesus.
But, uh, deadly with a gun.
Look, we...
We made a mistake.
It's not too late to admit it.
We did some terrible things
last night.
I know. I can't believe I
threw a dead guy in a lake.
We... We can just
go to the cops
and tell them the truth.
And this Brewer guy,
he was a scumbag.
Won't we get arrested?
Maybe.
And what about her?
Well, what about her?
Is she still here?
Well, I don't know, you know?
It's kind of hard to tell.
I've been watching, believe me.
You had to sleep.
Exactly. So who knows?
You know, all my life
I've lived here,
all I wanted was
something different,
something...
I don't know.
Something that's mine.
Hi.
How you feeling?
Like shit.
We were just talking
about last night.
What about it?
About how it's not too late
to do the right thing.
Which would be?
Go to the cops.
Right.
Look, it was
a stupid thing to do.
It just got out of hand.
Out of hand?
If we just tell our story
and stick together,
everything will be fine.
I woke up with the guy's blood
underneath my fingernails.
Look, I'm just saying...
You didn't.
Stay cool.
Car trouble?
Yep, she's dead as a doornail.
Don't worry, I won't bite.
I was just
getting out of the way.
Why do you have that off?
Um, well, I was just...
Put it back on.
Yeah, I was just
about to do that.
You sure it's got gas?
Yes, ma'am.
Do I look like your mother?
No.
Then don't call me ma'am.
Take it.
Be careful, it's loaded.
I seem to have lost something.
I think you boys
know what it is.
I think you know who has it.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
These two help you dump
the body in the lake?
No.
Get in the car.
Just bring me the car,
you little weasel,
and I'll let you keep
your pathetic little life.
Fuck you.
Ha, what?
You heard me.
You killed Dr. Brewer,
the three of us know it.
I want your car, and I want you
to get the fuck out of here.
I practically built that car
with my bare hands.
No redneck teenager...
No, you see, I'm not a teenager.
Shut the fuck up or I'll
tear your tongue out.
I could take that gun from her pretty
little hand right this second,
kill all three of you.
One, two, three.
Take this Hyundai and disappear.
No one would find me
because I don't exist.
But you do.
Your fingerprints are all
over the inside of that car.
His, too.
Strands of her hair are in the
backseat where you fucked her.
We didn't fuck.
Please, be quiet.
Was there blood on your hands
after dumping him in the lake?
Probably.
Now that blood's
on the steering wheel,
in your room,
on your clothes, even.
Just a trace and, well,
if I were a cop,
I'd be much
more interested in that
than, say, a weak story
about a woman in number seven,
lucky seven,
that no one can find.
Cops.
Oh, god.
Give me the gun.
How y'all doing?
Very good.
How you doing?
You J.T.?
Yes, sir.
And what's your name?
Uh, James.
James Wooly.
And you?
Tanya Bayer.
Ma'am?
Smith.
Do you know a Joey Evans?
What's so funny?
You know him, J.T.?
Yeah, I know Joey.
You see him last night?
Nope.
What about you, James Wooly?
No, no, I... I... I didn't
see Joey last night.
That's real peculiar,
'cause, uh,
Joey came down to the
station this morning,
he was pretty badly beaten up.
Said the three of you did it.
He's got a witness.
Says you jumped him
in a parking lot in town.
Said you were driving a
black Camaro or trans am.
This is the only car I own.
Yeah, we just
got it started, too.
Do you own a car?
No.
What about you ladies?
You got a car?
You see a car like that around?
I hear little Joey's got
a drinking problem.
Isn't that right, James?
Y-yeah.
Maybe Joey's got my friends here
confused with someone else.
Maybe Joey just
fell down drunk last night
and, uh, hurt himself.
Yeah, very possible,
'cause we were here all
night long swimming.
So is that the story
everybody's going to stick to?
Um...
You got something you want
to tell the officer, James?
No... No.
Look, we were here last night.
There were people here
to vouch for us.
Yeah, whatever.
All right.
How you guys doing?
You, uh, you guys go out
to the lake last night?
No.
Look, we told you.
We were here.
We were swimming.
We told your partner.
And what's your name?
Smith.
Smith?
Yep.
Is that first name, last name?
Smith is my last name.
And, um...
You're not from Coleman,
are you?
Just passing through.
And what's your, um, visit here?
I'm just visiting
my nephew J.T.
Uh-huh.
Oh, you guys are related?
Yep.
I got to ask
some questions here.
So, um, are you here
on business or pleasure?
Is that an official question?
Well...
I could be...
No, no.
No, it just seems to me
that you're dressed up so...
Elegantly.
You're a 5-star type
of girl.
Thank you.
All right.
You need help with the car?
Uh, no.
I can get you a tow truck
right away.
No. I think
it's going to be fine.
All right.
All right, guys.
Take care.
Say hello to your dad.
Detective.
Yeah?
What's your name?
Guadalupe.
Guadalupe Lopez, yeah.
Detective Lopez...
Yeah?
Uh, is there a problem
with the lake?
We had a floater.
What's that?
It's, uh, we had a
dead body at the lake.
Um, here.
You can, um, give me a call.
Top number, you can
call 24 hours, OK?
So, you're a pack of thugs.
You scare me.
You kids go on a crime spree?
How many other people
saw you in my car?
It's my car.
J.T.!
You're trying to prove
something, aren't you, kid?
Now's not the time.
You seen your pop lately?
No.
No?
Know where he is right now?
No.
Well, I do.
What about your dad?
What about him?
Do you love him?
I... I don't know.
Because after I kill
J.T.'s dad, I'll do yours.
Or maybe I should
start with Harold,
seeing how he's a pimp.
My dad is not a pimp.
And I suppose I could just look
up your name in the phone book.
All right.
We'll get you the fucking car.
I knew I could
count on you, James.
It's fully dark
at 5:30.
Don't bring the car
out until then,
and don't let anyone see you.
In front of my room,
keys and all, 5:45.
If the car's not there,
I start with the families.
And I work
my way in... to you.
That is so great.
This is perfect, we have her
exactly where we want her.
I'm going to fucking
kill you, man!
I swear to god!
You got us into this!
Now the fucking cops
are after us,
and this bitch
is going to kill us!
Relax, OK?
She is not going to fucking
kill anybody, you understand?
You fucking son of a bitch.
All you care about is your
fucking greed and yourself!
Well, you know what?
Leave me the fuck out of it
and give her the fucking car.
Son of a bitch!
You think he's upset?
A little.
Tanya, let's go.
Shit, my dad, with a client.
So?
So... So I gotta work.
What do you mean you gotta work?
Just get the car, OK?
You are the most beautiful girl
in the world.
What do you want?
I'm sorry, hon.
I got a fella here who's
interested in investing.
I thought you could fill him in
on some of the details.
Come in.
Sit down.
That's OK.
I'd as soon stand.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
You're choking me,
for Christ sake.
What's the matter,
you don't like that?
Not very much, no.
Your wife doesn't
do that to you?
No, no.
She doesn't choke you?
No.
She doesn't tie you
up and make you beg?
No, she doesn't do any of that.
Hmm.
Don't play dumb, daddy.
Maybe you're the one
that does the spanking.
Spanking, huh?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Make my day.
Ahh.
No, I...
Go ahead.
I can't do that.
See, that wasn't so bad, was it?
No, it wasn't so bad.
Yeah, go again.
Harder.
Let me hear the proposal.
Well, the 5,000 level,
the return is slow.
At 10,000 level, you get
your money back quicker.
What are you doing?
You're a whore, aren't you?
You're going to be
my little whore.
Jesus.
I heard about you
from the boys in town.
I couldn't wait to meet you.
Ah, you're just about
to meet Mr. Wiggle!
Ah.
Don't you want to meet
Mr. Wiggle?
Say hello to Mr. Wiggle
or he won't come out!
Don't you want to meet
Mr. Wiggle?
No!
Oh, I'm going to fill
that wet, screaming mouth!
I'm going to stuff
your mouth full!
Sorry to interrupt,
but I thought I heard
the word "no," right?
Let me leave!
I'll leave!
You wish!
Oh, goddamn!
Kill him.
I can't. I can't.
Go ahead, I got him.
Put the bell to this temple.
I don't know.
What about the cops?
I'll take care of you.
Do it!
No! Don't do it!
Don't do it!
Ta da!
I got kids and a wife!
This is a private party.
You're next.
What the...
Hey!
Hey, what's going on in there?
Blackmail's hard on a girl, huh?
If I kill him, will you
keep your promise?
What promise was that?
To take care of me.
Take care of yourself, sister.
I'll do whatever you want!
Take a good look
while I clean up.
Get a good look?
Uh-huh.
There you are.
Did you notice
who's not in the picture?
You.
That's right.
What are you doing?
Shut up!
I've seen what you
do for a living,
familiarize yourself with
what I do for a living.
I want my car.
Oh, my god.
What are we going to do?
She's not going to let us go.
What are you doing?
J.T.!
J.T. Ain't here, James.
Well, do you know where he is?
I just come in.
I ain't seen
hide nor hair of him.
He's supposed to be watching
things around here, but...
Yeah, thanks.
What?
He's taken it.
J.T., he's taken
the fucking car.
Shit. Where is it?
I don't know!
If I knew, I wouldn't...
Shh, shh, shh!
What time is it?
It's 5:00.
We're going to die in 45
minutes, I swear to god.
OK, all right, maybe
he's bringing it here.
Maybe?
Maybe?!
Shh.
Are you comfortable with maybe?
Oh, what the...
Look what you started.
Ugh.
Do you know who
that is in there?
Mr. Wiggle?
That's the fucking mayor.
Well, not quite.
You don't understand.
She's going to kill us.
No, she's not going to kill us.
If we don't bring her that car.
No, she is not going to kill us.
I don't care what you do, man.
But you better do it.
I will.
You have got to get
the fucking car!
I will.
I will not die
in this fleabag motel.
Come in.
You're not going to give me
a gun again, are you?
You want the gun?
Take the gun.
I'm sorry.
That was mean.
Take the gun.
Take it.
He's not bringing
the car back, is he?
Get out of here.
Think you can get out of here?
Do you?
No, you're here
for something else.
You're not going anywhere.
Have you got a plan?
I think you've got a plan.
You got a plan.
Well, there you are.
Hey, dad.
James is looking for you.
James is here?
Yeah.
His car is still out front.
Don't y'all have school tonight?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
How's it going?
What?
School.
Oh, yeah, it's fine.
Fine.
I, um,
I'm real proud
of you, J.T.
Sticking with it
the way you have.
I know it's gotta be hard.
Thank you, dad.
Where'd you see James?
He's out front
talking to somebody.
OK.
What are you doing tonight?
Eh, I don't know.
OK, well...
Watch TV, I suppose.
I mean, what I always do.
OK. Um, there's, uh,
been a lot of robberies,
I was hearing on the,
you know, news report.
So, you should
really be careful.
Lock your doors
and check the windows,
and...
All right.
Have a good night.
Yeah.
You know, get an American car.
Jr, Jr, Jr, J.T.,
come here.
Um...
Are you in a hurry?
Yeah.
Where you going?
Class.
Oh.
You going to, uh, college?
Mm-hmm.
You're a college boy now.
All right.
Let me ask you something.
How many guests
do you have in this place
staying in the last
couple of days?
Uh, just... three.
Three?
Uh-huh.
Can I see the register?
Yeah, but I mean,
it's just that girl, and...
Just... Just let me see
the register. OK.
All I've got...
is this...
Tanya... Oh, that's the girl.
The blond.
Is that your girl?
No.
No?
All right.
Harold...
Yeah, that's her dad.
That's her dad?
Mm-hmm.
And then my aunt Smith,
didn't fill out a card.
All right.
All right, you know, I had...
What's that?
No, I was just, um...
Hi.
Hello.
All right.
Um... What's your name again?
I forgot your name.
Tanya.
And what's your last name again?
Bayer.
Bayer. And you're...
You're in business?
You... pleasure?
What...
My dad's here.
Your dad's...
I'm with my dad.
Oh, your daddy's here, right.
And is your dad, um...
All right.
Is your dad... And your dad is in
business or something like that?
Yeah.
All right.
Is he here?
Is he staying here?
Yeah. He's in number five.
Can I talk to him?
Number five.
It's right there
on the end, on the left.
What's his name again?
Harold.
Harold, Harold.
All right, J.T.
Mm-hmm.
You know, you give me a call.
Whenever, you know.
If you hear something,
you know, we just...
We have to check every motel.
Of course.
And, uh, it's just going to
take a little time.
We might be back, you know?
Do you have anyone else
working in here?
Just me and my dad, yeah.
Yeah, just you and your dad.
Good luck.
All right.
We got to get the
fuck out of here.
No shit.
Do you think
he's going to get her?
Smith?
Yeah.
No. We're going
to end up in jail.
I'm not worried about that,
but I'll tell you something
I am worried about
is the fact
that we can't bring...
Her car here while
he's here, you know?
Are you really
going to bring it?
I don't know.
I think we should go get it.
Well, that's what
I'm going to go do.
I'm going to get it.
I want to go.
I'm going to get it, and I'm
going to bring it close to here,
and then I'll check out
if he's here.
I'm going to get in the
backseat with you.
It's really cramped up in there.
Perfect.
All right, we could do that.
Should we go?
Yeah.
All right, let's go. OK.
Uh, dad, I'm taking the Beamer.
What about your car?
Uh, later.
Where are we going?
Right over there.
Where's the car?
It's in there.
Oh, you moved it?
Yeah.
Why did you move it?
Because she pissed me off.
You know what, she was acting
all superior and everything,
and it was just like...
like I had to do something.
You were going to keep it.
No, I wasn't going to keep it,
because it's just a car,
and I don't want people
to get hurt.
I'm not going to keep it.
You painted it?
Yep.
You know,
I was going to keep it,
but I guess I should
take it back, right?
Right.
Oh, Jesus.
No, it wasn't me, I swear!
You ask Tanya!
This way.
She knows I wouldn't do it.
Sorry.
I'm innocent.
It was a tall woman.
Don't put me in here!
Ask Tanya!
They're closing in on us.
Move it, now!
I replaced the tires
so the cops could not
trace it back to the lake,
and...
Probably the coolest thing.
Every state.
It's beautiful.
Wow.
She thought of everything.
I know. It's too bad
I have to give it back.
Yeah, but...
I'm about to give you
something much better.
Close the door.
Red?!
Are you fucking kidding me?
Red.
You changed the tires,
and you got shitty
fucking taste in music.
Shut that thing off.
And get on your knees!
James, get over here.
We had to, man.
On your knees.
Why?
On your knees!
Do it.
She's going to fucking kill us.
Tape their hands.
The tape's in my bag.
She's going to fucking kill us.
Shut up.
Why are you doing this?
You said if we helped you,
you'd leave us alone!
Now get the fuck out!
- Aah!
- Hurry up.
You're a fucking bitch! I can't
believe you're doing this!
Why are you doing this?!
You stole my car.
It's just a stupid piece
of machinery.
I trusted you.
You said you wouldn't kill us!
I'm not going to.
She is.
A deal's a deal.
What deal, Tanya?
You had a deal with me,
you fucking bitch!
Just get in the car.
I want to leave
right when this is over.
No.
How sweet. A Judas kiss.
Tanya.
Please...
No!
OK, let's go.
The gate?
Are you dead?
Deaf, what?
Ohh...
Huh?
What?
I think I'm deaf.
I'm not dead.
Well, she said
fall no matter what.
What?
Tanya, she said fall.
I know.
She saved our ass, didn't she?
I can't believe...
what about her ass?
I think I'm deaf
in this ear now.
Not dead.
Get out.
Here.
You're a pretty smart girl,
you know that?
You think so?
You wouldn't be here
if I didn't.
What are you doing?
I thought you loved this car.
I do.
Sometimes, you have to
kill the things you love.
And sometimes you don't.
Are you coming?
Better hurry.
What now?
I don't do divorces
and it's never personal, OK?
You're quick and loyal.
That's good, because if you
killed those boys back there,
I would have had to kill you.
What?
They were friends.
If you'd done them, I never
would have trusted you.
Our ride's here.
Hey! Hey,
what the hell?
So...
Do you still want to be a model?
No.
What do you suppose those
boys are doing right now?
Swearing off women forever.
Let's hope so.
You brought the Beamer!
Bitching!
I love it!
Shut up, shut up.
Come on, let's go.
Let's get some beer, let's
go for a ride. Come on.
Might as well.
There's nothing else to do.
Oh. Well,
that figures.
♪ If I told you now
♪ I would go
♪ With our children near
♪ If I told you now
♪ I'm just passing through
♪ This world
is not my home ♪
♪ Passing through
♪ This world
is not my home ♪
♪ I'm just passin' through
♪ I can't live at home
♪In this world anymore
♪ In this world anymore
♪ I can't live at home
♪ This world where my children
♪ This world where
my children ♪
♪ This world where my children
♪ Have gone before
♪ This world where
my children ♪
♪ This world where my children
♪ Have gone before
♪ I can't live at home
in this world anymore ♪
♪ Ahhh
♪ I can't live at home
in this world anymore ♪
in this world anymore... ♪
♪ In this world,
it's over and done ♪
♪ I sleep all day
♪ When I get home
♪ In this world,
it's over and done ♪
♪ I sleep all day
♪ When I get home