Come on. Come get some bread.
Don't you want any?
Come on.
Here you go.
Go on. Here you go.
So! You've been giving them
permission to eat, have you?
My seed, eh?!
You've gone up in the world.
Is that it?
Is that what you think?
I'll give you something to think about!
Now, get out with you!
You've only been gone an hour.
- What's he done?
- Nothing.
Did he hit you?
Shame on you for letting him.
His father was my father's journeyman.
Keep in.
Mr Fawley!
- Should I take this off?
- For five seconds.
Right, stay still everyone.
Come on, if you're coming, then.
- Have you finished your work?
- Yeah.
Good boy.
- Come on. Come on.
- All right.
You look sad, Jude. Are
you sorry I'm going?
- Yeah.
- So am I.
- Where are you going, sir?
- Christminster.
Why do you have to go?
Do you know what a university is?
A university degree?
Do you see it, over there?
That's Christminster.
If you want to do anything in life, Jude,
that's where you have to go.
even if it means giving up
everything else for a while.
You have to read your books
while your friends are out playing.
Get out of bed early in
the morning when it's freezing cold.
Study every chance you get.
One day it'll all pay off, I promise you.
Once you're there,
everything's open to you.
You can become anything you want.
You can choose your future.
- Dinner!
- Come on.
Hurry up, Jude.
- Staying to eat with us today, Jude? - No.
- Thank you.
Look at that Jude. Have a piece
of this cheese, you'll love it.
- Who've you got waiting then?  Chip off
the old block, eh? Is she a looker?
(Reading in Ancient Greek)
"Swiftly she rose
from the grey sea like a mist."
"My child, why do you weep?"
Here's the poet.
- Thank you very much.
- I didn't throw it.
Nor me. I didn't throw it, I tell you.
I don't even like the look of him.
- None of you threw it.
- What's wrong with him?
- I think he's quite nice.
- He's all right. He's just standing there.
- Oh, look. You've scared him off now.
- He's shy.
I bet you think I threw it.
No.
Well I did.
But don't tell anyone.
My name's Arabella.
My father's a pig breeder.
We were washing innards
for black pudding.
- What?
- Nothing.
I don't work Sundays. You can see me then.
- Did you catch anything?  - No. I
should've thrown something else at him.
(Reading in Latin)
- Now all you do is read?
- Yes.
Nothing else?
- What do you read?
- Latin, some Greek.
I've read two books of
the Iliad, Thucydides, Hesiod,
some of the Greek testament.
- Hoity-toity!
Well I need to to if I'm gonna
get into Christminster.
Christminster?
Yes. I'm going to be a scholar.
- Maybe even a professor one day.
- My, my.
- Have you ever seen me climb a tree?
- No.
I've got something to show you, Jude.
Where are you?
Get up, Abby.
Why?
I want to kiss you.
Kiss me like this.
Be careful I'm hatching an egg.
I carry it with me everywhere.
It'll hatch in three days.
Why do you do that?
It's natural for a woman
to bring a live thing into the world.
Jude?
Yes.
It's late.
To the bride and the groom!
We'll send that to Aunt Drusilla.
Aunt Drusilla.
- What should we call her?
- Rosie's pig.
- What about Jemima Spot?
- Do you like that?
It isn't your own?
So?
What?
- You've got enough of your own.
- It's very fashionable in London.
Do you care what
people think in London?
Don't you like it?
- No.
- Then I won't wear it.
Leave it on.
I want to see us. You can close your eyes
if you like and pretend it's dark.
Jude.
Ask me nicely.
- Ask you what?
- What you want me to do.
- I don't know.
- What?!
We'll just have to make it up.
He's never going to get here.
He's probably bloody drunk.
We'll just have to do it ourselves.
- Be careful with those.
- Then find somewhere else for them.
This table is for the lard.
Right, move her.
- Where do you want it?
- On this side.
Thank God it's dead.
What's God got to do with pig killing?
It's a bit late to be looking
at other women.
I won't feel sorry for you.
You should have listened to me.
Fawleys are not cut out for marriage.
- I didn't have a choice.
- You had no brains.
- She's five months gone and not even a bump.
- Please don't say that.
Shall I get your room ready?
No, I'd better go.
(ARABELLA) "Dear Jude, I've decided
to leave, and I won't be back.
"I know you think
I tricked you into marrying me,
"but I swear
I really believed I was pregnant.
"I'm going to Australia to start again.
"Perhaps now you'll be free
to go to Christminster
"and become a university man.
"Good luck."
Can I help you?
.. then there's your back-to- back houses,
your grubby children
hanging off scaffolding.
It's the same city.
Maybe a five-minute walk
from Church Street to "Scum Street".
Why don't we go over?
Why don't we go over and
knock on their doors?
Because they've convinced us this is
the way it is. No change. Why change?
They've won the argument.
They educate their kind
to win the argument.
I'm looking for Jude Fawley.
I believe he works here.
- You'll find him around the corner, miss.
- Thank you.
Jude Fawley? I'm your
cousin, Sue Bridehead.
Aunt Drusilla wrote and told me
you were in Christminster.
- Hello.
Don't take this wrongly,
you don't look like cousins to me.
Why is that?
Because you're pretty and fine,
and Jude he's got a stone for a face.
- A big nose is a sign of nobility.
- Shut up Tinker.
They have the same noses...
...look at them.
One each, right in the middle
of their faces.
- Tell me some more about my cousin.
- He's a scholar, a true scholar.
- He's a sinner.
- Why is that?
- What was the last one called?
- Oh, you mean Vicky.
- No, Florence,
- The one before Elspeth.
- Mm...nice, isn't it?
- Oh, lovely.
Nothing up the sleeve, right?
Oh, yes! Now, that is good, that is good.
Jude. Jude!
Jude!
Not there, it's bad luck.
They used to burn martyrs there.
- Are you superstitious, Jude?
- No.
Nor am I, but I think
it's better to be safe, don't you?
- Where are we going?
Somewhere living, away
from this university.
- But it's wonderful here.
- It's all stone.
You're talking about the buildings,
I'm talking about the scholars.
I was talking about the scholars, too.
Finish it.
- How much are these two, please?
- Ten shillings.
- You're not going to buy them?
- Why not?
- Would you like me to wrap them up?
- No, thank you.
Why have you wrapped them up?
Because I don't want to give my
landlady an unecessary heart attack.
You're being rather confrontational
No, I was just wondering why
you bother going to church at all.
Because a part of me is still
a superstitious, backward country girl.
You mean, like me?
I didn't know you were a girl.
Do I irritate you?
No.
even when I'm trying to prove
how much cleverer than you I am?
You are.
- Don't say that.
- Why not?
Because it's not the sort of thing
you should admit to.
Why not, if it's true?
Say something.
I enjoy listening to you.
Catullus.
(Reading in Latin)
"God, like the man who sits at her side
"Who watches and catches the laughter
which softly tears me to tatters
"Nothing is left of me
each time I see her."
Beautiful
What does the law say
about marrying your cousin?
It's not about that. Says nothing
about falling in love with them.
- Is that so?
- Quite common, I hear.
- What do you think, Jude?
- You two are cousins, you tell me.
- Sue?
- How do you know?
- You've got a woman's hands.
- You'll have to do better than that.
- "Pruples" doesn't count.
- You've been following me?
I came to say goodbye.
Aren't you going to
introduce me to your friend?
It's Wilkes.
How do you do, Mr Wilkes?
Why are you leaving?
I had a row with my landlady.
She found one of my statues
and threw it on the floor...
and stamped on it and ground
the head to pieces with her heel.
She made sure I lost my job as well
Where will you go?
I don't know. I'm going
to teach somewhere.
- You can teach here in Christminster.
- Everyone in this city is a teacher, Jude.
I've got a friend who can help.
Mr Phillotson.
I was his pupil in Marygreen.
Don't worry about me.
I was going to look him up, anyway.
There's no harm in asking.
Why do you want me to stay?
Because we've only just met.
Yes?
- Mr Phillotson?
- Yes.
My name is Jude Fawley.
I was your pupil in Marygreen.
Yes, of course you were.
- Are you an old pupil too?
- No, this is my cousin, Sue Bridehead.
Hello.
Mr Phillotson, you once
showed me Christminster,
the same day you left Marygreen.
I came here because of you, sir,
to become a university man.
Through here.
I gave up the idea of
university a long time ago.
Other dreams have replaced it.
I'm very happy as a schoolmaster.
Here we are.
Sue's been looking for work as a teacher.
You've already had some
experience haven't you?
No.
Is it very hard to find work?
I'm thinking of applying
to a training college.
That's always a good idea.
What I need for this school
is a second-year transfer.
- What about an apprentice?
- Jude!
Are you serious about
being a teacher, Sue?
Yes, of course.
I'm sure it will be useful
for both of you.
- I can't afford to pay you very much.
- That doesn't matter.
All right, then.
(PHILLOTSON) One times seven?
(PUPILS) Seven.
- Two times seven?
- 14.
- Three times seven?
- 21.
- Four times seven?
- 28.
- Bye, Miss.
- Bye.
Mount of Olives.
Mount Moriah.
The Valley of Jehoshaphat.
The City of Zion.
Calvary. All names
at the very root of our history.
You see this is an exact model
of the City of Jerusalem...
as it was at the time of
our Lord, Jesus Christ.
And they took Jesus through
these hot, dusty, narrow streets...
Doesn't anyone know what Jerusalem looked like
at the time of Christ? I'm sure that man doesn't.
Of course he does. The model is copied
from the best conjectural maps.
Why Jerusalem?
Why not Athens or Rome or Alexandria?
Because of what Jerusalem
means to us as Christians.
Surely you must see that?
- Why are you so sceptical?
- I'm not, I was just pointing out that...
Jude!
- What a surprise!
- No, it isn't. You knew I'd be here.
- You've been watching me all the time.
- Mr Phillotson.
Jude. Your cousin is such a clever girl
she criticises all this unmercifully.
Please don't call me a clever girl,
Mr Phillotson. There are too many
of us about these days.
- I didn't mean anything, Sue.
- I know you didn't.
Come on, Jude, I think
we've had enough of Jerusalem.
This accusation, written:
"This is Jesus, the king of the Jews."
- He wanted to impress you.
- Not a very clever way to go about it.
He can't be clever. He's fond of you.
Well, I'm fond of him, too.
It doesn't mean I go
around patronising him.
I don't feel at all guilty.
(Reading Ancient Greek)
"Tell me, Muse, a man, many ways
"who wandered far and wide
after he sacked the holy city of Troy."
- Will you kiss it for luck?
- No.
A letter for the Dean of Admissions.
They took it.
Want a hat, Jude?
- What's the problem?
- It's raining.
- It's what?
- Thought you were the intelligent one.
Sue!
"Sir, I have read your letter
with interest,
"and judging from your description
of yourself as a working man,
"I think you have
a much better chance of success in life
"by sticking to your own trade
than by adopting any other course.
"Yours sincerely,
the Dean of Admissions."
I don't give a damn for any provost,
ward, principal or bloody Master of Arts.
All I know is I'd lick them on their own
ground if they'd just give me the chance.
It's always said there's more to be
learned outside the book, than in.
- Aye, but can you say the Creed in Latin?
- Yes, I can, I definitely can.
Excuse me. Quiet, please, quiet!
The gentleman in the corner is to rehearse
the articles of his belief in the Latin tongue
for the edification of this company.
Thank you.
Here's your chance.
Credo in unum Deum, Patrem,
omnipotentem,
Factorem coel et terrae,
visibilum omnium et invisibilum.
Crucifixus etiam pro nobis:
sub Pontio Pilato passus,
et sepultus est.
Et resurrexit tertia die,
secundum Scripturas.
Et in Spiritum Sanctum,
Dominum
et vivificantem,
qui ex Patre Filo que procedit.
You bloody fools.
Which one of you knows
if I said it right or not?
It might be The Ratcatcher's Daughter
in double Dutch for all you know.
Sue!
Jude...?
I've been drinking, Sue.
Will you let me in?
All right.
- I can do it.
- Jude.
You'll learn more than
they can ever teach you.
I'm sure this is the last
thing you want to hear,
but you don't need a double first from
Christminster to do some good in the world.
- You should try to eat something.
- He's too old for you.
I'll bring you breakfast
in the morning.
Out of work already?
Hello, Aunt.
Don't you make a fool of
yourself over her, Jude.
Marrying that woman Arabella was
the worst thing you ever did, until now.
Don't say that.
Your parents couldn't live together
and nor could Sue's.
They made each other's lives a living hell
and left you two as good as orphans.
- They were a different generation.
- With the same curse over your heads.
- The Fawleys are not meant for marrying.
- That's an old wives' tale.
Since when did you stop
believing in them?
(SUE) "Dearest Jude,
I'm writing to you from Melchester,
"where Mr Phillotson and I
have both moved.
"He is teaching at a new school
and I am studying at a training college.
"The rules here are strict beyond belief
and our visiting hours are limited,
"but I'd love to see you again."
Your hands are rough, Jude.
So would yours be
if they held a mallet and chisel all day.
I like them, they are noble hands.
What's wrong?
It'll take me a while to
get used to you again.
- I come here to forget Melchester.
- So where are we?
France, Australia, Spain,
Canada, Timbuktu.
- Is it that bad at the training school?
- Yes.
It's only another year.
Mr Phillotson thinks he can get me
a good job when I've finished.
- How is he?
- He's been such a help.
I'm sure he has.
- Are you being silly?
- No.
Jude?
I didn't realise he took a
long-term interest in your future.
- He's a friend.
- I'm sure he doesn't see it that way.
- An old man like him?
- He isn't that old.
You said so yourself.
- What's the matter?
- I wish you'd be more open with me.
All right, he asked me to marry him.
- What did you say?
- I said I'd think about it.
I'm sorry, maybe I shouldn't
have asked you to visit.
I'm not visiting, I've moved to Melchester.
Jude!
Let me in.
They locked me up for being out with you, so I
jumped out of the window, climbed over a fence
crossed the deepest river in England,
and here I am.
I can't get warm.
- I'll borrow some clothes from the landlady.
- Don't do that, for God's sake!
Then you'll have to wear some of mine.
How about this?
It might be a bit small.
I'll wait outside.
- I brought you some brandy.
- No glass?
- Some in the cupboard. I'd have to clean them.
- Don't worry, I'll drink it like a man.
- What will they say at the school?
- I don't care.
- I'll go back as soon as they're dry.
- It's late.
You could stay here tonight.
I wish I could get warm.
- Thank you, Jude.
- For what?
For being here.
- I'm glad you came to me.
- There's no one else.
I should let you sleep.
Yes.
I couldn't sleep.
Why are you looking at me like that?
- Does it frighten you?
- No.
I'm not afraid of any man.
Why not?
Because no man will touch a woman
unless she invites him to.
Until she says with a look or a smile,
"Come on", he's always afraid.
If you never say it or look it,
he'll never come.
You're the timid sex.
Shall I try again...
.. to close my eyes and fall asleep?
Good morning, Jude.
Morning.
- Can I talk?
- Yes.
This is about her running
away from the school?
And coming to you that night.
There have been rumours.
She's been expelled
from school because of them.
- That isn't fair.
- Jude.
I want to be able to defend her against
any scandal I need to know what happened.
Nothing happened.
- Is that the truth?
- So help me God.
She stayed with me,
but as a cousin.
Then we must both help her now.
- Hello.
- Did you go to the school?
- Yes.
They won't take me back.
They think you and I
are having some kind of affair.
They even suggested I marry you
for the sake of my reputation.
- I saw Mr Phillotson today.
He said he'd help.
I don't want his help.
He was anxious. He
cares for you very much.
I know.
I've never told you about my past.
Go on, then, tell me about it.
I'm married, Sue.
I haven't seen her for years,
but I'm still married.
Why are you telling me this?
Because it's the only obstacle.
Obstacle to what?
I don't love you!
I don't want to be your wife!
You are our closest mutual friend, Jude.
We thought you ought to
be the first to know.
Richard asked me to marry
him, and I said yes.
That's wonderful. Congratulations.
I'm very happy for you.
So are we.
- When did you decide?
- I've been asking Sue for months now.
But this time it was her idea.
- I know it's the right decision.
- Jude helped me make up my mind.
I know. I hope my cousin will make you
very happy, Mr Phillotson.
Jude, I have something to ask you.
Will you give me away?
I have no other family here.
Of course I'll give you away.
With all my heart.
Are you ready with that yet?
Hurry it up, then.
You're "father", you know.
That's what they call
the man who gives you away.
Was it like this
when you were married?
Can I get you a drink, sir?
Thanks, Arabella. I'll
have a pint and a whisky.
Aren't you supposed to
be a Christminster don?
Aren't you supposed to be in Australia?
Change, Arabella.
He's on the house.
- Who's that, Bella?
- That's, oh that's just my husband.
Can I have a pint now, please?
Cheers!
You know how I said I was pregnant
when we got married?
Jude?
Jude...?
I met someone in Sydney.
I didn't tell him about us.
It wasn't as nice as our wedding.
She'll find me lying here
as still as Lazarus.
And then I'll suddenly open my eyes.
Sue Bridehead, you little fool
I'll say it straight out.
You'll regret this marriage as much as
that ox of a cousin of yours regretted his.
Are you crying for me...
or for your precious Sue?
You ninny.
"Lord, have mercy upon us.
"Almighty God, with whom do live the
spirits of them that depart, enter the Lord,
"with whom the souls
of the faithful after...
they are delivered from
the burden of the flesh
"are in joy and felicity. We give thee
a hearty thanks, for it has pleased thee
"to delver this, our sister,
out of the miseries of this sinful world.
"Beseechingly, that it may please thee
of thy gracious goodness.
"Shortly to accomplish the
number of thine elect...
and to hasten thy kingdom,
"that we, with all those that are departed
in the true faith, thy holy name,
"may have our perfect
consummation and bliss,
both in body and soul
"in thy eternal and everlasting glory,
through Jesus Christ, our Lord."
- How long are you staying?
- Just tonight. I have to go back tomorrow.
I wish I'd seen her before she died.
She was looking forward
to seeing you, too.
What did she say?
That we both made bad
husbands and wives.
It shouldn't be allowed to set those traps.
- Did it wake you?
- I was already awake.
- Why?
- I was thinking.
About what?
I don't know.
(SUE) "Dearest Jude, I should never
have written this letter,
"and I beg you not to reply.
"Richard and I are husband and wife.
"Nothing can change that...
"not your frustration,
"nor my regret.
"Please try to forget me."
- Jude?
- How do you know?
You've got man's hands.
Did you get my letter?
Yes, but I never opened it.
Don't worry, I haven't moved
to Shaston this time.
- You say it like you've given up with me.
- Do you blame me?
I'm here, aren't I?
Promise me you'll
never stop trying, Jude.
- That must sound terrible.
- Yes, it does.
So, will you promise me that?
I can't help myself.
Jude?
- Sue didn't tell me you were coming.
- I didn't know.
That's a wonderful surprise for both of us.
How long are you staying?
My train leaves in an hour.
Sue's hardly had a chance to see you.
Maybe you can persuade Jude to stay.
How is the school at Marygreen?
The same.
Still the one classroom?
Same desks.
- Everything all right, Jude?
- Yes.
- Goodnight, then.
- Goodnight.
Sue?
- What are you doing?
- What's wrong with me, Jude?
Not a thing.
"When I do count the
clock that tells the time
"and see the brave day's sun
and hideous night. When I behold...
".. and the summer's green
all girded up in sheaves,
"borne on the bier
with white and bristly beard."
I have a wife I love, who not only
doesn't love me, but I disgust her.
And this morning
she asked me if she
could leave to live with you.
- I won't oppose it if that's what you want.
- Well it is.
I always noticed something extraordinary
between the two of you.
I kept telling myself it was because you
were cousins, but it's more than that.
Sometimes I think you are
one person split in two.
You knew all along
she'd made a mistake marrying me.
- Yes.
- But you did nothing to stop us.
No.
Nor did I.
I'll check when I get back home
to see if you've forgotten anything.
I don't think I have, thank you.
- What time's your train, Jude?
- Leaves in five minutes.
Goodbye, Richard.
Bye.
Yes!
Jude!
I brought your dinner.
Domestic laws should take into account
different temperaments.  - For example.
I may want to live with a man,
but only as a friend.
- And how may that be fair on the man?
- Because there are no precedents.
- His pride is hurt.
- But you want to marry someone you love.
Why do people have to be told to
love each other by someone else?
That's all marriage is.
- It's a government stamp. A licence to love.
- But if we could, would you want to get married?
I'd run a mile if you had a piece of paper
that forced me to love you.
Oh, please!
That's not fair.
- Drink up.
- Oh, another go. Another go.
Drink up, drink up, drink up.
Ugh!
You love it, you liar.
What?
- What's wrong?
- Don't touch me like that.
- It's just affections.
- Does it pull you to something else?
Something else? What something else?
I think neither of us know
the meaning of it.
I'm sorry.
It's just that I want everything
to be perfect between us.
I'm not ready, Jude.
Do you understand?
I'll try.
What are you writing?
Whatever his wife wants.
- Tea.
- Thanks.
"Here lies my husband Peter Porter, age 51.
"He tormented me, he cheated on me
and he spent all our food money on beer."
- He's dead, Sue.
- He can't hear me.
Tell him I'll have his
headstone ready in an hour.
Arabella?
Sorry to come here, Jude.
I didn't want to.
- I'm in trouble. I need to talk to you.
- What's wrong?
I don't want to cause any trouble for you.
Can we talk somewhere else?
- All right.
- I'm staying at the King's Head.
- It was Arabella. She wants to talk with me.
- Can't she talk outside?
- She wants me to go to a hotel
- That's convenient.
- Sue, I have to help her.
- Why? She's not your wife.
She's going to give you
what you want.
Can't you see what she's doing?
She wants you back.
But do you want me?
Yes.
Close your eyes.
- You don't have to do this.
- I want to.
But you have to help me. I don't know
what I'm doing. I only pretend.
- Do I talk too much?
- No.
- I'm doing it all wrong, aren't I?
- I'm intellectualising.
- You're not.
Kiss me before I start talking again.
You look pleased with yourself.
I'm cooking you bacon
and sausage and eggs.
Why?
Because you think you deserve it.
There's a letter for you on the table.
- Aren't you going to open it?
- I'll read it later.
Jude, I know who it's from.
(ARABELLA) "Dearest Jude,
I'm writing with this news
"because I never got the chance
to tell you face to face.
"There was a boy born of our marriage
eight months after I left you.
"So far, the boy has been
with my parents in Sydney but
"they can no longer afford to keep him,
and nor can I.
"I named him after you."
Are you Jude Fawley?
Yes, sir.
This is your father. My name's Sue.
It's nice to meet you.
- How was your journey?
- Fine, thank you.
- Can I carry this?
- Yes.
(SUE) What Arabella says is true.
He's yours.
I can see you in him.
But the other half is her.
- You'll protect me, won't you?
- If I can.
Can you believe your eyes?
Is the world really as it seems?
I can see some of you smiling,
that's there certainty that nothing...
can surprise you any more.
You've seen it all.
Well tonight, I'll surprise you.
I'll show you wonders.
I'll show you a world you've only glimpsed
in your darkest dreams.
Out of thin air, the terrors come!
(MIDWIFE) Come on now,
not much longer now.
You all right?
It's nothing to be frightened of.
Come here.
- No, baby, don't cry.
- Juey, can you help me, please?
Can you help me? Hold baby for me.
Support her head.
Look, I've got the baby.
Be careful
Morning.
Jude, can I have a word?
- Who are they?
- Daddy's going to talk to them.
The work is going fine,
Mr. Willis.
Jude, I'm sorry. I'm going to have to get
someone else to finish it for you.
Why?
There's some of the parishioners
have complained.
- About what?
- You never told us you weren't married.
I never realised that was a
necessary qualification for a stonemason.
I'll pay you for the week's work,
of course.
I'm sorry, Jude.
Six shillings. Yes, madam, seven shillings.
Is she going to get them?
Yes, she is, seven shillings.
Thank you, madam.
Right, we've got this rabbit now.
Couple of nice rabbits. Black and white.
But you can take the skin off, they look the same.
Goes very, very nice with
Sunday lunch for someone.
Come on. Four pence, five pence.
Seven pence to the gentleman out there.
It's going to be like this
everywhere we go...
as soon as people find
out we're not married.
We'll move on.
We move somewhere
where nobody knows us.
If they find out, we move on again,
and again and again...
as long as it takes
for the world to change.
We've done nothing wrong, Sue.
You're the one who taught me that.
Juey.
- Juey!
Take care of your sister.
How do you do, Mrs Fawley.
Arabella Wilkinson.
You look sick, Jude.
Thank you.
There's even gables and little windows.
How very sweet.
Still harping on about Christminster.
- How are you?
- All right.
My husband died, left me everything.
- What would you like?
- Oh, I think I'll have a whole college.
Which was the college
that refused you, Jude?
Well I shan't have that one.
You were such a proud man, Jude.
Jude.
Hello.
- Don't you recognise your ma, then?
- Yeah.
I bought you some cake.
Would you like some?
No, thank you.
- I think your little sister would like some.
- She's too small.
But you are big, though.
How old are you now?
Eight.
Eight years, three months
and six days.
I remember exactly.
Eight was my favourite age.
- I bet you want to be nine, though?
- Yeah.
- Hey, are you married yet?
- No.
- Be all right if I kiss you, then?
- Yeah.
You're a good boy, Jude.
What is it?
I want to go back to Christminster.
Because Arabella hurt your pride?
Because I still have some.
(JUDE) * The crow flew over the bush
The crow flew over the bush
# The crow flew over the bush #
What do you think he saw?
- Guess who?
- I know that voice anywhere. Uncle Joe.
Jim! Take your tail up.
Over here.
I've found the tutor of St Slum's
College, Christminster.
Hey, hey! Can you still say
the Apostle's Creed in Latin, Jude.
"Credo in unum Deum,
Patrem omnipotentem."
Look at you, Jude.
What have you been doing with yourself?
He's got himself more mouths to feed.
- You remember my friends, don't you?
- Yes, of course.
So cousins do get married.
- My eldest, little Jude.
- Oh, what's wrong with you, little man?
- He's tired.
- Nothing.
We've been looking out for you
in the parade every year.
Never thought we'd
find you in the crowd.
Things turned out differently.
- No regrets, I hope?
- Some.
Difficult question for any man to answer.
To follow his dreams no matter what, or...
give in slowly and let
life lead him where it will
And which are you?
I don't know.
When I first came here to Christminster,
I had a neat stock of fixed opinions.
Now the further I get,
the less sure I am of anything.
Hear, hear.
"Who knoweth what is good
for man in this life?
"And who can tell a man
what shall be after him under the sun?"
- We're looking for somewhere to stay.
- We don't take children.
- No, I'm sorry. No room.
- We're looking for somewhere to stay.
- How many children are there?
Two children and a baby.
- I have got a room.
- Thank you, thank you.
Juey, Lizzy, come up.
I'll look for work in the morning.
- How did they know?
- She asked me if we were husband and wife.
- And you said we weren't?
- I couldn't lie.  - Sue!
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
I won't hide it from anyone.
It's open.
I'm sorry, my husband is a bit unhappy
about the little ones staying.
- We can't leave now, not in this rain.
- I know, I said that to him.
- Staying one night is fine.
- But we agreed a week.
Thank you very much. We'll look for
new lodgings first thing in the morning.
- Why do you give in?
- What difference does it make?
Sshhh, nearly done.
I love this place.
even though I know
it looks down on people like me.
The self-taught,
too-determined.
It takes two or three generations to do
what I tried to do in one.
You're still Joseph,
the dreamer of dreams.
And the tragic Don Quixote.
Sometimes you're a St Stephen...
who sees Heaven open up,
even as they're stoning him.
(JUEY) I can't sleep.
- Come and sleep with us.
- Is it because of me we have to leave?
No, Juey...
because there's too many of us.
There's not enough room.
Go to bed now.
Go to bed. Go to bed!
I'll go and talk to him.
- What are you doing?
- Watching them sleep.
They love you very much, Juey.
You're their older brother.
If they see you upset, they get upset, too.
You have to be strong for them.
If there's too many children in the world,
why do people have more?
I don't know.
Because they love each other,
or because they don't think.
It just happens that way.
Mum said there were too many of us.
She didn't mean you.
There aren't enough of you.
Are you ready for bed?
Come on.
Good night, son.
I'd like to buy myself a dress with flowers,
flounces and ribbons. And I need a hat.
- Of course you do.
- With exotic flowers growing out of it.
Oh, Jude. We could buy...
We could buy clothes.
We could buy anything we wanted, really.
- Juey in school
- We could.
- Can I tell him?
- Yes, you tell him.
I'll tell him. I'll tell him!
Sshh, they must be asleep.
What is it?
"For we are made as a spectacle unto
the world, and unto angels and to men.
"even to this present hour we both hunger
and thirst, and are naked and are buffeted,
"and have no certain dwelling place.
"Being reviled, we bless.
Being persecuted, we suffer it.
"Being defamed, we entreat.
"We are made as the filth
of the world, and...
are the offscouring of
all things unto this day.
"I write not these things to shame you,
but, as my beloved sons, to warn you."
Shall we go?
- Sue?
- I want to be with my children.
I'll wait for you by the gates.
I should have kept him myself.
None of this would have ever happened.
If I had come back to you...
If...
- If...
- Arabella, please.
I thought about it.
- Do you ever?
- No.
It wasn't your fault, Jude.
Why won't you look at me?
Because it's wrong.
We have to be punished.
Haven't we been punished enough?
Our love is wrong.
That's why the children died.
We defied him, and now
he's punishing us.
- Who?
- God.
God has nothing to do with it.
You of all people know that.
I was wrong.
And now you can see clearly,
in this state?
- I'm trying to explain things.
- There's nothing to explain.
- It was an accident.
- It was judgement.
On what?
Why do you talk like this?
We've done nothing wrong.
"We are made a spectacle unto the world,
and unto angels and to men."
Sue.
- Sue, where are you going?
- Your child killed mine.
- Your child killed my babies.
- Sue, please.
How can I look at you?
How can I live with you?
Do you believe in God?
You think so, yes.
How many times have you missed
a church service in your life? Why?
What are you reading at the moment?
- What do you want with me?
- Come home.
You don't know my badness.
Yes, I do.
You make me hate Christianity and God
and whatever has reduced you to this state.
- It's right that I suffer.
- It's wrong.
That a woman like you
should give up her mind, degrade herself...
Don't talk to me like that!
- I'm sorry.
- Doesn't matter.
- You have to listen to me.
- Come home.
No, I can't.
- It's all right, Jude. I know what to do.
- We'll talk in the morning.
I have to go back
to Richard in the morning.
You go, too.
Write to Arabella, ask her to...
- They mean nothing to us.
- We're still married.
- No, you and I are married!
But not in Heaven, not in this church!
I married Richard in a church, Jude.
- I want to go back to him.
- Do you care for him? Do you love him?
- I'll learn to love him.
- No. How can you, Sue? You love me.
You love me, Sue!
Say it, Sue.
Say it. Say it. Say it.
I don't love you any more.
I'll pray for us, Jude.
Not for me.
How are you?
All right.
You look well
Do I?
- Where are you living now?
- Quite far.
- You won't tell me where?
- You wouldn't know it.
- I'd better go.
- I'll follow you.  - No.
I won't stop trying, I promised you that.
- Jude.
- Do you love me?
Do you still love me?
I won't come again, if that's what
you want, but I need to know.
You've always known.
Sue, come with me.
No, Jude.
We are man and wife,
if ever two people were on this earth!