Those are the decisions you drafted,
Chief,
I wrote them according to what we agreed upon,
Why is there a big question mark here?
I'm slightly caught aback,
Why do you think I put that there?
I'm sure you had a reason, but,,,
- Think hard about it, - Still, this is,,,
- Chief, will you really,,, - Really,,,
Really what?
I'll think hard about it,
Think hard about it,
Don't just bury yourself in Jang Soon Bok's retrial request,
Oh, my goodness, What is that,,,
A big red question mark?
Who did this? How rude,
Chief Oh reviewed this,
The chief reviewed it,
Does he usually put this huge question mark,,,
What? Rude? He's the chief,
I do not understand, Please explain to us,
I'll let you know later,
I, the main judge on the trial, drafted the decision,,,
and submitted it to the chief, and,,,
When we say, "submit," we refer to when an associate judge,,,
drafts the decision of the court,,,
and gives to the head judge of the panel for review,
When the chief puts a question mark, it means,,,
he can't understand or there is a problem,
and that you should think it over again,
There's so much meaning in it,
There's no meaning,
Isn't he saying scrap it and start over?
Ms, Lee, You have a talent,
How do you say something that would drive a person mad so casually?
Chief,
Chief!
I have a million question marks about this question mark!
If you're taking revenge for refusing to give up,,,
Jang Soon Bok's retrial request,
I'll give you a chance,
Get rid of this huge question mark!
Do you have something to say?
Chief,
I intended to think hard about it, but,,,
Our team dinner is tomorrow, correct?
If we didn't choose the menu item yet,
I'm craving bossam,
We'll all crave bossam then,
Yes, bossam,
Judge Lee, I thought you can't eat pork,
You get hives,
Hives won't kill me,
If Chief Oh would tell me what this huge question mark means,,,
I thought once you become a judge, decisions get written easily,
How could they get written easily?
A person's life hangs on every decision,
Of course, I'm sure how we feel when we write decisions,,,
is how doctors feel before surgeries,
When a junior judge receives a chief judge's edits,
you feel either joy or sorrow,
Every associate judge's wish is edits for minor typos,
A missing period,
That's the best possible result you can get,
Usually, they leave detailed comments,,,
or a question mark at certain parts,
(Refer to "Birth of Execution",)
They often say to refer to a certain book,
but if it's in red,,,
Help me!
Well, you shout, "Help me,"
I think Judge Lee expected a single period too,
Nothing but a large question mark on the first page,,,
It means he had it in for you,,,
because of Jang Soon Bok's retrial request,
You think that too, right? He has it in for me,
What should I do now? What would you do?
I thought it over,
and you know Jang Soon Bok's retrial request?
- We should back off, - Back off?
This isn't the time for us to work so hard to help Judge Lee,
What if it gets dismissed?
Chief Oh will come after us as well,
I never thought we were helping Judge Lee,
but setting right a wrong if the decision was incorrect,
That's our job as the committee for reviewing incorrect verdicts,
I thought it was our job as well,
but who gives us our evaluations?
Chief Oh,
What if we're the only ones not to get As?
Yes, but still, how could we be so low,,,
You stay out of it,
Sit straight,
I wouldn't say this if I were as young as you,
I left the Blue House at this age,,,
with everyone saying I was crazy,
If I want to become a part of this committee,
I can't get on the chief's bad side,
You too,
If you're going to raise Ha Neul as a single mom,,,
I received your submission, so please stop talking,
I'm sure you don't feel good saying these things anyway,
In exchange, let's dig deep into Choi Kyung Ho's case,
How could you do this if you know that?
- You're driving me mad! - Let go of me!
- Judge Lee, stop it! - Let go of my arms!
- Get back down here! Stop it! - Judge Lee!
All right, Starting now,
you'll be writing comments on the video you just watched,
Yes?
Anyone? Then I'll go first,
"Don't you ever tell anyone,,,"
"that I'm your role model,"
You, Trying to exit through the back door,
Actually, I'm not in this class,
If you're auditing my class, you can at least comment on the video,
Well,,,
I'm not in any position to leave any comments,
Why don't you just tell me? I'll type it for you,
If you insist,,,
"Why did you do that?"
"You should hate the sin, not the sinner," Put a crying emoji,
Is it possible to hate the sin, and not the sinner?
Who's responsible for the sin? It's the sinner,
Isn't it only natural to hate the sinner?
What I mean is that we must give,,,
sinners a second chance to reform their lives despite our hatred,
I'm sure this judge in the video,,,
must have despised this heinous defendant,,,
who didn't even repent his unpardonable act of crime,
I can understand her,
Judges are humans too, I can understand her rampage,
That's what I think too, Judges are humans too,
However, the moment you become a judge,
you must get rid of that thought,
When you're on the bench,
you mustn't give yourself the excuse that you're a human too,
Judges who are generous on their own mistakes are the most dangerous,
Don't you agree, Judge Lee Jung Joo?
That couldn't have been more embarrassing,
Professor Yoo, I know that you're trying to educate your students,
but is it fair for you to put me on the chopping block and condemn me?
It's funny how you came at that very moment,
Is it because of Choi Kyung Ho?
Han Joon told me,
Choi Kyung Ho had a trial,
and you were on the panel,
How much did you hear?
How much should I know?
I want you to tell me,
Someone else murdered the girl, and he had a deal,
And a warning,
Don't lose sleep over what he said,
I only came to talk about,,,
Jang Soon Bok's petition for a retrial,
I just had a few questions,
Ask away,
Jang Soon Bok murdered her husband, Seo Gi Ho,
I heard he managed your cottage,
That's true,
Kim Ga Young's dad, Kim Hee Chul, used to manage it for us,
but his daughter's death devastated him, and he left Korea,
Mr, Seo Gi Ho was killed as soon as we hired him,
Kim Ga Young's dad managed your cottage?
Yes,
I've never seen him since I've never been to the cottage,
I saw him for the first time at the trial,
- I'll do it, - No, let me,
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine, This knife is sharp,
Hold on, It's from the same brand of Jang Soon Bok's murder weapon,
Look at this,
I think we need to inform Judge Lee,,,
as this is crucial information regarding the murder weapon,
I told you to lay off,
This information is going to stay between the two of us for now,
This knife is the murder weapon,
This isn't a knife you can get your hands on easily in Korea,
Do you know the brand?
The Swedish royal family used this particular brand,
They manufacture the knives in limited quantities,
Right, When I worked at the Blue House,
I saw the First Lady use this brand,
Jang Soon Bok,,,
killed her husband with this?
That's not possible,
When my husband was the chief of staff at the Blue House,
it was a gift from the First Lady,
I heard that there's a limited number of them even in Sweden,
Are you sure?
It'd be hard to buy this knife in Korea,
How did she murder her husband with this expensive knife?
That would be your reasonable doubt,
You're right, I can't help myself, but doubt,
If there's still room for reasonable doubts,
shouldn't you start over?
You should,,,
listen to the defendant's claim even if it's late,
With that in mind,
you shouldn't dismiss what Choi Kyung Ho said,
If what he said is true,
it implies your ruling was wrong,
Would you be okay with that?
Would you be okay if you were in my shoes?
Given my disposition, I might bite my tongue and vomit blood,
I knew it,
Even if I do such things,
my guilt wouldn't be,,,
more important than the pain of the wrongfully accused,
What I feel isn't even close to the suffering the accused went through,
The possibility of misjudgment,,,
comes with the job,
If misjudgment scares you enough to avoid the substantive truth,
you must take off your robe,
For unavoidable reasons, today was the earliest she could join us,
This is Ms, Jin Se Ra,
I look forward to working for you,
All right, For your information,
I like people who do a good job rather than just look forward,
I was just being polite,
In that case, I'll do my job well,
You were a famous idol singer after all,
You should give us autographs,,,
My gosh, of course, she should,
- I'd like to get mine first, - Hold on!
She doesn't give out autographs,
She didn't even take a photo or give out autographs,,,
even to her fans,
Please try to understand, As one of the oldest members in Que Sera Sera,
I'd like to ask for your understanding,
That's a bit disappointing,
The ratio of the meat and the fat should be 8 to 2,
No, no, Without the fat, it will taste dry, It won't be delicious,
Our chief has high blood pressure, It must be moderately seasoned,
It should be on the borderline of being salty and bland,
Oh, right! You need to serve us either stir-fried anchovies,,,
or stir-fried fishcake as one of the side dishes,
Stir-fried anchovies with shishito peppers?
He's a fan of that dish,
I'll call you back later,
What on earth is wrong with this ruling? What is it?
I don't get it no matter how many times I read it,
Am I the problem?
That question mark is better than,,,
Chief Oh asking for the file so he could write the ruling himself,
When I was the associate judge on his left,
Chief Oh didn't even give me a chance to fix,
He corrected the ruling himself,
Whenever I think back,
I'm so humiliated that I want to go into hiding,
I won't ever write a question mark when I become the chief judge,
Never,
I can't figure it out, Please look over it,
and tell me what I'm missing,
I'll try, I don't know if I'd be of any help,
What is it?
What is it? What's going on?
Oh, no, This is not happening,
What?
"Ral",,,
- "Oh Ji Ral"? - "Oh Ji Ral"?
(Judge Oh Ji Ral)
"Oh Ji Ral"?
As in "a nut job"?
- Oh Ji,,, - Oh Ji Ral?
A nut job?
- I shouldn't be laughing, - Right,
No, don't, Don't laugh,
What?
Chief Oh, you are truly an oasis,,,
to the 73rd Criminal Judicial Panel,
(Oasis: the most-preferred chief judge)
I respect you immensely for taking someone like me who gets easily,,,
excited and chatty,
From now on, I won't frown on your suggestions to correct my rulings,
and I will do my best to meet the deadlines of my rulings,
I'm terribly sorry,
(Judge Oh Ji Rak)
Okay,
A true question mark,
This question mark will be my lamp,
I set it,,,
as my wallpaper so that I'll never forget it,
Every time I see this question mark,
I will remember to think at least one more time,,,
and become your left hand,
I will try again and again,
Sure,
How long do you plan to keep your mouth shut?
Where did you get that knife?
You won't talk?
I don't remember,
That's such an obvious response,
That's gibberish you give at a government hearing,
Forgetting is the greatest blessing from above,
I am enjoying that blessing,
That's right, I have something to tell you before I forget,
What?
That moron, Choi Kyung Ho,
said to relay a message to our Knucklehead Prosecutor,
This borders on being a warning,
He said not to touch Judge Lee Jung Joo,
He said you'll regret it if you don't leave her alone,
I relayed the message,
That warning sounds familiar,
You must be close to Choi Kyung Ho, so relay my message too,
You'll play your hand after receiving a warning,
That's interesting, Go ahead, Play your hand,
- She hasn't made any progress? - No,
You need to wake up and stand trial,
Please let me in,
I want to stay with my mom,
You can't go inside, Visiting hours are over,
My mom hasn't been able to eat,
She's hungry,
I need to bring her this,
She can't eat stuff like that!
Yong Soo,,,
brought this,
and this,
and this for my mom,
If you keep doing this, you can't stay outside her room either,
I have to give this to my mom,
What is this?
Why do you have this?
Tell me,
Why,,,
Why do you have this?
Please,
Where's the sneaker?
Tell me,
I,,, I don't know,
I,,, I don't have it,
Gosh,
The path to the team dinner,,,
was never so frightening before,
Chief Oh, I'm sorry, I made a huge mistake,
A mistake?
The names are automatically inserted these days,,,
in the template,
That's not what you call a mistake,
That was intentional, Intentional!
The thing is,,,
I deleted your name by mistake while I was editing the document,
so I typed it in myself and made a typo,
That's right, I did that before too,
I realized it was possible to make a mistake like that,
Say it was a mistake,
Why did it have to be "Oh Ji Ral" of all things?
How much resentment were you harboring,,,
that it was "Oh Ji Ral"? That's not even a name!
It's because you think I'm full of gibberish!
That's how you ended up typing "Oh Ji Ral"!
That's exactly what you were thinking,
I'm convinced you were thinking like so! You were!
You thought I was a nut job, so that's why you wrote that,
How else would you have typed that in?
Oh Ji Ral, Not even "Original" or something,
We should give you a big welcoming party, but,,,
No, it's fine, I prefer a cozy welcoming party with you,
- Here, - Thank you,
Do you not drink at all?
This is alcohol in the courtroom,
To render decisions that are as refreshing as soda?
That's beyond my abilities,
Even if it's a frustrating decision, I still do my best,
Even if it's a decision that is frustrating for the parties,
as long as it's one they can accept,
That's not bad, At least it wouldn't be a wrong decision,,,
like in Kyung Ho's trial,
I didn't know he'd say that in the courtroom,
I should've told you sooner,
When I asked Kyung Ho again later on,
he took it back and said there was no "real" murderer,
I don't know what kind of a deal he made,
- Five, please, - Hello,
- Where? - Hello,
Judge Sah!
Sit, sit,
(My mom, Jang Soon Bok, is innocent, She is not a murderer,)
My mom, Jang Soon Bok, is not a murderer,
My mom is innocent,
Here's to the Pyeongchang Winter Olympics!
- Cheers! - Cheers!
Bottoms up,
Why are you so sloppy?
You are so bad at anything you do,
When you first start,,,
working at the court, it isn't easy,
Jang Soon Bok,,,
They called to say they don't think she'll wake up,
Do you want to go to the hospital?
I'm going to go first,
Hey, Don't you know that a judge,,,
can't meet a defendant personally outside of court?
I'll follow protocol to go to the hospital,
I need to go finish writing a decision,
I see, A decision,
You need to write that well, You have to write it well,
Typographical errors that even clerks don't make,,,
- are mistakes that only,,, - Me too,
I'll go write my judgments well, Judgment,
Come here, Walk next to me,
I'm used to walking this way with my panel,
so I prefer it this way,
I'm an individual judge, so I prefer this,
They say it's light and day being an individual judge,
When will I ever become one?
Even the air in your office is better than in ours,
Are you on bad terms with Chief Oh,,,
because of Jang Soon Bok's petition for retrial?
It seems that way,
She's certainly getting in my way of success,
Gosh, it's cold,
Who is that?
Excuse me, Hey,
Is he okay?
He's sleeping,
It's too cold to sleep here,
Can you help him up?
Gosh,
Don't do anything others might get the wrong idea about,
Let's ask the security guards to look after him and leave,
Hold on,
Excuse me, Hey,
What's going on?
Hey, listen, Wake up for a second,
Hey, hey,
By any chance,,,
Where did you get that?
What is it about?
You're not in trouble, Just answer my question, please,
Is the owner of that sneaker,,,
Kim Ga Young?
Do you know Ga Young?
Yes, Do you know her?
Ga Young and I are close,
Really?
How did you get that?
It's all right, Just take your time, and answer the question,
He's scared,
It's all right, You don't have to tell us right now,
Kyung Ho told me that I could keep it,
Kyung Ho? Are you referring to Mr, Choi Kyung Ho?
Do you know Mr, Choi Kyung Ho?
Kyung Ho and I are close,
Kyung Ho,,,
went to save Ga Young,
He went to save her?
He went,
but Ga Young wasn't there, I only found her sneaker,
Then Choi Kyung Ho didn't,,,
Kill her?
Kyung Ho isn't a bad guy,
Kyung Ho,,,
told me that he had to rescue Ga Young,
Kyung Ho said,,,
that he was going to,,,
catch the bad guy,
1, 3, 7, 1,
(Han Joon)
It's the license plate number of the guy who killed Ga Young,
I don't recognize your warning,
Let's break our deal,
(Han Joon)
(Nothing to Lose)
If Kyung Ho is innocent, what should I do?
Be careful, If you keep this up, you might lose your life,
- Kill him, - Kill him? The crazy prosecutor?
You see, crazy people don't die that easily,
Do Han Joon,
There's no way,
Why do you,,,