JULIUS CAESAR
Citizens of Rome Gather round.
Welcome to Gordias. Now Gordias
was famous for his knot.
The oracles predicted that who
could untie the knot...
would conquer the whole world.´
Many came from far and wide but
none succeeded,
until one day the mighty Alexander
arrived
Alexander, Decended from the mighty
God Apollo.
Advance !
Apollo enlightened Alexander
and showed
him how to untie the knot.
Sylla has returned to Rome to
establish order.
He declares that the innocents
have no reason to fear.
But that those guilty of crimes against
him shall be most severly punished.
The men whose names are written on
these lists are declared outlaws.
They have no rights as citizens
enseforth they may be killed on sight
Anyone who takes it upon himself to
kill any of these men...
will be considered a friend of the state..
and shall be rewarded with the properties
and posessions these outlaws leave behind.
The biggest crime under Roman law.
Mother?
- Cornelia?
Where is my wife?
- at her fathers.
Grandmother The soldiers are comming
- Julia stay with her.
Sulla has taken the city with his army
He has made lists hundreds of people are on them
Are you?
- No my wife's father is.
Julia stay in the house.
Don't go.
- Father where are you going?
To get your mother.
Is he not on the list?
He's the one you want overthere.
- Right.
Have you heard?
- Yes we have to hurry.
What's the point running away
might as well die right here.
Please go.
- - She's right Cinna We must leave now.
Cinna hurry.
Go.
- Please, father.
Go Hurry!
Go.!
Please Cornelia, run !
He has helped Cinna to escape
Give me your name.
It's Caesar, from the house of Julia.
Arrest him.
No please no !
Are you Julius Caesar?
-Yes.
This way....
This way.
That is not negotiable.
Who is he ?
Julius Caesar.
Nephew to Marius...
You have unfortunate ancestery.
If you think it's unfortunate
to be descendent from the Gods.
Which God is that?
- The Julia descendent from Aeneas,
Who was...
- The son of Vénus, yes yes.
I recall Marius making such claims.
There are many people these days who
claim to be descendents from the Gods.
We have a crest which proves it..
I believe you can have them
fashioned in the market place...
...for a couple of dinars.
Why did you ask to see me ?
Your mother...
She came to see me.
Did she ask you to spare my life ?
And what you agreed ?
Well I promised that I would consider it.
And I'm supposed to be grateful to you ?
- No.
To you we are old friends.
- You killed a lot of old friends...
True, true true.
Old friends of the day become
fresh enemies at night.
What do you want in
exchange for my life ?
Why do you think I want anything in Exchange ?
And like you don't give things
away for free.
I'm not a man without compassion.
I will help you if I can.
First you must understand the
gravity of the crime.
Cinna was my greatest enemy.
And you helped him to escape.
Did he?
Of course not.
He escaped my soldiers only to be
killed by one of his servants.
My wife ?
- She's well.
I leave women to their health.
And since you are only the son of
Cinna by marriage,
I intend to leave you to yours.
If... ?
If you divorce your wife.
Well ?
No I refuse.
- You refuse to devorce your wife
Even though it may cost you your life ?
My wife is my teacher.
She's more clever than I am She's
more honest than I am,
She's a more compelling argument
than I am or you are.
Or your office is.
I won't devorce her.
That Is my answer.
- Ah, Pompée...
What can we do with men such as this ?
I don't know wether to embrace
him or strangle him.
I think we should let hin go.
- What ?
His uncle Marius
was my greatest enemy.
He got ten Marius inside him.
Look at his eyes.
You want to let him go ?
It's the ones who smile and flatter
you should worry about.
He speaks plainly.
You speak plainly don't you ?
Always.
Tell me...
Would you kill me if you could ?
In an instant.
You can go.
I said you are free to go.
What a big heart that boy has.
Bring it to me in the morning.
Was this Sylla's plan to slaughter me outside
so I wouldnt foul the carpet with my blood ?
I came to warn you.
- Why?
Because if you don't leave Rome
I'll have to do as he asks.
And ?
And I don't want to see men like
you die young..
What do you know about me ?
- You refuse  Sylla.
I'll tell you more some day
when there is time.
But now you must leave Rome.
Your family will be safe,
here take this.
Go east to Bythinie. Show this ring to
Nicomède, it will keep you safe in his service.
How do I know I can trust you ?
- You don't.
I'll not hand my fate over to that man.
So you'd let him kill you ?
He can try if he wants,
I'm not leaving Rome.
Why must you be so stubborn !
Pompée himself offers you help.
Why don't you accept it?
He's Sylla's man,
it could be a trick.
Don't you trust anybody at all ?
- yes.
I trust you.
- Then listen to me.
You're not the heaven and earth.
You're just a man.
And some things are bigger
than you are.
When you were in jail...
...I thought you were dead.
I started to grieve your death.
I'm asking you to spare me that, Caésar.
How can I live with myself if I knew
I had one chance to save your life.
And I failed
Is this pig for sale ?
- How much will you give me for it ?
Ten dinars.
- That's good money for a swine.
He requires carving.
Jules César.
We will feed it to my dogs.
That's the coast of Crête.
The ruler there used to make up laws
and hang them so high
that people couldn't read them.
And if they broke the law he'd
show then no mercy.
Today the shores are infected
by pirates pirates.
We need to anchore for the night.
Where has father gone ?
The other side of the water.
How long does it take to cross the water ?
It depends on the wind.
Sometimes you can cross it in days.
Sometimes if the air is still
you may not move at all.
Easy on the ropes,
we could use nails.
Its the Roman way isn't it ?
What kind of ransom do you get
for a Roman these days?
Two talents.
But I'll pay three to watch a roman drowned.
You'd get fifty from me alive.
And who would collect it ?
They would.
If your men...
...don't return before dawn,
you die.
Your time is up, Roman.
I'll fight one of you for another day.
That's another day.
Nobody is comming back for this Roman.
Throw him in the sea.
Ship !
Fifty talents.
And the money just happened to
find it's way into your purse ?
Sir I never stole a coin from you.
And I suppose it was the goldsmiths
who just happened to rob me again.
Sir they've been convicted for it.
_I know how these things work.
You share the profits with
these men.
You pay me well I would never risk
my life for a gold coin.
This is the magistrate's testiment
the goldsmiths have confessed.
Flavius had nothing to do with it.
Are you trying to tell me that a
man who handles so much gold.
never put a piece into his pocket ?
He's been proven innocent.
This needs your signature.
Strangle him.
- Wait !
He's been proven innocent.
Well I,
just disaprove of the verdict.
Sylla...
He's a good man,
and he's here on my introduction.
Allow me to vouch for him
and protect him.
You can vouch for him all you like.
But protect him you can't.
the penalty protests strangulation.
Strangle him.
- There seems to be an error of jugement.
My jugement ?
Pompée...
You're becomming very critical.
You want to rise above me.
Just waiting for your chance.
Those men worship the rising sun
and not the setting sun.
That's how the saying goes isn't it ?
But I am not the setting sun not
yet but in the meantime...
...I expect you to subordinate yourself
to my wishes wether you understand them...
...or not.
Strangle him !
No...
You...
You strangle him.
No.
Taije did you hear him say no ?
Ah, my dear general.
I asked you to strangle Flavius
and strangle Flavius you will.
And you will do it with your own bare hands.
You will strangle Flavius
or you yourself will be strangled.
Strangle him !
Strangle him now !
I will not have my orders disobeyed !
I swear to...
Father...
Who are your friends ?
Portia and Marcus.
Don't you remember them ?
Of course Cato's children.
Just don't grow them so much.
Thats our cousin.
Brutus...
What you reading ?
- ´Ethics.
Aristotle ?
- My uncle Cato gave it to me.
How is he ?
- He's as grumpy as ever.
Hasn't chamged a bit.
- Mother.
Caesar !
Don't get up.
- I'm not ill.
Let me get dressed.
I'm well,
I just got up too fast.
You don't have to get dressed.
Lets lie down together.
No wait.
Just...
Cornelia...
I never stopped waiting for you.
I never stopped missing you.
and now...
Here...
This is not supposed to happen.
I'm back now,  my love.
Two years is just too long.
There are those of you who work with Sylla.
and those of you who worked...
...against him.
But not all that worked with
him agreed with his laws.
I therefor propose that the rights
of the tribunes be restored
So that once again the people
can be fairly represented.
I propose a thorough reform of the courts.
And an unqualified reenstatement
of the senate
As the principal body of gevernment.
Caesar !
Its good to se you fresh
from another victory.
Oh he let me win.
It makes me feel old.
I'm Glad to see you made it back safely.
I hear you met with a number
of obstacles.
Yes. Fortunqtely your friend
Nicomede proved to be a valuable ally.
I never had a chance to thank you...
...for saving my life.
You defied Sylla.
He told you to devorce your wife and you
said no even though it meant sudden death.
That impressed me.
And it ...
reminded me of something.
You see my friend,
Sylla once told me
to devorce my wife.
And unlike you I obeyed him.
I left the one woman I loved.
Life is full of lessons .
So we tought each other
a thing of two.
Tell me how to get where
you are now.
Don't tell me I was wrong
to hope you were spared.
I have something to give to Rome.
But I have no voice.
If you want a voice in Rome,
Win the people,
Speak from your heart...
And when you make apromise,
Keep it.
Pompée...
Ipromise you
if you ever need my help...
...just give me a sign,
I'll come to your aid.
My name is Julius Caesar.
I'm here to honor
my wife, Cornelia...
...publicly
and for the last time.
She was a good woman.
She gave no thought to her own wellbeing.
Only to the wellbeing of others.
Rome was her first and greatest love.
We shared that love.
We dreamt of a Rome
without dictators.
Where sons never raise their
hands against their fathers.
Where brothers never raise
their swords against brothers.
Where Romans lived at peace
with fellow Romans by their side.
I ask you now to join with me,
In honoring not only the
memory of my good wife,
But in memory of all the good men and
women who have died fighting for a better Rome.
People of Rome, I, Julius Caesar,
make you this promise on the
body of my beloved wife...
...I will not rest until the Rome
she dreamed of is the Rome we live in.
Join me.
By not only the nephew
to our beloved Marius,
Who fought against the evils of Sylla
who took his life from him.
But I'm also a son of the Julia,
Who are descendents of the goddess Venus herself.
I offer you my hand.
A power supreme amongst mortal men,
Granted by the gods
superior to kings.
Let us work together comrades,
in our quest for an empire,
that is boundless,
united ...and free.
We shall have to watch him.
Or use him.
Good morning to you, Caesar...
Hail Caesar.
Greetings, Caesar.
Julia, I have something for you.
Now then... Ah here it is.
And I hope it will make you smile.
That's the first I seen
you smile in weeks.
Stop it all of you !
There is nothing he can do about it.
What happened ?
- The price of bread has tripled.
There is no grain in Rome.
--Why ?
Because the grain supply from Egypt
was cut off by pirates.
Half of Rome is without bread.
The city is close to panic.
Only the very rich can afford bread.
We must fight the pirates now or
Rome will be crippled forever.
So I propose that Pompee be given leigons
to attack this problem once and for all.
It's not a question of wether or
not we fight pirates,
It's a matter of how.
I propose we equip ten small armies to fight
the pirates at different parts of the coast.
So the pirates can destroy Rome
one two by the time ?
The pirates are a bunch of
uneducated hoodlems.
I hardly think they could stand
against a Roman assualt of any size.
Lets talk about things are gentlemen.
Not the way we would like then to be.
I can attest to the threat posed by these scavengers.
I was a victem of one of their assults myself.
Then perhaps you will regale us
with your sea stories Gaius Julius
In the tavern after the work
of the senate is done.
The work of the senate
is rarely done.
You see there are not thousands of pirates
in our waters. But hundreds of thousands.
Enough for all the rogue bands
preying on single vessles.
There are pirate admirals seeking,
With thousands of ships and troops
more skilled in naval combat even than our own.
Pretty speaches like this won't
even cook our lunch.
No speeches do as little
work as the senate.
How dare this arogent newcomer
insult this Auguste body ?
Auguste and plump, Bibulus,
like your own body.
Apparent from ardent chatter and inactivity.
Enough,...enough,...enough!
We have a man in our company who can
resolve this conflict with the pirates.
But do we honor him with that duty ?
No.
I'm with Caesar,
we have no bread.
Now are we a great empire or
are we going to be ruled by outlaws ?
To perform this commission,
Pompée will have to be given
an army twice the size
of the one Sylla used to take Rome
Have we learned nothing from the past ?
I see Rome should go hungary because Cato
can't find a single man he can trust.
Not any man with an army would take the state.
Not every man is a Sylla.
some men are ruled by circunstances but men
of character bend circumstances to their will.
They make nature behave in such a way that
their will is carried out on this earth.
They defy the elements.
And sometimes defy their own base of nature.
In order to see their ideals come
alive before their eyes.
Pompée is such a man.
Those of you who have lived know one
thing to keep the nation small.
Civil strife.
Tribes fighting tribes rather than
banding together in one arm of power.
As long as we fight in this room
seeking personal victories,
enacting petty revenges,
Rome will stay small !
I propose we put our opinions aside
and let one feeling rule us for a time
The love of Rome.
I propose we put our strengths
together and become a force
The world has never seen.
I propose you let a man...
...a single man,
lead us out of the dark.
I propose Pompée.
All those in favor.
Marcus...
- Julia.
Julia... look at you.
Brutus, wake up and tell Julia
how beautiful she looks.
.
Beautiful.
- You like it ?
All dressed for Pompée's triumph...
Who's going with me ?
None of you wants to join
the counsel of Rome ?
No offense, father, but do you really think we're
going to trail around with your lecters around.
Rome's greatest general has returned.
And we want to be free to run and follow him...
Run yes,...run...run
Go and enjoy yourselfs.
Come on.
- Thank you pompus.
Brutus ? Arent you going with them?
I want to return this to Apollonius.
- What is this ?
´Ah yes the Plato's law... Did you read it ?
- Yes.
And ?
Plato thinks that democracy is doomed to faliure.
He thinks that a state should
be run by a dictator.
A dictator who's become
enlightened through experience and learning.
I don't think plato would get
along with your uncle Cato.
Brutus ! Hurry up !
- Come on !
Hurry and catch up with your friends
or you'll have to come along with me.
See you at the ceremony.
Goodbye, father.
See, See...
Do you know what i want ?
Thank you for your kindness.
Let me take care of my son now..
Mother...
- Shh... rest.
Something happened to me there.
It's a affliction no more no less.
Your grandfather suffered the same
spells and lived into old age.
Name something else.
What happen I was watching Pompée.
He's been a friend to me.
We speak together easily like brothers.
Yet we couldn't be more different.
He's a great army leader.
His province has made him the richest
and most powerful man in Rome.
Your father wanted you to be a statesman
and now you are a counsel of Rome.
Happened to be beyond his dreams.
I need an army.
To turn yourself into a Pompée ?
How would you pay and feed such an army ?
Your counselship already costs a fortune.
Yes, I am counsel and I am broke.
Your attack today was stronger than usual.
There was something else mother, this
attack was different in other ways.
How ?
I saw something.
I saw something at that moment.
Not just about myself.
But about the whole humankind.
How we keep ourselves small.
Then  I realized I had not been inspired.
And as I watched pompee I saw
that he was not inspired.
And he would never be inspired.
And I realized the difference
between Pompee and me.
Pompée has merely done something.
But I, am for something.
I need légions.
Pompée has them.
He will lend them to me.
Why would pompee do that
diminishing his own power.
What could you offer him in return
to equal the value of an army ?
We trust in the wisdom of our fathers
And in their laws. and I, Cato,
trust in him.
Hail Pompée !
Cato, you flatter me.
But let us give credit to another man.
For I could not have fought
a war across the sea
Without knoledge that Rome was
in safe hands here at home.
For that we owe a debt of gratitude
to my friend and fellow council,
Gaius Julius Caesar !
Hail Caesar !
This is my daughter, Julia.
- Yes I know we've met.
It would honor my house if you
would give us a recitation.
Not in front of so many people ?
- You've done it in larger groups than this.
Father I assure you that I'm
not prepared for it.
Come...
The daughter of Caesar will recite for us.
Tonight,
Stands beside me and prays with me
A man dear to me and dear to the gods.
Mightier in victory than
the kings of Mycènes
With their golden haired horses.
And stronger more than the battle ghosts
That ride the shores of  Troy.
Hear me,
Sons of gold headed men.
Hear me sing the victory
Of a man dear to me and to the Goda.
Its really nothing.
- No, Its not your fault.
I'm not sure who's fault it is but I assure you I
will find out and he will be punished severly.
Thank you, counciler.
What is your name ?
- Calpurnia.
From who's house ?
- Lucius Piso.
I'm sorry for staring,
I thought perhaps...
...we met somewhere before.
Would you like to eat together ?
- I'd be delighted.
What hour do you call this ?
I think it's known as the fifth hour.
- Yes, The sun is comming up.
You're right, I was out with him.
We drank and ate and had entertainment.
He cares for me.
- Ah yes, he's twice your age.
And your friend remember.
Yes, he is my friend.
I just want to know if he
treats you with respect.
I like him... I do.
I don't love him not yet but ,
..that may come
Why are you behaving in such a manner ?
He is council.
He's the first man in Rome.
He has légions.
The price is high.
What price ?  It's customary for
the father to offer a dowery.
You know I have nothing to give you.
I accept.
I want a commission.
Gaul.
- Gaul ? It's taken.
By Cassius.
- I need a victory in battle.
Your not experinced enough in
warfare and you need legions.
Your légions...
She's all I got,
...I want 50 thousand for her.
50 000 talents ?
Soldiers.
How could you do it ?
How could you take my commission away ?
Because I think Caesar's
the right man for Gaul.
But I've put my staff to considerable
expense preparing my men.
And you'll be re-embursed.
- What ?
And I'll propose that you will
look after the garrison.
The garrison ?
- This won't do, Pompée.
We should put this before the senate...
- Lets not talk business...
...At my wedding.
It may tempt bad luck.
I have a confession to make.
What's that ?
We did meet before.
or rather...
...I met you
but you didn't meet me.
It was at the Pompée triumph.
You fell.
Nobody saw it but me.
I held you  to make sure you wouldn't hurt yourself.
- Thank you.
It shames me.
I never know when its
going to happen.
Many believe those who
have the condition
are holy...
...Blessed by God.
Perhaps.
What do you suppose a child of both our
faces blended together would look like ?
I think that it would look  rather beautiful.
Do you ?
Is it something you'd like to find out ?
- Yes.
Are you sure ?
I am less sure about my own name
than I am about this.
I am terible to have to ask.
- We have servants.
And if I want to go to bed early?
I'll follow you.
Ceasar...
You must make me a promise.
- Anything you like.
Come back from this war alive.
I promise you.
And hurry.
- That's two promises.
And win it.
- That's three promises.
Now it is your turn to promise me one thing.
Will you marry me before I leave.
How many dead ?
- In the region of 23 000 Celtes.
And Romans ?
- 1 12.
I'll have to prepare the burial back in Rome.
We're not returning to Rome.
We're going farther north.
There's a lot more of Rome out there.
Just has'nt called Rome yet.
The Romans !
We must tell Ceasar to retreat.
What I gave to Ceasar,
I will not revoke.
Wait !
Put down your blades.
Why have you come here ?
This land is ours,
you have no right to be here .
What is your name ?
Vercingétorix.
You stayed to fight alone ?
- This is my house.
I built it with my own hands.
And you'll burn it down.
You're free to go.
Give me a horse.
You heard him.
Give him a horse.
My dear Ceasar,
The people speak of you with admiration.
Some call you the great as
they called Pompée.
In the market people sometimes
bow to me as they pass.
You will also be delighted to know
The mariage that began as an advantage,
has blossomed into romance.
Watching Julia and Pompée together
delights me and saddens me.
That you're not here.
No one could be prouder to be
your wife, Ceasar.
But after so long without you,
I fear
I'm getting used to my solitude.
Come home soon my darling.
Until then I will be waiting.
Ceasar has killed 300 000 Celtes.
He attacked peaceful villages,
villages who pay taxes to the  Roman state.
Its beyond tolleration !
This is how you thank a great Roman general ?
Ceasar sent
100 000 slaves back to Rome.
Are you saying you havent taken any of them?
Then if any come from him I would have
got them from somewhere else.
Pompée, you have to be warry.
He's been away three years
fighting with your légions.
He's doubled their salary.
They are totally devoted  to him.
My lords,
As Cicero has put it so well:
Strain every nerve for the
preservation of the state.
Look in every corner for the storms.
They will burst upon you if
you do not see them in time.
I just remembered who he is !
What are you talking about ?
- That man.
Marc Antoine ?
Running from his debtors in Rome
to find wealth in the provinces.
Like all of us.
- not me !
I still fight for the glory of Rome.
My calvery has been attacked.
- By who ?
Gaél tribesmen. 14 000 dead.
- 14 000 ?
And many more wounded.
They acted under one leader.
His name is Vercingétorix.
Where could we find him ?
- In Alésia.
How long is the march ?
- Eight days.
Vercingétorix is in there
With 18 000 of his men.
Its the most invincible
stronghold in Gaul.
We'll never break it.
- We won't have to break it.
We'll build a wall around their city.
We'll trap them inside and starve them.
Noboby has ever built a
fortification of that length.
Then we will be the first.
Let's not waste time.
What do you want ?
I'm here to see Pompée.
- Come here.
Cato...
- Pompée.
Julia...
What brings you to Pisa ?
I've come to speak with you.
Your absence in Rome has been..
criticized.
As you can see,
my wife needs me here.
Can we speak privately ?
What's the matter, Cato ? Did your conversation
depend on speaking ill of my father ?
Sit, sit , Cato.
Thank you.
Ceasar is about to take the
last stronghold in gaul.
Vercingétorix has called for every tribe
from the mountains to the sea.
They are on the move toward Alésia.
How many men ?
Two hundred and fifty thousand.
And my husband ?
- Forty thousand.
He'll survive.
He has survived these many years.
He's never been up against so much.
Is this true ?
Will my husband lose this time ?
I don't know noone knows
the outcome of war.
You are consul, Pompée.
Do something.
If ceasar wins this battle...
- He will become the next Sylla.
Thats what you were going to say
was'nt it ?
That if he wins he will
become the next Sylla...
Why are you worried, Cato ?
You said he didn't stand a
chance against the Gauls.
Why call him back ?
Why not leave him there to fight
this battle to his own death ?
If you leave him there your next
Sylla will extinguish himself.
Your waiting for my husband to fail,
Aren't you ?
And so are you.
To arms !
This is it.
Soldiers at the gate !
He's trying to fool us into
gathering our troups here.
How do you know what he'll do ?
Because that's what I would do
I will wait here for
Vercingétorix to make his move.
His men are to weak to
attack our main camp.
He will move his calvery here and
try to break through the main wall
While his allies attack from the outside.
We cannot let these two
forces join together.
If they do,
We will not survive.
We must hold out !
Retreat !
Ceasar your men are asking for you.
It is with great sadness that
I write this letter to you my dear husband.
Your Julia gave birth early and
she suffered some pain in doing so.
The doctors were there
and did what they could to ease her suffering.
The child wasa boy but frail
their efforts could not save him.
He looked like you Caesar,
there was nobility in his face.
Your daughter struggled to
sustain this tragic birth.
But in the end she could not.
Pompée has kept himself from the senate,
prefering instead to pass time in no company.
He walks around the graveyard again and again,
Keeping fresh garlands on her tomb.
We take Alésia in the morning
.
Open the gate.
I know your only enemy is one man
and he is standing before you now..
I'm giving myself to you, Ceasar.
Our women died for us.
I give you my own life
so that you may let my men live.
If my men die there will be
nothing left of the Gauls,
and noone left to worship our gods.
I beg you.
Enslave my people if you need to.
But let them live.
Your men will live.
My dear wife,
You'll have to wait a bit more
before we're together again.
You see there are those in Rome
who would have me branded an outlaw.
So I have sent Mark Antony to
talk to the senate on my behalf.
Since there has never been a
soldier with an army such as mine
who would return to Rome
without taking her by force,
I too must be planning
such an assault,..but my crime is worse
Because I return
not in dishonor, but in triumph.
And this the senate cannot tolerate.
How long ago did Sylla ride
into town with his army,
Breaking the sacred Roman law stating
no man!
Must bring armed men past the
Rubicon into Rome.
How fresh in your memories does
bloodshed have to be ? for you to show caution.
Ceasar has done more for Rome than
any other general in its history. How do you respond...
You strip him of his councilship
in his absence without explanation.
He 's more than doubled the size of Rome
in the last eight years and what do you ask him to do.
Lay down his arms.
It's not  Ceasar, who is the criminal.
It is this senate !
This senate represents the
people of Rome.
This senate,
represents its own interests.
Sylla said the very same thing.
.
If he said it, he was right.
But the difference between
Sylla and Ceasaris
The people feared Sylla, Ceasar they love..
You know nothing...
...of peoples feelings.
Your right I don't.
Let me ask them.
People of Rome, I come to you
with questions from  Ceasar.
He wants to know what you want
so he can better serve your need.
The senate says they
represents the people.
But the senate wants Ceasar to lay
down his arms, and return to Rome as a man,
Not as a soldier.
And when he arrives, The senate
Will find him guilty of
crimes against the state.
Ceasar's crime is spending eight
years in battle, outside of Rome,
With none of the comforts we take for
granted with a daily treat to his life. Why ?
So he can bring wealth to the Roman people.
Temples, libraries, holidays and games...
Are all funded by Cesars levies in Gaul.
Yet what do they think in the senate ?
They think he's doing this for personal gains...
I ask you
If he's doing this for private gain,
Why does he stay in  Gaul ?
Why does he live in a tent ?
I, know why he does it.
He does it so we, Romans,
can live well.
What are you going to do about this ?
Whatever these men may think,
some of whom have never been
up on a horse's back,
I have never known a man
tougher on the enemies of Rome
nor gentler to his friends.
When I call myself a Roman,
The thing that makes me most proud,
Is to share that title with one other man.
A man who it has been my
privilage to fight beside.
A man
that has shown time and again
That he loves his own life
less than he loves yours.
His name is Caius Julius Caesar !
We must do something, Pompée.
Caesar could march on Rome
any time.
I'm not going to wait for him to come to us,
I'll gather our troups.
And attack him before he
sets foot in Rome.
I'm going to wipe him and his
legions off the face of the earth.
Men,
we have two choices.
We can be slaughtered by the army
Pompee is massing against us.
Or we can fight for our lives,
Just as we have done every
day for eight years.
I've made my decision.
I'm going to Rome.
I'm going to cross the Rubicon.
Will anyone be comming with me ?
To Rome !
Let the dice fly.
my legions from Spain
should bear up to Austria from the west.
The Thracerons will come to us from the north.
and from the east the Macédoniens.
Caesar is on his way to Rome.
How far is he ?
- Four days from here.
That's impossible !
- I heard it from Bibulus himself.
Caesar has passed the Rubicon.
We must leave Rome.
We cannot defend it without troups.
We'll go to Greese.
We'll amass what strength we can,
And then we'll take him in Rome itself.
I only hope
we don't arrive too late
And find the bodies of our
friends on the senate steps.
It has been decreed by the new senate
That the title of dictator is
bestowed on Caius Julius Caesar.
It is decreed
There will be fifty days of
thanksgiving in his honor.
He is given the courts and
elected counsol for life.
Hail Caesar !
You treat me as a king.
Though I assure that is one
role I shall never adopt.
I am Caesar, and only Caesar.
It is for this crown alone
I conqured Gaul.
Caesar...
Caesar !
Beware the ides of march.
The ides of march.
Beware.
The men and women of Rome
are crying out for your head.
For a moment ,
I saw them as you do.
You don't know how I see them.
I was disgusted with them.
How do you keep your purpose
clear in your mind ?
When i met you in your village, I could
see you had your purpose clear in your mind.
And it was pure.
I can see that it hasen't changed.
What could you do to preserve it?
You want to know ?
Yes.
I only fight my enemies.
You think
we are similar, Don't you ?
Thats why it pains you to see me die.
We are very different, you and me.
I know when its over.
And what's left isn't worth having.
Give me the honor of dying alone
By my own hand.
Instead of in a public spectacle
of your Roman mob.
I have to do what the people want,
I have no choice.
I thought power gave you more
choice, not less.
Listen to them. Do you hear that ?
For pity sake, give me a sword.
Have him dead within an hour.
Hail Caesar.
The ranks here are depleted.
My men will be joining you.
How shall we explain to the people
That these men have become senators ?
They haven't been selected by
the provisional leaders
.
The law is changed.
And keep in mind the
people trust my jugement.
You will be joined by my finest men.
I've spent eight years
with them in Gaul.
I must leave for Greece
to fight Pompée.
I'm leaving Rome in Mark Antony's capable charge.
- Do we have no say in this ?
I don't want to distract
you with bureaucracy.
I'd rather leave you free to
argue matters of the state.
You think there will be black lists...
There won't be any lists.
Sylla killed his enemies,
I forgive mine.
Good day to you, gentlemen.
They left in a hurry.
Attention Caesar !
I did not cross the Rubicon to kill old friends.
I did it to protect myself
against my enemies.
I hope we can secure ourselfs
through mercy and not vengefulness.
Your all free to go.
- We owe, all our lives to Caesar.
Did you say something,my old friend ?
I thought I heard you speak.
I'm grateful for your clemency.
Brutus, Come dine with me.
Caesar...
make peace with Pompée.
For years,
His only hope was that one day,
You would rule Rome,
together again...
With what ?
With Julia,
uniting you both.
He tolerated me,
Because he loved Julia so much.
Caesar he loved Julia because
he saw you in her.
He told me that Julia's death
made life unbearable.
And add to that the end of your friendship.
He counted his life as finished.
I'll make peace with him
if peace is what you want.
I want to establish some sanity in Rome.
The people had enough of fighting.
Will you help me ?
- How can I help you ?
I want you to go back to Rome
and be my préteur.
If peace is what you want,
Then it will be my honor to serve you.
Pompée has gone to Egypt.
The king died, leaving trone to be squabbled over
by a twelve year old boy and eighteen year old girl.
Ptolémée and Cleopatra ?
I don't know which one I trust less.
Help me ready the ships.
I'll follow him in the morning.
You don't need to take troups with you.
Pompée has gon to egypt alone.
the troups went to Utica.
With youruncle Cato ?
- yes.
Trust me, Brutus.
Whoever wants peace, will have it.
He was most cruely murdered on
the palace steps by his own men.
It's rumored that they were
bribed by Pothinus.
By Caesar.
There's only one enemy left.
I am Pothinus,
chief of the ruling counsul.
In the name of king Ptolémée,
I welcome you , Caesar.
Your king is very generous,
But as you can see, we haven't brought any horses.
This grain is for your men sir.
My men will eat indoors, Pothinus.
I'm sure you will put us up very
comfortably, in your palace.
I'll tell you the truth, Caesar.
Ptolémée fears for his life.
There's been a great deal of
discord in Egypt.
So he has forbidden all visitors.
You, of course, are very welcome in the palace.
And my men.
And your men.
Pothinus, you wouldn't have anything to do
with helping the king make his decisions ?
Would you ?
- The king is a boy sir.
Forgive him, and forgive me.
We are your allies and your
servants great  Caesar.
We only have the interests
of Rome in our hearts.
Bring out the gift.
This is Pompée's ring...
Where is he ?
We thought you'd be pleased.
Excuse me, Caesar.
There is aservant with an urgent
message from Cleopatra.
Bring her.
If you want to hear the message
you'll have to dismiss your guard.
What word from Cleopatra is
of such importance ?
Cleopatra asks for your protection.
Protection, why ?
Pothinus plans to kill her,
as he did Pompée.
Is that why you are disguised
as your own servant...
...Cleopatra ?
I came to you, Caesar,
Because you are the only
man I can trust.
Why does Pothinus want to kill you ?
My father wanted me to rule Egypt,
he wrote it in his will .
But Pothinus banished me with
a price on my head.
Now any servant can kill me
and be rewarded for it.
Caesar...
You and I, are alike.
You are the son of Vénus,
and I, am the daughter of Isis.
You and I, live by the same
devine heart beat.
That's why we must help each other.
- Are you trying to seduce me ?
I don't try.
I seduce...
...or I don't.
I do not have to seduce with my body.
I have something much better than that.
My country...
...It is the richest land in the world.
Egypt and Rome are different.
Rome is masculine.
Egypt is feminine.
Rome, is sunlight, Egypt is twilight.
But its not part of Rome not yet.
Make me queen, and the east
and west will be united.
We will be god and godess
ruling the world.
You kiss me with the tongue of a serpent.
I must test you to see if you are poison.
And am I ?
- No, but I can taste Gaul.
Will you stay in Egypt with me Caesar ?
- What does Egypt have to offer
That Rome does not ?
- Have you heard of the fertile cressant ?
Is it the region down bellow ?
- It is it is !
What grows there ?
I believe the region fertile
enough to haunt a king.
If you doubt it try planting
something there !
Only promise me one thing.
When you return to Rome,
you must be fateful to me.
But I'm married , I'm,
already being unfateful.
With you ! - What does married
compared to state and politics.
Demand you give  yourself to a woman.
In politics you lie you're unfaithful.
- We'll bury him with honors.
I'll bury him myself
.Let the state celebrate his life.
- Which state ? Rome ?
The Rome of Caesar ?
To accept your honors
would defile my name.
And on behalf of my
father and my family,
I decline.
Now I'm asking you to leave this room.
There is no peace in the
world like in my house.
Calpurnia...
Would you greet your husband
with a kiss ?
Dismiss them.
Can't a man return to his home and
expect a warmer mood from his wife ?
How could you bring her to Rome ?
It was for the good of the state.
Cleopatra rules a large part of africa.
And all of you.
Noone rules me Calpurnia.
Not Cleopatra, not even you.
But what I want is the love that you
promised me when we married.
You can't have it. You can have my
obediance, you can have my loyalty.
But I can't love those
who dishonor me.
No one can dishonored you.
- You're right I dishonored myself
When I gave my vows to you in mariage.
- You made a good mariage you're Ceasar's wife!
I should have married a man other than Ceasar,
That would have been a good mariage.
So I wouldn't have to watch my
husband perform for Egypt every night.,
in order to keep the riches of
that land flowing into Rome.
Between you and Cleopatra,
I don't know who is a concubine !
Retain your dignity ther's a limit
to what I'll hear from you.
I have no dignity left.
Perhaps I ought to buy some.
Maybe I should learn like you have,
that you can be bought and sold.
What's the price? What's the
price of consulship these days ?
What's the price of being king ?
When did your hope leave
and vision for the people
become this lust
for power itself ?
Was it when Julia died ?
I have nowhere else to go
so I'll stay here.
But I'll live apart from you,
not as man and wife.
May the gods forgive me for
breaking my mariage vows.
But I pray they forgive you for breaking yours.
You're an early riser, Brutus.
So are you.
Lately I am.
I couldn't sleep last night worrying
about the honor of your name.
You know something about these ?
I know the writting, but
don't ask me who wrote them.
Minds change quickly in
these troubled times.
And I take you to whoever doubt these men.
Oh Brutus i did my best to persuade
them that you are a man of honor,
Though you wouldn't pledge to
keep Ceasar from becoming king.
I gave you my pledge that I'd
oppose him in the senate.
But some of us feel that to oppose
a man like Ceasar with words
Is the same thing as handing him the crown.
I try to use words before the sword,
Cassius.
Just as I try to use reason before passion.
People say, calling on reason before
passion can lead to idleness.
And sometimes action is required. But
I know that you're a decent man
And that your meek and gentle nature
is how you feel you best serve the good.
I'm not gentle in defending my beliefs.
But you have given me no proof
that Ceasar will demand the crown.
Do you plan to be at the senate
at the calendes of March ?
No, I will be here.
They say that on that day ceasar
will move that he be made king.
I will come if I am sent for.
- Hu HU  This is what they mean.
People say that this is weakness to come
when you are summoned and at no other time.
To accept the favors of a
tyrant like Ceasar.
He spared my life.
- But he took the life of Cato,
Your wife's father,
who treated you as a son.
Has she ceased her mourning ?
No, and neither have I.
So you're greiving over Cato's death...
- Cassius, yes I'm greiving .
But private affection and public
duty are not the same thing.
And yet they say that in your grief,
you just weep and say prayers
and fill your wife's drinking
cup and go to bed.
And when Ceasar comes to you tonight you'll
be like his boy and fill his cup as well...
Who is saying this ? Who ?
I don't act for Ceasar.
I act for  Rome,  ...Always for Rome.
Brutus I've done everything to convince
them you're a man of action that you love Rome.
I've spoken in your behalf many times singing
your praise, condeming those who speak against you.
But...
some men have ideas.
They think highly of those who gave
their lives to expell the kings from Rome.
Your ancestors ! And they were
only men, not gods.
Please don't stay.
- I am staying.
Why do you want to torment yourself ?
- I won't be tormented.
Will he ?
Isn't that what you wanted to do ?
It will be the best thing for all.
I don't trust that you or any other
man knows what's best for Rome.
I will take my seat.
A woman has a right to see
varity, doesn't she  ?
Calpurnia...
Portia...
Romans we're here to celebrate
the return of caesar !
His return, not only with her majesty Cleopatra,
But with Egypt itself.
Where he has transformed the richest land
in all the world. It is now not only Egypt,.
It is egypt... and it is  Rome !
I said before
and I will say again...
I will not be king of Rome.
I an only Caesar.
I need no crown...
...to act on your behalf.
Do you still believe that
ours is not just cause ?
I'm with you.
We have to act soon.
We will wait when caesar brings the senate to order.
Lépide will call for the elections.
Casca, you will ask Caesar
to consider the petitions.
You, Cassius,
Will step behind  Caesar.
No man should go for his blade
until we're all in reach of Caesar.
Every knife must enter Caesar's
body at least once.
And if,.. we fail,
our plot is discovered before we even begin,
we turn our knives on ourselves,
Without hesitation.
We all agreed ?
For the senate. I will meet
with Caesar at Cleopatra's house.
Go.
Brutus...
Why are you pacing like that ?
- I'm concerned we will be late.
Caesar !
Calpurnia, What are you doing here ?
I had a dream last night.
Please don't go out today.
I'll come to you later,
at our home.
I saw you slaughtered,
in your own blood.
It was horrible.
Well I cannot let dreams or flights
of birds direct my actions.
I can't let you go.
I swallow my pride today to come to you,
Because your life is more important
to me than my pride. Now you listen to me...
The senate is conviened for the consul.
They can't conduct one day of
business without their Caesar ?
There are matters on the agenda which
can only be delt with by you Caesar.
They can wait a day.
- And what should I tell the senate ?
That their consul is at home,
Because his wife had a bad dream...
As your friend Caesar,
I have to advise you on this.
You called the senate together.
Show them you're a man of intention.
Meet with your senate.
They  are waiting for your guidance.
I'll be with him ledi.
I'll never leave his side.
I'll come to you later.
Hail Caesar !
Portia...
I'm not fit to be alone today.
Sit down.
Bring us some wine.
- Yes, let's have some wine.
What business do we have today ?
Two legal breifings,
And election for a questeur,
and the petitions from the senate.
Let's get the election out of the way.
_ The election
I move we take the petitions, first.
I called for the election the
election will commence.
But a...
Marcus Octavius, who is running for
the office, is not yet here.
Petitioners, Then. Approach.
I'm glad Caesar is with Brutus today.
Why ?
Last night I dreamth,
He was stabbed to death.
Brutus...
Caesar, I ask mercy for my exiled brother.
Why are you petitioning what so
recently has been denied ?
Who is the next petitioner?
I want to ask mercy for my father
who has been put in jail.
I ruled your father be in
prison and my word is law.
Old man...
You said something foretell
the ides of march.
nothing has happened yet,
The ides have come.
They have come,
but they've not yet gone.
I want to ask for your pardon,
my great Caesar.
And I pray for your soul.
Stop it !
Caesar !
Caesar is assinated !
Brutus...