Come on.
Babes?
Let me in. I'll help you.
Open up, Tams.
- St Tropez in here?
- Shit.
You all right?
Come on, you're gorgeous.
I'm a bit of a mess.
I swear, you're gonna love this place.
Trust me.
I reckon Ibiza
woulda been better.
Don't wear that. It's not really
my colour. It'll look great on you.
You'll look gorgeous.
Where's my phone?
Ryan? Fucking twat.
- Here, pass it.
- Why doesn't he just leave you alone?
- Kim, you wouldn't dare...
- He's toxic, babe.
I don't believe you.
You promised.
No more contact.
Here's to Tammi, for being brave.
- And a wicked girlie weekend together.
- Three of us.
Three of us.
Cheers!
I can't believe we're here finally...
This is gonna be so cool.
- Right, what's everyone drinking?
- Champagne.
Champagne. Right.
- You don't have to...
- Might as well buy a bottle, right?
- Bring it on, my good man.
- Don't posh boys drink this all the time?
I have it on my cornflakes.
I'm Marcus by the way.
- Kim.
- Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you.
Just do one thing for me?
Please.
- What?
- Game on.
Excuse me.
He wants his drink back.
Oh, shit, man! Let's...
- Come on, ladies.
- Are we going now?
So, all right...
Ptchaa!
- Fuck off.
- What?
- That's shit.
- It's not, it's good.
Is that supposed to be a trick?
Like, you're some sort of a magician?
It's not a trick, my dear.
It's an illusion.
Can you believe that yesterday
we was in Leeds in the sodding rain?
- And now we're here.
- I know, babe.
- I told you we'd look after you.
- We'll see yet.
What now, ladies?
Hit another bar or something?
Can't we get a bottle of wine
and drink it here?
You're welcome to come back
to the yacht and have a drink with us.
Yeah.
Right. You were nicking drinks,
but you've got a yacht?
We just wanted you to like us
for who we really are.
- You do not have a boat.
- Kim, they do.
I saw a dinghy parked over there!
- Daddy's boat!
- Course it is.
No, we're crew.
You know those boats in the marina?
- We crew one of those.
- You're sailors?
We just came back off
a three-month stint.
The owner flew out yesterday,
as did the skipper.
- And left you in charge?
- Absolutely. I'm the second mate.
- Josh here's the deckie.
- Skivvy, more like.
Well, what are you, then?
The onboard hairdresser?
International playboy.
Just flew in from 'biza to check out
my old mucker, the 'coose.
Look, the new crew arrive on Monday.
This is our last weekend together.
What do you say?
Lead the way.
- Here?
- Yeah, sure.
Ladies first. Then fellas.
It's just up here on the right.
- Oh, my God!
- Whoa, easy...
- How about this?
- Relax. It's going according to plan.
Wicked.
Right, you ready?
Is everyone ready?
You guys ready?
Yeah.
You lot.
I think we should go back.
- You what?
- No offence, but...
I thought it was just like
a girlie weekend, like the three of us.
Babe, if you want to chill at the beach,
then, we can catch up later, yeah?
Come on, Tam. Don't be mardy, yeah?
We'll just go for one drink.
Yeah, I know what you're saying.
I'm just...
This lot are a laugh.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
allow me to introduce to you the boat.
Seventy-six feet of pure luxury
motor yacht and may I say...
- Sean! Let us on!
- Oi, Sean! Oi, Sean!
Hey.
- Come on, Tam.
- Mmm, all right. One drink.
Wicked.
- I'm Kim, nice to meet you.
- Sean. Nice to meet you.
- All right, mate.
- All right, Blue.
- This is Sean, our engineer.
- Lisa.
- Tammi.
- Sean.
Nice one.
- So... you're Josh's brother?
- For my sins, yeah.
- He been misbehaving?
- A little.
No, bless him.
He's a right sweetheart.
- Kim, check it out.
- What?
What is it?
Marcus and Bluey, man, unstoppable.
We're so on it.
We? Right, what am I supposed
to be doing?
I don't know. Serve drinks?
- What do you think then, eh?
- Hmm, yeah.
- Impressive, or?
- It's not bad.
- You been on a boat before?
- Yeah. Ferry to Ireland.
I think this is a bit bigger.
You gonna give us a tour, then?
All right, yeah. Come on, then.
- Come on.
- Check it out. It's like the Tardis.
Oh, my gosh.
This is the stateroom.
The owner's bedroom.
Bloody heck.
This is bigger than my flat.
It's all right this, isn't it?
- Come on.
This is the master guest room.
For VIPs.
That will be us, then.
Come on. Show us the rest.
All right!
Check out these beauties.
They crank out 1,000 horsepower each.
OK...
Shoulda seen your brother, man.
He rounded them kittens up.
- Yeah, I'm very proud. Marcus...
- Shame he didn't bring one for you.
- Three into four don't go.
- Think I'll have to sit this one out, eh?
Suit yourself.
I'm on Kim like butter on toast.
Marcus has that other one.
- Lisa.
- Yeah, Lisa.
Funbags fitted as standard.
Funbags?
That leaves you and little Josh
fighting for bronze.
Get in there.
That Tammi's a peach.
Nah. Josh is after her. It's fine.
Real, man. You gonna let
your kid brother chew your grass?
I don't even know what that means.
He's been learning skills, mate.
Skills at the hands of the Bluemaster.
Oh, really?
So he knows how to talk shit now?
Mate, he's going to law school.
Euuurgh. It smells of boy!
- Is this where you stay?
- Yeah.
- What, the three of you?
Very cosy.
Hope you've been careful.
Ooh!
- Wicked.
- Babe.
Let's 'ave it.
Easy-peasy.
Just have to count to four, all right?
- Here we go!
- Just slip it in.
Oi, guys, guys, guys. I'm sorry
but you cannot pump the music like that.
Don't cock-block me, boss.
Mate, if one of the other skippers hears,
we're on the next flight home.
Blues, he's right. Be subtle about it.
Oh, man.
You leave your balls in Customs?
- Erm, is there a problem?
- Don't worry.
We'll be back on the road shortly, OK?
- Nice meeting you, but gotta go...
- Guys, guys. Look relax, yeah?
New plan, all right? Fuck the marina.
We party on the high seas.
That's really not a good idea.
Don't worry about it.
Drinking fine champagne,
watching the sunset over the Med?
- Can't do that in no club.
- Marcus...
Anyone says anything, we'll say
we're emptying the bilge tanks.
Sounds like a plan.
Come on, Sean.
Fine.
Game on!
Wicked!
You want a go?
- Don't know how to do it.
- It's easy. Just unwind it. Here you go.
You keep holding it, then.
- Now just throw it over there.
- Oh, I can't do that. I can't.
You can do it.
Did someone say they were seasick?
Cos I've got a very special cure.
- E's on the house!
- Yeah, but are they dud?
It's not the drugs you wanna
worry about. It's Bluey on the drugs.
I'm 100% dependable, mate.
- I'm a fucking Volvo, mate.
- Promise? We've got guests.
These are the shiznits, baby.
Give you a nice lickle tingle.
Give us one, then.
- Joshie?
- Know what, Blue, I'm fine. I'm good.
Josh, mate...
Mate, mate, mate, mate,
mate, mate, mate, mate...
Don't take that one! Ha!
- Do you just want to do half of that?
- Is that all right?
I cracked a nail!
This... is what it's all about.
Whoo!
- What's it like?
- 8.7!
- Oi!
- Aim lower!
Leave him alone!
It's a clay pigeon.
Marcus is teaching the owner to shoot.
Show us your gun, then.
Please. We hardly even
know each other.
Whoo!
10.0!
He's joined the Marines.
He's gonna be a lieutenant.
- Really?
- Really.
Oh, my God, I'm so happy.
Come on in. It's perfect.
- What?
- I've never been out to sea like this.
What?
- You can swim?
- Yeah.
Come on.
You lot, I swear...
- Wait for the E to hit, it'll be amazing.
- Better bloody be.
Ah! Friggin' heck!
- Come on, Blue, in you get.
- Come on, Blue! Get in here!
Kim, you gonna go clubbing
when we're back?
Yeah. Pasha. Do you want to come?
What?
Nothing. A mate who DJs there
told me the maddest story...
- Ah, who?
- Not saying.
But you'd know him, whatever
this geezer I'm talking about.
Tell us.
- I don't know. It's a bit full on.
- Go on. Tell us.
Oh... All right.
- He got tarmac'd.
- Tarmac'd?
It's well grubby. He pulled
this goth bird after a set, right?
Goes back to her place.
So she's on top, yeah?
All of a sudden,
she sits up on his chest...
- Blues, abort now. Seriously.
- No man. You gotta hear it!
She drops her load right on him.
Which is bad enough, right?
But then she rolls her butt up and down
like a steamroller. Tarmac'd.
That is fuck all.
Ain't you lot heard of a "Dirty Sanchez"?
Yeah!
Oh, my God. Turkey slapping?
You know what it is, right?
You take your dick,
and slap it round a girl's face.
Or a boy's!
You need a bit of length
to get a good swing on it.
Rules little Josh out, then.
- Anyone heard of a Donkey Punch?
- Yeah, man, sweet.
- Oh, you know it do you?
- Know it? I've done it.
OK, genius. Tell us.
Nah, man. You know, ladies present.
Basically, right, you're taking
a loved one from behind,
and just when you're about
to blow your load...
...back of the neck,
involuntary muscle spasm.
Ooh, man.
The clench?
You've never felt anything like it, mate.
- Still reckon you've done it?
- Fuck off.
What's in it for the girl?
- Don't understand the question.
- You're a wrong 'un.
The sky's incredible.
I love it out here.
- So, do you want to go back to Leeds?
- Not really.
There's too many people
I don't want to see any more.
So why stay? Make a leap.
- What?
- Oh, wait, come here.
- What are you doing?
- Back flip.
You idiot.
What's that?
Russian Ice, man. Huge in 'biza.
But the doctor recommends
just a baby hit.
It's proper hardcore.
I am hardcore.
Ooh, ooh.
Ah, it makes your chest go all cold.
Go on, then.
Come on, little Josh, suck it down.
Yeah, baby.
You're funny, man.
Why don't we take this downstairs, huh?
I'll take you...
Don't worry.
He won't do anything unless he's told.
Oh, yeah.
Pretty ladies, come to Bluey...
Naughty. Gimme.
OK, now you two.
Why not? You went to public school,
didn't you?
Shit, I got kicked out for being straight.
Who's got the best butt?
Ooh. It's not bad.
Now the other one.
Nice and firm.
Oi!
I was seeing someone
before we left, but it ended.
- Badly?
- She messed me about.
What about you?
Yeah, I was with someone
but people grow apart, don't they?
In fact, that's bollocks.
I caught him cheating
with a really old friend of mine.
That's horrible.
I felt like such a fucking idiot
for not realising...
No. He's the fucking idiot.
Wait a minute.
Them lot have all gone.
- Josh, too?
- All of 'em.
Leave him. He'll be all right.
Oi, mate, make yourself useful.
Back up, back up.
Get us all in, man.
Slow... slow down...
better not come yet.
How about my boy here gets involved?
Oi, mate.
Come here.
You're up, bro. Break off a piece.
'Harder, mate.
Harder. Fucking pound her.
'She loves it.
'Oi, mate, slap her arse.
- 'Gonna come? '
- 'Yeah. Yeah.'
- 'You know what to do, yeah? '
- 'Yeah. Oh, fuck! '
'Do it. Do it.'
- Do it!
- Ah!
Lisa? Lisa?
Did you get it over here?
Sean? W... will you come
downstairs please?
- Wish I could fucking find it.
- Let me.
- Mate, I think she's dead.
- Oh, God... Lisa!
- Lise!
- No, Lise... Lisa.
What happened?
We were just...
She must have OD-ed.
Look, I'm calling it in.
- The coastguard can pick us up...
- Look, don't...
- Kim, come on.
- Don't.
Just... she's...
Th... they're not going to get here...
By the time they're here, we'll be gone.
There's no point.
We've just got to keep it together
and we'll be back, OK?
What the fuck, man?
- What have you done?
- Me? I haven't done anything.
Mate. I saw you.
Wh... what the fuck?
What did you do?
This fucking mong donkey-punched her.
No...
Sh... she OD-ed or she...
had an allergic reaction.
To what, my cock?
He donkey-punched her. For real.
I thought...
- You said...
- I didn't say shit, mate!
It was a joke, you dick.
A story. No one fucking does it,
you stupid fucking cunt.
- This is not fucking happening.
- No?
Check the replay.
I just...
Bluey and Josh...
...acting weird.
Weird?
How do you mean weird?
They were shouting and...
...filming.
Bluey had a camera.
'Do it! '
We are in so much shit.
Did you call it in?
Your brother has something
he needs to tell you.
I erm...
I... I didn't mean to...
It's all right, babe, we're almost home.
Lisa OD-ed, babe.
It were an accident.
It weren't.
You have to help me.
Please.
What the fuck are you doing?
We're all going down for this.
For a long time.
- We just explain...
- Explain?
There's a girl downstairs with a broken
neck, and our DNA's all over her!
Doesn't look good.
The best thing for all of us,
and especially your fucking stupid
prick of a brother, is if...
We could say she fell overboard.
No body. No case.
What the fuck's going on?
It's all right.
I'm calling the police back home.
- 'Emergency response... '
- Shit!
What are we telling them?
What the fuck is going on?
Can you hear me?
Listen to me!
I know it sounds callous...
The girls'll never agree to this.
Girls? Are you gay? They're lucky
we don't dump them, too.
Fuck is your problem?
It's your fault we're in this mess!
I'm the bad guy? I didn't snap
a girl's neck like a fucking twig.
You gave him the drugs, you fed him
those fucking fairy stories!
He's a big boy.
Didn't do anything he didn't want to.
Shut up. Shut your face.
Don't push your luck.
You're going to chuck that tape
and keep your mouth shut. All right?
All right, then. I'll get it.
- Throw the fucking thing!
- Bluey!
What about when we get back?
They'll just go straight to the police.
And say what?
"We were E'ed up, fucking these lads,
"but it weren't our fault."
We don't need their consent.
Not anymore.
Someone needs to tell them.
Why aren't we going home?
We are.
- I'm not an idiot.
- Sit down.
Look, a really shit thing has happened
and everything's fucked.
Now, it's in everyone's best interests
that we do the right thing.
The right thing?
We just feel, like,
the best thing would be if we...
...bury Lisa at sea. Here. Now.
Why would you do that?
Because as far as the coastguard's
concerned, Lisa fell overboard.
You're all fucking mental.
Look, how long
have you actually known Lisa?
Do you want to be the one
who has to tell her parents
exactly what she was doing
when she died?
Look, I'm acting skipper of this ship.
I just want what's best for everyone.
We bury Lisa at sea.
We call it in,
when the coastguard comes,
we tell them she had too much to drink
and fell overboard. It happens.
But she didn't, did she?
You killed her. It's on that tape.
What tape?
Sean, you better tell them they can't.
Tell them. It's wrong.
- When they find the body, what then?
- They're not going to find the body.
The decision's been made.
This will all be over, very soon.
Marcus?
We have to be in International Waters
before we do this.
This ship is registered in Panama,
so once we're over that line
in International Waters,
we're under Panamanian law.
If it ever went to court...
we'd be in Panama.
Shut up, Josh!
It's the most corrupt place on earth.
There's no way they'd convict.
We do it now.
We call it in after we cross the line.
- I just... you know... Sorry.
- We need to do this now.
While those girls are still scared.
All right, Kim.
No, please. Please, no...
Don't you dare touch her.
Don't you dare fucking touch her!
Now why don't you sit down?
I'm not asking. Sit.
I'm not your dog.
Good girl.
Josh, go and stop the boat.
Now!
Sean, get the anchor out of the RIB.
If we don't weigh her down,
she'll be ashore before we are.
This is not right.
Look. I've worked too fucking hard
to let your brother fuck it all up.
This way,
everyone gets their lives back.
Not everyone.
Oi!
- Get off!
- You killed her!
- That's what I'll say when we get out!
- Yeah? Go tell the police.
Tell them about the drugs
you were taking,
how you were fucking a stranger
when your friend died.
Shut up!
Cos you've got no tape, no body,
no proof of anything.
It's your word against ours.
Right! Tie them up!
Fuck you!
Leave her!
Go on. You fuckers,
I swear to God I'll cut you!
So you're going to cut me, yeah?
Bluey, hold her.
Fucksake, Sean, let's just do it now!
No! No!
Fucking bastards!
- Do you want to join her?
- Do you want to fucking join her?
How would you fucking like it?
Fuck!
- Marcus!
- Go in there and find him!
- Quick.
- Where the fuck is he?
Marcus!
Oh, fuck! How do you?
Whoa!
Don't you fucking touch her!
Josh, get back here and help me!
- Fucking trying to kill me!
- The girls moved the boat.
I almost got through.
Fuck that. There's a gun here.
We've got to find it.
No, we need to get flares or something.
Someone's got to be able to help us.
Kim!
Where the fuck are those girls?
Downstairs.
Why? What are you going to do?
I'm going to go and have a hot shower.
You want to check whether that's OK
with our guests?
So you want to shoot me now?
We found Marcus.
Dead?
'Fraid not.
Here. Come on. It's freezing.
All this crazy shit is not helping.
- And what you're doing is really helpful?
- Look, you and me...
We're the only ones
with our heads screwed on.
You helped them throw Lisa!
You helped them throw her
like she were a...
Look, I just need...
...just need you
to keep Kim under control.
Fuck, man.
Marcus...
Thought we'd lost him.
Got to look out for each other.
Yes.
We're in the clear, right?
It's just their word
against ours?
Yeah.
Well, not quite...
Josh. What're you saying?
I dressed it up in legalese, but...
...basically it's all bullshit.
Wouldn't stand up in court.
The girl was off her face.
So there was no informed consent.
They'll say it was rape.
- But there's no body.
- Right.
Conspiracy to pervert
the course of justice.
Those girls get in front of a jury...
So, basically... we're fucked?
We're not.
Marcus is.
As acting skipper, anything that happens
aboard is... his responsibility.
He takes all the heat.
Legally, he's 100% liable.
Right word in the wrong ear...
You tricky little bastard.
What?
You think I'd shaft the 'coose?
- I'd never...
- Damn right.
Cos I've got a few tricks of my own.
Suck on that, bitch.
- Where's Sean?
- Dunno.
- Marcus wants you.
- What?
He's in the shower. Dropped the soap.
Needs some help picking it up.
Think you can take the piss?
Sean. I need to...
Right, play time's over.
We've got 45 minutes left.
We reach the International Line,
we call it in.
Well, why aren't we going now?
Until that moment, everyone stays
right here where I can see them.
Why don't you fix us a meal?
I'm starving.
- Starvin' Marvin.
- You are joking.
That's about the only sensible
suggestion I've heard all evening.
Thank you, Marcus.
- You're tired...
- Fucking paranoid.
We need to get
some food inside us,
before any more accidents happen.
Right, then. Why don't we take a look
what's in the kitchen?
Watch them.
Fuck, man. This all there is?
Josh?
You know what? This is really tasty.
So what's everyone doing
when we get back?
Reckon it's time for the Bluester
to move on.
Can't face Blighty. Quite fancy Goa.
Ever been?
- No.
- You should.
You're quite a goer yourself.
- Going home, Marcus?
- Am I fuck.
I've still got three months of freedom
before I get badged.
- Marcus...
- Not now Josh.
- We've only got 20 minutes left.
- Leave it.
Bluey didn't chuck the tape.
He lied. He kept it.
Someone's got a big mouth.
Marcus, we had an understanding.
Yeah, well, understand this.
I'm not your brother's
get-out-of-jail free card.
What are you going to do with it?
First edit me and 'coose out, then post it
on the web. A pound a pop. Kerching!
- Bluey...
- Josh will be a YouTube superstar.
Don't wet your panties, Josh.
Stay in line, yeah?
You girlies wouldn't get out of line,
would you?
No, they're gonna say the right thing.
Aren't you?
Lisa always partied a bit too hard.
Everyone knew it.
So it was an accident?
She had too much to drink.
Went outside to clear her head.
That were the last that I saw of her.
- Marcus, I trusted you...
- Those two hate my guts, fair enough.
Now I've got your fucking little weasel of
a brother trying to turn Bluey against me.
Think I don't like all this fussing
and fighting. Why can't we all just?
- I'm warning you. Do not touch me.
- Come on. You girlies are so tense.
Let the Bluester work you
with his magic fingers.
Leave her alone.
I know what this is about.
She's jealous.
Kim gets all the attention.
You're too uptight.
That's why your boyfriend
shagged around.
- Wanker!
- Bet he shagged Kim, too, didn't he?
Oh...
I don't blame you sweetheart.
- I myself am a diagnosed sex addict.
- Yeah, well, try cold turkey!
Tried it, mate. Prefer hot pussy.
Right. Let's do it.
No one calls it in until I have that tape.
- Sean, just call it!
- "Sean, just call it!"
Who cares?
We've got a beautiful boat...
- You promised!
...a bag full of drugs...
...two lovely ladies...
- That's enough!
We could do it again.
You and Kim, a little double act?
- Email it to your ex?
- Bluey!
Show him what he's missing.
Come on, give us a kiss, huh?
Don't you fucking touch me!
Get it out... get it out of me!
Do not touch that knife!
Marcus! Let go of her!
You're choking her!
Give me the Special K.
Give me the Ketamine, man!
- Shall I give him Special K?
- Just give it to him for fucksake!
Here.
You're gonna be fine.
Your lungs are filling up with blood
but that's why God gave you two.
Tammi, open up!
Tammi, please open the door!
What the fuck is going on?
Josh, back up. Open the door!
Kim.
Kim, where's the fucking motor?
No! No!
Where the hell are they?
We've got to find those girls!
Josh, where are they?
The flare.
They've got that fucking tape, Tammi.
We can't prove nothing
without that tape.
- Well, do you wanna go and get it?
- No! Fuck that!
We'll have to find help.
Tell them what happened.
There has to be something in here.
Which of these flares? Red or blue?
Kim?
If we wait out here till tomorrow,
no one'll find us. We can die out here!
What are you doing?
They'll see us!
Oh, no, they've seen us.
Fucking seen us, ain't they?
I'll throw you down the rope, OK?
Grab it.
Fuck off.
We're not getting on your fucking boat!
- What are you doing?
- Kim, just...
Hold on!
OK, I've got it.
Marcus!
- Get back on this fucking boat.
- Fuck you!
Get on the boat. Now!
If you don't get on this boat, I'm going
to shoot that thing from under you.
- Marcus, put it down.
- Back off!
- You fucking stabbed Bluey.
- He asked for it.
- Get on the boat.
- Back off or I swear to fucking God...!
Aaargh! Fuck!
Aaargh! Fucking hell! Help!
Fucking help me, please!
Jump in the water!
It's alight in the fucking water!
Do something!
You shot him!
You fucking shot him!
You. Stay here.
Fucking let us out!
Shit.
What the fuck's going on?
What the fuck have we done?
This is all your fault.
What?
You stabbed Bluey.
Got on a stupid dinghy.
Let the flare go.
The boys come back to us.
We wouldn't even be in Spain
if it weren't for you!
Shut up!
Oh, fuck.
Marcus is dead.
Yeah, I know.
But what are we gonna do?
Where the fuck are the keys?
- I... I don't...
- Look downstairs.
Sean! Let us out! Sean?
Fucking let us out!
Marcus must have had them.
Shit.
- Right, call it.
- And say what?
Call it! We need the Medevac now
or he will die.
Please, man... I don't wanna die.
OK. Yeah. I'll call it.
Come on.
There we go. I've got you.
I've got you.
There we go. You OK?
Come on. I've got you.
There we go.
That's right.
Just through in the other room.
Just through here.
There we go.
Just here.
In you go. In here.
OK? I'm just going to sit you down,
all right?
We can chat in here. All right,
I've got you. All right? I've got you.
OK?
I just need to know...
Where's the tape, Bluey?
My sister...
- I need to call my sister.
- OK. OK.
- Just tell me...
- I need to speak to her.
Where's the tape?
It's gonna fucking take forever.
Oh, fuck it hurts. Give me K.
I need K.
One of us is gonna
have to go at it, Kim.
You want me
to run through a glass door?
Babe?
You're heavier.
Oh, my God, Tam, you did it.
Are you OK?
- You want to find out if he's all right?
- I don't care about him. Are you OK?
No tape. No drugs.
In the bedroom.
Under the bed.
Please.
Please...
Fuck!
Oh, you prick.
You're 30 minutes from dying.
We're an hour from shore.
Mate, I told you...
Ah!
Fuck!
I told you!
Fucking told you,
it's in the fucking bed...
Where the fuck is it? Where is it?
Stupid, inbred fuckwit.
- Where is it?
- It's under the bed...
No. Stop it! Leave him alone!
He hasn't got it!
Kim!
He's dead.
He was losing too much blood.
There's nothing I could have done.
Yeah. It's not my fault.
You liar.
The tape.
You knew he didn't have it.
Why aren't you taking us home?
I can't find the keys.
Get away from her.
Now back the fuck off.
He's got the keys.
Move.
Fucking move!
Get in there. Fucking move.
Kim.
Kim, give me that.
- Where is Sean?
- Shut up! Fucking take me home!
Josh! What's going on?
Open the door!
- Call for help.
- I can't.
Sean reset the channels.
I don't know how.
Liar.
Where the fuck is he?
- He's with his precious engines, safe.
- Not when we're running...
- Liar!
- He'll die down there.
Open the door! Open the door!
Everything that comes
out of your mouth is a lie.
Tammi!
You stay...
Have you thought about what you're
gonna say... when we get back?
Yeah. You're going to prison.
You, too.
Fuck you.
What I did... was an accident.
But you're both up for murder.
And if your friend goes to court
with that tape...
Let me out, Josh, please!
Sean, you've got to help me.
You talk a load of shit.
I promise you,
you don't want that tape getting out.
- We can help each other.
- You want me to help you?
Listen. Marcus, Bluey and Lisa
were fooling around.
One of them killed Lisa.
Bluey argued with Marcus,
and they killed each other.
We stick to that story...
...clean the knife...
...dump the tape...
...and we all walk.
- Sean. Thank God.
- What the fuck hap?
- What have you done to her?
- The crazy bitch was gonna kill me.
Josh, don't! What the fuck?
- She's got it.
- What?
- Sean...
- Bluey's tape.
Just give it to me.
Give me that gun, now.
I want that gun. Josh...
- Don't!
- Please don't make me do this.
- Josh. It's over!
- Get out of my way!
This is enough! Fuck!
It's over!
Oh, fuck!
Sean! Sean!
Sean. Sean.
Sean...
He had the gun.
He was gonna kill you...
He had a gun.
Kim!
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry...
What have you done?
He was trying to help us!
Kim...
Babe, don't!
Don't leave me here.
Kim, no!
No!
They're dead.
They're all dead.
What are we gonna do?
Josh, we have to get off this thing,
cos if they find us here...
Come on. I am not staying here.
I'm getting off this fucking boat
right now.
OK. OK...
Yeah. I'll come, too.
Right,
come on.
Hurry up.
Chuck the tape.
Chuck it.