Ladies, ladies...
Why is Holly the only one
doing her stretches?
Mmm?
Hm-hm.
Stretch! Yes, stretch!
Stretch. Right. Good!
Stretch! Get those
bodies working. Stretch!
Karen. Put your head
all the way between your legs.
Listen, Helga. If God
wanted women to do that,
he wouldn't have invented men.
Ow!
Yes! That's right!
2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7...
Do it like Holly is doing.
Right. Lift! Good, good, good.
If I'd learned this a year ago,
it might have saved my marriage.
Good, Holly!
Up! 2, 3...
Gott in himmel! What is this?
What the hell was that?
That was an earthquake.
Just about ready
to tape, Sandy.
Just a minute, doc.
I'll put the wire
into the coat,
so that it can't
be seen. There.
Lucky you're wearing a jacket,
or Charlie'd go up
through your pants.
Only with you, Sandy.
Okay, Charlie,
give us a sound level.
Now, say something,
so I can get a sound level.
Good. Any time
you're ready, Sandy.
All right, here we go.
Dr. Davis, relax. Ready?
Rolling. 3, 2, 1.
Carla, that big shake
Southern Cali...
Cut!
Oh, my God! Are you
on the air? Am I?
No. No. It's okay. Really.
We're just taping.
Oh, good. I'm really
very sorry.
Rolling, 3, 2...
Hi, Sandy.
Cut.
Harry Crandall.
Remember Harry?
We were at
the nuclear freeze rally.
Ah! Of course,
of course. Harry!
You said some terrific things.
No. No, I didn't say
anything, actually.
I bit a cop, though.
You bit a cop?
I thought they'd charge me
with assaulting an officer,
but they reduced it to...
Harry, I think maybe...
Sure. Oh, here.
Dr. Davis.
One more time.
This is Sandy Dunlap
reporting from
the California seismological
center in Pasadena.
Hi, Mrs. Davis.
Hey, wait up for me!
Will someone let me in?
My arms are full!
Help. Help out.
Help, help, help, help.
Thanks. Can you take those?
Dad's going to be on TV.
He is? What, about
the earthquake?
Yeah.
What is this?
It's a sculpture.
Well, yeah, but what
is it supposed to be?
It's not supposed to be
anything.
I saw it in a gallery
and I liked it
and I brought it home
on approval.
Mom, commercial's
almost over. This is it!
Registering 5.3
on the Richter scale.
No lives were lost,
and there were
no serious injuries,
but there has been
moderate to heavy damage
from as far north
as Bakersfield
to as far South as San Diego.
Did you feel that this morning?
That really was a heck of
a jolt, wasn't it, bill?
Oh, yes. It sure was, Carla.
Where were you when it hit?
I was in the shower.
And dumb me,
I thought something was
wrong with the plumbing,
because everything
started shaking
and I thought,
"what is going on here?"
What a dipshit.
Jeff!
She is, mom.
How did she get
this job, anyway?
Who knows?
Hardly any.
But it sure is windy.
Jeff, get that.
If it's for me, I'll call back.
Hello? She's busy right now.
I believe they say
that you should
stand... In the doorway.
And he's no
Eric Sevareid, either.
Doorway?
I crawled under my bed.
There I was under there
with no clothes on
and all those dust bunnies.
Will you just get on with it
so I can see my husband?
Mom, it's for you.
Honey, just take a message.
I tried to, but she said
it's really important.
All right.
Holly, this is Helga.
Helga?
Helga, listen.
Can I call you right back?
My husband
is going to be on TV.
God, daddy looks so handsome.
A total stud.
Teach? A class? Who, me?
But I've never done anything
like that before in my life.
Mom, come on, hurry up!
Helga, that's really
very flattering, but...
Hurry!
Maybe I could
fill in just this once.
Then those predictions
that California
will soon drop into the pacific
are somewhat exaggerated?
Well, let me put it this way.
I don't go to bed
with my swim-fins on,
if that answers your question.
Mom, he's so cute.
You're missing the best part.
Let me just see
if I can manage it,
and then I'll call you right
back. Yes, I will. I promise.
Five minutes. Goodbye.
You missed it. It's over.
I missed it? Damn, I missed it.
See if it's on
any other channel.
Who was that lady on the phone?
Oh, that was the owner
of the exercise studio I go to.
She wants me
to teach a class tonight.
Teach? You?
Yeah, that's what I said.
Hello?
Chip, hi!
Why didn't you tell us
you were going to be on TV?
I'm sorry. I guess it got so
busy around here that I forgot.
Well, you know,
we could have missed it.
Jeff! I just cut those
for myself. Mom!
Will you two
hold it down, please!
Listen, I can still
hold dinner for you
if you think you'll
be home in time.
No, no, no. Don't do that.
I won't leave
until at least 10:00 or 10:30.
Harry, would you mind?
Sorry, wait, what?
Helga called
from the exercise studio.
And this is going to sound
a little crazy,
but one of her
instructors quit,
and she wants me
to come down and teach.
Teach? A class?
Yeah. I mean, you know,
I know all the exercises.
And I think I'm pretty good.
But I don't know.
You know, I still have the kids'
dinner to get and everything.
I'm doing my own dinner, mom.
Don't worry about me.
Anyway, I'm going
over to Cathy's
to work on my biology report.
I'm studying chemistry
with Wendy.
We'll get a pizza after.
You were cool, dad!
Sounds like
everybody's deserting you.
Yeah, well, I still
have to feed Stanley.
Unless you're going to
eat out, too.
Hey, you know,
I think you ought to do it.
I mean, you know, why not?
It's better than sitting around
all by yourself
without anything to do.
It's not as though I
don't have anything to do here,
but it might be fun.
Yeah, do it. Have fun. Really.
Okay, I will. I love you.
I love you, too.
Bye-bye.
I'm sorry. That was Holly.
She's all pumped up about
teaching some exercise class.
I bet she'd be
really good at that.
Why?
Well, because...
I think she'd be good at
anything she wanted to do.
Well, you're her
biggest fan, Harry.
Next to you.
That's right.
4, 3, 2, 1. We're clear.
Like doing the news
with chatty Cathy.
We're lucky to get out
of that alive.
George! Excuse me.
Good report
on the earthquake, Sandy.
Great stuff
with that seismologist.
Thanks. Listen, George...
I've really got to talk to you
we've got going here.
Now?
Well, yeah. Come on, George.
I've been here
two years, right.
And I think I've really
been pretty patient,
but this is ridiculous.
I can't talk now.
I've got a meeting.
That's what you said yesterday,
and the day before.
How about tomorrow?
Call Myra, have her set it up.
I thought that was such
a great show tonight.
Didn't you, George?
Lots of fun, you know.
Right.
I'm ready in five.
Give me time to change.
Loved your spot, Sandy.
Really cute.
Thanks.
A meeting, huh?
Carla and I have to...
Discuss something.
Right.
World peace...
or the dust bunnies
under her bed?
Tomorrow, all right?
Let Myra know when
you're free. Myra!
Um... okay...
Um... if we...
Could I have your attention?
Um... all right, every...
Could I please have your
atten...?
Attention, please. Thank you.
Hello.
My name is Holly, and...
Well, Helga had to teach
a whole bunch of extra cla...
What?
Helga had to teach
extra classes,
so she asked me if I would, you
know, sort of fill in for her.
So if you'll all just
bear with me... um...
How does she usually
start you off?
By making us sing.
"Deutschland,
Deutschland über alles."
A little Nazi humor...
Oh...
Well, okay, then.
All right, then.
We'll do a back
to the legs stretch.
If you'll all reach up,
inhale, over, easy, easy...
Head down, grab your ankles,
and gently pulse.
And reach to the left
and face the knee, and hold.
Other side.
Over, face the knee...
and hold.
Sit up, inhale,
exhale and extend.
Inhale, exhale and extend.
Holly!
And extend.
7, 6, 5, 4, 3...
Oh...
Hi.
You're really good.
Well, thanks. So are you.
Well, thanks.
Where have you been working?
I don't do this for a living.
I'm just helping out Helga.
Well, I hope
you got paid in advance.
Damn it! Why are there never
any clean towels around here?
I know. That's why
I bring my own.
I'll give you 50 cents
if I can use it after you.
A buck if I can use it first.
Oh God!
What happened to the hot water?
On the other hand, I may
be showering at home tonight.
I'll tell you,
this place is a sorry excuse
for a gym, if you ask me.
I thought the Germans were
supposed to be so organized.
Here.
Thanks.
So, do you feel like
getting something to eat?
Oh. No, I can't. My husband
will be home soon.
Well, I'm not usually out
this late on weeknights.
9:30?
Oh, no... I meant that
I ought to be there.
'Cause he'll be tired.
He won't fix anything
for himself to eat.
I don't want him to go
to bed on an empty stomach.
If he hasn't eaten already.
Though he probably has.
A simple yes or no?
Well, I guess no.
Sure! Yeah.
Actually, I'd like to.
I'm sorry,
I do that all the time.
I've got to speak to Helga,
so I'll meet you out front, huh?
Okay.
Make sure
she pays you. In cash.
I need those towels.
I need cash.
Cash?
Yeah, 52, cash.
I can't pay you in cash.
No towels.
Yes?
Well, it's about the class
I just taught.
I was wondering...
Yes, I got a lot
of compliments on you.
The girls said
you were just great.
Really?
Oh, isn't that nice? So...
I've got to let Michelle go,
and I was wondering if you
would like to take her place.
That's very flattering...
Helga, she is terrific.
I hope you're paying her
what she's worth.
The same as the other girls.
$20 a lesson.
That's not enough.
Hold out for more.
20 will be fine.
If you could just wait
until next week?
Sure.
That girl who just left...
What's her name?
She looks very familiar.
Sandy Dunlap.
She's on the news. On the TV.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
A celebrity.
I like your shoes.
Ah, thanks.
I wish I could wear
things like that.
Why can't you?
I wouldn't have the nerve.
I mean...
I know what you mean.
You should see them
when I plug them in.
Do you want to
get something to eat here?
No. There.
Ice cream?
I thought you meant something,
you know, more substantial.
More substantial?
Let's see. I had
a tab for breakfast,
a snickers bar for lunch, so...
this will be the most
sensible meal I've had all day.
Oh boy!
How did you get
into it? News, I mean.
Well, I started out as
a weather girl in Indianapolis.
You know, your basic
22-year-old airhead.
I didn't know
my ass from an isobar,
to tell you the truth.
And my producer knew it, right.
So he told me that
he would renew my option
if I would just do him
this small horizontal favor
every now and then.
God, what a pig!
I would have rather
have slept with king Kong,
who I'm sure had better breath
than this asshole.
There you are, sir.
Here you go. Thank you.
Want a cigarette?
No, thanks. I gave them up
a long time ago.
Did you really? Oh God,
I wish I could.
How?
It really was Chip, my husband.
He kept going on and on about
what life would be like
for him and
the kids without me.
So, of course, every time I even
thought about a cigarette,
I'd get this picture
of my little family
putting flowers on my grave.
I tried to quit
a couple of times
and my husband
was always begging me
to take it up again.
You're married?
I was.
But marriage and a career
in TV news don't mix.
At least not for me.
He just really couldn't
deal with my ambition.
I don't blame him.
Most men can't.
I keep having to make
these wrenching decisions
between my career,
which I'm good at,
and my life, which I'm not.
It just really fucks me up.
It doesn't have to, you know.
Doesn't have to what?
F-fuck you up.
You've never said
that before, have you?
Said what?
The f-word.
What I meant was, isn't that
kind of an old-fashioned idea?
Having to make a choice
between career and marriage?
I mean, sure, a lot of women
used to think that way.
I guess I did myself.
But that was a long time ago.
Not that I had
that much of a career.
What did you do?
I was a dancer.
Really?
Not Makarova or anything.
I was mostly doing
TV commercials.
Do you remember Mr. Peanut?
Intimately.
They were going to
do commercials
where he got married.
Yeah?
And I was going to be
Mrs. Peanut.
And then I got pregnant.
You got knocked up
by Mr. Peanut?
By Chip.
But who knows? It could
have led to something.
Sure.
Actually, I was pretty good.
But I made a choice.
And I've never regretted it.
I guess this is
the one thing I regret.
Yeah, it's a career
in itself in a way.
I mean, if I'm ever
going to have a kid,
I'd better start thinking
about doing it pretty soon.
Hard to do if you're single.
Yeah.
But not impossible.
Are you really serious?
I'd prefer to
do it with a husband, but...
I've been saving my money
for a couple of years
just in case I decided
to get pregnant.
See, the thing is,
I've always said that if
the right guy comes along,
I'd just do it, right?
Well, I've met him.
This guy is exactly
what I've been looking for.
He's handsome,
super-intelligent...
Good genes,
you know what I mean?
If he's so perfect,
why don't you marry him?
Well, he's not that perfect.
Well...
Maybe we can
do it again, sometime.
I'd like that.
What about Saturday?
You could come for dinner.
Bring your friend.
Oh, I don't think
he could make it.
Besides, Saturday's my
only night off this week.
Oh. You're probably busy.
Well, I have to do
tons of laundry
and re-tape the top
of my car, you know.
What time would you like me?
Meanwhile, the sixth fleet
was bombarding...
Takes the ball on the 50. 45...
Picks up a block on the 40.
35, 30, and still going.
25, and out of bounds
at the 25-yard line.
They have the ball at
the start of that 25-yard line.
Third and long.
Here's the snap.
Cindy goes up right past them.
Beats the 10, the 5,
and she's in for
the touchdown. She scores.
Hi, dad.
Hi.
Didn't know you were home.
I just got in.
What are you watching?
Something on...
bees.
It's really interesting.
Well, if you don't mind, I'd
rather not watch bees tonight.
Put our faith
in this book and the...
Three, ready, break!
I didn't know
there was a game on tonight.
Must be that new league, huh?
Must be.
Cindy again with the ball.
Picks up a block.
Nobody's going to catch her.
Good move she put
on that linebacker there.
Yeah.
I don't suppose
they have slo-mo replay?
You know, I think this is
what fatherhood is all about.
Sitting in your living room,
watching Monday night football
with your son.
Especially on Thursday nights.
Yeah...
It's really American.
Chip!
Good night, dad.
We'll do it again sometime.
You betcha.
Hi, mom. Good night.
Good night.
Hi.
After a day
of collecting pollen...
What are you watching?
Just this thing on... Bees.
Bees?
You had to be there
from the beginning.
What...? What's this?
It's a sculpture.
I saw it in a gallery today.
I thought it
was really... Interesting.
Don't you? Because I only
have it on approval.
You know, just to see
if we really like it.
Hmm...
And I guess we don't.
Is this new?
The leotard is.
Same old rear end.
Doesn't look so old to me.
Anyway, I met the most
interesting girl,
and we went and had
ice cream afterwards
and we talked for hours.
That's why I'm so late.
God, I haven't
done that in ages.
It might not seem like
such a big deal to you,
'cause you've got Harry,
but since Elaine
moved to Boston, I've...
you know, haven't had
a close friend.
Chip, I'm all sweaty
from class.
That's okay. I like you that way.
Earthquakes always do this
to you, don't they?
They do. They get me all horny.
And I guess that's why
I chose the field, huh?
I really should take a shower.
You can take one afterwards.
But I bought
this slinky nightgown.
You can wear it afterwards.
It's very...
sexy.
Well... No. No, no. No time.
Anyway, I invited this girl
to have dinner on Saturday...
night.
Listen, you can talk about
her afterwards, too, okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You always
go to sleep afterwards.
Even better.
Mom!
Yes... Kim.
How come the door is locked?
Because your mother and I
were doing it.
Is it? Dear, I was half asleep.
Thanks a lot!
I need some money
for new jogging shoes.
Wait a minute, here.
Were you going to go out
right now and buy them
in some midnight shoe store?
No, tomorrow. After school.
Then can we talk about it
tomorrow morning, please?
Okay. Good night.
Good night.
Did I disturb something?
No!
Yes!
Would you give me a second,
here? Let me handle this.
Did you ever think
how nice it might be
to have another child?
Isn't that funny?
I was just thinking
how nice it would be to
get rid of the two we've got.
No, I'm serious.
I was thinking
it might be nice.
I mean, the kids
are almost grown...
and I don't have as much to
do around here as I used to.
Maybe we could
talk about this later.
Mary. Here she is.
Oh, my...
Yeah, yeah...
It's George Margolin.
Damn, I was hoping to
catch you at home.
But listen,
I'm really sorry about
not being able to talk to you
tonight after the show,
but I really did have
a meeting with Carla.
Yeah...
Some contract problem.
Honestly, that's all.
What am I doing?
I'm your producer,
I don't have to make excuses
to you. Call Myra...
Hurry up, George.
You've only got 30 seconds.
Hi, it's me.
Listen, I'm sorry
I couldn't see you tonight,
but with all these aftershocks
we're all
working overtime here.
I really wish
I could have come over.
I mean, you always seem to
be able to make time for me
when I want to see you.
I feel lousy when you need
to see me and I can't.
Anyway, I've been thinking
about you tonight a lot.
I just want you to know that,
if that helps.
Probably doesn't, does it?
Who left their ice cream dish
on the coffee table?
I don't eat animal products.
Jeff, come and get
your ice cream dish
and put it in the dishwasher.
How many times
do I have to tell you
not to leave your things around
for other people to pick up?
And put it in the dishwasher.
I was going to pick it up.
When? There's penicillin
growing on it. Quickly.
Red sneakers in the fireplace!
I wish your father
would get home.
I don't want Sandy
to arrive before he does.
Does she drive
a little black sports car?
Yeah. Why?
Well, she got here
before he did.
She's 15 minutes early!
Put the crab puffs
in the lower oven.
Oh...
Hi!
Hi. Am I early?
No. I said 7:30.
Or 15.
Are you sure?
Yes!
You see, I have this problem
about being early.
I'm always catching people
putting on their make-up
or just getting
out of the shower.
Really, if you're not ready,
I could easily just walk
around the block.
No, no, it's fine. Come on in.
Can I get you a drink?
Sure. Wine, I guess.
Okay.
Holly! Who decorated
your house?
I did.
You're amazing.
You know, once I was so early,
I caught these people
in the middle of humping.
Yeah. They tried to
act casual about it,
but they were both real sweaty,
and the guy had his shirttail
caught in his zipper.
Actually, I'm
a little embarrassed
about something myself.
Chip had to go to the office
and he isn't home yet.
Oh, look, do you want me
to come back another time?
I can easily...
No, no, no! He'll be here.
Okay.
Do you want me to take that?
I'm sorry. This is for you.
Thanks.
Yeah. It was between those
and a decanter of amaretto
in the shape of the pope.
He was the one who died
after a month,
so they had it on special.
Shoes.
Yeah. I just guessed your size.
If it's not right,
you can burn them.
Those shoes! Oh, Sandy!
The size is perfect.
I love them.
You do?
I'll wear them.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
It's a sculpture.
Nobody seems to like it,
so I'm taking it back.
What do you think of it?
Well, Holly, I could tell you,
but what difference
does it make, really?
You know? I mean, art is
a very personal thing, right?
What's important is
that you like it.
Right.
Even if you're
the only one who does.
I hope you don't mind.
I invited a friend of ours
to have dinner, too.
A friend?
Yeah, this guy works with Chip.
Oh, my God, is this
Saturday? I've got a...
No, no, no. Come on.
It's not a fix-up, or anything.
I know you said
you don't want to get involved.
That's right.
He's just this old friend.
Well, not actually old.
He's young.
And he's kind of
attractive, too.
You know,
in a quiet sort of way.
He's been divorced from his wife
for a couple of years,
and he's...
He's just really this nice guy.
But it's not a fix-up
or anything.
Uh-uh. No.
Mom, they're ready.
Want to come in
the kitchen with me?
There was a whole gallon
of it in there yesterday.
I didn't touch it, Jeff.
Yeah? Well, if you didn't eat
the rest of the ice cream
who did? Stanley?
I don't think...
Jeff, Kim. I'd like you
to meet Sandy.
Hi. Kim.
Sandy Dunlap.
Jeff, hi.
We see you on TV.
Aren't you the one
who interviewed my dad?
Your dad? When?
After the earthquake.
At the seismology center.
S-s-seismology?
I didn't know that.
W-what's his name?
Chip Davis.
Well, actually
it's Dr. Thomas Davis.
Well...
Yes?
Well, I sure did.
Nice meeting you.
Yeah, really.
Really.
If that isn't
the darndest coincidence.
Is Chip ever
going to be surprised.
Oh, my God!
You know, I really enjoyed
our talk the other night.
I just think it's so rare
that people can
get past the small talk
and into something real
so quickly, you know?
Yeah, it is...
Ah! There's Chip.
Well, at last!
I'm sorry. One of
the computers is on the blink.
That's okay.
Chip, you'll never guess
who's here.
Hi.
It's Sandy Dunlap.
What?
Ah, there's Harry.
No. I'll get it. You... why...?
Hi.
Just be calm.
What?
Listen. I don't know
what's happening here, but...
Somehow, Holly
has just met Sandy.
She's in the kitchen right now.
Here? Sandy?
Mm-hm.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Is this your being calm?
Harry!
Hi. Empty-handed as usual, huh?
Well, I guess you know
Sandy, too, huh?
Sandy?
Well, yes. Hello.
Hello.
Lovely to see you again.
Thank you.
Aren't these nice?
Eh... This is for you.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Hmm...
And, oh yeah,
I saw this a few days ago,
and I thought it would
look nice in here, but...
I guess it doesn't, does it?
Yes, it does.
It looks wonderful.
How sweet. Just so
typically thoughtful.
Well, look, you two
get to know each other.
I mean, why don't you all
get to know each other?
I'll put these in water.
I'll help you.
Was that okay?
You were fine.
Are you sure? I don't know.
Can you just talk about
my problem for a minute?
Yeah, but do you think
that maybe I can
have a drink...?
Yeah, all right. Out here.
Does she know?
Does who know?
Holly. About you
and Sandy. Does she know?
No. No, I don't know.
How could she know?
I don't know.
Sandy could have told her.
Why would she do that?
I don't know!
God, this is awful!
Oh, thank you for
the wonderful insight.
Sorry.
Listen. Let me handle this.
Don't do anything
to give it away.
Sure.
Damn it, Stanley!
Oh!
Well, hello again.
Hello. Crab puff?
Ah, thank you, no.
I just can't get over the fact
that you know Sandy.
I know how you are
about meeting people,
so this is going
to make everything
so much more
comfortable for you.
Where is the damn corkscrew?
It's right there on the counter.
I put it out for you.
Why didn't you tell me,
instead of standing there,
watching me make an idiot
out of myself?
Hey, what's the matter?
Nothing.
Yeah, well, all right.
Coming home, hoping for
a nice, quiet little evening.
You know, a few drinks
with Harry,
some dinner,
and you spring
what's-her-name on me.
I didn't spring her on you.
I told you she was coming over.
When?
The other night.
After we made love.
Maybe you were asleep.
Ah...
These are great, just great.
I didn't make them.
No.
So, have you known Holly
a long time?
No. We just met the other night
at an exercise class.
Well, she's terrific,
she's just terrific.
You're going to
love her. Everybody does.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
Are you trying to set her up
with Harry? Is that it?
No. Sandy said
she's already involved
with somebody.
But I have a feeling it's not
very satisfying for her.
Well, I don't think it's
any of your business, do you?
You know, don't go playing
matchmaker with my friends.
You know how much I hate that.
I never do that.
Well, I do. I hate it.
I knew I'd forget the rolls.
I even left
a big note for myself:
"Don't forget the rolls."
This veal was wonderful.
Thanks.
I wish I knew how to make it.
Me too.
I didn't know
you liked to cook.
I don't.
Me either.
Well, I knew you two
would have something in common.
Not that that's really
something in common,
not knowing how to cook.
It's really not.
Everybody has something
in common in one way or another.
You take Sandy and me.
We've got...
We've got aerobics.
Right.
Is the veal okay, Chip?
Yes, it's fine. Thank you.
As a matter of fact,
it's excellent.
I'm just not very hungry.
Oops...
Whoa!
Aftershock.
Well, Harry.
Maybe I ought to go down to
the lab and check it out?
What?
It was pretty small.
Small?
You think that was small?
Yes!
All right.
What are you looking for?
I'm hungry.
Well, maybe if you'd
eaten your dinner...
This is really a first.
I have never had a dinner party
where the guests
were home by 9:30.
You just put the milk
in the cupboard.
What is the matter
with you tonight, anyway?
Nothing.
Nothing?
First of all,
you made a big fuss
about my trying to put
Harry and Sandy together,
and I thought that
they got along just fine.
God...
"God..." What's that
supposed to mean, anyway?
He hated her.
He did not.
Listen. Just stop
trying to fix up stray women
with my friends, all right?
Okay. All right.
Fine. No problem.
Holly?
Yes?
I'm sorry.
Me too.
I don't know.
Sandy and Harry just seem,
you know, kind of lonely.
But maybe they
like it that way.
Oh... Er...
The pro-freeze rally
in Washington
is this Wednesday.
Is Harry going with you?
No. Just me.
With all the seismic activity,
they're afraid
to leave the lab shorthanded.
Oh.
I've been working at
what I'm going to say.
You're speaking?
Yeah.
Oh, Chip!
I'd love to go.
It's so expensive.
Anyway, I told Helga
I'd teach a few classes.
Well, do that.
Yeah? Okay.
Who knows? Maybe
I'll be on the TV again.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I've had Saturday nights
like that, too.
Want to bet?
Jesus...
Hi.
Tennis?
She thinks
I'm playing with Harry.
Why here,
instead of your place?
Because I really
don't want us to be alone.
Knowing you,
we'd just end up in...
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Can you possibly imagine what
I was going through last night?
Yeah, I think I can.
This wonderful woman
invites me to dinner,
and she turns out to be...
Couldn't you have figured
it out? Davis... Davis.
Well, excuse me. I've met
a lot of people named Davis.
So far this is the first one
who turned out to be your wife.
Besides, she was always talking
about this guy "Chip"
she was married to, not tom.
Where did you get a name
like that, anyway? Chip.
Chip...
All right, when
we were first married...
Spare me, please.
Thank you. No cute stories.
So... Why didn't you tell me
you were happily married?
Hey! I never said
I was unhappily married.
No, but I just assumed.
Would it have made
any difference?
She is terrific, you know.
I know.
She's a wonderful person.
She's a great mother,
terrific wife...
Yeah. Gosh,
this is all making me feel
so much better. Thank you.
Listen. I love you.
No, don't. Ahh!
And I love her... Thank you.
I love her, too, but in
a completely different way.
With Holly, it's...
It's... okay, it's nice
and it's comfortable.
But with you it's...
Not nice, uncomfortable, what?
No. I'm stuck in this
"nice, comfortable" rut.
Just this
semi-dull academic type
going through the motions.
Wipe your nose.
And then I met you.
You are so...
So what?
Bright, attractive,
independent...
But Holly's bright
and attractive and...
Did you ever stop and think
she may not be independent
because you don't
want her to be?
Yes. No, no.
The difference is that you
would not have stood for that.
You still would have been
your own person.
And also make a lousy wife.
I was a lousy wife. I have
the divorce papers to prove it.
I'm not looking for a wife,
and you're not looking
for a husband.
Right?
Yeah, right.
Oh, God!
I wish you'd stop smoking!
I will, okay, I'll St...
I'll stop smoking,
but not now. I can't.
I can't give up these
and you at the same time.
Well, what else
are we going to do?
Look, I really wasn't
expecting this
to end like this, either.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Look, let's...
Let's not talk about
ending anything until I...
Until I get back
from Washington.
It'll give us time.
Time for what?
To think.
No. I really don't need
more time to think, thank you.
I've done nothing else
but think for the last 12 hours.
I can't do this.
I don't want to do this.
Not now that I know her.
And I don't think
you do, either.
Right?
Barbara, if you really
valued your friendship...
How did it go?
She wants to break it off.
I know it's easy for me
to be philosophical,
but maybe it's for the best.
For the best? I love her,
for God's sake!
I know, I know.
But look what you've
been doing to yourself.
And to Holly, and even
to Sandy, too, in a way.
I mean, you're
not the kind of guy
who does this kind
of thing, you know?
I hate the sneaking around,
the secret phone calls,
all the lying...
It's been hard for me, too.
I know.
What does that...?
What do you mean?
Well, I mean lying for you.
Pretending to be playing tennis
with you when you're with Sandy.
Oh, I'm really sorry I've
caused you any pain here, Harry.
I just figured
a friend wouldn't mind.
There are limits, okay?
All right?
I mean,
Holly is my friend, too.
I hate talking to her
about our tennis games.
Having to make stuff up.
And why do you tell her
you win all the time?
Is that what's really
bothering you?
Fine, Harry, I'll tell her
that you won today.
You got any particular
score in mind?
No. What's bothering me is
seeing you risk losing Holly.
She's the best woman I know.
Well, if I do lose her, Harry,
maybe you'll have a shot at her.
I'll tell you what.
Come up here and talk to him
and I'll go back there
and blow your horn for you.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's just really crazy.
It's okay.
Oh boy...
Mr. Hasegawa.
Hai.
Could you put
the paper on the porch
before you turn on
the sprinkler?
Hai.
Hi. I'd appreciate it.
It would save me having to
spread my paper out
on the kitchen floor to dry
before I can read it.
Listen, I was wondering...
Do you think that we could
brighten up this flower bed
with anything at all? You know,
some tulips, or something.
Tulips? Not in season.
Okay... uh, pansies?
No.
Hell, paint it orange.
I don't care.
Ugh...
Hi. I'm not home right now.
I'm in the yard
feeding my attack dog.
So if you'd like to leave
your name and a message
after the beep,
I'll call you back
as soon as I can. Bye.
Hi Sandy. I wasn't sure
you got my message yesterday.
Anyway, I just wanted to say
that we've all missed you
at the gym.
I mean, I've missed you.
Also, Chip's out of town
until tomorrow, and I was...
I wondered if you wanted
to have dinner tonight.
Just us girls... Women.
Anyway, you should at least
come to class.
You don't want to
get out of shape.
Not that you would. Anyway,
I hope I'll see you soon, okay?
Did I say
this was Holly? Davis. Bye.
Hello.
Collect call from Dr. Davis
do you accept?
Yes, I'll accept, operator.
Hi, it's me.
Hi. How are you doing?
I'm okay. How are you?
Oh, just peachy, thanks.
I was on my way to the rally,
and I... I remembered
that's how we met.
I got this overpowering urge
to call you.
No, that's not true.
I haven't stopped
thinking about you since I left.
I don't want you
to think about me.
I want you to think about Holly
and Jeff and Kim and your dog.
And I want you
to forget about me.
I have tried that,
I really have.
Look, I can't handle this
right now, okay?
I've been out all night
chasing a story
that led nowhere,
and I got this message
on my machine from Holly and...
Oh Jesus...
I'm standing here
in my underwear,
and this very happy Japanese
gentleman is staring at me.
What?
Just hang on for a second.
Damn it.
Yes?
Geraniums.
What about them?
Always in season.
Oh, great.
That would be great. Fine.
What's that?
You've got money
for the geraniums?
Oh, right.
Sandy, what's going on?
Shit...
Um, like, you caught me
at a really bad time.
Um...
I can't talk to you now. Sorry.
All right, all right.
How about when I get back?
No. No, we're not going to
start this up again.
I know that.
I just don't want to think
that I'll never see you again.
Please don't
make this any worse
than it already is, okay?
I'm going to hang up now, okay?
I'll call you from the airport.
No. No. I have to hang up,
I really do.
Let me call you...
No, I'm going to hang up now.
I have to.
Goodbye.
Helen, I don't want a divorce.
No, that's not true.
10:30 or 11:00.
No later than that, unless I...
I'm working on my lead.
Most news people that I know
tend to type their stories
rather than
write them out in longhand.
Oh yeah, I know, but I just got
these new porcelain nails.
I broke one typing yesterday
just before we went on the air,
and I felt really
self-conscious about it.
We didn't get any calls on it.
By the way,
it's "nuclear," not "nucular."
Really?
Cross my heart.
George? Got a second?
Just.
Before we have that talk,
I'd really like you
to take a look at this tape.
Why? What is it?
Just bits and pieces
of things I've done
over the past couple of years.
Things I'm kind of proud of.
You know, just in case
you missed any of them.
George, I'll be in make-up.
I'd really like you
to look at it, George.
Not once on the tape do I say
"nucular" or "Letch" Walesa,
or, ha, "s. Q.U.A.T. Team".
You'll be amazed.
Look, I think that I can
understand your frustration,
but what goes on around here
is not entirely
my responsibility.
George. I think you may want to
make this
our new lead for 6:00.
What is it?
You know, there was
this pro-freeze rally
in Washington today.
Yeah. What about it?
Well, one of the speakers
was Dr. Phillip Lorring.
Didn't he win a Nobel prize
a couple of years ago?
Right. And after the...
After the rally,
he was on his way back
in a rainstorm,
and the cab he was in
was in an accident,
and he and the other
passenger were killed.
I don't like to
lead with something
that doesn't have
a local angle.
Oh yeah, it does.
The guy was from Pasadena.
Some seismologist.
Hey, what's the matter? Sandy?
6, 7, 8, and reach and reach.
Let's go, let's go.
Look down. Let's smile.
Come on, have fun.
And the waist and the waist
and the waist and the waist.
Keep going,
keep going, keep going.
And twist, and smile.
Keep going, keep going.
Come on.
Sandy needs to talk to you.
I will take over.
To the floor, 2, 3, 4.
To the side, 2, 3, 4.
To the floor, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
And reach, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
To the side,
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
I don't know how she does it.
I can't believe
how well she's holding up.
When the elections come up,
the interest rates
are going to go up.
Well, my broker
told me to wait.
I'm really sorry, Mrs. Davis.
We don't have any
firm policy in central America.
Here, let me.
It's all right.
Oh, Holly. Any time, mmm?
Yes.
You'll call? Mmm? Mmm?
I heard that
they're back together.
No, I heard that
they are living together.
With his lifestyle...
The restaurants
in San Francisco
are so much better.
Because I know him, that's why.
Holly.
She looks good, doesn't she?
Sure does.
Chip loved you guys.
You and the kids.
You were
the whole world to him.
He loved you, too.
Who are you going to get
to play tennis with?
I guess I'll have to
find somebody.
Nobody as good as him, though.
He beat me
every time we played.
Thank you for the flowers.
They're just beautiful.
I hope you don't mind
my sending them here
instead of the funeral home?
I figured...
I loved the thought.
I'd better get this out,
they're starting to eat
with their fingers.
The creepy minister, he
keeps following me around
trying to persuade me to join
his Episcopal youth choir.
Maybe you should.
You have a very sweet voice.
Grandma! I'm an agnostic!
So you can hum.
Grandma!
Holly tells me
you interviewed Chip on TV.
Is that how you all met?
Yeah. Well, kind of.
I mean, that's how I met him.
But I met Holly
at an exercise class.
And then she invited me
over for dinner,
and then I met him again, here.
Small world.
Yeah. Very.
Oh!
My God! Look what I did.
Goodbye, Uncle Harold.
Be brave.
Helga! You came.
Of course I came. Here.
I'm sorry I'm so late.
What is this?
It's the money I owe you.
Don't tell the other girls.
Listen...
We want to see you
a lot. Don't we, bill?
Sure do.
Thanks.
It's just so good
seeing you again.
It kills me that it took this
for us to get together,
you know.
You are the last person
in the world
that something like this
should have happened to.
Listen, if there's
anything we can do,
just anything at all...
Want to stay and vacuum?
What?
That was a joke, Andrea.
It was just a little joke.
She's kidding, Andy.
Oh... bill, is she wonderful?
Joking at a time like this.
You're fabulous.
Do you know that?
Well, I...
Know that.
Okay.
Anything at all, now, you hear?
Thanks.
Holly, come on.
Put that down. I'll get it.
Will you sit down, please?
Okay.
I don't know how
I'd have gotten through this day
without you and Harry.
This day? The whole week.
You guys too.
You've been terrific.
It all just seems so unreal.
Totally.
I've got to tell you, Hol...
Holly?
I can't believe your mom.
My mom?
Yeah. She's exactly like mine.
She is?
Hearing yours talk
was just like being at home,
except... Except
I'm crazy about yours
and mine would have me
climbing the fucking walls.
The darn walls...
Don't worry, Sandy.
It's nothing I haven't said.
Or done.
I'm so tired.
Oh, sweetie, I know.
We're all exhausted.
Why don't you go to bed, huh?
I'll come in and
say good night in a minute.
Okay. Good night.
Good night. Sleep tight.
Good night, Sandy.
Sweet dreams.
This hasn't hit her yet.
It will.
I woke up last night...
and then I realized
that I'm never...
Oh, sweetie.
Nobody's saying
that we ought to
just unilaterally disarm.
I mean,
nobody's kidding themselves
that the Russians are
a bunch of nice guys.
But our own leaders
ought to realize
that it's in the Soviet's best
interest as well as our own
to stop escalating this
suicidal "nucular" arms race.
Did I say "nucular"?
I mean "nuclear." "Nuclear."
Hi, you guys.
Hi.
Is your mom around?
She's still in bed.
We didn't want to wake her.
She hasn't been sleeping well.
I hear her up in the middle
of the night.
I thought I'd try to get her
out of the house.
Maybe go play some tennis,
or something.
That's a great idea.
I'll pay you guys
to wash my car.
Or paint it...
Jeff.
What?
Holly?
Hol?
I'm awake.
Oh. Good.
I just thought you might like
to know it's 1988.
Thank you.
You've been asleep now
for about 2.5 years.
Let's see. Peace has broken out
in the middle east.
Robert Redford
is our new president.
And... oh, Holly.
They've discovered
this great new diet.
All junk food.
Doritos and ding dongs.
I'm happy for you.
All right, bones. Up and at 'em!
Get your ass out of bed
because we're going to
go play some tennis. Come on!
I don't play tennis.
It was Chip's game.
Do you mean to tell me
that I went out and
bought this outfit and a racket,
and you don't even play?
Well, you look like
you play tennis.
Yeah... well, I look like I know
how to do a lot of things
that I don't know how to do.
Okay. All right,
so you don't play tennis.
Neither do I.
We're perfectly matched.
Come on, Holly. Let's go out
and have some laughs, huh?
God, I am so scared.
What the hell am I going to do?
Um...
Look, I think maybe it's just
sunk in what's happened.
No, no, no...
I mean, literally,
what am I going to do?
Chip was always here for me.
Now that he's gone, I just...
I feel like I'm half a person.
No, you're not.
What do you mean?
God, it's so hard to get out
of this bed in the morning.
And you know why?
Because I know
I've got to go out there
and look for a job.
I know the feeling.
Hey, you'll find one.
Doing what? Driving car pools?
Making lunches? Setting tables?
Maybe you could teach?
Teach what?
Table-setting.
Oh God!
I mean, what was the actual
last job that I had? Hmm?
What about the gym?
You could teach that.
Helga can't even
pay me, remember?
That's not the only gym
in Los Angeles.
She only hired me
because she was desperate.
That's not true.
You're great at it.
Still, I'd like to get a job
where they might pay me money.
Holly...
Yeah?
I just don't think
it's very healthy for you
to keep his clothes in there.
Well, yeah...
I keep thinking I'll save them
for Jeff, and I...
Yeah. Right.
So, are we going to
go play tennis, or what?
Oh! Yes!
Absolutely. Let's go.
Well, now that
looks like a fun job.
I wonder if they
have any openings?
No, those are handed down,
father to son.
Listen, I have an idea. I think
you should buy Helga out.
What?
She's ready to go belly-up.
You could get that place
for a song.
I don't know anything
about running a gym.
She doesn't know anything
Plus, you're much better
with people than she is.
Oh, come on.
Don't say you're not.
Yeah, well, who isn't?
Plus you're smarter
than she is,
plus you give better classes
than she does.
Plus, I know if you thought
about it for 10 seconds,
you'd have great ideas
about how to turn that rat hole
into a winning proposition.
Yeah, but... Even if I did,
you're forgetting something.
I don't have any money.
What do you mean?
Didn't Chip leave you anything?
Yeah. But it's going
to be months
before it's out of probate.
I've got over 8,000 bucks
in my maternity fund.
I could lend it to you.
I guarantee she'd grab it.
Then you can get a loan
for the rest of it.
No! That's your baby money.
I can't take that.
Don't worry.
I can have a baby later.
Uh-uh. No, look.
If I did it, I'd wait
until the estate is settled.
No. You can't wait
until then, because if you do,
Helga will have gone bankrupt
and there won't be
anything to buy.
Do it now.
Timing is everything.
Sandy, I can't borrow
money from you.
Okay, okay...
I'll tell you what.
We'll be partners and go halves.
I'll put up the money,
and you work your ass off.
What do you say?
So, mom, what do you think?
You don't have to
do this, you know.
I mean, you could have come to
your father and me for help.
Yeah, I do have to do this.
And it's not just
for the money.
I understand.
You know, when you
went away to college,
your father gave me $5,000
to open up a little
needlepoint shop
with Edith Carter.
I didn't know that.
Well, actually,
I changed my mind
and put my money in IBM.
Oh, poor Edith.
She went bankrupt in six months.
This is cute.
You know, that wall over there
should be white
to bring out that red clock.
But I just took the paint
off the wall
you know, to show the brick.
Oh... oh, well.
Look at this. Huh?
I was going over Helga's books
and I found out that she was
spending an absolute fortune
on this terrible towel service.
Mm-hm.
And, so I figured out
that I could pay for this
washer and dryer in six months
if I did the towels myself.
You know what? You were always
wonderful at math.
Why don't you try bookkeeping?
No, mom. I want to try this.
It'll be fine.
Everything's under control.
Really.
And it's hit up the
alley between right and center.
Two runs are in. The cubs go...
Hi.
Oh, hi.
I was painting when you called.
I didn't mean you had to
do this right away.
No, no, no. I've put it off
long enough. Really.
And I'm sorry. I'm sure
you could have used the space.
Are you okay?
Sure. Why?
Well, you look awful.
Like you haven't shaved
in a couple of days.
Oh, I... I thought
I'd try growing a beard.
Oh! It's very becoming.
Yeah.
I picked up some boxes
at the market.
Thanks.
If you ever need to talk,
I'm available.
Maybe we could go out.
I mean, not for a date,
or anything,
but just for dinner
and to talk about things.
I thought you might have
a lot of time on your hands.
I know I did when Natalie
and I got divorced.
Oh, yeah, that would be...
Yes, I'd like that.
It's just that
right now I'm so busy.
You know, starting
the new business with Sandy.
Yes. Whenever.
Whatever you don't want,
just leave.
I'll help you
carry the stuff out to the car.
Oh...
Catch Carla and catch...
Oh! Damn it!
Geez, I'm sorry, Sandy.
All right, Janet.
It's just these damn cups.
The handles aren't
strong enough to hold on to.
Here.
That's all right, Janet.
Hey, hey, hey.
Sit down, all right.
I'll get you
another cup of tea.
Oh!
You seem a little jumpy.
Just a tad.
I haven't had a coffee
or a cigarette in a week.
The doctor told me
I had to give them up.
No. Junk food, too.
I've finally had a chance
to look at your tape.
So?
What did you think?
I think you've been doing
field reporting too long.
Oh.
What I mean is, I think there
are a lot of people around here
who haven't really appreciated
what good work
you've been doing.
Well, thank you.
That's terrific. Thanks.
You know...
Phil's leaving
in a couple of weeks
to take that job in Boston.
Which leaves the 6:00
anchor job opposite Carla open.
Right?
I'm... I'm going to
move Jim into that.
Right.
Which opens up his spot,
6:00 on the weekends.
Uh-huh.
So what I'm going to do is,
I'm going to try Pete out
in that spot on Sundays.
Right.
And you on Saturday.
Really?
Mm-hm.
Do you mean it?
Oh, George! That's wonderful.
I won't let you down, I promise.
You count on it.
Oh, great!
I want to see Sandy Dunlap.
She works here.
You got an appointment?
No, I'm a friend of...
I'm a friend of hers!
What's the name?
I'll see if there's a pass.
There won't be.
She wasn't expecting me.
But if you just call her...
I see her car,
so I know she's...
There she is. There she is!
Hey!
Buck, it's okay.
She's a friend of mine.
I'll meet you over there.
Hey, partner!
What are you doing here?
I thought you were
supposed to be painting
or plastering, or something.
Oh...
I am so glad to see you.
I just got the most
incredible news, and I'm...
Holly? Hey, Hol...
Is something wrong?
I just got back from
cleaning out Chip's office.
Oh, Hol. It must
have been terrible.
It's his whole life
right in these boxes.
His books, papers,
stuff the kids made...
Pictures.
All kinds of pictures.
Oh God! Oh shit!
Holly, um...
I was going to
tell you about this. I...
No, I'm glad you didn't.
It was...
It was so much better
to find out this way.
Holly. I didn't know you
when I met him.
If I had, this never
would have happened.
You've got to believe me.
It's all right as long as
you don't know the wife.
Is that what you're saying?
No. Of course not.
But as soon as I realized,
I ended it.
That's the truth, Holly.
Am I supposed to thank you,
or something?
Look, we really can't
talk about this here.
I'm going to pay you back
every penny.
I don't want your guilt money.
It wasn't that, Holly.
I really...
I really wanted to help you.
I love you,
and I just wanted
to be your friend.
Friend? Friend?!
You're not my friend!
But I need one, Holly.
I'm pregnant.
Here's my card.
Thanks. Have a good practice.
Hello. Shaping up.
May I help you?
Holly Davis, please.
Yes. She's just about finished.
Can you hold?
Okay.
Okay, thanks.
Telephone.
Oh. Hey, that tape is great.
Hello.
It's Sandy.
I really need to talk.
Yeah, well, I don't
want to talk to you.
Damn it!
There goes dad
after that gopher again.
Easy, dad!
He almost broke
his ankle the other day,
falling in one of those holes.
My money is on the gopher.
Mom?
Yeah.
I need to borrow $8,000.
Ah... running a business
isn't easy, huh?
No, mom, it's not the business.
The business is fine.
Really? Then what
do you want it for?
I borrowed it from Sandy,
and I want to pay her back.
I've got to pay her back.
I found out she was
having an affair with Chip.
Oh...
Yeah, I was afraid of that.
What do you...?
I mean, I picked up some clues.
Why didn't I
pick up some clues?
Probably because
you didn't want to.
You were too close to Sandy.
I mean, that...
That happens sometimes.
Where did you learn
so much about this?
Well, you know, women talk
and, you know,
they tell you things about...
That's a lie.
Honey, I went through
the same thing with your father.
What?
Yeah.
My sweet little old father
had an affair?
He wasn't so old,
and he certainly wasn't sweet
when it went on, but he did.
My God!
That jolt you felt this morning
was still another
in a series of aftershocks
that have followed
the August 28 earthquake
that hit
just west of riverside.
It measured
5.3 on the Richter scale.
The tax tables may be turned.
Congress is announcing
a plan to audit the...
Well, look who's here.
That's all of it.
The whole 8,000. Plus...
You could have just mailed it.
Yes, I know. But I wanted
to say something to you
that I think I have to say
face-to-face.
What's that?
When you and I first met,
you said you wanted
to have a baby with some man.
But I didn't know the man
you were talking about
was my husband.
No, neither did I.
Well, I was just wondering,
under the circumstances,
I mean, you know, considering
everything that's happened,
if you're absolutely certain...
The only thing that
I am absolutely certain of,
is that you are
the last person in the world
I want to discuss this with.
Hello, hello.
Hi, mom.
Hi. Hi, Stanley.
Where have you been?
I've been learning
a new billing system.
On Saturday?
Yeah.
You're working too hard.
I'm enjoying it.
But you should be
getting out once in a while.
Have some fun.
I don't have time for fun.
I've got too much to do.
It's the second time
the city has
been devastated by floods.
Haven't you got anything
better to do than to watch TV?
It's the news, mom.
Yeah, well, okay.
If you want news,
read a newspaper.
Hi, mom.
Hi.
Is that who it sounds like?
She's anchorwoman now.
Mm-hm.
How come we never
see Sandy anymore?
Well, you know,
I've been awful busy.
Well, to tell you the truth,
she and I had
a kind of a falling-out.
What about?
I don't want to get into it.
Is there any chance you guys
could patch things up?
No.
Too bad. She's cool.
Yeah, I really miss her.
Really.
Scientists at the California
seismological center...
I just can't get over
how much Heather has grown.
Hi, dad!
She seems to grow from
one weekend that I have her
to the next.
In-between,
I just have to be satisfied
with watching her on tapes.
"Video daddy." That's me.
I made some cassettes
of the two of us
and sent them home
with her once.
Natalie said
they didn't fit her machine.
It seems
I'm Betamax and she's VHS.
It gives you some idea of
what our marriage was like.
I like your beard.
Really?
Yeah.
Natalie hates it.
Screw Natalie.
Can we go on this, daddy?
I'm really glad you called.
It's wonderful seeing you.
It's good seeing you.
It's been too long.
Hurry up, Heather.
We're catching up with you.
Hi, Holly.
You look terrific.
Thanks.
I don't know if this is
the right time for me
to be saying this, but...
I guess I've always been
attracted to you.
I know.
What? You do?
Was I that obvious?
Pretty obvious.
Oh, my God.
Do you think Chip knew it, too?
Oh sure. We talked about it.
It didn't really bother him.
It didn't...
I suppose he didn't consider
me a threat, right? Is that it?
No, no, no, no.
It was just that he...
you were friends.
Friends don't do that
to each other.
Some friends...
Hi, daddy!
Did Chip ever say anything
to you about having an affair?
Chip? An affair?
I'm not asking you
if he had an affair.
I know he had
an affair with Sandy.
Oh...
I'm asking if he said anything.
Yes. But I know
he felt awful about it.
I mean, he didn't
go looking for it.
It just happened. Really.
I don't know...
Maybe he needed some variety
for sex, or something.
Did he ever talk
to you about that?
Was it sex?
Oh... Gee, I...
Is this making you
uncomfortable?
Yes, it is.
Because if it was sex,
you know, he didn't
have to go anywhere else.
I mean, because our own
sex-life was really good.
You know, at least it was...
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I really need
to know something,
and I want you
to tell me the truth, okay?
I will.
Do you...? Do you think
that I really mattered to him?
I mean, he told me that I did,
but it's really important for me
to know for sure.
You meant the world to him.
I'm looking for
the word "love," here.
Did he ever use that word
in relationship to me?
Yes. Love. Absolutely.
He did, didn't he?
Yeah...
Yeah... I mean, it sure couldn't
have been for the sex.
It wasn't all that red-hot,
if you want to know the truth.
Oh, I'm sorry. Is this
making you uncomfortable?
No, no, no, no.
It really wasn't that good.
That's what makes
all of this so ironic.
Makes what ironic?
I'm pregnant.
Yeah, I know.
How...?
Well, Holly sort of
mentioned it to me.
Oh yeah.
But what I wondered was,
how do you feel about it?
I don't know.
The timing sucks.
I mean, I really thought
I wanted to have a baby,
but this is going to be tougher
than I thought.
See, I didn't think
I needed anybody
to go through this with.
But if I do this...
I mean, I'm going to want
natural childbirth.
How do you go through that
without a partner? Right?
Mom, do you remember
when I made this?
Oh yeah. My favorite.
Shit!
Jeff!
Mom, this is the third one
that hasn't worked.
I have to go through
the whole goddamn string
just to find the light
that's burnt out.
I don't care.
It's no way to talk
while you're decorating
a Christmas tree.
Dad used to say even worse stuff
when he did it.
Yeah, well, that's a tradition
we can do without.
Of course, if you want to stay
that way for a couple of weeks,
maybe we could decorate you.
It's going to be weird
this Christmas without him.
Really...
Why don't we just remember
all the great
Christmas squabbles
we've had in the past?
He'd like that.
Oh...
Hello.
Can we talk?
Do you remember
when you paid me my money back?
Yeah.
Well, you paid me interest.
Interest?
I would have had to pay interest
if I'd borrowed it from a bank.
I'm not a bank. I...
I was your friend at the time
you borrowed it,
and I really resent you
putting a dollar value on it.
Especially when
it was only 7.5%.
I was wrong to
have paid you interest.
Yes, you were.
I figured you could use it.
Oh...
"Poor Sandy."
No!
I don't need your charity.
Now, just you wait a minute!
The last time I saw you,
you weren't sure whether or not
you were going to
have the baby.
And I just want you
to know that I've...
I've changed my mind.
I think you should.
Gosh. I just think
this is real swell.
I mean, this is just terrific
that you've had this
personal breakthrough. Really.
But guess what?
I don't need your blessing.
So, I'll see you
in a few minutes.
Do you want me
to come with you?
No. I just want to
see the baby.
Don't you want to
see Sandy, too?
No. Not really.
It's a boy?
Are you going to
keep doing this?
keep sneaking around,
peeking in windows
at his birthday parties,
and wearing a fake mustache
at his little league games?
No, Sandy.
If you are,
I'll leave town right now.
I just... Wanted to see him.
Oh... well,
you've seen him, right?
So leave.
Okay, I'm leaving. Don't worry.
I just want to ask you
one question.
Stephen.
Stephen?
The baby's name.
Wasn't that your question?
No.
Hi, how are you?
Did Chip ever say
he was unhappily married?
No.
Then why?
I don't know.
Besides, that's two questions.
Sandy, I want you
to meet the rest of...
Excuse us,
this is kind of private.
Oh, well.
I'm supposed to breast-feed
right now. Excuse me.
Marci. See, that's what's really
so neat about breast-feeding.
You can do it anywhere.
She's right. Women in India
do it on buses.
Well, yeah, but...
God, she's such a ditz.
She has more flowers
than a goddamn rose bowl parade,
and she never even waters them.
Well, I guess it's
easy to figure out
why he was attracted to you.
I was attracted to you.
You're so different from me.
So funny and open.
Interesting.
Then there's me,
this boring housewife.
You're not boring.
Maybe not now,
but I think I was.
It's true.
God, it's crazy, isn't it?
Now that he's dead,
I've gotten to be somebody
who'd be more
interesting to him
than I was when he was alive.
Don't you love this?
He's been dead eight months,
and I'm trying to
save our marriage.
It was worth saving.
Was it?
Holly. He made a mistake.
A real big mistake.
But look at what you had.
You had something so special.
And he knew that.
And you knew that.
And you would have
forgiven him.
Because what you had,
you don't throw away.
What about what we had?
We could have
taken a cab, you know.
A cab? Why not a bus?
Take care, Mrs. Dunlap.
Mrs. Dunlap?
Yeah. What do they got to know?
They're too goddamn nosy,
anyway.
Bye.
Yes...
"Thanks for one of the most
wonderful experiences
of my life. Love, Harry."
Yeah... see, I decided to
go for natural childbirth,
and you need a partner.
Harry? Our Harry?
Yeah. Harry.
Well, that's...
I mean, I've been
going to the movies
and dinner with him for months.
He never said a thing.
Oh, don't worry about it.
I mean, it was nothing intimate,
or anything.
He just happened to see
every single, conceivable
part of my body.
Can you go slower?
I'm walking backwards.
Come on, Stephen.
Spit up for Uncle Harry.
Would you believe
he tried to bring
that damn thing into
the delivery room with him?
But they wouldn't let him.
You wouldn't let me.
Well, it wasn't exactly
my best side, was it?
Watch it.
Can we do that again?
I blew that.
Can you sit down in
the chair once more, and...
Harry, come on!
Well, like, I really got
to get this chair back.
Oh, all right. Sorry.
Enough, enough. Go!
You went through
Lamaze training with Sandy?
She asked me to.
You never said anything.
She asked me not to.
Well, I think it's terrific.
Anything else
you haven't told me?
As a matter of fact, there is.
Ah...
Wai...
Could you...?
You don't just
say something like that,
and then walk away...
What's wrong?
I'm going to be
the worst mother.
No, you're not.
Yes, I am,
and he knows it, too.
He's bit me every time
I've nursed him.
I'm going to be the
shittiest mother of all time.
Come on, I said
the same thing myself.
So did Natalie.
Of course, she was.
Why did I ever think
I could do this?
Because you can. You will.
Look what a good mother
you are.
Look how good you are at this.
Oh God, this is so disgusting.
What is?
I like this.
Look out, here he comes again.
Oh God...
What? Oh.
Okay, just a second. Say "hi."
Ahh...
Hi, Stevie.
Hey, Hol.
Mmm?
At what age
do they stop drooling?
Well, let's see. Jeff's 17,
and you should see his pillow.
Harry, will you come on!
Harry!
Wham!
Bam!
Sorry.
That's all I got.
Unless you want to...
Unless you want to go for
a little
national geographic stuff?
Harry, forget it!
Oh look! Is Heather adorable!
Harry, you didn't
tape over Heather, did you?
That's okay. I've got Miles
of this stuff.
When was it shot?
I don't know.
I guess last summer.
Give me the camera.
Who did it?
I don't remember.
Come on, you jerk.
Oh yes, I do.
Don't let anyone
try to follow me!
I want to go on the swing.
Oh, my God. I'm sorry. I didn't
realize this was on here.
No, no, no...
Okay, honey. Here we go.
Got you! Ha, ha, ha!
Give me my hat back!
Excuse me.
Sandy...
It's okay.
Is that the best you can do?
What's wrong with that?
How is that for something?
Push me, quick.
Dumb.
Tell me, who's ever going to
watch this, anyway? Huh?
It's going to be fine.
Yeah.
So, how is the business?
Good, good.
Almost too good.
What do you mean?
Well I just...
Yeah, I hardly have
any time for myself these days.
Oh God! I know how you feel.
How about you? Are you
going back to work?
Ssh... Stevie.
Here. Can I?
Be careful.
Ah, yeah... in a couple
of months, I think.
I do have this job offer.
Ah, that's great. That's good.
You shouldn't give it up.
You are so good at what you do.
Well, thanks.
And you don't have to worry
about career versus child.
You can do it.
Well, look what you did.
Yeah, well. In a way.
You're really
looking good, Hol.
So are you.
I love those shoes.
Where did you get them?
You like those, huh?
Uh-huh.
An old friend.
Well, she has terrific taste.
But... Who picked out
the rest of your outfit?