♪ Da, da, da-ba-da, da, da,
ba-da-ba-da-ba ♪
♪ da, da, da-ba-da, da, da ♪
let's go!
♪ We'll be there ♪
♪ a wink and a smile
and a great, old time ♪
♪ yeah, we'll be there ♪
♪ wherever we are,
there's fun to be found ♪
♪ we'll be there
when you turn that corner ♪
♪ when you jump out the bush ♪
♪ with a big bear smile ♪
♪ we'll be there ♪
Okay, here it is.
The date is June 24th.
I've found
what I believe to be a cave.
Oh.
This furniture looks handmade.
Aw, dang.
Oh. There.
Nobody will notice.
Hmm. Porridge maybe.
Yep, that's porridge.
Oh, hey, I've read that... oh!
We were all freaked out,
you know? I can't really...
Hey, what the...
My chair!
My porridge! Who are you?
How'd you get in here?
Stay back! Aah!
All right, all right.
Turn on the light. Okay!
Ow!
All right, we got you,
you little rascal.
What are you doing in our cave?
Oh, wow.
So, this is your cave?
Perfect!
Mind games, eh?
I know your type.
Now tell us why you were filming
in here and touching our...
So it's true
what the scientists say...
Your cavities are atrocious.
Would you say that
your poor dental hygiene
contributes
to your surly nature?
I don't know
what "surly," means,
but I'm gonna pretend
it means "radical."
So thank you.
But that wasn't
the answer we need.
Wah! Oh, no!
Sorry. I can't find it. It's too
dark in here. Maybe it's over...
Aah!
Ohh! So bright!
How are we supposed
to be cool with you
throwing
our mood lighting around?
I'm sorry!
It was an accident!
My paws are sweaty!
Hey, now.
What are you writing there?
Let me see.
Highly suspicious, I'd say.
Yeah,
this is super-invasive.
Ice bear has too many secrets.
It isn't invasive.
Really.
I'm doing research
on local bears.
It's an assignment for my class.
Class for what...
Kindergarten?
Up top.
Actually, it's a college course.
I skipped a couple of grades.
So the joke's on you.
Well, the proof...
Is in the pudding.
We got your backpack.
I'm gonna mess with your stuff
and get answers
at the same time.
Oh-ho!
What's all this?
I'm eating your stuff!
How's it feel?
Whoa.
Aww. Is this you?
"Chlu..."
"Cha-low-ee."
"Chloh..."
"Ch..."
Ice bear has
never seen a smaller human.
Stop! Give me that!
And spit those out!
Gah!
You're not even
eating them right.
Here you go.
They're a little spicy.
Oh, my gosh, you guys.
These are so good.
Can... can we
have another?
Sure!
Whoo!
Actually, I vecan we
opior gu. Have another?
Would you mind ii around for a t
to study your behavior?
I'll bring
you as many gummies as you want.
Deal!
Should I be doing something?
Nope. Just be normal.
♪ Hey, hey, look to the sky ♪
♪ the sun is bright ♪
♪ there's not a cloud in view ♪
♪ not a cloud in view ♪
♪ I'm thinking we make
the most of the sunshine ♪
♪ "What do you say?" Says me ♪
♪ ooh, doo-doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ don't want a push ♪
♪ no gloom in these streets ♪
♪ I just saw
a guy with purple hat ♪
♪ And the elements
will be like a bind ♪
♪ yo, rain cloud, chill ♪
♪ Stay away ♪
♪ not in the mood
for your fluff, okay? ♪
♪ Come back in two weeks ♪
♪ or two years or maybe never ♪
♪ 'Cause I just want it bright
for now, forever ♪
♪ ahh, whoo-hoo ♪
♪ Doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo,
doo-doo ♪
♪ doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo,
doo-doo ♪
♪ Rain cloud, chill ♪
♪ stay away for a while ♪
Hey, friend. How's it going?
You need anything?
Are you almost done?
When can I see?
Hang on.
Oh, yeah.
Cool, cool, cool.
You got it.
Done!
Done! Done! Done!
Ice bear believed in you.
Um, now that you're done,
you wouldn't happen
to have anything spicy for us,
would you?
Spicy? I don't think I know
what you're talking about.
But you... you said...
The thing.
Just kidding!
I got loads!
Go ahead!
We worked so hard for this.
Oh, no!
The last bus!
I've got to go!
Sorry for dashing!
I'll see you guys!
Well, that was fun.
Now time to enjoy our spoils.
Huh? Oh, no.
Chloe's laptop... she needs this.
Hmm.
Well... Now that it's here,
a little peek can't hurt.
Here it is... the assignment.
Let's full-screen.
Next slide.
"Large and needy beasts
of the nor..."
wha... ugh. That's
a horrible photo.
"Powerful stench"?
It's an alluring musk!
Ice bear
smells like clean babies.
We don't make people
uncomfortable.
Cool. It's me.
Grizz, most of this stuff
isn't very nice.
I mean... what?!
My diet
is more balanced than that.
I mean, it's just more lies!
Ice bear
settled that out of court.
What's this? "The bear
will do most anything for food."
"Anything for food"?
That's just not true.
I don't understand.
This is just such
a misrepresentation.
Yeah.
That's not us at all.
Look at this.
"Left my laptop."
"Could you bring it
by the college for me tomorrow?"
Gasping face.
Tomorrow. Huh.
Oh, I'll bring it by tomorrow!
"Yes," winky, winky, winky.
This is our chance, bros,
to let the people know
who we really are.
Chloe won't mind
if we make a couple adjustments.
Break out the sugary drinks.
We have a project to write!
Chloe.
Hey, psst! Hey, Chloe!
We're over here.
You guys made it!
Of course! Here's your lappy,
safe and sound.
Awesome.
Thank you so much.
I got to run,
but I'll see you later.
Later, indeed.
Is there any more room
down there?
All right, everyone.
We're going to start now.
Will our first presenter
come forward?
Chloe? Chloe?
Huh? Oh, yes.
Uh...
Oh, excuse me, uh...
Coming through.
I'd like to introduce to you all
the topic of my report...
Bears!
I took the time
to locate and study
three bear specimens of
the northern California region
and have compiled my facts
on them to share with you today.
Let's start with the next slide.
You thought
you knew about bears...
You don't!
Nothing can re-create
the majesty...
of a bear overlooking his realm.
More often than not,
bears can be found saving
the human race from themselves.
Bears are also the cleanest
of this planet's creatures.
They bathe an astonishing
three times a month!
Bears have evolutionized to be
masters of all kinds of combat.
Bears have more than eight abs,
with new abs
being discovered every day.
Bears have lots of feelings,
and that's a beautiful thing.
Bears are smart.
Congratulations, bear.
In conclusion, majestic, action,
hygiene, Brazilian jiu-jitsu,
fire, magic,
sensitivity, competence.
I, um... I promise that wa...
It wasn't what...
Chloe, I think
it's very apparent to me
and everyone else
in this classroom
that you put no actual research
into this project.
I really did do the research.
I...
Nothing in your report was
based on any scientific fact.
Why's she so angry?
That was all true.
Pardon me, student.
What did you think
about that abs slide?
Very cool and accurate, right?
I have no choice but
to issue you an incomplete.
I thought you were
more mature than this.
Please take your seat.
Wait!
Your honor, please,
we have a confession to make.
We are not actually the handsome
rapscallions you see before you.
We are, in fact... Bear... bea...
Bears.
We're Chloe's friends,
and we... excuse me...
Are also... sorry...
The ones who wrote that report.
She really did do research.
We just wanted
to make it more exciting.
I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
We were such fools.
Ice bear feels shame.
Pardon me.
Um, now that you guys are up
there, would you mind telling me
whether it's true that bears
have horrible dental hygiene?
I also wanted to know...
Is there an evolutionary benefit
for bears
having such big behinds?
Are bears dogs?
Um, those are
some very nice, uh,
revealing questions
you got there.
Uh, I don't know if we...
All right, let's do this.
One, we are not dogs,
"b," our butts look awesome,
and "c," my dentist says
my teeth are getting better.
Keep those questions coming.
We're answering all of them!
Hey, that's pretty cool.
Good job in there.
Yeah, that was great.
Hey, Chloe, we're gonna watch
this new TV show
back at our place.
You want to come?
I don't know, you guys.
I have another test
to study for.
Aw.
Oh.
Oh, all right, then.
Yay!
Also, bring more gummies!
Ice bear will share
his secrets...
About other bears mostly.
Wah-wah wah-wah-wah wah-wah
wah-wah-wah wah-wah-wah!