MONDAY
We haven't got much time.
Take off your clothes, Slatan.
They're both ready.
But tomorrow, only one will go.
It's your decision.
I'll go.
Let luck decide.
Got a coin?
And you?
Should I go for change?
There's a supermarket.
No. How about you?
I haven't got anything.
I found one.
Heads,
tails.
Slatan,
you win.
TUESDAY
Move slowly.
Act sure of yourself.
Make eye contact.
What if something goes wrong?
Wrong?
What is your name?
My name is Slatan Sveraev.
Where are you traveling to?
Spain.
- Why?
- Work.
Alicante, pharmaceutical.
The jacket you're wearing
has nothing metal.
The scanner won't detect
the explosives.
Nothing will go wrong.
Are you carrying anything metal?
Oh, right.
It must be my wedding ring.
Remove your shoes.
What could I be carrying
in my shoes?
A machine gun? Plutonium?
What are you afraid of?
You must not be searched.
They cannot touch you.
What's wrong with you people?
This is disrespectful.
Why are you touching me?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You'll detonate the bomb
during takeoff.
Over the urban area.
With 90,000 liters of kerosene
in the tanks.
The metal components
of the detonator
will be hidden
in your personal objects.
There are two ways
to detonate the bomb.
The cord on your chest
detonates the bomb in your jacket.
If you're discovered,
push the auxiliary button.
The bomb will explode
after four minutes.
Right when the cops
are all over you.
They will never take you alive.
The mix of explosives
is very sensitive.
Humidity makes it unstable.
Do not drink.
Do not sweat.
If it gets wet, it will explode.
Act like a normal passenger.
Be friendly.
Alex!
Don't be a nuisance.
Sit down.
For years you've lived
hidden like a dog
in Alicante.
Do you speak Spanish?
A little bit.
He's not completely deaf.
He has 6% hearing.
He had an accident at home.
They can operate when he's older.
Women...
will embroider your face
on clothing.
Children...
will learn your name at school.
Slatan.
All of Karadjistan is with you...
Where's your luggage, Sasha?
We agreed that if I didn't relapse,
we were going to Spain today.
Your sacrifice
is the greatest act of love.
If I'm nuts, don't come with me.
Stay in this shitty city.
It smells like a hospital!
If I'm nuts,
you shouldn't be with me!
- You're not well.
- Of course I'm not.
- I'm not going.
- Wait...
It's your time, Slatan.
You'll be a hero.
Sasha, please...
Give me another chance.
Please, don't leave me.
I'll kill myself.
I swear I will.
People will never forget you.
You're going to die for our people.
Russia has offended our honor...
...murdered our hope.
100 years of oppression are enough.
We will not hang our heads.
We will not forgive their insults.
We will never forget our fallen.
100 years of oppression are enough.
All of our enemies will die.
They will die.
They will die!
Excuse me. Thank you.
Excuse me.
The Chinese make everything
their size.
Let's see...
Here we are.
Pardon me.
I just married this pretty
little mouse sitting beside you
and they gave us separate seats.
Would you mind sitting here
in my seat?
I'll change seats.
- Really? You don't mind?
- Not at all.
Thank you.
Do you speak Castilian?
Spanish, do you speak Spanish?
A little.
I saw you in Customs...
They checked everything
but my rectum. They're psychotic
about terrorism, Jesus.
It's crazy.
Hold on.
The seatbelt.
Where's the...?
Wait...
Oh, that's yours.
You're right.
Good lord.
My God.
Geez, it's hot.
"What to do in case of an accident."
Preparing us for the worst.
The wings on Russian planes
are stapled on.
Never fails.
Accident, Russian plane...
Two anti-anxiety pills
and a prayer...
and we'll be in Madrid.
I'm Eugenio Sanardy.
Eugene.
Slatan Sveraev.
Nice to meet you.
Russian?
Sorry, they spilled...
- There.
- Yes.
All set.
Thanks.
We're going to spend
more than 6 hours together.
A lot of marriages
don't last that long.
- Oh, newlyweds. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Honeymoon in the Caribbean.
- Yeah?
Who could ask for more?
After two years living in Moscow.
- Hooray for the newlyweds.
- Hooray.
What's wrong?
What's going on?
I told you.
Russian plane.
Something defective.
Technical problem?
It smells like gasoline.
Your attention, please.
The flight has been cancelled
due to the storm.
The passengers who need lodging
will be taken to a hotel.
But due to the number
of cancellations,
it's possible
the hotel will be out of town.
What time will the plane leave
tomorrow?
We'll pick you up at ten, sir.
Have your luggage ready.
Enjoy your stay.
Damn Russian music.
I can't believe it!
What are you doing here?
- It's a mistake.
- My room.
No, my room!
Okay, it'll be our room.
Seated together, sharing a room...
It's destiny.
- How about that!
- How about what?
No, I mean...
What's your trade, pal?
Your job.
What do you do?
I sell medicine.
We're practically colleagues.
I sell shoes.
Nothing like a good shoe
for a healthy body.
Look.
Check these out.
Not bad, huh? Ladies shoes.
You know why?
Know what my slogan is?
So comfortable
even a man can wear them.
No blisters,
never a damn chilblain.
Sanardy Shoes change your life.
I have some with me, look.
Yeah, springs.
Russian hotels still don't use
bed frames.
Like sleeping in a bird cage.
Don't move.
Why not?
Because... my bed.
Okay.
I'm going to the can.
Hi, it's Slatan.
I'm in a hotel.
Are you crazy?
They'll trace the call!
Hang up, you idiot!
Hang up!
Hang up! Hang UP!
WEDNESDAY
Hi.
I need some razors.
- Razors?
- Yeah.
The storm caught me off guard...
and I want to shave my legs.
Shave. One moment.
Razors.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Excuse me.
Good morning.
When are they taking us
to the airport?
It probably won't be today.
The forecast is snow, snow...
and more snow!
Okay.
I'd like to change rooms,
to a single.
All the rooms are shared.
This is a small hotel. It isn't
prepared for so many guests.
I'm sorry.
Good morning!
Any problems with the snow
last night?
Please try to understand.
Ruskie!
Come here.
You can sit by me.
Come on.
He didn't hear me.
There's no oatmeal?
A kiwi?
Something healthy.
What do you mean, I can't cancel?
7 thousand euros!
- Sorry...
- No, no...
Please, ladies first.
- Thank you.
- Miss, are you lame?
I'm trapped in Russia.
Russia!
How should I know what time
I'm getting to Puerto Vallarta?
Say you'll be there
at a quarter to.
Have them put some champagne
on ice.
Like hell I'm going to pay
the honeymoon suite.
I am being polite,
just don't fuck with me.
It's my honeymoon!
Once in a lifetime!
I won't send shit in writing!
Pinhead!
Thief!
You're corrupt!
I'm sorry, I can't talk right now.
I don't know what's happening.
I can't stop laughing!
Finished?
What's a lady with such
a great sense of humor
doing in the Russian steppe?
I was at a funeral.
My husband's.
Mmm, tasty.
Hi.
What happened to your wrist?
Nothing.
I cut myself on a bottle
of perfume.
Clumsy me!
Here we are,
the whole Spanish colony.
And it looks like
for a while.
We should do something tonight
for entertainment.
Alex!
Karaoke? Getting laid is pretty
unlikely.
Maestro, you play the piano,
right?
I've called the company
85 times already.
I talked to a machine that...
Camilo, what's your problem?
- Sorry, my love.
- You think this is normal?
Have you seen my son?
Always the same.
I turn around and he takes off.
Alex!
He was playing in the snow.
Hold him for a second, okay?
Wait...!
That was you
outside the door
in the bathroom, right?
It wasn't a bottle of perfume.
You know what?
If you really want to cut vein,
you have to cut vertical.
And zigzag.
So they can't stitch.
Then you get in bathtub
with hot water.
There you can go...
very peacefully.
Okay.
Can you watch baby?
Yes.
Get out of here.
Out!
Knowing that I loved you,
that you were my joy
and my blazing dream.
It's too late to comfort me.
That's why I get drunk
to forget
yourlove.
Bravo!
What's going on?
Karaoke night.
Who wants to try?
Come on, my shoes are full of swing.
That's it!
Ruskie! How about it?
Sing us something.
We're in your land.
Sing something
from Mother Russia.
You want a little help?
Maestro?
Hit it.
Ravil!
The storm has intensified
with a low pressure polar front.
In the next 48 hours o
we expect lows of -32C
along with strong winds
and heavy snow.
Oh, good.
There's a little left.
Bring it over.
Keep the party 90mg-
Lola, if you want to go to bed,
that's okay.
What? I have a babysitter for once.
I left them with the Argentinean.
He'll dance them right to sleep!
Tell me, sweetie...
What brought you to Russia?
Want me to show you?
Where is there a telephone?
Here.
No...
ls there a public telephone
anywhere around here?
I feel like going for a walk
to get the blood flowing.
It's 3O degrees below zero outside
and the nearest village
is 9 kilometers to the north.
To the north.
Thanks.
- You looked beautiful.
- There we are.
Six months after meeting
in Torrevieja.
"Listen to me, Dolores.
Do you find me attractive?
Well, honey?"
He should try a little sun block!
His face looks like
a monkey's ass!
"It's not the sun,
I'm red from the vodka.
From the liquor.
From the brandy.
From drinking anything."
Go on, put your tie
on your head, Boris.
Look, look!
"This is as calm
as you'll see me
in the next 8 years.
Everyone listen to me.
The Spanish girl married a Russian.
And she thinks
that because I'm old
I'll treat her with respect
and dignity.
Well, I won't.
I will leave her
with two children.
Without a single orgasm,
not a penny to her name
and with marks on her body.
With this open hand
I'll beat her for 8 years,
her and her children.
And if one of them goes deaf,
too bad.
That's life."
My wrist could have really used
one of your broken bottles
of perfume.
What rotten luck.
Such a pretty young girl
cutting herself like that.
Lucky it wasn't serious.
We can't take your call
at the moment.
Please leave a message.
It's Slatan.
This phone is safe.
The plane has been delayed
a few days by the storm.
If I don't receive instructions,
I'll blow myself up
at the Limbads Hotel.
I repeat.
Loan kill...
I can kill 20 or 3O people.
For Karadjistan!
THURSDAY
Go away!
Dog...
Easy“.
Good boy.
Stay there.
Stay.
Eugene.
Your roommate,
the Russian...
He never talks.
No, he's a little shy.
I'm calling from
room 104, Slatan Sveraev.
- Has anyone called me?
- One moment.
No, you have no calls.
Shy? I would say anti-social.
He doesn't even say hi to people.
Alex, honey, wipe your face.
Stop teaching them gross things.
Let's not judge Slatan
for not saying hi once.
It's not only that.
He kind of scares me.
Not just his appearance,
it's the look in his eye.
What look?
Listen.
Dragging my ass across the world
for 3O years has taught me 2 things:
The first...
Sanardy Shoes
make you walk better.
That...
Russia has offended our honor,
murdered our hope.
The second:
How to know people.
You look at the Russian
and what do you see?
He doesn't wear Christian Dior,
his cell phone is out of credit...
he doesn't go around telling jokes
in the hallway...
100 years of oppression are enough.
And you know why?
Because something tragic
happened to him.
Something is wrong
and he carries it inside.
He doesn't sleep.
He spends the whole night
pacing back and forth,
consumed by his anguish.
Maybe he never talks,
that's true.
But he listens.
So what?
Is that weird?
Maybe we're the ones
who are weird.
We let him eat breakfast
alone in a corner.
For Karadjistan!
For my people!
Slatan Sveraev!
Your call.
Slatan?
We heard your message.
The mission is still on.
You must blow up the plane
in flight.
Until then, behave like
a normal passenger.
- Understood?
- Understood.
For your people, Ruskie.
- For your people, Slatan.
- For your people.
For your people.
Thank you.
He is a little weird.
Just a little.
I saved this for you,
or the Chinese will eat it.
You have a button loose.
Take off your coat,
I'll mend it for you.
We hear you're buying breakfast.
Nice touch!
We're keeping you company.
I'll trade you this cookie.
These are delicious.
Here's to you, Slatan.
He's scratching his head a lot.
So is he.
What?
My God, look at all those
split ends.
I think you got lice
from the boy.
Lola. How about a ride
in my convertible?
Oh, a sled! Okay. I'll put up
my hair like Grace Kelly.
As long as we don't end up
like her.
Okay, you two are on your own.
Where are you going?
Qkay...
By the way, my name is Anunciacién,
but everyone calls me Nancy.
After the doll.
I'm Slatan Sveraev.
Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yes.
Wait, it won't rinse out.
Sorry.
I need your help.
Hold the towel with your hand.
It's very pretty.
What does "nadezhda" mean?
Hope.
Hope?
Wow, the Ruskie is sensitive.
Ready.
Up.
Parted in the middle, on the side
or shoulder-length?
Hold on, Lola.
Hold on tight
or you'll go flying.
This thing is a rocket
going down the hill.
Trust me, Lola, don't hold back.
Come on.
That's it.
Go with the flow,
you're with an expert.
Our trip was insured, right?
You should send an SUV
or a damn tank for us.
Mr. Garrido, I'm going to take
legal action.
Satan, watch out...
We're almost there,
one last push.
You look very handsome.
Who does your hair, Slatan?
You're dangerous with scissors, huh?
You know what?
A lot of people have tried
to dissuade me from killing myself.
But nobody had ever
given me advice
about how to do it
painlessly.
That's very nice.
Thank you, Slatan.
You're welcome.
Sorry! Hold on!
Watch out!
Eugene!
- Are you sure you're okay?
- Yes, yes.
That was quite an impact!
Just a scare.
It looked worse than it was.
Hey, Ruskie.
I have a question for you.
I need to ask him something.
Listen... Come with me...
I broke my balls.
- Look at me.
- What are you doing?
Is everything
where it should be?
It was like an explosion,
a crunch...
I felt something burst.
- I'm coming, okay?
- Take a look.
Please.
Well?
What the fuck am I doing here?
Should I put it on ice?
What's wrong?
Get out.
If you have a problem, so do I.
I must dry medicine,
need to keep warm.
Problem of life or death.
Don't worry.
Please, everyone come out here.
The Ruskie has a problem.
We need to dry his medicine.
We need heat.
- A hair dryer.
- I have a heater.
Please.
- A hair dryer?
- Please.
- I have an extension cord.
- Sure.
- I have an electric blanket!
- Get it.
My hair dryer!
It's dry.
What a mess.
Right, dog?
I have a theory about heels
on shoes.
Yes, I think the height is related
to a woman's problems.
Two centimeters, few problems.
Eight centimeters,
a ton of problems.
I love them!
Thank you very much.
They're beautiful.
How high would yours be?
Fifteen...
-at least.
- Good lord.
I don't think I have any...
Have you got family?
Divorced.
Well, in Argentina getting divorced
is required for citizenship.
It's in the Constitution.
Selling shoes
in three countries a week...
Well, you don't get home late.
You're never there.
Maybe I married the wrong person.
Me too.
So I decided to run away
with my children.
But the day right before
I got on the plane...
he goes and leaves me.
Myocardial heart attack.
He drank vodka
like chocolate milk.
I don't know...
He's upstairs, in the room.
- Here?
- His ashes.
In the room.
Here we go!
Press 1 if you'd like to buy
an airline ticket.
No.
Press 2 if you'd like to speak
to check in.
Not on your fucking life.
Press 3 if you'd like to buy
insurance.
Which later turns out to be useless.
Explain the reason you're calling
briefly and clearly.
Need flight.
We did not understand you.
Please repeat.
That damn Crematorium...
They vacuum seal the urn
and I can't...
Please.
A tool of my trade.
Sorry.
This will be weird for him.
All that ice and so little vodka.
Did you want to say
a few words?
Fuck him.
Amen.
He said 89.
Here we go. 43.
Wait, wait, wait.
I wanted...
to thank you
because you helped me...
It was nothing, son.
Here, sit down.
Come on.
We have 33...
Let's do this:
How about you turn the lever
-and say the number out loud.
- Go on.
Here we go!
I'm having a bad streak.
Here, let me.
Are you sure?
- No, but...
-Okay.
- He's all yours.
-53.
In Russian, please.
53.
This feels like...
-a vacation. It's funny.
- It is.
At least for me.
He always does that every time!
Well, well...
- Did he get you wet?
-It's holy water.
- Holy water, he says!
- Sure.
Silly.
72.
Who said I couldn't fly a kite
at 20 below?
We've done everything
but play smash ball.
Right, honey?
Slatan.
Give me a 22 and we'll run away
with the winnings.
Okay?
Let's go, bingo!
Who has the bingo cards?
- We'll play together.
- Are you having fun?
Tell me. Are you enjoying
your honeymoon?
Because while I eat shit
on the phone
all you do is play with dessert,
your kite, the snowman
and all the other crap!
We have nothing in common.
I married a little boy
who'll never grow up.
Grow up? What for?
To be unhappy, like you?
Because you seem very sad to me,
Natalia.
You know what the problem is?
The honeymoon wasn't the reason
I got married.
You are.
And you choose where the sun
and the beach are.
That's Russia for you.
Plenty of sun and beach.
That's how it is.
Russian cuisine is good,
that's true.
Yes, excellent.
Ruskie, let's make a goulash
for everyone tonight.
We can make Chinese food too.
We'll find out if it's true
the Chinese eat each other.
I'm kidding.
Where's your friend?
How about it, Ruskie?
Let's cook.
Goulash, goulash, goulash!
Goulash!
Goulash, goulash!
I'm not from Russia!
I'm not from Russia, Eugene.
I'm from Karadjistan.
Karadjistan. Do you know
where that is on a map?
No.
My people were crushed by Russia.
And they exiled us.
They cut our electricity,
communications.
Power.
Food!
Did the United Nations
do anything?
No.
Domestic problem, they called it.
Nothing is what your countries do.
They do nothing.
And after years of embargo...
nothing is left.
No hospital.
No medicine. No antibiotic.
Children die and diarrhea.
And then bombing start.
Ravil!
Slatan.
Slatan, I need you in the hall.
It's urgent.
Please, hurry.
Camilo!
What?
We have to wait?
Half an hour?
Please. Please.
Alex, Lola's son, ran off into
the woods. It's been half an hour.
- Let's do a sweep.
- We need to hurry.
-It's 3O below.
- My boy won't hear us.
But he'll see us.
Don't worry, we'll find him.
- Oh my God.
- Here.
No, I'm not going.
What? Weren't you listening?
A 7-year-old boy
is freezing to death.
I'm not going. 30 below zero.
Boy is dead.
Lola...
Lola!
How can you say that?
I thought I knew people.
I don't know shit.
Go on.
Go.
You know something?
You should get another tattoo
that says there is no hope.
Because there's a little boy
alone out there in the snow
waiting for his mother
to find him.
And he's going to die
like a little bird.
You know?
You don't care.
You're dead, Slatan.
You're dead.
And you don't know
how sorry I am.
Alex!
Mauthausen.
1944.
I know what you were
talking about in there.
The bombing, the killing,
the horror...
I can't complain. I'm alive.
Mom, Dad...
My five brothers and sisters.
They all ended up getting cremated.
Some nights I still dream about
the smell coming out
of the smokestacks.
The smell of Mom and Dad.
Son, no matter how much
you've suffered,
there's always someone
who suffers more than you.
Always.
Alex!
Find!
Slatan?
Slatan!
Slatan...
Where are you going?
Boy look for sound of quarry.
That way.
Alex!
Where are you?
Please, no...
Oh, my baby...
My baby...
Thank you... Thank you...
Thank you...
Look.
Ravil.
He's very handsome.
Yeah.
He took a long time
to come into this world.
He didn't want to leave
his mother's belly.
Smart, huh?
Neighbor had to come
to help with birth.
They had to cut her open
to take out.
No doctor,
no hospital...
My wife died during the birth.
But Ravil lived.
And he didn't cry.
Here we went to Kostani.
Kostani?
And I told him
that if he got lost,
not to move.
To stay where he was,
that Daddy would find him again.
You know?
And he looked at me
with face he made
and went like this:
When he did that everything...
I knew everything would be okay.
You know?
And he got lost.
And at 11:30...
M-15 started bombing
like always.
I lost Ravil...
He was good boy.
He didn't move.
In the middle of square.
Waiting.
He held duck very tight.
Tight.
Very, very tight,
like holding him...
would keep him in world
of the living.
But no.
- Don't cry.
- No, I'm not crying.
It's just...
Good night, Nancy.
You mean good morning.
FRIDAY
Don't be like that.
It's a Christmas sweater
from Santa Claus.
Your clothes are in tatters.
Nancy and the rest of us
all chipped in...
Why don't you shut up
a little?
Give me a hug.
Take it easy, man, come on.
That's it.
Thank you. Really.
For what you did
for the boy.
I misjudged you at first,
but I care about Lola and the boys
very much and...
We stayed up all night talking...
"Pim, pum, pam..."
Until dawn.
-"Pim, pum, pam?"
- What?
Mpim, pum, pam?"
- No, no...
No, talking, really.
She's a wonderful woman.
I see love here!
- No, no...
- What?
It would be crazy.
We live on different continents.
Come on.
Look at him run!
Bravo!
Thank you!
Hero!
Brave!
How are you?
Are you okay?
He's okay.
Bravo!
Okay, we can let the lovebirds
go back to their honeymoon
and keep the party going.
Who wants to give it a try?
Come on!
Slatan, sing a song from Rajistan,
from your country.
Yeah, come on!
- Let's hear it!
- I don't want...
Sing!
Sing! Sing!
Everybody settle down.
Singing isn't Slatan's style.
But yes,
- I can sing a song for you.
- Okay.
Okay.
Come on!
I can't believe it!
Let's go!
Let's go, my friend.
The stage is yours, Slatan.
- I only know one.
- Then sing that one.
- Or sing another one.
- Stud!
Russia has offended our honor,
murdered our hope.
100 years of oppression are enough.
We will not hang our heads.
We will not forgive their insults.
We will never forget our fallen.
We will fight the enemies
who strangle us.
We will fight to the end!
To the end!
The enemy will die.
All of our enemies will die.
They will die, they will die,
they will die.
Our country
we will free.
We will never give in
to the enemy.
Quiet!
Quiet.
Russia has offended our honor,
murdered our hope.
100 years of oppression are enough.
We will fight to the end.
Russia has offended our honor,
murdered our hope.
100 years of oppression are enough.
All of our enemies will die.
They will die!
Bravo!
Is that tasty?
Well, dog...
How are you doing?
The airport will be opening
in one hour.
The bus outside will take you
to the international terminal.
The plan is still on.
As we agreed.
Is that clear?
It's clear.
You...
You're a rock star, Slatan.
You're the man, Slatan.
The fucking king.
Holy shit.
Forget about Bon Jovi.
Spaniard...
When we get back to Madrid,
set up a concert!
For you this has been
a mountain holiday.
- Your mission ends here.
- No.
You can go back to your family.
They're waiting for you.
Tell your parents
that you'll be home for dinner.
And your wife Yedé will be there,
celebrating your return.
You must be eager to see...
your son Ravil
after all this time.
Of course I want to see
my son Ravil.
And I Will.
Everything is fine.
Don't worry.
Come on, we're leaving!
The rickety bus is here!
Let's go!
Excuse me...
Bye-bye Russia!
Here we go!
The best honeymoon!
The Caribbean is overrated.
Slatan...
I was looking for you.
What...?
It's just a little cold.
The 3O below zero will make him
stronger. Like an Eskimo.
What's the plan
when you get there?
Well... my sister is picking me up
at the airport after all.
Just as well.
Because with the baby
-and stroller...
- Yes.
And the bus to Madrid...
And you?
Run around, as usual.
- All over the place.
- Right.
- Eugene.
- Yes?
Sorry. Something's wrong
with Slatan.
He's been in the bathroom
for 20 minutes.
After the fajitas the other day,
I'm not surprised...
Excuse me.
Lola.
Go ahead and board.
What is it?
What's wrong with him?
What is that?
It's a bomb!
Eugene!
Son of a bitch.
You said it was medicine
and it's a bomb.
There's a terrorist
in the airport.
We don't understand.
Say it's not true.
They don't trust me.
What? What's wrong?
There's another terrorist.
Eugene“.
Understand?
Where are you going?
Eugene!
Eugene“.
Eugene, I swear...
I swear on my son Ravil
that you aren't wrong about me.
Andrei, come over here.
They only speak Spanish.
There's more medicine
on the plane...
What's the problem?
Dad?
He's my father.
He's not well.
Everything's fine.
They'll catch the terrorist, okay?
Are you wearing Mom's shoes again?
Sorry.
He'll try to detonate bomb
in the air.
We have to disarm him
before we take off.
He has a detonator on his chest
and delay button in his hand.
If he sees any police or notices
anything strange, he won't hesitate.
He'll blow himself up.
So we have to do it
by ourselves.
Pardon me, sir.
I just married
this pretty little mouse...
and they gave us separate seats.
Would you mind changing seats?
Excuse me.
I'll change with you.
Okay, yeah.
Young people
still get married, huh?
They don't know what comes after.
Break-ups, lawyers...
A total bust.
Hooray for the newlyweds!
Here, let me hold him.
Let me hold him,
see if he calms down.
Come here...
It's okay, come here...
Come on.
Just as I thought, a full nappy.
Let's change you.
Do you need some help?
- It looks like it.
- Thanks.
It's not easy in a plane.
I'm good with kids.
Yeah, they love me.
Here we go...
That's it...
Here, take him...
Sorry...
Easy“.
He's a baby.
Slatan!
Slatan...
- Hold him tight.
- Are you okay?
- Nancy.
- What?
He pressed delay button.
What does that mean?
That bomb will explode
in 4 minutes.
Slatan, what are you going to do?
Get the bomb out of here.
Tell the captain to stop the plane
or it will explode.
- Slatan, don't!
- Oh my God...
Take emergency positions
and lean forward.
- I'm not letting go.
- Nancy...
There's a bomb on board.
I repeat...
- Nancy...
- I'm not letting go...
I go wherever you go.
- You can't come!
- Yes!
Get it out of here...
Everyone...
Sound the alarm!
Are you okay?
We have to start over.
Start over in Russian prison?
Stop!
I said stop!
Stop, you scum!
Get down on the ground!
I said get down on the ground!
Hands on your head!
Go away, dog.
Go away. No!
Go away!
Go!
Get away from me!
Prepare to fire!
Stop or we'll shoot!
Stop!
Get away!
First and second, fire!
I'm his girlfriend!
If you die, I'll kill you.
If you die, I'll kill you...
You told the police
you're my girlfriend?
Yeah.
I finally find a good man and look
what trouble you get yourself into.
Don't talk now.
It will be okay.
Yes.
Slatan!
Sorry. Sorry.
- Sorry.
-It's okay.
Take it.
Slatan!
What did one terrorist say
to the other terrorist?
This is gonna be a blast!
Slatan!
There's always someone
who suffers more than you.
And you only have two choices:
Either rot inside,
or dance to the rhythm of life.
SATURDAY