You should be practicing.
I am practicing.
What you're doing you won't need these.
What's your problem?
What do you learn here?
No Weakness! No Pain! No Mercy!
Begin!
He's had enough.
Don't you remember what we learned?
No weakness! No pain!
No mercy!
Cheng, stop!
Go home.
What are you doing?
Why did you stop?
Finish!
Come here!
We do not stop when our enemy is down.
No mercy...
No mercy in the studio...
No mercy in competition...
No mercy in life!
Our enemies deserve pain.
What are you looking at?
He's the one that attacked me.
We are here to make peace.
Let your little thing mind himself.
One to one, no problem...
...six to one, too much to ask of anyone.
I see...
Prepare for match.
We are not here to fight.
You attack my students
and disrespect my studio?!
You want to leave? Not so easy!
Master Li...
You both came here.
One of you fights now.
The boy will fight there.
We accept your challenge.
Please instruct your students
to leave my boy alone to train.
Attention!
From now on, this little thing
is to be left alone...
...until the tournament.
Understood?
If he does not show up for the competition...
...I will bring pain to him and to you.
Sir...
...my name is Dre Parker.
My actions have brought...
...dishonor to your family.
Your daughter
has been a great friend to me.
And from her, I have learned...
...that a true friend...
...is a person who makes your life better.
But, if you give me a second chance...
...I promise that I will be...
...the best friend your daughter has ever had.
Let the tournament begin!
Dre Parker advances to the semi-finals!
And now the first semi-final of the evening...
Next semi-final
introducing Fighting Dragon, Liang...
...and the surprise finalist, Dre Parker.
But, I can beat him.
I do not want him beaten.
I want him broken.
You're disqualified!
He's done.
I'm sorry, you should not continue.
You've brought honor to your family.
Dre Parker has 2 minutes
to return to the match.
If he is unable to return...
...the Fighting Dragons win by default.
Since Dre Parker has not
returned to the ring...
Dre Parker will fight!
I want you...
...to break his leg.
No mercy.
The score is tied, the next point wins!
Can you continue?
Finish him!