This story is based
faith.
Faith makes the impossible
occurs.
possible.
One of those stories intended
by the sound of faith.
Here are your 10 rupees ...
Hey! Where are you going?
Give me that bribery o'hare
you fired!
Put some money or will lose
your work.
Put it there.
Karan Singh and Arjun Singh,
put my bribe.
- We do not descuestes today.
- What's special about today?
- That's a secret.
- What secret?
- We'll tell you later.
- We do not take out 2 rupees.
We'll give you all pay
tomorrow.
Oh, yeah? I trust units. that
They are the sons of Durga.
But tomorrow will repent.
Tomorrow, 20 rupees for me!
Father, tomorrow is Sunday.
No works.
Goodbye!
Art thou fallen from heaven, man?
Forget that. Tell me how
Bangles cost.
Why you should buy bracelets?
Do not worry about that. Just tell me
As the bracelets cost.
- Show me that.
- No. That green.
- Red These bracelets.
- These golden bracelets.
- These colorful.
- They are very beautiful.
- I win, right mom?
- No! I win!
Children are won and lost
in competition.
And only compete enemies.
- I first tap your foot.
- No! I did it!
- I did ...!
- Stop it.
They're still competing
between units.!
Neither this nor ahead ...
not from behind.
My children are ahead
worldwide!
- Ma, we have something for you.
- What is?
- First close your eyes.
- For what?
- Close your eyes! Come on!
- Okay.
Open your eyes now.
Now you will use bracelets as
the other village women.
We can not stand to see your
hands as empty.
Reach out your hand breast.
Come on, mom.
No!
I can not wear those bracelets.
Why not?
I can not use my bracelets
old tontitos.
I understand, mama!
She will use the bracelets only
when Dad gets back from the city.
- That's true, right?
- It's been many years.
He already would have returned,
if he wanted to.
- She forgot about us!
- We know nothing of him.
And you always wait for it!
Let's return
bracelets. We will.
No. .. wait!:By:Mr.MAGDY
Give me those bracelets ... give it to me.
I'll give these bracelets
their wives.
- But they were for ...
- Go to swim fast.
We have to go to the temple.
When the sun is far
the sky?
When the moon is far from
its rays?
When the fragrance is far
Wind?
When spring is far
the yard?
This bond is a bond of love.
It is the union of life after life.
When the sun is far
the sky?
When the moon is far from
its rays?
When the fragrance is far
Wind?
When spring is far
the yard?
This bond is a bond of love.
It is the union of life after life.
Only units. are my life.
Vivire only to watch them.
For units ...
Would drink all the poison ..
world.
In your holy feet ...
'll Do that .. you all heaven
make a bow.
If there is a fire in your way ...
Lieth me .. so your passes.
This bond is a bond of love.
It is the union of life after life.
In the temple of motherly love ..
You are in. .. more
dear.
In the temple of motherly love ..
You are in. .. more
dear.
The image of God appears ...
... When I see your face.
When born in this
world ...
Alone ... I'll find your veil.
On the wall separating the
births ...
Our love ... write.
This bond is a bond of love.
It is the union of life after life.
- Regards, ma'am.
- The counter? You?
Achieve get here very
difficulty.
If anyone saw me coming
here, my life would be in danger.
But what brings you here so late?
The old Thakur called you
his mansion.
That mansion?
In which we closed the
doors to the side of God?
The mansion, where the wounds
are still raw in
the heart?
Go. Never whereon the mansion.
Fulfill the last wish of a
dying man ...
Is considered the ... more
largest of the noble works.
As ... The landlord ...?
If. The landowner is
breathing for the last time.
His last wish is to see you.
But it makes so much damn
Durjan Singh threw his shadow there.
How can I ever go there?
Tomorrow is the festival
Goddess Kali.
Durjan, with his brothers,
Shamsher Singh Nahar and ...
Will be in the temple ... with
their families.
Wait for you outside the
mansion.
- Please come.
- Very good.
- Who was that man?
- And who is the landlord?
We hide a secret
many years.
How would I know that the time,
someday, stoke your fire?
It is the story of my life ...
... You always hide in
secret units.
But today I will have to tell
truth.
I'll tell you everything.
The landowner is his grandfather.
That!
Our grandfather?
The landlord?
If. I'm his daughter.
I was a poor woman. And the
father of you. she married me.
But the landlord, instigated
by Durjan Singh, his nephew ...
He ... refused to accept me as your
daughter.
They took me out of the mansion.
Your father found a job
in the village school.
We were happy in our own
world, despite our poverty.
And the arrival of pcs. brought more
happiness and joy to our lives.
But our happiness soon
he became pain.
Durjan Singh dreamed of inheriting
the wealth of the family.
And one night,
pure treason ...
Durjan Singh murderer father
of you.!
That! Papa was ...
You mean that you always
what ...?
If. To keep this
secret, make up a story.
I did not want you guys. feel
orphans.
How would I know that my past
golperia one day at my door?
I should go to the mansion
always detest!
No. We're not going to the mansion
fit our father!
If. No there will tread ...
You ... that sank into poverty
and despair.
I know how flames
fanning hatred ...
... When one remembers the
humiliation he has suffered.
But always teach them
lessons of love and compassion.
Do not hate.
Hate only makes the
man and society coming apart.
Hate is the shadow of the devil,
my children.
It is the shadow of the devil!
Gloria Goddess Kali!
Welcome, lady ...
The landlord was talking
on pc. since morning.
He longs to see Karan and Arjun.
Welcome, daughter.
Please do not touch me ... I'm
a sinner!
No, father. What happened was
part of our destiny.
No. It was my arrogance that
dampened your destination.
Lanze my own blood in
flames of misfortune.
I must be severely punished.
A terrible death that no
sinner has even suffered!
Do not say that.
Ointment every time heals
wound inflicted by life.
Before dying, only once ..
No ondary me the right to
hug?
Right? Our lives are
for you.
Karan and Arjun are their children.
Let my children.
My children!
I'm really unhappy.
I could not play with pcs.
We will return the right
snatch.
You are now this lady
mansion.
And your children are heirs.
Take this.
The body becomes useless in
old age.
But you ruined your life!
I did not come to this mansion
to go!
Every brick of this house is
mio!
We service all your life!
Eat? You tried to kill me
at every turn!
But no mori me.
Because I have a debt to pay,
give these guys your right!
I will not give them to these beggars
a penny!
Instead, you and your
I'll give family death!
No! I make this pledge.
We want nothing!
You can have it all.
What do you say?
Daughter called me and keep
close to your heart to my children.
We have all the wealth in
the world.
We want nothing more.
Let children.
Brother, you left those two
live snakes?
Snakes can show their
fangs at any time.
They are just snakes
small, they are not snakes.
Still do not have fangs
poisonous.
Their father was the
snake.
Children are dying in my
hands as the father died!
That? You killed my son?
If. I did it.
And their children will die too
in my hands.
- That can not happen!
- It happened!
Because your family this
sentenced to die in my hands!
Look at this man!
You see the black shadow of your
death in my palm!
Run!
Corran my kids!
Arjun!
Karan!
Let my children!
- Let me and my Karan Arjun!
- These small snakes?
The game just begun, old.
It will be fun!
Look there, old lady!
Look there!
Enough!
Bit me!
Mama!
You hit my mother?
Flee!
Spread Arjun!
I tell you to run!
Karan!
Mother! My children can not
die!
This can not happen!
You are also a mother.
A mother can not destroy
the womb of another mother!
My children are the gift that I
gave your feet!
You can not take the gift
once gave me!
You'll have to give me back my
children!
Give me back my children, mother!
Bid more. A little more.
He ate his mother as soon
as national!
Now you'll eat my bottle
liquor?
I have no money for my drink! Of
beareth money where your milk?
Do not cry baby.
Our son will grow and be
a great man.
Even God will feel proud
of the.
All thanks to Pestonbhai.
Work on your riding club and
I make my living.
It is the Lord who does all.
Who knows? Maybe your son
direct my riding club someday!
You bring alcohol?
No. I'm hungry. Brought food.
Rogue! When you were little
crying for milk!
And now food!
- Give me some alcohol!
- No, you do not dare!
Fighting with your father?
- Let go of my hand!
- No! First let the bag!
Small, but has the
strength of a horse!
- Do not will loose?
- Scoundrel!
What happened son?
He was stealing grain
so drop it.
Wow! That marksmanship!
Suddenly, that you?
Kill him?
Why do you hit?
The fighting for you.
This guy told you drunk.
So Ajay hit him.
Control your child.
All those who have no mother
end well.
Mother ruined it ruined it, mother!
I am with child!
- Mother ruined it!
- Doctor,'s wrong?
No need to worry.
This hallucinating.
Stop by high fever.
Mother! Mother!
Priest.
I listen? I hear?
My son cries for me!
They will come. My Karan and my
Arjun will return!
Lady ...
I heard it for 20 years.
Karan and Arjun will return.
But this world is a place ..
Once people destroyed
This world never more return.
Wait and see.
Me and my Karan Arjun will return!
Definitely will return!
What a joke!
Karan and Arjun will return?
Old crazy!
My father, Durjan Singh, les
gave a terrible death ...
God ... I think that even 10
times before sending them here!
Move!
Old crazy!
It seems that not even think
your sons are dead.
Here, put on the girnalda
photography.
Watch her every day so you
convince your kids
are no longer.
This is for me.
And for me.
Priest, my son is going to
abroad.
I brought it to Mother
Bless.
So again with the success of your
mission.
After torment a
mother ...
You ask your other mother
blessing?
You'll have to beg my kids.
Ruegales for your life.
To let you live.
Remember, these three garlands ..
If not ... your body adornment
these ...
I'm not worthy of my
name, Durga!
Remember this Durjan.
My children will return!
Me and my Karan Arjun will return!
Stupid woman!
As can return the dead?
They will break the land
and will come!
They rend the sky
That guy is finished!
Punch him!
You were great!
You did a miracle defeating
Kalia to favorite! Mira.
A shower of money!
Here's your part. From today
you are the favorite here.
Eunuch! You marry me?
I'll start the brain!
Papa, she mistreats us!
Get lost!
Never find a boyfriend
like me!
You seem to live in this area.
It's a girl or a boy?
Who you ask?
I'll tell you who I am.
Run! I enuco!
See that?
It was the fifth copy.
Before my dad will my
hand to someone else ...
Take my hand.
A's not interested in you, but your
persecuting him like a fool.
It has the special that
I just want him?
Pope has what no
else has.
He gave me a slap when
was small.
In my cheek, but I leave a
printed mark in my heart.
The day they give you a slap,
you forgot to get me a boyfriend!
No! It's nothing ... just a
remedy.
Liquor in a bottle of medicine?
I have a hard buy
remedies.
And you have this poison?
I want to save you and your
You want to die?
There is still time. Change!
Great! Just great!
Incredible!
It's fantastic!
Fantastico or elastic, any
girl who comes here does
their teacher.
You really are amazing.
As you learned such excellent
riding and target shooting?
I put my heart in it and learned.
If you put your heart in it,
you too will learn.
His heart is also in it.
That's what I'm seeing. It
comes daily half hour before.
I do? Since I came here,
I do not like being at home.
Like a comet that is pulled
with a thread ...
I'm the same.
Maybe that affect you.
- That?
- If. That.
But in just two meetings,
Mogambo step ...
Who is Mogambo?
My horse.
Yes, I am drawn to Mogambo
and someone else too.
Anyone else? Who?
- Really?
- If.
- Swear.
- I swear.
I can see it in your eyes, but
also want to hear.
- Who is it?
- La Gomera.
La Gomera?
This slingshot as I enter
a love scene?
People love hearts and your
you fell from a slingshot?
You can have my slingshot,
if not my heart.
- Do not know how.
- You just know how to shoot arrows.
I'll show you.
Hold this right hand
and this left.
And strip.
Now keep it tight.
Who is this fat hippo?
My bodyguard.
Your bodyguard?
I hate it.
Pope sent me.
If someone gives me problems,
on the LYM.
LYM?
Yes, let
And Mutilated travelers with disabilities.
Let's see.
Hippo, where are you?
- You?
- Yes, I do.
- With the baby ...?
- If the baby.
- What did you do?
- The kiss.
Be careful.
I pushed!
Rogue!
The hippo on a horse?
Where is my gun?
Oh, that fight!
You are a true Superman!
Goodbye!
Miss, seems I'll have
to teach something else ..
- In addition to riding and shooting.
- What else?
A kiss on the lips, not
cheek.
- Here.
- Also I will learn it.
Where is the ruffian?
Do not forgive!
Who does he think he is?
It was a terrible fight?
They like to heart.
And revano the villain.
My ears were burning!
- You also would be ...
- What?
In flames.
- Where?
- Mouth, ears, nose ...
You rostizare if you say another
word!
Always talking in a
sense as Dada Kondke!
Who was that ruffian, son?
A flower and a spine.
I take!
Well done son! WHILE your
this hand on the head ...
These thugs .. my club
hipico oversteering.
Who would take care of the stable
if it was not for you?
I am in your debt.
No man.
You took care of me after that
my parents died.
I loved him like a son.
You brought me up, gave me a job.
Your father was my friend.
What I did was friendship.
We will. It's time for your
students come riding.
He was talking about the.
He can alone against a hundred.
- If you see it once ...
- We'll see.
Papi!
You're back girl?
Papi not move!
Do not move!
- Put the bowl on top.
- The cup?
- Slightly higher.
- Oh, come on.
Shit!
- How childish is this?
- Gomera.
I was practicing, but my
aiming is not good.
Punteria?
You went to learn riding.
From where it comes?
What you plan to never go,
and what happens is not planned.
And what ever you think some
It happens.
I mean it was great!
You understand what I said?
If. I'm not stupid.
Hello?
Good morning, sir.
When I leave my mansion ...
I think in another world, the world
our friendship.
This friendship soon
will convert into a relationship.
Your son will be my son Suraj.
Suraj and Sonia can commit
as soon as you return from London.
Saxena, enough sweetness.
Let's talk about something bitter now.
So the poison
bitterness does not spread in
our friendship.
I have still not paying
your assets.
When I gave my goods
This retracing payment.
Since it is dangerous, I
that ...
When it comes to money,
I am very immoral.
Much more with friends and enemies.
Do not hesitate to kill my
own people.
My payment should arrive within a week.
Why did you stop the car?
Look forward.
Move.
Looking your eyes feel ...
May the Goddess Kali lives in it!
If she says with confidence that
their children will come, they must
be on the way ...
- Contador!
- I mean ...
Brother, the story ends
that old witch today!
Brother, his words penetrate
like needles!
Flatten.
What do you say? She is already dead.
Warriors do not attack
women!
- I said I will tread the old!
- No.
No! What are you doing?
Why do you get them?
They terrify the whole people.
Why do you want to kill yourself?
If I were to die,
I would have died long ago.
Death can not destroy me
until I have been destroyed.
My children will come to destroy them.
The arms of a mother.
Karan and Arjun will come.
Mama!
Mama.
Run! Arjun run!
What's going on? People
suffer from sleepwalking?
You talk in your sleep?
I see? My heart beats like the
neck sliced ??a chicken!
These bones resonate as
coins on a carom table.
Who are you talking in your sleep?
I do not know.
But I could see strange shadows
of my childhood.
I feel like I have
relationship with them.
A deep bond with them.
Something that attracts me to them.
Calling me.
And what happened today ...
Happened before ... ever.
What happened?
There's a town.
Bell in a temple.
A road ...
And I saw myself.
I'm running and someone yells ..
Run Arjun run!
Ajay, your father vomiting blood.
The doctor said that this is
very serious.
The liquor destroyed his liver.
We'll have to operate.
- How much money is needed?
- 10,000 rupees.
Well, let it run.
That?
- You will lose this fight?
- If.
Because today I beat
Death.
It is a matter of life my dad.
I need 10,000 rupees.
Another windfall!
Money? As a companion?
He is the favorite.
People bet on it.
He makes it his to lose.
And we will not have to pay
anyone!
But you really will lose?
10,000 rupees.
Is there someone else?
Anyone?
Here! Local favorite Ajay.
That is not crushed by the
picture you showed me?
If. But I do not understand how
change the tide.
Shut!
What are you doing? 'll Ruin us!
What are you doing?
Controlate. What are you doing?
You needed Rs 10,000!
You said you'd lose the fight!
But we arruinastes to win!
What's wrong?
I wanted to lose the fight.
But ...
I do not know what happened.
You've got a lifetime to
know who I am.
But right now your father
only has a short time. I take it.
And this is my card.
- Who are you?
- My name is Ajay.
- This Mr. Saxena?
- Yes, sit down. I'll go look for it.
Hello?
- Who is it?
- My name is Ajay.
Ajay?
But nobody called Ajay in
the home of Mr. Saxon.
I am visiting.
Caballero, all visits are
in this world.
However, my phone line
ud is a link.
During the talk, our
also be linked hearts.
And we could be friends.
So we're friends?
I'm not interested.
Lord,
looks tight man.
No. ..
I just turn on the pyre
my father's funeral.
Sorry brother.
Please call Sonia.
I am Vijay.
Sorry ... there is a call for
Sonia.
Tell Sonia came.
She came out.
Sonia darling, hurry!
We have to go to the airport
Suraj to receive.
- She recently came out.
- You?
How is your father?
He died.
Here are just 8,000 rupees.
Spend Rs 2,000 cremation.
Devolvere would soon.
I like your sense of dignity.
- Working for me?
- Working for you.?
Your strength, your obsession, the
fire burning in your eyes.
I like. Would work?
Otherwise I would have rejected,
but I am indebted with you.
I'll start tomorrow.
Not tomorrow, right now.
We have to go to the airport.
Welcome Suraj.
- How was the trip?
- Fantastico.
- Where is Sonia?
- This anxious waiting at home.
My white Mercedes this out.
You go ahead. I must go through the
customs.
Right.
This is the order of the
Mr. Saxena?
Save this briefcase in the car.
Hear what I said?
Save this briefcase in the car!
I'm not the servant of your father!
What a joke!
You dare to call on the name
my father?
Keep your right hand on the
pocket.
Or you'll have to eat with your
left forever.
What a joke!
I think that you. two longer
they met.
He is Ajay, a super fighter.
And is Suraj Singh,
Sonia's fiance.
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
I began to fear even
myself.
I have started to fall in love.
If you're afraid of your own ...
Like .. you'll love?
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
The magic of your body attracts me
to you.
When I see you ...
.. I lose control of myself.
The magic of your body attracts me
to you.
When I see you ...
.. I lose control of myself.
What do you think of this?
You have no faith in my love?
I trust you,
but I do not trust me.
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
I began to fear even
myself.
I have started to fall in love.
If you're afraid of your own ...
Like .. you'll love?
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
With the red of your lips ...
.. I will color my life.
Top up my dreams with you ...
.. So I can live another day.
Oh, the red of your
lips ...
.. I will color my life.
Top up my dreams with you ...
.. So I can live another day.
You must control yourself,
I also let me control myself.
Do not love me so much that you'll
crazy.
Love is madness,
no sanity.
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
I began to fear even
myself.
I have started to fall in love.
If you're afraid of your own ...
Like .. you'll love?
Now I'm ...
What's the hurry?
My heart is racing.
Why?
Now I'm ...
Dude, since you get only
I hear that.
Sonia is on the way.
Soon came.
Morning and afternoon returned
still no sign of Sonia ...
What a joke!
Here is Sonia!
Hi Sonia, how are you?
You did not go to the airport or
you were not home!
I want to tell you so many things!
And hear a lot!
First you listen to me or me
TELL you?
Now I must listen and
I have to tell?
Why?
If you hear me,
you will forget about you.
And if you forget yours,
did you remember me?
If you remembered, that sense
have to do something that does not work?
I'm right? Bye.
What a joke!
I said? Dude, you understand?
Son, I'm not stupid.
They saw? This weapon can destroy
a steel plate of 3 inches.
You can destroy pieces one
bulletproof glass.
As people choose pearls
in the bottom of the sea ...
Select this weapon ...
mortal and this is no joke.
Look at them ..
Knights ..
In one month, these weapons
will be delivered at the border.
As always, these weapons I
came through Durjan Singh.
And I'll give to the units.
Ask for the amount of
weapons they want.
- This clear?
- If.
Dude, I think, that one of
our customers did not come.
Vikto ..
That?
- It has been relebado?
- No.
He returned dishonest.
I do not pay for things that
suit last time.
And each time I send one of
my men for money ...
Not become live.
You mean swallowed
our money?
A man was not born yet so!
I have created a man of steel
to get back at him.
Peter, talk to your man
by telephone.
Ask him to pay me.
Or take your body!
What happens? You are trying
see you looking today?
Shot.
All my debts are paid.
Okay, sir.
You are paying all the debt.
- When you will pay my debt?
- That you remove?
That you took? than anyone
He could never take off.
Do not understand?
You took the heart of
this girl.
That? Your a girl?
Look in the mirror. You do not look
as a girl at any angle.
I'm not a girl ...?
A guy my age,
oh, a guy my age.
And watch it, know nothing about
affairs of the heart.
Just look at this cruel guy, no
knows nothing about love and romance.
A guy my age,
oh, a guy my age.
And watch it, know nothing about
affairs of the heart.
Just look at this cruel guy, no
knows nothing about love and romance.
My bracelets sound calling you.
I got beautiful just for you.
My heart is crazy ...
Crazy for you .. ..
Crazy for you ... ...
What good is my beauty if your
no notes?
Oh cruel boy, serving
my beauty if you did not notice?
Tell me why are you avoiding my eyes.
Not supposed to be shy
with your nearest and dearest.
Tell me why are you avoiding my eyes.
Not supposed to be shy
with your nearest and dearest.
I'll show you the way
which ...
.. Walk into the heart of someone.
Oh cruel guy, I'll show you the
way by which you enter the
heart of someone.
A guy my age,
oh, a guy my age.
And watch it, know nothing about
affairs of the heart.
Just look at this cruel guy, no
knows nothing about love and romance.
What happens?
Nothing. I felt like ...
I felt as if these bracelets ..
Sonia ...
I can only buy bangles
glass.
Not gold.
Vijay, happens to you today?
- You say?
- Yes, Sonia.
I fall in love with you.
But I never thought that your
serious ... a princess.
And the dust of the roads.
I could give you all ..?
You mean wealth
is everything?
No. The money helps man
to buy expensive things.
But not a heart.
Man can buy
food with money.
But hunger.
A man can buy a body
with money, but not true love!
Love is more wealth
big this universe.
Which we have.
Your love and affection.
These bracelets are the treasure
of my life.
Never leave this treasure
stay away from me.
I want to see in palaces.
And decided to do a caregiver
Horse your life partner!
Not only my life partner,
We promised to live and die together!
Your anger and cruelty can not
change our thoughts.
I'll change your life!
I will destroy!
I can do anything!
You can bring your pyre
daughter on your shoulders?
These blind in his love. I'll
show you when the time comes.
I'll shoot you if you leave the
room tonight!
You lead a quiet life.
You are very lucky.
You have no voltage
about food.
I massaged, I serve you.
Whoever serves me? Nobody.
In the next life will be born
as a horse ...
Lingayya ... and your like.
Why are you laughing?
Lingayya Hey!
Why do you talk to a horse?
You have time to talk
me?
These busy diving in
pool of love!
The sea of ??love is very
deep. If you drown ...
Hey! Drowning is what
call love, right?
It really became an
Lovesick Romeo in 1 week.
The emotion is not the same when
risk your life riding ...
When the emotion ...
risk your heart in love.
What a joke!
If you do not hear me, your life
will be at risk.
Because your death suit
my hand!
Death at the hands of a tiger
a mosquito?
Who is this impediment
the way of love?
Shut!
I am the son of Durjan Singh and
Sonia's fiance.
My name is Suraj Singh.
Papa ... papa ...
Burn it!
Clutch it and go! Rapido!
What a joke!
Love will burn!
The lover was burned!
All right, son!
The road shows obstacles
and destroy enemies ...
Is the tradition ...
this family.
So compliance with
Family tradition. Right?
What a joke!
Tonto! Joking aside. Prepare
for your commitment to Sonia.
We'll go there.
Your attention please!
Ladies and gentlemen,
great applause.
Thank you very much friends!
Friends ..
Today is the happiest day of my
life.
Because today announced the
My only commitment ...
... Daughter, Sonia with Suraj.
Durjan Singh's son.
As soon as he arrives, the
tradition of commitment will ..
Look, here comes.
Vijay!
Stop it!
You burned my father's barn!
I'll burn your fingers!
- Call the police.
- A non-police!
Hello police!
Ajay kill him!
Get off!
Run! Arjun run!
I tell you to run!
I arrest him!
We are Thakurs of birth.
Pride and anger are at
through our veins along
with blood.
Every time our women give
step in the quicksand of
Discredit .. ...
The buried alive in the
walls of our homes!
But the love of my son
stops.
I have always fulfilled every dream
my son.
And today will fulfill this dream.
You married my son in my
house.
Prepare to leave.
I do not understand.
Suddenly because our
hands stopped fighting?
And because I said that?
Spread Arjun!
And he obeyed?
You said? Repeat it again.
Spread Arjun! Run!
Something is very wrong!
This is the same phrase that
say while you sleep!
That's what I'm thinking.
The words repeat
while I sleep ...
Segui murmurandolas.
The same words.
The same name.
As they came to my lips?
Who is Arjun?
Who are you?
That's what I want to ask.
- What it feels like ...?
- We met?
We have a deep bond.
There is a bond that brings us close
from each other.
We have already met before?
No. I do not even know your name.
Then at the party
said ...
Spread Arjun! Run!
I am also worried.
I can not understand.
How are you words came
to my lips?
Who forced me to say them?
Arjun not know any.
I did not know
Arjun product.
It feels like we have one
strange relationship to that name.
Some old association.
My name is Vijay.
Thank you for saving my life.
God forbid, if any
After facing one situation so ..
I'll pay the debt.
Vijay!
Vijay! Sonia letter for you!
Something seems to be wrong!
His servant gave me.
What about child?
Are being forcibly
Sonia to my mansion
Durjan Singh.
She asks me to rescue.
She writes that if I will not
alli ...
Took poison and killed,
but not to marry Suraj.
What are you thinking?
Prepare to go.
If I go, what happens to your stable?
- Your business ...?
- Businesses continue.
But once that is lost,
as it comes to life?
She is your love. Go my son.
God be with you.
What a joke!
That rascal gave you these
bracelets, right?
Throw them.
- Throw them, dear.
- No! It is a memory of Vijay.
Vijay no!
That's forgotten history!
Rare station.
I do not see a single person.
We'll ask him.
How far is the mansion
Durjan Singh?
That's what I look?
Dude, where are you?
No. This can not be true!
I hope this is not the mansion
haunted.
The old fled on hearing the
name! Something is not right!
- Come on.
You fell in love, but the game
Love is very dangerous.
Unless you play with
you will enjoy the chance never
life with love.
Life is not a delicacy for
enjoy!
A people that bring me?
Here I do not see a single person!
You look in the lake?
Want to go fishing?
I feel like I've seen this
place before.
What do you say?
I know from childhood.
You were born between horses.
Something is not right here!
No. I've worked here.
Here they used to lift huge
rocks.
You're right sir.
People say that makes many
years by the rocks being raised
with camels.
Here, there are some market
bracelets?
There is a big market.
Art thou fallen from heaven, man?
Forget that. Tell me how
Bangles cost.
Why you should buy bracelets?
Show me that.
These golden bracelets.
These colorful.
Arjun!
I said?
I can not believe it! You are Arjun.
- Who is Arjun?
- The light of the eyes of this woman.
That was extinguished by a
bad man.
Your name was Arjun.
Listen to this name so many times.
I have seen this in my temple
dreams.
I can not understand anything.
What is all this?
Mother! This means ...
What have you done this miracle!
The impossible is born as
possible!
You are Arjun.
The blessing of the Goddess Kali.
The blessing requested in this
place by the mother.
's Mother?
The mother who?
Your mother.
My mother?
ARJUN!
My Arjun is back!
My son has returned!
Arjun!
MAMA!
I. ..
Where have you gone, leaving me alone?
Where have you gone my son?
I have shed many tears
in your pain.
There is no place or way in this
people ...
Where there is no ... searched by you.
You went too far?
What took you so long to come back?
Speak my son.
Ageing.
My eyes have weakened.
But my heart is not weakened.
He was sure he'd come back.
Definitely return to pay
debt of maternal love.
The Mother Goddess hear my
prayers.
And you came back!
My son!
No, my son. Do not cry baby.
Already cried enough for
us.
Do not cry.
Not brought Karan?
When will come the?
If returned Arjun, Karan also
will he, mama.
Ajay!
Do not cry.
I just sentenced to 6 months.
When I get out, I'll take care of
each of the Saxena family!
Where are you taking him?
A prison.
Ajay, the other day asked
who I was.
Today I bring not only my
presentation ..
But also ... yours.
You are Karan. And I'm Arjun.
We have reincarnated.
And our mother is still waiting
our return.
The sun gets tired and hides.
But the eyes of the mother
still searching for their children.
She is awake.
People die.
But faith never dies.
The impossible became ...
Possible .. in faith.
The dreams came true.
All and each of the
sentences are useful.
This bond of faith is such ...
.. We back together
everyone.
This bond is a bond of love.
It is the union of life after life.
It is the union ...
For a crowd met?
Someone fell off the horse?
Let me see.
Karan? Arjun?
Ready! The Thakur receive
its deserved!
The Thakur receive their
deserved!
He's finished!
Who should I give these
good news? Already!
We take liquor daily. We should
prove the beauty of the people?
If Nahar.
It's been weeks.
We hunt or animals or
women.
The caseria starts now
lords.
Are aimed to a cemetery,
wearing sneakers!
And I'm just looking!
Hey! What are you barking?
I bark. I am a dog.
But pcs. is a goat.
They will be slaughtered.
The owner is doomed!
What happens?
The drama will take place.
Both are back.
The owner is doomed!
- Who?
- The same.
- Karan and Arjun.
- Who are they?
Those who kill for years?
- Same Karan and Arjun?
- Yes!
- The dead are not revived.
- They do.
A miracle occurred.
I recommend you do the bags
and go on pilgrimage.
My heart beats faster!
The owner is doomed!
- I wonder if this ...
- Yes, Nahar.
If it is true what he says ...
Then we have to reach
their roots.
Let's see how the broken stick
old got together again.
Who are Karan and Arjun?
Look at these stones. Us
We used to work here.
What happens?
Why are you silent?
You were quiet when you saw
breast even before the
Village.
And even these are silent.
- This can not be true.
- It can not be true? That?
I do not think this story
reincarnation.
It's all rubbish.
Rubbish? All the people
I looked and I called Karan!
That's rubbish?
The heart of a mother you
and call you hug your child.
That's rubbish?
You could see the love behind
the tears of a mother?
That mother is lying?
His love is false?
Your wait for years is a
simulation?
But there may be born
like his son.
If that's true, that
stopped hitting me at the party?
What you said
'Run Arjun! Run '?
My name was Arjun
in my last life.
And you were Karan.
Us were children.
And a terrible injustice
he committed against her!
We were both killed.
And we returned to reincarnate.
Remember nothing, not even
now?
No. I do not remember anything.
Brothers! Shamsher Singh and Nahar
are bothering your mother!
Hear God commanded you support
you need for retirement?
Where are they?
Where are your children? Answer!
Answer elderly! Where are
Karan Arjun your and your?
Answer!
Elderly! To answer it or not?
Arjun!
The son of this mother
helpless ..
Has returned to ..
wipe her tears.
Son?
The same son who kill
years?
He is someone who looks
the son of this old hag.
I think it is a Cheat
city.
Sure did not hear the story
the death of their children.
If you'd heard ...
You .. you had not dared to
Pressing this town!
But now that he's here,
matesmoslo too!
ARJUN!
I'm there!
Son beat them! Do you know
my kids again!
Bailemos bhangada.
Come on, come on.
Tell me, tell me, where is
your heart?
My heart is where you are.
If you have your life,
not lose it.
While you live, do not
Stick with me.
Bailemos bhangada.
Come on, come on.
While living.
On the shore sounded the
anklets.
The river sing once more.
On the shore sounded the
anklets.
The river sing once more.
A smiles and wishes,
nobody can imprison.
Love shines in your eyes,
the heart becomes restless.
Everyone dances with abandon.
Bailemos bhangada.
Come on, come on.
Tell me, tell me, where is
your heart?
My heart is where you are.
If you have your life,
not lose it.
While you live, do not
Stick with me.
Bailemos bhangada.
Come on, come on.
That truth that can cut,
where a sword like that?
That can keep the love
imprisoned, where there is a
door so?
Let no one feel helplessness, which
no one is destroyed by pain.
Come on,
celebrate this happiness.
Bailemos bhangada.
Come on, come on.
Tell me, tell me, where is
your heart?
My heart is where you are.
If you have your life,
not lose it.
While you live, do not
Stick with me.
Fools! They became crazy
intoxicated.
They have gone to a world
illusions!
They say the Karan and Arjun
beat?
They Karan and Arjun
they went to hell?
Our eyes
they can not fool us.
We saw their faces! How could we
forget their faces?
If. You can forget when
someone hits them both!
Who are you arguing?
Who are Karan and Arjun?
Those who kill for years Saxena.
They say they have become.
And beat them ...!
How can it be? Impossible!
That's what I say.
You always retas my brothers.
Do not believe them at all.
- Shut up!
- Ask if they think the.
Why ask me what my?
If he does not believe them,
I would think that to me?
Right. Ask him to
villagers.
Villagers,
I ask them who are they?
Where are they?
Who dares to oppose me
and wait for their death?
Of the speaker, sir?
What a joke!
They do not know! I speak of those
two of my uncles beat them.
Who would dare
raise them a finger?
Hey, man!
Why do not you say that Karan and
Arjun beat us like dogs?
You make us look like liars
before our brother?
Why do not you say old man, who
Karan and Arjun beat us?
Where is the old Durga?
Durga is crazy!
that diambula by the people.
We have not seen in months.
So where did you see?
You die! One
girnalda decorate your photo!
Losing their cavity!
I myself saw.
They embraced Durga close
Hill.
Lord Karan and Arjun have
come to this town.
You not current. Today,
They got in trouble at all.
Tomorrow, the Ref
ud problems ...
Are there!
What a joke!
There's nobody there.
Hey! You're trying to scare us?
No, no ... I saw myself ...
I saw Karan and Arjun.
Ask him to his brothers
if you do not believe me.
- Not you see there?
- No.
- See them?
- No!
Haran kill me! Sometimes it
sometimes accept and deny.
Haran that hit me!
This is not an eggplant?
This is not a carrot?
This is not a radish?
If I can identify a
carrot and radish ...
Why could not do it
Karan and Arjun?
They were truly
Karan and Arjun.
Because you look around? I said
Karan and Arjun who were.
Who is this?
I'm talking, rogue. Yo!
But the voice comes
from the inside?
Tonto! The voice does not come from
in, but beneath you.
From under me? My voice comes
from above ...
I'm dead! Where I came
that earthquake?
From Latur!
Who are you? You scared me.
I am the one hiding and gives
know the truth. Your villager.
But ... I never saw you in the
people.
You call an eggplant one
carrot, and a carrot
one radish!
Implying that there is a
mistake in my eyes?
No. Your head tells you saw,
but your eyes say otherwise.
If. That is what is happening.
Listen to what your eyes tell you.
Karan and Arjun are in their
people. I saw them!
I have to give an answer
this beating by the owner.
Serious able to say this
before the owner?
Not only the owner,
I can say in front of everyone!
Even the terrible consequences
shame I will not have to talk to
the truth!
It is true what I said, I saw
Karan and Arjun.
- Then come with me!
- Where to?
You fixed a favorable date
Suraj for wedding and Sonia?
If. The auspicious date is three
days after 'Dasara'.
Created such a sensation ...
Marriage .. my son
would set an example .. a story.
- Bless you, sir.
- You're back again?
I receive for my honesty
and veracity?
Betel leaf. Eat it.
Lady, hit me very hard
front of all the people.
Also suit evidence.
Not just me, until the villager
has seen Karan and Arjun.
- That villager?
- Him ..
Blessings, landlord!
Get up! You saw?
See? I saw? Oh God!
Fed horses
strong and tall.
They were galloping. Black horses
white, good and bad!
Horse stables! Practice
shot in the stables!
Gomeras in the stables!
In the stables ...
As the bottles were breaking!
As white were
hit with the rubber!
As galloped Mogambo!
Mogambo was amazing, sir!
Why are you shouting?
He said it cost him
listen.
- When I say that?
- You did not say at the door?
You have not said what I brought you
here to say.
About Karan and Arjun ...
What did you say? Nothing!
Tell the Karan and Arjun on!
- Who are Karan and Arjun?
- Haras to kill me!
Haras it hit me! Hey, that ...
Karan and Arjun!
They looked so gallant, sir!
As they fought! They killed all
one by one!
Karan and Arjun are incredible!
- Where did you see?
- In television, sir.
I showed 'Mahabharata' in
TV. He told me to say ...
I saw ... Karan and Arjun,
She even gave me 100 rupees.
No!
No! No!
Lord ... he's ... lying!
- You came to tease me?
- No!
So if you play a joke
so ...
You will not be able to ... talk!
Go!
- Come on!
- My work is done!
I'm so close to you as your
own heartbeat.
At the first opportunity, you
I'm free and I will take away.
- Daughter!
- What are you doing?
I'll go crazy!
I saw with my own eyes.
You must be very happy.
Your children have returned to answer
Thakur's atrocities!
But villagers say
They have not returned.
You tell me if Karan and Arjun
have returned.
As children can be away
his mother after listening
call?
When a mother is tormented,
to heaven in strategic crisis.
Karan and Arjun are back.
Are there.
They are Karan and Arjun!
The same face! The same body!
The same eyes!
Thakur is dead!
If.
Spring returned to my
sad life.
Durjan Singh started this war.
But my children finished.
I am with you in this battle!
Check if everything is fine.
If Pope. They are the same weapons
you select.
That's his.
Take the truck to the warehouse.
And send it from there.
Be careful.
No mistakes this time.
Or suffer great losses.
This contains our profit
also, not just yours.
We have a participation in
this, like you. Do not worry.
- Go then.
- Because so much trouble?
First let me touch the band.
What a joke!
That band? The band who?
His band, and yours too.
It was your order.
Your organized a drinking party?
I made some fantastic arrangements
you ...!
Why do you have a veil
so long?
What did you feel
embarrassed?
Your friends tell you to say
quietly.
What did you do at night?
On the roof slept my brother ..
Slept with .. and thinking that
was you.
Forgive Ranji ..
.. For the mistake I made.
On the roof slept my brother ..
Slept with .. and thinking that
was you.
Forgive Ranji ..
.. For the mistake I made.
Your brother is your brother.
How is that not distinguished yourself
your husband?
He was covered with a blanket.
I thought it was my husband's bed.
He slept in a half
and in the other half.
Forgive Ranji ..
.. For the mistake I made.
There must have been a flame
lit.
The moonlight must have
Tugging on the roof.
You can not differentiate between
yours and strangers?
As you made this error?
I made a mistake but not a
great harm.
He and my husband have the same
height.
I was so tired of working
all day ...
As soon .. I slept I
fell asleep.
Forgive Ranji ..
.. For the mistake I made.
What we all thought ...
You did not do anything ...
We can see the truth in your face.
No difamaste your face for
overnight.
Where are the weapons?
Swallow is the land or
ate the sky?
I want to know how they disappeared
weapons truck.
The cost of over 10 million!
Who is responsible for this?
The bottle of wine is the
responsible.
They must have been
drunks lying like dogs!
By greed, we were deceived!
If you think I removed
money ...
Do not listen to the sound of
that money!
Hear the cries of the
death!
The shrieks of death!
I do not like anyone deceive me!
Tell me where are the weapons!
Or will cast shade
death on pc!
The Wall of Death!
I want weapons! Guns!
We were never so severely
insulted today.
If, Shamsher! We leave
this degradation clean!
But how?
Whatever the truth,
Karan and Arjun have something to do.
Both the saw.
Until we throw these two
dogs at the foot of brother ...
We will not see ... nor the surface
the truth ...
Neither brother will believe us.
But how did we get
Karan and Arjun?
There is only one way.
Mama! Mama!
Hey! He is the son of Usha.
Usha ... your son.
Son! He happened to my child?
Get up! What happened?
"If you do not send it to Karan and Arjun
the hill in an hour ...
Start sending the ...
body of each child here. "
I think Karan and Arjun not
received our letter.
We'll have to send another
letter. I understand?
Hey! Come here!
Yes, you!
Do not kill me! Do not kill me!
Run or shoot you!
Help!
Dress? Our hunters
came as our victims!
Kill these rascals!
No. No! First is the
show a brother.
And prove that you were right,
and the villagers lied.
- We came.
- Let the children.
Stand up!
Let the children.
Now take with brother.
Come on!
Why did you stop?
You garlands?
These are the garlands that
gave to the photo of their children.
These garlands stamp their
destination today.
Will turn into flowers
his coffin.
Flowers for our coffin?
Old! I think we should
read you the last rites ...
... Along with Karan and
Arjun.
Shamsher, start the jeep!
Run!
As?
These are the same weapons.
Thieves caught
with the riot.
They should have fought for the
loot and killed each other!
Make fed snakes!
Snakes? Call them pythons!
Someday they had swallowed
the mansion too!
They made a hole in my boat!
Good thing died the
bastards.
Or they had drowned and were
they had dragged with them!
- Police?
- Who called the police?
Yo.
These weapons worth millions.
And you called the police?
Think about it. If the landowner
I was caught with weapons ...
The police would have arrested
on, your child and you.
It would have been dangerous.
So the blame these two.
- Greetings, sir!
- Greetings!
It's good that we have
informed through your man.
Your brothers delivered the
illegal weapons.
If. Just listen to that.
They killed each other by
money and weapons.
Brought dishonor to the name
family.
Lady! The landowner is
doomed!
This is called kill two
birds with one stone!
Goods worth millions, Nahar
Shamsher and all doomed!
They are doomed ...!
Not only Nahar and Shamsher ...
Durjan Singh ... until no
would have been saved!
- Bindiya!
- Shut up!
Bindiya, give me a few grains.
Put more.
Mas.
- Hey, you!
- If?
Eating many grains. You were
a horse in your last life?
- What are you eating?
- Biscuits.
You were a dog in your last
life?
Eat beans! Come cookies.
Shamsher Nahar and are no longer.
When the rest ...?
When will be convicted?
Our hands are tied
while Sonia is his prisoner.
Sonia? Who is she?
Mama ...
She is your daughter.
My daughter in law?
Yes, and wants to make Durjan
his daughter.
No. At the mansion never
Wedding hear trumpets!
Only the death march!
Long live Mother Kaali.
If we have to take a life
or give our lives.
Offer a sacrifice.
Long live Mother Kaali,
the destroyer of evil.
Long live Mother Kaali.
If we have to take a life
or give our lives.
Offer a sacrifice.
Long live Mother Kaali,
the destroyer of evil.
Long live Mother Kaali.
When you're angry all the
world trembles.
When you're happy the sun shines.
Goddess of life, the flood.
Everything is in your hands, oh mother.
Long live Mother Kaali,
the destroyer of evil.
Long live Mother Kaali.
If we have to take a life
or give our lives.
Offer a sacrifice.
Long live Mother Kaali,
the destroyer of evil.
Long live Mother Kaali.
Who in this whole world ..
You can dare to raise
head against you ...
That head will be cut ...
.. Which is full of
arrogance.
Long live Mother Kaali,
the destroyer of evil.
Long live Mother Kaali.
If we have to take a life
or give our lives.
Offer a sacrifice.
Long live Mother Kaali,
the destroyer of evil.
Long live Mother Kaali.
Why do you look so scared?
I think I saw in the temple.
No! How can it be?
But ...
.. Who were they?
Who were they?
Papa, they are Ajay and Vijay.
Ajay and Vijay?
Who are Ajay and Vijay?
The same fools who were
in the temple, sir.
Those who thought they were Karan
Arjun and Ajay and Vijay are.
What nonsense, lady!
Two Ajay and Vijay two Karan and
Arjun. That makes four of them!
A coffin also need
4 shoulders! Be careful, sir!
Our stars indeed
appear to be unfavorable.
Weapons in millions
were encautadas.
Your brothers killed.
Now Ajay and Vijay.
Now there is another problem.
I want the plans
bodan stop for now.
Volvere to town with my daughter.
Stop the wedding?
What a joke!
Until yesterday, you were my companion
in profit or loss.
But now that we
you about, you are a partner
in joy and pain.
The wedding will not be postponed.
Will take place on the date
We decided!
- But ...
- If you wear reluctant ...
Not you, but your body will go to
town!
- Apologies?
- Yes, dear.
I am ashamed of my actions.
Fix your marriage with
wrong family.
A man threatens to
kill his friend ...
It is capable of anything.
So I can not bear to see
enter this hell!
Your Vijay has come.
Get away with.
If.
If dear.
I grew up with lots of love.
Do not cry my child.
I can not bear to see tears
in your eyes.
As anticipated wed help
escape from this house.
Where fleeing?
Stop or I'll shoot!
- But Daddy, you ...?
- Do not worry about me.
Run!
For me, run!
Brother!
A girl is screaming Vijay!
A girl?
Sonia? You and here?
Pope acceded to the light
our love.
He understood that my life would be
ruined that man.
The Bodyguard?
Papi?
See that? People use goats
to hunt tigers.
I use my daughter.
I did not think anyone in this
world was worse than me.
But I showed bastard
You can be at the right time.
That I became a slave to your
baseness.
Kill that rascal in such
so ...
God finished his ..
reincarnation system!
Go! Bring it!
When Arjun comes,
Karan also will come!
Kill him!
Where were those two?
Ahi!
Follow them!
- What happened?
- No one in the village.
- The town is abandoned.
- What?
- There's no one in town?
- No, the village is empty.
Villagers died?
They died before seeing the
flames of my anger?
Price, who gave shelter to
my enemies ...
I will not give them room to be
cremated!
His body rotted in the
way as stray dogs!
Where did everybody go?
Loons! Scoundrels!
Durjan!
What happens?
Durga!
I'm alive just to see you be
so tortured.
Play with blood! Today'll see ...
whose blood will be shed
body and who will fall!
As you can kill me?
Death to about
head!
The pattern is doomed!
- Rogue!
- Shoot!
Them!
Close the door!
Here come!
Drop!
Shot.
Rogue! Rufian!
How did that happen?
Son! He happened to my son?
What happened son?
My son!
Karan and Arjun killed my son!
They killed my son!
Saxena, Saxena.
Those ruffians killed your son.
They killed the husband of Sonia!
They turned off the lamp
of our family!
Controlate.
What are you doing?
PAPI!
Dress? I'm in my right mind!
There is no better way to catch
the murderers of my son!
My son died for you!
And now these two ruffians
will die because of you!
For you! For you!
These thugs will die for you!
Slowly walk towards me.
Do not get ready! Come on!
Hag!
Death is not in my head!
Instead, I am facing
to as the Death!
Save me!
Karan and Arjun killed me!
Perdoname.
This is your wreath
gave me.
Pierced my heart like a
spine until today.
Today will cast the same
wreath over your dead body.
And then I'll be alone.
And your sins were completed.
Karan and Arjun ...
Kill it ...!
I translated and synchronized subtitle
by viggo_sanlorenzo @
viggo_sanlorenzo@hotmail.com
When the sun is far
the sky?
When the moon is far from
its rays?
When the fragrance is far
Wind?
When spring is far
the yard?
This bond is a bond of love.
It is the union of life after life.