I am Ghost Agent K.
A shadow without a name or reputation.
Now, the wood carving mission is over.
Ghost.
Disappear.
Chairman Byung-do Mo's slush fund
is worth a trillion won.
Let's finish this up.
The tapes were sent.
The path is in the Word.
Found it.
EPISODE 13
Why have you come here?
Something this dangerous doesn't suit you.
If I were going to kill you,
there are more silent ways than this.
If you aren't here for revenge,
then what do you want?
A deal.
I will be your black ops agent.
A black ops agent?
I'm sorry, but I refuse any illegal deals.
Illegal and legal.
I'll decide on the method,
as long as the payment
for the result is guaranteed.
You must have been misinformed,
but I am cooperating with the NIS
to clean up our dark past
filled with slush funds and illegal deals.
Mr. Jang could never become
one of your people.
The fact that I'm alive is proof of that.
So, Congressman Baek's tapes were missing
from Chairman Mo's secret storage room?
It looks like your war against
Congressman Baek has begun.
Mr. Jang isn't an adequate weapon
in a dark fight where there are no rules.
Are you?
I'm a little expensive,
but I earn every penny.
Test Mr. Jang.
I showed up alive instead of disappearing.
See what he does with me.
Seung-jae Mo.
He clenched his jaw when I mentioned
the war against Congressman Baek,
so Seung-jae Mo doesn't have
the missing tapes
on Congressman Baek either.
According to the clue Agent Yoon left,
it's somewhere on the 58th floor
of the Songsan building.
It wasn't in Seung-jae Mo's office.
So it isn't in his office.
Where is it then?
There's one person who knows for sure.
If we profile him,
we'll find a clue as to where it's hidden.
Who?
Who else?
It's naturally the person who hid them.
Chairman Byung-do Mo.
He's dead.
If we look carefully
at what he left behind and didn't,
we can profile him.
It won't be easy.
There are perks.
The dead don't lie.
You approached Seung-jae Mo
in order to profile Chairman Mo.
Because the most critical hint
that Chairman Mo left behind...
is Seung-jae Mo.
Un-gwang's bodyguard is still alive.
I liked how thorough you were.
I'm disappointed.
I'll take care of it.
What about the missing tapes
on Congressman Baek?
We haven't found any leads yet.
That's not what I wanted to hear either.
The Prosecutor's Office and the NIS
are investigating the Baek Infantry.
If you want to wage a war
against Congressman Baek,
you should have conclusive evidence
to put an end to him!
I swear to you.
I will take down Congressman Baek
and the Baek Infantry.
Trust me and wait.
"Find the missing tapes
of Congressman Baek.
The traitor knows your weakness. Agent Y."
Agent Y?
But Robert Yoon is dead.
I think someone else sent it.
Who?
A few people come to mind.
Dong-hyun is looking into it.
What about the weakness
that was mentioned in the text message?
Is that your weakness?
Yes.
That's why if I stop here,
everyone will be in danger.
With Mr. Jang's Plan B,
we can't finish off Congressman Baek
or Seung-jae Mo.
So?
Will you continue with your mission?
I will return to work tomorrow.
I need to return to my cover
as your bodyguard for the mission.
You said the man who shot you
told you to disappear.
Living as Seol-woo Kim, the bodyguard,
rather than an NIS agent
is the complete disappearance
that I chose.
This mission is a two-fold one.
The only people who know about it
are Dong-hyun
and you.
Only me?
Doesn't Do-ha know?
I don't want to worry her.
What about me?
Is it okay for me to worry?
You and I promised
not to keep secrets from each other.
That's true,
since we are brothers.
What about the other promise?
Once the mission is complete,
I will discuss my retirement from the NIS
with you.
Good.
Okay.
I will help with your two-fold mission.
Thank you.
But you know, what about
the $5,000,000...
Do-ha.
Un-gwang, I'm here.
Oh.
Seol-woo, you're here.
Yes.
Here.
Hi.
Are you going back to work tomorrow?
Are you feeling all better?
Don't you need to rest more?
Are you on another mission?
Take a breath.
Ask one question at a time.
Is your wound fully healed?
Yes.
I can move without any problem.
You can rest a few more days.
I still have duties to attend to.
I was told to disappear,
so I should live
as Un-gwang's bodyguard for a while.
I can't get involved myself,
so Dong-hyun will do the hard stuff.
All I'll be doing until the $5,000,000
has been settled
is to keep doing
the lovers tactic with you.
That's all.
Is that really all?
Rest assured.
This mission is like a vacation to me.
NOLBOO RESTAURANT
I'm officially taking a day off today.
Okay. Sure. Go ahead.
But is there an international
soccer match or something?
It's much more important
than the World Cup.
What is it?
I need to make the right connections
before it's too late
and make money for Do-ha's wedding.
How?
Congressman Baek...
Save the country in times of chaos,
and get myself a job.
Good day.
Sir...
His ratings have gone up 5%
and is currently at 26.7%.
He is now in third place.
His ratings are low among
people in their 20s and 30s,
but he's leading among people
in their 50s and above.
The survey was conducted among
the residents of Seoul aged 19 and above.
We should've ended him for good.
If only the tapes on him
were in the storage room.
Aren't we at an advantage already
with the tapes on the Baek Infantry?
I'm not sure.
I wonder if I can fight
Congressman Baek with just Mr. Jang.
Something just feels wrong.
I feel like I was used in their reforming
of the NIS and purging of Baek Infantry.
You gave him a chance,
so trust him a little more.
I should, for now.
Test Mr. Jang.
I showed up alive instead of disappearing.
See what he does with me.
Guard Kim.
This coffee is...
made from the same beans
as Jongro Coffee from Jongro, and...
I truly think Do-ha is lucky
to have met you.
That kind of luck will never
come to her again.
Also, you're too good for...
As long as it isn't poisoned.
I respect you.
Weren't you on vacation?
I'm back as of today.
Hey.
I came to see Congressman Baek,
the first suspect
for impersonating Agent Y.
He's putting on such a show.
I sincerely apologize
to everyone across the country
for my people
being involved in the Songsan-gate.
This is wrong!
No! This is wrong!
This is unfair!
Congressman Baek is innocent!
Okay.
Thank you, but I'm doing an interview.
Congressman, be strong.
I love you.
- I introduced myself before...
- Please leave.
No! That's not it!
Congressman, I will join you
with vigor and the loudest voice!
Okay. Sign him up for my campaign.
Double his pay.
- Yes, sir.
- Wait...
I love you.
I love you, In-soo Baek!
- Let's go register.
- Okay.
I apologize for that. Let's start over.
I apologize to our great citizens
from the bottom of my heart.
Then, lift your pants.
I will whip you for you.
What are you doing here?
I sent you a summons so that we can
talk in the warm Prosecutor's Office.
What are you doing on the cold street?
If you're upset, just give your statement
at the Prosecutor's Office.
I'm the one who is upset.
Everyone, why must I go
to the Prosecutor's Office?
The people close to you said otherwise.
The Baek Infantry fellows
have zero loyalty, you know.
Don't give me false testimonies like that.
Bring me the solid evidence.
I need solid evidence!
I heard you didn't even find tapes on me
in Chairman Mo's storage room.
Didn't you think
that I would find it soon,
Agent Y?
Look, I don't know what you're up to,
but if you found them,
you would've brought an arrest warrant.
You're so quick.
Stop being crafty, and leave.
He's interfering with my campaign.
Can a prosecutor do this?
Okay. I'll see you again.
Good luck.
Take care.
Okay. Let's do it again.
There are several clues in this message
that help us identify the sender.
What clues?
The first sentence.
"Find the missing tapes
of Congressman Baek."
It must be someone who wants
the tapes of Congressman Baek.
Also, someone who knows
that they are missing.
Yes.
The second sentence.
"The traitor knows your weakness."
It's someone who knows you.
Also, the person knows who the traitor is.
But why did this person
impersonate Agent Y, who is already dead?
"If you're curious, come to me."
That's what it must mean.
My phone number.
Here. I'll enter the number.
Myung-suk Cha. Thank you.
It's me.
There's another person who meets
the criteria of that fake Agent Y.
UN-GWANG'S FAN SIGNING EVENT
- I love you.
- Un-gwang!
I love you.
Here.
Un-gwang!
- May I get a picture?
- Sure.
The worst there is.
- Thank you.
- I love you!
UN-GWANG'S FAN SIGNING EVENT
Un-gwang!
I need to go somewhere tonight.
Is it dangerous? Should I go with you?
It's okay.
Okay.
I have nothing special tonight,
so you may go after this is over.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
Look here!
- Un-gwang!
- Here!
Un-gwang!
I need to step away for a moment.
Who is that?
It's him.
Our side's traitor. The jerk who shot you?
Yes.
That jerk. How dare he come here?
Should I teach him a lesson?
I'll be back.
What are you trying to pull?
Who are you?
I'm Un-gwang Yeo's bodyguard,
Seol-woo Kim.
Don't you understand
what the missed gunshot means?
Ghost Agent K is dead.
Then, why are you back?
If you were going to throw me away,
you should've gotten rid of me for good.
I gave you a chance to live quietly.
So?
Should I thank you?
Are you going to let
your personal feelings ruin the mission?
What mission?
Let me make this clear.
Ghost Agent K is dead and gone.
You won't regret that decision, right?
Regret is what I see on your face.
If you stand in my way,
I'll have to change my decision as well.
I won't take it twice.
Okay, then.
I'm on duty, so...
Mr. Jang?
You must be Mr. Jang.
What are you doing?
What are you doing, Mr. Jang,
senior manager of NIS?
Are you illegally surveilling
our bodyguard?
Where are you going? I want to talk.
What's your problem?
Goodness, he isn't listening.
Goodness. Hey!
I got your license plate number too.
Don't you dare show up again.
I'll just...
What are you doing?
That's Mr. Jang, right?
I said, "Mr. Jang!"
Then he turned around,
so I totally got him.
But why did he show up?
He wouldn't make you do a mission
after what he did to you, would he?
- I ended it for good.
- That's good.
DELETE
Why are you deleting them?
We need evidence in case...
If you really care for me,
don't do something reckless
like this again.
It's none of your business.
Unbelievable.
They are so pathetic.
So?
Have you been avoiding getting arrested?
Yes, sir.
No one followed me.
Here's some spending money.
Thank you.
We'll have to move quietly.
I need to start the war against Songsan.
Bring someone for me.
We named the foundation for your son
as Future Songsan Scholarship Foundation.
For Jae-young?
We have to prepare for his future.
Songsan's future is Jae-young's future.
You have to prepare his inheritance now.
We will also donate 20% of Songsan
Holdings' stock to the foundation.
The experts took care
of the complicated stuff.
I would like you to be
the foundation's chairperson.
I've never done things like that before.
Whom else could I trust
to handle Jae-young's matter?
So, tomorrow's campaign event
is at 7 a.m.?
At the subway station,
during the rush hour?
Okay.
Sure. I won't be late.
See you in the morning.
For the nation!
Freeze!
Who are you and why are you following me?
I'm Dong-hyun Lee, the prosecutor.
Hello, Mr. Myung-suk Cha.
Mr. Lee?
Have you eaten?
Are you saying the one
framing me for Robert Yoon's murder
is Congressman Baek? Are you sure?
Keep it down.
Congressman Baek is the one
who hired the hitman to kill Robert Yoon.
Then arrest him and lock him up!
So don't go around
wearing things like that.
- What?
- Are you a janitor or something?
I'm so pissed off! That asshole!
That rat!
You scum!
Keep a distance from him.
Don't go anywhere near him.
One bad move,
and your innocent daughter
will suffer again.
My daughter?
Did that jerk do something to my daughter?
No.
I mean...
If the dad keeps going to jail,
the family will definitely suffer.
Think about it.
- That's right.
- That's right, so...
How shall I help you?
What is this?
A bag.
I know it's a bag.
Is this part of the lovers tactic?
Is there a special mechanism in here?
I already have a GPS tracker.
So is it a hidden camera? Or a microphone?
If I press this, will a video
be transmitted somewhere?
A spy bag?
It's just...
a pretty, ordinary bag.
It's a gift.
A gift?
I'm sorry for getting angry.
For what happened earlier?
I understand.
You can be sensitive during a mission.
What happened earlier was nothing,
so you just continue performing your duty.
My duty?
Carry the bag
and keep being the pretty you.
Do it as my girlfriend.
Hey. I met with Congressman Baek, and...
- Guard Kim isn't back yet?
- No.
But how did you know about this place?
This is our hideout. But why are you...
You're here for the mission.
The two-fold mission.
How did you know...
Brother and I have no secrets.
I wanted to have chicken
and beer with him.
I guess he'll be back late.
Yes, I guess so.
Chicken should be eaten
before it gets cold.
What do you say?
How about a drumstick and...
- Okay?
- Well,
I am always in.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Come this way.
Mr. Jang went to see you?
However, I'm still alive.
Mr. Jang has no intention of killing me.
So he wasn't on my side after all,
but with the NIS.
A person's nature doesn't change.
Even with menacing antlers,
a deer is still a deer,
and a hunter is a hunter.
Also, are you a hunter?
Whatever.
More like the side that eats,
not get eaten.
How can I know you won't betray me then?
How can I trust you?
You should not.
Since when do you need trust in a deal?
What will you offer me?
Yesterday's ally has become
today's most threatening enemy.
I'll get rid of Congressman Baek for good.
Why would a toothless fox be threatening?
If you want to make a deal,
call me before it's too late.
I can become anyone's shadow,
not just yours.
You drink so well, Mr. Lee.
- Have some.
- Okay.
So that's what happened
during the Black Auction mission.
It's $5,000,000.
That was amazing. You made
an incredible bet of $5,000,000.
That goes without saying. It was awesome.
You're extraordinary. That was great.
You're a real man.
While performing the mission,
I realized that I was born to be a spy.
I can fight. My acting skills
make me a top Hollywood star.
I have fast reflexes
and can make quick judgments.
Also, above all else,
I have the key criterion of a spy.
Good looks.
Pardon?
Maybe I should retire from acting
and give my remaining days to the country.
- No.
- Why not? You said I'm extraordinary.
Secret agents working in the shadows
get called a lot of names.
Come on. You must not know me.
I've heard people call me
an evil jerk all my life.
That doesn't even compare.
We have to even shoot a colleague
if that's part of a mission.
Is my brother like that too?
He's outstanding.
He's someone
you must not meet as an enemy.
His eyes usually look emotionless
unless he's on a mission
or playing video games.
But something seemed different
during this mission.
The kid that I knew
would've gotten payback
for being shot and disappeared
without a trace.
But rather than revenge,
he's saying he will fulfill his duty.
How odd.
Is it because of his weakness?
It could be.
I think so.
To a secret agent, the people he is
surrounded by could serve as a weakness.
Don't worry about it.
He always takes care of it.
Father Michael asked me
to give this to you when he left.
He asked me to do so if you return.
You probably came looking for me
because you wanted to ask something,
but I have no more wisdom
to share with you.
But I must warn you.
You shouldn't touch the item
that led Agent Y to his death.
It is far beyond what you imagine.
The darkest shadow's abyss.
Disappear while you can.
Don't trust anyone.
Cheers.
He has good taste in bags.
You're right.
You were half dead when you broke up.
Are you happy you're back together?
Yes, I am.
I'm so happy.
Then why do you look like that?
When I do think about it,
it's so good and I'm happy,
but when we're together,
he sometimes seems estranged
and scary.
He changes when you're alone with him?
Is he mean to you?
No.
I know it's because
he cares so much for me, but...
at times, he seems cold.
That's how real-life relationships are.
You don't understand everything
just because you love the person.
Is this how all love is?
After some time,
you'll wonder why you ever felt that way.
That's love.
When time passes,
would I wonder why I ever felt this way?
So enjoy it while you can.
Why is your mind so complicated
all of a sudden?
Okay. What's the point in worrying?
I should be as happy as I can be
while he's with me.
Because love is a happy thing.
Yes. But don't do anything stupid.
He's pretty affectionate.
I'm so jealous.
He's a good fighter.
That's not something to brag about.
No.
He has to be.
He does.
So, Father Michael disappeared.
Based on his letter,
I don't think he was the one
impersonating Agent Y.
I mentioned Agent Y
and tested Congressman Baek,
and it wasn't him either.
Agent Y?
I don't think Congressman Baek
would do something this complicated.
Who was the other suspect?
Myung-suk Cha.
- Do-ha's dad?
- Yes.
Since he worked with Robert Yoon,
I thought he could be, and I followed him.
Then?
It wasn't him.
Freeze.
I'm so pissed off. That rat.
He didn't even know
Congressman Baek framed him.
So it's none of the suspects
that we thought of.
What about Seung-jae Mo?
I threw him another bait,
so he'll nibble on it soon.
Go home for today.
What will you do about him?
Seriously.
Let him be. I'll wake him in the morning.
Will you let him sleep here?
Then what? Should I carry that big mass?
You go home.
He's such a nuisance.
Goodness. Sorry, I'm late.
Director Park of Songsan Group.
You know who I am, don't you?
Candidate number one, In-soo Baek.
I do.
But why am I...
I looked into your past activities,
and all the money you took under the table
while working
as Songsan's Director of Finance
was enough to buy a skyscraper.
Are you threatening me?
Exactly. You're smart.
Speak humbly and lower your eyes, asshole.
Did the late Chairman Mo keep
his video tapes anywhere else?
I...
I don't know.
You had been maintaining
his slush fund the entire time.
I handled the accounting,
but I really don't know anything else.
Also, did you continue to maintain
the slush fund after Seung-jae took over?
Yes.
Good. In that case, let's do this.
As a way of repenting
for your past wrongs,
why don't you make a public confession?
We'll make sure
that the scholarship foundation
provides opportunities
for underprivileged youths.
I'm here to tell the truth
about the recent Songsan-gate.
She'll run this foundation
with a motherly approach.
I'm Mi-eun Song and I'll be running the
Future Songsan Scholarship Foundation.
The slush fund was continued to be funded
through accounting fraud
even under the control of its CEO,
Seung-jae Mo.
Mr. Joon-won Park,
our Good Samaritan informant,
will submit himself
to the prosecutor tomorrow
and submit all the documentation.
I request that Seung-jae Mo,
the core of the slush fund,
be thoroughly investigated.
FUTURE SONGSAN SCHOLARSHIP FOUNDATION
What were you doing?
- How did you let this happen?
- I'm sorry, sir.
Bribe, threaten,
do whatever it takes to stop it!
I'll take care of it.
What happened?
Congressman Baek stabbed me in the back.
You should calm yourself.
Call the NIS,
and bring me that rat, Joon-won Park.
Do anything and everything necessary
to resolve this quickly.
Let's make a deal.
I'm sure you know what I need.
What do you want?
I need $5,000,000.
Okay.
Make sure you have results.
Who was that?
Dong-hyun wants to meet.
There's nothing left to do today,
so I'm going to leave early.
- Sure.
- Call me later.
It's been a while.
Are we on the same team again?
No?
Are you still working on a mission?
If you have nothing to say, I'll go now.
Here's a piece of advice.
If you've decided to join our side,
get your head on straight.
Now, it's live or die,
protect or lose, that is all.
Don't rule out any method and fix
the Congressman Baek problem.
Is everything okay
with the filming venues?
Everything is fine.
But then, I can't forget that cathedral
we went to the other day.
It isn't fit for the ending scene,
but it may fit the wedding scene.
A wedding at a cathedral?
Why? It sounds good to me.
I love it.
I should pick out a new wedding dress.
Something elegant and refined.
- Make your acting like that too.
- Why you...
Annam Cathedral is nice.
You know it too?
- Is that the cathedral you mentioned?
- Yes.
I know it very well. I went every week
when I was Mi-eun's manager.
Mi-eun went to that cathedral?
Yes.
But she never went there on Sundays,
but only on Mondays.
She said it was nice to pray
when it was empty.
It has a nice feel to it.
Seung-jae Mo
Seung-jae Mo called.
He must be pissed off
about what happened today.
He took the bait, so it's time to move.
What will you do?
Congressman Baek is the target right now.
He started the fight
using conspiracies and sabotage.
We can't be too gentle on them, can we?
Director Park.
We're with NIS.
Stop them.
This is official business. Step aside.
- You can't go.
- We'll arrest you for obstruction. Move!
Move.
Arrest them all!
It's Park.
The NIS agents showed up,
as you said they would,
but I got away.
Okay, good.
I should be there on time by 10 a.m.
Good. When you get to the Prosecutor's
Office, Prosecutor Park is one of ours.
Just answer his questions honestly.
I will.
The Prosecutor's Office is the other way.
Stay quiet.
If you do anything stupid,
the car will depreciate.
If you're with neither Congressman Baek
nor the NIS,
whom are you with and who are you?
Relax.
PROSECUTOR DONG-HYUN LEE
I'm a prosecutor.
I see. The prosecutor.
- But I was on my way to see you...
- Yes.
Park is Congressman Baek's dog
dressed as a prosecutor.
Are those the documents on Seung-jae Mo's
involvement with the slush fund?
Yes.
- Here.
- Let's see.
Let me ask you a few questions.
During Chairman Mo's era,
you managed the slush fund
and were close to him, correct?
Yes.
The details on the slush fund
are in those documents...
By chance...
Have you ever seen
something like a secret safe
on the 58th floor of the Songsan building?
Pardon?
I heard
there's a secret room on the 58th floor
where bribes are exchanged.
We don't have to meet like this anymore.
What have you been up to?
Did you kidnap Songsan's finance director?
I don't know.
A skilled Ghost agent doesn't leave
a trail like somebody.
Did you make a deal with Seung-jae Mo?
You weren't going to hand over
the director, were you?
You were going to protect him
before Seung-jae Mo could get to him,
- right?
- The NIS doesn't abduct civilians.
It's as predicted. How boring.
You really aren't cut out for this.
So?
What have you been doing?
Revenge?
You know how I work and complete missions.
Are you working on a mission?
- In-soo Baek.
Clean politics, transparent society.
Candidate number one. Please remember.
Candidate number one...
- In-soo Baek.
- Vote for In-soo Baek.
You...
It's been a while.
I'm not happy to see you though.
You were alive. You're like a cockroach.
I have too many grudges to die so soon.
Are you threatening me?
Take a look at your gift...
and withdraw quietly.
NUMBER ONE CANDIDATE
IN-SOO BAEK
Please vote for In-soo Baek.
- In-soo Baek.
I gave it to him.
Seung-jae Mo never ordered me
to maintain the slush fund.
You confessed to the public.
Now, you're denying it?
That's correct.
Robert Yoon is the NIS' mole.
Get rid of him tonight.
Should I kill him?
Also, make sure he can't be found.
Shit!
Shit.
I have decided
to take responsibility
for the recent corruption scandal
and withdraw from the mayoral election,
as well as retire
from politics completely.
You took care of things with spirit.
Good job.
Here are the ledgers.
You didn't make copies, did you?
Will you believe me if I say I didn't?
SONGSAN BORROWED ACCOUNTS LIST
You said deals are made on money,
not trust, correct?
Here's the $5,000,000.
Are you going to take that and disappear?
As long as the payment is right,
you can call me whenever you need me.
Okay, then.
The three of them were originally a team.
The other one must be lonely.
By the way, Un-gwang...
Seol-woo is working
on a mission, isn't he?
What?
No. I haven't heard anything.
I'm not stupid.
I have my hunch.
He's hiding it from me
in case I would worry, right?
That idiot. Like I wouldn't figure it out.
Weakness.
To a secret agent, the people he is
surrounded by could serve as a weakness.
Pretend not to know,
so that he doesn't worry.
He's a skilled secret agent,
so he'll take care of it.
Will you leave or stay
once the mission is complete?
Once the mission is complete,
I will discuss my retirement from the NIS
with you.
Stay with me
as my family,
and as my brother.
Are we continuing the lovers tactic?
Should I disappear as Mr. Jang said?
Where to?
Just...
to an average life.
Now,
you must choose too.
Seol-woo.
We decided to shoot the wedding scene
at Annam Cathedral.
I see.
Okay.
But you know,
Mi-eun went to Annam Cathedral
every Monday as well.
Isn't that kind of suspicious?
It is.
Yes! I win again!
Sorry, but I won again.
One more game.
Again? Do you want to lose again?
You've lost plenty already.
Enough to stop losing.
I went easy on you.
I'm too much of a gentleman
to hit a woman.
Such a gentleman, I am.
Really?
I believe you.
It's awkward if you believe
that a joke is the truth.
I'll believe your lies too.
When I'm with you, I want to be happy
regardless of anything.
Because we're doing the lovers tactic.
One more game?
One more.
I'll use him.
I don't hear from you for days,
then suddenly, it's "I miss you. Hurry."
What do you think you're doing?
I'm sorry I couldn't contact you.
It concerns national security,
so I can't say why.
Things must not have gone well.
Do you always drink to get over it?
- Will you...
- I can't drink soju.
Is it like this after marriage too?
Pardon?
I heard some women never find out
that their husbands are NIS agents.
I guess I should get used to this.
I can't drink soju.
But I'll stay with you.
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
I resign as of today.
What do you mean?
I am not qualified to be a civil servant,
let alone an NIS agent.
What nonsense is that?
Are you someone so irresponsible
that you would quit during a mission?
The mission will be completed
perfectly without me.
Ghost Agent K is on it.
Thank you for everything.
About that secret room on the 58th floor
where you made a deal with Seung-jae Mo,
I think there is definitely
something there.
The late Chairman Mo designed
the 58th floor himself,
so no one knows the exact layout.
He may have designed it,
but someone else
had to have constructed it.
I had the same thought,
so I looked into it.
But he died in a car accident.
It is extremely suspicious.
If it is the Lord's will,
He will lead you to the right path.
The path is in the Word.
"Then war broke out in heaven.
Michael and his angels
fought against the dragon."
Did you see Agent Y again, Father?
He said what was found was not everything.
"For God does speak - now one way,"
now another,
"though no one perceives it."
So, the answer is in the 58th floor.
VIP LOUNGE
It must be somewhere there.
I stopped by the office.
Jae-young...
I'll be home before Jae-young goes to bed.
Okay.
You.
I'm Un-gwang Yeo's bodyguard,
Seol-woo Kim.
Mr. Jang planted me there through you,
so you know I'm an NIS agent.
What are you doing here?
I'm searching for the missing tapes
of Chairman Baek as Agent Y instructed.
Pardon?
Wasn't it your orders,
Ms. Mi-eun Song?
No.
Fellow Ghost agent.
Why did you call me out?
We must find the missing tapes.
Whose side are you on?
Something the late Chairman Mo left
only to Seung-jae Mo.
Found it.
A little mouse sneaked in.
We will terminate the lovers tactic.
Tonight,
every mission will be terminated.
Just kill him on sight!