P.A.:
Attention all drivers to the grid!
All drivers, please form
into your last position.
Vic Davies:
Keep your eye on the starter.
When it goes green,
make your move!
It is race day
here at speedport...
Rodney Wells with the buff
and Kyle...
Next up, a young fireball,
watts Davies...
Vic: Come on, watts!
Oh, we've got big trouble
at turn three!
As they come off the corner,
they're wheel to wheel!
( Garbled radio transmission )
Girl: See anything?
Go!
♪ We're falling down
from a gray cloud ♪
♪ open wounds still bleeding ♪
♪ yesterday
will forget my name ♪
♪ tomorrow
will never forgive me ♪
♪ I never felt that
I want too much ♪
♪ I never said that
I need too much ♪
♪ but with the lack
of the strength I need ♪
♪ there I was almost giving up ♪
♪ then I saw beautiful ♪
♪ and it opened up my eyes ♪
♪ when I found beautiful ♪
♪ it opened up my life ♪
♪ now I know beautiful ♪
♪ and how things should be ♪
♪ you are my beautiful ♪
♪ beautiful to me... ♪
Hey!
Watts, talk to me.
Where you at, man?
About ten blocks
from the school.
You should be able
to see me now.
Radio: Unit 7. Street racers.
♪ Laying down on a quiet night ♪
♪ hoping that no one
will find me ♪
♪ I never thought
I could feel so low ♪
♪ definition of empty...♪
they reached it!
Rodney Wells just passed
watts Davis!
♪ I always knew that
I felt too much ♪
I cared too much ♪
♪ but at the edge
down upon my knees ♪
♪ there I was almost giving up ♪
♪ then I saw beautiful ♪
♪ and it opened up my eyes ♪
See ya!
♪ When I found beautiful ♪
♪ it opened up my life ♪
♪ now I know beautiful ♪
♪ and how things should be ♪
♪ you are my beautiful ♪
♪ beautiful to me... ♪
Aah!
Oh, my God!
Whoa! Watts!
( Screaming )
Come on! Whoa!
♪ Now I know beautiful ♪
( Crashing )
♪ How things should be
you are my beautiful ♪
♪ beautiful to me ♪
♪ you are so beautiful... ♪
( Screaming )
( Cheering )
Whoa...!
Well, look what we've got here.
Hey, light bulb,
how's the surf?
Bink: No fair, Wells.
You broke the rules!
Ted: Who's this kid?
The rules is
there ain't no rules.
Let's go, guys.
Leave this loser to the cops.
We're outta here!
Drowned rat.
( Sirens )
Dahlia: Don't I get
like a free phone call or something?
Dahlia, you sit down
and keep your mouth shut
until deputy west
gets off the phone.
Randall?
Here you go.
Thanks.
( Door closes )
Dad...
Yeah?
( Door closes )
Been seeing you in here
a lot lately.
( Sighs )
What's he done now?
You're that kid
they call light bulb.
Right?
Why do they call you that?
'Cause they're ignorant.
Nah, really?
My name is watts.
You get it? Watts?
Light bulb.
Who'd you murder
to get in here?
Caused a few Fender benders,
destroyed public property,
afflicted bodily harm
on a number of citizens,
including one bride
who was disrobed
in front of
St. Tristan's church.
It wasn't my fault.
You're going to have to
come up with something
a bit more original
than that, watts.
Me? I'm guilty as sin.
I, uh, threw a burn on the iga.
A tag.
A bomb?
Graffiti?
You heard of it?
Vic, God knows,
we tore up this town
when we were kids, but...
This is the third time
in the past few months
he's been in here.
Is everything... you know,
okay with you guys?
Yeah, I mean, we have
our moments, but...
He's a kid, Jenna.
What do you do with a kid,
you know?
Hmm...
Jenna: We're gonna have to
put watts on warning.
And the next time it'll be
judge Wallace's call, not mine.
Thanks.
Let's go, hotshot.
Dahlia.
Go get cleaned up for dinner.
Don't you wanna know
what happened?
I know what happened.
I raised
a juvenile delinquent for a son.
You want beef or chicken?
I'm not hungry.
And how do you throw a kart
into a pool?
( Sighs )
( Rock music playing )
( Rock music continues )
Right.
( Laser blasts )
Bink: Come on!
Look out, jarrett.
I'm going to tattoo 88 all over turn 4!
Come on, Gordon, let's go.
Hey, no fair!
He's gonna nail you, man.
Give it up.
You can't beat Gordon.
Come on, Gordon, let's go.
( Tires squealing )
Told you.
I had him in the last lap.
Hey, light bulb.
Time to get some scuba lessons.
Boy: Hey, that's a good one!
Toomey: Zee!
Hello, zee?
We want our money back.
That thing's rigged.
Look, man,
if Bobby labonte or jarrett
or if any of those
other nascar dudes
can't get over on Gordon,
what makes you think
that you can? Huh?
How many people
have actually beaten Gordon?
Nobody that's walked
into this little waffle house.
Then what good is it then?
What good is it?
I'll tell ya what good it is.
The good is that
no little freaky, little private school boy
with a little
squared-off haircut
and a winnie-the-poo knapsack
is gonna walk onto
my virtual machine,
stand toe-to-toe
and go head-to-head
with the best of the best.
Oh, no. This time
it's gonna take skill.
This time it's gonna take
coordination!
a message from God...
Things that are probably
way past you freaks
on your little burnt out
Nintendo ride to choo-choo ville, isn't it?
The cat that tames
that wild beast,
he's goin' downtown
on a ham sandwich,
and he ain't puttin'
any mustard on it.
The dude that wins that game...
You grab onto his tailpipes
because that dude
is destined for greatness.
That's the good.
That...
And that that games brings in,
you know, $3,000 a month.
$5,000 in the summer.
Come on, give me a potato.
You missed.
Uhh!
Aren't you a picture
of radiant joy?
What's up?
Are you lost?
Community service.
I'm collecting money
for new computers in the library.
Give me a buck.
You're not gonna beat
Rodney Wells with something
that's held together
with double bubble.
And what would
you know about it?
I hear things.
Thank you.
Um... hey.
Keep out? Is this where you've
got all the bodies buried?
It's my dad's old shop.
What kind of shop?
He used to build engines...
For nascar...
You heard of it?
He win anything?
You wanna see it?
Hey...
Looks like you.
He used to race
before I was born.
Okay, I'm impressed.
That's him when he won
nascar engine builder of the year.
Is that your mom?
Where is she now?
Cancer.
She's pretty.
Whoa!
Big block 350.
Turns the quarter in 7 flat.
Ever drive it?
No.
Why not?
I didn't want to die.
( Chuckles )
Don't touch that.
Let me see it.
"The Davies comet."
A two-stroke kart engine
that was better than anything out there.
My dad designed it.
He and my mom built it
together.
She was really good
with engines.
A chick mechanic.
Now, that's cool.
They made a good team.
But we never raced it.
Why?
Watts!
I thought we agreed
we weren't gonna come in here.
So, uh, catch you later, watts.
She's a girl from school.
Yeah, and the police station.
Nice group of friends
you run around with.
Tell me something. What is it about
our agreement you don't understand?
I understand it.
I just don't get it!
All this...
Look at all this stuff.
You should be proud of it.
I don't want you in here
for anything.
Whatever.
You understand?
Are you comin'?
Watts,
why do you always have to ask?
Radio: City council today
voted to...
( Motor rumbling )
( Dog barking )
( Siren )
Hey, watts.
I wanna talk to you.
I wasn't going that fast,
I swear.
What?
The throttle,
it just sorta got stuck.
What are you talking about?
I don't know. Maybe
we would talk about
what you wanna
talk about first.
No, that's... that's okay.
Wasn't sure if you
knew about this.
Ikf is coming back
to speedport.
Champ karts here?
Yeah, the regionals.
If I remember correctly,
your dad won the ikf
the last time it was here.
Grand national '74.
Yeah.
He was something to see,
your dad.
Anyway...
Thought you might like
to check it out.
Scott McKenna
and a couple of the top teams
are testing up there
this afternoon.
It might be better
than street racing.
( Drilling )
Dad?
Yeah?
Hey, I was deputy west
this morning.
Oh, yeah?
She said the ikf regionals
are coming back to speedport.
Really?
Yeah.
She thought maybe
we could put a ride together
and race like we did
before mom got sick.
I did pretty good
in my first race. Do you remember that?
Third place?
You know?
You said I showed
natural ability.
Regionals is a lot different
than racing junior-1, watts.
I know. But I thought maybe
you could show me
some of the tricks that helped you win.
I don't think
it's a good time right now.
Why don't you wanna help me?
Can we talk about this later?
Yeah. Like that's
ever gonna happen.
Why did you
stop designing, anyway?
Is it because of mom?
( Crackling )
Plug that back in.
Tell me, dad!
Please don't say people don't want
you to design engines anymore...
Plug that back in!
Answer the question!
Give me that.
No!
Give it here.
Why do you wanna do this?
Why don't you wanna help me?
Uh...
Oh, hi, Jen.
Is this a bad time?
A little family thing here.
Come on in.
Hey, watts.
What can I do for you?
I've had this in the car
for about a week.
Kept forgetting to bring it in.
I don't usually work
on anything
less than 8 cylinders, but..
I'd probably say
you're better of getting a new one.
They just don't
make blenders the way they used to
and that one right there makes
the smoothest Margueritas
you've ever tasted.
Better fix it up then.
So, uh,
watts mention that the ikf's
coming back to speedport?
Yeah. He, uh,
said something about it.
Could be fun.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
See that's, uh, that's shot.
Can you fix it?
Take a day or two.
Okay.
Thanks.
You know, Vic?
He's a good kid.
I see a lot of you in him.
( Rock music playing )
Switchback!
( Inaudible conversation )
Feel that.
That's precision engineering,
buddy boy.
You got four bridgestone tires
that cut on a dime.
You've got...
Bink: How much
uh, 4,000.
Dollars?
You wanna climb the track
and run with the best?
Ya gotta lay a little green.
He's only got a paper route.
Yeah, right.
Bink: Where are you
gonna get your hands on 4,000?
Might as well be 4 million.
Why don't you just
get your old man to help you?
He's never gonna know
about this, you got it?
Ever.
Okay.
Whatever.
Don't have an aneurysm.
I got a $2,500 savings bond
from my mom.
Supposed to be for school,
but if I raise the rest, I'm in.
Toomey: Racing Rodney
around the block is one thing,
but running in the regionals,
it's gonna bring out
some of the best karters in the state.
Those kids got
sponsored rides. What do you got?
I just wanna get out on the
track and see how I stack up.
Hey, it's your life.
You wanna hit the wall,
go ahead.
Your optimistic attitude
is infectious.
Hey, I'm a realist, brother.
I've got both feet
firmly on the ground.
Oh!
Oh, no!
And what if I pull it off?
Watts, guys like us?
We always hit the wall.
You can't get by Gordon.
Sometimes you gotta
rewrite the rules, bink.
Come on, Gordon,
show me something.
♪ I'm pressin' on,
pressin' on ♪
♪ all my distress
is going, gone ♪
♪ pressin' on, pressin' on ♪
♪ and I won't sit back
and take this anymore ♪
♪ 'cause I'm done with that ♪
♪ I got one foot out the door ♪
♪ and to go back...♪
yes! Yes!
Nice one!
You got him!
I don't believe it!
Toomey: Keep it steady, dude.
Bink: Everyone, come 'ere!
Watts is beating Gordon!
Girl: Pretty cool, watts.
Go, watts.
Come on, you little sea urchin.
Pound him, man!
Come on, watts.
♪ 'Cause I won't sit back
and take this anymore ♪
♪ 'cause I'm done with that
I got one foot out the door ♪
Bink: Dude, all right!
Wattsy, way to go, bro!
Pound it!
( Kids chanting "watts" )
Way to go, bro!
Bink: You beat him!
You beat Gordon!
What do you want?
Hi, I'm watts Davies...
And I don't know
if you're aware of this...
But the international
karting federation
is holding their regional
championships here
and I was wondering if you'd be
interested in buying some sponsorship...
♪ We're at the top
of the world ♪
♪ you and I... ♪
♪ We've got a lot of time... ♪
What are you selling?
A sponsorship
for my racing team.
Since when to you have a team?
I'm runnin' the ikf.
Sounds good.
Just, uh, be sure
there's no swimming pools
near speedport, huh?
♪ Sha LA LA LA LA LA LA ♪
♪ sha LA LA LA ♪
♪ sha LA LA LA LA LA LA ♪
Hi, I'm watts Davies.
And I'm not sure
if you're aware of this or not,
but the international karting
federation are holding
their regional championships
here this year.
My gold level plan
includes a $100 donation.
In...
My gold plan includes
a $100 donation...
In which you will receive
your company logo,
including a big logo
on the team hat and jacket.
Um...
My silver level plan, father,
is a $50 contribution.
Now, with that, you
and your church will receive
your name embossed
in the chassis,
along with a color picture
of you sitting behind the wheel.
I'm sure you know, father,
with God's money on my side,
I'll stand a good chance
of doing well.
Fifty dollars for
a picture of me behind the wheel?
How much to take the kart
around the track?
I saw this kart.
It's crazy... the wheels are so fat.
Another check for fifty bucks.
How'd you do it?
I just sold 'em on the dream.
Hey, girls.
Boy: Ha ha!
Look who we got here!
Hey, leave him alone!
Hit the road!
I gotta news flash for ya,
light bulb,
you don't got
the game for the ikf.
Those guys walk on water.
And last time I checked,
you don't.
Grab him!
Now, I'm gonna teach you
a little lesson.
Save you a little heartache.
Give it here, Wells!
I hate to see you
waste the next six weeks
trying to put together a ride.
And then get your butt kicked
in the qualifier.
Watts: Rodney!
Don't do it!
No!
Watts!
Watts: No! Stop it!
Take a look, light bulb.
( Alarm rings )
Uhh!
Out of my way!
Zee: Hey, what's goin' on?
Watts! Watts!
What are you doing, man!
Get outta here!
( Sirens )
( Sighs )
What happened?
It's not entirely clear.
There was a fire at zee's.
Seems watts was involved.
He started it?
We haven't been able
to get much out of him,
but if there were others,
he's not saying.
( Sighs )
Oh, man.
Can I ask you a question?
What were you thinking?
What am I gonna
do with you, watts?
You realize the judge
might send you to hillside?
Congratulations.
I'll finally be out of your hair.
"I'm not done talki" to you.
How come it takes
me getting arrested
for you to want to talk?
What are you
trying to prove? Nothing!
Huh. You sure proved that.
Where's that money
you collected?
Why?
'Cause we're gonna give it back.
That's... that's beautiful, dad.
You know, I...
I would really like to,
but it was lit on fire today.
Oh, this is funny?
You think that's funny?
I don't think
it's funny, watts. My kid gettin' arrested.
You aren't gonna help me!
Don't make this about me!
Don't you get it?
It is about you.
It's all about you.
Watts.
Get back here.
Watts!
And with the rotax 125,
you are gonna rule out there, my boy.
Just sign this.
Oh, watts!
Hey, little pyro.
You bust out,
or did someone post bail?
I'm not in the mood.
Sorry.
I heard what happened.
It'll probably be
a front-page headline
in the paper tomorrow.
Don't let them beat you, watts.
Hey, don't take this wrong...
But you don't know nothin'
about me or my problems.
I know more than you think.
Okay, so what do you suggest?
Hey, I got it!
Maybe I should
take out my frustrations by scribbling
paint over someone else's property.
Would that make me feel better?
Forget it!
All right.
You wanna talk about it, little dude?
About what?
Oh, I don't know.
Why don't we talk about
my grandmothers underwear?
How 'bout why I've been
moppin' all night, hmm?
After all, I didn't
set off the sprinklers.
I'm sorry, zee.
I'm sorry I screwed up.
It seems to be
the only thing I'm really good at.
I don't know, man,
I saw you do somethi"
on that machine that
nobody's ever done before.
It's... it's virtual reality, zee.
You know, it's not reality.
Hey! We don't use
that kind of language in here, okay?
For some of us,
this is the closest we're ever gonna get.
Listen, you little speed freak,
you know how to use
one of these? Huh?
Come on.
Uh-huh. Just what I thought.
Vic?
Hey, zee.
How you doin', man.
It feels like it's been
half a lifetime.
Yeah. Hey, how you feel
about the ikf movin' back to speedport?
It brings back
a lot of memories, doesn't it?
Yeah.
You sure left
some tasty stripes hangin' on those walls.
It looks like watts there
has your taste for speed.
You think?
Oh, yeah.
He's got that anger
in his eyes, man.
♪ Sometimes I scare myself ♪
♪ and I don't know
where to turn ♪
♪ I don't know if I should teach
or if I should learn ♪
♪ they both mean
the world to me ♪
♪ though leader I am not ♪
♪ with all eyes watching me ♪
♪ they cast their lives
on cause ♪
♪ well, I've got on
my strings ♪
♪ and still I'm fighting ♪
♪ you've got to
stand on your own ♪ dad?
♪ Fight for what's right ♪ dad?
♪ You've got to skip
the middle man ♪
♪ and keep your focus in sight ♪
♪ you've gotta stand
on the hill ♪
♪ scream you're alive ♪
♪ 'cause you won't die ♪
♪ you're alive tonight ♪
( Sighs )
( Tires screech )
You see those fenders?
Yeah.
Put 'em over against that wall.
Hey, watts?
Set those tires over there
by that metal beam!
What's goin' on?
What do you see?
Nothin'.
Well, look again.
You see it?
Yeah, I see it.
What do you see?
A lot of junk.
What do you want me to say?
Whoa.
( Chuckling )
No... no way.
No way!
You know what they say...
"One man's junk
is another man's treasure."
It's got all the key corners.
See, it's got the hairpin,
and through here,
you've got the chicane.
You gotta be real careful
through this tricky part.
You gotta keep your speed up,
get to the right-hander, brake,
hit the hammer down,
and take her all the way home.
My dad built this for me
when I was a kid.
To practice on.
So I could be
the best of the best.
That's what you can be, watts...
The best of the best.
( Beeping )
Hey.
I got us a new engine.
I thought we were
gonna use the comet.
That's just a prototype, watts.
That thing's
not even race-ready.
But we can make it
race-ready. You and me.
There's too many bugs,
not enough time.
But I thought...
If you wanna race the ikf,
this is the engine
that's gonna get ya there.
Looks fast.
Oh, dude, believe it.
It's so fast.
It better be fast 'cause your social
life needs all the help it can get.
Hey, watts! Are you really
racing in the regionals?
I'm gonna try.
Maybe I'll
come visit you in the pits.
I'll come, too!
Boy: Come on, come on!
Let's go!
What are you
even talking to them anyway?
Nice!
Did that just happen?
Put me in for that pit stop.
( Chuckling )
What do you think?
This one here, or... there?
Where you have it, I guess.
All right.
Bring her on out.
( Engine starts )
( Turns off engine )
So what's with the cans?
This'll help you
keep your line.
And your smoothness.
If you can make one lap
in one minute,
without knocking over one can,
you'll be ready
to race with the best.
That's all
I gotta do? That's it.
That's it?
Yeah.
No problemo.
( Starts engine )
( Laughing )
Oh...
Uhh!
Ah!
( Turns off engine )
This can't be done!
You just did it.
It took me like eight minutes.
It's impossible.
No, it isn't.
Why don't you do it then?
'Cause I've got stuff to do.
Come on, dad, show your skills.
Come on.
All right, all right.
I'll give you a deal,
all right?
You get around this course
in under a minute,
and hit no cans at all,
I got dinner detail
for the next two months.
Come on, anything
you want for dinner.
Come on.
Come on!
I feel like lasagna tonight!
( Laughing, chattering )
Hey.
Hey, watts.
Hey, Kate. You, uh,
you wanna go for a ride?
What's up?
Your old man give you the night
off from junkyard patrol?
Come on, ladies.
See ya, watts.
She's overrated, you know.
Who?
The future prom queen.
I could be wrong,
but I think you like your women
to have a little more... mystery.
Listen, about the other night,
um...
Forget it.
I'm beyond it.
Check this out!
This is sno.
He really knows
how to layer color into distinctive form.
Look.
It's beautiful.
Who's this?
Oh, that? Moi.
You?
With a little help
from Michelangelo.
You ever try to sell anything?
Kinda hard. Buildings
get very expensive, watts.
No, I mean, like, on canvas.
Who would buy it?
I would.
I'm flattered, but I think I'm
gonna stick to buildings for now.
See, in a couple of days,
this'll be gone.
Sandblasted away or
covered by someone else's paint.
That's okay, 'cause,
I don't want anyone
getting too attached to it.
So... wanna make out
with me now?
Bet you thought I was serious.
Whoa!
What the hell was that?
Weren't you lookin'?
Could you next time
give me a little warning?
On a race track,
there are no warnings.
You go in prepared,
you anticipate, and you react.
End of story.
Ah!
Bumper cars. Come on!
You wanna play rough?
Hey, where you goin'?
Watts: When did you first know
you wanted to design engines?
February 14, 1976.
It was the Daytona 500.
What a race that was.
Richard petty... he was
the man to beat that year.
He was comin' off
of 13 wins in '75.
He looked like a shoo-in
to take home his
record breaking sixth 500.
Held the lead for
almost the entire race.
Then on the last lap,
David Pearson
pulls out of petty's draft,
and both cars start
spinnin' and crashin'.
It was... it was chaos.
Debris flyin' everywhere.
It was one of the most
exciting finishes
the 500 ever had.
And I didn't see any of it.
What?
Because at the moment
that Pearson was making his move on petty,
I found myself staring
down in pit row
at the most beautiful
girl I'd ever seen
in a mechanic's jumpsuit.
She was standing up
on this retaining wall,
yellin' her head off.
But even from
where I was sitting,
you could still see
that fire in her eyes, you know?
That was mom.
Yeah.
And I realized that moment
two things:
What I wanted to do
with the rest of my life,
and who I wanted
to spend it with.
It was what you might call
a defining moment.
Hey, Scott.
What do you think
of my son Rodney?
Kid's got some talent.
Some.
Man: This way, Scott.
Great. Thanks.
Excuse me, Scott.
Um, I'm a local racer,
and I was at speedport
the day you were doin' the 360 spins...
Davies donuts.
You liked those, huh?
Pretty cool?
Davies donuts?
Yeah, I copied them off
a guy named Vic Davies.
Vic Davies.
The only guy to ever win
three grand nationals.
I'm still chasing
his lap record.
Yeah, I heard of him.
Thanks for your time.
Hey, what did you say
your name was?
Watts.
I look forward
to racing you, watts.
Okay, zero hour.
Time to show me what you got.
It's the best I can do.
I ran, like, flat out.
Not bad.
54 seconds.
Fifty...
Yes!
Hey, champ.
Come on in here.
My old racing colors.
Your mother always did
like you in red.
See you in victory Lane.
This is Bob Jenkins
and Paul romanuk,
and we welcome you to day one
of the ikf regionals.
Now today is qualifying day.
Only the top 25 fastest drivers
will qualify for tomorrow's
feature race.
These drivers
will be hitting speeds
well over 100 Miles an hour,
so there's no room for error.
That's a good point, Bob.
With 75 racers
gunning for only 25 slots,
there's gonna be
a lot of sad faces.
You all set?
There's a lot
of big names out there.
Yeah, well...
Worry about them
out there on the track,
not in here.
Let's go.
All drivers to the pits.
Let's get our first
qualifying round underway.
Scott McKenna,
current reigning champion,
will be first on the track.
I'm sure we're gonna see
a hot lap
from this young driver.
Yeah, this kid's got it.
Tooms: Ooh, baby!
Okay, let's take a look
at the competition.
We've got Kyle Walker.
He won the wka championships
last year.
And there's the babe herself...
Natalie prefontaine.
She's lookin'
mighty fine today.
Mighty fine.
The big question:
Will local underdog
watts Davies
find his way out
of the starting grid? Let's ask him.
Hey!
Back.
Go get 'em, wattsie!
You're the man!
Move back. This is
a restricted area here.
How ya feelin'?
I think I'm gonna heave.
Good.
Good?!
I always ran best
when I felt like tossin' my cookies.
It'll go away.
Phil!
Hey, light bulb.
Road kill.
Scott McKenna is on the course.
He is worth watching, Bob.
Smooth as silk in the corners.
Scott McKenna
has just clocked in
at 105 Miles an hour
in the back stretch.
He is flying.
McKenna has just turned in
a lap of 46 seconds flat.
That should give him
the provisional pole this afternoon,
unless somebody
can find more speed.
Next up:
Rodney Wells.
Watts Davies on deck.
Give me a hand.
Okay.
When you enter the track,
get your tires good and hot.
Don't worry about the time.
Just concentrate on
turnin' a good, smooth lap.
Everything else
will take care of itself.
Got it?
Got it.
Looks like Rodney Wells
has it dialed in.
Yeah!
Loser!
And no problems
for Rodney Wells.
He puts kart number 34
solidly in the field tomorrow
with a 48.06.
Burn 'em up, kid.
Next up is number eight,
the young fireball
watts Davies.
His name may be familiar
to you.
His dad is none other than
three-time national champ Vic Davies
and those are some
very big shoes to fill.
They sure are.
Watts is gonna have to show
some of his father's past magic
if he's to find a spot
in tomorrow's race.
He'd have to better than
48.27 to qualify.
He's in tight.
So let's hear it...
For watts Davies.
Davies' spinout, Paul,
leaves him with
just one more attempt
at a qualifying lap.
Yeah, it's
gut check time now, Bob.
You okay?
Yeah.
I just lost it there.
All right, refocus.
Find your line.
You can do this.
No sweat. Go!
And watts Davies
is back on track!
Whoo-whee!
That was one big miscue.
Are you gonna do this all day?
All right, here we go.
It's the last chance
to make it into the regionals.
Watts Davies... just one lap.
The green flag is out.
Here we go.
He's approaching
turn number five
where he had the spinout
on his first lap.
Come on, watts.
Much better line
through the corner that time.
It's not looking good
for watts Davies.
He may not make the field.
Sorry, watts.
You gave it your best shot.
Oh, no, don't tell me.
You're in.
Watts Davies
makes an amazing rally,
finishing with
a 48.21.
Yes!
Yeah!
He'll start inside row eight
at tomorrow's dash for Daytona.
Just like his dad.
( Vic chuckling )
Might tighten up
this gear ratio...
Hey.
Hey, why don't you guys
get yourself something to eat.
Got a big day tomorrow.
I've got some stuff to do.
What kind of stuff?
Stuff, ya know? Stuff.
Parents.
Yeah, I know.
( Siren blares in distance )
Thought you might be
getting a little thirsty.
Vic.
Yeah, I was, uh...
Kinda goin' through withdrawal.
So I hear congratulations
is in order.
I heard you guys
made it into the race tomorrow.
Yeah. Gonna give it a shot.
Bet watts is excited.
I don't know who's gonna get
less sleep tonight... him or me.
Thanks.
Good night.
Hey, Jen.
I thought we might give
that thing a little test drive.
See if it's
up to your standards.
( Tires screeching )
You really love it, huh?
Racing.
Sometimes when I'm drivin'...
Everything's clicking...
I feel like I could
just ride flat out,
and no one can get by me.
And then, of course,
I start thinkin'
of Scott McKenna...
Kids like that.
Corporate sponsors,
the best karts money can buy.
And I think to myself,
who makes me so sure
that I could beat that?
If I could just get in there
tomorrow, ya know,
and really just
hang with those guys,
it wouldn't matter to me
who wins.
Don't freak out on me, okay?
It's just...
For luck.
I tell you, ya know.
If I have any hope
of winning this thing,
I think I'm gonna need
a bit more luck than that.
It is race day
here at speedport
as yesterday's
25 fastest qualifiers
get set to go.
We have reports
of thunderstorms and lightning in the area,
so we'll be keeping
a close eye on the sky
as we get set
for the green flag,
but, Bob, I'm excited.
This is the big one,
the regionals...
A 25-lap showdown,
winner goes to the nationals
next month down in Daytona.
Whoa!
Is there something
you want to let me in on here?
Attention all drivers.
To the grid.
Hello, race fans.
This is Benny binks.
We've got us a real humdinger
of a race happening today.
Back in the pack,
local favorite fireball Davies
in the 15th spot.
Okay?
Yeah.
All right.
First few laps,
you're probably gonna
be forced from your line.
Just be patient.
When you see an opening,
go for it.
All crew members
to the pit area.
We're ready to go green.
Go, Rodney!
( Whistles )
Watch for trouble.
Keep your eyes open.
Dad, that kid just cut me off.
All right.
I'm boxed in.
Stay on your line.
And after one lap,
the leader is Scott McKenna.
And watts Davies
is in 21st position.
That's not gonna do it, folks.
Okay.
Stay on your line.
I'm tryin', I'm tryin'.
Watch your braking.
Don't be anxious.
Wait for your shot, watts.
It's now or never, dad.
We've got big trouble
in turn three.
Turn three!
Look out, look out.
And I don't know how,
but the leaders made it through.
Rodney Wells took a beating,
but watts Davies has jumped
up into ninth place,
making a big move in the field.
Good driving, watts!
Boy, that was close.
All right, listen to me.
Keep your eye on the starter.
When it goes green,
make your move.
All right! Come on!
Go!
Watts Davies moves up to sixth.
Good move, watts.
Hey, I found my line.
Rodney Wells bumps
and Kyle Walker finds some air.
Watts Davies
moves into third place
and has his sights
set on second.
All right!
Number 34 Rodney Wells
pushes his way back
onto the board.
All right. Hold it
right in there.
Hold it right in there now.
Come on. Whoo-hoo!
We've got a three-way battle
going on for the lead
in turn ten.
Come on, watts. Go!
Okay, light bulb.
The rules is
there ain't no rules.
Red flag.
We have lightning on the track.
All drivers to the pit area.
Maintain your positions.
We'll continue
when the weather allows
in your present running order.
That means when we do
resume this race,
it'll be a six-lap shootout.
That last accident
pushed our leaders
well down into the pack,
although Rodney Wells
has come back
into the four spot.
We're losing tire pressure
in the right rear.
You couldn't beat me
straight up, could you, Wells?
Come on, come on!
Get off!
Give him a shot!
Binks: Yeah, watts,
smack him.
Hit him in the face.
Break it up.
Hey, you should
be disqualified.
Me? You rammed me
on purpose.
What are you trying to do...
Get yourself run out of the race?
I had him
and he jobbed me out of it.
So?
You gonna let it beat you?
Watts, Mr. Davies.
Should the engine be smoking?
I'll inform the starter
you'll be withdrawing from the race.
Yeah.
Sorry, son.
You did well.
Davies'll be
pulling outta the race.
Dad?
You ran a good race, watts.
Why is it that
anything that's good
always goes away?
Would you give us
a second, please?
Sometimes bad things
just happen, watts.
Sometimes there is no why.
Can I tell you something?
When your mother died...
That was the hardest thing
I ever had to go through.
These last four years...
It's been hard feeling anything
except sorry for myself.
I know that I haven't
always been there for you...
In ways that maybe
I could have.
But you showed me
something today, son.
The way you drove.
From here on out...
It's you and me, 100%.
Prove it, dad.
The comet?
Watts, that thing's
never even raced.
Never turned more than
two or three laps.
I don't even know
if the damn thing'll run.
It'll run.
You and mom built it.
Please?
Excuse me. Guys?
I heard your engine got cooked.
I have a spare engine
on my truck.
It's yours... if you want it.
I wanna beat
the best out on the track,
not back here.
We appreciate that.
But we're gonna be okay.
All drivers need to reform,
watch the red flag
and prepare for
a running start.
Due to a short six-lap format
of this race,
there'll be no stoppage
until the checkered flag.
Green flag in one minute.
What's the story, dad?
We'll get there.
Here. Get your helmet on.
( Revs engine repeatedly )
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
If she burps,
you're going to have
to adjust the carb through the chicane.
Any last-minute advice?
Yeah.
Go fast.
It's up to the green flag
to decide who goes to Daytona.
Watts Davies has had
to change engines
due to that earlier collision
and now trails the pack.
Okay, she hasn't run
in four years, buddy,
so let her breathe.
All right, dad, I got it.
And here they go.
Go, watts!
Yeah!
Get 'em, watts!
You feel that? Huh?
That's a kick in the butt.
Rodney Wells moving toward
the head of the pack
while Scott McKenna
begins his battle back
from ninth position.
Lean it out, watts.
Lean it out
on the back stretch.
I hear you, dad.
Track's heating up.
Watch your tire temperature.
Rodney Wells takes the lead.
Yeah!
Go, Rodney!
The leader is
number 34 Rodney Wells.
Five laps left.
Another crash, this one
in turn number two.
Good move, watts!
Good move!
I found my line.
McKenna and Davies are each
making a big run in the field,
but watts has a long way to go.
Go, watts!
Lookin' good!
Four laps to go.
I got McKenna in my sights now.
The leaders are setting
an incredible pace.
The lap counts are going down,
the speed is coming up.
Good move, watts.
Good move!
Oh my, we've got a new leader.
It's watts Davies.
Scott McKenna
grabs back the lead,
but watts Davies
and Rodney Wells
are right there on his tail.
Two laps to go.
What an event!
Okay, light bulb.
Here we go.
It's like you said, Rodney...
The rule is...
There ain't no rules.
And Rodney Wells
is hard into the hay bales.
( Rodney yelling )
He looks okay.
Get off!
This is the greatest day
of my life.
Tooms: Yeah, Rodney!
Talk about getting tossed.
Coming down to the last lap.
Who's going to make it over?
We'll know
in exactly 40 seconds.
Come on!
( Engine sputters,
then accelerates )
Come on!
Come on, watts!
They come off the corner.
They're wheel to wheel.
They head for
the checkered flag.
Yeah!!
Yeah!
Damn!
Where'd you learn
how to drive like that?
My dad taught me.
The best of the best.
♪ I opened up my eyes,
and I found beautiful ♪
♪ it opened up my life,
now I know beautiful ♪
♪ and how things should be ♪
♪ you are my beautiful,
beautiful to me ♪
You did it, buddy!
You did it.
We did it, dad.
You're the big winner!
♪ Beautiful ♪
♪ you are my beautiful ♪
♪ yeah, you're so beautiful ♪