SubTitle By:
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
ÒíÑäæíÓ ÇÒ:
ãÍãÏÑÖÇ ÑäÌÈÑ (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
SubTitle By:
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
Planet Aradius
The Arid people, believers of the Wei,
have been enslaved and oppressed by humans for over a millennium.
In recent years,
the planet's declining population has become plagued by infertility
the ruthless human viceroy--Griffin--has begun an unyeilding campagin to find and kill the arid rebel leader--Moss--who speaks of rebellion...
Arid to the rebel leader, Moss, who speaks
an uprising, to find and kill ...
Where is Moss?
- Do what you gotta do.
Moss.
- We never betray our people.
Neither do we. My King, such acts
for those who are suitable for it.
Arid or human.
They must all admire you.
Admired for a short time.
- Think of the economy.
At this moment there are no strong men,
both work and leisure.
Take him to the pit.
Rest assured, I will find Moss ...
and if I do, I will destroy him.
And his crazy followers.
SubTitle :
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
They are close.
Human Rights.
- I can see.
Hirokin.
It's not like we know each other.
These people come to our planet ...
they steal our resources,
they spread infertility ...
among our women.
And what do we do?
We still fight against ...
how long we allow
Griffin enslaves us ...
for our men to take ...
our women to abuse ...
Are we so different from the people?
Because our palms shows our blood?
How is it that some people
the Arids so warm welcome.
No one is alike.
Wait here.
My Lord, what do you want us to do?
And?
With this uranium are your weapons sharp.
My people need not be pointed out
on the properties of their own uranium.
So?
- I have the solution here.
Deacons.
- You.
What?
- I knew we could not trust people.
I did not.
- Help us.
Kill them all.
My advice to you, run.
Pick the one with the mask,
then he must withdraw.
If Wood gets the mask in time,
the rebels will fail.
Yes, sir.
Do not touch her, man.
Is everything okay?
- Yes.
What is wrong?
Finley.
That was seven years ago.
I know.
Do you ...
we do not have to do.
I'm back for the first meal.
We came so close ...
we can not turn around.
We are really close to the horde.
Deacons can here everywhere.
We can not go back.
If I can solve this ...
we can go live.
And you will have a future.
A tea.
We all do what we must do.
I heard your name today fall
in connection with the slaughtering.
Do you believe everything you hear?
Less than half of what I see.
That's not what we had discussed.
This is better.
- It is not yours to decide.
This is all I have.
Hirokin ...
You're the only one in the neighborhood with the drug.
- Then you understand its value.
Grace, brother.
Grace.
My child is sick.
She has that medicine.
Those not willing to help
can not be helped.
I know who you are.
Is that so?
- How can you be so selfish?
We all do what we must do.
Deacons, get out.
Nora.
Ga.
Go inside.
It is time to exercise
in practice.
Hurry up please.
Complete silence as we had practiced.
Show yourself.
Come on out.
Human Rights. I am a man.
We thought you were vandals
So we hid.
We want no problems,
we are just passing through.
Do you have a Arib seen
named Moss?
No.
I see that they Arids ribbon wearing.
Is it that child birth?
Yes.
We are just passing through.
Let's have a long journey.
Which side are you on?
- East.
The food chase.
I have something for you, calm down.
It is at least a hundred gigs worth.
Earlier thousand.
Let us go and it's yours.
- I decide what is mine.
We do not want problems.
Problems?
My friend, anyway.
You're in a world problem.
Racing.
No.
Take it to the pit.
Maybe he does it better there.
Attention, the games begin
ten marks.
Attention.
Place your bets.
The matches start on ten marks.
My daughters.
This is the last place I wanted to see them.
They want to know what you
are willing to die.
Keep walking, inside.
- Come on, faster with those rows.
That is enough.
Bye, the next one.
Keep walking.
Here you go.
All right.
- Here he comes.
There, HONSu.
They say he is a sympathizer.
- He is a sympathizer?
Befriend the rebel leader Moss.
Hey, I got an idea.
We sell him the sword
that the man brought.
Yes, but what if he lit us again?
Simple, whatever he asks, we deliver it.
Beautiful.
- Note.
And what have the men for me today?
A love stick.
Attention, the games begin
five marks.
A gay stick?
Are you going to watch it all day?
It suits you.
It really brings your eyes forward.
Two palm woods for this.
Five.
He is worth at least five.
Five?
Really?
What man wants a Arib sword?
He is way too heavy to use.
No, no, you do not. If you were there
much interest in, it's worth a lot.
You're going we do not light up again.
You light up? Gentlemen, have you forgotten
what valuables I brought you?
I remember it.
Yes, that was really nice stuff.
Really nice.
Two.
I think two is good.
Let's take those two.
But you wanted four.
- Yeah, okay ...
but I think two is good.
Two, and then we are equal.
Almost, but why do we ...
this little strap at ...
and we have a deal.
- Two blue.
Two for two.
Okay, it's a deal.
Is this yours?
They say you have a
Arid woman and a child protected.
That's right, I said Arid ...
I do not call anyone a gig.
Arids are always better, right?
Then I am in your debt.
I always do.
That keeps me alive.
For a bit of force.
Walk strong in the Wei friend.
Attention, the games begin now.
Civilization has a delicate balance.
It shows what the people want
and what I need.
And I need stability,
order and discipline.
And for that ...
I give their Orange.
She is very beautiful.
Have you enjoyed last night.
I really enjoyed it.
A good barrel, but empty.
I'm more than a vessel,
once you understood that.
Anyone with insight could understand that.
Maybe I'm blind.
I will give you an heir.
It's only a matter of time.
Obedience to my orders ...
Is my freedom.
- I am a father of a civilization ...
I will not be forgotten.
Hirokin.
I will not fight.
I will not kill other Arid.
Then you will die.
Well, you people know the rules.
Kill your enemies ...
and save your loved ones from the point.
I love you.
Impressive.
Mama!
Dad!
No! Father!
Kore, you say that your man together
with that whore grabbed it.
And her child.
Let her go.
- He won the fight, according to the rules ...
the woman Fri
- Indeed.
Rules.
Where would we be without them.
Yes, master.
Do not let go.
No, Hirokin, no!
Moss and his remaining rebels
have a low threat.
Find him, Kore.
Each underrated invisible enemy.
- Moss will continue to hide.
Be sure of that, he and his people
in due time will appear.
So it is.
- I will find him.
Maybe you should just come back
if you have it.
That would make sense.
As you wish.
My lord.
Death.
- It's still breathing.
Not any more.
Have you seen that man in the pit?
- The skinny?
Or that fat.
- Was there a fat man in the pit?
No! Sometimes I do not
why I'm with you.
I like them, if she's a little meat
to themselves.
What do you like, with "a little meat on them?
People, Arids, it does not matter,
as long as they show a little flesh to themselves.
And what do you do when you're done with them?
- When I'm done that?
With them stabbing death.
Wait, what did you
I was talking about?
I do not know where you're talking about,
every time you change.
First you talking about a skinny man in the pit
And now you're talking about stabbing death.
It is very confusing.
Why?
I do not know.
- Is he not?
He's a bit skinny, right?
- Yes, he could use some meat on its use.
You know what I heard?
I heard that he was the Arids.
And he is a murderer.
- Killer.
A piece or eleven or something.
They say that he
Arid has a bunch of rebels slain.
That Griffin will be appreciated it.
If you call that appreciation ...
Well, I have him stabbing.
- Beware, do not stay stuck.
Exactly, yes.
What was that?
That sounded good.
It's good. It is well
you who live at root, my friend.
Otherwise, this' n very one-sided conversation.
My boy.
- No time to grieve.
Now it's time to flee.
Why are you helping me?
We all have our motives.
A friend of mine had a vision.
And I think it was about you.
Quick, we must hurry.
Good.
- Where are we?
A half day of the Horde removed.
I'll take you so far back.
See that red star?
Stay in the direction of that star walk.
Eventually you will find a friend of mine.
His name is Moss.
If he managed to escape the Deacons,
he will help you.
Here.
To support you.
Walk strong with the Wei, my friend.
Is this life worth living?
I bet you wish you were dead.
He is a man you can not trust him.
He would not be here.
He puts us in danger.
We would have to leave him immediately.
- He needs our help.
HONSu him with "a reason sent to us.
How do we know this rig
the medallion has not been stolen.
Maybe he HONSu be killed.
- There is little danger to help him.
Help him bring our tribe in danger.
It brings your daughter in danger.
You need a drink.
Here.
Good.
Gabriel, go find your father.
Water?
Go ahead.
We constantly search for water. A tribe sought
nearly two moons without 'n drop to find.
The water will be coming.
Because we are strong in the Wei.
Come.
We grind the thorns, and 'n drugs
liquid that helps with injuries.
See? Look.
This is how the Arid itself.
If, in a part of the system rooted.
In order to keep together the whole.
Maren. Water.
See?
Our thoughts, our words.
Our words ...
our words, our actions.
Our actions were our habits.
Our habits, our values.
Our values ??...
our values, our destination.
Moss, what you ask us, is suicide.
The renegade will not save a single soul.
It will only show a matter of time,
before they find us.
Time.
We must unite as a tribe, Cain.
If we do not like a candle
want to be blown.
You can not save everyone.
- The tribes will unite with Dead Rock.
Has your own life for meaning
when nobody else is ...
for the light to communicate?
And what is the meaning of death?
He will give us the first chance
he gets, revealing as a reward.
I trust that you keep an eye on him.
And Maren also.
Homemade liquor with spines.
But a few tribes make it.
We trade it for what we need.
It tastes terrible.
But it frees you from your problems.
We have saved your life,
the least you can do is talk.
Yes, Maren, I appreciate the
what your tribe did for me.
What is your band?
I am the second oldest daughter of my tribe.
Goodness gracious!
I thought you were much older.
Thanks for the drink spiked.
I really enjoyed it.
Good night Maren.
Second oldest daughter of our tribe.
Maren.
I missed you last night in singing.
- I also missed the singing.
I must help him, Cain.
Help him or help us?
Maybe it's the same.
- I wish ...
that things were simple, Maren.
But life is never.
Beautiful, is not it?
I do not know, it feels cold.
Lonely.
Amazing how such a small thing
many may determine.
Some say the lines
tell our future.
Does that mean I have no future?
I can not go a day longer life.
To the outside world.
None Arid, not man.
I mean, who are we?
We are in the outside world,
because we do not belong.
You chose this life, not me.
Audowen?
- They bleed.
She is bleeding everywhere.
Please, my baby.
Here is the baby.
Audowen?
00:44:03,231 -> 00:44:05,640
Each ribbon a song.
A ribbon for every life
what we are blessed.
Blessed. Even in death there is life.
Moss is near.
I leave at dawn.
Go back to your Horde?
Why?
Revenge.
- The senseless revenge.
Why people do not understand
that we all breathe the same air?
We drink the same water.
We cry the same tears.
I've seen, my friend.
I've seen ...
on the battlefield of my mind.
You are sent to the tribes to unite.
I'm not the answer you're looking for.
Am I crazy?
The Wei have brought him here.
Much suffering comes with believing in the Wei.
Suffering, what do you now suffer?
It is our tribe, which is haunted.
Like the night follows the day ...
it's coming, my friend.
No hope ...
You can change it,
the world ...
My friend, stay with us and learn our trade.
- No, thank you.
No hope and no change
unless you unite the tribes.
No, thank you.
Maren.
Clothing to keep you cool,
there is more than you need.
Nothing kills our spirit.
Cain?
- Cain clings too tightly.
Sometimes you something to cling
all you can do.
What you can do is accept the truth
and release.
How do you do that?
You just do.
It's time for me to leave.
I'm getting old by depression.
Hirokin.
That's what your name means in the old city.
Held.
He who fights for more than himself.
I fight for them.
- They are dead.
They are now free.
But that's not me.
- No, not you.
Not until the Griffin dead.
The Griffin will
your limbs torn apart.
Let me see it.
Do you think it is a game?
Come, put your hand up.
Let's play.
Push me over. Do your best.
Nice is not it? This game.
What was that?
I call not a massacre.
You're not ready.
Stop. Hold on.
Show it to me.
- What should I show you.
I will not leave my sheep,
like a wolf.
Until you learn the secrets of the Wei ...
you're just a slaughter
Grif for Finnish gang.
You're not ready.
She was your wife ... is not it?
You wonder why you could not save her.
Accept, the Wei.
I can tell you
that suffered by the Wei.
When I turn, there is a fatherless child
because you loved Wei.
Do not turn around so it means for you
what you think it means.
Yes ...
Yes, that is the fire.
The power of imagination, my friend ...
is a powerful tool.
Do me a favor, imagine a leaf.
Think of a jasmine leaf.
Do it for me ...
Do your best, it is important to visualize
I'm going to tell you so.
We have a huge connection Arids
with the world around us.
The air, land,
these are the foundations ...
This is the Wei.
It is no coincidence that the Arids believe in this.
Our visual side
is quite different from the human.
It is fully connected to our environment.
A millennium ago, there was an elite group
so connected with reality ...
that they were able to
ontraffelen times.
Decisions were seen
for they were made.
This special gift made
the people are terrified ...
A campaign was started
for us to eradicate.
All knowledge of our gift was wiped out.
After a thousand years of
slavery and genocide ...
the Arid varieties forget who we are.
See the future was a myth.
The scorched planet ...
made our women infertile.
We are the light,
it's not beyond.
But it is in here.
It flows out to the world.
So who are you?
A man.
Have you not known,
I am able to read your thoughts?
I am able to feel your connection
since the day we took you from the desert.
You were born in this world,
not quite human and not quite Arid.
Your association with the Wei ...
is the strongest I have ever encountered.
00:55:02,250 -> 00:55:07,005
If you follow me in my mind ...
do you go along with the flow
or you fight against me?
Amazing
something so small that many can identify.
I handle it.
- No, you will not. This is who you are.
You shame haunts you.
Let it go.
We create our own reality, my friend.
Reality creates us.
That is useful.
- Convenient?
Do you?
That boy ...
these are just memories now.
I tried everything I am.
But I could not ...
I could not ...
I could not save him.
You are what you create, right?
The light hiding inside you.
Let it flow.
For the times to unfold
let all your fears, emotions and thoughts.
That is Wei.
Start times to see ...
See selections.
Allow your senses to move forward,
hear the sounds.
Belief in a choice without a doubt.
That faith and that choice ...
will it really make.
It's all in your mind.
You just need the pieces in a fit.
Your vision creates your reality.
You let him leave?
The time has come.
I go with him.
- That's a dead weight between two suns.
If you go to the Griffin, take me along.
Give me your hand.
Give it.
Care for your tribe, that's what matters.
Attention, place your bet.
The matches start on five landmarks.
They can not give you what you desire.
Can you do that?
Attention, place your bet.
The games begin ...
I hope you find this enjoyable
than the last time.
I enjoy nothing
than the sight of my son.
You're so beautiful, Tara.
I mean in your conviction.
You would not be here.
Your father ...
- Is happy when I return with a good deal.
Commander, we have reported that Moss had
and his rebels gather at Dead Rock '.
Prima Deacon, sets sail from
and send message to the viceroy.
The mind has its own place ...
only he can enjoy
a torture to convert.
Or a torture fun.
And a prison into a sanctuary.
A sanctuary or a prison.
Where is my son?
- Stay nice now.
Why am I here?
- I want a child ...
And you want a better life.
We are a gift for each other.
Perhaps undeserved.
We are not so different you and me.
We both have needs.
I want you by my side today.
He will be there.
Yes, your son.
Join me with a smile
and you get what you desire.
Well, then ...
Hirokin ...
Is it true what they say about you?
In the City of Love?
Yes.
Innocent Blood.
Where can we find your friend?
- That we do not, he will find us.
Look. - The man from the Pit.
He clearly has more meat on the bones.
What ails you?
- Hold on, Sean, why no other disguise?
What do you mean disguise, wearing a cloak.
He is a meat eater like you.
I wonder what he wants?
Probably swap?
This is his so Moss Arid rebels.
A child and a man.
HONSu.
I bet he drinks it.
- I love how you think, my friend.
Is your father completely mad?
- My father is fine, thank you.
Have you already met Hirokin?
- Yes ...
the fighter where I did my best for
to get him out of here.
Welcome back.
Can you bring me near
of the Viceroy?
The viceroy?
You?
To his legions?
Come, follow me.
There is nothing so satisfying
the quest of the innocent.
I have brought you this.
It's incredibly sweet
So naturally I thought of you.
Indeed very sweet.
I will not admit him.
You have no other choice.
Nobody has that.
I'm sorry I can not
another route can bring.
Only one may enter.
Not what you expected?
- I do not know what I expected.
One thing is certain, you are here for her.
The question is, you have something interesting for me?
I am in no mood for games.
Griffin is not an easy man
to participate in the vicinity.
Your have succeeded.
- Yes, indeed. For now.
Griffin has needed an heir.
He thinks I do not give.
I think the problem is beyond us.
Take me to him and it does not matter anymore.
- Tell me now that you do not want?
It can be fun.
The chains cut deep.
I thought you were already familiar look.
Quite touching how you fought to save her.
I once had a baby.
Rather, I once gave birth to.
I'm sorry.
- Griffin will now leave the pit.
With Tara.
You did not?
Tara is still very much alive.
I see you've already found a replacement.
A younger girl, much prettier.
- She's alive.
Why do you look yourself?
Deacon.
My son.
My dear, dear son.
I missed you.
I love you so much.
My prince of the Horde.
So you revolt.
Maybe it's our fault, maybe we were
not strong enough in the Wei.
Look around you.
Your stupid wisdom ...
kills our people.
- There is nothing ...
fool ...
struggling for freedom.
If you can win.
But you can not?
So why not live?
With how it is now rather
resist and kill us one by one.
You see the world
through the eyes of fear.
And you see nothing.
We are not afraid of the path
that lies ahead.
Child prostitutes.
- Halo extra, you get them a lot fresher.
What do you want?
- Which?
Grace, Brother.
Grace.
I am not afraid
for the path I have chosen.
We are not afraid.
Take him away.
A bit dramatic, no?
- Can you see he has talent.
Keep the whore against children.
She escapes.
And then it starts.
Subtle.
Good throw.
- I like him.
I find that quite provocative.
- And now?
Flights.
- Good plan.
I think ...
- That this way comes?
Problems.
- Someone's in trouble.
Gentlemen,
we must flee.
Arab liqueur.
- And Blue tea.
This way.
- It's our smuggling route.
If it works.
Have you seen three rebels?
- They went that way.
Do you know who rebel?
You have the habit
foreigners to attract.
He is the father.
He survived.
- You start to sound scared, Viceroy.
You begin to disappoint me,
Tara.
Let my son go.
- Where?
The desert?
To disappear?
To join the rebels to join
and being slaughtered?
Nora needs protection.
I'll keep him safe.
I love you safe.
Let my son free
and I will submit.
I need much more than subjugation.
Rebellion, rebellion. The chosen one
has come to overthrow the Horde.
The tribes gather at Pilot Rock.
All tribes unite.
The chosen one has come to the Horde to defeat.
Everyone goes to Pilot Rock.
They say a man
Deacons twenty killed with a sword.
Face forward.
He was flushed with blood.
Every movement timed to perfection.
He came to a man to confront.
But he painted fate.
This is subtle.
I have some with finesse.
- You've certainly.
We understand that a human rebel
The Horde has attacked.
And that Arids gather around the rebel.
- It does not matter.
The resistance is the threat.
Moss, without the divided.
He remains our goal.
Moss is the key to this rebellion.
Cain,
that you?
We all have to choose
at a given moment, is not it?
Spare my people.
- The Viceroy want you.
Alive.
Only you.
- That was not the deal.
You said you would hurt anyone else.
Moss is the one you want, he's the threat.
Take him.
- You're lucky you live.
Cain.
- On your knees, rebel.
It's our people become today.
Because of you.
They join with us all now.
No more hiding.
Father was right.
Our vision is our reality.
I'm sorry.
They're still alive.
That's it.
Time to let go.
Time to plan.
I do not want another child
his knees by them.
Why me?
I am because of you
and you because of me.
I do not understand.
And I do not try.
That is Wei.
We accept just who it is.
You do not like me?
- That I do.
You're beautiful ...
and ...
I can not.
- Why?
Because I am Arid?
Because I am bound.
I will be
for a long time.
Then I will wait.
On you.
We arrived just another group.
- And Moss?
Let it be known that this man
or resistance within the walls of the Horde ...
will become known as Hirokin,
Sword of the resistance.
We are here to fight alongside you.
Under your command.
Stand up.
Ever ...
I fought,
because I had nothing to live for.
Now I fight ...
because I've seen everything to die for.
We have a chance ...
to do what Moss said we would do.
Shape, for the people.
We fight for Moss' vision,
of a united world.
For Moss.
- For Moss.
When is that big fight start?
- We attack at dawn.
Your rebel starts to irritate me.
I have people
I have his son, I'm his wife.
And yet he
still not attacked.
You did not.
Viceroy?
- Not now.
Something very important.
Hold that thought.
Want to see what opposing
the Viceroy you deliver?
It is better to rule in war,
than to serve in peace.
Well done, Kore.
The mighty Moss,
leader of the rebellion gig.
Broken.
- You will never break our spirit.
Resistance to the last breath.
- This is our way.
You still have the power
to preserve the lives of your pathetic people.
Only in death begins freedom.
For it will come ...
and he ...
will spread apart to the time
and you will be blown away as a breath ...
Griffin.
You fool.
Now is the death of your people, your fault.
Keep him alive, Kore.
Let him witness his
latest achievement in his glorious life.
What is the key to our success,
Kore.
Timing, My Lord.
- Timing.
You did not think we were ready for you.
No.
- What is it you want?
You. Death.
- Think about it.
Because at the end of your life
you will be reminded of this moment.
We choose life,
without fear.
Without you.
But you find yourself not
in a position to make demands.
Not?
He is arrogant.
- He's dead.
Great fights ...
define great people.
Kill them all.
What are you doing?
- We will play little war.
They are quite determined.
- It's who they are.
Relax.
This will not last long.
Keep the child quiet.
In obedience to your command.
- He is your freedom.
Love playing children.
Let him.
Your vision creates your reality.
That's the way Sentient.
Not true, Moss?
Moss here dreaming of peace.
But look around.
A strong desire to own
extend over the weak.
That is reality.
That is the Wei of my world.
Promise me ...
that you let your mother.
I promise.
- It's your family.
Fight for me.
Loss of love makes heroes.
Each ribbon a song left
in the fight for freedom.
Yesterday I had a dream.
I saw a man fight
for something bigger and himself.
For freedom.
He stands against fear.
And tyranny.
And the next.
Everyone was born free.
What a dream.
SubTitle :
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
ÒíÑäæíÓ ÇÒ:
ãÍãÏÑÖÇ ÑäÌÈÑ (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
SubTitle :
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
ÒíÑäæíÓ ÇÒ:
ãÍãÏÑÖÇ ÑäÌÈÑ (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
SubTitle :
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
ÒíÑäæíÓ ÇÒ:
ãÍãÏÑÖÇ ÑäÌÈÑ (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
SubTitle :
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
ÒíÑäæíÓ ÇÒ:
ãÍãÏÑÖÇ ÑäÌÈÑ (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
SubTitle :
MohammadReza Ranjbar (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com
ÒíÑäæíÓ ÇÒ:
ãÍãÏÑÖÇ ÑäÌÈÑ (M.R.R)
MohammadReza4853@yahoo.com