Let's get to work.
We make the perfect team!
Just remember.
You stay here. I'll go alone.
Why?
Dangerous work is a man's job.
Let me take care of it.
Lila was my third partner in the
"Anti-vampire League"
She was the only one I loved.
Because I didn't want my heart
broken any more,
I decided not to fall in love
with my partner again.
Master, do you really like this place?
It's really not bad...
I see! You're his boss!
You really have good taste!
When do you want to start the lease?
You can only talk to me.
Then, I'll talk to my master.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Prada, when would you like
to start the lease?
I don't want to rent.
You think we can't afford to buy it?
Take it home and count it.
Tell me if it's a penny short.
Prada, watch them.
I've told you,
we are members of the royal family.
We should behave well!
Remember, we drink blood,
but we don't suck blood.
We are different!
Sir, we're still vampires.
Even if we can bear to
live in a church,
it's still not a good idea.
Prada, don't be so retro!
We're new age vampires!
Let's move with the times, okay?
- Take a seat, please.
- Thank you.
Isn't it a bit crowded?
Excuse me!
As this lady said,
this place is a bit crowded for us.
Can you ask these people
to move to other seats?
I don't think we can do that, sir...
That's all right. I've got money.
I'll give them $5,000 each,
what do you think?
I'll try, sir.
- Thank you!
- You're welcome.
Ken, you're incredible!
Sir, that gentleman wants
to give you back $50,000!
Bobo, I have to tell you something.
I'm taking a big risk
having dinner with you.
You mean you're still afraid of...
Don't mention her name! She's scary!
Once you say her name, she'll appear!
It happens all the time!
But you can't keep avoiding Helen!
Miss...
What did you promise me?
What was it?
First, you won't stop loving me
before I stop loving you.
What does that mean?
Put simply,
only I can dump you.
Secondly,
when you choose another girlfriend,
she must be better than me.
That's right!
Come on! Show Helen your figure!
Where you go in, she goes out.
Where you go out, she goes in.
Where you're flat, she's round.
I've kept my promise!
I was just kidding!
It's okay!
May I borrow your knife?
It's okay! Take them all!
You promised me that
if you were not loyal to me,
you have to cut something off.
Sir, should I call the police?
No!
If I cut it off, are we quits?
That's right.
Okay!
This is to pay you back
for your wronged love!
Take it.
Let me drink this.
You can't drink this wine.
Let's order something else.
Hey, please open a bottle of finest
red wine for this lady, on me!
Why can't I drink this wine?
How can you drink this glass of wine?
Prada!
This is just my personal opinion.
Don't cry!
I didn't cry!
When I knew that guy,
he was 130 lbs.
When his weight reached 160,
I had no more feeling for him.
But, I respected him;
I didn't break up with him.
How can he cheat on me?
He doesn't respect me at all!
I'm happy to break up with him.
Is your name Helen?
Can we be friends?
I'm Kazaf.
I just got back from abroad.
9877, try to call me.
I can't find her! You got anything?
We've made hundreds of calls, sir!
I think she's just messing with you!
You can't trust human beings, sir.
Especially woman.
They're always having mood swings!
Did you notice that?
She cried and then she laughed!
She's crazy!
I just love that! I think she's great!
Have you ever seen a vampire
like that before?
Sir, even if you can find her,
human beings may not accept us.
It's better to date a female vampire.
After looking at her,
look at yourself.
Then, she'll come forward!
It's rather simple!
I want something more!
Something more?
You want to fall in love with food?
Men don't fall in love with food!
Have you seen someone
fall in love with a piece of salmon?
When you're hungry, you eat it!
I like her, so I won't suck her blood.
Anyway,
my father sends me blood every week.
Hello?
Hello? Is Helen there?
Speaking.
Is that you?
I'm the guy you met in the restaurant!
Are you crazy?
Do you know what time it is?
Show me how to send a picture, please.
My idol!
It's you!
Why do you have my picture?
Well, it's because you're my idol.
When I joined the League,
I heard many things about you.
I'm so happy to learn from my hero!
When did you come out?
I didn't see you!
I wanted to watch you waiting for me,
so I took an early flight.
Really?
I've heard so much about you!
You joined the League 5 years ago.
You've killed 123 vampires.
You're the best vampire killer
in the League.
You really did your homework.
Let me help you!
I've got it.
Thank you.
From now on,
let me handle this stuff, okay?
As my assistant,
you have to remember two things.
Just follow my orders...
...without argument.
That means I just have to follow you?
That's right,
just like Batman and Robin.
We ordinary people
can't fight vampires.
So, we have to use vampire blood
to upgrade our power.
It doesn't taste good!
If it lets us beat vampires,
we shouldn't mind the taste!
The effect of the vampire blood,
only lasts for one and a half hours.
If we don't take the antidote by then,
we'll become vampires for real.
So, in that case...
If one of us becomes a vampire,
what do we do?
Even though it seems cruel,
Kill without mercy!
What antidote do we need?
This is the antidote.
Banana essence?
Smart, eh? This is just a cover.
There isn't any banana flavor.
It's just for disguising it.
What is it?
Let me introduce you guys.
This is my new partner, Gypsy.
This is my sister, Helen.
Stop!
I'll sleep with you!
Would you please show me some respect?
She sleeps in my room,
you sleep here
and I'll sleep outside, okay?
All right, you take my room,
she sleeps here
and I'll sleep outside.
You told me that your sister is nice
and easy to get along with.
Well, everyone has their own way
to express their feelings.
She's really very nice.
What's up?
Come on! I only used a little!
How could she tell?
Okay. Anyway, you can use my stuff,
but never touch any of her things,
okay?
I wanted to keep you.
But you look too much like
that fat bastard!
I just want to dump all you fat guys!
What are you doing with my stuff?
You threw it away.
I just wanted to take a look at it.
I didn't throw it away!
I just put it there!
You're being ridiculous!
So what if I am? Give it back!
Stop!
What are you fighting about?
What are you doing?
You!
Is that any of my business?
Why didn't you tidy up
after the fight?
- Hello.
- Hello!
Is that you? Are you looking for me?
I just want to know whether your phone
is out of battery or not.
No, it's full!
So what?
From the sound of your voice,
I can tell you're bored.
I'm not in the mood!
What's the matter?
None of your business!
Let me tell you a joke!
Okay, see you at noon
the day after tomorrow, okay? Bye!
Sir, did you make a date
to meet her at noon?
Yes. What's the problem?
The sun!
Oh yes! The sun!
It will kill you!
What should I do then?
Make it at night,
12 midnight instead, okay?
No,
I promised her to go, so I must go.
Your report had been sucessfully sent.
Don't worry! We can get him!
I'm not worried
about getting him or not.
Actually, these European vampires
seldom appear in Asia,
When I got my orders this morning,
I thought the League made a mistake.
I think this is related to my orders.
Only one prince is left after the
assassination of the entire royal family
The vampire King
and five of the princes were killed!
Is that an internal conflict within
the royal family of the vampires?
My dear son, the Duke has revolted
against the royal family.
Your father has already escaped,
he asks you to take care of yourself.
He wants you to protect this book.
"Day for night".
Five princes were killed
and their blood essence stolen.
I think this is related to this book,
"Day for night".
Day for night?
What's it about?
It's the bible of
the royal family of the vampires.
It's a family treasure heirloom.
You mustn't lose it.
"Day for night",
a holy scripture of the vampires.
Within it, there is
the blood of the Ultimate Vampire.
If any vampire drinks it,
he'll be able to move
freely in daytime.
What's that got to do
with the death of the princes?
Its said that
the only key to open the scripture,
is found in the blood
of those princes.
So, he is the last key
to open the treasure.
That's right,
we must find him as soon as possible.
I heard that a vampire
tried this method before.
2000 years ago,
Sir Nicolas tried it in Poland,
What did he use?
As recorded in an ancient book,
he had a kind of sun cream.
After putting some on his body,
he could walk in daytime.
He could swim too.
Where can I find this kind
of sun cream?
Well, it's not for sale,
but I think we can make some.
First, add two drops of absinth juice.
Then, add some refined olive oil.
Mix with red wine.
Then, add some refined sesame paste.
With some potassium.
Then, add some face cream into it.
Is it just a test?
All scientific achievements
are the result of tests.
That's right! Okay, go ahead.
After diluting it,
Put in an oven for 3 hours,
then put under the sun.
For how long?
For 300 years.
300 years!
The longer its under the sun,
the better it'll work.
Perhaps you can try putting it
under the sun for 3 hours.
It may not have quite the same effect.
Have you tried it?
Of course not! You think I'm crazy?
I bet some vampires
have tried it before.
I think Sir Nicolas tried it.
Helen, Helen!
Who are you?
I'm Kazaf!
Well, you look great!
Really?
Aren't you happy?
If you don't want to date me,
just say so! I hate your look!
But you said it was great!
I was being sarcastic!
Let me be honest.
I've had a blood problem since birth.
I can't go out in the sun.
I'm risking my life
going out like this.
You should have just changed
the time for our date!
A man should keep his word.
- Hello.
- Welcome!
Sorry we're late. It's his fault.
He's going to a fancy
dress party later!
- I'm sorry.
- And you two are...
Where are lvy and Jackie?
They're over there!
Please help yourself.
Okay.
Do you always gatecrash
this kind of thing?
Don't you think joining
a wedding party is warm and happy?
Thank you.
Jackie, congratulations!
Wait! Even though I look so smart,
I'm not the groom. He is.
Congratulations!
Thank you...
I've never got married before.
I'm so nervous!
Son, just calm down!
You have nothing to worry about!
When I was shooting a penalty kick
in a soccer match,
I felt great pressure!
But I wasn't afraid!
Did you score?
- Jackie, lvy's gone!
- The ball flew into the grandstand.
Even though I failed, I wasn't afraid.
- Well, my son...
- Yes?
Where is your wife?
I am looking for her too.
Would you please
take care of yourselves?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Is he your boyfriend?
Yes.
Why is he so oily!
Where is my wife?
She's drinking!
It's great!
Honey, why are you drinking already?
I learned a new drinking game.
Let me show you.
One, two, three!
Stallone...
Bruce Lee...
Jackie Chan...
Isn't it fun?
Honey, how much have you guys drunk?
Just two cases of wine! Not much!
What? That's much too much!
I told my father that you're a lady!
A lady? Oh yes! I just forgot!
Don't embarrass me, okay?
Okay! I really love you!
Don't go.
My husband is giving me
a 4-karat ring.
I'm so happy!
I just want her to be happy.
Jackie,
would you come here for a moment?
Take care of her please.
Take care of her!
- Jackie
- What's the matter?
We've been friends for ages,
I am so proud
I introduced you to lvy!
And I really
appreciate that.
You're welcome.
So, if I make
a mistake today,
please forgive me.
What's up?
Well, it's no big deal!
I just lost your 4-karat ring.
You're kidding, right?
No, I really lost it.
Calm down.
Have you searched everywhere?
I did! Did I give it to you?
No.
I'm doomed!
You're really doomed!
No matter what,
you have to find it for me.
Don't worry,
I already asked someone to find it.
One more thing, don't let her know.
I've already searched
every inch of this place.
You really dropped me in it this time!
Are you crazy?
How can you lose something
so precious?
May I take a picture of you two?
- Sure!
- Okay.
One, two, three.
- All right!
- Okay.
Let's eat.
What do you want to eat?
Eat whatever you like! It's free!
Don't you want to eat?
You're hungry, aren't you?
Bananas!
Just bananas?
Yes, I love eating bananas.
- You love bananas?
- Yes, they're delicious.
Take a bunch, then! It's free.
I just heard something exciting!
The groom lost the wedding ring!
What? Does lvy know?
Welcome! Thank you being here today.
Let's give a big hand
to the bride and the groom!
Jackie and lvy have known each other
for seven years.
They met on this same day
of seven years ago.
So, they chose
this day to get married.
To bring them the greatest joy
and happiness.
Now, may I have everyone's attention?
May I borrow it?
I bet all of you want to see
how gorgeous the wedding ring is...
It took the groom 2 years
to save up for it...
What's up?
Just take it.
- It's time to change the rings.
- Just take it.
What is it?
It's a bat ring.
Are you kidding?
I'll give you the 4-karat ring later.
Just wait a while, okay?
It's time for the toast!
- Cheers!
- Time's up!
Honey, stop it! No more wine.
- Please.
- I want to drink it.
So what?
Please! Don't drink it.
Give it to me!
No!
I want to drink it!
It hurts!
Honey, I'm sorry, you...
No!
Honey, are you crazy?
I'm sorry. I shouldn't yell at you!
Ivy! Don't marry him. Come with me!
Ivy!
How dare you ruin my wedding party?
Daddy!
Great! Son,
you're got yourself a great gal there!
- Honey, you're the best!
- Honey!
Hey, you're burning!
Burning again?
Oh no!
My sun cream doesn't work any more.
Let's go!
Why are you staring at my back?
Nothing.
Well, it's just attractive.
Really?
Is it that why you...
ask your partner
to follow you everywhere?
Of course not!
Let me ask you one thing,
why did you call me your idol?
Vampires killed my parents.
So I swore,
I would kill them
all to avenge my parents.
You are the greatest vampire killer.
So that makes you my idol.
Do you believe me?
I just made it up!
Actually, its just because you're
the most handsome guy in the League.
That's it?
Girls are always so naive!
I made that up, too!
Why do you keep lying?
All your former partners say
you're a sentimental person.
I just lied to them.
You stay here! I'll handle this.
Let me do it!
It's gone.
I said it's gone!
It's really gone!
Really?
Where is the antidote?
I thought you had it?
You brought it. Give it to me.
I brought it?
Oh, yes!
- Banana flavor?
- I feel so good!
Does yours taste of banana?
No. You said it was just a cover.
So there's no banana flavor.
That bat has almost starved to death.
If we don't find some blood,
we'll starve to death too.
I've told you so many times!
I don't know how to suck blood.
You know, but you won't do it.
Hello?
How did you know I was here?
I followed you, that's how.
Do you always follow people?
Don't you like it?
Okay, I won't follow you again.
Why do you live in a church?
Are you a Christian?
Are you a devout Christian?
I made a banana cake for you!
I bet you haven't eaten yet.
Neither my master nor l
have eaten yet.
Prada, no!
Master.
No!
Are you hungry?
Come on! Take a bite! It's delicious!
Don't bother him!
Why is there a coffin here?
That's my bed.
You sleep in a coffin?
My family runs funeral business.
I'm trying some new designs.
You designed this?
That's right.
Really? It's beautiful!
Can I take a look at it?
Sure!
You're really talented!
Can I try it out?
I love the lighting! It's great!
Yes, it's great!
Did someone say he was hungry?
Yes.
Eat it.
It's banana flavor. You'll love it.
Don't worry. There's plenty more.
No! We've lost the antidote!
- Wait!
- What?
- Can you smell that?
- What is it?
Bananas.
Why did you use
banana flavor as a cover?
My sister hates the smell of ba...
What's the matter? What are you doing?
It must be the vampire blood...
Take it.
If I become a vampire,
Kill me, understand?
The cake must be full of antidote!
That's right.
Eat it.
Eat this one too.
How do you feel?
I feel much better.
Do you want water?
Thank you!
What's up? Do I look ugly?
No! Not ugly at all.
Any more cakes? Hand them over!
Make it quick!
You're driving me crazy!
I've forgotten to tell you one thing,
If I get vampire teeth, remember,
Kill me at once!
At once.
No! No!
Don't die!
Don't leave me alone!
I promise, I'll be your best partner.
I'll listen to you!
I won't fight with your sister again.
Wake up, please!
Do you want me to tell you everything?
I really love you!
Can you hear me?
I'm alive!
But I don't know what you just said.
What? What is it?
I said... I am not that easy to kill.
I couldn't hear what you said.
It's just too noisy.
Okay, I'll shut up!
Let's take a rest now.
Your cake is really delicious.
Your coffin is so comfortable.
Bye!
Are you looking for trouble?
That kiss was okay,
but you're not allowed
to kiss me again.
What you said before...
I heard everything!
Is anyone home?
Miss Momoko,
what a coincidence to see you here.
Mr. Prada,
I've brought you some papers to sign.
And I've brought you something else.
Please wait.
This is the last chance!
I'll bite her neck.
And you can choose
any position you like.
Pulse, or inner thigh, or an armpit.
Let's bite her together,
and then suck her blood.
I told you many times! I don't suck.
Okay, I'll suck her blood
and put it into a jar.
I'll serve you
with a glass of it, okay?
You used to serve it like that to me.
But that's all over now.
Forget the past!
I'm telling you for the last time.
I won't suck blood.
I see! You have fallen for that girl.
Tell me, you think
you're fit to be a vampire?
Have you got
what it takes to be a prince?
Are you qualified
to succeed the throne?
Are you giving me a lecture?
Try to tell her tomorrow,
tell her that you're a vampire.
See if she's generous enough
to give you her blood.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Is it urgent?
I want to tell you what I am.
Don't turn your back to me.
I'll get angry.
Let me be frank.
I am not a human being.
You're certainly not acting like one!
How can you talk to me like that?
I'm a vampire.
So?
Look at my eyes.
Cool!
Where did you get those contact lens?
What are you yelling about?
See? I want to suck your blood!
That's not the right way to suck.
Suck like this.
Let me go! Off!
I know what you're doing!
You want to dump me, right?
I'm a vampire!
Do you want
to fall in love with a vampire?
So what's a vampire?
Can a vampire brush
his girl off like this?
I know! You think I'm too sassy.
But most of the girls
in Hong Kong are sassy!
Don't you believe me?
Go find another one.
If you dare!
I have some dogs at home.
I don't mind having a vampire.
The only problem is
that my brother may not like you!
I am a vampire,
and a useless vampire, too.
What do you mean?
I haven't eaten for days!
What are you doing?
I am taking you to find food.
You stay here!
It's better for me to go alone.
Be careful!
It's time to eat.
Something's wrong, let's run!
Did you get caught?
Can you hear that?
What is it?
Bats.
If there are bats around,
it means vampires are around, too.
Let's run!
Why is the hospital alarm ringing?
Has there been a robbery?
I think it's just a mistake.
I don't think any thief would be
stupid enough to steal from a hospital.
Who knows? Thieves are everywhere.
Your car could even get stolen.
Speak of the devil!
What's the matter?
Who are you?
I am so glad to see you again!
I saved you last time.
Would you help us now?
Your friend is dying!
That's right! I think he's dying!
He has to get to another hospital!
Please take him there now.
But I have to take
something to the hospital.
The "something"
you have to take is him.
Take him there now, or he'll die!
Come on! Hurry!
Let's go! Please!
Are you feeling bad?
Do you want to suck my blood?
Of course not!
I can treat your teeth
like mosquitoes!
If you don't eat, you'll die!
Jackie, driver faster please.
What's up?
Who are these guys?
Help!
Be careful!
I don't know how to drive!
Hold the wheel tightly!
This is bad!
Are you okay?
What the hell are you?
This is terrible! I ran someone over!
Vampires! They are vampires!
Vampires?
He can fly!
Come on up!
- Throw me another bag of blood!
- Okay!
It's working! This is type AB.
Are there really vampires?
It works!
What did you give them?
It's a kind of tranquilizer.
It should calm them down.
They ate so much!
It's making them go crazy!
Turn on the music now.
Drink it.
Come on! I brought it for you!
Do you feel better?
Well...
Jackie asked me to return it to you.
What does this mean?
The ring is too tight!
I can't get it off.
Good morning.
Good morning!
You help my brother
to iron his clothes?
I'll iron them from now on.
Congratulations!
You've found someone you can love.
Haven't you fallen in love
with someone too?
He's great. He's just terrific.
But sometimes,
he's not that good to me...
The harder it is to fall in love
with him, the more I love the feeling!
Anyway, there is something missing!
So I just couldn't fall in love.
What's missing?
That is...
What is it?
Something is missing...
He is the "thing" you
and my brother hate most.
Have you fallen in love
with a vampire?
But he's a good vampire!
Vampires suck blood and kill people!
How can that be good?
He'd rather starve than suck blood.
He is really nice!
Could you say something on our behalf?
Your brother and l
are vampire hunters.
Please help us! Please.
I beg you to help us!
My dear sister-in-law!
Come on! Please help me,
"my dear sister-in-law"!
We are a family!
Family! As your sister-in-law,
I'll help you, right?
I always said my brother is lucky!
At the first sight,
I could tell you were really nice
as well as pretty.
Hey,
how did you win my brother's heart?
Watch this!
Superstar!
Can you do that?
It's terrible!
But your brother likes it.
No way! He's got special tastes!
He likes trashy girls,
but they must be simple.
Besides being simple,
she must be ordinary.
Do you have any better suggestions?
Does it work?
How about this?
Can you do that again?
My dear sister-in-law!
Do you have a date?
What do you think?
You put on perfume!
We can go now.
Do you like it?
How pathetic to find
a vampire living here,
in a church!
Now, where is the fifth prince?
This is for you.
What is it?
Why is it black?
Vampires wear black wedding gowns.
Really?
Well, you search over there,
and I'll check over here.
Why should I go there?
What are you doing? Let go!
Don't you love me?
Why did you let them go?
They're in love!
That's my sister,
and that's a vampire!
What did we swear
before joining the League?
When I took my oath,
I didn't fall in love.
Now, I know what love is!
Once you love a person,
you won't care about anything.
You can tell that from
what I'm wearing.
Didn't you promise
you'd do anything for me?
I've got it! I'll wait for you here!
Reeve,
right where you are least expected!
Good to see you again, old friend.
This is my room.
This is my bed.
May I lie down?
Just for sleeping?
Go ahead,
well, it's good to take a nap.
Our beds are not just for sleeping.
See, it's bigger than yours.
Are there other ways to use it?
Such as?
Well, chatting!
Many people love chatting in bed.
Haven't you ever heard of
"pillow talk"?
No. Shall we try now?
Sure!
Why don't you talk?
What's up?
Someone's here!
My dear sister-in-law, you're home!
Come with me now!
What's up?
Your brother is in trouble!
He's the only one person
who can save your brother.
Kazaf, how long have I waited
for this moment?
I didn't come for you. Let Reeve go.
You still dare to act like royalty?
Bow to me,
and I may grant you an easy death.
You still need my blood,
If I spill it myself,
it's worthless to you,
Let him go.
Why should l?
Your friends have already
gone to rescue Reeve.
Perhaps,
I should free this one instead?
Reeve!
Drop the knife and he shall be free.
No chance! Release him!
No...
Let him go!
Reeve!
Reeve! It's me!
I'm your sister, Helen!
So I see you are
stronger than your brothers!
Reeve!
Gypsy!
In this world,
there are still some vampires.
And there are
three more vampire hunters.
One of them is me.
One is my sister-in-law,
who's now become a semi-vampire.
And the other one
is a sentimental vampire!
I've brought you something to eat.
Come on, try some!
I really love to eat!
So, go ahead.
I've brought you some papers.
Take a look, see whether
you've got any questions.
I can do the amendments for you.
I think something is wrong.
What's the problem? Just tell me.
You're disgusting!
I feel so itchy!
Do you always act like that?
I haven't tried that before.
Honey, I told daddy that
you're "dickson"...
It should be decent.
You're "dickson"
I just wanted to speak faster.
I am sorry.
Decent.
Again.
No way, I have to deliver
something to the hospital.
Look at his hand!
His hand is right here.
No!
I said that's you,
you don't have to move like that.
I don't know.
You can just put it here.