Oh, lulla-lulla-lulla
Lullaby bye,
Do you want the stars
to play with
or the moon
to run away with?
They'll come
if you don't cry.
So lulla-lulla-lulla
lullaby bye,
in your mother's arms
be sleeping.
You let anyone jump
on your brother again,
and you just stand
and watch,
boy, I'll beat you
to death
i don't care
who started what
or whether he was
winning or losing.
Boy, you get a stick
or-or-or-or-or
or a goddamned brick.
Get anything,
and you knock the shit
out of whoever's
fighting your brother,
' cause if anything was to happen
to me or your mother,
you ain't got nobody
except your brother.
And this goes for him too,
but he knows.
You' re the one
that keep coming up
with this off-the-wall
bullshit about
Henry started it.
Now, if the son of a bitch
is too big for you,
you come get me.
You are not
a child anymore.
You soon
will be a goddamned man.
Now, start learning
what life is about now, son.
Oh, lulla-lulla-lulla
lullaby bye,
do you want the stars
to play with
or the moon
to run away with?
They'll come
if you don't cry.
stop right here.
Get him, get him, get him.
Get that mother.
You dirty little-
hey, man, quit bullshitting.
Damn
Hey, stop!
Can't you see
the man's hurt?
You old poop butt.
You all right?
Who hit him
with that rock, man?
Man, I didn't man.
Let me see, man.
Let me see
your sore, man.
Aw, that doesn't hurt.
You poop butt.
Hey, man, who you calling
a poop butt?
Hey, man, why don't we just
go to the Vicksburg-
go to Vicksburg Club, man,
and watch the hos
go in and out?
Naw, man.
If anyone told ma
that they even saw me
on the same block
as the Vicksburg Club,
shoot, man, my ass is hers.
They'd have to call the police
to drag her off me.
Come on.
Hurry up.
Come on, man
Stan Jr.,
where you going?
I'm going to get
my BB gun.
Push.
Push, you guys.
You ain't doing it. Push.
Hey, man, what you doing?
Hey, man, what you doing, man,
to my shoes?
Hey, you gone and broke
the motherfucking
antenna, man.
Oh, man, don't worry
about it.
What you looking at, punk?
I'll kick your heart out.
Man, let's get on, man.
You ain't seen nothin'.
Man, black gone
and called the police, man.
Hey, man, I just-
Hey, man,
come back here, man
Man, no, man
Oh, man.
No, man, I got something
for him.
No, man, no, no
I'm heading
for that punk
No, man,
I'm gonna fuck him up.
Man, I ain't playing.
I wonder,
my little darling,
where can you be
again tonight
while the moon
is shining bright?
I wonder.
My heart is...
just working myself
into my own hell.
I close my eyes,
can't get no sleep at night,
no peace of mind.
Why don't you
kill yourself?
You would be
a lot happier.
Go out like Johnny Ace.
No, I'm not gonna
kill myself.
Got a feeling I might do
somebody else some harm, though.
When was the last time
you been in church?
Back home.
Since then, I've done
a lot of things.
Haven't done nothing yet
that would make the devil blush.
I don't have
any trouble sleeping.
I ain't ashamed of nothing
I can't help.
Hey, what's going on,
killer?
Where's my BB gun?
Mama threw it away.
Daddy
Hey, boy, stop acting
like you ain't got no sense.
Daddy daddy
daddy daddy
Young man-
I got to go, man.
What's going on?
Oh, man, that cat's
something else.
Here come Bracy and Ernie Cox.
I don't want them asking me
for any money.
I'm going out the front.
I see the wife got you
towing the cart.
I say, Oscar
must have been here.
How do you know that?
He's the only one
I know
that wears that
Old Spice aftershave.
Oh, say, man, if you want
to catch Oscar,
he just left.
So you want
some coffee, man?
Yeah, black.
Angie.
Say, what does this
remind you of
when you hold it
next to your cheek?
Not a damn thing but hot air.
Didn't it remind you
of when you' re making love,
how warm her forehead gets
sometimes?
Just like this?
So I don't go for women
who've got malaria.
So how y' all been doing, now?
Walking the streets
all night,
We passed here
about 3:00 last night,
and we saw the lights on,
but we decided
to keep on stepping.
Why didn't you stop?
I'm always awake.
Yeah,
counting sheep.
Man, I guess it's time for me
to get ready and go to work.
Hey, man, maybe me and Ernest
can luck up on a slave
if we's lucky.
He played one,
he played knickknack
on my thumb
with a knickknack,
paddy-wack,
give a dog a bone,
this old man
came rolling home.
This is old man,
he played two,
he played knickknack
on my shoe.
With a knickknack,
paddy-wack,
give a dog a bone,
this old man
came rolling home.
Now I'm craving your body.
Is this for real?
Temperatures rising.
I don't want to feel
I'm in the wrong place
to be real.
Whoa, and I'm longing
to love you just for a night,
kissing and hugging
and holding you tight.
Please let me love you
with all my might.
Reasons, the reasons
that we hear,
the reasons that we fear,
our feelings
won't disappear.
Oooh
and after the love game
has been played,
all our illusions
were just a parade,
and all our reasons
start to fade.
la-la-la-la-
la-la-la-la.
you never smile anymore.
I used to think
you was just tired.
but I think
deep down inside,
you worried,
and you ain't happy.
Don't nothing ever
make you want to smile?
Why don't you try
to get some sleep?
I can do the dishes
tomorrow.
Hey, y' all,
stop whistling.
hey, y' all, look out
Hey, boy, you got to move
before you get hit.
What is America to me?
A name, a map,
the flag I see,
a certain word, democracy?
What is America to me?
The house I live in,
a plot of earth, a street,
the grocer and the butcher
and the people that I meet,
the children
in the playground,
the faces that I see,
all races, all religions,
that's America to me.
Mother's there,
expecting me.
Father's waiting too.
Lots of folks
gathered there,
all the friends I knew.
All the friends I knew.
Hey, Stan.
Can you come out
and play, man?
That's my
hope-to-die buddy.
Come on
out of there, man.
I know you here.
Hey, man.
Let me have
a buck, man.
Hey, Stan,
open the door, babe.
Come on out of there.
say, look here, we need
to rap with you a minute, man.
go on,
Tell him the plan.
Jive turkey.
See, look here, man.
You understand,
we need a third man,
you understand?
Somebody
recommended you.
Now, let me
tell you, man.
It's a one-to-five
proposition off-hand.
Me and him face a dark day
if we ever go before the man.
Hey, man, look,
I don't want to hear it.
No, I don't want
to hear it.
wait a minute.
Let the man
tell you the deal.
Mm-hmm.
Well, look, man,
you know somebody
that keep
their mouth shut?
Yes, you do, man.
And won't blush
to murder?
Man, you know more kind of
people like that than I do.
Who the hell told you
I'd help you
do away with somebody,
anyway?
A friend of yours.
Who?
That don't make
no difference, man.
Say, look man,
we' re gonna do
the actual killing.
All we want you for
is the unnecessary details.
Just be in the background,
you know.
Don't want to hear it.
Why don't you let me
borrow your Roscoe?
Man, I don't keep
no gun.
Why you always want
to hurt somebody?
Who, me?
That's the way
nature is.
I mean, an animal
has its teeth,
and a man has
his fists.
That's the way
I was brought up,
God damn me.
Right on.
I mean, when a man's
got scars on his mug
from dealing with
son of a bitches every day
for his natural life,
ain't nobody gonna
run over this nigger,
just drylongso.
Now, me and smoke here,
we taking our issue.
You be a man
if you can, Stan.
Wait-you wait just one minute.
You talking about
be a man; stand up.
Don't you know there's more
to it than just with your fists,
the scars on your mug?
You talking about an animal?
What, no, you think you' re still
in the bush some damn where?
You' re here, you use your brain;
that's what you use.
Both of you nothing-ass
niggers got a lot of nerve
coming over here, doing some shit like-
wait a minute.
What do you mean,
wait a minute?
I ain't gonna
wait a minute,
' cause if it was
you wouldn't ever come
in the first place.
And you' re gonna sit here
and let them do this?
Wait a minute;
look at Stan.
Wwhat have he got?
he worked all his life.
What have he got?
He don't even have
a decent pair of pants.
All we trying to do
is help the nigger.
Hey, you can't live
if you afraid of dying.
Is that right?
Forget it, man.
Forget it.
Let's go.
Come back here, girl,
and put on your shoes.
If you get sick,
I ain't got no money
to take you to the doctor.
Mot dear,
can I have a dollar?
say,
old longheaded boy,
how many times
did I tell you,
don't call your mother
'mot dear?'
You ain't in the country
or something.
Got to keep on rocking
to another day.
Keep bumpin', yeah.
I'm gonna shine my way.
Got to keep on rocking
to another day.
Keep bumpin', yeah.
I'm gonna shine my way.
Got to keep on rocking
to another day.
Can't get me,
Janice.
You can't run fast.
Get out of my way,
you skags.
Who you talking to?
I know you' re not
talking to me.
Kick his butt,
Suzie.
Ugly fag.
I'm gonna tell
your mother on you.
I'm gonna go get
my big brother.
Is he fine?
Come and get
your old raggedy bike.
You dog.
You got to come get
this raggedy thing.
You better
take it home.
Yeah, like I said, man,
You know, this apartment here
is beautiful.
But god damn, how you gonna live
in this apartment building
with all them fucking kids,
all them motherfucking people
bugging you?
If you want to go out
in the backyard,
You got to share it
with four or five other tenants.
Girl, come on
in this house.
Haven't I told you about
listening to grown folks talk?
What do you want with another
raggedy ass car for, huh?
Just trying
to get ahead, man.
You niggers are sick.
Now you think
you' re middle class.
Man, I ain't poor.
Look, I give away things
to the Salvation Army.
You can't give away nothing
to Salvation Army
If you' re poor.
We may not have
a damn thing sometimes.
You want to see somebody
that's poor?
Now, you go around
and look at Walter's.
Now, he be sitting over an oven
with nothing but a coat on
and sitting around there,
rubbing their knees all day
and eating nothing
but wild greens
picked out of a vacant lot.
Now, that ain't me,
and it damn sure won't be.
And tomorrow,
after I cash my check,
let's go over to Silbo's
and buy that motor
and put it in.
Right on.
How come you' re not
in the streets?
I need some money.
What?
Get yourself together
and get out of here,
because you know
you' re a no-good woman.
You get yourself in line.
It brings sorrow
to my heart.
Tears fall from my eyes.
It brings sorrow
to my heart.
Tears fall from my eyes.
Well, my baby...
Shut off this damn car and go
buy us some Johnnie Walker,
and leave that damn
ripple shit at the counter.
Man, baby,
I'm feeling tired.
Get your ass up,
and don't roll
your eyes at me.
Hey, Mister, you want
to watch that car door?
Oh, don't get mad.
I'm sorry.
May I help you?
Need a check cashed, please.
This is y' all's check?
Yes.
This is your check?
Jerry?
Hell, no.
Hi, Stan.
What can I do
for you?
Uh, I want to know
if I can cash a check.
Hmm, maybe.
How come you don't come
and work for me?
I don't know.
Liquor stores get robbed
too much.
I'd just hate to get shot
in a holdup.
Oh, I'd protect you.
You could work
in the back with me.
He takes care
of the register.
You think about it.
It's a warm proposition.
Maybe.
What's the matter?
You better sit down.
Hey, why don't you
separate the money,
and, you know, you won't
have to pull it all out?
Who beat you up?
None of your damn business.
Adolf and Boulevard
jumped on him.
Hey, what's happening?
What's happening,
old dude?
Hey, who's been working
on you?
Adolf and Boulevard
kicked his ass.
Who kicked him in the face?
Adolf.
What did he do that for?
He didn't have
nothing else to do
with his hands
and his feet, nigger.
Yeah, he kicked your ass
for being so smart, huh?
What till I get on my feet.
I'm just
going outside.
Okay, baby.
Boo.
How come you' re
not going to school?
I've been sick.
You' re gonna fall behind.
Can you play cards?
Solitaire.
Suit yourself.
All I got is $10.
I told you.
what is this,
A damn regular sideshow?
How is my sister married to such
A silly ass, foul-mouthed dick?
How come me and you
ain't never got together?
What would you do?
I wouldn't know what position
to take, mama.
You dirty dog.
You ought to find yourself
a place to stay
instead of sponging
off my sister.
This is my uncle's house too.
Please...
Well, tell this nigger
to shut up then.
Don't you have
any money?
I ain't got nothing but $5.
$5.
That's all.
Tell him we'll give him $15.
All we got is $15.
Don't sell them
nothing, uncle, hear?
Nothing.
Hey, man, why don't you
be cool?
You know, you would be
a good-looking fella
if you didn't frown so much.
Who, me?
Some sisters told me I look
just like Clark Gable.
You about as tasteless
as a carrot.
You always in an old nasty
frame of mind.
Tou' re just a regular
hardship case.
Someone always trying
to revive your poor ass
or give you first aid.
Always feeling sorry
for yourself.
If I don't,
nobody else will,
and you're just
an all-day sucker, bitch.
Sil, she kicked your nephew
over here, man.
Sil, man, come over here, man,
to sit by him.
I've got more important
things to do.
My hair is falling out.
Sil, man, he's bleeding.
Why'd you have to kick
the son of a bitch
in his damn head?
Sil, you'd better come over here
and see about your nephew.
Can't you see
I don't give a damn?
He shouldn't have run
his damn mouth so much.
Give me $15 for the motor
and a shirt for collateral,
and it be slick.
You got that?
We' re gonna do this.
Go all the way down.
You all right?
We got one more step down.
One more?
Got it?
Argh, raise it;
get it up.
It's on my finger.
All right, you got it?
Yeah.
You got it now?
I thought you went home.
You all right?
Just leave it there.
It'll stay there.
No, it won't, man.
Let's push it
back up in there.
It'll stay up there.
You all right?
Huh?
Just smashed them
a little bit.
I think it'll
be all right.
Should we put this
all the way back up there?
It'll stay there.
Just leave it there.
Let's get going.
It'll stay on there.
Block is busted.
How it ain't no good.
May as well forget it.
It ain't no good.
It's busted.
Nothing we can do with it.
All that work for nothing.
Just leave it to me.
Don't ever be ashamed.
Just give me a chance.
I'll take care
of everything.
Your troubles I'll share.
Let me know,
and I'll be there.
I'll take care of you
Anyplace and anywhere.
shake a hand,
shake a hand.
Shake a hand,
Shake a hand.
shake a hand.
Shake a hand
if you can.
Be truthful to me.
I'll be truthful to you.
I'm in love with you so,
and I don't know what to do.
So let's call it a day.
I said all I have to say,
except don't forget to pray
and shake a hand every day.
Throw my goddamn shades down.
Throw my goddamned shades.
You can forget about living
when I catch you.
The only thing
that looks good dying
is a rose.
Hey, Truman Doyle.
Truman Doyle, wait a minute.
Is that you, man?
Who the shit
does it look like, man?
It looks like somebody
that owes me some money.
Look, man, I ain't got
nothing but my good looks.
But look, do you know where
we can get us a few bucks at?
Yeah, go rob
a damn liquor store.
Look, you look better going
than you did coming, anyway.
So get on, nigger.
Come on, Gene.
Why don't you go in the house
and put some shoes on?
Shit on you.
This bitter earth,
well, what fruit it bears.
what good is love,
mmm, that no one shares?
And if my life
is like the dust,
ooh, that hides
the glow of a rose,
what good am I?
Heaven only knows.
Lord, this bitter earth,
Yes, can be so cold.
Today you' re young.
Too soon you' re old.
But while a voice
within me cries,
I'm sure someone
may answer my call,
and this bitter earth,
oo-oo-oo-oo-ooh,
may not, oh,
be so bitter after all.
Memories that just
don't seem mine,
like half-eaten cake,
rabbit skin stretched
on the backyard fences,
my grandma.
Mot dear, mot dear, mot dear
dragging her shadow
across the porch,
standing bare-headed
under the sun,
cleaning red catfish
with white rum.
Come get me.
Don't do that.
Where the dog at?
That mother
sucker fucker.
Come on, dog.
Keep running.
This is a mean old world
try to live in by yourself.
Can't get the one you love
and have to use
somebody else.
I've got the blues.
Gonna pack my things and go.
Yes, I've got the blues.
well, I guess
you don't love me...
450, 451, 452, 453,
453, 454, 455, 456, 451,
452, 453, 454,
455, 456, 450, 452, 450-
Can't you count?
Count yourself, then.
Look at them old ugly girls.
Your daddy.
You want to come on,
want to fight, then?
Okay, I'll see you later.
All right, take care.
Hey, man.
So what did
you do today?
Got to find me a job.
Tomorrow's Saturday.
Let's go to bed.
Catch a rat, cat
Gene,
we needed food
in the house.
You shouldn't have spent
your last dime
to get
this car fixed.
That ain't right.
Don'
If things come to worse,
we can always sell it.
What are we gonna do
about it now?
How's it going, Dian?
Ain't nothing to it,
you know?
Gene.
What it is?
Not too much.
What are you doing?
Oh, just trying to get
this old car together.
Yeah. Look, let me
give you a hand.
Oh, here, take this.
Miss Sally gave me $5
for cleaning behind the garage,
and she gave me
some peaches too.
Thanks.
I'll pay you back.
Go on,
you can have half.
No, thank you.
It's getting late.
Let's go in
and have some coffee
and see what my guests
are doing.
Slam
I'm gonna get up
in the morning.
I believe I should go
back home.
I'm gonna get up
in the morning.
I believe I should go
back home.
I'm gonna find my baby,
acknowledge
that I done her wrong.
Are you happy now?
Got a point.
You've got a point
right here.
Nine, nine more points.
What's wrong with you?
You' re going crazy.
Shoot the dice.
Well, you know
she's a mean, wild woman
' bout to drive me
out of my mind.
Hey, brother, why don't
you two fellas come on,
get in the game, man?
Back 'em up nine, yeah.
Nine.
Going over
the street sign.
And I said
all I could think of
Was the blood
getting to my head.
Huh? Huh?
And Alma Jean,
all I could see,
her was wearing
that cascade on her head
that looks
like a birdcage.
so her Boulevard,
as she calls him,
fire to her jibs
bring the rest
of the stuff.
Boulevard-
Man, what is your problem?
I don't have time.
We gonna get us
something to eat.
I don't have time.
Boulevard kept circling
the five-four ballroom,
Thinking we can get some music
and some food together.
Stop.
I said-I said, Alma Jean,
tell this nigger of yours
that don't he know
we can get 15 years
for him acting
felonious?
Get out of the way.
You ready?
Come on,
get in the car.
I said, Alma Jean,
don't you know that nigger
of yours can get 15 years
for being felonious?
Don't you know
people are changed?
Man, we' re ready to go.
We don't act like this
no more.
Get in the car.
Gene's gonna drive me
till I swear.
Don't go so damn fast.
We might miss
where we' re going:
the country, please.
If I had a few bucks,
I'd bet it on that old
son of a bitch
in the ninth race
at Los Alomitos.
How much you paying,
child?
Ten-to-one odds.
That ain't enough.
Catch one of them
long shots.
Hell, this is
a long shot, shit.
Ten to one?
Yeah, ten to one.
That's a long shot.
Shit.
Look, man, I told you
to have a spare tire
and don't be coming out here
in the middle of nowhere.
I got to get to this race
out at Los Alomitos, man.
Lookit here in the ninth race.
I got me a nag, man,
that I know is gonna come in.
I got me some money, man,
and you ain't got no spare.
Look, look, look.
aw, shit.
Man, I'm out here
singing the blues.
Got my money on a horse
that can't lose.
You out here on a flat.
I always told you
to keep a spare,
but you's a square.
That's why you can't
keep no spare.
Now how we gonna
get there, huh?
We'll just have to ride back
on the rim, that's all.
I ain't got no spare.
We'll ride back
on the rim.
Stan Jr. done left
this house open.
I'm gonna
kill that boy.
It's gonna rain.
And the roof
still needs fixing.
Daddy, what makes the rain?
Why, it's the devil
beating his wife.
Is that all I get?
Hmm.
Stan Jr.?
Stan Jr.
You know you hear me
calling you, boy
I know that boy heard me
calling him.
Oh, girl.
Well, well.
Look who's visiting.
Honey, tell me why
you' re wearing
that pretty smile
on your face.
Well, she's gonna
have a baby.
I thought her old man
was shooting blanks,
but I see he's dropping bombs
on occasion, I guess.
This bitter earth,
Well, what fruit it bears.
What good is love,
Mmm, that no one shares?
And if my life
is like the dust,
Ooh, that hides
the glow of a rose,
What good am i?
Heaven only knows.
Lord, this bitter earth...
Yes, can be so cold.
Today you' re young.
Too soon you' re old.
But while a voice
within me cries,
I'm sure someone
may answer my call,
and this bitter earth,
oo-oo-oo-oo-ooh,
may not, oh,
be so bitter after all.
I'm just going home.
Going home.