Have I got
something in my eye?
Seems a bit red.
I saved you some jello.
He returns her slap
with his right hand.
He approaches her, she raises
her arms and pushes him.
He steps back.
He moves toward her. As he's
getting ready to grab her...
she raises her arms
and takes hold of him.
Their bodies begin to move
irregularly in space.
She finds the opportunity
to lift her right leg...
and kicks him
in the stomach.
The guy doubles over.
She turns and
starts running...
escaping in the
opposite direction.
He gets up and
starts to pursue her.
He catches up with her.
He grabs her right arm...
twists it behind her back...
forces her palm against
her left shoulder blade...
and with his left hand,
he grips her throat.
He starts dragging
her backwards.
With her left hand, she
tries to hit him in the head.
She is unsuccessful...
so she decides
to jab him with her elbow.
The guy doubles over
once again.
She seizes the
opportunity to escape.
She is in flight.
The guy stands up again,
runs after her...
immobilizes her,
grabs her hair...
and throws her
on the ground.
After she falls down,
he bends over her...
and tries to thrust her
back against the dirt.
She manages to punch him
with her right fist.
She punches him again,
now with her left fist.
As the guy retreats...
she gets the chance...
to kick him
with her right foot.
The guy falls back.
She turns on
her hands and knees...
and attempts to break away.
The guy rises and,
with a swift movement...
in a sure plunge...
he grabs her leg...
pulls her towards him...
rolls her over...
and with slow movements,
crawling...
he slides on top of her.
- Should I make the room?
- Yes.
- Is it gonna take long?
- No, I'll make it fast.
- How fast?
- 10 or 15 minutes...
Good.
Go and wait
for me in the car.
Which one?
The grey one.
Slippers?
Spinach pie?
Piroski is the word
for spinach pie?
Yes.
Car?
Ice cube?
Road?
Bread?
Home?
Beach?
I don't know.
Magazine?
Can I offer you
another jello?
Got another one
in the freezer?
No, but I could stick one in.
Nah... Don't bother.
Hurry up! We won't make it.
When can I have
the videotape?
- As soon as I make the dub.
- When is that?
- When I get a chance.
- Wednesday?
- Which Wednesday?
- This Wednesday.
How about next Wednesday?
Alright.
How long was she
crawling on the grass?
Does it matter?
She looks a bit stiff.
You're cozy
when you're crawling?
Her neck position
shows that she was stiff.
It's probably her collar
that confuses you.
Her mouth is open.
Just enough
so she could breathe.
Did she sweat?
A little.
Did she ask for
a drink of water?
I don't remember.
That hole behind her...
what is it?
The pool.
That's what
the pool looks like?
I thought you wanted the photo
to check her clothing...
The shoes are on the
wooden thing with the slots.
As she is running...
the heels of her shoes...
the high heels of her shoes...
sink into the sand.
She loses her balance,
and falls down.
The guy swiftly
moves behind her.
Pulls her back vigorously,
dragging her to the car.
She resists, but he...
with increasing force...
he keeps pulling her.
He yanks her to the car.
He rolls her over, abruptly...
and thrusts her
against the hood.
She finds an
opportunity to escape.
She flees toward the beach.
She runs.
The guy spots her and
starts running after her.
He catches up with her.
With his left hand,
he grips her hair...
and throws her down
with great power.
After she's on the ground,
she stares at him...
she lifts her legs
to repel him...
to keep him away...
by kicking
her legs in the air...
and swinging her body...
in all directions.
He tries to find a way in.
He circles around her...
he keeps circling and circling.
Suddenly, he finds a way in...
and mounts her.
He blocks her.
His hands grab her
throat and squeeze it.
He chokes her,
until she loses consciousness.
Come in.
It itches.
It's bleeding.
Do you want
something to drink?
What have you got?
- Only water.
- Water.
- What?
- Tap water.
- Yes.
Thank you.
Do you want to listen
to some music?
Yes.
Where is your shoe?
Outside.
How much?
It's the same car.
The price can only
go up, not down.
How much?
- BMW.
- How much?
The owner...he passed away.
He drove it for six months....
It's brand new.
How much?
- 30,000 euros.
- 30,000...
Five years' guarantee...
brand new... power.
- Can't afford it.
- Think about it.
It'll change your life.
Ok?
Ok.
You grab your little shirt,
you lift it to your face...
till it reaches your eyes.
Until it reaches your eyes.
You stop there.
As you lift your shirt...
you raise your head...
revealing your eyes
that look straight at me.
You now remove
your shirt entirely...
and drop it
on top of the jacket.
You turn toward the painting.
You admire the poppies.
You stare at the sky
in the painting.
You suddenly raise your head
and stare at the ceiling.
With your index finger
and thumb...
you hold the waist
of your blue jeans...
and slowly lower them.
With your thumb
and index finger...
you hold the blue jeans...
and slowly you lower them.
You lower them.
Lower them.
Hold it right there.
You tilt your back
slightly forward.
Your back leans
like this...for a bit.
Once again,
two, three times...
left, right,
your head, your hair.
Now, as you are,
you turn...
you look at me...
you drop your hands...
and reach around to the clasp.
You undo the clasp.
Yes, like that. With both
hands, you undo the clasp.
And with your right hand...
you lower the left
strap of your bra.
And with your left hand,
you lower the right strap.
You turn once again
and look at the painting.
You sway your body...
sometimes to the left,
sometimes to the right.
You drop your bra
onto the sofa.
You drop your hands.
Simultaneously,
the bra falls on the sofa.
You make a leisurely turn...
and look at me.
You raise your hands, slowly...
and fix your hair.
Your right foot on the gas...
your left foot on the brake.
Right...gas.
Left... brake.
Are you hungry?
A little.
Do you want me
to make you a sandwich?
If you've got anything...
Should I put
mayonnaise on it?
Just a bit.
The bathroom?
Door on the left.