♫ I won't be sad, shaken or weak anymore ♫
♫ It's okay even if I fall, because I can get up again ♫
♫ Just like the stars in the sky and the birds in the clouds, I will rise ♫
♫ Hold my hand and walk with me, happy days are coming ♫
♫ I'm okay ♫
- Episode 14 -
Are you in insane? How could you think of going there by yourself?
Are you possibly really Seo Ah Shin's saseng fan?
How many times do I have to tell you?
I went because I was invited to Seo Ah Shin's birthday party.
Who would believe that?
Unless he's crazy, why would he invite Jumping Girl?
I can't even contact his manager. What am I supposed to do now?
Forget it.
I think I've been wasting my time.
Un..unnie!
Why are you doing this to my friend?
What are you talking about?
These paparazzi pictures. They look like they are in Seo Ah Shin's room.
What are you planning exactly?
I wanted to be with you more comfortably.
Thanks to Nam Sang Ah, it's possible.
We can't leave our scandal to spread.
It's to distract people's attentions.
I didn't want you to be harmed.
I am sorry about your friend's accident.
How? How are you going to repay her?
It wasn't just once, but twice!
What happened during Seo Ah Shin's birthday?
Sang-ah said that she was definitely invited by his manager. I heard you were supposed to go.
There was no birthday party, as far as I know.
Then...
Then... why did that punk did that to Seong Ah? Do you know anything?
Hey, Yenny Lee! You know something, right?
Where is he right now?
I'll get the car and be right back.
Who are you? Who are you that you do that to Sang-ah?
And who are you?
Don't mess with Sang Ah.
'Cause she's my girl!
I was doing it to protect my girl too.
You...
Hold on, hold on, why are you like this?
Leave me be.
Let go.
No.
Please empty your room by this month. I can't handle it because they do this non-stop.
What is this, seriously?
I am sorry. I will leave soon.
I am sor...
Unnie. Should I go to Australia?
It's just...I miss you.
Ga Eul?
Look here.
How old are you that you're fighting?
Who did you fight with?
I told you, I just fell.
I... I'm going to Australia next month.
I am going to help unnie and search up a school.
I am fine.
I talked to Yenny, and she does seemed to be worried about me a lot too.
I want to leave temporarily.
You said I can use this whenever I want to right?
And there's no time limit, right?
Here. Nam Sang Ah's free ticket.
I want to use it now.
Nam Sang Ah's free ticketTime period: Forever
subtitles ripped by riri13
Sang Ah...
I like you.
No, I love you.
From the moment I first saw you,
the time you drank the alcohol from the cold noodle bowl for me.
Sang Ah, don't run away.
I... will stay by your side.
I proposed to Sang Ah. So she can't go to Australia.
I didn't hear a reply yet but...
Don't worry. It will turn out fine.
Please leave for a moment.
I need to say something to Seo Ah Shin.
I...like you, Seo Ah Shin.
Seo Ah Shin, do you like me too?
What if I do?
If you really like me, reveal it to the world.
And don't make the wrong person be the victim.
I like the tenderhearted Seo Ah Shin more than the star Seo Ah Shin.
You know why I did that.
I don't want you to get hurt.
The moment I reveal that you are my girlfriend, the scar that you'll have...
Hiding me from the world is the biggest scar for me.
"I like Yenny Lee."
"This girl is my girl." Do you think I don't want to do that?
That day, the fans...to you...
What are you worrying about?
I am a black belt.
I am not scared of those fans at all.
This is Seo Ah Shin's concert ticket.Come with Sang Ah.
Would she want to go? I don't feel like it either.
I quit as his personal body guard.
I want to give a last chance for him to apologize to Sang Ah.
I don't know if it will work though.
Subtitles by The Jumping Girl Team @Viki
What is happening?
What is it?
Don't be ridiculous, Seo Ah Shin!
Who is that?