In black and white
Widescreen 1:1.66
And production sound
Shot in 11 weeks,
between July 1 and October 31, 1975,
between Lüneburg and Hof,
along the border with East Germany.
Last time you told me
you were a cinema musician?
I was.
Well...
my wife played the piano,
you know?
With me on the violin,
And if it was a big film,
like The Nibelungs or Ben-Hur,
then there was other music.
We added a cello, a double bass,
and a harmonium, you know?
Maybe drums and cymbals too.
It wasn't easy to play, you know?
- And they all lost their jobs?
Those were tough days,
when talkies came in.
I mean the real talkies.
At first it was on records, you know?
There were these big records.
Each of these films
had maybe 12, 14 small reels.
Of course it often happened
when a film broke
that the stuff didn't fit together,
so we had to spend nights on end
slicing it together, you know?
And still it was lousy.
And they booed us the next day.
That's how it was.
What was your biggest score?
I'd say The Nibelungs.
The film The Nibelungs
was in two parts.
The first was Siegfried's Death,
the second Kriemhild's Revenge.
Ben-Hur was
in two parts too, you know?
I think so.
I'm not sure though.
But I do know
that The Nibelungs
was in two parts.
If you had to live
from your theater alone, could you?
Impossible. Not nowadays.
Just imagine: In a few years there'll be
no theaters left in small towns.
I think where one theater
can survive -
For instance,
in places like around here,
like in Schirnding, Hohenberg,
Heckstädt, Thiersheim...
there used to be theaters everywhere,
in all these small market towns.
Today they're all gone.
But if there's just one left,
I'd say it'll still be going in 10 years.
If they're still making films.
I mean, if films
were still being made.
Could you make a living
off your theater at one time?
Yes. From 1951, you know?
I wasn't allowed to run one
for years, you know?
Because of the Third Reich
and so on.
Why weren't you allowed to?
Because I was a Party member.
SPD, you know?
I mean NSPDAD, or whatever
its name was, you know?
I had to sue from 1950-1951
to get my theater back, you know?
That happened
to lots of theater owners.
KINGS OF THE ROAD
How can you dream such crap?
They squeak, eh?
Take off your wet clothes.
I'll give you some of mine.
I need water for my truck.
Sleeping the day away!
Can I have this?
TERROR ATTACK IN JERUSALEM
PICTURE PALACE
I have to pee.
Your clothes are dry now.
What's the next big town?
I'm passing through Wolfsburg.
I'm Bruno Winter.
I'm Lander.
Sorry?
Robert Lander.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
How long have you done this
with the truck and the theaters?
Two years.
Alone?
Two years?
And where do you live?
Where's your home base?
The truck's registered in Munich.
That's where I bought it.
How do you cope...
with being alone?
I get by.
Better and better.
I can't.
Got any idea
where you might be heading?
Let's see.
This one goes to Lehrte.
Magdeburg, Dessau...
Braunschweig...
Helmstedt...
- I'll be in Helmstedt this afternoon.
At the Roxy.
Finished already?
Yes.
What day is it today?
Monday.
I just had a beer.
Yesterday I was still in Genoa.
That's why!
I'm tired. I'm not going on.
I can fix up another bed.
I'm going for a walk.
Down to the railway.
Do you know...
what a "loon" is?
That doesn't make sense.
How does the whole sentence go?
A waterbird.
A diver.
Morning.
Let's get going.
Like some music?
He's gone.
Kamikaze's gone.
Our daredevil friend,
the hell driver.
Oh, sorry.
I've got something for breakfast.
Fine.
The cup's fucked.
Do I get a new one?
Where is it?
Still okay.
It'll fall off again!
Come on in, children!
When can we get started?
The children are all worked up.
I didn't think
I'd have to repair a speaker.
Good thing I had a spare.
We've been waiting half an hour.
The children
can't wait much longer.
We'll install this.
Then we're all set.
Now be quiet!
The men have
to do some repairs.
We'll start in five minutes.
They're taking a long time!
Quiet now,
or we'll all go back to school.
Can't see a thing!
You want to see the film with sound,
so they have to repair the speaker.
Be quiet!
Vacation starts tomorrow.
Then you can do
whatever you like.
Turn out the light!
The next turnoff leads
to the village of "Powerless."
Only one road leads there,
a dead end.
About four miles
there and back.
Not worth it.
Just like any other village.
- Ever been there?
- Last time I noticed it on the map...
so off I went to "Powerless."
The village on the other side
of the hill is called "Peaceless."
And the hill's called...
"Dead Man."
"Powerless," "Peaceless,"
"Dead Man"...
I don't believe it!
I bought a few things.
I couldn't find a shirt.
They only have high collars here.
They chafe my neck.
It's terribly sticky.
A hot wind.
I feel like going for a swim.
Later.
In a quarry pond.
I don't have time.
I can always go on alone.
A nine-digit number.
A matter of life and death.
- What was the town where...?
- Schöningen.
Standing there on the ladder...
I suddenly freaked out.
I was watching my own shadow,
and in that moment
I noticed you watching me.
That was it.
I wanted to stop right there.
I was in a rage.
And helpless.
Why did I get involved in this?
But you went on acting the fool,
so all I could do
was join you again.
That made me even angrier.
Same thing with me.
What?
Cut it out!
I'm not sleeping
in the cabin again.
Sleep wherever you like.
- How was the sausage?
- Good.
Do you do anything else
except "test-driving"?
I'm a pediatrician.
- What?
A sort of children's doctor.
In Genoa I separated from my wife.
I didn't ask you about that.
There's no need
to tell me your stories.
So what would you like to hear?
Who you are.
I am my story.
The mattress is in the back.
It's not locked.
Take a cushion.
What a noise!
Beat it!
What's wrong?
Can I help you?
Leave me alone!
I'm not hurt.
This isn't my blood.
I wasn't even in the car.
It's my wife's coat!
There was some word...
a remark.
Yesterday.
It started something.
And then she drove into a tree.
We...
We spent a few days...
in a village inn.
There were these beds,
twin beds,
and the kitchen beneath...
When you opened the window -
And then she said, "I'm fed up!
Fed up with the bed,
the washbasin, the kitchen,
the lamp, the painting..."
Suddenly
the smell from the kitchen -
She'd had enough.
Go back!
She even told me
she'd drive into a tree.
She told me so!
That's a kind of blackmail.
I told the police...
that she told me
she would drive into -
They couldn't care less.
They...
completely -
An accident!
She was still warm.
She's dead.
I wonder if she knew that.
Life is all there is!
Death doesn't really exist.
Kamikaze...
have you got a tenant?
Sure.
There was some ink...
that you could erase
old writing with...
and write something new
at the same time.
I kept thinking
and writing down the same thing.
Even when I kept waking up
from this dream.
Abstract repetitions...
processes, paths...
that I experienced
and wrote down simultaneously.
That means...
dreaming was a form of writing
in circles.
Until I dreamt up the idea
of using another ink.
With this new ink...
there were suddenly
new things I could think...
and see...
and write.
Everything was solved.
No.
You're still in a fix!
Is the car still there?
Yes, it's still by the tree.
- Can I stay here?
- What?
In the truck,
till they tow her car.
No, we have to move on.
I've arranged it all.
They tow it away this morning.
Can't do it.
I couldn't stand
seeing the car again!
You don't have to pass it.
We've got to move on.
We don't.
I don't.
What did I tell you yesterday?
You weren't feeling well.
Because of the accident.
That'll do!
They're towing away the car.
Tell me when it's gone.
It's being lifted up
at the front now.
A tow truck with a crane.
The car's being pulled
up the bank.
Now it's on the road.
They're leaving. No -
They're turning.
Now they're leaving.
And now I can
no longer see them.
MORE THAN ONE MILLION
UNEMPLOYED
"I'm going to my father's place
in Ostheim.
I know your route. R."
Father.
Robert!
Just listen.
Still doing everything
on your own?
Does your paper
still come out every day?
No...
only three times a week.
You haven't had any repairs
done to the house?
You know...
this whole time
I've been away...
these past 10 years...
each time
I thought or talked
about something,
I always kept imagining
to see it in print right away.
That you immediately printed it.
- I know that myself.
- Be quiet!
Listen, once and for all!
If you start talking, I'll leave.
Last time I tried to talk to you,
I had to listen all the time.
I stood next to your desk,
all embarrassed...
because I didn't want to admit...
that you're a gabber...
that I think you're gabby.
Mother never had her say either.
That's what I wanted
to talk about:
that she didn't get anywhere
in her life with you.
Shut up!
Why...
didn't you...
let her...
Have you got a light?
I just won it.
Aren't you cold?
The sun was shining just now.
A Führer fire!
Is it too early
to go on the ride?
The ticket booth is still closed.
Couldn't I pay you?
- Don't you have anything smaller?
- No.
Hold the old fellow.
You could ride forever on that!
Is she with you?
How about an ice cream?
What if I get changed?
This evening?
I'll be at the movies tonight.
Here? I'll be coming!
This is my automatic press.
I bought it three years ago.
- I couldn't care less.
I want to talk to you
about my mother.
I know that!
But you haven't said
a word in two hours.
Listen to me anyway.
I want you
to listen to me!
Has the feature started yet?
Ten minutes ago.
But you haven't missed anything.
You tricked me.
I don't know...
But you got all dressed up!
Waste of time.
Or do we go
to the movies after all?
Best seats?
Yes. Two.
Eight marks.
Don't you have anything smaller?
At least give me some almonds.
You owe me two marks.
No, I'll treat you
to an ice after the show.
Okay?
Time to go in,
or your tickets will expire.
Your wife... I never met her.
We don't live together anymore.
I'm one up on you:
I separated from my wife.
- Want some coffee too?
- No, thanks.
Oh, of course.
- Just relax, my boy!
- No.
You're bursting with juices, right?
But don't lose control now!
Yes...
But Linda, I'm no rogue.
Yuri, I think you're crazy, but...
Don't you like the film?
Words fail me.
Besides, it's out of focus
and too dark in the middle.
And it's badly framed.
I'm afraid that's Greek to me.
Haven't been here long?
Just helping out my grandma.
Honestly!
You could call the projectionist.
He's just helping out too.
What do I say?
I'll see to it.
- Mother, I have a question.
- Yes, son?
- When is fruit ripe?
- When it falls into your lap.
The picture's out of focus.
Says who?
Me.
Looks fucking good!
Yeah. Good fucking.
What do we have here?
Put it back!
That's why the picture's
dark in the middle!
I'm doing this
for nothing anyway!
That's only right.
Son of a bitch!
I'm off!
You can't do that!
Come on. I'll put it back.
Go fuck yourself!
Are you leaving?
I don't believe it!
Shit!
- What's with the projectionist?
- He left.
- What did you do to him?
- Look, I have to change the reels.
- What do I do without a projectionist?
- He'll be back.
Don't worry.
I'll fill in tonight.
Do you know how?
Don't start pretending again.
Fuck this!
Do you intend to stay the night?
Yes.
I'll show you something.
Action, sex!
Ninety minutes of film
that TV could never -
Brutality, action, sex!
Ninety minutes of film
that TV could never -
The other day a woman had
vaginal cramps here in the theater.
My grandpa
had to call an ambulance.
The woman and her lover
were carried off together.
He couldn't get out of her.
This morning I met a man
whose wife
killed herself last night.
She drove into a tree.
Yesterday I saw a woman
sitting in her garden in the sun
under a hair dryer,
her hands folded in her lap.
- Did you talk to that man?
- Yes.
He said,
"Life is all there is."
But which life?
How do you live?
I live alone with my daughter.
And that stays like that.
Did you know
that my mother died
when I was born?
What?
Now what?
Now I'm in a fix too.
What?
I'm tired.
Father.
Have you got a pen?
Paper, too?
On the back.
Don't you need it anymore?
Keep it.
It's from Wolfsburg.
I'm leaving.
It's a good thing you're here.
Wait a sec.
HOW TO RESPECT A WOMAN
You didn't sleep much, huh?
It wasn't a bad night, really,
compared with the last few
in your traveling museum.
- Did you get what you wanted?
- What do you mean?
You published
a "special edition" overnight, right?
It was supposed
to be a speech, really.
Did you have to make it?
I mean, shouldn't you have left
the old man in peace?
I always have.
He's never left me in peace.
Maybe you can imagine.
No. I never had a father.
He got lost in the war.
How long
since you last saw him?
Since my mother's death.
Eight years!
I thought the King of the Road
wasn't interested in stories.
Where are we heading now?
- I've got business in Hassfurt.
- At the C&C Cinema?
- You know it?
Oh, yes.
As a kid I spent
all my money there.
Secretly. I didn't dare go
to the movies in my town.
Didn't you forget
a question mark in your headline?
What?
No, I left it out on purpose.
Did you learn all that -
typesetting and printing?
Of course.
Listen, do you really have to go
to the next theater?
No.
Let's go somewhere else then.
Like Genoa?
Not necessarily.
Where then?
Where did you grow up?
On the Rhine.
Just you and your mother?
Yeah.
Let's go there.
Everything looks the same.
We better hurry.
Wind it up.
Paul's still here.
Paul!
This is Bruno.
Remember
your dad's old BMW bike?
The one we used
to cruise around on?
Without a license!
You still got that old crate?
It's mine now.
And it still runs like a dream.
Is it still in the garage?
Who do you think I met in Sicily?
On Mount Etna.
"Softly."
"Softly"!
Geography.
"Stand up, Paul!
Sit down, gasbag!"
As security.
Beat it, cat!
Paul, you still owe me something.
Has he got
a driving license at all?
He's Mike Hailwood's brother!
Here!
On the island?
Yeah.
There's a house.
In summer
you can't see it from the bank.
With that boat?
The current's very strong!
Don't worry.
I used to watch how it's done.
Can we sleep in the house?
No.
My, oh my!
"Shortly before dawn..."
What a noise!
They're dredging the fairway.
Can you still ride
the motorcycle?
I think so.
I'm too tired.
I did sleep.
You're done?
Yes, sure.
But I got talked
into showing the film tonight.
The projectionist is sick,
and his grandma -
How much do you get?
Peanuts.
Otherwise they'd have to cancel.
Can you get me a free ticket?
You can have some peanuts.
I'm too good-natured.
- Has its good sides.
"Good-natured"!
How long does this go on?
Three more reels.
How about leaving one out?
Or two?
Let's get going!
- Stay cool.
- Let's not be conspicuous.
- Be inconspicuous.
- Walk, don't run!
Hang on!
We have to go that way!
- That way?
A waste of time...
What?
What's up?
You said something.
What? What did you say?
Everything's gone to sleep.
Coffee.
I'm going to make me
some coffee.
World champion.
"Where the organ is."
Four letters.
"Loft."
Right.
Been down to the river?
Yes.
Think I could use the phone?
If it's not long-distance.
But it is.
It's me.
How are you?
- Are you the projectionist?
- Yes.
Come along.
- They didn't teach you much, huh?
- I learned by watching.
You know
what a Maltese cross is?
"Maltese"?
Some sort of booze?
Didn't you notice
the picture was unsteady?
No more than usual.
Everything's filthy!
This is chipped.
Without this little thing
there'd be no film industry.
It draws the film
24 times a second
one frame further on.
It converts the torque
into a forward movement.
That's clever.
Where'd you get the jukebox?
I swapped it for a projector.
It's great.
And you?
Had an accident?
Yes, on my motorcycle.
Go on.
I've seen it done better.
Do we carry
that socle down too?
Yes.
I'm glad we went to the Rhine.
For the first time I see myself...
as someone who's gone
through a certain time,
and that time is my story.
That feeling is quite comfortable.
Shit!
This is the border!
We can't go any further.
Switch on the full beam.
Watch out! They'll shoot you.
Bring the whiskey!
From the Yanks.
Holiday Inn?
Not really, but still...
beds, pictures.
Let's get the mattresses
out of the truck.
- Here's something for you!
- Don't talk crap.
A pediatrician
shouldn't be so sensitive.
I'm not a pediatrician.
You said you were.
Well, yes...
I work in a border area
between linguistics
and pediatrics.
- So you are one.
I don't treat anybody.
I evaluate research
on the first months
of learning to read and write.
What happens then?
At that stage...
letters and numbers
are still an adventure.
Later, when writing
becomes routine...
this imaginative phase
is forgotten.
Only the impediments
sometimes occasioned
by these fantasies remain.
There was one boy...
To him lines were paths...
along which the letters moved
by means of a motorbike,
the pen.
"I" and "E"
always rode together.
"I" was clever and sharp.
That makes me "I" and you "E."
And for him...
"L" was stupid and lazy...
a crook...
living in the underworld...
all dirty and evil.
"Mean."
What?
Sometimes I have
a tune in my head
for hours on end,
with English lyrics,
without paying attention
to the words,
and suddenly -
Once I had a quarrel
with my girlfriend,
and I hummed
a tune the whole time,
even while
she was screaming at me.
Then I left the house,
and outside I suddenly
remembered the lyrics.
The Yanks have colonized
our subconscious!
You were not ashamed
to really give it a try!
I even got
the American operator.
I should've asked
for Lynchburg, Tennessee.
Why don't you go back
to your wife
if you can't stand
being without her?
That's impossible.
Why is that?
I'm no longer myself
when I'm with her.
Then why do you keep
calling her?
I'm afraid she might try
to kill herself.
You fucking coward!
You're afraid of yourself.
That way you'll really kill her.
She'll get by.
- You don't even know her.
- But I know you!
You don't know
what you're talking about.
You sit in your truck
like it's some kind of bunker...
and talk big
about "being alone."
Nothing can happen to you.
Enough has happened to me!
But not anymore!
You're as good as dead!
Is there any desire left in you?
Asshole!
I have a great desire.
For a woman.
Any woman.
Every woman makes me yearn.
I think every man feels that way.
And because I know this
and can't pretend
not to know it...
I'm keeping away from women.
I know she could be
a different woman from the one she is.
I don't know
how one can live with a woman.
If it isn't possible...
then it has to become possible.
It's no life at all...
if you're no longer able
to imagine any changes...
nor want any.
Of course I want...
to be one with a woman.
But just as much
I want to be alone.
I will never give that up again.
A contradiction
you have to put up with.
Nor do I believe...
in...
For instance, when you're fucking,
you're inside a woman.
But have you ever had the feeling
of really being with her?
I've always felt lonely
inside a woman.
Lonely to the marrow.
I can't imagine you fucking at all.
I can see you, though.
You're panting
like in a badly dubbed porno film.
"Everything must change.
So long. R."
What are you writing?
I'm describing a train station.
Everything I see.
And what do you see?
The tracks,
the gravel, the timetable,
the sky,
the clouds.
A man with a suitcase.
An empty suitcase!
A grin.
A black eye.
A fist...
throwing a stone.
- It's as easy as that?
- That easy!
If you give me your notebook,
you get my glasses
and my suitcase.
That's a good deal.
Good.
I'll do my best.
BORDER
Kamikaze,
don't think I didn't see you!
Getting by better and better, eh?
- Not showing anymore?
- No.
But I keep the theater ready
to reopen any time.
"Film is the art of seeing,"
my father said.
That's why
I can't show these films
that are nothing but exploitation
of all that can be exploited
in people's eyes and minds.
I won't be forced to show films
where people stagger out stunned
and rigid with stupidity...
films that kill
any joy of life inside them...
and destroy any feeling
for themselves and the world.
My father wanted this town
to go on having a theater.
Me too.
But the way it is now,
it's better to have no theater
than a theater
the way it is now.