LENFILM
First Artistic Association
KING LEAR
Based on the tragedy by Shakespeare
Written and directed by
Grigory KOZINTSEV
Director of Photography
Ionas GRITSIUS
Production Designers - Ye. YENEJ
V. ULITKO, S. VIRSALADZE
Music by Dmitri SHOSTAKOVICH
Sound by E. VANUNTS
Cast:
King Lear - Jyuri JYARVET
Goneril - E. RADZINYR
Regan - G. VOLCHEK
Cordelia - V. SHENDRIKOVA
Fool - O. DAL
Gloster - K. SEBRIS
Edgar - L. MERZIN
Edmund - R. ADOMAITIS
Kent - V. YEMELYANOV
Duke of Cornwall - A. VOKACH
Duke of Albany - D. BANIONIS
Oswald - A. PETRENKO
King of France - I. BUDRAITIS
I thought the king had more affected
the Duke of Albany
than Cornwall.
It did always seem so to us.
But now,
in the division of the kingdom,
it appears not which of the dukes
he values most.
For equalities are so weighed,
that curiosity in neither
can make choice
of either's moiety.
Is not this your son, my lord?
I have so often blushed
to acknowledge him,
that now I am brazed to it.
I cannot conceive you.
This young fellow's mother could:
She had a son for her cradle before
she had a husband for her bed.
Do you smell a fault?
I cannot wish the fault undone,
the issue of it
being so proper.
But I have a son, sir,
by order of law,
some year elder than this.
Attend the Lords of France
and Burgundy, Gloster.
I shall, my liege.
Meantime we shall express
our darker purpose.
Know all.
Know all:
We have divided
in three our kingdom.
Tis our intent to shake all cares
from our age,
conferring them on younger strengths,
while we unburdened crawl
toward death.
Our son of Cornwall,
and you, our son of Albany, we have
this hour a constant will to publish
our daughters' several dowers,
that future strife
may be prevented now.
The princes,
France and Burgundy,
great rivals in our youngest
daughter's love,
long here are to be answered.
Tell me, my daughters...
which of you
doth love us most?
That we our largest bounty may extend
where nature doth with merit
challenge.
Goneril, our eldest born,
speak first.
I love you more than
words can wield the matter.
Dearer than eyesight,
space and liberty,
beyond what can be valued,
rich or rare.
No less than life, with grace,
health, beauty, honour.
As much as child e'er loved,
or father found.
A love that makes my speech unable,
beyond all manner so much I love you.
What shall Cordelia do?
Of all these bounds, even from this
line to this,
we make thee lady: To thine and
Albany's issue be this perpetual.
What says our second daughter,
our dearest Regan,
wife to Cornwall? Speak.
I am made of that self metal
as my sister,
and prize me at her worth.
In my true heart
I find she names my very deed
of love,
only she comes too short.
And find am alone felicitate
in your dear highness' love.
In your dear highness' love.
To thee and thine hereditary ever
remain this ample third of our fair
kingdom.
Then poor Cordelia!
And yet not so,
since my love's more richer
than my tongue.
Now, ourjoy,
what can you say to draw a third
more opulent than your sisters'?
Nothing, my lord.
Nothing?
Nothing.
Nothing will come of nothing.
Speak again.
Unhappy that I am, I cannot heave
my heart into my mouth.
I love your majesty
according to my bond,
nor more nor less.
Cordelia, mend your speech a little,
lest it may mar your fortunes.
Good my lord,
you have begot me,
bred me, loved me.
I return those duties back
as are right fit:
Obey you, love you,
and most honour you.
Why have my sisters husbands,
if they say they love you all?
Haply, when I shall wed,
that lord shall carry half my love
with him, half my care and duty.
Sure, I shall never marry
like my sisters,
to love my father all.
But goes thy heart with this?
Ay, good my lord.
So young, and so untender?
So young, my lord, and true.
Let it be so, -
thy truth, then, be your dower!
For, by the sacred
radiance of the sun,
here I disclaim all my paternal care,
propinquity and property of blood,
and as a stranger to my heart and me
hold thee, from this, for ever!
Peace, Kent!
I loved her most,
and thought to set my rest
on her kind nursery.
Hence, and avoid my sight!
Call France!
Call Burgundy!
Cornwall and Albany, with my two
daughters' dowers digest this third.
Let pride, which she calls plainness,
marry her.
Ourself, by monthly course, with
reservation of an hundred knights,
shall our abode make with you
by due turns.
We still retain the name, and all
the additions to a king,
the sway, revenue, execution
of the rest be yours.
Royal Lear, whom I have ever honoured
as my king,
as my great patron thought on
in my prayers...
The bow is bent and drawn!
Make from the shaft!
Let it fall rather, though the fork
invade the region of my heart.
Be Kent unmannerly,
when Lear is mad.
What wouldst thou want?
That duty shall have dread to speak,
when power to flattery bows?
Answer my life my judgement,
thy youngest daughter
does not love thee least.
Nor are those empty-hearted
whose low sound
reverbs no hollowness.
Kent, on thy life, no more.
My life I never held but as a pawn
to wage against thy enemies.
No fear to lose it,
thy safety being the motive.
- Out of my sight!
- See better, Lear.
Now, by Apollo!
Now, by Apollo, king,
thou swear'st thy gods in vain.
O, vassal! Miscreant!
Dear sir, forbear.
Hear me, recreant!
On thine allegiance, hear me!
If tomorrow thy banished trunk
be found in our dominions,
the moment is thy death!
Fare thee well, king!
Sith thus thou wilt appear,
freedom leaves hence,
and banishment is here.
Here's France and Burgundy,
my noble lord.
My Lord of Burgundy,
we first address towards you,
who with this king
have rivalled for our daughter.
When she was dear to us,
we did hold her so,
but now her price is fallen.
Will you, with those infirmities she
owes, dowered with our curse,
and stranger'd with our oath,
take her or leave her?
I tell you all her wealth.
Pardon me, royal sir.
For you, great king,
I would not from your love
make such a stray,
to match you where I hate.
Must be a faith that reason without
miracle should never plant in me.
I yet beseech your majesty,
if for I want that glib and oily art,
to speak and purpose not,
that you make known
it is no vicious blot, murder,
or foulness that hath deprived me
of your grace and favour,
but even for want of that
for which I an richer, -
a still-soliciting eye, and such
a tongue as I am glad I have not.
Thou hast her, France:
Let her be thine!
For we have no such daughter!
Time shall unfold what pleated
cunning hides:
Who covers faults, at last
shame them derides.
An hundred knights to add to retinue!
A hundred knights to add to retinue!
Saddle the horses!
Call the train together!
The barbarian that makes his genera-
tion messes to gorge his appetite,
shall to my bosom be as well relieved,
as thou my sometime daughter.
Thou, nature, art my goddess!
To thy law my services are bound.
Wherefore should I permit deprive me,
if I'm 12 moonshines lag of a brother?
Why bastard?
Wherefore base?
Why brand they us with base?
Who, in the lusty stealth of nature,
take more composition and quality
than doth, within a dull, stale,
tired bed,
go to th'creating a whole tribe
of fobs?
Well, my legitimate!
Kent banished thus!
And the king gone tonight!
Subscribed his power!
All this done upon the gad!
Edmund, how now!
What news?
So please your lordship, none.
Why so earnestly seek you
to put up that letter?
I know no news,
my lord.
What paper were you reading?
Nothing, my lord.
Why, then, that terrible dispatch of
it into your pocket? Let's see.
Sir, pardon me.
It is a letter from my brother.
I find it not fit for your
o'er-Iooking.
Give me the letter.
I shall offend,
either to detain or give it.
I hope, for my brother's
justification, he wrote this
but as a taste of my virtue.
<<The reverence of age makes the world
bitter to the best of our times,
keeps our fortunes from us till our
oldness cannot relish them.
I find an idle bondage in
the oppression of aged tyranny,
who sways,
not as it hath power,
but as it is suffered.
Come to me, that of this
I may speak more.
If our father would sleep
till I waked him,
you should enjoy half his
revenue for ever,
and live the beloved
of your brother, Edgar>>.
Hum... Conspiracy!
O villain!
Abhorred villain!
Unnatural, detested,
brutish villain!
Where is he?
Suspend your indignation
till you can derive from him
better testimony of his intent.
Edmund, seek him out,
wind me into him.
These late eclipses
in the sun and moon
portend no good to us:
Brothers divide,
in cities, mutinies,
in countries, discord,
in palaces, treason.
And the bond cracked
twixt son and father.
We have seen the best of our time.
- When saw you my father last?
- The night gone by.
- Spake you with him?
- Ay, two hours together.
Parted you in good terms?
Found you no displeasure in him?
None at all.
Bethink yourself wherein you may
have offended him.
And at my entreaty
forbear his presence
till some little time hath qualified
the heat of his displeasure.
Some villain
hath done me wrong.
Have a continent forbearance till
the speed of his rage goes slower.
Retire with me to my lodging.
There's my key.
If you do stir abroad, go armed.
Armed, brother!
He hath no good meaning toward you.
What I have told you is nothing
like the image and horror of it.
By the surfeit of our own
behaviour,
we make guilty of our disasters
the sun, the moon, and the stars.
As if we were fools
by heavenly compulsion,
by an enforced obedience
of planetary influence.
And admirable evasion
of whore-master man,
to lay his goatish disposition
to the charge of a star!
Fut, I should have been
what I am,
had the maidenliest star
in the firmament
twinkled on my bastardizing.
Let me not stay a jot for dinner!
Go get it ready!
Dinner, ho, dinner!
Where's my fool?
Go you, and call my fool hither.
You, you sirrah, where's my daughter?
So please you...
What says the fellow there?
Call the clotpoll back!
Where's my fool?
I think the world's asleep.
Where's that mongrel?
He says,
your daughter is not well.
Why came not the slave back to me?
He answered me,
he would not.
He would not!
My lord, to my judgement,
your highness is not entertained
with that ceremonious affection
as you were wont.
But where's my fool?
I have not seen him this two days.
Since my young lady's going into
France, the fool hath much pined away.
No more of that. Go you,
and tell my daughter
I would speak with her.
Go you, call hither my fool!
O, you sir,
you, come you hither, sir.
Who am I, sir?
My lady's father.
>?
My lord's knave!
- I'll not be struck, my lord!
- Nor tript neither, football player.
I thank thee, fellow. What art thou?
A man, sir. A very honest-
hearted fellow,
and as poor as the king.
If thou be as poor for a subject
as he is for a king,
thou art poor enough.
What wouldst thou?
To serve you.
If I like thee no worse after dinner,
I will not part from thee yet.
There's earnest of thy service.
Let me hire him too.
How now, my pretty knave!
How dost thou?
- You were best take my coxcomb.
- Why, fool?
For taking one's part
that's out of favour.
This fellow hath banisht
two one's daughters,
and did the third a blessing
against his will.
If thou follow him, thou must
needs wear my coxcomb.
Take heed, sirrah,
the whip.
Truth's a dog must to kennel,
he must be whipped out,
when Lady the brach
may stand by the fire and stink.
A bitter fool!
Dost thou know the difference between
a bitter fool and a sweet fool?
No, lad. Teach me.
That lord that counselled thee
To give away thy land,
Come place him here by me,
Do thou for him stand.
The sweet and bitter fool
Will presently appear,
The one in motley here,
The other found out there.
Dost thou call me fool?
All thy other titles thou hast given
away, that thou wast born with.
This is not altogether fool.
Fools had never less grace in a year,
For wise men are grown foppish,
And know not how their wits to wear,
Their manners are so apish.
When were you wont to be so full
of songs?
Ever since thou madest
thy daughters thy mothers:
For when thou gavest them the rod,
and putt'st down thine own breeches.
Then they for sudden joy did weep,
And I for sorrow sung,
That such a king should play bo-peep,
And go the fools among.
Prithee, nuncle, keep a schoolmaster
that can teach thy fool to lie.
An you lie, we'll have you whipped.
Thy daughters will have me whipped
for speaking true,
thou'It for lying, and sometimes I'm
whipped for holding my peace.
I had rather be any kind o'thing
than a fool.
And yet I would not
be thee, nuncle.
Thou hast pared thy wit o'both sides,
and left nothing in the middle.
Here comes one of the parings.
How now, daughter!
What makes that frontlet on?
Methinks you are too much
of late in the frown.
Thou wast a pretty fellow
when thou hadst no need
to care for her frowning.
Yes, forsooth, I will hold my tongue.
So your face bids me...
though you say nothing.
Not only, sir, this your
all-licensed fool,
but other of your insolent retinue
do hourly carp and quarrel.
I had thought, by making this
well known unto you,
to have found a safe redress,
but now grow fearful
that you protect this course.
Which if you should,
the fault would not scape censure,
which might in their working
do you that offence,
which else were shame,
that then necessity
will call discreet proceeding.
For, you trow, nuncle.
The hedge-sparrow fed
The cuckoo so long,
That it had its head
Bit off by its young!
So, out went the candle,
and we were left darkling.
Are you our daughter?
I would you would make use
of that good wisdom,
and put away these dispositions,
that transform you from what you are.
Doth any here know me?
Why, this is not Lear!
Doth Lear walk thus?
Speak thus?
Where are his eyes?
Either his notion weakens,
or his discernings are lethargied?
Ha! Waking? 'Tis not so...
Who is it that can tell me
who I am?
Lear's shadow.
I would learn that.
[Skipped item nr. 368]
Knowledge, and reason,
I should be false-persuaded
I had daughters.
Your name, fair gentlewoman?
This admiration, sir,
is much of the savour
of other your new pranks.
I do beseech you to understand
my purposes aright.
Here do you keep a hundred
knights and squires,
men so disordered, so debosht,
and bold,
that this our court
shows like a riotous inn.
The shame itself doth speak
for instant remedy:
Be, then, desired by her,
that else will take
the thing she begs.
A little to disquantity
your train,
And the remainder,
that shall still depend,
to be such men
which know themselves and you.
Darkness and devils!
Saddle my horses!
Call my train together!
Degenerate bastard!
I'll not trouble thee.
Yet have I left a daughter.
Woe, that too late repents.
Saddle my horses!
Is it your will? Speak, sir.
Prepare my horses.
Pray, sir, be patient.
Detested kite! Thou liest!
Beat at this gate, that let thy folly
in, and thy dearjudgement out!
Go, go, my people!
I am guiltless, as I am ignorant
of what hath moved you.
It may be so, my lord.
Hear, nature, hear,
dear goddess, hear!
Into her womb convey sterility!
If she must teem,
create her child that be a thwart
disnatured torment to her!
That she may feel
how sharper
than a serpent's tooth it is
to have a thankless child.
Away, away!
But let his disposition have that
scope that dotage gives it.
What, Oswald, ho!
This man hath had good counsel:
A hundred knights!
On every fancy, he may enguard
his dotage with their powers,
and hold our lives in mercy.
Oswald, I say!
Well, you may fear too far.
Safer than trust too far.
What he hath uttered
I have writ my sister.
If she sustain him and his hundred
knights, when I've showed th'unfitness.
Take you some company,
and away to horse.
Inform her full of my
particular fear.
This milky gentleness and course
of yours,
though I condemn not,
yet, under pardon,
you are much more attaskt
for want of wisdom
than praised for harmful mildness.
A fox, when one has caught her,
And such a daughter,
Should sure to the slaughter,
If my cap would buy a halter,
So the fool follows after.
Old fond eyes,
beweep this cause again.
I have another daughter.
With her nails she'll flay
thy wolvish visage.
I'll resume the shape
which thou dost think
I have cast off for ever.
Thou shalt find it,
I warrant thee!
Go to the Duchess of Cornwall
with these letters.
If your diligence be not speedy,
I shall be there afore you.
I will not sleep, my lord,
till I have delivered your letter.
Nuncle, canst tell
why a snail has a house?
No.
To put's head in,
not to give it away
to his daughters,
and leave his horns without a case.
O, let me not be mad,
not mad, sweet heaven!
Keep me in temper:
I would not be mad!
Brother, a word!
Descend: Brother, I say!
My father watches: Fly this place.
Intelligence is given
where you are hid.
You have now the good
advantage of the night.
I hear my father coming.
In cunning I must draw my sword
upon you. Seem to defend yourself.
Fly, brother!
Torches, torches!
So, farewell.
Father, father! Stop, stop!
No help?
Where's the villain?
Here stood he,
his sharp sword out,
conjuring the moon
to stand's auspicious mistress.
Look, sir, I bleed.
Where is the villain?
Fled this way, sir,
when by no means he could...
Pursue him, ho!
Go after.
By no means what?
Persuade me to the murder
of your lordship.
How now, my noble friend!
I have heard strange news.
If it be true, all vengeance comes too
short. How dost, my lord?
O madam, my old heart is cracked,
is cracked!
What, did my father's godson
seek your life? Your Edgar?
O lady, shame would have it hid!
Was he not companion with the riotous
knights that tend upon my father?
I know not.
Tis too bad, too bad.
Yes, madam, he was of that consort.
No marvel, then, 'tis they have put
him on the old man's death,
to have the expense and waste
of his revenues.
I have been from my sister
well informed of them.
If they come to sojourn at my house,
I'll not be there.
Edmund, I hear that you have shown
your father a child-like office.
- Is he pursued?
- Ay, my good lord.
For you, Edmund,
whose virtue and obedience
doth this instant
so much commend itself,
you shall be ours.
You know not
why we came to visit you.
Our father he hath writ, so hath
our sister, of differences,
which I best thought it fit
to answer from your home.
Lay comforts to your bosom,
and bestow your needful counsel
to our business,
which craves the instant use.
I serve you, madam,
Your Graces are right welcome.
Filthy coward!
Draw, you rascal!
Come your ways!
Help, ho!
Stand, rogue, stand!
You neat slave, strike!
You come with letters
against the king?!
What is the matter?
With you, goodman boy,
an you please?
Weapons! Arms!
What's the matter here?
Keep peace,
upon your lives!
He dies that strikes again.
What is the matter?
The messengers from our sister
and the king.
- What is your difference? Speak.
- I am scarce in breath, my lord.
No marvel. You cowardly rascal.
One-trunk-inheriting slave,
a superserviceable rogue,
one that wouldst be a bawd
in way of good service!
Speak yet, how grew your quarrel?
This ancient ruffian, whose life
I've spared at suit of his gray beard.
Let me tread him into mortar, and
daub the wall of a jakes with him.
Peace, sirrah! You beastly knave,
know you no reverence?
Yes, sir,
but anger hath a privilege.
Why art thou angry?
That such a slave should wear a sword,
who wears no honesty.
Such smiling rogues as these
renege, affirm and turn their
halcyon beaks
with every gale and vary
of their masters,
knowing naught, like dogs,
but following.
Smile you my speeches,
as I were a fool?
What, art thou mad, old fellow?
How fell you out? Say that.
No contraries hold more antipathy
than I and such a knave.
- What's his offence?
- His countenance likes me not.
No more, perchance, does mine,
nor his, nor hers?
Sir, 'tis my occupation
to be plain:
I have seen better faces in my time
than that I see this instant.
Fetch forth the stocks!
You reverend braggart,
we'll teach you!
I am too old to learn.
Call not your stocks for me.
I serve the king, on whose
employment I was sent to you.
You shall do small respect,
stocking his messenger.
Fetch forth the stocks!
There shall he sit till noon.
Why, madam, if I were your father's
dog, not messenger...
Sir, being his knave, I will!
This is a fellow of the self-same
colour our sister speaks of.
Let me beseech your Grace
not to do so.
The good king his master
will check him for it.
I'll answer that.
Put in his legs!
I am sorry for thee,
tis the duke's pleasure.
I'll entreat for thee.
Pray, do not, sir,
I've watched, and travelled hard,
a good man's fortune may grow out
at heels. Give you good morrow!
The duke's to blame in this.
This strange that they should depart,
and not send back my messenger.
As I learned, the night before there
was no purpose in them of this remove.
Poor Tom's a-cold...
The foul fiend follows me...
Away!
Croack not, black angel!
I have no food for thee.
The foul fiend vexes him.
He hath led him through fire
and through flame...
Fie, foh, and fum!
Bless thee from whirlwinds,
star-blasting, and taking!
Hail to thee, noble master!
He wears cruel garters.
Horses are tied by the heads,
dogs and bears by the neck,
monkeys by the loins,
and men by the legs.
When a man's over-lusty at legs,
then he wears
wooden nether-stocks.
What's he that hath so much
thy place mistook
to set thee here?
It is both he and she, -
your son and daughter.
- No.
- Yes.
- No, I say.
- I say, yes.
No, no, they would not!
Winter's not gone yet,
if the wild-geese fly that way.
Fathers that wear rags
Do make their children blind,
But fathers that bear bags
Shall see their children kind.
Fortune, that arrant whore,
Ne'er turns the key to the poor.
O, how this mother swells up
toward my heart!
Down, thou climbing sorrow,
thy element's below!
Where is this daughter?
With the earl, sir, here within.
Follow me not!
Stay here.
How chance the king comes
with so small a train?
An thou hadst been set in the stocks
for that question,
thou hadst well deserved it.
Why, fool?
Let go thy hold when a great
wheel runs down a hill,
but the great one that goes up
the hill, let him draw thee after.
Where learned you this, fool?
Not in the stocks, fool.
Deny to speak with me?
They have travelled all the night?
Mere fetches.
My dear lord!
You know the fiery quality of the duke,
how unremovable he is in his course.
Vengeance! Death!
Confusion! Fiery?
Why, Gloster, Gloster, I'Id speak
with the duke and his wife!
Well, my good lord, I have
informed them so.
- Dost thou understand me, man?
- Ay, my good lord.
The king would speak
with Cornwall,
the dear father would
with his daughter speak:
Are they informed of this?
My breath and blood! No!
Tell the hot duke that...
No, but not yet.
May be he is not well, infirmity
doth still neglect all office.
I'll forbear. And am fallen out
with my more headier will,
to take the indisposed and sickly
fit for the sound man.
Death on my state!
Wherefore should he
sit here?
No, this remotion of the duke
and her is practice only.
Give me my servant forth!
Go tell the duke and's wife
I'Id speak with them, now,
presently:
Bid them come forth
and hear me,
or at their chamber-door
I'll beat the drum
till it cry sleep to death.
I would have all well betwixt you.
O me, my heart, my rising heart!
But, down!
- Good morrow to you both.
- Hail to your Grace!
I am glad to see your highness.
Regan, I think you are!
O, are you free?
Some other time for that.
Beloved Regan,
thy sister's naught.
She hath tied sharp-toothed
unkindness, like a vulture, here.
Thou'It not believe of how
depraved a quality - O Regan!
Take patience, sir, I have hope you
less know how to value her desert.
Say, how is that?
I cannot think my sister in the
least would fail her obligation:
If, sir, perchance she have
restrained the riots of your men...
My curses on her!
You should be ruled, and led
by some discretion
that discerns your state
better than you yourself.
Therefore, I pray you, that to
our sister you do make return.
Say you have wronged her, sir.
Ask her forgiveness?
Dear daughter, I confess that
I am old; age is unnecessary.
On my knees I beg that you'll
vouchsafe me raiment, bed and food.
Good sir, no more.
These are unsightly tricks.
Return you to my sister.
Never, Regan!
All the stored vengeances of heaven
fall on her ingrateful top!
Strike her young bones,
you taking airs, with lameness!
You nimble lightnings, dart your
blinding flames into her scornful eyes!
Infect her beauty,
to fall and blast her pride!
O the blest gods! So you will wish
on me,
when the rash mood is on.
No, Regan,
thou shalt never have my curse!
Thy tender-hefted nature shall not
give thee over to harshness.
Thou better know'st the bond
of childhood;
Thy half of the kingdom hast thou
not forgot,
wherein I thee endowed.
Good sir, to the purpose.
Who put my man in the stocks?
I set him there, sir.
But his own disorders
deserved much less advancement.
O heavens, if you love old men, if
yourselves are old, take my part!
O Regan, wilt thou take her
by the hand?
Why not by the hand, sir?
All's not offence
that indiscretion finds
and dotage terms so.
I am now from home, and out of that
provision which shall be needful.
Sojourn with my sister,
dismissing half your train.
Return to her?
And fifty men dismist?
No, rather I abjure all roofs.
Return with her?
Persuade me rather to be a slave
to this detested groom.
- At your choice, sir.
- Daughter!
I prithee, do not make me mad.
I will not trouble thee.
Farewell, my child.
We'll no more meet,
no more see one another.
But yet thou art my flesh,
my blood, my daughter.
Or rather a disease that's in
my flesh,
which I must needs call mine,
thou art a boil,
a plague-sore in my corrupted blood.
But I'll not chide thee.
Let shame come
when it will.
Mend when thou canst.
I can be patient.
I can stay with Regan,
I and my hundred knights.
Not altogether so,
I looked not for you yet.
If you will come to me,
I entreat you to bring
but five-and-twenty knights.
- I gave you all!
- And in good time you gave it.
Made you my guardians,
my depositaries,
but kept a reservation to be
followed with such a number.
What need you five-and-twenty, ten
or five, in a house
where twice so many
have a command to tend you?
What need one?
O, reason not the need.
Our basest beggars are in
the poorest thing superfluous.
Allow not nature more than nature
needs,
man's life is cheap as beast's.
You heavens, give me that patience!
Patience I need!
You see me here, you gods,
a poor old man.
If it be you that stir these
daughters against their father,
fool me not so much
to bear it tamely,
touch me with noble anger.
No, you unnatural hags, I will
have such revenges on you both
that they shall be the terrors
of the earth.
You think I'll weep?
No, I'll not weep.
I have full cause of weeping,
but this heart shall break into
a hundred flaws, or e'er I'll weep.
O fool, I shall go mad!
Most savage and unnatural!
I like not this unnatural dealing!
I have received a letter
and locked it in my closet.
These injuries
the king now bears
will be revenged.
We must incline to the king.
I will seek him.
Go you, and maintain talk with
the duke,
that my charity be not
of him perceived.
Pray you, be careful.
This seems a fair deserving,
and must draw me that
which my father loses.
The younger rises when the old falls.
End of Part One
Part Two
Blow, winds,
and crack your cheeks!
You cataracts and hurricanoes, spout!
And thou, all-shaking thunder, strike
flat the thick rotundity o'the world!
Good nuncle, in,
and ask thy daughters' blessing.
Here's a night pities
neither wise man nor fool.
Nor rain, wind, thunder, fire,
are my daughters.
I tax you not with unkindness.
I never gave you kingdom,
called you children.
You owe me no subscription.
Then let fall
your horrible pleasure!
But yet I call you servile ministers
that have with two pernicious
daughters joined
your high-engendered battles
gainst a head so old and white
as this.
O! 'tis foul!
He that has a house
to put's head in
has a good head-piece.
The cod-piece that will house
Before the head has any,
The head and he shall louse, -
So beggars marry many.
No, I will be the pattern of
all patience.
I will say nothing.
Who's there?
Marry, here's grace and a cod-piece,
that's a wise man and a fool.
Alas, sir, are you here?
Tremble, thou wretch!
That hast within thee
undivulged crimes,
unwhipt ofjustice!
Hide thee, thou bloody hand,
thou perjured!
Cry these dreadful summoners grace!
I'm a man more sinned against
than sinning.
Gracious my lord,
hard by here is a hovel.
My wits begin to turn.
Come on, my boy, how dost, my boy?
Art cold?
I am cold myself.
Poor fool and knave,
I have one part in my heart
that's sorry yet for thee.
Here is the place, my lord, enter.
- Let me alone.
- Enter here.
Wilt break my heart?
I had rather break my own.
Good my lord, enter.
Thou think 'tis much that this
contentious storm invades us?
Good my lord, enter here.
Prithee, go in thyself,
seek thine own ease.
This tempest will not give me leave
to ponder on things that hurt me more.
But I'll go in.
In, boy, go first.
You houseless poverty.
I'll pray, and then I'll sleep.
Poor naked wretches,
that bide the pelting of this
pitiless storm,
how shall your houseless heads
and unfed sides,
your loopt and window'd raggedness,
defend you from seasons such as these?
O, I have taken too little care
of this!
Take physic,
pomp!
Expose thyself to feel
what wretches feel.
Fathom and half!
Poor Tom!
Come not in here, nuncle,
here's a spirit.
Who's there? What art thou that
dost grumble i'the straw? Come forth.
Away!
The foul fiend follows me!
Through the sharp hawthorn
blows the cold wind.
Go to thy cold bed,
and warm thee.
Hast thou given all to thy two
daughters? And art thou come to this?
Who gives any thing to poor Tom?
Whom the foul fiend hath led through
fire and flame, over bog,
made him course his own shadow
for a traitor.
Bless thy five wits!
Didst thou give 'em all?
Couldst thou save nothing?
He reserved his blanket.
Else we had been all shamed.
- He hath no daughters, sir.
- Death, traitor!
Is it the fashion,
that discarded fathers should have
thus little mercy on their flesh?
Judicious punishment!
Twas this flesh begot
those pelican daughters.
Pillicock sat on Pillicock-hill -
Halloo, halloo, loo, loo...
This cold night will turn us all
to fools and madmen.
Take heed of the foul fiend.
Tom's a-cold.
Why, thou wert better in thy grave
than to answer with thy uncovered
body this extremity of the skies.
Is man no more
than this?
Consider him well.
Thou owest the worm no silk,
the beast no hide.
Here's three on's are sophisticated!
Thou art the thing itself.
Unaccommodated man
is no more but such a poor,
bare, forkt animal
as thou art.
Off, off!
You lendings!
Come, unbutton here.
Prithee, nuncle, be contented,
tis a naughty night to swim in.
- How fares your Grace?
- It shall be done!
I will arraign them straight!
Come, sit thou here, most learned
justicer.
Thou, sapient sir, sit here.
Now, you she foxes!
Will you lie down and rest upon
the cushions?
Arraign her first.
Tis Goneril.
I here take my oath
before this honourable assembly,
she kicked
the poor king
her father.
And here's another,
whose warpt looks proclaim
what store her heart
is made on.
Stop her there!
Arms, arms, sword, fire!
Corruption in the place!
Then let them
anatomize Regan.
See what breeds about her heart.
Is there any cause that makes it hard.
You, sir, I entertain
for one of my hundred.
Only I do not like the fashion
of your garments.
Now, my good lord, lie here
and rest awhile.
Make no noise, make no noise.
Draw the curtains...
So, so, so.
We'll go to supper
in the morning.
So, so, so.
And I'll go to bed at noon.
Who's there? What is't you seek?
What are you there?
Your names?
This is the foul fiend! He walks till
the first cock, he gives the web.
Aroint thee, witch!
What are you?
My name is poor Tom!
But mice and rats, and such small
deer,
Have been Tom's food for seven long
year.
What, have your Grace
no better company?
Trouble him not. His wits are gone.
I'll bring you where
both fire and food is ready.
And drive towards Dover where thou
shalt meet welcome and protection.
If thou shouldst dally, his life,
and ours, stand in assured loss.
His daughters seek his death.
Thou say'st
the king grows mad.
I am almost mad myself.
I had a son,
now outlaw'd from my blood.
I will have my revenge!
How, my lord,
I may be censured
that nature thus
gives way to loyalty.
O heavens!
That this treason were not,
or not I the detector!
The letter hath made thee
Earl of Gloster.
I will persevere in my course of
loyalty,
though the conflict be sore
between that and my blood.
Post speedily to my lord your husband,
show him this letter.
The army of France is landed.
Seek out the traitor Gloster!
Hang him instantly.
Keep you our sister company.
Advise the duke
to a most festinate preparation.
Our posts shall be swift and
intelligent betwixt us.
Where's the king?
My Lord of Gloster hath conveyed him
hence.
- Who's there? The traitor?
- Ingrateful fox! 'tis he.
Bind fast his corky arms.
Good my friends, consider you are
my guests: Do me no foul play.
- Bind him, I say!
- Hard, hard! O filthy traitor!
I'm none!
To this chair bind him.
What will you do?
What letters had you late
from France?
We know the truth.
What confederacy have you with the
traitors late footed in the kingdom?
- A letter not from one opposed.
- It's false.
Where hast thou sent the king?
- To Dover.
- Wast thou not charged at peril?
Wherefore to Dover?
I am tied to the stake, and I must
stand the course.
Wherefore to Dover?
Because I would not see thy cruel
nails pluck out his poor old eyes.
But I shall see the winged vengeance
overtake such children.
See't shalt thou never.
Fellows, hold the chair.
Upon these eyes of thine
I'll set my foot.
Give me some help! O cruel!
One side will mock another;
the other too.
If you see vengeance...
Hold your hand.
I have served you ever since I was
a child. I bid you, hold!
How now, you dog!
I bid you hold, too!
What do you mean?
My villain!
Nay, then, come on,
and take the chance of anger!
A peasant stand up thus!
My lord, you have one eye left...
...to see some mischief on him.
- Lest it see more, prevent it.
Edmund!
Edmund! Edmund!
All dark and comfortless!
Edmund, enkindle all the sparks of
nature to quit this horrid act.
Thou call'st on him
that hates thee.
It was he that made the overture
of thy treason to us.
O my follies!
Then Edgar was abused.
Go thrust him out at gates!
And let him smell his way to Dover.
Turn out that eyeless villain.
Throw this slave upon the dunghill.
Untimely comes this hurt.
Give me your arm.
Yet better thus,
and known to be contemn'd,
than still contemn'd
and flatter'd.
To be the worst, the lowest
thing of fortune,
stands still in esperance,
lives not in fear.
The lamentable change is from
the best.
The worst returns to laughter.
Welcome, then, thou unsubstantial
air that I embrace!
The wretch that thou hast blown unto
the worst owes nothing to thy blasts.
Away, good friend, be gone.
Thy comforts can do me no good
at all, thee they may hurt.
Alack, sir, you cannot see your way.
I have no way,
and therefore want no eyes.
I stumbled when I saw.
O dear son Edgar!
Might I but live
to see thee in my touch,
I'ld say I had eyes again!
Tis poor mad Tom.
Fellow, where goest?
Is it the naked beggar-man?
Madman and beggar too.
He has some reason, else he could
not beg.
In the last night's storm I such
a fellow saw.
Which made me think
a man a worm.
My son came then into my mind.
I have heard more since.
As flies to wanton boys,
are we to the gods.
They kill us for their sport.
I will entreat him to lead me.
Alack, sir, he is mad.
Tis the times' plague,
when madmen lead the blind.
- Sirrah, naked fellow!
- Poor Tom's a-cold.
Come hither, fellow.
I cannot daub it further.
And yet I must.
Bless thy sweet eyes,
they bleed.
Know'st thou the way to Dover?
Both stile and gate,
horse-way and foot-path.
Poor Tom hath been scared. Bless
thee, good man, from the foul fiend.
Here, take this purse.
- Dost thou know Dover?
- Ay, master.
There's a cliff, whose high and
bending head looks in the deep.
Bring me but to the very brim of it,
and I'll repair thou the misery.
From that place
I shall no leading need.
Give me thy arm.
Poor Tom shall lead thee.
Welcome, my lord.
I marvel our mild husband
not met us on the way.
- Now, where's your master?
- Within, but never man so changed.
I told him of the army that was
landed, he smiled at it.
I told him you were coming,
his answer was, >
Of Gloster's treachery and of the
loyal service of his son when I
informed him, then he called me sot,
and that I'd turned the wrong side out.
Then shall you go no further.
It is the cowish terror of his spirit.
Our wishes on the way
may prove effects.
Back to my brother.
Hasten his musters
and conduct his powers.
Decline your head.
I have been worth the whistle:
Become your head
You are not worth the dust which
the rude wind blows in your face.
She that herself will sliver and
disbranch from her material sap,
perforce must wither,
and come to deadly use.
No more! The text is foolish!
Wisdom and goodness
to the vile seem vile,
filths savour but themselves.
What have you done?
Tigers, not daughters,
what have you performed?
Milk-liver'd man!
That bear'st a cheek for blows,
a head for wrongs!
Who hast not an eye discerning
thine honour from thy suffering.
Where's thy drum? France spreads
his banners in our noiseless land.
Whiles thou, a moral fool,
sitt'st still, and criest:
>
See thyself, devil!
Proper deformity seems not in
the fiend so horrid as in woman.
- What news?
- My lord, the Duke of Cornwall's dead.
That shows you're above, that our
nether crimes so speedily can venge!
This letter, madam, craves a speedy
answer. 'Tis from your sister.
I'll read, and answer.
Why the King of France
so suddenly gone back?
Something he left imperfect
in the state required his return.
O thou good Kent, how shall I live
and work to match thy goodness?
My life will be too short,
and every measure fail me.
To be acknowledged, madam,
is overpaid.
A century send forth!
Search every acre
in the high-grown fields.
What can man's wisdom
in the restoring his bereaved sense?
There is means, madam.
Our foster-nurse of nature is repose.
Seek, seek for him,
lest his ungoverned rage
dissolves his life!
No, they cannot touch me
for coining.
I have this right.
I am the king himself.
Nature's above art
in that respect.
There's your press-money.
That fellow handles his bow
like a crow-keeper.
Draw me a clothier's yard.
There's my gauntlet.
I'll prove it on a giant.
Give the word.
- Sweet marjoram.
- Pass.
Ha! Goneril!
With a white beard!
They flattered me like a dog,
and told me I had white hairs
in my beard here.
To say 'ay' and 'no' to every
thing that I said!
There I smelt 'em out.
They are not men of their words.
They told me I was every thing.
Tis a lie. I'm not ague-proof.
Is't not the king?
Ay, every inch a king!
When I do stare,
see how the subject quakes!
I pardon that man's life.
What was thy cause? Adultery?
Die for adultery? No!
Let copulation thrive,
for I lack soldiers.
Give me an ounce of civet,
good apothecary,
to sweeten my imagination.
There's money for thee.
O, let me kiss that hand!
Let me wipe it first.
It smells of mortality.
Dost thou know me?
I remember thine eyes well enough.
Dost thou squiny at me?
Read thou this challenge.
Mark but the penning on't.
Were all the letters suns,
I could not see one.
- Read.
- What, with the case of eyes?
What, art mad?
A man may see how this world
goes with no eyes.
Look with thine ears.
See how yond justice rails
upon yond simple thief?
Hark, in thine ear:
Change places, and, handy-dandy,
which is the justice,
which is the thief?
Through tattered clothes
small vices do appear,
robes and furred gowns hide all.
Plate sin with gold, and the strong
lance ofjustice hurtless breaks.
Arm it in rags,
a pigmy's straw does pierce it.
None does offend, none.
I say, none!
I'll able 'em, take that of me
who have the power
to seal the accuser's lips.
Get thee glass eyes,
and, like a scurvy politician,
seem to see the things thou dost not.
Pull off my boots.
Harder, harder.
I know thee well enough.
Thy name is Gloster.
Thou must be patient.
We came crying hither,
the first time
that we smell the air,
we wawl and cry.
I will preach to thee:
Mark.
Alack, alack the day!
When we are born, we cry that we are
come to this great stage of fools.
It were a delicate stratagem
to shoe a troop of horse
with felt,
and when I have stolen
upon these sons-in-law,
then, kill, kill, kill, kill, kill!
Sir, your most dear daughter...
No rescue?
Use me well,
you shall have ransom.
Let me have a surgeon.
I am cut to the brains.
You shall have any thing.
No seconds? All myself?
Good sir...
I will die bravely, like a smug
bridegroom.
I will be jovial. Come, come.
I am a king.
My masters, know you that.
You are a royal one,
and we obey you.
Then there's life in it.
Nay, an you get it,
you shall get it by running.
Thou old unhappy traitor!
The sword is out
that must destroy thee!
Now let thy friendly hand
put strength enough to it.
Let go, slave!
Out, dunghill!
Take my purse.
Give the letter which thou find'st
about me to Edmund earl of Gloster.
Seek him out upon the English party.
What, is he dead?
I'm only sorry he had no other
death's-man.
<<Let our reciprocal vows
be remembered.
His bed is my gaol,
from the warmth loathed whereof
deliver me.
Your wife, so I would say,
affectionate servant, Goneril.
How does the king?
Madam, sleeps still.
There are many simple operative
whose power will close the eye
of anguish.
O you kind gods!
Cure this great breach
in his abused nature!
So please your majesty
that we may wake the king.
- He hath slept long.
- Very well.
Please you, draw near.
Louder the music there!
O my dear father!
Restoration hang thy medicine
on my lips,
and let this kiss repair
those violent harms that my two
sisters have in thy reverence made!
Had you not been their father,
these white flakes
had challenged pity of them.
Mine enemy's dog should have stood
that night against my fire.
And wast thou fain, poor father, to
hovel thee in short and musty straw?
He wakes.
Speak to him.
Madam, do you; 'tis fittest.
How fares your majesty?
You do me wrong to take me out
of the grave.
Thou art a soul in bliss,
but I am bound
upon a wheel of fire.
Sir, do you know me?
You are a spirit, I know.
When did you die?
- Still, still, far wide!
- He's scarce awake.
Where have I been?
Where am I?
Fair daylight?
I am mightily abused.
O, look upon me, sir, and hold your
hands in benediction over me.
No, sir,
you must not kneel!
Pray, do not mock me.
I fear I am not in my perfect mind.
Methinks
I should know you,
and know this man.
And all the skill I have
remembers not these garments.
Nor I know not where I did lodge
last night.
Do not laugh at me!
For, as I am a man, I think this lady
to be my child Cordelia.
And so I am!
Be your tears wet?
Let me see.
Yes, faith.
I pray, weep not. If you have
poison for me, I will drink it.
I know you do not love me.
Your sisters have done me wrong.
You have some cause, they have not.
No cause, no cause.
Am I in France?
In your own kingdom, sir.
Do not abuse me.
You must bear with me.
Pray you now, forget and forgive.
Know of the duke
if his last purpose hold,
or whether since he is advised by
aught to change the course?
He's full of alteration.
Bring his constant pleasure.
Our sister's man is certainly
miscarried.
Tis to be doubted, madam.
Now, sweet lord,
you know the goodness I intend
upon you. Tell me, but truly...
Some officers take them away!
Good guard!
Until their greater pleasures first
be known that are to censure them.
Shall we not see these daughters
and these sisters?
No, no! Come,
let's away to prison.
We two alone will sing
like birds in the cage.
When thou dost ask me blessing,
I'll kneel down,
and ask of thee forgiveness.
So we'll live,
and pray,
and sing,
and tell old tales,
and laugh
at gilded butterflies,
and hear poor rogues
talk of court news.
And we'll talk with them too,
who loses and who wins,
who's in, who's out.
And we'll wear out,
in a walled prison,
packs and sects of great ones,
that ebb and flow by the moon.
Take them away!
My Cordelia, have I caught thee?
He that parts us
shall bring a brand from heaven,
and fire us hence like foxes.
Wipe thine eyes.
The good-years shall devour them,
ere they shall make us weep.
Come.
Captain, hark!
Go follow them to prison.
One step I have advanced thee.
If thou dost as this instructs thee,
thou dost make thy way still higher.
Know thou this,
that men are as the time is:
To be tender-minded
does not become a sword.
Edmund! Edmund!
Thy great employment will not bear
question: Either say thou'lt do't or...
I'll do it. I cannot draw a cart,
nor eat dried oats.
If it be man's work, I'll do it.
Sir, you have shown today your
valiant strain.
And fortune led you well.
You have the captives.
We do require them of you.
So to use them
as we shall find their merits
and our safety
may equally determine.
I thought it fit to send the old king
to some retention and appointed guard.
His age has charms in it, his title
more,
to pluck the common bosom
on his side.
Sir, by your patience, I hold you a
subject of this war, not as a brother.
That's as we list to grace him.
He led our powers, bore the
commission of my place and person.
Not so hot: In his own grace he doth
exalt himself, not your addition.
In my rights by me invested,
he compeers the best.
That were the most,
if he should husband you.
Jesters do oft prove prophets.
That eye that told you so
looked but a-squint.
General! Witness the world that I
create thee here my lord and master.
Mean you to enjoy him?
The let-alone lies not in your
good will.
Nor in thine, lord.
Let the drum strike, and prove
my title thine.
Stay yet. Edmund, I arrest thee.
On capital treason.
For your claim, fair sister,
I bar it in the interest of my wife.
Tis she is sub-contracted
to this lord.
An interlude!
Thou art armed, Gloster.
Let the trumpet sound.
If none appear to prove
upon thy person
thy heinous, manifest,
and many treasons,
there is my pledge.
- Sick, O, sick!
- If not, I'll never trust medicine.
There's my exchange.
What in the world he is
that names me traitor,
villain-like he lies.
- A herald, ho!
- Come hither, herald!
Let the trumpet sound,
and read out this.
If any man of quality or degree
within the lists of the army
will maintain
upon Edmund, supposed Earl of
Gloster, that he's a manifold traitor,
let him appear by the third
sound of the trumpet.
Ask him his purposes, why he appears
upon this call of the trumpet.
What are you? Your name, your
quality?
And why you answer this present
summons?
Know, my name is lost, by treason's
tooth bare-gnawn and canker-bit.
Yet am I noble as the adversary
I come to cope.
Which is that adversary?
Thou art a traitor!
And, from thy head to the descent
and dust below thy foot,
a most toad-spotted traitor.
Back do I toss these treasons
to thy head!
Trumpets, speak!
- Save him, save him!
- Thou art but cozen'd and beguiled.
Shut your mouth, dame!
Or with this paper shall I stop it!
No tearing, lady.
I perceive you know it.
Say, if I do!
The laws are mine, not thine.
Who can arraign me for it?
Most monstrous!
Know'st thou this paper?
Ask me not what I know.
Go after her, she's desperate,
govern her.
What you have charged me with, that
have I done, and more, much more.
But what art thou?
The wheel is come
full circle.
Let sorrow
split my heart,
if ever I did hate thee
or thy father!
I know it.
Where have you hid yourself? How
have you known thy father's miseries?
By nursing them.
O, our lives' sweetness!
That we the pain of death
would hourly die
rather than die at once!
- What now?
- O, she's dead!
Who dead? Speak, man.
Your lady, sir.
And her sister
by her is poisoned.
She hath confest it.
Produce their bodies.
This judgement of the heavens,
that makes us tremble.
I was contracted to them both.
All three now marry
in an instant.
I pant for life.
Some good I mean to do,
despite of mine own nature.
Quickly send to the castle!
For my writ is on the life
of Lear and on Cordelia.
Quickly send to the castle!
For my writ is on the life
of Lear and on Cordelia.
Run, run, O, run!
Howl, howl, howl, howl!
O, you are men of stone!
Had I your tongues and eyes,
I'ld use them so that heaven's
vault should crack!
She's gone for ever...
I know when one is dead,
and when one lives.
She's dead as earth.
Is this the promised end?
Or image of that horror?
Fall, and cease!
This feather stirs. She lives!
If it be so, it is a chance
which does redeem all sorrows
that ever I have felt.
- O my good master!
- Prithee, away.
A plague upon you, murderers,
traitors all!
I might have saved her!
Now she's gone for ever!
Cordelia, Cordelia!
Stay a little!
What is't thou say'st?
Her voice was ever soft, gentle,
and low, -
an excellent thing in woman.
Who are you? Mine eyes are not
o'the best.
- Your servant Kent.
- He was a good fellow.
He'll strike, and quickly too...
He's dead and rotten.
No, my good lord. I am the very man.
And my poor fool is hanged.
No, no, no life!
Why should a dog, a horse, a rat,
have life,
and thou no breath at all?
Thou'lt come no more.
Never, never, never!
Never, never!
Pray you,
undo this button.
Thank you, sir.
Do you see this? Look on her.
Look, her lips.
Look there!
Look up, my lord!
Vex not his ghost.
O, let him pass!
He hates him that would upon
the rack of this tough world
stretch him out longer.
Bear them from hence.
Our present business
is general woe.
Friends of my soul,
you twain rule in this realm,
and the gored state sustain.
I have a journey, sir,
shortly to go.
My master calls me.
I must not say no.
The End