Who are you hiding from?
My older brothers.
Have you done anything wrong?
I saw them so many times.
I saw how they looked at each other.
Every night she'd massage his back.
She'd massage his legs.
I kept seeing them.
I kept wishing for death to come.
Who to?
Your wife?
My father.
They'll put me in jail!
Who is it?
It's me, ma'am.
What do you want?
- I came to hug you!
- Get out!
Why aren't you looking at me?
Shut up!
That's the worst punishment
you can give a person.
Shameless man!
You seduced a woman of this age!
I'm so ashamed!
Isn't your body's desire
also your soul's desire?
No, it isn't!
That's what animals do!
Human beings are
supposed to be different.
- But they aren't different.
- Shut up!
Wanton savage!
I came to love you
with body and soul, ma'am.
Get out!
Two are better than one.
For if they fall,
one will lift up his companion.
And a twofold cord
is not quickly broken.
When my soul isn't listening to me,
I step out and tell my skeleton...
Do not be rash with your mouth, and let
not your heart utter anything hastily.
For God is in heaven,
and you on earth.
Therefore let your words be few.
That's what I say.
- They've caught the thief.
- Really?
They caught him on the train.
He's from the village.
- The man killed his father as well!
- Don't! That's just not possible here.
- Which village is he from?
- The village up top.
Now a pharmacy's been robbed.
The man was there on his own.
He closed to go to Friday prayers
and that's when the bastard broke in!
Shame on him!
That kind of thing
just isn't possible round here.
These break-ins are getting
out of control.
If they'd given me that thief,
I wouldn't kill him right away.
I'd tie him to a pole, and punish him by
cutting a piece of his flesh every day.
What are you doing?
Get off him!
- Wait. He's OK.
- OK, gentlemen! He's fine.
Move away now.
Move away. Let him breathe.
Oh my!
What's going on here?
- It's as if my lungs are better.
- Possibly you're cured, Tahir.
Captain! Captain! Captain!
Captain, I need to talk!
I need to talk, captain!
Get off!
I did it, captain! It was me.
I did it, captain. It wasn't him.
He didn't do it, captain.
It was me.
I did it, captain!
Everything has a place of its own.
When everything finds its place,
it's all in peace and harmony.
Our bodies...
...find that place of their own
with their own gravity.
But it's not the kind of gravity
that pulls down.
Fire rises, stones fall.
The real gravity of our bodies
comes from the love we have.
Son, we need your cures.
My orphan boy has stopped speaking.
Doctors and hospitals are no good.
His mother died giving birth.
His father went away to find work.
He hasn't spoken for a year.
And it's made him all crabby.
There, that's what he's like.
Turn to the right! Quick time!
Left, right! Left, right!
Do they know they're going to die?
Of course they do.
They're even glad
they're going to die.
This place means release for them.
The sign!
And I thought,
"Oh no! A plane's crashing!"
- A star! It's a star, dad!
- Stars don't fall!
But there are shooting stars!
It was like an earthquake.
The earth roared.
It's a rocket. Definitely a rocket.
And obviously fired across the border.
Attention! The road is closed!
Going near the object is forbidden!
The area is declared a forbidden zone
until further notice.
- What has fallen?
- Must be a satellite again.
- We're being rained on with rubbish!
- They've sealed off the whole place.
I got sick.
You'll get better, son.
Praise be to God!
You can talk now, can't you!
May God grant your every wish!
Here, this money is yours.
- That wasn't my money.
- No. Take it. It's yours.
I don't need it.
- You keep it.
- No, don't take it!
I stole that money from him.
Don't take it! I stole it from him.
My punishment's over, isn't it?
That was over long ago.
It's time for rewards now.
He threw the kitten off the bridge.
He didn't think it would drown.
In his dream that night
he was in a cat court.
And the head cat said...
"As your punishment you mustn't speak
until we give you a sign."
- So he didn't speak.
- Right, he didn't speak.
- He served his punishment.
But now he's really sick.
Those pills aren't for your illness.
It's numb.
It's completely numb.
You were sent to us by God.
I've heard you cure the poor.
God bless you! Now could you
take a look at my son's mind here?
I've had so many hodjas pray for him.
None of them has done any good.
Could you just take a look?
For the love of God.
I don't know what my body knows.
My body doesn't know what I know.
My body and I fear God.
For in the multitude of dreams
and many words there is also vanity.
But you should fear God.
Son, please take a look at him.
We're poor.
We don't have money for a doctor.
What have you done to my back?
The illness is
in the column of your back.
His condition is serious.
He should be taken to hospital
immediately.
We can go in my car.
It's you who made my boy ill,
isn't it?
What happened to the pills?
What did you do with them all?
I threw them away.
Go and get them.
Go and get them then!
I can't do without them!
Dirty thief!
I gave you money!
I gave you money, dirty thief!
I can't bear it.
Why...
...does your heart
eat away at you like this?
Why do your eyes flash lightning...
...but you turn
your soul against God...
...and spit out words like this?
What is man
that he might be pure?
Don't lessen the stride
of your strength.
Your bones are full of
your youthfulness.
And you say...
what does God know?
Thick clouds
are a curtain to Him.
You say He doesn't see
you or your troubles.
I've been all the way
to the pole star and back!
I've climbed up and down
the seven layers of heaven!
Lift your face to God.
I've seen your illness!
I've got you now, asshole!
Wait! Don't run away!
- Where is he?
- Who?
Didn't you see him?
You said you hadn't seen him, huh?
Are you taking the piss?
He jumped over there!
Open the door! Go on, open it