Everything is over!
The mistakes and good things I've
done are appearing before me.
Anyway why shouId a rogue
Iike me faII in Iove?
Me...in his hands...
BIoody Iife!
My Iife!
ReaI name is MayaIori Madan.
But nobody knows that name.
PoIice or press peopIe recognise
him as Maya master.
He's such a big crook!
If he touches,
any Iocker wouId've to give in.
There's no difference of
day or night for him.
If he gets a chance,
he'II rob cIean.
JaiI is Iike In-Iaws pIace
for Maya Master.
Guards, prisoners, workers,
which ever Ianguage they may speak
or beIong to which ever region,
he mixes Iike poison in miIk.
Maya master went to jaiI
for Iong time.
He decided strongIy never to
get caught again by poIice.
He pIanned one Iast big heist.
Who is it?
Are you from KurnooI?
I'm Maya, MayaIori Madan.
You may remember my name.
- So what?
You and Venkat worked together, right?
He was with me after that.
In jaiI!
You both pIanned it together.
He died in jaiI.
I'm there, join with me.
PIan? There's nothing Iike that.
Don't taIk nonsense.
No need to taIk to a crook
Iike you, go away.
To heII with you !
If seems when Iuck came to him,
he chased it away thinking it as dog.
You're retiring in 5 or 6 days.
You'II not get saIary,
wiII you roam haIf naked on streets?
Are you doubting my workmanship?
I'II caII you after 2 days,
you'II accept.
Maya master aIways pIays on
the emotions of other peopIe.
Someone is caIIing for you
since morning.
BIoody! TeII me.
Master, I think he'II
go away from here.
If he escapes, I'II sIit your throat.
No, he won't go, but you pIease
come here quickIy, master.
If you Ieave him, I'II gouge out
your second eye.
He's Chitti, he's an expert
in cutting not beating.
He sees weII with just one eye.
He has to Iive under someoneis umbreIIa.
Distributing pamphIets.
Observing the area around.
SteaI what ever he can
if opportunity arises.
Take out money.
Are you here for me?
Don't disturb me, go away.
Chitti's Iife with this parrot,
this parrot is in a cage.
A thief's hands aIways itch,
he went on steaIing IittIe things.
He caught poIice's eye.
Stop...
Any partnership wouId end
at some point some day.
Chitti was shaken,
he surrendered to poIice.
He though Chitti wiII be very usefuI.
Chitti got himseIf a partner.
Maya got himseIf a worker.
Master is very angry.
If he escapes, Master wiII kiII us.
Is it?
Bujji! No connection with body and brain.
Very patient man.
Never others about famiIy or this worId.
Doesn't know what to do and when.
Eat tiII finishing whatever is cooked,
then exercise to digest it.
That's his job.
He went mad.
He went berserk.
His father threw him out of home.
Bujji's mind got bIocked,
Singh's Iorry haIted.
A man who works Iike donkey
wiII aIways get work.
Eat...eat weII!
Singh feIt he wouId end up a pauper
with this cIeaner,
he vanished with his Iorry.
Hey you, Singh is going away,
did he pay the biII?
Maya was impressed with
Bujji's strength.
This is chicken puIao!
I'II give drinks aIong with food,
wiII you work for me?
If I work, wiII you get me
chicken puIao?
Do I Iook Iike a fooI?
I must throw money on my father's face.
I'II give you a crore.
- Then, I'II give you my head.
Maya, PC and Chitti,
three cheats in this big city,
I didn't know tiII then.
You sIeep cIosing the other eye aIso.
Let him come out, I'II catch him.
Let's see what is he doing?
CIimb.
BIoody Iife!
Nobody toId me to Iive Iike a good man.
When Iiving itseIf is difficuIt,
my foot, who cares about
good man or bad man?
One has to Iive at any cost.
Ever since my chiIdhood days,
I've been running Iike a horse.
I'm a horse but aII others
in my gang are pigs.
Horse among pigs.
Don't beat me.
- Stop...
Why did you beat the oId man?
- What bothers you man?
I grew up, I made it a habit
to reach the unreachabIe.
I'm an expert in cIimbing buiIdings.
I've seen many and cIimbed many.
If you do anything quite often
you get bored.
I got bored of steaIing.
I got irritated.
I went to jaiI.
Don't know why in the game of
cops and thieves,
onIy thief gets caught aIways.
AII the day was heII,
I was going crazy.
I must escape from here.
Money can do anything.
It can bring down any man
on to his knees.
I wanted to change this bIoody Iife
by offering whatever I had.
Go!
There's a difference between
thief and poIice.
We spare after steaIing, but they'II
catch even after taking bribe.
I've a bumper offer for him.
Whether he Iives or dies,
he can never Iive outside the jaiI.
He's a prisoner for this Iife.
Changed the name and pIace.
I got job as a driver.
Everything was fine but
there's a bomb here.
A businessman trying for MP ticket,
he spends 20 days of
every month in DeIhi,
BIoody Iife!
I don't know if I'm his driver
or his wife's driver.
If he comes from DeIhi,
she's his wife,
if not she's an unmarried girI with me.
BIoody!
It's quite difficuIt to be
a good man than being a bad man.
Why did these rogues came here?
I must escape from here.
HeIIo Vamsi!
Are you doing weII?
He's finished.
Sunny, I asked are you fine?
Why do you get so angry for it?
Who are you? I'm not Vamsi.
Are you not Vamsi?
Have you forgotten, dear?
You saw me in jaiI, right?
You've mistaken me.
Name change can't change your face.
Okay, teII me what do you want?
I'm coming to the matter directIy.
I've a pIan, if it works out,
we'II get crores.
What's the pIan?
Goodness won't be there in
a man of cheat and deceit.
You know what I'm taIking about,
financiaI district, diamond house,
a secret Iocker there,
crores of rupees are kept in safe.
A pIan to steaI it.
Didn't get me?
JaiI...Venkat Rao.
- Venkat Rao?
Who the heII is he?
Has Venkat Rao become heII to you?
You came here to steaI that money, right?
Have you gone mad?
Am I going to steaI?
Do you know with whom
you're taIking to?
I don't care!
You must do as I say!
- What shouId I do?
You must cIimb diamond house.
- I'II not.
If I teII that poIice officer
that you're aIive here.
Are you mad?
Not mad but you'II meet a dog's death.
What can you do with so much security?
Have you gone mad?
- What did you say? Security?
How come he thinks about security, PC?
He says who is Venkat Rao,
what's this pIan?
Vamsi, I know Venkat Rao toId you
about the pIan in jaiI before me.
If he has toId me,
he wouId've toId everyone.
You came here trusting him.
To puII it off.
I've aIready a security guard in
my net to execute this pIan,
he'II give us the bIue print
of security set up and pIans.
He's Chitti, he'II cut the
security aIarms,
this big man wiII carry the gas
cyIinders, cutters and aII the materiaI.
BIoody fatso!
Why did you throw the bottIe?
Is it dust bin?
Did you caII me fatso?
Did you see my arms?
If I press you under my arms,
you'II struggIe to breath.
Shut up.
Look, you and your gang has good taIent.
Execute the pIan yourseIves.
You're expert in cIimbing
taII buiIdings, right?
You must cIimb and
heIp us to cIimb.
For executing this pIan
we need investment.
You do the investment.
We'II repay it.
Do you know how much I paid him in jaiI?
He robbed me cIean.
He Ieft me penniIess.
Not a penny with me.
Hey fat PC! This is not an ordinary ghost.
Take on him and show him your power.
I'm warning you, if you dare
touch me, I'II kiII you, fatso!
Leave me.
1There's a woman there,
hoId her tight, fatso!
Leave me.
You Iift him up, you Iift his Iegs.
BIoody idiot! Leave me, rascaI!
He's hiding it here.
OnIy a crook can recognise
another crook.
We've the investment for our job.
I don't want this miserabIe
Iife of a thief.
If you want take my money
but I've reformed.
I want to Iead a honourabIe Iife.
Don't feeI as if I'm asking you to
steaI Lord Venkateswara's donation box.
That's entireIy bIack money,
nobody wiII do anything.
I can't do anything
against my conscience.
PIease Ieave me.
3I'm teIIing you, we want your heIp
and you must do it.
I'm giving you 24 hours time,
if you say okay, no probIem,
otherwise Ranjit Kumar, gunshot...
Leave him...come.
Like a pubIic boring pump
everyone is using me as he wishes.
BIoody Iife!
What I don't want comes into my Iife!
I'm not fortunate to Iead
a honourabIe Iife.
Pick up...pick up...
hey oId man, pick it up!
You rascaI, get up.
Hey you come.
He thought he couId Iive
after sending him to jaiI.
Brother, pIease forgive me.
- Shut up!
Everyone was siIent in fear,
onIy this man, finding it free,
he pointed a finger at him.
If he kiIIs him,
what's your probIem?
I did Iike that without
knowIedge, brother.
If you see anything, watch it,
why did you give evidence?
I made a mistake, brother.
- Don't teII truth.
Withdraw yourseIf.
I'II, brother.
- If not...
Brother...brother...
PIease Ieave me, brother.
Take him away.
Chinnaiah, you promised to pay me today.
I did but I'II not give.
I need money urgentIy, Chinnaiah.
BIoody oId man,
you're troubIing me too much.
Where are you taking earIy morning?
- That oId wants Rs.5 Iakhs.
Who is he?
I promised him Rs.5 Iakhs.
- Are you giving my money to him?
He wouId teII everything
if you beat him, right?
We can't use force everywhere,
if money can do the job,
we must get it done by money.
If we beat or abuse him,
we'II be at Ioss.
My foot! I'm Iosing my money.
Don't feeI as if you're Seth ChamanIaI
and we're your servants.
Your money isn't enough
for anything.
Is it? Isn't that money
aIso not enough?
PC and Chitti are on the job.
What did I ask you to do?
You'II die in my hands.
Get up you big man !
Doesn't aIIow to sIeep aIso, get up.
Get up! We must compIete the
job before brother is back.
Get up!
Get up...get up!
LoveIy!
What are you peeping?
Get Iost rascaI!
Get up man !
Why are you disturbing me now?
Is there any connection
with your size and sound?
I'm better than you.
SmaII speaker but big sound!
How is it?
Come.
What's this meeting in train?
- I think orthodox.
Okay, forget it.
You or me? He caIIed you,
why shouId I join you?
The job is ours.
- You say something.
Did you bring it?
- We did.
Give him.
It's correct.
Did you bring it?
Look, Iisten carefuIIy.
If you've any doubt,
write it somewhere.
We'II never meet or taIk again.
Don't even caII me on phone.
If you do, aII of us wouId get caught.
It's new to you but not to us.
You start.
I don't know or care when you do
or how you do or never do it.
what I'm saying is,
if you do it whiIe I'm on duty,
I'II not think a second,
I'II shoot down everyone.
WiII you kiII us after
taking money from us?
I'II kiII...
You carry on.
TotaIIy four aIarms.
It's on each waII at
an height of 30 feet.
There's one more aIarm which
is connected to Iocker door.
If you open it without
cutting that aIarm,
the siren wiII ring
directIy in boss' room.
Who is he?
- I'II teII you Iater.
There's onIy one way to
reach the Iocker,
you've to reach it from roof,
there won't be anything
to cIimb in from the sides,
except cargo godown of Moin Brothers
about 40 feet away opposite.
Locker waIIs, ceiIing are made
strongIy with steeI and concrete.
If you've any crazy idea
of driIIing, forget it.
There's eIectric fence
around the compound.
If you touch,
you'II be reduced to ashes.
Guards are aIways on duty.
Guards are twice in night.
Last digits of the Iocker
combination is changed every day.
OnIy peopIe who open the
Iocker know it.
Locker door weight is 5 tons
and 2.5 feet thick.
5 tons weight and 2.5 feet thick?
We need a buIIdozer for it,
it's impossibIe.
Return the money, we'II go away.
You cooI off.
The advantages you've here is,
no CCTV cameras.
Because it's bIack money, to avoid
IegaI probIems, they don't use it.
Above aII this,
our boss is now in jaiI.
What the heII can he do if he's out?
If he's out, I don't need to
give you any information.
If you see him kiII anyone,
your heart wiII stop in shock.
Am I any oId hag Iike you?
BIoody oId man !
Though he's oId,
his punch is powerfuI.
He harps about boss, who is he?
What bothers us who ever it may be?
He says he's in jaiI,
it's very easy for us.
I got myseIf punched paying
Rs.5 Iakhs for this Iousy pIan.
I wouId've toId you this freeIy.
Don't worry about Iost money,
think about how to make money.
You didn't Iose anything,
you'd say anything.
OnIy a Iaying hen knows
how painfuI it is!
Don't worry, if you're in night,
it'II be cooI!
That's him!
He Iooks Iike a pimp.
- Shut up.
My darIing, there's nothing more
worth than you in this worId.
Take it.
Trust me, darIing.
Trust me.
- Take the change, sir.
TeII me, darIing.
Run...run...
Bye sir.
You're in my heart, my darIing.
TeII me, darIing.
You cut the caII.
Go.
- Nothing more than you, darIing.
Come...come...
BIoody thieves!
When a man was shouting for burning bums
another was crying for shorts.
Cut it, thief...thief...
Stop!
Run faster!
Stop...stop...thief...
Who is it disturbing my sIeep?
Stop man !
You disturbed me,
who the heII are you man?
Running between three wickets,
you short man.
Are you umpire?
No brother...
- Shut up.
You disturbed a man's sIeep
and abusing him.
What did I teII?
I was shouting thief...thief..
Is it bad word?
Did you shout thief?
I heard it differentIy.
One...two...three!
Why three men for it?
I'm aIone and they were two.
Jasmine fIower!
Don't pIay drama.
One, two, three peopIe are here
and pIaying drama with me.
I'm singIe.
- Are you singIe?
Hey stand stiII...steady!
Stay put there onIy.
Stay there, I'II come.
Thief...thief...
Chotu, get two teas, 5 biscuits
and 10 samosas.
Get whatever is ready.
O my Iove, I'm fine her,
are you fine there?
Leave it, I'm bored.
Wait, what wiII you do going so earIy?
You siIIy boy! Did you ever see
your face in the mirror?
What's troubIing you man?
You're one eyed rascaI,
she's a bitch,
your Iove story is sensationaI.
She'II sureIy hop on.
She's not as you imagine.
She very good girI.
She's a street girI,
Iover of aII men.
Do you know with how many
men she sIeeps every day?
Let her sIeep with any man,
her heart is pure.
If you marry her,
you don't need to steaI.
She'II earn and feed you.
Rain of money!
How can a prostitute
have a heart to Iove?
Shut up!
Do you know what Iove is?
You don't have Iove for
your mother too.
Can you anything eIse other
than eat and sIeep?
You're Iike this, that's why your
father threw you out of home.
I've toId you many times not
to taIk about my mother.
Let me get money,
I'II throw it on my father's face.
I said sorry.
Why are you stiII crying Iike a girI?
Okay.
You hurt me with words
and now say sorry.
I want pepper chicken now.
- Okay.
Get Iost man !
Come inside.
I toId you not to troubIe her,
you siIIy boy.
Stop, pIease Iisten to me.
They'II kiII you.
PIease Iisten to me.
Come on boys!
Who is barging in?
You thin boy, stop!
Who is it?
- PIease Iisten to me.
Hey you !
- Hands off, you skinny man !
If you Iike her,
have her for an hour.
If itis not enough,
have her for a day.
If you ruin a goIden goose,
I'II finish you.
She's my girI,
you want money, right?
TeII me, how much you want for her?
I'II throw it.
- How much you have?
If I bIow, you'II vanish.
Did you find those crooks?
- No, sister.
Sister!
- What?
They're the guys.
They robbed me, sister.
You robbed my man, paying with that
are you pIanning to take my girI?
Lock them up, boys!
Stop!
Bash them, boys!
PIease don't beat him, he may die.
Madam, pIease teII them to stop.
Throw them out!
Stop!
Hey skinny boy!
If you want her, pay her weight
in goId, we can discuss.
This is the right way,
you bIoody bitch.
I'II pay anything for my Iove,
I'II come back for her.
Come, fat boy.
Get Iost! Come in, boys.
Keep the Iuggage quickIy,
have aII chiIdren got in?
Why are you taking so much time?
Getting Iate.
We're getting Iate.
Come!
You carry on, I'II join you.
Come quickIy.
Did you see a girI in green dress?
Why are you pushing me?
Where's your ticket?
Move!
Sathya...my Iife!
One who introduced myseIf to me.
Coming cIoser to me,
she changed my Iife.
She was my worId.
Stop...stop!
You want fIowers?
- No pIease.
God...God! Everyone must be fine.
Forgive me if I do any mistake.
God!
Why are you so Iate?
The rooster didn't cock today, sister.
Sun Iight too came very Iate.
What couId I do, sister?
You're not afraid of anything,
I'II freshen up and come,
go to the cIass. Go!
My dear...
Without making noise...
Butter from the heart...
StoIe it...
Never comes anywhere...
PIaying hide and seek game...
Without coming near...
He watches...
Wherever you may be...
I can't find you...
Why don't you show yourseIf, Krishna?
You're the game...
you're everything...
Who is he sister?
- I don't know he's wounded.
Isn't he Iike a hero?
Look at those wounds,
he Iooks Iike a viIIain.
Shut up. TeII priest to
caII ambuIance.
Krishna, come to me...
Music from your fIute charms my heart...
I've brought cIothes
for him, Sister.
I'II give it to him.
WiII you take medicines now?
Who is that girI?
That girI is compassionate
about others' probIems,
Sister...
- I said you'II be fine.
What's your probIem?
Try to understand me.
Don't move, you're not fuIIy fit.
Where are you going?
- Where shouId I pay the biII?
She paid for you, you take rest.
You're Ieaving without caring my words.
Hey boy, you ! You pIease wait.
Hey you ! Sathya has brought
cIothes aIso for you.
What am I to teII her?
Sathya?
Yes, she brought cIothes aIso for you.
Keep it ready.
Where's the music coming from?
From Sathya's dance schooI.
Hey viIIain !
ViIIain?
You ! You were found wounded.
OnIy viIIains get wounded in fiIms, right?
Where's Sathya?
- Sister is rehearsing drama.
For evening show.
They're putting up a stage
in the back yard.
Go there!
Come here.
- No father.
Don't beat me, father.
No, father.
- can't do any work properIy?
What did you do with the food
you eat thrice a day?
can't ever Iift a gIass.
Hey useIess boy!
GoId...goId...
- He forgot the diaIogue.
You creep, finish the diaIogue.
Say goIden gIasses, you fooI!
Finish the diaIogue,
goIden gIasses, you fooI.
That's not your diaIogue,
you must say you broke goId Iike gIasses.
You're right.
FooI broke goId Iike gIasses.
Father, I'II not work,
I'II go to schooI and study.
I'II become CoIIector.
A tea shop man's son wiII
become tea shop man,
how can he become CoIIector?
Is it easy to become CoIIector?
Hey percussionist, pIay it.
You fooI!
It's your diaIogue, teII.
- It's your diaIogue.
Why are you sitting there, you idiot?
What's this, Ramaiah?
You're big Iike a buII.
Why are you beating him Iike beast?
What if he breaks the gIass?
You can buy another gIass.
He wants to go to schooI.
My damned fate!
You can't teII the diaIogue, right?
Wing...wing...
Bird without wings!
Shut up!
Wing...wing...
It's not wing, your fooI!
You cam pass comments sitting there.
You can't do it unIess you know it.
My fate!
Not that, say unIess you work,
we can't eat.
Right!
Ours is a Iife
unIess we work we can't eat.
Don't know which Goddess
wiII shower mercy on us.
Not here, there!
Stop it.
Son, the broken gIass won't come
back if you beat your son, right?
It's IegaIIy a crime to make chiIdren
under 14 years to work or to empIoy.
You'II be sent to jaiI under
Iaws of chiId Iabour act.
AIIow your son to study,
Iet him study weII and
earn a good Iiving,
he'II soIve aII your difficuIties.
Son...son...son...
Okay, madam.
You're weII educated,
you'II teII things correctIy.
How do we know?
What have you done, you fooI?
Take me up,
- You ruined the show.
See he can't say a diaIogue
but sIeeps weII.
Look how he's snoring.
I'm struggIing to get down from swing,
why are you standing here?
Did you drink again?
- No.- He did, Sathya.
You'II never reform in this Iife,
take and keep it there.
Such a good program is on show,
is it a IuIIaby to you?
Why are you sIeeping without
bothering to see?
Do you know Neeta gave you
a perfect name?
ViIIain !
Do it very weII.
Is that the way to deIiver diaIogues?
Like chiIdren reciting poems.
Didn't I do weII?
- He did very weII.
Criticize him Iike that.
Keep the things inside,
what a Iazy bunch I've got!
Why did you use bad words on stage?
I must take you to task first.
- No...
I toId you many times not
to use bad words on sage.
Look at the resuIt.
They were using bad words on stage.
There were chiIdren on the stage.
- Sorry I made a mistake.
I Iost my respect.
My name is damaged.
- Come...come...
I forgot to ask you earIier,
you were supposed to be in hospitaI,
what are you doing here?
Are you fine now?
You'II be fine.
If not why wouId you be here?
Where's your pIace?
Why did you come here?
How did you faII into water?
Did you faII on your own or
you were pushed by someone?
Suicide?
Love faiIure?
Did she reject you or
any probIem with her famiIy?
How come you're a coward, ViIIain?
WiII you kiII yourseIf
if anyone rejects you?
Anyway, is she mad?
You're handsome.
OnIy cowards commit suicide.
Why are you staring at me?
Can you hear me?
Do you understand me?
Bus is about to Ieave, come fast.
- Wait, I'm coming.
We work for peopIe Iike you onIy, ViIIain.
I'II taIk to my peopIe and
arrange a counseIing session.
Move, get inside.
by the way, what's your name?
Why didn't you tie it yet?
- I'm tying it.
It's dirty, wash it.
Sathya is here.
- Do it fast.
Drunkard Chakri ran away.
Last night he got drunk and
created a scene in home.
His wife got angry and
went away to her parents' home.
He too went after her.
Wife is more important
than job to him.
He'II reaIise job is more
important than wife.
I've toId you many times
not to engage drunkards.
Look at the resuIt.
Today evening we've a show,
we need a hero immediateIy.
You'II seIect a best man.
Where can I a hero urgentIy?
PIease find one for me, dear.
- Wait. I'II come back.
Don't want married men.
BIoody idiots.
Guru, I'm aIso not yet married.
We're fIowers unsuitabIe
for God's offering.
Hero's roIe, right? I'II do it.
If you...
- What a hero I've got!
You can't do two things
with two hands at a time.
Do it with yourseIf,
it'II be exciting.
I'm pIaying it weII, right?
Hey! You !
I'II come there myseIf.
I was caIIing you from there,
didn't you hear me?
You seem to be perfect now,
why are you idIe?
You come with me, come!
Come.
- Where?
What's the matter?
- You must act as hero of my troupe.
Am I hero?
- Yes, you are!- Come.
I can't act, Sathya.
Why can't you? Do I know acting?
Am I not doing it?
Are we any great actors?
You'd have known our taIent had
you seen our program, you dozed off.
Come.
Did you ever steaI?
You wouId've stoIen money from dad to
buy ice creams and chocoIates, right?
When your dad asks did you
take money from my pocket?
No daddy, I don't know, you wouId've
acted innocentIy, right?
That is acting.
PIease do it for me.
Cut the caII.
- UncIe, we got a hero.
Is he hero?
He's aIways after Sathya.
Who is after me? You or him?
Look after your tabIa.
You too Sathya!
That's a mridangam not tabIa.
Something, you keep shut.
How handsome he is!
Young age, very handsome.
He'II be very powerfuI.
- Oh Lord!
Show me once!
- What?
I mean your acting taIent.
WiII not aIIow these atrocities
and inhuman acts to happen.
There must a feeI in diaIogues.
How come yours is
so beautifuI, handsome!
Once more, pIease.
PIease teII.
These atrocities...inhuman acts...
barbarous behaviour...
wiII not aIIow it to happen...
it won't happen.
There's a IittIe tempo but diaIogues
must hit the heart straight.
Like your eyes...
These atrocities...inhuman acts...
barbarous behaviour...
wiII not aIIow it to happen...
it won't happen.
How weII he said that!
Your words have power!
You're my hero.
We found a hero.
- You've become a hero.
Mad man, get Iost!
Sathya, stop!
How Iong this injustice wouId happen?
How Iong wouId these atrocities happen?
How Iong can these
inhuman acts carry on?
I've been waiting for year
to act as hero,
wiII you offer the roIe
to some unknown guy?
My curse wiII hurt you, Guru.
Your curse wiII not do anything.
There's no current in you
but you taIk about eIectrocution.
Shut up.
Who is without current? You or me?
With that cowardIy face!
I've heard about current in wires,
what's this current in body?
Do you remember aII that you Iearnt?
What's this Iike a chiId?
Remembered about your Iover?
I'II taIk to her myseIf and
fix your marriage.
Okay?
Why haven't you changed
the costume yet? Go!
Get ready quickIy.
Go, ViIIain.
ChiIdren are ready there,
don't you know to tie this?
I didn't even thank you.
- Just thanks wiII not do, ViIIain.
Okay, ask, whatever you want.
WiII you do anything for me?
WiII you? You mustn't
go back on promise. Okay?
Promise.
- Promise.
Just ask me once, you'II know it.
You wrenched my heart! ReaIIy!
For the present act weII in my troupe.
That's enough.
It's not an easy task to
become Sathya's hero.
You're reaIIy Iucky.
I too don't know
how to tie this headgear.
Do it yourseIf.
Stand stiII time...
Happiness freeze this very moment...
For my sake...
AII these years...
What was my destination
seIected for me
And searched how many pIaces...
Don't you've anyone?
Except this.
ThriIIing emotions in heart
are beckoning me...
Heart is suddenIy soaring
into sky Iike a bird...
It forgot it's meandering way
and journeyed towards you...
My heart has reached you this moment...
You're the dream I see
in my eyes...
You're a boon who has
come aIive from dream...
This Veena is very good.
How much?
Rs.30000!
- Rs.30000?
You know to pIay Veena?
- ExceptionaIIy.
You know I Iove to pIay Veena.
I had one earIier,
my brother soId it.
I was very happy
when I had Veena with me.
The way I Iook at you has changed
and become my breath...
My shadow is pushing me
towards you...
Spread a dream Iike Iight...
Stopped Iike a river
without waves...
A statue is meIting away...
My heart...
Tie this ribbon properIy.
Come here.
Neetu hasn't come yet,
she's the star of this show.
HoId this.
I sent a man to home,
it seems she's not in home.
Her mother says she won't dance.
Stand here.
I'II show you to make
your anger vanish.
1PIease come with me.
- No, I'II not.
Come.
Just one second, come.
- Where?
Look!
- What's that?
How come this is here?
I said your anger wiII vanish.
Did you buy it?
How did you get so much money?
Did you seII your Iocket?
Are you mad?
I said I'II buy it Iater.
You said that Iocket is your Iife.
I didn't have anyone then.
I considered it as my Iife.
But you're there for me, right Sathya?
I reaIised this moment...
Thoughts which were unknown earIier
are taking over me...
It's aIways about meeting you...
What I couIdn't say beyond my Iips...
It stood before me sIeepIess...
When I face you,
I Iose my composure...
My heart...
What?
How am I to teII you this...
What's this, Neetu?
Do it properIy.
Do it properIy, don't smiIe.
That is...I...
...you...that is...
What?
I forgot.
Do it from the beginning?
Under the auspices HeIping Hand Trust,
Quit drinking, Save famiIy,
watch the pIay!
Hey you, what's that nasty dress?
Serve food!
Enough, I can't take it anymore.
I can't Iive with you,
you're ruining heaIth and
famiIy with drinks.
You've come drunk at odd hour
and shouting at me to serve food.
Stand outside the home
and taIk to me.
He you ! What's this?
Stop shouting on me.
Shut up and get me food.
If not I'II bash you.
You'II get bashed up not me.
Your acts wiII not be
entertained here, go away!
Go!
AIIow me and my chiIdren
to Iive peacefuIIy.
Go away!
Go...go!
They say a word for human
and beating for beast.
Why are you stiII standing
here shameIessIy unmoved?
Get out!
What happened to you, Vamsi?
You must go from here.
You don't have diaIogues here,
get down from stage.
What happened to you suddenIy?
Why are you staring at me?
Go!
Oh my God! Come down.
Get out! Go!
I want you !
You're my Iife.
I'II never hurt you in any matter.
I'II quit everything.
I'II quit.
I don't want anything.
I need onIy you.
That's aII.
My Iife is for you onIy.
If you promise to be good man,
it's okay to me aIso.
O sweet heart, why did you enter my Iife?
Why did you Ieave me shattered?
Thorns of your thoughts are
hurting my heart...
Your thoughts are fIooding me...
Our union has Ieft me
in pain and hurt...
My agitated heart is beating
with Iove...
This is the shore
you chose to traveI...
This is the void that's enveIoping me...
You've gone far Iike
a distant dream...
You've become a memory that
stays with me forever...
What are you thinking so much, sunny?
I'm a IoneIy man without
any strings,
who do I've to think about?
What's there to think?
AIways on top!
Stop that bore and teII
what have you decided?
I'm ready.
If anyone doubIe crosses me,
I'II see his end.
I've Iost faith on humans,
I may end up again in jaiI.
That's aII, isn't it?
I Iike your emotion.
There's onIy game to steaI money,
no doubIe games.
Trust me.
Is he here onIy?
- Yes sir.
What's that nasty name?
That's grand not...
You don't have any comedy sense.
How wiII you Iive man?
Come.
Who are you guys?
Do you've to shout Iike that?
How are you pIanning to go?
Let's go from their transport company.
You go that side, you go this side.
No other way?
I toId you, no other way.
Good! Her or she?
If we go from other side.
Wow! Finished!
Resting!
No other way.
If we go from behind...
Where are you man?
- Nobody can find us!
PIease don't harm me.
I'II come wherever you ask me.
WiII you come?
Are you done with today's duty?
Tomorrow at the same time.
Greetings sir.
- What? Two at a time?
Set type?
I'm finished with just one,
are you enjoying with two?
You've become very proud,
bIoody bastard.
PIease forgive me, sir.
Do you think I can't catch you?
Hereafter this area too comes
under my jurisdiction.
I'm here on transfer, got it?
Come...come...
- Come man.
Where is he taking them?
Why are poIice here?
Suspicious men are hovering your pIace,
keep me informed if anything happens.
I'II take care of them.
- Okay.
Master, poIice have come.
They've Ieft.
You can't do a work properIy, rascaI.
Do you want haIf share?
HaIf share? What's that?
This pIan is mine, 50% is mine,
you three share 50%.
I too know the pIan,
investment is mine.
Hard work is teams.
Let's share it equaIIy.
What do you think of yourseIf?
Okay, Iet's see.
Stop taIking nonsense and
think about baIance money.
Not Iater, settIe it right now.
Okay, Iet's do as you say.
Okay?
What about the baIance money?
I've another pIan for that.
Papamma, Iook after the house carefuIIy.
Take care.
We're Ieaving home.
Master is caIIing, go.
He's going, show your driving skiII.
Even peopIe waIking must
overtake your car.
Did you cIose doors, dear?
If we cIose or keep it open,
it makes no difference,
what do we've in home?
Money or jeweIs?
I feII for your these
practicaI jokes, right?
I got it, I'II get it from DeIhi,
Hi brother-in-Iaw!
Where can I good bangIes in Hyderabad?
I don't know, go away.
- Brother-in-Iaw!
I want bangIes, brother-in-Iaw...
- I said I don't know, go away.
At Ieast give me money to buy.
Brother-in-Iaw!
Won't you buy at Ieast bangIes for
your sister-in-Iaw, you stingy man?
Did I forget my phone in home?
Driver, reverse the car.
Sir, I don't know which way
he's going.
I'II not Iet you go.
I'II reverse as soon as I get it.
I don't get what you're saying.
I'm aIso saying the same thing, sir.
Can you understand what is he saying?
I've understood that you didn't
understand what he toId you.
You never teII me anything
straight forward.
Driver, reverse the car.
- Sir, I'm reversing the car.
Brother-in-Iaw...reversing the car.
Why are you taIking Iike
over a microphone?
ShouId everyone know about it?
Got in.
He's reversing the car.
It seems he's coming back.
Has he gone mad?
With great difficuIty I got in,
why is he coming back now?
It couId be your phone,
check it, sir.
My phone is here onIy.
Madam, phone is here onIy.
- What are you doing?
You move IittIe...madam...
I'II cut you.
Sir, in the foIds of madam's waist...
Phone is ringing.
- Why doubIe entendres?
Got it, here's your phone, sir.
Got the phone.
Thank God, got the phone.
Is he going again?
What did you find?
My head!
- Got head?
Watch out, I'II give him a shock.
Fish gravy is fantastic.
- You foodie!
Leave it, I'II kiII you.
I'II stab you.
Brother-in-Iaw, if you go to NepaI,
teII me, I'II aIso join you.
What do you say?
I don't want to Ieave you aIone.
Are you missing me too much?
ShaII we go back to home?
Yes, I've Iost haIf of my Iife in
trying to get an MP seat in DeIhi.
I feeI Iike spending days
happiIy with you.
If you stay at home aIways,
it's very difficuIt for me.
I mean I Iike!
WiII you run over me, bIoody?
Hey, move away!
Go!
This is my road.
I'II not give way.
Even if CM comes I'II not give way.
I'II not give way to you.
Is my tricycIe any Iess
to his car?
What's your probIem with him?
How do you feeI?
I'm not weII, sir.
I feeI Iike doing something
from inside.
I'm IittIe tired.
- Tired?
How can you drive then?
After dropping him,
I'II give you a good tabIet.
It'II give you immediate reIief.
- Okay madam.
Dear, I feeI something bad
is going to happen.
I've Iost the mood of going to DeIhi,
Tour is canceIIed, go back to home.
Is it usefuI to me, master?
I'II beat you.
- It's a joke, master.
You bIoody...
I shouId've made you stand out
and brought Chitti inside.
Coming...coming back to home.
What? Are you coming back to home?
Coming home...coming home...
Why are you singing?
Are you crazy?
Yes sir, don't why off Iate
I feeI Iike singing songs.
I feeI Iike shouting Ioud!
UnabIe to get the Iine,
what happened?
UnabIe to connect, I'm getting tensed.
Sir, we've IandIine in home, right sir?
Why do you want that?
Go home quickIy.
IandIine in home...
- Why that song?
If there's a IandIine in home,
it has a number, right?
So what?
Wherever IandIine is,
heaIth is there.
I got it but I don't know the number.
Sir, our number...what shouId we do
get such numbers?
You're great! I got it, brother.
I'II take care of it.
Are you tired or the car?
Why are you going so sIowIy?
How can I go fast in heavy traffic?
Give me your phone, pIease.
I'II caII maid and teII her
to warm up fish gravy.
What's this dear?
You're acting Iike reaI Iady.
Pick up the phone, I'm getting tensed.
Be carefuI, she may come in.
What's going on?
Why am I getting engaged tone?
What do you want?
I was to piss.
- Go away.
Chitti's missed caIIs.
I think he's caIIing us on IandIine.
Lift it.
Never gives me a peacefuI moment.
Why did you take so much time?
Who were you gossiping with?
We'II be there in 2 minutes,
What happened?
TeII me, Chitti.
She wants me to warm the
fish gravy kept in fridge.
Where is it? I had it.
We may get caught.
Hey you fooI! Are you reaIIy
innocent or you act innocence?
TeII me, Chitti.
- They're coming back to home.
You must come out in 2 minutes.
Do it fast.
Hey fat boy! If you move,
I'II stab you with fish bone.
Which hoteI wiII serve
fish gravy in 2 minutes?
Don't know the difference between
fire and ash, sit siIentIy.
Why has he kept medicines in Iocker?
I'm having indigestion probIem,
shaII I take a tabIet?
If you take it, it won't get
digested but wiII grow bigger!
You'II go wiId with rage!
What eIse shouId stiII grow in me?
Rich peopIe don't know
what to hide and where?
They're back, come out quickIy.
This maid servant...
- Get the Iuggage.
bring the fiIes in back seat aIso.
- Okay sir.
Don't you know where he
hides money and jeweIs?
What can I do if Iocker is empty?
Smoke cigarette...gutkha...
Have it together...
Smoke it!
Kiss, miss and Iuck are
in our favour...
We must steaI something reaIIy big...
We must pIough the entire worId...
BIoody heII...
Throwing out moraIs and ideaIs...
we must draw a cross Iine...
Who cares about sins and pious?
It's sunny aII through...
If you've a crore,
you're a King...
If he's a king,
he's an epitome of pride...
I'm ready with gas cyIinders,
cutters and other equipment.
We saw aII the aIarm Iines,
there's onIy one extra aIarm Iine.
If we cut that aIarm,
it won't ring in boss' pIace.
You don't worry,
I'II take care of other things.
There's a transport company
next to Diamond house.
Transfer aII the equipment we need
from Moin Brothers transport.
We don't need to carry it.
ShouId we take guns?
- We couId've done it in day time.
Arrange two vehicIes.
I'II manage money and bags.
Do you've any doubt?
Around this area of Kondaveedu,
when peopIe Iike you commit crimes,
I'm a Iion
who'II beat you bIack and bIue,
and wipe out every
criminaI from here.
Inspector Ranjit Kumar.
He's a new star...
Money is bad...
Money is best...
If you've money,
it's the biggest kick...
you've have everything...
Mix it with bIack and white...
Forget about big or smaII...
Throw out moraIs and ideaIs
and draw a cross Iine...
Life is a race...
Hit the top gear...
Beat it boys!
Why are you watching her Iike seeing
a woman bathing through key hoIe?
See properIy.
Come fast!
- What happened?
TeII me.
TeII me, why are you rushing?
You one eyed, stop!
No chance for it.
Who is he?
He's the boss that oId security
guard warned us about.
Demon under the garb of human.
He was born and brought up
in EduruIanka.
It's stiII his den.
Exporting girIs from AmaIapuram,
Iand grabbing in KurnooI,
smuggIing in SuItan Bazaar,
he grew richer with each trade,
if anyone takes on him,
he'II chase and kiII Iike a Ieopard,
his main job is safe guarding
bIack money of rich peopIe,
that is diamond house,
a pIace where bIack money is hidden,
he's the chief security officer,
a man whom he trusted
betrayed him to poIice,
ever since then Fredricks
stopped trusting men,
except Puranik,
when a witness charged him
with murder,
Fredricks went to jaiI,
Puranik is not human,
he's a bIood sucking demon,
he made witness turn hostiIe,
what can Iaw do without witness?
Master, I'm scared.
What shaII we do now?
Let Finger Fredricks come or his dad,
I'II take care of him.
Why are you scared of him?
BIoody! Shut your gob for some time.
We can't do anything in
this situation.
If we think we can't do,
we can never do anything.
Tonight we're doing it.
How is it possibIe to do tonight?
You be brave,
we're doing it, that's aII.
Good.
If it's today,
we'II sureIy get caught.
Is it you, son?
Mother, it's me.
Son, I know it's you.
Mother!
- How are you, son?
Are you eating on time or not?
Son, I'm worried about you.
Mother, you don't worry about me.
Father!
- I said that in an angry mood.
WiII you Ieave us for that?
Your mother cries everyday
thinking about you, son.
Your sister's marriage
is fixed, son. - Is it?
I'II never scoId you,
I don't mind if you do nothing.
I'II earn weII, I'II conduct
sister's marriage grandIy myseIf.
I'II show to the worId
who Bujji is!
My father has understood me.
What? What are you saying?
My father is sad.
My mother is crying.
It seems my sister's marriage
is fixed.
I'II conduct my sister's marriage
myseIf with money I get.
I know you can do it.
You're my cIose friend.
You've brain.
Chitti, you're much better
man than me.
I can give my Iife aIso for you.
I'II bring that girI and
fix your marriage myseIf.
Shut up, first Iet's finish
sister's marriage.
That's aII, just stay aIong with me.
Everything wiII be fine.
- You say Iike that?
When did you come, brother?
You too teII me, Vamsi,
I'II do that for you aIso.
Do you aIso have any girI friend?
Come out! Don't feeI shy.
I don't want anything,
I'II go to some faraway pIace.
That's aII!
You both must be happy aIways
Iike today!
Do what so ever it is now!
Tonight at the stroke of midnight...
Don't overact.
What wouId I do with it?
No girI no Iife.
Let's go.
Check the parceI.
This is it.
Be carefuI.
Come.
Let's both cIimb the buiIding,
you cut the aIarms and come back.
What happened?
There wiII be security guards,
we must go this side.
Come.
Leave it...move!
You coward, get down.
Looks Iike aII crooks are here.
You bIoody idiot!
- Let's be on job.
Got it?
Enough, as if you've done a great job!
I'II come back in a second,
very urgent.
Where's he?
Do you've any sense?
Be on job!
BIoody coward!
Hot tea sir.
- WiII you bring tea so Iate?
Keep it there.
Money, sir.
- How dare you ask money from me?
You said no guns.
This is my Iucky charm.
BIoody idiot.
He's useIess.
You wait, I'II try.
What? Turn that side.
Get up!
Look!
They've kept every God of this country.
You said there are crores of rupees.
What?
You said crores, what's here?
You wiII see.
- What wiII I see?
Stares at me for anything.
- Is Maya fun?
Entire pIan is waste.
Look at this!
Never seen so much money.
This is Maya master pIan,
anyone must bow to me.
WiII you settIe down, fatso?
Maya master is great!
We hit the jackpot, PC!
ShaII we name the company
as Maya master finance?
Name it is as buffaIo company!
- That is aIso good.
Push it quickIy.
- Do it fast.
Go away from here.
BIoody! Are you drunk?
How couId you park in the
pIace I park my vehicIe?
You rascaI!
- Shut up and get Iost.
You crook!
Crook?
How dare you caII me crook?
Am I a crook?
Who am I?
I'm tiger!
If I give punch,
you'II bIeed, rascaI!
Go away, if you stay here,
I'II finish you.
Get Iost!
Be carefuI!
Come!
SIowIy...sIowIy...
Nothing wiII happen, come...come...
BIoody drunkard!
UncIe, I heard some sound inside.
It was me, I was in toiIet just now.
I did it there.
Before guards see, get PC's body.
Get up!
Why did this happen, brother?
No time, take him.
I toId him not to drink
but he didn't Iisten to me.
What wouId he Iose if he
didn't drink for one day?
CaIm down !
I'II take on if security guards come.
Where are you going at this hour?
Take him to the car.
- We don't have that much time.
Come.
- I'm teIIing you.
Throw him in car immediateIy.
Go!
Come, Chitti.
AII of you three come together,
Iion wiII fight aIone!
OnIy pigs come in groups...
That side!
No, pIease.
Those crooks escaped
Come.
Go, I'II compIain tomorrow.
Go away!
I'II throw you in jaiI
with compIaint.
This is my pIace!
My pIace...I'II sIeep in my pIace.
I've faIIen down !
Chitti, Iisten to me carefuIIy.
FoIIow me, Iet's dump PC
somewhere on the way.
Yes, master.
Let's share the booty and spIit up.
Why?
- If not we'II get caught.
Got it?
Shut up!
Stop crying.
You see that turn on hiII road, right?
Stop the car there.
Keep his hand on steering
and push the car down.
Nobody wiII get any doubt.
They'II take it as accident.
Start the car.
Open it.
CaIm down, Chitti!
What can we do?
Come.
Brother! Why did this happen to us?
Forget it.
Come!
Stop...stop...
Hey fatso!
It's over!
CaIm down !
Stay here, I'II reverse the car.
He won't survive, come.
Get into the car.
Come.
We kiIIed him.
He won't die so easiIy.
I can't take it anymore,
can't stay here for a moment aIso. Go!
Chitti is there, stop...stop...
What are you doing, you bIoody?
Doing good deeds before death...
It's fooIishness!
How dare you oId man !
Got any news about that fatso
and skinny boy?
I don't know sir.
You search there,
you search this side.
They escaped 30 minutes earIier.
- Shut up!
This room is finished.
is she your girI friend?
Let's go to Vamsi's pIace.
Hey crook! Come out!
BIoody Iife!
Hastinapuram 123 kms
I'm very happy today.
PIease cIose your eyes once.
Why shouId I cIose my eyes
if you're happy?
I must taIk here and
you must onIy Iisten. Okay?
CIose your eyes.
How did you get it?
You said this was your Iife, right?
From now this is my Iife too.
Okay?
That is...
What?
Want me to drop you?
No need to take troubIe,
Vamsi is here.
Is he trying for you?
Can I take on him?
No, he's not that worth.
Upstairs...I forgot my keys.
Did you find it?
What have you hidden in heart?
See properIy, it's you Sathya.
I met you in this happiness
and won over you...
I spread my heart...
I forgot words...
Look at my faItering youth
and its struggIes...
Let my wishes and my breath
remain in your heart forever...
Let your mischievous thoughts
remain in my eyes Iike a dream...
Let our souIs and body
merge into one body...
Let happiness join and
stay with us aII our Iives...
Look!
What did you wish for?
Never ask secrets from girIs.
They Iadies first, right?
You teII me first.
I made a wish to be with you aIways.
Stop...stop it!
This marriage wiII not happen, no way!
You come here.
Father!
Don't stop the marriage
for shortage of dowry.
Don't ruin my daughter's Iife.
If you carry on Iike that,
won't you Iisten to my diaIogues?
Come on teII, as if you'II
give a deadIy performance.
Come on.
Hey you deIiver the diaIogues,
take out the paper and read the diaIogues.
DeIiver!
Don't stamp my Ieg.
I didn't struggIe to get him educated
for your daughter to marry,
who wiII pay for it?
Why shouId I pay dowry for your son?
I'm not a man who deIivers
diaIogues reading from paper bits.
Don't act too much.
- You wait.
Father! Don't go.
Why are Ieaving the scene midway?
I can't hoId on anymore, very urgent.
Who wiII teII the diaIogues then?
If you want I'II deIiver it
from toiIet.
BIoody short man !
Why did he come?
- What's this?
Why did you come?
Are you going to pIay his part?
You keep quiet.
He's my father.
But if he comes.
- Don't confuse me.
Why confusion? I'm your mother.
What shouId I caII him now?
Father-in-Iaw or mother-in-Iaw?
What eIse wouId you caII wife's
mother other than mother-in-Iaw?
You wait.
- I'II deIiver my diaIogues.
Why shouId I pay him dowry?
Won't he have to spend for Iiving
comfortabIy after marriage?
Won't my daughter toiI in your house?
She'II do cooking,
washing utensiIs, cIothes...
Don't act too much,
do you've to teII me everything?
If they've chiIdren,
she'II wash them.
Chicken on Sunday,
mutton on Tuesday,
by that way, you must...
- Father, I don't want to marry.
I hate men who take dowry.
I wouIdn't have agreed to marry
if I knew he wouId take dowry.
I wouIdn't have agreed!
You siIIy girI!
- You come here with me.
Father, I don't want dowry,
I Iike her very much.
Whether anyone accepts or not,
I'II marry her onIy.
Priest, chant the hymns.
You Iike me?
You managed it weII,
what are you doing now?
Tie the knot.
ShaII I tie 3 knots?
I'm feeIing strange Iike in dreams...
It is good to enjoy...
It happened with you and me...
Hey you dramatist!
My sister is roaming with some guy,
have you become her pimp?
Hide Vamsi somewhere, go.
- Okay, uncIe.
Hey you bIoody!
You're dead meat today.
It seems he's pIaying hero roIes
and he's after my sister.
Sir, we don't know anything.
TeII me.
- We don't know anything.
She's doing her job sincereIy,
how dare you go after her!
I'II hack that bastard.
Not a hero of pIays,
you and that man are buffoons.
Where is Sathya?
Brother!
Come.
Why did you shout now?
- I'II not come with you.
I'II not come.
Try to understand me.
- Leave my hand.
Come.
- I'II not come.
Come I say!
Brother!
What is he doing here?
Move!
Leave me!
Leave me.
Come.
- Where's Vamsi?
Brother!
Come I say!
Brother-in-Iaw, he's here onIy.
You're my breath...
you're my thought...
She's roaming with a man on streets,
what the heII were you
doing sitting in home?
She's my sister.
You come and go
when you remember us.
Why are you bothered about sister?
Don't you've shame to cIaim that?
- Shut up!
You're forgetting that I'm your
husband, I'II rip out your skin.
Stop! You'II Iose respect
if you dare beat her.
Get out!
Who gives you this courage?
Ask him to come, I'II settIe
the issue once for aII.
He's not a crook to fight
a crook Iike you.
He's a good man.
Everyone is good to himseIf.
I'm a very good man for myseIf.
If I marry him,
nobody wouId caII me as thief's wife
Iike peopIe caIIed sister-in-Iaw.
Roam with anyone you Iike,
but must marry the man of my choice.
I've seIected a rich man,
Iet anyone come, your marriage
wiII happen with him onIy.
Got it?
I'II die but not marry him.
You can marry him and then die.
AII I want is money!
Your set up is very good!
BIoody famiIy of thieves.
Who is she? Your sister?
I'm sure she wouId've found
a thief onIy.
I smeIt about a robbery
in this area.
Don't know why I suddenIy
remembered you.
Come, Iet's discuss IeisureIy
whiIe traveIIing.
Come.
Buying me drinks?
Sister, ViIIain gave you this Ietter.
Sorry Sathya, though I was to forget,
past is fast catching up with me,
unabIe to teII you truth and
unabIe to avoid teIIing truth,
I know I'm going through heII,
I didn't know what is happiness
before I met you,
After I met you I forgot
about pain and sorrows.
I'm not right choice for you,
but my Iove for you is true.
I shouIdn't do this
but I don't have choice.
I'm Ieaving this pIace.
Hastinapuram
I ran away Iike a coward.
But Maya wouId sureIy be
somewhere here onIy.
I'II not spare him.
How couId you thriII my heart
with your music?
Come fast hearing my pIeas...
You Ieft me.
You've come now.
Are you here to see
if I'm dead or aIive?
Why did you Ieave me aIone?
I hate to see your face.
AII men are same.
You gain our trust and then betray.
PIease Iisten to me.
I'm not a cheat.
- Shut up!
Don't teII me anything,
I don't want to hear anything.
When my brother created
such a big scene,
you shouId've heId my hands
and toId him I'II marry her,
you ran away Iike a coward, right?
I'm ashamed of it, Vamsi.
PIease Iisten to me.
Enough of getting cheated
Iistening to you.
I'II not Iisten, no!
AIIow me to teII, Sathya.
- I'II not Iisten.
I was in jaiI with your brother.
You know that?
EIder one! I found the boy!
Look there!
There...there...
KiII him...kiII him!
Are you here for money?
No, Sathya.
Don't Iie to me again.
My brother isn't just a thief,
he's a murderer too.
Are you aIso Iike him?
You want onIy money, right?
Take everything that's in
my home, Iive happiIy.
PIease Iisten to me.
I'm not here for money.
Don't know how to teII you...
Sathya, I've changed, trust me.
That too after hearing about
your marriage, I couIdn't bear it.
Am I married?
This sacred thread was tied by you.
How couId you imagine I wouId
marry another man?
It may be a pIay to you
but it is reaI for me.
Go away, Vamsi.
Go away!
You're waste!
Why did you Ieave him?
You shouId've kiIIed him.
There's an advantage with gun.
When you press the trigger,
there's a big sound,
the sound wiII send
shivers down the spine.
He must know Fredricks is here.
Get up!
You can sIeep forever
after sometime.
Why are you rushing?
Where is Maya?
Where's the money?
She doesn't know anything.
Leave her.
She has no connection to this.
You don't know about me
since you never saw me, right?
This is my punch,
one punch and you're dead.
ReaIIy I don't know.
Leave us.
I want my money back if not
I'II shred you to pieces.
If my opinion Ieaving means kiIIing.
She's innocent, Ieave her.
Leave her.
How can she not know?
She's that crook's sister, right?
Get my money and take her.
I'm giving you 2 days time.
You know my hideout, right? Lanka!
EduruIanka!
Leave me!
I must save Sathya,
I don't have anyone other
than Sathya.
Where's money with me?
How do I know where Maya is?
Where is he?
Where?
He toId me to find,
did I miss anything?
How did Fredricks know Maya
is in Hastinapuram?
That oId hag wouId've toId him.
I'm sure Ranjit Kumar wouId've known
about this pIan from the beginning.
Master, poIice are here.
I suspected something fishy
that day itseIf.
He's a crook, I'm sure they
both are hand in gIoves.
How couId he come to my room?
I'm sure he wouId've toId him.
Did he find Maya?
Why did Fredricks shoot?
Why did he ask about money?
It means nobody has found Maya.
He wouId've pIanned it
from the beginning.
He brought a gun warning us
not to bring.
But stiII gun was empty!
It means he Ioaded it
without my knowIedge.
He made the entire pIan.
I said Iet's cIimb from other side,
he said from transport buiIding.
I'm sure he wouId've hidden
it somewhere.
But how?
Where?
How couId he do it?
Now I remember.
We went to buy bags, he wouId've bought
extra bags from the same shop.
How many bags do you've Iike this?
Three is enough, right?
Pay the biII.
Yes, which route did we
go to dump PC?
He wouId've escaped definiteIy
in that route onIy.
Moinabad! He toId us to parceI
gas cutters from Moin Brothers.
Moinabad, Moin Brothers,
there's some connection.
When we took PC,
he went aIone for a minute,
he wouId've changed the bags then,
It means bags are in Moinabad.
Moin Brothers Cargo Company.
DefiniteIy money is stiII there onIy.
Where's my parceI?
Where's my parceI that
came from Hyderabad?
Your parceI, okay?
What's your name?
MayaIori Madan.
- MayaIori Madan?
The man who came two days ago,
was he Mayadari MaIIigadu?
He sent me, pIease teII me
where's the parceI?
We'II not deIiver to anyone
who comes here.
That's my parceI, teII me
if not you'II die in my hands.
KiII me! You've seen
how big the godown is!
It'II take 2 days to find it.
Get the LR, I'II get it
for you in 2 minutes.
If you teII him that I was here,
you're a dead man.
Are you fine?
PIease turn and
show your handsome face.
Are you shocked to see me here?
You're a crook.
I'm a crook and
aIso a poIice officer.
It seems you're in Iove!
Can you dare take money and
save her when I'm here?
She'II die anyway, give the money
to me and save your Iife.
If Sathya isn't there
then I'm aIso not there.
Go to heII!
Come on !
Where's he?
- He Ieft just now.
OnIy a crook knows about another crook.
Stop...stop...
PIease Iisten to me.
I don't have time.
He has taken Sathya to EduruIanka.
EduruIanka?
- Yes.
Both Ieave it here,
you can't escape from here.
Hey crooks, I'm warning you
the Iast time,
Leave the money and
surrender yourseIves.
Vamsi, come...come.
How dare you pIay games with me!
PIease stop...Iisten to me.
Maya, we must go away from here.
We don't have time,
if we don't return the money
by morning, he'II kiII your sister.
Who wants sister?
I want onIy money.
Money!
Got it?
Join hands with me, Iet's kiII him.
I'II give you 50% share.
Join me, don't think.
Fire at him.
My money...my money...
BIoody crook!
You wanted to me, right?
You became a crook after
becoming a poIice officer,
I'm a born criminaI!
I'm a crook!
Body is tiII thirst ends...
Lightning is tiII darkness onIy...
Listen to the truth of Iife's secret...
Turns and twists are
Iessons of Iife...
As my Iove you chiseIIed
my heart as you desired...
My heart Ioves you...
Time wiII not to now...
It'II not teach you moraIs...
A crime has thrown you far away...
It hurt your heart and
seething with revenge...
Sky, water and earth are aII mine...
Youth has decIared a war
and raising a war cry...
Hey you bastard!
Brother, he's here.
KiII him, brother!
KiII him...kiII him!
To puII the trigger
you don't need great courage,
any kid can do it,
if you're a gun, use it,
if you're a reaI man,
throw it and come.
Come, Iet's settIe it today.
Come on !
You said something, right?
Don't Ieave him...kiII him!
Get up!
KiII him!
What did you wish for?
I wished to die in you Iap.
Why are you throwing sand on me?
Who said I'm not a crook?
I'm a crook!
One who wishes to Iive wiII die in fear.
One who decides to die wiII kiII
the other man before dying.
EIder one!
You aIways thought I was
a viIIain, it is true.
I'm a reaI viIIain.
No Vamsi...no...
You're aIways a hero to me.
Come.
Did you fight that day for him?
When you said my sister is in
troubIe, I thought something eIse.
You paid me in my own coin.
How can a thief's sister
become a Iady?
Where's my money?
I want Sathya not money.
Take her...Ieave the money behind.
Take her away!
I'm ashamed to be your sister.
You've made brother's
reIationship meaningIess.
You want money, right?
- Yes.
Come, I'II show you.
Take it.
What are you Iooking at?
This is my money.
Mine!
Never again show up before me.
Go!
You toId me you'II go away
with her, right?
Go away!
I'II give you a Iakh,
take that boat aIso.
Rs.1 Iakh? Okay sir.
Start the engine.
You're damn Iucky, you crook.
Go quickIy.
I'm tired, Sathya.
I'm tired after running aII my Iife.
Enough !
I've hidden something from you.
It's my money.
You bIoody crook!
My name is Koti, you crook!