Hackney 1951
Please!
you tell them that
If they come near
us again we kill them.
I said the twins was cursed from birth.
Ron! Enough!
When they were babies,
they infected diphtheria.
Reggie recovered but the doctors talk
to their mother there is no hope for Ronnie
But She know all they
needed both each other
They brought Ronnie
home to be with his twin
The doctor said they nearly
survived by others per
aspect of violent crime
made a pact with the Devil.
Two Agents of Evil in
exchange one young life.
Have a nice day
‫**** The rise of the Krays  ****
We grew up in a world where you
on both sides of the law was
Measured by a single store value
And violence was a currency assurance
If the old man get you when
you are growing up
The chances world bloody
will laughing with
Fortunately the twins could fight
They were a school boys boxing champions
Both of them could able to win
But wasn't right it is  for
triumph was draw for them
But the violence.
And it was outside the rings
keep them more than enough
Call I both? yet
If I got smok?
Ramone fight you?
Who from you fought
yeah yeah, My land he is.
What is the school?
Harmons Bethnal Green.
clever guy ,huh?
That's how they look it.
I could spawn of pushing
in fun in kiddin case
It seems that you won that
yeah, I did like the teacher
out and stand on his head.
Run along
move along.
Why?
Have we doing anything.
I said ; move along
And I said we don't do anything.
You need to learn some respect.
He could lose his brain
We gotta get off the street.
I know a place where they will not find us.
Follow me.
The Regal Billiards Room!
No One can find us here, Boys
Parak !
-where he is
-You were Kray?
Who is asking?
-You Are there, son
Oh yeah?
Come on then.
Had he Enough?
He is yours
Release him, Mr.( Read.)
You carry, son?
Press on
How are you guys?
Ah Com on give this guy here
Who wins here?
Drink is on you right.
Literally.
Look at those ears.
Is quite some guy!
He looks like a man,ha ha
You sure you wanna take this on?
It is being full now lately
- So I
- We can handle it.
If you say so
That will be ten per week
Fair elsewhere.
Let us doing business with you.
Reggie, you do not forget anything?
Security.
But you're the security.
No anymore.
Let manage this; We can be seen to begin
involved in any rough stuff ; can we reach
On the prices of the troubles wages
with this stop the cost of security yet
Five per week.
But...
Fair elsewhere
Nice place is
Too little girls here.
Too expensive for a girl alone.
is more a replace for couples.
Look at that space girle there
Costs a fixed weekly wage to talk to her.
If have the last wages
for week on you?
Too long ago.
Luckily there is anything else
to keep her happy, you know?
Do me a favor and talk normally.
Look who she is waiting
What a waste.
Who is that fellow?
That's Jackspot ,He is
the chooser in London.
He is the chooser
in London, my ass.
What fucking a joke.
Is this tent of him?
No.
He runs it and some tents nearby.
You sit cross what, Ron?
I've seen him once.
Years ago.
He came down in a manner wear a cowboy hat
and boots. and had two gorilla with him.
I can't understand why a hard man in manner
borrow a scrap and run in a fancy dress
You do not sound impressed, Ron.
Impressed?
I wanted to shoot the bastard.
What earns spot in this tent, Teddy?
back to school in a week.
To school a week?
Go return attention to that.
I saw enough of there, they might have
a nice drink ;the name appear of the nice dry
These parasites drinking
delicious for free.
Speaking of free wine I think
my ticket will come up.
I'll see you later.
Guys.
Hello darling
What to drink?
-No Thanks, I'm with someone.
Other than sometime.
You do not look forward to
if you can afford it.
Do you like  expensive taste?
No, your eyes are bigger than your pocket.
You look clearly in the wrong pocket.
Hey, Lisa. The boss wants to table.
I am borred; is he ignore me at night
So what? You know the rules.
- Don't go  talking with Tom Dokirari
-Dick.
What did you call me?
I will call you anything
like if it can fits
Richard Baker. At your service.
My friends call me Dickie.
Alright I get it.
You should seem tough on the girl.
You had your moment. Get out.
Do me a favor both of you. Right Sam?
You've done your Job
I'll be there in a minute.
-Half a Minute.
Well, it has been fun.
Come to see me later
hah,to you see more
I do not think so. I am your leage
You're cute, I admit that
May be we have some time again
You never know.
What are you reading? Ron
Extracts of Churchill speeches.
Are you kidding ?; Ron
special service in it
A great man, Churchill, Teddy.
Listen. to this
"The price of greatness",
is responsibility.
We do that, Teddy.
Taking responsibility.
Hello there.
What I can get for you?
-As usual
how you got me
there on the freight
you are as you say
Tell the manager that Vittor was here.
you look at him
I am sure he lend you total
about the weekly arrangement
And what arrangement that be?
Ten pounds per week you pay me
Did he say that? What do you do for that?
We make sure that you are a
nice establishment here...
And there is no troubles
There are crazy
people around here.
ِAlright. Ten per week, you said?
I understand.
Would you excuse me?
Just for a moment.
As Churchill would say
Never turn your back to...
When any frequent danger.
Or run away from it.
If you make it promptly
And in falange;You reduce
the size of danger by half
Run away
Never remain here !!!  ...Never
Come on! Start!
Come on!
He is right in one thing, guys.
There are crazy fucking people there.
..You Must be wrong...
... Ron is a little fighter...
... He is messing Reggie, that's all.
I take him.
He needs to be with his brother.
We will do thing
Why?
We almost does nothing
don't so blame ;It's a freaks.
We give them a lesson
before I get a raid
Let us to see him try
Let us do , no harm will
happens to the little child
-it is over;
-What about sunday lunch?
I sould work about soon
Now , going!
Just do ; you could try any
kind manly Boy. drag one .
Quite seize the polite
Ah!!
Dickie.
Pay attention to the case.
Do you want.....
no company?
No, thanks.
We just go for a walks now.
I lost my ass night
Good afternoon, guys.
glad you may came.
You are a lot essential
if you invite us for drink
Let me buy you buff one
(Madge) ; Two lemonade
Shandy for our guests.
That what little boys drink isn't?
(Madge), take a little
break , and let us quiet
Go on (Madge), not too long.
That's enough.
Clear message, (Reg).
you get the message, alright
Two pints Malt, (Madge).
One for yourself.
It is so lovely place you got here.
Would do us three.
Come on, Frankie.
It is colder than watch is
Well? What do you want?
Is Frank in?
Frank! There is a some guy for you
You are Frank's sister?
Rummy. are you flow as new other ?
Do not get excited, it was
not a compliment.
Who are you then?
I am (Reg). (Reg Kray).
So. you going to the town then?
Yes. We go to the port.
Wait! - Do not cross my way ,
we are in a hurry. - Not
Beware. Hi Reg, sorry about her.
wasting wine for be as right
Bye Bye (Reg)
Nice to meet you.
Come on Reg,let us going
we'll miss the first race
The twins  move from strong to strong
(Regal) became the center
of their operations
And the rock (Ron) and (REG)
look it as their fortress.
A place to retry entertainment
and the two faces outside
But for it was Regal's
answer to the score run.
There was a stock exchange
faces trade information
They obtains and schmooze
well with their investors
There's a Bank of England how
will give in cash still downstairs
And there was the twins, taking act
return as free now in stock brokers
In meantime Jackspot was retired.
The Italians wanted to takeing over, threatening
everyone finish that made difficult.
The twins did was they always did.
strike first
Waching men
To Colonel, I want
to get the round first
You stay here
waiting for my signal.
Nobody choose my owe long
go to unfinished business
with me and my brother Reg
Well, we are here. So let's go.
What is the man?
Are you begged and
up to understand English?
Oh, yeah.
Now your stuff is
fucking smart ass...
What the fuck was that?
What is rong. What did you do there?
I have getting shot someone.
Where is your glasses, Ron?
-Dickie, Go inside. And
see if anyone was there
He shot Michelangelo.
Excuse me.And
have good night for you
I just take your time, sir.
So we meet again.
How long would it be this time?
It could be a few years. I would say
I'm not here for a friendly chat.
Say what you have to say,
on what be happening
You know...
Shoot in a night club full of people ,
It seem to be bad step for you,( Kray).
So a fraud, cab robberies,
is like you win every
But shooting?
But I told you.
I do not know what you're talking about.
We have get a positive id
From one of the club steward
look You shoot up in this time
the ID is stay out
Not include my brother Reg
Why  you shoot him?
One hear you to say:
"A little bird tells me,
you love to thank me for unfinished
business with me and my brother Reg"
ِAnything will you add?
Mooney. I hear you
One second
It's your wife.
Hello?
Really?
Well done.
Buy some
nice for the little girl
That bastards
Now everyone carry a gun
and think they can do anything.
I don't think Rone knew how much you
rewrite the rules that Italian incident
Until then only showing their guns,
even the Irish group.
What is wrong he did or not,
remains of matter of debate
He will stop to be into
a type of bigger boys
And there is anybody
will cross it off
- Hi Dickie.
- What can I do for you?
I want to Talk to Reg.
Excuse me darling for minute
What is it? Dikki
Jakki Taylor is a street gang threatened
one of our club owners this afternoon
Wich one?
-Bobby Ramsay.
He smash up their club,
and threat to move slashing
If they did not pays his waiting
pension to them instead of us
Most of Taylor personnes has
going down this night soon now
Who's talking with them?
Me, Teddy and Ramsay.
- Ramsay is Australian.
-That is matter of  Ron.
He is still be on it and said he comes back
when he see  Taylor Jackie's blood on it.
- shit
Go back to the Regal.
I meet you there.
Where is he?
Which one of you Taylor!
He was here just yet, eh?
Tell him...
Tell him I'll come back.
What?
He is Taylor's little brother.
Well, well, well,
look  we have get here?
How are you, Ronnie?
What do you fucking looking at?
Fuck off and close the door.
Tommy...
Blide
Modify it, Bobby. Do your worth
Over the head
stick in him.
Good guys you send his brother
a message will not forget.
Good Boys.
Let's going to the other bastards.
You can say go bring me all day?
God will save you, Ronnie Kray.
What have I done this time?
Robbed The Bank of England ?
Set the fire to Buckingham Palace?
You know when I first meet you
I show sorry for you
Now go ...
look to see what you got to say
or fuck for you?
I will  going before you
finish your paper work.
Not this time, Kray.
The victim is very determined
To testify against you.
And there were a number
of witnesses tell us so.
Is that was not enough.
the banging host on the attack was
found in the back of the car you were in
And you were found to be
in possession of a lamby gun
In a word, Kray. You fact
The fact kill you.
Put him downstairs
and lock him up.
we found the offended guilty my lord
Nice type of scotch
It seems the bad begin
Look at that.
Here I can get used to real class.
She is lovely.
Do you see what we can
achieve without hassles.
Excuse me, Dickie.
It went from bad to worse.
For Ron.
The trouble started when he was
transferred for good behavior.
After a while he start to behave strangely.
Said that everyone had to have him.
Ron.
Would you come to the game room.
It's not good to sit here alone.
He burst into games room I went berserk
He was transferred to a mental asylum
and they said he is not find in sane.
I know how things stand, Reggie.
I spoke to one of his doctors.
Without medication,
he's a time bomb.
He is a danger to himself
and everyone around him
And you will never move him into
the inevitable explosion anyone else
get out now
while we still can
Good. Have your way?
Hello dear.
Sying I and you pass good evening
I love your hair
Hello, nice face ,
Lady are you well?
Hi, Reg. You wanted to see me?
We need to arrange a meeting.
With the Italians and Maltese.
Ingress of gambling
we can make a fortune
Standing in a distance over
we should sit down and talk
They feel solid nothing.
The Italians are more easier
What about the  street gangs?
No chance. After what I've heard,
to me spit in our face.
Not after what we have
done with their club.
I tell around.
I heard Ronnie quickly becomes free.
Yes, we get it next week.
How is he?
If he takes his pills
and drink keep himselve ..
He will be fine
Thank you for coming gentlemen.
I know you're busy
So I get straight to the point
The new gambling law
brings new opportunities for all of us
There is more after around
Why would we fight ever?
It is wise now to
Find out what belongs to whom.
Each from them runs at term off
Free from outside interference
War is costly, gentlemen.
And no one likes to waste money
No one of you.
good.
Let's go to the business.
Ron.
What a lovely surprise.
I did you expect tomorrow.
You know Ronnie.
How is the club?
you should come
and pay your visit soon.
Vittor.
Nice to see you again, my friend.
Nice to injure here, Vittor.
What the fucks is going on here, Reg?
Why do we talk to these wankers?
We are not dealing with scum.
We take what we want.
Go on! Fuck up the lowers
Ron
-Don't ..
fucking touch me.
He took his damn pills
Excuse me, gentlemen. Dickie,
you close the meeting please.
Thanks for coming.
What did they say?
They said...
They understand  Ron illness
And they stay in your plan.
But...
-But what?
So long Ron go in the shops
they call not from the lines
It is funny just I am
It started already.
What can I do?
He's my brother
for fuck suck in sick
Reg...
-What?
Ther is more bad news.
just  you call for Jackie Taylor
He wants to have delivered Ron
at the tavern. Tonight.
He wants Ronnie delivered?
That's what he said.
He said, " Be there or else..."
We fucking will be there.
And he is lucky if he
see a day again after we leave
They saw peuple operate and Ronny was mad
and dragging Reggie with him
Tell that to Jackie Taylor and the others
who were beaten that night
Ron got something else that night.
He got the whole Reg and
the family under his wing
For a while, at least.
The Twins emerge from the flight with the Walton
Street is the undisputed bosses of East London
Then they Thought east land
to the west Land
In addition, they had a lot of luck, when
businessman Leslie Payne was joint the firm
As I've already told you Mr Payne
I have no interest in selling my shares in the club
Quite. I do understand.
But you listen to my terms before you
dismiss my clients inquiry out of hand
What are your clients terms Mr. Payne?
One thousand pounds.
In cash, of course.
A thousand pounds.
My shares are five times of that.
Calm down you have some exaggeration
No Mr. bloody well not
Else to introduce me to sell my share
in a very successful gambling club
frequented by extremely wealthy
clients for only one thousand pounds.
if you be kind enough
to sign on the final page
Where your initials show in pencil
I'm a witness the agreement
And all will be done
Congratulations, gentlemen.
Now ,I suggest you out of the club
order a bottle of champagne
And introduce the new owners
to the management staff.
That was straightforward enough
-Indeed.
Cheers.
May I have another 500?
-No.
What? but I've never refuse this.
- Now it is.
I always pay my debts.
-I do not care>
I'm David Litvinoff.
That give fuck to you.
This play is rediclouse
What was that about?
The customer exceeded his limit.
He doesn't understand he cannot
have any more credit
-I want this kind stay under control
- How much does he want?
Another five hundred.
Give it to him.
I always like to make a customer smile
With all respect Mr.
Kray,the success in this industry
is all about keeping
the bad debt to minimum
Don't let me worry about that debt.
Gave him his five hundred.
More you ready to
double the club credit.
- With all due respect ..
-Do it.
The more mony they lose,
the more mony we make.
Yes, Mr. Kray.
And enough now trouble
to turn in bad debt
Else the good one.
Ronnie! please.
Please Ronnie, no!
Now where did you say you get
your watch and jewelry bitch?
So you sign the report
that we received earlier,
That three men were suspend you
by your legs from a flat window ?
That must be mistaken
All five of them?
I have nothing more to say
now,  please may I leave?
I'm sorry, Reggie.
Just What I feel
Frances, you know I love him
And you say you love me too
So I want  you marry me?
I'm only 19. I'm
not ready for marriage and children.
And then my mom and dad
What about your mom and dad?
They want  rid of the relationship.
-Why?
I do not know.
Your own business ..
What's wrong with you?
It is cookie for staff ,
and you rub frequently people
beat them up and
steal their money ..
They said you felon.
It is  better for women
waiting for knock on the door
than tell your husband arrant or worse
I have to marry someone
with proper job.
And regim prospects
Regim prospects?
Half the millionaires
in London were once been..
as fun free and wanna gen.
That Ronnie and I planing to do.
Give me a year, Frances.
Give me a year to show you I could be
a kind man that you and your parents proud
I do not know, Reg.
-You can try, Frances.
Let me prove it.
And you can decide about that?
Please.
Ok.
I won't be up in case you want off in
Until we finish a year
It is over between us.
I understand.
I make it happen
I promise.
So, How we doing?
Well Reg. Very well indeed.
A license for long-term money.
We show clear on the ground this year
There is a born
Every minute Leslie.
In mean time, the protection payment for
the gamling Westend club was doubled  here.
That's good, Leslie.
Maybe it's time to get staff about gain it.
ben shops and restaurants that we could makes
Then the money running in.
And draws less attention from the police.
I express perfect sense Reg
What is this shit about  Leslie?
If that was all gentelmen.
I have a train to catch .
Reggie good evening.
-Thanks, See you tomorrow.
Well !
What is wrong with you?
You.
you go in soft
That's what's wrong with me.
Is tha go
This plan will fuck
your head mind
You supposed to be a man.
Instead you looks a sick poodle
Running around after her
with your tongue on her heel
Looking for bad on head
you should try hanging the cat instead
Then you might show more interest.
Don't fucking talk about Frances likt that
Or what?
You let me or love her  make you sad
and strike your fucking tummy
This is over; sit down
sit down Reg!
You are may be sick
Call yourself for man.
Take him outside.
The closer Reggie was with
Frances, the more Ronnie fell
And if the Ronnie fell frightened
No one will safe
Hi Dickie, do you want tea?
No thank you, I'm on my way home.
I'm gone for piss.
Still angry?
-Yes.
he became black by the day
If he does not take his fucking pills,
I am not want continuous.
Ron Hey, long time no see. How are you?
I am alright Joe. How about you?
Cafe pay back
at the moment.
You know the slut show via
I'm glad you say it.
How much you need?
-lot much just enough turn
Turn here in the end of the week.
-Five do you?
Like you want value.
Time is not
Look at you.
Talk to me nicely few
extra pounds as I want
Explain yourself Right.
Leave us.
Is this will  stop, Ron.
You go stop drinking
You go take your
medicine every day.
you hear?
If you don't , it's only a matter of time before
you do something really serious
And look you for good.
We belong together, Ron.
This stay old
Remember the Christmas card
mom sent when we were kids?
She wrote:
You two so I love
you love enviable
Do you remember that, Ron?
How I could forget !
I have it framed and hung in the hallway.
Every time I walked there I said
Staring me in the face
slack the fucking curse
I cross myself every time I see it.
Don't point on this. If we can not act
togother You end up in the gutter.
-Do Not you ever ever shut up?
You are so lucky
Day in day out
Your voice in my head
like a fucking parrot.
I do something. Does not matter.
Go bake cakes for all fucking care.
shut a fuck up before
I blow up huge.
Hi Reg.
You still can not talk?
Halo Boss
The work is sad
If you don't see what going on
It's okay
So new friends we need
Friends in high places.
You work someting on it?
Good evening and welcome.
-Ah, Reg.
Let me introduce you to
Tom Driberg district of Barking.
Tom, this is Reggie Kray.
Nice thing you have, Mr. Kray.
-Fijn Like it.
Come this way
Now Teddy  tells me you have a little problem
I may be able to help you
That depends, Mr. Driberg.
Depends on what?
Have your MPs have
a real much power?
Some do. Some do not.
But wouldn't reveal
to come to the empire such
But It is the Influence of
one has the whole power
Like you!
I imagine it the same
of  your business
Now then which lose about it ?
My brother and I do
much charity work.
Charity work?
When people love why
Excuse me?
You know ; People do in time
Their families are often our times in
Which want help
Sure It is not bad Idea But you have
something specific in mind.
Yes. I want a sick prisoner
to London transfer.
So his old mother
him to visit.
Now lot for us to vist him
Write his name on a piece of paper.
I'll see what I can do.
I have a friend on the
head office that can help fix.
I'll be back.
Handsome boy, huh?
Yes Hi is
He is very nice indeed
I'm having a little party
in my place tonight
When would you come?
Either he will be there
With some other friends.
It is spanded idea. But I am
meeting  a friend of mine
Bring him alone
If you think It is interest to him
Oh, I think it might
Cedar Court in Upper Clapton.
Why l don't tell Teddy Smith
to go and collect your friend
and bring
them back to the party
Here's the name, and the prison.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you Mr. Kray.
-Mr. Driberg.
Tonight, Mr. Kray.
Tonight. I make sure that Teddy
brings your friend and find the way right.
Thank you, Mr. Kray.
Shall we go?
After you.
Don't  you joint morning?
Later, Teddy.
that is appair bad, Ron.
It seems to be
obviously a worse
Not so late, Teddy.
Look at all these important men.
With their dirty little secrets.
and their silly bargains
I wonder what would happen,
as their secrets came out.
Imagine the scandal.
What price with the desperate man
on this ilande, Teddy?
But there's  more and more spider.
And there's more and more web.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I have good news.
Today we start a major
offensive against the Krays!
We are ready for it.
Prime Minister, the Commissioner was arrive
-Ah show him in
Good morning, Premier.
Mr. Secretary.
I take the read this morning
edition of the Sunday mirror
"Peer and a gangster in yard probe"
Claims police investigating alleged homosexual
relationship between a pair of the realm
And the east against them
With the suggestion of a blackmail
Before you answer why would you
find out if it is allegations is true
It could bring down the government
And undermined the political
establishment for the years to come
Joe, we need the right
anser from you on this one.
what I can say this, that Scotland Yard
is categorically not undertake an investigation
into organized crime in the capital
In fact if you ask I can
go in a the records
to see if the organized crime in
London is into the climb
Excellent. Thank you, Commissioner.
That will be all
Prime Minister,
and Secretary.
Prime Minister I'm sorry, I have the
opposition leader on the phone.
Thank you.
Good morning, Harold.
Good morning,
Premier minister
have you the liberty to discuss the
sunday paper allegations?
- Of course, Harold. - I say You know,
that we have no intention of making
a political capital after the story
too close of the general election.
That is very decent of you boy.
well in pieces you can believe
me under matter of the rest.
Arnold Goodman offers its services
at Lord Boothby.
Better he than senior Tory lawyers.
Yes, I agree. I am very
much obliged for the call.
-You spoken to be with me?
-You suicide look
We come to trial we
both be fault  the rules
Is it not strange, the leading Labour lawyers
saves the famous scandal story  pair?
It is not lose this political
scandal body about Tom
It is yours
After the perfume affair,we hold
the morale high ground.
I have not the intention of losing
that so close to the election
( Read )
You mean, close down
the Kray investigation?
We're working on
for three years.
with all due respect sir
you can't destruct that
Hello?
Bastard!
Come in
I sometime wonder
who the criminals are
I am sorry Harry.
The Krays are a no-go area
Black state are then
I know it is not
Fuck them I am not giving up
Krays taking cookies
And Fucking Ronnie's
things can wait to happen
we can sleep up
And when they do we will be there
We will be there you and
me for a very long time
Are you absolutely certain
about that Mr.McCowan ?
yes I keep coming into the club for point
out the interest for the fraction worth
So if I don't come to an
agreement soon
there is something unpleasant
will happen to me on my club or both
Well, the Krays are nasty and
a pieces of work Mr. McGowan.
you will arrest them to be surely
about they do this things
cuffs them
Can we nab the judge?
No, Reg. That will be illegal.
I mean, is it possible
to nab the judge?
No, absolutely not.
Right could you tell Mr. Smith
to prepare a paper for Teddy visit
and tell him runs go some
very compromising them before us
And we all on the way of the sunday
mirror and let he see what is that.
-Next.
-Nego sounds down last time
That prosecutor was a fucking warrior
On my side said this time of aid
Find some one for Ron.
His witnesses he said to go
go and show it
On every site on the
gallery be taken of our peuple
on the first
day of the trial .
And I want every member of
the jury find out that now
We need to turn one of them
Anything else?
Yes. Hire the best private detective
in which you can find.
McCowen process require a two pound note
I should just about do a reckon
The trial was fast
The case of the twins fell apart
as witnesses has changed sides
and certain members of the jury
couldn't agree on the verdict.
the twins emerge for reputation sky
height and become celebrities
We are extremely happy.
And all those charges against us
,unjuste to jury us and all false.
Our special thanks go to our  good friend
, Super intendent 'Nipper Red '
Hello, Nipper.
Reggie What are you going draw fuck up?
The poor man almost drowning.
You want to know who is inside.
Why don't you coming in?
There will not be any trouble
It's alright, Harry.
I won't be long
Come on
stady, Ron.
I said there will be no trouble.
What the fuck do you want?
I just want you know
That today there is change nothings
I'm still here.
And sooner or later...
I can put you into detention
Give this loser a glass of bubbles,
so he is remember that evening by
Am I need when I kick him said sorry
before I put him in the street
Who is that, Ronnie?
This is... Detective - Inspector
Leonard 'Nipper' Read.
From Scotland Yard.
Make sure you spelled
the name right
Keep sing, Kray.
I love that when I put you away
I suggest you go from here
when you are still care
And if you are serious
to bring us down,
Remember that we fight
according Queens bury rules.
We are...
Damn untouchable!
How you go?
I'm still one piece
The club will give up, Harry.
Those narrow bastards
are the last thing we do
Come on.
Excuse you
-Hello Stranger.
No Jack spot !
-I Grew up, and he need to have money.
Has time been kind to you?
Yes. For you too?
What are you doing here?
I suppose to attain an Arab sheikh
can offer shop company
But that silly old sort
quite just into the bed
Any gay men ah?
-No, do you mind
Overseas customers want
a little glamor for appearances.
when the business is done
everyone goes home
I wait, you still want mony alright ?
looks you have a pretty face and great body
So you're worth  for that
It's my lucky night.
I offer you to Dance?
Why not?
I'll be back, in a minute;  Right?
- Don't be long.
Teddy want  got hella
bands Tyson in a bit more lively
Sure thing, Ron.
You are already last loses, are you David?
Come on, Ronnie.
I'll pay you back, I promise.
No.
Yes.
No I know that you
know me for money
Now that you've been saying bad things
about me behind my back.
That's not very nice now is it?
Ronnie please. I had no idea
of  what you're talking about!
I think you did
-look I am sorry, I had no idea!
You are taking your liberties.
You have a big mouth.
- I'm sorry if I offended you .
- I am really Iam not..- Sss.
When I was little, David
I loved comic books.
First of all , I like Batman.
Have you ever read
that batman comics, David?
Yes, I have read them
Yes , I always loved
the bad guys myself.
You know, and I miss
your laugh  , David
You always remind
me of that villain
How is his name ?
Oh yeah....
The Joker.
Don't you think he looks
a bit the Joker yet
I can assume see
a resemblance , Ron.
Please
the problem is
his map.
His map... is not quite right.
- It is the wrong shape.
- Ronnie, please
-The mention right.
-Ron.
-I can see what you mean.
-yes.
- Ron.
He needs to be a bit bigger
- Please.
Do not you think?
What is it, Dickie?
A few words, Reg. Urgent.
Excuse me.
- Non, Please.
- Let's just say,
If we can  make that mouth
of yours a little  bigger!
O Jesus!
Fuck you, Ron.
What the fuck have you done?
Do you were said or no
That we are untouchable?
And I do what the fuck I want!
This is what happens...
This what happens if you
fuck with the Krays!
Damn , you don't!
fuck with me
Because with me
a long strange too
will fuck me hook
twety foots in the fucking air
And in your fucking ass!
Show you me!
the dog eat dog world
and power goes to the best
for the sharpest teeth
The posh accent not change the joe's saying
Power corrupts.
The greater is power ;
the bigger they abuse.
base of all things you need
to be careful what you wish for
Because nothing bite hard as the life
We are nest stone
We have every
fucking inch on this land
WILSON WINS ELECTIONS
The end of the rise