Previously
on "Childhood's End"...
At least 40 cities
around the world
now have these vessels
hovering over them.
- My name is Karellen.
- Suffering will end.
Injustice will end.
It's world peace.
All hold hands and sing Kumbaya.
This is an invasion.
Ahh!
My eyes!
Why are you here?
We need a messenger.
The birth rate is soaring.
We have a world that we are
proud to bring children into.
It's the golden age
of man, Utopia.
Why did you make this room?
Why did you send me Annabel?
Because she is still the most
important thing in your life.
One day you'll understand
why I came back
and why he built the room.
Ricky?
Karellen
is not letting you move on.
Are you stealing
the Titan drives?
Private research.
For 20 years, the Overlords
have told us precisely nothing
about themselves.
I'm a guy
that likes to know stuff.
It's Karellen.
He's back.
Very good to see you, Ricky.
He said that the Earth
has a new destiny.
[grunting]
Karellen said that there was
something in the fabric
of the ship that poisoned me.
Help us!
Karellen said that something
special was coming.
Don't touch us.
[loud thudding]
I take it you're the Greggsons.
Our son Tommy is having
some behavioral issues.
[screaming]
Tom just said
the strangest thing.
- Jennifer.
- What?
I know what to call the baby.
We need to reclaim some of
what we had when we were kids.
We're not moving to New Athens.
It might be good for all of us.
We need to add these people
to the guest list.
This gentleman wants to fly me
to South Africa
for a job interview.
Your whole family's invited.
- Milo Rodricks.
- Jake Greggson.
- Here's my card.
- He's here.
The supervisor for Earth.
You're killing
scientific curiosity.
Your scientific curiosity
would've destroyed you.
The supervisor would like
to meet with you.
[all gasp]
We'll find a new voice
inside you.
[loud humming, all gasp]
Tom!
Jennifer, she's awake.
No!
So each symbol is a letter.
This one is new.
I recognize the pattern, Rachel.
[screaming]
Jennifer.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Hey.
[baby wails]
Hi.
Want to say hi to Mommy?
Jennifer.
Hey, Jennifer.
Hello, pretty girl.
Oh, hi.
[baby cooing]
[baby gurgling]
[wistful music]
♪
[low thrumming]
[children singing faintly]
_
Kids: ♪ Down came the rain ♪
♪ And washed the spider out ♪
♪ Out came the sun ♪
♪ And dried up all the rain ♪
♪ So the itsy bitsy spider ♪
♪ Went up the spout again ♪
When the Overlords came,
they helped us put away
childish notions
based on greed and fear,
but this is nothing compared
to what they've inspired
in the younger generation.
They eat better food
and breathe better air
and are enjoying the healthiest,
stress-free lives
human beings have ever known.
As a consequence,
the next generation is fitter,
stronger, healthier.
Human 2.1.
Can you imagine what
their children will be like?
Undoubtedly, we are evolving.
So what are we evolving into?
Thank you for coming in,
Mrs. Ntaga.
I'm recording infant anomalies,
changes in the young children,
the kind of stuff the Overlords
are taking an interest in.
That's nice for you.
[chuckles]
For your experiment,
start with the juice.
Sami likes his juice.
Okay.
Do you want some juice, Sami?
[rapid tapping]
[skidding]
He always wants his juice.
[chuckles]
♪ Only you ♪
Mr. Hallcross,
it sounds like you're talking
about an armed resistance.
That's not correct.
But you were in the military.
Yes, I was military,
but I'm not anymore.
You're twisting my words.
What we're talking about here
is sanctuary.
Sanctuary from what exactly?
Looks what's happening
in your Utopia.
Look what's happening
to your beloved prophet,
who, by the way, is being held
together by alien Band-Aids.
I'm inviting everyone
to New Athens.
You'll be safe here.
Again, Jerry, safe from what?
[paper rips]
[music continues faintly]
[grunting]
[sighs]
[music continues faintly]
[panting]
♪ ♪
[crickets chirping]
[dog barking distantly]
[engine approaching]
[grunts]
[door creaks]
[horse whinnies distantly]
You seem weaker.
[sighs]
Yep.
Well, we've had the good times,
right?
And now we pay the check.
The final stage has begun.
I want to tell you
what will happen to the world.
My friend, we are not
the authors of this plan.
We are facilitators,
midwives if you will,
at the birth
of a new evolution of man.
I take it
you've never been a father.
I have 24 children.
And we have none.
I could spare you this.
You don't have to remain here.
If you want
to spare me something,
how about you leave
the both of us alone?
Hey, is she okay?
Hey.
Are you okay?
Are you lost?
[mysterious music]
♪
[ominous music]
Jennifer.
[speaking French]
[together] Jennifer.
Jennifer, Jennifer, Jennifer.
[together]
Jennifer, Jennifer.
Jennifer.
What the hell?
[door creaks]
Some of these kids
can lift a cup.
Some of them can move a car.
I met a three-year-old girl
who had a knack
for speaking to her parents
in their dreams,
in three languages.
I mean, their metabolic rates
have accelerated,
and there's undoubtedly
increased electrical activity
in the cerebrum.
Bottom line:
these are regular children
with cognitive, telekinetic,
and psychic ability,
and they're all linked.
All across the world,
they are somehow...
linked to one another.
It all goes back
to the first one,
the Greggson baby, Jennifer.
She's the key.
[answering machine beeps]
Hey, Jake, it's me again, Milo.
Look, I know
you want to keep your family
as normal as possible,
but it's gone
way beyond that now.
Look, I don't know
if you're aware of this,
but kids all over the world
are saying the name Jennifer,
and I think
it may have something
to do with your daughter.
Please, please, call me back.
She shows us things.
What things?
They're new worlds, Mom,
but I've not been before.
She's taking me so far away
that even the Overlords
haven't seen them.
All right, guys,
I don't care
where your parents are.
I want you out of here
right now.
I said right now!
[suspenseful music]
♪
Hey, sweetheart.
You have a lot
of new friends outside.
What do they want
to see you for?
I can see all of it.
I see your fear,
but there is no need
to be afraid.
[string snaps]
[suspenseful music]
♪
[shuddering]
[whimpering quietly]
Are you sure about this?
We don't need sheets, Amy,
just pack what we really need.
The rest we can find
in New Athens.
It's okay.
Hey, it's okay.
[smooches] Come on.
I don't always feel
like I'm really here.
You're not always here.
And now we can talk...
like this.
Yes, I hear you.
Kids: Jennifer is all,
divisible and indivisible
in one mind
that calls.
She calls to us.
We know you.
Kids: We hear you, Jennifer.
We hear you.
Kids: You are the end
of the beginning.
Kids!
Come on, Jen.
Come on.
[engine grinding]
[engine revving]
kids: Where do you go,
Jennifer?
Where do they take you?
[kids whispering indistinctly]
Your mother needs comfort, Tom.
Kids: We see you.
[kids whispering indistinctly]
Oh, my God.
[tires squeal]
kids: Where do they take you?
We must follow.
[kids whispering indistinctly]
Hello there.
On behalf of everyone
here in the last free city
on the planet,
welcome to New Athens.
Whoever you are,
I think you're gonna
fit right in.
Although we have no specific
immigration process,
we do ask that you read
and complete
the introduction packs
so that you
can formally register.
Orientation seminars are held
in many sites around the city,
and these will
help you get settled
into living life the old way.
Name, please.
The Greggson family.
Welcome.
♪
[traffic rumbling,
horns honking]
All right, guys, let's go.
You all right?
[accordion music]
Tom, Tom.
♪ ♪
Hey, Jake, it's me again, Milo.
Look, I know
you want to keep your family
as normal as possible,
but it's gone
way beyond that now.
I need to see Jennifer.
We have to learn
what's happening to her.
Please, please, call me back.
[brakes hiss and squeal]
Excuse me.
Sorry to bother you.
Would you come with me, please?
Um, what's the problem?
- Just come with me, please.
- Sure.
You're not in any trouble.
Mr. Greggson,
welcome to New Athens.
- Who are you?
- I'm Jerry Hallcross.
I'm the closest thing
this place has to a mayor.
Right.
I heard you on the radio.
This is my wife, Amy,
my son, Tom,
and this is our daughter.
What's your name, sweetie?
- Jennifer.
I seem to be
hearing that name a lot.
You're obviously very special.
We welcome everyone here.
Okay?
Maybe we can even help you.
Guys, please, relax.
You're not in any trouble.
I'm here to help.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Come on.
Okay, thank you.
It really is beautiful.
Of course, the majority
prefer Utopia,
whatever "Utopia" really means.
Can I ask you something?
The Overlords,
they really leave you alone?
They respect our decision
not to live
in their perfect world,
but do you know
what happens here?
Culture returns,
art, self-expression.
People screen movies.
They put on plays.
We even have the opera.
This year it's "Don Giovanni."
They wanted Karellen
to cameo as the Devil.
Can you imagine
if that happened?
[kids whispering indistinctly]
Red numbers will end it.
This is me.
Come on up.
Wow.
This is you?
- You're an artist?
- Yeah.
In another life,
I was a command sergeant.
- That facility out in the desert?
- Yeah.
Spaceships came;
I was out of a job.
Best thing that ever happened.
Aren't you worried
that the Overlords
might change their minds
about New Athens?
I mean, what if they
try and dismantle it?
Come on, Amy.
No, I'm not, and if they did,
I wouldn't let it.
This place is what I always
hoped it would be.
Utopia is dull, right?
I mean, to the creative mind,
peace is stupefying.
Look, we're not radicals here.
We're just trying to preserve
our cultural heritage.
We're just trying to achieve
something for ourselves.
I believe, I hope,
I pray you're going
to change here,
all of you.
You too.
Her name was Tilly.
My daughter, my joy.
She had a severe type of anemia.
So unusual.
I mean,
we can cure almost anything.
Yes, with their interference.
Tilly was getting stronger
with our medicines,
so...
so when she died, it--
"The act of dying
is the act of life."
Marcus Aurelius.
Tilly left the stage
to applause.
Jennifer will be
surrounded by life,
you know, real human life.
I'm hoping
that it will seep into her
like some sort of medicine.
It's a beautiful thought.
But what if we're wrong?
If New Athens fails,
if that day comes,
I'd rather see it burn.
You want to hold that
in your left hand.
Right here, all right?
Keep a little bit of slack
in that.
More towards the bottom,
the bottom
of that loop right there.
Here we go, ready?
You're gonna keep it
at ten o'clock, two o'clock.
Ten o'clock, two o'clock.
Do I let this--wait,
do I let this go?
No, no, no, no, hold onto that.
You holding that line?
- Hold that line.
- Yes, I am holding it.
Keep it tight.
Okay, here we go.
Keep it in a straight line.
They're like shapeshifters.
See?
It goes--there's a whale.
It's moving.
It looks like something
out of a--
like, a scary movie.
Now.
Open.
Now?
Aww...
Ells.
These are all from
before the Overlords came.
Yeah.
You and I had Utopia
before they came.
Thank you.
Home sweet home.
Huh?
[keys jingle]
Nice.
Go, check out your rooms.
It's nice.
Thank you.
Anytime.
Thanks.
Anything you need,
just let me know.
Hey, Jennifer,
come check this out.
It's so blue.
We can make this work.
[answering machine beeping]
It's that scientist, Milo,
calling again, isn't it?
Yeah.
If he wants to speak
to Jennifer, we should let him.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Maybe--
Anything that can help us
understand Jennifer better
is a good thing, right?
Milo, hi.
That's good.
Lock this.
Yeah, she's ready to go.
Okay.
Now, this won't take long.
You okay, honey?
All right, you see that?
It's all I could find.
It's fine.
I don't like this, Milo.
You have to understand
that Jennifer
is the conduit of a force
that is affecting
every kid in the world.
If you start testing her,
you'll be playing with fire.
Playing with fire
is how we learned to master it.
We're staying in the room.
It's just a few questions.
It won't scare her.
It's not her I'm worried about.
Jennifer, hi.
Remember me?
I want you to look
into the mirror.
You see into everything.
I want you to see into yourself.
What do you see when you
look into your own eyes?
Can you tell me what you see?
Do you see our future?
Do you see the power
that gave you this gift?
Please, Jennifer, just look.
Can you tell me what this means?
Jennifer, what do you see?
I see all.
I am all.
Come closer.
[Jennifer's voice echoes]
[dramatic music]
♪
[thundering roar]
- [glass shatters]
- [gasps]
[glass shattering]
The end begins.
Jennifer showed me this place,
the rock promontory.
Milo.
[buttons beeping]
Then she showed me
something else,
something destructive.
I think the Earth
could be in danger.
I need to go there.
Where exactly?
To their planet,
to figure it out, I guess,
to try and stop it.
Milo, you can't just
go to their planet.
Okay, look.
The next time
you hand over an animal,
I want to be on that ship.
I mean, you can vacuum pack me.
I mean, if the monkeys
and the snakes can survive,
then I can too.
You know,
I think you're evolving,
like those kids.
Your ego is becoming
super advanced.
How could you ask me to do this?
What do you mean?
You brought this?
My I.D.
from the kids' hospital,
the one I believed the girl
in the next bed stole from me.
It's where we started.
But where will we finish?
Hey.
Together.
There's a family movie day
every Saturday afternoon.
I saw a billboard.
It's just up the street.
Us, all together,
watching a silly old movie?
Yeah.
Sounds good.
[thunder rumbles]
Please, don't go.
Rachel, I--
Rachel, what I saw--
What if the world is in danger?
You said yourself,
the mystery is that girl,
Jennifer.
The mystery is here.
Yeah.
Look, you're right.
The mystery is here,
but the answer isn't.
It's out there.
Look, and I've done the math.
It takes the Overlords 48 days
to get back to their planet,
and they'll probably just
put me on a ship back.
So call it 100 days, round trip.
100 days
at para-light speed is--
80 years here.
But their ships
can come and go, right?
Rachel, we know
they can manipulate time.
Shut up.
I'm coming back.
[screams]
Oh, God.
[wincing and panting]
Is it these?
[screaming]
These things are useless.
[screams]
[yelping and panting]
I'm scared.
I'm so scared, Annabel.
Annabel?
[panting]
I'm here, sweetheart.
[stirring operatic music]
♪
[machine beeping]
[machinery whirring]
[air hissing]
[plastic crinkling]
[machinery clicking]
That's how we
put an animal into stasis.
Right.
What have you got there?
Yeah, um...
[sighs]
Okay.
Adrenalin shot, high-concentrate
steroid injection.
Great.
That'll kick-start
muscle action.
Full-spectrum vitamin shots,
mirtazapine anti-nausea meds,
alkaline eye-hydration,
a bottle of water,
and a--
and a granola bar.
We don't know if they
oxygenate the storage hangar
on the ships.
Hey, hey, hey.
What if you're wrong
about the ships?
You'll be gone for 80 years.
[sobbing]
[truck rumbling]
Container prepped for stowing.
Countdown, two minutes.
We don't have much time.
Right.
Will they run a scan
or something?
They run a body mass reading,
but she's a big girl.
You don't add
any suspicious extra weight.
Pressure steady.
[plastic crinkling]
[breathing deeply]
That--
that won't help.
[scoffs]
Will I dream at least?
If you do,
it'll be a 48-day nightmare
about suffocating.
[chuckles]
Fun.
[plastic crinkling]
[Over Loudspeaker] 'Prepare to
transfer specimen.'
[machine beeping]
[machinery whirring]
[exhales]
Overlord ship
entering lower atmosphere.
Don't go.
One minute until transfer.
[plastic crinkling]
What?
Rachel.
I'm sorry.
I know you're scared too.
Look, if I'm not back
in 100 days,
get on the Orbital.
It'll be safe there.
[brakes hissing, tires skid]
Get yourself on the Orbital.
Sleep the time away.
You'll figure it out.
Overlord ship
ready to receive specimen.
Here.
Love, right?
It means love.
Yes.
30 seconds until transfer.
I'm coming back.
You hear me?
Okay, okay.
You swear to come back.
I'll swear to wait.
[sobs]
Stand by.
I swear.
I swear too.
Stand by.
[air hissing]
Hibernation status satisfactory.
[chain jingling]
[ship roaring]
[machine beeping slowly]
Mm.
[chuckling]
[traffic rumbling distantly]
What time is it?
Actually, it's the start.
We're at the very start.
Of what?
The rest of our lives together.
I got something for you.
Oh.
[both chuckle]
What?
You said you wanted
to see the Yankees.
Well, yeah.
But hang on, do they
play here in this room?
Because we're not
leaving this room,
not for three days.
That's good.
'Cause this honeymoon,
the Four Seasons,
I might've run out of money.
[laughing] Okay, I yield.
[laughing] I yield.
[laughter echoes, fades]
[clock ticking]
I have a confession to make.
I didn't think that
you were gonna say yes
when I proposed.
Oh, is that what that was,
a proposal,
that business
with the Barry White
and the red rose?
Annabel.
When did you have these taken?
I don't remember.
I'm right beside you.
Ricky, I'm sorry
you lost the love of your life.
I'm here.
How did it get so late?
Where did the day go?
As surely as it rises,
the Sun also has to set.
Someone said that to me once.
Even the best day
in the world has to end,
never to be repeated.
Switch that mind off.
There's nothing to worry about.
We're safe.
Cancer.
She was so beautiful.
She had a light.
Finally, it went out.
Why are you talking like this?
This is special,
and we're happy,
so why spoil it?
You're going to stay
in this room with me.
I begged you to stay, Annabel.
I begged you
not to let your light go,
but you couldn't.
[stirring operatic music]
♪
I thought I'd never love again.
I thought would be a sin to.
It doesn't have to be like this.
But it was like this.
I mean, that's how she died.
But it wasn't here.
I can give her back to you.
I can slow down time
in this place.
You can stay here
and never leave
if that's what you want.
It isn't real.
It's a gift
from one friend to another.
The Sun doesn't have to set.
Oh, just stop, please.
You put that here, not me.
I'm so sorry.
This room...
Mm-hmm?
Bury it.
[operatic music continues]
♪
Sweetheart?
Ricky, baby, come back inside.
Oh, jeez.
Ells, you're so beautiful.
Let's go inside.
I'm gonna lie here.
I'm just catching my breath.
Okay.
I never loved anyone
more than you, Ells.
Never.
What's that one?
[wheezing]
Is it the two-headed rooster?
Two-headed rooster?
That one's the frog.
Huh.
The great frog.
[inhales]
[Randy Newman's "I Think It's
Going To Rain Today"]
♪
♪ Bright before me ♪
♪ The signs implore me ♪
♪ Help the needy ♪
♪ And show them the way ♪
♪
♪ Human kindness ♪
♪ Is overflowing ♪
♪
♪ And I think it's going ♪
♪ To rain today ♪
♪
[whimsical music]
[indistinct dialogue]
[chuckling quietly]
[laughter]
[projector clicks]
[audience groans]
[all groaning]
It's time.
People of Earth,
I speak to you again,
one last time.
You have enjoyed decades
of peace and prosperity,
a golden age for man.
But the Sun sets on even
the most glorious of days,
and it must now start to slowly
sink into the night for you.
Do not condemn us,
for we were tasked
by a higher mind
to oversee your evolution
to a higher level
of consciousness.
It is your destiny
and the destiny of many worlds.
You have grown accustomed
to our presence,
but we can be your guardians
no more.
Thomas, sit down.
Your children
are no longer yours.
In time,
they will cease to be human.
No more children
will be born on Earth.
No more children will be
born on Earth, ever again.
For the adults,
your future is yours
to live as you see please
for however many days are left.
My hope is that humanity
will go to its rest in peace.
[shrieking]
My baby!
- No, Jennifer.
- Jen.
Jen, no.
- Jen!
- No, Jen.
Jen, get down!
Jen!
Pasquale.
Jennifer.
[all shouting indistinctly]
No!
No, Jennifer!
- Honey.
- This is not gonna happen.
Jenny, no. No.
[all shouting indistinctly]
Gracie!
John!
He's gone.
[adults shouting and sobbing]
Don't leave, please.
No.
Tom, don't leave me, buddy.
Please.
Tom.
Please, don't.
Come here, come here.
Jerry!
Jerry.
[items clatter]
Amy.
Oh!
Okay, okay.
No.
He's taken it.
Mom.
Jake.
[steady beeping]
We were a greedy people,
selfish.
We screwed up in a big way,
but we made music.
We wrote books.
We mapped the cosmos.
That's right, Jerry.
We're amazing.
We're an amazing race,
so let's carry on being amazing.
Let's defy the Overlords
and get our kids back.
It's not gonna end.
We do not end,
but we can't give up hope.
There was hope,
the hope we had
since the beginning of mankind,
the only hope there ever was,
the children, Jake.
The children.
And they're gone now.
Maybe when we die,
we'll get a chance
to be with them again.
Jerry,
you built something here.
All this is in defiance of them,
right?
This is writing the book
ourselves,
so don't let them
decide the ending.
Jerry.
You know, I was thinking.
We're energy, right?
Human beings are energy.
When our bodies are gone,
that energy has to go somewhere.
Hey.
You're fading.
What?
She gave me some more time
to say good-bye, Mom,
but it's over now,
and I'm going.
You know what human beings are?
Martin Luther King,
Nelson Mandela.
They keep fighting.
We'll fight
to find our children,
and we'll fight
to bring them back.
Turn it off.
- Don't be absurd!
- Turn it off!
You saw it.
You saw it in their eyes.
They're beyond us now.
Turn it off.
Ask Jennifer
if you can stay here with us.
You belong with us.
Mom, it's all right.
I'm joining the others.
I have to go now.
She's calling me.
I have to go.
[sobbing]
You can't destroy this place.
What does it matter
what we want, Jake?
We're little men.
Just stop.
I was a little girl,
alone in a hospital bed,
and I was scared.
Remember?
And then I looked
into your eyes,
and I wasn't scared anymore.
Hey, hey.
At least we knew love.
At least we knew what it was
to be a family.
Okay, okay.
Okay, okay, I'm here.
I'm here.
[steady beeping continues]
I love you.
[explosion]
[engine roaring]
[wind swirling,
electricity crackling]
[beeping]
[air hissing]
[gasps]
[gasping]
[metallic clattering]
[choking, retching]
[coughing]
[gasping, panting]
I am is Vindarten.
This be--
This can be--
No.
This language is--
I'm new this language
but is fine and under control.
Is fine and good.
You are not well.
Hence the floor.
We use your terms,
and so in your terms,
we are 11 and 100 years
of light away from Earth.
We are orbit the sixth planet
in the Carina System.
This is our world.
You call home world.
We can call it Jenjedda.
I made it.
Indeed.
How long has it been?
It be 40 of your Earth years.
So you say it's been 40 years
on Earth, right?
What's it like there now?
Interesting.
You come this all way
here to ask for back
where you come out from.
Look, I came here
because I saw it.
The Earth is in danger.
Everything that is happen
on Earth was planned long ago.
Is natural, is the cosmos,
is the Overmind.
Overmind?
Overmind of all Creation.
Are you talking about God?
We have talked to the Overmind
for 100,000 year.
We go where it sends.
We change worlds.
We change Earth.
The Overmind,
can you show it to me?
You really want this?
I want to know everything.
It connects to the Overmind.
Step in.
You're the Overmind.
A faint reflection of it.
I am all,
divisible
and indivisible.
I am the collective
consciousness of this universe.
So we are God?
No, the children are God,
and they have left you,
as children must,
and you must let them go,
as parents must.
Only the children
can become a part of the whole.
It's an evolution.
Into one mind.
So we're finished?
We cease to exist?
We--
Oh, my God.
I have to get back to Rachel.
I need to go back.
Take me back home.
Hello, Milo.
I trust you slept well.
More comfortable than the squid,
I suspect.
I'm home.
It is not home anymore.
Right.
It's been 85 years.
While you've been asleep,
I have been
learning your language.
"Oh, for a muse of fire
that would ascend
the brightest heaven
of invention."
William Shakespeare.
What happened to the Orbital?
It happened long ago.
Rachel?
We brought her here.
Would you like to see her?
Yes.
[metallic jingling]
[jingling]
[shattering, Milo growls]
[panting]
You know a lot,
so I'm just gonna ask it.
Does anything of her
survive beyond death?
Yes, you.
It's not a consolation.
Consciousness, Milo,
is a community of minds.
Each exists
in the other's thoughts.
Rachel exists
in your consciousness
as if she had never left.
You still love her,
you still feel her,
so what has changed?
She's dead, gone.
But she once lived,
and you knew her.
You know her still.
Until I'm gone too, right?
It's all gone, everything
we built, we did.
It has been the destiny
of many worlds.
We have overseen them all.
Yeah, what about your people?
Is this gonna happen to you
one day on Jenjedda?
We have reached the end
of our development.
All our possibilities
are exhausted.
Oh, Milo.
You were so flawed as a species
and so passionate.
You believed in so much
and knew so little.
I envy mankind.
Your children can go
where we can never follow.
I miss cookie dough ice cream.
You ever have it?
It's, like,
the first time you try it,
you're all like,
"How have I lived so long
without this in my life?"
You ever come across
a civilization
with cookie dough ice cream?
No.
We did that.
Not bad.
I'm the last one.
You can stay here with us.
The boy who wanted
to know everything
can know everything after all.
Thank you.
But I don't share your view,
Karellen.
She's dead,
and I can't bear to live out
my life as the last man.
My place is out there,
someone to witness this.
If I went back to the Earth,
I could report back
what happens on the ground.
Has anybody ever done that?
You would do that for me?
Of course.
I'm a scientist.
My name was Milo Rodricks,
not that it matters anymore.
I'm--I was an astrophysicist.
I've lived more than a lifetime,
and--
and I can smell Pop-Tarts.
I'm the last human being,
enjoying his last
sensory pleasure.
I got a favor to ask.
Don't forget us.
We may have many faults,
but we don't deserve
to be forgotten.
Strike my first statement.
My name is Milo Rodricks,
until the very last second,
until the end.
[wind swirling,
electricity crackling]
Jennifer is--
she's drawing energy
from everywhere.
The Moon,
the ground beneath me
is disappearing.
She's taking everything.
Oh, God.
Jennifer, you're the last child.
[low rumbling]
It's gonna end.
[sighs]
Karellen, I'm scared.
Focus on me, Milo.
Hear my voice.
Don't be afraid.
It's natural.
You have nothing to fear.
[loud rumbling and crackling]
There's not much time.
You have to save something!
Save something from the Earth!
We can't lose it all,
you have to save one thing
please!
What?
Something from our culture.
Look, it can't be this whole
mankind never existed at all.
Please.
[beeping]
[dramatic music]
♪
[sentimental music]
[Ralph Vaughan Williams'
"The Lark Ascending"]
♪ ♪
Thank you.
[sighing]
♪ ♪
[wind swirling,
electricity crackling]
♪ ♪
[gasping]
[thunderous explosion]
♪ ♪
It is done.
What do we do with it?
Leave it here
for whoever passes through,
so they can hear it.
♪
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com