Hey, Eru...
What world...
What sky are you looking at right now?
[subbed my shinees at tumblr]
Why?
Why are you painting flowers?
Because it's what I see.
Grass?
Yeah.
Trees?
Amazing!
Huh?
I see.
You can see anything, right, painter?
That's why you have a smiling face.
No...
What's wrong?
It's scary.
Scary?
Everyone says it's disgusting.
What is?
My face.
I don't mind it at all.
B- but...
I'm... not a painter.
Hm, I see.
Then why don't you become a painter?
Huh?
Okay? From today on you're a painter!
Can I watch you paint again, painter?
Then, see you again!
Hey!
What's your name?
Ovesu.
Ovesu?
Ovesu, huh.
And... and you?
Eru!
Eru.
Later.
Okay? From today on you're a painter!
Eru!
What's wrong?
They died.
Papa and Mama.
Huh?
Their ship sank.
Papa and Mama...
What is that book?
Papa and Mama gave it to me.
Is that... me?
It's amazing.
- Hurry up and get lost!
- I'm sorry!
You're such an irritating child!
Seriously. We should've never taken you in!
Open it. Please open it, Auntie!
Open it! Open it!
Stop crying, Cinderella.
You always work hard.
You're a really good girl.
As a reward, I'll take you to the ball.
Uncle.
Are you okay?
Poor girl.
You can't win with her.
It'll be fine.
You're a good girl.
Stop crying, Cinderella.
You always work hard.
You're a really good girl.
As a reward, I'll take you to the ball.
Said the fairy godmother.
I remembered it.
Hey.
Aren't you lonely living by yourself?
Once in a while.
But... I have painting.
You always look like you're enjoying
yourself when you paint.
Huh?
Your cheeks are smiling.
Eru...
Are you lonely?
But not when I'm with you.
Then we're the same.
Is this me?
Wow!
Yeah.
It's beautiful!
Hey, Eru...
I decided to paint a picture.
I decided to paint your smiling face.
So that no matter how sad you are...
No matter how lonely you are...
You don't forget that smile.
Thank you.
Hey, did you know?
What everyone thinks of La vi an rose.
The land with no color.
That's what everyone calls it.
I can see it.
All types of colors.
I see.
You do, huh.
Have you ever heard of a place called Seravi?
No.
Papa told me about it a long time ago.
He said it's a gorgeous place with all kinds of colors.
Don't you want to see it?
I'm sure it has a lot of things that aren't here.
I want to see much more beautiful colors.
You don't need stuff like that.
To think that you're spending time
with that boy who's bad for you.
That guy.
Eru, I love you!
I love you more than anyone.
No!
What are you doing?
I'm the one who raised you until now.
Stop!
I'm sorry.
I lost all of your paintings.
Hey.
Did I smile?
Huh?
Did I truly smile?
Then paint it.
I won't lose it this time.
Ovesu.
Sorry...
Huh?
What's wrong?
Sorry.
Eru, do you have a moment?
Yes.
I have a favor to ask of you.
Okay.
I want you...
to die.
Huh?
You understand, right?!
If you don't, your uncle will be like that forever!
That's why, please die. Please die!
It's fine.
You just need to be declared dead.
You're new citizenship.
It's for Seravi.
I'm sure you'll make do there.
Seravi...
Your father worked there, right?
It's a good place.
Take this money, too.
It's what your parents left behind.
I'll give it all back.
Here.
Take it!
Give me back my husband.
I'm begging you! Please, please, I'm begging you...
You love him.
Thank you...
for everything.
It's only this place.
It never changes.
It's always nothing.
I wonder why...
The things I want changed, don't change.
Everyone I don't want to change, changes.
I won't change.
I won't.
I really...
loved your drawings.
Eru?
I really loved them.
Eru.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Ovesu.
Give that back!
Excuse me. That's mine.
Here.
Thank you very much.
It's your first time here, right?
Huh?
You were fascinated by the town. Am I wrong?
You can't give off that kind of atmosphere.
You'll be taken advantage of.
You know...
When I first came to this town,
I had the same look in my eyes.
You're not originally from here?
No.
I wanted to act here, so I came.
Then you're an actor?
I do act, but I do everything from step one.
That's amazing.
And you?
What's the reason you came to this town?
No special reason...
Then why don't you join my troupe.
I've never even seen a play before.
It's okay. I'll show you the ropes.
My place is just over there. Want to come see it?
Just for a bit.
What do you think?
Do you understand that I wasn't trying to trick you?
You're definitely suited to be an actress.
I have an eye for these things.
If you join my troupe, we'll be
the best in Seravi- No...
I have a feeling we'll be able to
stand on an even larger stage.
Acting is a really wonderful thing.
If you get up on the stage, you'll become
a millionaire and even a princess.
Even a princess?
Yeah.
Okay. First, should we start with the basics?
Here.
Try drinking this coffee.
Huh?
Come on. Try drinking it.
How does it taste?
What about the scent? The heat?
I didn't drink anything so I don't know...
Right?
But doing that is acting.
In other words, everything you've felt
until now, your senses remember.
What do you think is the most important thing in acting?
Being freed of your troubles.
That's the most important thing.
Ah... It's already this late.
Excuse me.
You don't have a place to stay, right?
If you'd like, you can sleep here.
Huh?
It's fine. I'll sleep over there, so rest assured.
Breakfast.
This bread is delicious.
I wanted you to try it.
The purpose of acting is to hold the mirror up to nature.
That's Hamlet.
No matter how long the night, the day is sure to come.
That's Macbeth.
You've gotten better.
- Raise your leg a bit more.
- Raise my leg...
And from earlier... Let me see your arm arm arm arm.
You look good when you smile.
When I'm with you, I feel happy.
It's been a really long time since I've laughed like this.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Do you have fun when you're with me?
Then...
Will you live with me?
Huh?
I want to see more of your smile.
Is it okay?
Being the best troupe in Seravi...
And traveling around the world.
What do you think? It's a wonderful dream, right?
Yeah.
And you?
Huh?
What's your dream?
My dream...
Your dream is my dream.
What's wrong?
This one will cost a bit.
Are you giving up?
I have no choice.
Dammit.
I got cocky.
Use this.
If it's for your sake.
Thank you.
I love you.
How's it going?
Can I look at the script?
Why?
I don't want to hold you back, so I
thought I should start practicing now.
What did you just say?
Hey. Hey, try saying that again!
I just wanted to see the script.
What do you know about my work?!
- It's hurts! Stop!
- What do you know?!
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
I'm in a slump and can't write anything.
Help me... Help me!
Support me.
It's okay.
It'll be okay. You're not just anybody.
I'm sorry, too.
I'm sorry that I don't understand.
Thank you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
You actually believe what they said?
But this is the money you borrowed!
They said you used the money on gambling!
You're not writing at all!
It's all blank!
It's fine if I don't become an actress.
I'll be with you.
Are you telling me to give up?
Look at the reality...
Look at the reality!
I have talent!
Someone like you who has no talent has
to support someone like me who does.
Forever!
You were born for that reason.
Sorry...
I'm sorry.
It's because you said terrible things.
You won't change?
Will you always...
be like this?
Why do I have to change?
You and I will live together and love each other forever.
Forever.
You're happy, aren't you?
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
At that moment...
she lost her glass slipper.
Stop crying...
Cinderella.
We don't need a customer like you!
What was that?!
You guys are the ones who suck at your jobs!
Don't think that just because you're a
customer you can get anyone to kneel!
Let's stop this, you're making my eyes hurt.
Dammit.
Geez.
What are you doing?
How did you get that bruise?
You're so cold.
It can't be helped.
Come inside.
Okay! Stand up on your own.
Do you plan on staying there forever?
Who is she?
A stray cat.
Again?
Introduce her to everyone first.
I know.
Thanks, owner.
Come on.
Just stay here for now and things will work out somehow.
Sorry, but can you leave a spot open?
Sit.
What's with that face?
Yeah.
I knew it was a nice face.
Okay. I can cover up this much.
I'm covering something up, too.
If this girl gets on the stage,
she'll gather customers for sure!
But she can't even get up on stage.
She'll get over that quickly.
Can you dance?
A little...
Starting tomorrow, your name is...
Black Cat.
The other day, that girl was given the name Black Cat.
- Huh?! What?
- Black Cat?
To think she was given the establishments name...
Unbelievable!
Enough already!
- He's always like that!
- What happened?
It's the owner.
The owner?
Since it's you, I'll tell you.
We're dating. The owner and I.
Don't tell the others.
Yet he always has his hands on other women.
Are you okay?
Did the owner do this?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
This always happens.
Always?
I don't want to say this, but...
It would be better to break up with him.
- A person who hits a woman can't be decent.
- Yeah, I know.
I know that, but...
He never hits my face.
Huh?
He likes this face of mine.
Isn't that strange?
I think he's amazing for making a place like this.
Yeah.
You know...
I thought I shouldn't, so I never asked...
But I want to know, afterall.
About you.
Not Black Cat. The real you.
- The real me?
- Ah!
Let's start with your name. What's your real name?
You don't have to tell me if you don't want to.
I won't ask for the impossible.
I want to tell you, too.
About the real me.
Okay! Then I'll ask to the end!
Okay.
It's raining?
Hey, you! It's a rainy night, you'll get dirty.
Let's go.
I'll leave first.
For crying out loud, you're too much.
You couldn't leave me alone either, Anna.
This and that are...
the same, huh?
He used to be banker and can do accounting.
Oh, really?
The owner said no at first, but after
talking to him he said it's okay.
That's why you're letting him stay in your room.
Don't tell me it's because he's your type.
No! I've been hurt before.
And that was a little tough.
Tough?
Yeah.
Um...
Why are you doing this?
Huh?
You helped me find a job...
And gave me a place to stay.
You told me before, right?
That no one would believe you.
I used to be like you.
I gave everything to the person I loved...
But when it became no good I ran away.
You and I are the same.
I'm no good.
And so I joined the establishment.
So you have to work hard.
Is that so?
Yeah.
That's why I'm sure you'll be able
to make a fresh start, too.
Thank you very much.
I want to quickly make a fresh start, too.
I'll do my best.
Yeah.
Then, goodnight.
Goodnight.
Excuse me. Here's your whiskey.
- Thank you.
- Excuse me.
Ah, would you like a drink?
Thanks for everything.
It's good that you found a place to live.
It's because of what you said.
Thank you very much.
See you again, okay?
Bye.
You... aren't a useless person.
You're a very kind...
and very wonderful person.
If it's with you, I'm sure I'll be able to start my life over.
Probably...
I'm sorry! For someone like me to say that...
Thank you.
Me too...
I might be able to start over if it's with you.
What's the matter?
We were tricked.
He took all of the money.
Huh?
That guy.
That guy?
The man you brought in.
There's no doubt it was him.
Is that true?
Seems so.
I'm so sorry!
I'll work hard to earn the money back!
- Yeah! If we work hard, we can do it!
- No.
I want you to stop, Black Cat.
Huh?
Just as I thought, you're too soft.
Someone who looks out for everyone
can't survive in this world.
Now. Let's go make money.
You need to find a real place for yourself.
Do you have a place to go?
You don't have a place to go home to, right?
I'll make do somehow.
The asked the owner.
He said you should be fine there.
Thanks.
If you're ever in a jam, come back any time!
Don't take it all on by yourself!
Okay.
I'm glad I met you.
Really glad.
Me too.
Every day was like a dream.
I've never had this much fun before.
It's fine.
You'll be fine.
There are a ton of fun things in store for you!
You'll be really happy!
Yeah.
Take care of yourself...
Eru.
- Thank you very much.
- I'll come again.
Welcome.
- Here you go.
- Thank you!
Ah, wait.
Here.
Wow! How cute!
- Pick the one you like.
- Okay!
Thank you!
Thanks for always doing this.
Ready to go?
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
We're done for the day.
Um...
Here. If you'd like...
How cute.
What a relief...
It's my first time seeing your happy face.
I always thought you hated me.
I don't hate you.
Then, would you stay here?
You don't have to answer right away.
It's just...
I'd like you to think about it.
Um...
I want you to stay with me forever.
I'm sorry.
Um...
I can't give you an answer right away...
Will you wait a bit?
Of course.
Will you...
make me happy?
I'm happy...
That I was able to meet someone like
you who's so beautiful and pure.
- Welcome.
- Hello.
How cute! Are these animals?
- A puppy.
- Yes.
What is this?
A pig.
That's a pig?
It moved.
I want to meet you already.
Mama will love you a lot.
I'll give you lots and lots of love.
We're closed...
I finally found you.
Ever since you disappeared...
my life has become a mess.
Let's go home, Eru.
What is it?
Let's go home.
- Come back and support me again.
- No...
No!
- What is it?!
- Stop!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Oh, your husband.
I didn't know.
The woman I've been looking for this whole time is here.
I'll take her back.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?!
- She has to support my talent!
- What are you talking about?!
Do you even know?
How this woman has been living until now.
Hm?
I've been looking for you ever since,
and I was shocked at what I found out.
Stop...
She met a man at a cabaret, stole money,
and lived a good life.
Stop!
And as for what's in her stomach.
Who knows whose child it is.
Is that true?
Of course not.
So you really didn't know anything.
No...
- Don't listen to what he's is saying!
- This person...
How did you come to live with him again?
We were in love.
Sir, could you leave the two of us alone for a moment?
Don't go, dear.
I'm going out for a bit.
Wait. Wait! Dear!
You have to support me forever.
You haven't changed at all.
Let me go!
In that case.
Die right here.
I'll follow you right after.
No!
I have talent!
If I have you...
If only you support me!
Right now!
If you support me...
What's wrong?
I'm sorry.
Why do I have to change?
You and I...
We were gonna live together and
love each other forever, right?
Forever.
It's okay...
It'll be fine.
I'll give you lots and lots of love.
A lot...
No!
Hey, Eru...
Have you found it yet?
The many colors you spoke of wanting to see.
I'm still the only one who can see it.
I'm gazing at so many colors.
If you're ever in a jam, come back anytime!
Don't take it all on by yourself!
Anna...
What happened?
What?
What is this?
He hit me.
On my face.
This person... hit my face.
It was the first time he hit my face. That's why...
That's why it turned out like this!
I mean that's a big deal, right?! Right?
Anna!
Are you...?
pregnant?
Did the owner know?
Yeah.
That's why... he gave me this.
Look!
He gave me this...
- And yet...
- That's why!
Huh?
That's why he hit your face.
Because of the child in your stomach.
That's why he hit your face!
Ah!
I see.
I feel refreshed.
Sorry.
I was wrong.
What are you doing?!
I have to go, too. I have to go to where he is!
You want to have this baby, right? Get it together!
Sorry.
I killed him.
Huh?
Do you understand?
I'm the one who killed the owner.
- Don't say strange things.
- I'll tell the police.
I'll say I had a a grudge or something. Anything!
- You can't possibly do something like that!
- I'm doing it!
But you'll get caught.
The child in your stomach...
You don't want it to be a criminals child, right?
Hey, do you remember?
When we talked about the land with no color.
The place you grew up?
Stay hidden there.
But...
- I can't do this, afterall. You'll-
- It's okay!
It's okay.
Live for that childs sake, Anna.
I'm sorry.
Just promise me one thing.
The child you give birth to...
Give it lots and lots of love.
Lots... and lots.
Once upon a time...
there was a very beautiful and kind girl.
One night...
A prince invited her to a ball.
First...
she went on her pumkin carriage.
But...
once the clock strikes midnight...
the magic will lose it's effect.
At that moment...
she lost her glass slipper.
Stop crying...
Cinderella.
Stop...
Hey, Eru...
What world...
What sky are you looking at right now?
Eru...
There's...
a future I want to show you.
Wake up.
Are you okay?
You're...
Eru-san, right?
How do you know that name?
I finally found you.
It fits perfectly.
Who... are you?
That ring...
Are you...
possibly...
Rino.
I'm...
Anna's daughter, Rino.
From back then...
I've been looking for you for a long time.
Now, let's go.
He... doesn't have much time.
He?
Ovesu.
He's waiting for you.
That's why...
Let's go home together.
To where Ovesu is.
What's wrong?
I'm afraid.
It'll be fine.
Ovesu is looking forward to seeing you.
But he's already...
He said that he wanted to paint.
Always, for you.
But, he couldn't paint.
Your uncle misunderstood, right?
Your relationship with Ovesu.
To think that you're spending time
with that boy who's bad for you.
Then paint it.
I won't lose it this time.
Sorry.
Then...
I took that away from Ovesu?
He's painting something himself.
Something no one can take away.
I can't do this, afterall.
What face do I make when I see him?
Painting was everything to Ovesu.
Yet I...
It's my fault.
He's been waiting for you this entire time.
He believe that you would come back some day.
Always, in that place.
Let's go.
From here... go in by yourself.
Go on.
Ovesu.
Eru.
I've completely become a grandma, right?
You're absolutely beautiful.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry...
Why... are you apologizing?
Because you could see it...
What I took away from you...
I'm painting even now.
I always have.
Right?
You're right.
You're right...
You're a painter.
The world best painter.
It's all thanks to you.
Huh?
It's thanks to you...
that painting...
gave me the strength to live.
Ovesu...
Thank you...
Eru.
That's not...
I didn't do anything...
I didn't do anything.
I haven't given you anything in return.
So tell me, Ovesu...
What should I do?
I think that...
you were surely happy.
Rather than the things you've been told to do...
the things you've done yourself...
is much more important.
That's why think...
of all the things you've done.
The things I've done?
See?
The days you lived...
weren't so bad, right?
I wonder if you'll...
smile.
Hey, Eru...
Right now I'm...
very happy.
The best day of my life...
is when I hold your hand in this room...
and fall asleep.
Ovesu...
Ovesu!
Hey...