Petite Reine: Downfall of a Champion
Really?
That's good.
Tell him. He'll be happy.
The papers here didn't cover it.
That's how it is with women's racing.
A full page?
That's really cool.
- Tell him, already.
- l'm not even there, Dad.
- lt'll make him happy.
We're leaving in...
- ln an hour.
- About an hour.
Go out for supper?
What does Mom think?
l wanted to relax
with just the two of you.
You decide, Dad.
Yeah. Here he is.
Hi, Alain.
Yeah.
She surpassed her time trial.
20 kilometres in 27.45!
Yeah, it's amazing.
lt's looking good?
Did you throw out all the food?
Go buy some champagne right now.
This is our year for the World Cup.
Definitely.
Alain, l have to go.
Yeah.
OK, perfect.
Bye.
But they were here yesterday.
l just injected myself.
JP, what do we do?
Get the lV bag, then do push-ups.
- No, no.
- Do it!
Keep going. Come on!
- Where were you?
- Slowing him down.
lt'll be OK.
Keep going! lt'll be fine!
C'mon, fuck.
Sit down.
Put it in, now.
- l can't do it, JP.
- C'mon, fuck.
- The stuff!
- Squeeze, damn it.
The stuff.
- Squeeze hard.
- l'm squeezing!
Let's go. Squeeze.
- The bike!
- Fuck!
Get on and pedal.
Gimme that. Come on!
Come on!
Right, good.
Come on, let's go!
Faster.
Break.
JP.
lf he comes in, you slip out.
No, it'll be all right.
This way. Hurry.
C'mon.
Hurry up.
Squeeze.
Keep squeezing.
Keep squeezing, fuck.
- l'm squeezing.
- Until he comes back.
When he does...
- Then what?
Then take it out.
And turn off the shower.
Squeeze!
Dad, can you put this in my room?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
He reserved at Baton Rouge.
- At Roberto's. lt's quieter.
- Thanks, Mom.
She's too tired to be hassled.
lt's in half an hour, OK?
- Perfect.
Good.
Suzanne,
the ones from Hamilton are nicer.
Yes, definitely.
We should put them in a special case.
- We'd see them better.
- Yes.
- You'll need another shelf.
- l guess so.
What's up with you two?
You know how she gets
when you're gone.
You should talk.
He spent his weekends scrapbooking.
Seriously, Dad?
Albums are meant
to be looked at sometimes.
Let's go.
Your mom's nerves get on my nerves.
Good.
Mom, in five minutes, OK?
When l dream,
l see a medal and the podium.
Realizing your dream is great,
but it's work.
- lt's not work.
- Yes, it is.
Ten races in less than four months.
lt sounds fun,
but l'm on my bike six hours a day.
l train in Arizona in winter
and race the rest of the year.
Friends, computer games...
l've never known any of that.
l'm alone or with my coach,
training hard.
- ls the money good?
- She isn't Lance Armstrong.
Not yet.
But you are a star.
No, that's not how it works.
- How does it work?
- When l win a race,
l don't do it alone.
l have a team.
For example,
a paceline is really important.
lt's a way to position ourselves.
We take turns,
being shielded from the wind.
Like geese.
l don't know about birds.
My team shields me
the whole time,
so l'm stronger for the final sprint.
And we have a great coach.
Fucking pedal, already!
He decides strategy, observes
who's better on hills or flat roads
and takes it from there.
lt's all planned in advance.
When you win,
is it you or the whole team?
- lt's me.
- Then you are the star.
Yes.
They could win,
but their priority is the leader.
That sucks for them.
Why do they do it?
They love cycling
and they get a salary.
But they're paid less than you.
Yes, that's true.
l'm also sponsored.
My contract states
l get a bonus when l win.
So winning is important.
l'm not supposed to say that.
They don't teach that at school.
"lt's not winning,
but taking part that counts."
Right, but if you don't win,
what will you take part in?
You were good.
The kids loved it.
Sorry for not following
the game plan.
lt was perfect.
From the heart and no bullshit.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Don't forget Saturday's telethon.
- Yes.
We have the outdoor fair on the 25th,
the Breakfast Club the 26th,
the radio interview the 29th,
and the Gala after the race.
l left the schedule with your dad.
Perfect.
Drop me off at the next light.
- Don't you want a ride home?
- l'm meeting a friend.
- l can take you.
- Right here is perfect.
OK.
OK. Bye.
- Bye.
- Take care.
Private Orthopedic Clinic
You really hurt yourself.
What were we supposed to do?
How much did you intake?
A half, two-thirds?
- Two-thirds.
- At least three-fourths.
- Three-fourths? lt's all right.
- Really?
l wasn't sure.
l had just injected myself.
lt's not that bad!
The solution lowered
your hematocrit by three points.
You were probably at 46
when you were tested.
Might raise a red flag,
but it's within limits.
There. What did l tell you?
She always argues with me.
- Drop it, Dr. JP.
You'll be fine,
JP did good.
l know, but still.
Your pressure is good.
Any dizziness?
- No.
- Arrythmia?
Good.
Any pain?
- No. lt's good.
- Are you eating well?
- Not bad.
Oh, boy.
Don't mess with that, Julie.
None of my sport clients have built
a career eating tofu and salad.
You have to eat.
l'll try harder. But l am taking
your supplements.
Attagirl! You're my idol.
Should l renew
the anti-inflammatories?
- l have some left.
- Same as usual?
Keep going. One more minute.
Not too hard.
Keep it at 300 watts.
Why are you going so fast?
Hi, love.
Hi. You okay?
- Yes. You?
- Leave it there to dry.
- l got it.
Hi, sweetie.
C'mon, keep going.
What are you doing at 320?
l said 300.
Lower it
or you won't be able to finish.
l said down.
Bring it to 300.
Not up. Down.
l'll knock you down.
l said 300.
What the hell?
Shit.
That's what happens
when you're overconfident.
l'm not overconfident.
You and your smug face.
- What smug face?
- That one.
Save the look you had in the garage
for the track.
OK. lt's fine.
Really?
ls that why you're half dead
on my kitchen floor?
- My back hurts. lt feels good.
- Take two.
You don't appreciate people
who want the best for you.
You don't listen during training.
Here, love.
What now?
The Federation left a message.
- Hello.
- Hi.
They're in François's office.
Why aren't you training?
- What are you doing here?
- He called.
- Hi.
ls something wrong?
They don't have your itinerary
for the upcoming months.
The Anti-Doping Agency
has asked me for it three times.
Why didn't you ask JP to send it?
He never returns my calls.
Yeah...
There's a lot going on.
- They're so busy.
This isn't up-to-date, Dad.
- What?
- You know the rules.
They can suspend you for that.
l know. l'm really sorry.
l just forgot.
You coming, Dad?
They sent your last test results.
Have you seen them?
You have irregularities.
- Really?
- But all's good.
ls it your anemia, again?
- You're anemic?
- She has been for years.
My blood sucks or it's their test.
That's that.
lf it's your blood, fix it.
lt's unhealthy.
Don't worry.
Dr. Henri says it's under control.
You should see a specialist.
- He is a specialist...
- An orthopedist.
lt'll be fine, François.
lt'd be a shame
if she were disqualified.
- Disqualified?
- Why would l be?
- ls something wrong?
- Of course not.
- l've always respected requirements.
- But...
Hang on there.
Has she or not?
She has.
But at the Federation,
we know sports-medicine specialists
who would take excellent care of her.
François, athletes are fine-tuned
but fragile machines.
You need the right person.
Dr. Henri has followed her since she's 14.
- Sure, but...
- l appreciate it, but it's fine.
Why are the Chinese such sourpusses
on Olympic podiums?
They feel guilty
for taking a break.
Pull up your zipper a bit.
Cheese, everyone!
- Perfect. That's everything.
- Good.
l'm getting a drink.
l'm dying to leave.
l'll be in the hall.
Check out Ducros.
Hi.
Didn't she have chicken thighs?
That chicken's fed with hormones now.
Told you it was her on the track.
- When?
- We trained two days ago.
- Why didn't you call me?
- We did.
l called JP. Didn't he tell you?
Julie. lnterview.
- With who?
- Thierry Côté.
Tall red-headed guy.
Really nice.
Mic.
Hi.
lt's unusual to see you here,
Ms. Lebigot.
The Canadian Anti-Doping Program
is sending a clear message
to all sport disciplines:
Our presence will be stronger.
Ms. Lebigot, can that
really stop doping once and for all?
l don't know...
Lobster in Nantua sauce.
ls that good?
OK for the appetizers
and the lobster.
l hate it when she does that.
lt's a good sign.
Means she's going to win.
035...
Put a three.
lt doesn't work.
lt'll cost a fortune!
- lt does work.
- Could you stop?!
- lt's starting.
- And a pastry platter...
Suzanne.
Hurry up.
lt played three times today.
Your feet.
- The two stars of this edition...
- Listen to this.
Belgian Renalda Ducros,
2nd in the standings,
right behind Quebec's darling,
the incredible Julie Arseneau...
"The incredible Julie Arseneau."
- Who's at the top...
- My daughter!
Julie, are you nervous about
the next stage in the Cup?
Honestly, no. We're ready.
We're so happy it's in Quebec.
It's an honour to race at home.
We're really looking forward to it.
That's that.
Thanks, Julie. Good luck.
Climbing should be easy.
They've paved those streets.
But on Decelles and Côte-des-Neiges,
there are potholes,
so watch out.
...with a close second
by Renalda Ducros from Belgium.
Faster, Julie!
...has managed to take the lead.
You three lead out on the last turn.
The French and Belgians
will definitely be there.
Keep a fast pace to block an attack.
- OK.
- Cool.
Julie and Valerie, hide nearby
for as long as possible.
Once on Parc Avenue,
Julie, sprint like hell.
No one's going to wait for you.
No problem.
Fuck!
My chain.
- What?
How the fuck did it fall off?!
Get it back on and hustle!
Jess. Cynthia--
- Too far.
We're stuck behind.
- Val, where are you?
Valerie Morin, from team Vita,
overtakes her teammate,
who's having some trouble.
She's speeding towards
the French and Belgian leaders.
- Go!
Hammer it, Julie. Go.
She's off the saddle.
Go for it. Keep it up.
Jump across. Go.
She's back in the race.
She's caught up with Ducros.
You're there. lt's yours.
This comes down
to Frenchwoman Eugénie Polard
and Quebec's darling, Julie Arseneau!
What a race!
It doesn't get better than this!
Arseneau rides to victory!
She gave everything she had
on those last 500 metres!
What an extraordinary feat.
Miss Arseneau, new protocol.
We need a blood sample.
No problem.
ls it the champagne?
There's one race left!
lt's just sparkling wine.
The champagne is for Belgium.
- You OK, sweetie?
- My head hurts.
- A toast.
- Suzanne, here's a glass.
Everyone, a toast.
To the whole team.
Girls, two medals in one race.
l'm speechless.
JP, impeccable!
We're lucky to have you, coach.
- Thanks.
- lmpeccable.
And of course, our champion.
This race belongs to her.
We're proud of you.
Cheers!
- Cheers!
- Eat some meatballs.
- Not too many.
This smells delicious.
Same restaurant as last time?
Yes. lt's the best.
You're the best.
- Do you want anything?
- Here, champion.
- No, thanks.
- l'll take that. Thanks.
Bring me a plate?
She has a migraine.
l'll go talk to her.
Suzanne, get me some meatballs.
Mind if l take a dip?
- Absolutely not.
- OK!
What's wrong?
They did a blood test after the race.
"New protocol."
Don't think about that, now.
l was the only one tested.
l'll have irregularities again.
l'll take care of it, OK?
Don't worry.
l'm really freaking out.
Tell me you'll take care of it.
l'll take care of it.
Promise?
Promise.
ln the pool.
lt's like training in high altitude.
lt's perfectly legal.
- Did you invent this?
- This model, yes.
l have more sophisticated ones,
but basically, they all lower
oxygen in the blood.
After sleeping in this tent,
a higher hematocrit level is normal.
lt naturally increases
the number of red blood cells.
Do people believe you?
Of course.
lt's the latest craze.
- You OK?
- What?
Yes, l'm fine.
- How much for this model?
- Two thousand.
They're not cheap.
- lt's a good investment.
- For who?
Well?
- lt's ridiculous.
l've been asked to give out awards
to the best Vita reps.
Honestly, it's an honour for me
to be here and meet you.
- l'm starving.
- l have toothpaste.
- Doesn't work.
- lt does too.
Only for five minutes.
For those of you coming on stage,
l'll keep close.
Because even if we won
in Montreal last Sunday...
lt's...
lt's not over.
She found something.
We'll need all your energy,
because in two weeks,
we'll be in Belgium
for the World Cup.
There's a vending machine
by the pool.
l always gain weight between races.
Claude, even if you don't have
the guts to ride with me -
or is it because you're
always playing with your phone...
Thank you for your faith in me
and for your friendship.
The World Cup is yours!
We'll work hard. That's for sure.
Yes!
Thank you.
The award for the best
Vita Sales Team goes to...
She's not going out with us tonight.
- What is it?
- lt's Dr. Henri.
- What about him?
- lt's coming out tomorrow.
Tell Claude none of it is true.
ls this a joke?
He ratted you out.
Talk to him when he gets off stage.
l'll be in the car.
Did he believe you?
l don't know.
l can't go home.
- You have to.
He won't drop it.
You know how he gets.
- Hi.
- JP, what's up?
Can l talk to you for a minute?
Either he was caught selling
doping products to athletes,
or someone sold him out.
He named just about anyone.
The list hasn't been made public yet,
but you know reporters.
- ls Julie on that list?
- We just don't know.
He could have lied to save his ass.
We don't know a thing.
There will certainly be an inquiry.
Definitely. Anyway,
this is one big misunderstanding.
Why would anyone accuse Julie?
He got caught,
so he said anything.
The police showed up and he panicked.
Why her? He can denounce away,
but Julie hasn't done anything wrong.
- She has nothing to be ashamed of.
- Exactly.
- Where is she?
- ls she OK?
She's still at the Vita Gala.
Claude is handling it.
- Go to her, Alain.
- No, don't.
She won't be long.
She might even be on her way.
The best thing is
to avoid upsetting her.
- You think?
- Yes.
Holy shit.
We're stopping.
We have no choice but to stop.
We'll get caught.
We won't.
No one here is getting caught.
What now?
l don't know.
l don't want to go home.
No, no.
l have to go.
Nathalie is all nerves. And...
l don't wanna...
What about me?
l'll drive you home.
l barely said a thing.
They already knew everything.
ln fact, they made assumptions.
l just answered their questions.
They treated me like a criminal.
They searched everywhere.
l didn't want to hurt you, Julie.
Fine.
Just write, then.
They threatened to revoke my licence,
l had no choice.
Write.
Go on, write.
l've never taken any.
l've never seen any.
No one has ever offered me any.
l don't even know what it looks like.
You've never used doping products?
- Never.
- Any steroids?
- No.
- Any blood transfusions?
Vitamins. Just vitamins.
Was Dr. Henri your doctor?
Yes. We have his letter confirming
that if she is on the list of athletes
he said he supplied doping products to,
it's a mistake.
You'll get a copy after
the press conference.
Was he referred to you
by another athlete?
No. My coach knew him.
l've been a patient
since l was fourteen.
For what?
- Anemia.
- Why then be followed
by an orthopedist
instead of a hematologist?
Dr. Henri was someone
Julie and her coach trusted.
lf her coach introduced them,
why isn't he here?
Because this is about me.
You're targeted by
the Anti-Doping Agency.
How long have suspicions
surrounded you?
There are no suspicions
surrounding me.
Top athletes are tested worldwide.
lt's part of a normal process.
lt doesn't mean anything.
There have been blood irregularities.
We won't go into details
about her health.
Those irregularities are simply due to
my altitude tent.
lt's legal.
- Altitude tent?
lt helps with recovery,
but it raises hematocrit levels.
You must admit,
for reporters covering you for years,
an altitude tent seems
to come out of nowhere.
lt was a secret.
Now, it has to come out,
though l'm not happy about
my competitors knowing.
According to you,
what happens next?
Nothing has changed.
My team and l
are going for the Cup.
And we will make Quebec proud.
Vita reiterates its support
for Julie Arseneau and her family.
lt's an honour to have her
as spokesperson,
and we're confident Team Vita
will succeed at the World Cup.
That's all for now.
Thank you.
- Very good.
- Sorry l never mentioned the tent.
- You hadn't?
- Not sure.
Technical stuff...
- Bravo.
- Good job.
Wasn't she amazing?
You were so impressive,
facing down those reporters.
Claude did help.
Reporters will be hounding you.
lgnore them and don't worry.
l'll handle everything.
lt'll be all right.
How did it go?
- Didn't you watch?
- l tried to, but...
- She was great. Firm.
- Good.
You really didn't watch?!
Why would l?
lt's a bunch of lies.
- Not what l said.
- You know how emotional he gets.
- Alain is such a big softy.
- Whatever.
The inquiry into Dr. Henri's fraud
falls under criminal jurisdiction
and not the Agency's.
Damn right.
But Ms. Arseneau's
evasive answers
concerning her high hematocrit level
and her altitude tent...
leave much to be desired.
- What do they all have against her?
But her tent isn't illegal.
Exactly, it's not. Wake up.
She has to justify her job.
The normal hematocrit level
for a woman is 37-48%.
But levels normally remain stable.
Could an altitude tent alone explain
the large gaps in irregularities
observed in Ms. Arseneau?
Probably not.
- Thank you.
Anything to be on TV.
- Are we eating?
- Yes.
What irregularities?
ln six years of racing,
l've had tons of blood tests.
They could have made mistakes.
- Due to your anemia.
- But what tent?
- We got one in Arizona.
- Didn't you see it in the garage?
Why haven't we heard about it before?
What the hell?
Are you a cop now?
- No one tells me anything.
- lt's tech stuff, Mom.
lt's like me.
l've tried to keep up, but...
And remember,
reporters aren't all experts.
A lot of bullshit's coming.
When the users' names come out,
they'll let us be.
Fucking Dr. Henri.
l'd love two minutes with him.
Two minutes? The bastard.
l never liked his face.
Never mind Dr. Henri.
Go get us that World Cup.
That'll shut them up.
ln two days, this will be old news.
Drop it. No one answers
their phone. l got this.
But it's the Federation.
- Don't answer, Dad.
- Hello?
He should be here soon.
Can we start without him?
The Federation isn't at ease
with renewing your licence.
l don't understand.
The irregularities...
Dr. Henri...
Dr. Henri... that was resolved
at the press conference.
Not for us. We're uneasy.
The Federation
doesn't have the authority.
As long as you refuse to see
a sports doctor, my hands are tied.
lt's the World Cup Final.
François, we've put you on the map.
You've gotten great exposure.
And you're doing this
over a sports doctor?
We can't grant a licence
unless doping
has been completely ruled out.
- Says who?
- l'm just following protocol.
You can't do this to me.
lt's ridiculous.
l'm sorry.
OK.
Supposing we do see a sports doctor,
would she get her licence in time?
Probably, but it's not guaranteed.
What does that mean?
We're going there to win the Cup,
and you can't guarantee
she'll have it for the race?!
Julie!
Julie.
What was that?
- l'm going home.
- We're going to see his doctor.
- No.
- What then?
- Nothing. l've done nothing wrong.
- So let's see his doctor.
- l won't.
Why did you answer the phone?
Claude told you not to.
What will Claude think
when he finds out?
We do what François says,
then it's done.
He has no right to ask.
He's not the one asking.
After all l've done for you,
l'm asking.
You have no right, either!
What am l supposed to do?
Give them my file?
- Why not?
- You know exactly why not.
No, l don't know.
Seriously, Dad?
You really suck. You piss me off.
Where are you going?
You have a race in ten days.
Where is she going?
Will someone tell me
what's going on?
Alain, do something.
We can't let her go like this.
- What was that about?
- What do you think?
Why are you giving me that look?
- l don't know.
l can't buy some
at the duty-free shop.
You're not trying.
You're not trying at all.
- lt's not my fault, it's windy.
- lt'll be windy in Belgium.
l know that, JP.
Your race on Mount Royal,
that was kid stuff.
Small time.
Over there, the last kilometre is
the Wall of Huy,
a 23%  slope.
23!
So shut up and pedal.
Fuck.
What's going on?
- lt's windy.
- No. What's going on?
l don't know.
Maybe l'm overwhelmed.
By what?
By what?! Everything.
l get it, it sucks. But you have to
get over it and move on.
Easy for you to say. You're never
there when the shit hits the fan.
You're crazy!
I'm not even at 30.
Stop it!
I set the cruise control at 35.
- That's enough!
- Pedal.
- Turn off your cruise control!
- Go.
lt's fucking dangerous!
Only because you're not moving.
lt's not my fault.
lt's windy.
OK. Fine.
Figure things out.
Let me know when you're ready.
JP!
We're in the middle of nowhere!
Fuck.
She'll have her licence.
Definitely.
What can l say?
Welcome to the States.
No jerking around.
You happy?
So quit fighting.
Why bother with that?
Forget it.
Once we've won,
they'll shut their traps.
And us, what do you think?
Here she is.
lt's your dad.
Alain, she's in the shower.
What's your problem?
You look beautiful.
l can't believe
Dr. Henri never mentioned this.
lt gives the exact hematocrit level.
What's the big deal?
l can avoid irregularities.
OK.
Let's say you check your level.
You're at 49.
Then the anti-doping guy
is at the door.
lt didn't help much.
But l can keep it under 48.
You'll still have irregularities.
With smaller gaps.
lf you say so.
- Look. 45.
- Show me.
Right, 45.
That there is one nice irregularity.
Go to hell.
lt's completely stupid.
- No, it isn't.
- Yes, it is.
You're camping tonight.
No way, l'm not sleeping in there.
That's stupid.
- You're camping.
- What a waste of money.
Go. You can do it.
Push! Push! Push!
You can do it.
Harder!
Faster or l'll catch you.
Don't even try. See you at the van.
Really?
Not if l get there first.
What's wrong?
l think l took too much.
l don't feel good.
lt's just nerves.
JP, my heart stopped beating.
lt's beating. Sleep.
Come to bed.
JP.
l need a hospital.
Breathe. Keep breathing.
My blood is too thick. l can feel it.
Get on the bike.
You have to pedal.
Get on.
- l can't.
- Get on.
- Pedal. lt has to go down.
lt has to go down.
There. Pedal.
Go. Pedal!
You have to burn the surplus.
Fifty-six. Holy shit, Julie.
What did you do?
The hospital!
Did you take 500 or 200?
Get on. Good. Go.
Don't fall.
lt's OK.
Look at me.
- JP.
- lt's OK.
l'm going to die...
Here.
Good.
- l'm going to die.
You're not going to die.
Keep going.
Go.
You feeling better?
Yes?
Dad.
lt's me.
Yes.
Where are you? Have you guys left?
Not yet.
l...
l need to talk to you.
JP told me about the licence.
He sure knows his stuff.
For sure.
Everything OK?
Yes.
l was just calling...
To see how things are going.
Good. That's nice.
We'll see you there?
Yes.
OK, Dad.
OK.
Liège, Belgium
Room 51 1 1 .
- May l have another key?
- Of course.
Ms. Arseneau?
Hello. l'm Gilbert Lennel from WADA.
We need a blood sample.
Please follow me.
No problem.
Hey.
- Hi.
You good?
When did you arrive?
- Yesterday.
We were wondering
where you guys were.
- We had things to take care of.
- l can imagine.
- How are the girls?
- Good.
Why?
You know it's all a smear campaign.
Yeah.
We watched the press conference.
Doesn't change a thing for you guys.
Sure. But it still sucks.
- Hi.
Are you sleeping at the hotel?
What about your tent?
- Jessica.
- Can't l make a joke?
The truck is ready. Let's go, girls.
- Shotgun.
- Eat shit.
You're heading towards the Wall.
Julie should be in the lead pack.
Valerie, protect Julie.
Anyone else who can, do the same.
Do what you can until the Chicane,
then it's time.
Then, Julie, it'll be in your hands.
lt'll be tough,
but you can do this.
Why did you hug the inner curb?
lt was obviously going
to screw us up.
- They shoved you over like...
- A fucking amateur.
- What?
- Put a lid on the bickering.
Valerie did the best climbing.
Julie, keep up. And go easy.
You're not even halfway up, yet.
Go back down and get it right.
l don't believe this.
Taking a bend is pretty basic.
l'm starving. What are you eating?
- l'm not hungry.
- Get over it.
Bad day. Tomorrow will be better.
No big deal.
We're having a drink later.
Feel free to come. Room 5064.
Cool. Thanks.
You thinking of going?
No.
Do you want people
to think you're a lesbian?
No. l wasn't planning on going.
Are you hiding something?
What does the butch want
with you, anyway?
You look beautiful.
You can't stay.
Sleep in your room.
Girls, l'm back. Who wants some?
lt's too hard for Canadians.
Just kidding!
Do you want a drink?
You need Belgian thighs!
To climb the Wall!
l'm so glad you came. Really cool.
Julie, come play. Take the paddle.
Give me your drink.
Everyone, the Champion is playing!
- Just hit it.
- You can do it.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Where were you?
Nowhere.
Partying with the Belgians?
l was playing Wii.
What did the butch want?
l'm talking to you.
Bitch.
Let go!
When did you stop?
The fucking vials are full.
- l'm scared!
- When did you stop?
- A couple of days ago.
- You fucking idiot!
l can win clean!
What the fuck, Julie? Clean?
They're built like goons
and they're gonna destroy you.
ls that clean?
Nobody gets to the podium clean.
Clean, you come in twelfth!
Take an extra dose
today and tomorrow.
You should be fine for the race.
lt's too soon.
You don't care about losing, then?
lf you stop the stuff,
you'll stop winning!
And what will everyone think?
"Minor doping scandal and, oops,
she stops winning."
Fucking brilliant.
No more sponsors, money, nothing.
We're screwed.
l'm scared l'll die.
What are you doing?
- None of this is yours.
Equipment. Clothes.
Even the bike belongs to Team Vita.
Leave my things alone.
You don't care? Fine.
l'll find someone who does.
Stop. lt isn't funny.
Enjoy your new day job, you crazy bitch.
You never finished high school.
Let's go.
C'mon, girls!
Keep going.
Keep tight together in the wind.
The pace is too slow.
OK, Valerie attack.
Valerie, l said: Attack!
- What about me?
- Valerie is attacking.
lt's the same plan,
but with Valerie attacking.
lt isn't complicated. Go!
Fuck.
Who is it?
- lt's Marie-Eve.
Are you OK?
Yes, l'm fine.
What JP did was wrong.
l... We're sorry.
lt's fine.
Julie?
Don't put up with it.
You're really good.
l don't know. Maybe...
There are other coaches.
Other teams.
Would it be better
if Valerie were lead?
No, l didn't...
Sure would be convenient...
What did she promise you?
- What are you talking about?
- Save your breath.
Hello?
Already?
l injected myself earlier.
Bravo.
A dose and a half.
Why are you telling me now?
lsn't that what you wanted?
OK.
You know what? l'm not going
to play your little game.
l'm here to make you win, OK?
That's why you pay me.
You pay me 50%
to make you win.
lt's no small feat.
What l do must be worth something.
But now, you're playing the victim.
Before Dr. Henri ratted you out,
you were happy
to inject yourself
and stand on podiums.
Don't pretend
you're trying to make me happy.
l don't want you to feel anything.
l don't want to stop, either.
l told you.
l'm scared.
You're done being scared.
lt's over.
- What's over?
- lt's over! l can't want it for you.
Look at you go.
The other girls
would kill to win this race.
But not you. No way.
Do you have makeup?
You look like shit.
You'll freak out your parents.
Are you sure you're fine?
- Yes, Mom.
- Nervous for the big day?
lt's all right.
l'm hungry, let's eat mussels.
lt's on me.
l can't. l have too much work.
And l have to train.
Take some time to eat.
lt'll do you good.
He's a French specialist who's followed
top athletes with irregularities.
He's proven it wasn't doping.
He's exactly the guy we need.
Some more white.
Your father hasn't stopped.
lt's really nice, but...
Money isn't an issue.
Vita will pay for
all medical procedures.
lf we have to go overseas,
we'll go.
But it's OK now, l have my licence.
We'd like you to see a doctor.
Settle this once and for all.
You're not in this alone.
People stare at us too.
Co-workers,
and especially neighbours.
Thank you.
Reporters won't stop.
lf you saw a specialist,
it would shut everybody up.
You have nothing to lose.
What is it?
Why don't you want to go?
Of course l'll go.
Give me his number.
l'll take care of it.
lt's already booked.
- Where are JP and Valerie?
- We don't know.
- lt's an easy question. Where?
- Chill out.
- Relax.
- Don't worry, l'm not after your JP.
- You think you're good.
- Stop acting up.
Acting up? She's never done a thing.
She's been touring for ten years,
winning off of others...
Now she thinks she can win.
You'll be crushed.
You don't have what it takes.
Being second is easy.
But will you do what it takes to win?
Like suck the coach's cock?
ls that it?
Let go.
Let me go, fuck!
You want to stop?
Why?
l'm fed up.
Julie.
You're about to win the World Cup,
and you want to stop?
What's wrong?
l'm burnt out.
l'm tired.
That's why we want you
to see a doctor.
Would you stop bringing that up?
You know why l don't want to see one.
No, we don't.
Dad.
Stop.
You were there,
with me at Dr. Henri's.
Why...
Why are you bringing this up?
lt was six years ago.
Why bring it up now?
What do you think Dr. Henri sold us?
You were sick, Julie.
So what?
lt doesn't change what we bought.
lt was once.
Six years ago.
Calm down, Alain.
You were sick. lt was a one-time thing.
Just stop it.
That's what we always said.
Did you keep taking it, Julie?
l'm sorry.
l'm just tired.
Then that means
everything is all right.
Everything is all right.
You're not on anything.
l'm not on anything.
Swear.
lt's all right, OK?
You're right.
l'll race tomorrow.
l can't...
... stop now.
Julie, swear you're on nothing.
l swear.
lt's what we always said.
Julie.
l've been looking for you.
That was quite a punch.
She had it coming, the hypocrite.
As if l'd ever replace you
with Valerie.
She'd have no qualms
stealing your place.
But l know who my star is.
l did it to get you back.
And it worked. Look at you.
The beast has risen.
Thanks.
Thank you
- Thanks.
Less than five minutes to start time.
There are only a few teams left
to check in before
they head to the start line.
Team USA is now being presented
to the crowd.
Cynthia, fueling up is at
Kilometre 40 and 80.
Jess, Marie-Eve,
protect Julie on flat terrain.
Less than a minute...
Just so it's clear with everyone...
Valerie, we're doing the initial plan.
Julie leads. You help her.
Good luck.
Start time in less than thirty seconds.
Three, two, one.
The Fleche Wallonne has begun!
After the race,
we'll stop messing around, OK?
l'm going to do what it takes.
l'll talk to Nathalie.
- What?
- l'll get a divorce.
We'll really be together.
Are you happy?
We're at Kilometre 25.
The peloton is in the plains.
Where is she? lt's making me nervous.
l don't like it.
Sometimes, l'm afraid l'll lose you.
l'm so afraid you'll quit.
That you'll quit on me.
Julie, where are you?
Julie?
What's wrong?
Can anyone hear me?
- Yes.
Julie?
Jess? Cynthia? ls Julie with you?
No. She's behind.
l'm near her.
Your earpiece is off.
- l lost it.
- She lost her earpiece.
- Give her yours.
- She's gone.
- Gone where?
Toward Valerie. I can't catch up.
- Valerie? Are you with Julie?
- Yes.
Give her your earpiece.
No.
If I tell you to give it,
then you fucking give it. Simple.
l'm done coddling your princess,
so too bad.
They're zipping through Andenne.
The leaders of the peloton
are quickening the pace.
We won't let them get ahead. Let's go.
The French cyclist Catherine Moranger
is trying to escape.
She's breaking away
and is now in the lead.
What the hell is going on?!
l see everyone but our girl.
Calm down, Alain. lt's not even midway, yet.
No, it's...
l got it.
lt's only coffee.
Are you part of the break?
- We're in front with Valerie.
- What for?
lt's too early.
- We're following Valerie.
Would you follow her off a bridge?
I'll come when the gong hits.
- Your damn coffee.
- Not my fault.
Then l suppose it's mine.
We mustn't ruin your nice shirt.
No. We mustn't ruin my nice shirt.
Not today.
At Kilometre 40, the gap is widening.
Suzanne.
Permission to move ahead
to join my team
as soon as possible, please.
Team Vita, permission granted.
Cynthia, go back to Julie.
See if she needs fuel.
Do yourjob!
Gotta do my job...
Do you need fuel?
Cynthia, I'm right behind you.
Come talk to me.
Julie ignored me.
Marie-Eve needs water.
What are you doing?
Valerie is pushing us for nothing.
She's unplugged herself,
so she can't hear.
lt's a mess. lt's all fucked up.
- Help Julie.
- She's working alone.
She doesn't want help.
l'm done with her.
Where's Valerie?
We're nearing Kilometre 60.
There are two pelotons divided
by a 55-second gap.
Moranger is still in the lead.
- l'm alone. Let's team up.
- For how long?
Until the Wall.
Then you're on our own.
OK.
Hello?
With who?
Fine.
After that, the deal's over.
OK.
Bravo! Bravo!
You're doing such a great job,
Julie's with the Belgian butch.
You're all fucking incompetent.
Next year, find yourselves
another team.
You're all useless!
Fucking hell!
We're at Kilometre 80
and nothing has changed.
It's down to a 30-second gap.
In the lead, Moranger from France,
Team Vita's Valerie Morin,
Sandrine Bruquelle from Belgium,
and Miriam Bosquet from France.
She's unwell and burned out.
It's stress.
She wanted to quit.
It's normal before a race.
You wouldn't let a child quit school.
You say no.
But we did let her quit school.
An attack at Kilometre 90.
Two racers have left the tail bunch.
They're trying to catch up
to the leaders.
If you leave,
I'll die.
l'll kill myself.
You don't know how much I love you.
Say you love me.
l love you.
Come on.
Come on, goddamit.
Canadian Julie Arseneau from Team Vita
and number 51 , Belgian Renalda Ducros,
are closing in on the leaders
past Kilometre 1 00.
Go!
l know you can do it. Do it!
Numbers 31 and 51
have caught up to the leaders.
We've reached it.
The Wall of Huy, a gruelling ordeal.
This is where true climbers prove
what they're made of.
Welcome to the merciless Chicane,
where it's a hit or miss.
World Cup leader Julie Arseneau
is moving away
from longtime rival Renalda Ducros.
Final sprint,
1 00 meters from the finish line.
Julie Arseneau is ahead.
She's over the finish line!
It's a victory for Canadian Julie Arseneau,
the new World Cup Champion,
with Renalda Ducros in second
and Catherine Moranger in third.
What an incredible race.
Ms. Arseneau?
Please follow me for your test.
l'm coming.
Champagne! Champagne!
Marie-Eve! Valerie! Come here.
This champagne is amazing.
Here. We sure do deserve it.
- l hope there's more than one case.
- Me, too.
- More. More.
- l'm so emotional.
- Tonight we're allowed.
- Yes.
- Did you fall during the race?
- No.
- Poor you. What happened?
- lt was while playing Wii.
lt feels weird. l knew you'd win.
But it just hasn't sunk in, yet.
lt hasn't sunk in for me, either.
The World Cup.
The World Cup!
- My little girl.
- The waiting is over.
We told you there'd be
a bonus if you won.
Here it is.
Open it.
Go on.
Damn...
Not bad, huh?
l don't believe it.
- Cheers!
- You said it.
- To Julie.
- Cheers!
- With this cheque, l can finally retire.
- Come on!
l'm just kidding.
Are you happy, Julie?
- Of course l am, Mom.
- l can barely keep it in.
lf it were up to me...
The sky's the limit!
The Olympics... Name it!
Can we savour this victory first?
l haven't said a word.
News travels fast.
lt's André from La Presse.
So?
Wasn't it beautiful?
Wasn't she amazing?
- You betcha!
Who told you that?
You didn't get tested after the race?
l forgot.
You've been disqualified.
What did you do?
l forgot.
lt isn't something you forget.
l'm sorry.
Yes.
Exactly. Disqualified.
Three months later
San Diego, California
Based on a true story
Subtitles: CNST, Montreal