No land more beautiful in this time
Than ours here, whether far or near...
Don't worry.
Adenauer will handle it. He's the captain.
Am I right?
I have two troublemakers in 6b.
I've never seen anything like it.
Completely wild.
And the parents won't do anything.
That's the way it is nowadays.
Hi there, pal.
Need a light?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
LABYRINTH OF LIES
Public Prosecutor's Office
Your Honor,
according to paragraph 2,
section 2 of our Constitution,
human life is the highest
inalienable right.
The prosecution is convinced
that the accused
acted maliciously and on base motives,
the preconditions for
paragraph 211, murder.
I cannot see a justification for
the defense's plea of acting under duress.
Therefore, the prosecution
requests the maximum sentence,
life imprisonment.
- Morning, Radmann.
- Morning.
How have the first weeks been?
Very exciting.
I'm only dealing with traffic violations.
We all had to do it.
Give it one or two years
and you'll get to clothe proper stuff.
Great.
...as it stands,
women are still only allowed to work
with their husband's permission.
And now, Vino Torriani.
Always do the right thing
Your father
Mr. Prosecutor, how nice of you to drop by.
- I apologize.
- We've started without you.
The defendant, Marlene Wondrak,
admits the offense,
but cannot afford the fine
of 50 Deutschmarks.
It was my boss' car. She mustn't find out,
and I only have 30 marks.
- Mr. Radmann.
- Yes?
With the prosecution's consent, we will
reduce the fine to 25 Deutschmarks.
And you promise you'll use your pretty
little head to concentrate on traffic,
if you absolutely have to drive a car.
All agreed?
No.
Come again?
The law determines the amount of the fine.
There are no grounds for an exception.
But I told you I don't have it.
The law doesn't allow for this.
You stickler, you monster!
You want to send me to jail for three days?
No, but...
So, Mr. Prosecutor, what
are we going to do?
There, I've paid.
Can I go now or must I still go to jail?
Don't think I'm grateful to you.
You'll get it back.
When I have it.
What an impossible person!
Damn it, she's got some spunk.
It's a scandal, an outrageous scandal!
There's a murderer on the loose out there.
Mr. Kirsch here recognized the man.
We've tried three police stations,
but none of them were interested.
Good day, Mr. Gnielka.
Desperate to find a story
for the Rundschau again?
I already have the story, Chief Prosecutor.
There's a murderer out there,
A former member
of the Waffen-SS at Auschwitz.
He now teaches children. Interested?
You really are a magnificent hothead.
I want to leave now, Gnielka.
This is just pointless.
Alois Schulz, Unterscharführer
in the Waffen-SS,
now teaches at the Goethe School.
Interested?
You?
Out!
Come on, Simon, let's go.
Before I have to puke.
Throw this away.
Show is over, gentlemen. Back to work.
- Where is the school board, Schmittchen?
- At the Römer.
I'm sensing something.
And I don't like it.
- Eintracht will win the league.
- If Egon stays fit.
I checked out the records on this Schulz.
The years from '39 to '45 are missing.
On who?
That teacher the journalist talked about.
Well, someones ambitious here.
After '45 the US confiscated
truckloads of documents.
The denazification by the Allies is a fact.
Gnielka has no loyalty to the fatherland.
Don't be fooled.
Excuse me, the document center?
- Second floor.
- Thank you.
Sorry, but the document center
isn't open to the public.
I'm researching this person's past.
He teaches children.
I need to know what he did in the war.
He was a Nazi.
You were all Nazis,
just like in the Eastern Sector,
suddenly you're all Communists.
Jeez, you Germans!
If little green men landed from Mars,
suddenly you'd all be little green men.
Kid, you're too young.
But your father was a Nazi.
What? No. He hated the Nazis.
Yeah, sure. Everyone became
a resistance fighter after '45.
And you are here by which authority?
Public Prosecutor's Office, Frankfurt.
Good morning.
Therefore I shall request
a three-year sentence.
Good work, Haller.
If you have nothing else, Attorney General,
I'll close this meeting.
Chief Prosecutor.
Yes, Mr. Radmann?
- This teacher, Mr. Schulz...
- Which Schulz?
Mr. Gnielka's matter.
I beg your pardon?
I did some research.
Schulz was indeed in the Waffen-SS.
He didn't disclose this
when he was employed in 1947.
He's not allowed to work as a teacher.
I wrote a report.
Let's have a look.
Yes, interesting.
You know what? I'll forward this
to the Ministry of Education.
Gentlemen, same time next Wednesday.
Your mother left this for you.
- What? When?
- Just now.
She wanted to wait, but your father
outside was honking impatiently.
That's how men are!
That's not my father.
He's been missing since '45. Eastern front.
I'm sorry.
- He didn't really say that!
- Scout's honor.
Mr. Gnielka.
- Do you remember? You...
- I know who you are.
I took care of that Schulz matter.
The ministry has suspended him.
Suspended?
What do you accuse him of?
Who do you think he killed?
He was stationed at Auschwitz.
Don't you know what that means?
Wasn't it a protective custody camp?
Believe me, no one was protected there.
I can't believe this.
Watch this.
Ever heard of Auschwitz, darling?
- No.
- That is what's scandalous.
- Ever heard of Auschwitz?
- No, and I'm busy.
- How old are you?
- 20.
- And you've never heard of Auschwitz?
- No.
Mankind's biggest atrocity
is simply denied and forgotten.
What are you talking about?
A German prosecutor not knowing
what happened at Auschwitz is a disgrace.
And if this Schulz has been suspended,
I'll eat my hat.
We don't have any guidebooks on Poland.
No one ever goes there.
And as to this...
- Auschwitz.
- That's it, Auschwitz.
There are two books on it.
One is out of print,
the other should be in Kassel.
- Shall I order it?
- Please.
It will take eight to ten weeks.
Yes, can I help you?
Chief Prosecutor, may I have a word?
Magnificent, I would like one of those.
What's up?
Schulz is still teaching.
I went to the Goethe School.
There was a shortage of teachers.
It's a matter for the ministry.
It's beyond my authority,
and definitely beyond yours.
But Schulz was stationed at Auschwitz.
They all had those camps.
The Americans, the Russians.
I myself spent a year in a French one.
Don't tell my wife,
but their cooking was better than hers.
I was forced
to watch a film about it after the war.
It's all propaganda.
The victors get to make up stories.
That's what happens when you lose a war.
But why start digging now?
Hi there. You were right.
- What do you mean?
- That teacher is still teaching.
Well, what can you do?
That reporter was waiting for you
in your office.
What a funny guy.
"Young and ambitious prosecutor Radmann"
"researched the past
of senior teacher Schulz."
"The Ministry of Education
was already informed on March 25th"
"and has been ignoring his Waffen-SS
membership for six weeks."
And so on... "Outrageous scandal."
Oh, boy.
I wouldn't want to be
in your shoes right now.
The Attorney General wants to see you.
Mr. Radmann, the article
contains internal information.
Did you pass this on?
No.
- But why didn't the ministry take action?
- Don't be so naive.
Do you think all Nazis vanished
into thin air after Hitler's death?
I can assure you they did not.
They did not.
But he can't be allowed to teach children.
What we should do is put the man on trial.
But having been stationed at this camp is
no criminal offense according to our law.
Shameful as it is.
And any crimes would have been
time-barred three years ago.
Except for murder.
But do we have one? An actual murder?
Is there an actual victim?
Open your eyes, Mr. Radmann.
The public sector is full of Nazis,
big ones as well as little ones.
And none of them has anything to fear.
Latest evening edition!
Evening edition!
Khrushchev renews ultimatum!
Report on the anniversary of Hiroshima!
Have you lost your mind?
The article was a hit.
- I'll sue you for stealing the file.
- I'm quaking in my boots.
You nearly had me fired.
You should be ashamed!
I'd be ashamed if I didn't make
this kind of story public.
I just don't get it.
How can all this be kept secret?
How? Easy!
They all did the same thing Schulz did.
They came home, hung up their uniforms
and carried on as if nothing had happened.
No one asks questions
because no one wants to know.
Are you free tonight? I'm sorry.
Reporters sometimes bend the rules.
Not to worry.
Come by.
There'll be pretty girls, sausages, beer.
Not necessarily in that order.
Typical male. They need water.
I'm Inge. The beer is back there.
Thanks.
She has class, hasn't she?
Come, I'll introduce you.
I can do that myself.
Ladies and gents' friends and combatants,
I've discovered a rare specimen.
An attorney whose armored chest still
contains a delicate flicker of humanity.
- So you're a poet after all.
- Thanks, Simon.
Please make him feel welcome
in our anarchic circle,
so that the flicker
may eventually become a raging flame.
That was theft, wasn't it?
Are you going to arrest me?
Petty larceny.
I'll put you behind bars for six weeks.
You wretched man.
Are you always like this?
Why don't you find out?
Maybe I will.
You're suffocating.
- Someone needs to take Simon home.
- I'll drive.
You're drunk.
I can drive.
Nice people, aren't they?
I saw it straightaway.
What do you mean?
She's a cutie, a dame,
a doll face, a sugar babe.
And Marlene likes you, Radmann.
And he was actually imprisoned there?
Yes, but he doesn't talk about it.
The Angel of Death.
The first painting he did after Auschwitz.
Would you believe it, he's entitled
to compensation, but he doesn't want it.
Because of that damned claim form.
Those idiots want proof
that he was at Auschwitz.
Is there anything I can do?
Yes, give me a hand.
There must be something here.
Nothing.
Get this suitcase down.
But I can't just...
No, let me do that.
Jackpot.
What are you doing?
We're helping you.
How dare you?
Simon.
I don't want your help.
You have no right to go through my things.
- Simon...
- Out. Out!
Out!
He's stubborn.
But maybe these contain something.
- So you learned something after all.
- I'll return them, of course.
Nothing in here.
Nothing in here either.
This one has an Auschwitz
concentration camp letterhead.
Have a look at this.
"Shot while trying to escape."
So?
"Shot while trying to escape" means murder.
And here it lists the
names of the murderers.
Order reigns supreme.
Unbelievable, isn't it?
Come with me.
Sorry to disturb you,
but I think it's important.
These are official lists
of the Auschwitz camp administration.
The names of SS men who shot prisoners.
Look, "Schmidt, Milde, Siebert..."
That's what you wanted.
This is proof, isn't it?
Come in.
Where did you get this?
From an Auschwitz survivor.
Good.
It's a start.
- How?
- What?
These are concrete criminal offenses,
perpetrators, victims, times.
The prosecutor can act on this.
So we'll investigate them?
Why investigate?
That's nitpicking. Here are the names.
These murderers must be arrested.
Don't be silly, Mr. Gnielka.
That alone won't be enough.
Attorney General, if at all possible,
I would like to be involved.
I would like to help.
You won't help, Mr. Radmann.
You will lead the investigations.
And no more articles for the time being.
Unless you want to warn the perpetrators.
Agreed.
Gentlemen,
if we succeed in ultimately
charging these men in Germany,
that would be quite extraordinary.
Schmittchen!
- What is it?
- No more traffic violations.
The start of a new life.
- I don't know what you want.
- We took some documents from you.
There was a list.
I need to know where you got it from.
Was it in my suitcase?
I've no idea.
The liberation was chaotic,
we grabbed what we could.
Why do you want to know?
I'm investigating the crimes at Auschwitz.
You were there. Did you witness
criminal offenses during your stay?
My "stay"?
What did this Schulz do?
He was a regular SS swine.
But did you see him killing anyone?
No.
I need witnesses, Mr. Kirsch.
You need to give a statement.
What for?
Just look around.
Petticoats in pink and baby blue.
This country wants sugar-coating.
It doesn't want to know the truth.
Please let me get on with my work.
These are the names
of the suspects we are after, Officer.
You must find out their whereabouts.
So, to summarize, they were at this camp
in Poland during the war,
and the police
should find them for killing people?
But they were soldiers?
Wasn't that their duty?
I'll be in touch.
Good morning.
Who's going to prosecute
the parking offenders now, Radmann?
First: Addresses? Still alive?
"You incur a speeding fine. Pay 100 marks."
- Inge, lend your husband 100 marks.
- Serves you right.
But I'm broke. Radmann.
Then you lose.
The prosecutor shows no mercy.
- Some people must be punished.
- Sure, and all of them by you.
Only the ones I catch.
Who hears my plea and lends me some cash?
I'll build a house on Goethe Street
and open my own fashion studio.
Then I can stop sewing curtains
for Mrs. Brettschneider. Great!
Oh, no!
That's justice for you.
Everything's fine, children.
Show yourselves, you dirty cowards!
You won't shut me up!
- I write what I want about who I want!
- Thomas, are you crazy?
Gnielka, please!
I told you the article was a hit.
Do you understand now?
They're still everywhere.
I need the addresses of the survivors.
They are important witnesses.
You pay them compensation,
so you should have their addresses.
No, we'll pick them up ourselves, then.
Yes. Goodbye.
Schmittchen, take a dictation, please.
Hermann Langbein leads
the association of Auschwitz survivors.
Please send him a telegram.
Dear Mr. Langbein...
- Mr. Langbein.
- Mr. Radmann.
Thanks for coming.
Where's the witness?
Mr. Bichinsky, what's keeping you?
Schmittchen, our first witness.
Mr. Bichinsky, you were detained
at Auschwitz for two years.
Yes, I was there from August 1943
until the Russians liberated us
in January 1945.
Just carry on, please.
Do you recognize the names on this list?
No.
- Not a single one? Are you sure?
- Yes.
Can you testify to the fact
that crimes were committed in the camp?
Yes, I can.
Hundreds of thousands were killed there.
Well, we would need
the names of the victims.
Didn't you hear?
Hundreds of thousands, it was a factory.
How is he supposed to know the names?
All right.
Then we'll write "victims unknown."
My wife and my son were murdered there.
I'm sorry.
Can you tell me the date
when this happened?
The SS didn't give us a calendar...
What do you think Auschwitz was like?
A little summer camp by a lake?
Mr. Bauer, what kind of greenhorn is this?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Would you like some coffee?
Schmittchen, coffee, please.
We'll be back shortly.
We can't investigate only that list.
What do you suggest?
I'll ask Bichinsky what he has seen.
Actual crimes he can testify to.
This means that all SS men
who served at Auschwitz are suspects.
- All of them.
- I'm aware of that.
I want to know what happened there.
Mr. Radmann...
This is a labyrinth.
Don't lose yourself in it.
Mr. Bichinsky, please tell me
everything you experienced.
Where should he start?
At the beginning.
What did he do?
Hans Brandner hit my witness
with his whip until he passed out.
My witness lost his right eye.
And you know why Brandner did it?
Because my witness dared
to glance at him during roll call.
- And now we'll arrest him.
- What? No.
- Why not?
- We have no charge.
- But...
- There was no murder.
Everything else is time-barred.
So what are we doing here?
I must look at him.
I must see what he's like.
- Thanks.
- You'll be as pretty as your mom.
You're a charmer, Mr. Brandner.
I see.
Wait.
- Mr. Brandner?
- Yes?
I think we know each other.
I can't remember.
I'm certain.
I never forget a face.
I don't know.
You're not from around here, are you?
Try one of these. You
won't find any better.
I've got to start my delivery.
Come on.
Get my robe, Schmittchen, hurry!
Please stay seated.
How do you expect this to work?
You want to fly in people from Poland,
Israel and God knows where.
We don't even have diplomatic ties
with these countries.
And what for?
To prove that someone did something
somewhere in Poland during the war.
These people are witnesses
to thousands of murder cases.
Murder? Be realistic. Where is the intent?
We didn't have any choice.
Whoever refused was killed.
Besides, all this was dealt with
at Nuremberg after the war.
Only 150 men were convicted at Nuremberg.
By the Allies, not by the German
justice system. So this isn't settled yet.
I'm sorry, Chief Prosecutor, I thought
your court session was in the afternoon.
It would be the first time
that a country charges its own soldiers
for their actions during a war.
It's a non-starter.
You know what?
I love this country.
I still do.
In spite of everything.
It had to endure so much.
All you will achieve
is re-opening old wounds
that were just starting to heal.
Did you know that Bauer is a Jew?
He himself was in a camp in 1933.
He probably never got over that.
- Take it easy, Toni!
- Lenchen!
Toni, I told you to take it easy!
No harm done.
Daddy, this is Johann Radmann.
He took me home after the movies.
Very pleased to meet you.
- Come on, I'll fix you dinner.
- Thanks, Lenchen.
- Debts are a matter of honor.
- No, this...
So, come again. What do you need?
I'm investigating the Auschwitz camp.
You're out of your mind.
Nobody wants that. Not you, not us either.
Just let things be.
Man, Hitler is gone.
The Russians, they are the new enemy.
I'll need the files of the SS men
who served at Auschwitz.
All of them.
10 million Nazis. Incredible, isn't it?
And those idiots wrote everything down.
If you believe you'll get
one of them in front of a court,
you might as well believe in Santa Claus.
I'm only interested in the Auschwitz ones.
Did you bring a truck?
There you go, 600,000 SS files.
About 8,000 of them served at Auschwitz.
But you'll have to dig those out yourself.
Thank you.
It was a machine.
What was?
Auschwitz.
It was a murder machine
made up of 8,000 parts,
small ones, big ones,
bureaucratic ones, sadistic ones...
Eight weeks ago, we had a list of 15,
now I've got 8,000 SS men serving there.
That makes 8,000 suspects, Gnielka.
My previous case
was driving without a license.
Look at it this way,
more enemies, more honor.
What are we drinking to?
Veritas.
That was my fathers motto.
To the truth.
8,000 Schulzes and Brandners.
And I need witnesses for every one of them.
- Let us in.
- What do you want?
You must testify.
- To what?
- You are a witness, Mr. Kirsch.
I need your statement.
- I won't talk about it.
- Simon, please.
You must testify. You
owe it to the victims.
What do I owe them?
What do you want from me?
Haven't you had enough?
What do you want?
You want to investigate Auschwitz?
You think that will change anything?
You have no idea.
No idea.
Why?
My girls.
Ruth and Klara.
So young.
We arrived in the middle of the night,
hundreds of us, thousands.
We were cold and hungry. It was freezing.
We were surrounded
by the SS with their dogs.
Everyone out, quick, quick, lining up.
My wife Hannah
was put on a truck straightaway.
Suddenly, there was this doctor.
He was wearing white gloves.
He looked like an angel.
He was very calm.
And then he knelt down
to look at Ruth and Klara.
He stroked Ruth's hair and smiled,
and then he said to me,
"Your twins are cute."
"I'll bring them to my ward."
And I thought, "He's a doctor."
"They'll be safe with him."
Then the others told me
what Mengele did to twins.
That he tortures them with his experiments.
That he injects them with viruses,
typhoid, TB, diphtheria.
He cut them open without anesthetic.
He removed organs from their bodies.
He stuck needles into their heads.
He sewed twins together, little children,
back to back, like Siamese twins.
And I gave them to him.
Why are they dead and I'm alive?
We'll put this doctor on trial.
I promise.
There was a camp physician...
Dr. Josef Mengele.
So you know the stories?
He's the one we must get, Dr.
Josef Mengele,
he's the one, he is Auschwitz.
All those who participated,
who didn't say no,
they are Auschwitz.
How are you getting on?
Calmly and matter-of-factly,
just say what you clearly remember.
Mrs. Mandelbaum.
Please.
All right, we will appeal.
- You can do that, Haller.
- With pleasure.
Chief Prosecutor, I request
support for my investigations.
Have Mr. Haller join him.
Attorney General, please.
I can't do without Mr. Haller,
we're already stretched thin.
This matter is of the highest priority.
Please,
even Chancellor Adenauer made it clear
that we must draw a line
under this unfortunate chapter.
A trial would be poison.
On the contrary.
Hushing this up is poison.
Poison for our young democracy.
And besides, I'm the one who decides
when to draw the line.
This is my good suit.
Right, you brief me,
then I'll develop a strategy,
and you can then report to me.
Don't worry, I won't bite.
I'm in charge of the investigation,
on the General's orders.
Well, well, look who's all grown up.
Who are the suspects?
- Everyone.
- What do you mean?
- Everyone who served there.
- That's ridiculous.
A small boy,
about five years old, jumped off the truck.
He was holding an apple.
Boger was standing at the door.
The boy stood next to the truck
and was so happy about the apple.
Boger went up to the boy,
grabbed him by the feet
and smashed his head against the wall.
Boger then picked up the apple
and told me to clean up the wall.
And then Boger ate the apple.
Everyday life at Auschwitz.
You find that ridiculous?
How many of the addresses did you get?
The authorities are stalling.
- Get every phone book.
- Pardon me?
I've had it!
Get every phone book in Germany.
We'll look up the addresses ourselves.
Mengele was the worst of all.
And you know why?
He's like you and me.
He had opportunities, became a doctor,
took the Hippocratic oath,
loves opera, he's cultured.
He's like us.
He was your age when he came to Auschwitz.
I look at his photograph...
Have you seen his photograph? He looks...
He looks like a nice guy.
If we let someone like him run free,
we are doomed, do you understand?
Come on, Gnielka,
I want to dance with my hubby.
- Come on, Johann.
- Just a second.
Our hero is tired.
You will nail this guy.
Don't worry about it.
Ladies, here I am.
Marching in spirit
Within our ranks
Our comrades shot by the Red From
What's going on there?
It's my dad's war comrades.
They meet once a month to get drunk.
It's awful.
Pioneer Battalion 221,
"Every shot downs a Russian."
I can't handle this today.
Let's go down to the river.
No, take me to your place.
My landlady has ears like a bat.
Come on, I'll take you home.
My darling.
Life is beautiful.
Can you tell me which country and city
has the area code 005411?
Thanks, I'll wait.
I know where Mengele is.
What? Where?
The long-distance calls
of the Mengele family in Günzburg.
Thank you.
Buenos Aires, Argentina.
I'll go to the BKA.
We have enough evidence against
this baker, Brandner. Issue a warrant.
Yes, I will.
Mengele is in Buenos Aires.
This is his telephone number,
that should be sufficient.
Here's the warrant for his arrest.
Please have him brought to Germany.
Interesting theory.
Unfortunately,
the Federal Police has limited means.
And South America of all places.
It's so far away.
But I'll be happy to pass it on.
I'll take you to the station.
- Don't worry.
- I insist. I'll drive you.
Now we can talk.
We knew that Mengele is in Buenos Aires.
We have a thick file on him, but...
But what?
Those who fled after '45 are off-limits.
An order from up high.
Is there any way you can help me?
We know he travels to Günzburg
to see his family.
He comes back to Germany?
Regularly. He knows there
is hardly any risk.
Thank you.
I don't have time to take you to the
station. I just wanted to talk.
I see. Of course.
Thanks anyway.
You've been to see the Federal Police.
- How do you know?
- Have a seat.
You're still not grasping
the extent of this.
Mengele, Eichmann and the rest
are protected by powerful friends.
You can trust no one.
No one at all.
- But I know Mengele's whereabouts.
- I know, but you must let it rest.
You obtained a warrant for his arrest,
just leave it at that.
Attorney General...
Concentrate on the other suspects
and leave Mengele to me. Understood?
You did say all of them.
And we're to comb through
all of them for our suspects?
Yes.
I'm not carrying them.
Your ideas always mean work for me.
Mengele's father died.
- Are your men at Günzburg?
- I told you what our position is.
That's all I can do.
Do you think he's inside?
If Mengele ever comes to Germany, it's now.
That stays there.
PRIVATE FUNCTION TODAY
Can't you read? This is a private function.
Johann Radmann,
Public Prosecutor's Office, Frankfurt.
We are looking for Josef Mengele.
You scared me.
Thank you.
Will you do something for me, too?
Do you know where Mengele is?
Everyone in Günzburg
works at the Mengeles' factory.
They won't say anything.
But my dad saw him at the cemetery today.
He recognized him.
But then he drove off.
I've got to go back in.
You hear a lot around here.
I urge you to call me if he turns up again.
- He did this to children.
- I don't want to see it.
Take a good look.
This is what Josef Mengele did to children.
I am certain he was at Günzburg today.
The Border Guard must check all passengers
to South America, flights and ships.
No, not "Naegele", "Mengele."
Mike, Echo, November,
Golf, Echo, Lima, Echo.
Look again, he must be on the list.
There's a warrant out for him.
There's no time for a written request,
he'll be gone by then!
I can't believe it!
- Where have you been?
- Why?
The baker, Brandner. He's disappeared.
- What?
- He's disappeared, gone.
Because you didn't issue
the warrant you promised.
- You had to go play Zorro.
- You know that...
I don't care!
We're public prosecutors.
Start acting like one.
And stop drinking in my office.
The Attorney General
wants to see you immediately.
Goodbye.
You've acted against my orders.
Quiet. How could you let
this Brandner get away?
You were busy
making a fool of yourself in Günzburg.
What were you thinking?
He was at his father's funeral.
Why does he dare
come back to Germany? Why?
Because he knows we'll let him go.
You've been working on this case
for four months, Mr. Radmann.
What have you got to show for it? Nothing.
We're running out of time.
For now, the Justice Minister
still supports me.
But the state elections could change that.
Then I'll be gone.
There won't be a trial anymore.
Without Mengele, the trial is pointless.
Do you want to try a mere phantom?
Your obsession with Mengele
jeopardizes the entire investigation.
What about all the others?
This Mulka, or Camp Commander Baer?
These men are responsible
for hundreds of thousands of deaths.
Aren't they dramatic enough for you?
Here.
"If you carry on like this,
you'll be gassed, too."
"A traitor is the worst scum
in all the country."
"Death or life, Jew?"
and so on and so forth.
That's why we're doing this.
The Germans must see
the crimes that were committed,
not just by Hitler and Himmler,
but by completely ordinary people
who did it voluntarily, out of conviction.
They are the ones we're trying.
One big trial.
This is the way to do it.
And this is your task.
Mr. Mulka. Radmann, prosecutor.
You couldn't answer our summons,
good to see you're well again.
What do you want?
You were Adjutant Camp Commander
at Auschwitz.
- So?
- I'm investigating you.
Listen, I was a soldier.
I never set foot in that camp.
I don't know what happened there.
Who are you trying to fool?
You were the commanders right-hand man.
I'll bring you to justice.
If you approach me again,
I'll cause you so much trouble
you won't know what hit you.
- Let's call it a night.
- I'm carrying on.
You know what, Radmann?
You definitely are crazy.
But you definitely aren't
a little green man.
Here, more photos of the ramp.
Left, right,
left, right,
left...
Don't you know where left is, Anton?
Right, left...
Which of you rascals has misbehaved?
Alois Schulz, I'm arresting you for aiding
and abetting murder in hundreds of cases.
I only did office work.
Here...
That's you.
Yes.
Several witnesses testified
you made selections at the ramp.
- You selected victims for the gas chambers.
- Yes, but...
Mr. Schulz, please.
It's like this.
You'll have to prove
that Mr. Schulz selected anyone.
The picture is out of focus.
It seems this camp was a horrible place.
I'm sure whoever arrived there,
after a grueling journey,
was in a state of shock.
I doubt very much that the testimonies
of those pitiable people are still valid
after almost 20 years.
And assuming Mr. Schulz
did indeed select anyone,
then the purpose was to prevent those
who were fit for work from being gassed.
So he was in fact saving people's lives.
You shut your mouth now!
I disagree with your legal interpretation.
Mr. Schulz has stated
that he only followed orders,
which was his duty.
Mr. Lichter, your client is a murder
suspect and stays in custody.
You should be gassed, you bastard.
Gentlemen.
None of us were thinking.
All we had to do was open our eyes.
Shit.
I've got one.
- Hello.
- Oh, dear.
Wow.
- I forgot.
- And?
- And what?
- This, you boor. I made it myself.
- Yes, very nice.
- Respect.
- Marlene, we're just...
- Come, we can't let the posh people wait.
Off you go.
Come on!
The Americans had just let me go.
I was 35 and had never worked as a lawyer.
And then my first client walked in,
looking for a lawyer
to register a patent for him.
Free of charge, naturally.
We've grown dramatically since then.
- Why did they invite us?
- I don't know.
But I have a suspicion.
Boy, do they have potential.
- I'm starving, Walter.
- Me, too.
Shall we?
I don't like to see
a good lawyer's talent wasted.
Let me introduce you to Dr. Mertens.
Excuse me. May I ask you something?
Tell me, where in Frankfurt
can one find a dress like this?
Oh, this...
At her shop, of course.
You have your own fashion studio?
I'm just starting out.
Your fiancée? My compliments.
But you're impressive, too.
Honors degree,
assistant to Professor Rimmelsbacher.
- That's correct, isn't it?
- Yes.
You're exactly the kind of person I need,
young, enthusiastic.
All that's required
is to channel that energy properly.
- Thanks...
- I know.
You don't have to decide now,
just bear it in mind.
You know where to find me now.
Four ladies ordered dresses from me.
It's been a lovely evening, Johann.
This is Prosecutor Radmann.
Mr. Radmann, this is Mr. Kleiner,
German correspondent
of the Jerusalem Post.
These two gentlemen are from Israel.
Pleased to meet you.
I asked Mr. Radmann to come because
he knows most about Josef Mengele,
including his current location.
We're cooperating to apprehend
Adolf Eichmann and Josef Mengele
in Argentina and bring them here.
Please share your information
with these gentlemen.
And you'll bring us Mengele?
If anyone does it, it'll be us.
Kleiner isn't just a journalist, is he?
No.
Can they be trusted?
Who can you trust?
I still live in exile,
only not in Sweden anymore.
The moment I leave my office,
I'm in enemy territory.
I trust you.
Watch out.
It's not dry yet.
It's beautiful, Simon. Thank you.
Johann!
Now then...
This is the big moment.
- As good as new.
- I've always wanted one like this.
To Marlene.
Cheers.
"Dear housewife, your dream has come true."
"The new Pfaff Automatic 230,"
"the sewing machine with endless
possibilities, is yours."
Great, isn't it?
We're nearly there.
We'll put Mengele on trial in Frankfurt.
"Make all your friends jealous"
"and bring a smile to your husband's face."
This is unbelievable,
falling asleep like this.
Mr. Prosecutor can't get excited about
a sewing machine, even such a grand one.
I was just closing my
eyes briefly because...
Because I was blinded
by the beauty of your sewing machine.
Careful, your nose is getting longer.
A good businessman
keeps track of all transactions.
Of course.
You are wonderful.
Thank you, Joseph.
Mr. Mulka.
This is a warrant for your arrest.
What's all this?
An accessory facilitates the offense.
Here's an order for Zyklon B,
signed by Robert Mulka,
Hauptsturmführer and adjutant.
That was long ago, I don't remember it.
You don't have to. This is enough.
I'm arresting you for aiding
and abetting murder in thousands of cases.
Come with us, please.
Have a drink with us, Chief Prosecutor.
You're getting younger every day,
how do you do it?
Cheers!
- Thai looks delicious.
- It's home-baked.
Of course, the bakers
are all fleeing from Mr. Radmann.
Where's your sheriff's badge?
- What?
- Considering your cowboy methods,
you should wear
a cowboy hat and a sheriff's badge.
This is outrageous.
I beg your pardon?
Why do you ridicule our work?
Because this show trial
is harmful, disgusting,
and has nothing to do with the law.
Of course, you would think that.
Come on, say it.
You think I was a Nazi, too.
You're convinced of it, aren't you?
For Mr. Radmann, everyone was a Nazi.
Why don't you ask what I did in the war?
I'll tell you if you're interested.
Law studies at Heidelberg, then the Navy,
lieutenant commander, 7th submarine fleet.
After the war,
one year as a French prisoner of war.
Released in August 1946, served with honor.
And by the way,
I was never a member of the Party.
Do you still want to arrest me?
These men must pay for their crimes.
It's a question of justice.
Of course, justice is
your exclusive domain.
Parading around some small fish,
while millions of others
are allowed to carry on.
How is this justice?
Your "small fish" are criminals.
Are you aware of the consequences?
Do you want every young German to ask
if their father was a murderer?
Yes, that's exactly what I want.
I want these lies and this silence to end.
You are Richard Baer,
the last camp commander at Auschwitz.
You're under arrest.
You pushed the prisoner's head down
until he drowned.
You forced the group to spend the night
outside the barracks in winter.
Two of them froze to death.
Dr. Berger, come with us.
You were involved
in the transport of prisoners.
You kept kicking him with your boots
until he lay dead on the ground.
You shot the child being
held by its mother.
Both died.
Mr. Rinke.
You're under arrest.
You fed the Zyklon B into the apparatus.
You used the clogs to chase the prisoner
into the electric fence.
That wasn't an order,
it was your own initiative.
Start telling the truth.
The arrests of Richard Baer,
the last Auschwitz camp commander,
and of Robert Mulka are the culmination
of our efforts at redressing these crimes.
Chief Prosecutor, I have a question.
- What will the charges be?
- Murder.
Kirsch had a heart attack,
he's in the hospital.
It was very close.
I never said the Kaddish.
What do you mean?
In the camp, God was...
He wasn't there.
When I lay on the floor, waiting for
the ambulance, all I could think of was
that I never said the Kaddish
for Ruth and Klara, my girls.
I won't make it anymore, I can't go there.
Please, you do it for me.
Go to Auschwitz and do this for me.
Say the Kaddish for them.
You'll do that yourself
when you're well again.
Today I cheated death for the second time.
You do it for me.
No, I must conduct this trial first.
Please.
No, Simon, I don't have time for this.
I must conduct this trial.
Johann!
- Look, they've abducted Eichmann to Israel.
- What? Incredible.
That is incredible!
Attorney General.
This is great news.
I would have preferred to have him here.
But Bonn refused to file
an extradition request with Israel.
So when will they bring us Mengele,
have they arrested him yet?
He must come straight to Frankfurt.
Mengele has left Argentina.
What? Where is he?
There are rumors he's in Paraguay.
Then the Mossad must get him there.
Please, Mr. Radmann, this isn't
a mail-order catalog to just choose from.
It's a lot more complicated.
You didn't want Eichmann,
so we're doing it.
Good. But you must bring
Mengele to Germany,
then we'll try him here.
Imagine two deer standing in a clearing.
When you shoot one, the other one's gone.
What do you mean?
Mengele is gone.
He's not an issue for us at the moment.
But you promised...
Eichmann was always a priority for us.
For Bauer, too.
What?
Eichmann organized the "Final Solution."
Mengele...
Bring Mengele to Germany, I implore you.
The UN already gave us a hard time
because of Eichmann.
We're a small country, a young country.
We can't afford to make any more enemies.
We're already surrounded by enemies.
Mengele is cunning. He could be anywhere.
I have to get him in Europe.
He must travel under a different name.
Otherwise I would have found him
after Günzburg.
I need that name, Mr. Fischer.
I was so close.
It's not my car's fault.
Hello.
Kathi, isn't it? Please, have a seat.
I don't have much time,
I have a train to catch.
Mengele has been to visit.
I heard his mother tell my boss.
He's flying back from Frankfurt today.
I wanted to call the police, but my boss...
Thank you.
I need to talk to Mr. Fischer.
Where is he? It's urgent.
Mr. Fischer has been suspended.
Your generation has no sense of loyalty.
I need the name Mengele is traveling under.
Please tell me.
I warned you. It was leaking oil.
- Can you fix it?
- The engine's seized.
We don't even know what name he uses.
Why go to the airport?
I'll know Mengele when
I see him, believe me.
Damn it.
And?
Mr. Radmann,
who do you think you are?
Mr. Wisnievska was very upset.
I convinced him to testify about his
ordeal at Auschwitz and you stand us up.
Mr. Langbein, I'm doing what I can.
What are you doing in Frankfurt, Mother?
If you don't call me...
What's going on here,
are you moving offices?
Son, I need to talk to you.
I'm busy.
Don't be stubborn, Johann, it's important.
Please leave.
Gustav asked me to marry
him and I said yes.
You're already married.
No one comes back after 15 years.
I've requested that he be declared dead.
I want you at my wedding.
But I don't. Gustav was a Nazi.
How dare you?
You don't even know him.
Gustav was in the Party. They all were.
My father wasn't.
Of course he was!
What?
Dad was a member of the Party.
He had no choice, just like Gustav.
That's enough. You're lying. Get out.
You sully Dad's honor to
excuse this Gustav! Get out!
- Be reasonable.
- Get out!
Dad?
Don't do it.
I must know.
Kurt Radmann,
born in Marburg in 1898.
Can you find out
if he was a member of the Party?
Wait in the lobby.
Marlene.
Johann, how nice. One second.
You're drunk.
How else can you cope?
I have one drunkard at home,
I don't need another one.
No, Miss Wondrak
runs with a better crowd now.
You forgot something there.
- Where's the swastika?
- What?
The dress is for the wife
of some Nazi criminal.
What? Are you crazy?
Martens, Lichter,
all these fine people are criminals.
How do I know that?
Because this is a nation of criminals
and they all act as if nothing happened.
All these colors.
We Germans should wear black forever.
Forever and ever.
And you're making this.
Careful!
Are you crazy?
I need to deliver this tomorrow!
You've become unbearable.
You only see the bad. You're blind.
- Not everyone is bad!
- I'm blind? It's you who's blind.
Pioneer Battalion 221.
Your father was stationed in Poland,
I checked him out.
Do you know what they did?
Why don't you ask him why he drinks?
I don't believe it.
How dare you do this? Get out! Out!
I never want to see you again! Out!
Sheriff Radmann
and his loyal companion, Chief Sharp Quill.
They are outnumbered in their fight,
but in the end, the good prevails.
In the end, the bad guys hang.
Sheriff Radmann and Chief Sharp...
- How did you know what it meant?
- What?
What "shot while trying to escape" means.
Tell me, how did you know?
I was there.
I'm sorry?
At Auschwitz. I was there.
You were at Auschwitz? During the war?
- You're a liar.
- Stop it.
- You are.
- You don't know what...
I know way too much.
I know you're a liar and a hypocrite.
That's the worst of all.
Have you forgotten who I am, Johann?
Listen to me.
You want to know what I did?
I was 17.
They recruited all the boys in my class
and then sent us to Auschwitz.
Sure, you just followed orders,
the big excuse.
And in the end it was all
just Hitler's fault.
You wanted to know, didn't you?
Now listen to me, damn it!
We had to watch the inmates.
There was a Polish professor,
Tadeusz Rosenthal.
I secretly slipped him bread and
cigarettes, but then they found it on him.
To punish him, they stood him
next to the fence and threw his cap over.
Then they ordered him to fetch it.
And then they shot him in the back.
"Shot while trying to escape."
Do you understand, Johann?
Just like on those lists.
You disgust me.
You all disgust me.
He's drunk.
What did you do? Were you a Nazi?
- Were you one of them?
- Idiot!
You.
Why didn't you do anything?
Why did you join in?
Outrageous!
You bum!
You were all in on it.
You were a Nazi.
You were one...
Why me?
- What do you mean?
- This trial. The investigations.
Why me?
Because you were born in 1930.
- You're exonerated.
- No.
Because I was naive enough
to burn myself out for you.
By the way, my father was a Nazi, too.
What did you expect?
Almost all the lawyers
were members of the Party.
He was as guilty as the rest of them.
If you think this is about
who's guilty, partly guilty or innocent,
then you've learned
nothing, nothing at all.
I'm resigning.
Radmann.
You can't let us down.
I'm very pleased.
I think you made the right decision.
You'll start on Monday.
I already know.
Congratulations.
I wanted to thank you
for all your help, Schmittchen.
Save your breath.
Your... Our client is in the wrong.
He violated patent law. All we can...
Son, we can't pay for all this
if our clients are in the wrong.
Come in.
- Peter.
- Hans. Very good.
Mr. Lichter, Mr. Radmann.
I like to consult Mr. Lichter
if it gets a little dirty.
I'm simply brilliant
and I do anything for our clients. May I?
Gentlemen, work out a trial strategy.
Money is no object.
I'm pleased we're working together now.
Come on.
Man is not born to be a hero.
Right?
Mr. Radmann?
I was just as blind as everybody else.
What are you going to do now?
I don't know.
But there's one thing I don't get, Simon.
How can you still live here?
How can you still live in Germany?
Look.
I came from Vienna when I was 18.
I met my Hannah
in the hat section
of Schneider's department store.
My children were born
at the university hospital.
I bought them their first ice cream
in the old town.
We fed the ducks at the Grueneburgpark.
One of them pecked Klara on the hand.
Now tell me.
Where else do I belong?
I want to go to Auschwitz
to say the Kaddish.
I would very much like to do that.
Will you give me the book?
Gnielka must come with you.
No, I'll go on my own.
Bubeleh...
All right.
Why did you never talk about it?
Because I'm ashamed.
Because I just stood there
and watched, just watched.
Kept my mouth shut and watched.
What about the trial?
How can you give all that up?
I always wanted to fight
for the good cause.
But I don't know what that is anymore.
How can I try another person?
I had been there...
I don't know what I would have done.
You're missing the point, Johann.
Look around. What do you see?
Auschwitz.
No. You see a meadow.
Trees, barracks, a fence.
Auschwitz is the stories
that happened here and are buried here.
Without the trial,
these stories will be forgotten.
There is no appropriate punishment
for what happened here.
It's not about punishment.
It's about the victims,
about their stories.
What do we do now?
Simon wrote it down.
Why have you come back?
Because the only response to Auschwitz
is to do the right thing yourself.
Good morning.
You're back?
I'm sorry.
Forget it.
Nobody's perfect.
Apart from myself.
Thank you. Goodbye.
I will get it on Monday then.
Hello. Can I help you?
I have a repair job.
I'll deal with this customer.
How can I help?
Can this be patched up?
It's completely torn.
I know.
But it means the world to me.
No, the tear is too big.
It can't be saved.
I will spare no expense, whatever it takes.
Get yourself a new one.
And then take better care of it.
I guess I'll have to live with that.
Yes, you'll have to.
This is the life.
Good friends, cake and champagne.
What more could you want?
I didn't bring
my mom's cake back just for you.
Let the boy eat, he's still growing.
The trial date is set.
To the Prosecutor's Office, Frankfurt!
And to you, Johann.
L'chaim.
To life!
That's all.
Johann.
I've brought your jacket.
I thought the tear couldn't be fixed.
It's not completely fixed.
The trial starts tomorrow.
I know. Good luck.
You'll give testimony on Friday.
Are you ready?
Greenhorn,
I've been ready for 20 years.
I'll go in now.
Gentlemen, today history is made.
I'm proud of you.
I declare the Jury Court
in Frankfurt now in session.
The Auschwitz trial started in 1963.
211 survivors of the concentration
and extermination camp gave testimony.
19 SS men who had sewed at Auschwitz
were charged
in the largest trial in the history
of the Federal Republic of Germany.
17 of them were found guilty.
Throughout the 20-month trial,
none of the defendants showed any remorse.
Fritz Bauer died of heart failure in 1968.
Josef Mengele lived undisturbed
in Brazil until his death in 1979.
He died in a swimming accident.
The trial is seen as a turning point in the
history of the Federal Republic of Germany.
The crimes of the Nazi regime
could no longer be suppressed.
In memory of attorney general Fritz Bauer
and public prosecutors Joachim Kügler,
Georg Friedrich Vogel, Gerhard Wiese
and journalist Thomas Gnielka.