Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
JUNE 1944
A TOWN IN SOUTHWEST FRANCE...
A French national broadcast
from Vichy.
Ladies and gentlemen, a talk
by Monsieur Philippe Henriot
on "History's Revenge."
It's amazing,
listening to Gaullist broadcasts...
how serenely consistent these partisans
of Moscow are in their treachery.
There is no difference
between broadcasts
from London, Algeria, or Brazzaville.
The tone, style and vocabulary
have long been familiar,
each emission bearing
the same distinctive stamp.
The shallow veneer of nationalism
and religion is always evident,
despite their best attempts
to conceal it.
You would hope propaganda
would at least refrain
from constantly insulting
one's common sense.
But never mind.
No one expects logic from them.
Let them go on repeating endlessly
that Laval is a traitor
and Darlan a Gestapo agent,
and that I serve
German propaganda...
What are you doing here?
Are you Lucien, Thérèse's son?
That's not yours!
Those dishes are my father's!
Maybe so.
Go see the boss.
He'll explain.
Is that you, Lucien?
You get up late.
It's Sunday.
Why did you take your father's gun?
You know guns aren't allowed.
Here.
I got a raise of 20 francs.
Good.
- Morning, Lucien.
- Hello, Monsieur Laborit.
Your son could let us know
when he's coming.
You staying long?
I have five days off.
What are those other people
doing in our house?
They're helping Monsieur Laborit.
I let them have the house.
Things have changed around here.
The work has to be done.
Your father's a prisoner
and Joseph's gone.
- Really?
- Joined the underground, the bum!
My son's a patriot - so there!
Lucien, lift his head.
It's coming.
Come on, let's have a drink.
He was a good horse.
I'll never find another like him.
'A nd the thunder...
rolled...
in muffled avalanches..."
Well, well.
Come in, Lucien.
'...in the distance."
Maurice, really!
You're hopeless.
You spelled ' stormy"
starting with S-T-A-U.
But I guess you don't need to know
how to spell to herd sheep.
Dismissed!
What do you want?
This is for you.
Thanks.
You came to give me that?
I want to join the underground.
What's that got to do with me?
You're the one who decides.
Joseph told me so.
You're too young.
And we have enough like you.
The underground isn't like poaching.
It's like the army.
I don't want to go back
to the nursing home.
You're lucky to have a job.
You can't stay here, Lucien.
Laborit won't let you.
When your father returns -
When he returns,
there'll be hell to pay.
Shit!
Are you crazy?
Where'd you come from?
Spying, you little punk?
Get moving. You've got some
explaining to do.
- Any news from Paris?
- The phone isn't working.
Kid, come here!
Curiosity is a nasty habit.
Who is he?
I caught him spying in the garden.
I was not.
I was going back to the nursing home.
Don't you know
there's a 10:00 curfew?
What's the matter?
Aren't you Henri Aubert,
the bicycle champ?
- You've seen me race, kid?
- Yes, in '39, at Caussade.
I was with my father.
You won.
I remember.
You from town?
- No, from Souleillac.
Wait. I know people in Souleillac.
The grocery woman - what's her name?
Madame Cabessut.
That's it.
Dark hair, right?
How about a drink?
Marie, two Suzes.
- So, you're from Souleillac.
- You been there?
Beautiful country.
Very wild.
I bet there's underground there.
You don't see much of them.
And how is Madame Cabessut?
Have another.
And what's this teacher's name?
Peyssac, Robert.
They say he's a Freemason.
What's a Freemason?
You're sure he's in command?
Yes, under another name.
- What name?
- Hold on.
Voltaire.
They call him Lieutenant Voltaire.
Wake up!
Time to get up.
Mademoiselle Chauvelot is on her way.
Oh, my head!
Poor boy.
You drank too much last night.
Want an aspirin?
Good morning, young man.
Forgive me.
There wasn't a room for him.
Very well.
- How are you today?
- Fine, thanks.
I'm almost finished.
- What a beautiful day.
- You mean what heat.
These are for Herr Müller.
They're so polite...
and punctual.
If we'd been like them,
we'd have won the war.
Darn! I broke a nail.
What did you say, Mama?
I broke a nail.
You've been drinking, Pierre.
It's so early.
Just a little Suze.
Does one good, what with this heat.
You'd think you were in Saigon.
How are you, my boy?
- All right, Monsieur Tonin.
Doesn't he look like Paul?
A little.
Paul was thinner.
Read me the mail, Mama.
'Dear Gentlemen of the Gestapo:
As a farmer, with WWI medals,
I must inform you of the shady doings
of a certain Etienne Louvel -"
Hurry up!
Move it.
Here's Lieutenant Voltaire for you.
We found him in bed,
sleeping like an angel.
These leaflets
were on his night table.
'German troops
are retreating on all fronts.
You will soon be free
in a Free France."
They could at least ask people.
I don't want to be freed
by the Rothschild Bank.
That's my right, isn't it?
Shut up, you bastard!
Welcome, Monsieur Peyssac.
Take him upstairs.
I'll be right there.
- Shall I start on him?
- No, wait for me.
It's funny,
but I've never liked teachers.
If you don't need me,
I'll go take a shower.
I don't know why they're all socialists.
Are you a socialist?
What will happen to him?
Don't worry.
We'll just have a chat.
We should find this young man
something to do.
He can open the mail.
Here.
Just do like this.
Go on, Mama.
'I must call to your attention
that the milliner,
Solange Leboeuf, of Lubsac,
is often visited by her two sons,
both outlaws and communists."
That's enough.
'Monsieur, as a practicing Catholic
who finds the black market unworthy
of Frenchmen and Christians,
I'd like to inform you -"
Nothing serious this morning?
Yes.
A complaint from the prefecture
concerning the disappearance
of Dr. Pradines.
Forget it, Mama.
They're not about to find
Dr. Pradines.
I'll go take care of Voltaire.
Are you Monsieur Tonin's mother?
Of course not!
Are there many more like this?
We get about two hundred a day.
One man even writes
to inform on himself.
It's like a disease.
- You'd like to work for the police?
- I don't know.
You're young.
I think Inspector Lanciaga likes you.
Monsieur Tonin is an inspector?
He was...
an exceptional policeman.
He isn't anymore?
They dismissed him in '36
as an undesirable!
Run along, kids.
Tell me, Jean-B.
What, my dear?
Is there a gypsy restaurant
in Toulouse?
No, my dear.
There's nothing in Toulouse.
When are we going
to San Sebastián?
The end of the month.
- What's it like?
- You'll see.
There's a great hotel,
and everything you like.
Ever shot with one of these?
Come here.
Grasp it firmly.
Raise your arm, loose and relaxed,
and hold your breath.
Aim at his left nostril.
His left nostril, not his necktie!
Try again.
- He's better than you.
- That's not saying much.
Where are we going?
To see Albert Horn.
Know who he is?
A top tailor from Paris.
You coming?
- He lives here?
- He's lying low.
He works exclusively for me.
What a surprise
finding him in this hole.
I was going to school nearby
in Sorèze. You know it?
They kicked me out.
Oh, it's you.
Am I disturbing you?
Never.
I brought you a customer.
It's his first suit.
An important step in a man's life.
Take off your jacket.
Does the young man
want the plaid or the blue flannel,
like the one I made for you?
The plaid.
Do you agree, Lucien?
I don't give a damn.
Remember when Papa
first brought me to your place?
I was twelve.
You were on the rue Marbeuf
back then.
Your mother's a strange one.
Nice materials.
I got them for nothing.
A few gas coupons.
I never told you
where they came from.
From Cassels.
Their liquidated stock.
Whatever happened to Cassels?
There's a camp at St. Denis
for the English.
The Jews are in Drancy.
I know.
Thank you.
It will be ready in five days.
Listen.
There's news about Spain.
But it will cost you.
You think it hasn't already?
They're coming down harder
on people like you.
What I gave you isn't enough?
That was for the forged papers.
The gentleman
is a rich and stingy Jew.
Stop that playing.
The music is bothering us.
You must miss Paris.
The number of nightclubs
has doubled since '39.
War has its good sides too.
The German general staff announces
that yesterday its troops took
hundreds of American prisoners,
confirming the poor morale
and lack of fighting spirit
among American troops.
General Montgomery now admits
that Anglo-American forces,
held in check
by the Germans,
were unable,
during the last 24 hours,
to effect any noticeable progress
along the Normandy front.
In Cherbourg, the battle
still rages.
The Americans suffered
heavy losses in street fighting.
That's not a real Pink Lady!
Please, sweetheart.
She tried.
The best Pink Ladys I ever drank
were at Rudy Hiden's bar.
The best English bar in Paris.
How about putting on some music?
There's a war going on,
Miss Beaulieu.
Do you know I'm in the movies?
Really?
Last year I had a good part
in Night Raid,
with Yvon Nevers.
People could see you
in the movies?
In Paris you could.
In this hole
they only show old films.
Like I thought:
The Americans aren't soldiers.
Seems they put their Negroes
in the front lines.
You're biased.
Who says the news is accurate?
- Are you joking?
- Not at all.
You have to listen to Radio London
and split the difference.
Aren't you warm with that on?
'To Lucien, on a June evening,
with my best wishes
for happiness, poetry and success."
You understand English, Stéphane?
No. Why should I?
I'm not a turncoat.
Know what I think of the English?
They make me sick.
They're better-Iooking
than the French.
I love Leslie Howard.
Even stupidity has its limits,
don't you think?
What was that?
Repeat what you said!
You want me to smack you?
You two fighting again?
Henri, a cognac.
- Still wheeling and dealing?
- I have no choice.
You're a boor and a fool, Monsieur Faure.
You don't know who you're speaking to.
You've got a job waiting upstairs.
Let's go.
- I'm coming too.
- There's no point, darling.
If it amuses her -
Yes, it amuses me.
I don't give a damn
which side wins the war.
I only know I'm wasting my time here...
surrounded by these nobodies.
If they were at least good-Iooking.
Do you ever think about my career?
This is Henri.
What's he saying?
Two loads of shoes
on the Spanish border.
Shoes? And the entry permit?
He'll get it from Max
in exchange for the tungsten.
Okay, tell him it's a deal.
A cup of tea?
You're not going to sleep
in the office again tonight.
I'm going upstairs now.
Wait a little.
It's the fifth door on the right
at the end of the hall.
- Will you be much longer, Henri?
- I'm coming.
Did you talk to Wiroth?
- Yes.
He's giving me a kickback
on the chamois skins.
- The Krauts want them?
- Chamois skins? You have no idea.
Madame Georges,
you're one hell of a businesswoman!
What about tanned leather?
- There's only untanned.
But at a very good price.
- A good price?
Watch your trousers, Jean-B!
Well, Monsieur Peyssac?
You gonna talk, you bastard?
Damn, he seems to like it!
Stay away from those people.
They're not like us.
First of all...
the Americans are going
to win the war.
Everyone says so.
You hear me?
The Germans are finished.
The Americans will win, I tell you.
I'll do the talking.
I should have been an actor.
I'd have been better than Betty.
Dr. Vaugeois?
Speaking.
I'm from the underground at Lorsac.
The Germans attacked.
I've got a bullet in my thigh.
I'm on vacation,
and I have nothing with me.
All right. Come in.
Patrick, get my bag.
And some bandages and alcohol.
That's my son.
Lie down.
Some buddies told me about you.
Commandant Méry in particular.
Is that so?
You know Méry?
Very well.
He's a friend.
He sends one of his boys
this way now and then.
I'm sorry. German police.
I'm sorry.
Keep an eye on him.
Put your hands up.
Move it.
Paul, what's going on?
Don't be frightened, dear.
Exquisite.
Are you related to Philippe Vaugeois?
I met him at La Baule.
That was September of '38.
Is that so?
A charming boy, Philippe.
An excellent tennis player.
He always beat me.
- Who's that?
- My great-grandmother.
- Well?
- Just as we thought. He works with Méry.
Paul, do something!
Call the mayor!
Don't worry.
You wish to speak to Dr. Vaugeois?
Just a moment.
It's his brother.
What shall I say?
That we're going to shoot him.
We're going to shoot him, monsieur.
That's right - shoot him.
And send him all our love.
We send all our love, sir.
He hung up.
Now, what can you tell us
about Commandant Méry?
A man like you working with terrorists -
I don't get it.
You want bolshevism in France?
- I'm a Gaullist.
De Gaulle's surrounded
by Jews and commies.
You want names?
Does Schumann sound French to you?
Save the politics for later.
Come on, Doctor.
Tell us about Commandant Méry.
Come on, start talking.
- What's this?
- The Wandera.
I built it.
It took me a year.
It's almost done.
Is it a lot of work?
Especially the portholes.
What about you?
Are you like your father?
You know nothing
about the underground either?
Your suit is ready.
I made you golf trousers.
They're more elegant on a young man.
Do you like golf trousers?
I could make straight-legged pants,
but I think golf trousers
are more... more -
What are golf trousers?
They're like these.
We must have a fitting.
These are golf trousers?
Are you from here in town?
No, I'm from Souleillac.
And you're a friend
of Jean-Bernard de Voisins?
Are you a student?
Are you on vacation?
No, I'm with the German police.
I knew Jean-Bernard's father,
Count de Voisins.
A charming man.
He worried a great deal
about his son.
So you're a Jew.
Monsieur Faure says
Jews are the enemies of France.
Not me.
Are you from Paris?
I was good at my work.
I had a good clientele.
Friends.
What do you want?
I'm going shopping.
Let me have some money.
Aren't you going to introduce me?
My daughter, France.
Lacombe, Lucien.
Hurry up now.
See you later.
Monsieur Jean-Bernard told me
to collect the money you owe.
Tell Monsieur Jean-Bernard
that his father would be very sad
if he knew.
He was a real gentleman.
But what do I care?
Come with me.
- Stand in line like everyone else!
- Who do they think they are?
Who does she think she is?
Kids today think
they can get away with anything!
Cutting in line, eh?
Aren't you going to say anything?
I've been waiting an hour!
You think I'll stand for this?
German police!
To hell with the German police.
Aren't you going a bit far?
What's going on here?
German police.
You work with Monsieur Tonin?
Sorry. I didn't know.
Why do you keep talking about it?
I forgot it long ago.
It was only a year ago, my dear.
I've never understood why you did it.
You never tried to understand.
I loved him. It's very simple.
- And did he love you?
- Why not? What would you know?
After what he did?
You can't tell me he was a decent boy.
Papa, stop it, please!
You're getting on my nerves!
Is Monsieur Horn in?
What is it?
What do you want?
I've come to see your daughter.
Sit down, Monsieur Horn.
I suppose you'll be
joining us for dinner?
It's nice in here.
Not like outside.
I brought you a present.
Champagne from Lossy.
Monsieur Jean-Bernard
says it's the best.
You like champagne, mademoiselle?
No, not tonight.
But of course you like champagne.
Bottoms up, granny.
A toast, Monsieur Horn?
You should have some.
Your champagne is warm...
and it's a bad year, besides.
France, this young man is a customer.
Forgive me,
but I've forgotten your name.
A nice name.
And your name is Albert.
To your health...
my dear.
My dear?
Are you happy
with your golf trousers?
Not really, Monsieur Horn.
Do you know Betty Beaulieu?
Monsieur Jean-Bernard's friend.
She was in Night Raid.
I don't know her.
More champagne?
Let's celebrate.
No, really.
Come on, Albert.
It won't hurt you.
What are we celebrating exactly?
France, you should go to bed.
I forbid you to go to bed... my dear.
Why do you call me ' my dear"?
I don't know.
What did you do
before joining the police?
- I was studying.
- Studying what?
I could have you all arrested!
France, be quiet.
Are you afraid of him?
Yes, and he's right to be.
I'll get it.
I'd like a word with you,
Monsieur Horn.
Certainly.
You have funny hands.
I might need the apartment.
Why should I do you a favor?
But it's not fair.
Yes, it is.
I have every right to raise the rent.
I'm taking quite a risk
having you here as it is.
Besides,
no one's forcing you to stay.
France isn't one big waiting room.
Very well, Monsieur Raverdy.
You know what Marshal Pétain says?
Marshal Pétain?
Mr. Tonin calls him the Old Asshole!
- The Old Asshole?
- Very funny.
Is this gentleman your guest?
German police.
What's all this about?
This young man is indeed
with the German police.
Your papers.
Get out!
You entertain people
from the Gestapo now? Bravo!
Is that where your daughter sleeps?
Yes, it is.
Then we'd better whisper
so we don't wake her.
By the way, Albert...
your daughter's pretty.
Why do you two fight?
We get along very well.
I didn't want to mention it
in front of her,
but I shot a guy the other day.
You know, you shouldn't always
believe Monsieur Jean-Bernard.
It isn't true
what he said about Spain.
All he wants is your money.
You think I don't know that?
Shit!
They got the boss!
Christ, just my damn luck!
- You're not in too much pain?
- I hope it's not my lung.
Don't worry.
You got a drink?
I told you we should have left it
to the militia.
Hold on, boss.
- See you, guys!
- Good luck, kid!
What do you want?
They got my boss.
What?
Your friends shot my boss.
- What friends?
- The Bolsheviks!
May I see France?
Look, Albert.
War loot.
You should go to bed.
Long live France.
This is for you.
Sad music, isn't it?
It's as if my whole life's been lived
in time to that music.
Papa, don't start again.
France is a gifted pianist.
She should have gone
to the conservatory. But then -
Please.
I brought you some flowers.
I've come to get your daughter.
It's a going-away party
for Jean-Bernard and Betty.
I'd like to take France.
Are you crazy?
France is very tired.
If she doesn't come,
I'll take you to see my friends.
And some of them
aren't too fond of Jews.
- I'm going.
- Stay here.
I forbid you to go.
Come now, Papa.
Hurry up.
We're going to be late.
Come dance, Lucien.
I don't know how.
You have to learn!
That's very tiring.
I'm thirsty.
You dance very well.
It's late.
I have to take you home.
You look bored.
May I have this dance?
She's beautiful.
Say good-bye to Horn for me.
As for Spain,
tell him I'm going in his place.
I'm not pleased about it.
Some Jewish girls
are so very beautiful.
They make other women
look like old nags.
I had a Jewish fiancée once.
Incredibly stacked and very rich.
What are you telling him?
Nothing, my dear.
You broke my heel.
You've had too much to drink.
I'll take you home.
It's a shame you can't dance.
I'll teach you.
Relax.
See? It's easy.
Bastard.
You bastard!
Aubert says she's a Jew.
She has no right coming here.
Filthy Jew!
So you're sleeping with a Jew.
You think you'll get away with this?
I'm going to get the Germans
this minute!
Take it easy, Marie.
It's nothing.
Filthy Jew!
They all have syphilis!
You hear me?
She'll give it to you!
Let me go! I want to talk
to the filthy bitch!
She has no right!
Let me go!
Marie is usually nice.
I can't stand it anymore.
I'm tired of being a Jew.
One last drink, Betty!
For the road!
See you soon!
To my friends! For the road!
We'll send you some postcards.
My father has to get to Spain.
You know...
Italians are great on a bike,
but I was never afraid of 'em.
Even a champion like Bartali
didn't scare me.
You know the guys
who really shook me?
The Flemish!
You never saw Sylvère Maes race.
South of Caen,
numerous Anglo-Canadian attacks
have gained them some terrain.
German troops
are putting up fierce resistance.
Get moving.
It's funny you can sew.
It's usually women who sew.
You won't talk to me?
What would you say
if I married France?
It's very strange.
Somehow I can't bring myself
to completely despise you.
There's someone
to see Monsieur Lacombe.
His mother.
She came to the hotel.
I thought it best
to bring her here.
He's very kind.
Have a seat.
Forgive me
for receiving you like this.
Have you come a long way?
- From Souleillac.
Our village.
I came to town with Laborit
for the fair.
Did you get the money orders?
I brought you a chicken.
Are you eating well?
This is Lucien's mother.
My daughter.
She's very pretty.
I came to thank you for the money.
I don't want to bother anyone.
But you're not.
Please sit down.
You're not from around here?
We're from Paris.
But life in Paris
is very difficult right now.
There's nothing to eat there.
You're not French.
More or less.
My daughter is really French.
Is she happy here?
Ask her.
Lucien will have to show her around.
Only he can't return to his village.
You know, Lucien worries me.
And me too.
But he's not a bad boy.
You're a friend of Lucien's.
Perhaps you could reason with him.
I'm not a friend of Lucien's.
My daughter worries me too.
Very much.
Don't you think we were better off
before the war?
- I'll see you off.
- No need.
It's better if Laborit
doesn't see you.
Look what I got.
It's nothing.
We get them every day.
They're going to kill you.
Laborit says so.
Why don't you get away from here?
I like it here.
I'll miss my bus.
Wait.
You should eat something, Papa.
It's hard to have an appetite
when I have a whore for a daughter.
That wasn't nice, what you said.
I think it's very rude
to call your daughter a whore.
You deserve a good thrashing.
I don't need you to tell me
how to treat my daughter!
France and I are very much alike.
We're very fragile creatures.
Forgive me, my dear.
Leave me alone!
They let Monsieur Zweig's mother die.
Fröhlich told me.
Don't worry, Papa.
We'll get to Spain.
Spain.
Spain doesn't exist.
Be reasonable, Papa.
Feeling better?
You know, Monsieur Horn...
I like you a lot.
- I'm sure we can get to Spain.
- Have they closed the borders?
There are still some
unguarded spots.
I'm going to bed.
Good night, my friends.
You know
your grandmother can't manage.
There's no point
even talking about it.
You're right.
Besides, the war
will be over soon anyway.
It's true.
The Americans are already in Rouen.
You went out?
I took a little walk.
I haven't been out for so long.
I feel like my old self.
France says you could get us
across the border to Spain.
Really?
Lucien, I'd like to talk to you
man to man.
We've never talked.
What do you want to talk about?
France.
I don't have time.
I have to get to work.
They really got him.
I'm beat.
I'm gonna take a shower.
Lucien, this gentleman
is here to see you.
- What are you doing here?
- Waiting for you.
I've been chatting with your friend.
He's very nice.
Another round?
You're crazy!
I came to talk to you.
Things can't go on like this.
You just can't help
acting like an ass!
Come on.
I'm taking you home.
- Who's this?
- A friend.
Horn? Isn't he the Jew?
You bring Jews
to the hotel bar now?
Forgive him.
He's young.
I'll see you in my office.
Show me your papers.
What's this? ' Jean-François Rivière.
Born in Paris, July 30, 1892."
De Voisins got this for you.
Precisely.
I want to see an ID
with ' Jew" written on it.
All I have is a calling card.
Last name: Horn.
First name: Albert.
Place of birth?
- Szekesfehervar.
- What?
Why don't you just put Toulouse?
Address?
52 rue Pierre Premier
de Serbie, Paris.
Nationality?
French.
Didn't anyone ever tell you
yids can't be French?
On occasion.
To me a Jew is like a rat.
No more, no less.
Really?
They breed like crazy.
There's more and more of 'em.
- I can leave, if you like.
- Stay there.
I'm calling the Kommandantur.
You can explain to them.
Why do you speak to me
in that tone?
We didn't get to talk about France.
She was asleep when I left.
What I wanted to tell you -
Guess what, my friend.
I have a Jew in my office.
Open up!
Old witch!
They put him on a train to Toulouse.
I don't know
where they're taking them.
It's his own fault.
Shut up!
You bastard!
I'm a soldier like you,
fighting for my country!
I demand to be treated
like a soldier!
Go up and guard that guy.
I'll be with those gentlemen.
You still have the strength to work?
More than ever.
Bear up, kid.
How old are you, kid?
So you're working for the Germans?
A young Frenchman like you.
Aren't you ashamed?
I don't like people
talking down to me.
Stop acting smart, kid!
You know they're gonna shoot you?
You don't look like a thug.
Listen.
I'll give you a chance.
Take off these handcuffs
and I'll take you with me.
Understand?
I don't like people
talking down to me.
Hurry up!
Get me the Kommandantur.
You may take a small suitcase
or knapsack.
Only personal effects.
No food, no books, no money.
Hurry up.
- But -
- Hurry up.
You're not alone.
I still have lots of names on my list.
There's been a serious incident.
Hurry up.
Monsieur Lacombe,
you work for the German police.
There are no thieves
in the German police.
Give me that watch.
I'm staying with her.
Where are we going?
I don't know.
Spain.
Damn it!
- What did she say?
- There's a card missing.
Lucien Lacombe was arrested
on October 12, 1944.
He was tried
by a military court of the Resistance,
sentenced to death and executed.