This movie is based on land disputes
which have been going on
in Texas since 1848.
Mom? What was that?
Don't know, hon. I'll go check.
Jackie, why didn't you
close the window?
An animal could've gotten in.
Take what you want and leave.
I could kill you very easily.
Do you want that?
No.
Me neither.
Would you please
take that painting off the wall?
Open it, please.
Hello.
You think you're real macho,
hitting a woman?
How did you get this number?
It's private. Who is this?
Don't worry about me.
Worry about the sheriff
who's on his way.
The sheriff?
Yeah, you picked
the wrong house to rob.
Don't tell me
the sheriff is on his way.
Sheriff Johnson, right?
The same guy that told me
where your house was.
And where your safe was.
Hello?
Jackie!
Jackie, huh?
Leave her alone!
The safe!
The safe... I'm the only one
that can open it.
It's encrypted.
Encrypted with my own
security software.
Then open it.
- Now!
- I'm opening it!
Wow. Impressive.
- Hello?
- Rex, tell me you got the documents.
Yes.
So you Want me to make it
look like an accident?
Just bring me those papers
and get the hell out of there.
Will do.
Why didn't you go to the police?
They said it was my fault.
For having trusted Moctesuma Valdez.
A conman who made millions
selling fraudulent products
to the immigrant community.
I lost it all, miss.
My home. My money.
I lost my self-respect.
It was a difficult time.
But one day,
I Went to my mailbox...
And I received a...
An envelope. A package.
It completely changed my life.
It was like a...
A miracle?
Yes, ma'am.
A miracle!
Somebody returned everything
the conman had stolen.
It was them.
Mr. Alejandro Toledo...
And Emilio Sanchez.
They helped us.
The Robin Hoods.
Thieves who rob thieves.
They were our heroes.
Thanks to them,
I was able to graduate from college.
Do you know where they are?
I never got the chance to thank them
for what they did for us.
Some say they work for the FBI.
Others say they wear disguises
so as to not be recognized.
But in reality, nobody knows
where they are.
They saved my life.
We need people like them.
MEXICO CITY
Sir, there's a young lady to see you.
She says it's urgent.
But I don't think she's a customer.
- I told you to wait outside.
- It's okay, miss. Thank you.
I thought you'd be more... in shape.
Are you Alejandro Toledo?
Alejandro Toledo?
The one they call Robin Hood?
Alejandro... Hood... Robin Hood.
No. I don't know Alejandro Hood.
Weird. I looked into him.
I know Alejandro owns this dealership.
Well, I don't know...
Look, please, I need his help.
I have a problem. We were robbed.
And I know Alejandro can help.
Please...
Here's some good advice.
Go to the police. They can help.
The station is two blocks that Way.
Good luck. Have a nice day.
I can't go to the police.
She owns the police.
She owns everything.
This is about justice.
We need him to do what he does best.
To rob a thief.
You just found him.
Okay.
SIX MONTHS LATER
Congratulations.
You've been caught red-handed.
Details.
If you don't consider all details,
you will get caught.
The heist isn't made in the vault.
The heist is made in the planning.
Excuse me?
Can you say it in English, please?
Yes.
I mean, yes.
Emilio.
You switched sides.
Alejandro.
No. I've always worked
for the good guys.
How the hell did you get in here?
You have serious flaws in Sector 3.
Your motion detectors are outdated.
And your surveillance cameras
don't work as they should.
I think it'd be wise
to go talk in my office.
Of course.
I shouldn't be seen
talking to a... thief.
I'm already six months into this.
- I need to do this.
- To do What?
Steal?
It's just the kind of heist
you and I do.
No. Used to do, Alejandro.
I am an FBI agent now.
If you do this job, I will arrest you!
On the other hand,
let's just say
you went to Santiago Guzman.
Santiago Guzman is not an FBI agent.
Nothing of the sort.
I don't know. Just maybe,
he could, perhaps...
Help.
So what's Guzman up to?
Relax.
The market goes up
and it goes down, Mr. Nakatomi.
But, fortunately for you,
Santiago Guzman owns this town.
So, when I say to you
that your stock will have
a dividend yield of 22.46%,
trust me, it's gonna be raining yen.
Arigato. And sayonara, Mr. Nakatomi.
Sayonara.
Casual Friday at the office?
The benefits of working from home.
- So good to see you, bro.
- You too.
What storm blew you out here?
Still quite the wordsmith, eh?
- You look good.
- Thanks.
So...
What's this I see here?
People see what they want to believe.
Besides, nobody on Wall Street
was going to hire an ex-thief.
Tell me the truth.
What brings you here?
Something simple.
- An advance.
- Nice!
You've always
had a Way with words too.
I promised my wife
I was out of the business.
Hang on a second.
Hold this for me.
It's nothing bad.
I'm reformed too. See?
Have lunch with me.
You like Tex-Mex?
Didn't realize we were...
expecting company.
Alejandro.
So your old partner shows up
and just invites you to lunch?
Exactly. And he's also my friend.
And it's just Tex-Mex.
I Want you at home, not in jail.
Please, honey.
I promise, we're just going to talk.
The theoretical probability of doing
anything illegal is 0.00 percent.
Almost nothing.
Long way to go for Tex-Mex.
It's homemade.
Do you know what this is?
Mexico. Before the war
with the gringos, right?
Correct.
And after that war,
Mexico lost a lot of land.
But then, the Americans
had to contend with one little detail.
Mexican rancheros who owned land
on what became
US. territory overnight.
Exactly.
But the Guadalupe-Hidalgo Treaty
stipulated that the US.
would honor the rancheros' land
if the rancheros could prove
legal ownership.
There's always a catch, huh?
And to do that, they'd need to have
their original land grants.
And Without those land grants,
they'd be evicted.
Forcibly, if need be.
Then their land would be
claimed by the Americans.
But with those papers,
the Mexicans could prove
that their land belonged to them.
Legally. Forever.
To pass down generation to generation.
Someone robbed your land grants.
Tell me more.
Juan Ramirez was the patriarch
of this family.
And was one of the few rancheros
who had his land grants.
He was an honest man...
...which is why
the other ranchers trusted him
to keep all their land grants safe.
So he hid them in a secret spot,
somewhere on his property,
that only he knew.
This was to keep the land grants
from the hands of the wrong people.
But it wasn't long
until the wrong people showed up.
Ned Kilroy was
a cold-hearted opportunist.
He didn't care about the treaty.
And he demanded that
Juan hand over the land grants.
No, Mr. Kilroy. I'm not telling you
where the land grants are.
I'm asking you to leave.
Leave!
Ned Kilroy searched for the documents.
But he never found them.
Nobody did.
The exact hiding spot
died that day with Juan Ramirez.
The other rancheros blamed Juan.
Because without any evidence
that the land belonged to them,
Kilroy stole their land
and built the town of Kilroy.
The Kilroys now own everything.
And have made millions as a result.
The ranchero families became renters.
On their own land.
Then, six months ago...
A miracle.
Josefa Ramirez found the land grants.
Buried exactly where Juan hid them.
166 years ago.
See? It's the original seal...
Josefa immediately called the sheriff.
And told him what she'd found.
Finally, the Ramirez family
could get their land back.
But she didn't know
that Sheriff Johnson
was in the Kilroys' pocket.
A man named Rex
would show up that night
and steal the land grants.
Now, Rex isn't your typical enforcer.
He's very superstitious.
Which is an advantage
we intend to exploit.
The land grants are now
in the Kilroy Resort,
on North Padre Island.
Nice. Beautiful.
And a fortress.
I mean her. The blondie.
She's our mark. Miranda Kilroy.
As conniving as
her great-grandfather, Ned.
I take it you've
infiltrated the place?
Six months ago.
Heard she was looking
for a new trainer.
So I showed her
some of my qualifications.
Took me a while
to gain her confidence.
But now, I'm always on call.
Even got my own room at the resort.
- Obstacles?
- Many.
Before coming to me, somebody tried
stealing back the papers.
They were unsuccessful.
And almost got caught.
Since then,
Miranda beefed up security.
She's gotten very paranoid.
She now has armed guards everywhere.
Security cameras too. Everywhere.
But the real reason
for all the security is simple.
Miranda is facing a ticking clock.
In two weeks, a judge
is going to finally rule
on who is the rightful owner
of the land.
So it all comes clown to who presents
those land grants that day.
Which is why, until then,
she keeps the land grants in a safe...
...behind a poster of her one and only
opera performance in New York.
But that simple poster
is protected by a force field.
Rex has an amulet around his neck.
And that amulet is the key.
It deactivates the force field
around the poster.
Wait.
That amulet deactivates a force field
around a poster which conceals the--
Like I said, Miranda is very paranoid.
It's a complex heist.
But nothing we can't handle.
What do you say?
Thank you for the meal, ma'am.
Within the risk-return spectrum,
I'd have to classify this heist
as a junk bond.
Alejandro's plan isn't junk!
It's a financial term, kid. It means,
high yield, but too much risk.
I feel bad for all these families.
But I can't get back
into this business.
I promised my wife.
The decision's been made.
Goodbye.
Alejandro.
Can I get a ride back home?
Yes. After you hear this last part.
That's Fransisco.
Top of his class.
Wanted to be a lawyer.
But right now,
he has to work in a factory.
Margarita?
Excellent student.
Accepted into a school of medicine.
She had to drop out. Why?
Because she's broke.
There's a lot of talent here.
But very few opportunities to show it.
Because they're forced to pay
high rents to Miranda.
Besides, it's not just that
we were robbed.
This affects everyone who lives here.
Look.
This will be
the Kilroy Cultural Center.
They Want to build it here.
Over our land.
See? She's determined to fulfill
her fantasy of being an opera singer.
If the judge rules in Miranda's favor,
she'll destroy everything.
They're going to kick us out of here.
It's our home. It's been our home
for generations. My God.
Please. Help us get justice.
I'm not like you and Emilio,
where you pull a job
and give away the money.
Doing what's right is the best pay.
I knew you were going to get
all sappy on me.
Partners?
Fine. I'll help you out.
On one condition.
I'm only going to consult.
In other Words, I'll just advise.
To do this job, we need specialists.
Highly skilled people.
Where are we going to find such people
on such short notice?
From around here.
From here?
- Yeah.
- Here?
Pure reverse engineering.
See what talents they have.
And build the heist around them.
Come on, now!
Great idea!
Why not hold auditions?
You already know me.
I'm Josefa. I'm a gardener.
But what's your real talent?
She's a molecular scientist.
But she's always frustrated
that nobody recognizes
her true genius.
Very good. She's in.
Next.
- I tell philosophical stories.
- Let's hear one.
There once was a man with great luck.
Every girl that he met said,
"Hey, you wanna--"
Next.
Not a talent!
I'm Mario. I like cats.
See this curl? Here, in South Texas,
there's lots of humidity...
Horrifying hair. Too much frizz.
So I've spent years
training my friends
to recognize weather variations.
In order to save their hair.
Right, girls?
- Next!
- No, no.
Every con needs a good distraction.
And a woman is that distraction.
Nice to see you. What's your name?
Maria Elena.
Jackie tells me
you can read tarot cards.
Yes. In my spare time.
I do spell work, consultations,
cleanings. I'm a spiritualist.
So you can predict the future?
No, that's a clairvoyant.
I'm a spiritualist.
She's in.
My turn!
I'm Ray. I work at the ranch here.
I'm an expert on horses.
But as you'll see,
ladies and gentlemen,
today, I will demonstrate
how pain is all in the mind.
This guy drives me crazy.
He drives me crazy too.
When the flame touches my skin,
I will feel nothing.
My body rejects pain.
See?
Nothing.
Because I've conditioned myself
to be impervious to pain.
Stop! You're gonna hurt yourself.
You can smell the flesh, right?
Sure. But I feel nothing.
For my next demonstration--
We've seen enough. Thank you!
He's in.
- What?
- Him too?
He's Jackie's boyfriend.
Nice guy. Dying to help.
We'll find something for him.
What else are we looking for?
The key to the plan,
the resort's head of security.
He'll be accused by a Texas Ranger
of robbing their jewelry store.
That guard always ends up
working for the wrong employer.
That's a good plan.
We've seen all the talent out there.
None of them are actors.
We need a real actor.
No Worries. I know one.
He likes playing characters
that are...
Very complex.
He's scary.
What the hell are you doing?
You're here to entertain the kids.
Not traumatize them.
Ma'am, I'm playing a hungry bear.
If a hungry bear
happens upon these kids,
he's gonna eat them. That's real.
I'm a method actor.
I keep things real.
You ruined my party.
I just wanted to entertain.
This is a very risky job to pull off
with just a crew of amateurs.
What are you getting out of it?
Hey!
You may want to know,
Hurricane Inez is predicted to hit
North Padre in four days.
What a coincidence!
The hurricane doesn't worry you?
No. It's only a Category 1.
Well, maybe 2. So no biggie.
Tell me something, Jackie.
Can you hack all communications
with this thing?
So they see only
What I want them to see?
Sure. But check this out.
I built this.
It's a transmitter.
Plug it into the mainframe,
and we're good.
Everything beams back to my computer.
Wow. I'm impressed.
You're very intelligent.
Yes, she's very intelligent.
Now ask her why
she didn't get into Harvard.
Not now, mom.
Better yet, ask that doofus.
It doesn't hurt.
What is it?
See where the mainframe is?
Right next door
to Miranda's penthouse.
Paranoid.
There's only one way in there.
Yeah, I know.
I'm on it.
Look who decided to drop by. What?
Tired of playing
with your little friends?
Come on. What friends?
You know I love you.
But do me a favor.
Don't be mad at me.
Do I look mad?
Relax, woman.
It's only a couple of days!
Good morning, friends.
Am I your friend?
Is he your friend?
- Let's go. Against the wall.
- Again?
Every day it's the same thing.
I'm here to train Miss Kilroy.
- She's expecting me!
- Then go on in.
Welcome. Right this way.
Don't stare, I ain't that pretty.
Now that we're all here,
I'm gonna give you
your assignments. To avoid screw ups.
I already know mine.
Knock Rex out. Get that amulet.
For you, my friend, anything.
What do you need?
For me to sit. Got it.
Considering that Rex
has a black belt in Aikido,
is a weapons specialist,
and an ex-mercenary,
not just you, but even four guys
won't be able to take him down.
Maria Elena when you gain entry
dressed as a maid,
your mystical powers
will play a key role.
Of course, with Josefa's help.
Her science skills will ensure
all of this runs like clockwork.
I get it.
- Miguelito.
- Talk to me.
I need you to research
how to become a Texas Ranger.
You won't believe this,
but I've always wanted to play
in the Major Leagues.
I don't mean a baseball player.
I mean the elite police force,
The Texas Rangers.
Santiago.
What am I doing?
Ray.
Impervious to pain, right?
Haven't figured out
What to do with that talent yet.
Talent? What talent?
He's just a pretty boy.
I'm sorry, Ray. I am.
Don't mean to be tough on you,
but you are a bit slow, aren't you'?
Ray! I know what you're going to do.
You're going to rob the jewelry store.
What?
Are you telling me you gave
the most crucial part of the job
to an amateur kid?
Call it an honor among men
with bitchy mother-in-laws.
How're you doing, sir?
Mind if I mosey on over...
Hey, Alejandro,
how are you, my friend?
You seem busy. I'll let you
get back to work. Keep going.
It's all good.
And you? Who do you think you are?
Pancho Villa?
You asked me to dress
like a Texas Ranger.
So I'm dressed
Take that off!
- That hurt, bro. It had glue.
- Come here. I need a favor.
Discreetly, look to your right.
See that girl in the middle?
- The one that has the big--
- Yeah, her.
I need you to train her
to play a meteorologist.
Play a meteorologist?
Why her? I'm the actor.
Do you watch Spanish TV?
Of course.
When was the last time
you saw a meteorologist
who wasn't in a short dress,
with a smoking bod?
Good point.
How're you doing, ladies?
Oh, great. Are you gonna turn me in...
Oh, Virgin of Guadalupe!
Nobody's going to believe
that that clown is a Texas Ranger.
Just wait till I'm done with this.
I'll transform the digital model
into an actual solid object
using an additive process
where successive layers are laid down
in different shapes
that connect like a puzzle.
How did you not get into Harvard?
Wait a minute! You're falsifying
government credentials, Jackie?
Don't worry, Josefa.
If it gets traced,
it comes back to me.
She's using my laptop.
Besides, we have a friend in the FBI
looking out for us.
Why do I even try?
You could've said, "Wow, Jackie.
You're incredible with computers.
That's my daughter! She's awesome!"
But no.
Always with the criticism.
Excuse me.
I'm gonna take a shower.
Care to join me?
You should be so lucky.
I'm in.
Good. Now just connect it.
It just switched on. See anything?
Nice! I got it.
Good job!
It's fake. Rubber. See?
Oh, good.
But this baby...
is real.
Helps me stay in character.
How y'all doing?
There's a new sheriff
in this "barrio",
and he's flying "huevos".
I don't think Miranda Kilroy
will believe you're a Texas Ranger.
Everything you're doing
with the character is... ridiculous.
Look.
I don't need an amateur
who's never stepped onto a stage,
who's never performed for an audience,
talk to me about acting.
Me, a professional actor,
with more than 20 years of--
You okay, kid?
I think I shit myself.
But that didn't hurt.
False alarm.
Super.
Tomorrow, we will do some weights.
What are you up to?
What are you doing here?
You've been training me
for six months.
We're together almost every day.
I give you a room in my resort.
I send you sexy pictures of me.
And you haven't made a move.
- I'm a professional.
- Bullshit.
Bullshit.
Listen, honey.
I'll explain.
I like you.
I want this to move past
a trainer-client relationship
into something more personal.
Sounds really nice.
Good.
Do you know what
always makes me relax?
Music.
You probably don't know this about me,
but when I was a little girl,
all I wanted to be
was an opera singer.
But daddy killed that dream
real quick.
"Kilroys aren't dreamers," he'd say.
We are doers.
Which is why I'm building this.
The Kilroy Cultural Center.
This... will change Texas forever.
And this will be my pride and joy.
The Kilroy Opera House.
Now, I'll be able to sing
whenever I want.
You see, Alejandro,
I am a doer.
And I'll finally be able
to tear down that hick town.
And what about the people
that live in that town now?
What about them?
Okay. That's Plan B.
If the hurricane turns away,
we'll use this one you created?
- Yes.
- Nice.
At least I don't have to
worry about you.
Wish my mom would think that.
- Sorry, gotta take this.
- Sure.
Emilio, I'm glad you called.
Why the hell are you calling me?
What do you mean, bro? You called me.
I've told you a hundred times.
I can't help you. I work for the law.
Bro!
But if I were able to help you,
I'd tell you,
there is no evidence
that Kilroy stole the papers.
Which means she has to be
caught in the act.
Stealing the land grants. Understand?
Understood.
Hurricane Inez, only a Category 1.
Won't cause much damage.
But still be careful...
That's it, perfect, perfect.
Beautiful.
It's getting there.
All you have to do is focus.
Understand?
Nonchalant. Do it in a fluid movement.
Like nothing's going on.
It's as easy as
taking somebody's underwear,
without lowering their pants.
Okay.
Why would I need to
take somebody's underwear off?
Forget it, kid. It's just a saying.
People, hello.
That hurricane is turning away.
My hair is drying out.
Santiago, we gotta go to Plan B!
Hurricane Inez is turning away
from the resort. It's going away!
See'? Unlike my ex-boyfriends,
my hair never lies.
It's time to get going. Just remember,
the heist is made in the plan,
not the vault.
Ray. Come here, kid.
- I gotta talk to you.
- Sure. What's up?
I was thinking,
when I get into the jewelry store,
I should throw myself
against the glass
like Rambo or Jean-Claude Van Damme.
I can't let you rob the store.
What? Why?
I've been perfecting my own technique.
I call it "Screw the pain."
My decision is final.
If you get caught,
you'll get 20 years.
I can't take that risk.
I'll find something else
for you to do.
Fine.
Hey.
So, who's robbing the jewels?
Remember, ladies.
5:00 p.m., poolside. Don't be late.
- Can I help you with this?
- No, no.
Housekeeping!
Force of habit.
I'm used to entering that way.
What are you doing here?
You promised you'd set it all up
and then leave, Jackie.
- I'm staying.
- No, you're not.
Mom, nobody knows
how to use this equipment
better than me,
and you know it.
Relax, mom-in-law-to-be, relax.
If anybody messes with Jackie...
Lights out.
Get it? Lights out.
I should go.
I'll be in position.
And I'll be ready.
Okay? Bye.
Jackie, you lied to me.
Well, we'll talk later.
Don't be upset with your mom.
Look, she sees you like a baby horse.
Like a newborn foal. All weak.
With skinny legs, trying to stand.
Trying to, you know...
I love you.
I'm on the beach, kid.
What? You're here?
Yes.
What happened to "only consulting"?
No, that'd be a bad investment.
I can't let you guys do this alone.
Let's get the party started.
Release the hurricane.
Initiating Hurricane Miranda.
Interesting...
Now we're talking.
Look this way. You're so hot.
I love this job.
People see what they want to believe.
Santiago, before you go,
Ray wants to know
if you have anything for him yet.
To watch your back.
Why can't he see that I can be
an important part of this operation?
Why does he treat me like an idiot?
BACK DOOR...
I love this job.
Hello, girls.
Yep. I'm the guard here.
In charge of all the security.
Tons of responsibility.
Damn it. Are you kidding?
And you can trust my hair
more than the radar.
Frizzy hair means imminent hurricane.
And judging by my curls,
the hurricane will hit tonight.
So be careful.
I love Spanish TV.
The surfers will have
a great time though.
Hello?
Sir. Sorry to disturb you.
I recommend you turn on your TV.
Hurricane Inez has turned back.
I'm Tina. Hair, weather.
Weather, hair.
This is an unstoppable
force of nature.
- Good?
- So good.
Miss Kilroy?
I don't mean to interrupt.
But I thought you should know that
Hurricane Inez has turned back to us.
And one more thing.
There's a Texas Ranger
coming up to see you.
He says it's urgent.
Thank you for seeing me, ma'am,
on such short notice.
I'm Chuck Norris.
You're Chuck Norris?
I'm sorry. That was a joke.
Because he played the Texas Ranger
on that TV show.
It's a good one.
I got it and it's funny.
Please, come in, Ranger.
- Please, have a seat, Ranger.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Pardon me for asking,
but you seem a little nervous.
Everything all right?
Nervous? No, I'm not nervous.
No, no.
You mind?
See, I've been all over Texas, Ranger.
Never heard an accent like yours.
What part of the Lone Star State
are you from?
I'm from the, you know,
the northern, western
eastern, southern part?
My poppy's Cuban, which makes me
more Southern than you are, ma'am.
So, the reason why I came here
to talk to you, ma'am,
is we got some information recently
about a possible suspect
here on premise.
I thought you might want to...
I ran his match. He's legit.
Just get rid of him.
He's ridiculous.
I don't think Miranda Kilroy
will believe you're a Texas Ranger.
Opportunity.
A lot of us fail in life
because of a lack of opportunity.
But when I look around
your gorgeous suite,
and it's gorgeous,
I see plenty of opportunity.
Opportunity for a thief
to rob you blind, ma'am.
Are you saying that someone's
planning on robbing me, Ranger?
Yeah, I get off at 11:00 p.m...
I'd like to buy you breakfast.
Clothing optional.
It's a joke. Forget it--
Miss Kilroy! Hi! How are you?
I was just keeping an eye on the...
- Hurricane for you.
- Right.
- Thank you, Carlos, really.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry. Where are my manners?
I Want to introduce you to someone.
Texas Ranger Danuza.
Ranger.
How are you doing, Carlos?
You can have a seat.
Have a seat.
Okay.
Okay, now pick up the phone,
call Santiago
and tell him the jig is up.
I'm sorry, who? I have no idea
What you're talking about, Ranger.
Boy, don't piss on my boots
and tell me it ain't raining.
Were talking about Santiago Guzman.
The man set to rob the jewelry
store tonight with your help.
Okay, this is preposterous,
Miss Kilroy, I have no idea...
Boy, don't be using
big college words on me!
- What's that?
- It's the jewelry store alarm.
Look, that's him! That's him!
Okay, Miss Kilroy,
I will take care of this.
Please, do not worry.
Okay, I'm sorry.
- You're kidding me, right?
- I'm sorry. I'm a little nervous.
Section one! Section two! Report
immediately to the jewelry store.
I repeat, immediately
to the jewelry store.
We have a code 10-bravo.
I repeat, a code 10-bravo.
To the jewelry store, now!
- You don't belong here. Go home.
- Yes sir.
So cute!
Take that mask off.
Consulting?
Woman! What are you doing here?
This is very dangerous.
Grab him. Go! Grab him!
Don't let him go, boys!
Hold onto him.
Forgive me. Men don't change.
I'm just a thief.
Carlos!
My brother, I'm really sorry.
I tried robbing the diamonds
as we planned, but I failed!
- I'm stupid, Carlos.
- Stop saying "Carlos."
I'm really sorry, Carlos.
Don't beat me again, please.
He beats me up all the time.
All the time he beats me.
He does pervy things to me.
He tries and tries, but I resist.
Look... He's crazy.
Carlos, please forgive me.
I've never seen this guy in my life.
He's crazy.
So a total random mustachioed criminal
just happens to know your name?
It's a set-up.
I mean, look at him.
He's dressed in black,
all cat-burglary and shit.
Who dresses like that?
Cracked the case, dickhead. Boom
I mean, who dresses like that, right?
Thieves do.
Good. You're here.
Everythings ready.
Listen. Everything works
with this remote control.
Hide it in your uniform.
- Josefa... I can't. I can't.
- Now what's wrong?
I can't do this.
This goes against my principles
as a spiritualist. I don't do this.
Listen to me.
I admire your principles. Okay?
It's what I love most about you.
But, oh, my God, cut the shit.
CUT ALL RADIO COMMUNICATIONS.
DONE!
Why are you guys here,
when all the other guards
are pursuing the thieves
who robbed the store?
What do you know
about that, trainer-boy?
Nothing.
We're the firewall.
Sure. It's just I heard Rex
call for all the guards,
before the radios got out,
so I assumed...
But that's none of my business.
Come in, Rex. Echo One.
Come in, Rex. Echo Two.
Anything?
Pretend I said nothing.
She's very understanding.
When has she fired
anyone over small stuff?
Let's go get some coffee.
I'll wait here.
Let me go, man! Take it easy!
I didn't do anything.
Shit!
That's far enough, boys.
I'll take this thief from here.
The chubby guy!
What are you looking at?
Not bad for a retired ex-thief.
Meet The Cobra.
She has a lethal bite.
Don't you sweet talk me.
You're all in on it.
The trainer too?
Yep.
See you at the rendezvous.
What are you doing here?
I told you to go home already.
I don't work for you.
I work for Miss Kilroy
Where are the guards?
They weren't here when I arrived.
Echo One, Echo Two, what's your 20?
I got to go find those two idiots.
I'll be back. And you...
Well, if you don't need me tonight,
I'll be here tomorrow as always.
You know what?
A workout would do me good.
ELEVATORS!
DONE!
Echo One, Echo Two, what's your 20?
No. Sir! There's no elevator.
Don't go in there!
You saved my life.
How did you know?
I can see things before they happen.
I'm a spiritualist.
That's a clairvoyant.
This was clairvoyance.
I know! That's what I always say!
I'm both.
I see darkness.
Wait a minute.
That darkness you see in me...
How bad is it?
Real bad.
Yeah?
- May I?
- Please.
My visions go by fast.
But this one is very clear.
There's a woman behind you.
You've done terrible things for her.
Hey, hon, what's bugging you?
I'll admit it. I'm jealous.
Jealous? Of what?
Of you. That you got
to pull another job.
I miss it. The planning.
The execution.
- Getting away with it.
- Yes.
That's the most important part, right?
I don't know what's worse.
Being locked in here.
Or having to listen
to all this bullshit.
You need to have a soul cleaning.
You can't live with this energy.
You need a cleaning.
You have to do it!
Before it's too late. This is no joke.
You need to save your soul!
Right now!
I can't right now. I'm real busy.
As you wish.
But I'll just tell you this.
There may not be somebody around
to stop your fall next time.
Okay! Let's go to my room.
No! Not your room.
It has to be someplace neutral.
You'd better not be lying to me.
Come in.
- Get undressed.
- Excuse me?
I need it all off, so I can
unblock all that negative energy.
Of course.
Keep your underwear on.
It's cold.
I'll lower the AC?
Also, I need you to remove the amulet.
It blocks your heart chakra.
Impossible.
Listen to me...
You need to start
believing me right now.
If not, there isn't anybody that
will clean that soul of yours.
If you'd prefer it, I'll leave.
Put it there. On the bed.
Have a seat.
Frizzy.
The hurricane!
Damn, that storm is really coming.
I can't breathe.
I'm not going to work out.
Don't leave.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's really...
It's really coming.
Spirits of darkness,
I compel you to leave this man.
He will be good and noble.
- Don't promise much.
- Shut up!
In the name of divine spirits,
I compel you to leave this body.
Be good as you should be.
Exit the darkness.
We're not scared of you!
She speaks for herself. Not for me.
Housekeeping.
Close your eyes.
I got it in here.
Thanks.
Where is my amulet?
Who are you?
You're a fake spiritualist!
How dare you say that to me?
I'm an incredible spiritualist!
Darkness...
Consume this man!
Nice job, Josefa.
On, shit.
The hurricane!
HURRICANE INEZ
COMING TO US. FOR REAL.
DO WE GO BACK TO PLAN A?
OR DO WE STICK TO PLAN B?
- Which is real? Which is fake?
- Real. Fake. I made that one.
BACK TO PLAN A.
INITIATE NEXT PHASE.
- Okay. Ready?
- Yeah!
Bye-bye, electricity.
That's our cue. Alejandro must
be wrapping up with Blondie.
The power's out?
I'm glad I spent a fortune
on generators. Alejandro!
It happens. Well.
Don't worry. Have a seat. Relax.
The power will come back
any minute now.
I'll stay here to make sure
everything turns out fine.
That's my girl.
- Did I bite your lips again?
- No. I ruined it.
Jackie, you should be packed up.
No, listen, Santiago.
When I out the power,
it released the
automatic jail cell doors!
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
I'M ON IT. NO PROB.
SEE YOU AT THE RENDEZVOUS.
Don't worry.
It's just something special I ordered.
- Even with the power out?
- Of course.
You're the boss.
I still have service.
At least something works
around here still.
Time to get out of Dodge, little lady.
What are you... What the hell?
Juan Ramirez sends you a message.
He wants his land back.
Wait.
Ramirez.
You're a Ramirez.
Yes. After today, yes.
Look.
See this? I'm gonna go get our land.
Careful. Put it in the center.
Done. It's deactivated.
There are backup lithium
batteries, geniuses.
You'll never get it open
without the combo.
No.
No land grants?
No land grants in that safe?
So strange. Who could have moved them?
Miss Kilroy!
It's a set-up! They framed me!
They're actually here to rob you!
That Texas Ranger
with the shitty southern accent?
He's in on it. Your trainer.
And some hot chick
who can really kick ass.
You can stop talking now.
I know that! They're in here!
Go find them and kill them!
I can't do that. I'm a security guard.
I'm not a killer.
I'm here to save you.
Don't be a dumb-ass.
They set you up
to take the fall for this.
I think I'm just going to free you
if that's okay.
Where are the land grants?
Alejandro!
It has been 166 years
since a Kilroy killed a Ramirez.
Stick around! We're due.
I got it.
- Can you free this up a little bit?
- I'm trying.
Yeah, come here.
Carlos, watch the door.
- Don't let anybody out of here.
- Don't worry, Miss Kilroy.
Unless they can Walk through walls,
they're hot going anywhere.
There's no safe!
Where'd she hide the papers?
Miss Kilroy, look!
They must've used some kind
of corrosive liquid
to burn a hole through the wall
and escape.
Good morning, South Texas!
Some storm last night, huh?
But it seems to have
passed with minimal damage!
In other news...
I'm so happy. It turned out perfect.
Just as planned.
But how'd you knock Rex out?
- How'd you manage that?
- I don't follow.
He just passed out.
How'd you do that?
Witchy, that's more your thing.
I'm going to check on the papers.
So, I did that part on my own.
Alone. On my own.
See? She's a witch.
Don't listen to them.
People fear what
they don't understand.
I'm Cuban. That doesn't scare me.
In fact, I find it sexy.
Thank you, Miguelito.
Thanks for helping my family.
I know what it feels like
to have your land taken from you.
You move. You die.
Right, Sheriff?
So this is how the other half lives.
I can't believe you were so stupid
to come back
to Ramirez Ranch, Alejandro.
Hello! I know where you live.
Did you really think this was
going to have a happy ending?
That you'd all, I don't know,
ride off into the sunset
and live happily ever after?
I don't think so.
This is no folktale, Alejandro.
And you? You're no Robin Hood.
The papers. Put them in the case.
Nice try.
I want all of the land grants.
From all of the families here!
This land
and all of its riches
belong to my family.
No one will take them away from us.
Not 166 years ago, not today.
No. No.
No, Josefa. No!
If the market changes, you adapt.
This belonged to Juan Ramirez.
Good luck to you.
Come on!
There's no way we'll catch them.
Now what?
Go! This is why they
call you "jackass."
Take the other horse. We have three.
Ray already took it.
Don't worry. I'm sure
Ray knows what he's doing.
Follow me. I know a shortcut.
Let's go!
Kill Alejandro, go!
Like stealing your underwear
without lowering your pants.
You idiots! We were distracting you!
They got the case!
Shoot him! Shoot him!
'Cause of all the distraction,
you idiot?
Let's see how you do
against someone who hits back.
Not sure if you've heard,
but I'm impervious to pain.
Okay, that hurt.
You okay, kid?
Don't move, kid. You've been shot.
Let's see. It went in. It went out.
You're fine.
Help! Someone help me!
I'm stuck in here.
Well, well, well...
Really?
Si, really.
I've always depended
on the kindness of idiots.
Alejandro...
This isn't over.
Drop the gun.
Good boy.
To me, you got rid of
the gun too soon.
We could've used it.
Drop the case.
Drop the case!
I wouldn't give it to her.
Sure, easy for you to say.
She's not pointing the shotgun at you.
Still, I wouldn't give it to her.
Enough of this!
Little girls shouldn't play with guns.
This is Texas, honey.
We always carry a second gun.
To me, you got rid
of that gun too soon.
We could've used it.
Miranda Kilroy!
FBI.
You are under arrest.
FBI! Drop the gun!
Hand in the cookie jar.
You've been caught in the act.
Thank you.
I got it the first time.
Wait. Wait a minute, please.
So that's why you went back
to the ranch with the documents?
Because you knew Blondie would
show up to steal them again?
Well, well, well.
Aren't you a sneaky bastard.
What happened?
What did I miss?
I'm so impressed.
It's incredible what you can do.
I feel so...
I feel so proud of you.
Wait up. Are we having a
mother/daughter bonding moment?
I was wrong.
Ray is good. He's a good guy.
I know you're listening.
Come on out.
Look at him.
You have all my blessings,
from the heart.
Thank you.
But promise that you won't
waste your talents like I did.
- Promise me.
- Hey, Mom...
You didn't blow your talents,
because you're not just a gardener.
I've always been proud of you.
You raised me alone.
You're the most... Hey.
You're the bravest, smartest,
and most loving woman I know.
- I love you.
And because of your example,
Jackie got into Harvard.
What? But... Didn't they reject you?
What?
You didn't tell her?
It's just, the letter arrived
when the land grants got stolen.
That day, I decided to stay
and fight for the family.
You got in?
I got in to Harvard!
These kids grow up so fast.
Like I always say,
what matters most
is not numbers and percentages,
but rather, people.
You've always said that?
I do now.
I mean this. Thank you.
You have no idea what you've done
for my family.
No need to thank us.
And if the Ramirez family ever
needs anything else, just ask.
Actually yes.
There's one more thing.
Come, please.
That was quick.
Who are these people?
The other families.
whose land you saved.
And now, it's easier to imagine
engineers and doctors
coming from this town.
Or lawyers, or whatever...
Depends on our dreams.
Thanks to them!
You see it. There it is.
What are you talking about?
The answer to your question.
What do I get out of this?
Helping others.
Thank you!
THE END
Where there is injustice,
they'll be there.
Where the strong abuse the weak,
Reporting for Despierta America...
Do you think they'll figure out
how we'll do this mission?
I'm an FBI agent.
How did you convince me
to do this job?
Simple.
Because this is what we do.
Hurry up!