In the daytime, I'm Marinette.
Just a normal girl with a normal life.
But there's something about me that no one knows yet,
'Cause I have a secret.
♪ Miraculous Ladybug!
♪ Miraculous!
♪ Simply the best!
♪ Up to the test when things go wrong!
♪ Miraculous, the luckiest!
♪ The power of love, always so strong!
♪ Miraculous!
♪ Merry Christmas to all!
♪ Dad, Mom, I'm gonna help you at the bakery.
♪ To give the Yule logs to all of my friends.
♪ Alya, Merry Christmas to your whole family.
♪ Thank you Marinette, Merry Christmas as well.
♪ Alix and her dad, Merry Christmas to you both.
♪ Lively hearts, Marinette, all of our best wishes.
♪ Rose and Juleka, it's for you, happy holidays.
♪ Merry Christmas too.
♪ Merry Christmas Marinette.
♪ Merry Christmas to you, Manon and Nadia.
♪ Merry Christmas Nino and Sabrina.
♪ Merry Chri-
You want my picture?
Marinette, it's Christmas.
♪ Merry Christmas, Chloe...
Can you repeat?
I didn't hear.
♪ Merry Christmas, Chloe.
Chloe, Christmas Truce.
♪ Merry Christmas, Marinette.
But I hate you.
♪ Merry Christmas to all.
Adrien's bodyguard?
The gift.
Be right back.
I can't believe it.
The gift.  Where did I put it?
It can't be real.
Here.
Thank you, Tikki.
Sir!  Wait!
Please, it's-it's, um...
A gift for Adrien.
Can you wish him a Merry Christmas from me?
I mean er, to you too.
By the way, Merry Christmas.
Sir, from-from me...
I hope Adrien will have a Merry Christmas.
What do you think, Nathalie?
You think he'll like all these decorations?
Why isn't he coming?
Did you call him?
Maybe he needs...
some time.
What's the point of all this?
He's not coming.
That's nice.
I wish you both a Merry Christmas.
Yes?
I can imagine how hard it must be, sir.
But consider that this is
Adrien's first Christmas without his mother.
I sincerely think-
I know, you're right.
I will talk to him.
Give me just a moment, I'm coming.
Even on Christmas,
he only thinks about himself.
I want to be done with this blasted day.
I hate holidays.
Plagg, transform me.
♪ The city lights up, yes it's Christmas in Paris.
♪ But I'm all alone in the night...
♪ Family reunions and dazzling gifts,
♪ a Chat Noir all alone tonight.
♪ I too am dreaming of warmth and tenderness.
♪ But I roam alone like a cat, in the night.
♪ I'm a poor kitty, why does no one pity me?
♪ Chat Noir's feeling so lonely tonight.
♪ If I stray, if I get lost, what does that matter?
♪ After all, I'm just a cat in the night.
♪ Your tree despairs me, I'll blast it to ashes.
♪ I'm the vengeful cat of the night.
♪ Cataclysm!
I can't...
♪ Being alone in this cold
♪ doesn't do me any good.
♪ Brooding over my anger,
♪ it didn't do anything.
♪ I'd like to go away,
♪ get back to my home.
♪ It'll be better tomorrow,
♪ I know it.
Let's go back home.
Plagg, detransform me.
Plagg?
Plagg!
♪ I'd like to help you,
♪ yes, help you transform.
♪ But take a look at me,
♪ I can't help it.
♪ I'm tired, my stomach is starving.
♪ I'm exhausted,
♪ I can't go on anymore.
Plagg!  What have I done?
Wait, wait, I'll help you.
"Merry Christmas,
signed Marinette."
She's so nice...
We're gonna get you back up
on your paws, Plagg.
You hear that?
Merry Christmas, Plagg.
Merry Christmas, Adrien.
Adrien?
Adrien!
Find him immediately,
immediately!
Good evening, I..
Yes, thank you,
Merry Christmas to you too.
No ma'am, he's not at my place.
Adrien isn't home?
Maybe he was kidnapped.
Don't worry Sabrina,
we're gonna find your friend quickly.
A kidnapping,
maybe that's a little exaggerated.
Let's go check the neighborhood
anyway, presents can wait.
You coming,
Marinette?
Erm, I don't feel to good...
I'm just gonna wait for you guys here
and if I have news, I'll call you, okay?
We have to find Adrien.
Quick!
Tikki, transform me.
Don't worry Plagg,
I'll find you food.
I can't promise you Camembert, but...
No need to throw a tantrum,
Santa has a gift for every kid.
Your presents are lame.
And your beard is ugly.
Hey, easy kiddo.
I'm sure you're not even
the real Santa Claus.
Hey, that's enough,
what's gotten into you, kids?
Aren't you ashamed
to lash out on Santa Claus?
This young man is right.
Apologize right now.
Sorry, Santa Claus...
It's not a big deal, kids.
Have a Merry Christmas anyway.
Sorry sir, is everything alright?
Don't worry,
I'm an old tough Santa Claus.
But, and you?
What are you doing out a this time?
Did you get lost?
Dressed like this, you must be cold.
Do you want a cup of
hot chocolate?
I have some left.
With pleasure, sir.
There's nothing better.
Except maybe, a piece of camembert...
You're lucky, kid, I have some left from my lunch sandwich.
I've never had one with such a strong smell.
This cheese is perfect.
To each their own.
You're not lost?
It's my first Christmas
without my mother, sir.
My father, he...
He doesn't know how to deal with it.
I understand, you know.
But your father must be
wondering where you are.
And worrying a lot about you.
Now that you got some fresh air
and thought a bit...
Don't you think it'd be good
to go back home?
You're right sir.
That's good.  A family reunited under
the tree, that's the spirit of Christmas.
I'll drop you off by sledge.
Come here, Plagg.
Alright, but wear this.
The friend who gave it to me
would be happy for you to have it.
A gift?
For me?
Everybody has the right
to have a Christmas present.
Thank you, my boy.
♪ There's only one power
♪ that can do so much damage,
♪ Chat Noir's cataclysm,
it's for sure.
♪ And this Christmas card,
♪ it didn't fall from the sky,
♪ but from the gift
♪ I gave to Adrien.
♪ Adrien disappears and
♪ then Chat Noir appears.
♪ He must be trying
♪ to protect him.
♪ The only explanation
♪ to these questions,
♪ is that a supervillain
♪ wants to harm Adrien.
♪ He can count on me,
♪ I'll get him out of there,
♪ For he's the one
♪ I secretly love.
♪ I'll do all I can,
♪ to help you the best I can.
♪ You're the one I
♪ secretly love.
♪ Even if I have to hide,
♪ I'll be by your side.
♪ You're the one
♪ I secretly love.
♪ But what would you do,
♪ if you were to know the truth?
♪ That's why I love you, secretly...
Who could even get akumatized
on Christmas Eve?
Footprints...
And you, sir?  Where are you going to
celebrate Christmas?
Me?  Well, everywhere in Paris.
The entire world, even.
You're all alone, huh?
Listen, here's what we're gonna do.
Get me back and
stay at our place for dinner.
Help me bring back the
Christmas spirit, sir.
Well, Okay, but I won't be able to stay long.
It's that I have a lot of work
on Christmas Eve.
Thanks, Santa.
Adrien?
It's you?
And you, who are you?
Well, it's obvious, no?
I'm Santa Claus.
Of course.
And me, I'm the Easter Bunny.
Aren't you ashamed to bother us
on Christmas Eve?
Get lost or I'll send by bodyguard.
Father, you're mistaken.
No, he's right.
Your father saw through his plans.
This man is a supervillain
under the Papillon's hold.
Wh-What?
You've all lost your minds.
No, Ladybug.
Stop!  This man isn't akumatized.
I know how to recognize an akumatized.
Trust me.
Go back home, it's safer.
No, wait.
Adrien.
Plagg.
Go ponies, hup hup!
Are you crazy,
what's gotten in to you?
Without realizing it, you just gave me
a wonderful Christmas present, Ladybug.
A poor innocent wrongly accused.
And the spirit of a scorned holiday.
It's all my akuma needs...
...to darken this heart.
Adrien?  Where are you going?
To my room, of course.
Since my father doesn't want to celebrate Christmas.
You're wrong.
Your father came to see you,
but you were out.
I'll tell him you're waiting for him.
But this time, we'll make sure
you stay in your room.
You-
You aren't a supervillain?
Of course not.
You read too many superhero stories, my dear.
I'm sorry,
I really thought-
Don't touch me.
You've done enough as it is.
No one respects
the spirit of Christmas now days.
They don't believe in me anymore.
I believe in you.
My dear Bother Christmas,
I am the Papillon.
They wrongly accused you of
being a supervillain.
In that case,
that's what you'll be from now on.
In return, since I was good all year,
I'll ask for not one, but two presents.
Ladybug and Chat Noir's Miraculouses.
And you'll have them.
Merry Christmas to you, Papillon.
Ladybug!
♪ You think I'm going to accept
♪ you mocking me?
♪ You think I'm going to let you
♪ accuse me like that?
♪ I am Bother Christmas.
♪ Wonderfully cruel.
♪ I'm gonna scare you stiff.
♪ It'll be an awful Christmas for all.
Santa Claus?
Not quite.
♪ I am Bother Christmas.
♪ Wonderfully cruel.
♪ I'm gonna scare you stiff.
♪ It'll be an awful Christmas for all.
Don't worry, Adrien.
I won't do anything to you.
I owe you.
You gave me a gift
and I won't forget it.
On the contrary,
I'll avenge you, even.
Avenge us both.
No, wait!
It'll be the revenge Christmas.
Plagg, transform me.
It looks like Santa Claus came by,
my dear Chloe.
I wish you all an awful Christmas.
♪ I am Bother Christmas.
♪ Wonderfully cruel.
Hey, my presents!
♪ I'm gonna scare you stiff.
♪ It'll be an awful Christmas for all.
I wish you all an awful Christmas!
It's you and me, Bother Christmas.
You and us, My Lady.
Chat Noir?
Where were you?
And what happened to Adrien?
It's...
It's a long story.
Cats have their little secrets too.
Who's gonna deliver the kids their presents
to night, Bother Christmas?
All that is ancient history.
Farewell presents and Christmas spirit.
You should have been nice.
I was nice all year.
Obviously not enough.
I got you.
How about a little ride in the sledge,
little elves?
Hang on tight!
Here we go!
It's not like that he'll get his sledge license.
It's time to open your presents, kids.
I'll take care of the sledge.
I'll leave Santa to you.
Whoa, easy there.
Thank you so much.
Ladybug!
It's happening again.
Ladybug?  Chat Noir?
That's one Christmas scoop.
A little word for my Ladyblog?
Oh, erm, no no, it's not what it looks like.
No, wait.
I have another idea.
Lucky Charm!
Oh, top notch.
With that, for sure,
it's in the box.
I'm gonna need tape, scissors,
that kind of stuff.
You have that here?
Up there.
Here too.
Here.
My Christmas list.
Run by the Dupain-Cheng bakery
and bring me this.
We'll meet at the Eiffel Tower.
I'll explain everything there.
I've always dreamed of being your Santa.
Don't worry.
Everything will go back to before.
Good luck, Ladybells.
It's me?
♪ Bother Christmas,
♪ this time it's settled.
♪ We give up, you won.
♪ No one to come rescue us,
♪ we give you our Miraculouses.
♪ But before that.
♪ We have a gift for you.
♪ For, on Christmas Eve,
♪ even you, you have a right to it.
A present?
For me?
Don't listen to him.
It has to be a trap.
♪ You scare us so much.
♪ You're so cruel.
♪ But we all have the right to a present
♪ on Christmas Eve.
Merry Christmas!
Cataclysm!
Merry Christmas, My Lady.
Thank you, Kitty.
You've done enough harm, little Akuma.
I'm freeing you from evil.
Gotcha.
Bye-bye, little butterfly.
Miraculous Ladybug.
Good job.
Ladybug.
Chat Noir.
you can very well have a Merry Christmas.
We'll see next year who
will have the best presents.
Adrien.
I can't accept you disappearing too.
I couldn't bear losing you.
You have visitors.
I took the liberty of informing them
that Adrien was safe and sound, sir.
They were worried for their friend.
Please, Father, it's... it's Christmas spirit.
Very well.
Come in.
Merry Christmas, Adrien.
♪ Merry Christmas to all.
Merry Christmas, mom.