The forensic service is here,
hurry up.
She bled yet...
It's so clean.
(Episode 19: No one knows)
I won't buy back the company.
There's no one left by my side
who can run the company.
Then I have no choice but to sell
it to a different group.
You should go back home, Mr. Ahn.
What a sad life.
I...
Died.
(The day after Park Bok-ja's death)
Detective Lee.
We checked with the security company.
They said someone voided
their contract 15 days before.
Who voided it?
It says Park Joo-mi.
Park Joo-mi?
It's the oldest daughter-in-law.
So we can't check the security
camera footage?
She's definitely been murdered.
But what's up with this will?
This is her call records from
her cellphone company.
Park Joo-mi is the last person Park
Bok-ja talked to before she died.
Before that, Park Bok-ja spoke to Cheon
Bang-soon for a minute and 30 seconds.
She's accused of stealing
by Park Joo-mi.
The last text message in her inbox
says, "Mrs. Cho's daughter is"
in a hospital in Gyeonggi-do."
Mrs. Cho?
The one who ran away?
Who sent the text?
Here.
Here, Pungseok-jung.
Pungseok-jung?
Oh, welcome!
Let's talk for a bit.
Park Bok-ja came and ordered the pufferfish
porridge personally for Mr. Ahn?
Yes.
Father did really love pufferfish porridge
from here.
He never had any problem from it.
But why did he have such a serious
stomach issue from it this time?
He could've died if things
got any worse.
I'm sorry for what happened.
I thought I was careful when I was
making it.
You expect me to believe that?
What kind of a place is Pungseok-jung?
You don't even accept money for food if
there's even a piece of fish bone.
However...
You didn't get rid of poison in pufferfish
and made porridge out of it?
And it was a mistake?
Ma'am.
Were you really trying to kill Park Bok-ja?
What are you saying? I...
I don't mess around with food.
You didn't think Mr. Ahn
would eat it, right?
You didn't know that he came back.
Is our conversation being
recorded right now too?
Go and give a thorough testimony
at the police station.
Otherwise, I'll make sure the entire world
knows that you've been selling
every information about people
who live in Gangnam.
Ma'am, please don't!
That'll be the end of me.
Why'd you do such a thing?
I just...
I just wanted to make her suffer a little.
I know how much poison it takes
to kill someone or just cause
a bit of a stomach.
I just wanted to show her.
"If you mess with me, you can
get hurt,"
was the warning I wanted to give her.
It's the only type of power I have.
Ah-jin.
Are you suspecting me too?
I was going to live like
a good and kind person.
But always!
Something bad always happens.
It's the food from Pungseok-jung.
She's been recording all the conversations
the maids of Gangnam would have.
That's what Park Ji-young said to
Woo Ah-jin via text.
Recording? No way!
Many different types of people
go in and out of that place,
it's a ridiculous speculation.
You should come and investigate
for yourself.
We'll just leave it at that then.
You made pufferfish porridge
for Mr. Ahn, and
a little bit of poison was found in it?
Yes.
But...
Park Ji-young isn't the one who
gave you the order?
Right.
Cheon Bang-soon gave a testimony
about that.
She said it must've been ordered
by Park Ji-young.
Why would she do such a thing?
Probably because once Mr. Ahn died,
Park Ji-young would get even more
of his possessions as inheritance.
Anyhow, I was never asked for
such a favor.
Last February 28th...
Where were you at the time of her death?
What do you think you're doing?
What?
You...
Were you trying to kill me?
You didn't die.
Mr. Ahn passed out after
eating that porridge of yours.
Mr. Ahn ate it?
What do you think is faster, to tell people
that someone ate your food and passed out?
Or that you've been recording all the
conversations about people
of Gangnam? That you've been
eavesdropping?
Or...
Tell everyone both of those things,
one stone with two birds?
I'm not sure how powerful some of
your clients are...
But you've been using them to
get out of trouble so far.
You must know someone really high up
to dodge a tax evasion investigation.
But it's all over.
Go turn yourself in to the police.
Before I call the police first.
You didn't know that one of my clients
is the head of all the prosecutors?
I'll make sure to mention that too,
so the head prosecutor will be in
a difficult position as well.
An illegal establishment that's been
dodging paying taxes is involved
with the head prosecutor?
Last February 28th...
Where were you at the time of her death?
I was sleeping at home.
Eat it with ramen you guys work
overnight shifts.
Hey, take this with you! You can't
give me stuff like this.
Man, what is this?
Ahn Tae-dong was not at the hospital
at the time of Park Ji-young's death.
I met with the nurse there.
What?
It says that you were in the emergency room
at the time of Park Ji-young's death.
You had fainted after eating
a pufferfish porridge.
That's how it's recorded.
Yes.
Did you think Park Ji-young gave you
that porridge on purpose?
Yes.
Then...
You must've been very angry.
To the point I wanted to kill her.
So then?
I woke up at a hospital.
So...
Kim the Driver, it's me.
I need to get home.
Come to the hospital at once.
So I went to the hospital, but
Mr. Ahn wasn't there.
I looked for him for a long time.
Mr. Ahn!
Mr. Ahn! I'm here, where are you?
He said he'll just stay
at the hospital.
So I just returned home after.
I'm at the hospital.
Just go home.
Father.
Why do you think she did it?
Why did she try to kill me?
It's not like that.
She was trying to protect you, actually.
(The day of Park Bok-ja's death)
We need to talk, now.
Ah-jin.
Are you suspecting me, too?
I see.
I...
I did come here to seduce Mr. Ahn.
I planned it all out to approach him,
and I came to this house
following that plan.
In my entire life...
When would I...
Live in such a nice and fancy house?
When I was little,
we were incredibly poor.
We'd eat dukbokgi after
leaving in it in the water for a while.
When you put it in water,
dukbokgi that was only this big
would get this big.
I really...
Wanted to live like a normal human being.
Live a fancy and rich life.
Say boldly whatever I want to say.
Show off to people about my life.
Ride in a nice car.
Be mean to people at times.
Why must a person...
Live like a cow or a pig?
Why should people be born with
their level of class seared on their backs?
For me...
I just wanted to erase it.
The seared mark of the level of class.
It was already yours even if you
didn't run away with it.
Why did you run away then?
I thought someone might steal it from me.
In my entire life...
People always stole from me.
Even my parents.
God stole them from me.
I was kicked out even after
I was adopted.
I never stole anything but...
people would blame me for it.
My life was full of misfortune,
one after another.
That's why I ran away.
I was afraid someone might
steal it all from me again.
But I did feel bad about Mr. Ahn.
His children...
Only think of their old father
as a bag full of money.
That's why I...
This time, I...
I wanted to take care of Mr. Ahn
and live a good life with him.
But...
But then...
I thought she fed me that
to kill me.
I thought all she wanted was money.
I thought she was after my inheritance
after I die, that she only saw me
as a bag full of money.
Father.
She doesn't wish for your death.
Then it is possible that it was all a part
of Park Bok-ja's plan to
kill Mr. Ahn and take all his possessions.
No.
She has no reason to do so.
What do you mean?
She signed a prenup before
she married Mr. Ahn.
It's clearly stated there.
In case of Mr. Ahn's death, she gives up
all rights as the legal heir.
There's nothing for her to take
if he were to die.
Was Ahn Tae-dong aware of that fact?
He didn't mention anything like that
during his testimony here.
He learned after.
I forgot all about this.
I forgot this even existed.
Mr. Ahn was not at the hospital
at the time of Park Ji-young's death.
Only people with legitimate alibis
are just you two, you and Ahn Jae-suc.
The first person who reported
Park Bok-ja's death was Cho Gyung-ja.
She went by "Mrs. Cho" at your home.
Yes.
We got her testimony, and she is under
a theft charge, separately from this case.
But she brought back all that she took.
Did you check what she brought?
Yes, I've checked.
I'm sorry, Ma'am.
I have nothing to say.
Why did you do such a thing?
My daughter is sick, and I needed
money.
I was told that your family
is now ruined.
It just happened.
I apologize.
Then why did you come back?
Park Bok-ja called the hospital
my daughter is in.
She said she'd pay for the hospital
fees, and asked me to come back.
She said all will be forgiven
if I just come back.
That's why I came back here.
But...
Please take good care of Father.
- I'll get going.
- Ma'am.
But...
I have something to tell you.
Is that true?
Yes. I saw her.
I clearly saw her.
Did you tell the police?
No.
Why didn't you?
It's just...
Should I?
I'm sure it's not her.
Woo Ah-jin and Ahn Jae-suc must have
alibis at that hour.
Yes, legitimate alibis.
(One hour before Park Bok-ja's death)
What are you doing?
Go and help her!
I can help her?
I guess it's up to you.
But in the eyes of a third-person,
it's the right thing for you to do.
You're not a third-person here,
you're a second-person.
If I'm the second-person,
are you the first-person?
Wait, are you talking about you and me?
Ah-jin.
Don't be so distant, you feel
like a complete stranger these days.
Mr. Ahn Jae-suc, pack your bags and
leave first thing tomorrow.
But the third-person is leaving!
Then the first-person, me, and
the second-person, you, should stay!
I can't believe this, how can you
be so thick-skinned?
Don't you know that I never take back
what I say or revert my decisions?
Don't be like this, Ah-jin.
Go!
Are you OK?
Hold on a second.
But it's because of my wife you get to
have an exhibition in New York and stuff.
Don't hate me too much.
You're a piece of trash.
What? Trash?
You...
You were just playing with me,
weren't you?
You were just trying to
get me into bed.
That was all, wasn't it?
What do you take me for?
I'm letting you go like this because
I have to protect my family.
But my feelings for you were true.
I did love you.
What?
Love?
I don't believe this.
You're the most selfish bastard
in the whole world!
You love me and you love
your wife too?
You should've been born into a noble
family centuries ago.
I know, right?
I did come to the conclusion that
I don't fit this modern era.
It's all my fault.
I'm sorry.
You...
Let me just hit you once.
What?
You're bleeding.
Not there...
It's from your nose.
Nose bleed?
I never got a nose bleed
from anyone before!
Do you know how much I hate
violence?
What is this...
My life is ruined!
I can't believe I used to
like a guy like him.
A guy like him...
This is why my love for you
grew cold!
I hate violent women the most!
I'm bleeding!
I've never even donated
blood before!
But why do you keep saying that
she's the one who did it?
It's this case itself...
It's very strange.
It's all tangled.
It's strange that she's still so involved
in that family matter after her divorce.
That's no reason to suspect her.
I just... Feel that way.
You spread the wanted flyer
for Gu Bong-cheol?
And asked other departments
to help?
Yes, of course.
But what about Cheon Bang-soon?
Why did she call Park Ji-young first?
She asked for money, but Park Ji-young
refused.
How much did she ask for?
I forgot to ask.
There's a lot more to go over still
about that woman.
Cheon Bang-soon.
Come out, it's time for your investigation.
You're put under arrest because
you might run away.
But why only me?
She ran away too.
How about Mrs. Cho?
She gave back all that she stole.
She'll still be punished, but she's
just not put under arrest.
What did you talk to Park Ji-yong about
when you called her last?
I already told you.
I asked for money.
How much did you ask for?
A million dollars.
A million dollars out of nowhere?
What's that based on?
Where the heck are you?
You should turn yourself in
before the police finds you first.
Give me money.
I'm gonna tell everyone you used
to work at a bar.
You took 75 million dollars and took off?
I think you can give me at least
a million dollars.
What did you tell me when you
brought me into this?
You said I won't feel sorry for this.
Hey, Cheon Bang-soon.
I knew you'd be like this, that's why
I threw you away.
You're gonna tell people that I
worked at a bar?
Sure, do as you wish.
You need to clean out your past
completely if you want to
move up to the high class.
You're gonna live the rest of your life
as a former bar hostess?
You think people will believe that?
You don't know how great money is.
All the truth and lies you say...
Money can resolve all of them.
You just don't know because you never
had any money.
Cheon Bang-soon.
It's very possible that
you'd be in jail for libel.
Park Bok-ja! I'll never forgive you!
Come back and bring all the stuff
you stole.
Then I'll forgive you.
I'm home now.
I came back.
So...
You went back there?
No.
I didn't go back there.
Why not?
Just...
I just didn't trust her anymore.
Aren't you sad that Park Ji-young's dead?
If no one else killed her,
I would've.
Why?
She's just...
Nothing, she's nothing in the world.
But she'd show off so much!
She used to pour drinks for the customers
at the bar and sold her body too.
She was that girl, Cho-hee.
She's no different from me.
What if you did go back home?
What do you think Park Ji-young would've
done with you?
What a fool.
You shouldn't have followed me here.
It's me.
I came back home.
I'll pay you for all the jewelry
Cheon Bang-soon stole.
Drop your suit against her.
I'm on my way to the police station
to give my testimony.
Your phone rang several times.
The police ordered me to come in.
Don't dodge it, they'll suspect
you even more.
- I'll talk to them first.
- I'm thinking about it.
I'm thinking about how to testify.
What do you mean?
Should I start lying about the fact that I
went to her hotel room to take her money?
Where do I start? I'm not so sure yet.
She's already dead, it doesn't
matter.
Say whatever you want.
How about Father?
Is he doing alright?
Let's go back home. It's our home again.
She's dead now.
So you're saying... You came back home
from your mother's, and Park Ji-young
was back?
Yes.
There's a record of you and Park Ji-young
talking on the phone before she died.
What did you talk about?
She just told me that she'd pay for
the jewelry Cheon Bang-soon stole.
Where and with whom were you
at the time of her death?
I was with my husband.
You reported him missing.
I did.
But I got in contact with him a few
days before she died.
Where had Jae-gu been that whole time?
Hunting is his hobby.
He said he was at a cabin
he frequents while hunting.
Then...
Where is Ahn Jae-gu now?
It's a members-only resort
called "Leo."
My family members take a break from
time to time here.
Then...
Where's Ahn Jae-hee?
Who is it?
It's me.
Why did you come here?
Jae-suc told me where you were.
Why are you looking like this?
Jae-gu... I'm terrified.
I'm so scared!
Scared about what?
- What do I do?
- About what?
I...
- Saw it.
- Saw what?
The murderer!
What?
That day...
I dozed off for a bit upstairs.
I was thirsty, so I went downstairs.
But...
There...
I saw Park Bok-ja dead!
Mrs. Cho was standing there before.
I got so scared, and I ran away.
So...
It was Mrs. Cho who killed her?
Yeah.
What do I do?
I better tell the police, right?
Of course.
But...
I already lied about being there
at that hour.
Really? Why'd you lie?
I just didn't want them to suspect me.
Cho Gyung-ja, the first person who saw
Park Bok-ja dead, called the police
at 9:17 AM.
That's when Ahn Jae-hee happened to walk
downstairs to find Cho Gyung-ja.
Yes.
And Mrs. Cho mistook Ahn Jae-hee
for the murderer from seeing her run.
These two are testifying that each other
is the murderer.
At the time of Park Bok-ja's death, Cho
Gyung-ja was at her daughter's hospital.
She has a clear alibi.
- And Ahn Jae-hee?
- She was home.
She was the only one home when
Park Bok-ja died.
- But then?
- She lied and said she wasn't.
She's not making any sense, she said that
she saw Cho Gyung-ja, yet
she wasn't home.
All the children are a little strange.
I feel like that's why the father gave all
his possessions to the caregiver instead.
The oldest son hasn't come in yet?
He said he's coming in soon.
Let's get the murderer quickly.
Who do you think it is?
But...
We found this will.
We compared it to Park Ji-young's
handwriting, and she didn't write it.
We also looked through her belongings.
We found this in her wallet.
The handwriting on the will is the same
as the handwriting on this note.
What is this, and what is this?
You're going to be
in the fourth grade soon?
Yes.
You said the new house is closer
to your school?
Yes, Grandpa.
I can even walk to school.
That's so nice!
Grandpa.
Yes?
You changed a lot.
Changed? I did?
Yes.
How?
You got younger than before,
and you speak more nicely too.
Your face looks brighter too.
You don't yell anymore either.
- Me?
- Yes.
I'm glad to hear that, it makes me
feel good.
You've been this way
since you met... Grandma.
Let's go, Ji-hoo.
Father, we'll get going now.
Please take care.
Ah-jin.
Yes.
Give her a nice funeral.
You should come.
I'm not.
Ji-hoo, can you stay in your cousin's
room for a bit?
OK.
Someone from our family killed her.
I did so many things wrong.
Please don't say that.
I killed her.
It's the same as if I killed her myself.
I can't lift up my face and watch
her go at her funeral.
Take care of her alone.
OK.
I will do as you say.
Live a good life.
I was thankful for you.
Though I'm now a stranger to Jae-suc,
I'll come and visit you.
I was happy.
I was happy while I lived with her.
I see.
Yes, you were.
I know.
You know, life...
Now that I lived to be this old...
It's just about eating what you
want to eat,
going to places you want to go,
and meeting people you like to meet.
That's all there is to it.
It makes you angry if you can't,
and makes you feel good if you can.
And you just get old throughout
the process, that's life.
While I was living with her, I was...
I was happy.
But where's the young grandma?
Did she go somewhere?
Yes, she did.
To where?
- Overseas.
- Overseas where?
You're gonna attack me
with all these questions now?
Overseas where?
- France.
- France? Why?
She wanted to study art.
Study art?
Yeah. Her dream is to be an artist.
Ah, I see.
I knew it, she just had that vibe.
Hm? What do you mean?
Have you seen her eyes?
Her eyes?
A person's eyes cannot lie.
Her eyes were... How can I say it...
Her eyes were always dreaming something.
Dream?
Dream...
Desire.
What is the difference between
a dream and a desire?
Maybe the kid is right.
Maybe...
I should've just kept dreaming.
If I ever get to be born again,
I want to be a painter.
You're leaving from Ah-jin's place?
Yes.
It's OK for artists to be a little
promiscuous.
I just had a problem with the fact that
it involved someone I'm close to.
First check the guy's social life
before starting dating your next guy.
It's a small country.
Maybe it'll get a little bigger
after North and South Korea unify.
Before that happens, everyone
knows each other somehow.
You need to prepare for your exhibition.
Yes, how many paintings are needed?
I need to talk to Ah-jin about that.
You heard Park Bok-ja's dead?
Yes, I gave my testimony and proved
Ah-jin and Jae-suc's alibis.
Try painting that, "death."
I think that exhibition will change after
this year into a bi-annual event.
It'd only show really colorful paintings
about hope and vision and things.
Rather than a utopia, try depicting
a dystopia.
Try that direction instead.
Would such a dark concept work
for the exhibition?
"War II" was the most impactful painting
you produced.
Isn't it inspiring? "Park Bok-ja's death."
She had a very sad life.
I always felt bad for her.
She did taste a moment of bliss
before she died.
But her festival was so short.
Someone dies.
And that death just becomes
someone else's topic of gossip.
But if my death can become
a painting...
Life can be so ironic.
Yet there's something so consistent
about it.
Five compasses...
Where's my will?
Your will?
Yeah, it's this thing...
Ah-jin.
Here.
It's pretty, isn't it?
Yes, it came out really well.
It's sad that it came out so pretty.
It's now sewn yet, but I guess
she never got to wear it.
She'd look good in it.
Daesung Pulp has been bought
by Gangil Group today.
Daesung Pulp was sold as soon as
its vice chairperson received
all the stocks from the founder, Ahn
Tae-dong, last year.
It had gained much public attention
because of it.
But as Park Ji-young was murdered
last February 28th,
there are many questions left
unanswered.
The police said that they found
solid evidence left at the scene of murder.
It also said that it's getting closer
to finding the murderer.
It seems that the murdered struck
her twice, which caused her death.
No footprints anywhere in the house.
No fingerprints or bodily fluids either.
Just the fingerprints of the family.
So a family member did it?
Someone who knew the front door pass code.
Someone who knew Park Ji-young as home.
And more than anything, the ones with
the clearest motive to kill are...
The family.
And...
The most conclusive evidence is this.
I think we have a suspect.
How was going to the police station?
It was fine of course, I gave
my testimony.
I hate going to the police station.
I'll distribute the money tomorrow.
I signed for 120 million dollars.
So 4 million dollars each.
Are you guys into something these days?
What's with the looks exchanged?
Are you guys dating?
Stop being ridiculous again.
I'm going to the bathroom, you can
have your secret talk now.
What happened?
The branch manager was so upset.
I guess Park Ji-young had friends
who were journalists.
She fed them information that
MK Capital swindled her.
I know.
We'd be in big trouble if we're caught!
They might kill us!
Why do I have to be so scared
just over 10 million dollars?
Let's split it 6 to 4.
Think about all the work I did.
You bastard, don't do this again!
I got blood on my hands!
Did you really...
Kill her?
It was you?
No, right?
People who've tasted money are not
ashamed about lies or deception.
And they never consider people's lives
more valuable than money.
(Transfer of corpse)
The body's been sent to Gangwon Hospital.
OK.
I hope you get through the funeral fine,
and I ask you to return here testify.
I understand.
With this dress, please.
We worry about being unhappy
while we are happy.
And we hope for happiness
while we are unhappy.
More than anything, we live our lives
desiring for something we do not have.
There's more sadness than joy.
A life is filled with pains that are
even greater than sadness.
But I should've been thankful
for life itself.
"Thank you."
"And I love you."
"The life I've lived and all those I got to
meet in my life..."
What is this will?
You went to look for Park Ji-yong at
Saint Palace Hotel last January 23rd.
Then you were stopped by her bodyguard.
Tell me what happened after that.
Park Ji-young felt unsafe from
unending threats from him.
So I took him somewhere else.
Why didn't you call the police?
My client didn't wish for it.
I only did what I was told.
Park Ji-young told you to do it?
Yes.
So?
Then what happened?
I explained it to him so he can
understand.
Then I let him go.
What?
That was also ordered by my client.
But that makes no sense!
Ahn Jae-gu's reported missing, no one
knows where he is!
He probably went hunting.
That's what he told me.
He said he's going hunting.
I don't understand this.
I'd think he would just go back
to Park Ji-young and threaten her again.
But Park Ji-young is the one who
told you to release him?
Yes.
Yes, Mr. Han.
I caught him and I put him
in a motel nearby.
That's good then, just leave.
It's their family's problem.
No need for us to get involved.
We just do what we need to do.
OK, got it.
Did you really go hunting?
Yes.
Why didn't you go back?
You didn't go back home nor did
you go back to Park Ji-young.
That's because...
I didn't want to pester Park Bok-ja
anymore.
That's all, just...
I just felt like nothing mattered anymore.
Around 2 AM on February 28th,
you were with your wife at Leo Resort?
Yes.
I checked all the security camera
footage that day.
But unfortunately, there was no footage
of your going into your room that day.
I stayed in my room starting the 24th.
I never left the room since.
- Where were you that day?
- I was at Leo.
This...
Belongs to you, no?
It's the knife you used when you
attempted to kill Park Ji-young before.
You dropped it at the scene of murder.
You didn't realize it, right?
What?
This was found at the scene?
You had a deep hatred towards
Park Ji-young, who's now dead.
You planned to kill her many times!
But you failed each time.
You learned that she returned home.
And this was on top of how you
mistakenly believed that she tried to
poison your father to death.
I'm sure your hatred and anger toward
her were at their extreme.
After you killed her,
you immediately left the house.
Then you saw that there were muddy
footprints you left from the rain.
So you thought to clean them up.
Then...
You dropped this jack knife
at the front door.
What are you doing here?
Did you really...
Do it?
It wasn't me.
I wasn't in Seoul that day
on February 28th.
I was in Leo.
Boss, please pay me including
the 28th.
Do you think I killed her?
It's all done.
Good job.
Go to a sauna or something
and get some rest.
Whom do you think the police suspects
of killing her about now?
Why do you think I let Ahn Jae-gu go?
I wanted him to take care of Park Bok-ja.
That's why I let him go.
So he'll kill her.
But he did something else instead.
What did he do?
Did the funeral go well?
Yes.
What did you do with her belongings?
The things she wanted to have so badly...
I wanted her to take them with her.
The smell of leather's burning...
It was so terrible.
What a waste.
You burned such expensive things.
And...
I burned the last gift to send her.
What was it?
- You like paintings?
- I just like looking at them.
Especially because life is so tough.
When I look at paintings...
I feel like I'm being healed.
If I ever get to be born again...
I want to be an artist.
We found this from her belongings.
I wrote this.
What?
To explain...
It was homework for the members
at a mind-training class I'm in.
We were supposed to write a will.
But why was it in Park Ji-young's
possession?
I must've dropped it at that house.
Then...
Does this belong to you, too?
(Thank you for doing my laundry.
Please always be happy, wherever you are.)
It seems like an old note.
Yes.
It seems so.
So then...
You said you first met Park Bok-ja,
or Park Ji-young, when you
interviewed her as a caregiver.
But it was long before that, based
on our investigation.
You and Park Ji-young first met
in no other than...
The place where she was staying
as a long-term guest after
she ran off with the money.
It was that hotel.
You really can't remember?
Saint Palace Hotel.
The suite room.
I do... Remember.
But...
I'll be good from now on.
Do you believe me?
I do.
You...
I was always thankful for you.
Here.
I must've left it here, I've been
looking for it.
Hello.
I think I lost my wallet here early
morning of February 28th.
Can I check your security camera footage?
Not right now.
The boss has to approve it.
Can you come tomorrow morning?
Hello, Driver Kim?
I'm at the hospital.
Just leave.
(Woman of Dignity)
We must be destined to meet!
I love Matisse, too.
I do prefer Manet over Matisse.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have gotten her
into the house.
I'm sorry.
I introduced that painter to you.
I introduced that woman to Father, too.
That's not your fault.
It's the fault of the people
who made those choices.
There are things you can't help,
even though you know.
I liked her a lot.
I'm going to the police.
Blame everything on Park Bok-ja.
She's already dead!
Bong-cheol! Gu Bong-cheol!
You have an alibi?
My husband and I will prove
each other's whereabouts.
Joo-mi told me to kill her.
Why did it happen?
Let's do our best for them to consider
your extenuating circumstances.
Tomorrow... Is another day.