Hi, Joaquín.
Put Mom on.
Where is she?
I know, but where is she?
No, don't bother.
It's all right. I'll call her later.
No, don't wait for me.
I don't know, Joaquín.
Make yourself a sandwich.
I don't know.
Bread, ham, cheese...
Bye, Joaquín.
Bye.
"LA RAYA" AUTO REPAIR
"RENACIMIENTO" AUTO REPAIR
Good morning.
Excuse me.
Can you help me?
We're closed.
I crashed near here.
- Okay. Thanks.
- No problem.
"DON HEBER'S" AUTO REPAIR
Morning!
Good morning!
I didn't come to steal.
You can tell that to the cops.
Where's the phone?
Here's the cable...
Now where's the...?
...phone book?
Here we go.
Police, police...
I didn't come to steal.
I heard you the first time.
Police.
20, 20...
I crashed.
Where?
Near here, in the outskirts.
What kind of car?
A Nissan sedan.
How did you crash?
Into a post.
Are you all right?
The front or the side?
The front.
But the engine starts?
It's probably
the distributor harness.
Harness? Harness?
Let's make it 100 pesos.
No thanks.
I've already had breakfast.
Sica.
Okay. Let's look for the part.
Look, it's like a little box with a switch
and it has cables coming out of it
that connect to the distributor.
I'm going to lie down on the porch
because I get tired very quickly.
When you find it let me know
and I'll tell you how to install it.
Come on, Sica.
Here, boy. Let's go.
Sir.
"ALEX" AUTO PARTS
"OASIS" AUTO PARTS
"ORIENTE" AUTO PARTS
Do you have a harness
for a distributor?
What make is your car?
It's a Nissan sedan.
Do you know
what the distributor's like?
No. It's a harness.
It's like a little box with cables
and things poking out of it.
Sure. Hang on.
Can you wait 10 minutes?
The guy who knows will be back
in 10 minutes.
Do you think he's going to be
much longer, this guy who knows?
He should have been here by now,
but he'll definitely be back.
This is Fidel, my son.
Fidel.
Come on.
- I just need the part.
- Hop on.
I'll install it for you and you'll have
your wheels in five minutes. Come on.
See you in a bit.
I won't be long.
- See you.
It'll set you back 300 pesos.
300?
Yep, 300.
I was told 100 at a different shop.
Come off it, man.
The part itself is worth more.
But I don't have 300.
How much do you have on you?
112.
Can't you get another
100 pesos somewhere?
100 pesos and your car'll be
ready in five minutes.
Hello. It's Juan speaking.
Is Arturo there?
Yes, thanks.
Yes, thanks. We're fine.
I'll tell her.
Could you put
Arturo on, please?
Hi, Arturo.
Good, thanks.
Hey, could you lend me
a 100 pesos?
Yes, I'm near your house.
Okay. I'm on my way. Bye.
No, it's that way.
Wait here for me.
I'll be right back.
Hello.
Hi, honey, how are you?
Fine, fine, thanks.
Is Arturo in?
Yes, but... How's your mother?
Good, good, thanks.
And your brother?
Him too. Sorry,
but I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Sure. Go on in.
He's in his room.
Juan!
Are you all right?
Yes.
Oh, shit!
No way!
Come and take a look at this.
This is generation one...
and yours is generation two.
Come on.
Where are we going?
Where do you think?
To find the part.
Come on.
What about the part?
Have a look at this while I find it.
Shi Yan Ming.
Do you have the part or not?
He's a Shaolin monk.
There aren't many of those around.
Shaolin monks are a rarity.
And they're real special.
One in a million.
Or more like one in a billion.
Do you know him?
Shaolin Workout,
written by Shi Yan Ming.
Read it.
I'll get one of my own later.
Thanks.
Don't thank me now.
Thank me once you've read it.
Breakfast is ready!
Coming.
What about my part?
Oh, the part.
I said breakfast is ready!
Let's have breakfast and I'll find the part
for you when we're done.
Come on.
Don't you say grace
before you eat?
Amen.
Have you never heard
the word of God?
Mom.
David, please.
Behold I tell you a mystery:
We all shall not sleep;
but we shall all be changed,
in a moment,
in the twinkling of an eye,
at the last trumpet:
For the trumpet shall sound
and the dead shall be raised incorruptible,
and we shall be changed.
For this corruption
must put on incorruption
and this mortal
must put on immortality.
What do you think?
Can I use your bathroom?
Sure. Take your time.
You scared him.
The word of God
never scares.
Do whatever you like.
I don't do whatever I like;
I do His will!
Why can't you
leave people in peace?
You said it. In peace
is exactly how I want to leave them.
Where were you?
Out.
Are you going to watch the game?
I dunno.
Where's Mom?
Is she still in the bathroom?
You haven't cleaned up the yard.
Don't tell me what I have to do.
You promised him.
Mom.
Get out.
It's full of smoke in here.
Get out, Juan.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Now get out.
Mom.
Get the hell out!
Are you going to watch the game?
Hi.
He left the part for you.
Can I have it?
Can you hold him a minute?
What did you do?
Nothing.
No, keep him until he's asleep.
Then you can give him back to me.
You're going to wake him up.
No. We'll keep it low.
"I don't have time for anything
except fooling around.
I'm not the kind to live worrying...
...nah... nah. "
I used to sing in the school choir,
but I was good.
I wasn't the lead voice
or anything,
but I always say you don't need
a good voice to sing.
You need energy,
strength. Right?
I think he's fallen asleep.
Don't you want
to hear another track?
I have to get going.
Can you take him?
Thanks.
See you around.
Let me see.
This is the right one.
Do you know where
the distributor is?
Sica, settle down. Sica.
It's all right. I like dogs.
You like dogs?
Hey, could you
do me a big favor?
Could you take Sica for a walk?
I haven't been able to
take him out for a while.
I'm not up to it anymore,
but he needs exercise.
It's an active breed.
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Just once around the block.
Can't he go out on his own?
No. He doesn't like
going out on his own.
He's very attached to people.
Just say "Heel, Sica. "
Heel!
Heel, Sica!
Sica!
Haven't you fixed it yet?
What part is it?
The distributor harness.
Hey, what are you doing tonight?
Nothing.
Can I ask you a favor?
I know we've only just met,
but I feel I can trust you.
Could you babysit Fidel?
Sorry, I can't.
I've never seen anyone put him
to sleep the way you did.
I told you... Jessy Bulbo
is playing tonight
and I don't have anyone
to look after Fidel for me.
I took him to a Rata Blanca concert
a couple of months ago
and we nearly got crushed.
No?
Come on. Please?
Thanks anyway.
Open your eyes and look at me.
Don't be afraid, come closer to me.
Do you think he'll come?
Who?
David.
Yeah, sure thing.
Why did you run off like that?
Let's go.
I'll be back shortly.
See you.
Bye.
Kill it.
Try again.
Stop.
Come over here.
This is the part that's screwed,
not the distributor harness.
Is it expensive?
Yes, it's expensive.
What did I tell you?
Didn't the expert tell you I'd fix it?
"If you think something is impossible,
you will make it impossible. "
Bruce Lee.
Juan.
Cheer up!
Let's get out of here!
Try it now.
That's enough!
Try again!
Give your sensei a hug!
What did I tell you, bro?
Didn't I tell you I'd fix it?
I'm the guy who knows.
Thanks.
Hey, where do you
think you're going?
I have to get the car back.
No shit, man. I was going
to invite you to the movies.
I can't.
I have to get the car back.
You can take it back later.
"Enter the Dragon" is playing, man!
It's only playing today.
I can't.
Tough. If you change your mind,
it's on at the Meteoro at 7:00.
Okay.
Do you want a ride?
No. I have my bike.
Okay. Thanks.
You're welcome.
Have you eaten?
Cool! It's Dad's!
Do you like it?
Yeah.
It's for you.
Where did you get it?
Somewhere.
What's condolences?
Why do you ask?
People have been
calling all day,
and when I answer, everyone says
to accept their condolences.
Do you want a yogurt?
Fucking hell!
It's screwed.
Hang on.
Joaquín, answer that!
Don't.
For the love of God,
answer it!
Hello?
No, he's not in.
His son.
No, we're not interested
in a timeshare.
No, he can't come to
the phone right now.
He just can't.
Because he's fucking dead!
I'll be back in a while.
Where are you going?
Sica!
No.
Drive!
I said drive!
It's your dog.
Kick me!
What was that?
An exhibition?
We need emotional content.
Try again.
I said emotional content,
not anger;
now try again, with me.
That's it.
Open is war,
closed is peace.
You can sleep in my bed.
Do you have any brothers
or sisters?
Yes. Joaquín.
Well, look after him
as if he were your brother.
I won't be late.
As soon as it's over,
I'll be straight back.
Chemo? What's up?
Hey, it looks like I'm going
to be able to make it after all.
Can you pick me up?
What?
Yesterday?
Did you go?
I bet it was.
Tough luck.
Maybe next time.
Bye.
I'd better be going.
Do you want some?
OK then.
I'm home.
Did you fart?
You dirty pig!
No, don't go!
I'm not going anywhere.
Let's make hotcakes.
Like dad used to?
What's wrong?
I have to pee.
Then go pee.
OK, but don't eat them all.
I won't.
What are you doing?
That's mine!
What?
It's missing something.
Come with me.
We never took it off.
He hated the sight of it.
Ever since we stuck it on,
he hated it.
Do you remember
Lake Tahoe?
We never went
to Lake Tahoe.
Aunt Marta
brought it back for us.
It looks pretty in the picture.
I bet it is.
Come on. Let's go.
TO MY FATHER AND JONÁS