Dramatorrent.com
Come with me.
- Don't answer that. - Sorry?
Don't answer any calls.
What are you doing?
What else? You're mine,
so I'm marking you.
We're dating from today.
Hey.
How long were you there?
I'm going to tell Yuh Ri.
Hey. Hey!
(Mr. Son)
- Hello? - Moo Yul, are you home?
Is Yuh Ri home?
No. She isn't back from school yet.
Why are so many people looking for her today?
What do you mean?
Was someone looking for her?
Some wealthy looking lady came by earlier and...
Hello?
Mr. Son?
Joo Ho, your mom and I...
grew up in the same orphanage.
We endured the sorrows and loneliness of not having parents...
by being there for each other.
That's why...
you don't seem like a stranger...
since you're Joo Ho's daughter.
I had no idea.
My father never said.
Yuh Ri.
I have a favor to ask.
You are...
the only person in the world who can do it for me.
Can you do it?
Sure. Tell me what it is.
Yuh Ri.
My son Hae Sung...
Get out right now!
Father, how did you...
I'm sorry I couldn't take your call earlier.
- What happened was... - Get out right this instant!
Get out!
Go straight home and wait for me.
But Ms. Hong wanted to talk...
Didn't you hear me?
Okay.
What do you think you're doing?
How dare you take Yuh Ri?
What else could I do?
What parent wouldn't go crazy when her child is dying before her eyes?
How much did you tell her?
Don't tell me...
you told her everything.
I couldn't.
I was about to.
I wanted to beg, but I couldn't.
Ji Won.
Listen to me.
I...
can't help you.
I can't hurt my child in order to help yours.
I was your slave for 10 years.
But not my child!
So...
don't touch my baby.
Those 10 years weren't for free!
Your family was able to survive thanks to that.
You should repay us.
You should show gratitude!
Now, you sound like yourself.
You're finally showing your true colors.
You're right.
I survived on my salary that you and your husband paid me.
With that, I clothed Yuh Ri,
fed her, and was able to send her to school.
For that, I'm forever grateful.
As the chairman's driver,
I was his puppet, overseeing his personal life,
doing any disgusting task he asked of me,
and sometimes voluntarily obeying him.
In order raise Yuh Ri...
properly.
- Joo Ho. - Don't say my name.
You never once...
sincerely considered me your friend.
I won't give up.
I'm...
Hae Sung's mom.
I won't give up.
Yuh Ri.
Hey.
Shouldn't you be tutoring right now?
So many people were looking for you, but you couldn't be reached.
I was worried, so I rescheduled.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Yuh Ri!
Guess what? My brother...
and another girl...
Yul Mae, you've grown so tall.
I'd better work hard...
and make you grow more.
Come with me.
Father.
Listen to me.
Don't meet with anyone...
from Wid anymore.
Don't answer any calls.
Not Hae Joo, Ms. Hong, or the chairman.
Anyone.
What's wrong? Did something happen?
- What's with everyone today? - Do you understand me?
Yes.
Hae Sung has stabilized,
but you should get the donor's guardian's consent...
as soon as possible.
What's for dinner?
I'm craving meat.
Maybe it's because I'm in a good mood.
Should we go for steak?
- What? - You're in a good mood?
You're craving meat?
How can you think about food when Hae Sung's lying there like that?
Mom.
Your only sibling is barely hanging on,
fighting for his life.
How can you eat right now?
Should I starve because I feel bad for him?
Should I not breathe either?
Should we all die together?
Hae Joo!
Ever since he got sick, I'm invisible here.
You and Dad care only about Hae Sung.
Have you given me any attention recently?
Why are you taking it out on me? Like yesterday too.
You humiliated me and slapped me in front of Yuh Ri!
Is Hae Sung your only child? What about me?
Hey...
I needed to get on Yuh Ri's good side...
in order for Hae Sung to get the transplant, so I wasn't thinking.
- Don't get the wrong idea. - Don't you ever...
touch Hae Joo again. If you do,
I won't forgive you.
Are you suspecting me?
Do you think I hit her because I'm her stepmom?
If you do, I'm hurt.
You know how I've raised her until now.
After my baby died...
without ever feeling a mom's embrace,
Hae Joo...
entered my heart a few days later.
Mr. Koo. I've brought the documents you asked for.
Your ex-wife, the minister's daughter, left you and your baby...
because your mother wasn't your father's wife but someone...
he brought in to give him a child as his wife was barren.
That's when I first met Hae Joo.
Even when you proposed to me, I knew...
that what you needed wasn't me,
but a mom for Hae Joo.
But I did my best...
to you and to her.
And yet,
you're accusing me because I hit her once?
While my son Hae Sung, who took us 10 years to have,
is fighting to stay alive...
before even starting school?
That's enough!
You're overly sensitive.
There's something...
I want to confirm.
That baby that you had before marrying me.
Is that baby really dead?
If not, I would've found my baby somehow.
I refuse to watch another one of my children die again.
So I'll do anything...
in order to save Hae Sung.
So you find a way to convince Mr. Son,
regardless of the means.
(Police Station)
Wait.
Detective.
I wasn't trying to eat and run.
I forgot to get cash.
I just returned to Korea, so I was just out of it.
Detective. Look.
See? I have a credit card.
I wasn't trying to run.
Then you should've used that to pay. Why didn't you?
You should be ashamed.
How much did you eat all by yourself?
You look normal enough.
I have my reasons.
Hello. Thank you for your hard work.
I just received a call...
that Koo Do Chi was here.
Mr. Son.
- Mr. Son. - Do Chi!
- Do Chi. - Mr. Son.
Wow. You've grown so much.
It feels like only yesterday...
that you were crying and insisting you didn't want to go to the US.
I know.
That runny nosed, whining crybaby...
grew up already.
I'm sorry about back then...
for not being able to help.
That always bothered me.
It's so good to see you now.
That's right. Does the chairman know you're back?
No.
When I heard about Hae Sung,
I came to Korea to try to help as his uncle,
but he says there's no need.
He said he found a donor.
But still,
I got tested secretly just in case.
That's right. Just a minute.
I found it.
Ta-da. Congratulations.
Happy early birthday.
You and I have the same birthday.
Here.
Gosh.
I never would've expected this.
I'm so thankful.
I don't have...
anything for you.
You're thankful, right? In that case,
rather than a gift,
lend me some money.
What?
Well, I...
need to go to a hotel,
but my brother will know right away if I use my credit card.
That means...
I'll be on the next flight out.
How's your hand?
Did you take your medicine?
Yes. They said it'll heal soon. Don't worry.
You're not hurt anywhere else?
I'm fine.
Let's get surgery once you start college.
It looks bad.
I've had it since I was a baby, so I'm used to it.
I don't even notice it.
But how did I get this scar?
That was...
It was my mistake.
Sorry...
for not giving you a pretty, flawless body.
There you go again.
A scar like this is nothing.
That's right.
You know that painting you asked for last time?
I just need to redo the finishing touches.
But whom is it for?
Someone I want to cheer on,
saying the tide will come in someday...
just like that painting.
Enough.
Please disappear, Mother.
You need to disappear...
for me to live.
You and Do Chi need to be gone...
so that I...
can become the owner of Wid.
Do Chi.
Do Young!
I'm sorry.
I won't do it.
I'll never do it again!
Do Young!
I won't pee in my pants again.
So please let me see my mommy!
I want to go to my mommy's funeral too.
Do Young!
I want to go to the funeral.
I won't eat.
Take that out!
I'm sorry.
I should've been more understanding.
Please don't do this. I can't handle it.
Can't you stop punishing me?
I'll do anything you want.
Do you mean it?
You'll do anything I want?
Which one is prettier?
Let's ask my father
- Knew it. - Knew it.
We're so alike.
Wrap it nicely, please.
My future father-in-law will be wearing these.
- Are you going to the studio? - Yes.
I need to finish off a painting.
You're meeting your new tutoring student?
Yes. The professor strongly recommended me.
They're paying double my usual rate.
Plus, they asked for me by name.
You know I'm outstanding.
Naturally. You're my boyfriend after all.
Hey. Hae Joo.
How did you find me?
- Were you stalking us? - What about you?
Are you a puppy dog?
Why are you wagging your tail at my boyfriend?
Scram before I grab a pair of scissors and cut off your tail.
What? A dog?
Boyfriend?
Hae Joo.
If you're going insane, at least maintain your dignity.
Or wear a sign saying,
"I'm crazy," so that I can avoid you.
Moo Yul. Let's go.
Didn't you know?
We've kissed already.
Is that true?
It was against my will. She just...
Hae Joo.
Watch.
Let's kiss.
- Don't do it! - What are you doing?
Hey! Stop that right now!
All done.
Perfect.
Resist all you want, Moo Yul.
You're mine regardless.
One,
two, three.
Hello, I'm Kim Moo Yul, sophomore at Hangook University,
here on Professor Jang's recommendation.
We've met before.
My daughter insisted on you,
so I called Professor Jang myself.
Pardon?
Hi, First Love.
You...
Don't go.
Don't play games like this again. It's offensive.
Games? Who says I'm playing games?
I'm drawn to you.
How is this a game?
I like Yuh Ri,
and she likes me too.
So?
You look down on us, don't you?
You think you can step on us,
- disrespect us and insult us. - No.
I don't know about Yuh Ri,
but I don't look down on you at all.
So take a good look at me, Moo Yul.
What?
Look at who's standing before you,
and what I have behind me.
The students at your school, who are the top 0.1 percent,
strive to get a job at Wid.
Wid Construction. Wid Commerce.
Even Wid Foods.
I'm the Wid's only daughter.
So grab the opportunity while you can.
Your life will change in an instant.
You...
Are you intrigued now?
really are the worst.
Forget the tutoring.
- Doctor. - Hello.
The results are out for the person who requested to be tested.
The results? Who...
Get up.
Do Young.
How are you here?
The test results are out.
You are not a match for the bone marrow transplant.
You've completed your business here, so go back.
Wait a second.
I don't want to get physical again,
so leave quietly.
Do Young.
I want to live in Korea.
I want to live here with you,
Ji Won, Hae Joo, and Hae Sung.
In the land where Father and Mother are buried.
Even if I go to the US,
there's nothing I can do.
Shut it and do as I say. Go back!
Ta-da.
Happy birthday, Father.
This is your gift.
The one and only pair of sneakers in the world...
with a painting from the artist Son Yuh Ri.
Thank you.
Try them on.
You and Moo Yul wear the same size,
so he helped me.
They fit perfectly and they're comfortable.
Naturally. I picked them out after all.
- Happy birthday, Mr. Son. - What?
It's not much. It's a belt.
- Gosh. - Happy birthday.
You too?
Thank you.
You didn't forget, did you?
We're having a birthday party tonight.
Come home early. No drinking allowed.
Goodness. Fine.
I invited one other person.
Is that okay?
The more the merrier.
Is it the person the painting is for?
Yes. I'll see you later.
- Bye. - Bye.
(Letter of Resignation)
What's this?
I'm resigning.
I'm leaving.
Leaving? Where to?
I've decided to move already,
so I've put the house on sale.
I've decided...
to take Yuh Ri and live somewhere no one knows us.
Mr. Son.
How could you do this to us?
Will you really shun Hae Sung?
I'm sorry.
I won't forget your mercy in helping our family...
eat and survive.
You're a father too, aren't you?
You should know how we feel better than anyone.
I'll give you anything you want whether it's money or anything else.
How much do you want?
Just say the amount.
I'll make sure your family is set for three generations.
I won't use Yuh Ri...
to make deals.
Mr. Son!
As a father,
let me say one last thing.
The truth is,
my wife and I...
adopted Yuh Ri.
From the day we brought her home,
I never once thought she wasn't my child.
However, I can't tell her to give a part of her body to someone else.
I can't harm a single hair on her body.
The fact...
that she suffered so much...
emotionally and physically because of her loser father...
is bad enough.
In exchange, I'll find Ms. Hong's child...
as promised before I leave.
Don't bother.
Pardon?
I confirmed with Ji Won.
If the child was alive,
I wanted to see if the child was a bone marrow match with Hae Sung,
but she said she's sure the baby died.
Then...
you looked for that child...
only for Hae Sung...
Hello?
Yes, I'm Son Joo Ho.
Who's this?
I heard the baby died for certain.
It wasn't bad enough that she gave that baby a burn scar.
She left the baby on the cold floor in the dead of winter...
which killed the baby.
So she wailed, punching herself in the chest.
A burn scar?
The baby had a burn scar?
She dozed off while making formula...
and dropped hot water.
The baby's skin was so fragile...
that it created a scar along the neckline...
or shoulder.
She was so upset because of that.
A scar.
But how did I get this scar?
Do you know where she abandoned that baby?
She said it was where she grew up.
Love... Love Orphanage?
That's right. Love Orphanage.
Love...
Hong Ji Won?
It couldn't be.
Hello?
Is that Love Orphanage? Yes.
Where's the director, Mr. Cho Ki Chul?
Mr. Son quit and is moving away?
What were you doing?
Why are you letting him just leave?
You should've broken his legs if necessary to keep him here!
What do I do?
He wouldn't run off like this, would he?
I'll give Mr. Son the building in Nonhyeon-dong.
I'll give him money or whatever else will work.
If that still doesn't work,
I'll break his neck and bring Yuh Ri.
That's right.
Two babies were left at the orphanage that day.
Two babies?
It was the 10th anniversary...
of my becoming director of Love Orphanage,
so I remember clearly.
One of the babies...
froze to death.
Did that baby that died...
have a burn scar?
A burn scar?
I didn't see any.
Anyway, the dead baby's mother...
showed up a few days later...
and cried so much.
The baby's mother came?
Wait. Then...
Ji Won is not the mother of the baby that froze to death?
I don't know the details either,
but I think Ji Won mistakenly thought...
the baby that died was hers.
Later on,
when the real mother showed up, I wanted to clear up the mistake,
but I couldn't reach her.
Then I heard that she got married.
She married into some rich family, I think.
She didn't even know whose baby it was anyway.
I didn't want her to think about it, so I didn't tell her.
Even if she knew,
nothing would've changed anyway.
Mr. Cho.
Just a minute.
That means...
Yuh Ri really is...
Father!
I brought your favorite rice-cake cake.
Is he not home yet?
Who are you?
Madam Hong.
Where's your father?
He hasn't come home yet.
Are you home alone?
Pardon?
Are you all alone?
(Unknown Woman)
- You need to know something. - I don't want to hear it.
Mr. Son isn't picking up. Is he running late?
Yuh Ri is your daughter.
Your daughter that you abandoned at Love Orphanage!