Back in the '70s,
every cop wanted out of the city.
But the only cops allowed to live
outside New York were transit cops...
because the Transit Authority
was also run by Jersey and Connecticut.
So these guys I knew at the 3-7...
they started pulling overtime
at subway stations...
and got the city to declare them
"auxiliary transit cops".
They bought some land in Jersey.
Got some cheap loans from people they knew.
They made themselves a place
where the shit couldn't touch 'em.
Every precinct has its "cop bar"...
a private club, all blue.
For the 3-7, it was the 4 Aces...
just across the river.
So this Armenian guy,
he's from the other side over there.
He tells her that she's dead.
She's gonna be dead by morning.
- Right.
- So he drops this box off at her place.
They call you guys. They call Bomb Squad.
We go in there. We X-ray it on scene.
- And we can't see anything in there.
- Right.
I cut a little hole in it.
I can see there's something in there.
I see that there's some white fuzz.
There's something pink.
I can't figure out what it is.
Suddenly I realize
I am looking at a tongue.
- Shit!
- A big, fat tongue sticking out at me.
- No way.
- Yes. The guy put a goat's head in there.
This at the end of the 20th century.
I mean, HG Wells,
he'd turn over in his grave...
to think at the start of a new millennium,
some Iranian guy-
Armenian.
Some Armenian would be deliverin' a goat's
head to the door of the woman he loved.
- People are-
- Backward culture over there.
Let me tell you.
We're all backwards, Berta.
Our machines are all modern
and shit, but our minds?
Our minds are primitive.
Our minds are primitive, Berta.
Hey.
- I gotta go home, baby.
- Wait. I'm just waitin' on the call, okay?
Come here. Come here.
- I gotta pick up the car. This is not-
- Monica, sit down.
Excuse me. Do you mind?
- Do you mind?
- Sorry.
Roberta, that's Freddy.
Freddy's cool. Freddy's cool.
He's got a bad ear. He's good people
though. Don't worry about it.
You have no authority.
Yeah, yeah. Fine.
It's quiet tonight, huh, Freddy?
It's quiet.
Everyone's at that bachelor party
across the river.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Whoop-de-doo.
You got any quarters?
Don't look at me.
I just put two more in the goddamn meter.
- It's his birthday.
- Oh, yeah?
- He's going for high score.
- Happy birthday, Freddy.
Happy birthday. Let me see what I got.
I wasn't into making a big deal
after the 10-year thing.
Hey. How you doin'? Sorry, Freddy. Hey.
I was wondering
if you'd be able to come by.
Yeah. 4 Aces. Where else?
Shit!
Damn it.
Two kinds of people in this world.
Pinball people and video game people.
You, Freddy, you're pinball people.
- Always got somethin' to say, Figgsy.
- Come on.
Freddy, Freddy, Freddy.
Freddy! Freddy! Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
It's bedtime, Sheriff.
You all right to drive?
- You sure?
- Positive.
- Take it easy, Freddy.
- Take it easy.
It was not Lady Luck
that Jim Maloney found in Atlantic City.
It was the cops.
The 30-year-old native
of the Caribbean island of Antigua...
was captured in a casino
just days after an aspiring rap artist...
was fatally beaten
in a Queens convenience store.
Sources have filled in some of the blanks
for 1010 WINS saying Maloney-
Shit!
All right. Take it easy, take it easy.
- I apologize.
- Murray!
Magilla Gorilla, you fucking ape.
- Mikey, I'm out.
- Where're you goin'?
- I'm gettin' outta here. I love her.
- Yeah! Hangin' out in your apartment?
- Roger.
- Okay, Superboy. You're my man, Superboy.
- My man, Roger.
- Keep it up.
You guys take it easy. Davey,
can you dispose of this legally, please?
I don't like bachelor parties.
See you back in Jersey.
Shit!
Goddamn it!
Fuck.
Fuck!
Shit!
You have the fuckin' wrong stuff here.
- Jesus!
- Frankie?
Jesus Christ! What are you guys doin'?
You're giving me a heart attack over here.
Hey, Superboy, what do ya say, kid?
- You all right, Jackie?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Yeah? I'll see you guys tomorrow, man.
You're like creepers back here.
Thanks, kid. Be careful driving.
Giants leading it 10 to 6 as they move
to the bottom of the seventh inning.
In a game characterized by big rallies...
the Giants scored seven times
in the first inning off-
- Motherfucker!
- The Yankees lost to the Angels today.
Chili Davis hit two-run homers
from either side-
Hey!
Pull over. NYPD. Pull over!
Hey, you hear me? Pull over!
No!
Bang!
Fuck! Shit!
Fuckin' cocksucker!
Freddy?
Traffic incident? Bullshit!
Hey, what's up, man?
These guys were shot like six times.
Hey, just shut up, do your fucking job!
- Fucking nurse.
- What've you got?
I got four vials of crack here and a pipe.
That's it.
Russell, what you're thinking, swallow it.
The guy saved five babies
out in Red Hook, all right?
That's right, black babies.
Mashed potatoes don't mean gravy.
- I'm on the bridge.
- Is Babitch there?
- Yeah. I see him.
- Take care of it.
Uncle Ray?
- Uncle Ray, I saw a gun.
- Calm down.
I swear to God, he took a shot at me.
Tell 'em. They took a shot at me.
Stay right here with us, all right?
Tunney didn't even get the grand jury
for shit like this.
Fuck the GJ. You're Superboy.
You saved, what?
Six black babies?
Come on, kid, the shit plays!
- Three babies.
- One at a time, please.
I got PA on another channel,
the mayor's office, assistant DA.
Press up the yin-yang.
They're not here because we got gridlock
from across Bronx to the Palisades.
There's no gun.
You didn't see it, Jack?
You can't find it?
- Flaky.
- Listen, I heard a shot, Ray.
- I heard a shot. I saw a gun.
- In my trunk, in the grand union bag.
- I heard a shot, Leo. - The kid had
a steering wheel lock in his hands.
Your tire blew.
You're fucked up,
and you wasted a pair of shit-bags...
who aren't worth the hair
in the crack of your ass.
So you cool it
with the patty-cake morality.
Because without me, kid,
those stiffs'll put you in a room...
where you will fuck your uncle
and everything he's built.
Hey, Leo.
The black van's gonna be here in a minute,
and I haven't done shit!
- What I'm doing is highly-
- Sympathetic.
- Yeah, damn right.
- It is.
- Ray, we don't have to do this.
- Calm down.
Fuck, Ray!
Ooh, baby! Hey, we got it.
Look at that, huh? We got it!
- What the fuck are you doin', man?
- I found their piece.
- Found their piece?
- Jesus!
- That wasn't in there.
- It was underneath the floor mat.
- Bullshit, man. You can't do that!
- Man, come on.
- Shut the fuck up!
- It was underneath the fucking floor mat.
- What the fuck are you doing? Fuck you!
- Put it down!
I told you not to do it like this, Ray.
- We're just doin' our job, so calm down.
- I told you!
- It's a fuckin' Uzi!
- Take it easy. Hey!
You boys should take care
of your own business here.
Take my fuckin' shield away from me.
- Hey, put it down!
- What? You gonna shoot me?
- Put it down, Chico!
- Chico this, motherfucker!
- Frankie, Help me start it up.
- What the fuck you gonna do?
Kiss my ass!
Fuck!
Hey, Jack, Jack. Hey, hey.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Leo!
Leo! Jesus! He jumped!
Oh, my God! He jumped!
- He jumped!
- Murray?
Somebody shine a light down there.
He just hit the water,
and... he went down.
Davis? Where's Davis?
I want Aviation, I want Harbor.
I want some illumination now!
Stupid fucking kid!
Oh, my God!
We got a man over the fucking GW!
How long is the car gonna take?
Lenny won't know
till the parts guy gets in.
You should take number two.
What did you tell Lenny
about the accident?
- Chasin' a speeder.
- What?
Sheriff was chasin' a speeder.
Our top story on 1010 WINS:
A fatal shoot-out on the GWB
and a cop's suicide.
Harbor Patrol continues searching
the Hudson River for the body...
of Officer Murray "Superboy" Babitch.
Babitch leaped off
the George Washington Bridge last night-
Put it out.
an apparent suicide,
after engaging in a high-speed chase.
Fucking asshole.
There's no way that guy jumped, man.
There's no fucking way!
Controversy swirls
around events on the bridge.
Officer, how can you testify...
that Superboy jumped off that bridge
when you didn't see him jump?
I'm looking at your statement right here...
that you filled out at 0200 hours.
Wait a minute. I'm gonna object
because we went through this.
He's been up all night.
How many times are you gonna
ask the same question?
Let me ask you another question, brother.
Have you ever been to Garrison, New Jersey?
- What kind of question
is that, Lieutenant? - Counselor.
Have you ever been to Garrison, New Jersey?
- Those white boys on that bridge-
- Come on, Lieutenant.
- You think this is The Mod Squad?
- Please. I object to this!
I'm offended by this.
All right! All right, listen.
He doesn't tell us what we want to know,
he's gonna lose his job.
That's about as simple as I can make it.
He's gonna lose his fuckin' job. All right?
Do you want that?
What do you take us for?
A bunch of fuckin' morons?
- What is the matter with you?
- With all due respect, but I think-
- You be quiet! You be quiet! Shut up!
- I'm just saying- I believe-
If you don't mind my French, all right?
You be quiet.
He's off the force if he does not
start answering questions.
You want to save your ass?
Start giving us answers.
And I'll tell you something.
We know anyway.
So do yourself a favor,
and stop fuckin' around.
Hey!
- We gonna talk or what, man?
- When your rep gets here.
- No. Fuck the rep. I gotta talk to you.
Ruben, can you call EMS about this guy?
Yeah. Hey, Moe, Harbor found
one of Superboy's shoes.
What about the socks?
They find them too?
Fuckin' shoe.
Jack Rector's comin' in tomorrow at 9:00.
- What about Donlan?
- Next week.
- His PDA attorney says-
- Who's that? Who's his lawyer?
- This guy Sloan.
- Sloan? Ooh, big gun.
Says he's grieving
and all depressed for his nephew.
Ray's all grieving and depressed.
I'll bet he is.
If Superboy is alive...
he's the fuckin' plague
right about now, right?
You're not gonna bring that home.
I mean, you don't shit
where you eat, do you?
I do, Carson.
I live in a house, and in it I shit...
and I eat.
It's Grotto.
- Murray, get down.
- It's Freddy's new girl.
Cover yourself.
- Hi. Can you turn your engine off for me?
- I got the air on.
- You on the job? - No. We're comin'
from Forest Hills, honey.
I'm John McEnroe. That's Jimmy Connors.
Is your license in there?
Can you pull it out for me, please?
- This is a school zone.
- Oh, Christ!
Listen, Miss Betts. You're new, right?
Yes, I'm new here,
but I'm not new on the job.
- I was a municipal deputy in Elmira.
- Freddy! Freddy!
You see, Officer, in Garrison...
when the car you're gonna tag
has got a PDA sticker...
I'd advise you to think to yourself,
"Hey, that's one of the good guys.
I think I'll go catch me a bad guy. "
If we didn't pull over PD, there wouldn't
be any violations in this town.
The problem ain't the people that
live here. It's the element that visits.
Is this a new car, Ray? It's nice.
We didn't recognize it.
Come on, Freddy. I wanna go home.
Tell this cupcake to heel.
- Okay, that's not necessary.
- Cindy.
- Listen. Take care, guys. See you later.
- Hey!
What happened to you, Freddy?
This was a fender bender.
She's kinda cute.
Dispatch. Hi!
Can I call you back? Bye.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine. I got it.
Dispatch.
No, no. That's the next town over.
You called Garrison.
Right. The town with all the police.
What are you gonna do with Superboy?
You gotta stash him someplace.
We lie low.
Hey, Moe!
Hey, Ray.
- Sorry to hear about your nephew.
- Yeah, he was a good kid.
We were up all night with it.
I know you need to talk to me.
I'll come in next week sometime.
How's that?
- Jackie's comin' in early for you.
Tomorrow. - Hi, Jackie. Moe Tilden.
Yeah, hey.
- Moe Tilden.
- Yeah. Frankie Lagonda.
- What house?
- Out of the 3-7.
- You been there long?
- Maybe too long, huh?
- Too long. Right.
- Moe was my classmate at the academy.
Back in the day.
Before he fell in love
with this redhead at IA and transferred.
Is that how it went, Ray?
So what brings you to our fair city?
Checkin' up on us?
I heard there was a way of life out here.
Thought I'd check it out for myself.
Yeah. What are we, like the Amish now?
See you around.
You fuckin' rat.
Shit!
I thought you gave me a ticket.
You the sheriff?
- I thought you gave me a ticket.
- One second.
Hey, hey, Gordon, that's it.
Knock it off. Let him go.
- Asshole! - Just let him go.
Everyone, go to the park.
Go on, before I kick your ass.
Get on!
- Sorry.
- How long you been a sheriff?
- Ten years.
- That's great.
I see there's a lot of city cops here.
- Oh, yeah. A lot of cops.
- Great gig.
I like it.
I don't wanna waste your time.
Let me give you my card.
It's a special unit in the city.
If you ever wanna talk about anything,
it's all confidential.
Okay.
Nice to meet ya.
Ray, that fuck Tilden
shows up here with that grin.
Freddy's new girl pulls us over.
I mean, someone's talkin'.
I say it's Figgs.
I mean, we got some loose ends.
Freddy's my man.
Unfortunately,
he's on the wrong side of the river.
That don't mean you can't trust me, Ray-
with anything.
I trust you, Freddy.
I trust you to make sure the kids
don't kill themselves on prom night.
I trust you to suggest a good opera record
for my sister at Christmastime.
I'm serious.
Freddy, when I leave here everyday...
I trust you with my town.
Maybe I don't trust you with anything...
but I trust you
with my home and my family...
and, to me, that's everything.
I'm sorry. Jesus.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay. I heard voices.
I was gonna have the base
call you back anyway.
Freddy!
Look what you found.
She's gonna be so happy. Her dad
won it, and I left it on top of the car.
I know. I saw from my window.
It's awful about Ray's nephew.
What happened to your nose?
Little accident.
I was chasing a speeder.
Mommy, I need some black!
Look what the sheriff found. Remember
how you were crying for that today?
Freddy, do you want some coffee?
No, I'm fine. Thanks, Liz.
- I got a little bit on me.
- You got a little bit on you, didn't you?
Come here. Okay. All right. You know what?
I have to get something
to clean this off of you.
Okay. We got it off both hands.
Isn't that nice?
I'm gonna go get a washcloth. Okay?
All right. You just draw a rainbow.
Enough with the sparkles.
I'll be right back.
All right?
Well. I was gonna call you.
Not you. One of your guys.
Why? What's up?
Someone's been dumping garbage-
garbage bags.
Is that them?
Just one of them. The rest are mine.
I don't tell Joey, 'cause then
he thinks he's got to deal with it.
Not that he doesn't think much
of the local- about you guys.
I'll take care of it. It's okay.
He's got the city to worry about, right?
Anyway-
What's the point with the black garbage
bag?
It's just I found your phone bill
in a black garbage bag down the street.
So, what if I said I didn't know
where it came from?
I'd take your word for it, Rose.
- Is Ray home? - No. He's taking care
of our little visitor.
My garbage gets picked up every Tuesday.
All right.
Thanks for your time, Rose.
You tell Joey that he should
come and talk to me...
if he thinks I got no right.
I wanna believe you when you tell me
something. Did you dump these bags or not?
Freddy, this isn't a law problem. Okay?
You tell Joey Randone
if he does not like my garbage...
then he should stop soiling my sheets.
You gonna tell Ray about this?
- Hey, Ray.
- What's up, Freddy?
Decided to give me that ticket?
No.
Somebody's been dumping garbage.
A felony.
- What's wrong, Officer? - Could I see
your license and registration?
- I was just asking-
- We just came to get a view of the city.
- I don't believe this.
- It'll be all right.
- They're just a couple. - They pull us
over for watching the sunset?
- I'll sit.
- All right, roger that.
We just drove down to visit the city.
He can't give us a ticket
for driving to the city.
I don't understand.
You should get his badge number.
This is racism, plain and simple.
- Ass motherfucking pig.
- We came here to watch the view!
- And you pull this?
- Speeding? My ass! Goddamn.
Do you know the meaning of "harassment"?
That's what this is, you know.
- It was Rose, wasn't it?
- Liz.
If you want me to, I'll talk to 'im.
Why?
You didn't marry him.
No.
But I'm your friend.
Freddy, look, I gotta go.
And let me be clear.
It was the system that drove Murray
"Superboy" Babitch off that bridge.
There it is.
Murray Babitch was a hero cop.
He deserved a fair hearing, but he knew
this would not happen, not in this city.
Activist Cyril Johns
met the parents of the slain teens...
calling for a human blockade
on the bridge tomorrow.
A drunk cop jumps off a bridge. That does
not erase the murder of two black children.
- Mayor Farelli responded to reports-
- 2-for-1.
of cops attempting to plant
evidence on the bridge.
We are looking into it. There may have
been some irregularity on the bridge.
- But as I say-
- Your mother's an irregularity.
No more comments. I'm here to enjoy
the ball game with my wife. Thank you.
- Yankee fan.
- That's your boss. Are you kidding?
- You'll never get another raise in your
life. - Who's gonna tell?
Wanna see something really cool?
Diagonal rule.
Diagonal rule. Red light, don't fight.
You make a right.
It's more important than the golden rule.
If Superboy knew that, he'd still be alive.
Freddy, I heard you saved
Ollie the turtle today.
- What happened to your nose?
- Nothing. I just had a little accident.
Listen, there's something we should
talk about if you've got some time.
- What?
- If you have a few minutes.
Pretty boy Joey bettin' against the Bulls.
What is that?
What, are you some kind of high roller?
- Fuck you, Figgs. I had 12 points.
- Against the five-time NBA champs?
What kind of bet is that?
You night guys watch way too much Oprah
when you should be catching your Z's.
Figgs. Well, at least I'm not the one
sniffin' my money away.
That was your inner child
making that wager, Joey.
Little boy Joey with the little Met poster
taped above his bed.
Really? Tell you what, Figgs.
Why don't you do me a favor.
Come on over here, unzip me, pull out
my inner child and take a bite, baby.
Bite it hard and bite it big.
- Fuck you!
- No, fuck you!
Dumb fuck like that PD.
How's that make you feel, Freddy?
- I don't care.
- Yeah?
You like eatin' doughnuts?
Look, Freddy.
I say it's okay to be jealous.
You saved this girl's life, right?
From it, from risking yourself, from saving
her sorry ass, you go deaf as a result.
- In one ear.
Then you have to watch as this girl
you saved, this beauty queen...
marries this cocksucker!
And you, with your ear,
you can't even get a desk on the force.
Right? You're fucked.
Be jealous, Freddy.
Let it out. I would.
Purge! Cleanse yourself.
Fucking cleansing.
Del, Del, let me have another beer.
I gotta go, Freddy.
School's in session. See you later.
This guy bets against the Bulls.
No one wants to get involved
in your personal life, Gary.
But just because you're undercover now,
that don't mean people aren't watchin' you.
What's going on here?
This is fuckin' bullshit.
This is bullshit.
What is this, omerta?
Listen, if IA's gonna fuckin'
hang me by the balls...
it ain't gonna be over
some fuckin' missing evidence.
Figgsy, you've been a cop 12 years.
Six grams missing.
It's not a white socks violation, babe.
Come on! You bought that big ol' house.
Maybe you're tryin' to get out from under.
- Hey! Jack.
- What the fuck's up your ass?
You're telling me you're gettin' by
without gravy, any of you?
I was putting out Ray's fires when you were
still suckin' on your mama's titties...
so just back the fuck off, all right?
So you want to toss me? What? You can't-
- Sit down, Gary.
- No! Tell me what's going on!
- This is bullshit! - Even better,
why don't you get the fuck out?
Fuck you, you fucking child!
Just back the fuck off.
At least I'm not shackin'
with no reekin' whore.
You're supposed to fuck 'em, Gary,
not open up a methadone clinic.
- Figgis, get the hell off of me!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, Figgis, come on.
That's too much now. Hey, hey, hey!
- Gary.
- Fuck you.
You got a problem with me
helpin' a girl in trouble?
- Figgsy.
- You have a problem with that?
No, you're a fuckin' humanitarian!
Come here.
You think you're so fuckin' bad?
- Oh, God!
- Come on. Come here. You see this?
Look at Tunney. You see him?
- That was my fuckin' partner. That was a
cop! - Enough!
Let go of him, Figgsy.
Go home.
You all right, Jack? Let me look at you.
Don't shut me out, Ray!
You found us a sweet little town. You got
us the low interest, and I'm grateful.
But don't forget who it was that you
came to two years ago to cover your ass.
Get him outta here, Freddy!
- Come on. - It's not my fault
that you can't look at him!
You sit in this chair
with your back to 'im!
You want it to go away, but I'm still here.
In for a penny, in for a pound.
Don't shut me out, Ray.
I'll take care of it, Ray.
It's bullshit.
I'm gettin' the fuck outta this town!
- Open the door.
- You wanna play games? I don't play games.
Liz, open the door.
I want the door op- I want-
Open it now!
Shut up!
Why don't you go up the street
and get into bed with Rosie?
- Liz, open the goddamn door now!
- Idiot!
Open it... now!
Freddy, go home.
Everything is just hunky-dory. Please go.
- Mind if we check up on Liz?
- Yes, I do. I mind.
I said I mind, Freddy.
- Joey, I've had it, okay?
- I'll get the kit.
Liz, it's Freddy.
Does Ray know?
Freddy, does Ray know?
- Hi, Freddy.
- Are you okay?
Your Uncle Freddy is here
to rescue you again.
Liz, maybe you and the baby
need a place to stay. Let him cool off.
I could take you over to the Ramada.
Do you want me to do that?
He didn't do anything.
I... hit him with a bottle.
Freddy?
His girlfriend was in the basement.
- So where's Figgs? - I called him
at the precinct. He's on his way.
We got no pressure. I wonder if there's
still water in that tower over there.
Monica, can you hear me?
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Monica!
Baby, what were you doin' in there?
Hey! I came back to see you.
I needed some-
Wanted... to see you...
but you weren't there.
I was workin'. I was workin'.
Monica! No, baby.
We're losin' her.
Oh, my God.
- The fucker's gettin' payback.
- Who is?
Ray. Who do you think?
Lenny said it wasn't suspicious.
He said it was electrical.
Figgsy?
Look at me, Figgsy.
Did you call in?
I'm not on till Tuesday.
I'll call in. Buy you a couple weeks.
Dispatch.
Tell them they can't, ma'am.
Just because they're TV people, that
doesn't mean they can park on your lawn.
In a cemetery practically
reserved for cops...
you come across the tombstone
of Officer Glenn Tunney.
You may recall his case.
He was murdered in his jail cell
awaiting the grand jury.
Two years later, deja vu.
Another hero cop- Murray Babitch
is his name- dubbed "Superboy"...
unwilling to trust the system
that destroyed his friend...
jumps from the George Washington Bridge.
- Freddy.
- How ya doin'?
Freddy.
Maybe we should go up there.
Okay.
I want you to meet the head
of the Patrolmen's Defense Association.
Great.
Vincent.
Vincent Lassaro, I'd like you to meet
Sheriff Freddy Heflin.
You did a good job here.
You did a great job. Real nice.
- Thank you.
- Freddy's a hell of a guy.
Good. Great.
He tried to get on the force for years,
but he had this problem with his ear.
- You're not a lip reader, are ya?
- No, no.
It's just this one ear-
when I was a kid I had this accident.
You should call me. I mean,
when Ray Donlan puts his thumb in the air-
It's not the force,
but I got my own people. Call me.
Is he serious?
Freddy, my boy, that is how things happen.
- See you later.
- Detail! Atten-hut!
"Eternal God, our Father,
the Lord of our life and death...
we acknowledge Thee in all our ways
and in all events which befall us.
Lift us above the shadow-"
What's in the coffin?
His uniform.
"Then in Thy great mercy,
grant us a safe lodging and a holy rest.
And peace at last
through Jesus Christ, our Lord. "
Amen.
Unto God's gracious mercy
and protection, we commit you.
The Lord bless you and keep you.
The Lord make His face to shine upon you,
and be gracious unto you.
The Lord lift up His countenance
upon you and give you peace...
both now and forevermore.
Amen.
Hi, Sheriff. How you doin'?
How you doin'?
This is Detective Carson.
- How's it goin'?
- Come on in. It's your office.
That there is Manny Cardoza
and his brother.
They're drug runners.
I didn't know they allowed
classical music in Jersey.
Who's this?
Toy Torillo. You heard of him?
Oh, yes.
I don't know how you do it, Sheriff.
Keeping all these Hessians in line.
All blue.
Everybody packing. All together.
One door down from the next.
The wives borrowing the sugar.
It's like you're the sheriff for Cop Land.
Look at this.
You see, Sheriff, I got a sticky problem.
My jurisdiction ends, in a sense,
at the George Washington Bridge.
But half the men I watch
live beyond that bridge...
where no one's watching.
I'm watching.
I can see that. You've got a crime rate
here of about, what?
The lowest in northern New Jersey.
You got Hoboken and Jersey City
over here. Newark.
We try to do a good job with what we have.
With a staff of three? No, Sheriff.
What you got here is a town
that scares the shit out of certain people.
Lieutenant, I told you, I'm watching.
If you look around, you see none
of these people are wearing silk shirts.
Their pools are above ground. You know?
You raise your family somewhere decent,
I guess that's a crime now.
Lieutenant, look around.
This is a town with a population
of 1,000 people.
- I got news for you. Not all cops
are dirty. - I'm not saying they are.
This kid, he was- He lived around here.
He used to come by,
have drinks with the guys, hang out.
He never caused any problems.
You mind if I sit down?
We buried a suit today.
We buried a suit today!
That doesn't bother you?
- He jumped off the GWB.
- Yeah, but his body never hit the water.
That doesn't bother you.
What does? That I investigate cops?
- Being a man who always pined to be a cop?
- I am a cop.
Pined to be NYPD.
Three forced absent, 10 years
appeals of hearing tests.
Right?
You may be law enforcement,
and so am I, but you are not a cop.
Now, I may watch cops,
but tell me if I'm wrong.
Every day out these windows, so do you.
You watch cops too.
And since we are both law enforcement,
we share a duty.
Do we not?
If there is a stink, we must investigate.
We must gather evidence
because evidence makes us see the truth.
Is this the stink of a criminal act,
or is it a turd in a bag?
I'll tell you something, Sheriff.
I see cops who lose their way every day...
and I don't like that...
because their ambivalence is contagious.
They infect those around them.
They're like maggots.
Where you find one, you find a nest.
And I take that real personally.
I went to the same academy
as our friend there.
Ray? Good man.
I stood by him at graduation.
He was a beauty.
- He's been good to me.
- Yeah, a real collar man.
To the cop that he was,
to his memory, I am loyal...
but through the fog of my loyalty
to the men...
the evidence makes me see...
and, these days, what I see...
like an island out of my reach...
I see this beautiful island
shining through this fog...
every house financed
by one of two mob banks.
That's right, Sheriff.
What I see is your town.
No, no, you don't see that.
Babitch isn't dead.
You know that and I know that.
Ray got him off that bridge alive,
before he could talk.
But he wasn't so lucky the last time
when the shit hit the fan with Tunney.
That boy he took care of later.
But now what? What does Ray do now?
That's the $64,000 question.
And that's why I'm here.
That's why I'm here, Sheriff.
Because you're on the inside.
Besides the church traffic and the cats
in the trees and all that other bullshit...
there isn't much here for you to do
to keep your mind busy.
But I look at you, Sheriff...
and I see a man who's waiting
for something to do.
And here I am.
Here I am saying, "Sheriff...
I got something for you to do. "
So let's make the most
of this beautiful day
Since we're together,
we might as well say
Would you be mine?
Could you be mine?
Won't you be my neighbor?
You know, Figgsy...
you don't have to sleep at the station
if you don't want to.
You can stay in my basement
until you find a new place.
Come on. Let's get this guy, Frank!
- It's gonna be a long day, Papa!
- Kid, you're up. Your turn to be a hero.
Billy heard they're having a party tonight.
I'll take care of it, Bill.
Hey, Frank, is Ray home?
What, you need us to turn it down?
No, I just need to talk to Ray.
Come here. Come here.
Wait outside there.
I don't wanna go through this again.
- It's too fuckin' bad.
- I can't! I told the boys-
I mean, they're downstairs now
saying good-bye.
Ray, how many people you got
at this party? The whole 3-7?
You got a party downstairs.
He needs to talk to you.
Here I am cleaning this thing up for you,
and you're throwing a fuckin' party.
The mayor's gonna suspend this case.
I'm making it happen tomorrow!
But sooner or later, Ray,
they gotta find a body in that river...
or it will not hold.
Mets, it's my sister-in-law's kid!
Didn't you say he was adopted?
Turn it down!
- Don't go yet.
- I gotta drive Donna home.
Take her to the train.
Ray, this doesn't make things
very easy for me.
This is a pretty big thing you're having
here the day after. How do you think-
Freddy, what are you talking about?
This guy came to see me yesterday,
this Moe Tilden from IA.
- He brought all these pictures and-
- Freddy.
That guy's had a hard-on for me for years.
It's a personal thing.
- He is a scumbag.
- All right.
You know how they recruit at IAD?
They catch you on the take...
and they tell you
you can either do time or join 'em.
He knows you know Superboy is-
I told him he was dead, Ray.
I told him he was wrong about you.
But I'm the sheriff.
I mean, I'm supposed to know
what's goin' on.
How do you think this looks?
Go home, Freddy, and don't think so much.
- Ray, I can't go.
- Freddy-
- Freddy, go home. Go home. Go home.
- I can't go-
Yo, Ross, come over here. Look at this.
Super!
It's not Murray. It's not Murray.
He's part of a search.
- In Tempe, Arizona.
- Atlanta, Georgia. Atlanta, Georgia.
Murray, Murray.
Okay. Listen.
- I want you to have this. - No, Aunt Rose,
I'm fine. Seriously. I gotta go-
Look, Murray, look.
Listen to me. I want you to have this.
All right. You made it for me?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Hi.
You guys have another fight?
We were supposed to have a big talk.
So I sent Caroline over to my mom's.
And-
And Joey called
and told me that he was stuck...
and that he made some arrest.
I mean, I... can't believe him
when he tells me...
anything.
Liz, you wanna come inside?
You can get this on CD,
you know, in stereo.
It wouldn't matter to me.
Oh, right.
You know, it's a funny thing
when you owe someone your life.
Why is it you never got married, Freddy?
All the best girls were taken.
This is crazy.
Yes.
All right. Take it easy. All right?
All right, Gabriel. Take it easy.
Murray?
Hey, Murray!
Ray's outside waitin' for ya.
- You comin' or what?
- I'm comin', I'm comin'.
That was a great party, Ray.
You know, Ray,
it's a really great thing you did.
Makin' a place where everybody
could stick together.
I mean...
I know you didn't have to do this for me.
You could've just-
I wanna let you know I appreciate it.
- I really do.
- Everyone's gone.
- Just us, buddy.
- That's it.
I always said to my mom,
"Uncle Ray doesn't like me, but-"
I always liked you, Murray.
You just sweat too much.
- Hey, what's doin'?
- Hey, Superboy.
So what are we gonna do now?
I'm gonna go meet some people?
How does this work?
I got all my bags packed
and everything, Ray.
Just I'm a little buzzed.
You know, maybe we could
do this tomorrow or something.
I'm really tired, Ray.
- Where's Joey?
- He's working tonight, kid.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Sorry it came out this way, Murray.
It's not that bad, Jack.
Yeah, it is, Murray.
- Fuck!
- What the fuck is going on here?
What is this? What are you doin'?
What are you doin'?
- Stay outta this.
- What the fuck is this?
Ray, you said PDA was gonna
set him up with a new life.
You think I'm all that, Joey?
Fuck it.
Put your files in there.
We're done. It's over.
- Moe-
- We were shut down by the mayor. Here.
- What the fuck is this? - Put your files
in there. The case is closed.
Ruben, what are you doin'?
What are you doin'?
- I'm on hold with the phone company.
- Is that the Garrison file?
Is that a Garrison file?
Give me your Garrison files.
- Give me it all. Give me it all.
- All right.
Is that more?
I'll take everything. The case is closed.
The case is fucking closed!
Closed!
The case is closed, finished, over!
Go to lunch.
Go to lunch! Go! Hey, go to lunch.
Go to lunch! The case is closed.
Everybody, get the fuck outta here.
Get outta here!
The case is fucking closed!
With community leaders
and pundits crying "Cover up"...
Mayor Farelli's suspension
of the Babitch case is a big gamble.
No one's gonna read this. They never read
it. It's just a bunch of red tape.
- Sheriff! Sheriff!
- She's gonna fuck up my insurance claim.
- Don't pull the paper out of the thing.
- Here's your coffee.
Cin, please just try it
his way for a while.
I'm tellin' you,
you don't need to do this.
It's just a bunch of bullshit.
What do you want?
Are you gonna help us or not?
Help you help what?
Help Ray here find him?
Help Ray finish cleaning up
his goddamn pool with the guy's head?
Is that it, Mr. Humanitarian?
You got something
you wanna say to me, Ray?
Or is this about something
a little more personal?
I'm on at 10:00. I'm outta here.
We all are. We got another hour.
Hey, come on, Joey.
Instead of taking cop lessons
from a cokehead...
maybe you should be lookin'
at that fire, you know?
My girl over at Chase
says Figgs is missing a few payments.
Where were you that night, Jack?
I had nothin' to do with it.
That would be retribution,
and that I leave to God Almighty.
I'm Gandhi.
I'm tellin' ya, the mob built
this town for Ray...
so they could own a fuckin' precinct.
It's a deep and dark motherfuck.
What you're feelin' right now, Freddy-
friendless, angry, nervous, misunderstood-
this is it, this is the life.
You're lucky your ear
kept you off the force.
You know...
if I saw Liz...
drowning in the water-
If I saw that today...
I wouldn't go in.
I'd stand there, and I'd think about it.
And that's the best thing
I ever did with my life.
- So?
So you wanna sit around your whole life
wishing you were on the force?
Or do you wanna bring the faggot in?
Let him spill.
I wouldn't know where to begin.
All right. Brother's in deep shit.
He's down, he's bleeding,
and you gotta get there.
But there's lights, right?
All over the city, red lights.
You go through the red lights.
Sure, you fire up the roof, you wail,
you go through the red lights.
But that's slow, Freddy,
fighting your way through traffic.
The goal is perpetual motion.
You want greens.
But how do you ensure the greens?
You can't. As in life, in traffic.
So what you do
is you leave yourself an out.
At every corner,
you leave yourself an alternative.
You move diagonal.
You turn the wheel
when you hit a red light.
You don't drive down Broadway
to get to Broadway.
If you move diagonal...
you're gonna get perpetual motion.
That's what you want.
But how does this apply
to what you were saying in there?
It applies, Freddy!
It's just as easy to tail a man
walking in front of him.
You butt heads with these friends of ours,
you're gonna come at them head-on?
- Okay.
- They got lives, Freddy.
Families.
No.
You move diagonal.
You jag.
Christ! Where the fuck are you guys?
We're on our way- in 20.
I'm down.
But Joey, he's tryin' to hold on...
but this big bastard, he cut me up.
I need help!
- He's a fucking monster!
- I need your location, Tom!
- I need an assist.
- I can't move. I think he cut my tendon.
What the fuck-
Shit-
You got a wife?
You got a baby?
Quit! Tell me you quit.
I'll let you go. You can go home.
Kiss your wife.
Eat your baby's Fruit Loops and shit.
You thank me, motherfucker.
You're gonna be redeemed.
Redeemed...
Officer... Randone.
Shit! Stupid-
- You motherfucker!
- Shit.
It's the roof, Jack. That's a clusterfuck.
You got units, send 'em in.
I'll check the front.
We don't know what's going on!
Come on, come on.
Son of a bitch!
Please.
No!
Help! Help!
In here!
Joey's in trouble, Ray.
Ray, let's just break
the fuckin' thing down.
Got it.
God.
His father is serving a life sentence
for murder, murdering an ex-girlfriend...
with a sawed-off shotgun back in 1988.
The New York Times is quoting
one friend of Royster as saying...
that the guy had an IQ of 160.
I need your help.
They're tryin' to kill me.
- Who?
- "Who"?
My friends tried to kill me.
Ray Donlan tried to kill me.
Shit!
Holy shit!
Speak of the devil!
Freddy, forget it.
I don't get this.
This doesn't make any sense.
Why'd they get Superboy off the bridge...
to bring him back here and kill him?
Ray had a plan...
and it got very fucked up.
You awake, Freddy?
I feel like shit.
Fuckin' allergies are killin' me.
Hey.
In sure and certain hope
of the resurrection to eternal life...
through our Lord, Jesus Christ...
we commend to Almighty God
our brother Joseph...
and we commit his body to the ground.
The Lord bless him and keep him.
The Lord make His face
to shine upon him...
and be gracious unto him.
The Lord lift up
His countenance upon him...
and give him peace.
Honor Guard, retreat.
- No, I don't know.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I just- I gotta-
- What are you doing?
- Call you back.
- Excuse me.
Moe, I apologize.
He just walked in here.
I'm sorry for rushing in like this,
but you were right.
They tried to kill him like you said,
but he got away.
Now he's runnin' through the woods
like a scared animal. He's scared to death.
That motherfucker should be scared.
His uncle got this case closed
with one phone call.
I'm sorry it took so long for me
to come around, but you were right.
I couldn't see the truth. The evidence,
my loyalty, they were confusing.
They never give you
any napkins in this place.
What am I supposed to use?
You want this?
What is this?
You came to me, to my town...
with all these speeches,
talking about doing the right thing.
I'm doing the right thing.
What's goin' on? What are you doing?
That was like two weeks ago.
Two weeks ago?
- What about Babitch?
- What about him? Fuck him.
- What about Donlan?
- Fuck him too.
What about Joey Randone?
He fell off a building.
Don't you read the papers?
Listen, Sheriff, I'm really sorry...
to have awoken you from your slumber,
but it's over.
Hands are tied now. You shut me down.
Listen to me. You're IA. That's why I came
to you. You can do whatever you want.
Remember you came to me, said,
"You wanna be a cop?" I'm bein' a cop.
- I offered you a chance.
- I'm asking you for some help.
I need to do something.
I need to do this for myself.
Listen, you deaf fuck.
I offered you a chance.
When we could have done something,
I offered you a chance to be a cop...
and you blew it!
You blew it.
You people are all the same.
That cupcake makes a mess,
we got a case again.
The mob runs millions in drugs
through their precinct...
and everybody gets a nice house.
Figgs is right. The mob owns this town.
They closed the case, Freddy.
- If they don't have the stomach for it-
- They had to. It's circumstantial.
You don't have anything either.
All that stuff is illegal. You stole it.
I know this guy.
He's a corrections officer.
They took care of Tunney
when he was gonna talk.
How come Figgis didn't do somethin' about
it? He was Ray's right-hand man back then.
Then they tried to kill Superboy.
They were hiding him, Freddy.
Then they burned down Figgsy's house
when they think he might talk.
You don't know that.
We went over every inch of that house.
Not everything is a hexagonal conspiracy.
I think you been hangin'
around Figgs too much.
He's the only one getting cash
out of that house...
and he's totally playing you-
just like those assholes in the city.
And I'm sorry, but... there's nothing
you can do about this.
Yes, there is.
I can find Superboy,
and I can bring him in.
I'm going back upstate.
I want my old job back.
I don't want any part of this.
I don't want any part of this place.
Come on, Cindy.
Shit.
Freddy.
Look, I don't know about Ray, okay?
But everyone in Garrison
is not a murderer.
No. They just keep their eyes closed
and their mouths shut, just like me.
Hey, Freddy.
All right, thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, sweetheart. I love you too.
All right, terrific.
- Two in the center?
- No. Rules are different for cops.
- I'm losin' my shirt here with you guys.
- So what do I got to do?
- Five out of six in the star.
- Five out of six.
- Hey, Freddy.
- You a cop too?
Yeah, yeah, I heard ya.
Enjoy your trip to the big city?
You gotta hit the next five to win.
Shit!
I just hope you're not trying
to prove anything, Freddy.
I know some of them are real assholes.
They think they're high priests
or somethin'. I don't know.
But why would they do all this?
Maybe they're doin' the right thing.
Liz, I saw these pictures of Ray
meeting with these guys.
You know, like mobsters.
Everyone's houses are financed
by these mob banks.
Says who? IA?
Even you said Joey's death
was no accident.
Joey fell off a building, Freddy! Okay?
I don't need this opened up.
Maybe you do. I don't.
All Joey wanted was a place for us to live.
Who are you to judge that
until you've walked in his shoes?
Maybe that's what
you're tryin' to do with me.
What are you gonna do, Freddy?
You gonna arrest the whole town?
You goin' to New York to take
"paint by number" cop lessons?
You know, Ray likes you.
That don't mean
I'm gonna let you fuck him over.
Ray Donlan gave you this job, Freddy.
You forgot that? We made your sorry ass!
So now you can do us a favor.
You could tell us... where Superboy is.
If I knew where he was,
he'd be in the city already.
You're gonna be hurtin', Freddy.
You're not gonna know when,
you're not gonna know where.
You're gonna be hurtin'.
You mark my words. I'm watchin' you!
Hey.
- You got your check.
- Yep.
Thanks to you, Freddy.
Filing out those forms
in such a timely fashion.
You with Liz?
Where you goin'?
I don't know.
My leave came, so I thought I'd look
around for a new reality. You know?
Anyway, I'm sure you could use
your privacy, Freddy.
No, no.
Look all you want, Freddy.
You're not gonna find anything.
I took care of it.
That lady cop from the Bomb Squad...
got you the stuff
to do this with, didn't she?
You didn't know Monica was gonna be here.
Did you, Figgs?
No.
Monica said she was going over to her
friend's house to watch some pay-per-view.
The thing was on a timer. I didn't know
she was gonna be here, Freddy.
It's all bullshit.
You, Figgs, are the bullshit!
Smarten fuckin' up!
You even turned your back on Tunney
when he needed your help!
Figgs! I'm gonna find Superboy,
and I'm gonna bring him in!
And for once, everybody in this town's
gonna tell the truth!
- You gotta find him first, Freddy!
- I'll find him.
Listen to me. I got a check
in my pocket for $200,000.
I got a chance to start my life again.
I don't give a shit about this town!
I don't give a shit about that town.
And I don't give a shit
about your fucking justice!
Bein' right is not
a bulletproof vest, Freddy!
Go on, Figgsy!
Go on! Run away!
Hey, Freddy.
- Ray's not home.
- I know.
I'm lookin' for your nephew.
I don't know where he is.
Why the hell would I tell you if I did?
Rose, I'm his only chance.
Let's go.
- You workin' with the feds?
- No.
- IA?
You're alone.
Let's go.
- Oh, shit.
- All right. Get down. Get down.
- And stay down.
Shit.
Bill, where are you?
Bill, if you read,
we're going back to the station.
You gonna keep me in here?
You gonna keep me in here with cuffs?
- You don't know what you're doing, do you?
- Shut up.
You don't have a clue as to what the fuck
is going on, do you, Sheriff?
Bill, do you copy?
Bill, do you read?
- It's just club soda, Freddy.
- Finish it.
- Hey, Ray.
- Hey, Freddy.
I came to tell you I found Superboy...
and I'm bringing him in
tomorrow morning...
and I'd like you to come with me.
I owe you that much.
He's a fugitive, Ray, and he's convinced
you're tryin' to kill him.
Just tell me where he is, Freddy.
You got him at the station?
Ray, there's gotta be a way
out of this for everyone.
So, I say why don't we all
go in tomorrow together?
Listen to me, Freddy.
You know the difference
between men and boys?
Boys bet everything on everything.
Boys think every hand is a royal flush.
You play cards with a man,
he knows his limits.
Freddy, I invited men...
cops...
good men...
to live in this town.
And these men, to make a living,
they cross that bridge every day...
to a place where everything
is upside down.
Where the cop is the perp,
and the perp is the victim.
But they play by the rules.
They keep their guns in their holsters...
and they play by the rules.
The only thing they did
was to get their families out...
before it got to them.
We made a place where things make sense...
and you can walk
across the street without fear.
And you come to me
with a plan to set things right.
Everyone in this city holding hands,
singing "We Are the World. "
That's very nice.
But, Freddy,
your plan is the plan of a boy.
You made it on the back of a matchbook
without thinking!
Without looking at the cards.
I look at the cards.
I see this town...
destroyed.
That's not what you want, is it?
I look at this town...
and I don't like what I see anymore.
Who the fuck do you think you are?
The sheriff of Garrison, New Jersey.
Then be the sheriff!
Defend this town! Protect these men!
Freddy, you got him at the station?
Just drop the keys.
A little too rich for my blood.
Maybe they fell out of your pocket-
or maybe Cindy's.
Now, you go home and you sleep...
and you wake up and you guide the traffic
through this town...
and everything will be the way it was.
I'm taking him in
tomorrow morning at 6:00.
That's in a few hours.
I'd like you to come with me, Ray.
There's nothing I can say?
Okay. Then 6:00 it is.
Yeah. No, Lis.
Who was he supposed to call?
Ray knows everybody.
What am I supposed to do?
Let him go in alone? What?
You know what? Okay, fine.
Why don't you go home?
I mean...
I wanna be here for you, Freddy, but-
Lisa's nervous, you know. She's pregnant.
- I mean-
- So, go on. I'll be fine.
Yeah.
You be careful, Freddy.
Yeah. You too.
Shut the fuck up! Would ya, please?
Fuck!
Come on.
- Oh, shit!
- Get down!
- All right, you jackass.
- I said get down, buddy.
Jesus. You guys
don't wanna do this. Jack.
Don't shit in your pants, Freddy.
He's not gonna kill ya.
This is the good one, right?
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Move, move, move!
God!
All right, hit it, Jackie. Hit it, Jack!
Jesus Christ!
You fuck!
Freddy!
I can't hear you, Ray.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey. What're you doin'?
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
Come on, guys, it's cool.
Everything's cool.
Everything's cool. Everything's cool.
Come on. Everything's cool.
- Please move.
- Where the hell are you goin'?
Please move!
Holy shit!
Wait. Guys, guys. Beat it. Beat it.
Everything's fine.
Everything's fine. It's cool.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- What the fuck?
Come on, Freddy.
Everything's cool. Everything's fine.
- Wait. Where do you think you're goin'?
- Call EMS. Call EMS.
Come on, fellas. Back up.
Back up. Back up. Back up.
- He can't hear.
- Rubens, take him.
- Hey, hey, it's all right. It's okay. It's
okay. - They blew out his ear.
It's all right. It's all right! It's okay.
It's okay. Come on.
Go on, Freddy.
Come on inside.
Come on.
So Gary Figgis copped a plea.
Gave up the connection between Ray,
the PDA and the mob.
There were a shitload of indictments.
And the sheriff, Freddy Heflin-
You know, there's people on both sides
of the river wish he never recovered.
They cursed the day
he took down Ray Donlan.
But what they don't know, he figured out:
No one is above the law.
Four cops dead,
and one dead cop resurrected.
Murray "Superboy" Babitch
sits alive and well in a holding cell-
Sheriff Fred Heflin apprehended
Babitch single-handedly.
...he will be recovering the hearing
in his good ear, so that's good news.
Files were seized this morning-
Officer Gary Figgis testified
about mob influence and bribery.
Three months since the shoot-out
in Garrison, New Jersey...
reputed mob boss Toy Torillo has been
indicted on four counts of racketeering.
An unidentified corrections officer
was arrested today...
for the murder three years ago
of Officer Glenn Tunney.
I understand Jim Allen is with the mayor.
Do you want to go back to him?