- I do not know where I am. I am lost.
- It is an island. - What?
- How can you on an island lost?
- I know that it is an island.
And you made it, to get lost?
Yes, it is possible to get lost in Cyprus.
- How - Because I have made it possible.
Listen, I'm sorry, I'm tired.
I do not understand,
why are you so mad.
- What have I done? Come on, tell me.
- You have no idea?
- I do not think I'm wrong thing did.
- Because you never do what.
What do you mean by that,
that I never do what?
That's why you're mad, because I know
nothing doing? That can not be true.
Hello? Hello!
Hello - Hey, buddy.
- George? What time is it?
- No idea.
- Where the hell you are?
No idea.
Oh, man,
It is six clock in the morning.
Six clock in the morning, George,
on Saturday. Are you hurt?
- No.- In prison?
- No. - Then I'll call later.
- You're an asshole.
- Seems today to be a widely held opinion.
Do you know why - Look,
I think I've got it with Christina dirty.
We were on this
Engagement party last night.
We talked, and then all of a sudden
there was a heated argument.
What you fought her?
- George - Yes, here.
- You're an asshole. - Why?
- Answer the damn question.
- In addition I'm not ready.
She was smart enough
at least this time to leave you?
Listen, driving home,
sleep it off and call me later.
Yes. Let's see.
What is...
Sorry.
Is everything okay?
Best. Thank you.
Can I help you?
Maybe Do you want a ride?
In a church would be conceivable.
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
- I did not mean to be rude, but we are here
the middle of nowhere and... - Do not worry.
My car has broken down and...
But wherever you want?
I do not know.
Great.
I go obviously in the same direction.
- You should ride a piece?
- Probably not, but thank you.
Okay.
So, all the best.
Actually...
Wait! Wait!
Thank you very much.
Buckle up, please. You're welcome.
I don't want to talk about it.
Is just curious.
I am George, by the way.
Are you from Cyprus?
Original yes.
But growing up in the States.
My Greek is not so good.
You are not a serial killer,
or something like that?
What?
- Hello? - George - Mom?
- What happened?
- I'm going to inform the police.
- Mom, it's all right.
- No, no, I'm fine, I'm in the car.
- Did you have an accident?
No, I had not. I could
otherwise talk to you, if it were so?
Why are you yelling at me?
You are gone.
- I do not shout at you.- Christina makes
worried and you drive through the area.
- When are you coming home?
- Mama mou, I do not know, later.
- When later I don't know.
- Do not shout so later on, now, Mom.
- But I did not cry yet.
- But why do not you call?
- We are very worried and you disappear just
- Mom, please.
- I have the phone always with me.
- Okay.
- Okay, see you until then.. - I love you.
- I love you too.
- Can that answer your question?
- Yes.
Yes, even Norman Bates
loved his mother.
- Good Morning.
- Even so.
Do you feel better?
Where are we?
Well, I'm not sure
but I think somewhere east.
Did you know,
where you are going?
No plan. Is there a place
where should you be?
Actually yes.
'Cavo Greco' so against sunset.
This is the cliff by the sea, right?
A wonderful goal.
Yes, a very popular place
for weddings.
Yes, I heard.
- Are you married?
- What?
No, not yet.
And you?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, yeah, all right.
Are you a mechanic or something?
Mechanics? No.
I am an engineer.
This is my hobby.
Take often with anybody,
if you are traveling?
They call themselves
So even 'someone'?
- And you answer questions with questions?
- You do that?
Oh, we are similar.
So, how does your story?
- There is no story. - Oh please.
- What?
Look at us. Everything we lack,
is a giant white cake,
and we were both these figures,
the top of it are.
Tell me your story,
everyone has one.
All right, fine, Let me guess.
They are on the run, but you flee
nowhere because you are without a goal.
So you need
run away from anything.
Of what would a man
probably run away?
In law?
You do not look like a convict.
Hardly money problems.
Looks not at all like it.
So it can really
merely still being here, right?
This is not original.
This is only a bombastic clichés.
I'm so sorry,
that I have to disappoint you.
Her story is certainly fascinating.
No, I am also a cliché.
But I'm going to change that.
Then make straight
a really good job.
So what is it? What now?
Her girlfriend?
Fiancée?
She's your fiancee. And you have
dissolved the engagement, right?
No.
It is not my fiancé.
But I think, they would like to.
And she's tired of waiting,
that you overcome your commitment phobia.
You have quarreled
and fled. Yes?
This really is not original.
They are really a bombastic
Cliché with a small capital 'K'. - 'C'
- Which toe? - In French is from
cliché with 'C'... Oh, by me.
No, in your case it is a 'K',
as in 'schrec'K'lich'.
I'm not a cliché, all right?
Things are as they are.
I do not understand why they
This piece of paper so desperately needs.
- It's not just a piece of paper. - Yes.
I like happens to be the way things are.
And to be honest with you...
You know, I'm here,
because I want it, not because I have to.
Is that what
as the fear of commitment Mantra?
I am sorry,
that's me, of course, nothing.
So, 'Cavo Greco'?
If you do not mind?
Why not? Good thing I
not have to go elsewhere. Let's go back.
- Wedding at sunset.
- From wedding was out of the question,
- only of 'Cavo Greco'.
- Okay.
So you love them?
- Excuse me, please?
- A very simple question.
What are you? Psychologist?
- No, I am a teacher. I give Film Studies
and Drama. - Shocking.
If you really love, you should
call her. And you should do it now.
- Now she sleeps probably.
- No, she does not.
She was on all night and did you
a long Mail wrote about their feelings.
In my opinion, if you
they lose and it does you very sorry,
They are at this
Remember the moment here,
beat his head against the wall and say
to himself: "I should have to call."
I do not want to offend,
but you are not in the position,
People advice
to give in relationship matters.
- Think about it only once,
as you just look like... - How?
- More like a Hochzeitsfee.
- I am the Hochzeitsfee.
I always appearing all
lost men and save them from...
Crap! - What?
- Hold On Stop the car. - What?
Stop the car.
"Buckle up, please."
Blue?
- Hey, you're on.
- Yes, I'm going to write something.
- Where are you?
- I drive just like wars, clear head.
- George, I will not argue.
- I still do not.
I'm very happy, you called.
I have him!
I've been thinking and... - Me too.
- I have him again.
Who's that?
George, who is with you?
- You no further.
- What the hell is going on?
Nothing at all. I swear to you,
the does not mean anything, it's just...
I drove around and ran because
suddenly a bride in the street...
Everything OK?
Was there turn your fiancee?
It is not my fiancé.
- You may not even my girlfriend,
thanks to you. - Hey!
How could I know,
that you talk to her?
Opps.
Shall I call her?
No.
- Is there anyone, you want to call?
- No.
I have not even my phone here.
Only the dress and my veil.
You think determines I'm crazy.
Today is the day of my wedding.
I have planned it for a year.
We have 500 guests expected.
We had tons of white roses and hundreds,
hundreds of torches as decoration.
Did my parents cost a fortune.
Because it yet everything
should be like a fairy tale.
What happened?
No idea.
I really do not know it.
What's happening?
Oh, damn it!
Whatever it is, I'm sure you get
the way 'Mr all rounders engineer'.
Yeah, right.
We just need gasoline.
Wait here.
I'll get what I'm back.
The nearest gas station
is in two kilometers.
I'll come along.
My best buddy Chris introduced us,
as we have studied in London.
- So that's your British accent.
- Yes.
He said she was perfect for me.
She is a female version of himself.
Even for the same name,
Chris, Christina.
Feel it?
I love it, when the wind turns.
They just do not respond.
- Maybe she has it on silent mode.
- No. Your phone is always on.
And she logs in rhymes.
How does it work, please?
If you 'Yes, please' would have to say,
she says 'Yes, Quince'.
And if I call her now,
says she always 'blue' or 'purple'.
That also I could be.
She's not like you.
Because that is their only tick.
I'm not so bad.
Okay, stop. Ow!
Ow!
Just a sec.
What happened?
They really wanted 2 km
running in stilettos?
How could I know,
that the time has come?
Well, why do not you
back to the car and wait there for me?
Running all the way back?
In addition, how far can
Be the gas station to get away?
Could you do it because
make it to the gas station?
No.
So, then pull it out yet.
I'm not crazy,
all the way to go barefoot.
So what do you suggest then?
I'll get petrol,
go back to the car...
- ...then I come back here, okay?
- Okay.
Want to society on the way back?
Can I cash
have for something to drink?
Oh yeah, sure.
Thank you very much.
But they did not fuck off,
You come back, will you?
Should I maybe a pledge here be?
No, I trust you.
Have I done something?
Is there a reason,
that you do not let me sleep?
You would not believe what I
I for one day, my friend.
Where are you?
I'm on my way.
I have picked a bride.
Is 'bride' now
synonymous with 'whore'?
No, she's a real bride.
I think this whole wedding talk
brought you to the brink of madness.
Chris, please, shut up.
It is not imagination.
And Christina knows about it?
She has mitgekriegt on the phone.
And she broke up with me.
All right. Where are you?
I'll come pick you up.
No no, all right, I'm fine.
I'll come back soon.
Okay.
Hi, this is Christina,
all good news, please.
That's why need bridesmaids.
Bride!
Hello!
Hello?!
What are you doing?
Nothing at all.
I just wanted to stretch my legs.
Okay.
Can we go now?
- No. - No?
- No.
I need two minutes.
All right.
I wait in the car.
- Ready when you are.
- Okay.
Are you in any Difficulties?
- What do you mean by that?
- I'm surely not stupid.
- What was that just with the cops?
- Because it was nothing.
Listen, I do not want
be involved in something.
- Whatever you have done...
- There is certainly nothing.
My fiance is a cop.
He may have sent his boys,
looking for me,
but I'm not ready.
- Why should the police are looking for you?
- Not the police, my fiance. - Okay!
Her fiancé.
Why should he look for you?
Because I was gone and no one knows,
where I would go.
I woke up this morning
and the first time I thought
of my time after the wedding.
And what will be afterwards.
And my whole future
overtook my eyes
and everything seemed so unexciting.
- I thought that should be there?
- What do you mean by 'unexciting'?
To do just that,
what is expected of you.
You'll even get married,
then comes the credit, build a house,
have a baby
and still a baby, work, school...
The same story,
which every human being has.
I knew exactly
how my life is run.
But is it any good?
I mean, to know?
No.
I want the uncertainty.
I want it all prefer to explore.
Yes. And what will be,
if nothing happens?
The risk you should take.
I would choose the challenge,
instead these predetermined boredom.
That's not boredom.
Life's like this calmly.
- What kind of adventures await You then?
- Perhaps you're right.
But even before I was engaged,
there was at least
the possibility of some adventure.
From something secret.
Now I feel as imprisoned.
I could not do it.
He was not the love of my life.
Oh, and women get cold feet.
It's more than 'cold feet'.
And why then the dress?
I woke up and suddenly panicked.
I thought, pulling it at times, may bring
it get me down and I feel better.
But everything was worse
and then woke up all.
I thought I can not go back.
So I got into the car and drove off.
Do you have something underneath...
You know. Something like 'Blue'?
That's everything you
interested in the whole story?
Okay, sorry.
But has your family
somehow not afraid for you?
Yes.
Then call them but to please.
I can not at the moment.
I'm embarrassed,
we can not just continue?
- After 'Cavo Greco'?
- Yes.
And not on the highway,
when it's done.
Then that will certainly
take a long time.
That's okay, as long as we
sunset are there.
As they want.
Oh, just so,
I do not even know your name?
Oh yes?
I do not know what you want,
at the end of the two are together.
- But they do not stay. - Stay still.
- No, no chance.
- But of course.
- Definitely not.
How can you know that?
In the film, they come together.
Yes, but it will not hold.
What? How so?
Johnny and Baby,
they come from different worlds.
It is a small,
rich princess and he is a bum.
Eventually, she had enough of 'Dirty Dancing'
and leaves him for a lawyer or something.
Yes, but you forget,
that the two of them but love.
- Not such a big thing.
- What?
Lust? Yes. Love? No.
Because this whole Liebesgetue
is a product of movies and society
and we should believe in it.
- They do not believe in love?
- Of course, love between friends,
in the family, yes, but not at the
'romantic love'. They do not exist.
Are you crazy,
as you can only...
- How can you say such a thing?
- Because it's the truth?
The whole history of the world
shows yet but that love exists.
Empires on up
and fell because of love,
- People sacrificed their soul...
- That is not love.
That is an illusion. That is a
temporary feeling of infatuation.
It can never remain forever.
Why probably ending any
great romance with a bad breakup?
To create the illusion alive.
Not every great romance ends
in a nasty separation, that's ridiculous.
'Romeo and Juliet'.
'Casablanca'.
'Gone with the Wind', 'Titanic'...
- 'Pretty Woman'.
- That's not a great romance.
What the hell, that should now?
- I'm afraid of goats.
- What?
- Buckle up.
- What is this belt-obsession?
Just do it.
So, you love him?
I mean, this magical feeling,
to which you want to believe so deeply.
- I thought.
- Is the feeling gone?
No. I just think,
that it was wrong to begin with.
- So you do not love him?
- No, I love him, it's just not Filmlie...
Say it.
No movie love. Say's already going on.
You women, you have the film industry ruined,
looking around this romantic comedies
and thinks that the
True love should be as accurate.
- All these films are based on something yet.
- Yes, on one's imagination.
- True love exists. - You need to be crazy,
do you think that really.
And you do not believe,
So you are crazy.
Can you keep a short time? - What, here?
- Yes. - How so? - Just for a second.
Here.
Hold the.
- What are you looking for?
- Messages. There are certainly some news.
- Leave me.
- Oh thank you.
- What are you doing just?
- The Beginning previously loosely.
That was not easy,
You have aborted him.
Do you know how hard it is,
to find these parts?
I'm sorry,
it happened by accident.
By mistake.
Do you realize,
that you are going to destroy me?
Now you are sometimes not as dramatic.
It is also clear,
that you know nothing about love.
- I know a lot and that's enough
for me also. - Oh yes? - Yes.
- There is even a scientific Declaration.
- Of course there's the.
We men are programmed to
to find a wife.
Because our biological
Determination is to procreate us.
Then we find that particular person
and our brain secretes dopamine.
What identical
the same effect as cocaine.
And why turn
people through when they fall in love.
- Real a stupid photo.
- Can you put away that, please?
You are suddenly
an obsessive man.
You can not stop,
to think about them.
That's why you want it,
like a drug.
And these hormonal state describes
anyone who can, stupidly as 'love'.
- Is that your mother?
- Yes.
Then, finally,
Are you sleeping with the person.
And another chemical
is active, Oxitocin.
The stimulated the togetherness.
Whereas it is important because the couple
so long together,
until the boy has grown.
So, there you have it:
Dopamine and Oxitocin.
Where is your father?
I have no idea.
It is a forced brainwashing,
that connects us with one person,
they have to get married
and to have babies.
That is our specific
Survival mechanism.
Of these poets and dreamers
transfigured as love. Damn it!
Oh, oh, hold on!
- Hold on.
- What? - Let me go a bit.
- No, it already. I am okay.
- Hold on, immediately.
Chill out, You must not drive.
I'm going to "The Ants Go Marching" sing,
continue until you.
You're welcome.
♪ The ants go marching one by one
Hurrah, hurray!
The little one stops to suck her thumb
♪ And They all go marching down
♪ To The Ground to get out of the rain
Baram Baram, Baram
♪ The ants go marching one by one
Hurrah, hurray!
♪ The ants go marching eight by eight
Okay! Hey, stop!
Now, right now, okay?
It's nothing,
I'll stop immediately.
The car belongs to you, okay?
Satisfied?
Jesus Christ, my ears.
Hey! Hello! What...
You should have seen your face.
Come on, get a.
Oh, no, please! Come!
That was the last time you promised.
Come.
Keep them.
Thank you very much.
- Go barefoot?
- You want me to go with it?
Good argument.
Hey!
Where the hell are we?!
Listen.
What should I hear?
Nothingness.
Is not it grand?
You can not see anything
and nothing hear for miles.
Yes, for example the road.
Where is the street?
We will the road back.
Can not you be quiet
and enjoy the moment?
Would you dance with me?
Exactly here?
What?
This dress deserves a dance.
- No.
- Why not?
- No one will look.
- We are sorry, no.
Okay.
Are not you hot in that?
No.
- Drag at least, the gloves.
- This is an ensemble.
So where is the road?
Buckle up, please.
What you just do?
You're right, it's hot.
Stupid petticoat.
If you were single,
would you data myself?
- I think I am now single.
- No they are not.
There's still hope.
And you are not distracting.
Whether I'd data?
No.
Why not?
You must be crazy for me.
- It's just not a very good day.
- I wish you a good few days,
before you to be proud again.
And you have to get rid of the dress.
They act so much too greedy.
I am sure that I
would data on a good day.
- Do not be but please so condescending.
- Am I that?
You should be afraid of anything.
- Hey.
- How are you?
- Do not like it.
Listen, I do not know what's wrong with
you, or who is the woman with you, but...
It is no one, as I said.
Anyway.
Come home, so we can talk.
If you want that too,
you need to come home.
I'm going tonight
be at our meeting place.
You can decide whether you want me
want to meet. I'll be there at eight, okay?
- Okay.
- This is our last chance, George.
I can not take it anymore.
Eight clock.
- Okay.
- What did she say? - That they want to
meet today evening with me.
That sounds good, right?
I don't know.
- Please, stop.
- How so? - Just stop.
You should turn on the spot
and go back to her.
No idea on what kind of love
They think. You love it.
I love them now.
- Okay. - But how it will probably
look in the future with it?
Do not know whether you
in ten years are still alive.
What's with you and 'Cavo Gredo'?
For me, everything will be fine,
I'll find out it.
We should at least
experience the views.
Buckle up.
What are they doing?
They will not be back in time.
- However, I will. Buckle up.
- It's nothing.
Maybe Are you hungry?
Can you see it,
we can 'Cavo Greco' drive to
and I'll even sooner be back.
Okay, maybe not really earlier,
but we can do it.
So you eat.
- Know the 'Ham and Eggs-likeness'?
- That what?
That life as 'Ham and Eggs' is.
The more one is involved,
the more connected you are.
What does that have
to do with 'Ham and Eggs'?
'Ham and Eggs' is the difference
between involved and connected.
Chicken is involved,
Pork is more than that.
So, how was that out?
- In a restaurant.
- Why do people mean?
Well, he has the sandwich
taken apart.
No wonder,
that you have forsaken him.
He did not know better
and I said 'Yes'.
I was so in love,
I even had dance lessons.
Forget it.
What a pity.
I have a friend,
of has a crush on me
and says that,
he would make me a request,
he would surprise me with it,
me to make him while driving or something.
So, like, "We go left here
and will you marry me?"
And he has the ring
hidden in the glove compartment.
Is not that sweet?
- Well, you will find something nice?
- Yes. How would you do it?
You tell me.
No idea...
I have no master plan.
I just think that when the time comes,
I'll just ask.
I do not understand you.
What can you find only
on the idea of ​​marriage,
- if you do not believe in love?
- That's what I did not say that.
But, sure.
No, I said, 'romantic love'
or the imagination of eternity.
- Do we have a wedding today?
- Oh, no, certainly not.
- No no. No wedding.
- No, no wedding.
- But what about the dress?
- No, I have tried it only once.
We got lost
and are randomly ended up here.
- Just for practice. - We are already gone.
- You got married elsewhere
- and want to make here only photos.
- No, we're blown. - What?
- Do not say something like that.
- That he the nowadays still makes...
- What's now with the ring?
- What about it?
If you do not have special
Moment for the request search,
as they say,
what happens to the ring?
- No idea.
- Do you have a case?
No no no no.
Wow!
The is beautiful.
Listen, put it back.
In fact, you have to ring it.
I do not understand,
why you bought a ring,
if you do not want to ask?
Well, I guess,
it's like your dress.
I wanted to buy the ring,
so I can take the next step.
To give himself courage,
that's a pretty expensive way.
I think, They want it really.
I don't know. I think I should
really have the courage to ask them.
If it were not so difficult.
I think this means
that they are not frivolous.
Maybe make you worry too much,
but you are not frivolous.
Can I plug him?
No.
Listen, put him back easily.
Come on, what are you?
Superstitious?
Seriously now?
See, that's it,
what I'm talking all the time,
stop it,
to be so damn scared, please.
Shit!
Okay, that was not my fault.
What?
Say already.
They are just amazing.
You need the most irresponsible
Person that I've ever met.
Know the Meaning
the word 'consequence'?
Makes your behavior
other people unhappy.
Without a word, you knock on the wedding
and destroy her husband's life.
Your family must perish with worry,
but apparently not interested.
And who knows exactly what the
is with the police or 'Cavo Greco'?
Finds there instead of the ceremony?
Right there?
And now you lose even my ring!
You do not know anything
about me or my story.
And maybe I'm stupid,
but I'm not so paralyzed
from fear of the future,
I prefer doing nothing.
- I am paralyzed by fear?
- Yes!
God forbid, only enter into no risk
or even do something out of the ordinary.
What are you so afraid of what is
the worst that can happen?
This one!
They!
They live in a fantasy world!
What do you want to deny?
Keep people
not suddenly occupied dance
or not fall in love in a miraculous
Way or glued to each other forever.
The huge disappointment,
you prepare,
ruin the lives
all other around them.
Hey, Mom.
- Where are you?
- I told you that I drive a car.
to drive a car?
Where are you going?
- Mom, please.
- I've been expecting you for lunch.
Yes I know.
- There are Koupepia.
- I'm sorry. - It's all right.
I was just all morning
stood in the kitchen
and now thrown away everything.
Do you understand?
- Did you eat A Sandwich? - Yes.
- What? What did you eat?
This is not a meal.
And did you sleep?
I do not understand,
Why are you just disappeared.
Mom, I'm not
just disappeared, okay?
something happen with Christina?
Oh, no, you're killing me
even into the grave, you're killing me.
Mom, relax, I take care
to make things with Christina, okay?
It's been three years.
What are you waiting for?
You'll find no more like them.
And they deserve something better.
Yes, you're right, Mom, she has something better
earned more than me. Maybe I should quit Use
and then they can perfect their
Find husband. How's would it?
- I did not mean...
- Give me the Hello..
- Hi, I'm a friend your son's.
- Who's there?
. Yes - You do not mean...
- - Oh, no, no, do not worry.
We have nothing or something.
I am engaged. I was engaged to someone.
Anyway.
I just wanted you to know,
that a have wonderful son.
He's nice, he's honest
and apart from that,
how stupid he often sounds,
He does not hang people.
He could not be better,
he has only one really bad day.
So, if you ask me,
they should be happy to have him.
- I do not understand anything.
- What is? I beg your pardon.
I can not hear you.
I think we have no signal.
Hello - We are sorry.
- Give me George. Immediately!
Do you hear me? Hello?
Hey, thank you very much.
- Was I really?
- No idea.
- Favorite band?
- 'The Police'.
- Favorite book?
- 'A Tale of Two Cities'.
- Is that yours?
- No. That's Chris.
- Bands?
- Norman Rockwell.
Yes.
Favorite painting?
'Lady Godiva' by Collier.
- Was that the one naked
riding a horse? - Yes. - Okay.
- Best holiday.
- My birthday.
- This is no holiday.
- For me it is.
- Wear a garter?
- You will at times nothing.
But if I did,
it would not be blue, but pink.
Favorite quote?
What of Nietzsche,
something like, 'this dance'...
- 'Music'...
- Yes, that must really be a favorite quote.
What is that, please,
I have long thought about.
The most spontaneous,
what you have ever done?
This one.
The best compliment so far?
- This one.
- Oh, come on, please.
Your worst pick-up line?
You look like my
first woman from.
And you have to ask me now,
how many times I was married.
Oh, but what about...
How many times had it?
Not once.
Oh, my God, that's so pathetic,
have you really say that?
Yes I know.
I was very drunk.
She knew right away
what do you think really about marriage.
- I told it to Christina.
- Poor woman.
This can not be true,
They should really shoot it.
Maybe I should give her
so make the request. Yes.
Yeah, maybe you should.
- Hey buddy.
- Hey. What's happening? Where are you?
- I am on the way to 'Cavo Greco'.
- Okay, your mother has just freaked out.
- What, they called you?
- Yes, they did and she said,
you with another woman
are blown.
- Hello
- Yes. - What's going on?
Nothing's going on, I'm going
a bit through the area.
alone - As I said,
I'm traveling with this bride.
Listen, it's not,
what it looks like, okay?
Have you talked to Christina?
Yes, she wants to meet with me today
evening. - Okay, that sounds good, or?
I do not know, we will see.
What the hell,
does that mean again?
I'm not sure yet, if I go.
And what are you doing
with this bride?
I might bring them,
where they want to go, I guess.
Is she hot?
Well, it is unusual.
All right.
Okay, buddy, but remember,
that during your small excursion
everyone goes me on my eggs.
- That's what you deserve.
- Shut.
What will you do?
- What do you mean?
- With your girlfriend?
What do you think,
what should I do?
Honest.
Why interesting my opinion?
Let's say,
one year I do not want someone
in my wedding suit
be gleaned on the road.
They have the best
Experience with such things.
How nice that I will
can help with it.
So what do you think?
Well...
Whatever you do,
Be just a coward here.
If you want it,
then you must be brave.
But, if not,
Be the decency to tell her that.
Waste
Christina's no longer time.
You must not be a coward,
like me.
- You're not a coward.
- Yes, I am.
Instead of me problems
question about, I'm running away.
- Sometimes you need time, to be brave.
- How much time do you need?
Approximately one day.
I'm just kidding.
While it lasts.
So what will you do?
Why are we not both cowards
and run away together?
So what's going on?
Nothing at all.
Do you know,
nothing makes men more crazy,
as if a woman says that nothing is going on, where
it is very clear but that something is going on.
- And why do you ask if you know that
it is quite clear? - We could fix it.
That can not fix it.
My name is Eva.
I am pleased,
to get to know you.
Do you believe in destiny?
Not really.
I believe in free will.
Determines your will
not your destiny?
Well, then it's
not really fate, right?
All right. There is a reason,
that we met today.
- That was fate.
- Yes? What is our destiny?
That's not decided yet.
Then there is free will,
no fate.
Okay, what is your will,
what should be your fate?
Let him put us out of the way.
I'll take that to not.
- What?
- We should just go around it.
- We can not here do not, that's dangerous.
- All right.
- There's something in there.
- Okay. So, stay away and let us go.
- Come on.
- No curiosity?
- Curious? What then? - Then what's inside.
- No.
What if it's a million?
And if it's a bomb?
Yes, because here, the middle of nowhere,
a really worthwhile destination is.
Why do you want the box
absolutely open?
I just want to know what's inside.
- Why are you not a little curious?
- Because it does not interest me.
Have you ever
part of 'Pandora's box'?
Some things
better stay unopened.
I have not before,
the 'pure evil' to unleash.
- It could be a human head.
- The moves?
Well, let me a stick
or something will find that open.
Only Do not touch it.
Not, do not...
Okay, it do not take up...
Oh, she takes him up.
You do not know where he comes from
and perhaps he is ill.
- Look how cute.
- I know where that leads.
- Can we keep him?
- No.
We?
I mean, me.
I want to keep him.
This thing
does not come to me in my car.
Thank you, Uncle George.
Say thank you, Uncle George.
You know that the
is a great responsibility, right?
Responsibility.
How scary. Yes. Yes!
Hey, you're bleeding?
No, that's nothing,
that's just an old wound.
Must be risen,
when I played with the puppies.
- And will not you see?
- No, it's fine.
I'll tell you what. At the next stop
you can buy me bandages,
if it makes you feel better.
Okay.
KIOSK
patient disappears from mental hospital
Everything OK?
Yes sure.
How do you feel?
I'm fine.
I love my flip flop.
Why did you stop?
Actually, I still have time.
Oh well.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay, you can take the little guy?
Well, go.
Come on, take off.
Take off.
- What now?
- Hey, I have a problem.
Please do not.
The bride is a patient who had fled
from a mental hospital.
Why?
What did you?
No, I mean really.
It is in fact in psychological treatment.
What the hell,
is there to laugh about?
How do you the know?
From the newspaper,
black on white.
Apparently she wanted ago
one years to marry a man,
but cut down before the altar
and had a nervous breakdown,
So the family has
put them in the hospital.
And now she has broken
and in my car.
And she knows that you know
- No.
Okay.
How crazy is it?
I mean, is it 'I-slay-dense
with-a-ice pick 'crazy,
or crazy as usual?
What do I know?
She seems to be normal. It was...
It was a great day with her.
Maybe you're just as crazy.
Could you please stop
and just tell me what should I do?
Bring her back,
That you should do.
But maybe there's
for everything a reason.
Oh, my God.
You like them, am I right?
Listen, it does not concern me at all
nothing on, anyway, so...
She wanted to go
Be 'Cavo Greco' brought.
I'll bring them back and then
we just go separate ways.
Are you completely crazy?
- How so?
- You're going after 'Cavo Greco'?
Yes and?
You want a crazy girl
bring to a cliff?
Yes, you look so... if
Is that a dog?
Hi!
Well, who do we have here,
you sweet little thing.
Was it nice, yeah?
Here, again better
Thank you for bandages.
Eva?
Yes, George?
You know,
the day is almost over.
If you can not call anybody
and say that everything is okay?
I can not.
Not yet.
- So what happens next?
- But what then?
This, now,
where you are a free woman.
I start by, I guess.
And you're ready for that?
Its possible.
Hiking trail Cape
We are there.
Is not that great?
Wait wait.
I have to ask you something.
So what's going on?
Why are we really here?
- What do you mean by that? - What's really going on?
- What do you mean, what's really going on?
Your story
stand today in the morning newspaper.
- Let me go!
- No no!
- What is this, I just wanted here!
- Take off your gloves.
No! - Take them off.
- No! - Why are we here?
Let me go! - No.
- You are hurting me! - I want to help you.
- Only, please be honest with me, please.
- All I wanted was just here.
- How so?!
- That's why!
Because I've always been here,
before all this happened.
Before I was someone's girlfriend.
Or fiancee
or pathetic ex-fiancee.
And before I was sent away.
When I was just myself
and I just wanted to remind you.
Could not you talk about it?
What to talk about?
Do you feel better?
Yes, almost.
I should hurry,
before it is really good.
Okay.
Would you bring me back?
Is the same direction,
in which I have to.
- And you're sure, that we're really here?
- Yes. For sure.
But there's nothing here.
Only ten minutes walk.
Then let me take you.
No.
You're welcome.
Especially because I flip flop
have, it will go fast.
What about the little one here?
I'll keep him.
Honestly?
Yes.
Wait wait...
You need a little more light.
You'll get a flashlight.
Be brave.
Oh, wait.
Which reminds me...
What?
"And those who were seen dancing were those
, the music could not hear as crazy."
www.moviesubtitles.org