-= Last Dance =-
With no warmth inside
we surely will shiver
So we sleep
We sleep so satisfied
Lay down, lay down, lay down
Down and feed
And feed the fire
Lay down, lay down, lay down
Down and feed
Think I'm lost
with all your promises
Think I act strange
when you talk to me
Oh, that's gonna kill you.
...represent concepts.
Now, what you're...
I'm sorry. Could you tell me where
the chief of staff's office is, please?
- Sure. Up the stairs and to your left.
- Up the stairs. Thanks.
The one nearest the front door
at the crossing represents justice.
- Hi.
- I'm Rick Hayes.
- I'm here to see John Hayes.
- Oh, you're John's brother.
Yeah, among other things.
- Louise, John's brother is here.
- Okay.
- He's right here in the conference room.
- Great.
We should take each case
on its merits.
Now, we have restricted
out-of-state travel...
and we've delayed the purchase
of new state vehicles.
It doesn't sound like enough.
We have to trim ten million...
from department spending over
the next fiscal year. John?
I've requested the department trim
five percent across the board,
except for education.
Okay. But we're gonna have to
find some additional measures.
Cutbacks? With an election
next year, it might...
You want the tooth fairy to come,
you're gonna have to put some teeth
under the pillow.
Agreed. With what we've done,
we're now in a position to take stock...
make our judgments regarding
the staffing and expenditures...
and we will take a long, hard,
critical look at all...
I'm just trying to figure out what kind of
idiot shows up his first day of work...
late and stinking of wine.
I guess now you know.
You wanna try to explain
your resume?
- What do you mean?
- Well, you went to law school.
Did pretty well.
Worked for Hayes Development for
three years. Working for your old man?
- On and off.
- Mmm.
And then there's this gaping hole.
What have you been doing with
yourself for the last two years?
Well, my father passed away. Maybe you
know. I helped settle his affairs.
And after that?
Um, well, after that I, uh, I did
some travelling and I, I just
tried some different things.
Partied for two years.
Well, call it what you want.
Okay. What do you want to do?
- What do I wanna do?
- Hell, it's your call.
Your brother's
the governor's chief of staff.
Well, um...
Well, while you think about it, I'll get you
a desk and a subscription to Playboy.
Of course, if you're interested in actually
working, I'm up to my butt here.
Yeah, I'd like to give it a try.
You know anything about this office?
You know what clemency is?
Yeah, it's the power to pardon
people, commute sentences.
- Whose power?
- I believe, the governor's.
In this state, his sole power.
He makes the final decision.
The Clemency Office makes
recommendations, but we're not here
to retry the case.
This is about mercy.
Has the prisoner rehabilitated himself?
Will solid citizens
speak out on his behalf?
Does his own mother
have anything good to say?
- Will I get some kind of training for this?
- Yeah, by doing it.
Well, this is it...
124 pending cases.
Everything from tax fraud
to murder.
Wow. How do you keep on top
of all of it?
You don't. You prioritize.
I've got death warrants
coming down any day.
Obviously they come first.
Every time a death warrant is issued or
reissued, we have to make a new report.
- You know anything about John Reese?
- Uh, yeah, John Reese.
That's the cop killer who pleaded
self-defence, right? I saw him
on 60 Minutes
Right. Yeah. Big celebrity.
Even wrote a book.
Every time I see him, he gives me one.
Couldn't get through the damn thing.
- Well, great. I'll take Reese.
- No, I've already got that one started.
Take Cindy Liggett.
Look through her file.
- It's a death penalty case?
- Yep.
- Get your dick wet with Liggett.
- Okay.
Helen'll get you a desk and a Playboy
if you change your mind.
- Slow down, slow down.
- All right.
Are we there?
All right. Okay.
Well, what do you think?
It's not bad, huh?
Bedroom, bathroom,
office area up there...
and gourmet kitchen
and swimming pool.
Never know who you'll meet
down there.
- And I got you into the tennis club.
- What's this?
- Oh, you'll be needing that.
- I got a tux.
It's an Armani.
I thought the days of profligate
spending were over, John.
Oh, don't worry about it. You're in the
majors now, you gotta look the part.
Okay. Thanks.
Ah, don't look like somebody
slammed your nuts in the door.
- It's... It's gonna be good.
- I know.
- Wait and see.
Listen, it doesn't mean
the party's over.
It's just a better class of guests.
Well, you know, her crimes, you don't
think of a woman committing
a crime like that.
I mean, I don't, anyway.
That... That brutal.
Most of the time a woman kills,
it's a crime of passion.
Usually her husband
or her boyfriend.
And last time she got a stay of execution
with about four days left.
- Well, when was that?
- About 18 months ago.
It's all a delaying game, really.
They come up with some new
constitutional theory...
and find a sympathetic judge to grant
a stay, then they start appealing
all over again.
Right, and they just
stretch it out indefinitely.
Well, no, not this time.
It looks like she's run out of arguments.
- And a lot more women
are gonna be executed now.
- Why's that?
Women's lobby. They all want equal
treatment in the eyes of the law.
- Hey, Frances, what's up?
- Where you goin', girl?
What's goin' on?
- Hey, Frances!
- I'll tell you something now.
Don't be like that, Frances.
- Frances!
- Hey, Cindy, you checkin' out
of death row?
- You don't like it here?
- Hey. Hey!
...somebody. He don't need
to know my personal life.
I have my own life, and just because I have
a kid don't mean my life needs to stop...
and I need to stop
what I need to do.
She ain't the only one raising him.
The father raises him too.
Oh, yeah. On the weekends he...
And that's my business.
That's my time now.
How 'bout self-respect?
Every dollar you have, these sweet
and innocent-looking girls...
shamelessly tell us
they are money hungry and...
I'm Rick Hayes. I'm with the Clemency
Board. Would you like to have a seat?
I'm gonna be working on your report,
the update, so we need to...
- No.
- No?
No, we don't need
to do anything.
- Well, what do you mean?
- I'm not playin' your game.
Um, l...
Well, I don't understand.
It's one big, sick fuckin' joke.
- How's that?
- This governor doesn't give clemency.
Well, uh... What is it
that you're saying here?
I'm saying you go ahead
and you make your damn report...
then you give it to the governor and you
let him give it serious consideration...
then you can all go ahead and
kill me with a clear conscience.
Miss Liggett, maybe you can explain
to me... what is it that you have to lose?
I mean, there is really no good
reason for you not to cooperate.
Just give us something we can work with
here. There's gotta be a...
I'm very, very proud of my 17-year-old
'cause she works and goes to school...
What'd you say your name was?
Rick?
- Right.
- What's that short for?
- Eric? Richard?
- Richard, yeah.
- Mm-hmm. So, what's wrong
with Richard?
- What's wrong with Rick?
Every Rick I ever knew was a slick,
two-faced motherfucker.
- I know quite a few.
- Well, you just met one who isn't.
That's the first thing every slick,
two-faced motherfucker tells you.
All right, Miss Liggett.
Frances.
Wanna know what the second
thing they say is?
What do you got to lose?
- You should really think about this.
- I have.
For about 12 years.
You take care of yourself, Rick.
Gotta bust out some cash, anything.
I don't care what it is.
- What kind of presents do you get?
- Gold.
I got a bedroom set,
a TV, stereo...
- You got a bedroom set?
- Mm-hmm.
- Did your mom ask you where
it came from?
- No.
Well, we don't need
her cooperation anyway.
- What do you mean?
- The report's required, with or without it.
Oh, man, she is a pisser.
- Sounds like she sure as hell
had your number.
- Yeah.
- Rick, come on.
- Hey, John.
- Hey, Emerson. How are you?
- Hi.
- Lobbyist.
- For what?
- Oil companies.
Oh.
- The Brothers Hayes.
- Governor.
- John.
- My brother Rick.
- How are you, sir?
- Rick. Of course.
- Yes.
- Mrs Governor.
- Tom.
- Nice to meet you.
In the governor's business
we call this a "meet and greet."
Well, it wouldn't be hard
to get used to.
Bart, stay right where you are.
Don't have too much fun now, fellas.
The guy's in perpetual motion.
He's incredible.
Hey, you know, I've been glancing at the
files. He's never granted clemency, huh?
- No, not true. No. We've granted
15 pardons since I've been here...
- Yeah?
- And scores of sentence reductions.
- Never in a capital case.
No, not in a state where 76 percent of
the voters favour the death penalty.
Well, then why the hell did you
put me in a goddam useless job?
Oh, I figured if you messed up,
you couldn't do much damage.
Well, you're just a condescending
son of a bitch. Why is that?
- Oh, relax. Listen.
- No, no, I'm...
- If things work out...
- Hi there, you guys.
- There's an opening in the press office,
the first of the year.
- Ladies, ladies!
- Rick, this is my friend Jill Venable.
- And Jill, you know John, of course.
- Everyone knows John, of course.
- Hi, Jill.
- Hey, yeah, I know you.
- You used to live down the street from us
on Oakmont, right?
- That's right.
- She's almost the girl next door.
- That's sounds terrible.
- I don't remember you being so cute.
- Oh, well, thanks.
- I've been working on it.
- Well, it sure makes my job a lot easier.
- Your job, huh?
- Yeah, I'm supposed to take you around...
and introduce you to people
of power and influence.
Oh, I see. Big brother's
looking out for me again?
Oh, we can start with a few corrupt
committee chairmen,
work our way down.
Ah, none of that. Let's get a couple
of drinks and have a chat.
- Do you think your parking space
could've been further away?
- That's what I said. The...
- Is this it?
- Yeah, it's right here.
- Ohh. John must have found
this place for you.
- How could you possibly guess?
'Cause he's been here seven years
and still rents his furniture.
- We used to go out.
- Oh?
We're just friends now.
My decision.
I haven't had a chance to stock the bar
or unpack glasses, but I got some beer.
Great.
Haven't even had a chance to unpack
the stereo, unfortunately.
No drinks, no music.
How do you expect to make
any progress?
Well, l-I don't know. I guess I'll, uh, just
have to rely on some personal charm.
You might be in trouble.
Well, I could hum something.
What would you like to hear?
How about Beethoven's Ninth?
- That's a lot to ask on a first date.
- Well, I expect a lot.
Sorry.
My God, what is that?
I'm sorry. This is a case
I'm working on.
What's the matter, you don't come across
stuff like that in Consumer Affairs?
Uh, no.
- You got that?
- Okay, go on.
Write him I'm looking forward to when
he's on leave from the Marines...
so he can take me to that club
he wrote me about...
that Waikiki bar
in Honolulu, Hawaii.
- Hey, slow down.
- Honolulu?
- Child, what you talkin' about?
- Your pen pal said he's gonna
take you to Hawaii?
He's stationed in Korea, girl.
It ain't that far to go.
He said he gonna marry me
and have a big party there,
cause he know the owner.
Oh, yeah?
You're so full of shit.
- Did you tell him about
your other husband?
- Bitch, shut up.
Meet... you... in...
Honolu...
Is that two O's and two U's?
- I'm right here for you, girl.
- Let's just finish the letter.
Go on!
- Sam, good morning.
- Good morning.
Um, look, l-I've been
looking at this Liggett file.
L-I'd like to go back and see if
I can get her to work with us.
Oh. So now it's
a matter of pride, huh?
No, no, no, I just... I think it's the only way
we're gonna get anything new.
You're wasting your time, Rick.
You've got two dozen people
to reinterview for the update.
But they're all gonna say
the same thing, no?
You're not gonna get anything
out of Liggett.
She's making her stand.
I've been through this before.
Well, Sam, I'd at least
like to try.
Of course you would.
Everyone does the first time.
It's called
the rescuer syndrome.
That's great. I'm on the job three days,
I got a syndrome.
She won't deal with you. They served
her death warrant last night.
Execution's in 30 days.
- I got five more minutes.
- Visitor.
- Today?
- Someone from Clemency.
- Tell him I don't wanna see him.
- Hey, I'm not your social secretary.
Come on.
You know you are.
This is your last clemency report.
Open it up, take a look.
No, huh? I'll do it for you.
You just look at the cover page, okay?
That's all. Just the cover page.
You see what it says under
"recommendation"? "Deny clemency."
- I can read.
- Yeah? Well, that might as
well read "Let's kill her."
Now, you know why it says that?
Because you ain't give 'em anything.
- They had nothing to work with.
- How long you had this job?
Four days.
So basically,
you don't know jack shit.
That's right. I don't know why you're not
a good candidate for clemency.
Now, maybe if I had more experience
I'd just give up and write you off as well.
You probably think you know
everything about me.
I know what's in that file.
Look, even if I get clemency...
it means life in here with no parole,
and that's no life.
I'm not beggin' for mercy
I'm not gonna get.
You think I wanna die?
I do not wanna die. Okay?
- Well...
- But if I do, it's gonna be on my terms.
You got that? My terms.
That's all I got.
Frances!
They know how to harness Negroes
down south too, I hear.
With a strap across their back.
Come on.
Mmm. Hmm.
Get out of my house. Get out
of here, you thievin' whore!
Get out of my house, damn you!
Hey! What the fu...
Cindy!
Reg? Reggie?
Reg, you awake?
Reg? Reg?
Untamed youth with one thing on
their minds... Barq's Root Beer.
I know that you were
involved in her appeals.
That's right, and I assisted
Ed Duffy at the trial.
Listen, maybe we should
talk later. I got a hearing.
Just a minute. Is there anybody
else I should be talking to?
Her only family's a kid brother. It's been
a defence nightmare from day one.
- That's because of the brutality
of the crime.
- That, yeah.
And we only had nine days
to prepare for trial.
Well, now, the girl... she, in
fact, knew her in school, yes?
Yeah. And the boy was the son of none
other than of William J. McGuire.
McGuire? What, construction?
- Yeah. Hey.
- Hi, Linda.
- Listen.
McGuire wanted her to get the death
penalty, and he lobbied like hell for it.
- Huh.
- Listen, she got a tough break.
- Is there...
But it wasn't like she would've
ever gotten the sympathy vote.
Is there anybody out there with
anything good to say about her?
Nobody I'd let
baby-sit my child.
- You again.
- Me again.
- Well, it gets me away from the TVs.
- TVs?
Well, they got those TVs
down in the pod...
blastin' game shows
and soap operas all day long.
That's what I'd call cruel
and unusual punishment.
Yeah. No question.
Guess they figure by the time they get
around to killin' you, you'll be grateful.
Well, I'm just glad you consider me
a notch up from that kind of torture.
Just a notch.
What do you want?
Well, let's start with
some names, okay?
Anybody out there with anything
good to say about you?
When I was out in the free world,
there wasn't anything good about me.
- You could talk to Reggie.
- Oh? Who's Reggie?
She's my cell neighbour.
She killed both her husbands.
By the time they were about to arrest her,
she was just about to marry
number three.
Well, she... she might not make
the best character witness, uh...
- What about your brother?
- Billy?
I know he thinks I hate him,
but I don't.
I just wasn't a very good sister.
I was runnin' wild.
- Is he still in St. Charles?
- Last I heard.
He's almost 22.
His birthday's in April.
Were you close?
Well, we had different fathers.
Neither one of us knew 'em.
After my mama died,
it was just us.
Yeah, you were, uh, what, 16?
Yeah. She died two days
after my 16th birthday.
What was she like?
Pretty. Wild.
When she was feelin' good,
she could be a lot of fun.
She wasn't like
anybody's mama I knew.
We were more like sisters,
I guess.
She just couldn't stay clean. I guess
she passed that on to me.
Now, what is it
you're drawing there?
Oh. Well, sorry I asked.
It say in my file
I take drawing lessons?
- No, I don't think so.
- I do.
Through the mail.
Helps me pass the time.
You know, and every week they
give you something new to draw.
This week it's castles.
Takes me away.
Do you think you could get me
a picture of the Taj Mahal?
- Yeah. Why?
- I wanna draw it.
Taj Mahal? I expect that's
not too easy to draw.
Well, I got 23 and a half hours
a day to get it right.
No. No, hold our table.
We are on our way.
- Order a good bottle of red.
We'll be there in ten.
- No, Johnny, l...
- The ladies are not happy.
- You gotta apologize for me, cause I gotta work tonight.
- Aw, come on.
No, no, no, I been going through
the transcripts from the Liggett trial,
and listen to this...
- Sam gave you Liggett?
- Yeah. He's got that guy Henry Reese.
Well, Liggett shouldn't keep you that
busy. It's a pretty open-and-shut case.
- No, no, not necessarily.
- Huh? Well, it always
seemed that way to me.
- Yeah, but...
- And I'm familiar with the case.
No. L-I found this
police report, right?
Her brother said that she and her
codefendant had been up for two days...
smoking crack
and robbing houses.
At the sentencing hearing, her lawyer
doesn't say word one about drugs...
or intoxication or even a possible
lack of premeditation.
Well, that's a judgement call.
Yeah, but when juries vote to execute,
the key issue is intent.
I mean, was this murder intentional?
Was there a reasonable expectation
that death would result?
I was a prosecutor.
I know the law.
Well, then why didn't the lawyer use it?
'Cause this girl was blasted
out of her mind.
It would've at least raised
a doubt with the jury.
- Does it make it a clemency issue?
- No, not technically.
Then stay within the guidelines
of your office and wrap this one up.
Hold on. Does she have to die because
she had a lousy defence lawyer...
and the father of one of her victims
is a buddy of the governor?
No. She has to die because
she committed a double murder.
Well, I'm not saying that she doesn't
deserve to be behind bars.
I'm saying I don't think this woman
deserves to be put to death.
Let's go. Come on.
- Whoa.
- I want things to work out for you here.
- What does that mean?
- It means be sensible.
- Don't patronize me.
- Oh, not intended.
- Oh, I see. I'm just supposed
to shut up and be grateful...
- No, not grateful. Successful.
- And you're dead set on preventing it.
- Oh, boy, John, I really
appreciate your confidence.
- I want you to have a chance.
- Oh, by putting me in a job
where no one expects anything.
What have you done
to deserve anything more?
I think I've lost my appetite.
- Can you tell me where Morris lives?
- Next one.
Hi.
- Who are you?
- Uh, Miss Morris, well, I'm Rick Hayes.
I'm with the State Clemency Board.
- What's it about?
- Well, it's about your niece,
Cindy Liggett.
- No.
- No, she's not your niece?
- No. Not any more.
- Well, she did live here, yes?
- Mm-mmm. No. No.
- Well, uh, can I just ask you...
- There seems to be a...
- No.
Ooh, baby, you drive me
So don't send me home
I dressed up my windows
and I shined up my chrome
You're blowin'my gaskets
Lay down a five and I'll
show you my kitty cat.
Come here. I'd like to talk to you about
a girl named Cindy Liggett.
Don't turn up my heater
Don't shut off my light
How she got into it?
How far back you want me to go?
I mean, her mama's boyfriend
got her high on smack when she
was 14, and then he fucked her.
- So...
- Cindy got into fuckin' and shootin' up
because that's what her mama was into.
Tell me about
the girl she killed.
- Debbie Hunt.
- Yeah. What, you knew her?
Everybody knew Debbie.
Her daddy was foreman at McGuire.
You... Cindy's mom, she worked at
McGuire Lumber as well, yeah?
Hunt's bookkeeper. Hell, she couldn't
add water to orange juice.
What, like personal favours?
On-the-job services.
Sweet deal for old Hunt
till rumours started flyin'.
Then she spread it around she stole
from petty cash and fired her.
I'm sorry. You're saying that she knew this
when she went in that house that night.
It's like she was trying to
get even for her mom.
She was too screwed up
to know what she was doin'.
- I loved her and all, but...
- Did you see her that night?
You know if she
was on any drugs?
Look, I'm on next.
Doug? Hi. I'm, I'm Rick Hayes.
I'm with the Clemency Board.
The reason I'm here is, uh, it looks like
Cindy could be executed in three weeks.
- Uh-huh.
- Well, l-I'm just...
l-I'm wondering, uh,
now that it's ancient history...
if there was anything you might
like to add before it's too late.
- Like what?
- Well...
Well, l-I know you plea-bargained
down to second-degree murder...
- in exchange for testifying
against her at the trial...
- Yeah.
And at the trial you said
the whole thing was her idea.
- Actually, that's kind of unusual, isn't it?
- Why?
I don't know. I mean,
17-year-old guys...
don't usually let girls lead 'em
around, now, do they?
Maybe she was the one
that was unusual.
Th-The two of you had pulled off
quite a few burglaries that summer.
- So she masterminded all of'em.
- I was 17 fuckin' years old, boy.
Oh, uh, I see what you mean. She was...
She was older. She was, what, 19?
Yeah, 19, goin' on about 30.
And drugs. What kind of drugs
were you on?
Some weed, some beer.
- That's all?
- Yeah.
What about crack?
- Nah, no crack.
- You sure? Because the,
the police report...
- Am I sure?
- Yeah.
You think I'm ever gonna
forget that night?
Well, you would if it would save you from
being executed, now, wouldn't you?
- You're fuckin' with me.
- No, you help me, and maybe
I can help you.
- Did she send you?
- No.
She suckin' your cock?
Oh, shit, she can get a guy
to do anything she wants.
She's a cocksuckin' witch!
I'll kick your ass!
Fuckers!
Have you got mental problems?
Is that why they stuck you down here?
- Hey...
- 'Cause that's gotta be it.
- It got out of hand.
Listen to me. I don't care what your
name is. Your brother can fire my ass.
- Look...
- You're not here to retry this case or duke
it out with the prosecution's witness.
Sam, when I came here you asked me
if I wanted to work. That's all I'm
trying to do.
I thought you'd be a lazy bastard. I didn't
know you'd go into business for yourself.
Well, maybe the woman
doesn't deserve to die.
- That's not your decision, Rick.
- Okay.
- You understand? Huh?
- Yeah.
Good. Now, I'm reassigning you. Do some
fact checking on the John Reese report.
- What about all the interviews
I'm supposed to do?
- No, no, no, no. John Reese.
Or you're out of here.
Who do you think you are, man?
Get your butt over here.
Attention on the yard.
The following inmate, Labarber, Michelle,
report to the visiting room.
Well, I'll be damned.
- Hey, Reg?
- What?
Reg, come here.
I wanna show you something.
- You remember that guy?
- What guy?
- That guy from Clemency.
- Yeah. What?
- He sent me a picture of the Taj Mahal.
- The what?
The, the, the, the Taj Mahal.
It's this place in India.
This king built it
for his queen.
Oh, yeah, that's nice.
I like that.
Here, come on.
Hey, hey, let me see.
Cindy. Cindy,
turn it down this way.
- Got that?
- Oh, that's nice. Nice!
- That looks real good.
- Yeah, I've seen that one before.
- Oh, yeah. I bet you been
there a hundred times too.
- Well, I think it's pretty.
What's it say?
It says, "I wish you were there.
Sincerely, Slick Rick."
- What the hell's that mean?
- Oh, nothin'. Just a kind of a joke.
Good luck with your appeal,
Mr Reese. Goodbye.
Mr Reese, how are you? Hi.
- Where's Sam?
- Well, he had to work
on another case today.
- Who are you?
- I'm Rick Hayes.
- I'm gonna be working on your report.
- I can't believe Sam didn't come.
Well, uh, I'd just like to verify a few things,
if that's okay.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
- Tell me, have you read the report?
- Of course I read it.
- There's another letter comin'
you have to put in.
- Oh? From whom?
Dr Arnold Marks.
- What's the nature of the letter?
- You don't know who he is?
- No.
- He's the top cardiovascular
surgeon in New York City.
- Oh.
- And a personal friend.
He did my bypass.
Man read my book, came down here,
did my bypass, no charge.
Well, you have a lot of
impressive friends, Mr Reese.
Yeah, and right now I'm gonna need
every one of'em. You read my book?
- Yeah, I started it.
- Finish it.
- I plan to.
- You see the letter from the
dean of the Yale law school?
- Yeah.
- I've been corresponding with him.
I've strategized all my appeals,
you know. I taught myself.
I've taken control
of the killing machine.
Look at me.
Is he working
for the white girl now?
- What?
- Cindy Liggett.
Is she the one getting clemency?
Is that... That's why Sam's not here?
Mr Reese, the governor
determines who gets clemency.
Yeah, but what is
the smart money saying, huh?
I mean, who's gonna live, me or
the white girl? Who's he gonna forgive?
A man of colour
who earned a law degree...
who wrote a best-seller and won the
admiration of some of our best people...
or a white trash girl who
bludgeoned two people to pulp...
without blinking an eye?
They will be diminished...
by my death...
'cause I represent everything
they love and admire.
How they gonna go
and kill a man...
who has been on The New York
Times best-seller list?
- Hey there.
- Hey.
So, what's all that stuff?
Homework?
No, these are your trial transcripts. Um,
look, I'm not supposed to be here, okay?
- They took me off the case.
- How come?
Mmm, doesn't matter.
But there's stuff in here,
especially in your sentencing hearing.
- Forget it.
- Grounds for appeal that
haven't been raised. No...
- Just leave it alone.
- Think your lawyer really blew it.
- You might not have gotten
the death penalty.
- Well, it doesn't matter now, does it?
Yeah, it does to me.
What do I have to say to you?
Look, if you wanna be my buddy,
just come see me on Saturday, okay?
I got two left.
What... You tell me what it is I have to say
to you to get you to want to save your
own life.
- What is this with you, some
kind of ego thing or what?
- What?
You don't like to lose.
Is that it?
What are you
tryin' to prove here?
I'm just trying to do my job.
I mean, I guess this is
the first real job I've had.
I knew you was a rich boy.
Huh. Yeah? It shows, does it?
See, growing up I thought everyone lived
like me. I had a good time.
I mean, I graduated law school
and...
- I'm sorry. I don't want to bore you
with this, but I'd like to...
- I know.
I been listenin' to the same four
life stories for way too long now.
One more would be just great.
Well, uh, I graduated
law school and, uh...
I drew a salary from my dad's company,
and I travelled and I partied.
Tough. Breakin' my heart here.
Yeah, well, the recession hit
and my father's business fell apart.
I tried to help with
the company and...
I mean, we almost got things
turned around, but, uh,
a bunch of loans came due...
and, and one thing
led to another and, uh...
See, we ended up juggling the books
and borrowing on false collateral...
and we lost everything, and,
and I beat a fraud charge...
and, uh...
and l-I almost got disbarred.
I mean, I don't even
know how it all...
It's just...
One thing led to another.
Yeah, I know how that goes.
Yard recall and lockdown.
You gotta go.
- Well...
- See ya.
Saturday?
Saturday.
Sam! Hold on there.
- Goddam it, what are you trying to do?
- Just hold on one second.
Let me see that stick
you got in your hand.
- It's a sand wedge.
- Ah, well, you don't want
to use a sand wedge.
I'm up to my eyeballs in sand, and
you're telling me I don't want to use
a sand wedge?
- That's right. You wanna use
a pitching wedge.
- Just back off.
- Give me the sand wedge.
- Listen to me. Pitching wedge, okay?
Break your wrists off right away,
cut straight down into it.
Trust me.
All right, but if you're wrong you're
working the Department of Highways
tomorrow.
Okay.
Right down now.
- Okay!
- You're welcome.
Goddang. I forgot
who I was dealing with.
Probably grew up on the
ninth hole at White Sands.
Well, golf's about as close as we came
to any kind of organized religion.
Let's put it that way.
- The Reese reports ready to go?
- Well, yeah, except for
your recommendation.
- You want this in or out?
- You can take it out.
Why don't you finish up
on Liggett.
Go to St. Charles County and
do those last few interviews.
No problem.
Nice.
You gotta watch yourself, Rick.
You get sucked in,
it does nobody any good.
- You hear me?
- Yeah.
So you do all this work
on these capital cases...
for a governor who, who never
grants clemency, huh?
Always a first time.
- Well, how do you stay with it?
- I'm highly motivated.
If I don't pay my child support,
I'll end up in state prison.
You never get involved
emotionally?
You ever hear of a guy
named James Nichols?
Um, no, I don't think so.
I got to know him pretty well.
Big kid in a man's body.
Killed three people.
Yeah?
He wanted me to be there
at the end.
- Here you go.
- Made me promise.
They were still using the electric chair
then, and they messed up.
Took a long time
for Jimmy to die.
He started to burn, literally.
His knees fused together.
Smoke started coming off of him.
You could smell it.
Jesus.
I can still smell it.
This is her senior picture.
The high school dedicated
the full page.
They were all wild kids.
We let 'em run wild.
I mean, the things they were doin',
it could've happened to any of'em.
But I don't believe in killing.
"Thou shalt not kill."
Not even Cindy Liggett.
L-I can only i-imagine that must
be difficult for you to say.
Well, I'm not saying
that I forgive her...
although I'm trying.
God, I known her since
she was five years old...
and they were sweet kids.
It's just that
putting her to death...
is only gonna keep us
locked in this darkness.
Well, ma'am, would you consider signing
a statement on behalf of Miss Liggett?
No.
Bu... Can you tell me why not?
- Good day, sir.
- Hi. I'm Rick Hayes.
Mr McGuire's in the drawing
room waiting for you, sir.
Thank you.
Mr McGuire, hello.
- This is Mr Faring, my attorney.
- Hi. Rick Hayes.
You wanted some kind
of a statement.
Well, it's an update.
It's required by law.
A copy of this has already
been sent to the governor.
- All right.
- I'm not in the best of health.
But I promise you...
that I'm gonna live to see this
woman pay for what's she's done.
This scum brutally
murdered my son...
and she's brutally murdered
an entire family's chance...
for another moment
of peace or happiness.
There's nothing left
for us now except justice.
My boy would've been
about your age today.
He didn't deserve to die
like that.
What she did to him...
It had to be a closed casket.
Mr Hayes, what if
it was your son?
First time I picked her up
was on a Drunk and Disorderly.
I was a beat cop. She was 14.
Had a set of balls on her
even as a kid.
This was no surprise.
She and Barnes had committed at least
20 burglaries that we knew of
that summer.
The brutality of the crime...
uh, did that seem in character?
- Character.
- Yeah.
A crackhead's got no character.
Doug Barnes was so hot to cut
a deal with the D. A...
he testified against Cindy and then
tossed in a couple of dope dealers
just for good measure.
- I'll sign it after this hearing.
- Yes, sir.
I have to be in court
in 30 minutes.
Okay, we're just about
finished here, Mr Rusk.
- I am trying to find her brother though.
- Her brother.
- You think he's gonna help you?
- He's in Walkerton.
Next time he screws up,
state prison.
Okay, well, I appreciate
your time. Thank you.
You can include these
in your report, Mr Hayes.
They were considered too inflammatory
to be introduced at the trial.
I hear she's changed quite a bit in there.
Is that right?
- She has.
- That's great.
You know, it's a shame that these people
don't get to change.
They'll stay like this forever.
Look, I prosecuted this case.
It was my first big case,
and I know it cold.
The attorney general's office is totally
behind us, and so is the public...
and we're gonna see
this sentence carried out.
Now, you can dick around all you want,
but this sentence will be carried out.
It's good to see you, Joe.
"...call our grandfather
Grandpa."
Frances?
What time is it, Frances?
3.30. Saturday hours are over.
Shit.
Ain't no man worth
gettin' upset over.
Shut up.
You wanna get mad, I can give you
a lot better things to get mad about.
- Just stay out of it, bitch!
- Who you callin' bitch, bitch?
Calling' you bitch,
you stupid bitch!
You think anybody's gonna marry you
after you killed two husbands?
At least I ever got married.
That's more than you can say.
- Shut up!
- Girl, you losin' your mind.
...since the tender age
of 12 years old.
Carrie says that men are stupid,
and Carrie specializes in...
Hey.
Didn't think you were comin'.
Well, I was out of town.
So much for promises.
I was doing interviews
for your report.
Then I guess you know
everything now.
No, I know about the past.
You're not that person any more.
All right, look, I need you
to tell me about that night.
That night?
That night is...
inside me like this...
big, terrible shadow.
I hated Debbie Hunt.
I hated everything,
everything I didn't have.
And Debbie Hunt used to just
rub my nose in it.
And all that hate...
just blew everything apart.
I killed them.
I killed myself.
I know what I did.
I can't change that.
I can only change myself.
Uh, I guess there are just...
some things...
can't be forgiven.
Why not...
if a person's able to change?
'Cause the people doin' the
forgivin' have to change too.
Today for the first time
in my term as Governor...
in light of a number
of most-compelling reasons...
I am granting clemency
in a capital case.
I'm withdrawing my order of
execution for John Henry Reese...
and commuting his sentence
to life imprisonment.
- What about Liggett?
- There should be no mistake however...
- No.
- That I remain a strong proponent
of the death penalty...
- Why?
- And a firm believer of its place in our society.
- What the hell do you want, a religious conversion?
- Wouldn't have hurt.
- And I know the people of this state...
overwhelmingly agree with me.
- There are, however...
- Look...
- those rare occasions when
exceptions cry out.
- It's an issue of credibility.
- And the rule of law...
- Whose credibility?
- Mine.
Must acknowledge
extraordinary circumstances.
- I'll take a few questions now.
- Governor.
Governor, could you tell us
the compelling reasons
that prompted your decision...
to commute
Mr Reese's sentence?
- Mr Reese has gone as far as any prisoner I've ever seen...
- I stick my neck out, there better be a damn good reason.
- Transforming himself into a thinking, contributing...
- I don't see it with Liggett. Maybe you do. I'm sorry.
- This is about reelection, isn't it?
- Responsible and very unique voice.
It's about getting
the black vote, isn't it?
It's about clemency.
Governor, what about
the Liggett case?
Clemency was denied. Miss Liggett's
death warrant is set to be carried out...
at 12.01 a.m. On Saturday,
one week from today.
If it's carried out, Cindy Liggett will be
the first woman in 11 years...
to be executed in this state.
- Any comment?
- Miss Liggett committed a brutal
and senseless double murder.
Her sex made no difference to her victims.
It makes no difference to us
under our legal system.
- It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
I know.
Look, I've got an idea
for an appeal.
No, no. You've gotta keep
letting me fight this.
I am afraid to say no...
and I am afraid to say yes.
Look.
There is somethin'
you can do for me.
- One, two, three, hey!
- What's this about?
- I'm a friend of your sister's.
- One, two, three, hey!
- Here's how it is.
Uh, she's got six more days, okay?
Maybe you already know that.
Now she wanted me
to get you this.
You're the only family she's got.
She loves you.
- She said that?
- Yes, she did.
You'll be doin' K.P., boy!
Let's move it!
Six days.
We're doin' all we can.
I'm the one who turned her in.
Did you know that?
Look, she doesn't hold anything
against you, okay?
She's... She's actually grateful that
you stopped her. Believe me.
- The cops, they, um... they said
I'd be savin' her life.
- Yep.
What I did,
I did it to help her.
She was all messed up. Couldn't
tell what she was gonna do next.
I didn't know this
was gonna happen.
Listen, she knows all that,
all of it.
She's okay.
Come on, boys! Move it!
So my next trick, kids,
is very impressive, very exciting.
What I'm going to do is show you
a beautiful bouquet of flowers.
- Would ya like to see that?
- Yeah.
Would ya? Okay. Good.
Hold on. Ah, here they are.
Aren't they beautiful?
As you can see, there's blue...
and red and pink.
What's so funny? Why are you giggling?
What do you mean there's no flowers?
- Hi, I'm Rick Hayes. Remember?
- This happens to be my home.
- Look, I, I need your help. I'm sorr...
- It's my daughter's birthday.
Okay. Well, I need you to file a stay of
execution in Federal District Court
for Cindy Liggett.
- Mama, Vanessa took my M&Ms.
- Okay, sweetheart, go back.
I'll take care of it.
- Okay.
- I'll be right there.
L-I'm sorry. But we... we have some
big-time grounds for appeal here.
- What grounds?
- Well, ineffective counsel.
Basically, your partner Ed Duffy blew it.
- Oh, you got a hell of a nerve.
- All right. Well, you take a look
at this, uh...
I've got a police report here, okay?
And this is a statement made by
her brother before the arrest.
She and Doug Barnes had been
up for two days smokin' crack.
Now, he never introduced it.
You tell me why.
Well, I don't know. Maybe he felt a jury
sees a drug addict as subhuman.
You and I both know they'd be a lot more
likely to execute an addict.
Hey, we're talkin' a level of intoxication
here that might save her life.
- Oh, man, it was a strategic move.
- Oh, come on.
- Maybe he should have
pressed the drugs.
- We're six days from her execution.
This is the only chance
she's got.
Will you do it? Look, I'll handle
the research. I'll do the legwork.
- Mom, I wanna open my presents.
- In a minute, baby. In a minute.
One, two, three.
Abracadabra.
- I'll do my own research.
- Good.
Good night.
Good evening, sir.
Thanks.
Nice to see you.
- Hey.
- You made it.
- Yeah, I'm sorry I'm late, sweetie.
Well, you missed the soggy crab cakes
and the California champagne.
- Well, you look beautiful, though.
- Thank you.
- Hey, here's John.
- There he is.
- Hi. - Hi, how ya doin'?
- I'm good. You? - You okay?
- Yeah, everything's good.
- You free on Sunday, maybe
for some tennis or whatever?
Uh, yeah. Maybe.
Rick?
- They spent hundreds of thousands
on the building alone.
- Governor? Governor?
- Excuse me, sir. Hi. Um, I'd like to...
- Mr Hayes.
- Yes, sir.
- Clemency.
- Yes.
You fellas did a mighty
fine job on the Reese case.
- Thank you, sir. I'd like to talk to you
about Cindy Liggett.
- Liggett?
- Yes. I urge you to reconsider. - Oh, not now.
- I believe that this woman deserves clemency as well.
- This is completely inappropriate.
- It's all right.
- No, it isn't all right.
- We'll talk tomorrow in my office.
John, set that up.
- She had ineffective counsel.
- She should've been given a life sentence.
- I'm sorry.
- Shut up.
- Prison is the only stable environment...
- This is difficult for all of us, Mr Hayes.
- That this woman has ever known. Her life outside...
- Rick, come on.
- John, let go of me.
Her life outside was a nightmare.
She's changed. She's grown.
She's a different person now. Now,
we're... we're not settin' an example here.
We never gave her a chance to become
like us, sir! We've become like her.
You have an eloquent tongue, Mr Hayes.
Must run in the family.
- Well, Cindy Liggett didn't have a chance,
sir. And if you'd just...
- Now, you've had your turn!
Now, the rule of law demands that
this girl receive the maximum penalty
for what she did.
- Governor, you...
- May I finish?
- Yes.
- Now, if you don't like this particular law,
by all means, change it.
But in the meantime, it's my sworn duty
as governor to uphold the laws
as I find them.
You understand? You just pour
yourself a good, stiff drink.
- Enjoy the rest of the party
with your brother John.
- Sir.
- Let's go.
- Mark, I'm sorry about that.
Now, the building...
Young turks.
- I hope you know what you just did.
- John, the man pulls the switch.
Bottom line.
- Quiet. Quiet. Quiet. Quiet.
- Look, I don't care who hears this.
- What the hell is wrong with you?
- For what? Do you think this is about me?
- Do you know what you're doing?
- Yeah.
- You're ruining your life and mine too.
- What about her life?
- You can't change what's gonna happen.
- Then you try and stop me.
- I'm trying. Believe me, I'm trying.
- Uh-huh.
I kept you from being disbarred after
that mess with Dad, but I don't know.
- You've got me on this one, brother.
- What are you talkin' about?
- John, you think this is about us?
You and me?
- You tell me.
You are so way off. This is the first thing
ever that is not about you and me.
I figured I'd save you
the trouble.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
And congratulations on Reese.
You were right.
There's a first time for everything.
She has unlimited visiting time.
You know that, don't you?
Then I'd better get goin'.
Sam, thanks.
- Thanks?
- Hey, I don't regret anything
that's happened here.
It's the next four days
I'm worried about.
I wish I could tell you
something that would help, but...
- Well, there is somethin' you could do.
- What's that?
Well, her brother's up
at Walkerton Work Camp.
Now, if you could get him a visit with her,
that would mean a lot.
- I'll see what I can do.
- Well, that'd be great.
- See y'all.
- Bye, Rick.
- Hey, how's it goin'?
- I tried to reach you at the office.
- We heard on the appeal?
- We got turned down.
- Shit!
- This came this morning.
- No hearing, nothing. Just a ruling.
- Man.
Our next move should be Judge Gorman
on the Federal Court of Appeals.
He's a good guy.
- Who's that, Gorman?
- Yeah, Gorman.
- They're in recess now.
Can you track him down?
- Yeah, l-I'll get to work on it.
Look, uh, you should know I left the job.
I have no authority any more.
Well, great. Now that you're no longer a
third-rate bureaucrat, you can really help.
Well, let's hope so.
Mrs Gorman, I promise you I would not be
calling you at your home at this hour...
if it weren't urgent.
No, l-I understand. It's-It's...
It's his vacation, but...
Well... No, I'm...
I'm sorry, but...
Well, all right.
Uh, look, I'm sorry
to have bothered you.
- Hi.
- Remember me?
I've got a fully-stocked bar now.
Uh, this is for you.
He's a family friend...
and, uh, I guess
you'll be lookin' for a job.
- Senator Paul Hagan?
- He's looking for a new legislative aide.
He's expecting your call.
- No strings.
- No strings?
Well, I figure if you can
chase a lost cause, so can I.
I mean, uh...
What are you doin'?
I don't understand.
You're just...
You're throwing it away. L...
Is it some kind of...
romantic slumming?
- No.
- You're too young for a midlife crisis.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I don't get it.
- Look, Jill...
- No, I gotta go.
- You listen to me, Rick.
You have done more for me...
- No.
- Than anyone ever has.
- Look, it is not over, okay?
- There is a judge on Federal
Court Appeals.
- No.
- Yes.
I have screwed up a lot of things in my life.
This one I wanna do right.
Now, I want you to
get me somethin'. Okay?
Okay.
It's not so bad.
What isn't?
Knowin' what comes next.
What do you think
about this one?
Uh, it's...
It's fancy too.
I don't think it's that fancy.
Well, l-I just... It's something
simple, you know? Like, uh...
What exactly does
she need it for?
It doesn't matter.
What about this one?
It's simple.
Yeah.
I mean, would you donate
two dollars if you had two?
- This is the third time she's
done this to me.
- It's about time someone told her.
Well, I'm sorry.
There was nothing you or I
could've done. It's the system.
Well, we're the system.
Aw, wait a minute.
Why not let it go?
- You wouldn't understand, John.
- Try me.
Everyone gave up on her.
Meanwhile, the clock continues to count
down for death row inmate Cindy Liggett.
Sometime tomorrow evening, Liggett
is expected to be transferred...
to Men's State Prison, where she will
spend her last 48 hours on deathwatch.
Liggett was convicted of the murders
of Matt McGuire and Debbie Hunt...
in St. Charles 12 years ago, and her
execution has been scheduled
three times.
This time, however, her attorneys'efforts
to achieve a fourth stay...
appear not to have succeeded.
Thank you.
I hear there's some people up in Catesville
who are real eager to see you, Doug.
- I don't know anyone up there.
- It seems Cindy wasn't the only one
you put away when you copped your plea.
You also turned in your dealers.
Now, do you remember that?
- That's news to me.
- Oh, then you won't mind
being transferred, huh?
- What?
- Yeah. It's all arranged.
You see, someone I care about might die
'cause of one lyin' scumbag.
So I'm gonna send that scumbag
to Catesville.
- Do it.
- The two of you were out of
your mind on crack that night.
That fact could've saved her life.
Now, why'd you say it was only beer
and marijuana?
- I'll see you in Catesville.
- Hey, wait, wait, wait, wait.
- What the hell you want?
- I want a statement.
I want to know why you
kept quiet about the drugs.
- Well, they said to.
- Who told you to?
The D.A. Rusk.
The D.A. Instructed you to lie?
- And you won't get me moved?
- You sign this affidavit.
- Clemency Office.
- Hi, Helen. It's Rick. Did you have
any luck finding thejudge?
Yeah. Um, he's at the Gulf Winds Fishing
Camp somewhere near Marquesa Lake.
- But there's no phone.
- How'd you track him down there?
Well, Sam...
Sam says good luck.
- Tell Sam thank you.
- You're welcome, Rick. Bye.
You won't be able
to take those.
- Why not?
- It's a part of the procedure.
- What harm is a few drawings gonna do?
- I'm sorry, Cindy.
- Hey, Reg.
- Hey, baby girl.
Why'd you shave your head?
It's for you, girl. Nothing left to lose.
You know what I mean?
You keep the faith now.
Bye.
All right, Cindy.
Miss Liggett?
I'm Warden Laverty.
This is Reverend Cummins.
Officer Mulkey
will be right here.
Anything you want from the canteen
in the way of sodas or candy,
just let her know.
- And she'll also have a TV hooked up
for you to watch.
- No TVs.
That's okay too.
We will need for you to change
into that blue uniform there.
Cindy, I'm on 24-hour call.
I'll come to you
whenever you want.
Okay. Well...
we're going to try to make you
as comfortable as possible.
Thanks.
Okay, c'mon. Let's go.
Get your ass outta the car.
They go to the beach
every weekend.
- They got a V.C.R.
- Yeah, I'll get it.
Shit!
Oh, it's you, you fuckin' whore.
Get outta my house.
Get outta my house!
Get outta here, you thievin' whore!
There it is.
Judge Gorman!
Goddam it, Will! What the hell
are you doin' here anyway?
- Judge Gorman?
- Yes.
Your Honour, I'm sorry.
My name is Rick Hayes...
and I have a motion from State Legal Aid
to stay the execution of Cindy Liggett...
which is scheduled for 12.01 a.m.
This Saturday, tomorrow night.
Now, attached here you'll find
a witness's statement...
- that the prosecution attempted
to suppress evidence.
- All right, all right. I know the case.
Well, once you've read it, when might
we expect to hear from you?
I'll radio my ruling back
from the ranger station.
Thank you, sir.
All right.
Thank you.
DDKnews time, 12. 14.
In other news,
prison officials continue
preparations for the execution...
of double-murderer Cindy Liggett.
Unless a stay is issued, Liggett is
scheduled to die in less than 24 hours.
I found that judge.
I think he might help us.
- You gonna stay?
- Yeah.
To the end?
When I go,
will you be there?
It's too much to ask, huh?
No.
If it happens, I will be there.
I'm not a real breakfast person.
Yeah, I'm just a...
I'm a coffee man myself.
Me too.
You see arriving here today some
who are for capital punishment
while others are against it.
Others are carrying placards
saying "Cindy must die."
- Kill the bitch.
- Others saying, "Thou shalt not kill."
She know I'm comin'?
Well, she's gonna be
glad to see ya.
Bill?
Bill.
Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- I know.
I know, but what
you did was right.
I didn't know this would happen.
If I'd known...
I'm so glad that you're here.
Amazing Grace
How sweet the sound
- That saved a wretch like me
- You know damn well she should die!
- You over there with that sign!
- The crowd is becoming
more and more vocal.
As the hour of
the execution approaches...
every man, woman and child
that is gathered here...
- has some opinion, whether they think...
- Kill her!
Do you know what you're gonna do
when you get outta there?
N-No, I'm not sure yet.
Well, you better start
thinkin' about it.
You better make some plans. Listen to me.
You're gonna end up right back there.
- Hello.
- Linda. What's going on? Anything?
No, he hasn't called yet, Rick.
All right. What are we gonna do
if he turns us down?
Only place left is
the U.S. Supreme Court.
- Well, is there time?
- Not really.
You need fourJustices to issue a stay.
We'd need at least a day.
Well, then... then he just better come
through and that damn radio
better work.
- I hope so.
- Well, do it.
- All right.
- All right or yes? Look at me.
You better look me in the eye and say yes,
'cause I'll be watchin' you.
And I'm tellin' you, if you screw up,
I'm gonna come all the way back here
just to kick your ass.
- Oh, this is insane.
- I know. I'm sorry.
I mean, we don't pick up
that goddam signal, she's dead.
Listen, Rick, we've still got
some time. Don't give up.
Aw, Linda, he's gotta
come through.
- Man.
- I decided to stop watchin' my weight.
Filet mignon.
Yeah, I always wanted to try it.
Cindy, did you get
everything you asked for?
Looks like it.
Well, it's quite a meal.
Hope you enjoy it.
They get so nice
right before they kill ya.
Hello, Cindy.
How's that steak?
Fine... what I had of it.
Cindy, if you want me,
remember I'm just down the hall.
Well, right now I feel like I got
everything and everybody I need.
Oh, they sent these over
from Bridgeland.
They thought
you should have 'em.
Thank you.
Miss Liggett?
Dr Forrester would like
to see your arms.
This is hard for everyone.
We're going to get through
this together.
- Would you like a sedative?
- No.
- It's quite common.
- I'm not spendin' my last hour like that.
- Well, if you change your mind...
- I won't.
We'll be back
in about five minutes.
Bill, come here for a minute.
Now, listen to me.
We'll always be
brother and sister.
Nothing can ever
change that. Okay?
You're in my heart.
You know that? Hmm?
Now, you go on, okay?
- Well... - Look.
- Our timing wasn't exactly the best,
- was it?
Cindy?
"I have been directed
at 12.01 a. M...
"by the Superintendent of Prisons...
"to cause the sentence of death
to be executed on Cindy Leanne Liggett...
"by intravenous injection
of a substance or substances...
"in a lethal quantity sufficient to cause
the death of said Cindy Leanne Liggett...
and until the said
Cindy Leanne Liggett is dead."
Warden?
Yes?
Yes. Stand down.
Stand down!
- Calm down. Calm down. It's over! It's over.
- Stop it! Stop it!
- You've been saved. It's over.
- Stop it! No!
Cindy. Cindy.
You're saved. You're saved.
It's over. It's over.
It's over. It's okay.
Shh. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
In a surprise announcement,
Deputy Warden Marvin Heinrich...
here at Men's State Corrections informed
us just moments ago that the execution...
of Cindy Liggett scheduled for
12.00 midnight six minutes ago...
was abruptly cancelled three minutes
before it was to have been carried out.
We are told Federal District
Court Judge Byron Gorman...
issued the stay of execution based on
a petition from Miss Liggett's attorneys.
We have no idea on whether or when
the State will appeal this ruling.
You can see here we have
protestors on both sides.
We will follow this big story throughout
the night. This is Peter Bellows...
We stopped 'em.
- I can't take any more.
- No, no, come on. You hold on.
You hold onto me. I'm right
here for you. Come on.
I saw you.
I could feel
your eyes on me.
I know.
I wasn't scared.
- Good evening.
- Ah, gentlemen, I think you know
District Attorney Rusk.
- Pete, sorry to bring you out so late.
- Good to see you, Judge.
Your Honours, any questions
you might have...
any information you need,
I brought the files for each of you.
Thank you.
So that is their decision?
Mm-hmm. Hmm.
Good night.
Cindy, a special panel
of Federal Court of Appeals...
- was convened a short while ago.
- Oh, no.
The stay of execution has been lifted.
We've been ordered to proceed.
Are you kidding me? Are you kidding me?
What, they couldn't wait?
- This is...
- Let it go! Please.
You have got
to let me go now.
Yes.
Don't take your eyes off me.
...built by Shah Jahan
in 1631 to 1653...
in the memory of his
beloved wife, Mumtaz Mahal.
And Mumtaz Mahal means "the beautiful
ornament of the palace."
And she was so beautiful
that Shah Jahan...
and Shah Jahan
so loved his queen...
that he commissioned this
building to be as beautiful...
and inspiring
and graceful as she was...
that he made in soul
of his love and her beauty.
Darling
Don't you understand
I feel so ill at ease
The room is full of silence
And it's getting hard to breathe
Take this gilded cage of pain
And set me free
Take this overcoat of shame
It never did belong to me
I need to go outside
I need to leave the smoke
'Cause I can't go on living
In the same sick joke
It seems our lives have taken on
A different kind of twist.
Now that you have given me.
The perfect gift.
You have given me the gift.
For we have fallen.
From our shelves.
To face the truth.
About ourselves.
And we have tumbled.
From our tree.
Tumbled from our tree.
And I can almost.
I can almost hear
the rain fallin.
Don't you know it feels so good.
It feels so good.
So let's go out
into the rain again.
Just like we said
we always would.
(Felirat - Diesel)
(diesel.@mailbox.hu)