We came to get you.
You're not allowed on the tracks.
Please... Go.
How could they...
Come on.
Come!
Use Karate!
Go then! But Evert and I are coming too!
No, we're not!
Evert is going to die too.
- No!
Rupert, don't!
Rosenqvist will call the police.
We'll all end up in jail.
Stop it.
Rupert! Don't...
Come away from there.
Promise you won't do that ever again.
Or anything else.
I promise.
I won't.
You behave yourself now.
I feel faint.
- Have something hot to drink.
We can make you food.
Rainbow cake.
If you're tired we can clean up.
And we have
a Sugar Baby Love show, too.
Yeah. Evert.
Something happened in court.
That's why she was crazy.
Damned ostrick.
Ostrich! Learn to speak.
You're moving to Hym-Hym Hyrylä.
The court decided so.
What's happened to this?
It's gum. A food storage.
It belongs behind the toilet bowl!
It'll get hair all over it, shitwig!
Go. It'll be like an adventure.
Ok, let's go.
You say goodbye to Mom, too.
I'm not going if Mom's not coming.
Let go.
Are you going on a trip?
We're moving.
You lied. I hate you.
Where to?
- Some place called Hyrylä.
It's Skavaböle in Swedish.
I know even though I'm younger.
Is Evert moving too?
For me? You're giving it to me?
Time to leave the ladies
waving on the shore.
Will you ever come back?
I'm glad you're moving, retard.
Double retard.
- Shitstick.
Dearrest, rratarrse Rebecca Rosenqvist.
Bye.
Shitshoes!
"Don't show this to Rebecca.
Hi Lotta. I think you're pretty cute
or I mean beautiful.
There's no one prettier in the world.
I love you.
Don't call me a retard cause I'm not.
Yours truly, Evert Kallio."
Hyrylä is the center of Tuusula.
The writer Aleksis Kivi came to die there.
Composers, artists, sculptors... culture.
Hands up, outlaws!
What? Look, Hannes. A young faggot.
My name is Evert Kallio. What's yours?
- What the fuck's it to you, Bonanza.
Do it Keke, fart in his face!
Say you're sorry
that you look like a prick.
I'm sorry I look like a prick.
Stop! That's my brother.
Say you're sorry
that you look like a prick.
I'm sorry I look like a prick.
- Twice.
- Louder!
I'm sorry I look like a prick!
We have to go home for lunch.
Ta-dah!
Guess who just came in, Anneli?
Elvis and Aaron Presley?
Mister Rupert and Mister Evert.
You made something nice for us again?
Could it be chicken?
We should call Mom.
Do you like Dajm bars?
That reminds me, enjoy your chocolate-
and listen to this.
Slade!
Does it have "Cum On Feel The Noize"?
Took me forever to find it.
Are they as good as Dad's favorite, Elvis?
Let's set up a disco, boys!
Anneli, come and disco with us!
I'm going to call Mom.
You can't even dance.
Let's keep the phone bill down.
I'm starving...
Highly agitated... illogical speech...
manic psychosis...
Dangerous to others...
Signed: Ossi Kallio.
You're a real gentleman.
Head of the Board of Commerce.
Head of administration
at the National Board of Commerce.
Attorney. Inactive reserve...
Any Johnny Walker left?
Who's that?
Rupe, come meet the pearl of Hyrylä.
This is Tamara.
A dear friend of the Magician.
Was in a pageant, even.
- Blah. Miss Denim Finland.
Boy, how young you look.
Porcelain pop prince.
Did you steal my bottle?
I've had enough! Get out!
Did you find it?
- What?
Johnny Walker!
Where could it be... we just bought it.
The boys have hidden it.
Have you noticed you have
a jetty in your attic?
Don't you dare sell that!
It's a surprise for the boys.
Maybe I could sell these sugars...
From cafeterias.
I grab a few whenever I stop
some place for coffee.
There're some nice ones from abroad.
We could buy some yeast,
make some homebrew!
My bag...
How did that get in there...?
Why are you looking
at me like that, Rupert?
You don't think the Magician
came here to steal?
From the war.
Shrapnel?
Bullet.
I didn't kill anyone else.
He was my age.
Shot me in the throat.
When I went back in the morning...
Did Pekka doze off?
Pekka!
They're building tenements on Ilpo's farm-
he's selling everything for a pittance!
Why isn't Rupert speaking?
Hasn't said a word to me all week.
The silent treatment?
Rupert, what are you staring at?
You won't let him call. We were
supposed to see Mom this weekend.
It's only to help you adjust.
You'll see her later.
Evert, come here.
You wanna hear a secret?
Even Anneli doesn't know this.
I'm retired now. My spine is bent.
Ten years and it'll be like a barrel.
A rolling man gathers no moss.
They gave me a party at work,
cake, coffee, champagne and all.
The girls kissed me and the director
gave a speech.
It was shit, but who cares.
They gave me a nice vase with roses in it.
I threw the roses out
and put the sugars in.
Look, Evert.
We'll plant a mountain pine over there.
On that mound there.
It'll be real pretty.
You could even drop an urn there.
Don't tell Rupert.
Argh, I'm going to start crying again.
Anneli got a job in Germany as a diplomat.
Don't put on too much weight.
We stayed home to keep Dad company.
Well, well...
We didn't see Mom all winter.
Dad said she was ill or traveling-
and finally we were told
she didn't want to see us.
And we still weren't allowed
to use the phone.
Come.
Come and see!
What?
Do I look dreadful?
Does Pekka know about this?
They're my children.
Help, are they here already?
The door was open.
Father Kinnunen.
Just call me the Magician.
I sell carpets.
- We're not buying.
Kallio...
I knew an Eero Kallio during the war.
Medical captain. Any relation?
Yes, on my ex-husband's side.
But he doesn't live here anymore.
He moved to Hyrylä.
I don't need a carpet.
It's good to have something to stand on.
Boys, I got that nice Sugar Baby Love
record for you.
You could do your act later?
- Yeah!
I made you a train cake.
Are you hurt?
I can't do this.
- Sure you can. Just get up.
The little shits come in their
fancy cab to mess with me.
Pirjo?
- And you, you...
Go have some brewskies with Ossi!
Go to hell, all of you!
You crazy bitch!
That spring Dad worried about Evert.
His testicles wouldn't drop.
And I went to specialists,
he thought I had trouble with my eyes.
We wondered why Dad sometimes
smelled like Mom's perfume.
Rupert!
Come and shoot!
You can be Kaj Pahlman,
the banana kick man!
Notorious Kaj Pahlman
comes to take the penalty shot.
Up against Lev Yashin, the Black Spider.
What? Protest!
Pahlman threw a banana peel
at Yashin's feet!
He can't stay up!
What's going on?
From Anneli.
Hot damn, she's bought
you guys Lederhosen!
Now we'll practice some German
leather pants slap dance.
Joe's barn!
Jack Ass speaking.
Rupert...?
It's Mom...
Bumsky, come!
Why's your head so small, Jesus?
I don't want to go on.
Let's stop it right here.
I have to keep going.
I have bled all my blood.
Drip drip drip.
Have mercy, my Lord!
Bullet straight into the heart!
Luckily the sheriff's star stopped it.
Thank you, Jesus!
The fortress! Finally!
My mission is fulfilled.
That dinner hit the spot.
The fresh air sure makes you sleepy.
Now this mama is going to sleep.
My God! A man crawling in the desert!
It's my son, Black Leopard!
Here is the message
that will save the fortress!
My son! You died a hero's death!
Valiant Black Leopard!
This message will save the fortress
at its moment of despair!
Bravo! What a captivating performance!
Your death was very touching.
Auntie Hippa even shed a tear.
And it took him only half an hour.
Where's Anu?
She's resting.
Who all took part?
Bah. We did all the parts.
I was also Hoppalongheis and the Indian.
Evert tried to be Frank the Avenger,
and the barman...
At the funeral.
Whose?
- Your Mom's.
Was it a beautiful funeral?
Whose?
You didn't tell them?
Is she dead?
How did she die?
Heart attack.
When people die what age
are they in heaven?
Are they babies or old geezers or what?
Dunno.
Tell me a story.
But not Grimm.
Remember when we slept over
at Auntie Hippa's place?
The ceiling was made of boards.
Wasn't it?
Some sap kept running out of a knothole.
It looked like the ceiling was crying.
I said: "Don't cry ceiling,
ceiling don't cry".
Don't you, either.
Rupe. Can't you sleep?
Bring me some water?
Help me out.
We have to hide this.
We should call the clinic
and tell them to fetch him.
That's the stairway you're pissing in!
He's going crazy or something.
Then at least we'll get rid of him.
Rupe! You seen my Johnny Walker?
- You looking for a place to shit?
Yeah right.
Stop kidding, boys. Give it to me.
You want money?
I lost my wallet.
I kinda need some covers
for my schoolbooks.
Did that flathead ape take it?
Evert, why don't you kill yourself?
It disgusts me to look at you.
You found it.
Little dormouse, come here.
- Don't go.
I just want to talk.
You're a repulsive, disgusting child.
Don't! Sicko!
You stop, I stop.
It was no heart attack.
What?
Mom.
Your mother was very sensitive.
It was an accident.
You shut her in a mental hospital.
With Ossi's help.
You took us away.
Same as if you had killed her.
I loved your Mom!
And I loved you!
Hit me.
Hit me!
I'd get to make you happy for once.
Hug me then.
I won't let you hit Dad!
That's my gun. Stop playing with it.
Seems you take after your Dad.
Maybe I do.
You won't become like me.
You take after your mother.
I won't become anything.
Could someone shave my beard?
My clothes need changing.
Boys, you wanna go to the lake
and find a place for the jetty?
Boys!
Which party?
Pekka Kallio. Which party are you with?
Lasse's in trouble.
Here comes Putteman
at a dangerous speed!
Wow.
Easter witches.
Sure you can!
Aren't you going to answer?
Who's calling?
I am.
Boys!
Evert?
Wake up.
Lemme sleep, damnit.
I think your father is dead.
He's not getting out of bed.
He's not breathing.
A fine person, your Dad.
Evert...
If you see someone punch me-
you punch me, too.
You wanna go to Kurre's Bar?
Let's walk. Past Koivuhovi.
Get some color on your cheeks.
You're so pale.
Hurry up, so we'll have time
to get loaded.
Quick! The train is coming.
- Is my hair ok?
What?
Do I look pretty?
- Why...?
Give my love to the boys. And kisses.
I'm sorry.
Pirjo! Don't!
Distinguished public official,
long career in administration...
Father of two sons.
Sociable, well-loved...
Yep, and we'll keep it short.
I think that should be all.
Ok if I stay for a while?
I'd like to have a moment
alone with my Dad.
Of course.
Rupert.
How are you holding up?
Where's Evert?
- He left.
Said it wasn't Dad being buried.
- He's right.
Pekka is in another place already.
Rupert.
I have some of your father's old stocks.
Evert needs some covers
for his schoolbooks.
You don't know how much
I've thought of you.
Don't sneer at the Magician.
Nothing dies.
Nothing ever dies.
You lay it.
Thank you, Rupert.
Good night, sleep tight,
kissy kiss, buggy bug-
night night, et cetera et cetera.
You didn't come to the funeral.
- Did you have a good time?
We could make some coffee.
But there's no sugar.
Someone took Dad's sugar collection.
Anneli, maybe?
You shouldn't lie.
Don't you want to be my brother anymore?
One can't lie.
Or die before the other.
Or leave the other in trouble.
I guess I'll have to go live
with Anu and Ossi.
What are you going to do?
Will you stay here?
Where will you go?
To find a place for the jetty.
Will you ever come back?
I'll crawl through the desert-
and deliver a secret message
that will save the fortress.
And even Jesus will cry.
I wish something happened.