You'll meet two Chiefs on the Komodo Island.
Good luck, The Law of Jungle.
- Today, - Salute to the Chief.
it's the second part of the Komodo Island special.
A new Byung Man's Tribe is here to make legends.
Nobody in the jungle was as funny as these two.
He's a great entertainer...
who makes the Chief laugh.
That looks so ugly. Don't ever come again.
Byung Man and Soo Geun's hilarious jungle life starts soon.
They're coming.
Meanwhile, Byung Man's Tribe divided up into two teams...
to patrol the island.
Help me, Crab Man.
Wan, the Crab Man, was doing very well...
and they finally found a huge crab.
You can catch it.
It's a confrontational situation. What will the result be?
- Should I use a net? It's alive. - Go ahead.
(It's pretty big.)
- This is it. - What if it bites?
(They observe first before approaching it.)
- You can catch it. - Here.
(He pokes it.)
It's upset.
(It attacks back.)
(He approaches it carefully.)
(He prepares for a good aim.)
You caught it.
You got it.
(She's suddenly a fan of Wan.)
Let's take it in the net.
- But... - I'll hold it.
(Min Gyu tries to help.)
Should I do this?
Hold the back legs.
(It's still resisting a lot.)
It's so strong.
It ripped the net.
(It has a deadly weapon.)
(This is a matter of his pride as the Crab Man.)
(Let go.)
(They take a step back.)
I've never seen a crab like this. It's so strong.
It's holding onto this.
(It's holding onto the net.)
Let go. Please let go.
It won't let go.
(It's persistent.)
(They decide to take it as it is.)
- Just carry it like that. - It's so strong.
(That was a good fight.)
I can imagine how full this will be.
(It's enough to share.)
We can eat this.
- I'm hungry. - Let's go.
We can catch more crabs.
- Crab Man. - Crab Man.
Crab Man.
(They get to eat the crab because of him.)
(He's the Crab Man.)
Press it with your hands.
The Chief is not available to guide them,
but the team left on the Komodo Island...
worked together to secure food for dinner.
How do I catch this?
- Did you get it? - But these shrimps are good.
It's not a lot but they can share,
so they return home.
Meanwhile, the Chief and his team managed to catch a big fish.
I'm going to make fire but not burn the wood.
- Is this smoke? - Yes.
(Byung Man knows how to cook the food appropriately.)
- It'll take away all the smell. - I think so too.
- Smell the charcoal. - It looks so good.
(The smell of the charcoal seeps through the cuts.)
It's taking a while.
(Jung Sik has a question.)
I can't understand how you're so fit.
How can you keep going?
(You can make us do things.)
I can't say it.
I can't order people to do things.
(He'd rather do the work himself than order people around.)
I can't do that.
Are you introverted?
I'm very introverted.
I overcame it a little bit.
(He was naturally an introvert...)
(but he overcame it by meeting people on The Law of Jungle.)
This show...
helped me overcome it.
I was shy during "The Master" too.
I was like that when I first started this show.
I didn't know how to talk to people.
I didn't know what to talk about.
(He was shy then unlike now.)
(He carried the responsibility as the Chief.)
(He did more than speak...)
(and overcame all hardships.)
(And...)
Good job.
(He spoke about what's on his mind and showed tears.)
- Good job, Kwang Hee. - Good job, everybody.
This show changed my personality a lot.
I...
learned a little bit about how to become a leader.
It changed me a lot.
Shouldn't you do something to clear your mind?
Don't you have to find a way to release the stress?
Skydiving makes me clear my head.
Skydiving?
You have to focus on it solely...
because...
you can't think about anything else.
For that day,
I don't need anything else.
There's nothing impossible in this world. That's my state of mind.
(He gets liberated from all the anxiety.)
Ready, set, go.
(When he throws his body into the blue sky,)
(he feels completely free.)
(It's a time for himself and nobody else.)
"What do I do?" "How do I make it fun?"
"What should I do so that this can be a memorable time for them?"
My head is filled with thoughts like that.
(He's been thinking about these without telling his Tribe members.)
I'm getting mentally exhausted.
(Sky)
(It's the only escape from his mind.)
That was the best.
I loved it.
I'm a skydiver!
(Byung Man is a skydiver.)
When I get stressed, I want to do it again.
(He can't give up on the freedom.)
That's why people do extreme sports.
(Skydiving is precious for Byung Man.)
It gives me a sense of satisfaction.
(We wish Byung Man a speedy recovery.)
Let's start cooking.
(Hani and the guys start cooking now.)
(They're busy.)
When is Kang Nam coming back?
(Kang Nam is missing.)
This is too long...
and the strings came out, so I made it short.
I'll get some food for breakfast.
(He takes the handmade tool.)
I'll be quick.
We have no food, so I have to find something.
I'll be back.
I'll be quick.
(He goes back to hunt without dinner.)
(He's awesome.)
He's so cool.
(He sets out to the water alone at night.)
(He dives in without hesitation.)
(He has Byung Man's spirit.)
Chief Byung Man wasn't here with us,
so I wanted to act like a leader.
I was trying my best.
(Kang Nam steps up and takes the responsibility.)
(Did he spot something?)
(It's a sleeping turtle.)
(That's too bad.)
(What will the Vice-Chief bring back from the sea?)
Kang Nam is quite...
- family-oriented. - He's awesome.
He's quite awesome.
I think he has to rename himself as Kang Quite.
Kang Quite?
- Yes. That's his nickname. - Quite.
(They start cooking without Kang Nam.)
- How do you skewer this? - The net is all ripped.
(They're using the landing net as skewers.)
Hani worked so hard to make it.
I want to say thank you.
Do you want the shrimp?
(It's Min Gyu's cooking class.)
- Is that how you do it? - Yes.
- Through there? - Right here.
(Throw away your conscience when skewering the shrimp.)
(Imagine how good the food will turn out.)
You can put them on the skewers.
- It's a shrimp skewer. - The shrimp looks really good.
(They're excited about how the shrimp will turn out.)
- Kang Nam. - What about the crab.
- You're back. - You're back.
- Did you catch anything? - How did it turn out?
(Show us...)
(your power.)
Don't pay attention to me.
Pretend like I'm not here.
Act like I was here the whole time.
- No, this is... - I've been here the whole time.
I did catch one.
Let's see.
Don't focus on me.
(He doesn't want the attention.)
- You caught something. - Kang Nam.
It's perfect for breakfast.
(However,)
Kang Nam.
(he didn't expect such a warm welcome.)
It's perfect for breakfast. We have another one.
- It's a crab. - Really?
(These guys make me want to cry.)
How did you catch that?
- Good job, Kang Nam. - Thank you.
(They only have each other without the Chief.)
- Move it to the middle. - We can boil this.
- This looks so good. - It looks amazing.
It's a shrimp and crab skewer.
How many are there?
Break it.
- Good job. - How did you do that?
Do it like this.
(They're amazed.)
- This'll taste good in soy sauce. - It really will.
- It's coming out. - All right.
We did the same yesterday.
- It has to be beaten. - It shouldn't have any fishy smell.
I got some of this today.
Here you go.
(They start cooking the mud crab.)
- This looks good. - It looks great.
Squeeze it hard.
(They add Jae Hee's tamarind.)
(Exclaiming)
(They're done preparing the herbal steamed crab.)
What's that? It's aromatic.
(Jae Hee completed the preparation.)
I finally did something to help.
Doesn't this look like a set menu?
- Yes, it does. - It kind of does.
Let's have a set menu.
We used the torch.
(It gets roasted in the fire.)
This looks fantastic.
Roast it until they dry out.
(Dazed)
It's turning red.
(As it gets cooked,)
(it gets painful for them to keep staring at it.)
- I don't think it's cooked yet. - It doesn't look like it.
I kept on thinking about bread for some reason...
and it's because that looks like a hardtack.
Hardtacks taste great when you're in the military.
It tastes really good if you add sugar in the bag and shake it.
You're so young, but you've had such variety of food.
This won't do.
I have to introduce you to the paradise of food.
- Are you good at cooking? - He can't be.
I always cook at home.
You cook for 13 people?
Have you ever cooked 20 bags of ramyeon.
- At one time? - Yes.
- Is that possible? That's amazing. - Right?
- How do you make 20? - You can't make them soggy.
How do they not get soggy?
You do this.
You add the soup base when the water is boiling on high heat.
You add the noodles after, and then press them down.
- Do you use your hands? - You shorten them.
(The noodles have to be short.)
- They have to be short. - You have to cook for five minutes.
- No, 30 seconds or 1 minute. - 30 seconds?
- 30 seconds? - I call the other members...
then tell them to line up. They get cooked during that time.
I hand the bowls out and some are more cooked than others.
They can line up according to their preferences.
The 7th or 8th place is when the noodles are perfectly cooked.
Really?
(They get more hungry after hearing that.)
Do you live by yourself, Wan?
- I used to, but after... - You live alone?
my sister got married,
- After she got married? - my mom was on her own.
So it hasn't been that long since you moved back in?
I live in the same neighborhood as Rain.
Are you close to him?
You are, right?
We're a family.
- But I'm trying... - He's new to the family.
so that I feel like he's truly a part of the family.
Do you call him brother or brother-in-law?
- I sometimes do. - Should we open this?
- This looks good. - Wait.
You were in the same drama as your sister.
- That was my first drama. - The song is called "I Miss You".
(He was young on his first drama.)
(Kim Tae Hee was also beautiful then.)
(It was a special drama for the sister and the brother.)
We were brothers and sisters.
You were brothers and sisters in the drama.
- There was a twist. - You were in the drama together.
It was my first drama.
- She's your sister. - I hid the fact...
that she was my sister.
Right.
- I changed my name too. - Right.
- You changed your last name to Lee? - Yes.
Even when we bumped into each other, I would just bow and say hi.
- Really? - It just occurred to me.
- They were both in the drama. - That's insane.
- That's right. - You said hi to each other...
as if you were strangers.
That drama was a big hit. It was big in Japan too.
- I watched it too. - When you were in Japan?
It was big.
- This is interesting. - It is.
- Do you see the color changing? - It's turning red.
- Where? - It's red now.
Cook it until it's crispy.
Can we eat it now?
One is about to come out.
- You must like the sea. - This looks amazing.
- This makes me happy. - Doesn't it?
(This is their savior after not eating for a long time.)
This looks good.
- It looks amazing. - Try it as is.
- How did you take it out? - Is it cooked?
- It's good. - Really?
It's so good.
It's really good.
(The grilled shrimp has a special flavor.)
You can eat it.
(Hani tries the crab first.)
(It makes her shiver in joy.)
- It's good. - The shrimp is fully cooked.
- How was it? - The shrimp is really good.
The crab too. It's savorier.
- More than the shrimp? - Yes.
- How do you do that? - You can just take it off.
Try the shrimp.
(Wan gets a bite of the crab.)
It's excellent.
It's good, right?
- I like the shrimp. - I think the crab...
- tastes better. - It's really good.
(Kang Nam eats a shrimp.)
(It suits his appetite.)
Try the crab.
The shrimp is really good.
(Crab versus shrimp)
(It's either you like crab or shrimp.)
It's good.
(Kang Nam tries the crab.)
The inside of the crab is good.
- The crab is good, right? - It's good.
I told you the crab is good.
It's really good.
It's good.
(It's fine as long as it's good.)
The crab is good.
- The crab is good. - The crab is really good.
- That is our main dish. - There's something we have to do.
- That was our appetizer. - It was good.
- That was the appetizer. - It looks good...
- because water steeped through. - It does.
(Crab dish in the jungle)
(How does the herbal steamed mud crab taste?)
(This is the real deal.)
I'll open it. In 1, 2, 3.
(They open the main dish.)
Look at the color.
(What's wrong with the color?)
- It's good. - It's fine.
(They laugh at how it looks like.)
I don't think we can eat the soup.
- The color looks like poison. - Wait, the color...
Isn't it because the crab roe spilled out?
What should we do with the soup? Are we going to eat it?
Should we see if it's good?
(It's the fiery pit steamed mud crab.)
- Let's eat it. Can we dig in? - Should we? Should we try it?
- It looks good. - The crab roe is coming out.
(The meat looks delicious.)
- Do we have a knife? - Look at the roe.
In 1, 2, 3.
(He opens the crab shell.)
(It's full of crab roe.)
- My gosh. That's amazing. - Look at the roe.
(It's the crab roe party at Komodo Island.)
- Look at the roe. - It's awesome.
- That's amazing. - Look at the roe.
(There's so much crab roe.)
- Just leave it as is. - Shouldn't we get rid of the soup?
- What about the soup? - Let's drink it.
Try it, Wan.
- Crab Man. - Hurry, Crab Man.
I hope it's good.
(He takes caution and smells it first.)
It might smell fishy.
- Try the roe. - What do you think?
- Hurry. - Come on.
- Someone else try it. - Give it to me.
Really?
(Hani tries it for them.)
The roe must be good.
(What did I just eat?)
- It has so much sand in it. - What is it?
(Smiling)
Do you want to try the roe?
- I'll try it. - Did you just put it down?
Why?
(He tries it right away.)
How is it?
(He spits it out.)
It's okay. There's meat.
- This is not cooked yet. - It is.
- It looks good though. - It's not?
- No, it's cooked. - We still have the meat.
It's not cooked. It has to be more firm.
- We need a microwave. - What do you call it?
Just microwave it. Hurry. Please.
Just microwave it.
- Do we have one? - The oil shouldn't be there.
Let's close it.
- It never happened. - We're going to put it back?
- We have to cook it more. - Leave it like that.
It'll cook sooner or later.
- Right. - The fire's not strong enough.
- What should we do? - What's that?
- I think the oil drained out. - I think so too.
(The fish is getting cooked to a golden brown.)
(It makes your mouth water, and everybody is happy.)
(They're having a party thanks to Byung Man.)
(Should we try it?)
This needs to be opened.
(He opens it.)
(Chief is the best.)
It looks amazing.
(It's golden brown.)
The sound,
the smell,
and the way it looks are insane.
- It'll taste good too, right? - The taste?
It's the pandemonium of the five senses.
(It gapes open.)
(The meat is stuck to the wood.)
- Look at this. - It's the bamboo.
It's the bamboo grilled fish.
You eat this.
(There's a lot of meat on it.)
- You should eat this, Chief. - It's okay.
- Thank you for the food. - Try it.
(He takes a big bite.)
(He can't help but smile.)
(Byung Man takes a big bite as well.)
(His expression changes while eating.)
You might cry again, Dong Keun.
Don't cry.
(It's just too good.)
We don't even need salt.
We were so hungry.
(He takes a big chunk.)
We need to binge.
(He allows himself to eat as much as he wants.)
(His expression changes again while eating.)
This is what I wanted.
(Jung Sik takes a handful.)
This is like bread.
(He agrees.)
(The fish is so good that they're delirious.)
The meat comes right off the bone.
(It tastes great and they have plenty of it.)
This is endless.
Eat the skin too.
Take the bone right off.
(There's a lot of meat on the bone too.)
You can have this...
and worry about nothing.
- You need to worry about nothing. - There you go.
(He takes the fish...)
(and goes to his space.)
Look at the meat.
(He takes a bite slowly.)
(He's one with the fish.)
Try the meat.
We're not going to have leftovers.
(Is this really fish?)
Dong Keun tends to eat...
good food far away from people.
He goes to the hammock and eats by himself.
(He prefers to eat alone.)
(He's away from the group.)
He's appreciating the taste.
(He's in his own world.)
This is chewy.
(Even when people are being noisy during dinner,)
(he eats by himself.)
(This is it.)
It's because...
I want to enjoy the taste as much as I can.
When I'm next to people who are eating,
I feel like I have to eat fast too.
I only chew a few times and swallow.
So I'm trying to eat...
- as slow as possible. - It almost looks like...
you're writing a poem while you eat.
He was doing that yesterday too.
(He's the poet of the food industry.)
I'm full.
Thank you for the food.
We'll sleep well tonight.
- We have to wake up early. - It's because we're full right now.
When we're sleepy, we'll sleep really well.
We have to protect the island tomorrow.
That's right.
We have to eat it.
(This suits the Komodo Island.)
(Good night.)
(They get ready for bed.)
(Byung Man writes a journal entry before going to bed.)
(Dong Keun copies him.)
(It was a perfect day except that they couldn't go home.)
The fire's back on.
(It's 12:05am, and they're still cooking the crab.)
The crab we had wasn't cooked.
(We miss the Chief.)
- I'm tired. - I want to brush my teeth.
- It's 11:56pm. - It's burning.
Let's blow on it until the wood burns.
(The steamed crab is not getting cooked.)
- The fire... - Leave it.
The fire is not strong.
(Two hours have passed.)
I'm so hungry.
(I miss Byung Man.)
- When is it going to be ready? - Should we just roast it?
- Let's steam half of it. - Exactly.
That's right. Let's take half.
- Let's open the shell and roast it. - Let's roast it.
- Let's do one side here and there. - We can roast it like this.
- We can do that. Put it on top. - Roast it.
That's right. We can just put it on top.
Forget it.
(They don't care about the lemon tree anymore.)
- That's enough. - Kang Nam.
- Let's try the legs. - There's nothing.
- The legs should be cooked. - I'll take the shell off.
- Let's try the legs. - It looks cooked.
How do you eat it?
- Open it. Use the ax. - We can eat it.
- You just do this. - That's the way.
It looks good.
(It's full.)
It looks good. Try it.
- Crab Man, try it. - Crab Man.
- It looks good. - Eat it in one bite.
Wait.
- This is good. - It's cooked.
- Is it? - This one's fine.
- It's cooked. - This one's perfect.
(He takes off a piece carefully.)
(He slurps it down.)
How is it?
- Is it good? - Crab Man.
This is awesome.
(He gets up and gives it to Hani.)
(Exclaiming)
Is it good?
(Kang Nam hurriedly eats it after seeing Hani's reaction.)
(Exclaiming)
- It was merely uncooked. - Jae Hee.
- It's perfect. - It wasn't me that was weird.
This is perfect.
- This is better than the crayfish. - I think so too.
- It's so good. - It is.
It's so good.
(Why is he making that face?)
(How is my crab?)
(Delicious)
What is this? It doesn't taste like a snow crab.
It tastes like...
- a snow crab and a lobster. - It tastes similar to a king crab.
- It's chewier. - The texture feels like a lobster.
(The crab legs are disappearing fast.)
This is amazing.
(The pincers are full of meat.)
It's a bone.
What does it taste like?
It's so good.
(They gobble it down.)
This is so good.
(They didn't eat for 20 hours.)
It's crunchy and tasty.
(This is a crab party.)
This is it. This is perfect.
(The body is cooked as well.)
Try it.
- We need to cook it a bit more. - No, this is perfect.
- It's hard. - It is hard.
This is amazing.
- The smell changed. - Does it?
(This piece goes to Wan.)
- Look at the meat. - It's hot.
Do you need some help?
This part is good.
This is fine cuisine.
It tastes like an expensive dish.
(It's more flavorful...)
The lemon tree makes it taste better.
(It's more flavorful thanks to Min Gyu's lemon tree.)
It's hot.
(They scrape the roe off.)
It's so hot.
(There's not a lot, but they share.)
It's good.
- This is even better. - It's good.
(They take care of each other and bond.)
That was good.
We did really well cooking for ourselves.
- I didn't think we'd be able... - But how is this crab so tasty?
to eat without the Chief.
Although it took us five hours longer...
It took us a long time, but we caught it with our own hands.
We also cooked for ourselves.
- This was so meaningful. - Me too.
(This is their first meal without the Chief.)
Let's keep a night watch.
We have to.
- Let's do it properly. - Should we do it?
Byung Man's Tribe, don't let your guards down.
There are deer remains near their shelter...
where the Komodo dragon left them during the day.
They just had dinner,
so a Komodo dragon might be roaming nearby...
with its great sense of smell.
I'll do it.
The rest of you should sleep. Go to bed.
- Good job, everybody. - It's not good to be here.
- Good night. - You can do it.
- We ended off well. - Good night.
- Thank you. - That was excellent.
(Rattling)
(There's a bell sound.)
- Is it a boar? - Yes.
- Look. - Where?
(You can see only its eyes in the dark.)
I keep thinking about...
when it was biting off the deer's hind leg.
(It might be somewhere in the darkness.)
Blood smells a lot.
(They were all chilled with fright...)
(when the beast had a feast during the day.)
It might be eating right now.
(It looks like it's roaming about.)
I'm more scared than yesterday after seeing the Komodo dragon eat.
I need to be a real man.
(Sneezing)
(He's startled.)
What was that?
What do real men do?
Real men fight through it.
(Min Gyu is the first to stand night watch.)
It's scary.
A deer died near our shelter.
The smell of blood must have spread.
Thinking that Komodo dragons will come,
the members each took turns to be on guard for an hour.
(The watch number 2, Kang Nam)
(I am sorry for walking you up.)
How did you sleep here? I'm sorry you had to sleep here.
(After an exhausting day, they rub their tired eyes...)
(to keep each other safe through the night.)
(The watch number 3, Lee Wan)
(I'm sorry.)
(He drags his body out of bed...)
(and heads to the searchlight by the fence.)
(The watcher number 4, Jae Hee wakes up as well.)
(While the air is cold at night,)
(the way they care for each other keeps them warm.)
(The team at the dinosaur island went to bed early.)
(The trio is sleeping in peace.)
(For Jung Sik, who was curled up due to the cold,)
(Dong Keun shares the warmth of his blanket.)
(The way they care for each other keeps the Tribe as one.)
(It's another morning at the jungle.)
We should go now.
Let's go.
(They go on patrol.)
(They had decided to patrol the area in the morning.)
Can Komodo dragons appear around this area?
They could be hiding.
I am a bit nervous since the grass obscures the view.
My goodness.
(They follow the beach and the forest...)
(and go up the hill to have a good view.)
The Komodo rangers...
sure do hard work.
While I have never been to Africa, this place reminds me a bit of it.
It really does remind you of Africa.
This place doesn't feel like Indonesia, but a country in Africa.
It seriously does.
- It looks like Africa, right? - It does.
It's like Africa.
This island is incredibly beautiful.
Look at the sunrise to your right.
(The overwhelming scenery puts them between reality and fantasy.)
It feels like dinosaurs really do live here.
I feel like I am on the back of a dinosaur.
(It feels like dinosaurs really do live here.)
The moment I saw the scenery on the hill,
all exhaustion left my body.
The Komodo rangers work...
at a very beautiful place.
They really coexist...
with the nature and the animals.
Byung Man's team finally finished patrolling the area.
Watching the striking scenery of the Komodo archipelago,
they think about the Komodo rangers' coexistence...
with the wild.
(How is the morning at Komodo Island?)
(Hani was the last watcher.)
(She patrols the area around the shelter in the morning.)
- It came. - What?
A Komodo dragon is walking towards us.
It's at the end of the light.
A Komodo dragon is walking by.
I think it's walking towards the deer.
(Did a Komodo dragon come?)
(Is it the one from yesterday?)
It looks like it'll come out from here and keep walking that way.
It's over there. You can see its face.
It's walking towards the deer, right?
(The Komodo dragon circles around the deer carcass.)
(It hides behind a tree for a second.)
I see another one over there.
- Where? - It's really big.
There are two Komodo dragons.
I see 1 and 2.
(Loitering)
My gosh. There it is.
(They still remember what they saw yesterday.)
(Both Komodo dragons move towards the deer carcass.)
They are eating the deer.
Did they come to eat the deer?
(How did the two Komodo dragons come here?)
- Is that the deer? - Yes, it is.
Komodo dragons can smell something that is 10km away.
Detecting the smell of a deer carcass,
Komodo dragons begin to swarm.
(They dig into the carcass as if it's a competition.)
(The scene is as imposing as it was yesterday.)
(The Komodo rangers circle the fence.)
Are they mating?
- Kang Nam, you have to see this. - Come here.
Come here.
(It turns out they are a romantic pair.)
- Kang Nam, you have to see this. - Come here.
Come here.
- They are mating. - Come here and look.
One Komodo dragon climbed on top of the other dragon.
Was it the one in the back?
- Wait a minute. - It's running away.
(Running away)
I guess it doesn't like the other one.
Be careful.
They must have met each other for the first time.
(What is going on?)
The two Komodo dragons are male.
The strongest male komodo dragons fight during the mating season.
Currently, the two are checking each other's strength.
"What kind of a male is it? Is it strong or not?"
Okay.
They are fighting to figure out...
who is stronger. Was that a fight?
(The winner eats alone.)
Ever since we came to this island,
don't you think we saw almost every behavior...
of the Komodo dragons?
(After showing the members how it competes for food,)
(the Komodo dragon leaves.)
We spotted Komodo dragons and searched the forest.
The sea has interesting things other than Komodo dragons.
The sea?
If there are Komodo dragons on the land,
then there is something...
- in the sea. - There's something there.
Really?
In Komodo Island,
there is another kind of a king...
other than Komodo dragons.
(The king of the sea)
With fear and excitement,
they prepare to go to the sea.
Byung Man's team spent the night at another island.
They will join the other members at the sea.
Byung Man's Tribe goes to meet the king of the sea.
What kind of surprising experiences will they have at the sea?
(They go to the sea, a place of endless possibilities.)
(The members of the Tribe reunite in the middle of the sea.)
- Hey. - Did you have a meal?
Why am I so happy to see them?
(They are happy to see each other after a day.)
(Byung Man's Tribe goes to find the king of the sea.)
Let's go.
(They promptly get ready.)
Go catch a lot of fish for us.
(Refreshing water surrounds their bodies.)
(Byung Man takes the lead...)
(and the other members of Byung Man's Tribe jump in.)
(If they want to be free of their exhaustion,)
(the sea is wide and deep enough.)
(A school of fish welcomes them.)
(The scenery is a treat to their eyes.)
"Finding Nemo" moved me a lot.
I felt like I was watching a real-life version of it.
It was so pretty. I looked around with excitement.
(The scenery is just like it is in an animated film.)
(It is the symbol of luck.)
(A turtle is spotted.)
It was so cute.
A sea turtle is a symbol of luck...
and a good omen.
I thought to myself, "Bring us luck", and then sent him on his way.
(What luck awaits them?)
(What is the king of the sea?)
(The tribe members move forward with Byung Man in the lead.)
(They look around carefully.)
(They make a swift turn.)
(Chaotic)
(Byung Man's camcorder)
(Byung Man slowly moves forward by himself.)
(A graceful silhouette swims in the sea.)
(The living king of the sea is before them.)
(Byung Man's recording)
(The manta ray is 7 to 8m wide and weighs 0.5 to 1.5t.)
The flying carpet.
It really looked...
like a piece of fabric or a carpet...
was flying in the wind.
(The manta ray seemed like it was a flying carpet.)
I felt like I was watching the scene unfold...
on a big screen.
It moved forward...
and swam downwards.
It was like a spacecraft. I was in awe.
It was like a fairy.
The time slowed down. It moved slowly...
in a relaxed manner.
I was so happy to see it in front of me.
(The manta ray and Byung Man's Tribe swim together.)
(They respect each other's space.)
They coexist with the nature and the animals.
They even get bitten by Komodo dragons from time to time.
Some Komodo rangers had to quit because they were bitten,
but they still coexist with the Komodo dragons...
and protect them.
I thought that must be why...
the Komodo dragons haven't gone extinct.
It's hard to protect them.
It's hard to preserve the nature.
The Komodo rangers made me realize it. I am very happy...
that I got to meet amazing people.
Working with the Komodo rangers,
Byung Man's Tribe learned to coexist with the nature.
It's time to meet the new Byung Man's Tribe.
(They will face a different legend.)
(It's the fantasy world you dreamed about.)
I love fantasy novels. They are the best.
(If this fantasy world appeared before your eyes...)
If I become a hero in a fantasy novel...
These are things that don't happen in real life.
Before the nature, people are incredibly small beings.
These moments will go on the records of my life.
(The new Byung Man's Tribe stands amidst the primitive nature.)
(The legend of hobbit)
They say hobbits live on this island.
It was fascinating.
Thousands of islands make a band like the Milky Way.
Flores Island is a remote island in the East...
that has the mythology of the Ebu Gogo, the little people.
They had the height of 1m and hairy bodies.
They lived in the cave inside the rush forest.
After the 20th century, they gained another name.
They were called hobbits.
It's homo floresiensis.
(It's the legend of survival.)
The legend of the hobbit.
(The 8 new members of the Tribe)
(Find traces of a hobbit)
Bats!
(They explore a deep cave like in the legends.)
(In 2003, 18,000-year-old skeletons were found in Flores Island.)
(They are in the land of the primitives.)
(They welcome the nature with their bodies.)
We are living like the hobbits.
It's the legend of the hobbits and Byung Man's Tribe.
(Another fantasy will be written.)
- The Law of Jungle, - The Law of Jungle,
- the fellowship of the hobbits. - the fellowship of the hobbits.
They found us. Let's run away.
(The best friends finally come together.)
For goodness' sake.
My goodness.
It's Gollum.
(It's a hobbit.)
(Byung Man and I look like people who have always lived here.)
Don't we?
(We are small, but our teamwork is perfect.)
(Everything is small here.)
(It's the story of two real hobbits in the land of the hobbits)
There is nothing to eat.
(He specializes in interpreting the language of the hobbit.)
(Surreptitious)
(The tall member likes it too.)
(I feel like a character in a fantasy novel.)
(I feel like I can do anything with Byung Man.)
(He works on improving his comedic skills in front of his best friend.)
(You are such a small hobbit.)
(Soo Geun keeps making people laugh.)
I lack the energy...
(It's always a happy jungle.)
The fellowship of the hobbits.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Banana!
Welcome to the land of the legend, Flores Island.
- We now know the island's name. - Which game will we play?
- The time stopped. - Let's have a meeting first.
The time stopped.
- This is now... - Should we stay still?
Lee Soo Geun's The Law of Jungle.
(This is now Lee Soo Geun's The Law of Jungle.)
(He makes everyone laugh from the start.)
No one is tired.
Let's get started with Season Two.
- It's your first time, right? - What?
It's your first time on The Law of Jungle, right?
(Soo Geun plays around like fish in the water.)
(Byung Man responds by pulling his ear.)
(He greets his best friend like so.)
(The atmosphere softens.)
(Soo Geun's presence makes Byung Man cheerful.)
He was waiting.
I thought he would be exhausted.
- I am exhausted. - Are you?
(Byung Man and Soo Geun finally meet.)
Lee Soo Geun.
He puts me at ease.
I can depend on him emotionally.
Even I am curious...
about how Soo Geun will do in The Law of Jungle.
People will see that Byung Man is the comedian.
He and I will have a lot of fun in the jungle.
It will be like "Gag Concert" in the jungle.
(Look forward to the Funny Jungle Show.)
- I am sorry. - He says he's sorry.
My goodness.
(A more joyful Part 2 is coming up.)
We have perfect looks.
We actually had a meeting.
The theme is Chief Byung Man's healing time.
We prepared a colorful show for Chief Byung Man.
I can't wait. When you are in the jungle,
you only have to worry about eating and sleeping.
- Just forget about everything else. - Only eating and sleeping.
Forget about everything else.
I talked to the people in the village.
They agreed to take me in for a night.
A little boy told me to sleep at his house.
- You talked to the people already. - What did they...
What did they say?
- What? - What did they say?
Hurry up and come on down.
- What? - Hurry up and come on down.
- "Come on down." - "Come on down."
(His joke suits my taste.)
I can't wait to see how much he will joke around.
I can't wait to see how much Soo Geun will joke around.
He keeps trying to host a talk show.
Among the female idol singers who visited the program,
- she wore the most appropriately. - He's right.
Bugs won't go in.
She didn't worry about style.
She likes to swim.
- She likes to swim, - I heard she's good at swimming.
but we ended up on a mountain.
(She smiles prettily no matter where she is at.)
I want to give strength to a lot of people.
I am red ginseng, which is one level above vitamin.
- Red ginseng? - That's right.
(Ye Rin shows her cuteness in 3 different ways.)
(GFriend has the strongest fandom and digital music sales.)
(GFriend's newest song, "Love Whisper" takes top 1.)
(She is the center.)
(Ye Rin)
(She has unexpected charms.)
(Sweet and scary)
She is easygoing and fearless.
(She is armed with good cheer.)
(She is scarier when she eats.)
(Her eyes are fierce.)
(She is so cute.)
(The red ginseng is coming soon.)
- I am red ginseng. - Red ginseng?
I am red ginseng of the group.
It's better than vitamin.
Are you saying that you brought red ginseng?
No, I am red ginseng.
- You are red ginseng. - You're not mad, right?
How long has it been since your daughter was born?
It has been 10 days.
- It has been 10 days. - It has only been 10 days.
- He should have stayed at home... - Why is he here?
- to watch his beautiful baby. - He's here in the jungle.
Hello.
I am an actor, Choi Won Young.
(He played Kim Chul Gyu in "A Hundred Year Legacy".)
(He married Sim Yi Young,)
(an actress who played his wife in the same drama.)
That's how we met.
After becoming a family and having a child,
many things changed.
Your wife gave birth the day before yesterday.
That's right. It was the day before yesterday.
It feels different to have a second child.
I have more stability.
I have to leave for The Law of Jungle.
Next week?
Are you going away for three nights?
I am going away for two nights.
- For two nights? - Yes.
There are two.
(Throwing)
Are you giving this to me?
- Will the magic wand protect me? - Yes.
(This is the joy of raising a daughter.)
(Daddy will be back.)
Coming to a place like this is...
because you and your wife are on bad terms, right?
Your kid has nothing to do with this.
(Soo Geun is just kidding.)
It's an escape from parenting.
- It's paternity leave. - There was...
- a great project. - He's on paternity leave.
So I jumped on the opportunity.
Whenever people asked "Which show do you want to be on?",
- I said "The Law of Jungle". - Really?
- She really wanted to on the show. - Since I wasn't famous.
Pilates is actually very close to nature.
I want to really challenge myself.
I want to go to the jungle.
(Pilates is very useful for one's survival.)
- Nice. - Good.
(She's exercising and making a fire at once.)
Do you need flexibility to do pilates?
(A survival story of a sportswoman)
There aren't many who can try pilates in nature.
I majored in sports psychology.
I can lead and assist people.
I want to be a helpful person.
- I see. - Great.
- So she did want to come here. - I was surprised.
How do you feel about joining the show?
- Tae Hwan. - I...
Honesty, I don't think of this as a variety show.
I'll consider this as a documentary.
I've done a lot of research on the internet.
I'm going to survive.
I'm going to learn everything from the Chief.
(Lee Tae Hwan is an actor.)
I'm Lee Tae Hwan, an actor.
(He performed with Lee Jong Suk in "W" in 2016.)
I recently finished "Father, I'll Take Care of You".
A lot of people recognize me.
(He has the perfect body for the jungle.)
(A middle-aged man is jealous.)
(With a superb physique, he becomes the jungle's body guard.)
(Her heart races.)
(He's survival is a documentary.)
Everything seemed like a movie to me.
(He's peeling coffee beans in his mouth.)
(He's a human thresher.)
You won't be able to fall asleep because of coffee.
(He's serious.)
(Be ready to fall for his innocent charm.)
I want them to relax and be energized.
Did you know that there were...
supposed to be eight of you?
- That's right. - Yes.
- There were eight. - Right.
- Hong Bin of VIXX will... - Hong Bin.
join you after his concert in Taiwan.
Hello, I'm Hong Bin of VIXX. It's nice to meet you.
(Hong Bin is a member of VIXX.)
I'll just go there with some luggage.
I'll do stuff when I get there.
(He sounds like a tough guy.)
It's not like I'm not going to die.
(He's very passionate.)
We've been to the jungle, so we're helping him pack.
I got it the second time.
- 1, 2, 3. - Let's go!
Good luck.
(After 12 hours)
Hello.
(He looks depressed.)
I had to make a transfer,
but I missed it because I had wrong information.
I missed my transfer.
(Hong Bin couldn't get on the plane to the jungle.)
I'm waiting for my luggage.
(He is alone in Hong Kong without a manager.)
I had work in Taiwan.
I was supposed to fly to Hong Kong than transfer...
to a flight to Bali.
I missed the flight because I had wrong information.
First, I tried to deny the reality, but then I accepted it.
Then I tried to find a solution.
(First stage is denying the reality.)
I'm...
really sorry.
(Second stage is accepting the reality.)
I'll find a way to get there soon.
(After 4 hours of waiting)
Right now...
(He's in a hotel in Hong Kong.)
it's two in the morning.
(He left the airport.)
There was no flight, so I went to a hotel.
But it was full, so I went back to the airport.
I kept waiting, looking, and I kept repeating that.
And now it's this late.
(I used to be so passionate.)
(Now all I can do is sigh.)
My luggage is...
(Instead of the Tribe...)
here with me.
(only his luggage is with him.)
My poor luggage.
I'll fly to Bali tomorrow morning.
(He'll spend the night in Hong Kong and fly out the next day.)
He's in a city jungle instead.
Is he joining us?
Hong Bin wants to be here no matter what.
He's coming here without a manager.
- Alone? - That must be hard.
I'm so stupid.
(He's completely lost it.)
I can't believe I missed the flight.
(Will Hong Bin be able to arrive in the jungle safely?)
He has a good heart. He's really passionate about this.
- It isn't easy. - He has passion.
Right. It isn't easy.
You will go into...
the jungle behind you.
- Okay. - It's so pretty there.
- Yes. - It's so pretty.
- It is. - It's pretty.
- Okay. - Are we going there?
Let's go.
The Tribe is headed to the forest with a legend.
In a deep forest without human touch,
what kind of mysterious things will happen there?
(The Tribe goes to find the land of Hobbit.)
Byung Man.
Shouldn't we get these coconuts here, now?
(He suggests picking the coconuts.)
(He found them at the entrance to the village.)
Shall we pick one or not? Is it...
too high? It's too hard, isn't it?
(It's up too high.)
Soo Geun, shall we get some?
It's too dangerous, isn't it?
(The tree is 15m tall.)
It's up too high.
Gosh, it's too tall.
(When they're about to give up on their dream...)
- Gosh. - Don't do it.
- No. - Goodness.
(Byung Man climbs up.)
You should wear this belt.
Be careful, Byung Man.
- Gosh. - Goodness.
Should I get one too?
(Jae Hee decides...)
(to pick a small one.)
(He'll climb a shorter tree.)
I can do it.
(He's showing an example as an experienced member.)
There are more here.
Jae Hee is picking them.
(Byung Man is already half way up the tree.)
Be careful, Byung Man.
Don't I look like a caterpillar?
Go for it!
- Goodness. - Amazing.
I feel like I'm watching a movie.
(This isn't computer graphics, is it?)
- Gosh. - That's so cool.
(This is the basics.)
(He reaches the top in no time.)
(He's relaxed even when he's 15m off the ground.)
(This is why he's the chief.)
I got it.
(They're watching the Chief.)
I think I can get this.
(Jae Hee is working hard even when nobody is watching.)
- Gosh. - What's going on?
I'm tired.
You can't get tired. If you are, then I'll have to be the Chief.
(You can do it, Chief!)
- What? - Does he need to split it?
(Please look at me.)
What do we have to do with it?
(It's the Chief's show time!)
Gosh. That's amazing.
- Gosh. That's amazing. - I've only seen it on TV.
(Awesome!)
(The Chief teaches them by showing.)
I'm too tired to pick them. I'll get one.
- I'll just pick one. - Be careful.
Just have a taste.
Hey, be careful.
You pick your own. I'll only get one for me.
No. You'll scrape your hands.
Be careful.
(When Byung Man heads down...)
You need to support your bottom.
(he struggles without anyone watching him.)
Byung Man.
(He's skillful.)
Please take this.
Please take this one.
Help me.
- Be careful. - I have no strength.
- Gosh. - Good work.
(They applaud and praise him.)
- You're awesome. - My gloves...
I've never seen something like this.
(Jae Hee climbs down alone.)
You'll hurt yourself climbing like that.
A vice chief should be able to do this.
Chief and vice chief picked coconuts for us.
Are you okay?
It's lighter than it looks.
- Good job. - Nice.
- Let's try one. - This one.
- Let's try one. - Do we break it?
(Nice!)
(He breaks it and drinks from it.)
- It's fresh. - Take it.
(He drinks like a tough guy.)
- Nice. - We should finish it.
- That's cool. - I'll drink like him.
- Gosh. - Drink it like a man.
It's good.
- My turn. - Yes.
- Gosh. - I'll drink it like a man.
I'll be quick.
That's awesome.
(Fresh drink)
Let's try it.
Does it taste different?
- Here. - It's sweet.
(You can't taste this in a studio.)
- Look. I even got some meat. - It's like watermelon.
- It's good. - Does it taste different?
It's sweet.
Lean back. That's right.
(It's Tae Hwan's turn.)
It's good.
(Dancing)
Isn't it delicious?
- Is it good? - Yes.
- It's delicious. - This is the best.
I'll try it.
- It tastes like an energy drink. - It's like...
fresh watermelon.
Yes, it tastes fresh.
Here.
I think it tastes more delicious...
because the Chief went up there and got it.
(He is happy to hear that.)
- He set an example. - Please take good care of me.
Take good care of us.
- You're great. - Shall we put it in here?
- Well... - There's an ax.
Right here.
(He creates a funny skit.)
Thank you. Let's go.
- Mine is really big. - What's that?
- Does it take one hour and half? - Let's go.
- Do we need to walk for 1.5 hours? - It's...
I'm starving now though.
The ground is so muddy.
(The Tribe sets out to find the cave with the legend.)
(How will it look?)
Are we going into the jungle at last?
From this point on, there are no traces of people.
Gosh, it's so tiring.
(The Chief takes the lead as always.)
(He walks into this unfamiliar jungle without any hesitation.)
(Soo Gun, a close friend of the Chief, follows him.)
You're not tired, are you?
No, I'm happy to be here.
I'm honored that I can star on a show...
my friend hosts.
- Be careful starting now, everyone. - Okay.
- It's horrible... - Be careful.
- if you sprain your ankle. - Okay.
3 or 4 days would go by so quickly.
- It's dangerous since we can't see. - What should I do?
- I can't see the path. - The path...
Should I cut this and go?
This is a jungle.
This is a real jungle.
(It's a rugged and dense jungle.)
(And the ground is muddy.)
Be careful over there.
On the ground,
there are a lot of branches. If you slip on it,
you will be hurt badly.
- Okay. - Okay.
You need to be on your guard. There are so many of this.
(Even when he's crossing a pit,)
(he takes care of the younger members.)
(Jumping)
Do I have to jump like him?
- Where should I step on? - On here.
Excellent. Let's go now.
(Soo Geun is building a strong character for Tae Hwan.)
- He has such long legs. - They're no jokes.
- They are so long. - They are like the bridges.
The name serves a purpose.
Then what about yours?
I have short legs.
I feel very reassured.
I don't have to talk because he's doing them for me.
(He feels at ease.)
He does them on his own.
Look. We have to take the surrounding path.
(He's a comedian that will make everyone laugh in the jungle.)
Hello.
(Let me say hello.)
(Ye Rin is following them with the best she can.)
- I'm having fun. - You're having fun so far?
So far? Did you say, "so far"?
Will it be scary from now on?
It's fun for now.
I think wherever I go,
I'll survive well.
I have a strong will to survive.
(An unyielding survival instinct)
I really want to live a long life.
(Her dream is unusual for an idol singer.)
(I have to lead a long life.)
Doesn't Ye Rin look like the youngest member of a hiking club?
Yes!
(Ye Rin, the youngest member of a hiking club, looks around.)
I wish a chicken would walk past us here.
- A chicken? - Yes.
(Walking with stealthy tread)
(This is a hunting skill of catching a chicken with bare hands at once.)
That's how he catches chickens.
(She's fast.)
I think this is okay.
There must be a lot of snakes here.
We can roast the snakes and eat.
You're a girl though.
(Ye Rin is dreaming of living long as she recharges her energy here.)
(Cute)
I don't think we can find food here.
(Their journey for the cave continues.)
Watch your head.
(Tae Hwan takes care of others.)
Thank you. Thank you.
I used to do a lot of house chores.
I do a lot of work that may not be so visible.
When we film at restaurants,
I'm always the last one coming out and brings our stuff.
I'm sort of like the Snail Bride in the fable.
(He pushes the tree that's sticking out.)
Be careful.
(He even takes care of the crew courteously.)
Goodness, why did it break? Now, I feel bad.
I'm sorry, tree.
I'm surrounded by nature...
like the palm trees.
(Won Young moves like a middle-aged man.)
(He smells the nature.)
The jungle is very jungle-like.
This feels great.
I bet I'll say I want to go home an hour later.
(He's nervous.)
Please let me go home.
(Jae Hee takes big strides at the end of the line.)
I have gloves, so it's better.
It's because I'm just tired.
(His legs must've given way for picking coconuts.)
- Wait. - Let me help you.
- Jae Hee, get some rest and come. - I'm fine. I'm serious.
I'm not a chief assistant.
I've just been here longer than they have, but they keep calling me that.
- It's making me uneasy. - Hey.
Be careful. We have to be careful.
Hey, if we go at this pace, we're going to get lost.
Let's hurry.
Chief!
Chief Kim! You have to take us. Why are you going on your own?
What?
- Byung Man. - Yes?
- Hey, you! - What?
We have to go all together!
You have to hurry then.
The girls can't keep up with you.
I'm right here.
(Ye Rin caught up quickly.)
Why are you slower than the girls?
Has it been a while since you two met? Or do you meet often?
- We don't see each other often. - You don't?
When he's free, he works on...
getting the skydiving instructor license.
So that makes me worry about him.
He enjoys extreme sports.
It's great having a hobby...
for men in their 40s like us.
He has to think about his health though.
(That's his wish.)
(The Chief feel energetic as he's with his friend.)
(Rushing)
Can't you hear the sound of water?
I do.
- I can hear the water. - It's water.
It's water.
(The Tribe arrives at a lake nearby their destination.)
Great.
I can see the water.
(The Chief is concealing himself.)
Here's a great spot.
(Approaching carefully)
(Hiding)
(Startled)
(He pulls a prank which he doesn't usually do since he's friend here.)
I felt dizzy for a moment.
I thought you saw me here.
The cave with the legend is...
located under the waterfall that you see here.
That's the location.
Would you want some pork belly meat?
I'll get it ready.
Sit. Let's have some pork belly meat.
(Jungle Hiking Club's outing)
Let me grill the meat.
(Sizzling)
That's a wet wipe.
(Wringing)
(He's sweating.)
Why are you grilling a wet wipe?
(The Chief tries grilling the pork belly meat.)
Your fingers are burning.
We used to do this kind of skits.
Let's scream our slogan...
- and go down. - The slogan.
Ridge!
Let's climb it!
(The Chief takes the lead again.)
(The cave next to the lake is their final destination.)
Step on this.
- Good job. - Okay.
(Soo Geun is on his way to follow his friend.)
(He was jumping confidently.)
(Stopping)
(It's a cliff.)
Hey, don't come here.
Oh, my goodness.
Hey, be careful over there.
Come this way.
(Slippery)
(It makes their bodies stagger.)
I... What do I do? Look at that.
- Goodness. - I...
How did he go down there?
(This is the place the Tribe must go.)
(It's a mysterious cave with the legend of hobbits.)
(It's disconnected from the outside world as it has no entrance.)
(How are they going to go down to this cave?)
(The Chief looks down without saying anything.)
(Let me think.)
My legs are shaking.
(Trembling)
I'm shaking here.
I'm trembling.
Now I feel like I'm in a jungle.
What is the height?
It's about 15m.
(The height is approximately 15m.)
We weren't going to lower the rope...
in order to climb down.
We had to climb down as we lower the rope ourselves.
It was a safe way to go down.
That's the thought I had in mind.
- We have to use the rope. - Then you should go down first.
- We have to climb down by the rope? - Yes.
Let me show you how to climb down first.
- You're going to use this? - Yes.
It's quite high. It's over 10m.
- Are you serious? - Everyone, be on your guard.
I'm afraid of heights.
I have acrophobia.
I get sick just by looking at high places.
I don't look at the ground since it makes me feel nauseous.
I was taken aback and flustered.
(It threw her off.)
I'm an icon of worry.
I always think and worry about things.
I even watch out for the falling leaves.
When I walk, I'm on my guard. What is it falling?
(This is making me worry.)
When we climb down here, there will be a cave.
(The Tribe must overcome their fear.)
Our goal is to go to that cave.
Goodness, it's finally starting. We have to climb down there?
This is unbelievable.
(The Chief installs the safety ropes.)
(Dazed)
Watch the Chief going down first.
If you think you can't go down by rope,
there's a route you can take, but it goes around the cliff though.
This is a vertical route which is fast and safe as long as they can...
overcome their fear.
Or there's a dangerous, winding trail that goes around the mountain.
This is a barren, mountainous path.
Their journey to the legend isn't easy.
Now, all they have left to do is decide.
(The Chief is ready to climb down.)
(After checking the safety one more time...)
If you put your weight over here when you're going down, you'll slip.
- Should we lean back? - Lean back.
Trust the rope.
If the rope is right there, how will you go down?
We are going to take these two off later.
We are going to hook it over here.
Here's the rope. Hold it here.
Go down slowly. You're releasing your grip in the back slowly.
If you want to stop, you have to pull the rope.
(Getting up)
We will go down first...
to check the rope is safe and working.
So you guys can come down at ease.
(Saying it is easy.)
I can do it,
but it's scary going down.
- I'll go down. - Okay.
- I'll release you when you go down. - Okay.
- Byung Man, be safe. - You can do it!
(They cheer for him energetically.)
Be careful.
- It's scarier because we can't see. - We can't see a thing.
- It's scarier because we can't see. - We can't see...
- a thing. - There's a rope when you're here.
(Slowly, step by step,)
(he sets foot into the cave of the legend.)
(Feeling nauseous)
My feet can't reach.
We have to lift our legs like we are rappelling down.
(Is it the rope or the dangerous trail?)
If I do this, I can stop myself from going down.
That's right. Hold the rope.
- Just like this? - I can't wait to try it.
(There isn't a place he can put his feet.)
When you reach this point, there are vines.
(The Chief gets down as he steps on the vines.)
(When he loosens his grip of the rope,)
(he moves down smoothly.)
(Rappelling down isn't hard.)
(In no time, the Chief has come down halfway.)
(Soo Geun feels nervous as he watches Byung Man.)
(She's free from...)
(all the distraction.)
(It's a frightening descent of 15m of the cliff.)
(Now, he has 5m left to go.)
(As he gets closer to the ground, he looks calmer than before.)
(He finishes his descent.)
Gosh, the cave.
(At last, he is face to face with the final destination.)
(This is a cozy, mysterious cave of the legend...)
(where the primitive hobbits once lived.)
It worked.
(He checks the safety.)
Come down.
(He calls for his tribesmen and women.)
(Just trust me and come on down.)
Byung Man.
(Soo Geun gets ready.)
I don't think he did.
- Byung Man. - Chief!
It's good.
(It's safe.)
(The place is good too.)
This is quite stiff.
- It doesn't go down smoothly. - I'll see you later.
Hold it tightly.
You can do it!
(He slowly goes down.)
- Aren't you scared? - If I hold it tightly...
Right now? I'm not scared because I can't see.
I should lean back. It's really tight.
(He starts to walk backward into the cliff.)
Lean your upper body.
There's nothing to step on starting this point.
- There are vines here though. - Step on the vines.
(The Chief is coaching Soo Geun from below.)
Goodness, Byung Man.
You can slightly step on the vines.
- What? - Step on the vines carefully.
I'm going to the side. What is this?
(He's dangling from the end of the ground.)
How is it so empty here?
Release the grip of your right hand little by little.
You got it.
- I think I leaned back too much. - There you go.
That's it.
Look at Ye Rin's face.
It's the face of someone with acrophobia.
(It's a worried look with the helmet on.)
Loosen your grip slightly. Release it.
Even if you come down at once, it's okay. I can pull it from here.
You'll be fine.
(Sliding down)
My hand is getting hot.
Come down.
(Come down a bit more.)
- I'm in such a weird position. - That's it.
There you go. Release the grip of your right hand.
That's it. There you go.
Can't I straighten my back?
When I pull it like this, you won't fall.
You don't have to.
You have to hold the upper part. Slowly. That's it.
Okay. Now, you have to stand up.
- Hold on. There you go. - Gosh, this is hard.
- You got it. - This is too hard.
You did it. Hey, you can't fall backward.
You're going to fall in the water.
You have to hold this part.
- I knew it. - You have to hold this.
I couldn't have done it myself.
Byung Man was holding the rope safely from the ground.
(Thank you, my friend.)
- I have to put this on. - I think I have to change.
I can't feel it's real since I didn't look down.
I can't feel it.
(They feel more nervous as they watch Soo Geun going down.)
(Should I go around it?)
(On the other hand, he feels at ease since he climbed down.)
(He enters the legendary lake after taking off his shirt.)
(Goodness, this is nice.)
Is there anything?
(He wants to goof around.)
I should go that way.
Goodness, the water is so cool.
You're going over?
(Okay, this is the time.)
(Lowering his pants)
Okay. Fine. Stop it.
(He smacks his bottoms out of love.)
Gosh, it hurts.
(He's satisfied with an elementary skit.)
(I can't lose out to him.)
(He climbs on top of the rock.)
What?
He's a hobbit! A hobbit.
(His facial expression is impressive.)
(He finishes up with a massage from the waterfall.)
(The cool water pierces into his body.)
(He's happy that his friend likes it.)
I'm getting the good energy from this trip.
Byung Man.
(I like it here.)
(However, they can't be at ease.)
Let me put this on for you.
(Next up is...)
(Won Young, the icon of worry.)
Won Young, how did you manage to decide to take the rope?
(The reason that gave him the courage to stand at the cliff)
(Ta-da)
(It's the lucky magic wand.)
This is the lucky magic wand I need in times of danger.
Hadn't I challenged myself at that moment,
I thought I'd compromise...
and look for something that would make my life easier.
The fear and my worrisome thoughts were fighting each other.
During that battle, I made my choice.
My daughter gave me this to protect me from the crocodile.
- She said to carry it at all times. - That's so cute.
(Middle-aged men might be weak, but dads are strong.)
(My daughter, Daddy is coming.)
Should I put it on?
(I want to see my dad too.)
(Won Young moves to the starting point.)
Let's start.
(He can only sigh.)
Be careful.
- Go for it! - You can do it!
I will be back.
Try to withstand it with your legs.
I'd like to cheer for my family.
- Good luck! - I'll see you down there.
- Stretch your legs. - Bye.
- All right. - At once, you have to...
I got it.
(Can he become a strong dad?)
Lower yourself a bit. If you stand up straight,
- you might get stuck. - Should I sit down?
Yes.
This is the spot.
(It's the section the rock disappears.)
This is it.
(Slippery)
That's great.
(It's a relief that he looks calm.)
(As he remembers his precious family,)
(he steps down courageously.)
You are such a cool dad!
(Goodness)
- The view is magnificent. - The scenery is awesome.
It's incredible.
I thought I shouldn't be scared and let my fear get the better of me.
I thought about good things.
I climbed down as I thought about my family whom I miss so much.
(He starts to enjoy the ride down to the cave.)
(Honey, are you watching?)
(He approaches the destination.)
Hey.
That tree hit me.
(He picks up the speed.)
(He makes a perfect landing.)
You were waiting for me. Thank you.
He successfully landed!
(Won Young, the icon of worry, succeeds his challenge.)
(Feeling proud)
You were already bathing.
Really?
(Jung Won goes down fearlessly.)
(She gets herself ready with the mind of a sportswoman.)
Loosen your grip of your right hand. Release it more.
More. You can come down more.
- Great. Stand up. Step on the rock. - Well done.
Step on it and stand up.
(She succeeds in an instant.)
It's not as smooth as I thought it'd be.
I can rely on the rope then.
I will see you down there.
- I can do this. - Let go of your left hand.
(Exceptional strength)
That's right.
There you go.
(He's serious.)
- I can't see. - You want to come down?
He's good.
Go, marine!
Marine who did this all the time!
I can even do this in my sleep.
- That's right. - Hold it.
- I'm doing it. - He's right.
(He's fast, and comes down safely.)
Look at the ground.
He didn't let go yet.
What is this?
(Jae Hee lands safely.)
(Now, the youngest member, only Ye Rin remains.)
I can't talk anymore.
(Ye Rin has acrophobia.)
I keep thinking about this.
I wondered if I could do it when it was so high.
I did question myself if I was capable of doing it.
Everyone was older than I am.
With the thought that they are protecting me,
I could overcome my fear although it was very hard.
At that point,
I started to think I was capable of going down 15m.
You can do it!
(It was hard for the last one to decide to climb down.)
This is scary, sir.
If I go down safely,
I will treat you something tasty in Korea.
Okay, sure.
- Should I go? - Step back.
(At last, Ye Rin's challenge begins.)
I'm holding the rope, so don't worry and let go of the rope slowly.
Let go of it. That's it.
- You won't fall. - Loosen the grip of the right hand.
- Release your left hand's hold. - You can do this!
(Everyone roots for her with one heart.)
Just lie back.
(She slips.)
Just lean back from where you are.
- What should I do? - Lean back. Don't hold the rope.
- Just lower yourself. - Lower my feet?
Lean back.
Lean back!