Fair eastside
by thy side
we'll stand
and always
praise thy name
and ever lend our hearts
and hands
to help increase thy fame
the honor
of old eastside high
brings forth our loyalty
so cheer
for dear old eastside high
lead on to victory
man: As the tension mounts
throughout the free world,
the ladies have a surprising
15-0 lead over the boys.
Now next question,
bonus question for 20 points.
What is the origin
of our civil rights?
The magna carta.
No, tom, no.
Ellen, take it.
English common law.
20-point bonus.
Boys lose 10 points
for ringing the bell
without knowing the answer.
It's a 10-point loss.
The magna carta was a document
guaranteeing rights,
but the rights of whom?
Uh, stacey.
The aristocracy.
10-point bonus
for the girls.
The aristocracy
vis-a-vis the king.
The people got their rights
from the common well.
The common well.
Hence... come on, who knows?
Uh... anthony.
Commonwealth?
10-point bonus
for the boys.
Good, but, guys,
watch out.
Girls have a 45-0 lead.
You're not doing too well.
Next two.
Come on. Quickly.
All right.
Here we go.
Bonus question
for 10 points.
Define the word
"imbrue."
Aha. I'll spell it
for you.
L-m-b-r-u-e.
Imbrue.
Mr. Clark, could your class
spare you for a minute?
Surely. Kids,
take your seats. Quickly.
Come on. Quickly.
Take out your pencils.
Write this down.
Imbrue-to taint,
to stain.
The cancer of racism
imbrues our national
character.
It stains the spirit,
taints the soul.
It is a blot,
a shameful, greasy spot
on the fabric
of our national conscience.
Imbrue-to taint,
to stain.
30 words tomorrow.
Test.
What's the matter?
They're holding
a meeting
of the union
executive board.
Without us?
They didn't
tell me, either.
I told you we couldn't
trust them.
Keep it down.
Those no-good bastards
sell us out-
out of a union we started?
Betray us like
a bunch of judases?
They won't crucify me.
No, sir. I got
the hammer and nails.
I won't be anybody's
martyr, frank.
I'm sick and tired
of spineless jellyfish.
Save it
for the meeting.
Why, man?
I got plenty.
I'm the rockefeller
of outrage.
What the hell are
you people doing?
We're having a meeting.
You're
selling us out.
We cannot have
an effective voice.
Our curriculum will
be impotent
if we sell out every
time they threaten us.
You want to talk,
about this, call me in
we have
to stick together.
What we have to do
is pay our bills.
You want to carry
picket signs.
We just want to work.
We're tired
of the agitation,
the posturing
of crazy-
how can you talk
about posturing
when you're always
bent over
kissing posteriors
at the school board?
You want to
step outside?
If you had any nerve
at all,
you'd be fighting
on my side.
Mr. Clark, i'm afraid
that's a moot point.
We just found out
that the board of education
will grant
our salary increments
if we agree
to accept their condition
that you be transferred
to school 6,
and we agreed.
God bless you, man.
Pay your bills.
Joe.
They can go to hell.
Come on, joe.
This place deserves
exactly what it gets.
Welcome to the jungle
we got fun and games
we got everything you want
honey, we know the names
we are the people
that can find
whatever you may need
if you've got
the money, honey
we got your disease
in the jungle,
welcome to the jungle
want to bring you
to your n-n-n-n knees, knees
i want to
watch you bleed
welcome to the jungle
we take it day by day
and if you want,
you're gonna bleed
but this is the price
you pay
aah!
In the jungle,
welcome to the jungle
it's all right.
Shh. It's all right.
It's all right.
What are you doing?
Go back
to your class.
Leave me alone!
Welcome to the jungle
it gets worse here
every day
learn to live like
an animal
in the jungle
where we play
you got to remember
what you see
you'll take it
eventually
you can have
anything you want
but you better not
take it from me
in the jungle
welcome to the jungle
want to bring you
to your n-n-n-n-knees, knees
what's up, brian?
I'm gonna
watch you bleed
when you're high
you never, ever
want to come down
so down, so down
so down
yeah, oh
yo! Where's
my money?
I said,
where's my money?
Where's my money?
Hey, hey, hey.
Stop it, stop it,
stop it.
In the jungle,
welcome to the jungle
want to bring you
to your n-n-n-n-knees, knees
in the jungle
welcome to the jungle
want to bring you
to your
it's gonna
bring you down
huh
don't make me
fight you, man.
Get in the locker.
Come on, man.
You're messing up
my books.
I'm gonna-
markus, what are
you doing?
Let him out.
He lives in there.
He likes it.
Somebody!
Somebody help!
Help somebody,
please.
Help! Help me!
Let me out!
Somebody help!
Please, let me out!
Let me out, please!
Help!
Somebody let me out!
I can't breathe!
Somebody let me out,
please!
Somebody help me, please!
I can't breathe!
Somebody open up
the door!
Open the door, please!
Somebody let me out!
I just don't
goddamn believe it.
I've got an election
coming up,
and you hit me
with this now?
The state report came
from trenton just now.
And we... well, actually,
they ranked the schools.
We were last
in the state.
Oh, that's a crock.
They can't just take
my schools away.
You're quite right.
That's what
i thought.
But, well, no, see, now,
actually, they can.
What?
The house passed
a bill last week.
75% of high school
students
must pass the minimum
basic skills test,
or the state takes control
by the end of the school year.
Well, how many
passed last year?
About 38%.
38%?
What in god's name
are they doing
down there
at eastside?
They were
your appointees, don.
Don't try pinning
this on me.
You're
the superintendent
of schools,
remember?
Now, look, i'm not
going down the tubes
just because
those kids
can't pass
some test.
It's a can
of worms, don.
The only person
who would take this job
is someone
with nothing to lose
then the question becomes
what would we want with him?
I'm sitting here
racking my brain-
you're sitting there
setting me up.
I know you
like a book.
No, wait a minute.
No!
No, no, no, no, no,
not that nut! No!
No way!
He's the only guy
i can think of.
Oh, lord help us.
Derrick, derrick,
slow down, now.
I am, mr. Clark.
Slow down!
Bye, mr. Clark.
So long, kids.
Hey, joe.
Am i in trouble?
You gotta bring your lawyer?
Rosenberg.
Joe. Hot
for october.
How's it going
over here?
Ok. Same old,
same old.
What brings you down?
We came from
the mayor's office.
They need a new principal
at eastside high.
Gotta get
those test scores up.
He specifically
thought of you.
Sure.
Ok. I thought
of you.
All this time
i been stuck down here,
and you ask me now, frank.
I'm not a miracle
worker, joe.
Hello,
dr. Napier.
Mr. Clark,
the girls
need that room
for baking class.
We continue to find
gum under the desks.
I'll make an announcement
in the morning.
Will that satisfy you?
Mrs. Hamilton, you
know mr. Rosenberg,
the school board
attorney.
Yes. How are you,
mr. Rosenberg?
Excuse us,
mrs. Hamilton.
Dr. Napier wants to
inspect our new sandbox.
Our sandbox?
I didn't mean to interrupt.
Good seeing you,
dr. Napier.
Yes, yes.
Forget about what
happened before.
This is a chance
to make changes,
stop blowing smoke
up each other's butts,
see if we can turn
this thing around.
You mean nobody else
wants the job?
Nobody i'd want.
You add my name
to the list.
You're bullshit.
Don't talk to me
about saving those kids.
The mayor wants
to save his budget,
and you want
to save your ass.
Well, so what.
You want
the truth, joe?
Yeah, frank.
Let's have some truth.
For all your talk
and all your
crazy joe routine,
what have you done?
Nothing!
You're nothing but
an insignificant man!
It's like
you were never born.
Your life hasn't
made any difference.
Neither has mine.
Want to take that
to the grave.
We want to welcome
mr. Clark to eastside.
We've heard so much
about you.
In anticipation
of your arrival,
ms. Levias, your other
vice principal, and i
have appointed
an executive committee
to oversee
certain areas
where we have noted
a need for improvement-
you may sit down,
mr. O'malley.
You think you can
run this school?
If you could,
then i wouldn't
be here, would i?
No one talks
in my meetings.
No one!
Take out your
pencils and write.
I want the names
of every hoodlum,
drug dealer,
and miscreant
who's done nothing
but take
this place apart
on my desk
by noon today.
Reverend slappy.
Yes, sir.
You're now
the chief custodian.
You will scour
this building clean.
Graffiti goes up,
it's off the next day.
Yes, sir.
The very next day.
Detention students
can help you.
Let them scrub
this place for a while.
And tear down those cages
in the cafeteria.
You treat them
like animals,
that's exactly
how they'll behave.
This is my new dean
of security,
mr. William wright.
He will be
my avenging angel
as you teachers
reclaim the halls.
This is an institution
of learning.
If you can't control it,
how can you teach?
Discipline is not the enemy
of enthusiasm.
Mr. Zirella.
Yes?
Mr. Zirella, you are now
my new head football coach.
Mr. Darnell.
Stand up,
mr. Darnell.
Mr. Darnell will be
your assistant.
You know why
you're being demoted?
Because i'm sick
and tired
of our football team getting
pushed all over the field.
Thank you. Sit down.
I want precision.
I want
a weight program.
If you don't like it,
mr. Darnell, quit.
Same goes
for the rest of you.
You've tried it your way
for years.
Your students can't pass
a minimum basic skills test.
That means they can
hardly read!
They've given me
less than one year,
one school year to turn
this place around,
to get those
test scores up
so the state
will not take us over
to perform the task
which you have failed to do-
to educate our children!
Forget about the way
it used to be.
It's not
a damn democracy.
We're in a state
of emergency,
and my word is law!
There's only one boss
in this place,
and that's me,
the h-n-l-c.
Are there
any questions?
Mr. Wright.
The h-n-l-c?
The head nigger
in charge.
Everybody, right up here,
right here.
Check this out.
When i want
your body...
george, brian, sams,
they want you onstage.
Let's go.
Right now.
Mrs. Santos,
what about us?
What about you?
What about me?
Sit down.
I said sit down.
What do they
want us for?
I don't know.
Go.
What do you got
to do around here
to get picked
for something?
Maria, sit down.
Get down
get down
some guys are lame
they want my fame
i got a girl
with juice
her name is deluce,
so check it out
look at chita,
holmes.
Let her
check me out, man.
Afraid of the girlies?
Flash some cash, boy.
Want some?
I'll give you some.
Buy her
some stupid gold.
Step off, man.
You're a joke.
Is this normal?
I'm afraid so.
Is everybody
on the list onstage?
Yes, sir.
I gave their names
to homeroom teachers.
Ladies with the crabs
let me hear you say yeah!
Who's got the crabs?
Mr. Clark.
Don't you remember me?
Kaneesha.
Kaneesha,
how are you, baby?
You know him?
Oh, we go way back.
Fifth grade.
Yeah. How are
things going?
Ok.
Just ok?
Listen, you have any problems,
come and see me.
I'm in my office
every morning at 6:00, ok?
Ok. Good to see you.
That was my elementary
school principal.
All right, people.
Settle down.
Get down
off the seats.
Settle down.
Settle down, boys and girls.
May i have
your attention?
Quiet.
Quiet down.
Take your seats.
You people sit down.
Sit down.
Quiet down.
I am your new principal.
My name is joe clark.
I want you to be quiet!
I want you to listen!
From here out,
there will be no smoking
in this school!
All of you who are smoking,
put out your cigarettes
on the soles of your shoes.
Put the butts
in your pockets now!
You, there. You.
Put out your cigarette.
I'm going to ask
the people onstage
to open
with our school song.
Mr. Roland.
Boy: Do you believe
this guy?
Go, go, sing!
Suck my dick!
You sing the song.
You sing it.
Joe: All right. That's enough,
mr. Roland.
That's enough.
I want all of you
to take a good look
at these people
on the risers behind me.
These people have been here
up to five years
and done absolutely nothing.
These people are
drug dealers and drug users.
They have taken up space.
They have disrupted
this school.
They have harassed
your teachers,
and they have
intimidated you.
Well, times are
about to change.
You will not be bothered
in joe clark's school.
Yeah!
Shh!
These people
are incorrigible,
and since none of them
could graduate anyway,
you are all expurgated.
You are dismissed.
You are out of here
forever.
I wish you well.
Oh, shit.
Mr. Wright.
I don't need
your school.
I'm going in
the air force, man.
Know what i'm saying?
You know
what i'm saying?
I told you, man.
You ain't nobody.
I'm gonna
get you, man.
You ain't nobody.
Next time it may be you.
If you do no better
than they did,
next time itwillbe you.
They said this school
was dead
like the cemetery
it's built on,
but we call our eastside teams
ghosts, don't we?
And what are ghosts?
Ghosts are spirits
that rise from the dead.
I want you
to be my ghosts.
You are going to lead
our resurrection
by defying
the expectation
that all of us
are doomed to failure.
My motto is simple.
If you do not succeed in life,
i don't want you
to blame your parents.
I don't want you
to blame the white man.
I want you
to blame yourselves.
The responsibility
is yours!
In two weeks,
we have a practice exam
and the minimum basic
skills test on april 13th.
That's 110 school days
from now,
but it's not just about
those test scores.
If you do not have
these basic skills,
you will find yourselves
locked out,
locked out
of that american dream
that you see
advertised on tv,
that they tell you
is so easy to get.
You are here
for one reason,
one reason only-
to learn
to work
for what you want.
The alternative is
to waste your time
and to fall
into the trap
of crime, drugs,
and death.
Does everyone
understand that?
Do all of you
understand me?
Then welcome to the new
eastside high.
Mr. Clark
don't play.
What happened this
morning is an outrage.
My boy's no criminal.
Those children
belong in school,
not back out
on the street.
You're a fascist,
clark!
Our kids don't
deserve this!
Some of them
are smart.
They're just
discouraged
about their chances
out there,
what kind of jobs
they got waitin'.
Now what kind of
chance do they have?
He insulted the black
football coach.
The man's gone crazy.
He's declared war
on his own people.
Remember,
miss barrett,
mr. Clark
was nice enough
to come to this
emergency meeting
after a very
trying day.
I think we owe him
a chance to respond.
They say
one bad apple
spoils the bunch.
Man: My son
ain't no bad apple!
Well, what about 300?
Rotten to the core.
Now, you're right,
mrs. Barrett.
This is a war.
It's a war to save
2,700 other students,
most of whom don't have
the basic skills
to pass the state exam.
Now, if you want
to help us, fine.
Sit down with your kids
and make them study.
Go get your families
off welfare.
How dare you talk
about welfare!
Give our children
some pride.
Let them get their
priorities straight.
When dr. Napier
came to me
offering this job,
i saw the lightning flash.
All right!
I heard the thunder roll!
Give it to 'em!
I felt breakers crashing,
swamping my soul.
We are not in church,
mr. Clark!
I fell down
on my knees...
and i cried,
"my god...
why has thou
forsaken me?"
Tell 'em
about it.
And the lord said,
"joe, you're no damn good."
No, no. I mean this...
more than you realize.
"You're no earthly
good at all
"unless you take
this opportunity
and do whatever
you have to."
And he didn't say,
"joe, be polite."
Do whatever you have to
to transform and transmogrify
this school
into a special place,
where the hearts and souls
and minds of the young
can rise,
where they can
grow tall and blossom
out from under the shadows
of the past,
where the minds of the young
are set free.
That's right!
And i gave
my word to god.
And that's why
i threw those bastards out.
And that's all
i'm going to say.
Mr. Clark, i wanted to
talk to you
about those kids
you threw out yesterday.
Well,
what about them?
I was one of them,
but you made
some kind of mistake.
Mistake?
Yes, sir.
What's your name,
son?
Sams.
Thomas sams.
You're a freshman?
Yes, sir.
Cutting class and
smoking crack, mr. Sams.
There's no mistake.
No, sir. It wasn't me, sir.
I swear it wasn't.
It wasn't you?
No.
Do you think
i'm stupid, son?
No, sir.
Yes, you do.
You're trying to con
a con man.
You're not even
learning anything
on the streets,
are you?
You come with me.
What are you doing?
What's up here?
Now, let me
tell you something.
The trouble
with being a teenager
is you don't
know nothing.
You think you're smarter
than people who've already been
down the road
you're traveling.
You know
what i'm saying?
Do you?
Yes, sir.
Did you tell your father
i threw you out of school?
Look at me, damn it!
No, sir.
Why not?
No guts, huh?
Afraid of what
he'll say, aren't you?
My father doesn't live
with us anymore, sir.
Is that what
you're doing?
Going around feeling
sorry for yourself?
Get out of here!
You're wasting my time!
Please let me
back, sir.
I have to
get back at school.
I can't tell my mama
i got kicked out.
Now, why should i let you
back into my school?
Because i'm going
to do better, sir.
How?
By doing my work.
What else?
And staying
out of trouble.
What have you been thinking
about all this time?
Why should i
believe you now?
Because
i changed my ways.
I don't believe you,
sams.
I don't think you've changed
a thing. Go on, jump!
No. I don't
want to jump.
Yes, you do!
You smoke crack, don't you?
You smoke crack,
don't you?
Look at me, boy!
Don't you smoke crack?
Yes, sir.
You know what
that does to you, huh?
No, sir.
It kills brain cells, son.
It kills brain cells.
When you're destroying
brain cells,
you're killing yourself,
only it's slower!
If you want to
kill yourself,
don't fuck around with it!
Do it expeditiously!
Go on, jump!
No. I don't want
to kill myself, sir.
You're sure?
Yes, sir.
I tell you
what i'll do.
I'll go back on my own word
just this once
and let you back into
my school,
'cause you're still a baby,
and you don't know shit.
But you understand
this, boy.
You're not gonna get
a moment's rest.
I'm gonna be on your case
every minute.
You mess up just once,
and you're out of here.
You understand me?
Do you understand me?
Yes, sir.
Now, go on
back downstairs.
All right, people.
Let's settle down in here.
Now, settle down,
quiet down.
Let those who are trying to
eat their lunch digest.
Robert, boy, you had lunch
at fourth period. Go on.
If mr. O'malley didn't
do anything, mr. Clark won't.
Louisa, you're looking
mighty good today.
Gonna have to tell
these boys to watch out.
You kids
having any problems?
Yeah. She is.
Tell him.
Louisa?
Why do i have
to take home ec?
I want to take auto shop.
I have brothers and sisters.
My mother works.
I've been cooking
for 11 years.
Does it look
like i don't cook?
I want you to take this
to mr. O'malley.
You know how much
auto mechanics make?
$17 an hour.
Boy: That girl
right there, man.
Yo, sweetheart. Right here.
I got hunger pains, baby.
You could be my lunch.
Boy, get off this table!
Get your hormones together!
It ain't hormones.
She's fly, man.
She's a fox.
I just saw you with your
arms around clarisse.
You honked off
with that skeezer?
No, i never-
check it out.
It was only one time.
Chill out, man!
Richard, for your first job
as class president,
i want to build
an atrium.
Track me down tomorrow.
We'll talk about it.
Don't worry about it.
How you doin', brother?
Good to see you.
Oh, you, hey!
Yes, mr. Clark?
What's your name?
Kid ray.
How you doin'?
Nice suit.
Just like you,
mr. Clark.
Got to
look the part.
These kids don't
understand that.
Hey!
Sams, put it back!
Put it back!
How many times have
i told you, boy?
Put something in
your head, not on it.
Pull your pants up!
Show some dignity!
Have some sense!
What's he doing
hanging out with you seniors?
You're providing
a deleterious influence here.
Mr. Clark,
he's my cousin.
We was just
goin' over music.
Music, huh?
Come here.
Let me have your attention.
Everyone quiet down!
I want all radios off
instantaneously.
All radios off.
I want all of you
to look at this...
slovenly, sloppy boy here...
as an example
of how not to dress.
Now, if you
look like this
when you look in your mirrors
in the morning,
find something else
to put on.
Self-respect permeates
every aspect of your lives.
If you don't have it
for yourselves,
you're not going to get it
from anywhere.
Now, to prove
their self-respect,
mr. Sams and his friends here-
you boys stand up.
I'm going to
pound him.
Mr. Sams and his friends
are going to sing
our school song.
I want
absolute silence.
No one
is permitted to move
during the singing
of the school song.
All right.
Let's hear it.
Fair eastside
by the road-
mr. Darnell, no one
is permitted to move
during the song!
I was picking up
trash.
Report to my office!
Immediately!
Woo!
Quiet!
Quiet in here!
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha!
All right. Continue.
So cheer for...?
You boys are on detention,
3 days each.
You will
learn this song,
or next time,
you'll be suspended.
This goes for everybody!
You will sing the school song
upon demand,
or you will suffer
dire consequences!
Mr. Wright, take this
riffraff to my office.
Hit the road, jack
and don't you come back?
No more, no more,
no more, no more
hit the road, jack
and don't you come back
no more
what you say?
O, o glorious
is thy name
o mighty lord
glorious is thy name-
people, what are you-
can i help you,
mr. Clark?
Yes, you may.
I want everyone
to be able to sing the
school song on demand
or be suspended.
Can you see to that?
Certainly, mr. Clark.
From the top-
mrs. Elliott, may i see
you in the hall, please?
Now?
Yes, now!
Will you see if you can
get these people together?
Mm-hmm.
If you sing like that
in new york,
we will not
be invited back.
I don't like
being ignored.
I'm sorry if you weren't
getting enough attention,
but i'm training a chorus.
You don't think the school
song is important enough
to warrant
a little interruption?
It's fine, but we
were doing mozart.
We were in the middle
of a difficult part.
If you'd like us
to respect your work,
try to appreciate ours.
Who do you think
you're talking to?
A man who seems threatened
when any other adult
does something
the children like.
Mrs. Powers, i want it quiet
in here right now!
I'd love to chat,
mr. Clark,
but i have a concert
next week in new york,
and i'd like to be
prepared.
What?
Prepared-you know
what that means-
capable, ready,
and up to your job.
What concert?
The one at lincoln center.
We do it every year.
Until now. Your concert
is canceled.
What?
Cancelled!
You know what canceled
means, don't you?
Over, finished,
terminated!
Why? They've worked
too hard!
For not telling me.
Oh, i filed a form
in your office!
And for rank
insubordination!
You've questioned my
judgment, intelligence!
You're the one who comes
around here to bother me.
You're a despicable man!
I've nothing to say to you.
Let's accommodate that.
You're fired!
You need
a psychiatrist!
Get out!
Right now!
Fine! Fired? You'll hear
from my lawyer!
Mr. Clark.
Ms. Levias, these miscreants
don't know the school song.
They've got
3 days' detention.
Mr. Darnell,
into my office.
Fellas, come on up.
What was that all about?
I said no one move
during the school song.
If you can't understand
that, find another job.
I was picking up
paper!
You contradicted me
in front of my students!
They'remystudents!
They are my students,
mr. Darnell!
Just what are you
trying to prove?
I'm working
my ass off for you.
I took the demotion.
I'm doing my job!
You're just
getting your rocks off
by treating me like trash.
No, sir. That's what
you were picking up.
God damn it!
You give me the goddamn respect
you would want yourself,
or i will kick
your black ass!
You are suspended,
sir, as of right now!
Get out!
Ahh!
Oh, my god!
What is going on?
Mr. Darnell is suspended.
Indefinitely.
You don't have the power
to suspend a teacher!
Then i can recommend.
Get me the forms.
Yes, sir.
Please, mr. Darnell is more
than a football coach.
He teaches english!
Not anymore.
The state practice test
is tomorrow. Why do this now?
Ms. Levias-
mr. Clark?
What do you want?
What?
It could wait.
Mr. Clark,
do you have any idea
of the chaos you have
caused around here?
Nobody knows
what you're doing!
That's exactly
the way i like it!
Never made first period
for one year straight
forget a diploma,
it's education i hate
i feel like droppin' my books
and just strafin' it
'cause the way i'm feelin',
i ain't makin' it
school's the place
i don't really want to be in
the day i quit,
that's it, i'm leavin'
when people tell me
about gettin' grades up
my reply-"am i gettin' paid
or what?"
Bright in the morning,
my alarm awakes me
my mom won't, she's a witch,
she hates me
failin' all my classes,
i don't give a damn
success,
i ain't makin' it
stay to your right.
Let's get to your classes.
Come on, now.
We got 20 seconds to the bell.
Let's go. Sams, sams,
come here. Where you going?
Lunch.
Try to eat
some vegetables
for a change, ok?
Lay off
those muffins.
See you later.
Don't bunch up
down there, people.
That doesn't concern you.
We'll tell you about it later.
All right, richard.
It's all yours.
We have two groups
to thank-
the black and hispanic
alumnl-
for giving us
sofas and armchairs.
It makes the school
seem, as mr. Clark
would say, a home
away from home.
Having fun?
I am.
I haven't heard a word
about those test scores.
They'll send them-
send them how?
By pony express?
Am i supposed to
wait for them?
Get yourself
down to trenton,
where they're probably
on some desk.
Bring them back here
where they can do some good.
But now, ladies
and gentlemen,
for the grand finale-
ms. Levias,
if you would-
our very own
passaic river falls.
Good job. You're doing
very well, son.
I'm very
proud of you.
Mr. Clark,
come to the cafeteria quick!
Some guy's
beating up kid ray!
Hey, stop it!
Stop it!
Come on, old man.
I been waitin' for this.
Come on.
Get this disgrace
to his race out of here!
You already threw
this disgrace out once.
Then what's
he doing back?
Someone must have
let him in from the inside.
I want every door
in this school
chained and locked-
all of them!
Yes, sir.
Hi, mr. Clark.
Oh, hi, kids.
How you doin'?
Hi, mr. Clark.
What's up?
Hi, nathalee.
Kaneesha, what's
the matter, doll?
Kaneesha?
Now, i told you if you
have any problems,
you come and see me.
Come on, now.
I've known you more
than half your life.
What's the matter?
How are your grades?
They're not too good.
Well, why not?
You're a smart girl.
You shouldn't be
having any problems.
I don't have
no place to live.
Well, where's
your mother?
She don't want me
no more.
Now, here.
Come with me. Come on.
I'll see what i can do
about this.
Ms. Levias, you know
kaneesha carter here.
You go on in
to miss ruiz.
Is he all right?
He'll survive.
Kaneesha here is having
a problem at home.
Pull her file, talk to her,
get back to me.
Come on, kaneesha.
Because it
never made a difference
i never paid attention
to the sound
of my own despair
trick or treat!
There was
never no feelin'
never not needing
that child
even though
i couldn't always be there
and time don't wait
on love, now
life don't wait
for a break
in the weather
what if i'm left
with no love at all?
No love at all?
Who's there?
Mrs. Carter?
Mrs. Carter
doesn't live here.
Kaneesha: Mama, it's me.
It's joan levias
from eastside.
I'm here
with mr. Clark.
'Cause time
don't wait on love, now
and life don't send you
an invitation
been a long time,
mrs. Carter.
Please.
Come in.
No love at all
i've been meaning to come by
and talk to you.
Mind if i try and act
civilized for a moment?
Offered you two
a seat.
Mrs. Carter, i ran into
kaneesha in the halls.
Was talking
about her grades.
She says you don't want
her around anymore.
I don't expect
your sympathy,
but i ruined my life.
I know that's my business
to deal with that.
It's been hard enough.
Joe: When kaneesha
was in the fifth grade,
you were one of my most
active parents.
You were always
at school helping out.
We don't mean
to pry, mrs. Carter,
but kaneesha
has a gift.
She has that spark.
We have to look after her.
Why would she think
you wouldn't want her?
I had kaneesha
when i was 15.
I didn't want
no welfare,
so i quit school,
worked,
came home at night,
didn't have no life.
So when she was old enough
to take care of herself,
i ran out and got one.
Is that what
you're doing now?
I'm just now getting back
on my feet, you know?
As i get clean...
i see myself
for what i am...
and i hate it.
And i don't want her
to see me like this no more.
So when the people from
the foster home came by,
i thought it was
the right thing to do.
Why would i want
to get rid of her?
I love her...
more than myself.
Mrs. Carter...
if we helped you
find a job,
a better place
to live,
would that help?
Because, frankly,
i don't see
kaneesha making it
without you.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Good.
Thanks, bob.
We'll talk tomorrow.
What was that
all about?
Chains on the doors.
Thought you people
didn't like chains.
You see this yet?
You know,
all of your shit
comes down
on my head.
Oh, frank, look.
This is-
no. You let me talk.
It's like you're
a big bird with radar.
I'm tired of getting hit.
Is this my fault?
This is nothing!
I've got union lawyers
threatening me.
There's talk
of a walkout.
Let 'em!
They're not teaching
anything anyway!
Then do something
about it!
Not one of 'em
has a personal stake
in that school!
Not one!
The fire chief says
it's illegal to bar doors.
Mrs. Barrett is organizing
a parents group to remove you
since you suggested that
they get off welfare
because quite a few
of them need it.
I wasn't talking
to all of them, frank.
Look, you came
and recruited me, man.
You disappoint me.
The disappointment
here is you!
Me?
Yes!
You've known me
30 years.
You know
how i operate.
Nigger,
can you keep quiet?
The fact is
you're screwing up!
You're alienating
everybody!
You have no life.
Your wife left you.
I ought to
walk out myself!
Go ahead,
bail out!
I said
i'd back you up!
That's what
yousaid, frank!
Brother, i'll go
through the fire with you,
but you are not
taking care of business.
But this shit you're
pulling now,
you've just gone
plain loco!
You suspend darnell!
What the hell was that?
Darnell is symptomatic
of disciplinary-
he is a good, strong,
young black teacher!
He dumped that desk
on top of your head.
Good for him.
You will reinstate that man!
You fire
mrs. Elliott. Why?
She didn't want to
kiss your ass.
I wouldn't either!
Mrs. Elliott
has an ego problem.
Well, you lost
the best teacher we had!
I don't have time for
mrs. Elliott's problem!
You better make time!
We're being crucified
by a process
that's turning blacks
into a permanent
underclass here!
See? Nobody wants
to talk about that!
Mrs. Elliott's missionary
zeal about mozart
has nothing to do
with our problem!
What good will mozart do
children who can't
go out and get a job?
Joe,
your personal battles
are going to
cost us the war.
Worry about
the test scores.
What the hell you think
i'm worried about?
End of discussion!
Debate is over!
You will write
a formal apology
for your treatment
of mrs. Elliott and darnell
and for your thoughtless insult
to the women of this community!
You will kowtow
and step and fetch.
Get used to it!
It's the way of the world!
If you're so hot
on discipline,
then start
by accepting mine
because contrary
to popular opinion,
i am the head nigger
in charge!
Come on. Let's get
something to eat.
Boy...
you really think
you bad, don't you?
You're all in violation
of the fire code!
You cannot prevent me
from going in.
You're not getting in,
and that's that.
You have no right
to lock these doors.
This isn't a plant.
This is my school.
If you want
to get in here,
apply for a pass
like everyone else.
What the hell
is the bat for?
They used to call me
crazy joe.
Now they can call me
batman.
I got thugs and drug dealers
trying to get into my school.
You might be one.
I don't know.
Are you crazy?
I got all day,
chief.
How much time
do you have?
I'll be back, clark.
Thanks, mr. Darnell.
Good to have you back.
You shouldn't have fired me
in the first place.
You're right, but don't
get used to it.
Mr. Clark, why did you
lock the school?
Aren't you concerned
about students' safety?
Get these people
back to their classes.
Honey, get back
to your class.
You're playing
into his hands.
That was
the fire chief.
Know what he's saying
right now?
"Black bastard
can't throw me out,"
know where he's saying it?
Out in the parking lot.
Mr. Clark,
a baseball bat?
If they'd got me
those emergency doors
that sound an alarm
when you open them up
like the ones
white schools have,
i wouldn't
have to chain them.
Those doors cost
a fortune.
We don't have enough
money for books.
Tell the mayor that.
Call the federal government.
Never mind
what i'm doing.
Why don't you do
what i ask you?
Where are those
test scores i asked for?
Hey, mr. Clark.
Hi. Where you been?
I was sick.
Sick, huh?
Hi, eric.
What was that
altercation about?
Alteration?
Are my pants too tight?
The fight you had
in the cafeteria.
Don't get cute with me.
I've already had enough
shit from this.
Why did he come after you?
You dealing drugs?
We don't need
to get into this.
I just came here
to tell you something.
I don't think
i'm cut out for school.
I just came
to say good-bye.
Dropping out
on me, huh?
I'm not dropping out.
I'm moving on.
You'll be dead
in a year, son.
You hear
what i'm saying?
You'll be dead
in a year.
Mr. Clark,
i got to go.
You know, baby,
i look at you,
and i want to do
the hootchie cootchie.
Hootchie cootchie,
that's what i'm doing.
You know, sometime,
baby.
Come on, fellas,
not again.
Sams, freeze.
Where are you
running off to?
Why aren't you
carrying a book?
I got lunch
then gym-
why did i let you
back in here?
To get an education.
How you gonna get an
education if you don't read?
I read.
When do you get
your report card?
Next week. Miss james
says i'm getting a "b."
I knew you were smart.
I knew it, too.
See you later. Nice tie.
Sams, get back here.
Let's see
what's in here.
You don't want to go
in there. It stinks.
My, my, my.
Aren't you
my little songbirds
from the cafeteria?
Weren't they with you?
Who, these guys?
I'm sure you've learned
the school song by now.
You better know it
because this time
if you don't
get it right,
you're suspended
for 10 days each.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
All right,
let me hear it.
All right, fellas,
let him hear it.
Fair eastside
fair eastsl-l-ide
fair eastside
by thy side
we'll stand
and always
praise thy name
praise thy name,
to heaven, yeah
lend our hearts
and hands
to help increase
thy fame
ooh, lord
the honor, yeah
of old eastside high
calls forth
our loyalty
loyalty, loyalty
so cheer-
all right,
all right!
Who taught you that?
Answer me!
I know you didn't
do it yourselves.
Sams!
What?
Who taught you this song?
Speak up!
Mrs. Powers.
Mrs. Powers, eh?
Come with me, all of you.
...out this world
gonna shoulder up
my cross
gonna take it home
to my jesus
ain't that good news?
I got a savior
in that kingdom
ain't that good news?
I got a savior
in that kingdom
ain't that good news?
No, no, no, people.
You must remember,
we need intonation,
phonation, accuracy, and pitch.
Now, this is your note.
Hmm
mrs. Powers.
Yes, sir.
These hoodlums
told me something.
Did you change
the school song?
Mrs. Powers-
let her answer!
The children thought
the song was boring.
Boring, huh?
I have
never heard
a school song
like that.
I didn't authorize
you to change it,
did i?
No, you didn't.
I want everyone
to learn that song
in english and spanish.
Immediately.
Take a bow,
mrs. Powers.
You've rewritten
our alma mater.
The honor
of old eastside high
brings forth
our loyalty
loyalty, loyalty
so cheer for dear
old eastside...
how's it going?
What you got
in there, malachi?
My future.
All right.
...aboard eastside
all aboard, all aboard
yes, eastside
how's it going,
mr. Darnell?
Good, good.
That's great.
...high
ge-e-et
fellas?
On
that
train
ms. Levias...
hi, mr. Clark.
I just heard something
you wouldn't believe.
Uh, mr. Clark,
mr. O'malley just brought
this from trenton.
The school's
practice test.
I had to wait
all this time for this?
Next time i order you
to go get something,
you better damn well
go get it yourself!
Oh, no.
Oh, my god.
Give me your
attention, everyone.
First three rows
take 4 steps forward.
Right now! Come on!
1, 2, 3, 4.
Ok, that's good.
Turn around.
Hold it,
mr. O'malley!
What's
your excuse?
I was filling out
a big stack of forms.
I didn't know
what time it was.
This is a prime example
of the kind of
inefficiency and apathy
that is destroying
this school.
Mr. O'malley, i can't
believe you're that bad.
I'll give you a chance
to revitalize your image.
Set up a student-peer
tutoring program.
Maybe the students
can help themselves.
Lord knows, you teachers
aren't doing the job.
Ms. Levias, i want
remedial reading on saturdays.
Volunteers will get
regular pay.
We can't afford
overtime.
Mr. Clark, the problem
isn't our pay.
What is the problem
as you see it?
How to get the students
in on saturday.
You hear that, people?
How do we get the students
in on saturdays
for remedial reading?
I'll tell you how.
We'll go to their homes.
We'll talk to their folks.
If their folks
can't read,
they can come in, too.
The only way
we'll get anything done
is to get everyone
involved.
And that goes
for all of you!
It's time
to get involved.
Everyone in this section,
put both your hands
above your heads.
Raise your hands!
Put them up!
You people represent
the 70% of our students
who just failed
the practice exam.
70%!
But that is not
their failure.
I don't blame them.
The failure is yours.
That's right, yours.
How many hours do you spend
preparing your lesson plans?
How often do you
stay after school
to give those children-
the ones
you know need it-
the extra help
that they require?
Keep your hands up.
Now you're getting a hint
of the hopelessness and shame
that makes those
failing students
throw up their hands
at the thought
of facing a world
for which you have not
prepared them.
You're getting an inkling
of the despair they feel
when left to the mercy
of the streets.
Keep your hands up high.
Look around
at yourselves.
Turn and look
at yourselves!
Because you are failing
to educate them,
this is the posture
our students will wind up in,
only they'll be staring
down the barrel of a gun!
Ooh, yeah, yeah
ahh ha ha
if a man is born
in luxury
it proves to me
through history
he is somebody
if a man is born
in poverty
privation and misery
he is nobody
everybody is somebody
nobody is nobody
i mean, apart
from all the wealthy
ooh
everybody is somebody
oh, yeah
so look at me here, man?
Ooh ooh ooh
oh, yeah
ooh ooh ooh
poverty is what,
what it takes
it makes such dangerous
mistakes about who
who is somebody
when a woman
has a child
before that child
is born
she, she is somebody
everybody is somebody
nobody is nobody
i mean, apart
from all the wealthy
doo doo doo doo doo
everybody is somebody
yeah, oh, yeah
all right, you guys,
forget it.
All right, i got one.
Who's this?
People, move to the right
of the halls.
Move expeditiously.
Francesca,
come over here.
How are you?
Fine, mr. Clark.
How's your sister?
She broke her leg.
That's good.
You have any problem,
come to my office.
Here's the key.
Ooh, that
ain't the key.
Sams, sams.
Where's sams?
Anybody see sams?
Pull your pants up, son.
Clarence, come here.
Get your hormones
under control, boy.
Let me feel your butt.
Joe: Clarence.
What do you think
you're doing?
I was just...
i was just, um...
francesca,
come here.
What is he doing?
Can he do me?
Does he have
the juice?
No way, mr. Clark.
Clarence, report
to my office.
Mr. Clark, i was
just fooling around.
Got you.
How do you learn the alphabet
? be on time
come on, sams!
You can do it.
...he's on time
j-o-e c-l-a...
don't give up!
Fall in together,
going "how do you like
the weather?"
Going "how do you
learn the alphabet?"
Be on time
school bell ring
at a quarter to 9:00
that's it, sams!
Stay with it, boy!
...be on time
"how do you learn
the alphabet?" be on time
how do you spell eastside
, eastside high?
How do you spell joe clark?
He's on time
j-o-e c-l...
holy cow!
I'm out of here.
Clark can't even get them
past that test.
I thought we'd
settled this.
With the doors chained,
that school's a firetrap.
He's laughing at us.
The man has
a legitimate problem.
How does he keep drug pushers
out of his school
if their buddies
can let them walk on in?
He's got a point.
This doesn't
concern you.
Don, we can both
go to jail.
By statute, we are
legally responsible.
If a fire broke out
and a kid got hurt,
they're going to
get trampled.
A bunch
of savages anyway.
Savages?
Don, can't you
control your men?
Ladies and gentlemen,
please leave me alone
with mrs. Barrett.
Don, i want to
talk to you.
I'll call you later
at your office.
Thank you, frank.
Close the door, eh?
I want to apologize for
the chief's use of language.
I don't like
none of you people.
Then let's cut through
the formalities.
What do you want?
Clark!
Just like that.
Head on a platter.
You think
i got an attitude.
Let me tell you
what i think.
You like clark
because he's a guard dog,
does your dirty work,
keeps the black folk in line.
That's fine, but you got
to get re-elected.
I got enough folks
lined up with me
to give you a damn hard time,
and i'll get more.
Unless i do what?
Appoint me
to the school board
so we can
vote clark out.
Otherwise we'll have to
vote you out.
It's always a pleasure
to see citizens
avail themselves of
the democratic process.
My job will be easy.
You're not too popular
these days, are you?
I'll sic the fire chief
on clark.
Will that satisfy you?
Yes. And then i'll get
the school board to dismiss him.
Then you'll come out
publicly for me.
It'll be my pleasure,
mr. Mayor.
That barrett
is a bitch on wheels.
Smart. She's smart.
Yeah. She got
your number.
When am i supposed
to do this?
Now we'd just
disrupt things.
Give him another week
to prepare for that test.
Then we'll catch him
with chains on the doors.
We nail him,
and we make her
happy.
Politics.
What a business.
It's just like yours,
putting out fires.
The mayor's going to
nail me, huh?
What do i
always say?
He's got the hammer
and nails himself.
These are some
of my white students.
Frankie, bernard,
steve.
Boys, this is mr. Rosenberg,
school attorney.
Let him hear
the school song.
Fair eastside
by thy side
by thy side?
We'll stand
we'll stand?
And always
praise thy name-
all right!
I can't stand this.
Needs work, fellas.
Some things
you can't teach.
Bad singing
isn't genetic.
How's your mother?
She got that job.
She's feeling good.
Girls,
what are you doing?
The phone's broken.
My baby's sick.
Make your call
from the office.
When will you girls
learn?
I ain't ashamed
about my baby.
Nobody's saying
you should be ashamed.
And she ain't
ashamed of me.
Whenever
she look at me,
she don't see
no wrong.
Ok. Go on and make
your call.
Mr. Vanzetti,
let these girls make a call.
Hey, mr. Clark.
We can't let them know
who told you.
Why not?
Mr. Clark,
we got a problem.
How come
you leave us out?
Everything's
for the black kids.
The gospel chorus,
football, basketball
is for the blacks.
I'm short. I can't
play basketball.
The point is,
you're ignoring us.
We're getting
really ticked off.
With a mouth
like yours,
you ought to
study law.
Really?
You kids wait for me
in my office.
If you all talk
at once,
i can't do anything.
I'll be with you ladies
in a minute.
Boss, you and mr. Rosenberg
better wait out here.
Miss lynn,
give markus a pass.
Ms. Levias,
is everyone here?
Yes, sir.
Let me have
your attention.
With the help of my ubiquitous,
clandestine informants
i have learned that the mayor
has told the fire chief
to catch me
with chains on the doors.
They want to prosecute me
and get me out of here.
The security guards are
our first line of defense.
If you see the fire chief,
stop him at the gates.
Call in code 10
on your walkie-talkies.
We will repeat code 10
on the p.a. System.
All teachers and guards
have keys to the exit doors.
When you hear code 10,
proceed to your assigned door
and remove the chains.
Guards, resume your posts.
Ms. Levias, take over.
Tell those kids in my office
to meet me here 7th period.
How did it go?
It's under control.
I have
the progress report
on the reading
program.
I thought you'd
like to hear it.
I would like to hear it.
I'd also like to hear
the kids in my office,
and mr. Rosenberg,
and dr. Napier.
I can't be 10 different
places at the same time.
Maybe my vice principal can do
something without me for once.
Mr. Clark.
I'll help you
7th period.
Excuse me.
Good night,
mr. Clark.
Good night.
Mr. Clark.
Yes, ms. Levias.
May i talk to you
for a minute, please?
What do you want?
I want you
to transfer me.
To where?
Out of here.
This doesn't
surprise me.
I've sensed resistance in you
since our very first meeting.
You're an egomaniacal
windbag.
Who you talking to?
You!
You like to whip people
who can't fight back.
I thought i could take it
because i had a father
in the same kind of pain
that makes you
such a bastard,
but i was wrong.
Life is much too short.
I will not endure you
any longer.
The only reason
i haven't walked out
and half the staff
with me
is because
those children need us.
You're so busy
talking discipline,
you forget to educate.
What the hell do you think
i've been doing here?
You cleaned it up.
That was easy.
Those children
want to be helped.
They've done everything
we've asked,
but i feel
sorry for them.
They're not ready
to take that test.
What the hell
are you talking about?
I have done everything-
i. It is always i.
There are 300
teachers here.
You don't
do it alone.
I don't have to listen
to these accusations.
Youwilllisten!
All right, ms. Levias,
go ahead and talk.
You've been flapping
your mouth,
and you haven't
heard a thing.
You haven't seen what's
painfully obvious.
I'll tell you what-
no, let me finish!
Everybody here
may not like you,
but we all applaud
your effort.
What you don't
understand
is the same people
who support you
are the ones
you're beating up!
You don't even
say thank you.
You just constantly
abuse them,
criticize them.
What the hell
do you want from me?
I want you
to get this straight.
Most of the teachers are
here because they care
about those children,
this school, this fight.
They're in it with you.
They take it home
the same as you.
They are part of those
children's lives.
You are thoughtless
and cruel,
and it hurts.
And none of them
deserve it.
They are sick of it,
and so am i.
Ms. Levias.
What's this?
The transfer
you asked for.
All right, people.
Here we are.
This is the day.
In one hour,
you're going to take an exam
administered by the state
to test your basic skills
and the quality of education
at eastside high.
And i want to tell you
what the people out there
are saying about you
and what they think
about your chances.
They say you are inferior.
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
"You are just a bunch of niggers
and spics and poor white trash."
"Education is wasted on you."
"You cannot learn!"
You're lost!
I mean all of you.
I want all the white students
to stand up.
All my white students,
stand up.
Come on.
Stand up.
That's it.
Come on, stand up.
These are my white children,
and they're the same
as all of you.
They've got no place to go.
Otherwise, they would have
abandoned us a long time ago,
but they couldn't.
So here they are at eastside,
just like the rest of us.
You can sit down.
Are you getting my point,
people?
Yes!
Is it sinking in?
We sink, we swim.
We rise, we fall.
We meet our fate together!
Now, it took the help
of a good, good friend
to make me know
and understand that,
and i do understand it,
and i'm grateful.
I'm eternally grateful.
And i've got a message
for those people out there
who've abandoned you
and written you off.
Can you hear me?
Yes!
Good!
You are not inferior!
Your grades may be.
Your school may have been.
But you can turn that around
and make liars
out of those bastards
in exactly one hour!
You'll take that test,
pass it, and win!
So here's what
i want you to do.
When you find
your minds wandering,
i want you to knuckle back down
and concentrate.
Concentrate!
Remember what's at stake
and show them what eastside high
is all about-
a spirit that will not die!
Sometimes in our lives
we all have pain
we all have sorrow
but if we are wise
we know that there's
always tomorrow
lean on me
when you're not strong
and i'll be your friend?
I'll help you carry on
for it won't be long
till i'm gonna need
somebody to lean on
you just call
on me, brother
when you need a hand
we all need somebody
to lean on
i just might have a problem?
That you'll understand
we all need somebody
to lean on
why don't you
lean on me?
Lean on me
if you need a friend
you can lean on me
i'll be your friend
lean on me
you can lean on me
come on
and lean on me
lean on me
you can lean on me
please, won't you
swallow your pride?
If i have things
you need to borrow
for no one can fill
those of your needs
that you won't let go
why don't you
just lean on?
Anytime
lean on
come on and lean on
lean on me,
you can lean on me
if you need a friend
lean on me
you can lean on me
and if you got a problem
i'm your problem solver?
You can lean on me
why don't you lean?
Lean on me
uh-huh
come on and lean on me
you can lean on me
call on me, brother
sister, give me your hand
lean on me,
you can lean on me
you can, you can, you can
lean on me,
you can lean on me
swallow up your pride
lean on me,
you can lean on...
please, children, people
lean on me, oh
eastside!
Eastside! Eastside!
Eastside!
Eastside! Eastside! Eastside!
Eastside...
dum dum-dum-dum-dum
dum-dum-dum-dum
dum-dum-dum dum-dum
dum-dum
sometimes in our lives
we all have pain
we all have sorrow
dum-dum-dum
but if we are wise
we know that there's
always tomorrow
i told you
these things take time.
Just how long
am i supposed to wait?
You boys are messing
with the wrong female.
He won't
let me in.
What's
going on?
Would you
talk to her?
I thought
we had made a deal.
Don't broadcast it
all over town.
I have got a school board
meeting tonight
and enough votes
to get clark kicked out
if i can prove
he's chained those doors.
We can get that
if you move on him today.
Chief gaines
already tried that.
Bullshit! I've made
promises of my own.
I've got people
with me right now.
If i can't deliver-
just a minute.
And i do not issue
idle threats.
Then don't, because
i don't want to hear it.
Ok, chief.
Mrs. Barrett was
promised some action.
I think it's time
we get a court order
and get you past
those guards.
Sounds good to me.
He ain't
worth it.
Jerk.
That's right.
He's a jerk.
I told you that.
You don't listen
to me.
What are you two ladies
doing in here?
Lillian, aren't you supposed
to be in class?
Huh?
Kaneesha?
What's going on
here?
Lillian?
What is
this?
You'll have to
ask her.
Kaneesha,
what's the matter?
I got pregnant.
Please don't
be mad at me.
Let me talk
to her alone.
Did you tell
your mother?
I can't.
Reggie's
the father?
He says it's not his,
but i know it is.
I've never been
with no other boys.
I never meant
for this to happen.
You girls never do.
So many of you bringing
babies into this world
just to prove you can
accomplish something.
And you're doing
so well now, kaneesha.
There are other
alternatives.
I'm scared.
I don't know what to do.
I'll tell you
what we'll do.
We'll have your mother
come to the school.
We'll put our heads
together.
I'm sure we'll be able
to help you decide
what's best for you
to do. Trust me?
Mr. Clark!
8:00 a.m.
I'll call your mother.
What is it?
The fire chief.
He got past
the gate.
Code 10! Get those
chains off the door!
The enemy's
here!
We got it locked,
mr. Clark.
Mr. Clark,
you're under arrest.
For what?
Basically
for being an asshole.
Specifically for conspiracy
to violate of the fire code.
I got no problem
with the fire code.
The only problem here
is you.
And your problem
is your mouth.
Joe: Get those chains
off the doors!
The enemy's here!
Guard: We got it
locked, mr. Clark.
Cuff him!
Hey, mr. Clark!
What's this
all about?
It's about someone finally
standing up to this man
instead of taking
his orders like a maid.
How dare you
speak like that!
Mrs. Barrett-
shut up!
You're finished!
The school board
will hear this at 7:00,
and we'll vote
your black ass out.
Yo, bitch,
vote on this!
You go to class!
You're
acting principal now.
I expect you
to perform as i would.
What-
what's going on?
What did you
do?
I chained the doors.
You break the law,
you pay the price.
We still got to
go to class?
Yes. All of you,
get back to class! Now!
Mr. Clark...
go on!
Who will look
after the school?
Go on!
Get back to class!
Get back in there,
all of you! Go on!
Ms. Levias,
they're your responsibility!
I guess we ought to
be getting out of here, joe.
That school board meeting's
about to begin.
Do whatever we can.
Have you thought about
a new line of work?
Perhaps an exciting career
in electronics?
It's just
a little joke.
I'm going.
I've got
no complaints, joe.
As far
as i'm concerned,
what you accomplished
down at that school
was a goddamn miracle.
Those kids have a light
in their eyes now
that was never,
never there before.
Thanks, boss.
You know, i'm always
trying to teach my kids
to stay out of jail.
Look at me.
You go on.
Do what you got to do.
He has failed
at his professional task.
We brought him in
to save our school
from a takeover
from the state.
That was the mandate
from our mayor.
But the test scores
on the practice exam
were 35% below passing.
Now, maybe
if we dump him now
and get a new principal
ourselves-
show the state
that we're doing something-
we can pre-empt
the takeover,
but only if we get him out
before those final
test scores come back.
After that,
it'll be too late.
This board won't
have any power.
It'll be nothing
but a rubber stamp.
Mrs. Arthur,
those are the facts.
I appreciate your personal
loyalty to mr. Clark,
but he has let
our children down,
and our loyalty
should be to them.
Our loyalty should be
to the man we hired.
Order! Order!
Free mr. Clark!
Napier: Order,
ladies and gentlemen!
Order, please!
We cannot continue
this meeting
with this kind
of chaos! Please!
Sit down!
Come to order!
Dr. Napier,
dr. Napier,
i think you should
call the question now.
I cannot call
the question.
All points of view seem
to have been exhausted here.
No further purpose
will be served by this.
Why don't you have
someone on the board-
mr. Clark's students
have assembled outside
in an exercise of their
first amendment rights.
How many?
It looks like
all of them.
Free mr. Clark!
We're in a tough spot here.
I have to ask
your help, joe.
It's not for me.
It's for those kids.
They're very emotional.
They're all jacked up.
You have
to send them home.
I don't have to do nothing
but stay black and die.
For crying out loud.
Free mr. Clark!
People, before
this gets out of hand,
listen, for your own safety,
listen to me!
Free mr. Clark!
All right, joe.
Let me put it this way.
First, i wanted you
to succeed.
Now, don't think that i
ever wanted anything else.
But you're a realist,
joe, just like me.
Think what
would happen
if there was a riot
and cops had to
clear that square.
I'd have law and order
on my side,
and the only people
who'd be hurt
would be your kids.
Free mr. Clark!
Listen to me!
People, please!
You must all disperse
and return to your homes!
Your presence here
is helping no one.
Why don't you use your brains
and listen?
Free mr. Clark!
Thank you.
Listen up.
Settle down. Give her
a chance to talk.
She might actually
have something to say.
Chill. Settle down.
Let's listen to the old
loudmouthed wench.
Here you go,
barrett.
Here you go.
You can call me
what you want,
but the simple fact is
mr. Clark has broken the laws
of this state
and exposed you all
to grave danger.
His behavior
is irresponsible.
Chaining those doors
was a criminal act.
Why do you think
they call him "crazy joe"?
Because you don't
understand him.
Yeah.
That's right.
He chained
those doors
to keep out
the drug dealers.
You're twisting
the law.
The laws are made
to protect the people.
That's what
he's doing for us.
Yes!
The thing that
you don't understand
is that mr. Clark
believes in us.
He doesn't
believe in you!
You don't
take care
of your
responsibility!
Despite what he himself
may believe,
mr. Clark is not
eastside high!
Mr. Clark is not
only eastside high.
Mr. Clark is
like a father,
the only father
some of us know.
You don't
know a thing
about mr. Clark!
People!
People, just hear me!
The school board
is meeting right now,
and we will give you
what eastside high deserves-
a good principal.
We don't want
a good principal!
We want mr. Clark!
You may think you know
what you want,
but the question is
what is best for you,
for eastside high.
This thing's getting
out of hand.
Talk to them,
please.
...to see
that this gets resolved
so that you can
continue your education.
Free mr. Clark!
People! People...
yay!
All right!
I wonder why i can't get
this kind of turnout
for study hall.
All right, now.
Kids, this is
all very nice,
but now i'm going to insist
that you all go home
and let the laws
of the land prevail.
No!
No! No! No!
Now, listen.
Listen.
If i've taught you
anything,
i have tried to give you
respect for the law.
Now, i want you all
to go home
in an orderly fashion!
No! No! No!
Your voices have been heard!
I appreciate
your concern for me.
No! No! No!
But now is the time
to go home.
No! No! No!
Kids, listen. You're not
helping the matters any.
You're not helping
our cause
if you stay here.
No! No! No!
I thought i left you
in charge of these students.
You got to
read this.
Is this taking care
of your responsibility?
Read it!
No! No! No!
Boss.
Dr. Napier,
it is my duty-
it is my privilege
and my honor to report to you
that the students
of eastside high
have passed the minimum
basic skills test!
Mr. Mayor.
Boy: Yeah!
All right!
Go get him!
Mr. Mayor,
on behalf of myself
and on behalf of the students
of eastside high,
you can tell the state
to go to hell.
I told you.
You should not
have brought him here...
joe louis clark
is not going anywhere.
Are you ready,
my ghosts?
Yes!
Let me hear it.
1, 2, 3!
Fair eastside
by thy side we'll stand?
And always praise thy name
to ever
lend our hearts and hands
congratulations.
Come on, son.
...thy fame
the honor
of old eastside high
brings forth our loyalty
so cheer for dear old
eastside high
lead on to victory
so cheer for dear old
eastside high
lead on to victory
lean on me
when you're not strong
and i'll be your friend?
I'll help you carry on
for i know
that it won't be long
till i'm gonna need
somebody to lean on
you just call on me, brother
call me
if you feel
you need a hand
'cause we all need
somebody
just to lean on
oh, i just might
have a problem
a problem
you'll understand
we all need somebody
to lean on
oh oh oh, yeah
listen, now
if there is a load
you have to bear
that you can't carry
just remember
i, i'm right
up the road
i'll share your load
if you just call on me
you have to call me
call me
whenever you're in trouble
i'll understand
call me
we all have pain
we all have sorrow
call me
hey hey hey
just lean on me
lean
lean on me
lean on
j-just lean on me
lean
lean on me
just, just
lean on him?
Yes, yes, why?
Things are better
and we're finally
working together in unity
and you're soon to see
eastside high
as a better place to be
the students, the pupils
have morals and scruples
our learning ability
has increased quadruple
and we're off
to a brand-new start
i played my part
to prove that you're smart?
And it's proven
but i ain't movin'
i won't be going,
i'm here
when you need someone
to lean on
so take heed to this
as a blessing and remember
ain't no half steppin'
get it in full gear
i'm sure that you'll care
in the long run
when you got full gear
that means authority
positivity
word
so let knowledge
uproot you
go for yours,
'cause we're the future
the ones who rise
to supremacy
and if you ever
need a hand
just lean on me
j-j-j-just
lean
just lean on me
j-j-j-just
lean
just lean on me
j-j-j-just
lean
just lean on me
lean on me
lean
Captioning performed by the
national captioning institute, inc.