subtitles
PingPong5
Production
LEAP YEAR
Hello?
Hi Mom.
Fine and you?
How nice.
What are you doing?
Oh, it's raining?
It is already tomorrow is February.
What did you eat?
Delicious.
And who did,
you or Grandma?
Delicious...
Who?
Oh really?
Oh how nice.
You said hi for me?
Good afternoon. I'm Laura Lopez
the Your Business magazine.
Very well, thank you.
Is that you?
How nice.
Let me explain.
In the May issue
we will publish an article
30 tips to take advantage
the economic crisis.
And I wanted to ask, please,
you could share your ideas.
Exact.
Do you think he wants to build a
heritage for my sister and me?
But the father left that
property for me, Mom.
But Mom!
At the club I drink vodka.
I like the Mandarin.
So you're designer?
Listen, Raul.
I think she's an idiot.
She has light skin,
then you find hot.
Well, you know that, but I do not
I think that suits you.
It's all right...
Yes, I have eaten.
I ate with Miguel.
Actually he just left.
Yeah, let me sink
full of dirty dishes.
And made me a Chow Fan.
Chow Fan.
It is a Chinese fried rice.
He put shrimp.
He is fine,
It is again boyfriend.
Yeah, they went to Acapulco.
Exactly.
It's not like you
You are seeing them.
Because everyone is equal.
IT IS.
I know, the less you.
And what time did you say
him I was going to call?
It's all right,
then we'll talk tomorrow.
A kiss.
I love you so much.
I always use,
It is straightforward.
I have big, small,
of all flavors.
And there's no risk of infection.
That's incredible.
You can put both
lubricant you want.
Hello?
Hi Mom.
It is just the battery
phone.
No, I am eating dinner.
I did some steaks.
Why not talk about it
when I'm there?
Yes, I'll think.
Mom, I'm having dinner!
It's all right.
You too.
Goodbye.
Get my pants?
Hi darling.
I was already sleeping?
Excuse me.
No, I'm on my way.
I do not know, in five minutes.
And me too.
It's all right.
You already see, okay?
Bye Bye.
Made peace?
And what did you tell him?
Oh, Raul ...
Well, it's like Grandma says,
'' There is no bastard without a jerk. ''
Oh, Raul!
For nothing here ...
Hey, you think that.
They did a park
amusement here at home.
Tomorrow I'll be there,
and buy walnut bread,
I'll get on a horse
carousel
I will be very happy.
Tell me you.
Okay, perfect.
Shall I come see you?
All right, whatever.
Yeah, I hope you here.
It's all right.
Sleep on the bus, right?
Little kisses!
How are you?
I'm fine and you?
I asked first.
How was it?
It went well.
Very tired.
Because?
8 hours by bus.
8 hours?
IT IS.
You are very good.
Inviting?
I am glad to see that
you are using the treadmill.
What Mom said?
Anything.
Call him later.
How is she?
With her boyfriend, as always.
And Grandma?
Still have that problem
in the eyes.
She will have to operate.
When?
At the end of the month.
I will see how I will be
work.
And how are you going
with Sofia?
Going ...
What will you do
on 14th birthday?
I think a movie
and then dinner.
Is that you?
Miguel is presenting me
her new boyfriend.
Are you ready?
I'm going to take a shower
and then we? - Let's go.
Do not put your feet
in my bed.
governments leave them on the street,
then they stop paying
health, education,
all utilities.
And as they have no money,
they have to sell.
So what's left?
The security.
It's the only thing the government
American worries.
And when security
It is their only political function
and their only source
legitimacy,
you have to make the
people feel in danger.
So people need
you and pay. Understood?
You do not feel
longing for Oaxaca?
It's a fucking bike racks.
I have many friends here.
I'm giving myself very well,
I am very happy.
Take care.
Go carefully.
Oso ... hi.
No for nothing.
What happened?
But he told me,
I have the recording.
But who told you that?
And how do they know?
Which is,
how can it be a scam?
But you sent me
the contact,
you have chosen it as a
entrepreneurs of the year.
How would I know?
Yes, I better have checked.
But you're my editor.
And the way he spoke thought
it was a magazine of choice.
Well, okay.
Well, then do not publish.
They are already ready?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, Oso.
How would I know
that would happen?
Excuse me...
Yes...
I get it.
But it's not fair to the reporter
scapegoated.
Until July?
Of course I have other work!
I'm Adolfo and ...
IT IS!
I get it.
It's ok.
I'll wait here.
Goodbye, Oso.
Wait a minute.
You come?
Why do men
always want to know that?
I my name is Arturo.
I know.
As you said
what was his name?
Why do you want to know?
Adolfo is Laura.
Lopez.
No, I'm in the magazine
Your Business with Oso.
Hello how are you?
We met in an Irish pub
about two months.
You are busy?
Okay, perfect.
Who is doing the summaries?
And I took a collaboratively and have
one free hour a week.
Okay, perfect.
I'll send you them right now.
And it okay if I call you
the second at 11am?
Okay, perfect.
You have the right number of Carlos,
the Latin Business magazine?
Okay, perfect.
Thank you, Arturo.
Adolfo, sorry.
So I'll call you
the second at 11am.
Thank you, bye.
Hello, ma'am, can I talk
Carlos Guerra, please?
I'm going!
It is green.
What?
I hurt you?
Do not.
Do you have whiskey?
Laura Lopez Martinez?
Meddler.
Long ago you
He came from Mexico?
And you like it?
I like this building.
Downstairs has an old couple
that seem to my parents.
I have dinner very often with them.
The front neighbor
It is my best friend.
Sometimes we go out
with her boyfriend.
On the day we met,
they had just left.
I take the kids
low at the fair
when their mother
Are you busy.
The building is not pretty,
but I feel ...
protected.
What do you know about me?
Anything.
Not if I ...
Do not.
Do you know what time is it?
I need to go.
AMAR ART
Shut up!
You crazy!
You're completely paranoid!
Go away,
goes away forever!
Bye!
Hello?
Hi what happened?
At where?
And what you
You are doing here?
Ah yes.
It is the exposure
universities, right?
What is your name?
When you arrived?
Where are you?
Yeah, come here.
DO NOT COME TO HERE.
I HAVE A VISIT.
Where were you?
I here beating.
How are you?
I am fine.
Because I was drying her hair.
You women have no way ...
Who is it?
A friend.
I'll call her later.
After the exhibition we walk?
Where you want to go?
What time do you have that be there?
At 10am.
Let's go now.
Okay then.
Who were you with?
When?
The SMS you sent.
Do not be stupid!
With my brother.
You're a whore, a liar.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I dislike.
Can I borrow?
An old rat
it was carpet
I was going to quit
He ended the burnt tail
She spent an ointment
and then tied a cloth
but the poor little mouse
He was without the tail
Tell me something
that no one knows about you.
I wanted to have a child.
It will be named Ariel.
And I will love it too.
And we'll both be
very happy together.
Far away from here.
My ass hurts.
Do not be a crybaby.
You know, I'll be an actor.
Oh yes?
At about one year
I did a commercial.
They never spent on TV,
but they paid me.
Wow.
And I also did a lot of testing.
You'll still talk to me
when famous?
Why marked
this day red?
You're welcome.
Let says.
On the 29th will do four years
my father died.
How many people died
on 29 February?
I do not know.
I suppose it's the only one.
Take the table.
Strip!
Close the eyes.
Lie belly up.
Masturbates.
Masturbates, motherfucker!
Close the eyes.
Want some quesadillas?
Do not.
If you want something else
I can go to the supermarket.
What do you feel being pissed?
Warmish.
Tell me more about you.
What you want to know?
When you lost
your virginity?
When I was 12 years old.
With whom?
It's none of your business.
What do you want to do with me?
The other.
Hi, Oso.
A little bit, but tell.
Thank you, Oso,
but ... you have a problem.
I'm leaving the country.
No, to live.
In Switzerland.
I will work at the embassy.
It is expensive in Mexico.
Thanks.
After tomorrow.
Yeah, I'm packing
everything like crazy.
It is my mother
He has a friend who is a diplomat.
Okay, perfect.
Yes of course,
we are in touch by email.
Yes, I send a postcard
when I get there.
Of course yes.
Come on, go to your meeting.
Thanks.
Goodbye.
Why do not you cut me?
Would you like to cut my
throat while eating me?
Come inside me,
while watching me dying?
You start cutting
my breasts.
Can you imagine the blood coming out?
You spread throughout
my body.
Then you mete me ...
and while eating me ...
I'll be looking
in your eyes.
You can make a hole here ...
and yet another here.
And so I bleed
until death.
But I can keep talking
with you all the time.
And like anyway
I am dying,
you can beat me.
It cuts.
Burns me.
You can do
whatever you want to me.
Meanwhile I will
looking in your eyes,
and saying I love you.
And when I can not
more move,
and is very weak ...
and is dead ...
you can enjoy
within my body.
Would you kill me?
Do not worry.
No one would realize.
Nobody knows you
know me.
I can leave clothes
clean in the dining room.
And a bag for you
take dirty clothes.
You can use gloves
not to leave fingerprints.
And I give you the number
the nearby phone,
for he finds
my body.
You can come tomorrow at 22h?
Please?
What are you doing here?
What happened?
Come here.
She broke up with me.
It's all right.
She said I'm
taking very seriously.
She did not allow
I did not explain myself.
It's all right.
All right, Raul, okay ...
Come here.
Do not Cry.
Calm down.
You will meet more girls.
You will meet many people
who will love you.
You will always have
each other.
You're my little brother.
And I'm your little sister.
It's the daddy?
IT IS.
When you picked up?
The last time I went to Oaxaca.
Mom never said, is not it?
You know what today is?
When I was little ...
I thought that my father
was is best person in the world.
She was a good person.
Everything will be fine.
He did not come.