LEAVES OUT OF THE BOOK OF SATAN
Four stories by Edgard Hoyer
Adapted for film by Carl Th. Dreyer
directed by Carl Th. Dreyer
cinematography by George Schneevoigt
So goes the legend of Satanas:
And God said to Satan,
the fallen angel:
"You fell because you wanted
what even I did not want.""
"In your pride you tempted men..."
"Satan, you shall continue your
wicked work amongst humanity."
"Go out among them,
take their shape.""
"And whoever yields to your
temptation shall be judged by me.""
"And whenever your temptations
are resisted, -
- you shall be relieved of
1000 years of your punishment.""
The first story.
Thirty years
after the birth of christ.
It happened during the last days -
- of the wanderings of christ
upon this earth.
On the second day before aster -
- the priests and the scribes were
gathered in the house of caiphas.
The teachings of christ had offended
the scribes, and Satanas, -
- who found the ground prepared
for his evil seeds, -
- took the form of a Pharisee
and went to caiphas.
Satanas - Helge Nissen.
Caiphas.
On the same evening, Jesus
and is disciples were guests -
- in the home of Simon the leper.
Jesus - Halvard Hoff
But Satanas found easy ears with
the priests and the scribes, -
- who feared the favour Jesus had
won with the people for is miracles.
I am just out of Bethany,
where everybody speaks of Jesus.
After the raising of lazarus
from the dead, -
- Jesus is hailed everywhere
as if he were a king.
but Satanas is secretly grieved to see
that the seed he has newly sown -
- is already beginning to bloom..
If we let him go on in this manner,
everybody will believe him in the end -
- and our temples will stand empty.
The anointment of Jesus.
and the woman poured ointment
on the feet of Jesus -
- and dried them with her hair.
Why was this ointment not sold
for three hundred pence -
- and the money given to the poor?
but Jesus reproved Judas, saying:
"Let her alone.""
"For the poor ye have always
with you, but me ye have not always.""
but the scribes claimed
with one voice -
- that caiphas should let Jesus
be seized and slain.
Your will shall be satisfied.
Woe to him, who opposes us.
He must die!
Why do you believe in him?
God's son is what he calls himself.
The devil"s son is what he is.
and you have been tied
by the power of the devil.
We shall meet tomorrow at noon-tide
outside the Golden Gate.
I know you will come.
The next day was the first day of the
festival of the unleavened bread.
Judas had spent a sleepless night, -
- harassed by the doubts
put in his head by the Pharisee.
But towards noon he felt -
- as if a will
stronger than his own -
- directed his steps
towards the Golden Gate.
I mean no ill by you.
only the salvation of your soul.
But on this day the disciples
had come to Jesus and asked im:
"Where wilt thou that we prepare
for thee to eat the pass-over?""
and Jesus answered: ""Go into
the city, and there you shall meet -
- a man carrying a pitcher of water.
follow him.""
You suffer, and it is his fault.
he promised you a Messias ingdom.
but he is not God"s son,
only a man. An impostor.
He is doomed.
He must die.
and Israel's God has chosen you
for his tool.
I cannot do it.
I will not do it.
Swear not. I know you will.
I shall expect you at the well -
- when the Romans sound the
second change of the watch.
And when the hour had come, -
- he sat down to eat,
and the disciples with im.
and when they were eating, he said:
""Verily I say unto you, -
- one of you will betray me.""
Master, is it I?
and he broke the bread, dipped it,
and gave it to Judas, saying:
"That thou doest, do quickly.""
and Jesus blessed the cup.
the hymn.
and having sung the hymn. -
- Jesus and the disciples
went out to Gethsemane.
but at the same hour, -
- men of the Jewish temple guard
went out at the bidding of caiphas -
- to seize Jesus, and
Roman soldiers accompanied them.
Lord, where are you going?
We are tired. et us stay here.
and Jesus rose from is prayer
and went back to the disciples, -
- but found them asleep
with sadness.
How am I to know Jesus?
The kiss of friendship
shall be the sign.
and Jesus prayed:
"Abba, my ather, if it is possible,
take away this cup form me.""
but Jesus said:
"The hour is near -
- when the Son of Man will be
betrayed by the sinner.""
and Jesus asked:
""Who are you searching for?""
but Jesus asked once again:
and Jesus said:
"Judas, are you betraying me,
the Son of Man, with a kiss?""
but Satanas, the fallen angel,
whose whole heart was set -
- upon finding favour again
in the eyes of the lmighty, -
- he was grieved to see
his evil work completed.
and his grief was deeper,
because it had fallen to his lot -
- to deliver the son of God
into the hands of human tormentors.
but the Lord"s voice was heard:
"Continue thy evil doings."
Setting: Seville in Spain.
Setting: Seville in pain.
Time: 16th century.
In the 16th century, the Spanish
Inquisition was at the height of its power.
countless are the reports
from those days -
- about the horrors of the torture
chambers of the Inquisition.
the noble don Gomez de castro,
who, much to his own satisfaction, -
- was a diligent student of the modern
sciences, astronomy and astrology.
don Gomez de castro -
Hallander Hellemann.
his daughter Isabella, receiving
instruction in mathematics and history -
- by the learned monk
don Hernandez y Argote
Isabella - Ebon Strandin
don Hernandez - Johannes Meyer.
José, the butler.
José - Nalle Haldén.
My nephew, count Manuel,
intimates that -
- he has been granted leave
from his duties in the war -
- and will pay us a visit.
In vain, don Hernandez subjects
himself to the strictest penances.
his thoughts always dwell
upon Isabella.
the Grand Inquisitor.
Satanas - Helge Nissen.
don ernandez has become so
engrossed by his desire for Isabella -
- that even the holy saint
at the foot of the cross -
- to his eyes assumes the figure
and expression of Isabella.
My son, why do you not put yourself
at the service of the Inquisition?
Remember: for the Inquisition,
nothing is unattainable.
a few days later.
count Manuel de errera.
count Manuel - Hugo Bruun.
circumstances that I cannot explain -
- have compelled me to
take this decision.
It is with grief that I leave this house, -
- whence I take the
most cherished memories of my life.
for Isabella and Manuel the weeks
passed as if in children"s play.
and the day came when Manuel
must resume his duties in the war.
At the same time, -
- don Hernandez swore unqualified
allegiance to the Inquisition.
Swear that you will be ready
to serve God ...
... and will be prepared
to give up anybody, -
- even your father and mother,
sister or brother, -
- to the holy punishment
of the Inquisition.
the horoscope.
Look, Saturn is opposite
its own sign - in the death house.
My last hour is near!
In the antechamber
of the Grand Inquisitor.
Be not surprised. José is a
faithful friend of the Inquisition.
You are right, José.
He who pretends to read God"s will
in the stars is a heretic.
You have heard José"s evidence.
don Gomez is a heretic.
and a heretic"s daughter
is a heretic, too.
It will be your first task
to bring them both -
- safely behind the walls
of the Inquisition prison.
Is your belief no greater?
have you already forgotten your oath?
When the shadow on don Gomez"
sundial showed -
- that the day was drawing
to its end ...
he torture chamber
of the Inquisition.
untie him.
the trial is over, for the present.
the trial is over for ever.
God, have mercy on the poor sinner.
the Inquisition Prison.
I order you to continue the trial
in the torture chamber.
I am not master of myself
in the presence of this woman.
What is the body of a heretic to me,
as long as her soul be saved?
How strange!
Next morning, the sun rose
like on any other morning.
... the court sentences Isabella
to be burned at the stake ...
But the lord left Satanas
no time for contemplation.
With inexorable severity,
the words of doom rang in his ears:
continue thy evil doings.
Setting: Paris.
Time: utumn 1 793.
On the 21st January, 1 793, -
- Louis XVI was beheaded as a
victim to the Republic of iberty.
Many hands were now busily
erecting the guillotine -
- for Queen Marie Antoinette.
during the night between
the 1st and 2nd August 1793, -
- the unfortunate queen was
removed from the prison -
- in the temple to the conciergerie, -
- called
""the Prison of the condemned"".
Marie Antoinette - Tenna Frederiksen.
and the queen was made
to sign a receipt -
- evidencing that
she had been duly handed over -
- to the prison ward
of the conciergerie.
one month later,-
on the 5th eptember 1 793, -
- the Paris convent
enacted the sinister law -
- instituting
the Army of the Revolution.
accompanied by guillotines,
this army in small detachments -
- was to make a circuit
of the French provinces -
- to incarcerate and execute
""all suspicious characters"".
The music room of chambord castle.
count de chambord - Viggo Wiehe.
countess de chambord -
Emma Wiehe.
carefree youth.
Lady Geneviéve de chambord -
Jeanne ramcourt.
The guillotine is coming!
In times like these,
each man is nearest to himself.
these itinerant tribunals -
- with authority to pass and execute
death sentences on the spot, -
- were presided over
by a people"s commissar, -
- whose only qualification was that
he must know and show no mercy.
the people"s commissar -
Emil Helsengreen.
Joseph, I know you will grant
your master his last wish.
Promise that you will lead
my wife and daughter into safety, -
- and that you will for ever
remain a loyal friend to them.
Joseph - lith Pio.
""here is thus indisputable evidence
that the count the chambord -
- has been the actual leader
of a conspiracy -
- to help the former Queen of rance,
the Widow capet, -
- to flee the country.""
an escape in the night.
In the conciergerie.
After a wearisome
couple of days" travel, -
- the fugitives from chambord were
approaching their temporary goal:
Paris.
Joseph had succeeded
in obtaining a forged passport -
- made out to citizeness Grandet
and her son and daughter, -
- by which they hoped to be
admitted undetected into Paris.
In the taproom of the Parisian
"Taverne Pitou"", -
- Michonnet, the popular singer, -
- was admired and applauded for his
rendering of ""a Marseillaise"", -
- which in those days had just
become popular in Paris.
Old Pitou - Viggo indstrom.
On the high road.
At the city gates.
Erneste durand, -
- up to quite recently a footman in
the service of count de chambord, -
- is now heart and soul engrossed
in the new political ideas.
Satanas - Helge Nissen.
I deserve no thanks,
for I merely did my duty.
But if you wish to make me glad,
then please bestow upon me -
- the medallion with your daughter"s
image as a keepsake, -
- which I know you always wear.
I give it to you gladly, -
- for you have the right
to claim the best from me.
Have no fear! I promise
that I will not give them away.
They have always been kind to me.
Why should I return evil for good?
They are the coming men, -
- and meet here every night
to discuss the political news.
In the conciergerie.
Nothing at that time was abused
as much as the motto:
Liberté - Egalité - Fraternité
( Freedom - quality - brotherhood)
It was printed everywhere.
Even the tattooer used it for his art.
Believe me:
hat fellow will go a long way.
With his gift of the gab -
- he is certain to reach the
highest posts in the state.
What was I two months ago?
A servant like yourself.
Now I belong to the inner circles
of the Jacobin club -
- and am on the point of
securing a seat in the convent.
You may go as far,
if you will.
his card admits you to the
sessions of the Jacobin club.
Be there tomorrow, -
- when I shall introduce you
to some of my political friends.
At the conciergerie -
- the dregs of the imprisoned women
gathered almost daily -
- below the window
of Marie ntoinette"s cell, -
- whence they hurled the
lowest insults at the poor queen.
That wicked witch
is the cause of all our misery.
Why don"t they make her
a few inches shorter?
Here I have kept the latest
issue of ""Pére duchesne"".
I suggest we give it to her Majesty.
By now she must be fed up with
the history of the Passion of christ.
PÉRE dUcHESNE
The tyrant is dead, but his wench
and cursed brood are still alive.
You will not have peace
before they are destroyed.
Watch out! Freedom is at stake!
Some time has elapsed.
Through Erneste"s influence -
- Joseph already belongs to the most
trusted henchmen of the Jacobins.
Why don"t you pluck up the courage
to propose to her?
You forget that you have
means and ways to force her.
do you think she wants herself
or her mother adorned -
- with the collar of the guillotine?
At the conciergerie.
For Marie Antoinette all
secular ties have been severed -
- save the one which forever
will bind a mother to her child.
At her bosom she kept her son"s
portrait and a lock of his hair, -
- both successfully smuggled
into the prison -
- in an old yellow glove.
Although Joseph now belongs to
the Revolution with all his heart, -
- he does not for one day fail
to visit his former masters, -
- who, thanks to him, have been
accorded tolerable conditions.
This period of terror
so brutalized the human mind -
- that even children
devoted themselves -
- to playing with the guillotine.
The accused.
The public prosecutor.
The audience.
The judge.
citizen cat is guilty of
contempt of the Republic -
- by having worn in public
the white colour of the court, -
- and so he must catch it in the neck!
In the meantime Joseph
had a long interview -
- with the countess de chambord.
The subject matter
was known to no one, -
- and no one must know.
On the way to the guillotine.
You have given ample proof
of your loyalty -
- and endangered your life
for our sake.
Joseph, you know I hold you in great
esteem as a generous friend.
But you know, too, -
- that anything more than friendship
between us is impossible.
Long live liberty!
But on the same evening
a poor cripple, -
- whom an evil fate
had even made deaf and dumb, -
- paid a visit to Fouquier-Tinville,
the public prosecutor.
Fouquier-Tinville -
Vilh. Petersen.
Countess de chambord
and her daughter Geneviéve -
- are hiding under the name of
Grandet in t. Antoine Street, -
- and are on the point of
fleeing the country.
Meanwhile,
preparations for the flight -
- were in progress
in t. Antoine Street.
The cripple had achieved his object, -
- but there was no exultant joy
of victory in his eyes.
For he was Satanas, disguised
in the cripple"s poor clothes.
Satanas who must tempt mankind
in obedience to the divine doom.
With Fouquier-Tinville.
You ask about our names.
Read them in our passports.
My child,
I am too old to tell lies.
Yes,
I am the countess de chambord, -
- and the young lady at my side
is my daughter, Lady Geneviéve.
But you, citizen ...
... you whom we
all considered a good patriot ...
You wanted to help
the aristocrats flee, did you?
countess de chambord
and her daughter Geneviéve -
- are hiding under the name of
Grandet in t. Antoine treet.
Now I understand.
You are the real informer
who sent the letter.
There are problems
which are hard nuts to crack, -
- even to a Fouquier-Tinville.
Now, speak up.
did you or did you not
send the letter?
You shall not in vain have shown
devotion to the Republic.
The office of police prefect falls
vacant in the immediate future, -
- and I shall see
that it is given to you.
Judas' reward falls to Judas.
On the 14th October 1793 -
- Marie Antoinette was taken
before the Revolutionary ribunal.
The trial lasted two days.
When she returned to her cell -
- during the night between
the 15th and 16th, -
- the jury had unanimously sentenced
the Queen of the French to death.
On concorde Square -
- the executioner and his assistants
dressed Marie Antoinette"s death bed.
While the day was slowly dawning, -
- Marie Antoinette wrote her
famous, tear-stained letter -
- to her sister-in-law,
Princess Elisabeth.
The letter
which has passed into history as -
- ""Marie Antoinette's Testament"".
October 16th
4:30 a.m.
This letter to you, my dear sister,
will be my last.
I have just been sentenced,
not to a disgraceful death, -
- for it is disgraceful
only to criminals, -
- but to leave this earth
to join your brother, -
- innocent like him ...
In another cell, not far off, -
- another woman was writing.
To Joseph Gilvert
from Lady Geneviéve de chambord
At this moment I can hear the
death-cart rumble into the yard -
- to take my mother to the scaffold.
These lines are my last appeal to you.
Erneste is the soul of a conspiracy
to liberate the queen.
Help him and I shall forgive you,
and bless you in my last moment.
Take this to Joseph,
with my final farewell.
Of the miserable clothes
left to Marie Antoinette, -
- at one time the most
beautiful lady in France, -
- she had dressed this morning
as if for an occasion.
It is her you have to thank -
- for me making a traitor
of myself to the Republic.
Yes, I remember the young
woman well. Where is she now?
She has been beheaded?
Who was callous enough to hand that
child over to the executioners?
Be quick! The way is clear.
Remember your promise
to Genevieve, -
- and do not think of yourself.
But of wounded vanity,
in the flare of a moment"s anger, -
- Joseph forgets his solemn vow
to Geneviéve and the queen, -
- whose fate
had been entrusted to him.
Now she is being prepared
for death out there.
Is that good enough for you?
Three women"s faiths
have been betrayed by you.
Three lives you have wasted.
Murderer is your true name,
just like Satanas is mine.
Eternal damnation to you, -
- who dragged me into your ruin.
eternal damnation!
In the agony of despair,
Satanas pauses in his wanderings, -
- which, paved as they are
with dashed hopes, -
- seem to carry him further away
from his eternal salvation.
For him there is no mercy.
Anew is heard the voice from above:
continue thy evil doings!
Setting: Finland.
Time: Spring 1918.
Everyone knows the marvellous
picture of Finland -
- symbolized by a young woman,
fighting the Russian eagle.
Was not fresh life given to
this picture -
- when the Red insurrection
made its way from Russia -
- across the Finnish frontier?
Our last story takes place
in the little town of Hirola, -
- which was partly occupied
by the Reds in the spring of 1918.
The White eadquarters.
corporal Matti receives orders
from his commander -
- to lay telephone
and telegraph wires -
- across to the
railway station of Hirola.
corporal Matti - christian Nielsen.
If you will not be mine, -
- I shall inform on your husband
to the Red tribunal.
Next day.
corporal Matti on his way to Hirola.
Thank God you came.
That means we shall get real coffee
again soon, doesn"t it?
Siri goes into the woods
to gather bark -
- for baking with flour.
Matti and his men proceed to Hirola.
hat"s Mother.
Go and meet her - hurry up.
The Red tribunal.
In this story from our own time, -
- Satanas is represented by the
Russian monk Ivan, -
- who has rushed to the aid
of his Finnish ""Red"" brothers -
- against the
"Bloodhounds of the White Guard"".
Satanas - Helge Nissen.
I am afraid
we shall have to acquit him.
Let him have a bullet
when you get into the woods.
And now for a bite to eat.
Ivan has turned the schoolroom
of Hirola into a lecture hall, -
- and there is always
a devout audience -
- when he gives his social lectures.
Rautaniemi has fought a fierce battle
with his own conscience, -
- but it is as if a power beyond
his own control drags him -
- towards the school house
of Hirola.
Now I know how to avenge my father.
Take me to your commander at once.
I want to join the Finnish army.
The Red catechism
You need only fear one God:
your own will
You need only obey one law:
The one you make yourself
with the blood of the rich.
Where do you live?
I no longer have a home.
You must give an address anyway, -
- where the body may be sent
if you are killed.
It makes no difference to me -
- as long as I am buried
in Finnish soil.
May the pact you are making now
be a blessing to you.
One evening, about a week later, -
- just after the last train
had left Hirola.
In the Red headquarters -
- important discussions were
in progress on the same night.
I"ll tell you. The Whites have
established a connection -
- by telephone and telegraph,
to the station.
We must catch Paavo off his guard -
- and force him to draw the Whites
into an ambush.
The Reds.
I must be off to the inn,
and get hold of the boys.
oftly!
It is not time yet.
Red outpost.
Send that telegram to the Whites.
The Reds have occupied
the railway line.
You can waylay them -
- if you go by the main road
through the wood along the river.
The Reds ...
If you don"t obey my command,
your husband will be shot.
don"t do it, Siri.
You are now going to die, -
- but even the worst of sinners
has a claim -
- to be comforted by religion.
The inn.
Naimi cannot wait for Matti any longer
and goes over to the station, -
- well armed with hand grenades,
to meet a contingency.
does she now belong to me?
Not yet.
In a few seconds, your husband
will have drawn his last breath.
Will you not reconsider,
while there is still time?
dear God! Give me the strength
to resist the temptation.
Your husband"s life
can no longer be spared ...
... but there is still time to
save the lives of your children.
This is my last warning.
If you refuse, your children
will be dead in the next instant.
Well?
do your duty.
Forgive me, Paavo.
I did it only ...
for Finland"s sake.
Siri"s simple heroic deed
released Satanas -
- from a thousand years
of his doom.
But the doom
pronounced by the ord -
- was written with the
characters of eternity, -
- and its words urge Satanas on
to new goals, new fates.