June 6, 1982, at 03:00, first
day of the Lebanon War
- Hello.
- Assi.
- Shmulik.
I am the commander.
That's Hertzel.
I’m Yigal.
Hi.
Come on, Yigal. Let's move.
"It's the man that's made of steel,
the tank is only a piece of iron"
Cinderella to Rhinoceros.
Continue north.
Past the banana field, go up the road
and wait for instructions.
Welcome to Lebanon. Over.
We're taking the road!
Hertzel, you son of a bitch!
Where are we, Assi?
What's happening?
Maybe you should call them
on the radio, tell them we have arrived.
They said wait, we wait.
Someone is coming.
Don't point this shit at me!
- Who was it?
- A guy with a megaphone.
- Let me see.
- Wait.
- Are you in charge?
- No, I am.
So listen carefully.
There’s your vehicle
12 men and a list of
assignments for 3 weeks.
How do you mean 3 weeks?
No, it's just... we were told...
I follow a precise work plan,
I have a program to implement.
I will try to make it easier and explain
every mission in detail,
After that you will ask your questions.
The first job is easy.
There's a town, north, north east.
Our air force has bombed it clean.
At 7.00 we enter the area,
We make sure there is nothing left
and go out the other side.
From there we continue north.
At 9.30, 10 tops.
to arrive at the friendly zone.
It's a hotel called Saint Tropez.
We'll eat and continue with
our next assignment.
In the meantime you will remain
here with the vehicle on the road.
If another vehicle comes by,
fire warning shots.
If they won't stop, shoot the engine.
I'm Jamil, your CO.
Questions?
Okay. You have an hour until morning.
- Good night.
It’s a walk in the park
to Saint Tropez.
- We have half an hour to sleep.
- Jamil said an hour.
Doesn't matter. If I say we have a
half hour, then that's what we have.
- You keep watch.
- Why does it have to be me?
I am the commander and I decide.
So, that’s how you want
to start? Great!
Next time you'll tell
me to call you sir.
Call me what you like,
just shut up and let me sleep.
Wake me up in half
an hour. Goodnight.
Tell me, why me. Huh?
Why not Yigal?
Or... what's his name.. the new guy.
It's time, maybe he's not tired
Listen, Hertzel, I have my reasons.
I can ask him, right?
Would you like to be keep watch?
- Are you in charge of this vehicle?
- You are! But please...!
I just asked the
new one to keep watch.
I also know that one
guard is needed.
- Do you have a problem with that?
- No, no, I'm fine.
- Who asked you??
- No, it's that...
Did I ask you to keep watch?
- I told you I have my reasons!
- What reasons, Assi? Please!
I'm on my last legs...
the new guy is about to replace me.
- And you tell me you have your reasons!
- Yeah, I have my reasons.
Right...
You can say what you want.
But they’re reasons I don't understand.
Ah, you don't, don't you?
Yigal has to drive, right?
I can go on duty.
No problem.
There...
You be quiet!
The new one is the aimer.
I am in charge of the vehicle and
I am responsible for our team
What does it mean? Like I don't count?
I'm not important?
I'm not saying this, what I mean
you are the loader,
you just grab shells and put them
in the gun, just that.
It's physical work, Assi.
It takes strength to do it.
But the aimer? What does he do?
He just takes aim and fires.
Who bends down, lifts heavy stuff,
breaks his back, burns himself,
breathing in all the fucking stink
from the gun? You? Him? Him? It's me!
For me there's no problem.
Seriously, I can keep watch, really.
Goodnight, Yigal. Sleep, sleep,
you need to rest.
You have to make
that F-15 fly tomorrow.
Hertzel, please let us sleep now.
Goodnight.
Some reasons.
Cinderella to Rhinoceros.
A car is heading our way. Hello.
Cinderella to Rhinoceros,
Here we go!
Fire!
Shmulik. Fire!
He's not stopping. Shoot the
engine, Rhinoceros! Fire!
Fire, Shmulik! Fire!
Shoot! Fire!
Shmulik! Fire!
Shoot, damn it! Shoot!
What are you waiting for?! Fire!
Shoot, Shmulik!
They're going into the field.
Take them out!
To the right, Jonathan!
The right...
There he is!
This is two: we're
chasing him on the plantation!
Why didn't you shoot? You had him
in your sights! I'm talking to you!
One, this is two. We took out one terrorist.
We're following the other one.
- What's going on? Jonathan!
- He's been hit! He's been hit!
One man down. No. 1, this is no. 2:
I repeat: we have a wounded man.
Bring him here. Over.
Want some?
Here.
This is two.
Ready for resuscitation.
- Is the wounded man responding?
- Negative.
Talk to him, make him say something!
Talk to me, Jonathan!
I panicked.
He's not answering!
Before I only shot at cans.
I panicked.
Pass me the bottle?
Cornelia? Cornelia, this is Cinderella.
We have an angel.
I repeat: we lost one.
We need to evac the body. Over.
Can't send a chopper.
Evac the body on the Rhinoceros.
Cinderella to Rhinoceros.
A pickup truck is coming.
Shoot the engine, no warning shots,
fuck this! Over.
Peace! Peace!
Cornelia, this is Cinderella.
We are moving.
This is Cornelia.
We'll send a chopper to evac
the body within the hour.
Over.
Rhinoceros, he's stopping.
Stop! Stop! Don’t move!
Don't shoot!
Are you crazy?
I’m hot. This stench makes me sick.
I'm sick too. I'm gonna throw up.
From now on water is rationed,
is that clear?
- Is that clear?
- Yes, yes.
Avoid contact with civilians. Over.
Move! Move!
Go, go. Move!
Rhinoceros, this is Eagle.
I am above you.
Prepare the body for transfer.
Attention.
I’m lowering the harness.
Secure the body.
We're going to lift the body.
The body is going up.
You want some, Assi?
Here, Shmulik. You want some?
- You want some, Hertzel?
- Cereals, yeah...
Ok. We will ride into the town.
We will have one hour to cross it.
Should not be difficult,
the Air Force have already had their fun,
we just need to clean up the leftovers.
Remember that international conventions
prohibit the use of phosphorous bombs.
We will respect the law and
no longer use the word ‘phosphorus’.
From now on we will say ‘smoke bombs’
instead of ‘phosphorous bombs’.
Any questions?
- Good.
- I have a question.
Is it possible for someone,
maybe Cornelia
to call my parents to tell them
that I'm alright?
I am the only son,
my parents are old.
- What's your name?
- Yigal.
Negative.
You're killing me with your
stupid ass questions.
- What have I done?
- Nothing. You have not done anything.
Hertzel, what have I done?
Another stupid-ass question...
Cornelia to Cinderella.
We have information about terrorists
who have taken civilian hostages.
The orders are to put
an end to that game. Over.
What are you doing? You know
smoking is not allowed in the turret.
Assi, I'm hot. Get off my case.
- Will you put it out?
- And relax a bit!
Put that cigarette out, Hertzel!
That's an order!
This is Cinderella.
On my mark we go in.
Do not forget the cover.
Over.
This is Cinderella, keep your eyes open
and cover one another.
From this moment you do
not take risks, you shoot to kill.
Go on, Rhinoceros.
Rhinoceros, stop.
We’ll search the area.
- I have to pee.
- What?
- I gotta pee. Can’t hold it.
- Later.
- Herztel, give me the box.
- Not now, wait.
Hertzel, what are you doing? Hertzel...
Rhinoceros, they’re shooting at us
from above.  Take them out. Over.
Rhinoceros, fire.
Fire!
- What? What’s he yelling?
- I do not know what he’s saying, Shmulik!
Shoot! Shoot!
Rhinoceros, wake your aimer
and let's finish with the bullshit.
Shoot, you read me? Fire!
Shit, are you deaf?
Can’t you hear? Hertzel,
Do it!
- It’s a little girl, Assi!
- Rhinoceros, shoot!
Tell him there’s a girl, Assi!
Tell him there’s a girl!
Shoot, Rhinoceros. Shoot!
Shoot, Shmulik! Shoot! That's an order!
You hear me, asshole?
I'm begging you! Shoot! Shoot!
Down! He's down!
Do not come closer.
Leave him, Michael!
Look up!
This is number two.
We’re at the entrance to the building.
- Do not come near. Step away.
- Have you seen my daughter?
- Have you seen her?
- Do not come any closer. Get away!
The stairway’s clear.
Her name is Wafa.
She’s only five. What happened to her?
Go away!
- Where is my daughter?
- Do not come closer! Go away! Go away!
Where is my daughter?
Answer me! Give me back my child!
- Don’t touch me! Stop it!
- Give me back my child!
Do not get up!
Don’t get up!
They’re shooting!
Stay down. It's dangerous.
We’re entering an apartment.
Grenade!
Apartment clean.
Bodies of two terrorists and a girl.
No losses.
Come out of there. Over.
Listen to me carefully...
So far I haven’t said anything.
I kept saying to myself:
Don’t be hard on him,
Whatever happened, happened.
But from now and until
further notice...
if so much as a fly moves,
I want a phosphorous bomb...
I’m sorry, what I meant was:
I want a smoke bomb.
- What's your name?
- Shmulik.
Shmulik, don’t let me down.
You are responsible for what
I have told him. Be careful!
So far we have played cops and
robbers, now it’s war.
Understand? I'm talking to you.
You understand?
Because if it doesn’t work, I’m fucked.
You’re playing with my life here.
The aimer... he’s a virgin!
- I will not die because of you!
- Assi, relax a little, wil you?
Relax? If he won't change his
attitude we’re all gonna roast here.
This is phosphorus here. You know what it is?
I’m talking to you. You know phosphorus?
Not even fingernails will remain!
Not one fingernail!
Not even a piece of meat for
the flies, not a drop...
So you take the trigger, ok?
- What?
- You have a trigger too, right?
- Yes, so what?
- Then squeeze it.
Show me how you do it.
I will aim and you pull the trigger.
You’re giving me orders? Did you hear?
He’s giving me orders…
What orders? Come on!
What orders?
Just don’t put their blood
on my hands.
You can shoot too. That's all.
What’s with the face, eh?
Nothing. But you must admit
he has a point.
Whose side are you on, mine or his?
On mine, Assi.
You are in charge,
you can’t take sides.
I don’t know what to say to your
stupid-ass explanations!
You are a shitty loader,
any moron could do your job!
You’re giving me a headache, relax.
Who are you telling to relax?!
I am more relaxed than you!
What’s coming over you both?
We’re being shot at !!!
Rhinoceros, the left!
"It's the man that's made of steel,
the tank is only a piece of iron"
The tank is fine,
it wasn't hit badly.
This is number two, Cinderella
I have something for you.
This is Cinderella, we’re coming.
Shmulik, you see something?
Jamil is with someone.
Yigal, do you see something?
There’s a wall in the way.
It is the Syrian who shot at your vehicle.
Everyone alright? No injuries?
Yigal, take the chain.
Take it, move! Tighten it!
Hold his hands. I'll hold him down.
Lock it! Lock it!
Lock it! Did you lock it?
- Did you lock it?
- I can’t!
- Lock it!
- It’s done!
This is morphine.
If he starts to stir
give him a shot of this
drop after drop.
Cornelia, this is Cinderella.
We have a cricket with us.
Sure it's a cricket?
If it sings like a cricket and looks
like a cricket then it must be a cricket.
- Your position?
- More or less in the center of town.
In some travel agency
or something like that.
Copy that. Wait for us.
What are you doing here,
Syrian soldier boy?
- What's your name?
- Hertzel.
You have problems with Syrians?
No, but we’re in in Lebanon.
We thought you had Lebanese here.
This is Cornelia. You seem to have
deviated from your route.
Maybe it seems that way from
where you stand. I see no deviations here.
Predatory birds want your
location, Cinderella. Wait.
Cinderella, attention.
You deviated from your course
and entered an area controlled
by the Syrians.
Cinderella to Cornelia,
I am in the center of town.
I have not deviated one iota from the path
that had been established.
I have not deviated.
It does not matter now what you
have or have not done.
You’re out of our reach
and this is a problem.
Stay holed up in that
travel agency
do not move and do not engage
in any offensive activities.
We are working to solve your problem.
Over.
Copy that.
Get the vehicle out and
get yourselves cleaned up.
I’ve lost a lot of energy.
I have a question.
- He said that up in Saint Tropez...
- The question.
Where are we now?
Because in two weeks
I’m going on leave.
This is a state of emergency.
Your leave is postponed until further notice.
Questions?
OK.
The vehicle is fucked.
No dial is working.
No oil, no power.
No way we’re moving.
If the vehicle is gone,
we’re no good either.
We have wounded people.
They’ll send a helicopter to save them.
We’re going home, Hertzel.
No, listen... you’re seeing things...
Only from a certain perspective.
In short you need to look
at the big picture.
I don’t understand,
we’re going home.
If you no longer have a vehicle,
you have to evacuate, right?
Listen, you're also the oldest one here,
but there are some things that you...
That I what? Come on, talk.
Issues... that you overlook.
Assi, He's right. And then you have to
file a report about the vehicle.
- Guys, trust me, if I tell you...
- What are you talking about?
I have my reasons.
So who’s caling? Me or you?
- Put it back, Hertzel.
- Your decide, Assi. You call or should I?
- Put down the receiver, it's an order.
- Fuck your orders!
Hertzel!
- Rhinoceros to Cinderella.
- What is it, Rhinoceros ?
What is it, Rhinoceros?
- Speak to us, come on. Speak.
- Assi, answer them.
Rhinoceros, answer!
I'm coming there.
I did not expect this of you.
I did not expect this.
- You did not expect what?
- Not this!
What?
To disobey an order is one thing,
but to do this to a friend...
No, no, stop! Haven’t you
yelled at the new one
that you don’t want to die
because of him?
So what the fuck are you doing now
busting my balls with your friendship crap?
This is my life too, okay?
My life!
Jamil is coming.
Put pride aside and you'll see
that I'm doing you a favor.
Now talk to him. Because if you can’t
do it, I'll do it for you.
And we have never been friends.
Tell him, Yigal.
The vehicle is gone. Just look
at the dials, they're all dead.
All dead.
- Have you tried?
- The dials speak for themselves.
We have wounded men, they’ll send
a helicopter to take them away.
If the vehicle is gone
there's nothing for us to do here.
Shut your face!
Start it.
- It won’t move, the dials...
- A tank doesn’t break just like that!
Nor does it jump in the air
or walk. Start it.
Spin it! Do not stop, go!
- Why did you stop? Keep it spinning!
- But if there’s no power...
Start it! Fire it up!
Pump it!
Pump it.
Keep pumping, do not stop!
Do not stop!
Keep going! That’s right!
Pump! Pump! Pump! Pump!
The pedal! Push the pedal! Push!
Speed up, come on! Speed up!
- Push harder.
- What?
Harder down! Push it all the way!
Faster! Go faster!
Go! Go, faster!
Ok! More! More!
Go!
It’s the second or third time
I’m telling you that:
Wash your faces and
Clean it all up.
You can not make war
in this mess.
- I swear that the dials...
- Enough with the dials already!
Truth is I can’t count on anyone.
Cornelia to Cinderella.
Two phalangists are coming your way.
- They will take care of you in case of evacuation.
- Copy that.
My mother must be on
Valium again.
She’ll sit there, sorting photos of
when I was a kid, in her flowery dress...
Now would seem like the right moment..
She sorts them by year, or separates
color ones from black and whites.
I finished my freshman year in high
school when I lost my father.
They called me in class and
told me he was dead.
Heart attack.
Then my teacher took me aside,
hugged me, ah...
She spoke to me, but I did not understand
a thing, just felt her tits against me.
Then she took me home
in her car.
I had a boner all the way home.
Anyway we finally arrived.
We got into the house,
It was full of people.
When they saw me they came to me.
They all wanted to hug me,
but I did not want that;
They would have felt my hard-on.
My teacher, however, thought that
it was psychological, like trauma from
losing someone, things like that, you know?
So follow me into my room and
tells me that I should cry;
that if I cried... Then...
I would feel better.
And so I thought if I cried
She’d hug me again.
So I focused and started
telling myself:
"My father is dead. He died,
I am an orphan, I have no father,
My father is dead. And so...
I started to cry.
What are you gonna do?
And things went just as I predicted.
She pulled me to her,
hugged me and told me:
"Yes, cry my darling. Cry it all out."
And my thing was pressing
against her belly
And I knew that she felt it.
So I kept crying and she
kept holding me tight.
And for a minute, or more,
I was crying.
pressed against her tits
smelling her smell,
the smell of her hair;
and my cock rubbing against
her soft belly...
And suddenly I felt her... pull
me stronger towards her,
and move
slowly with me.
I stopped crying and
bit my lips to hold it in.
And then she whispered:
"Do not be ashamed,
do not stop, let yourself go,
cry, you have not finished yet"
"Let go, my darling" she says,
"Let yourself go". And so I did.
I felt it rise and then bang!
And here I come,
I’m coming and coming...
And she hugged me, shaking me.
And I felt...really free,
just like she said.
You just gave me a hard-on,
for fuck's sake!
Cinderella, it’s Cornelia.
Two phalangists are coming your way.
Wait until darkness, they’ll
guide you to Saint Tropez. Over.
Who are the phalangists?
Christian Arabs... they’re on
our side, they’re allies.
Christians, Muslims, what's the difference,
what matters is getting out of here.
Rhinoceros, let the Mercedes go.
Move to the side. Over.
Cornelia, I have a problem
with your phalangist.
I wanted to know how to get out
and he gave me conditions,
He says that first he wants to talk
to the Syrian prisoner.
He says he made a deal with you.
Can you explain this? What does this mean?
Let him talk to the Syrian prisoner.
Over.
- Hello, welcome.
- Can I take...
I am the officer here. Assi.
- Do you speak Arabic?
- No.
No Arabic. You speak Arabic?
- You speak Arabic.
- No, no English...
Light, you have light?
- Fire.
- Fire, fire, yes.
- Good.
- Yes
Oh... Hi.
Listen, you sonofabitch.
When we come to Saint Tropez
I'll tell what's gonna happen.
I'll take you to a suite...
First we’ll strip you.
The boys haven't spent a night with
a cute boy like you for a long time...
Then I’ll pluck one of your
eyes out with a spoon.
Just one, so you can see
what I do after that.
- You're from the Phalange?
- Yes, yes.
I'll cut your dick off. But I don’t want
you to die and ruin the party.
Can you give me one?
The morning after I will tie your legs
to two cars. I will pull you apart.
Start praying to Allah.
Treat him well.
He is a prisoner of war.
Very.
What did he say, Yigal?
I don’t understand his Arabic,
but I guess he was reassuring him.
But what is he saying?
It is not the Arabic I learned in school.
It's different, I don’t understand it.
Take a cigarette, take it,
I’ll give you the light.
He thinks we’ll kill him.
We do not want to kill you.
Calm down, listen, calm down!
He doesn't speak English.
What are you speaking English to him for!?
- Tell him something in Arabic.
- What am I supposed to say?
Assi, do something!
He’ll hurt himself.
Stop! Stop! Stop it!
What? What? Want water?
Give him morphine, Assi!
- Here, here, hold it.
- Okay. Envelope! Envelope!
Fuck! There! Here it is,
Assi. I found it!
So we’ll wait until dark and go
on our own to Saint Tropez.
Be careful.
- And the phalangists?
- What about them?
They were supposed to guide us
Now you’re saying
we're going alone, in short...
We’re going alone!
We’ll get out town at this
point, okay?
From here we’ll head north...
to sector... 9-11
Cornelia to Cinderella.
... Where is our Saint Tropez?
Saint Tropez.
- Cinderella, answer.
- This is Cinderella, over.
Prepare to move.
The Phalangists will guide us.
It’s final. Confirmation received.
I’m not going with them.
I am the highest-ranking officer
and I’m telling you I’m not going with them!
You see, you can send a helicopter,
or force me to take
what's left of my platoon
and be on our way...
without even knowing how
many fucking Syrians...
Use Pluto.
Prepare to move.
They’re saying that someone...
made a mistake and now we're surrounded?
- So?
- So what?
- Ask the question!
- Is it true or not? What's happening?
There are Syrian forces around here.
Well here’s a newsflash!
But is it dangerous?
This thing we're doing
is called war.
and war is notoriously dangerous.
What the fuck is he saying?
Like I don’t know war is dangerous?
Who the fuck am I? Fuck you!
Wait, I bet that he...
knows stuff he won’t tell us.
No, no, now... we move north,
and we open a road.
But which road are you talking about?
Or maybe even he doesn’t know shit?
And after all who is he?
A lieutenant, a captain...
...that fucking Cornelia, who
sends people on suicide missions?
- What, what are you looking for?
- Pluto.
No, no, Hertzel. It’s not allowed.
- It is an emergency channel.
- Oh, really, Assi? Wake up!
Have you done morphine?
You need another shot to wake up?
- You’re edgy, Hertzel. You shouldn’t...
- Don’t touch me! Don’t touch me!
- You see you're nervous?
- Fuck nervous!
I’m trapped in here with you,
you can’t read instruments,
and the other one can’t shoot.
Of course I’m nervous!
Calm down, Hertzel. We'll go north
and we'll open a road. You'll see.
Get the tank’s manual, Yigal.
You’ll find Pluto’s frequency.
Don’t give it to him, Yigal. Wait.
Don’t give it to him!
We’ll end up in solitary for 40 days
Yigal, don’t give them...
Ask Assi. He knows the frequency.
Ask Assi!
- Come on, Assi, what frequency ?
- You really don’t want to understand...
If I go to jail my father
will never forgive me!
What jail, Assi? What jail?!
We’re about to die here!
Give me, give it to me!
1-5-2-5.
I need air evacuation, you hear me?
Send a helicopter and we’re
out of here in a minute.
Too dangerous to land there
and then there is the tank.
It was hit by a rocket, remember?
It would be great if could even move.
It’s not possible.
We can not let the tank
fall into their hands.
Are you even listening to me?
I’m calling for help and you’re wondering
whether to leave the vehicle?
I don't have bags of blood,
No first-aid kits, nothing.
I'm asking for help! And you’re holding
me here for hours with those two clowns.
That you sent to help me,
but don’t you understand? I need help!
Do you understand what
I'm saying? I need help!
I’m trapped, trapped, damn it!
And that's all the army
can offer me,
two assholes in a Mercedes?
One of whom is not even capable
of pointing the road on the map
The other one tells me he’s Turkish.
What the fuck is he doing here?
- We know them. They’re reliable.
- Who, who knows them?
Maybe you know them?
Can I trust them to get
us out of here?
- You have no choice.
- I have no choice.
That's the way things are, Jamil.
Get out of there before it's too late.
And between you and me...
Feel free to improvise. Be creative.
The driver, ah... I think he’s called
Yigal, can you check?
- Yigal Yomtov. What?
- Call his mother, tell her he’s fine.
Anything else?
Call my mother too. I’m leaving
Pluto’s channel. Over and out.
Clean the vehicle
and prepare the gun.
Then we’ll move north and
we'll open a passage.
- You're nuts!
- On the contrary, Hertzel.
Now I know. Now I know
that I was wrong and you were right.
Right? What are you talking about?
- You were not supposed to keep guard.
- What are you saying?
You do physical work, Hertzel.
You need to save energy.
If you had slept, you
would not have been so nervous.
You're going crazy!
Hello? Wake up.
You see, Hertzel,
see that you're nervous?
- What are you doing?
- I am an officer, Hertzel.
I need a shave.
Order and hygiene are paramount.
Every tank commander knows that.
We must organize and arrange
the tank’s ammunition.
Put it in the front.
3 fluorescent rockets,
3 fragmentation missiles
2 anti-tank missiles and
a phosphorous bomb.
Actually, I stand corrected,
a smoke bomb.
Then we head north and we
open up a passage.
But first we must
clean the vehicle.
You can’t go to war
in this mess.
This is Cinderella, prepare to move.
Over.
Rhinoceros, stay on top of the Mercedes.
We will keep behind. Over.
Why is the radio silent?
Where is Jamil?
I don’t know. Shmulik,
can you see him?
No, he’s gone.
What's happening, why are we stopping?
It’s the Phalangist, he made a sign.
I do not take orders from
fucking Phalangists, is that clear?
What orders?
He just waved!
Rhinoceros to Cinderella.
Rhinoceros to Cinderella, do you copy?
You have to go now!
Go there. Three kilometers.
What?
We do not go anywhere unless
we talk to Jamil.
Jamil's gone! Go!
- Wait, I’ll call.
- There’s no time. Go now!
- But..
- No time!
I’m taking the prisoner.
Give me the key!
The key!
Jamil has it.
Trust me, you have to go now!
Go there!
- What did he say?
- That he has to pee.
What is this music?
Let’s go..., like
the Phalangist told us.
I’m not leaving without Jamil.
Rhinoceros to Cinderella. Jamil?
What do we do, Assi?
Assi...
- Cinderella to Rhinoceros.
- This is Rhinoceros.
- Why did you disappear?
- Problems with the radio.Over.
Listen. We were cut off.
and we made a small detour
to Saint Tropez.
You have arrived at Saint Tropez?
Affirmative. Keep moving.
Are the Phalangists with you?
Negative.
Start the engine and keep moving.
Stay in touch with me.
I don’t know where to go,
which direction to take.
Where we are in now, at some point
we heard some music.
Hertzel, calm down.
Take a deep breath and listen.
You must not stay there.
Start the engine and go.
Rhinoceros, Cinderella here, talk
to me. Are you moving?
Rhinoceros, you have to get away
from there! Rhinoceros!
Shmulik, Hertzel, Yigal, respond!
Hertzel answer me. Where are we going?
where are we headed?
Go north. Flatten everything you see.
Move! If you stay there,
you’re fucked!
Yigal, go, start the engine! Go!
It’s not starting!
It’s not fucking working!
Push the accelerator! The gas!
The gas! Push the accelerator!
Push the fucking accelerator!
- It doesn’t work!
- Stop crying!
Keep pushing. Pump!
Pump! More gas! Don’t stop!
I don’t want to stay here, okay?
I want to leave!
That's enough, I want to go
home, okay?
- I want my mom...
- Yigal... Yigal...
Don’t cry. Stop crying.
We're going home, don’t cry.
- Push on the gas. The accelerator!
- I want to get out of here.
I want to go home!
They’re shooting at us!
- Who?
- How the fuck should I know? I gotta shoot!
I have no air. I can’t breathe!
I can’t breathe!
Yigal! Yigal, I need power.
I can’t shoot without power!
- I can’t breathe! I’m suffocating!
- Push on gas, Yigal! Gas! I’ll shoot!
Go, Yigal! Go, go, go, go!
Go, Yigal!
Go! Don’t stop! Floor it! Go!
Go! Go! Don’t be scared!
Go, Yigal! Go!
Full throttle, Yigal!
Full throttle!
Go, Yigal! Go!
Load it, Hertzel!
They’re shooting at us!
- They’re shooting at us, Hertzel!
- Hertzel!
- Loaded!
- Fire!
Go, Yigal! Go, go, Yigal!
Fire!
Keep going, Yigal!
Go! Yigal! Don’t stop!
Let's get out of here!
Did they hit us from the front!
Yigal, are you all right?
Yigal, answer me, Yigal! Yigal!
Yigal, are you okay?
He’s been hit!
Yigal! Yigal, can you hear me?
Help me Hertzel.
Let’s get him out of here!
Yigal?
Yigal!
Jamil to Rhinoceros.
- This is Rhinoceros.
- Did you get out of town?
Affirmative.
Cornelia, this is Cinderella.
We're out.
This is Cornelia. Copy that
Tell your driver
that his mother got the message.
Over and out.