Don't let him up.
Final score 7-5,
in favor of Cal Chetley.
Team score
Riverdale 12, Claremore 9.
That was Cal Chetley's first win ever
in a Riverdale uniform.
Let's hear it for our 135-pounder.
Keep going.
No.
Hold him.
- Damn it.
- You got speed? Let's see it.
- Oh yeah, I got speed.
- Show-off!
Thanks.
Hey.
We're gonna pick it up a bit
for regionals.
- More time?
- No.
A better use of the time.
How?
Well, you got that week off
for spring break.
Eleven days till they start.
That's enough time to get serious.
- Serious?
- Yeah.
Serious enough
to show me the reverse cradle?
No.
You know, a good friend
wouldn't eat those in front of me.
Don't watch.
So we going to the dance together?
- Might be working.
- What?
Yes, I'm taking you to the dance.
- What are you wearing?
- I haven't really thought about it yet.
- And dare I ask what you're wearing?
- It's a surprise.
- Well, is it legal?
- I'm making it.
Well, that's encouraging.
Luli, you're not still showing the boobs,
are you?
You're looking good on that mat, Calvin.
You actually look like you know
what you're doing.
Yep.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Depends on what you wanna talk about.
I just want you to know I'm proud of you
for getting out there.
- But?
- But nothing.
I wish it were golf, but it's not, so...
Just know I'm gonna be there for you.
- Okay.
- No matter what, I'm gonna be there.
You gotta know that.
Just don't let it push you too far, please.
Mom, I'm having fun.
One day when we're older
and sitting in rocking chairs...
...I want you to describe to me,
in a way I can understand...
...how wrestling is fun.
Okay.
Hey.
Practice ends about 4:30
every day, right?
So, what exactly do you do
for the next few hours?
I just, you know, jog.
Work on the weights, go to lab.
Okay.
Well, it must be working. You look good.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Shit howdy.
Who are you?
His name's Theo Henderson.
He's a bigtime tiny wrestler.
We call him the Gnat.
- He's the smallest guy I could find.
- Well, it's nice to meet you.
- What's up, man?
- How much do you weigh?
- About 145.
- Each leg?
- Come on, come on, spin. Get it.
- Good job.
Switch.
Come on, Cal. Let's go.
Let's go. Beat him.
This is kind of like
that Extreme Makeover show.
Minus the boob job.
No one's ever done anything like this
for me before.
You're gonna be the belle of the ball,
Miss Luli.
- What are you wearing?
- Something I made myself.
- You do that?
- Oh, yeah.
I make sure I accentuate some areas
more than others.
How about some girl-to-girl advice?
Well, that would be a first.
Scooch over.
Don't sell the whole package
at one time.
Give them small hints.
Keep them guessing
as long as you can.
And then keep them guessing
a little more.
Let them know you have other options.
Be confident. Don't chase, be chased.
I wish.
Well, this helps.
- Miss Chetley?
- Yes?
How old were you
when you first kissed a guy?
- Thirty-two.
- What the hell?
- I was 16.
- I guess.
- Was it Cal's dad?
- No, but it got his attention.
He was second.
- Were you chasing?
- No.
Sort of directing.
That's what I'm talking about.
- Good kid.
- Yeah.
He seems to know
where he's going, man.
Where you been, Mike?
Look, I don't hear from you for I don't
know how long, and then out of the blue?
- I don't know.
- You broke one of your golden rules.
You stopped moving. You're up now.
You look good. Stay up.
Keep moving.
There's your reason.
I don't know, man.
Sometimes it ain't that simple.
Cal.
Come on.
Get down.
All right.
The reason the reverse cradle
is such a risk...
...is you gotta trick your opponent
into thinking you're done, okay?
- Okay.
- All right? Now, listen.
If I know you're stalling, I'm going
for a pin. You're gonna ball up.
So when you ball up, I gotta press you
to flatten you out, right?
I'll press you and my head will come
over your shoulder.
You see it come over the second time...
...you got a moment.
You gotta grab a headlock.
Grab it, right there.
Okay, good.
You're gonna roll to your shoulders,
hook a leg and squeeze.
Roll, hook and squeeze. Go.
Lock it. Good.
Reverse cradle. No escape.
- Don't mess with me.
- What?
- You don't mess with me.
- Oh, my God.
Shit howdy. You wanna go?
Check it out, man.
Now the party's started.
Yeah. For sure.
That was nice, Cal.
- You hungry?
- Yeah.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
We are gonna pick it up a little
for you guys.
Hey, Stringfellow.
Will 5 bucks
get me a little private showing?
Come on, babe. I'm like the only kid here
who hasn't been down Boob Boulevard.
Sounds like a personal problem.
- Barrow, walk away.
- Come on, Luli. I'm a big spender.
- Hey.
- You pervert.
- What the hell are you thinking?
Get off me. What, Chetley?
What are you gonna do?
You all right?
Come on. Let's go.
- You okay? Come on.
- Back up.
Get off me, man.
Why does stuff like this
always happen to me?
Because you're Luli.
You bring it on yourself.
- I hate myself.
- No, you don't.
Just stop trying so hard.
You're like a butterfly in a wind storm.
Meaning what?
Meaning...
I don't know what it means.
It means you're just special, I guess.
No, it doesn't.
- They just don't like me.
- They don't know you.
But you go about it the wrong way.
If they knew you, if they really knew you...
...they'd like you.
I do.
Hey.
You really look nice tonight.
Thank you.
Hey. Come here.
- Hey, Mike. It's been a while.
- Hey.
So, what are you drinking?
- Whatever's on tap is fine.
- You got it.
Excuse me. Here you go.
I don't want to do this, man.
I don't think you got
a whole lot of choice in the matter.
Hello?
What?
Where?
I... I can't understand you.
Cal?
Was that Mike?
- Why is he calling you?
- What did he say?
I don't know.
He's drunk.
- No, he's not drunk.
- He's in jail.
- That's bullshit, Mom. He's not drunk.
- How would you know?
Cal, how would you know?
Because I see him every day.
That's how I know.
We've been working on the mat
for the last month.
Mom, he hasn't had one drink,
so something happened.
- A month? And that's where you've been?
- Just a month.
- How do you think I've won anything?
- Coach Tennant.
- He's working with two dozen wrestlers.
- How and where did you find Mike?
In his house. It's not that hard
if you're really looking.
That's not what I'm asking you.
This is me you're talking to.
You've never kept anything
from me before.
You've spent more time with Mike
in the past month than I have in 10 years.
And you don't even know him,
and you don't think I should know?
- I didn't want it to go wrong.
- What?
- Mike.
- Why?
Because he's my brother.
I have the right to know my own brother.
What do the two of you talk about?
Wrestling.
That's it?
Work and school.
I guess it's not like we talk about the
wives or kids or our favorite colors.
I don't even know him that well, do I?
That's not fair, Cal.
I was afraid of you and Mike together.
- Why?
- Mike is unpredictable.
I became afraid of him.
I didn't know how to help him.
But you're the best friend I've ever had.
What exactly happened in the car?
Your dad and Mike...
...were headed to Eufaula
to scout one of Mike's opponents.
That's what they did.
These guys were prepared, Cal.
But there was...
There was heavy snow, ice.
Mike was thrown from the car.
Mac wasn't.
I begged them not to go.
Dad knew Mike
could take this other kid, but...
But...
And he didn't think they needed to go,
but Mike pushed it.
I remember him throwing
your dad's words back in his face.
"Take no opponent for granted."
So Mac did what he always did.
He kept his word.
- Did Mike quit wrestling after that?
- No. No.
No, he got hurt a year later...
...but he really gave up
the night your dad died.
He blamed himself for Mac's death.
I think maybe...
What?
I was...
Cal, I was so lost.
I was so devastated,
and I didn't know it at the time...
...but I blamed him too, and Mike felt it.
I was 18 when Mike was born.
Your dad and I were just kids.
He was my first,
and your first is always your baby.
You were an adult
when you came out.
I had to ask for your ID.
Then I lost both of them.
Ma, you said that Mike blamed himself...
...for Dad's being killed.
Did anybody ever tell him
it wasn't his fault?
I think everybody in here has a shot
at the medal round this weekend.
The next couple of days, we're gonna
show them what we're made of.
So let's get it in our heads right now.
Okay?
I'll see you guys in the morning.
Bus leaves at 7:30 sharp. Be here.
Let's get our hands in here.
Tornadoes on three.
One, two, three.
Tornadoes.
Hey. Good luck. Good to see you.
Something told me I should be here.
Why now?
Cal.
He believes in you...
...and he was right.
A friend in the DA's office...
...a guy I dated for about 20 minutes...
...ran down the waitress
where you were arrested.
She'll testify you didn't take a drink
and you didn't start the fight.
I talked with your parole officer.
Cal needs you, Mike.
It scares you, doesn't it?
Yes.
This scares me...
...but Cal really wants you
to be there for him.
And I want you to be there.
For Cal.
You know, Mike...
...I've tracked you over three states...
...and not a day goes by...
...that I don't think maybe
this is the day you'll show up.
And I'm listening to Cal tell me
that you two wrestle, that you talk.
And I'm thinking, " I want that."
I want...
I want my son back,
but I still don't know how.
Let's get you out of here. Come on.
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah, kid!
- You did fine.
- Hey, Cal. Calvin?
With that win, Riverdale's Cal Chetley
moves into the 135-pound semi-finals.
What the hell?
You don't belong here.
- Maybe I do.
- No, you don't.
For all the goodness
your dad brought to your life...
...I don't believe he ever taught you
how to accept loss.
It was always
about showing up prepared.
I need you to show up.
Maybe I'm not right for Cal.
It's like you said, just don't think
I know how to lose.
You do now.
This may sound simple...
...but that boy waiting for you...
...hasn't experienced
the pain we've been through.
I can't breathe sometimes.
Because in my heart...
...I know I blamed you at a time...
...when I should have been
protecting you.
And I never made it right.
I am so sorry.
I'm your mother...
...but I was choking
on my grief and my anger.
But, baby, we have to somehow
put Mac to rest.
Yeah.
I think that's what Cal is trying to do.
He's...
He's trying to help us.
Dad, he made me feel invincible.
I just... I couldn't pull him from the car.
Cal. Cal is trying to pull you out.
Let him.
Was I right?
Seems that you were.
Is he out now?
Yeah.
Beyond that...
...I'm not sure.
Hopefully he's working some things out.
How did you do?
I'm still in it.
Good for you.
Now, go wrestle.
When you show up, things happen.
I know that's what Dad would say.
- You coming?
- I'll be there.
All right.
Welcome to Tulsa in day two of the
Oklahoma District Three championship.
All coaches report
to the director's table by 10.
Jesuits Lugats,
report to the scores table at Mat 2.
Know anything about Leonard?
Well, from what I hear,
he puts his pants on one leg at a time.
All wrestlers begin clearing the mats
at this time.
One-hundred and 35 pound
semi-final match.
Hayes vs. Rayber.
Red. What are you doing here?
Rumor has it
you won some matches yesterday.
Yeah.
Where you going?
Oh, I'm done.
I didn't want this.
I was looking for something else.
You sure about that?
Took a lot of courage to come this far.
You made something happen.
Now I hear you're two matches away
from a district title.
I'd say that's time pretty well spent.
How come you always seem to know
what to say?
Sometimes these things take time
to work out.
But no one's asking you to win, Cal.
Just don't quit.
Hey. I'm gonna grab a cup of coffee,
head inside there and get a seat.
Looking forward to your match.
Winner Mark Hayes, by decision.
Second semi-finals, 135-pound class.
John Leonard, North Shore...
...vs. Cal Chetley of Riverdale.
Leonard vs. Chetley, center mat.
- Hey, where you been?
- Just wandering.
- Come on, you ready?
- Yeah.
All right, listen. Two minutes at a time.
Listen for me. Get out there.
Chetley in the red anklet,
Leonard in the green.
Give them cauliflower ear!
Come on, Cal. You can do it.
Come on, shoot.
You're okay. You're all right.
You're all right. You're all right.
Go, go, go!
After one period,
Leonard leads Chetley 5 to 2.
You're all right. You're good.
You're good. You're good.
Come on!
All right.
Get him!
There you go.
Yeah. Yeah.
Come on, get in.
Come on. Go! Go!
- Go. Crack him. Crack him.
- Damn it, come on.
Come on. Yep.
Come on, Cal!
Take him down.
Hey.
You're all right, man.
Winner Chetley, Riverdale High School
by injury default.
That's my Cal!
Oh, God.
- Who taught you the guillotine?
- I've been doing a little homework.
That was textbook wrestling.
You showed a lot of character,
no two ways about it.
I'll come back and get you.
- Good to see you, Mike.
- You too, coach.
- Been a long time.
- Smell of the mat never leaves you.
You're welcome to take the coach's seat
next to me when he's up if you want.
- I'd like that.
- Good. I recognize the Chetley spirit.
In about an hour I'll come back
and get the both of you.
Okay.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
- I had a little help.
- Mom?
Okay, remember, Cal.
You're not me. You're not Dad.
You gotta wrestle your own way.
Use your opponent's momentum
against him.
Use them long legs, damn it.
It's your best weapon.
- You got your music.
- Right here.
You got 10 minutes. What do you got?
- Opera.
- What?
It's like Italian opera.
Who are you?
Never mind, we're doing it your way.
- Crank it up, you take it in.
- All right.
Opera.
This is a good day.
You know our boy listens to opera?
I want you to know you're everything
Cal described, only better looking.
- I'm Luli.
- Hi, Luli.
Could you give this to Cal
before this last match?
It's real important.
I sure will.
What is this, a Volkswagen?
Hey, Shaquille O'Neal.
That was horrible.
What's this?
This is a heavy present
from somebody named Luli.
"Here's your edge. I love you. Lu."
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- A pump.
- Now, that's romantic.
- It is if you know Luli.
What the hell's this?
That's Luli too.
Hey, give us one more, kid.
We're all out there.
I will.
Cal.
You're already a medalist.
Let's go out as number one.
Okay.
What the hell?
Damn, coach.
I hope the fire marshal
doesn't shut us down.
You know that guy?
That's Dad's coach.
- Red's Dad's coach?
- Red. That's Harry.
- Harry?
- Harry Newman.
"Peace, my fearless friend.
He touched so many
with his courage and heart.
You took it far, we'll take it from here.
Harry Newman."
That guy's Harry Newman?
You know him?
Yeah. Through fishing, mostly.
- And now, our 135-pound finalist...
- Dad's here.
...representing St. Paul's with a dual-meet
record of 23 and 0, Mark Hayes.
And representing
Riverdale High School...
...with a dual meet record of 5 and 6,
Calvin Chetley.
Chetley in the red,
Hayes in the green.
And please welcome back
to the tournament past All-American...
...NCAA finalist...
...and three-time
state champion, Mike Chetley.
Here we go.
Get around him.
Gotta get around him. Come on, now.
Get him, Cal.
Let's go.
He's setting it up.
Come on. Come on!
- He's out! He's out!
- Come on. Cinch it, Cal. Cinch it.
- Get him!
- Come on!
Oh, baby, buckle up.
Squeeze it, Cal. Squeeze it.
Cal, squeeze it! Squeeze it!
Come on, come on!
Come on! Get him.
- Get him, Cal, get him!
- Come on, cinch it, Cal, cinch it.
Come on.
- Get him, Cal!
- Come on!
Cal, come on! Pin him!
Mark Hayes, winner by decision.
Final score: Hayes 11, Chetley 9.
Like I said,
not all legends are about victory.
Some are about struggle...
...finding out who you are
and your reason for being.
Big Mac Chetley died before
he had a chance to finish the job.
That was his greatest fear:
that Sharon and the boys
would struggle on without him.
- You got heart, kid.
- Thanks.
- You thought I was done, didn't you?
- Yeah, I did.
He once asked me
if anything were to happen to him...
...that I might help keep an eye
on the boys.
Mac, your boys are fine.
So is your girl.