What are you doing here? Go away.
- What about the child?
Dead.
Is it still in her womb?
- No, over there.
Who are you?
It was dead. That is an undead.
No, I breathed some of my soul
into him. He's not an undead.
Take the child and look after him.
I'll come for him in due time.
And woman, if I don't find him here,
I'll cut your head off.
I always keep my word.
God is my witness, lord. It was dead.
And then this man
gave it some of his soul.
Is that what he said?
- Yes.
That he gave it some of his soul?
Yes.
Give it to me.
He said he'll cut my head off if I lose it.
- I'll cut your head off if you don't give it.
Give it to me.
Now go away and close the door.
Forgive me.
Now let our souls
compete against one another.
Did Sydal at least get wounded?
- No.
He can't be far yet. I came too late.
Will you take the child?
- It can grow up at the blacksmith's.
And'?
- He's frail.
To survive the winter,
he'll have to show iron mettle.
Let him stay without a name. If he's still
alive in spring, let his name be 'lsenhart'.
15 years later
What are you looking at, lsenhart?
Come.
Here.
Now listen to me. Those are daughters
from the House of Laurin.
Someone like you mustn't even
think about them. Keep working.
What are you staring at my sister for?
You know each other. My son Konrad.
Chlodio, lsenhart will as of now only
be at your disposal in the afternoon.
Walther von Ascisberg
will educate the two.
You will receive something
usually reserved for clergy and nobles...
namely education.
That's a great privilege.
What is a 'privilege'?
That word comes from a language
you will soon learn: Latin.
The preponderances of one of these
humours determines one's inclination.
If someone has too much blood,
he's the sanguine type.
The phlegmatic suffers
from too much slime.
If yellow bile is dominant, he's choleric.
Excessive black bile spells melancholy.
'Give me a fixed point in space,
and I'll move the earth.'
Archimedes said that.
- Was he a soldier?
No, a scholar.
Lever action allows us to exert
great force with only little effort.
Enough for today.
Et habeo clades.
Claves.
Et habeo claves.
One, two.
Stop striking like a girl, dammit.
Now listen, I want to hear you scream.
Is there anything forbidden in there?
- Yes...no.
Tell me, what does it say?
That's Lancelot, by Chrétien de Troyes.
Anna, stay here.
My father will beat me black and blue.
No, we're not going this way.
- Yes, we are. I get to decide.
Come.
For me?
It's beautiful, lsenhart.
- It's a wedding gift.
You know about it?
- Konrad told me.
You'll do well with Oliver von Schundeler.
- You think so?
Konrad says he has connections
and owns land.
And he has 42 years behind him.
Von Schﬂndeler is an old man.
I don't want to be his wife.
Oliver von Schundeler expects a virgin.
I don't just want to be the one who...
- Sometimes you can be a real idiot.
I'm a serf, Anna.
- I'd rather flee than marry anyone else.
You'll be pleased. Look here,
goods from all over the world.
I have salt from Salzburg,
cloth from Bruges.
This might interest the fair ladies.
One pinch a day
helps against skinniness.
You'll gain weight faster
and easily get the shape you desire.
Lies, all lies. All that stuff did for me
was give me constipation.
Honoured Lady of Laurin, here, a sample.
Would you like to try it?
You owe me money,
Alexander von Westheim.
At six o'clock?
- Look at him.
Yes.
- The Jews is at a loss for words.
But I told you, it only works
if you don't sin for three days.
What extraordinary beauty
graces the daughter of Laurin.
She has no need of this potion.
The Lord is the beginning and end.
His will is also inherent in the seasons.
In spring the plants sprout,
in summer they bloom.
In fall they lose colour and in winter they
wither, so that it may all start over again.
Alpha and Omega.
I think the trees shed their leaves
so as not to dry out in winter.
Of all your ideas in recent years, this is
the most absurd. How can you say that?
If you squeeze a leaf in summer,
sap comes out.
But in fall the leaves dry out.
The question is: Where does the sap go?
Well?
In spring the tree sucks up water
and distributes it to the leaves.
In winter it absorbs the water again,
so it doesn't dry out.
The only explanation is God's will,
nothing else.
Are trees creatures? Do they have
muscles? Can they draw humours?
Why not? They also distribute
water to the leaves. That's why...
That's why until seven o'clock
you will recite the penitential psalm.
Today? Today I can't.
- And now until eight o'clock.
Anna?
He inserted it here, one phalanx deep.
And then he pressed in further,
from right to left.
Do you have to touch her?
- What I'm touching is not Anna, lsenhart.
What constitutes her is her soul,
which has gone up to meet its Maker.
I'm only examining her shell,
her mortal form.
He inserted it here, till he realized
the blade couldn't go deep enough.
Is that really important?
- I don't know.
This wouldn't have happened
to an experienced killer.
Maybe it was his first murder.
Here he slit the skin open.
But at the ribs he didn't use a knife.
No, these aren't knife wounds.
He smashed them. But why?
You can't do that.
- Oh yes, in fact I have to.
No semen.
He didn't rape her.
It wasn't Anna he desired, but her heart.
Isenhart...
the murderer took Anna's heart.
My sister's murderer, we got him.
We got him.
Call the guards.
Quiet.
Did you lay hands on my daughter?
Speak.
- Please, I...
I have nothing to do with it. I'd never lay
hands on your daughter, I swear to God.
What's wrong with you?
I gave that stone
as a present to your daughter.
I forged the bezel myself.
A present.
Where did you get it?
You won't believe me.
Isenhart, heat up an iron.
- No, wait.
Wilbrand von Maulbronn.
He gave me the stone. The archbishop.
Let him burn for his impudence.
- I swear.
You're lying.
- Wilbrand von Maulbronn gave it to me.
Archbishop Wilbrand
is after your vineyards.
He will use the merest trifle,
and he has the protection of the emperor.
Maulbronn Abbey
Hand the traveling salesman over to me,
Sigimund of Laurin...
and I will draw the truth out of him.
He accuses you of giving him this stone.
It belonged to my daughter.
- And you give credence to that man?
I don't give him anything.
I think he wants to take revenge on me.
He threatened my treasurer
and I had him chased off my land.
I can assure you
I didn't conduct business with that Jew.
That's for the impudence of accusing me
of the murder of your daughter.
Konrad.
Isn't it?
Now leave.
He won't forget about it. It's just the thing
Wilbrand von Maulbronn was waiting for.
It was my fault.
I shouldn't have taken you along.
On your knees.
Pray.
May God give strength
to the righteous one.
Whoever drops his arms first
is accused of injustice by God.
Please, Lord, don't abandon me.
Don't punish the wrong man.
God has passed judgment.
I'm the wrong man.
You're killing the wrong man.
Please, Lord, have mercy.
Quiet at last.
Why is he allowed to breathe?
Doesn't it prolong his suffering?
He'll freeze to death soon, lsenhart.
The pipe isn't meant for breathing.
The soul must be able to leave the heart
and rise up to heaven through the mouth.
Why?
Otherwise he'll climb out of his grave
and come after us for revenge.
What news does he bring?
Wilbrand von Maulbronn
demands your surrender.
What did you answer?
- That he'll have to deal with me first.
Konrad, come here.
You look after your mother and sister.
lsenhart, stay on his side.
When the gate falls, flee together.
If you surrender the castle,
Maulbronn will be forced to be lenient.
I only serve God and the Emperor.
Draw your bows, fire.
Father, we need every man.
I'm not your father, Isenhart.
I raised you, but I'm not your father.
What's that?
So who is my father?
- You don't want to know.
Wait.
Fire, now.
The gate is down. They're here.
Mother.
Help
Keep still.
Sophia.
Did he hurt you?
Get out. Flee through the escape tunnel
and wait there.
Get out.
- Come.
Konrad.
I'll give your son a fair trial...
and sell your wife and daughter
for a good price...
so that they'll serve decent people.
Come, we can make it.
There they are.
Come.
- Konrad.
Konrad?
What happened?
What happened? He needs treatment.
We can't ride like this.
We don't have time.
Where are mother and father?
- Let's go.
Are they coming? Where are they?
Where are mother and father?
No, I have to get them.
- We have to go.
Let's go.
- Mother, no.
Go on, keep going.
Go on. Keep going.
Keep going, I'll detain them.
Isenhart, come.
- Go away.
Don't do that. Come with us.
Is the escape tunnel still free?
- Laurin Castle has fallen.
What?
And Sigimund?
Go away. Leave and go to Spira.
Wilbrand won't find you there.
Five years later
Heiligster near Spira
Look who's coming.
Here. My dear brother.
Are you well?
- Yes. You?
I am now you're here.
- Good to see you again, lsenhart.
The horses need water.
- Put me down.
Konrad, keep your hands off of her.
For you.
How long are you staying?
- We have to go back to Spira tomorrow.
I think I have one.
Can you help me?
- Gently.
One, two... Now.
Maybe we caught it in its sleep.
-'From sleep to death is but a small step.'
Aristotle said that.
'Love is one soul in two bodies.'
I think that's his most beautiful statement.
I read it somewhere.
Watchmen of Spira, what has happened?
- My daughter.
What has happened?
- One of the cows is gravid.
Johanna, my daughter,
spent the night with her.
I'm going to have a closer look.
Who had she been with?
- With no one. Johanna was a virgin.
Her heart's been cutout.
No.
- My friend has to do that.
How else can we find out if he raped her?
She hasn't been violated. Everyone
not related to the deceased, get out.
Go on, get out.
Go on, beat it.
Two stab wounds.
What are you doing?
- I want to see if she defended herself.
There's no blood or skin under her nails.
What's the difference? She's dead.
- It suggests she knew the murderer.
He could come so close...
- Stop.
Because she trusted him.
- Who are you?
My lord and I were called for. Gunther
von Martensen is the doctor of Spira.
I'm his aide, Henning von der Braake.
Who are you?
Konrad, watchman of Spira.
- I'm lsenhart.
We serve as watchmen
and happened to walk by.
You're no longer needed.
I'm going to examine the victim.
Are you the mother?
- Yes.
Did you find her?
- The watchman's already examined her.
Is that so? What did you conclude?
That she's dead?
Johanna defended herself. I found red
hair in her hand. The killer had red hair.
He killed her with two stabs in her neck.
But he didn't murder her out of lust.
The girl is still intact.
He wanted her heart.
He cut her torso open
and amputated her left breast.
The costal arches were separated
with a coarse-toothed tool, like a saw.
And he took her heart.
Why are you leaving?
What am I supposed to do?
You can bury your daughter.
Does anyone with red hair work here,
or has a stranger been here?
A man was here.
A man with red hair and one arm.
Do you know him?
- No, he didn't mention his name.
He only said he wanted to cross
the Rhine and go to Wurttemberg.
We can still catch up with him.
He has a headstart of a few hours.
And he's heading south.
No, I think he's heading north.
He hopes to send the search parties
the wrong way.
If he's heading north,
Spira will be his next stop.
So, off to Spira.
Off to Spira.
Did anyone with red hair enter the city?
- Yes, two hours ago.
And he didn't leave the city again?
- No.
Close the gate.
Go on, close the gate.
Nothing.
Did you see a man with red hair?
If you see a one-armed redhead,
tell the watchmen.
All gates are shut and under guard.
- Alright, spread out and find this man.
Search every tavern,
every inn, every barn.
Hey, get out of here.
- I'm going.
Alexander von Westheim didn't kill Anna.
- He did have the stone.
Maybe Wilbrand von Maulbronn had it.
- Westheim just wanted to save his skin.
We have a clear pattern here.
The murderer didn't rape the girls
and he took their hearts.
He actually tore their hearts out.
- But why?
Two identical proceedings,
establishing a pattern to the murders.
And if it's the same murderer,
Alexander von Westheim was innocent.
That would mean that we buried
an innocent man alive.
It was a judgment of God.
He's nowhere to be found.
- We went to every tavern, every inn.
He entered Spira and didn't leave again,
yet he's untraceable.
As if the earth had swallowed him up.
He must be here somewhere.
We have to find him.
Konrad, weren't you at the lepers' lately?
- I was indeed.
If nothing has fallen off, you can come in.
- No, I can't.
Leeks and chervil.
I learned that from the Arabs.
But they're our enemies.
- Sure.
I learned it from them
before they became our enemies.
Isenhart, back on your feet again?
Did your aide find out anything?
- No.
Henning is at the city archives.
Isenhart.
Good that you're here.
Follow me. Come, look what I've found.
Here: Spira, the year of our Lord 1193.
- On September 24 a murder took place.
You surprise me, not for the first time.
A watchman who knows how to read.
Latin, even.
- Favourable circumstances.
I'm sure.
A year ago, during a fight by the river, a
certain Michael von Bremen killed a man.
Von Bremen has only one arm
and flaming red hair.
He lost his arm
in the Battle of Dorylaeum.
I'm sure he's our man.
He's lord of a castle at Tarup.
Does it say from when till when
Michael von Bremen was here?
Yes, why?
- If what I think is true...
an unsolved murder of a virgin
took place during that time.
Of course.
Here. Here: 'Heart removed.'
Just two days after the fight by the river.
-'Murderer unknown.'
If he's not insane...
What if he's possessed by the devil?
Dig her up?
- No.
Konrad.
- No, you can't dig up the dead.
It disturbs their eternal rest
and they'll come to haunt you.
We'll take the risk.
- Come.
If you get caught,
you'll be burned at the stake. Not me.
What is it?
How was she killed? Check.
Great, Isenhart.
Desecration of a corpse as well.
Four stabs to the back of her head.
Let's ride on to Tarup.
He slit Anna's throat.
After that, he refined his method.
You mean that he hones his skills?
- Yes.
He stabbed the girl at the cemetery
four times, the girl in the hay just twice
You think he eats them?
Their hearts, I mean.
In the Orient they say that you take
over all your enemy's good qualities...
when you eat his heart.
- Only a godless people can think so.
So what does he expect
from three young women?
Not strength, for sure.
- Virginity, perhaps.
You're right. All three were virgins.
At least he could assume they were.
The question remains: Why does he kill
virgins? Why does he want their hearts?
I said there's a pattern to his murders.
That also goes for his victims.
They're young, inviolate and...
- Female.
A malicious weapon, the cross bow.
One shouldn't use it against Christians.
The man we're after is no Christian.
People say that since '91 the dead
have been walking around at Tarup.
People say many things.
Many serfs of the Lord of Tarup
starved to death at the time.
The ones who survived ate the dead.
The Lord himself devoured three hearts.
One of those hearts belonged to a Hun.
A man so big and strong,
the like of him had never been seen.
Then something strange happened.
The Lord was suddenly able
to run as fast as a horse.
And he was able to bend iron.
- Nonsense.
He was much stronger than before.
This Lord was Michael von Bremen.
The one-armed man.
Tarup Castle
Tarup.
We'll split up.
- Alright.
During the famine,
they ate their fellow men here.
Can you imagine?
I mean, if you hadn't eaten for a week...
and we were alone?
- I don't think you taste well, Konrad.
Good to know.
Over here.
What have you got?
Here's an entrance.
- Let's go inside.
Gijlnther?
- Yes?
That's incredible.
What knowledge.
Is that why he sinned against creation?
- What is that?
Maybe the course of blood
through our body.
He's investigating the human body.
- Is that why he kills? Out of curiosity?
No, we have no disemboweled victims.
- That's sick. The man is a monster.
Monstrous only
because the Church forbids it.
They're creatures of God, also in death.
He had no right.
Their souls had already gone up, Konrad.
The dead have no use
for their mortal shell.
That's true, Konrad.
Do you somehow admire this butcher?
- Of course not.
But I have understanding,
understanding for scientific curiosity.
This here, this is progress.
This is a mark of the future.
This man has inestimably
valuable knowledge.
He can probably treat the ill better than
the clergy with their four-humour theory.
But he sinned. It's against God's will
to lay one's hands on His creatures.
Who says so?
- The Church.
These drawings provide answers
to important questions.
But we live in a time
in which we have to swallow everything.
In which you can't ask questions and
everything that happens is God's will.
But it is, isn't it?
- No.
God's will doesn't explain everything.
God's will doesn't explain
why the trees shed their leaves in fall.
If we'd only study birds
and their flight movement carefully...
we might just learn how to fly ourselves.
But just thinking that is already forbidden.
Because otherwise they'd dry out.
- What?
Yes.
The trees.
They shed their leaves
because otherwise they'd dry out.
I know it sounds absurd...
- Not at all.
It's the most sensible explanation.
We're not chasing a lunatic.
We're chasing a man of learning,
maybe a genius.
What are you doing in my home?
You only have one arm to contend with,
but three hearts.
He's downstairs.
Blood.
- There's more over there.
If there is no other exit,
he'll come this way again.
I'll stay here.
Excuse me.
Gunther, careful. He can be anywhere.
- Let's keep searching upstairs.
He took his own life.
Come, lsenhart.
There's nothing for us to do here.
Why did he hang himself?
I don't understand.
In Spira they'd have quartered him for
his crimes. So he'd have died anyway.
In any case, your sister's death
has been avenged.
I'll miss your company.
I feel the same way.
- I can accompany you part of the way.
What are we doing here?
- Just a little rest stop.
Hieronymus, Maria, they're here.
Sophia of Laurin,
Henning van der Braake.
What did you bring'?
- I'm glad to see you.
Grain, flints, salt, dried fish,
flour and dried fruit.
Come.
- Excellent.
Take care of the horses.
Come, take off your shirt.
You're very fond of him.
We grew up together.
The blacksmith raised him.
Is he an orphan?
His origins are obscure.
- He's an undead.
Undead?
- Yes.
What do you mean?
- Why don't you go and feed the hens?
Chitchat, nothing more.
- Who is his father?
Why does that interest you?
-lsenhart can't just read and write.
Most people aren't able to see past
their own life, into the world at large.
But he is.
I know.
And you?
We have to go.
His name was Michael von Bremen.
Him.
He also fought at Dorylaeum.
He lost his arm at Dorylaeum.
How do you know the killer had red hair?
- One of the victims defended herself.
We found these drawings...
on Michael von Bremen.
You're suspecting someone else.
Yes.
But he doesn't have red hair.
Have you ever met a living dead?
- No.
Then you may just be about to.
What's that in front of your eyes?
- A lens.
That's not a lance. It has no point.
- It's beryl, a rock crystal.
You can use it to magnify things.
My eyes are growing weak, you see.
Here, look for yourself.
Perhaps people will suspend glasses
like this in front of their eyes one day.
It wasn't Michael von Bremen.
Our man disguises himself.
He colours his hair before murdering.
Here.
-'The Non-Existence of God'?
Yes.
It was written by an extraordinary man.
'The real world can only be understood
by rejecting God as an explanation.
Anyone who answers a question
by invoking God's will just doesn't know.
The way to knowledge
is paved by curiosity and inquiry...
not by faith and dogma.
Inquiry means movement...
faith means stagnation,
for faith is content with ignorance.'
Sydal von Friedberg wrote that.
The non-existence of God.
He wrote it right here. Ever heard of him?
- No.
We were acquainted.
We both took part
in the crusade to Jerusalem.
After the Battle of Dorylaeum,
Michael von Bremen was badly injured...
and Sydal moved to Toledo, in Iberia.
He came back a changed man.
- Changed in what way?
He'd lost his faith. Sydal had become
an atheist, without hope of life eternal.
Then he started killing.
Virgins, whose heart he'd take.
He did just what Anna's murderer did.
- Yes.
Let go of me.
- Konrad.
Why? Walther, speak up.
- He didn't tell me.
You also encountered him once.
You owe your life to him.
I think I'd have known.
- No, you can't. You were stillborn.
You already saw the hereafter once.
What?
Shortly after your birth, a man breathed
life into you, and your heart beat again.
That's sorcery.
- Oh no, not necessarily.
Your mother had died. I brought you to
Laurin Castle. The blacksmith raised you.
But you owe your life to that man.
To Sydal von Friedberg?
- Yes.
Why did he do that?
- He was your father.
Isenhart.
And who was my mother?
Who was my mother?
Her...her name was Loretta.
I personally...
She was a virgin.
Sydal von Friedberg raped her,
and she died after giving birth to you.
Isenhart, it...
The son of a beast.
What is that?
I don't know. I...
I don't know what he wanted
to tell us with that.
I don't know.
To Toledo? Do you realize
it'll take months to get there?
It's where my father became a murderer.
- What do you hope to find there?
I have to know
if we're chasing my father's ghost.
What's the motive? Why the murders?
We couldn't ask Michael von Bremen.
And you think Toledo has the answers?
- He left Toledo as a changed man.
The answer lies there.
My father and Anna's death are related.
Isenhart.
What happened at Dorylaeum? You didn't
just come home, did you? I have to know.
Michael von Bremen had lost an arm in
the battle. He was more dead than alive.
He'd saved your father's life, so your
father felt responsible for von Bremen.
They'd captured a Turkish doctor.
He offered to help von Bremen,
in exchange for his freedom.
He also demanded...
the heart of one of the dead,
of a strong man.
You got into a quarrel with my father.
- Yes.
The next day Sydal and the doctor had
disappeared with one dead man's heart.
Did my father and this doctor
go to Toledo?
Yes.
- What was his name?
Ibn Al-Hariq.
Are there any more truths?
Anything you haven't told me?
- No.
Isenhart.
I got it from...
My father gave it to me.
It protects its bearer.
Since I have no biological son...
May it protect you on your way to Toledo.
Sophia, lsenhart and Konrad are here.
Come with me.
One day Anna brought me
a seashell from the market.
When you put it to your ear,
you heard the sea.
I don't really know, of course.
I've never been at the sea.
I hear rushing.
That's what the sea
is supposed to sound like.
Isenhart, if you had the choice,
where would you like to live?
Here or by the sea?
- In the future.
In the future.
Do you still think of Anna often?
Always when I see you.
But you're not Anna.
Don't forget me.
How could I forget so much grace?
- What grace? The grace of her behind?
How can you be so coarse?
Isenhart, you lost a father twice.
I'd ride to the end of the world to spend
an hour with mine, while yours still lives.
Go to Toledo.
Don't wait.
Go at once and don't give up.
Don't give up.
At least you find your peace.
We should go.
Take care of that foolish brother of mine.
- I promise I will.
And of yourself.
How did they wind up here?
- Children's Crusade.
They followed faith
rather than knowledge.
Do you see that?
- I'm so hungry I can't see.
Moors, Jews and Christians.
And they're not at each other's throats.
You're right. I don't like this city either.
I need some bread. I'm so hungry.
Bread, my friend. Please, have some.
Thank you. You're very generous.
Here, olives. Please try.
Try before you buy. Very good, really.
I'm thirsty.
- Thirsty? Orange, very good for thirst.
Thank you, friend.
My friend, you have to peel it first.
You don't eat the skin.
Ibn Al-Hariq, does he still live in Toledo?
Who?
- Not so fast.
Friends...
He often stayed at the fortress.
You can see it from that crossing.
Draw your bows.
Muslims.
Who are you
and what are you doing here?
We are Konrad of Laurin
and lsenhart...of Laurin.
We're here to talk to lbn AI-Hariq.
- Hand over your weapons.
We need our weapons,
to decapitate a couple of infidels.
Who told you where to find lbn Al-Hariq?
- Some merchant.
His name?
- We don't know.
Kill them.
- No.
I'm lsenhart, Sydal von Friedberg's son.
Let them go.
The undead child.
Gentlemen,
lbn Al-Hariq left us two years ago.
He was a great philosopher,
and an even greater doctor.
But I'm sure you didn't undertake
your long journey without a reason.
I'm here on account of my father,
Sydal von Friedberg.
After the crusade he came here,
together with your master.
When he returned to the Holy Empire,
he started murdering women.
What happened is terrible.
- What took place before my father left?
Their conversations
revolved around the human soul.
Around the question
whether it is immortal.
And where it's located.
- In the heart?
That was the conviction of both of them.
But there was no certainty, of course.
I remember very well
that it almost made them ill.
They believed that what constitutes us...
the I, that this I is located in the soul,
or even is the soul...
chained to a mortal shell.
That's how your father called it.
Did Al-Hariq and my father think
you could see the soul?
No, they thought...
it was invisible,
at least to the human eye.
Did they also talk about purity?
- Yes.
The purer the soul, the more valuable.
That's what they said.
Why did my father leave?
They got into an argument, unfortunately.
Your father had crossed a limit.
You understand?
He was possessed.
- My father wanted to investigate the soul.
He wanted to watch a soul escape.
Yes.
What is this here?
- An exchange.
Between the East and the West.
A bazar of knowledge.
Scholars no longer believe
the soul is located in the heart.
But instead?
- In the brain, behind the eyes.
Are there doctors here as well?
- Those without hope come here.
Doctors try out new methods
and ointments on them.
This room is yours
for as long as you wish to stay.
How do you call that knot?
That's a cross knot.
It comes from seafaring.
Your name is lsenhart, right?
That's correct.
And you?
- I overheard your talk with Khamud.
Did you know my father?
- Oh yes.
Your father is alive.
My father is alive?
I was told my father was dead.
- By Walther von Ascisberg, right?
Why would Walther von Ascisberg...
- Lie?
Walther didn't kill Sydal that day,
but he captured him.
He let him live under three conditions.
- What conditions?
That he'd never set foot
on German soil again...
that he'd stop murdering...
and that he'd never reveal himself
to his son as his father.
Isenhart, you won't believe it...
- I've just...
Wilbrand von Maulbronn.
What is he doing here?
Inside these walls
no one but me carries a weapon.
So if you need to settle anything,
settle it outside the gates.
Wilbrand von Maulbronn...
- Don't let him provoke you.
I'm surprised to see you back alive,
young Laurin.
You can remedy that tomorrow at dawn
outside the gate.
You and me, if you're man enough.
What do you want, bastard?
I've never seen a dead man on two feet.
Interesting place. A lot of soul searching.
Finally, lsenhart. Now Wilbrand von
Maulbronn can't hide behind his lord.
What's he doing here anyway?
Here in Toledo, at the Puente?
I have no idea.
- It can't be a coincidence.
First my father was here, now Wilbrand.
What brings the archbishop here?
We always run into him
in places of death.
Maybe I'll let him live long enough
for you to ask him.
He won't wait that long, Konrad.
He won't wait that long.
What's the matter?
Konrad of Laurin.
It's my father's blade you feel.
You get the horses, I get the weapons.
- No, you get the horses.
What was Wilbrand doing in Toledo?
- You killed him before we could ask.
Your father lives. Maybe he committed
the murders. Or somebody copied him.
The only one we can ask is Walther.
Gerhard.
Walther von Ascisberg is dead.
- What?
Since when?
- A month ago.
He had business in Spira. He must
have been attacked on his way back.
He was found dead by the roadside.
- And the murderer?
Speak.
- What did he go to Spira for anyway?
I don't know.
A young monk had been murdered.
My lord wanted to inspect the corpse.
His heart had been torn out.
- How do you know'?
A monk doesn't fit
what you call a pattern.
Ever since celibacy was introduced,
a monk is also immaculate and pure.
This is all yours now, lsenhart.
Walther von Ascisberg
appointed you as his sole heir.
Where did you bury your lord?
You needed it more.
Who would have had a reason?
The murderer disguises himself.
He pretends to have red hair, while in
fact it's brown. That rules out Wilbrand.
You think the murderer is still out there?
Sophia, someone's coming.
-lsenhart and Konrad.
What happened to you?
Let me take care of you. Come.
Where's Father Hieronymus?
- He's very ill. You can't see him now.
Come, you need to be washed as well.
There.
Reimar von Vogt has been courting me
for some weeks now.
He couldn't have made a better choice.
I'm going to feed the hens.
What did you say to her?
I told her I wish her all the best
with her future husband.
You idiot. You're blind and deaf.
She wants you.
I know. I know.
What's the matter?
I'm not the right man for her.
Sophia deserves better.
Isenhart, sometimes you really are dumb.
I often feel like an island,
unconnected to the mainland.
Without a bridge or ferryman
to get me across. She deserves better.
Father, we're back.
-lsenhart.
How are you?
Father, a question. You went out to sea.
- True.
But that was long ago.
I was still a young madcap.
- Do you know the cross knot?
Yes.
- Can you tie one for me?
Isenhart. ..
- Try it.
Try doing it with one hand.
Do it for me, Father.
I can't. The cross knot...
- It's okay.
Is too elaborate.
Why do I have to do that?
Because Michael von Bremen
only had one arm.
So someone must have hanged him.
Is that what you're saying?
We were in Tarup with the four of us.
Henning stayed with Konrad and me.
Only Gunther von Martensen
could have killed him.
The question is: what does Henning
know about his master's murders?
Hail.
The doctor and his aide left months ago.
Gunther von Martensen was very ill.
They wanted to go to Maulbronn.
- Maulbronn.
The dead monk
von Ascisberg wanted to examine...
had two stab wounds in his neck, right?
- Only one. How do you know'?
There's a connection
with another murder.
Henning van der Braake.
Isenhart was here, right?
- Yes.
Isenhart, you're alive.
I'm glad to see you.
What about Konrad?
I hope he's fine as well.
Sure, but after our long absence
he didn't feel like riding out again.
You're right, it's been a long time.
Come.
I heard that Gunther is ill
How is he doing?
The Grim Reaper will come for him.
But on his way to the Lord
he wants to be of use for an experiment.
Come. Come.
Step aside.
We did all this while you were gone.
Gunther.
Look who's here.
Isenhart.
I'm so happy...
to see you.
I don't have any pain any more.
Don't be sad. I'm...
I'm curious...
like a little child.
What are those cots?
Keep an eye on him.
They are all terminally ill.
They come here to die.
I take them in
and look after them till the end.
Those cots suspended above water.
Those ropes. I've seen all that before.
In a drawing by a man who'd lost his faith
and searched for the location of the soul.
Sydar von Friedberg?
- Yes.
You knew Sydar von Friedberg?
No, Gunther knew him.
They met in a place in Iberia.
- Toledo. Konrad and I were there
Yes, you were there.
At the bazar of knowledge.
Tell me, is it really as wonderful
as Gunther always tells me?
Scholars striving for knowledge,
unfettered by origins or religion?
Exchanging ideas?
It was impressive.
And is it true that the only barriers there
are those of the mind, not of the Church?
Yes, religion hardly plays a role.
What progress.
What does Gunther know
about Sydal von Friedberg?
A whole lot.
He told me, for example...
that Sydal didn't tolerate it...
when they tried to curtail his thoughts.
He murdered women.
- The time has come. He's dying.
Your soul has set out on its journey.
And is released.
On the way to a better world,
if there is one.
Did you see the rope?
- I did.
Did you see it go up?
At the moment of death.
- After he died, Gunther became lighter.
The soul.
How many grams?
45.
- Always?
Always.
- And with the dogs?
Not one gram.
Have you been able to see one?
We tried with water, but no air bubbles
issued from the mouth of the dying.
Maybe...
Maybe it doesn't leave
through the mouth.
Did you try it with smoke?
- Also without success.
You have to get Gunther ready.
Of course.
Isenhart.
We saw that at Michael von Bremen's.
The same handwriting?
- Yes.
Look, that's Michael von Bremen's.
It's identical.
Gunther or Henning
One of them left it in Tarup,
so that we'd find it.
And you thought he was a genius.
All those visitors.
You were leaving already?
What do you know
about the murder of Anna of Laurin?
Let go of her.
Put that dagger away.
- Let go of her.
Put it away or I'll ruin her beauty.
- Don't talk so much, Simon.
Stop.
May I?
Murderer.
And now you.
- No.
He doesn't even know who he is.
Murderer.
My sword, give me my sword.
Detain them.
Where are we?
- In Maulbronn Abbey. Trapped.
On your knees.
Konrad.
- That's impossible.
I'm afraid not.
Did you still want
to measure yourself against me?
If your courage has doubled
and you feel man enough by now...
to fight a blind man, anytime.
You are under my jurisdiction.
Tomorrow Cardinal Ernst of Regensburg
will come to me...
to be present at your trial.
- And what are the charges?
That we defended my father's castle
against you?
That you tried to kill me in Toledo.
Then you might as well
sentence us right away.
Not so hot-tempered, Konrad of Laurin.
Not so hot-tempered.
Tomorrow the Cardinal of Regensburg
will come to Maulbronn.
He'll be present at the trial...
where you'll be sentenced to death.
- Where is Sophia of Laurin?
In my rooms.
There she's able to assist me.
Here you can rot away.
Isenhart?
- I'm over here.
Maybe it's our destiny
that it ends like this.
What are you doing? Digging?
- There's water under this flagstone.
The flagstones are too heavy.
You can't lift them by yourself.
'Give me a fixed point in space
and I'll move the world.'
Archimedes and the lever rule.
Walther taught us, remember?
No.
How many have you opened?
Many.
Alive?
- Of course not.
I don't enjoy inflicting suffering.
You and I are of one kind.
We're both ahead of our time.
Sydal von Friedberg made a start,
back in Toledo.
I've continued his work. First Gunther
assisted me, now von Hainfeld does.
But what could we accomplish together?
- Gunther was your student.
I know the theory of the four humours is
false and can do harm, even kill people.
Don't you want to share
that knowledge with me?
We can expand it.
There's so much more to discover.
What's so funny?
Your knowledge is an incredible treasure.
Your light would outshine my father's
many times over.
But it won't happen, because you can't
share your knowledge. You'd be burnt.
Tomorrow I'll breathe in your soul,
lsenhart, so you will be inside me.
What does Wilbrand von Maulbronn
have to do with all this?
An alliance of convenience. I wanted to
study the soul, he wanted to possess it.
And he got what he wanted.
- What does that mean?
He breathed it in. 45 grams.
Did you forget already?
I didn't give him this one.
Her shell was unusually beautiful.
Anna of Laurin.
Murderer.
Wilbrand von Maulbronn picked her out.
He wanted her soul.
He gave the stone to a merchant.
Anna would never have been harmed if
I'd known it would cause you such grief.
If I ruled over life and death,
I would give her back to you.
Who killed her?
Who is there?
Murderer.
To study the soul, people have to die.
What? So many lives destroyed
for the sake of your curiosity?
A few destroyed lives
for many fulfilled ones.
The death of a few
can prevent the death of many others.
Only when they let us study
typhus and smallpox...
and no longer keep us from studying
God's creation more closely...
only then will we be able to help alleviate
suffering and perhaps even defy death.
If we didn't sacrifice a few, it'd be as if
we killed thousands by not helping them.
So who of us is more humane,
more just?
Why did Wilbrand
want to breathe in the souls?
Don't you understand? The soul's
essence. That's what it's all about.
Immortality?
- An ancient dream of mankind.
Life unlimited.
What would a genius like Aristotle be
able to achieve in two or three lifetimes?
Only the ideas we leave behind
are immortal, and the soul itself.
Is that right?
So how old is Wilbrand von Maulbronn?
I don't know.
-76.
He's 76 and moves like man
in his mid-thirties.
What would that be? Chance?
- Exactly that.
You also think Sydal von Friedberg
showed up at your birth by chance?
He was on the run
from Walther von Ascisberg.
He knew his time was running out and
Walther would kill him sooner or later.
He wanted to leave something behind,
so that in a certain way he'd live on.
Something of the souls he breathed in
is alive in you, lsenhart.
And in me.
Sydal fathered two children. Two boys.
He kissed both of them upon their birth.
Both grew up with adoptive fathers.
One with a blacksmith..
The other with a doctor.
We're not just soul mates, lsenhart.
Ernst of Regensburg
has occupied Maulbronn Abbey.
Murdered for their souls?
Is that what you want to tell me?
- Yes.
Those are serious allegations.
Wilbrand, my friend,
it's very questionable...
that you didn't know what Henning van
der Braake contrived in your dungeons.
I swear it's true.
- That does you honour.
Still, I can't form a clearjudgment.
Or you must want a judgment of God.
If Wilbrand von Maulbronn
and Henning van der Braake win...
the accusations against you
will be deemed lies.
But if lsenhart
and Konrad of Laurin win...
Henning van der Braake
will be convicted of heresy...
and you and Wilbrand von Maulbronn
will suffer God's punishment.
And I'll personally assume responsibility
for the estates and lands of Maulbronn.
I call for a judgment of God.
Then let the judgment of God decide.
Tell me where they are...
and I'll vanquish them.
Not today, my friend.
Not today.
Let your rage guide my hand.
You're not immortal.
No. lsenhart, don't.
No, let go of me.
I don't want to kill you.
What for?
We're half-brothers.
We have the same father.
We both carry him inside us, lsenhart.
We both stand outside our own time.
That's an illusion. We're stuck in
this time, whether we like it or not.
No.
No, stay here.
Stay here.
Will you follow the way of your father?
I don't have to.
I'm home.
Translation: D. F. Frank
The Service Station