So I just start talking?
Pretty much.
Is there a specific
topic or...
You're the one that wanted to
hijack my video today.
Fair point.
Hello everyone.
As you might surmise from
Lizzie's last videos,
she and I have
begun... a relationship.
And it's been six days now...
- It's been a week.
No, it's been six days.
I have it in my calendar.
It's been a week!
We kissed on my birthday,
one week ago.
Kissing you marks the inception
of our relationship.
Yes, but that was
in the evening.
It wasn't a full day.
Partial days count!
We're rounding up,
so it's been a week.
Fine.
It has been a week,
now.
And it has been
without a doubt...
the best week of my life.
My name is William Darcy and...
Lizzie Bennet is amazing.
You know I'm just
teasing you, right?
About the week
versus six days.
I know.
I've been learning.
Slowly.
Eat enough dinners
in the Bennet household
and you learn plenty about
being teased.
That just means
my dad likes you!
He did invite you
to see his trains.
Still, had I known about the
casual nature of social interaction
in the Bennet family,
I might have better understood
what I was doing wrong.
You didn't do
anything wrong.
I believe you typify
our first meeting as...
the most awkward dance ever.
Oh, yeah!
That was really bad!
Not my finest hour.
But you didn't wanna
to like me then.
You wanted to take Bing
and get the hell out of dodge.
My mind changed soon enough.
When?
When did you change
your mind about me?
I haven't a clue!
I honestly don't remember when.
I don't think there was
one specific moment.
I was in the middle of it
before I knew that I had begun.
What about you?
When did you discover
your feelings had changed?
Oh... I think...
The moment I saw the offices
at Pemberley Digital.
You should know,
those napping pods?
Women swoon!
No, like you...
it happened...
gradually.
Until...
one day...
things were just...
We should probably
change that topic.
Good plan!
Well...
I've been thinking
about the future.
There's a mood changer.
As wonderful
as this week has been,
I can only telecommute
for so long before
my investors start
to think I'm...
neglecting my responsibilities
for my own personal indulgences.
Which technically, you are.
Point being...
I need to get back soon.
And I know you need
to finish up
your degree, which,
according to my calendar,
will be in about
the next six weeks time.
Which terrifies me
in no way whatsoever.
Well, I was thinking
it might terrify you less
if you had a job lined up.
Say at... Pemberley Digital.
Oh. Wow!
I would set up an
entire department around you,
you could have access
to state-of-the-art equipment.
Not to mention you'd be
in San Francisco with me.
What do you say?
No.
Is this one of those times when
you're teasing me? I cannot tell.
I don't wanna work
at Pemberley Digital,
as amazing as it is.
I want to be with you.
But I don't want to be
the girl who dates the boss.
Does that make sense?
Yes.
Well, what do you think
you will do when you graduate?
Yeah...
funny thing.
When you have a video diary
that gets millions of views,
it attracts the attention
of several people
who run digital media companies.
So you wanna work
for my competitors?
Actually,
I was thinking of
becoming one of
your competitors.
Since I wrote
about the diaries
as a start-up for
my final independent study,
I have the business plan
in place.
And since I mentioned
that project on the Internet,
I have been getting messages
from potential investors.
I might know
some investors too.
I was also thinking that...
If I'm going to be starting
my own company, that...
San Francisco might be
a great place to do it.
Optimal, even.
I think I'm warming up
to this vision of the future.
Be aware that my vision
of the future includes
lots of trips home
and visits from Lydia.
I'm really enjoying getting
to know my little sister better.
Of course.
I should apologize for anything
I ever said about her.
You don't think
she's energetic?
No, she is. But...
then again, so is Gigi.
Just took a while for me
to see the similarities.
To see anything
other than my first impression.
So...
sound like a good future?
I think it will do nicely.
But right now, we need to worry
about the present.
I made a reservation for
our one week anniversary.
I thought you said
it was six days.
My aunt Catherine
is in town.
I thought it might be nice
to get dinner with her.
I think she and your mother
would get along well.
Very funny!
But I can tell
when you're teasing.
You're... You're teasing. Right?
- Right?
- We have to go!