Episode 23
Hand over Jeong Gi Joon.
Then that would be the base
of trust you yourself create, no?
And as the head of the
political faction called Milbon,
inside the royal court,
you could just insist on
a genuine parliament, no?
You take the Haerye
and block the letters
and I, afterward
I'll spearhead Milbon and
realize Teacher Sambong's will.
Is it power you want?
If my desire
to create the good nation
of my thinking and of my
creed is greed for power,
then greed for power it is.
My identity as Milbon has been made known
to the King already, hence I can longer achieve
fame and prestige as a Confucian scholar.
However, I have no intention to
surrender as the King desires either.
What do you want?
Hand over the names of
all Milbon members to me.
And declare me as the new Bonwon
and hand over the Milbon pledge to me.
Then you will give me Haerye?
Though the King has yet to appoint the date,
he has already declared he will promulgate the letters.
He would not promulgate
without the Haerye.
Hence, the Haerye is the best
weapon to block the promulgation.
I will make it so that you can
have the Haerye at once, Bonwon.
In everything, do as you will.
Except, not as Milbon's Bonwon,
but personally, as Jeong Gi Joon.
When do you want to hear my reply?
There isn't time.
I want the answer by
the day after tomorrow.
I will be at the inn in Mapo.
Contact me.
I will wait.
Why did you select Lee Shin Jeok between
Lee Shin Jeok and Shim Jong Soo?
Yes.
Minister Lee Shin Jeok is a veteran, so he doesn't
hold much influence over the young members.
Wouldn't Shim Jong Soo be
better suited to move Milbon?
That's possible.
However, Shim Jong Soo is lacking
in trickery, compared to Lee Shin Jeok.
What trickery?
Political influence, I mean.
All the subjects in the current royal court,
though they may each have
their fault, none are stupid.
They are all people to be feared.
Among them, to be able
to rise to the top three,
means he stands atop
the vertex among the fierce.
Though Lee Shin Jeok
is avaricious as a scholar,
in the ability to draw people to his side,
he is even greater than Minister Hwang Hee.
He is someone who won't hesitate to use witchcraft
if he deems the circumstance ill. So of course.
Why would you want to
appoint someone like him?
If I am to remove this and that among all,
would Minister Hwang Hee still be alive?
Since in the end, the seat of the
King isn't to remove those people,
it is to control them so that their
skills are used to better the citizenry.
And we are now at a time when Lee Shin
Jeok's evil sleight of hand is most needed.
Even if it is by mobilizing his tricks, so that
Jeong Gi Joon can be handed over to us,
Lee Shin Jeok must find the way to do so.
At times, Your Majesty is truly...
Do you mean I am more cunning than my father?
Can't be... the royal guard commander?
Yes, Your Majesty.
That's what I was about to say.
My heart lives in hell.
Would I be Bodhisattva?
There are times when the process is important
and there are times when the result is important.
In creating the letters, the process
of making them is important.
But in their promulgation,
the result is important.
We must win.
So that we can promulgate.
A win is needed so that the work can start.
We must win, so that this
work for the citizens can start.
Lee Shin Jeok, you mustn't disappoint me.
No matter what.
Hand over Jeong Gi Joon.
Then that would be the base
of trust you yourself create, no?
The one who betrayed Milbon is you, Bonwon.
My allegiance wasn't to
power or to Milbon or you.
It was solely to the great
cause of a genuine parliament.
Subtitles brought to you by the Deep Rooted Friends @ viki.com
I am a Confucian scholar of Joseon,
the beginning of Joseon and the root of Joseon.
This is my path.
It's him!
That guy!
I heard two warriors and maidens
crossed by boat yesterday during the day.
Oh, I guess you're talking about them.
Yes, those people from yesterday.
They went to Daeseong Mountain.
Daeseong Mountain.
Yup, Daeseong Mountain.
It's a placed called Rabbit Rock.
Aigo...
The boat couldn't sail
smoothly so it was rough.
Take us there too.
Again?
How much will do?
We'll pay you all the way.
Well then, sure.
Get on.
You go and report to Royal Guard Commander
at once, and wait at the palace.
We'll contact you as soon
as we grasp the location.
Okay... be careful.
Let's go.
Hey, why are you getting on?
I need to take revenge too.
The scum who killed my sibling!
I'll do it.
I'm the reincarnation of revenge.
So you hurry and go home and
feed your sibling a memorial meal.
He must be quite hungry (from the other world).
But still...
A punk like you getting involved is
just a matter of time before you die.
Here, we're departing.
Hurry and go!
Do you see anything?
Nothing except the warriors.
Same on this side.
We must find a way to get out.
No matter how, we must complete our mission.
What?
Daeseong Mountain?
Yes, Rabbit Rock.
Chae Yoon and Cho Tak
are already on their way there.
Is this accurate information?
Yes, it's accurate!
Hence, please prepare so that the royal guard troop
can move at once as soon as the contact comes.
I got it.
You two take the first team of Palace Guard and prepare
so that Chae Yoon's message can come without fail.
Yes.
Their location is finally identified?
Once their exact location is verified,
he will send a message to us.
Chae Yoon.
You must find So Yi.
You must.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I will return for sure.
Since you need to leave tomorrow,
hurry and see to the preparation.
You should bow when
you return. What is this?
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty said,
the promise to Kang Chae Yoon...
Yes, after this work is done, leave
with that punk who has no manners.
Though I can't pull out a fortune for you,
I'll put together enough gold for a house.
I just hope that punk
won't make you go hungry.
Your Majesty.
So Yi.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Though it's true I wish
for you to be at my side,
it seems I will get to
breathe at last once you leave.
Isn't that true for you as well?
Day by day,
you must live in joy.
Together with Kang Chae Yoon.
Promise me.
Your Majesty.
I will surely keep my promise to you.
There must be a way.
There has to be. Surely.
What?
Why did you bring the kid here?
She was in danger because of me.
There was... someone chasing us.
How much danger
could the kid be in!?
To bring the kid here
under the situation?
Just leave it be.
Instead of Gaepayi
going out to see her,
it is better that Yeon Doo is here.
You did well to bring her here.
As everyone here knows,
I've conveyed all of
my intentions last time.
I will acknolwedge Milbon as
a political party and accept them.
I said, "come to the court
before the day of promulgation."
However, no one has yet come.
Hence, I will now make
my final proposition.
Promulgation of the letters...
on the sanghan (first ten days) of the 9th month.
Amidst the gaze of ten
thousand citizens, I will carry it out.
Your Majesty!
The Ministry of Personnel is to install Eonmun
(Hangul book) and Jeongeum (Hangul typeset) Bureau.
And the Ministry of Rites is to
adopt the letters into the civil exams.
Make preparations to carry it out.
Your Majesty, it mustn't!
Yes, it can't!
It cannot be!
But why is everyone like this?
I clearly said it was
a proposition, didn't I?
What kind of a nation is Joseon?
Is it a nation where a monarch's pressing of
independant threats are automatically carried out?
Joseon undoubtedly has
a system of State Council.
Hence what I have proposed just needs
to be determined by the State Council.
Just as I mentioned, the Ministry of Personnel
and the Ministry of Rites prepare to carry it out,
and submit their plans to the State Council, and the
three high councilors can discuss matters thoroughly,
and then determine a yes or no.
And I will make the decree
in accordance with their decision,
Hence, the most important event
of the promulgation of the letters,
rests on the approval
of the three state councilors.
Your Majesty!
That is still not permissible!
If you insist on the promulgation of letters...
Look here!
Didn't His Majesty just order the three state
councilors to make the decision after discussing it?
Hence, you just need to wait for the decision
by the State Council, Deputy Chief Scholar.
Is that your answer to last night?
I haven't made a decision yet.
It just means I will put effort in it.
Your Majesty.
Do you think we will receive the approval
from the three state councilors?
I'm not sure.
Now we've done our best,
so we await God's disposition, no?
You guys work toward persuading
just one more if possible.
Yes.
Speeding up the Dong-guk-jeong-woon
[instructions of phonological structure of Chinese characters]
will be an asset in persuading the aristocrats.
Yes.
We will work with all our heart.
Alright.
Your Majesty,
I've completed the preface.
The reason for the creation of the letters,
and the excellent qualities to these letters,
I've included the principle
of all things in universe.
Alright.
Has Your Majesty completed the foreword?
I haven't.
Our nation's speech is different from that of
China, so the language does not match the writing,
For this reason,
even if the ignorant citizenry
has the will to communicate, in the end,
many cannot express their intention.
Hence, I, for this...
But this is where I'm stuck.
How is it that I can't seize it?
Such a...
Then, Your Majesty...
Postpone the promulgation,
even just for a few days.
Are you saying to postpone just
because I didn't quite write the foreward?
As you already know, we haven't got the
Jejahae (explanation of the design of the letters).
We cannot miss the promulgation no matter what.
With the dispersal already failed as is,
we must secure the knot when it's hard.
However, Your Majesty,
if we only recite the preface but not the explanation,
how is that really a promulgation of the letters?
Shall I look through the materials and see if I
can make a brief Jejahae (explanation of design)?
Don't do it.
Since without So Yi, we can't make a perfect
Jejahae before the promulgation anyway.
Isn't she the only person who knows the entire
process from the start of the creation of the letters?
It is not that I don't know Your Majesty's
heart of waiting for So Yi...
If perchance, So Yi won't
arrive by the promulgation...
Tsk, tsk, So Yi...
Didn't I tell you to do not do it?
Your Majesty.
How come...?
After you come back from completing
the circulation mission, then write it.
But, Your Majesty,
to prepare for the perchance...
Where the first sound "geu" began,
and where the middle
sound "yeo" began,
you are the only one
who knows them all.
Though I explained each step
along the process to you,
I don't remember.
No.
I had no reason to remember.
And I don't have it written down anywhere,
for fear it may leak out somewhere.
Hence, you are the only one who knows
the explanation to the designs of our letters.
Hence, Your Majesty,
I will write it now before I leave.
I don't want you to.
I won't take it from you.
If by chance, I...
before promulgation...
Come back.
As for me, I will do what I
have to do inside the palace.
As for you, you also
complete your work,
and without fail,
come back safely.
The promulgation of the letters,
you have to see it with your own eyes.
Do you understand?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I'l definitely come back.
So Yi will come.
Your Majesty.
We...
should do our work.
And you must persuade
Choi Man Li to the end.
Yes.
What do you think,
First State Councilor?
His Majesty said he would receive the
sanction by the three state councilors.
So shouldn't we discuss it?
We have to.
However, both His Majesty's words,
as well as the words of the subjects,
I believe they all make sense.
Then...
How are we to do decide?
I believe it is best we choose
the one with the stronger will.
What about you,
Left State Councilor?
I don't know.
My seat as State Council isn't a seat where
my personal opinion matters most, right?
To understand the intention of all
ministers and officials before deciding,
is the seat of the Left State Councilor, no?
However, I wonder what
Right State Councilor thinks.
Right State Councilor would
be the same, I believe.
He would study the sentiment
of the court vassals.
But...
Right State Councilor personally,
would not object, I daresay.
Look here, Man Li!
[ resignation letter ]
Have a drink with me today.
Don't try to dissuade me.
Even if I am to live with the
grudge of having to resign,
I'll be against it till the end.
Even if the promulgation of the letters is to become
that which is colossal and inevitable in history,
someone like me needs to object.
That is what makes Joseon
a nation of debateand verification.
Isn't that a testament of it?
Do you...really have to do this?
Except for this,
I will not incite the scholar officials,
nor regulate them.
It's nearly time for the promulgation.
What if you confess
yourself to His Majesty now?
You just need to follow me.
Yes.
Is there anyone outside?
Yes, Sir.
Send a message to Gyun Jeok Hee.
Find out where Vice-Deputy Chief-Scholar
Shim Jeong Soo is lodged.
Yes.
What? He will do as the
three state councilors decide?
Yes.
And in addition, the promulgation date has been
set as the sanghan (first ten days) of the 9th month.
So we only have a few days left.
He's bent on pushing it forward.
How will Lee Shin Jeok act?
Has he already gone
to His Majesty's side?
No one has come forward as being
Milbon inside the palace as of yet?
Yes, no one has come forward yet.
That's a relief.
No Milbon has fallen for
His Majesty's sweet-talk.
Of course his words all sound right.
Almost ideal.
Acknowledge Milbon as a
political faction and embrace it?
However, His Majesty won't live forever.
Also, when and how His
Majesty might change his mind
we can't predict.
And after His Majesty passes away,
whether the next and the next king after
that will acknowledge us as a political faction,
no one knows.
Hence,
Milbon must remain a secret society.
So that regardless of what kind of a king is to
ascend, our existence won't be threatened by him.
Sir!
What's the matter?
You are truly an untrustworthy person!
No message from Kang Chae Yoon still?
Yes.
Still no news.
We just keep going in circles.
This mountain... something's strange.
The temple where those
scums were at last time,
it was as if though they knew I was coming.
They suddenly disappeared.
That's what I sensed.
How did they know I was coming?
Why are you thinking
about some other matter?
That's there, but this
is Daeseong Mountain.
I'm saying that because I get the same weird
sense here in this mountain just like that time there.
What's weird, you mean?
I don't know.
We circled the mountain many times.
But we didn't see even one animal.
Isn't that weird?
Now that you mention it, I didn't see any.
But how can a mountain, no animals...
not one is sighted?
I found out later, too, that
the King was feeling me out.
That Minister Hwang Hee
didn't put in a resignation letter...
I found out later and I was shocked too.
This is the King's discord-producing measure.
But how could you just act upon things
without even confirming with me first?
Yet I didn't see you as that...
You disappoint me so much!
So you sent Gyun Jeok Hee?
Right!
I did!
Did you expect me to stay still?
A misunderstanding starts from something petty.
But once it starts to go
awry, it can't be controlled.
But you know that too!
This is why whether it's the matter to
put a genuine parliament into realization,
or to preserve Milbon,
how am I to work with you?
The situation gets more dire by the day now that
the King has declared a date for the promulgation!
Think carefully.
Bonwon must be devising
his last strategy as well.
Why this damned shit!
It's all gone bad now.
All wrong!
Our plan to preserve Milbon apart
from Bonwon has all gone awry now!
Not yet.
Why do you mean?
Then you have some brilliant move?
I found out where the Haerye is.
And I asked him to name
me as the next Bonwon.
What?
You?
So in the end,
you achieved it?
Finally...
Hence,
what was Bonwon's reply?
He said he would give me
his answer by dawn tomorrow.
We agreed to meet near the mountain.
He will give you the answer?
Tomorrow at dawn?
So tomorrow at dawn.
I mustn't miss Shim Jong Soo's movements.
The King said he will promulgate
on the sanghan date of the 9th month.
So he is bent on pressing it forward.
But he said he would receive the approval of
the three state councilors of the State Council.
And he will follow their decision.
The approval of the
three state councilors?
Yes.
He told the three state councilors
to determine yes or no, I'm told.
But that is, you see...
Wouldn't that mean the King and the three
state councilors already have a pledge?
Hence, Minister Lee Shin Jeok has already...
That must be the case.
That punk must have,
for his own sake.
Therefore, the three state councilors would
surely sanction the promulgation of the letters.
And if that's the case,
the Milbon members will falter.
Some might even turn themselves in.
In the end, the King would be successful in
his measure to cause discord inside Milbon,
and he would promulgate
the letters as well.
However, Lee Do does
not have the Haerye.
What?
The King doesn't have the Haerye?
Shim Jong Soo said he
would give me the Haerye.
What would that signify?
The Haerye is not inside the palace.
Then?
We get a hold of the Haerye first and we block
the circulation of the letters from the first cause.
What do you mean first cause?
I will kill all who know
the letters afterwards.
Truly...
You truly intend to do that?
Hasn't Lee Do already created the
match called promulgation ceremony?
Did you say the promulgation
ceremony was tomorrow?
By tomorrow, have them
have the poison ready.
By poison, you mean...
In the arrows, as well as
the swords and the spears.
They all need poison.
We must kill everyone with the attack.
And the Haerye must be
destroyed no matter what.
Even if everyone's killed,
if the Haerye remains,
the letters will revive.
Those who know the letters,
as well as the seeds of the letters...
All must be destroyed.
And the aftermath?
What about Milbon after that?
Bonwon.
What do you think
about Shim Jong Soo?
I don't think it's possible.
There are too many warriors.
Even if we flee, we'll
be caught again at once.
Yeon Doo?
It's Yeon Doo!
From the Banchon tavern?
What is she doing here?
She's close with Gaepayi.
Gaepayi must have brought her here.
Good thing.
Let's ask her to rescue us.
Yeon Doo!
Why this chit... is she crazy?
Broadcast to the whole
neighborhood, why don't you!
Then what?
We need to get her to come.
Give me your handkerchief.
Alright.
Yeon Doo...
Please look at this direction.
She saw!
Yeon Doo saw!
Come out.
Subtitles brought to you by the Deep Rooted Friends @ viki.com
Why?
Why do you help the King?
Did you call for me because
you were curious about that?
Isn't he the enemy who killed your father?
So much so that you couldn't even sleep.
You suffered such a gruesome plight, didn't you?
Like I did.
And in addition,
like me, you blamed yourself.
For that one childish act during youth,
from which the event originated,
there is self-blame you can't escape.
That self-guilt.
Isn't it so?
It's true.
It's possible that we suffered the same plight.
In suffering that, that victim mentality and self-guilt,
are natural.
But?
Those mentalities impoverish a person incessantly.
I am more aware of that than anyone else.
You and I, through those long years,
we must have been trying to overcome that.
Except that, our methods have differed.
Hence, it was the letters for you?
Victim mentality.
Though I have lived unaware of such an existence...
no, I think it did exist.
However, it is not due to me having
suffered such a gruesome plight.
That has to be because of Lee Do.
In order to rebuild an organization
that had pretty much collapsed,
I have lived through 20 years working as a butcher.
During that time, Lee Do became the
sage king the world heaped praised upon.
That unbearable feeling,
can you understand it?
But you see...
I've overcome everything now. How?
Precisely due to those
brilliant letters Lee Do created.
I realized, as if I were
struck by a divine revelation,
that to block those letters that
are more brilliant than any others,
was to be the heaven's mandate to me.
Regardless of how brilliant a King he may be.
No! Even if it's not the King, but whatever it may be!
It cannot test the thousand-year-old history.
I hear Lee Do is going to
promulgate during sanghan.
On that day, I will assuredly block it.
And with that, the long talk
between Lee Do and me...
will end.
Subtitles brought to you by The Deep Rooted Friends Team @ viki.com
[ mom ]
Why are you looking so shocked?
By chance, do you know this court maiden?
No.
I don't know her.
How are we going
to find them like this?
How many hours has it been?
Instead of this,
let's go and get the troops spread everywhere.
No. What if Dahm and
the court maidens are
put into danger, what will you do?
It's just that no matter how hard
we look, not even a rat shows up.
A rat.
Yes, a rat!
What is it now?
If someone, on purpose,
pulled out all the animals on this mountain,
what would be the reason?
In case,
something touches it?
What?!
What?
What are you saying?
You think something's going to happen on the day
of the promulgation ceremony? What do you mean?
I don't know.
But, there is definitely something.
We must get out somehow and alert them.
Hey, but there's nothing.
My back's killing me.
I almost peed.
Stop!
It was indeed this.
It's danger warning toll.
If we follow this, there will be a bell.
If this string is touched,
that bell will toll.
And that is the warning
that an intruder is here.
But it ends here, so what now?
We need to call them out.
What?
What the heck are you doing?
Now, if we follow this,
we'll find the place where Dahm is.
Miss So Yi.
Yeon Doo.
Miss, why are you captured here?
Can you help us to get out?
This... I can't do it.
We must get out now!
Help us please.
No.
I'm sorry.
One moment.
Then, we won't ask you to get us out.
Can you listen to a different favor?
What?
Really?
What are you doing there?
Yeon Doo.
Yes?
Ahjussi...
is thankful.
And sorry.
Okay?
Why?
Nothing.
No.
Yeon Doo, you see.
Kill her.
Painlessly.
Hey.
Gaepayi is looking for you.
Really? Where?
Follow me.
Gaepayi... where is he?
That's strange.
He said he would come here.
Bonwon has sent message.
He says to meet at
Naksan at 5 kyeong 5 (5 am).
Finally.
You're coming to answer?
Bonwon?
Yeon Doo, are you alright?
Ahjussi!
It's alright.
Yeon Doo... do you think
she got there safely?
We need her to do
the favor we asked her.
What about Miss So Yi?
Here.
This is where Miss So Yi was jailed.
But other than Miss So Yi,
there were other court misses.
Really?
How many?
Counting Miss So Yi, three!
You take Yeon Doo down at once.
And contact Sir Royal Guard Commander.
Alright.
Got it.
Be careful.
Let's go.
Sir!
They found the location in the mountain.
Where is it?
As you already are well aware,
the mountain location
is discovered to be Daeseong Mountain.
Search thoroughly.
Block all routes into Daeseong
Mountain completely.
Got it?
Yes, Sir.
Your Excellency.
It seems they've discovered the location.
Right now, the royal guard
and royal investigation armies
are heading toward Daeseong Mountain.
Send a message to
Gyun Jeok Hee at once.
Yes.
Daylight will break soon.
Why aren't they coming?
It seems he hasn't come out yet.
Excuse me,
but do you trust Lord Shim Jong Soo?
I apologize.
I've overstepped my bounds.
No.
Do I trust him?
I didn't trust him.
For a long time.
Shim Jong Soo always
seemed to be disloyal to me.
Furthermore,
after Shim Jong Soo
came to the mountain alone,
I finally understood.
He never once
was allegiant to me nor Teacher Sambong.
My premonition was correct.
He merely...
that system of a genuine parliament,
he was only loyal to that.
Not relying on people.
He is loyal to his creed only.
Hence, he will do well.
Did you summon your answer?
Bonwon?
Why are you looking at it?
It's the Milbon pledge and the
roster of all Milbon members.
This is...
truly... ?
What you said is all correct.
Actually, I was already
troubled by thoughts
of the next generation.
You gave me the answer.
Spearhead Milbon.
Bonwon.
Where is that Haerye?
Do you really have it?
I will burn and rid of that Haerye.
The day Lee Do makes the promulgation.
I will kill Lee Do.
And I will kill all who know the letters.
Now.
Where's the Haerye?
Yes.
That was created by the King,
the Haerye of the letters...
On the account of the white powder you
spread, we were able to get all the way here.
But is there no more of
the warning toll from here?
I've verified to this point here so far.
We should be able to charge
in without much resistance.
Alright, then this very moment, we charge in.
Royal Guard Commander.
Above all else, the safety of the
hostage is top priority. Please say so.
Of course.
The Haerye...
is not a book.
The Haerye is...
Which scum are you!
So you've succeeded
in trailing me at last.
Gyun Jeok Hee!
As I know it, this isn't
the time for you to bluff.
Well, you won't die.
I'm told you are still of use.
I have to find out where
that Haerye or whatever it is.
They are Ming agents.
There are too many.
Lee Shin Jeok sent you then.
You are Jeong Gi Joon?
I will block her however it takes.
Please evade that way.
You too. Instead of getting captured by
the Ming agents, this is probably better.
Why... do as you wish then.
Attack!
Chase him!
Anyone who defies the federal law,
wipe them out without sparing any.
What exactly... happened?
The royal guard troops.
Then, the warning toll didn't function?
Hurry and evade.
Bonwon!
What about Bonwon?
Our Black Concourse is the
top in the continent, you see.
It won't do.
What is it that you want?
I'm not sure.
I don't quite know either.
Let's go together for now.
Aren't you looking for the Haerye?
The Haerye...
What scum are you?
When did you come?
What is it?
Who is it?
Run.
What?
What did you say?
If you run,
you can live.
Why this scum thinks
he's so big... so he's crazy.
What are you doing?
We haven't got time.
Hurry and kill him.
Yes.
STOP!
All retreat.
Now!
We did nothing here.
We will just leave quietly.
Spare us.
Spy senior, what's wrong with you?
Shut up!
All retreat!
How did you know to come here?
The mountain camp has been ambushed.
And Yeon Doo has disappeared.
Ambushed?
What are you talking about?
Bonwon.
Are you alright?
The mountain camp was ambushed?
What is that talk?
The soldiers from the royal guard.
They raided the place.
Spy senior.
What exactly is going on with you?
There was a Tolgol mercenary troop
during Yuan Dynasty's power restoration.
Then he is...
"Undefeatable on earth"
Kareupeyi Taemukan.
But he is just one.
No one.
No one can beat him.
Hurry and alert Peking.
Palace guard!
Don't worry.
It's all finished.
But So Yi?
Where's So Yi?
So Yi...
So Yi got dragged away.
Dragged away?
By who?
To where?
She was dragged away
by that punk Garion.
You must find her.
Hurry!
It seems you lost.
Everything.
Now.
Isn't it ended?
Your base is gone and
your peers are captured.
The Haerye, you couldn't find.
You've lost.
Haerye...
Haerye is...
Bring So Yi.
You won't be able to find it!
Because I myself...
have never seen it either.
Can't you give me a discount here?
Mister Garion.
Seriously, you scared me.
Hey, why the fuss!
I have to start over now!
Well if you won't give me a discount...
Kill her.
You...
are the Haerye.
Dahm!
Subtitles brought to you by the Deep Rooted Friends @ viki.com