Color of Woman
Episode 19
[Love Hurts]
When I first met Jun Su he piggy-backed me.
You didn't know that, did you?
From then, I started liking him.
He acts cold, but he's a warm man.
That's how Jun Su is.
Chairman, I really like Jun Su.
Chairman, please get well quickly.
Get up and be a strength for Jun Su. Please?
Head Manager.
What did you say?
Let's get engaged.
I told you before that I'm
very bad at adapting.
If I start liking something: food, movies,
books, even the feelings of liking someone...
I can't easily change.
I know.
To start loving someone else will take time.
It might take longer than I expect.
But if you wait for me, Jin Ju,
I'll look at only you.
Head Manager.
Can you hold my hand?
[Emergency Medical Center]
Sunbae.
So Ra, where are you?
Can we meet?
Did you run?
Yes.
I have something to tell you...
Me too. I have something I need
to tell you, Sunbae.
You say it first.
No, you can say yours first.
All right.
I thought I should tell you
before anyone else.
What is it?
I'm getting engaged... to Jin Ju.
What did you say?
I'm engaged to Jin Ju.
Because of business?
To save the reputation of Yoon-line?
No. It's for real this time.
I feel sorry for Jin Ju, and
I think she's the one who's right for me.
You had something to tell me?
No, it's nothing. Work... it's about work.
Congratulations, Sunbae.
I'll get going, then.
Let's take a picture.
I'm taking it.
[Jun Su, So Ra "Love you forever" 2011. 11]
Jun Su, So Ra, "Love you forever"...
Will L'aura Cosmetics fall like this?
False marketing, negative effect
on consumers...
Oh my god.
To make things worse, the Chairman collapsed.
By any chance, will he just die...
Hey! Don't say a word!
If you don't want to lose your job!
Talking nonsense.
The stocks are falling.
Wait, wait.
Oh my god.
It'll reach the bottom.
Oh my, oh my! My stock! Look at it fall.
Oh my, even Manager Park isn't here now!
[Chairman Yoon's loss of conscience,
second day of L'aura's crisis]
[L'aura Cosmetic's crisis]
Is this what you wanted?
Chairman Yoon collapsing was unpredictable,
but everything else is going as planned.
They say a hero appears at times like this.
I would gladly give Director Kang
an opportunity to be a hero.
I don't need anything like that
Director Kang, are you naive or foolish?
By any chance, did you soften upon
Chairman Yoon's collapse?
Have you already forgotten what
Chairman Yoon did to your mom?
What do you want from me?
Call a special meeting of the board
of directors under your name.
The agenda being getting L'aura out of this
crisis, as well as the next executive election.
If you and I combine powers, L'aura Cosmetics
will not only be Korea's summit,
but we can make it a world beater.
I don't want to start a fight with
someone who has no conscience.
If you don't take this chance, I don't know
when another might come along.
Don't you feel a grudge, living under
Chairman Yoon's lie for 15 years?
It's not that the strongest man wins,
but that the person who wins is strong.
This is the last chance you will get
for both work and love.
[Diagnostic Check Medical Science]
[Blood Collection Room]
You're my son, same as Jun Su.
Compared to what you've given me,
what I'm giving you now is nothing.
Just say thank you and accept it.
After some time, Jun Su will accept it.
Don't you feel a grudge, living under
Chairman Yoon's lie for 15 years?
Chan Jin.
Engagement?
I think I'm a really bad person.
I know that Head Manager's heart
is with So Ra, but I couldn't say no.
No, I didn't reject him.
You said before, Chan Jin, that we should do
as our hearts feel.
I feel really sorry for So Ra, but I don't
want to let go of Head Manager's hand.
Chan Jin, you're going to be
by So Ra's side, right?
Your engagement, does So Ra know
about it?
Head Manager said he was going to tell So Ra.
Did you really get engaged to Jin Ju?
Yeah, it's true.
What about So Ra?
I think there's always
a matching pair with people.
For me, Jin Ju matches.
And So Ra, she has you.
Hyung, you're always like this.
You act cool all by yourself.
Don't you know what I did to you?
I made up the Cinderella story and
leaked the information.
Don't talk rubbish! You may have started it,
but the end wasn't your doing.
At least the Kang Chan Jin I know
is not a coward.
Don't talk as if you know!
What do you know about me?
What more do I need to know?
All I need to know...
is that you're my younger brother.
Stop showing off!
This is worth seeing.
You're quite a sight too.
Do you remember?
When I came home beaten up, Hyung,
you always went back to avenge me.
Because I had you, Hyung, I felt reassured.
I feel the same way.
The house I hated going into,
after you came I started to like.
Because it felt like I had a supporter.
If you hadn't asked me to
I wouldn't have come back to Korea.
Even though So Ra's here?
That's right.
Even though So Ra was here, if it weren't
for you, I wouldn't have come back.
Your engagement to Jin Ju,
is it because of me?
No. It's because of me.
Because I want to become happier.
Did you just come in? Have you eaten?
What are you doing?
I'm sorry So Ra. I'm really sorry.
Wang Jin Ju. Get up at once!
I can't get up, because I'm sorry.
Jun Su sunbae and I are already over.
Of course, if I said I wasn't shocked,
it would be a lie.
But I respect Jun Su's decision.
I think that's why people say
first loves are not true.
So Ra.
I can't congratulate you yet.
I think it'll take me some time.
I hope you can understand that.
I'm sorry, So Ra.
Oh, Hyun Ah, it's been a long time, yes?
It's morning over there, isn't it?
Oh, it's nothing much. But,
the school you were talking about...
Is it still possible for me to go?
Yes, the sooner the better.
Okay. Can you look into it? Please.
Hey, Byun So Ra!
Who is that?
Who is it at this hour? They have no manners.
Who is it?
Good morning. Good morning. Good morning.
Kang Chan Jin. What are you...
What's wrong with your face?
Chan Jin, did you get in a fight?
Oh, yesterday I ran into gangsters
and fought 17 to 1...
What?
But that's not important right now.
Hurry and get dressed.
Why, what's wrong?
Hurry up and change.
Hey, stay with me!
I won!
Aw, what a waste!
See. I told you you're no match for me
in running.
All right. I lost, I lost. Tell me your wish.
What do you mean, wish?
Hey, the loser was going to grant the other's wish.
I'll grant your wish. Tell me anything.
My wish? My wish... I don't have one.
What if I had a wish? It wouldn't come true.
On your birthday, do you know what
my wish for you was?
Let Byun So Ra always smile.
Kang Chan Jin.
I don't know how to make you smile always.
But when you smile or cry
I want to be by your side always.
Whether as a friend or a man,
whatever you want.
So don't go study abroad.
You... How did you know?
Last night, Jin Ju called me,
crying for me to stop you going.
That Wang Jin Ju and her nosiness.
Don't go. Or, let's go together.
You tick! You stalker. It's disgusting
being with you now.
I'm going to go.
Really, those two, can they become lovers?
Oh, do you want to make a bet?
Granting the winner's wish.
Hey, you want to bet with a person's heart?
It's because I'm curious.
Oh, what is love?
Hey, if I knew that would I have
stayed single till now?
Get some exercise! You have to get rid of
your stomach fat to start dating or whatever.
But that's your job, Boss. Wow, it's dynamic.
Yeah, that's my story.
You heartless boy.
Today's goal. 500. 500.
Now, hurry. Hurry up and get up.
Oh, you're here early.
Yeah. I couldn't get any sleep.
It's big news. Big news!
What? Head Manager and Jin Ju
getting engaged?
You've heard already?
I heard it on the way to work.
Assistant Manager Byun, are you okay?
We'd already broken up.
Even so. When I see you,
Assistant Manager Byun, I feel sorry for you.
When I see you, Assistant Manager Song,
I feel sorry for you too.
How could Manger Park leave like that
without a farewell party?
It's because he's much too important
a person! You're talking nonsense.
If he's arrived there safely, he should
at least message me or send me an e-mail.
He looked like he was going to
live and die in front of me.
That's why, he's my man when in front of me
but when he turns around he's just a man.
Did you guys hear it already?
It's really big news.
She already knows about
Head Manger Yoon Jun Su's engagement.
Oh Jin Ju, congratulations!
You've really become Cinderella now.
Thank you.
It's spring for someone, and for someone else
it's like the Siberian steppe.
Cheer up.
This time I really thought I was
going to get married.
You unlucky fool. You unlucky fool really!
Don't be too upset. He's only being sent
to China for a year.
But how can they send someone
all of a sudden like that?
He can't even speak Chinese.
Hey, just think how it worked out.
When Chan Ho comes back he doesn't have to
worry about getting fired. We have the lives of flies.
Isn't that nice. That someone held on to
a line before that.
Oh, Manager Park sent me a video message!
Oh, that man. He doesn't even send me a
message but he sends that to you. What is it?
Hello. Are you doing well Mi Rae?
This is Chan Ho. I'm doing well too.
There's something I want to ask you.
I've suddenly noticed, about being sent to China.
I forgot to tell Ye Jin to wait a year for me.
So Mi Rae, tell her to wait
just one year for me please.
And also, without me Ye Jin will be lonely,
so Mi Rae please meet up with her.
Buy her good food, chat, and buy her drinks,
and later I'll pay back all the money.
Oh Chan Ho!
Also, lastly tell her this:
Ye Jin, wo ai ni ("I love you" in Chinese).
Bye, Mi Rae.
Me too, wo ai ni
It's a good morning.
Hey, what's wrong with his face? His face?
What happened to Head Manager's face?
Did you see?
Director, Director!
I think the rebellion against the princes started,
but it's stopped with them beating each other up.
I think their bond is stronger than we thought.
He's young so he doesn't know
what's bitter in the world.
As an adult, should I let him know
how to live in this world?
The last party, get it ready.
Yes. All right.
I put medicine on it yesterday, so it's okay.
How did you get hurt this badly?
Yesterday I met with a gang
and fought 17 to 1...
Chan Jin already used that.
Chan Jin already went and told you.
This morning he came to the house,
to stop So Ra going abroad.
Is So Ra going to study abroad?
Yes, she said she's going to go.
I told you to come to my room.
I heard from Jin Ju that
you're going to study abroad?
This is being spread around everywhere
by your fiancée, Sunbae.
Don't go abroad.
You're someone this company really needs.
I want to continue studying.
I want to study more about cosmetics.
Then go with Chan Jin.
I'll send both of you to work in the U.S.
Don't try to force Chan Jin and me together.
Chan Jin is just a friend to me.
It's not like that for Chan Jin.
Chan Jin needs you.
You don't realize those words
actually hurt me more.
So all this time, I meant that to you:
"Since I'm over you, you should go to another. "
I was that kind of weak presence for you...
So Ra...
My job, whether it's work or studying,
I'll take care of myself.
Yes, it's Byun So Ra.
You want to scout me?
Byun So Ra, I was very impressed by
your masters' thesis paper.
Oh, yes. Thank you for
looking at it so kindly.
It made me think you're someone we need
in our company.
I'm sorry, but I'm planning to
study abroad soon.
Our company can also sponsor
your studies abroad.
These are our company's terms.
Please read them over and give me a call.
I'm sorry.
At least read it.
All right. But please don't expect much.
You're here?
Are you all right here by yourself?
I'm fine. Head Manager, you've come here,
and yesterday Chan Jin came as well.
Chan Jin came?
Yes, last night.
When will my father start to move again?
Due to the after-effects of the car accident
15 years ago, his body has gotten weak.
We have to keep an eye on him longer.
Chairman was in an accident?
[Special Board of Directors Meeting
Announcement Notice]
Have you already forgotten
what Chairman Yoon did to your mom?
[1. Agenda: L'aura Cosmetic's crisis
management and the next executive election]
Chairman, you were always a strong
and scary person.
Seeing you lying down like this,
it's a strange feeling.
As an employee, before I start a war,
I thought I should make my greetings.
Thank you for all this time.
Don't worry too much.
I'll take care of your later years.
There is a pleasant guest here.
I was late coming to visit him.
As you know,
the company is in a state of war.
It's funny that the creator of
this state of war is saying that.
If it's a company that can fall
at such a small attack,
isn't it evidence that something
is very wrong.
Are you saying my father didn't
lead the company right?
It's something people see as they get old.
When did you, Head Manager, suddenly get
interested in the company and your father?
It's all thanks to you, Director Seong.
Thanks to you, I've discovered how important
my father, the company, and Chan Jin are.
It's a pity. I should have helped you
realize this earlier.
I have a feeling it's too late now.
You don't have to keep guessing.
Soon, you'll know.
And also, one more thing,
just a tip on life.
Don't trust people too much.
You can have the engagement at our hotel.
If you tell me the date you want, Jin Ju,
I'll set it up with the hotel. When is good?
Head Manager says the sooner the better.
But I want it when the Chairman has
recovered a bit.
The Chairman, how is he?
Still no progress.
He had major heart surgery 15 years ago,
so they say his body is weak.
Heart surgery 15 years ago?
Chan Jin you didn't know either?
15 years ago he was in a big car accident.
When exactly was that?
I don't really know that…
Chan Jin!
In January?
Yes, that should be exactly right.
Because of Chairman Yoon's surgery,
I couldn't go to the Sung Soo meeting
at the main branch.
So I remember my parents were worried.
Do you remember how the accident happened?
He was going somewhere with a female
colleague when the accident happened.
A drunk truck driver was colliding with the car.
To save that colleague
he threw his body across hers.
And because of that his heart was injured.
It was a miracle the Chairman survived
that accident.
That female colleague, how did she...?
She died at the scene of the accident.
When the Chairman gained consciousness,
I remember he kept looking for her.
Chan Jin.
What's wrong? Did something happen?
Why is our rival company doing an
investment presentation on our special line?
- Take a look
- [Investment Proposal: Moisturizing cream
from natural ingredients]
If you take a look inside, all our special
line core information is there.
And it's very similar to Byun So Ra's patent.
How can this happen?
I think there's a leak.
If it's similar to Assistant Manager
Byun's patent, then...
Me?
Don't say things without evidence.
The people who know about this
are Director Kang,
me, and all the members of
the special line team,
and the legal department who dealt with
the patent; more than ten people know.
But if the patent information is written
in detail like this,
isn't it too difficult for anyone
not directly in the know?
Please think this through.
Our company is the innocent victim!
If you invest in the special line now,
you will regret it.
Chairman, Chairman.
Yes, Jin Ju.
Right now?
Yes, all right
Is Father all right now?
Yes, he's past the critical point.
There isn't a big problem with his heart,
so once he gains strength, he can
live his normal daily life.
Jun Su.
Father.
Oh, where's Chan Jin?
I had no time to think, so I just came.
Hold on.
[Jun Su hyung]
After the beep, please leave a message...
I think the company is so busy
his hands are full.
Is there something going on at the company?
No, there's nothing going on.
Did Chan Jin...
Father, this person has been
watching over you this whole time.
I'm Wang Jin Ju.
She's been a strength to me.
I'll tell you everything bit by bit.
Excuse me, but can you please
give us some space?
Yes.
Does he not like me? What if he opposes?
Chan Jin. How much does he know?
He knows everything.
The story about you and his mother.
What are you doing, not getting off work?
Something is strange.
It's a part of my patent that we were
supposed to use,
but our rival company has more
information that I didn't reveal.
Maybe that company's researcher
had similar ideas.
Yes, so I'm looking through everything
like this,
and there's similar data,
but nothing exactly the same.
You know too, don't you? That I worked hard
on this patent for three years.
I know. I saw it with my own eyes.
Because of those three years, I can't have
this special line taken away from me unjustly.
Leave that problem to the company
and get ready to study abroad.
No, I can't just go like this.
My pride and honor are on the line.
It's hard preparing everything by yourself,
isn't it?
Oh, no. The Chairman is in hospital
and the special line is also a bit...
and also, I'm still a secretary.
If you say that, I feel bad.
I'm just kidding. If you're sorry, then you can
look at this and get off early today.
You haven't seen the wedding hall yet.
Oh, that's right. All right. Let's go together.
[Special Board of Directors Meeting
Announcement]
[1. Agenda: L'aura Cosmetics crisis
management and next executive election]
[2. Place: L'aura Cosmetics Council Chamber]
[3. Time: 2012, February 07]
Yes, Director Park.
I've just received it.
Who called the Directors' meeting?
Where's Director Kang.
He didn't come in today.
I'm going out now.
Get hold of Director Kang and let me know.
Yes, all right.
[Special Board of Directors Meeting
Announcement]
Chan Jin...
I need to meet Chan Jin.
Stop it.
Let that child do as he wishes.
Father...
Chan Jin has his own thoughts.
You look more beautiful than on TV.
Thank you.
It's your last day for fitting the clothes,
but your husband didn't come again?
Yes, he's quite a busy person.
Please give me the size from before.
Yes.
You said you'd pay the rest today.
You must be happy.
You've become a successful model,
and marrying such a handsome man.
You haven't slept yet.
You said it's better for your skin
if you sleep early.
It's your engagement tomorrow too.
I can't sleep.
Oh, am I really doing the right thing?
It's what you wanted.
That's right. But I'm not happy.
My chest feels stuffy and
I can't breathe well.
It's probably because you're nervous.
If it were you, do you think you would have
left it like this?
It's hard to get hold of him even once a day.
You know he's busy because of
the board of directors' meeting.
But I really don't know Chan Jin's mind.
It's as if he's not the Chan Jin
I knew before.
How could he do that to Head Manager
and to the Chairman who raised him?
What are you talking about?
Chan Jin called for the
special board of directors' meeting.
What?
Didn't Chan Jin tell you?
I've been so busy these days
I haven't called him.
I think he changed after finding out that
his mother died because of the Chairman.
How do you know?
No, does Chan Jin know about that?
He knows.
That's why he convened the meeting, to take
revenge on Chairman and Head Manager.
So Ra, the only person who can
stop Chan Jin is you.
Tell me, do you really want to
end things with Jun Su?
Kang Chan Jin.
Stay still, Jun Su hyung is still watching.
I want to see you, Byun So Ra.
[So Ra]
Yes, So Ra?
Jin Ju.
Sit down.
If you sleep late your skin will be ruined.
Tomorrow, Jin Ju, you're the main character,
so only you need to be pretty.
It would be nice if the husband
were also handsome.
Don't worry about that
because I have a good pedigree.
You know how to make jokes like that?
I'm actually a fun person,
but I think I haven't shown that much.
Because the time we had together was short.
I'm sorry that because of company work,
I was so busy.
I didn't pay attention to you either.
It was hard getting ready by yourself,
wasn't it?
I thought you'd be hungry
so I made some lunch.
I was about to get hungry. Thank you.
It's good.
Liar.
It's true.
Head Manager, I think you can't lie,
because it shows all over your face.
It's been a long time.
How many days has it been?
Byun So Ra withdrawal symptoms,
our telepathy worked.
Have you been doing well these days?
What is it? You called me out and
you're not saying anything.
Do you like me?
How many times do I have to say I like you?
You said you always wanted to be
by my side whether I smiled or cried.
Was that true?
Do you want me to tell you one more time?
How come you started liking me as a woman
all of a sudden?
What?
You, by any chance were you using me?
To take revenge on
Chairman and Jun Su sunbae?
Am I worth only that much?
Saying you'll try hard and do your best,
I know you're sincere.
But, Head Manager, your face right now,
doesn't look happy at all.
Jin Ju.
And I'm not happy either.
Let's stop this.
I won't go to the engagement ceremony
tomorrow.
I really believe you didn't.
I know that you would never do that.
But if you have something else in your heart,
give up on the directors' meeting.
Stop making it hard on Jun Su sunbae.
To you, Jun Su hyung is still number one,
huh?
If I say I can't give up...
Then I won't see you again.
You and I... it would be the end.