Serial Thriller Fantasy.
the Children of God.
-=The content of this drama is not related to a specific group,
a particular religion or the other.=-
I...
just saw.
See what?
Your sister.
Before he died.
My Sister Is So In?
he's trying to convey a message.
You get out of the way.
-=Episode 4=-
I told you not to shoot.
Look at you, like a beggar.
Still dare to oppose?
We almost died
because of the gun this motherfucker.
How dare you say so?
Han Sang-Goo didn't pull the trigger.
Can you get
without the shot.
Already.
You see, right?
He shot first.
You manipulate the SCENE.
Appears enforcement of justice.
People who don't know will think
she is your wife.
Motherfucker!
Son of a bitch!
Hold yourself.
Release.
Take care of him.
Take care of him also.
What did you say?
Rabbit.
Do not also.
Like a duck.
So In trying to send the message.
Don't-don't...
Certainly, such a beast.
take a good Look, Oppa.
Side of the truth.
What is this?
True. What is it?
Picture the Rabbit-Duck illusion-his
Ludwig Wittgenstein.
What do you call this?
Initially looks like a rabbit.
If seen again, like a duck.
If your mind is like a child,
you can't see the duck.
People...
often be fooled by a first impression.
As much as I am.
For you see this picture?
D
Da
Dam
Damn
Damn!
Damn!S
Damn!Su
Damn!Soup
Damn!Super
Damn!SuperS
Damn!SuperSu
Damn!SuperSub
Damn!SuperSub I
Damn!SuperSub In
Damn!SuperSub Ind
Damn!SuperSub Indo
Damn!SuperSub .
Damn!SuperSub T
Damn!SuperSub Indonesia
Translated by:
~ Ifabee ~
Abeojimu also the police?
I used to be.
My parents died a long time ago.
Your family just stay your sister.
Wow, dusty.
Wow, the house is right to live.
For 2 years
what are you, ran away from home?
I'm not a teenage boy.
Escape from the house.
The never view a house at all?
've never been here.
Rent what?
This is my home.
In the center of Seoul
got a property on his own behalf.
Oh, my gosh.
All the plugs still
attached when you leave the house.
That's why the electric bills are high.
Hey.
Now this I'm reminded of
the memories are sad.
You don't have empathy at all?
Insurance.
Bills of the property.
Gas bills.
This.
Kesedehanaan is called reality.
Now, don't remember back those memories.
I thought 2 this year
upayaku too persistent.
I think I'm out of here.
Escape from feelings of guilt.
No.
Where?
What are you looking for?
I help you find it.
Birthday gift.
Also as a congratulations
because he is so reporter.
your birthday.
Hey, what's this?
Oh, the pen recorder.
it Seems expensive yes.
Take the time of the interview.
Sure.
About Love?
Why?
Oppa I want to get married?
Because it is a long, long time
I stress.
What shall we do?
Do not rely on the face.
It's duck-rabbit.
-=Happy Birthday.
Ugly chick, looks like you could
long-lived without the disease.=-
You this, I'll stuff bonyok you!
Oh, hey, hey.
The camera, the camera.
Camera.
I must be calm.
Oh, looks like you moved.
From another point of view
the truth can change drastically.
I Hope you can be a repoter
that could see everything.
Since then he always bring this book.
The book was...
and handbook of journalism.
But why Han Sang-Goo it?
Not The Han Sang-Goo.
So he's your brother.
No! Only one time.
other...
The man behind Han Sang-Goo.
But why did he take
his So In?
Can ask you a favor?
There are other things to investigate.
I heard you were good friends So In.
Many a reporter sitting next to me.
Before So In died,
what does he do?
I don't know, I don't remember.
What's more, a long time ago.
Ah, yes.
Looking for someone.
Someone?
You.
What?
If you want to find missing children
22 years ago,
should to do?
22 years ago.
For there is a miracle.
This is not a joke.
Him?
Yes.
Sure is still alive?
A lost child is already 22 years old
I will look for it.
Although live or die.
We must see the case first.
But...
why do you want to look it up?
If it is found, I'll tell you.
Maybe...
this Child may be a Pandora's Box.
-=Willing to pay 50 million=-
Sought a missing child, the name: Lee Soo Yi.=-
Pandora's Box?
Who is that kid?
A long-haired boy.
Certainly, it looks like he wants to
a job out of town.
To where?
I'm calling you.
Please provide the footage of Han Sang-Goo
transferred.
Yes.
He know very well of CCTV cameras.
Hey, please hurry up.
30 minutes again.
- Yes, better.
- Yes.
Oh, my gosh.
-=Reports, a serial Killer.
Han Sang-Goo escape and related reports.=-
the Case is buried with the truth
invisible to the eye.
the Girl who wanted So In
before he died.
the handbook of Journalism is lost.
What may because of that photo?
is that why they kill?
-=The culprit?=-
Since the beginning of Han Sang-Goo is just a tool.
Although the return with the case of murder
he didn't feel guilty.
But...
How do they engineer
serial murders?
It's a deal.
-='The DNA of a serial Killer do not match',
Police release suspect.=- (7)
Han Sang-Goo, it's him.
Not him.
No DNA is not a coincidence.
that Day...
Call it...
based on the runaway.
But 2 years later he was back.
Han Sang-Goo back with a lot of cases.
Like a time bomb.
So open your mouth,
cannot be undone.
That's why he killed Han Sang-Goo.
Don't shoot!
Popeye waiting for you.
Who are you?
-=Popeye=-
You have to see this.
Yes.
Where are you?
We got a briefing.
Briefing what?
The case of Han Sang Goo closed.
Why?
Isn't Baek Ah Hyun could not
questioning?
What do you mean?
The Princess of the day it was released.
No.
Han Sang-Goo made a scapegoat.
Choi Seung-Gi.
Are you ready?
Yes, ready.
5 more minutes.
Stop briefingnya.
It's over.
This case can not be directly closed.
Get out of the way.
There is someone in the back of Han Sang-Goo.
What do you mean?
The probability the suspect can escape
but, how much?
Ji Gang Heon in '88
and Choi Boy Bo years '90.
2003, a suspect of theft.
2005 so a drug suspect
and pembunuhaan.
In the last 30 years
there are only 5 events.
So...
Are you going to say?
The opportunity is great.
Plus,
he could release the handcuffs.
Seize a gun and trying to escape.
Open the video.
Look at this.
It's the key to the handcuffs.
That's the key?
Han Sang-Goo escape is not a coincidence.
Someone helped him escape.
But instead brought him death.
Perhaps it was she who ordered
to kill my brother.
You mention the hallucinations?
Because of your sister.
Your obsession against Han Sang-Goo
too excessive.
Han Sang-Goo detained in prisons.
Disconnected with the outside world.
Who can give him the key?
Surely the police in in.
Watch your mouth, Nyuk!
There is one more.
I don't know
what's the key to real.
People get into the interrogation room
what name is not a violation?
Using the identity of the previous
Although you said
one of us wanted to kill Han Sang-Goo
and let him escape.
But who of us
who want to kill him?
He himself was carrying a gun.
It...
Baek Ah Hyun how?
Why princess Songha Group that released?
The victim of a student's right not aware.
See this boy.
Hey.
You're always in the back of Chun Jae In.
Didn't see the news?
=Serial killer Han Sang-Goo.=
=She said...=
Choi Eun Yoo already aware
2 hours ago.
What?
=He stabbed me.=
-=Han Sang-Goo kidnap victim Choi, 21=-
"Han Sang-Goo stabbed me."
Choi Eun Yoo why...
He lied.
Choi Eun Yoo not stabbed Han Sang-Goo.
But the woman was.
Already I assure you.
The results of the analysis of her blood is clear...
Game Detective Conan.
How is this possible?
The prosecutor's office rejected it.
Snap out of it.
Do you mean the police are behind all this?
As savage as the-wild tiger,
he will not eat his own son
You don't like this.
Who?
Police are targeting who?
At least 2 people who are here
I think I know.
Hey, briefingnya?
- Ready?
- Yes.
Yes.
In the last 4 years
wandering around Gyeonggi-do, Seoul.
The serial killer who kidnapped
and kill women.
Han Sang-Goo was declared dead.
=Han Sang-Gok middle transferred=
Seize a gun and escape.
-=Police shoot Han Sang-Goo
for the sake of the safety of the residents.=-
=In the process of arrest=
Han Sang-Goo holding the gun.
-=Han Sang-Goo gun, trying to escape, and menyadera.=-
That's why our personnel shoot.
The case is officially closed.
The cost of living and money semester
already transferred to Your account.
Help on You
will be continued after graduation.
You can get to our hospital
for this to work.
After graduation, I want to be independent.
Please pass.
Better.
The daughter of a rich it
really have extraordinary powers
Up can make people like this.
For him easy.
Evil woman.
Baek Ah Hyun-ssi was kidnapped Han Sang-Goo.
True.
The reason of her abduction what?
I don't want to think about it.
I don't want to.
Anyway just a formality.
Responsible course.
Who stabbed student?
I.
-=Han Sang-Goo=-
The situation at that time?
I have to stay alive.
A kind of game
in between the 2 only 1 living.
If you,
what are you doing?
I picked up the knife.
If only 1 life
than the girl in that room
my life is expensive.
He let us experience the
what has been experienced.
Han Sang-Goo said so.
No human will be hurt
at the same time learn
how to hurt the other person, not so?
Is that why you're here?
What?
Don't underestimate me.
I was her case worker Han Sang-Goo.
I want to see Geomsa.
Please wait a minute.
You're liberated.
The secret tell me.
Ah, who am I?
I met in that hospital?
Choi Eun Yoo you buy with what?
I bought the front of the woman.
Actually only a few thousand won.
Of course.
not that what I'm doing wrong.
You...
find out Han Sang-Goo will be dead.
I don't know.
It looks like you're curious about a lot of things.
Reinkarnasilah born in a rich family.
Seonbae.
Preferential treatment.
What because she's his daughter Songha Group?
Ah, he is...
Okay, I know who he is.
Baek Ah Hyun attempted murder
why not arrested?
Statement of student victim
and Baek Ah Hyun's partner.
And the suspect dead.
It looks like you have a fantasy about the law.
The law is indeed a respecter of persons.
The results of the analysis of blood
submitted as evidence.
Why rejected?
Because there is a cause.
Their untrained
what have the qualification rate
the methods of science?
What does that mean?
For you to understand?
I see you write a function trigonometrinya
so detailed.
In fact, I
just understand some of it.
Continue to why...
The murder case of Itaewon
blood so decisive evidence.
But...
different with this case.
Because 2 people at the crime SCENE
so the main suspect.
The technique of analysis of blood
introduced in China in 2008.
I got all that after review of the data
using such a technique.
At the hearing very little evidence
expressed.
So...
if you want the rich princess it is
jailed
please bring proof of the other.
I don't know
you're the one who holds the principle of
although our paths are not the same.
this is not my style.
Talented police officer who failed to,
ever so the legend
consider the death of his family
as his own fault.
wasted 2 years.
The lapse of time, narcissism changed
so torture yourself.
Because of that I couldn't recognize
his or her identity.
Get in here gave a lecture Geomsa.
I'm sorry, but that's not my style.
I have something to say
on hyeongsa.
I'm sorry,
've made a mistake.
Sorry it's free.
Now I understand.
The water in this case
deeper than I thought.
I heard you're a hero
that catches Han Sang-Goo.
It was a coincidence.
Before you die, you see?
Yes.
Han Sang-Goo said what?
In his last moments.
Because I failed to investigate
crime other, please.
Nothing special.
Name.
Asking me to remember a name.
The name of what?
The Name Of Apollo.
What is it?
I don't know.
It was he said.
He asked you to remember the name of it?
Yes.
-=The fugitive=-
D
Da
Dam
Damn
Damn!
Damn!S
Damn!Su
Damn!Soup
Damn!Super
Damn!SuperS
Damn!SuperSu
Damn!SuperSub
Damn!SuperSub I
Damn!SuperSub In
Damn!SuperSub Ind
Damn!SuperSub Indo
Damn!SuperSub .
Damn!SuperSub T
Damn!SuperSub Indonesia
Translated by:
~ Ifabee ~
I heard the man who killed your brother is dead.
He cursed.
For this, thank you.
You've been looking for her.
Anytime, please come meet us.
You need time,
we all know it.
The difficult years
that makes you suffer.
Take this to cook soup.
This radish love soy sauce
and the garlic sauce.
Eat that regularly.
Chun Daepyo.
This...
This is the most I loved.
For you.
Style my child is young.
- Eih, you.
- Come on.
Come on, put it on.
Wear.
Don't have to.
Wear, come on.
You wear.
Wow
Handsome.
What's next?
Chun Daepyo will say
a few words.
A round of applause.
Try to be able to meet
on a regular basis.
The nation's debt continues to grow
China's economic growth amid weakened.
The uncertainty in the country
- in luarpun big a risk.
- Uh, hey.
Well. This.
Now you can go.
Yes.
Take it.
What are you gonna do?
Anyway in here no one had a cell phone.
My number's on speed dial.
If there are people like that time
interfere with our members, just call.
Olalala.
If you need anything, just ask.
Not for nothing,
keep contact each other yes.
Of course.
Be careful.
I see you have
good luck this month.
Ah, never mind.
You should be careful with the water.
I go.
Try not near water.
Understand?
Personal information that You have requested.
-=Personal Information=-
Look at you.
I ask you to come,
but you don't want to hear.
Sometime our pilgrimage
to the tomb of your father.
During this time, news You good, You?
No.
You Hakjang-nim University Police.
You.
Yesterday I got to the police station.
Reportedly you make leadership a major upset.
The news quickly spread.
I told the suspect not the Han Sang-Goo,
but no one believes.
The Korean police do not do investigation.
They want to protect the organization
that's why.
So you want to protect something,
you will do anything.
Isn't that so?
You are already old.
Different from the previous
first You like the snaps.
Life's getting older.
But...
You find something
for So In?
New one proof.
It seems So In to investigate something.
What?
I don't know for sure.
Therefore, You must know something
what he's here every day
for dinner?
It's been so long,
but that time,
his face looks uneasy.
I ask her what's wrong.
What did he say?
Didn't say anything.
Don't have a clue.
Because it...
How are you here, Kim Hyeongsa?
Continue to Geomsa-nim, why are you here?
This is called not claimed.
No funeral expenses.
No mourners or family.
Officially not called a cemetery
only recorded as a corpse.
Considered the goods burned.
Rich or a beggar.
Either villain or hero
for the last time
at least, not considered goods.
Should be treated appropriately human.
So sometimes I come here.
If you?
I?
Actually
why I'm here
I don't know.
To die,
I can't forgive Han Sang-Goo.
Popeye.
Waiting for you.
what exactly does that mean?
-=Cremation=-
You're more humane
than I thought.
What?
You said you often come here to see
bodies not claimed were cremated.
Because the current is small,
I never experience hunger.
The snow fell.
So see the snow come down
I always feel hungry.
Because the granules of snow-like rice.
Really, if rice
it would be nice.
So...
When you have the time?
Let's get some dinner.
-=Police Seoul=-
Although the line only 1 cm
take all of it.
Ready.
The morning assembly is finished.
Disperse!
- Yes.
Chun Jae In Hyeongsa.
Seonbae.
I Chun Jae In.
Today back to the team of the Criminal investigation.
Timjang-nim.
How can he be back here?
I don't even know.
A letter of resignation is not accepted.
Because...
I want to catch the guy.
I want to go back.
Please help me back.
If it is I can't help you.
don't be lulled by the comfort,
it's the principle.
But...
resignation letter has not been received.
case.
The Case Of Han Sang Goo
will be re-investigated by this team.
This team? Our team?
You know, it has been closed.
I already report it to superiors.
Hey, not at work?
Still want to hangout?
Better.
Hey, Chun Jae In.
Do not overdo it.
Rabbit if disturbed will bite.
I will be working as a police officer.
Arrogant little brat.
Seonbae, I didn't expect
we will meet again.
It is also true.
If talent remarkably buried
will be a pity.
Yes, I am a rather noisy person.
Certainly,
let's work the best.
Yes, yes.
Applause!
What?
Why?
With the uniform look,
she said what is it?
I yes look.
What do you mean?
I often hear people say that.
That my good looks
undisputed.
I say bath man pesticides.
Indeed why?
I hope you can distinguish
personal affairs and work.
No, just...
to say your face shows
your liver is not good.
Your skin looks yellow.
Provide a list of evidence
the case of Han Sang Goo.
Yes!
This.
- This course?
- That's all that we receive.
The rest of it?
There are still some in his room.
I'll take it.
Room Han Sang-Goo
just cleaned.
Where?
The place of burning in the church.
-=Church Cheon In=-
What happened?
Get out of the way.
Welcome.
-=Alain de Botton,
"Why do I love you?"=-
This book So In.
I buy you for a birthday gift.
-=Willing to give compensation takes 50 million Won=-
Sought a missing child, the name: Lee Soo Yi.
Before So In was killed
he is looking for a missing child.
The lost child?
-=Byeol find Popeye
Apollo=-
Byeol.
Apollo.
Byeol, do not forget.
his Name...
of Apollo.
Popeye waiting for you.
Popeye?
Popeye really there.
It's me.
Why So In search of a child
the face is similar like you?
There again...
The name of the Apollo how do you know?
Who Is Popeye?
Actually, who are you?
I don't know.
What actually happened?
At the age of 7 years were you ever lost?
No.
Actually, I don't remember at all.
Hello.
Ah, hello.
Long time no see.
Yes, please.
What his election smoothly?
Everywhere I'm talking about You.
Politicians where can dream again?
The owners of this country will never change
this is just meet the wishes of the people.
I want to invite You
in a comfortable hotel.
Why even...
choose a simple place like this.
This place is also comfortable.
Had stood 40 years.
I don't care about people or restaurant
over time scent
new will smell.
Change the brand, change the people that are communicative.
Like this less is better.
This person
his feelings are very deep.
Your daughter how?
Well, thanks to You all.
I heard...
the dead girl
her oppa so crazy.
Yes, Chun Jae In.
A police officer.
That makes other people cranky that a yes?
He pursuing Han Sang-Goo
for the past 2 years.
In addition, he back on duty
in the police force.
I'm curious why You just shut up.
Actually, we can stop it
restored.
Tripang this...
so someone wants to eat it
will spew the organ itself.
[Open ulcers own]
When the enemy offers take
the innards
he could run away again.
Nothing to do with his shell.
Then...
what if he's investigating
the past?
The doctrine of article 13 of the said
During the mouth closed
people could survive.
that can not, will perish.
Watch your mouth.
Oh, you came.
Already had dinner?
Why the sudden see the photos?
Appa, what I've lost?
What are you talking about?
Well, last I saw
ads of missing children.
She's like me.
His name is...
Soo Yi.
Just like times.
The age is the same.
You're just all lost in the pool.
In addition to it's never.
Yes, aren't you?
Certainly not me.
Oh, yes.
Anyways, his hair is long.
But, Appa.
Why do I always wear the same clothes the man?
Appa wanted a son?
There is a saying
"sex change so I can live."
So that can grow up healthy.
Really superstitious.
You're that sickly.
Whether superstition or not
must necessarily be carried out.
Born sickly
Appa raised you.
Tell me my childhood.
If you drink milk,
you vomiting and crying.
All the photos taken that time
only the doll is filthy.
It is very unfortunate lost
when we moved in.
Images before the age of 7 years.
> > Just this one only.
Album picture is missing
what really just happened?
Your father said what?
Of course I'm not.
Kidnapping, kidnapped, lost
at all never.
How is she?
I check it out.
I think I know.
Doppelganger.
Do you mean in other parts of the world.
There is someone like you...
Doppelganger?
Yes.
You know Goethe?
A writer from Germany.
When still young
he met with his doppelganger.
I read in his autobiography.
But he said that 2 doppelganger meet
one of them will die.
Hey, why are you dead?
Of course, to make sure
we should check his DNA.
Not long ago I downloaded the application.
I can find my doppelganger.
You want to try?
How could you look smarter?
My Doppelganger is a superstition Germany
you know what?
The police criminal investigation kok yes believe
on superstition abroad.
Yes, write use red ink.
-=Chun Jae In=-
Do not written.
Don't write.
He said don't believe.
[Note: By adding scratches, so in other words]
But moodku more ugly.
Lately because someone
I experience things that don't make sense.
But...
Looks like he's from a rich family.
Return...
1993, dare to give 50 million won.
A large amount.
True.
So In looking for a lost child.
Why did the kid look like you?
Kim And.
Come on.
Where?
Investigate.
D
Da
Dam
Damn
Damn!
Damn!S
Damn!Su
Damn!Soup
Damn!Super
Damn!SuperS
Damn!SuperSu
Damn!SuperSub
Damn!SuperSub I
Damn!SuperSub In
Damn!SuperSub Ind
Damn!SuperSub Indo
Damn!SuperSub .
Damn!SuperSub T
Damn!SuperSub Indonesia
Translated by:
~ Ifabee ~
Wait a minute.
December 1994.
This.
Why?
What is it?
The record investigation no.
Only the last page.
True.
-=Name: Kang Cheol Gu.=-
That handles this case how?
This person already died
a few years ago.
-=Kim Seon Ja=-
=The number You call
already not active.=
Number of the guardian is not active.
Where the guardian Kim Seon Ja?
Can give you the address now?
Please wait a minute.
There is a tear of the paper.
True.
What accidentally torn out?
Who would dare to tear
records of the investigation?
Well, this is.
There is a small island in there.
-=Jollanamdo, Namdong-gun, Jami-myeon=-
Her name is Jami-do.
Thank you.
Sorry,
2 years ago, what there is a female reporter here?
He is looking for the same child.
Ah, I remember that reporter.
He said he was going to the island.
I got to talk to.
Not now.
Go home, at home.
So In.
Actually what are you doing?
Captain.
Aigoo.
How much?
-=Jami-do, Day 1=-
Oh, mainland, mainland.
Oh, there Hainan.
Let's eat fruit!
This, this.
Too heavy for you.
Aigoo, Chong-gak(young).
What are you doing?
Here, bring it.
Oh, so strong.
Aigoo.
Sorry, Ajumeoni.
You know Kim Seon Ja?
Ah, Kim Seon Ja.
Ah, that Wolguk.
Already a few years ago
he don't live here.
He moved?
Moved where?
He cheated with a man people.
Where possible
he said move on where?
Why want to Wolguk?
We from the Police station in Seoul.
We would ask him.
Are you guys the police?
Yes.
20 years ago, he lost his daughter, right?
His daughter?
Princess what?
She had no children.
When diving for shells,
he was brain dead.
Her husband died after a long lay ill.
Oh, that's why he cheated.
Strange.
The child was like this.
Kim Seon Ja guardian.
You don't know?
Don't know.
This is the first time I saw it.
Hey, who is this child?
This is the first time we saw it.
Beautiful.
Settlement Wolguk it
exactly where?
From here, go straight follow the road that
you'll find home
the roof is red.
Of course it's empty.
Come on, you two.
Because ship-to-3 this
the last ship.
If there is no ship,
we will be staying.
It's no hassle.
For young people like you
definitely not convenient.
Anyway this isn't a tourist destination.
I've been having a difficult thing
it doesn't matter.
Thank you.
Aigoo, she must fall in love with the girl.
See.
Why the sudden change?
I often see in the movies.
Swank missed the boat.
Break it first, new go.
Shut the fuck up.
I only test the reaction.
Reaction of what?
Don't look back.
Continue to course.
The fuck?
They...
I feel there is unnatural.
They are right the inhabitants of the village.
We'll see.
What you don't resonate with something in here?
What?
Feel the middle of reminisce.
Or the view is no stranger yes.
Not at all.
Ah, it's him.
It looks like a really blurry
in the last night.
Don't like people who give
prize of 50 million.
And no children.
Continue to why is he so her guardian?
This news 1994.
Everything is using that to close the window.
The yes live in exile?
What this guy ran off with his neighbor?
Seonbae, see this.
Now what?
The record investigation no.
The child, the guardian is also not there.
His house abandoned.
Come on.
Where?
There are drinks like this?
Stuff from the 90s.
The date of expiration of the same.
That's why I collect junk
from Wokguk.
Certainly, the boy was lost in 1994.
Did something happen on this island?
Maybe this trip will be even longer.
Your rifle there is a permit?
None of your business.
It is the task of my profession.
I'm a cop.
I have a permit.
Or You could make sure of it.
What do You do with that rifle
in this small island?
Because there is always a boar
down the mountain.
You two be careful.
There are people?
Grandma.
Ah...
I want to ask you something.
I thought who...
You're back.
Son.
I?
But...
What are you doing here?
What?
Aigoo.
A child who has supernatural powers
don't wander off.
Grandma, You know me?
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Where possible I don't know you?
Both of you!
You are the owner of this inn?
The air is cold, come on in.
You want to stay?
Yes.
30,000 won.
He Your Mother?
Alzheimer's Disease.
Anyone he met
he felt know.
I rented 2 rooms.
In this village, how many families?
22 the head of the family.
Around 60 people.
Seems like a lot of the move.
I was here after the financial crisis.
The pond here is broken because of the hurricane.
Not bad.
Yes.
Towel.
Thank you.
"Get off this island!
Fast."
What does that mean?
-=Go from this island! Fast!=-
He insisted didn't know.
It looks like a warning.
I feel bad.
I don't think I could stay on this island.
There is no way.
The last ship was gone.
Hey, you guys.
It...
Yeonsang-nim invite you
dinner together.
Aigoo.
Seafood...
Have a drink.
I don't drink.
Fill your cup, and drink it.
True.
Come on.
I'll take it.
Yes, yes,
Come on.
You guys,
they this 2 a guest from Seoul.
Let's toast the guests in Seoul.
Oh, yes.
For guests in Seoul.
- Cheers.
Toast.
Drink, drink.
Aigoo.
Oh, delish.
Let's eat.
Try the scallops.
Good.
Yes.
Hey,
Eat fish don't be reversed.
If you turn it over
this island will be reversed.
Therefore if you eat fish
don't ever be reversed.
I'm sorry.
It's all superstition.
People like us fishermen
dependent life
from the sea.
Superstition?
Not superstition, but faith.
The era of our first, had a boy
One thousand forty two
like the birth of bait fish.
Because work on the boat
always throw the bait.
Aigoo, don't digress.
Gala day this how?
Yes, yes.
What is it?
You don't know?
Based on the lunar month this day
is the 'Hungry Ghost'.
'The Hungry Ghosts'?
Yes...
This.
1 month 16, month calendar.
According to the dating of the East
on January 16 no activities of any kind.
Don't take any objects from the wood.
should a warning of death.
He said the bottom of the clothes
can be stained with eve ghost.
So they don't get out of the house.
The ship also did not go to sea.
Even at night
they hide his shoes.
If the ghosts come and wear your shoes.
Then in between your family
there is someone who will die soon.
Hey.
Fear yes?
Makes your skin crawl.
Aigoo.
Be careful when sleeping.
Chong-gak(young).
Oh, yes. Well so, have a drink.
Let's drink again, Chong-gak.
Aigoo.
Come drink, eat again.
Ghost, ghost.
There is a ghost, a ghost.
What is it?
Ghost.
A-I see ghosts.
Ghost-ghost it even take
my shoes.
Ghost?
Where?
What are you looking for?
Tomorrow morning, we go.
Ah, basic.
Shoes.
In-in there.
You see?
You scared me.
You go first.
Can't.
Where are you going?
Let's go back.
Come with me.
What is this?
Grandma.
Out cold, Grandma.
Made the blanket and go to sleep.
If so, we excuse me.
They are... condemned.
What?
Who are they?
I'm trying to stop them.
Dangje want abolished.
[Dangje : a kind of ritual worship to the gods]
Dangjib even already destroyed.
[Dangjib: place of worship of the gods]
By whom?
Their own.
He said the day of judgment will come.
Said so repeatedly
then they were all dead.
Sorry...
Grandma.
What...
You know him?
Soo Yi.
True.
Who is he?
Halmeoninya mudang(shaman) number wahid
in this village.
Want to ask how good
first ship in our area this
though the rain storm
we can go through safely.
This child
now where is it?
If it...
Soo Yi...
What are you doing?
Ah
I thought you guys left.
Grandma keluyuan outside
so I delivered him home.
Due to her living a lot of.
Okay, Ma'am.
Go to sleep.
If so, we excuse me.
Ah yes.
I have few bottles of makgeolli.
Get some rest.
Excuse me..
What my Mother didn't say anything?
The trial, the plague...
that's what he said.
Crazy.
Why?
I can't explain.
And tomorrow, go ride a ship the first.
Note that, You wrote it, right?
Kim Sajang!
My light die.
Yes, yes.
I'll fix it.
what is it with this island?
Again...
view it again
in my dreams.
instinctively I know...
never looked back.
Appa.
-=Island Jami=-
Having come to this island
I understand.
Maybe I'm not
who discovered the island.
But the island was calling me.
no signal.
If you don't have a ship
this island will be like
"Chamber Of Secrets".
-=Jami-do-Day-2=-
Damn!SuperSub Indonesia Facebook Fanpage:
facebook.com/DamnSuperSubIndo
Visit the blog Damn!SuperSub Indonesia at:
~ ngesub.com ~
~ Follow us on twitter: @DSSIndo @ngesub
and look forward to the next episode. ~
-=Next Episode Preview=-
We're on this island
not a coincidence.
hide these people
we have to find out.
All there's the connection.
Everything.
Actually, who are we fighting?
First we want to tell
instead you want to be killed.
You dig up some graves.
I know.
When I grow up
every day I'll have a drink.
Boy of the woman, Soo Yi.