He's lying.
This son of a bitch
has been playing us the whole time.
- No. No, wait.
- You really think we're that dumb? Huh?
- No, I didn't say
- Easy. I didn't say-
No! No!
Dream, send me a sign
Turn back the clock
Give me some time
I need to break out
Make a new name
Let's open our eyes
To the brand-new day
Expenses and overtime are two areas
we should really take a look at.
And we should consider changing
our company investments portfolio.
- You've started dating again, haven't you? Yeah.
- Oh, stop it, Cal. Right now.
- Right. Um, stockbroker?
Money manager? Banker?
Oh, I thought you wanted to have some fun.
- Oh, I'm having fun. Don't you worry.
- Oh, yeah?
Yes, Torres?
Uh, there's a visitor in your office.
Sally Robinson from London.
What?
- Whoa. Sally who?
- Uh, Robinson.
High school sweetheart or something?
- In my office?
- Uh-huh.
Gotcha!
- God Almighty.
- Yeah, but my mates still call me Terry.
Come here.
Sally Robinson, eh? Hello.
Is that a canoe in your pocket there, Cal?
- Nicely played there, Mia.
- Ria.
- Oh, well. Thank you anyway.
- Mm-hmm.
Excuse his manners.
Terry Marsh, his ex-partner in crime.
- In a manner of speaking.
- Gillian Foster, current partner in crime.
- Nice to meet you, Terry.
- You too.
All right. That's enough of that.
Good-bye, Dr. Foster.
Wow, Cal, that is so charming.
Well, it's been 22 years, hasn't it?
Listen, Jill, you fancy
meeting us for a drink later?
It's Gillian, actually. And she's busy.
- I'll take it.
- Call me if you need me.
- Listen-
- Oil
Yes.
Who we drinking to?
Um, how 'bout Sally Robinson,
wherever she may be?
You wanker.
- You all right there, Terry?
- Don't start that bollocks with me, Cal.
- What?
- With the eyes, like you're reading my fortune.
I'm just pleased to see you, really.
Though a touch curious as to why now.
Well, truth be told, I've thought twice
about looking you up loads of times.
Terry Marsh thinking twice.
Well, that's a first, innit?
- Come on.
- Come on where?
I tell you what, Cal.
I'll do a deal with you.
What's past is past. What's done is done.
It's just all...
water under the bridge. Fair?
Uh- Water under the bridge then.
Oh. Hello, lovely lady.
- I'm Terry.
- Hi.
- You should say hello to my dad.
- Hi, Dad. I'm Kara.
- This is Alice.
- Stage names?
Oh, down, Dad, down. Forgive him.
Right?
Oh, feast your eyes. Hey, Cal.
No. Not that way.
Over there, son.
- I don't play cards anymore.
- Look at me very carefully, Cal.
I did not get this jailbird for nothing.
Don't make me say it.
I owe you my life.
There you go. I said it.
Do this for me tonight,
and then we're all square.
- How much do you owe 'em?
- Twelve large.
- Twelve grand?
- It'll be like the old days, you know?
- I'll do all the talking, and you do the-
- Yeah, yeah, science. Yeah.
Yeah, well- It's Texas hold 'em, no limit...
and this is my last two grand
in the world.
- Right.
- Cheers. Come on.
I think I've had
a bit too much to drink for this, Terry.
Yeah. Well, that's rubbish. But nice try.
Hey, Terry.
You're feeling' luckier tonight?
Hey, gents. An old mate of mine,
Harry Sloan from N.Y.C.
How you doin'?
Hey, Foster. Have you seen Lightman?
He's taking a personal day.
Yeah, he's with a man who's on
a Scotland Yard watch list...
which means when he's over here,
he's on an F.B.I. watch list.
It's part of the special relationship
with the Brits.
What's Terry done wrong?
Nothing recently. Watch lists
are more precautionary than anything else.
Yet your tone is telling me
it's more than just a heads-up.
Then it should also be telling you that
I'm not at liberty to discuss this any further.
"G.B.H. Grievous Bodily Harm. "
Twenty-two years ago?
They want you to dig into
Lightman's past with Terry?
Let's just say it's his immediate future
I'm more worried about.
Thousand.
I fold.
Call.
Thousand.
You okay, Terry?
I'm good for it, Lance. You know I am.
I know you are. We're all gentlemen here.
Someone get this man a drink.
Thanks.
Call.
All in.
- I said-
- I heard you the first time.
Call.
Ten high.
You called me on a jack high?
That's ridiculous.
Apparently not.
Gentlemen, it's been a pleasure.
Listen, could we have, um,
a little break, please?
Just a minute, huh?
Why not? Order up some eggs.
Cheers.
Do you mind?
Harry Sloan from
New York City? You're out of your bloody mind.
Quiet!
I could hardly say you're Dr. Lightman...
the lie expert and the reader
of faces, now could I?
So the 12 grand was just a teaser
to get me in the game, is that it?
How much do you owe this psychopath? Oil
- How much?
- Ninety-five.
- Ninety-five grand?
- Yeah.
You expect me to take that kind of money
off these men...
instead of just walking out of here
while I still can?
- 'Scuse me.
- Hey. No, no, no, no.
Cal. You know exactly
what's gonna happen to me if you walk away.
So is this a prank
or a serious death threat?
Very soon now, you will all be sorry.
It's all gonna end this week.
The pain will stop.
Uniforms. Private school?
Uh, college preparatory.
You the only one this video was sent to,
Mr. Anders?
As far as I know. It was, uh, left
on my desk during the lunch hour...
in an envelope marked
"Headmaster. Urgent. "
Has anyone else seen the tape?
Just the F.B.I.- and now you.
- Have you closed the school?
- School’s out for the rest of today.
- My first piece of advice to you, close the school.
- For how long?
Until we determine who made this.
So indefinitely.
Dr. Foster, do you realize what that would
do to us? That would ruin our school.
So this is about money?
From handwriting analysis
on the envelopes, student files...
locker searches and security camera tapes...
agents on site were able to make a preliminary
list of students who might fit the profile.
Twenty-five names?
Fit the profile for what?
- Homicidal intent.
- Oh, God.
First of all, hands up,
who's heard of the Lightman Group?
All right. Well, we are scientists
who interpret human emotions.
And this morning, with your help...
I'm gonna run an experiment,
which should be quite informative.
So rather than listen to me drone on all day,
let's just get started, shall we?
Very soon now, you will all be sorry.
It's all gonna end this week.
The pain will stop.
No one's that good.
You two are working together.
Who is he, Terry? You cheating me?
'Cause I will put a bullet in your head.
There's 105 grand there.
You and Terry are even now.
You keep the change.
We're all gentlemen here.
At least for now,
with all those witnesses in the next room.
I said he keeps the change.
Mate, say something.
You're welcome. Don't mention it.
I love you, Cal. Don't forget that.
Yeah. I'll see you in another 22 years.
Mount Vernon Square.
Rough night, huh?
- Yup. No rest for the wicked.
- Yeah.
Something tells me you already know that.
You want to know what else I know?
You know your buddy, Terry Marsh?
Spent three years
in Belmarsh Prison in England-
'87 to '90- for assault and battery.
Yeah. It was a long time ago.
And he's gone now, and I'm tired...
and I'm hung over,
and it's none of your business.
No. You made it my business
when you spent the night...
at the penthouse suite at the Park Hotel...
where there were prostitutes
and illegal gambling.
Those women were prostitutes?
How did you know?
Did you follow us? That's interesting.
There. Surprise and shame
in less than a second, then nothing.
Pulling down the mask.
Put her on the list.
- Hey.
Oh. Go back a few seconds, would you?
There you go. Right. See this girl?
Same girl. She glances at the teacher.
There you go. See?
And he catches her eye. Yeah?
He's got his eye on her for some reason.
So does this girl here. Look.
Then she looks over at that guy.
Nice one, Loker.
Soon you'll be asking me for a raise,
which I've been assured that we can't afford.
So... stand down.
Right. Well, keep watching the tape then.
- Be back in a minute.
- You look awful.
And yet, I feel so much worse.
I said 22 years, not 22 minutes.
We're in a lot of trouble, Cal.
They know who you are and what you do...
- and they ain't happy.
- What do they want?
They want to see you saw a girl in half.
What do you think they want?
They want you to be their magic man...
and they're waiting for you
around the corner, in a van.
And if you don't come now,
then... I'm done.
As in "dead" done.
- Yeah, I'll see what I can find out from him.
- Hey.
Hey. Your buddy's lost his F.B.I. tail.
- Now, do you have any clue on where he could be right now?
- Yeah. Come with me.
- He's in my office.
- He's in your office?
- Yep.
- What the hell is he doin' in there?
- I've got a major bloody problem here.
- You're damn right, you do.
You do understand that Terry's involved
with an extremely dangerous criminal, right?
- Lance McClellan.
- Lance McClellan. Exactly.
He's a new-school crime boss- educated,
well connected, hidden in plain sight.
This ends now.
Look, Terry's family to me. There's no way
I'm gonna let him hang himself.
- I'm not gonna let him hang you, either.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
- What's McClellan’s game?
- It depends.
Which means you don't know, right?
That means that you're gonna help me
help Terry to help you.
If anyone's helping anyone here...
it's gonna be you helping to bring down
McClellan and Terry.
And I know he's your friend,
but those guys are bad sons of bitches.
Look, McClellan sent Terry for me, which
means he needs something from me, right?
And whatever it is, he needs it quick.
If you're suggesting what I think you're
suggesting, you can forget it, okay?
You're not a trained undercover agent.
- Knock it off. I'm doing this.
- Not if I arrest you, you're not.
- You're gonna arrest me?
- Yeah.
I won over a hundred grand
in cards last night.
- I know a bluff when I see one.
You're not arresting me.
And you keep Foster out of this, all right?
- Okay.
- Her focus needs to be 100% on that school.
And I'm banking on you
to have my back for this.
- Oh, you mean like a real F.B.I. agent.
- Something like that, yeah.
Hey. So we're meeting
in the conference room.
- Torres is in there with three kids from the school.
- All right.
- So... what's wrong?
- Nothing.
Look, Reynolds was just
telling me what a bad seed Terry was...
and it came as a bit of a shock...
'cause there was I,
thinking that he was a choirboy.
All right.
Stand up. Stand up. Stand up.
All right. When'd you make the video?
- What? I-
- What's your name again?
- I didn't make it.
- Exploding buildings.
- That was news footage, right? Your name is-
- Stacey.
- I-I don't know. Probably. I couldn't-
I'm the one who made that video.
- Jared?
- Jared Rollins is my name.
I made the video.
Get your hands out of your pockets.
So what's the plan, eh?
This a bombing or a shooting or what?
'Cause you know
there always is a plan, right?
You tell me.
So when did you make the video, Jared?
- What does it matter? - Well, I-I thought
it would've mattered a great deal to you.
I made the video.
That's all you need to know.
Well, who did you send it to?
What?
That stall right there?
He's Lying. He didn't make it.
Jared, why would you lie
about making that video?
Because maybe they all deserve to die,
or at least worry about it.
- Who?
- They know who they are.
If he didn't make the video,
he sure wishes he had.
His face, body language-
That's homicidal intent, right?
Yeah.
- Your name is-
- Stacey.
Stacey. That was news footage?
I- I don't know. Probably.
- I'm the one who made the video.
- Jared?
Jared Rollins is my name.
Okay. When he said he made the video...
he deliberately interrupted Stacey.
Yeah. She's relieved.
He's covering for her.
He's protecting her.
Oh, nice shirt. Help yourself?
I thought you'd fallen in.
Right now, that'd be a quality problem.
How's your hand?
Ah, it's all right.
I don't normally approve of torture,
but in your case, as it's personal-
What's going on, Terry?
Eh? What's going on?
You all right? You all right?
You remember those, uh-
- the property flips we used to do back in London?
- Yeah.
I only broke in and sold
the wrong man's Miami mansion.
But it turns out-
he was connected.
Answer the question, all right? All right?
- What you draggin' me into?
- I don't-
- Huh? Eh?
- I don't know. I swear to God, Cal. I do not know.
Well, come on then.
Thank you.
Oh, shut up.
So the video...
even though you didn't make it,
does speak to your needs.
And which is partly
why you took false credit.
And you say they deserve to die,
but you're clearly scared to name them.
Loker, take Jared
back to the conference room.
I need to talk to Stacey now.
We're done.
Where's Lightman?
He's not in his office. We keep calling,
but it's going straight to voice mail.
Where could he be? That's not like him.
- Will you keep trying?
- Yeah.
All right. Let's go.
Hold up till we get the door.
Straight ahead.
Dr. Lightman. Good of you to come.
- I warn you, I'm not cheap.
- Oh. Terry's life cover it?
Barely.
We have a deal then.
I like to think
of all of my people as family...
but one of these three has been informing
on me to the government.
Now you're going to tell me
for certain which one is the rat.
- What, so you can kill the man?
- Three minutes, Dr. Lightman.
All right then.
All right, boys?
Well, you're right.
There is a liar in the room.
Liar's you.
What are you doing?
- Now's not the time to play
the comedian, all right?
- Get up.
- Just give him one more chance.
He won't let you down. Will you?
None of these men is an informer!
But you already knew that, didn't you? Eh?
Good.
Yeah. Told you he was the best, didn't I?
Yeah. What I want to know is
when you told him that, Terry?
Was it last night?
Last week? Last month?
Quiet, ladies.
Nice one, Terry.
Stacey, are you and- and Jasmine friends?
The exact same look she showed
for Jasmine in class- contempt.
She's mean to me- in P.E...
in the locker room.
But she's not the only one. I hate P.E.
Well, did you tell your teacher?
He knows.
Stacey, I wish I didn't
have to ask you this...
but do you ever wish Jasmine, or any of
the other kids who were mean to you, harm?
Harm? Like-
You think I made
that video, and that it was-
I may have thought about revenge, but...
I don't want them to die.
She's telling the truth.
She doesn't want to harm anyone.
Please don't tell Jasmine I told on her.
Oh, sweetie, uh-
Maybe she is the one who made the video...
and all this is her fantasy revenge.
Uh, who's the P.E. teacher?
- Why?
- It's not you, is it?
Yeah, but I would never
turn a blind eye to bullying if I saw it.
Did you know that these kids
were picking on Stacey?
Well, I could see
she wasn't the most popular.
- Is Jasmine popular?
- Yeah, I'd say so. Very, actually.
It's always the popular ones
who think they can get away with murder.
- Spoken like a true scientist.
- Trust me. I just know.
We should get Jasmine in there now.
So, you two go back a ways.
Well, I'm sure Terry's
told you all about it.
Property scams.
You picked out the easy marks.
Terry took 'em for everything they had.
Yeah. If that's how Terry remembers it.
I remember you were the business
at picking out just the right mark.
I mean, he was
the absolute bloody business. I swear.
Hmm. Terry tells me that you owe him
your life, Dr. Lightman. Tell me about that.
I thought it was water under the bridge.
Even so. While we're waiting.
Well, suffice to say, we were, um,
West Ham supporters at a Millwall game.
He saved you from soccer hooligans.
- Manner of speaking.
- Or... were you two the hooligans?
Not guilty, Your Honor.
You see that look, Terry?
That look says that your time
on this planet is running out.
Yeah. Put a cork in it, Cal,
all right? That's enough.
See, it's always the same, the criminal mind,
you know? Never sees the end of the road.
Forever hoping, often actually believing
that there'll be just one more corner to turn.
Not his fault.
He's not the only one.
I'm basically wired the same way.
Right.
They're on their way. Five minutes out.
- Who?
- The man that you're gonna meet with...
see if he's on the level or not
before I do business with him.
- Call him back. Cancel it.
- Excuse me?
- What?
- Look out the window.
Right. There's an F.B.I. tail out there.
They've been on Terry
like a cheap suit since he landed.
Don't play games, Professor.
You can thank me later.
Show me.
- See it?
- The blue one.
No, not- not the blue one. The other one.
The one over from it.
The red one. The red station wagon.
Might as well have had a blue light
flashing on top, know what I mean?
Call back. Change the meet
to the warehouse.
Get up!
A lot of people think that it's just
the victims of bullies who get hurt.
But the bullies pay a price too.
You know, maybe not physically, but-
We were just joking around at first.
Yeah? About what? Stacey's weight?
That and-
Uh- I can't explain.
It got out of control.
- I'm so sorry.
- Are you, though?
It wasn't just me. There are others.
If that video means what I think it means...
then it's all coming to an end.
The pain- her pain, mine. I wish it would.
I hate myself for what I did to Stacey,
but I couldn't stop.
- He didn't want us to.
- "He" meaning you.
- Hmm?
- And you still mean to tell me...
you had no idea this was going on?
I can't be everywhere all the time.
Ducks the question
while grabbing for an excuse.
Yeah. Classic deflection.
If Stacey made that video,
it's because of me.
- Where's Stacey?
- She went to the bathroom.
- How long ago?
- Few minutes.
More like 10, I think.
Stacey?
Stacey!
Stacey. Come on. Open up now, please.
- Stacey.
- I can't find a pulse.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I missed it. It wasn't homicidal intent.
I misread the sadness.
It was suicidal intent.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah, I need an ambulance.
Bring her around the alley!
All right. Let's go.
But stay three cars behind.
Dr. Powers, I. C. U.-
- The parents have been contacted, right?
- It's been taken care of.
Tell me she's gonna be okay.
- Wait out here.
- Monitor's on the way.
She's gonna be okay.
Go!
Stay here. Talk amongst yourselves.
- Was there really an F.B.I. tail?
- Yep.
- And you just ditched them?
- Yeah. To earn his trust.
Oh, well, that worked like a charm, Cal.
We got blindfolds and locked doors.
Are we even yet, Terry?
Are we ever gonna be even in your eyes?
You think that's what this is about-
it's about who's even with who?
That's a bit rich coming from you, mate.
Oi, mate. I did three years
in prison, saving your ass.
So what have I gotta do?
Die to save yours?
You should've come to me in the first place.
You should've been honest with me.
You should've said,
"Cal, I'm in a bit of bother...
could use some help from
a friend I know I can count on. "
- And you would've done what?
- I don't know. I'd have done something!
- Anything's better than this.
- I haven't heard from you in over 20 years, mate.
Over 20 years!
Why was that?
Let's just face it here. You wanted
the past dead, and me along with it.
Apology accepted, by the way.
Where the hell is Lightman?
My financial adviser, Harry Sloan.
How do you do?
I see you two already know each other.
Well, any-
any friend of Terry's is a friend of mine.
So, pleasantries out of the way.
Let's get down to the heart of the matter,
shall we?
The merchandise, Mr. Jones. You say
it is the best ever- flawless, in fact.
I gave you my word. Man to man.
See, now, that's why I'm here.
- Yes or no questions, they only go so far.
- Uh-huh?
So... how flawless is the merchandise?
The currency is perfect.
There's a flicker of doubt there...
but that might just be
about the deal in general.
I mean, "perfect counterfeit currency. "
That's an oxymoron
if ever I heard one, right?
What is this sideshow, huh?
He's telling the truth, though,
when he says that the counterfeit's perfect.
He truly- He does believe that.
But then again, he's just, uh-
He's what's-his-name, uh,
down at the U.N. all over again, right?
Uh, excuse me?
That guy, he truly did believe
all that W. M.D. nonsense.
So, cleverly, they sent him off
down to the U.N. to sell it.
Rest is history.
No one sent me here.
The currency... is flawless.
Nah. Uh-
I mean, I'm sorry,
but it's not good enough.
Who is this ass, huh?
Screw him. Let's go.
We're not done yet.
- No! You swore to me that you wouldn't-
- Hey, hey!
Is he telling the truth,
Dr. Lightman? Yes or no?
Yes! Well, he believes that he is, yes.
Good. So do we have a deal or not, huh?
Is this the best you got,
Professor Lightman?
Because so far, I'm underwhelmed.
Or is there more?
Right. Well, you put me in front
of the actual counterfeiter...
with the bank notes in his hands...
and I'll know
just how good his product is.
Just you. Terry can stay here.
No. Terry's with me.
It's not negotiable.
- No. I'll be all right.
- Don't be daft.
- You need to be thinking about yourself right now.
- Yeah, now you tell me.
It's not negotiable.
Come on!
Say nothin', Terry. Not a word.
This is him?
It's your counterfeiter, right?
The best there is.
Fifty thousand Euros, right there.
Bloody hell.
- How many containers you got?
- That is not your concern.
Put it back.
All right, um- What's your name?
- He doesn't need to know that.
- I've got to establish a baseline here-
easy answers to easy questions.
- Then I can get to the bigger questions.
- Otto.
- Hammil.
What's your real last name?
- Frankel.
- Yeah.
- How many kids you got?
- None.
- How long you been married?
- I'm not married.
- Where you from?
- Chicago.
Hey, get on with it, please, will you?
All right. Um, these notes
are counterfeit, right?
- Yes.
- How good are they?
We already tested a modest amount
without detection.
- Well, Dr. Lightman?
- What?
Well, he hasn't answered my question yet.
Easy, fellas. It's taken care of.
He was right. F.B.I.
- Okay.
- I don't think I can do this.
I'll be right here
the whole time. Don't worry.
Just take your time, Stacey.
You knew what they were
doing to me, Mr. Fitzgerald.
You didn't just ignore it...
you started it all.
- Oh, Stacey-
- You kept telling me...
I was fat and lazy in front of them.
- The-That's not true.
- Your hands and eyes say otherwise.
So do I.
I'm so sorry, Stacey.
You know, I had a coach like you once...
who had it in
for one of the kids on the team.
Constant verbal abuse
disguised as authority.
Eddie, Eddie Johnston. And nothin' that
Eddie ever did was ever good enough.
- You're out of line.
- And the example that that coach set for the rest of us...
just like you did for Jasmine
and all of her buddies...
we thought it gave us the license
to make Eddie an outcast.
I never touched a hair on her head.
Right. Because we did it for you.
I wanted you to have to live
the rest of your life-
knowing that what you did to me made me-
You knew what this
was really about all the time.
I know, because I sent you a video too.
Which you, uh,
neglected to mention, Mr. Fitzgerald.
Making you guilty
of obstruction of justice.
And if this keeps you
away from kids forever, I'll take it.
Right, Stacey?
Yeah.
Wait a minute. One kid has a-
has a psychological breakdown...
an illness, and I'm to blame?
- Come on. We need to-
- I don't-
Thank you.
Well, there's a whitening
of the skin around the eyes...
which is a dead giveaway for the kind
of fear that we try to hide when we lie.
And, uh, slight rotation of the right arm...
which is what we call in the trade
a shrug fragment, which means...
he's got zero confidence
in what he just said.
The eyes of a cheat...
who thinks he has all the cards...
but who knows I'm telling the truth.
Well, he's Lying.
This son of a bitch has been
playin' us the whole time.
Whoa. Easy. No, I didn't say-
- You really think we're that dumb?
- Easy. No, I didn't say-
No, no!
F.B.I.! Nobody move!
Anybody else?
Down on your knees! Now!
Move! Move! Down!
On your knees! Do it!
How'd you do that?
- Blanks.
- Blanks?
No, no, I mean with your eyes.
How do you do that?
Oh, it was... just practice.
What's going on?
- Get up.
- Oh, blimey.
Put your hands behind your back.
I swear, I'm gettin'
too old for this, Terry. I really am.
F.B.I. have been onto you
and McClellan for a while now.
- Special Agent Hutton.
- Oh, nice to meet you.
You too. Superior work, Agent Reynolds.
Likewise, my friend.
So, how's that for having your back?
Just like a real F.B.I. agent.
- Thanks a lot, Cal.
- What?
So, uh- When'd you first
realize I was undercover, Dr. Lightman?
Back at the poker table.
You were angry and fearful,
but on my behalf.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Come on. Let's go.
Ben? Hold on a sec.
I tell you what.
Terry walks for his part in this.
- What?
- And then we're evens.
You know I couldn't
have done this without him.
He goes from here to the airport,
and he doesn't come back.
- Suits me.
- Ever.
You know, you're one lucky son of a bitch.
Hey. Hey, um- Can I borrow him
for a minute? Just personal stuff.
Yeah. Just- Just make it-
quick.
I knew you were up to something
the moment you walked into my office!
Then I had to sit there and watch you play
me like one of those yuppies back in London!
McClellan had me
by the short and curliest, Cal.
- My best mate!
- Oh, come on! You think I wanted to do it?
You were in on this from the start, Terry!
They knew who I was before I even sat down
at that poker table.
What was that?
That was just some little test run.
- So what do you call this, eh?
- That?
A couple of broken fingers
for a slice of that pie? Do me a favor.
And you can stop treating me
like a bloody moron now.
Yeah, well, maybe I just
came to resent you, Cal.
Hate me, more like. Eh?
Years will do that, Terry.
You saw all the way through it, didn't you?
You saw right through it from the start.
Still helped me though,
didn't you? You know why?
'Cause you always have been
and you always will be my best mate.
Don't count on it, all right?
I'll tell you what.
My debt is now paid in full.
No. Wait a sec. Wait a sec.
You owe me now.
Yeah, I saved your bacon,
and I covered your ass with the F.B.I.
I'm a very lucky man.
Yeah.
Well, all luck is earned, in the end.
Well, go on, then. Off you go.
Don't you dare look back!
Hi.
- Have a seat.
- Why?
- This is an intervention.
- What?
All right. So I had a, you know,
few drinks with a mate.
- Yeah, well- More than a few, actually.
- This isn't about drinking.
Well, then if it's about poker,
I won a hundred grand.
- Hundred grand?
- Uh, hundred and five, actually.
It's not about gambling either.
- What is it about then?
- It's about you trusting us.
You were in trouble,
and you never came to us.
- Wait a minute.
- No, you wait.
We're a team, and you risked your life
without letting us help you.
Look, I wouldn't be here at all
if it wasn't for Terry Marsh.
Fine. So where does that leave us?
- That leaves you all fired.
- You gotta be kidding.
- I didn't even want to do this intervention thing.
- Just you then.
Just you are fired- for having no spine.
- I don't believe this.
- Good. 'Cause I'm lying'.
Oh, what? You didn't spot that?
Oh, did your emotions get in the way?
You should really work on that.
Well, this has been terrific.
Really fantastic.
Quite the intervention.
We should do this again soon, very soon.
The intervention was my idea.
My mum died when I was young,
and my dad was long gone by then.
Terry and his family, they took me in, even
though there was no room, even less money.
And one day, um, Terry and I got into
a little bit of trouble with the police.
Not your concern.
But... they were on their way...
and there was no way
we could get out of it...
without one of us
acting as a decoy for the other.
- So Terry took the fall for you?
- Yeah, he did.
He said that, uh...
"You're supposed to use
that brain of yours for something...
not be dragged down into the muck
by stupid bastards like me. "
- He was right.
- Yeah, he was.
Yeah. Cost him three years of his life.
So anyone who wants to compete
for my loyalty with Terry Marsh...
not really in a fair fight.
Night, love.