...Edith Piaf Triumphs...
... Fame for Street Singer...
...The Little Sparrow Premieres...
...The first man Who Helped Me...
...Piaf On Tour...
...Edith Piaf's Appearance
in the A.B.C. Theatre...
The Little Sparrow is
Dead Long Live Edith Piaf!
"I was hurrying home,
needing your love to lean on,
...only to find an empty room. Waiting
and waiting; I know that room. "
I can't wait to see you in this
piece. Look out, here comes Canetti.
- The conductor's been waiting three hours.
- So?
The premiere is less than 48 hours away.
Do you know many people whom
Cocteau's written a piece for?
- Miss?
- Yes, Suzanne?
Meurisse called. Dinner
with Mr. Cocteau at eight.
You see?
- Ask him to come back at midnight.
- Are you sure?
You're worse than Raymond. Do this, do that.
- That's why you fired him.
- Stop it.
- Do you wish to see the gowns?
- Yes, the gowns.
That's all of them. Careful with those pins.
The simplest one, without the collar.
There's a man at the door...
He has something for you.
- Who is it?
- A soldier.
I told him you were busy. He's outside
in the corridor. A bit embarrassed.
Have him come in.
Will you come this way?
- Here she is.
- Much better without the collar.
Yes?
My name is Michel Emer. I'm a corporal.
This isn't the army. What do you want?
I have a song for you.
Not another... I've enough already.
I have a premiere in two days' time.
I wish this one.
Tomorrow I leave for the front.
There's the piano. You have five minutes.
Edith...
We shall have to wait.
Stop.
I want it.
Everybody out.
You can't mean that. We're already late.
What can't she mean?
Play it. I want it for Bobino.
You can't do that.
Edith Piaf can do whatever she pleases!
French, please.
- She's too hopeless, too poor...
- Help us out here, Charles.
I'm no translator.
'Miserable. And not in the French tradition
of the Can-Can and Gay Paris. '
A complete flop.
This isn't the first time I've had to fight.
The Americans want pretty girls, not me.
I'm not the Parisian sex
bomb you were hoping for.
Can you picture me in a ballet?
With a feather in my arse?
Go ahead and laugh. I'm not what they want.
- They think I'm too doleful, THEY are stupid.
- Yes, too stupid.
- You made the front page.
- Two columns.
I can't read it. Translate it.
He says that she shouldn't let
you go. That it would be a mistake.
The Americans don't deserve you.
I knew something would
happen! I have to change...
...Ginou, help me help me choose a dress.
I'm going out tonight. I have a date.
- What's this, Marcel?
- Beef... try it.
It smells like damp dog.
What?
Your English is as good as the meat.
Don't you like it here?
I was taken a bit by
surprise. I didn't expect it...
...when you phoned to say that as two French
people in New York we should have a meal...
- ...I didn't expect this.
- I come here all the time.
You sure know how to spoil a girl.
- Have you decided?
- Twee broodjes pastrami.
two Tournedos Rossini, and a
bottle of Chateau Langelus 1938.
- Are you hungry?
- It's better than cooked dog.
I'm sorry.
Let's start over. Okay?
- How long have you been in New York?
- Eight weeks.
- And do you like America?
- It doesn't interest me at all.
I don't understand them,
and they don't understand me.
- You must miss Paris.
- Terribly.
What do you do when you're not singing?
Your like the police with
your questions. I knit.
Give me your size and I'll knit you a sweater.
No, but thanks all the same...
- Those people recognized you.
- Really?
'That schmuck lost his recent
fights. He's washed up. '
- I'll show them who's washed up.
- No!
Relax. I was joking.
It's fine.
- Can we be less formal to each other?
- Of course.
- What do you do when you aren't boxing?
- I train and I run...
- And after the training?
- In Morocco I work on my farm.
You have a farm?
I breed pigs.
Well, why not?
Absolutely. Why not?
modern, with superb, fat pigs.
- Who takes care of them when you're boxing?
- My wife.
You have...
...wonderful hands.
- Did you hear what I said, Momone?
- You have really beautiful fingers.
Listen.
What colour are your eyes?
- He leaned over...
- And his breath smelled.
- You can be such a bitch!
- He is of course a pig breeder.
- He said...
- Violet blue.
Of course, violet blue.
It was the way he said it.
As though he was a child.
You're just like a fairy.
A bit of an exaggeration.
- Did you kiss him?
- I didn't dare.
- It was a wonderful evening.
- Too short.
- Will you come and see me box?
- Of course.
Did he try to kiss you?
I don't know if he even thought about it.
And I'm supposed to believe that!
I'll come to see you sing.
Goodnight.
He's the love of my life...
You were superb.
Mr. Lucien Roupp, Mr. Cerdan's manager.
Mr. Jameson, of CBS television.
Marlene.
Good evening. I'm sorry, I
just wanted to say something.
I haven't been in Paris in years.
But this evening, when you sang
I was right back there again..
...on her streets, beneath her skies.
Your voice is the soul of Paris.
You took me with you on your
travels. You brought tears to my eyes.
- Thank you, from the bottom of my heart.
- Thank you.
Come on.
I'm beginning to like this
city. The stars are out tonight.
Let's go.
Marc, do you know how long a frog lives for?
In fairytales or in real life?
No one ever read me fairytales.
You never had the chance to hear them.
That's true, but all the same...
Dreux. 13 December 1959
I'm a little tired.
I'll be right back.
Lay her down there.
- I'll go back on in a minute.
- Out of the question.
Nobody tells ME when to stop.
- What are we going to do?
- Sorry, you'll have to clear the house.
- I'm going back there!
- No, Edith.
- I have to continue.
- It would be suicide.
You're going to hospital.
No, I'm begging you!
She left hospital only three
weeks ago. There'll be more galas.
Take me back to the stage.
I have to sing.
I have to sing, Louis. I have no choice.
Edith, please...
- Can't you hear them?
- Stop...
Shut that door!
Take me back there, Louis.
If I don't sing tonight...
If I don't sing one song at least, I'll
lose faith in myself. Do you follow?
Doctor...
...do what you have to do.
Not this time, boys.
You think I'm going to
collapse, but I'm in great shape.
Don't you dare write that
this is my suicide tour!
'Padam'!
Saint Theresa, first of all my thanks...
I know you're behind it
all. You sent him to me.
I've found love, thanks to you.
Baby Jesus, protect Marcel.
Come on, Marcel!
No!
- It's too early, Edith.
- He's going to win. I feel it.
- If things go wrong, you've a problem.
- What do you mean?
If there's no problem, I'll call you. Now go.
Hurry up!
Come on, Marcel!
One more round!
Finish him off!
- What's happening?
- Zale is sitting it out.
Did he do it? Is he the world champion?
You look like an angel.
Not a fairy any more?
You're my champion.
I want to be with you always.
There was nothing before I met
you. All that is in the past.
Stay with me.
My dearest, before going to bed
last night I crossed off a day...
...a day that was long and short.
Such pain, that plane flew away
with my heart. My life, my breath...
...my sweet boy, my child, my dearest love...
...your scent is still on my sheets,
and my heart sleeps without waking...
...in the arms of sadness.
Darling, I love you. What have you done to me?
I miss you.
I'm depressed, lifeless, as
though I'm waiting for something...
...hold me close against your heart and
know that nothing means more to me than you.
Bring me back my heart.
Whenever I'm in a restaurant
and hear 'La Vie en Rose'...
If I see, my love, how devoted you
are to your wife and children...
...I have the urge to go far away...
...and perhaps one day you'll
be grateful for what I've done.
I can't have you to myself
and I can't live without you.
As God is my witness, I
ask nothing for myself...
...and am prepared to sacrifice everything.
'If life were to take you from me...
...if you should die or be far away, and
you were to love me, I too would die. '
In three months' time,
wait for it, in April...
...I'm going to star in L'Olympia.
Full house and then we're back again.
Your liver is damaged...
...you've been ill and need
rest. It's serious this time.
I'm only 44. I'm not dead yet.
Because of all the cancellations we're broke.
Oh, so it's my fault?
I didn't say that. The taxman
is breathing down our necks.
We have to pay 120.000 franc.
I only have jaundice! That won't
last 100 years. Don't exaggerate.
I want to sing in L'Olympia.
- Anything else?
- We shouldn't give in all the time.
I can't watch her all the time. She
discharged herself too soon from hospital.
L'Olympia is in 3 months.
That's going to be a disaster.
- She needs this sort of challenge.
- This is hopeless.
In that case I'll have to tell the
insurers that we're cancelling everything.
We have to make the decisions for
her. Whether she likes it or not.
I said to myself, 'Edith, it's over. '
- There's someone else. You've lost him.
- Did he have an affair?
I he did have, would I be telling you?
He left the restaurant. I followed him.
My Marcel walked the whole of New
York to eat with an old blind boxer...
...whom he'd met a couple of
years before. Can you imagine that?
- Men like that are scarce.
- My Marcel...
...that's all you ever talk about.
That's the only thing that counts.
But listen, Ginou, I'll never have him.
He'll never be mine. He'll
remain with his wife and children.
He phones her every day.
I pretend I don't know what's
going on. I want him to be happy.
I'll be right back.
I could have been Edith Piaf.
There's more in life than chansons.
It's been too long, Marcel! Call
Orly. Book a flight this evening.
I'd never survive it. I miss you, Marcel.
I can't bear to be apart from you.
- Perhaps I have to return to Paris.
- Hold on.
- I'm no more than Madame's lapdog.
- Stop it...
Rum, coke! Whisky! People think I'm rubbish.
Getting drunk in Belleville was better.
You abandoned me.
That's enough, Momone!
Take her away from here.
I'm taking the boat.
To your career, Edith!
Marcel, leave tonight. For me.
- You won't be sleeping if I'm not there.
- Thank God for that, Marcel.
I'll make you coffee. You stay where you are.
Let me serve you.
What are you doing here?
I knew you'd come.
Lucien found it hard to get tickets.
I've a gift for you.
You don't look too well. You could
do with some sun. You're pale.
Ginou!
I'm looking for that watch!
Wat nou? I'm looking for that watch!
In the red Cartier box.
Shit, it was right here!
What's the matter with you?
I'm looking for Marcel's
watch! Where is that watch?
I'm looking for Marcel's watch! What?
Louis? What's the matter?
I want you to be brave, Edith.
Is it Marcel?
What?
The plane crashed...
Marcel!
What more can I tell you?
They say you're the best clairvoyant there is.
This is your third visit this
week. I've told you all I know.
Why do you keep coming back?
So you can tell me again.
So that I know why I should continue living.
He died in the air, so
that is where he must be...
California, August 1955
Jack Peals! Can we go any faster? I need air.
I love the heat. It makes me dizzy.
- Step on it. Our pin
- up is melting!
I'm getting a sore throat. Then you can
take care of me. Like a good husband.
- The best I've had.
- The FIRST you've had!
Are you going to spend the day gawping at up?
I'm feeling nauseous.
Look out, you'll drive us off the road.
Let me drive. Stop, I'll
drive. Then Ginou can throw up.
Go on, Ginou.
May I, Madame?
Go ahead, Ginou!
Very good!
Bye bye, Ginou!
Wait for me!
My, you're some driver.
Our journey hasn't been wasted
after all. We just murdered a tree.
My God, the service here is
awful. Can nobody take our order?
Take it easy. You're no star
here. Mocambo is tonight.
Remind me who invited us.
Marlon Brando, Ginger Rogers, Mr. Chaplin...
What's this?
- We didn't order that swill!
- That's your cocktail.
Don't touch me! I said don't touch me!
Here, wipe it off.
We should get a divorce.
How many times a day are you shooting up now?
About ten.
Excuse me for being so
direct, but why do you do it?
So that my body doesn't protest.
When did you start injecting every day?
Five years ago, after the plane crash.
I contracted rheumatism.
I couldn't knit any more.
You're very dependent on it.
- It's an addiction...
- Doctor?
I want my wife to kick the habit.
I want to be well again. I can do it.
October 1960 - 5 years later
Danielle, a chair!
Edith?
Here you are.
Sit down now.
Bruno...
...there won't be another L'Olympia.
I understand.
No!
The composer Charles Dumont and the
lyricist Michel Vaucaire are here.
They wish us to hear their chanson.
Quickly then. I'm tired.
no, no nothing at all
no, I regret nothing at all
not the good times I had
not the pain it means nothing to me
Stop!
I love it. Carry on!
with my souvenirs
I build a fire
my sadness, my pleasure
I don't need it any longer
the loves are gone
the traumas as well
erased for ever
I must start anew
You're wonderful!
That's precisely what I was looking
out for. Unbelievable. This is so ME!
That is MY life. That is me!
Call Coquatrix. L'Olympia is on!
Play it again. It's exquisite.
no, no nothing at all
no, I regret nothing at all
You're doing well, my dear.
Your friend, Marguerite'
Aznavour, Mr. Cocteau, Yves Montand.
Montand's here? I read that he wasn't coming.
He's come for you!
- They've been waiting a half hour.
- The room is jumping.
Not too tight?
- Who's that?
- A friend.
Let's go, Edith.
Up you get.
My crucifix?
My crucifix...
- I forgot. I'll fetch it.
- I won't sing without it.
Everybody out!
Grasse, Oktober 1963 The Final Night
See you tomorrow.
I'll do it.
I'm afraid, Simone. I'm losing
my memory. It's serious this time.
My brain is confused.
I try to remember things but they won't come.
Things do come, but not the things I want.
I wanted to see his watch. Don't
you remember? Marcel's watch?
- I'm afraid not. I never knew him.
- I wanted to see his watch...
What a face!
You have wild eyes.
I like the little one.
- Simone?
- Yes, Edith?
I haven't said my prayers.
I must get down on my knees and pray.
No one will think less of you if
you don't get down on your knees.
I wish to pray for my papa.
Marcelle...
...my little ghost...
Only Momone knows. I must
tell you about my ghost.
- Take it easy, Edith.
- Marcelle!
Marcelle, go to bed. Enough for today.
And I'm supposed to look out for the
police... and your child! What Louis up to?
It's your father.
Has she eaten?
- They're saying you were on the street with her.
- Who says that?
You only have her twice a month
and you can't even do THAT right!
not on the street!
Come quick.
It's Marcelle! Come quick!
She's in the hospital!
Are you her mother?
Meningitis. We could do nothing. I'm sorry.
Edith?
I have the crucifix.
They told me you were on the beach.
- Thanks for agreeing to this interview.
- My pleasure.
How strange to meet you so far from Paris.
I'm never far from Paris.
I have a list of question. Just say
the first thing that occurs to you.
- What is your favourite colour?
- Blue.
- Your favourite food?
- Roast beef.
- Would you like to live sensibly?
- I already do.
Who are your most loyal friends?
All my genuine friends.
If you were unable to sing...
Then I could no longer live.
Are you afraid of death?
I'm more afraid of loneliness.
- Do you pray?
- Yes, for I believe in love.
I don't want to, Simone.
Where's Theo? I want my husband.
Theo will be here in less than an hour.
What was the finest part of the show for you?
When the curtain went up.
And as a woman?
My first kiss.
- Do you like the night?
- Yes, with lots of light.
- The morning?
- With a piano and friends.
The evening?
Because that's our morning.
You see, you're breathing.
I can't go back.
I can't.
What advice would you give a woman?
Love.
- To a young girl?
- Love.
- To a child?
Whom are you knitting for?
For anyone who'll wear my sweaters.
That's it. I hope it wasn't too long.
- Thank you so much, madame.
- Thank you too.
no, no nothing at all
no, I regret nothing at all
not the good times I had
not the pain it means nothing to me
no, no nothing at all
no, I regret nothing at all
it is done, wiped away
erased, the past interests me not at all
with my souvenirs
I build a fire
my sadness, my pleasure
I don't need it any longer
the loves are gone
the traumas as well
erased for ever
I must start anew
no, no nothing at all
no, I regret nothing at all
not the good times I had
not the pain it means nothing to me
no, no nothing at all
no, I regret nothing at all
because my life
and my joy
today
begins with you.
Edith Piaf died on 9 October 1963.
She was only forty-seven...