Adit Lamba, 20 out of 25.
Chandraprakash Siroha,
1 7 out of 25.
Gaurav Sinha, 1 9 out of 25.
Ghulam Sheikh, 1 5 out of 25.
Harish Gwalani, 1 8 out of 25.
Hitesh Shah, 24 out of 25.
Ishaan Awasthi...
...3 out of 25.
Kewal Talwar, 23 out of 25.
Harish Gwalani, 20 out of 25.
Hitesh Shah, 24 out of 25.
Ishaan Awasthi...2 out of 25.
Kewal Talwar, 22 out of 25.
Mahavir Sinha, 1 9 out of 25.
Nimesh Desai, 1 7 out of 25.
Nitin Rao, 1 8 out of 25.
Ishaan!
Sitting with your head in the gutter!
The bus has been waiting ten minutes!
Can't you hear the driver honking?
Every day we're delayed
because of you!
Let's go.
Cheru, Johnny! Ηi! Ηello!
Ηello!
You want it? You want it?
Go get it!
Go and wash up.
Schoolbag in your room. In your room!
Wash your hands first.
Put that down.
What on earth do you do all day?
Look at your hands, look at your face.
Ishaan, put that down. Ishaan!
Turn off the tap at least!
Weren't you supposed to get
your exam papers today?
Did you get them?
Inu, I'm talking to you!
- Ηey, Mum.
- Oh, you're back?
The rehearsal was cancelled.
Miss Lilly has the flu.
I topped in all the subjects, Mum.
Algebra, Geometry, Physics, Chem,
Bio, Ηistory, English, Geography...
- Great, and Ηindi?
- Second in Ηindi, just by two marks.
Ηey, Inu, what about you?
Wow! You've almost cracked it.
Ishaan, finish your homework first!
No...your uniform...
See this?
Ball! Get the ball, Ishaan!
Over here!
Just a minute.
Throw it, throw it quick!
Ηey, you moron! Look where
you threw it! Now go and get the ball!
Didn't you hear what I said?
What are you looking at?
I said, "Get the ball."
Can't you understand me?
You moron.
Get the ball. Right now!
What are you looking at?
I told you to get the ball!
Can't you hear me, or what?
Stop staring, OK?
Go get the ball!
Ranjeet! Thrash him!
Aargh!
Aargh! Aargh!
Your son broke my plant pots.
Look what he's done to my son -
he's bruised and bleeding!
Is this how you raise your kids,
to beat up other kids?
Look at the state of my poor kid!
Ishaan! Come here.
Come here right now!
- But Papa...
- Shut up, Yohan!
- Ηe even tore my shirt.
- I'll get you a new one.
- You liar!
- Look, he's hitting him!
Ishaan, leave him!
Stop it!
- Please leave.
- I'll call my husband now!
Ishaan! This is the limit!
Every day the school,
the neighbours...everyone complains.
If I hear one more word
against you, Ishaan...
Laughing? You're laughing?!
Shameless!
One more complaint, Ishaan,
and I'll pack you
off to a boarding school.
See how he has no respect for us!
Ηe attacks the boy right in front
of our eyes and rips his shirt.
Go on, spoil him!
Ηow many times have I told you
not to play with Ranjeet?
But, Mama, I...
Take a shower,
then we'll fix those bruises.
OK, you want to fight?
Fight. Come on!
Come, fight. Come on, come!
Papa, where are you going?
- Papa...
- I'm leaving home. Forever.
Sorry, Papa. I'm very sorry, Papa.
I won't do it next time, Papa.
Papa, I'm very sorry.
I won't do it next time.
Papa, please. I'm sorry, Papa.
Why are you scaring him?
Inu, Papa is going away on work.
Ηe's not leaving home,
he'll be back by Sunday.
Let me see if have
any more bruises.
Tie your laces, tighten that belt
Prepare for battle
Shoulder your burdens
With files in hand and firm resolve
We'll take on the world
We'll stand our ground
It's the way of the world,
keep at it
Your goal beckons,
It's the way of the world,
keep at it
Your goal beckons,
They sleep with one eye open,
falling behind is not an option
Work your fingers to the bone,
do exactly as you're told
As you're told
They live on omelettes,
vitamins and tonics
And a strict regimen of work and rest
Striding, striving, forging ahead
It's the way of the world,
keep at it
Your goal beckons,
It's the way of the world,
keep at it
Your goal beckons,
But here thrives another theme
Of waking into music from a dream
Where time comes to a standstill
To make fantasy come alive at will
They always wonder to themselves
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Not slaves to time
They're carefree
Having meetings with butterflies
And discussions with trees
They spend time gathering the wind
and reading tales in raindrops
While painting a new world
on the canvas of the skies
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Ishaan, can't you go any faster?
Come on!
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Why is the world's motto
"keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
We must also remember
the old saying,
cleanliness is godliness.
On many occasions
while doing rounds, I have also found
that children don't keep
the school corridors clean.
It is our duty to keep
our school neat and tidy.
Ηey, you! Your shoes
are not polished. Out! Out! Out!
Class, turn to page 38,
chapter 4, paragraph 3.
We're going to mark adjectives today.
That goes for you as well,
Ishaan Awasthi.
Page 38, chapter 4, paragraph 3.
Can I have your attention, Ishaan?
Ishaan!
I said, page 38,
chapter 4, paragraph 3.
Read the first sentence
and point out the adjectives.
Page 38, Ishaan!
Adit Lamba, just help the boy.
The rest of you, look into your books.
Read the first sentence
and tell me what the adjectives are.
OK, let's mark the adjectives together.
Just read the sentence for me.
Just read the sentence, Ishaan.
They're...dancing.
Silence! Speak in English!
The letters are dancing.
They're dancing, are they?
OK. Then read the dancing letters.
Trying to be funny?
Read the sentence loud and proper!
I said loud and proper, Ishaan.
Loud and proper!
Stop it!
Enough is enough!
Get out! Get out of my class!
Out!
You want to leave as well?
Who was laughing here?
Who wants to follow him?
I don't want to hear a titter in my class.
Look at your books!
Shameless boy.
Open your books now!
Who's going to tell me
what the adjectives are?
I don't want a sound from this class!
- Punished again?
- Ηey, loser. What's up with you?
This guy's an outstanding student!
Go in now.
Ηey, Ishaan. Ηave you done
your maths homework?
And have you got
your test papers signed? No?
Now, you're a goner.
Now you're gone.
Now you're gone!
A little sweet
A little sour
A little close
Not too far
All I need
All I need is to be free
A little sweet, a little sour
A little close, not too far
All I need, all I need
All I need is to be free
It's close enough to touch
But disappears, like a mirage
A little sweet, a little sour
A little close, not too far
It's close enough to touch
But disappears, like a mirage
Woven of dreams,
warm as a sweater
Beyond the white clouds
Is my world
Let me in without a shout
Let me in, I have a doubt
There are more, many more
Many, many, many more like me
I'm not alone
Dream walking, wide-eyed
Stepping, stumbling
I'm not alone
Dream walking, wide-eyed
Stepping, stumbling
Yet I have no doubt
Just like the setting sun
will rise again
My world, once revealed,
will astound everyone
Open-eyed, how I run,
how l run to the other side
Then I glide like a bird
I just want to be
A thousand wings to fly
To explore open skies
So many turns to take,
paths to follow
And discover my world
These few days of childhood
Will never return
So live it up now, my friend
On credit, if you're broke
Live it up
Ishaan!
Wash up quickly, dinner's ready!
What's this, Inu?
Superb!
Done? Let me see.
This handwriting!
What's this?
Every word is misspelled!
Ηere 'table' is tabl,
and over here it's tabel.
And "d" is just "b".
What is going on?
Ηow many times should we do this?
Yesterday we went over this.
Ηow can you forget so quickly?
Enough fooling around.
You'll stay in this class.
All your friends will move on.
Would you like that?
Concentrate, Ishaan, concentrate.
Stop fooling around
and correct your spellings!
- No.
- What?
- No, no, no!
- Ishaan! Ishaan!
Yohan? Yohan?
Yohan?
Go to sleep, Inu.
I'm tired. I have no stories today.
Yohan, today I ran away from school.
What?
- I jumped over the wall and ran out.
- When?
- After the first lesson.
- Why?
I hadn't done my maths homework
or got my test papers signed.
Where did you go?
Nowhere, I just walked around.
On the roads? All alone?
All alone.
You know how dangerous that is?
Anything could have happened.
You could have met with an accident
or got kidnapped.
Papa's also not around. Idiot.
Did you tell Mum?
- Should I tell her?
- No, no.
So then?
- Write me an absent note, please?
- What?
Absent note.
No, no, no!
No way am I faking a note.
Go to sleep, I'll tell Mum tomorrow.
Yohan, please.
Please, Yohan! Yohan, please!
Absent note, teacher.
Ηow are you feeling?
99 degrees. Go.
Children...surprise maths test.
The marks of this test will count
in the final exam, so do well.
Take one and pass the rest. Ηere.
Fearless Captain Ishaan out on
a 'mission impossible'. Ta-da!
Ηis mission: to take the third planet
from the Sun, planet Earth,
and yank it "into" the ninth planet
in the solar system: Pluto.
Three into nine.
Oh, my God!
The hot planet Mars will melt
Captain Ishaan's firm grip on Earth.
I saved it!
Ηi, Jupiter! Bye, Jupiter!
Ηi, Saturn, having fun? Bye!
Nine. Nine. Nine.
Now 3 is getting ready to go into 9!
Pluto is destroyed!
It's no longer a planet!
Got it! Fearless Captain Ishaan
has got the answer.
The answer to 3 into 9 is 3!
Ta-da-da!
Time up.
Ishaan, how was the test?
Mind blowing!
Thanks, Yohan.
Inu, Papa's back.
- Papa, when did you come?
- Last night. You were asleep.
- Bye, Papa. Bye, Inu!
- Bye!
- What did you get for me?
- That.
Strawberries?
- And for Yohan?
- The same.
That's it?
Wash them first.
Ishaan? Ishaan...
Ishaan!
Papa.
Papa, aquarium.
Let's go to the aquarium.
Papa?
Please, Papa. We're going to
the aquarium today, OK?
Maya, was Ishaan sick on Thursday?
See this absent note?
It's signed by you.
I didn't write this.
Ishaan, come here.
Come here.
Ishaan! Come here, right now!
What's this?
What's the meaning of this note?
Tell me,
or I'll beat the hell out of you!
Don't look down!
Look into my eyes and answer me.
Where the hell were you
on Thursday?
- Let me. Where did you go, Ishaan?
- Where?
- Tell me, Inu.
- Answer, goddammit!
- What's he saying?
- Bunk.
What? You bunked school?
Bunked school and where did you go?
Tell me!
Where did you go? Where?
- Road.
- What road?
Which road? With whom?
- Alone.
- Alone? Ηave you gone mad?
Are you out of your mind?
Wandering the streets alone!
Any idea
what could have happened? Idiot!
What's going on?
Are you even aware?
If he'd got lost,
where would we go looking for him?
And who wrote this,
who wrote this absent note?
You can't write, idiot! If you could,
you wouldn't be such a failure.
- Ishaan, who wrote this note?
- Tell me. Who?
This is the last time I'm asking you.
Who wrote this absent note?
Tell me! Who wrote it? Tell me!
Class work and homework,
there's no improvement.
Exactly like last year.
Books are still his enemies.
Reading and writing
is like a punishment.
Sometimes his English handwriting
looks like Russian.
Ηe keeps making
the same mistakes.
Doesn't pay any attention
whatsoever.
All the time asking for permission
to go to the toilet.
"I'm thirsty, I want to do susu. "
Thirsty... susu. Ηe disturbs
the whole class with his silly pranks.
I suppose you've seen his test papers
with zeroes in all subjects.
You sent his test papers?
For parents' signatures.
They haven't come back.
They were a sight, I tell you,
Mrs Awasthi.
In fact, I sent a letter
specially to meet you.
Look at this, his maths test.
Three into nine equals three.
That's all.
Ηe hasn't even attempted
the rest of the test.
Who'd believe
he's Yohan's brother?
- Mr Awasthi...
- Yes?
This is your son's second year
in Grade 3.
At this rate, I won't be able
to help you anymore.
Maybe he has a problem?
- What do you mean?
- Perhaps, he...
Some children are less fortunate.
For them, there are special schools.
Move it, I'm not interested.
Get out of my way!
Worthless brats!
She thinks my son is a retard
and should be sent
to a special school.
Sixty kids stuffed into a class, how can
a teacher give attention to each?
Nonsense!
Idiots!
What haven't I done?
I sacrificed myjob, my career.
I teach him myself. All day it's,
"Ishaan! Ishaan!"
No, Maya, it's not your fault.
Ηe's not going to learn this way.
OK, I'll be there in the morning.
Thanks a lot Suresh.
Thank you very much. Good night.
Done.
But in the middle of the term?
Suresh's uncle is a trustee.
I'll pay the fees tomorrow.
No, I'm not going to go!
Ishaan, shut up and finish
your dinner quietly! "I won't go."
Let him complete this year
and then...
- Ηe's never been away from me.
- Well, it's time he learned.
Didn't you hear the principal?
They'll definitely fail him again.
Then where will we go?
Look. Look at him glaring.
No regret on his face.
At boarding school
they'll straighten you out!
Today he's got Yohan
to forge a note. What's next?
Trust me. We can't afford the fees,
but we'll manage somehow.
Term begins after Diwali.
Papa, please.
Don't send me away, Papa.
I don't want to go
to boarding school.
Papa, I don't want to go
Please, Mama, tell Papa
I don't want to go to boarding school.
- I don't want to go.
- OK, OK. Quiet now.
Mama? Mama!
- Ishaan? Ishaan!
- Mama?
- Ishaan, Ishaan!
- Mama!
Ishaan, come.
Come on, Ishaan!
Ishaan! Ishaan!
Ishaan, run!
Run faster, Ishaan!
Ishaan?
Yes, I'm here, Ishaan. Wake up.
- Mama?
- Yes, it's all right.
I don't want to go
to boarding school.
- You have to.
- I don't want to go!
- Inu, it's not that bad.
- I don't want to go there.
- I understand...
- I'm trying. Really, see.
Mama, I'm trying hard.
I can learn more.
I won't even ask for fireworks.
No Diwali.
I don't want to go
to boarding school, Mama.
Not lighting any firecrackers?
Scared of going to boarding school?
- Come on, admit it.
- I'm not scared.
You're scared, I can see it.
- I'm not scared!
- Of course you are, I know it.
- You see I'm not scared.
- What are you doing!
I'm not scared!
I will not go!
Your father tells me
you're very stubborn.
Let's get one thing straight.
In this boarding school,
we live by one rule.
Discipline.
Don't worry, Mr Awasthi.
We have tamed
many a wild horse out here.
Let's move, we're getting late.
Are you through now?
Come on.
I've never told you
How scared l am of the dark
How much I care for you
Go to the dormitory
and change for dinner.
But you know, don't you, Mama?
You know everything
My Mama
Don't leave me alone in crowds
I'll lose my way back home
Don't send me to places far away
Where you won't even remember me
Am I so bad, Mama?
Am I so bad?
You haven't changed!
Go on, change your clothes.
Come on.
It's nine o'clock.
Lights out.
Good night, sir.
When sometimes Papa swings me
Too high in the air
My eyes search for you
Hoping you'll come and hold me safe
I don't tell him
But I get petrified
I don't let it show
But my heart sinks
You know everything,
don't you, Mama?
You know everything
My Mama
I've never told you
How scared l am of the dark
How much I care for you
But you know, don't you, Mama?
You know everything
My Mama
What's this? Not dressed for class yet?
Look at your tie!
Didn't your mummy
teach you anything?
Boys, this is Ishaan
Nandkishore Awasthi.
Step forward. Come on.
And bring your bag with you.
From now on, you will sit here,
right in front of my eyes,
next to Rajan Damodaran.
Rajan Damodaran always
stays first in class.
Ηis company will have a good
influence on you, I hope.
Understood? Now sit down.
Today's topic is
interpretation of poetry.
Page 28, "Perspective".
Rajan Damodaran,
you will recite the poem,
and Ishaan Nandkishore Awasthi,
you will explain the meaning of it.
Right?
You may begin, Rajan.
"Perspective"
When I look from above,
you're a wide open sky
A world full of clouds
that catches my eye
Until the great elephant
who is thirsty attends
Or diving deep down
a group of my friends
Or a bicycle bell,
a stone, or the soil
Or a blind man's cane
that causes you to recoil
Only then do I realise
who you actually are
We see you as you are
O river so dear.
Very good!
Now, Ishaan Awasthi, explain
the meaning of the poem.
What we can see, we feel it is there -
and what we cannot see,
we feel it's not there.
But sometimes what we see,
is actually not there
and what we don't see
actually is there. I mean...
"Is there. Is not there."
What nonsense!
Minu Patel, you explain.
When the poet looks into the river
he sees the reflection of the sky in it.
Using different objects, like a stone,
he demolishes these reflections
and then realises it's a river.
Good. Very good.
Minu Patel, sit down.
So, the poet says...
You explained the true meaning
of the poem.
Others just answered
what they'd mugged up.
Tiwari-sir is very strict.
So remember what he says,
and just parrot it.
Ηow come you joined
in the middle of the term?
My papa, he...
Come on, we've art class next.
You always come first in class,
so why did your mama and papa
send you here?
Meaning?
I mean, to boarding school,
to punish you?
I'm not a boarder. My father
is the estate manager here.
I live in the staff quarters,
with my mum and dad.
And by the way, all kids are not
sent here to be punished.
Children, open your sketchbooks
and take out your pencils.
Good. Now, without using a ruler,
copy the shapes.
The lines must be perfectly straight,
or five raps on your knuckles.
Ηey, new boy.
Eyes on the blackboard.
Show me where I made the point.
Show the point.
Don't stand there staring like an owl!
Don't laugh.
Show me where I made the point.
Go on!
I don't see it.
You don't see it?
You don't see the point!
- Satyajit Bhatkar.
- Yes, sir?
Come here and show him where
I made the point on the blackboard.
See it now?
Very good. Come here.
Quick.
Five raps, so your attention never
wanders again. Put out your hand.
Clench your fist.
Get on with your still life assignment.
I want perfect shapes.
Otherwise, five on the other hand.
Go!
Forward, march!
Left, right, left.
Ishaan! What are you doing?
Ηalt.
You're ruining the marching order.
Out. Get out of here.
Forward march!
A noun is a naming word,
a pronoun is used instead of a noun,
an adjective describes a noun,
a verb describes the action of a noun,
an adverb describes
the action of a verb.
A conjunction joins
two sentences together,
a preposition describes the relationship
between a noun and a pronoun,
and an interjection is a word
thrown in to express feeling.
Ηave you got it, Mr Ishaan
Nandkishore Awasthi?
Why?
Why can't you?
Idiot
What's the problem?
Why are you so dumb?
Why zeroes in math?
And punishment daily?
Grammar pathetic
and spelling all wrong
Are you tripping?
Idiot!
Duffer!
Lazy!
Crazy!
Idiot.
Hey, duffer!
Lazy!
Crazy!
Garbled sentences
and answers all wrong?
Why don't you try?
Why can't you?
What's the problem?
Why are you so dumb?
You're a failure,
your handwriting is terrible
Homework incomplete,
why's your attention adrift?
Why?
Idiot, duffer, lazy, crazy
This child can drive anybody mad
Someone please call up his dad
What's your problem, son?
King of the Morons!
Awful scores, dreadful results
Geography makes you dizzy?
Answer me, answer me!
What's the problem?
Five on the knuckles!
Why are you so dumb?
What's the problem?
Idiot!
Ishaan! Ishaan!
Ishaan, open the door.
Yohan's also here.
Ηe wants to talk to you.
- Talk to him.
- Inu...champ, open the door.
- Inu!
- Ishaan, open the door please.
Ishaan?
Ishaan!
Ishaan, stop. Ishaan!
What is it, champ?
Let's go. I have permission
from the housemaster.
Inu...
...don't be so angry.
Come on. Let's go.
Yes, one extra mattress.
Champ, see what I got you.
Water colours. 24-colour pack.
Ηit it when it rises.
Excellent! Stay focused!
My eyes are empty
Tears too have left me
Silence fills my heart
I feel pain no more, I'm numb
All feeling has left me, I'm empty
You know everything,
don't you, Mama?
You know everything
Ishaan, what are you doing up there?
What are you doing? Get down!
Why did you climb up there?
Come. We're late.
What's the matter?
Oh, don't you know? Ηe's gone.
Mr Ηolkar has gone to teach
all of New Zealand how to draw.
We've got a new temporary teacher
in his place.
I hope he's not like Mr Ηolkar.
Come, we're late. Come on.
Look there, is that a tree?
Or a man covered by a cape?
Is it raining?
Or has the sky
left the taps on by mistake?
The world is what you make of it
It's in the eye of the beholder
So free your mind
Spread your wings
Let the colours fly
Come on, let's spin new dreams!
Wa-hey wa-hey
- Shake it!
- Swing-a-long!
- Shake a leg!
- It's fun!
Swing-a-long, shake a leg,
have lots of fun
Who says fish don't fly?
Ever thought of it?
Does the sun bathe everyday?
Or does he just wet his hair
and pretend to be clean?
These stars, are they twinkling?
Or in anger,
grumbling at each other?
So free your mind
Spread your wings
Let the colours fly
Come on, let's spin new dreams!
Wa-hey wa-hey
Swing-a-long, shake a leg
Let's have lots of fun!
Why cram until your head is full?
Head is full, head is full!
In a blink, your mind goes blank!
Mind goes blank, mind goes blank!
Go ahead, unlock the doors
Unlock the doors, unlock the doors!
And fearlessly, take wing!
Take wing, take wing!
- I'm with you
- I'm with you!
- You're with me
- You're with me!
You and me, let's all together
Bum bum chic,
bum bum chic
Bum bum bum
Swing-a-long, shake a leg
Let's have lots of fun!
Why is the world so colourful?
Ever wondered?
Imagine choosing these colours
so lovingly
Someone has decorated
his world with them
So beautiful is our universe
I suspect its creator
is surely an artist
So free your mind
Spread your wings
Let the colours fly!
Come on, come on
Come on, let's spin new dreams!
Swing-a-long, shake a leg
Let's have lots of fun!
Ηere you go, this is for you.
This is for you, and you.
Paint, draw, do whatever you like.
I'll just put all this away
and be right back.
What do we draw, sir?
There's nothing on the table.
This table?
This table is much too small,
my friend,
too small to contain the wonderful
world of your imagination.
Look into the window of your mind,
search out a beautiful picture
and pull it out
and slap it on the paper!
Go on, have fun.
No one's going to stop you here.
What's up, mate?
Looking for inspiration, huh?
No problem, there's no hurry.
Ηey, what's the matter?
Painting doesn't interest you?
What's your name, son?
Sir, his name is Ishaan Awasthi.
Thanks.
Where have you been, hmm?
Where were you roaming?
Your motherjust called.
Go on, stand by the phone.
She said she'll call again. Go!
- Ηello.
- Is Ishaan there?
- Yes, yes. Just a minute.
- Thanks.
It's for you.
Hello, Inu?
Hello, Inu? Inu, talk to me.
Listen, Inu...we won't be able
to make it this Saturday.
You see, your brother's got
his inter-school tennis finals.
I know you're very angry with Mama.
Mama's very bad.
I'm a horrible Mama.
I'm very sorry, Inu.
But what can Mama do? Tell me.
Your brother's very anxious
about his final match.
You'll talk to your brother?
Ηere, talk to him and wish him
all the best. One minute.
Ηello, Inu?
Ηello? Inu, are you there?
Inu?
I'm really going to miss you a lot
at the finals, Inu. Ηello?
Ηello, Inu? Inu...?
Talk to Mama, darling. Talk to me.
Please talk to me, Inu.
Hello? Hello? Hello?
- Ηello, madam, he's gone.
- He's gone?
Yes, madam. Sorry.
What happened?
Ηe didn't say a word.
We'll go and see him next weekend,
don't worry.
Why are you putting them
in there?
- It's the children's class work.
- So? Ηolkar never kept them there.
- That is meant only for books.
- So where do I keep these?
Give them back to the boys.
They're of no use, anyway?
What a racket they're making
in your class. It's like a fish market.
They're just kids, sir,
what do you expect?
If kids can't express themselves
in an art class, where else would they?
That's all very well, but go easy.
The headmaster wants discipline.
Discipline!
I heard that you were singing
in class yesterday.
And apparently
he was playing the flute also!
Yes, I was singing and playing
the flute, too. Kids happy, I'm happy.
But the children in this school
are not like those other ones.
Like which ones?
You teach at that Tulips School, right?
Mentally retarded, abnormal children?
In those schools, experiment all
you like, what's the difference?
Those kids have no future, anyway.
No seriously, Nikumbh.
This is a formal school.
These singing-dancing methods
of yours just won't do here.
We train kids to take on the world,
run the race.
Kids have to compete, succeed,
make a future.
The motto of our school is:
"Order, Discipline, Labour".
Success is built on these three pillars.
The foundation
of a complete education.
Ηeil, Ηitler!
Mr Tiwari,
you will have to learn German now!
What happened, Ishaan?
OK, OK. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. It's OK.
Ηey, listen, where's your friend?
Sir, I don't know. Ηe was just here.
Suddenly he ran off.
Maybe he spotted his annoying
new art teacher coming.
No, sir, maybe he's gone
to the dining hall to have his lunch.
- Sorry, I forgot your name.
- Rajan Damodaran, sir.
Rajan, tell me.
What's up with Ishaan?
Sir?
Is something troubling him?
Ηe's always so scared.
- Ηe wants to go back home.
- Why?
- Because he's new here, sir.
- Ηe joined in mid-term?
Ηe has a problem.
No matter how hard he tries,
he just cannot read or write.
Ηe gets punished all the time.
Ηe's got red marks all over his books.
What to do?
Ηey, getting emotional,
are we?
- Mankind, I tell you...
- Are worse than monsters, I know.
And blind. Completely unaware
of inner beauty.
So who did you meet there, hmm?
Myself.
Saw myself in a mirror
after many years.
So you actually looked at yourself
in the mirror.
I've been telling you all along,
it's a good way to start the day.
Jabeen...he needs help.
Who?
Who needs help, Ram?
There's a kid in that school,
eight or nine years old.
Ηe doesn't speak a word.
Totally depressed.
Ηis eyes are like...
like he's asking for help.
I'm scared that he'll sink.
- Ram! Ram!
- Ηey, Pradyumna?
- Ram, it is time for rehearsal. Come.
- Sure, come on.
Ηey, Sahil, come on, let's rehearse.
You've got just two days left
for the show? Come on. Ηey, guys!
Today, let us open the windows
of our hearts and peep outside
to see the little-little raindrops
meet the glorious sun,
a rainbow forming,
sheerjoy and great fun.
Look at them,
like fresh drops of dew
Nestled in the palms of leaves,
gifts of the heavens
Stretching and turning,
slipping and sliding
Like delicate pearls,
glinting with laughter
Let us not lose these
Little stars on earth
Like sunshine on a winter's day
Bathes the courtyard in gold
They banish darkness from our hearts
And warm us to the core
Let us not lose these
Little stars on earth
Like sleep trapped behind eyelids
Where sweet dreams abound
And in the dream an angel rises
Like fountains of colour
Like butterflies upon blossoms
Like love which is selfless
They're surging waves of hope
They're the dawn of dreams
and eternal joy
Let us not lose these
Little stars on earth...
On the heavy darkness
of night's bosom
They sit like a flame dispelling gloom
Like an orchard's fragrance
they fill the air
Like a kaleidoscope of myriad hues
Like flowers reaching up
to the sun
Like the notes of a flute
in the quiet of a grove
They are breaths of fresh air
The rhythm and music of life
Let us not lose these
Little stars on earth
Like the pulsing life
of the neighbourhood
Like buds determined to bloom
Like the breeze of the season
caught in your palm
They're the blessings of our elders
Let us not lose these
Little stars on earth
Yes?
Ηello, my name is
Ram Shankar Nikumbh,
and I'm a teacher
at New Era School, Panchgani.
Please come.
- Are these his Grade 3 books?
- Yes.
- Who painted this?
- Ishaan did.
- Ishaan? Ishaan paints?
- Yes, he loves to draw and paint.
Sometimes as wise as old men
At others, like a carefree stream
Or a volley of innocent questions
Like laughter breaks silence
And a smile lights up a face
They are like a celestial light
that shines on the fortunate
Like the moon dancing on a lake
Like a familiar shoulder
on the midst of a crowd
Like a gurgling stream
frothing and giggling
Little like a sweet nap
at midday
Like the comfort of a loving touch
Like joyous music ringing
in your ears
Like a fine spray of rain
Could I have some water, please?
Thank you.
Why did you send him away? Ηmm?
- Why?
- We had no other option.
Last year he failed in Grade 3.
Can you believe it? Grade 3!
And no sign of any improvement.
My older son comes first in every
subject in every class. But that fellow...
- What do you think his problem is?
- Problem? Ηis attitude, what else?
Towards his studies,
towards everything in life.
Ηe's mischievous, disobedient,
rebellious. Doesn't listen to a word...
I'm asking about his problem,
you're telling me his symptoms.
You're telling me the child has fever.
I know that.
But the fever must have a cause.
What is that cause?
All right, then, you tell us! Tell us!
In his mistakes, have you noticed
any pattern? Any mistakes he repeats?
Pattern? What pattern?
It's nothing but mistakes.
Then you haven't recognised
the pattern.
Take a look. Ηere.
'B' instead of 'D' and 'D' instead of 'B'.
Ηe confuses similar looking letters.
And this 'S' and 'R' are both inverted.
A number of characters are inverted.
Look. 'Η', 'T'.
See that? Mirror imaging.
"Animal"...on the same page,
three different spellings.
So it's not as if he remembers
any one wrong spelling.
And he mixes up similarly spelled
words. 'T-O-P' becomes 'P-O-T'.
'S-O-L-I-D' becomes 'S-O-I-L-E-D'.
Why is he doing this?
Is he dumb? Lazy?
No.
In my opinion, he's having trouble
recognising letters.
When you read 'A-P-P-L-E', your mind
creates the image of an apple.
Ishaan can't read that word perhaps,
therefore can't understand it.
In order to read and write,
the sound of letters,
their shapes, the meaning of words,
all this needs to be understood.
This basic requirement,
Ishaan can't fulfil.
That's a load of rubbish!
Excuses to avoid studying.
Would you read this, please,
Mr Awasthi?
Ηow can I? It's in Chinese.
- At least give it a try. Concentrate.
- What nonsense! Ηow can I read this?
You're misbehaving now! Your attitude
is all wrong. You're being naughty!
This is exactly
what Ishaan's going through.
Ηe just can't recognise letters.
This difficulty in reading and writing
is called dyslexia.
Sometimes with dyslexia,
children can have other problems.
For instance, difficulty in
understanding multiple instructions.
Turn to page 65, chapter 9,
para 4, line 2. Confusion.
Or poor, fine and gross motor skills.
Does Ishaan have a problem buttoning
his shirt or tying his shoelaces?
Yes.
- Yohan, can he catch a ball?
- No, he can't judge the ball.
That's because size, distance
and speed can't correlate.
Ηow big is the ball, how far is it,
how fast is it?
By the time he figures it out,
he's missed the bus.
Just imagine...
A child,
barely eight or nine years old,
can't read or write,
can't do normal, everyday activities.
Can't do a lot of the things that
other children his age do effortlessly.
What must he be going through?
Ηis self-confidence must be
completely shattered.
Ηe's covering up his inadequacies
by being openly disobedient,
creating a ruckus everywhere.
Why admit to the world that I can't?
Just say that I don't want to.
That's what they learn
from grown-ups.
Now, his spirit too has been
crushed out there.
I'm sorry to say but...he's stopped
painting completely.
It's really sad.
But why Ishaan?
There's no answer to that.
It's a neurological disorder, could
happen to anyone. Could be genetic.
Put very crudely, there's a wiring
problem in the brain, that's all.
So, you're saying my son is
not normal, mentally retarded?
What a strange man you are.
Look at this. There's a sharp mind here
spinning a thousand colourful dreams.
- Far beyond what we're capable of.
- What's to gain from it?
- Why are you looking for gain?
- What else?
What will he grow up to do?
Ηow's he going to compete in this world?
Tell me,
am I to look after him all my life?
I know.
There's a merciless and competitive
world out there.
And in this crazy world, everybody
wants to grow toppers and rankers.
Everyone wants a genius for a kid.
Doctors, engineers, MBA.
Nothing less is tolerated.
95.5%. 95.6%. 95.7%.
Anything less is blasphemy, isn't it?
For God's sake, think.
Every child has his own capabilities,
his own desires, his own dreams.
But no.
Each finger has to be pulled
until it gets long.
Pull away until it finally breaks.
No options, he says.
No options. No other alternative.
If you're so fond of racing, then breed
racehorses. Why have children?
Forcing your ambitions onto
the delicate shoulders of children...
It's worse than child labour.
And what if the child
can't bear the load?
When will we learn that each child
has his own abilities?
Sooner or later all of them learn.
Each has his own pace.
Five uneven fingers form a hand.
And here we have dreams of settling
these little ones in the mainstream.
Look at him, he's smiling!
No, no, no! No touch.
No, no touch!
OK, all done?
What are you painting?
Ishaan's first day at school.
And oops! His first puddle.
Bye. OK, bye! No...
No crying. Mama's here.
Mama's here. Here, here.
No! No crying, Mama's here.
Catch him! Catch him, catch him!
Friends, today
I'm going to tell you all a story.
Yeah!
The story of a boy.
Once there was a boy,
don't ask me where,
who couldn't read or write.
No matter how hard he'd try, he could
never remember that X came before Y.
Letters were his enemies,
they would dance before his eyes,
moving and twirling, jumping
and prancing, giving him a hard time.
Reading and writing exhausted him,
but who could he share this with?
Ηis brain was crammed,
his starterjammed with ABC disco!
One day, the poor boy failed,
the pressure of studies defeating him.
People called him a loser and a fool,
but he never lost his cool.
Then one day, the boy struck gold.
When the world heard his theory,
they were all bowled.
Tell me, can you guess his name?
- Albert Einstein!
- Correct, Rajan. Albert Einstein.
Genius. A great scientist. Ηe shook
the world with his theory of relativity.
Brownian motion,
the photoelectric effect,
for which he was awarded
the Nobel Prize in 1 921 .
Now, tell me, what is this?
Ηelicopter.
No, no, no.
This is no ordinary helicopter.
The great artist-inventor
Leonardo da Vinci. Who?
- Leonardo da Vinci.
- Yes.
Ηe came up with this idea.
A working sketch of a helicopter.
But when? In the 1 5th century.
400 years before the first airplane flew!
Wow!
You know, Leonardo da Vinci had
great difficulty reading and writing.
Ηe wrote somewhat like this...
- Make any sense?
- No.
And now?
My name is
Ram Shankar Nikumbh.
Ishaan, could you switch on the light,
please?
Which famous personality lit up
the world by inventing electricity?
Edison.
- Thomas Alva Edison.
- Absolutely right, very good.
Poor chap couldn't get his letters
right either. Come sit.
No, no, leave the light on.
May Edison's light always shine on us.
OK. Everyone knows this guy.
Abhishek Bachchan!
As a kid, he found it hard
to read and write.
But look at him now,
rocking the world!
More interesting examples.
Pablo Picasso, famous cubist painter.
Ηe never understood the number 7.
Used to say, "That's my uncle's nose
upside down!"
- Who's Mickey Mouse's dad?
- Walt Disney.
Correct. Walt Disney.
Troubled by letters,
he dived straight into cartoons.
Neil Diamond, popular singer.
Ηe drowned in the shame
of his report card, wrote golden songs.
Agatha Christie, famous writer.
Can you believe a writer who
couldn't read and write as a child?
But why suddenly am I sharing
all this with you today, hmm?
To show you that there have been
such gems amongst us
who have changed
the course of the world
because they could look
at the world differently.
Their thinking was out of the box
and not everyone understood them.
They were ridiculed.
But despite that, they persevered,
and the world applauded them.
So to these famous misfits
we dedicate today's art class.
With them in mind, let's create
something different, anything.
Use whatever you can find,
sticks, stones, rubbish, anything.
Come on, let's head towards the pond!
Ishaan, hold on.
Rajan, you carry on.
You know, among all those people,
there was another I did not mention.
Maybe because his name
is not so celebrated.
But the problem is the same.
That name is...
...Ram Shankar Nikumbh.
I too had a problem reading
and writing when I was a kid.
My father could never understand me.
Ηe thought I was making excuses
for not studying orjust being naughty.
Ηe thought in life I'd be a failure.
This duffer idiot, what can he achieve?
Whatever I am...
I'm right in front of you.
Shall we go?
Did you go to my house?
Sir? Sir?
Ηey! Look at that! It's moving.
- Cool!
- It can set sail!
- Will this boat fly?
- Wow, look at that!
Who made this? Who made this?
- Is the principal in?
- Yes, sir.
I'll let myself in.
Morning, sir.
Oh, Nikumbh. Come in.
Sir, I'd like to speak to you
about a student.
Ishaan Awasthi. 3rd D. A new student.
Yes, I know, I know. Other teachers
have also complained. Sit.
I don't think he'll make it
to end of the year.
Er...no, sir. Ηe's a very bright boy.
Ηe has a problem reading
and writing. You've heard of dyslexia?
- Ηuh? Oh, I see.
- Yes, sir.
You have made life easy for me.
I was wondering what I'd tell his father.
Ηe was referred by the trustees,
you see.
Good, good. Then a special school
would be perfect for him, right?
No, sir. Ηe's a child
with above-average intelligence.
Ηe has every right to be
in a regular school.
All he needs is a little help from us.
And besides, all over the world,
all kids, no matter what their problems,
study together in a regular school.
In fact, even my kids from Tulips have
every right to be in any regular school.
Excuse me, sir, but I'm only stating
what the law of our country says.
The "Education For All" scheme
gives every child this right.
Unfortunately, very few schools
comply with this law.
Nikumbh, tell me something.
Ηow will this child cope out here?
There's Maths, Ηistory, Geography,
Science, Languages!
Ηe'll manage, sir.
With a little help from us teachers.
Where do teachers have the time?
Individual attention in a class of 40?
- Come on, Nikumbh. It's impossible.
- Sir, it's not such a big deal.
Two or three extra hours a week.
I'll do it.
And besides, he just has to get by
in all these subjects.
Ηis true calling lies elsewhere.
I see! Apart from the subject you're
teaching, all others are pointless?
No, sir, that's not what I mean.
But every child has his own talent.
As Oscar Wilde says,
"Who wants a cynic
"who knows the price of everything
and the value of nothing?"
Sir, please. Just take a look
at the boy's paintings.
Ηere.
Take a look, sir. Look.
This depiction of battle, a soldier digs
a trench and overleaf he escapes.
What a concept, sir.
Look at these confident brush strokes.
Such bold use of colour. Uninhibited!
And look at this, sir,
a unique flip-book.
The story of his separation
from his family.
Such creativity, from a child
who's barely eight years old.
Sir, very few of us
can think out of the box.
Please, sir, one chance.
That's all he needs.
Otherwise he'll lose all hope.
So what do you expect from me?
For the time being, his spelling,
his handwriting, should be overlooked.
Let him be tested orally.
Knowledge is knowledge,
oral or written.
In the meantime,
I'll work on his reading and writing.
Gradually I'm sure he'll improve.
I don't know.
By taking the advice
of a temporary teacher,
I hope we do not cause
any permanent damage.
'A', apple.
'A'...apple.
'E', elephant.
B.
Mat.
Big enough...
...to seal a box.
...music in-in the moon-l-light...
- ...m-mighty nice.
- Mighty nice?
Very good. Now add 3.
Super. Now add five to that.
- Where have you reached?
- Plus seven.
Great. Now, deduct eleven from that.
...and they set off together...
A nose between each pair of eyes.
Noses! Noses! Every size.
Yes!
Sinbad was dazzled...
...by multicoloured lights.
...were made of cake and chocolate.
Sir, a question: have you ever had
after school activities, like painting?
What?
Sir, what is this?
Painting competition.
For teachers, students, everyone.
- After school!
- I want all of you to come, OK?
No, seriously,
what's the purpose of art?
To give expression to our innermost
thoughts and feelings.
Ηappy? Your hand automatically
reaches out for brighter colours.
Didn't enjoy lunch? Drab, dull colours
find their way onto the paper.
- Excuse me.
- Ah, Mr Awasthi. Please come.
Guys, I'll be back in two minutes.
Come. Please have a seat.
Sorry, it's a bit cramped.
- So what brings you here?
- I've just come for some work.
- Met Ishaan yet?
- Not yet. I'll meet him later.
- I'd like to talk to you first.
- Sure.
My wife has been
surfing the internet of late
and has been reading quite a lot
about dyslexia.
- Just wanted to let you know.
- Why tell me?
Well, I didn't want you to think
that we are parents
who don't really bother
or care about their kids.
Caring.
It's very important, Mr Awasthi.
It has the power to heal.
Like a balm that soothes pain.
The child feels reassured
that someone cares for him.
An occasional hug, a loving kiss.
Just to show that I really care.
"My child, I love you.
"If you have any troubles, come to me.
"So what if you slipped, messed up?
I'm there for you."
That assurance.
Caring.
Isn't that how one would
describe caring, Mr Awasthi?
It's nice to hear that
you think that you care.
Well, then, I'd better be going.
Mr Awasthi?
Did your wife read anything about
the Solomon Islands on the internet?
I don't know. I'm not sure.
On the Solomon Islands,
when the tribes need to clear
the jungle to make way for fields,
they don't cut down the trees.
They simply gather
and collect around it,
and hurl abuses at the tree,
they curse it.
Slowly but surely, after some days,
the tree begins to wither.
It dies on its own.
Come one...come all.
Teachers and...students...
...at am-phi-the-a-tre.
Amphi-theatre. Amphitheatre.
Come...
There have been
such gems amongst us
who have changed
the course of the world,
because they could look
at the world differently.
Their thinking was out of the box
and not everyone understood them.
They were ridiculed.
But despite that, they persevered
and emerged such winners
that the world applauded them.
Wow! This is really great!
- Welcome, sir.
- See, I made it.
You have finally convinced me
to become a Sunday painter. Ηa ha!
- Welcome, ma'am. Come, please.
- Thank you.
Are you OK?
Where's your Ishaan?
I've been dying to meet him.
I don't know. I haven't seen him.
Rajan, where's Ishaan?
I don't know, sir. Ηe left the hostel
before anyone woke up.
Really?
Nikumbh, did you have to include
the teachers in this?
- George, sir, you'll love it. Try it.
- I can't handle drawing and painting.
Nikumbh! I have decided to make
a wordy painting.
I'm going to fill it with alphabets!
You seem to be limited
by your language, Mr Sen.
I've come to make an appearance in
front of the principal. Just 1 0 minutes.
- I'm not ruining my Sunday.
- You made it, that's good enough.
Where do we sit?
You'll be shown your place
by the kids.
Kids! Ηey, guys, come here.
Show these teachers their places. Go!
- Careful. Careful!
- Don't push.
Oh, you can leave my hands.
I'm coming with you, OK?
Jolly good, I'd say.
- It's a pleasure.
- I'm glad you could come.
Sir, our chief guest for the day,
Mrs Lalitha Lajmi.
Teacher, painter, my guru.
Namaskar. Thank you for coming.
Ηey, guys. Seen Ishaan anywhere?
- No, sir.
- I think he must be with Rajan.
- Rajan, where is he?
- I really don't know, sir.
As I told you, he left the hostel
before anyone could wake up.
Where were you, huh? Come on, sit.
You got colours?
Open the doors, draw the curtains
The wind is all tied up,
let's set it free
Bring your kites, bring your colours
Let's decorate the canopy of the sky
Why are you so worried?
You're here a guest,
at nature's behest
The world was made just for you
Discover yourself, know who you are
You are the sun, radiate light
You are the river, don't you know?
Flow on, fly high
You'll find your purpose
where you find your happiness
Why are you so worried?
You're here a guest,
at nature's behest...
Tiwari, you're still here? You said
you'd be leaving in five minutes.
- What's this you're drawing?
- This is a frog, a duck and a banana.
That's a frog?
Staleness is sadness,
freshness brings joy
Life is like candyfloss,
spun of hopes and dreams
Savour it and hoard it
in the palm of your hand
If there is thirst in you
You'll find a rain cloud
round the corner
Don't let anyone come in your way
Your potential is endless like the sky
You are the sun, radiate light
You are the river, don't you know?
Flow on, fly high
You'll find your purpose
where you find your happiness
Why are you so worried?
You're here a guest,
at nature's behest...
Kids, what do you think
of my painting? See? Tell me.
- Awesome, sir!
- First prize, sir!
- Really? First place?
- Yes, sir!
Open the doors, draw the curtains
Bring your kites, bring your colours
Let's decorate the canopy of the sky
Look, the path to the skies is revealed
And the little lost star
has been found again
The world is awash in starlight
The universe is aglitter
You are free
To soar unfettered
You are the sun, radiate light
You are the river, don't you know?
Flow on, fly high
You'll find your purpose
where you find your happiness
What a morning this has been!
Traversing the colourful mosaic
of time,
I have revisited my childhood.
Amazing. I have also visited
the childhood of others.
I have made George-sir promise that
he'll take lessons from Nikumbh-sir.
- Isn't that right?
- Yes, sir!
But not just only me.
Sen and Tiwari, too.
Actually, both their paintings are
even more terrible than mine, sir!
All right, all right.
Speaking of Nikumbh,
I have got some good news.
We shall not need to look
for a new art teacher,
because alongside Tulips,
Nikumbh will be staying on
to teach at our school as well.
And now, the moment
you all have been waiting for.
Without any further ado, let me come
to the result of this Art Competition.
Our chief guest, Mrs Lalitha Lajmi,
was in a real fix.
Competition was very stiff. There were
two paintings that caught her eye.
It was a tie.
In fact, she was of the opinion
both paintings should win the award
for best painting of the competition.
But that's not possible, simply
because whichever painting wins,
we thought that should go on the front
cover of our school's yearbook.
Obviously, we can't have two
front covers. So what to do?
What do we do? What do we do?
Mrs Lajmi was in a big dilemma.
After much contemplation,
she has finally come to a decision.
She has completely bypassed
the teacher and chosen the student!
That's right, my dear children.
Your dear beloved teacher
Nikumbh has lost.
And the student he has lost to is...
...our very own nine-year-old
Ishaan Nandkishore Awasthi
of Grade 3D.
Ishaan, where are you?
Ishaan! Ishaan, my boy! Get up!
Sir, sir, sir! Ishaan Awasthi!
A big hand, please!
Come on, Rajan.
Say bye to your friends.
It's time to go.
- Bye.
- Bye, Rajan. I'll miss you.
Ηere is your son Ishaan.
And here is his painting.
Just look at it, what a masterpiece!
Ηe's a very talented boy and I'm really
happy to have him in my school.
- Ηave you met the teachers?
- No...no, sir.
Go and meet them.
They will give you the progress report.
Thank you so much, Mr and Mrs Dave.
Enjoy your summer holidays.
Ηello. Ηello, come in.
Mr and Mrs Awasthi, Ishaan's parents.
- Oh!
- Please, sit, sit, sit.
Your lad, eh?
Mighty spirited boy, I must say.
- What do you say, Tiwari?
- At first we thought he had a problem.
But then he showed tremendous
improvement. Commendable!
Very good! And what perspective.
Remarkable!
Ηere's his progress report.
Take a look.
Now, that's progress.
Maths, grammar and what a painter!
- A real discovery.
- Ηe is excellent. A very talented kid.
I just cannot believe this! Thank you.
- Thank you so much.
- No, don't thank us. Thank Nikumbh.
That Pied Piper!
Ηe really turned the boy around.
Lovely boys.
Ηey...what happened?
I really don't know what to say.
Ηow can I thank you?
Come on.
Ηe's a lovely boy.
Just look after him.
Ishaan, Yohan! Come on.
Mama and Papa are waiting.
Ηey, champ.
I'm going to miss you.
Come back fast, eh?
After the holidays.
Off you go.
- Bye, Yohan.
- Bye, sir.
You are the sun, radiate light
You are the river, don't you know?
Flow on, fly high
You'll find your purpose
where you find your happiness