That's him!
What do you mean?
what do you mean with him?
Who? Him? Joon Hee?
You! Don't just keep silent!
Let's her hand go!
Hey!
Get out!!
What's going on?
Why?
Omo! Omo! Omo!
- You still don't want to let go?
- Hey! Seo Joon Hee!
- Hey!
- Ohmygosh! What's this?
What's happen?
What's going on?
-= Episode 3 =-
What do you want a$$hole!
Shut up!
- Why do act like that?
- Shut up!
What's happen with you actually?
Let's talk outside!
Hyeong, do you know him?
Where do you know him?
He's my friend.
What? Friend?
So you're much younger than me.
Oh, you're so young.
What are you looking at?
I won't just let him go today.
What's actually happening?
Why are you like this?
Hey, what's going on?
I'll explain later.
Shit.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
Where are they going?
They're not outside too.
What's actually going on?
I'll tell you later.
Why should...
Tsk, really!
Don't clean it up.
Just go into your room and change your clothes.
You're coming out with this kind of style
is weird enough.
Doing a thing that you never did.
Aigoo, really....
What's going on?
Explain it hurry!
You need to explain even you want to punch each other.
hat's happen with both of you?
Ahhh i'm going crazy.
Hey, ai'm gointg crazy too.
Jin Ah tell me that she like him.
The person she likes is here.
What?
Hyeong, he's my friend.
I'm also surprised.
Hey, what does it means?
Don't just stay silent you bastard!
I already warned you to get lost that day, right?
Are you Yoon Jin Ah's stalker?
Are you tired of your life already?
Bastard!
What did you say?
Hyeong what? Stalker?
This bastard dated two girls at one time.
Therefore she broke up with him.
He's a bastard!
- Hyeong, did you cheat?
- No, no.
This is...
It's not only me who's cheating.
Jin Ah is also having an affair, with him.
I've said it already, right?
She even told your parents
that she like him.
She said that just now.
Go away!
Seung Ho...
I told you to go!
Before my friend ... not ...
Before I kill you you better go away.
You didn't hear it?
You bastard! I told you to go!
You do not believe me?
Okay, just look at it later.
One day you will be sorry
because of this bastard.
That stupid Yoon Jin Ah, really
Hey, since when did you know?
You should told me if you knew it already.
The way you talk sounds like
you really care about your Sis.
Shit!
If only I knew it earlier,
I'll throw him down.
Don't butt in!
By seeing it you should know.
Ahh.. i'm going crazy.
Yoon Jin Ah said that she likes you.
His mind is crazy or what?
What happened?
Did you guys fight?
Lee Gyoo Min is cheating.
Then?
Do not talk about it first.
Joon Hee you why--
Mom!
Because Lee Gyoo Min is always bothering me,
I ask Joon Hee for help
pretends to be my boyfriend
to get rid of it.
Why did you say that you like him or what?
I just talk whatever
To get rid of him.
At least listen to my explanations first.
That's because you always talk nonsense.
You know how shocked I am?
Why did you angry to the kids?
The one is wrong is someone else.
Nonetheless thank you, Joon Hee.
It is okay.
Sorry for creating trouble.
You don't have to be sorry.
We are the one who should be sorry
Yoon Jin Ah you're really embarrassing!
How old are you to be cheated.
Do not date again next time
Ah you're noisy!
Time to eat.
No.
I'll be back
later when the atmosphere is calmer.
Come here!
Tell me everything!
Is it true that Gyoo Min cheating?
You're not really like Joon He, are you?
Mom, what do you mean?
Aigoo, don't you feel ashamed in front of
Jun Hee?
He is your brother's best friend.
What will other people think?
You ruin your own relationship.
Surely people will think like that.
What about Seung Ho?
His friend had to intervene.
You're not embarrassed?
Why are you so useless?
So why did you invite him without I asked?
Why ask Lee Gyoo Min to come here?
Want it thirty or twenty one
I was always told to get married.
Do you think marriage is a kids play?
You still have another reason?
If you're good enough,
how could Gyoo Min do this?
How many time did i tell you?
Mom!
Aigoo, you're the only one left in our neighborhood.
Other's daughter
is already married.
Once when the time comes they date
and then get married.
Where is the problem?
You're old
but why not get married too?
Because I'm not that great
like other's daughter.
Because I am your daughter
that's why I'm so useless.
This girl...
Stop it!
I'm here to get a beer.
It turns out that the owner is at home.
Looks like you're a bit depressed.
Who are you fighting with?
I'm a little tired.
I'm right.
A good person like you
rarely get mad.
Is it exciting fighting each other?
I'll take a bath first.
- Want to have a beer?
- Nope..
It looks like a real fight.
It's up to her want to marry or
want to become old just like that.
I do not want to know anymore!
Is it my fault?
I say like so for the sake of other people?
It's all for her.
Get some sleep.
How can I sleep now?
How could I sleep, my heart is burning!
Jin Ah will do it better next time.
You too!
You're not good at anything
Never fought anything.
Indifferent.
In the new office your rank rose to the leader
then left immediately.
Uh, why do you have to bring up
this problem again?
Why can't I?
If you stay longer in that possition,
how could something like this happen Jin Ah?
It's all because other people underestimate us.
Sorry.
No need to apologize to me.
You guys are not fighting out there, are you?
Joon Hee was about to hit him.
He hit him?
Almost.
If you want to find a substitute boyfriend
at least find someone more appropriate.
Lee Gyoo Min does not flinch because he's my friend.
Your brain is a little slow huh?
Then... what did you talk about outside?
What talk..
I told him that he have to go before
me and Joon Hee start to punch him.
Why is your life so great?
I've scolded enough.
Now you want to scold me too?
It's late, why are you here?
Because of the smell of alcohol,
so i'm here.
It turns out...
You...
But why did you know...
Ah, you didn't find me so you're going up here?
Yes, i rang your door but no answer.
I knew it you're here.
I'm here stealing the beer.
Come on! Where's Joon Hee?
He's home since before.
But went out again
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle b
Subtitle by
Subtitle by:
~
~ D
Subtitle by:
~ Da
~ Dam
Subtitle by:
~ Damn
~ Damn!
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!S
~ Damn!Su
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!Sup
~ Damn!Supe
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!Super
~ Damn!SuperS
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSu
~ Damn!SuperSub
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub I
~ Damn!SuperSub In
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Ind
~ Damn!SuperSub Indo
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Indon
~ Damn!SuperSub Indone
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Indones
~ Damn!SuperSub Indonesi
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Indonesia
~ Damn!SuperSub Indonesia ~
Indo Trans by:
~ totoro ~
Eng Trans by:
~ RIN ~
I'm really bored.
You're my savior.
Where did Joon Hee go?
Dunno.
Seems like he had a fight with someone.
He's so emotional when reached home.
He didn't answer when i ask.
He refused when i ask to have a drink too.
He's fine from the outside
but i don't think so for his mind.
Maybe his heart is stuffy.
Seems like he's upset
Maybe it's too stuffy so he went outside.
Honestly, when Joon Hee's mood is bad
i also become a bit awry.
As a man, he has no father figure
or brothers as a place to complain on.
Also do not have a mother who
standing by his side.
It's me only.
My ability is very limited.
That's why sometimes these days
I like to scold him.
Looks like you're here not for a drink.
W--Why?
Here I drink again!
Let's drink!
Why are there so many problems?
Tell me, quick.
This girl has no problem whatsoever.
Come on!
- Just sleep here then go home.
- Hmm.
That happy?
Still alive?
#*&$%# Really...!
Why?
Just kidding!
Why are you so angry?
Have a taste.
This is a new product.
You come to work so early?
Yes, pretty early.
Last night...
Really, thank you very much...
So unexpected.
I thought I was going to be scold because of
make a scene.
What?
It's late!
Go in.
What do you mean just now?
Why do you think I will get angry?
Well...
I messed up your plan to be back together with your ex.
Do you think I'm trying to get back with him?
If not, how could you
dress up excitedly?
Then invite him to your house?
yeah, right.
I did that, ofc you could missunderstand.
But...
That's because there's other reason.
Of course there is.
It was not me who invite him to the house.
According to your logic, does this make sense?
Is it possible for me to do that?
No matter who invited him,
if your attitude is firm,
No matter who invited him
he will not come.
That's common sense.
Nothing else, is it?
I went down first.
Deputy Yoon, come here for a while!
What happened to that store in Gasan?
I'm asked you to take care of it.
You instead create a content certificate?
Do you know how Isa-nim scold me?
Is this how you work?
What have you done?
The store owner in Gasan comes to the headquarters.
Why are you still standing here?
Solve this problem immediately !
If you can not fix this problem,
we will all be fired.
All of us!
Just because of you Deputy Yoon.
May I come in?
Hmm.
You go in first.
You sit here.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I do it this because
I have no other way.
The head office did not give me any more discounts.
I was told the i can't sell milk again?
You think based on you logic,
Does this make sense?
What kind of logic is that?
Ah!
Sorry.
I'm really depressed.
Therefore...
Certificate of content you send,
that means you will fight till the end, right?
Ahh.. even rabbits will bite when it's frightened.
I can not always be passive
and accept all requirements.
Of course.
If it always like that, then I can not live.
Right.
Then fight till the end.
Try keep walking till the end.
If every day just act half hearted,
better not doing it at all.
It's also inappropriate.
Yes, right?
This is something that should not be
spoken by people from headquarters.
I'm planning to resign.
I can not keep on with this job anymore.
Always sandwiched between companies
with the franchisor.
I'm also pretty sick of it.
You are likely to
take the legal route, right?
f necessary I can testify for you.
Uhm ... you will resign?
Then what do you plan to do?
I never told you huh?
My father is retired and always travelling.
I plan to go with him.
Do you want to come with us?
Just pulled the collar,
why are you sick already?
Wake up for a while.
Aigoo, aigoo...
Let me see.
Aigoo...
You're old.
That's why you're always so careless
What to do?
You eat the meds i bought first.
Then just sleep again,
maybe able to recover soon.
You need to eat rice first.
Standing may be difficult for you.
You better keep seated.
I'll cook for you.
Maybe it would be better to eat porridge?
You really have done a big thing,
big things.
Hyeong Jeong?
Yes?
Have you check the service desk?
- Yes, I checked it just now.
- Welcome.
Hello!
Hello, what kind of drink do you want?
I am from head office.
My name is Kang Se Yeong.
Are you Jeonju?
[Jeonju - franchise shop owner]
Yes.
What do you need?
No, nothing.
I happen to be passing by so
i just want to greet you.
I heard that you're
Deputy Yoon Jin Ah's friend.
Yes.
I heard alot about you from her.
Then you are Seo Joon Hee's sister?
Yes.
I've met him once
through Deputy Yoon Jin Ah.
Ah, so it's like that.
Since you're here,
want a cup of coffee?
May be inspection too?
You are very humorous.
Of course, I want.
But the coffee is on my personal expenses please.
The coffee ... maybe next time?
All of the total sales
must be returned to the head office.
The rest will be returned.
Must contact the recycling plant.
Wonder!
Why the hell you people really impatient?
Uhm... of course it must be stopped immediately.
You can save little by little.
This is for your sake.
What did I say?
Of course I am very happy it's for the sake of me.
Just say it.
Why is it so extreme?
Really!
Because my life is meaningless.
Life is ... why it's so complicated?
Stop! Your life is still long.
What are you talking about?
Do you think that being young will ensure
that everything will go smoothly?
Betrayed, hurt and then looking
consolation somewhere.
Trying to collect the passion
and then feel frustrated again.
Even so, never stop looking for hope
and trying climbing up with all of your might.
Everything is like this.
Exactly the same way of thinking.
I know, it's all for the sake of living.
Be strong!
You're going to stay up again tonight?
Why you're so dedicated suddenly?
I'm like this from the beginning!
Hello!
You're not full team today?
Oh, Deputy Yoon Daeri is around here
soon--
She went on a date.
That's not ossible.
I'm witness it.
I saw his boyfriend.
Oh Jeon Hee, I went to your sister's store.
Ah, yes..
Then one person goes on a date,
where are the remaining three will be going?
Of course going home.
I still don't know yet.
I thought you have a plan.
Just about to make a plan.
Joon Hee, when are we going to have fun
in an exciting nightclub?
Now is okay.
Hey, you stay up late ...
Apparently you mean going to stay up like this.
I'll take my bag first.
Me too.
Are we seriously going to a club?
My dress is not quite right!
If I knew it I'll  wear a sparkly shirt.
You pretty familiar with a club!
Deputy Geum...
You do not want to come, do you?
Just follow us! Just look around
like me.
Okay, if so...
What did you say? Yoon Jin Ah has another man?
Are you kidding me?
I've seen it several times.
Don't you know it?
If so, now way i don't know it?
But since I do not know,
it means nothing.
Then it means she lied.
Hey!
I saw him at her home.
In front of her parents.
She said it was the man she liked.
Hey, but do you know what's more silly?
That's he's Seung Ho's friend.
His brother's friend.
You ... do you mean the one in front of the office building?
The man who brought Jin Ah away?
Uhh! You know it right?
Why did you tell me that you don't know?
Hey, this moron do you asked to be beat?
How could he knew our meeting place?
Is there any other place around your shop
besides this one?
Ah!
Kyeong Seon, please go out now.
Your mood is like you're going to war too today.
Where did you fight before you come here?
People who provoked me is
not just one or two.
Pathetic.
But he's really stupid.
He thought there was something between
you and Joon Hee.
He said he met him at youre house.
Why did you not tell me?
Oh, I plan to tell you later.
Because i even feel annoyed to tell
you the story.
How annoying.
Is there such a situation?
I'm totally lazy to bring it up about that person
that's why I disn't tell you.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
But can you do it well?
If not, i have to die.
If it's like this I trust you.
I hope you keep the fighting.
-= Ye Eun =-
-= Deputy, come here! =-
Hey, Lee Gyoo Min!
Where are you going? My house?
Are you crazy?
I'm not crazy ... I'm being blamed.
I'm the only one who is considered as a trash.
I'm going crazy.
I want to meet your parents.
I want to tell them you're not much better than me.
- Because of it you have to apologize to me!
- Hey!
That moron too!
That Seung Ho's friend!
I want him to kneel in front of me and apologize.
Are you really this crazy?
- How bout you?
- You are such a lowly person?
Houw bout you? How great are you?
Does your education higher than me or does your family rich?
You forced me to be like this.
I told her we're here.
But Deputy Yoon can not be reached.
Do not mind her.
I'm going to die.
Just die!
Do you think I'm lying?
Yes, you lie.
You are really...
Hey! You really hate me that much?
You don't even care if i die?
Why can not I die?
How many times have I convinced you?
Because of that idiot?
Don't say this idot that idot
He's not a man that you can curse as you please.
It's not because of anyone.
Because I myself have been disgusted.
I'm the one who's stupid who has been thinking of you
as the center of my life ...
I was disgusted, as simple as that.
Gyoo Min, don't let us hate each other.
Live your life well, okay?
Be careful.
I will not give up!
I'll make you change your mind.
What is it?
What are you doing Deputy?
Did you dance the most popular move lately?
I saw you keep dancing
when did you have time taking these pics?
Who's keep dancing?
- When we leave Deputy Geum seems like being forced
but it turns out she's the craziest.
- Yup, exactly!
I am a highly capable person to
dissolves in the situation.
Good morning!
Deputy, last night I sent a message to you.
Everything went smoothly after meeting with boyfriend?
Where did you know?
That's not important.
What's important is you're back with him or not?
So, how?
It's practically ended.
I really want to contact you again
but your Joon Hee does not allow it.
Yes, Boss?
The store at Gasan did really gives me a headache.
But Yoon Jin Ah manages to finish it.
Looks like the store owner wants us to close
our eye so that he protest against us.
Not only that, but most likely
is a feeling of dissatisfaction.
But if we let it go, everyone will
follow in his footsteps.
Better to cut it right to the root.
In such circumstances it is somewhat
not a good move.
You're right.
The main focus of our priority is
we have to make the store can maintain
the operational well.
In short let Yoon Jin Ah finish it
and make the store recover as before.
At this stage, execute the company thightly
is the best solution.
Have you eat?
Oh ya, Deputy Yoon...
Regarding the using of personal cost for promotional merchandize
for new outlets opening ...
Ah, thst's...
I will try to finish it as soon as possible.
No, i think it would be a bit heavy
for an employee.
Let it be paid by the company.
I've done it. Just to know.
Isa-nim, I really do not think you are
pay that much attention to employees, I really respect you.
Nothing.
Yoon Daeri what are you waiting for?
Lower your head and say thank you Quick.
Why? No need.
Thank you, Isa-nim.
Is it the work of you Director, right?
Remove the personal funds issue.
I'm not that great.
I just finished it accordingly
with company procedures.
How many years have I been working here.
Arguably I still have the ability
to judge like this.
Before other people who also have the ability
to judge people knows..
You'd better get to work right away.
Thank you for always helping me.
I'm not just helping you.
So for a while you don't have to go to the office?
Yes, I have to work in the field.
Therefore...
the person in charge of this store
will be replaced with Kang Se Yeong.
I know who she is.
When Lee Gyoo Min's time came yesterday
she happened to be here to introduce herself.
How fast.
What?
Uh? Nothing
She works so fast.
In terms of work it should not be
causing any discomfort.
In terms of work?
Except this is for another period?
I mean if...
Oh!
You're worried I'll get closer to her?
So you're jealous already?
No, Mama.
I am hungry.
Let's go to eat!
I treat you.
Next time.
Today is the anniversary of mother's death.
Ah, it turns out today huh?
I forgot.
Even so it's okay.
Hey, do you want to accompany me shopping?
- I took my bag first.
- Okay
Time passed by.
It's been 10 years.
Yeah, right after Joon Hee's high school exams
she died.
It was really cold.
That's right, it's very cold.
About Father ... no news at all?
I'm more afraid if there's news from him.
I'm afraid if he said that his households
has gone again.
And invite me to live together.
Seeing you like this I feel that
You're cruel.
Because I'm cruel today is exist.
Hey, when I was left alone with Joon Hee
how do you think we can
survive?
Later after i met again
with my mother in heaven ...
I have to file a super expensive
demand letter.
I will tell her if I am
raising my mother's son very well.
Do you think I have a right to do that or not?
Still need to be questioned?
You raised him so well.
Although I do not know what kind of woman he'll meet
and how Joon Hee will live his life,
but I want to be a vicious sis in law.
I could not bear to see him seeing
other people's faces everyday.
I have to pressed her from the beginning.
Hey, by hearing it only already makes me
feel scared.
Interesting, right? You just watch
from the side.
Yeah, right.
Is it really ober between
You and Lee Gyoo Min?
Let's just talk other things!
Hey, one more question.
No matter how stupid he is,
how could he say there's something
between you and Joon Hee?
In which world is there a comedy like this?
Don't you think it's ridiculous?
That's why.
The evening crowd is not over yet.
Wonder if we can get a taxi
or not.
Joon Hee says he can pick us up.
Jin Ah, you're just going to go home.
No need.
I'll just go back from here.
It's not that far.
We'll just drive you home.
You hurry up and get the food ready.
I'll get the cart back.
Hey!
Hey, even if it's just for manners
at least you offer her.
She's already said no?
Really!
You're still angry since a few
days ago?
What's wrong?
What's makes you upset?
Upset what...?
Jin Ah Noona stopped by your shop?
Yeah, for this time being she has to go somewhere else
and worked as a temporary manager.
Just before almost spit out of words like
trash stores or something.
Maybe because she does not have the heart
so she decide didn't do it.
She is.. really!
She did not broke upe with Lee Gyoo Min
firmly,
may be understandable.
She said you went to Jin Ah's house.
Why didn't tell me?
I was there just for an hour.
She told you this?
Nope.
Lee Gyoo Min came looking for me.
Really gave me a headache.
Looking for her? When?
Yesterday.
With employees from head office ...
What's her name then?
Ah, Kang Se Yeong.
I was talking to her...
He suddenly went inside.
Yoon Jin Ah also chases him inside.
Maybe they had a big fight yesterday.
Jin Ah looks as if
she'll have a duel with him.
It makes people feel uneasy.
I really hope Jin Ah can stay
near my house.
When you get angry, went home then went out again that day ...
I went to your house for a beer.
I heard there's people who rang the door bell
so I opened.
Apparently it's Jin Ah who stood in front of the door.
My house?
She said because I'm not home,
so she thinks I'm at your house.
Hey, hey, turn right!
What are you thinking about?
I'm home
Yes.
Why buy so many fruits?
From Kyeong Seon.
Today is the KyeongSeon's mother's death anniversary,
so we're shopping together.
She asked me to take this for Eomma.
That's why I often say if
she is my eldest daughter.
Hey, sit here for a while.
- What is wrong?
- Sit down first.
You and Gyoo Min are really over?
Mom!
Yes, this is Gyoo Min's fault.
I know he did something inappropriate.
What part of him that makes you
fall for him?
Because of his education is high?
Or because he's a rich kid's son?
What do you think I am?
One day, i don't care anyone you met,
I hope you can find
someone who's better than him.
Do not just look at his appearance only.
Already fall into a hole, then unable to go out alone.
There will be no such thing.
You promised me.
Eomma wait for me?
Eomma how do you look us?
My daughter is great.
My son... is super handsome.
Yoon Jin Ah loves to eat this.
If I know, I'll take her here.
Anyone who hears must have thought
she is your daughter.
Sometimes I feel like she's
my daughter.
And I'm like his mother.
At the time Dad married again and
we live alone,
whose shoulder do you think that i could
lean my head on?
After all you are my little brother.
Jin Ah was the one who wipes my tears
and wiped my nose.
Even for a siblings,
there may not be such a bond.
I still have two dreams.
You guessed it.
One, whatever that is
but that must have something to do with me.
The other one I do not know.
Jin Ah finds a good husband.
Ah, because of talking about her
I miss her already.
What's that kid doing again?
Hey, what are you doing?
Tidying up the past?
Delete memory?
What?
Want to throw it all away?
You're wasting money again?
That's a show, a show.
Hey, what sins does your clothes have?
I Know.
Yes.
You...
Why are you here?
She said you came to my house.
Why did you go there?
Kyeong Seon just say this?
Why did she talk only a half?
Really.
Why just say this?
I went to Kyeong Seon's house
but she is there.
I have a feeling that she's in your house,
so I went there.
You're there to
meet my sis?
If Not... who else?
I want to ask, were you there looking for me?
That...
Yeah, I went there looking for you.
I feel guilty.
I also want to thank you.
But when i hear you talk
about logic and common sense ...
I'm glad that day i did not meet you.
If I hear that
in front of Kyeong Seon,
how embarrassed I am.
Why embarrassed?
Nothing wrong with my words.
Why are you ... suddenly here just to scold me?
Do you think I'm an easy person?
That's right.
Why do you have to show if
you are easy?
So that you meet a situation like this?
Dragged around by people who's
no one at all.
Who's dragged by whom?
You're ... really funny.
Really funny.
You're not laughing at all.
What is so funny?
Okay, just think of everything you
say is true.
Nothing else you want to say?
Satisfied?
I'm not done talking yet.
What's about the umbrella?
I have a feeling it'll be raining tonight
so i bring it with me.
Why?
Did you say you want to tidying up
your past?
You said you want to throw it all away.
What do you mean by this?
Then give it to me.
Let me throw it away.
Why should it be thrown away?
I struggled to pick it up again.
Looks like you really like that umbrella.
Shit, you bas ...
Then keep it well.
Come here!
Do you think i'm easy?
Try it if you dare.
Are you angry?
You can not not go home huh?
Then where should i go?
Just what is on your mind?
Nothing.
Why? What is wrong?
Let's get out!
Okay.
What do you want to eat?
Ah, no need.
Why? How about Cola?
I feel guilty again.
I don't bring any money.
If you do not have me, you do not have the fare home.
You can not go home!
Ah, got again.
I have to exploit it.
Then let's just say the Cola
is a service from me.
If so, popcorn too please!
S
Su
Sub
Subt
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle b
Subtitle by
Subtitle by:
~
~ D
Subtitle by:
~ Da
~ Dam
Subtitle by:
~ Damn
~ Damn!
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!S
~ Damn!Su
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!Sup
~ Damn!Supe
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!Super
~ Damn!SuperS
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSu
~ Damn!SuperSub
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub I
~ Damn!SuperSub In
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Ind
~ Damn!SuperSub Indo
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Indon
~ Damn!SuperSub Indone
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Indones
~ Damn!SuperSub Indonesi
Subtitle by:
~ Damn!SuperSub Indonesia
~ Damn!SuperSub Indonesia ~
Subtitle by:
Indo Trans by:
~ totoro ~
Eng Trans by:
~ RIN ~
That's mine
What?
Oh...
That movie is bad.
So the one you watched was not a movie.
I think you watch the same thing
as mine.
No way!
Are you hungry?
Yes I'm hungry!
Try saying "please treat me a yummy meal!"
You want to die?
Give it to me.
What? You want to buy me a meal?
You're gonna treat, right?
Seems so exciting.
Even so do not praise it in front of me.
Ah, okay okay.
I do not understand how to read a situation.
I'm provoking me to get beyond that.
Seems a bit too far.
The model really ...
When will it be done?
So tired.
Less prominent features or something like that.
Nothing special.
Stop it.
I am done.
Let me see!
Where's my pay?
I told you I did not bring money.
Have to be money?
So what do you want?
I did not bring anything.
Oh, there it is!
What?
Great facial expression.
Here!
Wow!
This is my look?
Exactly!
Wow, exactly as if it's photographed.
Does my body looks like this?
Yes, your body is small.
Hey, but it does not seem as small as it is.
It does though.
Nuna is small and adorable.
Adorable?
How old I am, really.
It depends on who sees it.
Hmm... okay.
Ah, still.
I'm now way past the age where
people call me adorable.
When I was in my 20s, I often did
hear people say so.
Ah I really know Nuna's past.
It's not till that much.
Yeah right, you know my past.
If not, that's ok.
Ah, after I think about it
it seems yes.
True, quite adorable.
Like a movie star.
Today let's just walk and eat until satisfied.
I'll find a time to
get it back to you 10 times.
You have to get ready for it!
I won't be shy.
I'll finish you.
Just leave my clothes alone.
This woman, really.
It seems like you like a
porn joke?
I'm just kidding.
You said you wanted to
fix your past.
Then I'm one of your past,
is that like that?
What's that like?
No.. what does that mean?
How could you have any thoughts
to throw it away?
What do you mean throw it away?
It's because i accidentally take it out.
That's why i keep holding it.
You said that you're affraid it'll be raining
that's why you take it with you?
Well, if it's raining, i'll use it.
If it's not raining then all is good.
What other purpose does Umbrella have?
Why do you insist to have a meaning behind it?
No, it's not like that.
But still do not throw it away.
Who said I will throw it away?
What if you throw it away?
I won't for sure.
Why for sure?
*gosh he's teasing her so hard XD*
You forced me again to think strange things.
What do you want?
Take care of it carefully.
I will.
*awww ^3^*
I am home.
What are you gonna do upstairs?
Ha?
Sleep right away?
Not right away
Why? What do you want?
*please think the same thing as me :p*
What are you going to do?
*kidnap you and put you on my bed UwU*
I do not know.. what do you want to do?
Want to join?
*=^3^=*
How about this?
*kay won't spazz again from now on, sorry /bows/*
Not yet, not yet.
Where am I supposed to go? Come here?
Nuna I will find you.
You wait for me there.
Have you found it? Have you found it?
Follow me.
Okay, you wait for me.
You come with me, right?
How long will you be placed in the Gasan store?
Don't know.
Please take good care of my other shops.
Later after I return
I will buy you a good food.
We'll wait for it.
Then I go out first.
Hmm, sorry has troubled you.
Deputy Geum's location is slightly far.
That's why I only gave you two locations.
Want me to thank you?
What's with her?
Deputy Yoon Daeri is not on purpose
do not want to work.
So? Nothing special with
shop in Suseo?
The one that the shop owner need is
might be something like personal taste.
Why ask her?
Just ask your brother right away.
Geum Bo Ra's really have a brain.
Later do not forget to treat me to eat a good food!
Yes
It should be her who treat you, isn't it?
Looks like after taking over the store
in Suseo you're so happy.
Working happily, of course I'm happy.
I'm not talking about work.
She wants to have developments with
Seo Joon Hee.
Ye Eun, why you don't want them
to get along?
Not only don't like it.
If Deputy Kang is dating your brother,
what do you think you'll do?
My brother?
Yes
That's ridiculous.
What are you talking about?
See that.
Seo Joon Hee is your friend's brother.
'It's not much different from your brother?
Yeah, right.
But my brother is my brother.
Friend's brother with my own brother
How could it be the same?
Any coffee in the office?
I go first.
Gosh, so fresh!
It's so good.
Really?
I just brewed it carelessly.
Careless brewed coffee is already this good?
Good coffee is different.
Who did this exactly? Really!
Lately there is a series of actions that destroy the goods.
It's hard to get noticed.
Why do not we have something special?
For example a kind of mason and wizard.
Bricklayer? Wizard?
Classic!
It's the same that Seo Joon Hee once talked about before, right?
It seems so.
Are not you feeling well?
I slightly nauseous also got a headache.
All day not feeling well.
Try eating this.
Yes...
If you're sick better go to the hospital.
All right, then I'll be right there.
He just said that he's a bit not
feeling well.
Yes.
I can take a taxi there.
You're so busy.
You skip work, right?
Nope...
I'm going out after the meeting is over.
I'm very competent.
Without me our company won't be
able to operate.
Oh, that's great?
How come I don't think it's like that?
Don't you think?
Noona is not very smart
in judging guys.
Huh, are you a man?
I'm just a metaphor.
Why should it be clarified?
I do not mean to ensure anything.
You are a man.
It's true You are a man.
What are you talking about?
What time are you going back?
Later?
Officially starting to work tomorrow.
I can go out anytime at Night.
Why?
I'll pick you up.
Really?
Ah, what's for.
Can I?
Aigoo, really.
Starting tomorrow we'll start earlier.
You should not drink beer.
Have to sleep earlier, kay?
I'll make a PO for all the ingredients
which still in deficit.
Aigoo seems to be the host and guest role is twisted.
Either I may or may not torture employees from headquarters.
It is a luxury to pay attention to the heart right now.
Aja-aja hwaiting!
Lots of profit!
Hwaiting.
But ... you suddenly turned so cheerful.
Me? Really?
It feels like two different people.
Due to the person waiting outside?
I'll go home first!
Have a good time.
Noona, that..
I mean if...
If what?
If I...
You what?
I mean not me...
Noona, I...
I...
Ask you to treat me tomorrow,
will you do that?
Did not I ever treat you?
Of course you can,
treat you to eat until you are full.
Seriusly?
Ofc!
Alright.
So soon?
Yeah!
Today I feel good.
Can be more exciting if you want to.
It's not only today...
Isn't it?
- In that case...
- Yeah.
I went home first..?
= The door is already open. =
You go home.
It's a service for you.
thanks.
Now is not the afternoon drinking time, but here still many guests huh?
It seems that Deputy and Jeonju-nim are very cohesive.
Your tone sounds a little strange.
I mean you meet at the right time.
The relationship between men and women also depends on the timing factor.
Mostly it's because the guy is blind.
It's so easy to mess things up.
Yes
I feel this way too.
But what if the timing goes wrong?
Wait until the timing is right?
If not dead by age,
it would be die because of weakness.
If you keep testing until things become clear,
it will be game over.
Why?
At least both know that they like each other.
Knew it, but it feels like almost dying because of short of breath.
Suddenlt there come a hunter who
immediately shot to the target.
It feels good and fresh.
He will be taken immediately.
Looks like the timing is really important.
-= Cup Ramyeon =-
-= Samgak Kimbap =-
[Triangle Kimbap]
-= Budae Jjigae =-
-= Tteokbokki =-
-= Tteokbokki ramyeon =-
-= Samgyeopsal =-
-= Chicken =-
Shoot it hurry!
Cepat tembak!
-= Kkott deungsim =-
[Ribeye Steak]
What?
Got one serving!
Hit it?
Good! Perfect!
Yass... the cool Team Leader Park!
The technique is cool! The technique is cool!
Daebak! Daebak!
Which is soft.
Pass!
Hey, it's your turn.
Here, here.
What? What?
Ribs, ribs.
- = Kkott deungsim = -
Hey, do not mess up.
No way you can hit that?
Got it! got it!
Clear this place.
Yes, Yes.
Boss,we really got a ribeye steak!
Tonight I have to go back to the office.
You're still working?
My team dinner will be over soon.
Until when do you plan to stay there?
There are still unfinished jobs.
It looks like it will be long.
Who do you texting with religiously?
Oh, my friend.
From Suseo shop?
I mean Joon Hee's sister.
No, another friend.
Ah ... it's done!
Hungry.
Let's go eat outside!
You have to treat me.
I ... there is still something to be done.
What else other than activity reports?
Clearly finished.
What is it?
You do not want to treat me to eat huh?
Come on, I treat you.
thanks.
The second round is next time?
What do you mean?
It's not you who pay this.
You're planning to force people
eat to death?
Hey, that's...
The pretty one from the coffee company.
Where are you going?
Yes, true.
Noona!
Hello!
Where are you going?
We just want to eat.
You guys just have a company dinner?
Yeah, just a few people.
Where do you want to eat?
Around here.
We're still looking too.
But Joon Hee, if you just have company dinner
you should have done eating, right?
Ah, we want to go have a drink.
There's nothing to eat.
If we go together ... is it okay?
I do not know ...
We also do not plan on eating.
Really a lot of people who think
like that.
But I'm not at all.
I have a little experience on relationship.
Deputy Yoon Daeri is far more experienced than me.
Oh really?
What then?
What kind of guy do you like?
Well...
Who makes me feel comfortable is enough.
Ah, you hate bad guys.
Then Seo Joon Hee is not qualified.
You're dead!Go home, go home.
Joon Hee, you a naughty guy type?
They talk nonsense.
What nonsense?
Yes, okay.
Then just think as if you are not.
How many time did you fail when chasing
a girl?
Never, right?
This means...?
The time you determine your mind,
the girl you want
Definitely--
You want to die?
You mean the success rate
is 100%?
No, 99%.
What's one percent left?
This means there is one girl who failed
to be conquered by Seo Joon Hee.
Who?
Who is it?
Let's drink! Drink!
Do you know who's the lady that
Joon Hee mention?
How could I know?
It should a woman younger than us.
We're not that old, okay?
Don't know who claims that she is old
and having trouble getting up early.
That's because .... so tired so
body condition is not good.
How great is the woman?
How could Seo Joon Hee
failed to get her?
But you ... why have you been smiling by yourself?
Me?
i didn't though!
For sure, he has someone.
But no progress at all
with that person, right?
If attack at a time like this,
victory will side with me.
I have to speed up the progress.
Must be more passionate.
Hey, but actually because of what
until such an expert hesitates.
There must be some fatal reason behind it.
Just ... afraid there is an 'if'.
What's that?
You mean you're not sure?
No.
I'm sure I have.
She's not sure?
I have not opened my mouth and asked her out.
You also can be nervous?
Why? You're affraid she reject you?
That's why I say fear there is "if".
Does that girl knows you did
trash stuff like this?
Trash? What about me?
Aigoo...
Looks like you like her a lot.
You really like her till you feel you're going to die.
Ah, where...
Come on, change topic! Change topic!
What's important for now is you
still have not take any decision.
Is that right?
For now ... you can say so.
EngTransBy RIN
Damn!SuperSub Indonesia di:
~ ngesub.com ~
EngTransBy RIN
-= Next episode=-
That's because you do not know how important it is
timings between men and women.
So are we dating?
You're beautiful.
Are you crazy?
I'm crazy.
Crazy because of someone.
Do you want to play my house?
But ... is this really okay?
is it a sin?
You set yourself right.
If I catch you, you're dead.
Jin Ah said you want to come here.
But i can't contact her phone.
Since when does Deputy Yoon
pay attention to this all?
I ... should not hold your hand.
What should I do if I have this kind of thinking?
Next time I will not let you
alone again.