Original: Anonymous
Translation: DigitalMediaful
Come in, please.
Thank you.
November
Please tell me your name,
age and date of birth.
My name Nonomiya Keita,
I am six years old.
My birthday is July 28.
Do you think Keita is more,
like his father or mother?
It seems my wife for her peaceful nature
and kindness towards others.
Have any noticeable flaws?
Probably, therefore,
but tends to do it all in stride.
Neither seem to mind losing.
For me, I'm his father,
it's a bit disappointing.
Keita,
What is your favorite season?
Summer.
What did you do last summer?
I went camping with my father
And flew kites.
Your father is good at flying kites?
He does good.
FUKUYAMA MASAHARU
ONO MACHIKO
MAKI YOKO
LILY FRANKY
Written and directed by Koreeda Hirokazu
Like Father, Like Son
It's changed?
Should do very well.
The stadium is not the one I knew.
Lower your voice.
I'm here!
- Have you studied much?
Fathers and mothers,
we're done for today.
We wish you a safe journey home.
Thank you.
Keita.
I've never been camping,
right?
Why do you ask?
The teacher advised it.
You have learned a lot in the academy.
She said: "The
omelet prepared by my mother."
You have fun?
- Yes
You have painted balloons?
With a handsome monster.
- A handsome monster?
Wow, I've been caught with their hands in the dough
.
How strange to see you here on a Saturday.
I wanted to leave before you came.
The model is fine.
- Thanks.
I've checked three times.
All yours.
I won't bother you anymore, I'm leaving.
Not be long,
take something then?
Well, I've been with my wife for a movie
.
Thanks to you and your delivery
I have time to spend with my family.
Counting on you.
- Very grateful.
Here is the South and here, the North,
right?
Yes, the sun comes out here.
For a few families in the park.
With dogs?
- Yes, it will look more everyday.
Listen,
boss invites them to eat something,
it's too late.
Can choose between pizza, rice with meat...
I do not dislike you go to a private school.
Ryota
believes should now strive for the future.
Sounds fixed.
I get it
- Maybe it's Dad.
I'll tell you what Aunt, bye.
Tell me, what?
It's Dad.
Coming to dinner?
I thought you'd come back later.
Not playing the piano?
I've finished exams, for once...
You have to have discipline.
If you lose one day...
- It takes three to recover it, I know.
Come on, Keita.
It's time for piano.
Come to play.
You've eaten?
The bath is ready.
Almost nothing, a piece of pizza.
Why didn't you text me a message?
Nothing to say.
I'll make a broth with pasta.
Minura sent us homemade pasta.
That's fine, go ahead.
Go easy with the pasta.
Don't worry. I'll be careful.
No eggs at night
too much cholesterol.
One is not going to make a difference.
Keita?
Penalized!
Why am I punished?
Come on, try again.
I hope Minura
does well with the new job.
Sure, yes.
Is made to live in the countryside.
Don't seem important.
You always were protecting.
Needless to waste time with losers.
Wow, I'm so sorry,
I'm also a loser.
Going to sleep?
I was stressed and tired.
We did what we could,
now it depends on him.
He works hard,
wants to be like you.
Do not you think he has matured?
You think so?
It appears that you have told Daichi
to leave him alone.
I hope it's true.
Today,
goodness is a defect.
In the interview you said that it was his strength.
You should praise him more.
Simply one of the two
spoiled him.
Is it possible?
Thanks for taking the day off.
Keita was delighted.
I would like to dedicate at least Sunday.
I will have more time when
we finish this project.
Six years I hear you say exactly the
same thing.
Really?
Yes, it is.
I forgot.
The hospital called, Maebashi.
What hospital?
Where I gave birth to Keita.
Yeah, and?
I don't know; they want to talk
to us.
About what?
They'll tell us when we get there.
I'm worried.
I hope it's nothing bad.
Exchanged kids?
This has happened before?
Yes
Most cases date back
to the end of the sixties.
Following on from that experience,
we write the names
with ink
on the soles of
newborns.
Then, what has happened?
Well...
How do we know that the child is not the child of someone else?
The blood test for school entry
does not match the parent.
But ours do agree.
- No.
Are you sure?
So, Keita...
is not our son?
Three babies were born male
in the hospital that day.
First we must ask for DNA testing.
Then we will know...
We have two, one left.
CONGRATULATIONS, KEITA
Come together.
Keita, congratulations for passing the entrance exam.
Okay.
- Later.
Well done!
- Great.
The tomato is good.
- Really?
So eat.
Open your mouth...
A fried shrimp.
A shrimp.
Take it.
Oh, okay.
- Very good.
Now!
Okay.
Want to see them?
Click here.
If you click here, see the previous.
- Exactly.
Come on, you can do it.
- Yes, hand here...
The four together.
Open your mouth.
The results of test 1
Nonomiya Ryota,
The results of test 2 Nonomiya Midori,
and the results of test 3 Nonomiya Keita
Show that they are not blood relatives.
Conclusion of the report.
Now I understand.
That is why I asked
if this provincial hospital was safe.
My mother had me there.
And my brothers.
- That is not enough.
You were very busy.
I felt very lonely.
At least
my mother could come see me.
Why I didn't realize it?
I am the mother.
Yes, they're here.
- We were delayed.
I told you to fill the tank.
Here they are.
Excuse use, we're sorry for
the delay.
My wife insisted
that I change my clothes
just before leaving home.
Good morning.
Family Saiki.
- Good morning.
...it's just been a tremendous surprise.
I'm his wife, my name is Yukari.
- Sirs...
- Nonomiya, my wife Midori.
Ryusei.
He is Keita.
We took that last summer,
we were in Sunpia.
You don't have a clearer picture?
This?
-Where was this?
-In Karasugawa.
Yes, the Karasu River.
In that river, salmon and trout fishing are
a good catch.
Look, look.
Ryusei with his brothers,
-the water gun.
What day was he born?
On July 28.
The same day.
Maybe we met here
then..
After giving birth I was pretty sick,
I had to stay in bed.
He was born on a very bright
sunny day.
Reminded us of a sunny day in Okinawa.
That's why we used the name, Ryusei,
as Chinese pictograph for 'sunny day'.
In cases like this,
a hundred percent of parents
just opting for the exchange.
For the sake of the future of children,
should be decided soon.
-Before the start of primary.
-It's too soon.
We talked about April,
less than six months.
-They are not pets.
-Although they were.
You're right.
Nor is exchanged for a pet.
Also,
apart from a drastic solution,
you haven't come up with another possibility?
Yes, of course. The hospital lawyer, Mr. Orima,
is studying the case.
I imagine, as a parent,
it is a very difficult situation.
However, right now,
we must consider the future of children...
It pleases them
What do you see without them?
Yes, we would also like to know
Keita.
Well, we'll be in contact.
-It's too late.
-I know, I'm sorry.
It's not important.
Well, how'd it go?
How are they, what do they do?
-He's got a shop.
-A merchant?
Go on...
-Mother.
Yes.
I forgot to give you this, before.
A gift!
From my sweet Tiger!
-I think it's sweet beans.
-Simple.
Sweet beans is not so bad, Mom.
If you insult the sweet beans,
you'll wake up the tiger.
-How is Keita?
-Asleep.
We played a lot of tennis on the Wii.
Tomorrow I  will have shoelaces.
I did not say anything then
but when the old Yamashita, our neighbor
,
saw Keita for the first time, said:
"He doesn’t look like any of them."
That was...
two years ago.
I think.
Ryota, your husband
is truly privileged,
compared to our family.
Some people did not see your marriage
favorably.
On second thought, many people.
It is possible that such
negative energy...
That's enough!
It has nothing to do with people
envying us.
Poor little me.
This is the area from the west exit of the station
Shunjuku.
It is an honor to introduce Shunjuku Spiral Tower.
It's a terrible tragedy.
I will make sure that it will
not affect my work.
But what will you do?
Change them?
No, we have not yet reached that point.
A solution may be to raise
them both.
Both of them?
Yes, you don't think it's right?
What's wrong?
You don't want to meet our son?
Course I do.
But if we continue like this,
end up ignoring the hospital.
It'll be fine.
Trust me.
Excuse me, excuse us.
He began to pick up when we were already out.
Hi, my name Ryusei Saiki.
And I am, Yamato.
I am Miyu.
Come, introduce yourself.
Hi, my name Nonomiya Keita.
Hello, how are you?
Thank you for your patience,
here are the drinks.
And here's the meal ticket.
Come Ryusei!
Equally. I've asked a lot.
That'll be 6,030 yen.
No, no.
-Let me do.
No, no way.
Check, please.
The name of the Maebashi hospital.
Yes.
And add this as well.
-Yeah, thank you very much.
You don't eat, you devour!
You've gobbled up all the potatoes.
I'm finished.
You want to play?
I want to go and play.
Go, go.
-Miyu!
-Take your brother.
Ryusei, watch them.
Children learn fast.
I wonder how much we can remove the
damages.
Damages.
The money it not important.
But have you discovered how this could happen.
Of course I have.
I think like you, but...
You will see,
they can only show good faith
compensating us economically.
Exactly, that's the way.
Have you already contacted a lawyer?
Being the case, let me handle the issue.
A friend of mine has a law firm.
Okay, ask him what he thinks.
-Dad!
I'm gonna make a call.
My neck hurts.
My mother!
We are not alike.
But he thinks so.
A friend frankly accused me of having an affair.
I found it very cruel of him.
But I never imagined it would like this.
'Goodbye, goodbye!
-Bye, Keita, see you soon.
What is it?
A note from Ryusei's mother:
"Stand by Me".
"Count on me"?
A rather arrogant comment.
You must be prepared.
It is possible that we have to take them to court.
A judgment?
Sorry, I had an unexpected
press conference.
-I know you're busy.
-I've been groping.
I do not care about money,
I want to know how it happened.
The hospital's lawyer is a redneck.
Knows bankruptcy and nothing else.
He understands nothing.
Appreciate your interest.
Do you mind?
I don't want the case to go to court.
I would like to have
custody of the two children.
Is an amazing idea.
Want to be the father of another child?
I wish they lived with us,
take my blood.
Your blood?
Today that is no longer needed.
It's not that, but,
it's the fate of being a father.
And even at least you
keep your paternal attachment.
Go, just leave it.
Listen to this.
In England
if the State determines that the
parents are unable to care for their children,
they end up under the care of an institution.
Yes, in the case of drug addicts,
or if the mother uses the house
for prostitution.
The mother speaks out immediately and the father cannot do anything.
I doubt that a court would deem
that parental neglect.
They have rights.
We can offer a lot of money
if I legally adopt him.
They will not accept
You could suggest it
at the right time.
Nothing's changed, as stubborn as ever.
As a lawyer,
I advise you to join them
to sue the hospital.
January
Have you thought about it?
This is our fourth meeting.
Perhaps
it's a good idea to start
sleeping in the other house.
Children adapt very easily at this age.
We considered this possibility,
but it has nothing to do with compensation.
Yes, yes, of course.
What's your opinion?
Mr. Saiki?
Yeah, well...
We've had good meetings,
but we should get to a solution, right?
He says that we can fix this.
Is there a better way for us then?
Well he said, it's good, but
I don't know if I like the suggestion.
But, it can work out.
They are of the same blood,
and that is what counts.
Once you understand it,
everything will work out.
We must also think about Miyu and Yamato.
I do not want to rush.
Exactly, we see no need to rush.
And you, Mr. Nonomiya?
I suggest we test it some other weekend.
On Saturday night, for example.
The elders are talking,
go and play.
Keita
You like to play the piano?
You do not have to do if you want.
But, Dad said I was very good at.
He's right, and there is the concert.
Shall we continue then?
We continue!
I'm not good at this.
I won!
Keita, eats soba pasta.
But not raw fish.
Listen, Keita.
Tomorrow we will leave here
at ten in the morning.
Because...
is white.
Because tomorrow you'll be
in Ryusei's home.
-Agree?
-Okay.
See,
it's kind of a mission,
so you get stronger.
-You know what a mission is?
Yes.
-Really?
It's part of a strategy
for you to grow up and make you stronger.
Mother...
This is really pathetic.
Good morning.
-Hi.
Hello.
Please take care of him.
Ryusei, in the back, please.
Oh my God.
Chuji.
Hey ,
you know that Spiderman
is a real spider?
-Man, it's cold.
- How are you all right?
Good, good.
I'm changing the bulb in the bathroom.
For the bathroom?
Use 60 watts.
Close the door, it's cold.
Want an LED bulb?
Don't need to piss with so much light.
40 watts is fine.
190 yen.
You have something to do
next Saturday?
-Wings--6 a.m.
-Still playing baseball?
You're a little old for that?
You throw.
I'm not for this shit,
my shoulder is old.
-He's an man.
-But, you're a boy!
'Come on, we'll see.
-I count on you, thanks.
Croquettes ?
Yes, croquettes.
Three
Four
Five
Six
Seven
Eight
Nine
Ten
Eleven
-Twelve
-That's a good number.
Thirteen.
Fourteen
Fifteen.
Here is the food.
Well, it's time to eat.
I'm hungry!
That's good.
Hurry or there will be nothing left.
It's warm, and tastes great.
-And for Dad.
-Only one egg for Dad.
Let's eat more eggs with sukiyaki.
-Eat.
-Is it good?
It's too hot. I can't eat it.
I'll turn down the flame.
It's good.
-You like it?
-It's good.
Ryusei.
Chopsticks; I'll teach you how to hold them?
Like this?
Look.
Wait, look how I do.
Move it like this.
Come on, you try it.
Keita, son.
You put this on the altar, please?
There.
Above!
It's time?
Can I ring the bell?
-Of course.
-Good morning.
Good morning.
- Have you done this before?
- In Grandma's house.
-At your grandmother's?
- Yes.
Well, hello all.
-Hi.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
Grandpa, this is Keita.
Please greet him.
Don't go near it.
It's smoke.
I think it works.
The batteries for the car.
Good!
-Which one?
-That one.
-That is "Skytree".
Yes, it is.
Oh, my God.
What time is it?
- It's quarter to three.
- Thank you.
-Want to go home?
-What?
- You want to go home?
Yes, let's go home.
I'm back!
Welcome home!
You've done well?
We came from far away.
Don't worry,
I was born in this city.
- And Ryota?
-He had a very important meeting.
He works hard.
I wish my husband would do the same.
"Leave for tomorrow
what you can do today,"
is my motto.
Yeah, keep it up and you'll be dead
before you do anything.
Do not try to scare me
I still have a few years.
Wow, what is this?
Nothing, an incident in the park.
I ran a lot and fell.
Bled a little, but it finally
stopped.
The bleeding stopped?
Does it hurts?
So you bathed?
It's very small.
As half of ours.
And how's Ryusei's mother?
In the beginning, she was scary, but
she's very good.
Very good.
Keita.
Do you think we should escape?
Where?
-Far.
-How far?
Someplace where nobody knows us.
What would Dad do?
Yeah, Dad...
Dad is very busy with his work.
Wait, Ryusei!
Yamato!
Wait, Yamato!
I caught you.
You're hair is soaked.
Wait, come here.
-Be still, I will dry you off.
-Now, it's dry.
Of course is not dry!
-It's dry!
-Behind is very wet.
-Turn around.
-Not my face.
Come here.
Come on, now we sleep together.
They create damage,
but don't, even bother to apologize.
For this, you should come with me.
No good to mess with me.
I'll put on a dressing
In Ryusei's house,
it's called a bandage.
Really?
Well, that's it.
Come, go say goodnight to Daddy
.
Good night, Dad.
-Sleep well.
How was the food, good?
A success. Kaoru found a college boyfriend.
The director was a great disappointment.
They say anything about me, make any comment?
They wondered why,
as a mother, I didn't notice?
Nothing at all.
Basically, I'll question you, then.
-I do not question it.
-Lying.
You think it's all my fault.
When can I go back to Ryusei's
house again to spend the night?
Next Saturday.
Can I take this?
Of course.
That's fantastic.
He's able to fix anything.
How marvelous!
Now,
ask him to fix the radiator.
Mom, do you want to stay?
April
I have...I must go.
It also gives me the feeling of being in a
hotel
I prefer to go home.
During the war,
many children were separated from their parents or lost,
and others just simply adapted.
In reality, what matters
it is who you raised.
I have not decided to raise him.
But then why all of this?
Why let them come and go?
We'll talk about it,
and see what decision we make.
Excuse me.
An old woman like me should not intrude.
On the contrary, your opinion counts a lot
I appreciate that.
We are prepared.
You're dressed well.
You're more handsome than the most handsome prince.
Good morning.
I'm here.
Yes.
Mr. Saiki.
Good morning.
The hospital has paid my
trip by train.
Please come in.
-For you.
-Thank you.
Nice place.
Ryusei already said looked like a hotel.
Keita, hello!
You're handsome!
You must be
prince from a distant country.
Is a pleasure to meet you, I'm his
grandmother.
Course, you are Keita's grandmother,
pleased to meet you.
But you are very young.
You do not get anything with flattery.
I guess that around you,
it's not needed.
-Can I?
-Don't worry.
Keita, what have you found?
-Here..
-A lovely petal.
-Take a picture.
-No need, no.
Look, I filmed myself
see?
Tsuyuki  Mao.
Mao-Tsuyuki, answered.
Yes.
Nonomiya Keita.
Yes!
I do not quite understand.
When I saw the face of Keita,
I saw Ryusei.
But now look at him,
and his face is that of Keita,
True?
Mr. Nonomiya.
Ryota!
He plays!
Look up!
What pain, what pain!
It can not go on, it's over.
I'm exhausted.
I should have had them before 40
I am too old.
Ryota is younger than me.
You should find the time
to be more with your child.
Well, in this world there are many types of families.
They don't bathe together?
At home, our idea is that it is separate.
Your idea
certainly is very respectable.
But believe me,
it's worth spending time.
Let's be honest,
in these last six months
I've spent far more time with him than you.
Come on, there's plenty of time.
Make no mistake,
for children, time is everything.
There are things in my job
that only I can do.
But no one can replace him
in his role of father.
Hey!
Ryusei!
We're going.
They look like brothers, it's incredible!
A pork curry take out, please.
A moment, please.
My father is at home
he's hungry.
Slowly, he's returning to childhood.
It is as if we had four children.
More like five, I think.
I can not take care for them all.
You mean me?
If so, perhaps
we can take care of the two.
Two?
Keita and Ryusei.
Wait,
are you serious?
Yes
Doesn't it seem possible?
I can not believe it.
Now you insults us.
-If we think of their future...
-Ours don't have a future?
I have more economic opportunities.
There are many things that money
can not buy.
Trying to buy a child,
that is it now?
He said before that he was interested
in money?
Excuse him, he's tired,
He doesn't know what he's saying.
The children are looking at us.
Your pork curry is ready.
He has never lost a game, right?
You don't understand how others feel.
How can you fix it?
Once, you get it, it's nothing
I still don't believe it...
clearly they're angry.
Please shut up a minute, let me think.
Now we started to get along.
Why should I tolerate a shopkeeper
giving me advice?
Do not start that again.
You're back!
-Latte for Mom.
Thanks.
Coffee just for dad.
Thank you.
-You're change, Mom.
-Thank you.
Well, here goes!
You have returned to give!
Well, way to go!
You left out, Keita,
must bounce within the track.
It's not okay, be careful
that doesn't leave the track.
You remember the nurse Miyazaki?
No.
- Maybe when you see...
- Are you going to testify?
Guess the hospital will try to show
working conditions of the staff were correct.
They were ironing, when we were leaving...
Please,
is not the time for nonsense.
I apologize for the other day.
Yes, of course.
No, no, it was our fault.
I swear to tell the truth and nothing but the truth,
according to the dictates of my conscience,
concealing nothing, and speaking the truth.
-Saiki Yukari.
-Nonomiya Midori.
Miyazaki Shoko.
Assuming the hospital commits a mistake,
shouldn't you have realized it?
As the baby's mother,
under normal conditions.
But I had a postpartum hemorrhage.
I was barely conscious
for several days.
Do you think that children are
exchanged without difficulties?
I don't know.
Even if we decided to exchange them,
there are no guarantees that the
children would adapt.
The pain this mistake has caused our family
is not easily erased.
It is a suffering that will continue
with us for many years.
Tell me, about the times,
you worked the night shift
several days in a row?
No.
Compared to other hospitals,
shifts were very good.
Being so, why do you suppose
this accident happened?
It was not an accident.
It was not an accident?
What do you mean?
The Nonomiya's seemed very happy with their child.
I did it on purpose.
I've had many problems raising my
children.
I took out my frustrations with other
babies...
Nonomiya's room most was the
expensive of all.
She told me that her husband was
in a large company.
His family came to see her all the time.
In comparison,
I had nothing.
Can you try to describe how you felt then?
Honestly, I think I was very happy.
That, I was not the only one with problems.
Well,
let's see.
Why are you confessing now?
...because of my children.
...and what I did then, was really monstrous.
I want you to punish me for what I did.
I apologize. Please forgive me.
I'm so sorry.
You can't relieve their frustrations.
I knew that her husband had children
when she married him.
Seemed relieved.
For her
is like stealing from a store.
Not seeming to understand the consequences of their actions.
Now he says he is happy.
How can someone be so selfish?
I think...it seems to me,
that the hospital must pay more for
damages.
- It's obvious.
- Yes, of course, much more.
Please ,
do not forget to ask Mr. Suzumoto.
Yes.
-She will go to jail, right?
-Yes.
Of course, that she will go to jail.
Now, about 5 or 6 years,
does not seem enough.
Unfortunately, the crime has prescribed this.
Prescribed?
Yes, I said it Suzumoto.
We could accuse her of child abduction,
but the statute of limitations is 5 years.
She apologizes and that's it, that's it?
-It's ridiculous!
-Please, lower your voice.
We can not allow it to be so easy for her.
We will always suffer,
yet, nothing happens to this woman.
She realized that the statue had
expired, so she confessed.
I know,
I will never forgive her.
Never.
Ever.
June
Let's see what you're doing.
See what flower stalk Megumi prepared.
She did so very well.
I was taking pills for the tension and
stress.
Is this the second?
The third.
Luckily it was Mr. Nobuko.
Well, yes.
Try calling her "mother"
when you see her, right?
Yes.
Don't you?
Imagine Dad is so weak that he asked,
his children to go to see him.
Just as well, you will not be bad at all
somewhat weakened.
When he see the roses, he'll cry.
-Change.
Thanks.
-Thank you for calling.
-Thanks for coming.
It's the only restaurant in
the neighborhood.
You are fully recovered from your illness?
Otherwise, you would not be here
visiting.
I told you the last time
I can not give more money.
I do not need money.
I work in a building in the Minowa district.
And she,
works part time.
-Stop playing the stock market.
-Silent, Ryota.
You like the salmon eggs? Eat as much as you want.
I love to do that.
But I must be careful with
uric acid.
I'll make an exception.
Why you know so much about salmon eggs?
And horse racing?
By your expression,
because you lose a lot.
You bet again on the wrong number.
Why you insist on suffering?
You have the wrong horse.
As you can see, it gives me no pleasure.
It appears that I am like you.
Well, that's married life.
You are completely devoted to him.
You work more than a nurse.
If I'm your nurse, you must pay me
thousand yen per hour.
That's what they pay me.
Takes three years with the piano,
but always plays the same,
"Delicate Flower".
There is no rest.
Quiet, or he'll hear you.
Exactly, I want him to hear me.
Well, you know him?
I mean your real son.
Yes, I recognize him.
- And you think he looks like you?
Sure yes.
That is the meaning of family.
Your children seems like you,
although they don't live with you.
Come on, Dad, don't start with this.
Right?
Listen to me, it's a matter of blood.
It's the same in humans,
as it is in horses.
That child will look increasingly like
you.
But, Keita
increasingly will resemble his
blood father, trust me.
Interact with the child soon
or, you'll never see that family.
It's not that simple.
It's slippery, so be careful.
I know it's slippery,
don't be so demanding.
Are you my wife?
I just try to be nice to you.
You keep it up and you'll be
without friends.
I haven't had friends for a long time.
In spite of what your father says,
just live, blood is unimportant.
You want other people to be like her.
It happens between married couples.
And, probably the same thing happens with children.
In my case,
it's what I felt in my heart
over the years as I grew up.
-Come back soon.
Yes.
Tell Manami that I'll see their beautiful quilts, soon.
Yes, please come.
Goodbye.
And next time,
bring something to drink, forget the flowers.
-I'm glad your Dad is okay.
-I played it off.
I had to ask off at work.
He said something about Keita?
No, nothing major.
Keita, Dad is in the house.
-Welcome home.
-Thank you.
For Father's Day, he did it in school.
Keita
Thank you very much.
The second is for Ryusei's Dad.
I want to thank him for fixing the robot.
I understand.
You are very kind and generous.
How come we don't follow,
like so far?
As if nothing had happened.
Every day that passes,
Keita will look more like you.
And Ryusei,
will look more like us.
You can
love him as before knowing
he is not the same blood.
It has nothing to do with that.
I'm just concerned
that your child won't like it,
because it does not feel like a real union
with him.
The longer we delay,
the harder it will be.
For us.
For the kids.
Keita , you take care of them.
I have to go.
-Go, goodbye.
-Bye!
The bento is ready.
400 yen, please.
Keita, you get another piece
of fried chicken.
-Be careful on the way home.
-Bye.
When summer arrives,
we'll launch flares in the garden.
We'll swim in the pool
and eat a lot of freshly cut watermelon.
-You too, Keita!
Yes.
How funny!
I'm home.
He's arrived, now.
Yes, you've been very helpful, thanks.
We'll talk.
Good.
Where is Ryusei?
Bathing.
I have not noticed the time.
I feel that you should take care of him.
I have the day off tomorrow.
It has always been so, as
nothing happens.
It's not important.
Who were you talking to?
With Yukari.
Yudai says, she wants to open a surf shop.
when she turns 50
But, she knows nothing about surfing!
You should not have contacted her.
As mothers, we need to share many things.
But you do not.
She plays good.
Of course.
Keita, I do not understand.
if you lack willingness to play well,
you'd better let her.
Not everyone is able to work like you.
Now work is a defect?
Not everyone can work, although we want to.
I think Keita is a lot like me.
He's asleep?
I've done what you asked.
However, you want Keita to leave.
Said you that's the solution.
Liar.
I didn't think that it would end well.
I had decided from the beginning.
Six years with Keita, is enough time.
-Blood is important.
-You're wrong, it's not.
Didn't you tell me...
Did you say when you know that Keita was not ours?
You do not remember?
Yes, I remember.
I don't understand why I did not see.
Excuse me.
-Not your fault.
-No!
Not about that.
I remember what you said.
"Get it now".
Now, it makes sense.
What makes sense now?
Nothing.
Can't you accept that Keita
does not have the same ability as you.
I will never forget,
what you said then.
Ready?
You're doing great.
Tremendous!
Ready? Here we go.
Can I have it?
There.
The camera,
you wish for the Royal family?
Why?
You don't want it?
That, I do not want.
I understand.
Listen, Keita,
when you go home,
better that you call Dad
and Mom; Uncle and Aunt.
Although there are times you feel alone,
you can not call us.
Promise.
Is a mission?
Yes, it's a mission.
Will I have a goal?
It's not yet clear.
Keita,
Now, you don't really understand
what's coming in this mission.
But surely, in ten years,
you'll understand.
Ryusei's house.
I will play the piano, again?
As you wish.
If you want to keep playing,
talk to them and work it out.
Hey, nothing but kites here.
Is the time of spawning...
They have wires to protect them
from the birds.
Come on!
Enough!
Ryusei!
When we were young...
Well,
the truth, I'm a little older than you.
But my father
made kites with bamboo sticks
and fine white paper.
Trimmed strips of newspaper to make the kite tapes.
Now, flying kites is nothing.
It cost much more then it does to make them fly.
My father
didn't fly kites with his children.
Of course.
But nothing forces you to act
as your father did.
Please, go to fly kites
with Ryusei.
Yes
It's a train.
It's been!
Not likely, but a lot of things give fear.
It took him to overcome his fear to go
to the bathroom alone at night.
I always had to accompany him.
But when Yamato was born, it made him
the big brother.
I promised that when Yamato
was no longer in diapers,
he would accompany him to
the bathroom at night.
Keita
often tells me he wants a brother.
But
I can not have more children.
Therefore
I think he'll be happy
with a brother
and sister
the way things are.
Keita
when you go home,
don't worry about anything.
Ryusei's parents
love you very much.
More than you, Dad?
More than me.
Hey,
we take a picture together?
-Yes.
-Come on.
Ready?
Come on!
Smiles.
We always smile.
Come on, get ready!
One,
two
and three!
-Why are you laughing?
-Why am I laughing?
-I don't see what's funny.
-Me neither.
Don't bite the straws.
I'm going to English class every day
and studying hard.
I feel when I go to the toilet.
I bathe alone, quietly.
I just watch TV
or play on the game console for a
half hour.
Should I call you Mom and Dad?
Why?
You're not my dad.
From now on, I will be your dad.
Why?
That does not matter.
Well,
they...
I'll explain.
Your dad and your mom
live there.
As always.
But now
You can call us
father and mother, right?
Why?
That does not matter.
You must explain to me why it's the same.
-Someday you'll understand.
-Why?
That does not matter.
Anyway?
Why?
-That's what I'm asking.
-Why?
Brush your teeth.
Take.
That's better.
Hey
What's the matter?
You broke it?
Okay.
Let's see if we can fix it.
Here?
Here, here, here?
Already fixed?
August
Utsunomiya Engineering Department
Yes
Why send it to me?
Nohara can deal with that.
Good...
It's almost time for the trial date.
Excuse me, sir,
but I am the plaintiff.
Yes, I know perfectly.
See,
You've always been in a hurry.
At some point it must stop.
But you are where you are
because you failed to stop.
It's not the same,
times are changing.
Try to spend more time with the family.
Ramen pasta boxes can be red or blue.
- And what do you prefer?
-I like the red.
Red carries soy sauce.
- Right?
- I didn't know that.
What did you say?
Dad hasn't arrived yet,
-We won't tell anyone.
Why have you drawn this?
You're done crying to Mom?
You asked for forgiveness?
No?
Okay.
Go to bed.
You don't say, 'goodnight?'
Goodnight.
Dad---Mom
You're making a lot of noise.
Stop it.
I've said enough!
Enough of this...
This does not work, it's broken.
Tell your mother to buy you another.
When I go home, Dad will fix it.
Ryusei.
You'll never return to that house.
From now on, you will live here.
I am your real father.
Let me see it.
I just told you that you've won,
but you do not seem very happy.
I have not gained or lost.
Well, in many trials,
is not clear who wins and who loses.
No, I do not mean that.
It's not typical of you,
it might start to be like you.
I do not fall well.
You worried about the opinion of others?
You have really changed.
I almost forgot it.
This.
I got it from the nurse,
In addition to the amount of the hospital.
This is the maximum contribution
in good faith.
Good afternoon.
Look,
I come to return it.
Your good faith.
I'm so sorry.
What has happened
has destroyed my family.
Teru.
It has nothing to do with you.
This is about me.
It's my mother.
Nonomiya's house,
Talk to me.
I'm Ryota.
Ryota, how are you?
Thanks for coming the other day.
Listen.
You want to speak to your father?
No.
I called to apologize.
No, Ryota, do not get serious
at this point.
As of then.
I never want to go back there,
it's ancient history.
I won't talk of nonsense with you, it's
not important.
Which famous wears a wig and what else has he operated.
I agree.
Your father is calling, he's out of sa-ke.
Okay.
I understand.
We use much less water in the Green Roof Project
now we channel rain water.
If all the water is added
for watering plants and filling the pit
does not exceed 42.6 cubic meters.
I also started
being an architect, like you.
This forest has been created by man,
for research.
And this,
is it born here?
Yes
Insects
reproduce here easily.
But they need 15 years from the time
that a cicada lays eggs
to become larvae
and leaving the ground.
So much time?
It seems much?
I say it is.
Excuse me, Nonomiya.
Forgive me for taking so long.
Hello, how are you?
Apparently he decided he
wanted to fly a kite.
A kite?
He sneaked into the commuter train
behind an adult.
He's smart doing things like that.
It's not a source of pride.
-You should punish him.
-What do you suggest?
That he return with an empty stomach?
We are not like that.
Yes, I understand your point of view.
If you think that it isn't fitting,
he can stay with us for a while.
Clear.
We have no objection in having Ryusei and Keita.
It'll be fine.
I'll see.
Ryusei!
Ryusei , come home.
You don't need
We'll call your father and mother immediately.
Bathe and don't do anything stupid.
Keita.
If I rub well,
it's like
if it were you.
I also ran away from home.
I wanted to see my mother.
But my father came and dragged me quickly
home.
- And now what?
- We go to father!
Oh, my God!
Ryusei!
Ryusei, Ryusei, are you okay?
Father!
You hurt?
Father, are you hurt?
Enough!
Be careful!
You're gonna win. You're gonna win.
I won!
-What did you find?
- That's it?
-It’s really small.
-Thank you.
Prepared attention...
Go!
- You've fished for your father.
- Be careful.
Cancer, Scorpio,
Gemini.
Sagittarius.
Libra.
Aquarius.
-Virgo.
-Look...
A shooting star...
Make a wish.
What have you wished for?
I can get back with mom and dad.
Ryusei.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
What's wrong
I also want what Ryusei wants.
Then
why are you crying?
Because
I feel terrible about Keita.
It is as if you betray him.
How will Keita feel?
Want some breakfast?
Do you want to eat?
Good.
Bulbs, right?
In how many watts?
-I'm home.
-Welcome home.
Ryusei, how's it going?
Keita.
Keita!
Sorry.
Dad
It could not be more without seeing you.
I've jumped the rules to see you.
Dad is not my dad.
You're right.
But listen,
for 6 years...
For 6 years I was your Dad.
I was not a good Dad,
but I was your Dad.
The flower you gave me...
Sorry, I lost it.
I'm sorry.
In the camera
where all the photos are that I took
And the piano...
Dad also stopped playing the piano.
Listen
the mission is over.
They've already returned.
Good.
Let's go inside.
Yes
-Let's
Yes, let's.
Did you know that Spiderman
is a real spider?
I had no idea.
Translation: DigitalMediaful