You look beautiful tonight.
Just tonight?
I can't make continuously
complements?
Do you got her
telephone-number?
It's not in the phone book.
And I won’t give it to. . .
. . . you. I don't won’t to be
guilty if you run into a trap.
I need to know the truth.
This I can tell you.
She dates with the
highest Nazi magnates.
She doesn't need any food
coupons. She got all privileges.
She is part of the
cream of society.
And she obviously
enjoys is to the full.
I'm sorry Robert.
We all make mistakes.
That's true.
This song serves as a iron link between
the soldiers on the front. . .
. . . and the loved ones at home.
In front of the casern,
in front of the big gate,
stands a lantern,
and it is still standing there,
So we will see each other again,
at the lantern will we stand,
Just like once Lili Marleen.
Our two shadows looked like one,
That we loved each other was obvious.
And all people shall see,
when we stand at the lantern.
Just like once Lili Marleen.
Already the post
horn blows curfew.
It can cost you three days.
Comrades I'm coming soon.
So we said good by,
How much I would
like to go with you.
Be with you, Lili Marleen.
Your steps she knows.
Your beautiful walk.
Every night she burns that
you wont forget her hand.
And should anything
bad happen to me,
Who will stand at the lantern?
My beloved Lili Marleen.
I shall greet you.
Greetings?
From Robert.
Where is he?
Can I have an autograph?
Lili! Lili! Ah there she is.
Move away. We want
to take some pictures.
Please move back.
We have been looking
for you everywhere.
The group-leader invited us to the "Eagle"
He wants to celebrate your success.
I'm not feeling good.
Does that mean you already
turn me down again?
I'll get you an aspirin.
I feel miserable I got
a bad headache.
I'm sorry. My chauffeur
can bring you home.
It's not necessary. I think I walk
the fresh air will do me good.
It's not needed, good night.
I know her, she is so stubborn.
Follow her.
Yes, group-leader.
This is Blonsky.
Send a second man.
Are you crazy? I know you take
big risks, but this is madness.
You have to go at
once, immediately.
Why shall I leave?
Your life is in danger.
With your position you
surly can protect me.
Do you think so? How
do you get this idea?
That's very easy.
But you are in some ways a
figure-head of this regime.
What, for Christ’s sake.
I'm just singing a song.
Your song that's all.
But you have friends. Very
influential friends I was told.
Which are at the top
of the Nazi hierarchy.
Why do you say this.
Of what importance is this?
This you ask me?
Yes, Robert I do.
Maybe you should
ask this yourself.
They are just acquaintances.
No friends.
In my position this
happens automatically.
I can't always reject them
or I'll be suspected.
But you like it or not. You
enjoy the privileges you got.
In some ways, yes.
And it doesn't bother you all the
terrible things that happened?
Germany is at war.
There were was before.
I'm not talking about your war.
Unimaginable atrocities take place.
I don’t know anything
about it Robert.
I'm just singing a song.
Finally, I thought I stay here all night alone.
It's not particularly comfortable her.
I'm Jew.
I knew that before.
But you have been
ordered to despise us.
I love you as you are.
Robert, I missed you.
Eternal.
What's going to
happen to us?
Let me see your
papers, Gestapo.
I must say first class work.
Excepted a small thing not
visible with the naked eye.
Who are you?
My name is
Robert Hoffmann.
I didn't ask under which
name you are traveling.
I asked who you real are.
All right. I'm
Robert Hoffmann.
OK let's assume you
are Robert Hoffmann.
What are you doing
here in Berlin?
I'm passing trough.
You spend one night in
the Pension Jakobite.
That's right.
Two nights, and one night
you had a visitor, a lady.
Yes, from time to time
I have a female visitor.
The lady I’m talking about
is pretty famous.
I don't know about which
lady you are talking.
Normally she doesn't go to bed
with Tom, Dick or Hoffmann.
She prefers the higher ranks,
does at the very top.
Why are you telling
me all this things?
Miriam, I still don't know more than an
hour ago but Aaron will be here soon.
Would you like to
drink something?
No thanks, not
at the moment.
This arrived from
Drewitz via Amsterdam.
Robert didn't have anything on
him when they caught him. . .
. . . but of course it's just a matter of
time before they find out his true identity.
Was he with her?
She was with him.
I thought he forgot, as it's
several years ago already.
Blonsky, here Blonsky.
Object has boarded a black
Mercedes, model 1936.
Robert was arrested yesterday
only a few hours after you meet.
Robert my god, Gestapo?
Yes.
You don't think that I. . .
. . . put yourself into my shoes. Your
friendship to Robert proves nothing.
So why do you meet me?
Hurry please, I
want to get out.
Maybe because. . . I would
like that Robert is right.
Why did you stop?
I'm waiting here for the Bose
of our resistance group.
He thinks this meeting is necessary.
Frau Drewitz, I'm glad
to meet you. . .
. . . only the fact that we meet is
an enormous risk. - For all of us.
But because Robert Mendelsson
trusts you, I trust you too.
Have you ever heard of
Treblinka, Auschwitz, Majdanek?
What?
We need evidence about
what's happening in Poland. . .
. . . in the concentration
camps and ghettos.
And you could
get this evidence.
How?
Yes, you do front theatre. . .
does art tourneys.
Yes, and personal journeys
to Poland are forbidden.
I don't know what I could
do there for you.
You could say you want to do
troop care on the east front.
Nobody would deny you,
on the contrary,
Can I help Robert with this?
I can't promise you this, lady.
But you would help our case a lot.
I would like to
know how you are.
You can stop we are here.
Please tell me how you are?
I'm sorry we still don't know.
We know only one thing our Robert
Hoffmann isn't Robert Hoffmann.
Robert Hoffmann is dead since
three years, car accident.
I only see one way to shade light.
Right, this woman affair?
But for this we need
permission from the top.
Of course I keep
you up to date.
Soldiers.
Friends.
This is a very happy day.
Today we celebrate the birthday of the
man which is in thoughts with us. . .
the man which will guide. . .
our people to the final victory.
Our beloved Fuehrer. . .
and chancellor, Adolf Hitler.
Three times "Sieg Heil"!
Tell here to come once more!
Where has she gone?
Do you know where Willie is?
I haven’t got a clue.
He asks if you are aware of the
danger if the film is found on you.
He says you seem a bit. . .
seem a bit nervous.
He says you look frightened.
But at the moment
you are our only hope.
We wish you all the luck.
Look for a save hiding place.
And if everything works out, greet. . .
Günter Weissenborn from us.
Stop! It's driving me mad!
Stop it!
Lili is involved in something,
she hides an item in her bag.
Your attention please.
We are happy to welcome
among us our Lili Marleen.
May I asked why you
only joint us now?
I didn't feel comfortable.
Headache again?
No, it's ok now.
We have been looking for you...
I'm dancing very often.
It's ladies' choice now.
Come on boy, ladies' choice!
Get out of my way!
Your room is over there,
group-leader.
I have to talk with your partner.
Do you understand!
Willie is not only my
partner she is my fiancé.
And if somebody touches
her breasts it's me.
You got nerves Taschner.
But unfortunately you prove
this on the wrong place.
You will get a chance to prove your
courage where it will be needed.
Why didn't you shut up?
Was that really necessary?
Thank you, next please.
What the devil
is this for?
It's a physical inspection.
I'm vaccinated against
smallpox and typhus.
Complain by the group-leader.
Please fall in line.
What?
May I enter.
Give me the film.
Trust me.
Physical inspection? And you just put up
with it like this? But you normally wouldn’t?
Nothing.
This is the photo from our
contact man in Zürich.
What's the name?
Mendelsson.
Oh. I see.
OK, leave it to me.
Mr. Group-leader
You will return to Berlin tomorrow.
They are expecting you.
Does that meet that
my tourney has finished?
We would have liked
to keep you longer.
But the more
important has priority.
What do you mean? With the
more important has priority?
The urged request to
send you back to Berlin.
Is for me as good. . .
as an . . .
order.
By the way your piano played
Mr. Taschner also returns to Berlin.
His services are required
at the east-front.
She vehemently denies to
have maintained a. . .
relationship the
Jew Mendelsson.
But admits to have spend the
night in question with a man.
But which name she
doesn't want to give.
As he is a high ranking
person in the government.
She think it isn't appropriate
to disclose his name.
Is this right?
Than sign here please.
Thank you very much.
Just a moment.
I think that will end the matter.
I'll be back immediately.
Do you permit?
You somehow look familiar.
You probably saw me
in the newspaper.
Properly.
Would you also
like a cigarette?
Ah, I remember.
You are Lili Marleen.
I'm singing Lili Marleen
to be precise.
Hum, excuse me please.
What do you think?
Ah, it doesn't look like
they know each other?
There you are in best company.
Even the Fuehrer was fooled by her.
Congratulations, on you a
big actress has been lost.
This was a great act!
Blonsky, bring Mr. Mendelsson
back to his cell.
Come Mendelssohn.
You can leave too, I
won't need you anymore.
By the way from today
Lilie Marleen is blacklisted.
You can be thankful
that you are so popular.
Kaufmann, connect me
to our man in Zürich.
Now I still have to go.
Do you know where you go?
For a start to the east.
Maybe a mine search commando.
That's where pianists are required
because of the sensitive fingers.
Promise me one, promise me that
you want play the hero.
Now you don't have
anybody to protect you.
You also Willie.
One or the other
way we will make it.
Of course, we will.
My cards, can you believe
it I forgot my cards.
I'll send them to you.
Oh, it doesn't matter.
Hey Bernt, Bernt!
My good what are you doing here?
I was wounded, now
I've to go out again.
It was nothing.
Good day Mr. Taschner!
You two should take
care of each other.
We'll.
I have to go now.
Also take care of yourself.
You too, Heinz.
You to Bernt.
Sure Willie.
But I have to go now.
Yes, that's here.
Stop it!
That song has been forbidden.
Don't sing that song.
Stop, that song has been forbidden.
I would love to blow
the whole bunch up
We resort to the outmost only if
it's necessary. Do you understand?
On my list I got 78 people.
I only see 4.
Where are the others?
We can't be so wasteful
with people.
I also don't see my son?
As soon as everything is over.
Here it's the film.
You can keep it. Don't underestimate
us. Don't think we are stupid.
From films you can make copies,
but not from humans.
I make you an counter-offer.
We'll meat here in regular intervals.
Your friends and you look
that this film stays secret.
Agreed, we meet in six months.
In three months
with 100 people.
Don't be so greedy more than half
a dozen is out of the question.
Every three months is ok. Agreed?
Agreed.
Where is my son?
The first group can come now.
This settles it.
Now the other.
Let me blow them up.
No!
Bend down!
Why did you do this?
I hate this sort of deals.
Did you meat Willie?
No she is watched
by the Gestapo.
She tried to commit suicide
properly they arrested her.
So, we must try to be first.
Please send this today to Zürich.
Yes we must force them
to officially denounce it.
That is your only
chance Drewitz.
We just received
this from Drewitz
What does that concern us.
Can I see?
Sure, Weissenborn is right.
This is the only possibility to do something for here.
If we want to do something for her.
By the way in two hours a red
cross plain flies to London.
But why should we suddenly
help such a woman?
I haven't told you
everything, Robert.
I knew that she smuggled
the film out of Poland.
But this is terrible father. . .
horrible, dreadful. If Robert would have
known he wouldn't have married me.
I don't think so, Miriam.
Yes, please forgive me Robert.
I'm truly sorry. But I thought
it would be the best.
For you and for all of us.
If you want to catch the
plane you must leave now.
Goodbye Miriam.
You can't enter now! They are
broadcasting. Let me pass!
Let me!
Here speaks Robert Mendelsson.
I address all German soldiers.
I just have received news that the
women which mad the song. . .
Lili Marleen famous was killed
in a concentration camp.
Switch on my micro.
Here is Radio Calais, Calais
calls all German solders.
Wherever you are,
You will still be able to
listen to "Lili Marleen".
If not anymore over Radio Belgrade then
via the free soldiers broadcast Calais.
Yes Reich’s-chancellor
I have heard it.
Yes, it came as
a big surprise.
Yes very unpleasant,
I fully agree.
Yes of course we
have to do something.
Yes I keep you up to date.
She is still very weak.
I toke the liberty, I would
like to send you greetings.
A personal greeting from Dr. Goebbels.
He asks about your condition.
We were all very touched.
You gave us quite a shock.
Please announce to the press
what we agreed on before.
We all wonder why you
asked us to come here.
We asked you to come
here to tell the world. . .
once and for all to prove. . .
that the Jewish smear
campaign are only lies.
So they haven't refrained form using
one of the most famous and loved. . .
German singer for one
of there lie campaigns.
Radio London and Calais have spread the heinous lie. . .
the singer of the famous song Lili Marleen
was murdered in a camp.
We give you the chance to show loyalty
to the great German Reich. . .
and the Fuehrer. That's
what we want of you.
And if I don't?
You don't want that we have to
agree with the news of the BBC.
The times where you could
threaten me are over. . .
were I couldn't fall asleep because
I was afraid to wake up.
But that's over I'm not afraid
anymore, can't you see?
This will be interesting for you.
About one week ago we deported your
friend Robert Mendelsson to Switzerland.
Robert is in Switzerland?
I knew this would make
you fell better.
I cannot believe it.
Connected the line.
Please see for yourself.
Here is Willie.
Robert, for you?
Robert, your voice.
You're alive.
I'm all right too.
Really.
What do you
want from me?
You have to sing tonight?
That's out of the question!
That we understand each other
this is a order from the top.
She must look better than ever.
Make the light as wide a possible.
Excuse me Mr. Henkel, can
I ask you a few question.
Why is a doctor when?
When will the show begin?
At the usual time 3 minutes before 10. Gentleman
you better go now to the spectators room.
Me properly too?
Yes.
Here is the Reich’s Broadcast Berlin all
German Broadcast-station are joint.
To the 211 time again out of the
over crowded sport palace.
The request concert of
German armed forces.
And here she is. Impossible to
ignore for friend and foe.
As every evening at the
usual hour Lili Marleen.
In front of the casern,
in front of the big gate,
stands a lantern,
and it is still standing there,
So we will see each other again,
at the lantern will we stand,
Just like once Lili Marleen.
Russians.
We announce the
unconditional surrender. . .
of all our armed forces on land,
on water and in the air.
so as all other forces. . .
which are under German command, in
front of the high command of red army. . .
and also to the command of the
expeditional forces of the Allais.
How much longer my god,
how much longer?
What?
What did you say?
How much longer do
we have to hide?
We must first wait before we can explain
everything to the military command.
And how knows if
they believe us.
And before in a eventual process
Weissenborn or others can testify. . .
a lot more water will flow down the
stream before they will believe us.
Do you know Willie that a
murder toke place here?
No, when did that happen?
I think 1928 or 29.
But before the
Nazi took power.
A pimp shall have
killed his girl here.
It's a very mysterious story.
Where did that happen?
In the front of the fallen tree.
This case was put into
a novel at that time.
Tell me more.
I don't know more.
I just heard about it.
Do you still love me?
In my ways.
What do you mean?
It's just as it is.
May I kiss you?
Once more only, please.
What happen?
I think you should go to him.
To Robert in Zürich.
Willie, back after a long time?
Nice you visit us tonight.
Is this Robert?
Yes Robert, I always knew he
would become famous one day.
Yes I remember
how he started.
It's great.
Just fantastic.
I think you have
to bow once more.
You don't have to tell me how you are.
I wished for a long time to meat you.
Where is Willie?
She left.
It was brilliant.
The audience want’s
to see you once more.
Hallo Willie, where are you going?