to the girls of Hornos and Magdalena
to the boys of Gorina and Olmos
oy! oy! oy! Iook at the ball
that bounces on the head of that kid
who's that kid?
my neighbour
where does he live?
in that house
where is the house?
on a street
where is the street?
in the city
where is the city?
between the mountains
which mountains?
the andes mountains
where are the andes?
in south america,
american continent
washed by the seas
at the heart of the planet
and how is the planet?
a ball that bounces in the sky
LlON'S DEN
-Want some lunch?
-No, thanks.
See you later.
There's a lot of blood.
Lots of blood everywhere.
-Take it easy.
-Please help me.
-Tell me what happened.
-Don't know. I don't understand.
There's a lot of blood.
I don't know if they're okay.
I can't go near them.
Ramiro!
Ramiro, are you okay?
Nahuel, come here.
Listen to me, Julia.
-See Nahuel?
-I think he's in the kitchen.
-And Ramiro?
-He's in the bedroom.
Or in the corridor,
but I can't go...
-See if he can move.
-I can't.
Listen to me.
It'll be alright.
Do you hear me?
-ls he breathing?
-Yes, he is.
Is he a friend of yours?
Stay calm, we'll help you.
-Police!
-Someone's at the door.
Open the door! Police!
-I won't.
-lt'll be okay.
Do you hear me?
Open the door!
-Please tell them to leave!
-Open up!
Easy.
-They're knocking too hard.
-They're there to help you.
I can't move.
Do you hear?
We're coming in!
Take a shot of this.
Take the chest.
The belly.
Hand over the chalk.
Get the neck wound.
Got it?
Okay, let's turn him over...
and see what happens.
That'll do.
Ramiro? Can you hear me?
Don't move.
I'll get the stuff,
we'll take him out.
Take it easy, Ramiro.
Julia...
Look at me. Are you okay?
Take it easy.
Do you want to talk?
I won't hurt you.
I'm Mr. Jauregui,
your defense counsel.
I'll represent you before the judge
and the D.A.
for your statement.
You're accused of the murder
of Nahuel Heredia.
We knowthe circumstances...
around the case are complicated.
The other accused in this case
is Ramiro Nievas,
who was arrested and hospitalized.
He must sign the statement, too.
Draw your home, Julia.
And now draw yourself.
See a gap...
between your thoughts
and what you want to say?
Do you remember Nahuel?
And Ramiro?
I must inform you
you cannot be released...
due to the nature
of the crime you're accused of,
and that you are to remain
at the Court's disposal.
Julia Zárate
is to be remanded on custody.
Notify the state prison authorities
of her confinement.
Pleased to meet you, young lady.
Guard, take her away.
Stay calm.
'Evening.
Zárate, Julia.
-Good evening.
-Right hand, please.
-First and last names.
-Julia Zárate.
I.D. number?
27 010 989
-Single or married?
-Single.
Left hand.
-Father's name?
-TomásZárate.
-Deceased?
-Yes.
-Mother's name?
-Sofía Giusti.
Wipe your hands.
Take her away, please.
Let's go.
Hey, new girl!
Blondie, give me a cigarette.
Undress.
Blonde bitch, give us your cigs.
Raise your arms.
Turn around.
-Howfar pregnant?
-I don't know.
Pull your pants down and crouch.
Pull open your panties.
Get up.
Pull up your pants.
How long since you slept?
I don't know.
I'll give you something later.
Let's go.
Hurry up!
I'm going to read to you...
the rules in here.
Violation of discipline can be...
slight, medium,
serious and very serious.
Serious violations are:
break-out or attempted break-out.
Inciting or participating...
in attempts to compromise order.
Assaulting or threatening
an officer or any other person.
Physically, psychologically
or sexually intimidating others.
Is that clear?
You're not here
'cause I want you to be,
or because I have space
and I sent for you.
You know
what got you here.
Easy...
This is your cell block.
You're free to walk around.
You can go to any inmate's cell,
and she can go to yours.
One of you stands outside.
Understand?
I can't hear you.
-Yes.
-'Yes, Madam."
Yes, Madam.
I'll show you your cell.
Take it easy.
Easy...
Don't make things worse.
Get in!
Hey, skinny blonde!
Hey, honey, do you have a smoke?
-Ponce?
-Here.
-Miòo.
-Pérez.
-Here.
-Cardozo.
-Quiniche.
-Here.
-Alegre.
-Moreno.
-Here.
-Ricciardi.
-Cardozo.
-Here.
-Rojo.
Zárate.
!Zárate, Julia!
!Zárate!
?Zárate, Julia?
Out here at seven.
Can't hear you.
-Yes, okay.
-Yes what?
-Yes, Madam.
García.
Here.
-Ratti.
-Here.
Here.
-Thanks.
-It's nothing.
-Nice body you got.
-Try it out, blondie.
What tender breasts you got, darling.
-Stop it.
-You don't like this? Don't be shy.
Stop it. Get off me!
Stay away, Gauchita.
You brat,
give me back my shampoo!
What's wrong, dumb ass?
I'm tired of your brat,
you hear?
Shut up, you bitch!
Guard! Fight in the showers.
Alegre! Quinoche!
Shut up!
That's enough.
That's enough, I said.
Miòo, Ponce, visit.
Zárate, no visit.
Rojo, no visit.
-Alegre, Escalante...
-Nobody came?
-See you, Marta.
-Good luck.
Ávalos, Núòez, visita.
And your family?
I don't have a family.
Mine is far away.
In Anauá. Been there?
Come, I have pictures.
-See you later.
-Bye, girls.
My sister.
She stayed with my other kids.
I send her my allowance, but...
it's useless.
You don't have anyone?
My old lady, but she lives abroad.
You don't belong here.
Why are you here?
-You don't know?.
-I knowwhat we all know.
What exactly?
You killed your boyfriend.
Is it true?
He wasn't my boyfriend.
Why are you here?
'Cause I'm poor.
And a fucking fool.
That's all.
-Some maté tea?
-Okay.
You're rich, aren't you?
If you've got money,
everything will be easier for us.
This is Julia.
Noelia...
Noelia's about to leave.
Rusa.
Susana.
Pacha.
Anything you want to know
about Julia, ask me.
You too.
Any doubt, you ask me.
What're you doing?
Go away with that cigarette.
No smoking around the kids.
Transfer!
Hello, Julia.
I'm Hugo Casman,
your defense attorney.
Your mother sent me.
I've been reading your case,
the evidence.
I need to understand.
You want to tell me?
You don't?
If you're not interested,
I can get up and leave.
Okay?
I wanted them
to get out of my house.
What was your relationship
with them?
One was my boyfriend
and the other, his lover.
Inmate Julia Zárate?
Any relative by the name of
Giusti, Sofía?
My mother.
You've got a package.
Three pacifiers.
Baby shoes.
An undershirt.
A baby bottle.
Family photos.
A letter.
Here.
No, thanks.
Still vomiting?
Did you sleep?
You're lucky you're pregnant.
This cell block isn't a prison.
Get me cards, Julia.
-Cards?
-Phone cards.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
Who sent you this stuff?
Shit!
I'll be back.
Raise your arms.
Take a deep breath.
Up and down.
Okay, now your legs.
Now let's do the legs.
Take deep breaths.
Very good.
-Howfar along are you?
-Eight months.
All set to go.
We're outcasts, you're in heaven.
Zárate, Julia.
Hand over some cigarettes.
So you're Zárate Julia?
Bitch, you're no kitten.
What's your problem?
You see her get off her ass?
Fat bitch!
She should stop eating.
The filthy bitch is ready to lay!
We tie pussy cats
to the cell bars.
Tie 'em tight
so they don't come loose.
This is what you tell the judge.
Read it out loud.
Why out loud?
To practice.
"l live in my family's apartment.
My mom's been in France for 1 3 years.
I lived alone for 4 years.
I met Nahuel.
He asked to stay.
First, for a week,
then he stayed on.
Later...
he brought a friend, Ramiro,
to live with us."
Do I have to learn it?
No, not by heart,
you've got to believe it.
In court you'll face the judge,
the prosecutor, the legal experts.
You'll shit your pants.
You have to convince them.
"Little by little,
they started to edge me out.
I supported them.
I was a stranger in my own house.
But I tried not to make trouble,
to get along as best we could.
One day I found them both in my bed,
but they never left.
It all started
about two years ago."
They must believe you,
not Ramiro.
Stick to the script.
Don't go for pity. Be strong.
And don't you dare cry.
That's very important.
What are you looking at?
Hey, can't you see she's pregnant?
Is this gonna take long?
We've been here since 6 AM!
It's damn hot in here.
Those bastards jacking off all day!
Here we are,
shitting ourselves in the heat.
Son of a bitch.
Look at this.
Look at those hungry chimps.
You guys from Campana?
Campana, right?
Who are you to ask?.
Well, I'm asking.
-Where are you from?
-None of your business.
Never seen you before.
-Where you from?
-Olmos.
Olmos? I was told that at Olmos,
they're all faggots.
Go sew your panties!
Don't be jealous
or I'll steal him from you.
Zárate, Julia.
Come here.
About time.
Why make her suffer?
Why not come get her earlier?
Good luck, Julia.
I met Nahuel,
he spent a few days at my place.
He stayed on.
Then, Ramiro showed up,
a friend of Nahuel's.
-He stayed for a few days.
-Alright.
What exactly happened that night?
That night, when I came home,
they were arguing in my room.
I heard fighting.
Then, Ramiro came out.
He had bruises on his face.
He went to the kitchen
and grabbed a knife.
He went back.
Nahuel came out.
I think he hit me.
The knife was on the floor.
There was a lot of blood.
I grabbed the knife.
I don't remember any more.
Did they know
you were pregnant?
-No.
-Why didn't you tell them?
I didn't have time.
It went so fast.
-Do you knowwho the father is?
-Nahuel.
You mean Nahuel Heredia,
the victim?
Please, help me!
What'll you do to me?
A Caesarean.
Don't worry, everything is fine.
No, don't cry.
You're drugged.
You won'tfeel a thing.
-You're gonna cut me open?
-A little.
-You won't feel a thing.
-No, please.
Easy now.
It'll be over soon.
Do you feel anything?
-No...
-No? Okay...
Don't be afraid.
Your baby will be born soon.
We're almost there.
Can I sit up?
Madam, you're here to see Zárate?
Please, come in.
Wait here.
How are you?
Took me forever to get here.
Why are you here?
Casman called me.
When did you arrive?
Two hours ago.
Couldn't get a better flight.
How do you feel?
Okay. The stitches bother me.
You were also born by Caesarean.
Yes, I know.
Hello, baby.
He's cute.
What's his name?
I don't know yet.
Did you get the things I sent?
-Excuse me...
-Yes, thank you.
I'll change your lV drip.
Why are you here, Mother?
I want to be with you both.
I'm tired. I need to sleep.
Go away.
Go home, Mom.
Okay, I'll be outside. Sleep tight.
This way, Madam.
-Last name?
-Zárate.
-First name?
-Tomás.
-Mother's name?
-Julia Zárate.
-Single or married?
-Single.
-Father's name?
-He has none.
I'll organize
a vaccination control plan...
to have the baby take
all the required shots.
Ms. Zárate, you need to know...
that the minor will stay with you
until he's four years old.
After that, a relative
will have custody,
or if not,
he'll be sent
to the Court of Minors.
Make your boy shut up,
you bitch!
Let us sleep, you fucking bitch!
Feed him!
Shut him up!
Make that brat shut the fuck up!
We want to sleep!
Hey, make the brat shut up,
you fucking bitch!
Give him to me.
Stop crying,
give me the pacifier.
Now, now, Tomás.
That's it, love.
Come and get him.
I'm with the others.
They're awake, too, goddammit.
Come on.
Take some milk.
Very good, Tomás.
There's clothes to wash.
-I'll do it later.
-Do it now.
Phone cards.
-Cotton, towels, diapers.
-Hold on, I'm writing it down.
How many?
Enough for all of us.
-My family is waiting, too.
-Nearly done.
-What about Tomás?
-You heard from Casman?
-Cut it short.
-Okay.
-Come on.
Did you talk to him?
-Yes, take care.
-Okay.
"l ignored them,
I made myself something to eat.
I heard Nahuel screaming
in the bedroom,
I went there
and he was hurt,
all bloody, and Julia
with the knife in her hand.
She threw herself at me,
-and stabbed me in the arm."
-He's a son of a bitch.
Hold on.
"l ran back to the living room,
she attacked me from behind."
It's only logical that Nievas'
defense...
consists in blaming you.
We'll prepare for a confrontation,
we're going to be well prepared,
and get a trial date.
Don't get like this.
You know he's lying!
I know Ramiro! Why?
Come on, take it easy,
you're not alone.
-Stop.
-I'll kill Ramiro.
-Stop, Marta.
-Come on, Julia.
No, leave me alone.
Hand me a clothes peg.
We welcome little Tomás,
Julia's son.
Tomás, I bless you...
in the name of the Father,
the Son,
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Another soul for our church.
A big hand for Tomás.
I'm staying in Buenos Aires.
Why stay?
-Everything is fine.
-To be closer to both of you.
I can help you.
Where will you stay?
I thought I'd move
into the apartment.
Okay.
How could this happen to you?
How could it end like this?
-I feel so guilty.
-Stop it, Mother.
Stop it. Stop crying!
Putting on a show!
What's wrong with you?
Control yourself.
Get a grip.
Everything is okay.
Stop it.
Will you bring Tomás to me?
Will you stop crying?
Yes.
Alright?
Will you control yourself?
Marta!
Marta, this is Sofía, my mother.
-Hi, Marta.
-Let her hold Tomás.
He's asleep.
That's okay.
Let her have him.
Don't wake him up.
Hello, Tomás.
Your father wanted
to call you Tomás. Did you know?
No.
You want anything? Water?
Mom!
You wantwater, something?
-Are you okay?
-No, I'm okay.
You want to hold him a while?
Yes.
Come on, let's go.
Candela, go to sleep.
This kid never sleeps.
Kindergarten, girls!
Let's go, girls!
-Rojo, Zárate, cell block.
-Just a minute.
-Hurry up.
-I'm coming. Just a second.
Come on, let's go.
What do you want, Tommy?
You want to play?
Do you want me to swing you?
What do you want?
You can't go out now.
You like that?
Come on, Tomás. Let's go play.
Come here, you'll fall down.
Come. Come on, Tommy.
Come with me.
You'll fall down.
Sofi, will you take this letter?
It's for my wife.
Go on.
-Names?
-Julia and Tomás Zárate.
Lift your T-shirt.
Turn around.
Spread your arms.
Pull down your T-shirt.
Turn around.
Open your mouth.
Your pants.
Crouch.
Pull open your panties.
Get up.
-Now, the kid.
-Don't touch him.
Then, you can't come in.
Pull up his shirt,
pull down his pants.
Nearly done.
-Don't touch him.
-I have to examine him.
His pants and diapers.
That's it. Okay, love, that's it.
-Anything else?
-No, go ahead.
Look at your hands.
Is that your son?
Say hello.
What's your name?
Tomás.
Hi.
Sure he's Nahuel's kid?
Yes.
How do you know?.
I read your statement.
Why did you say that?
I stopped smoking.
Julia...
I have to help myself, not you.
Get it?
Look, Tomás.
I can't stand it anymore.
I have to get out.
You didn't tell the truth.
I don't remember what happened.
Do you?
I don't knowwhat I remember.
We're on our own.
I'm not alone.
Look.
Let's get nice and pretty
for Lucía's birthday.
Tommy...
Tomás...
Come on, Tommy.
Let's get ready
for Lucía's birthday.
It's Lucía's birthday.
Come on.
Hot, isn't it?
Come on, let's go.
Marta, bring out the cake
so we can blowthe candles.
Kids, come blowthe candles.
-What happens?
-Guard!
-What happened?
-Guard, call the chief!
-What's going on, Marta?
-Hold Candela.
-Guard!
Call the chief!
What did you do?
Let me go!
You don't understand!
Don't take her away from me!
Lucía is all I've got.
Let go!
-Let me go, you bitch!
-Easy, easy!
Raise her arms!
-Open!
-Don't take her away from me!
Open!
Take her to the nurse!
-She's my baby. Don't take her!
-Close!
Don't take her away!
Merry Christmas!
Tommy, Merry Christmas.
Can I give him his presents?
I'll give them to him later.
Tell him they're from me.
I'm planning something at home
for NewYear's Eve.
I want to take Tommy.
I told you
I don't wantTomás to leave here.
It's time he got out.
He has to leave one day.
He's staying with me.
He's leaving with me,
you understand?
-Want something to eat?
-No.
Hey, Santa Claus!
The icebox is for Rusa.
She'll pay you,
then you send me the money.
Okay.
Keep the diapers and the food.
You're leaving...
-Bye, Marta!
-See you on the outside!
You take care.
-Hey!
-I'll go with her.
-Will you behave?
-Yes.
No further, Zárate.
-Candela, kiss Julia goodbye.
-Bye, Cande.
Let's go, Zárate.
Let's go.
-Let's go.
-Coming!
Come on.
Take care of your mommy.
-Take care.
-Come on, Rojo.
-I'll come visit.
-Have fun.
-Bye.
-Take care.
Who's the bear's friend?
-Here's another bear.
-I don't know.
What's his name?
Stick it up there.
Pepe.
Pepe? Good.
Here comes the witch.
And the knight attacks her.
Look.
The butterfly comes to see
if the witch is okay.
Show me.
He covers her up?
He's upside down?
Look at the witch
all covered up.
-Hello.
Where's Tomás?
At kindergarten.
They didn't tell you
I'd come to see you both?
They did, but...
he's better off there.
Well...
This is for him.
It's very pretty.
Did you make it?
-Yes.
-What is it?
A cement truck.
Why did you come?
After the last time we met...
I started thinking.
The truth is,
I'm not alone, either.
I think of you and Tomás
all the time.
Maybe...
we could be together
when we get out.
That's ridiculous.
Why?
I'm not getting out, Ramiro.
I could talkto the lawyer,
change my statement.
Guard, may l?
-No, don't touch me.
-Julia...
-Look at me.
-No.
It's me.
Stop, please.
You look pretty.
Slowly, a little more.
A little more?
Let me see.
Want me to carry you?
-ls he any better?
-The fever's down.
He's much better.
Did you get an appointment?
Yes, this afternoon.
Tomorrow he gets
a complete check-up...
to make sure
everything's okay.
You get results the same day?
I think so. It's quick.
-Be a good boy.
-Yes.
-Yes?
-Bye.
-Call me.
-Don't worry.
-Take care of him.
Bye, Tommy. Love you.
Take him out to play.
Here we are.
Hello. Give me a hand.
Hi. Yes.
Is his room ready?
I don't like you washing my hair.
Yes, an appointment.
I need to set a date.
I'll just have a look.
-I don't like elephants.
-What's wrong?
You liked the pictures.
-It's a nice elephant.
-I'm scared. Let's go home.
This is Sofía, leave a message.
Mother, it's me.
I want to know about Tomás.
I'm worried. Call me back.
I left lots of messages.
Hello, Casman.
It's Julia Zárate.
I must talk to you.
Where's Tomás?
Please call me.
-Where's Tomás?
-At home.
-ls he okay?
-He's okay.
It's better this way.
For your file.
Just for a few days.
He's with your mom.
-It's important.
-Tell him to leave.
I have to talk to you.
Okay.
Bring Tomás to me.
Tomás is at home.
He had a slight fever.
He's with Estela.
-Who?
-She takes care of him.
I take care of him.
Bring him to me.
At the start, it was good
for him to be with you,
you were feeding him,
but he's got to get out.
Mother, bring me Tomás.
I beg you.
Go get him.
He shouldn't be here.
You have no right to decide.
You can't bring that fucker here.
Go getTomás.
I beg you to do so!
-He's your son, but he's not yours.
-He's mine, my son!
-So go get him.
-You don't want to listen...
but deep inside,
you know I'm right.
-Look, mom...
-There's no reason for him...
-to be locked up here!
-Look, mom...
You don't decide whatTomás does!
I decide.
You understand? Fucking bitch!
Bring him back!
I'll kill you!
I'm going to kill you!
-Easy.
-Let me go!
Stop it, Julia!
Bring him back!
-Fucking bitch!
-Calm down, please!
Bring him or I'll kill you!
-I'll kill you!
-Leave her!
I'll get you and kill you,
you bitch!
-Don't hit her!
-Stop!
Fucking bitch!
Let me go!
I'll kill you!
I'm going to get you
and I'll kill you, bitch!
Julia, calm down!
Leave her!
-Don't hit her!
-Did you hear?
-Let me go!
Let me go, bitch!
-Julia!
Fucking bitch!
Leave her alone!
You're hurting her!
Let me go!
You're hurting me!
I'll call the head warden!
Let me go!
I wantTomás back!
You don't understand!
Leave me alone!
Let me go!
Get out! Let me go!
Let me go, bitch!
Open up, bitch!
You fucking dyke!
Rusa!
Rusa! Call Marta!
-Rusa!
-Julia!
Tell her
they tookTomás away from me!
I'll tell her.
Take care!
Guard!
Do you know anything
about my son?
Guard! Guard!
Guard!
Where's my son?
Call the head warden.
I need to see him. Call him.
Call the head warden!
Call him!
-Call him, you fucking dyke!
-I'll call him.
Call the head warden!
Guard!
Bitch! I'll get you, you bitch!
Call the head warden!
-I need to see the head warden.
-We'll see.
-No, now.
-Come on.
Guard!
-What, Zárate?
-I need to see the head warden.
-He isn't here.
-Well, call him.
-What?
-Call him. I need to see him.
Don't you understand?
-I need to talkto him.
-Go back to your cell.
I won't go back to my cell.
I need my son here.
-I want to talk to the head warden.
-Tomorrowthey'll bring your son.
-No, I need to see him now.
-The head warden comes tomorrow.
Don't be a pain.
Go back to your cell!
Call the chief.
I won't wait!
No way. Go to your cell!
-I want to talk now!
-What's going on?
Stay out of this.
Go back to your cell!
-I need to see Tomás! Call the chief!
-Go to your cell!
Look at the shit you started!
Go to your cell!
I don't care! Get the chief.
-Go and look for the chief!
-Go back to your cell!
Some shit you started, Zárate!
Go to your cell.
Girls, wake up!
They tookZárate's kid!
-Call the chief!
-The warden comes in the morning!
No! I won't wait for tomorrow.
-Call the chief!
-The head warden is not here.
-Call the chief then!
-Shut up!
Go to your cell!
Quit making trouble.
-I won't go.
-Look at the mess you've made!
Come on, girls!
We've taken Cell Block 1!
-What's going on here?
-Get down!
-I told you to get down!
What's going on, Zárate?
What's the problem?
-Shut up!
-What's the problem?
What's the problem?
I want to see the head warden.
I want my son back.
Bring her son.
This is a mess.
No diapers, no milk...
He's her son. Give him back.
-We can't go on like this!
-Shut up!
Not in these conditions.
Let's try to talk.
They are telling you he's not here
and he's not!
Stop it, girls. Cool it.
Calm down, everyone, please.
Just a second.
Wait a second!
Stop, stop!
She won't come out
in these conditions.
You want her to come out?
Get down off the table.
-Get down off the table!
-Open the door!
Get down off the table!
Hurry up, kids!
Get in there!
!Come on, Pacha!
The pillows, quick!
Get some water!
Come on, girls, hurry up!
It's inadmissible!
Things like this
are not supposed to happen here.
You'll getTomás back,
but first, calm down.
Okay?
The head warden is on his way.
-What's going on?
-I just want to talk to you.
-I need my son!
-Calm down! What's going on there?
She wants her son.
See what she's done.
What happened here?
What did you do?
Nothing. I've been asking
to see you...
for five hours!
-Look what you did.
-I didn't startthis.
I only wanted to talk to you!
Calm down.
If not, we can't talk.
I have a family.
This is your fault.
Okay! Butthis is your job!
-My son is all I have.
-Look. What do I do now?.
Look at all this mess.
What do I do now?.
-lt has nothing to do with me.
-Okay, calm down...
-Stop shouting at me.
-I want him back!
-Don't shout. We'll talk.
-You let them take him away.
-You let my mother take him away!
-I won't help you like this.
This is no way to ask.
-I didn't ask for this.
-You stirred everyone up.
No one listened to me.
Now, I'm listening.
Let's agree on something.
Can we talk?
Let's do something.
I'll help you with the court...
to get your kid back.
You want your son?
But you put an end to this mess.
The girls are worked up
because of you.
There are kids there.
They've started a fire.
Kids like your son,
kids who played with your son.
So, let's calm things down.
I help you, you help me.
This isn't the way
a jail operates.
Do we have a deal?
Calm down.
It's over.
Fucker! Bunch of assholes!
Faggots!
Let's go get them!
Motherfucker!
Julia... After our talk,
we organized
this assessment meeting,
to decide whether Tomás stays
with you until he's four.
This is not our decision.
The Court decides.
Through this one-way mirror,
we'll observe Tomás.
I'll see him alone first.
Okay, Tommy, pile them up.
Which is the smallest?
-A big one.
-A really big one.
Hi...
Hi there, precious.
Hey, look at me.
Hi.
Miss me? No?
I missed you a lot, you know?.
Give me a kiss? A hug?
These gentlemen over there...
are the ones who think
you shouldn't be with me.
-Were you hurt?
-No, that's old.
Good, here we are.
Marta knows me well,
she knows how I work.
I need your trust...
and your honesty.
First, we need to solve
your legal status,
and get a prison term
as short as possible.
The best we can hope for
is eight years.
-No, that's too long...
-You've done four.
In 1 year and 6 to 1 0 months,
you're out of here.
-I can't stand it.
-Calm down.
-Then...
-And Tomás?
Once you've been sentenced,
you'll get leave.
-Do you trust me?
-Yes.
That's very important.
What was the relationship
between Nahuel and Ramiro?
What was your relationship
with them?
Following the Penal Code,
we'll now proceed...
with a confrontation
between the accused,
Ramiro Nievas and Julia Zárate.
I was sleeping with...
Nahuel Heredia,
when I heard the door open.
She came in,
she started to scream at us.
-I didn't want a fight.
-That's a lie.
-lt wasn't an accident.
-Silence.
Silence, young lady.
Carry on. Look at her, please.
Ramiro, tell the truth.
Don't lie.
It's not a lie.
She started to shout,
pulled us out of bed...
and started throwing things at us.
-Nahuel tried to restrain her.
-He's lying!
She grabbed the knife.
It was very complicated.
-He's lying. Ramiro, don't lie.
-Please, Zárate.
-He's lying!
-Zárate...
-Do you have something to say? Do it!
-Yes, of course!
He's lying.
That's not what happened.
-I came home...
-Tell me what happened.
-I came home and they were...
-Look at him.
They were in my bed, arguing.
They weren't sleeping?
No! They were arguing,
hitting each other.
Why were they arguing?
Do you knowwhy?
-That's not true.
-lt is!
What did you do, then?
-I went in...
-Look at him.
Ramiro was all bloody.
Nahuel was holding the knife.
-Ramiro, tell the truth!
-You know it wasn't me.
-I didn't say that!
- Look at me.
I didn't say it was you!
I tried to defend you!
-But I didn't have the knife!
-But it was an accident.
But I didn't have the knife!
You did!
I arrived
and you were both fighting.
-You were holding the knife.
-I didn't have it.
No, Nahuel had it!
-What are you saying?
-I didn't bring it.
Why do you say that I had it?
I didn't have the knife!
-You two were arguing.
-lt wasn't me.
I'm not saying
it was you,
I'm saying I didn't bring the knife,
but you both had the knife.
You were fighting in my bed.
-ln my house, in my bed!
-I didn't kill anyone!
You're a son of a bitch.
Please, no insults.
Continue.
I don't remember anything else.
I don't get you.
As a child, her mother left her...
in the care of her sickfather.
As a grown-up, two men subject her
to all sorts of humiliations.
The abuse suffered by Julia
is not a crime,
but it served to crush her,
insult her, humiliate her...
beyond tolerable limits.
As a result of this abuse,
on July 14,
Julia Zárate discovered
she was pregnant.
Anything else?
No, Your Honour.
In relation to Ramiro Nievas,
considering what is in his file,
he is to be acquitted,
as there is insufficient evidence...
to find him guilty.
The Court sentences Julia Zárate,
Argentinean, single,
a college student,
born November 8, 1980,
the daughter of Tomás Zárate
and Sofía Angélica Giusti,
responsible
for first-degree murder,
to 1 0 years' imprisonment.
Let it be notified,
recorded and filed.
Lead the accused out.
-Miss me?
-Yes, I do.
-You want to see me?
-A little.
-Are you crying, Mommy?
-No, I have a cold.
-Let me talk to Grandma.
-She's not here.
-Where is she?
-I don't know.
-Are you alone?
-No, with Andrea.
-ls Andrea nice to you?
-Yes.
-Tell Grandma to bring you.
-I told her.
Tell her I want to see you.
Okay, I'll tell her again.
When are you coming to visit?
Soon?
Yes, soon.
"Gato". What type of word is it?
Oxytone, paroxytone, proparoxytone?
-It's paroxytone.
-Paroxytone.
Right. "Pájaro".
-An oxyotone word?
-"Arroz".
-Do you have the cards?
-Yes.
-How many?
-Ten.
Okay, check them.
Better count them.
-I can't take it anymore, Marta.
-You can. Take it easy.
-You got the papers?
-It's being arranged.
You said that last week.
I'm on it.
-You're sure?
-Positive.
-It's so close.
-See you soon.
A big kiss. Love you.
-Bye.
-How long's the trip?
-Two hours.
-How long is your leave?
-Twelve hours.
You only have eight hours.
Give this to your kid.
-Thank you.
-Kiss Tommy for me.
I love you.
-You look real cute.
-Okay.
-Zárate, let's go!
-I'm coming!
-Bye, Julia, take care.
-Bye...
-Bye, Julia.
-Bye.
-Good luck.
-Zárate!
-Coming.
-Don't forget the smokes.
No, I'll get them.
In a hurry, huh?
Door!
Send this to my cousin.
-Okay.
-See you tomorrow.
-Good luck. Kiss your baby for me.
-Thanks.
Bye, Julia! Don't look back!
Processing.
-Full name?
-Julia Zárate.
-l.D. number?
-27 01 0 989.
-Father's name?
-Tomás Zárate.
-Mother's name?
-Sofía Giusti.
Ready.
-Ready?
-Yes.
Transfer!
-Hello.
-Hi.
Good, you're here.
I'm on my way out.
That suits you.
-Tomás?
-He's waiting for you in his room.
-Okay.
-I'll be back in a little while.
Guard, can I see my son?
Go ahead.
Hey, will you give a hug?
What's this? A dragon's tail?
Cool! A cap, too.
A cape!
Excuse me, guard.
Can I speak to her?
Go ahead.
-Tomás wants his snack.
-I'll get it.
-Okay.
-Would you like some tea?
Sure.
-Go ahead.
-I'll take it to him.
Thank you.
-You give him chocolate, too?
-Yes, of course.
Thanks.
Do you want to go to the beach?
Yes? We go to the beach...
And we'll fight the dragons?
What do we take?
We take the dog.
Let's go to the beach! Let's go!
Do we go to the beach? Yes?
To the beach!
To the beach, this way...
Don't make a sound. Shush!
So what did the prince do?
What did the prince do, Tommy?
Come on.
Come with me.
Guard... Can I have
some water, please?
-A glass of water?
-Yes, come in.
-Where can I get a glass?
-Up there.
Zárate, open this door!
Zárate, open up! Are you crazy?
Okay, let's go. Come, Tommy.
Zárate, open the door!
You're taking the kid?
They'll kill you.
-Mom.
-Let's go.
Let's go.
-And the dog?
-What?
-Where's the dog?
Zárate, open the door.
I know you're there!
Don't do something crazy!
Okay, let's take the stairs.
Give me your hand.
Here's the dog.
Come on.
Come.
Let me carry you.
Here.
I cut my hair like you.
-You did?
-Yes.
-You like it like that?
Great.
Look.
Do you want to go
to the beach?
What kind of beach?
With water and lots of sand.
-Lots of sand?
-Yes. Lots of sand.
Cool!
A beach with lots of sand?
Let's go to the mountains.
Where can we go?
-To a park?
-I said I want to go to a beach.
Watch your head.
-Tickets.
-When do we go back?.
-Tickets, thank you...
-We'll see. A little later.
-When is Grandma coming?
-Do you want to see the river?
-Yes.
-How are you?
-Good.
He's grown!
Don't wake him up.
This is yours.
-Look at the picture.
-Here'sTommy's.
-Are they good?
-Sure, they're fine.
Put them away.
Some clothes for you
and for him.
Thank you.
You look pretty.
How much longer?
About five hours.
Put this away.
How are things?
I'm working a little.
-The kids?
-We get by.
-What?
-It's a mess.
With all of them, it's a mess.
-Not in trouble, huh?
-Nah.
Hey, come here! Don't run.
Give me your hand.
Wait for me.
I'll get you!
-Good afternoon. Name?
-Zarategui.
-Where d'you come from?
-Buenos Aires.
-What part?
-The city.
-Go ahead.
-Thank you.
-Pick me up.
-Yes, come with me.
Careful, Mom.
Look at the water.
-Are we going to cross it?
-Yes.
-My hand is a rock.
-Then, throw it away.
Are you happy?
We're almost there.
Yes, nearly. See?
Look over there.
See how close?
Look over there,
where the flag is.
Like it?
Here we are.
Off we go.