Where is he?
He promised.
You know his promises.
He's not gonna miss this, is he?
He'll be here, sweetheart.
But...
Well, that's okay, Joaquin,
just put them all on
the front of the float.
Where's all the flags?
Okay.
See ya later.
Jeff, for Gods sake.
I'm here.
I'm ready, I'm going.
Jeffrey, Jeff.
General Grant, right?
Get dressed.
I'm getting dressed.
Go. Go!
He had a beard, you know.
Jeffrey.
Never mind, never mind!
I love it, it's fabulous!
Hurry up!
Yes!
That looks like a blue ribbon.
You say that every year.
I know.
We're right up front between Valley Realty
and Darrell's Body Shop.
I'm telling you.
You're not dressed!
What do you mean, I'm not dressed?
I'm dressed great.
This is a parade.
And I'm ready to march.
You look like you're ready to dance.
That outfit does not spell defense.
What does it spell?
Barbara.
Do you still prefer McDonald's
for work experience?
Miguel.
McDonald's for work experience?
I'm having second thoughts.
Not now, Miguel.
Ms. McLaughlin.
I'm considering Long John Silver's.
I looked into the future
and it may be fish.
Miguel, after the parade.
I'm busy with other
people's futures right now.
Looks like you're doing
fine, Sergeant Leathers.
I'll be over at the Army booth,
they always need help.
And what are you gonna
do after the parade,
Ms. McLaughlin?
I think I'm gonna lie down.
Alone?
Standby!
Ten-hut!
Hey, Jeff.
Come on down here.
Jeff.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Air Force Academy.
They're setting up interviews.
We gotta sign up.
Look here, cadet, how many fingers?
What, what?
Four, the man said.
Correct.
Now, what's the color
of your white jacket?
You've lost it totally.
The man said white.
White is A-okay.
Certify him for night flying.
You're in!
Congratulations, cadet.
Sign right here.
Give me it.
Applicant, that's me.
Alright.
What are you doing here?
You shouldn't be here.
What do you want?
Are you crazy?
No!
It was the first
summit handshake...
His tie comes from Paris.
Certainly an improvement on Brezhnev.
The suit is Italian.
Madam sends to Milan for her clothes.
What about my roof?
Your what?
My...
His cover.
San Diego County Agricultural Exchange.
Do you know the area?
Intimately.
When you reach San Diego
you have not only
the FBI to deal with.
Also the Navy Investigative Service,
the Defense Investigative Service,
plus Customs and Immigration officials.
San Diego is very active.
You do understand?
Young man, I was crossing into the west
before you could spell Bolshevik.
A cannon is loose in San Diego.
You'll know him, he belongs to us.
The Americans have coded him Scuba.
Their attempt to be amusing.
You are to apprehend Scuba.
He has killed one of our best agents.
Scuba is an embarrassment to the premier.
The premier prepares for the summit.
A sideshow.
This IRS man was working for us.
Scuba is blackmailing us.
He will keep killing our agents
until we give him money.
Return Scuba to Russia alive.
That is your assignment.
You have seen the
dossier on your backups.
I prefer our man in Vancouver.
The operative word is discretion.
No press.
No publicity.
No news at all.
What we fear most is the American media.
I remember when we used to fear the CIA.
Everything changes, Karpov.
This latest series of talks
between the two great superpowers.
Nothing changes.
The first historic meeting
between these two world leaders signals
the beginning of a new chapter.
More applications, Roy.
These didn't come up kosher, either.
I say that we've got a run on
the Air Force Academy this year.
That's one way to beat Army.
Chief, you're drowning me in paper.
Stats, Roy, stats.
The inspector's going to pay us a visit.
Did you see the thing about
the IRS man at Caliente?
What IRS man?
The one they found
behind the pari-mutuel
with his throat cut.
What do you and Totten do in here
every morning at 6 a.m.?
Check the Hong Kong prices?
I know a horseplayer.
Oh, forget about Scuba, Roy.
The man is a burnt out double agent.
Scuba has been turned so many times,
he looks like an omelet.
The man killed my partner.
You don't know if he killed him or not.
Jesus, Roy.
That was 20 years ago.
So what?
I gotta go.
I'm presenting the
hole-in-one trophy tonight.
Hey, hang in there, Roy.
Grant.
Jeffrey N.
Okay, let's see this kid.
What have we got here?
I need a reading on Richard
and Elizabeth Grant.
Fountain Grove, California.
Son Jeffrey.
Yeah.
It doesn't track for me.
Did these people die or what?
Go Air Force!
Yeah, go, Air Force.
Will you sit down.
Turn the radio off.
Look at this guy.
Jeffrey Grant.
Alright!
Go get 'em.
Good luck, buddy.
And remember,
you live in fame, go down in flame!
Off we go...
Into the wild blue yonder.
Climbing high into the sun.
Here they come zooming
to meet our thunder.
At 'em boys...
Give 'er the gun...
Excuse me, Corporal.
What do you think?
I'm sorry?
Corporal Holden.
Oh, her.
Yeah, she was very nice.
Yes, very nice.
Sometimes I slip up and
call her Corporal Hogans.
Roy Howe, Jeff,
Air Force Reserve Liaison.
I'll be conducting your academy interview.
You got a wet palm there, son.
What's the matter, nervous?
Yeah, I'm nervous, sir.
What are you nervous about?
I don't know, I want to pass.
There's nothing to pass,
this isn't a test.
Relax.
Be yourself.
Okay.
You are nervous, aren't you.
Why?
Because you told me to be myself.
Whenever people tell me to be myself,
I don't know what to do.
How come?
Because I don't know what myself is.
You like girls, Jim?
Jeff.
How do you feel about girls, Jeff?
I love 'em.
You got a girl?
You bet.
You have one girl?
Yeah.
No.
Yeah, I do have one girl.
And I like her a lot.
But I love girls in general.
You're doing fine.
Why do you wanna go to the
Air Force Academy, John?
Jeff.
Jeff, Jeff.
I hear you.
You hear me?
I wanna fly.
I wanna be a pilot.
That's it?
I love my country.
That's all?
Hey, what can I tell ya?
I gotta fly.
Why?
I like to go fast.
I can see that.
Only three tickets.
In a month.
40 in a 35.
I was on a freeway at five in the morning,
alone on the road.
Oh, you don't deserve the citation.
No!
Yeah, I do.
I drive too fast, but I'm a good driver.
Sorry.
I'm working on it, sir.
Work hard.
Yes, sir.
I will, sir.
You suckin' up to me?
Yes, sir.
No, sir.
I...
What do your folks say
about your heavy foot?
Dad, you know how fathers are.
No, I don't know how fathers are.
Well, he's not crazy about it.
Neither is Mom.
I can understand it,
they don't want me to get hurt.
What about your folks?
What about them?
There're not much to tell.
They're Mom and Dad.
They run a garden nursery and...
And what?
And I love 'em.
What do your folks think about
you're going to the academy?
They don't know about it.
I wanna surprise them
with some good news.
Did I say the wrong thing?
No.
Not at all, comrade.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
Is that all?
For now.
Jeffrey N. Grant.
What does the N stand for?
Nicholas.
You of Greek extraction?
Or is your birthday near to Christmas?
I don't know.
I used to hate the name.
Then I went through this period that
that's all I wanted to be called.
Nick.
I thought it was tough.
But now I hate it again.
We'll be talking again.
Great.
About something else.
I thought I passed.
For now.
Blue skies, Jeff.
Happy landings and pack a tight chute.
What was that?
No good?
I practiced this morning,
I thought I'd do it.
Now I blew it.
Wasn't too bad.
Bye, Corporal Hogans.
Good, Jeff, good.
You must be tired, Comrade Karpov.
No, just have nothing to say.
I still do not understand why
they sent you here.
To get the job done.
I think we should go through the list
of your contacts again.
What for?
To make sure you remember them all.
Even you could forget.
I doubt it.
I put them here.
Too bad about our lovely water skier.
She was a good agent.
Scuba made contact with you only once.
As I told you, a brief message.
Pay $200,000 or I'll kill
every agent on the list.
Only four more to go.
I heard you gave him
the code name Scuba.
No.
An FBI agent did.
But why?
He loves water.
Like a shark.
No, like a rat.
Stop here before we get to the border.
We have organized a pickup
on the other side.
I prefer public transportation.
I guess that's okay,
but I don't have to tell you.
No, you don't.
Welcome aboard
the San Diego Trolley.
Bound for the Sante Fe
depot in Center City.
We appreciate having you
on board today
and hope you have a pleasant trip.
You call taxi?
Are you the man who wants to go
to Fountain Grove?
They crossed the border yesterday.
Turned up in a coffee
shop in Fountain Grove.
He didn't give up on
public transportation, did he?
Meaning?
He was at the Union Station stakeout
in D.C. 20 years ago when Scuba...
Oh yeah, right.
Look at that son of a bitch.
He still looks real good.
Why did you ask me in here
before everyone else?
Because you're the best, Roy.
I should be reporting to you
instead of
the other way around.
Don't stroke me, Jim.
What do you want me to tell you?
That I got Scuba.
You know there's a case.
You can feel it inside just like I do.
Karpov is here to get Scuba.
The bureau is maintaining
a hands-off policy.
Screw the bureau.
What is your policy, Jim?
You know I'm right.
I don't give a damn
whether you're right
or wrong, Roy.
I just wanna see you
get on with your life.
Get it resolved.
You owe it to yourself.
So I got Scuba.
Yeah.
You got Scuba, he's all yours.
But you're on your own.
It is strictly unofficial.
No one but me knows about it.
Understand?
Thanks, Jim.
Don't forget your
Air Force applications.
So...
They spotted him in a coffee shop
in Fountain Grove.
Fountain Grove?
Wait a minute.
What's the big deal?
I'm just applying for traffic school.
Down the hall, Grant.
Room one.
Please.
All I want is Saturday's class.
If I don't get in,
I don't get my license back.
Sorry, Grant.
Room one.
Hello, Jeff.
Hi, Major.
What are you doing here?
Let's take a ride.
Take a ride?
Take a ride where?
Why do I wanna take a ride with you for?
Because I asked you to.
Did you read it?
I'll show you my I.D.
It gets me a beer in a disco
in Encinitas.
What does yours get you?
Mine gets me this.
I could fix the license
but not that picture.
Am I under arrest?
What for, did you do something wrong?
No.
What's the matter then?
Nothing.
Relax, I just wanna
ask you a few questions.
See that storefront over there?
That's Congressman
Larkin's suburban office.
Someone in there is selling
nominations
to the service academies.
If someone's selling,
someone's buying.
Bingo, A plus.
Is that what you wanted
to talk to me about?
How long have you known
Tony Stanton
and Tom Stubblefield?
All my life, they're my friends.
Friends have a way of changing.
Now wait a minute.
How about their parents?
Their parents are my friends too.
If you think someone did
something funny,
go talk to someone else.
Okay.
Which brings us to the Grants.
Folks working late?
Yeah, they're in the potting shed.
I guess the mushrooms are coming up.
Can I go now?
Keep your ears open.
You mean sneak around my friends?
You wanna go to the Air Force
Academy, don't you?
You think it's fair for
a guy to buy his way in?
Take your place?
Oh, no, no.
Okay.
And don't mention anything
to your folks.
What do you mean?
Let's just keep this between us.
Why?
You wanted to surprise your
parents, didn't you?
Yeah.
Okay.
And Jeff?
I'm glad you got your license back.
Oh, this is pretty.
I think I'll take this one too.
No, if I take this one,
I'll have to have another one.
Oh, that one!
That one over there.
Jeffrey.
Jeff.
Jeff, Jeff!
Did I tell you fruit trees?
Fruit trees?
I thought this was a cactus sale.
I wanna dress it up a little bit
with a pair of dwarf persimmons.
Dwarf persimmons?
Fruit trees for short people.
Bring out a Mexican old man.
Now I'm a social worker.
You can take these right
to the cashier.
Alright.
Thank you very much.
There's nothing to be
afraid of with plants, sir.
I know what's coming.
Talk to them.
I don't wanna talk to them.
But I will water.
But not a whole lot, however.
I don't have the time.
How is the light in your nook?
Don't start that.
That's what the last guy asked me
and I was doing sun studies
for a month.
I guess what I'm looking
for is something fat.
A fat plant?
All fat with leaves.
Bushy?
You tell me.
Hold on, hold on.
Richard?
The gentleman is looking
for a fat plant
to fill a nook, lots of leaves.
And he doesn't want to worry
about water or light.
Plastic.
You want a plastic plant.
K-Mart.
No, I don't want plastic.
I want real.
Excuse me.
What are you doing, mister?
What do you think I'm doing?
Not what I told you to do.
You told me to find
the Mexican old man.
That's not a Mexican old man.
That's a candelabra cactus.
Now put it back, put it back.
What is this?
That's a meditation tree,
they're from India.
To help you relax.
That's for me.
What do you think, son.
Will it help me relax?
Certainly hope so.
Now, let them off there, folks.
Then come on aboard,
they're really biting today.
What'd you get, Richard?
Bonita, sheepshead, mackerel, bass.
What about you, Jeff?
Tell him, Jeff, tell him.
Tell him what?
Tell him what you got.
I got a tire and a tin can.
Hey, next time.
Okay, hit the smoker, anglers.
Oh, thanks.
Eight pounds.
Okay.
Where's Aurelio?
Yeah, three-time loser.
Border patrol grabbed him.
Someone blew the whistle on him.
Hello.
I like your new helper.
Yeah, he's Joe.
Yugo out of Vancouver.
Wouldn't you believe it.
Talks less English than Aurelio.
Why don't you just get
another bracero?
I don't know, this guy
just showed up.
I'll see ya in a couple weeks, Bucky.
Yo, Richard.
Do you have a file on Jeffrey Grant?
What kind of file?
Grades.
Extracurricular activities going back,
say a couple years.
Why would I show you
Jeffrey Grant's file!
I'm FBI.
You could be NFL for all I care.
Please.
Good kid?
Straight A's.
Tells his friends he gets C's.
Wonderful kid.
What about his parents?
PTA, the Rotary, the United Way.
They love their kid,
their kid loves them.
It's a close family.
Close?
Pardon?
It's close in here.
If there's no window,
there's no air.
An old saying.
Well, that do it for you?
How'd a pretty girl
like you get mixed up
in guidance counseling?
How'd a nice guy like
you get mixed up in FBI?
You ever guided any students
towards the bureau, Verna?
I hope not.
How about me guiding you
towards dinner?
Richard!
Mom?
You okay, Mom?
Looks like a one dash.
No.
Dash one.
Two three...
Six seven eight nine dash one.
Kirov opening.
Okay, Cindy, go get the ball.
Diego, the ring.
Starbuck, the block.
Okay, good girl, Cindy.
Great, guys.
That a boy, good boy, Diego.
Yeah, that's a good boy.
Where'd this come from?
Where'd you get this,
you little devil?
There's a body
in the water!
Call the harbor police!
Let's get the police!
Jeff!
What happened?
Is he hurt?
Oh, honey.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fine, I'm fine.
Howdy, folks.
Roy Parmenter here.
Your new neighbor from
across the street.
Oh, I'm Richard Grant.
This is my wife, Elizabeth.
And this is our son, Jeffrey.
Are you okay, Jeff?
Yeah, yeah, fine.
Have we met somewhere?
You look so familiar.
Sure.
I swung by once to buy
a plant for my office.
Hi, Jeff.
Put her there.
Oh, now that's what I call
a handshake!
And I could use
the other hand too.
Help me load in over there,
know what I mean?
I don't think so.
He'd love to, Mr. Parmenter.
Call me Roy.
May I call you Richard?
And you're Betty, right?
Elizabeth's good enough.
What happened to Sergeant Juckett?
Oh, he got transferred
back to Paris Island.
Lucky me, hey.
I pay well.
You don't have to pay
Jeff a thing.
You're in Fountain Grove
now, Roy.
Oh, and it's real pleasant
to be here.
Where do you hail from?
Philadelphia.
Navy.
I write specs for ships and they
transferred me out here.
Talk about a break.
Oh, great weather, San Diego.
And nice neighbors.
And someone to shoot baskets with.
You ready to go one-on-one, Jeff?
Nope.
Jeff.
Come along now.
Help out Mr. Parmenter.
What the hell are you doing here?
Every time I turn around
you're around.
Just trying to get to
the bottom of something.
Yeah, well, the last
guy kept running into me
accidentally on purpose
was Maurice.
A waiter I bussed for
at the country club.
You gay, Roy?
Can't say as I am.
Then why the hell are you breathing
down my neck?
Go live with Tom.
Go live at Tony's.
They have pools in the neighborhood.
Please, get off my block.
Ease this baby a little to the left.
What the hell kind of investigation
is this anyway.
Are you gonna tell me or aren't you?
You're asking all the
right questions, Jeff.
Something big is coming down.
Come on, Dad.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Hi, Bill.
Hi, girls.
Hi.
You girls gonna say hi?
Now look both ways.
I wanna go on the slide.
Me too, me too.
Dad, can you get in trouble
with the IRS
if you don't report
all of your cash sales?
It's impossible to report all of them.
Why, you gonna turn me in?
Never in a million years.
Have you ever been arrested?
No.
Now why would you wanna know that?
Oh, just curious.
Are you trying to
tell me something, Jeff?
No, why?
What do you mean?
What's on your mind, Jeff?
How about everything?
Can we narrow it down
a little bit?
See, now you're making
fun of me.
C'mon, Jeffrey.
Relax.
Can't worry about the whole world.
Okay, Dad.
I'll just stick to our block.
Hey!
And it's fruit juice
for Mr. Morose.
Thank you.
See you guys in a bit, okay?
Do you wanna watch the movie?
No.
Were you troubled at home, Roy?
I had a great home.
I can't imagine you as a kid.
Oh, I was a wonderful kid.
What did your father do?
Cop.
Good cop or bad cop?
Bad cop.
Wouldn't kiss ass.
Good father.
You're making me revise
my opinion of the FBI.
Barbara?
You don't have to say anything.
You love me?
Only two left, Konstantin.
The money, comrade.
The money.
Jesus.
Come on, give me the ball.
That's 11.
Don't you have to win by two?
I already won by four.
Want something cold to drink?
What have ya got?
Everything, help yourself.
I got chips to go with that.
Jeffrey Nicholas Grant.
Well, that sounds official.
Your parents are Russian spies.
Your parents are KGB agents.
Sleepers, they're called.
Deep cover.
They blend with the country
they're assigned to.
Own homes, hold jobs, raise families.
They sleep for years.
But when they awake, they're lethal.
Let's go back to your Air
Force Academy investigation.
What happened to that?
What about it?
What happened to your investigation?
There wasn't any.
Richard and Elizabeth
Grant entered this country
through Canada.
Took their IDs off headstones in
a Spokane cemetery.
Three years later, you were born.
Wanna see your birth certificate?
No, thanks.
Sure you don't want some chips?
I exist on corn chips and jalapenos.
I'm not too swift around a stove.
Your dad loved western music.
Hustled Beatles records
in Central Army Park.
What they call a fartsovsnchi,
black marketeer.
Can you spell that for me?
He did two years
in Lubyanka prison
then they shipped him to Gaczyna,
KGB's Quantico.
Dad liked Gaczyna better.
That's where he met Mom.
I see.
Your mother was a dancer in the
Bolshoi Children's School.
She toured the U.S. when
she was 17.
Picked up English so fast
and so well,
they shipped her to Gaczyna,
American Department.
A marriage was approved.
KGB likes husband-wife teams.
Are you finished?
I'd like to go home.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Hi.
I'm Larry.
This is my brother Daryl.
This is my other brother Daryl.
Hey, Jeff.
Hello?
Who is this?
Barbara, I gotta see you.
What's wrong?
I'm leaving, I gotta get outta here.
Calm down.
What's going on?
I don't know anymore.
I just wanna run away.
What happened?
You get another ticket?
I wish.
Listen, Barbara.
Will you come with me?
I can't leave now.
I thought you loved me.
Don't do that.
That's not fair.
Yeah, you're right.
I'm sorry.
Go home, please.
Yeah, I will.
You promise?
I do.
Listen, get some rest.
I love you.
You had me there for a moment.
What time will you be home?
Five, six, something like that.
Could you be a little more specific?
I get tired of cooking dinner twice.
I'm gonna take my
truck to the shop, Mom.
Your truck, again?
It's my clutch.
My clutch is all mushy.
Remember, I told you about it.
What about it?
The lining for the clutch.
Brett's gonna do the work for me.
He only needs $50 for the parts.
$50?
I gave you $50 for your truck
last month.
I told you about it, Mom.
You said okay.
I didn't say okay.
You didn't say okay,
she said okay.
What are we doing here?
Sitting in Parliament?
Might as well.
Forget the clutch.
Forget you promised me.
I'll just strip my gears
and scrap my 4x4.
Hey, hold on.
I gotta go.
Jeff.
You know what it takes to run
that truck of yours.
Do you have any idea
what a teenagers
insurance costs?
Do you know what a promise is?
What promise?
Mom promised me
she'd advance me $50.
Okay, now she's unpromising.
Dad's right, Jeff.
It wasn't a promise.
Forget the truth.
Why bother with the truth.
Where'd that word come from?
Exactly.
What's truth got to do with it?
Truth has no meaning in this house.
You're yelling, Jeffrey.
I'm not yelling at you.
I'm yelling at her.
Lower your voice, Jeff.
Act like a human being.
That's right, I'm an animal.
Well, this animal tells the truth.
Alright, apologize to your mother
and then you apologize to me.
I will not.
You're both liars.
You watch, you watch
what you're saying.
Glad to.
You're both a pair of fucking liars.
Go on!
- Hit the animal!
- Stop it!
- Stop, for God's sake!
Go to school, Jeffrey.
Here's $40.
It's all I have until
I get to the bank.
I'll leave $10 with Mrs. Valdez
in the principal's office.
I think I got $10.
It's okay, it's okay, Dad.
It's okay, Dad.
You can't go around
with a busted clutch.
You'll have an accident.
Here's your lunch.
Thanks.
On your starboard,
notice those cigar shapes
over there?
Those aren't cigars,
ladies and gentlemen.
They're nuclear subs.
The big mamas next to them,
they're tenders.
Floating machine shops
that keep these
deadly defenders
of our underseas...
Did you check your
personal belongings, folks?
Watch your step off the gangplank.
Carry on, mates.
Remember to tell your friends
about the SS Margarita.
Bye, everybody.
Hey, friend.
The tour's over.
The next cruise is two hours away.
Are you trying to beat
the price of a ticket?
They've tried that before,
it's not gonna work.
Hey, do you hear me?
Dead.
Jesus.
I just saw this guy the other day.
Did he talk with you?
No.
What about your father.
Did he talk to him?
No, I don't think he spoke English.
He just gave us our fish.
What fish?
Smoked fish.
We traded our catch for the smoked fish.
What do my parents have
to do with all of this?
You remember I told you
about sleepers,
the inactive agents?
They were all sleepers.
Your parents are the only two left.
Well, who's killing all these people?
Us?
No, of course not.
A renegade Soviet agent
named Scuba.
Oh, this is too much.
What do you want from me?
Stay around the house.
Watch them.
Look out for new faces.
Someone's got to contact them.
Spy on my parents?
You've gotta be kidding me.
You want me to help you
put 'em away.
Never.
Look, Jeff.
I know it's hard.
But you're gonna have to
face the facts.
Look, Mr. FBI man.
If you're so sure,
and if you're so right,
then why don't you arrest them?
Because they haven't done
anything yet.
You manipulating son of a bitch.
Calm down.
You don't have much choice.
They could be next.
Wouldn't break your heart.
They're just bait for
your Scuba guy, right?
All you care about is nailing him.
You can come and identify
the bodies.
Good evening.
We can't help you.
We haven't done anything
for 20 years.
I know what you haven't done.
That is precisely what makes you
so valuable right now.
Comrade Karpov,
we are at your disposal.
But we're ill-equipped.
Just follow the story.
It's all right there
in front of you.
A prick of a thorn and
the princess sleeps.
And many years later,
the handsome prince awakens her.
It's all quite simple.
It's a true ensemble, the Kirov.
I prefer it to the stars
of the Bolshoi,
don't you agree, Elizabeth?
We can't!
Don't you see?
We can't anymore.
It's been too long.
We can't serve you now.
We are of no use.
We can't.
Please understand, we can't.
Elizabeth is understandably
upset.
But why be upset?
You're merely going to pay
a man some money.
How much money?
What kind of man?
Scuba.
Who?
Your old classmate from Gaczyna.
Gaczyna.
English.
Please.
I almost forgot.
I brought you a little something.
From Beriozka.
The good Beriozka on Gorky Street.
How is...
What is his name, Jeff?
It's a good likeness,
don't you think?
Don't shoot!
Ms. McLaughlin.
Is this work experience?
Go out in the yard.
I'll be out in a minute.
Life's little surprises.
No problem.
I'll just go topless for the rest
of the student body.
What are their names?
It's not important.
What are my parents' names?
Elizabeth Lazarova.
Mikhail Stropovich.
And what's my name?
Jeff.
That's not a Russian name.
You took a walk tonight, didn't you?
You found something you
didn't wanna find, right?
Battle of Stalingrad.
Probably belonged to one
of their fathers.
They're pretty common.
So many men went down.
Hey, do I detect a
little admiration there?
For who?
Your parents?
Yeah.
Why?
'Cause they had you.
Spare me the violins, G-Man.
No violins.
Just a lot of hard work.
You gotta be crazy to bring a child
into this ugly world.
What's so hard about it?
Making a buck, raising a family.
Keeping it all together takes talent.
Love.
Put these back where
you found them.
Back to business, huh?
G-Man's on to something big.
I'm trying to look out for you.
Don't give me that crap.
You're out for yourself.
The big collar, the major bust.
The two-bit G-Man will
shove it up your ass.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, easy!
You're not my father.
You're not even my friend.
Now we have to tell him.
No, no.
It would destroy him.
You're wrong.
He would understand,
I know he would.
We must send him away.
Where?
I don't know.
We should call Bill.
Have him put everything in Jeff's name.
It always was.
You knew this would happen?
We both did.
I'll never regret it.
We had Jeff.
I don't think it's over.
Oh, yes it is.
It can never be the same.
We could run with Jeff.
It wouldn't be fair to him.
He has his whole life ahead of him.
We have to tell him.
He probably wouldn't believe us.
How could he?
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Dad.
How was the ballet?
Very nice.
Dad?
Yeah, it was very nice.
Well, I think I'll turn in.
How's the new clutch?
Great.
Here, I almost forgot your change.
What's my name?
Come on, Dad.
What could the head of
the Grant family have
to hide from his first
and oldest and only son?
What's my name?
Nika.
J. Nicholas Grant.
Nick.
Nikita.
Hello.
Your moment has come.
I told you we're not ready.
You've had 20 years to get ready.
Who is it?
It's him.
Let's get outta here.
It's too late.
How about if you give us time?
Hang up the phone.
How can we prevail?
For God's sakes, Dad!
We beseech you.
Your discipline is sorely wanting.
The directorate will be most unhappy.
You must go to work immediately.
And if we don't?
If we choose not to.
If we have the strength
to turn our back
on Elizabeth's father and my mother!
Roy!
You have neither the
strength nor the choice.
They are both dead.
Our parents are dead.
Yes.
And to answer your next question,
of old age.
Roy!
Now, are you ready to proceed?
Give me your answer.
The answer is no.
Roy!
Roy, where are you?
It's me, Jeff.
Then we will have to skip
a generation.
Roy!
Come in, Nikita.
Sit down.
Oh, my God.
No, no, not God.
Just Nikita.
You will make contact
this morning at 5:30.
Meanwhile, Nikita and I will
keep each other company.
Please.
Please, Konstantin
Ivanovich, I beg of you.
Leave Jeff.
Anything you say!
You have heard what I said.
5:30 a.m. the G Street Pier.
You give him the money.
The boy, he is charming.
He looks just like his mother.
You speak Russian, Nikita?
No.
And the name's Jeff.
Jeff?
To me, you're Nikita.
And I am Konstantin.
You may call me tovarich.
It's our Russian word for friend.
Do you have another
cigarette, Konstantin?
You smoke, Nikita?
What would the Surgeon General say?
Russian cigarettes.
You will acquire the taste, Nikita.
As you will for all things Russian.
I once had some Popov Vodka.
Did you?
Bully for you, Nikita!
What a guy!
On your feet.
We're leaving.
Where are you going?
To the bathroom.
You have a weak bladder, Nikita?
Come again, Konstantin?
Go.
Make it snappy.
Leave the door open.
Stick this up your bladder, Boris.
Let's go.
Karpov?
He's got him.
You're next.
You stay out of it.
You're the bait,
Karpov wants Scuba.
We want Jeff.
Alive.
You've got to take me with you.
- You need me!
- Step aside.
The payoff is a trap!
Here's the passports.
He wants money, Karpov wants him.
If Scuba doesn't like
the rendezvous,
you are next.
We'll take that chance.
What do you think your odds are?
He'll kill you!
He'll kill anybody.
Okay?
Okay, okay what?
Okay, you tell me
where the rendezvous is.
Okay?
Okay what?
What?
You're not his father!
Hey, hey!
You've got to trust me!
Wait, wait!
Stop this damn truck!
There's no...
Roy!
Come in, Nikita, sit down.
Oh, my God.
You are entering the
United States illegally.
Out, out, out, out.
Hey!
No more monkey business!
Drive!
Come, come, come.
We go, we go.
Welcome aboard
the San Diego Trolley.
Bound for San Ysidro
International Border.
Go.
Go, go, go!
Up there.
Where the hell is he?
Richard!
- Jeff!
- Hey!
Richard, there it is.
Alright.
Over there!
- Faster!
- I see it.
- Alright, alright.
- Faster!
Richard!
Your attention please.
I'd like to remind all
passengers that there is
no smoking, drinking
or eating permitted
while onboard the trolley.
And in consideration
of other passengers,
please do not place
your feet on the seats.
Thank you.
Take a seat, please.
Please.
We did our best.
Don't take our son.
Wasn't good enough.
Take us.
But you are of no use
to me in Russia, Mikhail.
Our next station is Byer.
Byer is next.
Anybody got any change?
Hey, how about you, lady?
You got change?
Hey, you got any change?
Hey, how about you guys,
you got any change?
Hey, how about you guys.
You look like buddies.
You wanna chip in together
and make
change for me?
Oh, that's okay, hombre.
I'll manage.
Don't move, folks.
Everybody steady.
Konstantin.
Roy, my friend.
I lost you.
1967, Union Station.
And now we have found each other.
On the trolley.
A chance encounter of old friends.
You bring me my assignment?
What a friendly gesture.
No?
Did I presume too much?
Ah, of course, of course.
I'm mistaken.
You hold all the cards.
And all I have is a 17-year-old boy.
Get up, Jeff.
How?
Like you always did, kid.
What are you laughing at, scum?
What did he say?
How can he let me go
after I killed your friend.
No, not friend.
Partner.
He tried to be...
I heard what he said.
He tried to be a hero.
He ended up a fool.
You heard me, kid.
Plant your feet and rise.
Now.
On your feet, shithead.
On your feet!
Alright, Jeff.
Cross the aisle.
Nice and slow.
I would never give up a man
who killed my partner.
You never had a partner.
I like you, Roy.
Our last station
is San Ysidro
International Border.
All returning passengers
are reminded
to purchase new tickets
or validate
multi-ride tickets just
prior to de-boarding.
You stay with me to the border.
You stay here.
Stay out of this.
Come on.
You walk in front of us, kid,
and hide this mess.
No, no!
You don't want the cops here,
do you?
Jeffrey!
Nikita, I'm going to miss you.
We could have had such a
pleasant trip together.
Come visit me sometime.
And by all means,
bring Barbara with you.
Goodbye, Mr. Parmenter.
Keep an eye out for me.
I always have, Konstantin.
You know, Roy.
Russians don't shoot their children.
What's new, Roy?
Nothing much.
Tamales and cock fights.
Yeah, I know.
Same ole, same ole.
Let's go home.