You look nice.
Not bad.
Really nice.
I just went out for a walk.
I must bring a chair, you go with me?
I shouldn't have taken
the chair with me.
It's of no use here.
It's a stupid idea
to have a rest here.
The livestock here...
...they don't stop
making noise every night.
I cannot sleep well.
It's really bad.
You must tell this to my father.
It's useless to tell me about this.
I don't like the livestock.
Since you don't like here,
why did you come here for a vacation?
I don't know the reason either.
It's very clean here.
Nothing to worry about.
Nothing will happen.
Has everything been ready?
Damn, something goes wrong again.
Do you need a hand?
No, the TV is still all right.
I don't know what is wrong with it.
It's really a mess.
You go to the kitchen first.
Get me something to eat.
May I come in?
Sure.
I plan to play the movie inside.
It's unnecessary
to go to the cinema.
The screen is sill in need.
What you are doing is
all for playing the movie.
Yes.
When you finsh
then you give me a message.
Not yet.
You know it's not really simple.
What's the content?
No dialog, only monolog.
My mom and the others
will not really understand this.
They won't like it.
But it's interesting for you.
Then you keep it on.
Don't waste time.
This would be better.
Julien, you always have
the braveness expcept the idea.
You are in the daydream.
I cannot understand this.
I want to have a rest.
Am I late?
No.
It's all right.
My dad don't allow me to come here.
He said the persons
who made movies were crazy.
He's right.
I'm happy to be a crazy person.
I'm sorry, I didn't notice you.
Hello.
It seems that it's me
who trouble you all.
How long can you fix that stuff?
One hour.
Look at this.
I show you from the beginning.
I'm a little scared.
Don't you think that this
will be very abstract?
Abstract?
Yes, abstract, not real.
Why?
What's the reality?
Not like the shrug here.
I'm asking you what
the reality is, you think.
Brice's movies,
you maybe think those bad.
I think their movies
make people feel boring.
They did not vey badly.
You make me scared.
His last movie is the
worst one my mom shot.
He's just a movie bureaucrat.
He has something with
the culture minister.
Listen.
She got the letter, but she didn't open that.
She thought there was two kinds
of people could write letters.
One is the people who wantto get the reward.
The other is the people
who tell the story personally.
You must be the first one.
What?
I'm not like the chinese women
who are so sensitive.
What I'm now caring about
is the sunshine protection.
Protect the skin.
Whatever, it's done.
I could have a sleep.
I dreamed that I could not sleep.
Is it funny?
I could have a rest.
I forgot.
It's a long time
that I haven't had the nap.
It really drives me crazy.
Once I dreamed of my little son.
He's 12 years old.
My sister is also in my dream.
By chance...
I was 12 years old at that time.
What's this?
Damn.
Wait.
Me?
No, it's me.
It's me whose nose is bleeding.
My nose will bleed
if I use some strength.
Where has your mother gone?
The movie of Julien will be played.
The time is near.
What are you doing?
Do you think it funny?
I've got drunk.
Hey.
I don't know where she is.
Your wife is so boring.
It's the best time to play the movie.
OK, stop.
Dad, shall we go?
Did you see your mom?
I don't know either.
I know.
He's there.
I'm sorry to be late.
The doctors are always busy.
Really?
Let's go, Julien is waiting for us.
Hello, doc.
Do you want some advice?
Yes.
Wait.
Look. She's coming.
Mom is coming.
We are all waiting for you.
Where have you gone?
I've gone to change my clothes.
Here are chairs.
Please be seated.
May I have a smoke?
No.
I must have one.
How many cigars do you have everyday?
At least three.
Then you can only live till 40.
What's the movie?
Short movie.
No one sit here.
Thanks, Julien.
He's so kind that he
remembers my back illness.
This is Lili,
the actress of this movie.
Nice to meet you.
Is the movies finshed?
Yes, by myself.
Yourself?
I finish it with a partner
with the computer.
You are really great!
Glad to see this.
Is everything ready?
Yes, I've put the tape in the player.
You didn't tell me you are ok.
Just to make him happy.
Please sit down.
I go to close the door.
Don't fall asleep.
Is everyone here?
Yes.
OK, let's begin.
These actors are all like the people
who share the common genes.
OK, action.
Damn, where is the remote control?
It must be really nice.
Thank you, you are so nice.
I'm not falttering.
I often did something stupid
when I made the movies before.
I consider the actors
as the ticket for the money.
You are all the audience.
That's the old idea.
It depends...
The old actor is really natural.
More truly.
Nature is nothing to me.
It's true to have the house to live in.
Stop talking.
It's about to begin.
I make movies not for selling
something natural.
It's ok to beign.
No subtitles in the beginning.
Damn, I cannot hear anything.
I want to sit there.
I go with you.
I want some water.
Man.
Lion.
Glede.
Snake.
Spider.
Silent fish.
The shrimp in the pool.
Starfish.
They all have a kind of strength.
The love for the life.
All the life.
All the life has its own mark.
But it will disappear finally.
We cannot say this...
For thousands of years...
Nothing alive can live on the ground.
But this poor moon...
It gives out the light in vain.
On the grassland the horn stops.
The songs of birds in the tree
cannot be heard.
The shell of life becomes the dust.
The forever matter changes them into...
...rock, water and cloud.
Their soul is connected together.
The soul of man and animal is connected.
I can remember all this.
All this.
I can even feel the living
of every knid of life from my body.
OK, stop.
What happened?
You don't really care this,
you make me bored.
Wait.
It needs people to think, doesn't it?
You are a boring woman!
You are a boring person!
We are all waiting to say something.
Especially when you show it to the people
you must wait for the commments.
What criticism are you talking about?
Do you want us to see the movie
you shot with him?
I can also say my feeling, if you like.
Listen, you make me feel boring.
Are you clear?
So rude!
He's the rurigenous person.
You are so pushing.
Why are you so angry?
We cannot talk with this kind
of kids like him.
Why?
Am I not right?
Nothing.
The young directors are all the same.
They all praise well.
He showed us somehing unintelligible.
He thinks it wonderful.
This is my genius son.
But your reaction is beyond of control.
I don't think so.
Lili, I don't mean this to you.
I think your performance is really good.
Your son wants to do better.
Boring, this is normal.
The young men are all like this.
No, no, the young men are not like this.
Not boasting, not naive.
He thinks himself an angel.
He's a fool.
Overconfidence, pride,
he makes all the people tired.
He's gone.
I don't feel well.
Don't talk to me about somethin
with the young men.
The so called young men.
Go to hell.
Do you know where he's going?
Dunno.
He thinks himself a genius.
Nothing.
We are used to this,
We all like your performance.
Do you like it?
Very much.
Me too.
Nice.
Pay attention to this compliment.
Wait, do you really think so?
I always tell the truth.
Or else I will shut my mouth.
It's not easy to shot the movie like this.
You will fall into it sometimes.
Do you think that it's a little too free?
Yes, surely.
You must have a feeling,
a feeling without life.
Tell him.
I told him about this.
Once in the vacation here...
...we spent summer here.
It would be nice that we can sing again.
We sang until late.
With something popular.
You sing nice.
You can sing for such a long time,
I like it.
I still remember...
...when you danced on the Mantile Island.
Oh, Mantile Island,
Simon, do you remember?
Listen, the animated shot is just like this.
Dad, at that time on the Mantile Island.
Those songs made me feel sad.
Do you remember that?
Soemtimes we will fall in the movie,
won't we?
Yes.
Becasue of something you are doing now?
No, because of something we cannot do.
Can you make the dog stop barking?
My dog, for the safety.
We are not afraid of thieves.
Come on, eat something.
Wait, Julien.
Not bad.
It's your idea.
Are you OK?
Don't talk to me like this.
So softly and slowly,
it seems that I'm a patient.
I don't treat you like a patient.
I know.
Listen, leave me alone.
I want to be alone and don't
need any comfort.
You go this way.
Go.
See you.
You can help us, Jeanne-Marie,
we won't stop you.
This cigar is not bad.
Thank you.
Not bad.
There are moe in my car,
if you like it.
This, very interesting.
I have no time to go there.
OK, have dinner,
the beef and the aubergine.
No, if you like you can do better.
This is my body.
This is my life.
OK, Simon, have dinner.
You are talking about
something impossible.
You think this naive.
You do everything.
Do you think so?
I must go.
Now?
I must catch the last boat.
Are you leaving?
Yes, I've got to go.
It's a pity.
We should talk about the movie.
I'm also happy to talk about that.
But I can't, my dad will kill me.
OK, byebye.
Bye.
See you all.
I'd better go now.
See you, Mimi.
Your movie is wonderful.
Thank you.
See you, Mimi
See you.
See you, Mimi.
I must have some fresh air.
So many people here are shouting
like a dog!
Why do you say so?
Maybe I'm wrong.
You are right.
But why did you sa so?
That girl looked at you.
I didn't have more words with her.
I swear.
The man like you will make trouble
with the beautiful women.
It's Julien.
OK, I will go.
You here?
Believe or not,
but I think you are a genius.
I'm flattering you.
Do you have to say this? Because...
No, you, wait.
I'm not your actor.
Let me finish my words.
Because I won't tell lies
to the guy I appreciate.
I'm not the only one.
You impress us so deeply
just like your mother.
Do you understand?
She's not so fashionable,
either is with you.
I like your movie very much.
I find many sparking points.
It's very good for you.
You won't always shut your mouth.
Hmm.
Ok, say something.
Say anything you want.
Be yourself, you are Julien.
You are right about the discussion
of the reality.
We haven't discussed the problem
of eternality.
You are the artist, while I'm not.
No, this is because I am fond of it.
OK, see you.
I send you back.
No, thanks.
I cannot sleep at night.
Oh, you know that.
Everyone has his own role.
Mado, Julien
Everyone appricates the stuff
standing on the different spots.
What they see is different.
So this cannot work.
You don't like the movie of Julien?
I like it.
I think this is a wonderful movie.
Just like him.
His favorite is so pure like water.
What are you doing?
You are smoking again, Jeanne.
Don't tell this to my dad.
Your dad is right.
He's not a boring guy.
He is, a stupid guy.
You don't understand him.
wait.
You.
Do you think I'm attractive?
Attractive? Of course!
Do you want to make love with me?
No, of course not.
You are not strong enough.
I just want to know if you want
to make live with me, that's all.
What's the difference?
Some people are very voluntary.
What's your point?
You are right.
We are originally talking
about the movie of Julien.
Of course.
Apparently.
Damn.
Julien won't like you, Jeanne.
He hasn't grown up.
Can't you see that?
What's more...
You are really amazing
All the people are in my house!
I'm fed up with it!
Good bye, doctor. Good night!
Look.
It's always the same.
Look! I come across her in my way.
No, I used to have a bike
As light as yours.
So happy to see you.
What's the party for?
I'm very happy. My father took a holiday
on weekend with his girlfriend.
I can be quiet for some days.
Then you can stay here
for another several days.
That's great.
Of course, if you all agree.
Why not?
Don't leave any more.
It's really fine for me to be here.
I want to live with you.
I like you. I love you.
Me too.
So do I.
Agnes went to pick some flowers.
I'll go to visit Julien.
Oh! I forgot to tell you Julien is not here.
He and Brice had gone to Paris
together this morning.
They are going to make a film.
Oh.
There went out all the directors?
Yes.
Oh, don't be upset.
They haven't gone yet.
The big one went to buy fungus.
What about the kid?
I don' t know where he is.
don't worry.
You will see him jump out.
14.9. Not so bad.
14.9?
You see? Sometimes,
you make little tricks.
What can I do for you?
No. Thank you. But it's all prepared.
What did Julien do yesterday?
Do you understand?
He is in a grouch with his friends.
I don't know.
Me neither.
This is Julien. It's his style.
It's not hard to understand.
For him, movie is life,
Something saintly.
Right! So what?
how can we go that far to adore him?
No. He's a pure-hearted person.
We ought to be pure-hearted
in front of him.
But it doesn't work.
Are we still not pure-hearted enough?
Aren't we?
This is his new production.
We can't talk with you
about these things, Mado.
It's very important to his job.
Fine.
Life will not stop.
We have to learn to try something.
Nothing worths complaining.
You are not in my side.
I am!
Let me help you.
No.
Why not?
Take it.
Take this on my thumb.
Good. Take it to others.
There.
Yes. Come on!
He should beat you.
Beat me?
It's a nice place.
Good night.
What happen?
I haven't slept yet. I'm hearing you talking.
No matter what, I can only sleep
because the doctor didn't willing to treat me.
No one is not willing to help
a seventy-year-old ill man.
It's.
I still want to live.
You are 70?
You are kidding!
I'm at least 30 years younger in your eyes.
You smoke. And drink.
Old man, that's not good.
Are you criticizing me?
The salts I've ever had are much more
than the meals you had.
You're really a fool.
Just you said I'm smart?
You are very clever, but certainly foolish.
You haven't mentioned the effort
of the treatment yet?
To tell the truth, it somehow works.
I don't know how he can manage it.
He even starts a clinic.
You do have endurance to your patients.
Don't you kiss the ugliest woman
in this flat?
Ok. I'll go to walk.
Anyway, It's bad to be exiled.
You're right.
I don't quite like this.
Even the world is cruel.
Life is serious.
Yes, serious.
I have been living. But I got nothing.
Just like what it is now
I once waited in my life.
Do you know, little girl?
But things never came.
Nothing.
I'm a total loser.
Life is short.
To be honest, life is short.
Life is not short.
It exists, and then disappears.
You see, not complicated.
Life is impenetrable,
ridiculous and nonsense.
In what direction does
the rain in the sky drops?
And how about the sun?
Are you joking me?
You are right.
People will die one day.
We will keep on doing these.
I once dreamt about you.
Oh?
It seemed to be the end of this world.
This is really funny thing.
Is that true?
What's true?
OK, fungus.
You are not only my sister's lover
but also a capable child.
Are these OK?
I don't know. I'm not an expert
for the colors and the tastes.
These are fine.
But not these.
What about these?
Good!
These are Mousse Mushrooms.
I like them very much.
Very delicious.
Are they Mali Mushrooms?
They are Mali Mushrooms.
Arhh£¬here we have Mousse Mushrooms,
Mali Mushrooms.
I had tasted Mali Mushrooms.
This is a kind of fungus
that can make people forget everything.
That guy does is foxy.
He thought I didn't go there.
Of course I went afterwards.
I just forgot it an the very beginning.
Hi!
Does everyone know some sports?
A little about golf.
But I didn't go further.
Usually there will be some activities
when propagandizing.
Need to face those journalists.
Is it good?
Yes.
I apologize for all the things last night.
Last night?
I had forgotten about it. Don't mention it.
Sorry.
I'm not apologize for my personal thinking.
I'm still thinking.
No one feel interesting. Stop it.
Everybody has their dinner quietly.
Forget it!
Nothing happened. Everything is all right.
And everyone likes your film so much
I am one of them.
Maybe just a little.
You like it for a little.
I prefer you don't.
I think you don't in your heart. Really.
Probably.
Listen, it's wrong either for
him to say these were nothing.
He acted rashly.
Julien, forget it!
No, I can't!
Only one sentence before it's all over.
It's what a fool do.
That's the point.
We must choose to be fool.
Why do you say that?
For example, for me,
You are one of my enemies.
You know, Julien,
there is real war now.
Some people are suffering.
I know.
I'm not saying this.
I only say to you what I want to.
Without any hostility.
Listen,Julien,
Your mother is angry.
You can't make others like this.
Go and hide. Wait!
We don't want to see you.
Let's make it.
I have the right to say what I want to say.
I don't stay here for myself.
I want nothing.
You are right.
I'd like to know that I am your enemy.
Why?
Did I threaten you?
You are a threat to me.
Am I?
Yes,the movie you made.
Julien,you can't say that.
What? What can't I say?
We can say anything.
Sticking at your own thoughts in life
It's important.
You are right.
What's my movie to you.
You can laugh at me with my mother.
First, I won't laugh at you
Second,I think I said I like your movie.
I think you didn't hear that.
Yes,I like it very much.
You say that with commanding tone?
Like those masters?
But I don't like you.
Then what I've done may be ridiculous,
coarse and childish.
But it's costful.
Belief comes from the fountain.
I agree.
No,you don't.
Because,if you would like to,
In last movie you made with my mother,
,the movie you made with her.
You called it ,right?
Yes,
Okay,I'm telling you why I don't like it.
Shut up.
No,wait,let him talk.
I want to hear it.
The people live in same mode.
The descriptions of those peoeple
are overdone.
The figures are too imaginary.
They don't exist,it's a shadowland.
That's all nosense.
Only exist for the actors,
let them be the stars in the world.
But what have we seen?
Nothing.
We've only seen the actors were working.
Nothing with the real life.
Please leave the table,it's my house.
It's my house too,it's dad's house.
Why I can't say what I want to say?
You are sick of everyone.
Haven't you lived enough as an stranger?
Aren't you sick of yourself?
It's weird,you all say the samething here.
Let's go when they are talking.
Your words are a big shock.
I feel that you judge people
by their habbits
Like in the court.
Those of your thoughts.
Film is a material stuff,
very meterial.
It's you.
Star,payment,budget
Julien,it costs much money
to make money now.
We have to make a compromise of money.
And,the result will be like you.
You stay at home,write some poems.
Yeah,it's still a life.
Julien,don't say it.
You can't offend people like this.
Wait,Lili.
Anyway,what he said is right.
What do I call it?
I can't speak clearly at this moment.
You should know,once,
you were as unsophisticated as me.
But I'll never be like you.
It's enough. Julien.
I don't believes the thoughts of genius.
I believe energy
I believe impulsion and desire.
Good,you are animals
Sometimes.
Listen,Julien
There is something beautiful,
just like Van Roost said.
When he talked about fun,
he was like that's a beast.
original impulsion and pleasure
The enthusiasm of enjoying body.
Even remember some trivial pleasure
He talked about a girl lost her virginity
He said,when enjoying
the corporeally pleasure
He felt that he could make
her mother's spirit cry
The spirit of angel
makes the spirit of god cry for it.
It's so beautiful.
That's how you think.
You are very exited.
Are you a little sad?
A little.
Can I have a look at what you wrote?
No.
Then I'll take a peek at it.
That's not easy.
I always carry it with me.
Lili
Let me have a peek at your diary,
I'll keep the secret
Lili,come here,I'm talking to you.
I don't wanna go.
I'm good here.
Come here,please.
You are not sleeping,aren't you?
No.
Lili.
What?
What's wrong with you?
Nothing
It's you who's weird
I've lost the all.
What have you lost?
Movie,play,everything.
You are so stupid.
It's the end.
Why are you so cold?
Why don't you care about it at all?
I don't understand the whole thing.
It's just like there's a deep
hole in my head
Why couldn't you just be more simple?
Life is more simple than that,isn't it?
What's simple?
Last night,you were with
them until very late.
You didn't even come to see me.
You don't care.
Is it simple?
What makes you become like this?
You fall in love with that stupid guy?
You love him?
I don't love anyone,let me go
Lili.
Don't go,Lili,please.
Lili,I can hardly recognize you.
What's wrong with you?
You are too stupid.
The yesterday's and today's
you are very funny in my eyes.
I'm funny?
Don't talk to me.
I can hardly think.
Think of what?
It's enough,you suddenly
walk to the other side
Who were you with?
With whom?
Myself.
And I've never said I love you.
I thought our relationship
was not gonna change.
It can't disappear just like this.
It's the thing that protects us.
Lili.
Don't do this,no.
I'm going out for a while.
Say goodbye to Mado and Simon
Bye.
Serge,be careful.
Serge,I wish we could leave together.
You take me to somewhere far away.
I can't stand any more, Serge
Don't do this,please don't.
Then what do you want?
Don't do this.
We can't just go away.
You are not a little girl anymore.
Are you okay?
You don't look like ...
Don't you want to have a walk?
I'm tired.Because I feel I'm old.
You?
I don't think so.I feel
like I have dignity.
I'll have to join a party
in Paris tomorrow.
An Film Award.
I'll go with Brice.
I want to go too.
No,you don't.Simon.
I've to go,you stay here.
you don't like Paris.
You always say that.
You won't be alone.
Julien,Jeanne-Marie will be with you.
And that kid,Lili
Don't complain.
What could you do at Paris?
You can only wander here and there.
It's true, though.
Then you stay here with Julien.
Please take care of him.
I'm afraid of him.
He treat his mother as...
I even don't know what to do.
I love this kid.
It isn't the problem.
I love him, too.
He's my son.
I mean I don't know him very much.
But he is reasonable to the life.
Why reasonable?
Of course.
A proud kid he is, though.
He's very acuminous.
Neither a favourite son, nor a skunk.
He has the viability.
What are you saying!
So boring you are!
Okey, it's enough.
He's a futilitarian, but not tragical.
You are a futilitarian, too.
Well, I may go to the toilet.
I want to have a life like yours.
It's reasonable.
You have a wonderful life.
You see, some excellent people.
Yes, it's excellent.
What a genius you are, Lili!
It's because you have a success life,
but you care nothing for it.
Obviously, your life is deep-seated.
You LIVE indeed.
It's important that you share
the cheer with others.
If I were you,
I would devote my myself to the public.
You are right, I'm devoting my mind
to the cinema and audience.
Lili, do you know that people like
packman like tobacco pack.
They would think of you when they want.
If we think a lot of something,
we couldn't respect the audience.
How the level it is!
What's the meaning?
It means you would lost your own opinion.
That's my mother's house opposite.
I have the very same experience with Julien.
His father is dead, and my mother, too.
Both we grow up like this.
I live through my childhood here.
I kept all in my mind.
The sea, and the island there.
They're good materials of a movie.
Really?
About some fairy tale.
There's an unsophisticated girl.
She lives beside the sea.
Free, and happy.
One day,
A man came to her.
He made she felf very happy.
I...
I will devote myself to the happiness.
Love you, make films, these're happiness.
I'm stupid.
Let's leave tonight.
We together.
Don't look for it anymore,
it's here in my hand.
What did you write?
Nothing.
Something interest me.
Did you see them? Or just coin them?
I saw , I heard.
Did you record them?
Of course.
About something happened here.
What people did and said.
Yes, a lot of them.
But nothing special.
They would occur anywhere, anytime.
Do you thing so?
You are right.
Want some?
No, thanks.
Are you open-eyed?
I know many girls like drink.
The same as man.
I don't like the alcohol itself.
But the fettle after drink.
They are all there, not mine.
What are you writng?
What you said just now.
Anything can happen at any time.
Is it funny?
Yeah,I write it for the audience
You should know it.I can write it for you.
You think you are not watching,
but actually you are.
I'm watching.
In the movies,those great moments
are always unforgetable.
Those who sacrificed
People are looking for the mystic things
for their life times.
During the life time,one should learn how
to keep itself,not to go after fashion
Ok,write this down too.
one should learn how to keep itself,
not to go after fashion
Life should be more unambitious
Looking for some thing equable.
Somthing insignificant.
The waiting is useless,do not wait any more
I'm eager to live with some normal persons.
My trouble is very simple.
Not too much worry and joy,just like this.
I make you sick.
This is what I need.
I want you to be sick of me.
You are beautiful,Marie.
You are very beautiful.
I don't know if you know it,
but you are very pretty.
Though Julien dosn't like you.
You are the most interesting people here.
I don't care if I'm intertesting.
I want to be happy.
Then you shouldn't be here.
Shouldn't be here,Jeanne-Marie
You can go with Lili
Did mom go away?
No.
Brice and Lili went away together.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I know.
I knew it.
Be careful,it's hot.
Where is mom?
Will she come to dinner soon?
Dinner begins in half an hour,if you want.
Serge went away,didn't left me his equipment
You take this basket.
I wanna go to the station at 8.
It's not early now.
Julien,wait.
When I saw them go,I wanted to tell you.
I looked for you.
'Cause I think you may want to speak with Lili.
I was looking for you everywhere,
but couldn't find you.
It's okay. Jeanne,thanks.
Mom
Mom.
Who's there?
Me.
What's going on?
What's the time now?
I'll have to get up in 3 hours.
Let me sleep for a while.  Go ahead.
Please.
I feel sick.
I'm scared.
Of what?
I don't know.
I'm scared to be alone.
Be alone.
We are both unlucky.
Come here,don't cry.
Sleep with me.
Do you still remember we used
to sleep together?
How was that?
You slept very well at that time.
Yeah.
I'm thirsty
Aren't you?
I'm gonna drink that bottle of water.
I'm getting up.
It's too hot here.
Look.
Let go,let go,let go.
No.
I've already made some programs
that make people dizzy.
Do you still wanna talk?
I have nothing to do.
Be careful,he always borrows money from me.
I won't do that.
I don't like those journalists
Patrick doesn't know what he's gonna do either?
He doesn't want to go anywhere.
He have to talk something about acting.
I know it's important.
But agreement is more important to me.
I'm fine,I don't need to shoot some bad films.
They don't spend money in propagand at all.
Wait,do you think it's enough?
Paste some posts in the cinemas
No,you ...
No,you are too exaggerated.
You can go to watch that program.
Bring me a sandwich,
I need to have some strength back.
Sure,nothing else?
A big one.
Okay.
Julie
I have to talk to you.
Okay,you guys come here.
Okay,emily
Ah,Lili.
Hi.
Hi
Let's kiss,like in those movies.
Like they do in the movies.
Lili,how are you doing these days?
I'm fine.I'm going to make a
propagandistic program now.
On French Station 2.
How about you? Is everything okay?
We are good.Just like this.
Do you walk this way?
Yes,I'm going to Makinpot,are you?
Makinpot?
Someone invite us to have dinner
in a restaurant there.
We'll visit those historic buildings there.
Okay.
We are very good now,
planning to shoot my next film.
Our.
Ah,our next film,sorry,honey.
We are both producer now,
especially Mado
Sorry,I've to answer a call.
How's Julien?
He's fine.
He wanted to put yo uin the first place,
but because you...
Why didn't you ever call him?
I don't dare
I saw he entered the hospital that day.
I was very scared,I missed the train.
I didn't have enough courage.
Um,listen,it's all over now.
It has... how to say it?
Time limitation, is it?
How is his life now?
It's okay,everything is over.
It's been 2 years,hasn't it?
I can't remember,I can't remember the date.
I haven't seen him for 4 years.
I have to say,he lived well,
he even started to write plays.
Is it a short play?
No,it was his first feature one, on tv.
Julien is going to shoot his first movie too.
It's just like a dream.
Are you talking about Julien's movie?
Yes.
It's not bad,really.
Great,what's it about?
About something we've been through.
But he refused those professional actors.
So you will act in the movie?
Yes,we act as ourself in the movie.
He also persuaded Brice to act a role.
Oh?
Actually I was very tense.
Director and actor are so different.
What do you shoot in the movie,
in details?
We can't tell you yet.
Of course we can.It's a big family,
everyone has his own problem
Actually it's the real life in pain.
Sure. I don't know either.
Anyway,it's our real lives.
I don't even know what I will be like.
But,i'll act.
I'll act when he ask me to.
If it's our lives,
what should I do in it?
Ah,I don't know. Lili.
I talked to Julien,he just shaked his head.
Ah,Emily,you are here.
Hi,Mado.
Hi,Brice. How are you?
Fine. Goodbye.
Sorry,we have to go.
Wait,goodbye.
Bye.
Bye,Mado.
Let's go.
Bye.
Let's go faster.
Wait,I'll have a call.
I'll be right back.
It's me again.
No,i've to go to the studio.
I don't call you for this.
Can you look for a movie that's
gonna be shot for me?
The first movie by Julien Marceaux.
Director Brice and Madeleine
will have roles in it.
Yes,he has a role,don't ask me abou this.
Can you ask if he find the actress
for that girl's role?
Okay.
Will you call me again?
I will,bye.
I thought you wouldn't come.
No,you saw it.
Good evening.
Take this.
Thanks.
Is it good?
You'll know it after seeing it.
The topic is interesting.
Not at all.
You can sit for a while.
I feel you grow up.
Of course it's impossible for you
to not grow up.
I think you became a star when you was 25
I saw the house is ostentatious
when I was outside just now.
It's your house,isn't it?
Yes,it's large.
But not in my house,it's my friend's
He's in London now.
Come here.
Have somehting.
Good evening.
I feel so good to call you.
How's Marie?
What? She didn't sleep yet?
Okay,let her speak with me.
Hey,baby.
How about you?
I'm not very happy.You can hear my tone.
Me neither.I wanna talk with you,
but I have to sleep.
Or you'll be tired.
Of course I'll miss you every minute.
Give you a big kiss.
Pass the phone to mommy.
Okay.
Yes. I've to go.
I shouldn't come here.
Because...I'll tell you at the right time.
I miss you two so much.
Kiss you.
Bye.
I thought you went away already.
How were you talking to?
Jeanne-Marie
We have a daughter.
Marie
It's so interesting.
How old is your daughter.
Do you live well here?
I feel like to do anything here.
Good life.
The scenes I watched on tv are unimaginable.
Just like a dream
I hardly have time to be here.
I'm shooting the movie at the most time
Sorry
Mado said you started to shoot your movie.
Yes.
It's great.You can do what you like to do.
Yes.I did it.
I've read your play
What?You've read it?
I think it's not complicated.Not bad.
I didn't know you would read it.
Because it's not a good play.
I wrote it with Jeanne-Marie.
We did it only for some money.
Jeanne-Marie worked with you?
She picked the actors with me.
She did some other things
She controled you.
Who will act my role?
That's not your role.
You can't say it.
I still have the right to know it,don't I?
Your movie is about the things
we've been throught,it's about our experience.
Exactly,it's about something
we haven't been though.
Who on earth will play my role?
That's my role,that's me.
I know.
There are serveral possiblities,
I'm still trying.
Have you ever thought to give
this role to me?
No.
Why do you ask this?
I'd better be more careful.
Be careful of what?
You should know the movie will
e easier to shoot without you.
If so,you are too cruel.
You are pretending.
I think it's strange for you to come see me,
don't pretend.
I'm not pretending.
Is it something that you come to see me?
To me,it's just like your putting
your hands in my heart.
And hug each other,like this.
I knew it was not gonna happen.
Why do you come if you knew it.
That's okay. We won't meet again. Bye.
Julien.
Julien,is that you?
Yes.
Lili is calling for you.
She's not good at all now.
Come.
Let go of me.
Let go.
Do you want some coffee?
I make some coffee for you.
It's not in my house.
Are you okay?
I miss you very much,always.
I miss you very much.
I wanted to call you.
I went to the hospital to see you.
But you were sleeping.
Come.
If you knew...
If you knew I was lonely with Brice.
Do you know what he wrote in his notebook?
That day when we kissed,
Do you know what he wrote down?
He wrote.
When he kissed me,
he made my life became unlucky.
He wrote,
he suddenly felt it would be a kind
of unlucky experience.
Do you know it?
Julien.
I'm here.
I know,
I know our meeting together is like
a dream to me.
I still wish we could meet again
in the movie.
Please.I wish so.
Or you'll feel empty too.
You can't give my role to others.
It's impossible.
Please,Julien.
Please.
Is it okay?
It's okay.
Just like your putting your hands
in my heart.
Then we hug,
just like this.
Sorry.
Mom.
Shhhh.
Baby.
I don't want to shoot the movie.
No,it's being remade
Galanty show?
Yes
Are you okay?How is your back?
Hi
Up there.
It's so cold.
There's nothing to eat here.
Is that true?
Yes.
Michelle,
yeah,
let me introduce a person to you.
Ah,you are Simon.
Yes.
It's nice to meet you.
My pleasure.
Don't say that.
Ah,you act as me
What do you want me to write down?
After I kissed her,I was still me.
But I took her into the endless pain.
Okay.
Hi.
I hardly come.
Not for the salary of course
Where is Mado?
There.
I wanna write the part of my own
After I kissed her,I was still me.
But I took her into
Okay,I knew it.I knew.
Grandma.
You can't call me grandma,my angel.
Why?
Grandma is shit.
No,not shit.
Is your name Marie?
Can you spell your name?
I don't know
Why don't you know?
Because mom's name is Jeanne-Marie.
But I'm her little garbage
No,you are a big garabge,very big.
Oh,yeah,you are a big one.
How are you gonna shoot?
Wait,of course.
Of course there can be some legends,
as meeting Brigitte Bardot.
You will say,it deson't matter,
you only want to write a novel
There wouldn't be Bardot if no novel.
Yeah,I want to write some famous plays.
So that my name will be used on a streen,
or a station.
When I was a kid,I always wanted
to pee while in the street.
I wanted to be a political person.
But I'm just a chicken now.
You should know,the name of my novel
is
Actually you should act this role.
You are so good at it.
No.
You should take a part in the movie.
Ah,my little castle. Come,come to me.
Sorry ,we have to shoot.
Can you get up please?
We have to use this chair.
Okay,green or black?
I like black.
I can't make it,friend,
I need a special doctor.
I'm sick.Because I'm smart.
No,no,
You don't want to look after those
smart people.
Why do you become like this?
I wanted to talk to you.
All these.
I wanted to talk to you about
all these things.
No,I don't think so.
I don't like real representation.
I don't believe people can have an agreement
in a same direction at all.
I think you are a mistake.
I think man will be lost.
But belief is the reason I exist,
sometimes it is...
Oh
It comes after me again.
You make me hurt,it's so annoying.
Move it to there.
Start.Quiet.
First scene in  110 scenes
Start.
Tonight,I have to greet the delicious
conjee especially.
Time for me to act.I'm looking for Julien.
Julien,have you thought about the things
you wrote carefully?
I speak the wrong lines.
It'll cost 4 hours just like this.
No,there's the ending of the movie,
we'll shoot it tonight.
Everybody gets ready.
Tell me.
Excuse me,
did Julien provide the wash room?
Okay,I'll look for it myself.
Okay,everybody in his position.
Start.
Good,quiet.
Engine.
Getting ready the engine.
Do you enter in red suit?
Yes.
Start.
First scene in  110 scenes
Action.
Oh,the door wasn't shut.
I'll do it.
It's better,there was some wind.
His son commited suicide just now.
It's the actress of Emily.
Great.
What are you looking for?
My keys.
Let's go.
Don't go.The movie is not over yet.
Okay,everybody in his position.
Come,Simon,come here.
Simon.
Come here.