Hey, it's Lotte!
Isn't it Lotte who's come home?
Did you manage to
save the world, then?
You don't recognize me?
I'm Fischer.
Shall I say hello to him?
I'll tell him hello then.
The UN Resolution gave us the
right. I've done nothing wrong.
The prime minister
rejected criticism...
of Denmark's
militaryrolein Iraq.
- Check.
- King high.
Raise. Call One pair.
Nines.
Ace high.
You lose.
Yes?
Peekaboo!
Hi, dad.
You've come home?
Yes.
How long have you been back?
A couple of months.
And your old dad had to hear it
from Fischer?
Been partying, maybe?
- You haven't got much of a tan.
- Leave it.
- You came home early.
- I'd had enough.
I thought you'd signed up for years.
I've quit smoking.
Nice.
Get dressed.
- Why?
- You need a proper meal.
Get dressed and we'll
find somewhere to eat.
Do as your old dad tells you!
Do as you're told!
Come on!
When a real sailor goes ashore.
You never know what will happen.
All along the dockside
The girls wave and say
When a sailor.
A real sailor Goes ashore.
You never know what will happen.
If a girl is nice to him
Maybe she'll get a kiss... Lotte!
Let's have Lotte on stage!
Lotte!
Lotte, Lotte...
When a sailor
When a real sailor goes ashore.
You never know what will happen
...I'll tell you in a whisper
When a sailor...
A real sailor goes ashore
You never know what will happen.
All along the dockside
The girls wave and say
When a sailor...
Don't look so miserable.
You're a good-looking girl.
Haven't you got a boyfriend?
- I want to go home.
- Get back in the saddle.
Back in the saddle.
Hop up!
Come on! Come on!
You're too heavy, baby.
Baby?
You're too heavy.
Can you lend me some money?
I'll give you a job.
... Get back in the saddle, baby.
I am your dad
and I'll give you a job.
Baby? Lotte!
Little soldier, you've got no money.
Lilly?
... Almost 6 weeks.
I'm pleased you got home in
one piece... did I tell you that?
- Home made.
- She cooks, too?
I made them. All she can do
is moan and shake her booty.
Well, as long as
she's good at that...
I used Splenda instead of sugar.
It's just as good.
- For goodness sake...
- They taste great.
That job...
- There isn't a job, is there?
- Of course. For my daughter.
You can be the odd job girl.
Drive me around. Stuff.
- Drive you?
- I'm banned.
I'd had a couple and Iran into
the back of a van on the bypass.
- In the Jag?
- No, the old wreck, luckily.
Can't you take cabs
and lend me some money?
No.
This is nice.
The manual is in the glove
compartment if you need it.
- There's a funny noise. Hear it?
- Just.
I miss driving.
Badly.
Fischer's got a grandchild.
He's younger than me.
Just thought I'd mention it.
Hi, Kurt.
Sit.
You can start by putting these
into a ring binder. In date order.
- Yes. I might need two ring binders.
- Got to start somewhere.
Hang these up.
And then get us some lunch.
What the hell is this?
Hi, Lotte.
I'll ask you again:
What the hell is this?
I fell down my steps last night.
"Fell down my steps?"
What use is that to me?
- I won't be able to drive for 6 weeks.
- She needs a driver in an hour.
- I can drive her.
- Like heck. The drivers are men.
Don't you think I can handle it?
She can, you know.
400 crowns a ride.
And it's only for today.
I'll find someone else.
Okay, ladies...
Could you say hello?
Alright? You two.
Get outta there.
- She can drive.
- I will not have any female driver!
- She's a soldiers.
- I'm not anymore.
Hey... your my girl.
I'll let nothing
happen to you, you know that.
And...
you'll be save with her.
Come here.
That is no good.
- I'm not happy.
- I will make you happy.
You know that, hm?
Now smile, hm?
- You're my girl, Lilly.
- Yes, pappa.
Now, now, now.
And drive safely.
She really doesn't want to meet
the cops, if you know what I mean.
You look wonderful.
Fuck you, very much.
...garbage and whether politicians
are interested in recycling...
I'm in room 218.
I'll go up
and meet the customer.
And if everything
seems okay,
I'll call you before
10 minutes and say "okay".
Okay.
If I call you and something
is wrong up there,
I say a differnd name
when I call you.
I call you Nico, I say: "Hello Nico.
Everything is fine up here".
"Nico" means,
everything is not fine.
You now come and kick in
the door and get me out.
Okay.
- Do you have a baseball bat?
- Don't worry.
Get a baseball bat.
- Yeah.
- Everything is fine up here.
- I come down in 1/2 hour sharp.
- Have fun.
- That was fast.
- It was good.
To another
- Yep 500.
- Thanks.
So, did you kill anyone?
So... did you fuck anyone?
All the time.
The next one is a handicapped guy.
His mother pays me.
- I'm a saint.
- Yeah.
Pappa is still at work.
- Du knepper ham da, right?
- Sure.
- So, he's not your pappa, is he?
- You're jealous.
- There were hundreds before you.
- Yes, pappa's still going strong.
Don't slam the door, please.
Thanks.
That funny noise gets worse
once the engine warms up.
One of the trucks was involved
in a bad crash in Milan.
Piss!
I keep feeling dizzy.
And I can't find her a driver.
Not one I can trust.
I'll go on driving her.
I am her driver.
That's fine.
- Like hell.
- I'm only helping.
- Till Fischer is all right.
- Fischer is a fucking twat.
I'm not sure your
lady'll be too thrilled.
- It's none of her business.
- No.
I know you can handle it.
So your old dad had a job
for you after all, eh?
Eh?
Yes, he's just fantastic.
You can go. I've got to wait for
a fax from Milan. I'll call a cab.
We'll go out for dinner
again soon. Right?
You have to come with me
to the next one.
- He has necrophilia.
- What?
He likes to fuck dead girls.
He gives me something,
to fuck me, you must come.
He pays more.
He's a good customer.
I got to go to
the post-office and send this.
Send it?
For my daughter.
You think I'm here
for laughs?
Don't slam the door, please.
Good to see you, Henning.
Good to see you, Lilly.
This is my driver
for today, Lotte.
Brought a lady today?
She is tough.
She's a soldier.
I better behave then.
Come inside, please.
Yes, come in.
There's the money,
right here.
Thank you.
Now turn around please, Lilly.
Thank you, Henning.
And now... please take
your vitamin pill.
- I better go and lie down.
- Yes.
And now we wait.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
Fischer usually sits over there.
I drink too much coffee.
I'd like to cut down.
I've never seen
a lady driver before.
Lilly and I leave
the bedroom door open...
so you can always check to see
that everything is all right.
Yes?
It's Lotte from next door.
- Yes?
- I've locked myself out.
- Okay, I'll let you in.
- Thanks.
- Hi.
- Don't you have a key to my flat?
- I don't know.
- Miriam has just moved out.
- Oh.
Come in and we'll see
if we can find it.
It's nice to hear
noise from your flat again.
Yes.
- Was it hard?
- Well...
My mom would be very upset
if I went there.
- What did your mom say?
- Oh, she's dead.
- I didn't know.
- She died ages ago. I was 11.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to...
That's all right. I grew up
with my granny and granddad.
- What about your dad?
- He runs a hauling company.
- Hey! Is this the one?
- Yes.
Thanks.
Wait a minute...
That's for you.
It's a geranium.
They usually die on me.
I'm not very...
It just needs watering
now and then.
If you forget, don't worry.
It'll survive.
Thanks.
- What are we doing?
- Trading.
Trading what?
I'm trading girls
with some geezers from Sweden.
We rotate them.
How many girls are you running?
I'm doing them a favor.
Nigeria is a fucking dump.
I help them.
I've done nothing wrong.
- Why're you so miserable?
- I'm driving.
Yes, like a twat.
Let's step on it.
- Yeah, yeah, Cheeky bastard.
- Who is this?
That's my daughter.
Maybe
there's something you like.
It's great stuff.
Take a look.
They're great, huh?
- A present.
- Thanks.
I'll take these.
No, forget it. We're friends.
It's a present from...
- one friend to another.
- Alright, thanks.
- Be seeing you.
- Yeah.
She's living here now.
- Hello, Lotte.
- Hello, Fischer.
Hi Lotte!
Hi.
- Nice car.
- Ah, it's my dad's.
What're you doing here?
- What are you?
- I work at the school here.
Trying to knock knowledge
into impossible kids.
- What're you doing?
- Finding something to eat.
You like Thai food?
Shall I cook you
a Thai dinner tonight?
- Seven o'clock?
- Eight.
- I must be getting on.
- See you at eight?
Yes.
We have three hours to kill.
- You don't dance?
- No.
- Do you like my bag?
It's Prada. A copy.
So... why did you become
a soldier?
Were...
- To do something good.
- Soldiers do good?
Yes... sometimes.
You kill many people?
- What about your daughter?
- What about her?
- How old is she?
- I'm saving up money for her.
- Nine.
- When did you see her last?
- Are you the police, or what?
Business isn't too great, is it?
Look what I'm wearing...
Cute as hell.
Look what I found at home.
Look!
From your confirmation.
- You looked sweet in that dress.
- Look at those shoes!
Look!
- It was a real occasion.
- Not that you were there.
- I was!
- Come on!
I begged granny for years to
let you come, but you never did.
Yes... for that...
- I took the pictures!
- Christian took the pictures.
I was...
- I gave you a Walkman.
- Yes.
You sent it by mail
and I sent you those pictures.
A good thing
I've got charm.
I'm taking Lilly out for dinner.
And you too.
- Not tonight.
- Why not?
- They're going all to a party.
- They'll have to wait. Come on.
- Everything okay?
- One customer.
Oh, oh, our buisness
is terrible.
Don't you slap me!
What're you doing?
I want my money back!
Now!
- She's useless.
- Take it easy.
- Now!
- He's crazy, I do nice.
Shut up.
I want my money back. Now.
Hey, you better calm down.
Shut up, you ugly tart.
Don't call me a tart.
Tart.
Wait...
His jacket...
get his jacket.
And don't come back, pal.
Thank you.
Right.
Right?
You can go, me and Lilly...
We'll take a taxi.
Did you like it?
I'm sorry. I...
I had to help my dad and...
I lost track.
I just wanted to make sure
you were all right.
Are you?
Would you...
ike some coffee?
Maybe it's a bad time?
I'll come for coffee another day.
I'm busy, actually.
Oh, Okay.
- Purges.
- You got it.
- Hello, Soldier.
- We have to go now.
I only wish I could, he cancelled.
He's to sick to fuck.
You can come in
and have coffee with us.
- Come in, Soldier. Come in.
- Come on.
Hey, I can do your hair,
make a lots of big
braidings for you.
- Okay?
- No.
- Our Madam in Nigeria...
- She has no hair.
And says she wants braidings.
"Make me breadings,
make breadings out of...!"
- She's a big fuck, big butch head.
- And she sets you up too.
You can be just
a big Madam like her.
Who is Madam?
- "Who is Madam?"
- Fucking dog. Madam.
- Madam...
- She said once you go to Europe,
you become a Madam
and borrow money from her.
You borrow maybe
40 to 60 thousand euro,
and she'll arrange to get you
to Europe... Italy, France.
But you must pay her back, and...
of course they'll come and get you.
- She knows exactly where we are.
- She's your family.
Yes.
But I would like
to be a Madam too.
You, go fuck that ugly man, bitch.
and give me my 500 kroner.
As Madam,
you have to be really forceful.
- Hello.
- It's me.
The telephone lady says
there's not much going on today.
So, come and get me.
Pick me up at seven...
at the shop, okay?
Did that noise get worse?
Maybe it didn't.
What the hell's
the matter with you?
- What're you getting at?
- About the fight with the John.
You're hard.
Really hard.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Your dad's an old fool.
I froze, okay?
Let's not talk about it.
I am a hauler.
I'm old.
Yeah.
Forward march, bum, bum, bum.
Piss on them.
Don't Albanians learn
to tell the time?
Maybe there's a time difference.
So, this is Pearl.
Maria. Hot chick.
Very popular in Sweden.
- What the hell is this?
- That's no problem.
No problem?
Who wants to buy her?
You can't punish 'em like this,
there's other ways.
- It's bad for business.
- Little make-up, she'll be fine.
I see a sexy, hot body.
Send me another one.
I can't use her. We're leaving.
Don't make a big deal
outta this. She looks fine.
They're out of their damn minds.
What the hell are they thinking?
Nobody'll buy a tart that looks
like she's been hit by a truck.
Ouch...
What's the matter?
It's gone now.
Just get me home.
- My keys...
- I'll get them.
Come on.
- Pffrrrr. Pffrrrr.
- Let's take the jacket off, come.
- Kiss...
- Lotte...
take off your jacket.
So.
- You want to kiss?
- No, you're somthing...
- You can kiss me.
- No, I can't do that.
- Hey, you can kiss me, come!
- No, thanks.
So.
- Come on. Come!
- Off with your jacket...
- Kiss...
- No! No.
- Come on...
- No.
Ah, no, no. Come, you need to
get some sleep. Go to bed.
- Yes, with you.
- No, not with me.
No... no, Lotte.
You need some sleep.
You would rather
have a school teacher...
who has her hair in a bun...
enjoys watering her plants and
has dinner, at 6 o'clock sharp.
Exactly.
Lie down.
And after that you hold hands...
and watch TV.
And now the blanket...
No, Lotte.
Please stay with me.
And kiss me.
No, Lotte.
No.
Good night.
Lotte, lie down. Come.
Stop.
Lie down.
go to sleep.
Get out
before I'll kick your ass.
- He wants two hours.
- Jesus!
I don't think so.
He's Swedish.
Room 555.
I'll call you.
Yes?
Hello, Nico.
Everything is okay.
Lilly?
- Hey?
- Yes?
My sister's inside and needs help.
Can you open the door for me.
- Please, don't shoot me.
- You're a goddamn cunt!
- Full of dirt.
-
- I hate the smell of cunt.
- I don't want to die.
Forgive me, forgive me,
forgive me. You're so lovely.
You're very beautiful.
Please don't shoot me.
Your skin is so soft.
I'm going to cut off your boobs
and feed them to the dogs.
No, no, I really didn't mean it.
No, no, I'm sorry.
I'm real tired and exhausted
I just can't sleep, right?
I'm so tired. I'm tired,
but I just can't sleep.
Yes, you can sleep now.
I love you.
Come on.
Okay.
That bastard is history.
Okay?
If you say so.
I'm okay.
I'll forget that sick fuck.
I'll forget him like that.
Two more hours.
Let's have coffee then.
Okay.
You did okay... up there.
You did okay, Soldier.
- I don't think so.
- Neither do I.
What is her name?
Blessing.
We called her Bess,
but for her it's Blessing.
- Who takes care of her?
- My mother.
When did you see her last?
Five years ago.
I have her picture.
Look.
My mother has no work,
my father is dead,
So I earn money.
I also have her
on a little videoklip.
Shew, fly, don't bother me,
'cause I belong to somebody.
I feel, I feel,
I feel like a morning star.
- What about her father?
- Ass-hole.
I do well. She has
good food and good clothes.
She can go to a good school
and become somebody.
- I'm a good mother.
- 5 years is a real long time.
- I want to save up the money.
- Yes. Fine.
We are lucky. If I were fat
and ugly, we all would starve.
When are you going home?
I must pay back Madam
the last 8 thousand euros.
I'll save up the money.
Then one day, I'll marry
a good man in Europe...
and get her here.
Nice life, nice place,
London maybe.
- I know what you think.
- You don't know what I think.
I do, I know.
But you're wrong.
It's possible.
Is it too much for you?
Should I get another driver?
What'd you mean?
What lousy customers, eh?
Shall I find another driver?
- I'm doing fine, don't you think?
- You're doing a fantastic job.
Daddy's tough warrior.
- We'll go out for a good dinner.
- I'm not hungry.
Something real nice.
Something differend.
Maybe Bananas.
Bananas.
Lotte...
23~24~48.
- What?
- The code.
You're my daughter.
The money it's yours.
I'm proud of you.
We have to send out the ships.
We must send... the ships...
Out...
We... must... Lilly...
Where's Lilly?
On her way.
What?
They say it's nothing serious.
Just my insulin again.
I'm always getting it wrong.
And there's the stress.
And too much booze.
And I forget to eat.
You just need a vacation.
You told me stuff...
Just a bunch of nonsense.
I don't remember a thing.
I just collapsed.
Thank you.
- You scared me, pappa.
- Don't worry, sweetheart.
Don't worry.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
Don't worry,
- Are you okay?
- I am okay.
- Come in with me.
- I'm tired.
- I don't want to be alone tonight.
- You are alone.
Not if you come with me.
Your "pappa"
might be home tomorrow.
Have you seen
how the other girls live?
He don't drink.
He don't beat me.
It's a good house.
- Maybe he will marry you someday.
- I am lucky...
I'm with the boss.
I only work in that town.
I have no rent
I get the good customers.
The other girls must take
this shit back then, wind up...
with burns from cigarettes
and get piece of shit.
I'm lucky.
- But you're alone.
- So are you!
My name is not Lilly.
My real name is Kimmie.
What is this?
I was shot.
Shot?
I made a mistake.
I...
I... I didn't...
I didn't
It's okay.
Shew, fly, don't bother me
shew, fly, don't bother me.
- Lilly.
- Shew, fly...
- Peekaboo!
- Are you alright?
- You're now full-time, huh?
- She was in a mess.
- She didn't want to be alone.
- No?
No.
- You can drive me to work, then.
- What about your head?
Blah, blah, blah. I've got two
artics to get off to Madrid today.
Oh, hello beautiful.
Come to pappa.
- You feeling betTer?
- Oh yeah, I'm king of the world.
Hello?
- We're leaving in 5 minutes.
- Yeah, okay.
- That noise is getting worse.
- We'll take it to the mechanic.
The sailor knows
That there are sweet girlish hearts.
Beating in every port.
As soon as he's there...
When a sailor...
When a real sailor
steps ashore.
- Sure you wouldn't like coffee?
- I'd rather not.
I need mine.
I could make tea?
You can have your money back.
Lilly? Lilly? Come on!
My nose!
Drink this.
- Where am I?
- In my place.
What happened?
I hit him
and gave him his money back.
You did what?
You hit Henning?
- I got you out.
- You hit a good customer?
Are you a fucking idiot?
- You hit Henning?
- He's a sick person.
Mind your own
fucking buisness.
- Let me help you.
- My money is for my daughter.
- Please, let me help you.
- You hit Henning!
Okay?
Easy for you.
You are so fucking spoiled!
My money for my daughter!
- Well, I...
- Fuck you, very, very much!
- Nice of you to drop by.
- I thought you'd like your car back.
Henning's been using my girls since
I started, and he always behaved.
Well...
- You slapped me?
- There's more where that came from.
And she's off to Sweden on Friday.
So you can beat it.
Sweden?
Beat it, I said.
- You're giving her to the Swedes?
- She wants to make money.
But you don't get that.
You're too damn spoiled.
- You cannot up there.
- I'm not talking to you.
These men are sick people.
I'll take a taxi.
I forgot my fucking insulin.
John will pick you up.
He isn't here.
He took a taxi home.
I don't know if he'll be back.
I'll go, then.
Yeah.
- See you, Fischer.
- Yeah.
Come in.
Call John.
Everything is fine here.
So...
How would you like me
to fuck you?
Put this on.
You want to fuck yourself?
- Your passport.
- What?
And money.
You're going home.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
There's a plane being charterd
by some buisness men...
and they're
going to London in 3 hours.
I've booked a seat for you.
From there you go to Lagos.
Fix your own life.
You have a daughter, and now
you have money. Go home.
I'm not going anywhere.
Do you want to fuck or what?
- You're going home.
- Fuck you!
I will call up the police.
I will tell them where you live
and what you're doing here...
and then... they will
send you home with no money.
I'll do it.
I know poor countries.
This is a lot of money
in a poor country.
I'll go home,
when I... want to.
You can pay your Madam.
Look...
You can even start
a new live, with this money.
You don't understand.
- You don't understand!
- Listen to me, listen!
I will call... the police.
Understand?
You fucking bitch!
You have a daughter, come on.
You have a daughter!
She's... she's in Lagos,
and I'm getting you out.
- No!
- I'm getting you out!
- Understand?
- No!
I'm getting you out!
- You fucking...
- I'm getting you out!
Don't do this.
You're free now.
Put this on.
Come on.
Are you going London?
- Yes we are.
- Are you with us?
- Yes, thank you.
- Do you need this?
We're going.
- This is shit.
- No.
- Say hello to yout daughter.
Hi, baby.
You've been into my piggy bank.
You said it was for me.
Come with me.
- You gave Lilly all the money?
- She's going home.
I doubt it.
They never go back to the pig sty.
They make too much here.
She's going home.
She'll get off in Rome.
Or London.
Or wherever.
And set herself up as a madam.
Now she can buy her own girls.
She's going home.
You still think you can
save the world, don't you?
I wouldn't know.
You need a lesson.
A beating
never did anyone any harm.
In that case
you'll have to give it to me.
I won't hit back,
don't be scared.
What do you reckon, John?
Don't you agree?
A dad gives his own beatings.
Give him the bat, John.
I won't hurt him.
Give him the bat, John!
Go on.
You can do it.
Go on!
Lotte?
Come on.
We'll take you home.
And say no more about it.
We're hard, you and me.
We're a tough breed.
My little soldier.
Baby?
Lotte?