- Let's go.
- Whoo!
Have a
good ride, guys.
I feel for you.
Water?
Come on, beauty queens.
Come on.
Amos.
A-M-O-S.
Jenkins.
J-E-N-K-I-N-S.
Do you have
a personal representative
present with you today?
No.
Now, Mr. Jenkins,
we'd like to thank you
for going on the record.
Your testimony,
as you can imagine,
is of the utmost
importance to us,
since you're the only
survivor of the accident.
So if you could just
begin by telling us,
best you can,
what happened that morning.
Do you remember
leaving home?
Well, it was, you know,
just like any other day.
I don't remember if we even
started working, you know,
before it happened.
Well, how did you
get to work?
My truck.
What was it like
outside that morning?
Was it raining,
or stormy?
Was it raining?
I don't remember.
Was there lightning?
I can't say.
Did your cap lamp work?
It was working
as far as I know.
But then it went out
like the rest of them did.
What are you
doing over there?
Get away from
that old mine!
You don't know
how deep those
things are.
Remember what
Dad said?
There are snakes
and chiggers in there,
you better watch out.
-Hey.
-Nice headphones.
Let me see that.
-This an MP3?
-Yeah.
-That's cool.
-Look, it's even got
a little camera on it.
-I gave you everything I got.
-Dude, we need
three more bucks.
I got like two bucks,
give me a beer.
What's in this wallet
of yours, huh?
-Hey, wait.
Come on.
Give it back.
-Let me see this.
You should have wads
of cash in here.
You hit the fucking jackpot.
What do you mean?
My dad said.
You're gonna be rich.
Hey, over here,
come on.
Dude, you better not...
- Whoa!
- Oh, shit!
Mr. Jenkins, can we have
a word on your recovery?
No, it's not okay,
it ain't okay.
Get back out of the way.
You all right?
Hey, kid, it is good
to see you again, buddy.
Hey, Carl,
nice to see you.
Wow, it's a miracle,
that's what it is.
Hey, folks, how about
a round of applause
for Amos Jenkins here, huh?
I heard that you was
having some problems
remembering stuff
in the interview there.
Yeah, you know,
things get a little blurry.
Don't let us down now.
There's lots of folks
counting on you.
Ten men got
crushed down there.
Yeah, I don't need
no reminding, Carl.
Why are you boys
interfering with
my lunch?
Basil, don't be a scab.
You've been a miner
your whole life.
Easy, Carl.
I ain't on
no side here.
Don't be underestimating
the position you're in.
Nobody's
underestimating anything.
That's the guy representing
the other families.
Hey, I'm just trying
to take care of everyone.
You're a victim, too,
you know.
Will you just let me
do the talking
with the union guys?
They're a bunch
of vultures.
Every time something
bad happens they just...
Circle the carcass.
I don't need you
meddling in my business.
Well, if I
ain't meddling,
everybody else is
gonna be meddling,
because everybody's gonna
be wanting a piece of you.
Hey, baby.
What did you
do all day?
You still
playing those games?
How many damn gunshots
do I gotta listen to?
Hey, sweetheart!
-Hi.
Let me see all
these new games,
you spoiled brat.
Quit messing with
my shit, Aunt Nellie.
Mom!
Give me a kiss.
Thank you.
You should buy
something nice
for yourself.
They don't need
more stupid toys.
Well, buying them
new video games ain't
gonna bring Junior back.
Amos is back,
you know.
I don't know.
It's probably gonna
weird me out.
He looked good,
better than everyone said.
You already break that?
No, I'll fix it.
It fell on the ground.
Are we rich now?
You see all those
bills on the table?
Why are you asking that?
Well, because of Dad.
Are we richer now?
Well, sure. I mean,
there's a little extra money
that they gave everyone.
I mean, that's why
you got us this thing
and the Xbox?
Why? Did someone
say something to you?
No. They were just all like,
"Oh, that's new."
Just ignore it,
there are so many
trashy kids in this town.
How long you gotta leave
that crap in your hair?
This crap? You want some of
this crap in your hair, huh?
-No.
-Come on,
get out of here.
Go put your
brother to bed.
-Okay.
For what we are
about to receive,
let us truly
be grateful. Amen.
Amen.
How's that
right arm?
Oh, it's all right.
Left side's
perfect, though.
I think I can start
driving on my own now.
I ain't stopping you.
I was thinking
I'd call that lawyer,
that the union
folks suggested.
These lawyers,
they'll trip you up,
if you don't watch them.
Make you say
all sorts of stuff.
They ain't gonna
put words in my mouth.
Are you so sure?
And then what?
You gonna be
the big shot
that closes down
the Bonford Coal Company?
We lost men in there.
I'd keep to myself,
if I was you.
Just keep telling them
you don't remember.
Try to get back to work,
back to being productive.
How many notebooks
do you think you need?
Five.
And you need pens
and stuff too, probably?
Yes?
-Yeah, that's fine.
Where's Dad?
Dad? He's in Pittsburgh.
Doing what?
He left Wednesday.
The coal convention.
Is that me?
Stupid car.
Fuck.
-Oh, my God.
Shit. Who the
hell did that?
Okay. Come on,
let's get back inside.
Come on, come on, come on.
It's just some punk.
Are they mad at Dad?
What?
Because of the mine?
or that was just some
dumb prank, or what.
Yeah, well,
online, people
are mad at him.
Please stop
reading that stuff.
I don't understand
the half of it.
Now I gotta
get that fucking
thing replaced.
It's fine.
Hey,
Mom will be back at nine.
She went to
the union meeting.
I'm going out for
a little bit, all right?
I wanna go.
No, you stay here.
Keep your butt on that
couch, and watch your TV.
Don't move.
Why are you following me?
Go on back,
I'll be home soon.
Go back,
before I smack you.
Go home.
- Light it.
- There's one left.
No. No.
Like, swing it.
Whoa!
No.
That's some nice
stuff right there.
What's that?
Fireworks.
Stay there.
Hey, guys.
Nice.
Good going, dude.
Give me one of those, man.
You ever heard
of a six-pack before?
Man, that smells.
These smoke
balls are lames.
Shit, there ain't nothing
to do in this fucking town.
Get out of this
fucking shithole,
take the first damn bus.
I bet you've
never been on a bus.
No, he only rides
in fancy cars.
-Shut up, Kenny.
Next dig, come on!
Does your brother
know to like do shit,
like read and write?
He can read a little.
Do you think he's gonna
be able like fuck girls,
and get a driver's license?
That would suck
if he has to live
with your mom forever.
JT, you might never
get your driver's license.
Hey, it's almost 7:00.
Katie said we could
all come over, so...
Oh, I want to see her.
-Yup.
Let's go.
Dude, I just got here.
Come on.
Oh, yeah, we'll
miss you, man.
-Aww.
Group hug!
Oh, my God!
You guys like
to act like faggots?
Ooh, girlfriend,
you got a saucy
mouth on you!
Come on, come on.
Wait up!
-Dude, you better not.
Come on.
Come on, James.
Let's go home.
Why you walking funny?
You gotta pee?
I think so.
You can't hold it?
Come on, this way.
Hurry up.
Come on.
Go back here
to this tree.
Go pee.
You and your retard
brother are still here?
You're an asshole.
Why don't you speak up?
I didn't hear you.
I hope your dad
goes to jail
for killing 10 miners.
What'd you say?
Hope he rots in there
for what he did.
My dad had nothing
to do with that.
You're fucking trailer trash,
and you people
are fucking milking it.
Hey!
I'm gonna beat
your fuckin' head in!
Oh!
JT?
James?
Don't watch.
What are you doing?
Stay there.
Don't move.
If you tell anybody,
I'm gonna be mad, okay?
-Okay.
-Okay, come on.
Come on.
Come on,
we gotta go, come on.
James, come on,
we gotta go.
Come on.
Hello.
Hey, Sandy, hi,
I'm trying
to track down JT.
Were they all
going to Katie's?
Isn't he home yet?
Yeah, he's...
He's not.
-No?
No, I called his phone
a million times.
Oh, no.
Yeah.
I'm sure it's nothing.
All right.
Yeah, I will.
I'll let you know.
All right. Bye.
Hi, this is Bill,
please leave a message.
Bill, please call me
when you get this.
Go on and brush your teeth,
James, it's 9:00.
What's wrong?
I want dessert.
You can have an
ice cream sandwich,
and that's it.
and get ready for bed,
all right, buddy?
You want some?
No, I'm not hungry.
Here you go.
You guys gotta
get back to going to
bed at a decent hour.
It's gonna be a rude
awakening on Monday.
You better be good.
Now, we're gonna
need your okay to get
the word out to the community.
And we still have the phone
going to voice mail?
Yeah, he's not
picking up.
Now, Mrs. Doyle,
you answered a number
of questions last night,
but I'd like to fill
a few holes for myself,
so bear with me.
Does JT have
lots of friends?
Yeah, he's
a very social kid.
He's got lots
of activities,
football, baseball.
Baseball.
Mmm-hmm.
Would you say
he's a happy kid?
Yeah, I'd say so.
He was real
frazzled yesterday,
you know, someone
broke my windshield.
I'm sorry?
Yesterday morning,
somebody smashed up
my windshield.
Well, would anyone
be trying to hurt the family
for a work reason,
something in response
to the accident?
Well, I can't even
imagine that.
Do you have
a sense of the miners
that work for you?
Any of them
strange, violent,
resentful of you?
Have they expressed
any threats?
-No. No.
Excuse me.
She doesn't wanna
think that this could
involve foul play.
Can't it be that we're
just making a bigger
deal out of this,
that he's just
goofing off,
you know, with
a friend of his?
Was there any
joking around
in the woods,
like, being rowdy?
Just normal stuff.
Talking, laughing.
Anybody fighting?
No, just goofing around.
The other boys said
that you brought beer.
Yeah.
No, there was
some whiskey, too.
So after the guys
left, did you ever
see JT come back
down that main path?
No.
But the boys told me
that he went back to get
the bottle of whiskey.
So you must have
seen him, right?
I didn't see him.
I guess I was already gone.
Is there something
that you're
not telling me?
No, sir.
Everybody,
let's welcome Amos back.
Thank you very much.
We have a
little surprise for you.
No.
You should take
what's leftover.
-Oh!
-Yeah.
Thank you.
My dad might
appreciate it.
How you been doing
these past few months?
All right.
Things got pretty
ugly around here.
It's good
you missed it.
Yeah.
Well, if you ever
need anything,
or you wanna see
a movie sometime,
just let me know.
I can't do that anymore.
I can hardly move and stuff.
I didn't mean it
like that.
I guess I just
don't feel like my
old self yet, Nell.
Well, I guess it's
gonna take some time.
Nice seeing you, Amos.
So you're saying that
you never saw Bill Doyle
or any other individual
in management disable
a monitor?
Please answer
the question.
I say no.
I never saw nothing
regarding the monitor.
Okay.
Well, I'd like to ask
you now about the issue
of coal dust.
Do you remember
hearing about
an incident in which
Junior Briggs
had an argument
with Bill Doyle?
Junior warned him
he personally felt
uncomfortable going
in the mines
with that level of dust.
Can't say I remember that.
Now, do you remember
hearing a story in which
Bill Doyle then reprimanded
or threatened Junior
for warning other workers
about the coal dust?
My memory's bad
with this stuff.
Well, if we gave you
a little time,
do you think you could try
to recall any facts about
the alleged incident,
one way or the other?
Yeah.
Yeah, I could try,
but I can't guarantee it.
I wouldn't be too hard
on myself, if I was you.
I never could make a fuss.
I had a family to support.
All you got was
a bump on the head.
Don't be comparing us.
What is that?
I got that when you
was in the hospital.
It goes real good
with them cigarettes.
What's going on
out there?
Ah, they're looking
for that Doyle boy.
I'm gonna get me some air.
You don't have
to give speeches
and thank everybody.
The police can do that.
The police
have a job to do.
I just don't think you
need to play boss today.
Diana, I just don't
know what to do.
I feel like I'm
in a foreign country.
Who's that?
Amos?
Bill Doyle.
Bill.
Thank you so much
for coming out here.
It sure means
a lot to me.
Well, I'd like to help
you out any way I can.
Real sorry to hear
about this for you.
I bet you got journalists
and newspapers chasing
after you now, huh?
You're a real
hero here.
Well, I don't
know about that.
Well, anyways,
it's good to see you
on your two feet.
Slow and steady
with that cane
now, you hear?
Yes, sir.
Bill, I...
I was thinking.
If you need anything,
we run a Bible study
at the church
every Tuesday.
I don't count on God
for much these days,
if you know
what I mean.
Yeah, I get it.
I get that, boss.
-Well, you
take care now.
-Yes, sir.
Amos Jenkins
just invited me to
Bible study at church.
Oh, that's
who that is.
No developments
in the case of JT Doyle,
the Stinton teen who went
missing on the afternoon
of August 27th.
A month-long police search
has failed to find any trace
of the 15-year old,
and investigators
are still not saying
if they have
a person of interest
at this time.
His parents Bill
and Diana Doyle have made
an emotional plea
to the community.
If you have
any information,
please contact
Crime Stoppers.
Amos Jenkins,
how you doing, pal?
Hey.
Part-time.
How's it going, man?
-How you doing?
-Listen, I'm gonna
take off.
-Okay, be careful.
-All right.
-Good morning, Gus.
-How are you?
Well, do you got
enough bolting men
for the morning shift?
What do you mean?
I'd like to do
a little something, Gus.
I can't let you
go in the mine.
You have to be
re-certified,
re-trained.
Gus, I ain't looking
for a handout now.
I just... You can't
put me underground?
Can you use a computer?
Maybe I can put you
in the dispatcher's office,
or the hoist house,
or something.
I ain't the best, Gus,
but I'll learn it.
Well, thanks, y'all.
I'd say we got
a lot done today.
Bill, can you stick
around for a second?
Yeah. Sure thing.
As you probably know,
there's gonna be
an internal investigation.
we've already started
looking into timelines
and events and things.
And based
on these findings,
we really think
it's best for you to
seek your own counsel.
Sure. I understand.
And it's customary
that you'll be suspended
for the length
of the investigation.
This is... This is
a rough time for you,
Bill, we both know that.
but you're gonna have to be
gone by the end of the month.
And then we'll
see how it goes.
I'll see you out, John.
Take care, Bill.
You're a lucky stiff
with this swing set.
I know.
What happened in the woods,
that was an accident.
Yeah, accident.
Like dad, remember?
Yup. He didn't
come home.
That's right.
It happened by mistake.
Mom was upset.
She cried.
Yeah, you don't want her
to cry again, right?
You understand?
You better keep
your mouth shut.
Where's that boy?
Forget about that boy.
You promise
to be quiet?
Yes.
I won't give these
to you anymore
if you don't,
you understand?
-Yes.
-Good.
Good night, Georgie.
-Take it easy.
Why are you
home so late?
Sorry. I'm just
going through some
files from work.
I already had
a sandwich,
I'm good.
I've got three
meteorologists
on record
saying lightning
struck at 6:28
and 6:29 a.m.,
and apparently
they were
strong strikes.
Maybe everyone will
stop pointing fingers.
Bill, company counsel
is already talking
criminal negligence,
Just be careful
what you say to the other
employees, all right?
Yeah.
At least Jenkins
ain't talking.
And seems like
he's not joining
the class action.
-Yeah.
-That's good
news for you.
I could sure use
some good news.
Will you try
to take it easy?
I will.
This is Joel Kitts from
Wexler, Burnham and Kitts.
We're a firm
that specializes
in coal-related
personal injuries.
Carl Bishop may have given
you my card a while back
and I've called a few times.
I can't seem to reach you.
I'm representing
a number of families
in the class action suit
against Bonford Coal,
and I'm gonna be organizing
a closed-door meeting
with the victims' families
at Sherry's Diner
at 7:00 p.m.
on Monday night.
I would really
encourage you to join us.
Your involvement could
really help these folks.
My number is 555-7653.
This is a Bible study.
We're in session.
I know. I, uh...
I, uh...
Would you
like to have a seat?
Could someone please
make a space for her?
Welcome.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I'm sorry. So sorry.
We all welcome
you here tonight.
And we're all praying
for the safe return
of your son.
It must be
a difficult time.
Thank you.
We were discussing
this week's topic,
the importance of
sharing your weaknesses
with each other.
Let's continue
around the room.
Nellie,
we're at you, right?
Well, it's hard for me
to talk about my weaknesses,
since weakness
isn't really something
that we talk a lot
So... And we're always
just trying to put
on a happy face.
I'm trying to be strong
for my sister and
my nephews, especially.
You all know what I mean.
I've been praying
a lot to help me
in the past few months.
my baby sister lost
her son in the accident,
you know.
It's causing her
lots of depression...
Ma'am, you having
trouble breathing?
Are you okay?
You need some air?
It's fine.
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry.
It looks like you're
hyperventilating, sweetie.
Let me get a bag
for you to breathe into.
Oh, please,
please don't get up.
Would you like to go
to the fountain
and get some water?
It's in the hall.
-Yes, I will.
I will get some...
Please don't get up.
I'll get some water.
Amos.
-Oh, okay.
I'm sorry, um...
Well, I ain't sure
what to say.
It's been awful
rough to get out
of a coma, for sure.
You know, I thank God
I'm alive, I really do,
but I just want
to be normal again.
Everything back
the way it was.
I don't know what
to do when I wake up
every morning.
Lost 10 miners in there,
and I can't get them
out of my head.
It's rough on you to know
that you're the only one left.
You feeling
any better?
Not really.
I'm happy to
give you a ride,
if you need one.
I just need a minute.
That was nice
what you said.
It must feel good
to have a group
of people to talk to.
Yeah, well,
it's about the most
I've said in a year.
We never officially met.
You're Amos?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Diana.
-Nice to meet you, ma'am.
I'm really not in
a condition to drive.
I sure ain't
the best driver.
You can get me from
point A to point B,
can't you?
Yeah, I can do that.
I'm just up here,
on the right.
I know where
you live, ma'am.
It ain't a
big town, is it?
Got no leads?
No, they found a runaway
in Tennessee last week,
but it wasn't him.
What are all the folks
in town saying about it?
Everyone's really
upset, ma'am.
This is me.
Let me get you
to your door.
Oh, no. I'm good.
Oh, it sticks.
Your, uh... Your car
gonna be all right?
Yeah. I'll have one
of Bill's guys get it
for me in the morning.
All right.
-All right.
Thank you.
Good night.
You go down to
the police station
to see the new photos?
Yeah.
There's nothing.
And you heard
they brought in
some meth-head
for questioning,
and nothing came of it?
I guess he was clean.
Yeah, that's what
Peterson said.
Everything just
bounces off you
so easy, don't it?
Sorry?
It seems like
you're cheerful,
grilling your steaks.
Well, we can't expect
you to cook around here,
now can we?
We'd be eating
potato chips
and onion dip.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I have something else
on my mind.
I don't have the luxury
of sitting around the house
all day in mourning.
And I don't have
the luxury of drowning
myself in my work.
It must be a nice
distraction for you.
I'm just trying to
actively do things,
Diana.
Don't you think
it pains me to
watch you unravel?
We don't know
anything yet.
It's like you've
fucking given up.
I have not.
Pills, cigarettes.
It's hard to watch you.
You should get
your shit together.
Mrs. Doyle?
I didn't mean
to startle you.
No. It's, uh...
It's okay.
What are you
doing out here?
New pack.
I wouldn't be out here
too long if I was you.
All kinds of weirdos
out at this hour.
God, not much
fazes me anymore.
I drive around
a lot late at night.
I'm just...
I think maybe
I'm gonna
spot him somewhere.
It's crazy.
It's so crazy.
No, it ain't crazy.
What are you
doing out here?
It's so late.
I can't sleep.
I had to get
some medicine.
Oh...
Can I do this?
I'm sorry.
Please, don't say
you're sorry.
What are you
giving away?
Free yard work.
I can work any Saturday
you want this month.
Oh. Well,
that sounds good.
My yard's a mess.
What's your name, ma'am?
Diana Doyle.
I have to put it
on the ticket.
Good luck.
I've never been
in a motel before.
We used to come
to a place like this
in high school.
The seniors would
rent the rooms,
and we'd all file in
with six-packs.
You okay?
Yeah.
They're gonna
find him, ma'am.
Don't call me "ma'am."
You going in?
Oh, no.
I just swung by.
Why are you
working there?
Because I like
to work, Carl.
Coal is all I know.
Makes you look like
there's something
wrong with you.
You want those
people to think
you're on their side?
This thing is big.
Don't you get that?
Dumb son-of-a-bitch.
You like watching
from the sidelines?
I wonder what Junior
and the rest of them
would be saying
if they could
see you now.
Why don't you go
fuck yourself,
how 'bout that?
Seems like you're feeling
like your old self again.
People been saying
some interesting things.
One of my workers
said they saw you at
Bible study on Tuesday.
Yeah. Yeah,
I've been twice.
I guess that's good
if it helps, huh?
It gets me
out of the house.
This Bible study thing,
it's what Amos Jenkins
invited me to?
Yeah, that's the one.
You do realize that
he's the guy the Feds
are talking to, right?
If people in town see you
talking to mining folks,
it could be weird,
don't you think?
What do I care
what people think?
You might wanna
connect the dots, Diana.
It just looks shitty.
Bunny and Sandy
say they never see
you anymore.
They say...
Bunny and Sandy...
They say you're
avoiding their calls.
Jesus. I can't...
I can't deal
with their pitying...
They're not
pitying you.
It's not pity, Diana.
They're just
checking in on you.
-Oh, it's pity.
-They're just being nice.
Speaking of Sandy,
I heard you
hired a lawyer.
Greenbaum?
He's a lawyer the
company recommended.
Yeah. Why is it
you need your own
lawyer anyway?
Jerry doesn't
have a lawyer.
Company's not vouching
for you anymore?
It's worse
than I thought.
I ended up being
more exposed
than I thought.
More exposed?
What does that mean?
It's not my
fault, Diana.
I just did
what they told me
they wanted me to do,
and in the process,
I made a shitload
of money for everybody.
You were right
to spare me
the details,
because they
make me sick.
And you don't care
that I could be
the fall-guy here?
Well, I guess
we both know
it wasn't
a lightning strike
now, don't we?
Hey, you say what you will,
but you like your things.
Your car, this remodel,
all your clothes.
So don't you go
acting all high
and mighty!
My wife's putting you
to work now, huh?
Yeah, she won
the raffle.
Yeah, I heard.
Bill.
-Owen.
Owen. Owen what?
Owen Briggs.
Owen Briggs,
you're in high school,
right? In JT's school?
Yeah.
You're Junior's son?
Yeah, you look like him.
How's your mom doing?
-She's fine.
What I'd like to do
is get rid of all
this beach furniture,
and the patio stuff,
just get it all
moved out back.
Just generally get
this corner cleaned out.
You like to ride?
Yeah.
You have a bike?
No, ma'am.
I did, but it's
small now, I guess.
Hey, Bill.
Bill, can you dig
out this old bike?
Which one?
The old blue one.
JT got this
new one anyhow.
It's just
collecting dust.
Will you make sure
it's still in good shape?
All right. Good.
I'll see you
on Saturday, then.
How do those
wheels feel?
They're good.
-Yeah, they're all right.
All right, well...
You sure it's okay?
-Yeah, it's okay.
Be safe.
Hey!
How did you
get in here?
I jumped the bank.
You shouldn't be
snooping around in here,
it's dangerous.
You're walking.
-Yeah, I'm getting there.
Are you taking care
of your mama?
Yeah, I am.
Well, can you
tell me what is it
that you want?
Nothing.
I was just
looking around.
Did you
find anything?
No.
You think you can
take me in the mine?
You can't be
going down
in here too far.
Is this
the Number 3?
No, of course not.
It's been closed down.
Sealed up.
You miss your pop?
Yeah.
Sometimes I think
James forgets about him.
No. He don't forget.
He's a sly one,
your brother,
he's a whole lot smarter
than you think he is.
All right,
turn on that light.
Them beams
hold up the roof,
and the face is
all the way down
about a mile in.
Does this look
like Number 3?
Oh, that's
a whole lot bigger.
Did you see
my dad die?
Were you near him?
Yeah. I was near him.
We was all taking care
of each other.
Helping each other
with the self-rescuers.
Y'all couldn't
breathe, right?
We was having a hard time.
How come you survived,
and nobody else did?
Did you do
something different?
I had luck, I guess.
It was a waste to save me,
if you think about it.
I ain't got
no family, no kids.
You got your dad.
That's true.
What do you think
it's like to die?
Son, there was
no one in pain in there.
You understand me?
Come on, now.
They'll give me
an ass whooping if
they find you down here.
Go on, get that
door open for me.
Which button?
That one right there.
You can't use
that bar of soap
in your hair.
I use soap.
I'm a one-stop shop, baby.
I don't use
that stuff.
No.
Come here.
I'm gonna take
care of you.
I don't want
the pink stuff.
I don't... Don't put
that in my hair.
I don't want it.
I use soap.
Come here.
-No. No,
I don't want that...
Come here.
Don't say "no" to me.
I'll say "no."
-Don't say "no" to me.
Oh, God.
I got soap in my eyes.
Oh, get in.
Ah!
Get it out.
-It's okay, now.
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
-I got it, baby.
Come on, Owen.
Owen, stop!
That was
such a pathetic...
Wait for me.
Nobody goes
in there anymore.
If you're scared,
we don't have
to go any further.
Did he
do it again?
-Yeah.
That's the third
time this week.
He's a bundle
of nerves lately.
What's wrong with him?
Did he say anything to you?
No.
Maybe if you'd
stop babying him.
You guys don't tell
anybody what's going
on in your heads.
That's what I think.
You just keep it all in.
Please.
You got work this
morning, don't you?
Yeah.
Don't linger
at that place, okay?
Just in and out.
Okay. I won't.
How do you want
these folded?
Oh, honey, I don't
think the Salvation Army
is gonna care.
You're not gonna throw out
any of JT's stuff, right?
No, just, uh...
This is all old,
junkie stuff.
I'm keeping all the
special sentimental things.
I can't even think
to touch his room.
I wouldn't want
to move a pencil.
Oh, my God.
I got this the year
I was married.
Yeah, it looks old.
It's crazy what
you hold on to
for no good reason.
Have you ever been
in a coal mine?
Uh, not really.
I went on a field trip
in grade school, and that
was enough for me.
I was real claustrophobic
down there.
I went down in one
the other day.
It was a rookie mine.
My dad died
in Number 3.
I just wanted to see
what it looked like
where he died.
Actually, we kept
three of my dad's shirts.
We each picked one out.
Me, my mom, and James.
We wear them sometimes.
Oh, who's that now?
Hang on,
I'll be right back.
We never talk about
your son now, do we?
I don't want
to burden you.
But you can,
though, babe.
It's just...
Something I don't
wanna talk about.
I think about it every
second of every day
when I'm at home.
So this is your
vacation then, huh?
Yeah.
Mmm.
Hey, Amos!
Shit.
Why can't you
lift your arm up?
See how the
table's turned?
Just a couple months ago,
I was doing this for you.
Yeah. Ain't we the pair.
You need you
some medicine now.
That cough ain't gonna
go away on its own.
You want that oxygen?
I'll get it later.
Don't worry about it.
You want me to
turn that light off?
Yeah. Turn it
off for me.
Make it a double, Patty.
Here you go,
and this one's
on Bill Doyle.
On Bill Doyle, huh?
-Yup. On Bill.
What's up, Amos?
-Hey, boys.
How's it going, buddy?
What's going on, Amos?
Let's buy you a drink.
Hey, Patty,
get a round for the bar.
Yeah, get us a round.
Give Amos
a double here.
Yeah. Get him drunk.
We're waiting
to hear what
you're gonna say.
You ain't gonna put us
out of work, are you?
You know we're
a dying breed.
Yeah. We're a dying
breed, is right.
I might as well be
in the dirt with
the rest of them.
You wanna...
You wanna take care of us?
Yeah. I'll take
care of you, Jerry.
Are you sure
you're not gonna
fuck us over?
Yeah. If they find
something wrong,
they're gonna shut
us down completely.
You like getting food on
the table, don't you, Jerry?
Yes, sir.
- We need to work.
- We gotta work.
Have one
with all of us.
Come on, cheers!
Cheers.
- To Bonford Coal, man.
- To Bonford Coal.
You enjoying
your freshman year?
Yeah, sort of.
It's been
a weird year.
I'm sure.
Make any good friends?
Yeah, I guess.
I'm not very popular,
but I have
a few good friends.
Well, that's really
all you need.
I think people that
have a lot of friends
are usually not
that interesting.
Were you popular?
You seem like you were.
I do?
so that always
brought me a certain
amount of attention.
What was he like
that Friday?
Who?
JT.
I know you were
in the woods with him.
With all them boys.
He was joking around.
He was having a good time
with those fireworks.
He was having fun?
Yeah.
You guys were
all laughing,
having a good time?
Yeah.
Was he happy?
Do you remember?
Yeah.
That's good.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Owen...
I shouldn't have
asked you about that.
That's... It's not fair,
it's just upsetting.
You wanna use
the restroom?
You're testifying again?
Yeah.
Last time, I hope.
I hate it.
When is that gonna be?
I don't know.
In two weeks.
What are you gonna say?
Well, my dad don't
want me to say nothing...
Nothing that would
incriminate the company.
What do you want to do?
What do you mean?
I mean, you always just
do whatever he says?
No.
If you know what happened
in that mine, you should
say something, Amos.
I don't wanna mess up
your life more than it's
already been messed up,
to tell you the truth.
You should worry
about yourself.
I mean, ain't your
life messed up?
They made you
a goddamn cripple.
I ain't no
goddamn cripple.
You're keeping
quiet, and you're
working there now?
What do you care
if I work there
or not?
What's it to you?
-You shouldn't
do it for me.
Why can't I
be nice to you?
-No...
You're hung up on this
whole goddamn thing.
Way too hung up.
I mean, what am
I supposed to be to you?
Your girlfriend?
No, you ain't
my girlfriend.
That would be beneath you.
I have a family.
-I ain't good enough
for you, am I?
Do you?
Oh, Diana. I'm...
-That is cruel.
Diana, come on.
This place is
like a dungeon!
These curtains
are disgusting.
You want me to fry
a bit of ham for you?
Cook it up with
that string bean?
I said, "Do you want me
to fry up that ham?"
What's the matter?
I know you didn't
say anything.
You've been good.
Uh, yes.
Can I talks
to Joel Kitts?
Mmm-hmm.
Yes, it's
Amos Jenkins.
Don't I get a hello?
Hi.
Are you hungry?
-No, I got cereal.
You're good at cleaning
other people's houses,
but not your own?
I saw your employer
at the hair salon.
I gotta say my heart
goes out to that woman.
Not knowing
is gotta be awful.
You think Bill Doyle's
gonna get in trouble?
Don't he deserve trouble?
Not if lightning
struck the mine.
They're not as bad
as everybody says.
Who? The Doyles?
-Yeah.
Why? 'Cause they
gave you a bike?
What about all the things
I've given you?
Your father gave you?
What's up your ass?
Excuse me?
Don't you talk
to me like that.
Where's your
fucking head at?
Even when you're here,
you're not here.
I can't do
everything on my own.
This is stupid!
Where are you going?
Well, look who it is.
What do you say,
you want you a milkshake?
Yeah.
Get him...
What do you want?
I want chocolate.
Sure thing, sweetie.
You're awful quiet.
Hey, are you okay?
Hey, Owen.
I didn't know you
were coming today.
Was the coal dust
level something that was
a concern before
the accident?
Yes, sir.
Who voiced
this concern?
Well, we all did.
But it was Junior
who made a fuss mostly.
He came to me a few days
before the accident.
he was gonna request
a transfer to another mine.
He felt like something
bad was gonna happen.
did Junior ever
confront Bill Doyle about
these safety concerns?
Yes, sir.
Junior said Bill told him
that he better keep
his mouth shut if he knew
what was good for him.
What do you think
Bill meant by that?
I reckon he meant,
"Don't start talking
about it being dangerous."
Like, "Don't say nothing
to the other workers to
get them upset."
Would you say, in general,
that there was a tradition
of silence in the workplace?
Well, with Junior
we could usually find a way
to get things fixed
without hurting production
too much.
But if, or when,
you complained to
higher management,
would you be afraid of
any sort of retaliation?
Yes, sir.
I'd say that's just
about the way it is.
Do you remember
being rescued, Amos?
No. Not really.
I was too far gone, I guess.
You don't remember
the men finally reaching
you underground?
I just remember...
I remember being carried.
Carried up, and seeing
that light again.
Like the air
came back into me, like...
...Breathe easy again.