Whom did...
Joong Tae kill?
It was 25 years ago.
In your villa,
he killed my biological father.
That's right.
I'm Kim Soo Hyun.
Do you know how I feel now?
Just like Yoon Joong Tae tried to kill you,
I want to take care of you now.
Please.
Please don't kill me.
You kidnapped three people.
You kidnapped my biological father,
my father who raised me,
and Great Aunt who made me who I am now.
And you still want me to save your life?
Mr. Choi.
Go meet with him.
If Joong Tae killed your biological father,
he will be of help.
You still believe Choi Tae
Seok is on your side.
Think how your map reached
Yoon Joong Tae's hands.
Was it...
Tae Seok?
Correct.
They're on the same side.
I guess you've already
met with Choi Tae Seok.
That means Joong Tae knows
that you're all right.
He'll try to murder you again then.
All I need is to sit back and
wait to get both of you.
You'll be killed by your son-in-law,
and I'll arrest him for murder.
How efficient.
Please...
Please save my life.
(Episode 32)
I have a question.
It was you who kidnapped
my biological father.
Then why did Yoon Joong Tae kill him?
Why did he kill him when you took the map?
I have no idea.
I don't know why,
but Joong Tae...
got in my way...
when I was looking for the map.
I think Joong Tae's grandfather was...
the one who betrayed the Heroic Corps.
He betrayed them?
Some of the lost treasure...
was found in his house.
Please help me.
Joong Tae is our mutual enemy.
I can trust neither the police...
nor the prosecution.
As you said,
if Joong Tae finds out that I'm conscious,
he'll come to kill me.
I will do...
everything you say.
Please help me.
Dad.
Why are you out here?
They're replacing his urine bag.
What about you?
Well...
I came to see your grandfather
when people aren't around him.
They all don't want me to be here.
By the way, his condition
is a little weird.
He regained his consciousness
the other day.
He said something to me.
What did he say?
The doctor said his mind can come and go.
Why are you telling me this now?
Mom told me not to tell you.
Did something happen between
you and Grandfather?
Wait.
Why are you wearing a mask?
Take it off.
This is for hygiene.
Anything wrong with it?
Nothing. You can leave.
Dad, what happened?
I'm very sensitive about his safety.
Father, how are you feeling?
Hwa Young told me that
you are able to speak.
Please say something.
Grandfather.
You recovered your senses the other day.
Do you recognize me?
I don't.
Who are you?
Thank you.
That's okay.
You paid my kid's medical bill before.
You don't have to do this.
Still, it could be dangerous.
I know you wouldn't do anything bad.
Please let me know if you need me again.
You don't answer my phone calls.
Where are you?
This is the file you asked me.
I think...
Joong Tae's grandfather was...
the one who betrayed the Heroic Corps.
Before she died,
she said Yoon Jae Hong is a traitor.
She also left the word "betrayal"...
in that secret room.
"Betrayal"?
- Maybe a traitor.
- Shut it.
There was a traitor?
I think Joong Tae's grandfather was...
the one who betrayed the Heroic Corps.
The one who concealed his identity
to protect his children...
said this before he died.
There was...
a traitor within them,
and he buried the evidence
that proves his betrayal...
with the treasure.
I think I know why you want
the map so desperately.
You're not interested in the treasure.
You just don't...
want the truth about your
grandfather to be exposed.
- Shut it.
- Did you think...
you could hide it forever?
All the historical truth
are revealed in the end.
You made a mistake.
Since you kidnapped my kid,
I'll find out who you
really are by any means.
I told you to shut it.
You're here.
Sit down.
- Let me fill your glass.
- Thank you.
Did something happen?
I have a favor to ask you.
I am worried about Chairman Hong's will...
which will be revealed after his death.
I'm sure most of his property...
will be inherited to Mi Ae and Yoon Ho.
We can't let such people
run a major company.
It's also a national tragedy.
In regard to that,
I'm investigating the owners of
Yoon Ho's borrowed-name accounts.
That's not enough.
If the old man's shares go to Mi Ae,
from that point on,
the game won't be fair anymore.
Then what do you want me to do?
The documents about Chairman Hong's
attorney and witness for his will.
I'm telling you I want to
change Chairman Hong's will.
Chief Prosecutor.
But that's a felony.
His life has been a series of felonies.
It's a bigger crime...
if those with silver spoons in
their mouth who are incompetent...
inherit the company.
I want to turn Cheonmun Group
into a social enterprise.
I want to remove the rich
from running the company.
After I make an environment
where everyone is pleased with,
I plan to leave my post without
any lingering feeling.
Why?
Because my dream lies somewhere else.
Joon Hee,
I want to trust you.
You've already set your foot in the mud.
We ought to stay together.
We ought to make the lotus bloom together.
Where have you been?
You said you wanted to go on a date.
I'm sorry. I forgot.
I was waiting at your office
and left the files there.
I know. I saw.
- Did you wait long?
- Yes.
Did I scare you just then?
I was just kidding.
But why? What is it?
The truth is...
I retrieved my last memory.
When the three maps are put together,
I can find the national treasures
the Heroic Corps had stolen,
but something more important
is with the treasures.
What is that?
The evidence that Yoon Jae Hong
betrayed the Heroic Corps.
To hide that evidence,
Yoon Joong Tae killed my biological dad.
You mean Chief Prosecutor Yoon Joong Tae?
Yes. I clearly remember...
the last moment of my dad.
Then...
is it possible my dad...
It's either Yoon Joong Tae...
or his henchman.
Sir.
What were you talking about the other day?
Did Chief Prosecutor Yoon really try to...
How dare you!
Are you here to kill me?
Did Yoon Joong Tae put you up to this?
- Sir.
- You little...
How dare you plot with him...
and steal the maps from me?
You scumbag. Do you think
I'll let you off easy?
Calm down. That's not true.
I didn't know Chief Prosecutor
Yoon stole the maps from you.
Stop lying, you piece of trash.
You were the one...
who stole the maps from
me in the first place.
I trusted you.
Wait until I'm completely recovered.
I'm going to finish you first.
You little...
Grandfather. What is wrong?
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I'm Mr. Choi.
I used to work for him back in the days.
I take that he hasn't recovered yet.
Grandfather. Do you really know him?
You're home.
I was worried that you wouldn't come home.
Let's spend some time together.
Just the two of us.
Please?
Let's go in.
How does it look? Doesn't it look nice?
Here you go.
Honey, I'm sorry that I doubted you.
Because of Dad,
I must have had a lot on my mind.
Do you still...
believe that I tried to kill your dad?
It's a known fact that Dad is not himself.
But if something like that happens,
it'd be weird if I weren't flustered.
Or it could mean that you
didn't trust me enough.
From what you did to me,
you just proved yourself how
lowly you thought of me.
You know how much I love you.
I...
married you when I was 24 years old.
It's been 30 years already.
It means the time I spent with you...
is longer than the time
I spent with my dad.
Let's not...
think about Dad anymore.
We should live our own life. Please?
I should buy another bracelet.
It doesn't look good on you.
What are you talking about?
He's gone missing after he fell
into gambling debts in Macao?
Find him even if the thugs
were involved in this.
Right now, he's the only hope I have.
Soo Hyun must be alive.
If I can find him, then
I can find my son too.
I can't give up this time.
Never. I won't ever give up this time.
How are you going to find the map?
If this is about a revenge
for your biological dad,
the only way is to take down Yoon
Joong Tae after finding the map.
That's what he's dreading the most now.
Dol Mok.
When I found out Mr.
Jang and Master Kwon...
broke into Chairman Hong's secret office,
I was really shocked.
Anyway, you can't take that approach.
I'm sure we can find a legal
way to deal with this.
Let's find that way together.
Okay.
You must be tired. You
have to work tomorrow.
- Let's go in and rest.
- Okay.
Tell me if you want to cry...
or if you're hurting.
I can't imagine how shocked
you must be for witnessing...
your dad getting murdered.
When you thought about that again,
I'm sure it got harder for you.
I'm right behind you.
Don't turn your back on me
pretending you're okay.
Okay?
I heard no one can be
completely free of crimes.
I mean, you are the corporate
lawyers for Cheonmun Group.
It'd be odd if you were so innocent.
What is it that you want?
I need you to revise the will.
I want the primary inheritor...
to be Chief Prosecutor Yoon.
That's not revising. That's fabricating.
You are an officer of the law.
Did Chief Prosecutor Yoon
instruct you to do this?
Attorney Kim, let's go.
Your son in the US.
What do you plan to do with him?
Drugging and raping a
girl isn't a small crime.
Since you covered it up, it
will be a bigger problem.
If the chairman finds out that we
fabricated his will, we are done.
Don't worry.
Isn't he suffering from dementia?
Hong Il Gwon's era is a bygone era now.
Join the new wave.
- It's so hot.
- I'm sweating so much.
This way.
- It's so hot.
- Oh, hello.
Good morning everyone.
What are you doing here?
What are you doing in my house
from early in the morning?
He's renting the annex from today.
Isn't it already so crowded with us?
The house feels lonely, and it costs a lot.
Should I charge you more?
It's good to have more people.
No house is better than a crowded house.
The problem is that he stinks.
Jong Beom likes to save water.
That's even better.
Shower won't change him.
I'm a bit disappointed.
You were against us moving in here.
Right.
She tried to kick me out.
When did I do that?
Then let's vote to be fair.
Hold on.
Before we vote, I'll have a pre-activity.
Take this first.
- What is this?
- What is it?
- Take one.
- Here, Yeo Wool.
If you accept me,
I promise you...
to give one free chicken every month.
- I agree.
Then I agree.
You're all capitalists.
It's not even spring, but
the spring breeze...
is making me sad.
You must be happy.
They must be.
They're just happy to see each other.
Well...
I think there's a misunderstanding.
We didn't do anything.
What do you mean nothing? I
saw it with my own eyes.
We're all old enough. You
don't need to hide it.
I said no. What's wrong with you all?
Gosh.
Hey, Mr. Oh. I'll kick you out...
if you don't stop.
My goodness.
There's nothing wrong with being in love.
There's no need to be upset.
They scared me.
Why would you get upset?
Mom. Can't you see it?
They're flirting.
What? Really?
What is it? What's going on?
Stop it.
Master Kwon and Mr. Jang
look great together.
- You think so?
- Yes.
What do you mean?
You were tricked by a handsome man before.
You should know better by now.
Mr. Jang is tall,
but he's not handsome.
But when I look at Uncle Dol Mok,
he must've been handsome when he was young.
Tell me about it, Yeo Wool.
- Mom.
- Hey, stop it now.
It's up to her. You're
going over the limit.
What's wrong with you?
It's a misunderstanding.
I've never said I like him.
- No way.
- Don't try to hide it.
I'm against it.
You're so tender hearted
that it's obvious...
- you'll pour your heart out.
- Hey...
You'll end up getting hurt.
I'll never accept it...
until Mr. Jang begs me.
Do you get it?
Hey.
You have a great daughter, Master Kwon.
Do you want me to work on her, Master?
I told you there's nothing.
My gosh.
- Just say it.
- Stop it.
I didn't know Dad was such a ladies' man.
When did you make Master
fall in love with you?
You never know...
if he only caught her heart
or what comes after.
What are you talking about?
It was only an accident.
Father. You know I respected
you for a long time, right?
I'd appreciate if you could tell
me how to cause that accident.
- Gosh. You asked for it.
- That hurts.
Master Kwon was only giving me...
an acupuncture treatment.
He misunderstood it.
Dad. As you know,
Master never do anything for free.
She only cares about her profit.
She's seriously not my type.
Listen to what he's saying.
Don't be so picky. You're old now.
You just blend in.
I think you two are meant to be.
- That's what I mean.
- Dol Mok.
I'm really scared of Master Kwon.
She even protects you at night.
There's nothing to be scared of.
- That's right.
- Be quiet. Leave.
- Out. Go out.
- What's wrong with you?
- Father...
- Out.
- Try kissing her.
- I said out.
Our medical appliances...
will take care of your health...
in this 21st-century aging society.
I'll never forget to develop
a new technology...
for the aging society, and
be the leader who puts...
the customer service before anything else.
(Jamun Medical Appliances Conference)
Come here.
What do you think?
This is too much for me.
I doubted you and slapped you.
I feel so ashamed.
Come here.
Have a seat.
Take this as my apology.
Okay.
Great. Then sign here.
I'm buying this for you.
So many people want to open a store,
but I'm letting you open up the first one.
Mom. It's an emergency.
Aunt Mi Ae just notified she'll
have a major shareholders' meeting.
What?
You look so powerful, Mom.
Finally,
everything is in its place.
I'm the direct lineage of my mom.
Are you really going to
take over the whole thing?
Yoon Ho.
Listen.
This one hunter...
captured an eagle and kept it in a cage...
with a chicken and a duck
feeding chicken feed.
But five years later, the eagle...
didn’t fly with its 3m wings.
You know why?
Because it doesn't...
need to hunt.
You're so smart, Yoon Ho.
The eagle was satisfied
with the chicken feed...
that it refused to fly.
It has the spirit of chicken...
instead of the eagle's.
What's wrong? You're scaring me.
I won't let you eat chicken feed anymore.
So you better...
stop showing interest in chicken feed.
Get it?
Sure.
Do you have a borrowed-name account for...
Vice-President Lee Yoon Ho?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I have all the data.
This Singapore account is in your name.
Were you aware when you received
this vitamin drink box?
Taking Hong Mi Ae's money
isn't just a simple bribery.
What did she ask you in return?
I'm sorry, but how would I
know when Chairwoman Hong...
gave it to me first?
If you continue to do this, I'll
look into all the bribes...
you received for the last 10 years.
I don't know what you mean by that.
Is this how you're going to play it? Fine.
I have all the evidence.
Hey.
What are you investigating?
What do you mean?
Look at you playing innocent.
Han Joon Hee is in the
interrogation room...
with Cheonmun Group committees.
You brought them, didn't you?
What?
We never heard of it.
You didn't know?
No. He didn't tell us anything.
What's he thinking?
After he had a meeting
with Chief Prosecutor,
he let Hong Mi Ae and Lee Yoon Ho free.
Why is he working on the
unnecessary ones now?
What did you say?
After Prosecutor Han had a
meeting with Chief Prosecutor,
he let Hong Mi Ae and Lee Yoon Ho free?
You don't need to know.
What was that?
Don't you think Prosecutor Han is fishy?
What do you mean?
I couldn't understand why he let...
Hong Mi Ae and Lee Yoon Ho free.
Usually, if someone gives
50,000 dollars and embezzle...
300,000 dollars of company
budget, they'd get imprisoned.
Do you think Prosecutor Han...
let them go after getting a
bribe from Chief Prosecutor?
You're thinking too much.
Have you forgotten who he is?
Nothing would make him change his mind...
even if it's Chief Prosecutor...
or it's from the Blue House.
I've been working with him for many years.
Why do you think...
he's investigating Cheonmun Group
committees without telling us?
He probably has his own reason.
Small birds like us will never
know what's on his mind.
Right. You're a small bird. I'm a crow.
Dad.
Dad, how are you today?
Mi Ae will hold...
a special general shareholders'
meeting tomorrow.
Even if you were in your right mind,
you'd be on Mi Ae's side.
- I'll go freshen up.
- Okay.
I finally got to see you, Hong Il Gwon.
If it weren't for you,
our family would've lived happily.
You ruined everything.
I won't let you die in peace like this.
As you all know,
(2017 Cheonmun Group Special
Shareholders' Meeting)
my father...
Chairman Hong is in hospital
for a chronic illness.
Considering his condition,
his recovery is doubtful.
If the position of chairman is
left vacant for a long time,
it will cause enormous trouble
in running the company.
So I called the meeting today.
- Is there any objection?
- I have an objection.
- What?
- It's true he is in hospital,
but the company is performing
well with the proxy system.
The chairman already announced...
he'd officially retire as
Chairman of the company...
due to the inheritance issue.
I don't think we have to elect...
a new chairperson now.
Hey, a puppet boss is not a real owner.
The owner should make decisions.
This is an official meeting.
Please stop being rude.
Let's decide by a show of hands.
Let's make it simple...
and get back to work. Okay?
All right then.
Except Chairman Hong, Hong Shin Ae and I...
have the first shareholding.
You're supposed to choose
between these two people.
You can cast a vote with your holding.
The one who gets the most votes...
will be the new chairperson.
I know this is planned out.
What's the point of taking a vote?
Because this is a democratic society.
Ms. Hong Shin Ae, if you have a problem,
you may bow out.
Please cast a vote using your smartphone.
Let's begin.
(The result of the poll)
I'll announce the result of the poll.
(Hong Mi Ae 5,267,500 shares,
Hong Shin Ae 5,593,200 shares)
- What?
- Gosh.
What's going on?
- What's that?
- Is something wrong?
What's happening?
Now I hereby announce
the new chairperson...
of Cheonmun Group...
is Hong Shin Ae.
Hey!
Darn it!
Gosh.
Here.
Thank you.
Prosecutor Han.
Jung Hye, come here.
Come toast with us.
- All right.
- Congratulations.
For Chairwoman of Cheonmun Group.
- For Chairwoman.
Let's have a seat.
This is nice.
It still hasn't hit me yet.
When I calculated the votes,
I was sure Mi Ae would win.
I know. What were the
dissident votes about?
That's because of Prosecutor
Han's under-the-table work.
He pried into Yoon Ho's
borrowed-name bank accounts...
and the executives' secrets.
Really?
Chief Prosecutor Yoon helped me a lot.
All I did was draw the
sword from its scabbard...
with the given data.
You look so amazing today.
Do you know that?
I know. Maybe I should give him
a piggy-back ride or something.
Should I feel threatened by him?
I'm not kidding. You are really amazing.
I thought you were just a taciturn man,
but he lets his actions speak for himself.
He's just like you, Dad.
You're praising both of us, right?
Stop it.
Let's make a toast again.
Jung Hye.
Dad.
I fell for her.
Shin Ae did it...
behind my back.
If you were with me, it
wouldn't have happened.
Why are you lying down here like that?
Stop it, Mom.
You should've left your
property to me sooner.
Why did you make me suffer
such a humiliation like this?
I'm so furious. I can't believe this.
Dad. Dad.
Please say something.
- Dad.
- Just stop it!
You can just live with the shares you have.
Why do you want to become
a chairwoman so bad?
What did you just say?
Don't rub salt in the wound.
The whole thing happened
because you're like this!
Why are you taking it out on me?
You should've got your head right.
If you did, the executives
wouldn't have cast the votes...
to the daughter of a
concubine instead of you.
- You jerk!
- Stop it!
It's no use crying over spilled milk.
I'm going.
Lee Yoon Ho!
What's wrong with the door?
Dad.
Gosh.
I'm so frustrated.
Did Prosecutor Han leave?
- Yes.
- I told you.
I really need him.
Make sure to be nice to him.
Still, he's not marriage material.
He's not attractive at all.
You said he was amazing.
I was just being nice to him.
Is it that...
you have Jang Dol Mok in mind?
It's true Dol Mok is...
much more attractive than Prosecutor Han.
I've never seen a man who's
so attractive before.
- You can't marry him.
- Why not?
You just can't.
Don't even think about it.
He's too dangerous.
Right.
Do you know a guy called Mr. Choi?
- Mr. Choi?
- He came to the hospital yesterday.
He said he used to work for Grandfather.
I think Grandfather came
to himself at that moment.
What did he say?
I don't quite remember what I heard.
Grandfather sounded very angry though.
I think he talked about maps.
You fabricated his will?
Are you out of your mind?
It's a fraud by Additional
Punishment Law on Specific Crimes.
You even threatened the
executives of Cheonmun Group.
You'd be sentenced to at
least five years in prison.
- I know that.
- Then why did you do that?
Because I have to win Chief
Prosecutor Yoon's confidence.
So what's the result?
Hong Shin Ae got Cheonmun
Group in her hand,
but you're just her pawn.
Now that Yoon Joong Tae has your weakness,
you'll have to do as you're told.
I'm not the only one who's blindsided.
I also have something on him.
He's the one...
who instigated the whole thing.
Dol Mok, if I can't get a confession
about your father's death,
I'll jump off a cliff...
holding Chief Prosecutor Yoon in my arms.
The statute of limitations on
the case has expired already.
If we fail to find the maps...
or to reveal the historical truth,
it might be a better option.
What are you talking about?
Why would you do that?
This is about my biological father.
Because you're my brother.
If you fight, I'll fight with you.
I'll sacrifice myself rather
than to see you get hurt.
You've done your best with Dad so far.
I'll never let them go from
strength to strength like that.
What will you do then?
Did you hear that?
Hong Shin Ae took over Cheonmun Group.
Take me...
to the police station.
No, call the police for me.
You said you can't trust the
police or the prosecution.
What do you want to do?
Yoon Joong Tae tried to kill me.
I'll tell them about it.
The medical officer tried to
kill me in the detention center.
I heard him talking on the phone.
Hey, Mr. Hong Il Gwon.
Do you think an attempted murderer...
would admit that...
he tried to kill you?
You saw that too.
Yoon Joong Tae tried to kill me.
I did.
But why would I...
stand as a witness for you?
Even your own daughter remains silent.
Why would I have to do that and
reveal why I was hiding here?
He'll simply deny it.
Then...
call my attorneys over here.
I'll change my will...
and give all the stocks I have to Mi Ae.
This way,
she can take over...
the ownership of Cheonmun.
Please help me. Please.
Please. I admit...
that I kidnapped your biological father,
foster father, and Great Aunt.
I admit all these.
And I will pay the price
for my wrongdoings.
Please tell me everything you want from me.
Please accept my sincere apology.
Mr. Hong,
play it cool.
Do you think Mi Ae will
be able to keep it...
if you leave everything to her?
Yoon Joong Tae can put your daughter
behind bars anytime he wants.
It might be better for them...
to live with what they've got.
Do you want to make Mi Ae and Yoon Ho...
end up like you now?
Then...
should I just let him do
whatever he wants to do?
I will take revenge on Joong Tae for you.
Then will you do as I say?
I want to change...
my will.
So that old geezer gained
his consciousness...
when he met with Choi Tae Seok.
If that old fox is playing
the fool with me,
does it mean he knows
that I tried to kill him?
Are you sure?
Yes. I think he recovered his senses.
Mom, wouldn't he try to change his will...
once he fully regains his consciousness?
Then, he'll leave everything to Aunt Mi Ae.
You might not be able to take
the chairperson position then.
That's not good.
I won't let it happen.
It's not over yet.
What are you saying? It's too late now.
I just need to inherit everything.
Then I can throw Shin Ae out.
We can open his will only
after he passes away.
We'll have more stocks if he passes away.
But we don't know when he'll pass away.
That can happen anytime soon.
He almost died twice already.
Hong Il Gwon.
You'll meet your nemesis
just like Yoon Joong Tae.
Stop lying!
It was you who first took my map.
I trusted you,
and you collude with Joong Tae?
I won't let it slide once
I recover my health.
You'll be the first one
to be taken care of.
What is this?
I'm returning your kindness
when we were four with this.
Isn't it too petty compared to my kindness?
I'll repay it throughout my life.
You're wearing lipstick.
I am. I put on makeup for a change,
and I looked weird with bare lips.
I can't kiss you as I want
if you wear lipstick.
What? You're so selfish.
I heard...
that women eat about one
lipstick every year.
And men eat one and a half of it.
I don't want to die young.
I'll live happily with you for a long time.
Will you do nothing with me
when I'm so pretty like this...
just to live long?
Fine.
I'll willingly die young then.
No way. Do you really want to live long?
There.
It looks good.
Let me put it in your mouth.
Open your mouth.
You're like a vamp.
This is nothing.
Gosh.
I guess you won't like this.
What is it?
Open it.
(A coupon to use Jang Dol Mok for a day)
When did you make it?
Right after you moved into Sanwoonyul.
When were you planning
to give this to me then?
Always, whenever I had a chance.
- Can I scratch it?
- Go ahead.
It's for you anyway.
(I'm sorry, but only a kiss is allowed.)
What is this?
You said you made it when I moved in.
Then you already imagined
kissing me back then?
I just wished I could.
Goodness.
Let me scratch one more.
(My goodness. You can
spend a night with me.)
Why? What is it?
It's nothing.
(My goodness. You can
spend a night with me.)
By the way, it's not valid
after the expiration date.
Make sure to use them soon.
Open your mouth.
(Seoul Jeil University Hospital)
He passed away because
of cardiac infarction...
at 2am.
The doctor attempted CPR right
after he found the symptom,
but there wasn't anything he could
do as it was his third time.
Dad...
What's going on, Dad?
He was fine yesterday. What
on earth happened to him?
This is my fault. Please
wake up, Grandfather.
- Grandfather...
- I can't believe this.
Dad.
How can this happen all of a sudden?
- Father.
- Dad.
Father.
How dare you...
How dare you come here?
- You killed him, didn't you?
- Stop it!
- You killed my dad.
- Stop it already.
Dad...
Goodness. My poor dad...
All the wealth is useless.
- Grandfather.
- He died in the end.
Grandfather, open your eyes.
- Dad...
- Dad!
- This is nonsense.
- Dad...
Have you heard the news?
Chairman Hong of Cheonmun Group died.
He had a heart attack
early in the morning...
and died instantly.
- Sorry?
That's hard to believe.
We were in the middle of
preparing for the trial.
And what on earth is this?
What happens to the trial then?
What do you mean? The
person involved is dead.
The prosecution will be suspended.
Goodness, what a waste.
We prepared for this trial for months.
But Joon Hee, you acted quite quickly.
What do you mean?
Yesterday, shareholders' meeting was held.
Chief Prosecutor Yoon's wife is
going to run the company now.
What? Really?
But isn't the eldest daughter
holding most of the shares?
That's what the media reported.
However,
some voted against the popular sentiment.
Of all the people,
the executives he investigated
voted for Chief Prosecutor's wife.
Could this be coincidence?
My investigation has nothing
to do with the voting.
Is that so?
But...
after you investigated them,
they changed their stance.
How would I beat you in this mind game?
Good for you.
You're Chief Prosecutor's favorite.
Now, all you have left to do
is get on the fast track.
Goodness, the universe can be mean.
He has committed countless crimes.
He ought to pay for his crimes.
He lost consciousness not
long after getting locked up.
They moved him to a ward,
but look at what happened.
"I will take good care of you..."
"on your way to your afterlife."
Is this some kind of a new business?
Even the universe is siding with the rich.
In a way, the universe is making it
easy for the rich to die peacefully.
What a piece of garbage. He didn't
give me a chance to take my revenge.
Forget it.
Don't even think about taking your revenge.
If you have time to think for that,
focus on rehabilitating your leg.
You're only worrying about Mr. Jang.
Hey, you. That's not it.
Goodness, the best way...
to take your revenge is living your
life to the fullest. Understood?
But how can that old man cope with dying?
He left so much money behind.
Doesn't this look fishy?
Before he was sent to the detention center,
he was acting all confident.
Out of the blue, he lost consciousness...
and died.
What are you implying?
Are you saying his daughters did
something to get his money?
That makes sense.
When it comes to money, love,
loyalty, and family...
are no use.
When I became penniless after
Cheonmun Group stole my invention,
my wife packed up her things and left.
Then who's going to take
over Cheonmun Group?
He only has one grandson, Lee Yoon Ho.
Hey, you. I think you've
gotten the wrong idea.
Marrying a rich guy is the
same as living in prison.
Why did you let this
octopus stay in our house?
Hey, where is Dol Mok?
He wasn't in his office.
Did he go to meet So Joo?
I am going to revise my will.
I am Chairman Hong Il Gwon's doctor.
After Chairman Hong collapsed
in the detention center,
he was transferred to this hospital.
It is true that for a while, his
consciousness wasn't stable.
However, as of now,
he has fully regained his consciousness.
Chairman Hong...
has requested not...
to inform his family for his own safety,
and I complied with his request.
What is this? So Dad had put
up an act in front of us?
Because he couldn't trust us?
Goodness, Grandfather...
is surprising us even
until his last moment.
Please keep it down.
He hasn't even started yet.
Considering my physical health,
before I lose more time,
in order to wrap up the matter
regarding the inheritance,
I have decided to film this video.
Even before I was arrested,
through Attorney Jang,
I was going to revise my will.
I have Attorney Jung and
Kim as my witnesses.
I'd like to...
delegate authority to Attorney Jang
Dol Mok regarding everything...
including the inheritances.
- Jang Dol Mok?
- Dad.
Hello, everyone.
I am Attorney Jang Dol Mok...
in charge of executing
Chairman Hong Il Gwon's will.
You all know who I am, don't you?
What's going on?
Why would Dad entrust him
to execute his will?
That's right. Grandfather knows that
this jerk siphoned the money...
from Cheonmun Group and framed me
for embezzlement. Why would he?
He must've wanted to teach you
a lesson, Mr. Lee Yoon Ho.
He especially asked me to look after you.
- What?
- I know you are a competent lawyer.
Why would he ask Attorney Jang to
handle this after disregarding...
2 attorneys who've been with
our family over 30 years?
I can't understand this.
How did this happen?
We don't know the details.
The chairman put us up as witnesses...
and appointed Attorney Jang
as the attorney of record.
All right.
Can I disclose his will?
("Many Came to Pay Their
Respects to His Wake")
("A Complete Coverage from
His Arrest to Death")
Investigator Kang, what are you doing?
You didn't have lunch?
Prosecutor.
Is your investigation of
Cheonmun Group's committees...
irrelevant to Hong Shin Ae being appointed?
Are you still on that?
Under the circumstances, what
Senior Prosecutor said made sense.
Why did you investigate them?
Investigator Kang!
I investigated them on the
suspicion of corruption.
What corruption?
Was their corruption worse than
Hong Mi Ae or Lee Yoon Ho's?
Why are you investigating them in secret?
Hey, Kang So Joo!
Have you lost your mind?
How dare you insult Prosecutor Han?
- Investigator Nam, what's wrong?
- Stay out of it.
Apologize to him right now.
How could you be so ungrateful?
How could you insult him? He
brought you here from Chuncheon.
- Stop it.
- This newbie went too far.
I told you to stop.
I'll apologize if my speculation is wrong.
However, as your subordinate,
I'm politely asking you a question.
I'm going to arrest Hong Mi
Ae and Lee Yoon Ho one day.
But let me just say that right now
isn't the right time for that.
Did my answer satisfy you?
Aunt and your shares are about 330,000.
Even if Grandfather was furious at Dad,
there's no way he didn't
leave anything for us.
Yoon Hwa Young, don't even think about it.
Didn't you hear from Attorney Jung...
that Dad wasn't going to
give you a single share...
before he collapsed?
Every real estate property, saving account,
antique, and national treasure...
under Chairman Hong's possession...
will be donated to the families of
deceased independence fighters.
Two million shares out of...
Chairman Hong's 8,206,000 shares
related to Cheonmun Group...
will be used as funds for
a scholarship project...
of children from low-income families.
Hey, Jang Dol Mok.
Are you sure my dad wrote that will?
After I disclose the will,
I will disclose the chairman's recording.
So please be patient.
2 million shares out of his
remaining 6.2 million shares...
are left for his eldest
daughter, Hong Mi Ae.
In addition, his grandson, Lee Yoon Ho...
will receive 1.2 million shares.
It's over, Mom.
If we combine our shares,
we have 3.2 million shares.
Cheonmun Group is ours now.
Okay. Wait a second.
Then what about the rest
of three million shares?
What's going to happen to those?
One million shares of...
the remaining three million shares
will be given to Yoon Hwa Young.
And the rest of two million shares...
will be passed down to Hong Shin Ae.
Hey!
This is nonsense! How can she...
How can I be treated just like
her, a mistress' daughter?
Mom, Aunt has 8,467,000 shares.
We have 8,593,000 shares.
We still have the control over the company.
Ms. Yoon Hwa Young, we are not done yet.
However, Hong Shin Ae will
receive two millions dollars...
under the condition that she divorces...
Yoon Joong Tae.
If she doesn't divorce him within a month,
the shares left for Hong Shin Ae
will be donated to the society.
However, in the case of
Hong Shin Ae's death,
the shares will be passed onto
his son-in-law, Yoon Joong Tae.
Hold on. He still has 6,000 shares left.
In the case that you two live
happily until your death,
he has left the remaining
6,000 shares for both of you.
Attorney Jang.
I was going to say hello, but I was busy.
Why did you become an attorney
for someone like Hong Il Gwon?
He's a descendant of a pro-Japanese family.
He has caused harm to society.
I'm a lawyer.
I only did what I had to do as a lawyer.
Were you a lawyer who sells your soul?
Didn't you quit fencing...
because the Hong family bribed the judge?
That's the past,
and this is about the will.
I can't help it. I can't just watch it.
What do you mean?
Are you saying you'll divorce me?
Then do you want me to
watch Mi Ae take over...
Cheonmun Group?
I'll never let that happen.
You're finally revealing yourself.
You're willing to dump
me if it's for money.
What about you?
Are you trying to kill me too...
just like how you...
tried to kill Dad to take my portion?
Watch your mouth.
Why do you think Dad added that condition?
It was to save me from you.
If I die now,
you'll be blamed for
killing me for my fortune,
so you can't dare to get your hands on me.
You're out of control now.
You denounce me for what I didn't do?
Well...
I knew I'm only...
a shield to protect you from the complex.
What did you say?
The only way to get your
father's attention...
as a concubine's daughter...
was to cover up his disgrace
of being a pro-Japanese...
by using me.
How could you say that?
Is that why...
you told Father...
about your corruption to bring me down?
When I tried to imprison Father...
for the gold collection case,
do you think I didn't know you stopped me?
That's great.
Everything will clear up if we divorce.
What if Aunt Shin Ae really gets a divorce?
I mean, they're too old to talk about love.
Since she has the money, if
she gets Cheonmun Group,
young men will line up to serve her.
Don't you think?
I must stop her from divorcing...
by all means necessary.
Get out of there.
That's not your place anymore.
It still belongs to me.
Have you forgotten the committees chose me?
You'll lose it soon.
Have you forgotten about the inheritance?
You're not...
thinking about dumping
your husband, are you?
For money that you consider ridiculous?
You said...
you'd choose love over money
and chose your husband.
You even live with the man you don't love.
Getting a divorce for the record...
won't stop me from loving him.
Stop joking.
Say what you have to say.
It's not your husband you love...
but money.
After all, you're going to divorce...
to get Cheonmun Group.
Don't pretend to be so elegant.
Right.
If you don't get Cheonmun Group,
you're left without money,
love, and power.
I'll reach the place you
can't even imagine,
so watch what I can do.
All the insulting your
mom has done to my mom.
I'll return it all to you.
- Lawyer Jang Dol Mok?
- Yes.
He's the inheritance lawyer,
and he ruined everything.
No way.
How is that possible?
That's what I want to ask you.
What were you doing?
I was manipulating the will...
with the lawyers just like you said.
We should be glad that...
Chairman Hong didn't announce
it when he was conscious.
Then both you and I...
would be in trouble.
That old man stabbed me in the back...
before he died.
He was pretending he was unconscious.
What should I do now?
I won't let...
Jang Dol Mok get away with this.
How could he dare side up
with him and attack me?
But we must find the last map.
Hello.
I was thinking about paying you a visit,
but I thought it'd make you upset.
When did you start to side
up with Chairman Hong?
Did you contact him first...
or did he call you?
Whatever it was,
we decided to side up because
we have the same goal.
So...
what did you two talk about?
You sound like you're interrogating me.
You're not my boss.
I didn't commit any crime in this case.
You're the one all tensed up now.
You're probably well aware...
how serious murder instigation
and attempted murder are.
You look like you're suitable for prison.
You look like a petty criminal.
Don't accuse me without evidence.
A rookie like you is no match for me.
I'm sure...
you want to...
strangle me now.
Just like how you killed...
my dad Kim Chan Gi 25 years ago.
(The Good Thieves)
Do you have anything to say to me?
I was in charge of Chairman
Hong's inheritance matter.
Are you out of your mind?
Did you do something to kill your dad?
What did you say?
How dare you use me to cover up your crime?
What were you doing on the
night your dad passed away?
What took you so long to arrive?
Hong Il Gwon is dead, and the
person who benefits the most...
out of this is Hong Shin Ae.
It smells fishy.
No one is getting in my way.
It's time for me to spread my wings.
Let's see who wins.
I'll reveal the ugly
details of your family...
and prove all the crimes you committed.