No!
You know, I'm playing and
I don't even know who...
It was nothing.
What happened?
Just need the last touch, I'm there.
Yeah, sure.
I left it there for you.
So, what happened?
The last touch!
I pressed the wrong button.
- How are you? Good?
- Have some maté.
Everything OK?
Yeah, just check out...
the rudder system oil.
- Is it leaking a lot?
- Just a bit.
See if we have
to fill it later on.
It's a bit washed out.
Hey!
Are you crazy?
Don't sleep here!
- How about some coffee?
- OK.
- Hi, Nacho.
- Hi, captain, how's it going?
- Fine, so far so good.
- Any news?
- Seven hours navigation to get to
Ushuaia... - And the weather?
Bad. Snow, heavy winds...
horrible, as usual.
- Ok, fine, all's clear, then.
- Captain?
- Do you have a minute?
- Yes, excuse me.
- Yes, tell me.
- Look, I need to go ashore in Ushuaia.
Was born there but I've been away a long
time. Want to see if my mother's alive.
She used to live in a saw mill,
I don't know if she's still there.
- All right. How much time do you need?
- A couple of days.
It'll depend on how much time
we'll be at the port, but...
fix it up with him, see
the paymaster... and...
he'll give you all the details,
whatever you need.
- OK, good luck.
- Thanks.
- Right, take care of...
- Sure, no problem.
Bye and thanks. Any problems,
just call me.
Farrel, remember that the ship sails
on Thursday and waits for no one.
See you!
- Good morning, how's it going?
- Good.
- Are you heading for Tolhuin?
- No, I'm waiting to load up.
Are you heading that way?
- Yeah.
Over the bridge, by the Pastoriza house,
they might be going that way.
Do you know if the road
to the saw mill is open?
I think it's open. It was closed
yesterday, but I think it's open now.
- Right, thank you.
- Good luck to you.
- Good morning!
- Hi, good morning.
Don't know which one to play.
This one!
- Have some coffee if you want.
- OK, thanks.
- What did you play?
- The eight.
Just my luck.
What an idiot I am.
Play a good card for a change.
Just one good card.
My hand. Look!
You lose there.
Don't search there!
- Who deals?
- Me.
- Bye, see you tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye!
Don't you cheat!
Ready? You go up front, Mariela.
- You go in the back.
- Got it.
Let me know when you're getting off.
Bye!
Hi. Any place to eat around here?
There's a cafeteria over there.
Fine. Thanks.
- Hi. - Hello.
- Anything to eat?
Yeah, sure. I'll bring it right away.
Just have a seat.
Fine. Thanks.
Thanks.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Go ahead, base.
Good evening, Torres. Everything
all right over there?
Good evening. Yes, work is
normal over here.
Listen, I'm sending the truck tomorrow.
How's the road?
Is it heavy with snow?
It snowed a bit last night,
but the road's in good shape.
Listen, tell Trujillo to gather the
sheep for tomorrow or the day after.
How's the situation, Torres? Over.
I'll tell Velazquez to tell Trujillo to
gather the sheep tomorrow. Over.
Fine. Torres, do you need diesel oil?
Well, by what Zapater told me,
the diesel oil is fine.
There's enough. Send 400 liters
next week.
How's Nazarena?
How's her health?
She's... still getting worse, so...
there's no improvement.
Okay, understood. If it doesn't snow
a lot, I'll send the truck on Friday.
Right. We'll expect the truck, then.
- Tell Torres to bring the food.
- I'll tell him right away.
Torres, you can serve the food.
Torres!
Let's go, Analia. I'll walk you.
You can go.
What did you come for?
As soon as you left, Analia was born.
Nobody knows you here.
Not even your mother. She's sick.
Don't know why you came back.
Nice legacy you left me.
What are you looking for?
I know that you can hear me.
Here's the maté for you.
- Hi. - Hi, how are you?
- Can I have one?
Thanks for everything.
Hi! How are you?
I've brought you some fresh bread.
Have some.
What are you drawing?
"H-hobellazang. "
Give me money?
My legs hurt.
And you?
Do you know who I am?
So many people come,
some known, some unknown.
I'm Farrel.
Farrel!
Farren?
I was this small, when you
were already grown...
Did they call you?
That's good enough! Fussing...
When you're nice
and warm, you go out...
and it's cold.
Isn't that true?
- I'm Farrel.
- Huh?
How's that again?
- Farrel!
- Oh!
Your hands are cold.
Won't you give me money?
Here. Keep it safe so
nobody can take it.
Wait.
Do you still have the money?
It's your money, stash it away.
I'll give you something.
Here.
I'm leaving.
Make yourself comfortable over there.
Have a bit more, it's good for you.
- Is the bread pushed in there?
- Yes, it's pushed.
You need to eat.
In a hurry to get the bread?
Yes.
Go get the food from Torres.
A bit more.
Good thing Farrel's gone.
- Do you like music, Analia?
- Yeah.
Analia, here you are.
How about some gin?
- How was the work?
- They've worked all day.
But they need more logs,
they're trickling in.
- Is the... coming on Saturday?
- Yes the truck's coming in on Saturday.
That should fix it.
How's Trujillo?
All right, I guess.
Always behind the animals.
He's taking care of Nazarena.
Analia! Analia!
D- did you catch anything?
Nothing.
Let's go. Let's go and
see the foxes, Analia.
Walk slowly.
Let's go, Analia, I've caught a fox.
Let's go. I caught a nice one.
You almost fell there,
you have to be careful.
Come on, we still have to lock up
the sheep and it's getting late.
We'll have to remove the mold.
The one we brought is larger.
Take the traps and go
and feed the sheep.
Subtitles: scalisto for KG