Can I help you?
A neighbour of mine,
an old lady who can't come
because she had an accident
and broke her leg,
asked me to
sell this for her.
- What is it?
- It's English china.
- Does she have the whole set?
- No, I don't think so.
Twelve pesos maximum.
Tell your friend that if she
doesn't have the whole set...
- Twelve pesos.
- Yes.
Well, I don't know.
I'll have to talk to her.
I think she expected more.
It's English china.
- Do you want to see it again?
- No, I've already seen it.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Keep the change.
Thanks.
- Don't you have the keys?
- They must be somewhere.
What did you bring?
- Have you seen the teapot?
- Yes, I have it.
I went to see a friend of mine,
he runs an antique shop.
He had a look at it.
He thinks it's wonderful.
Really unique.
You know what date
is today, don't you?
Yes, I know.
Did Guillermina call?
- Dora...
- No, she didn't!
- Where are you going?
- To the supermarket.
- We ran out of detergent.
- Oh! Wait!
I'll give you the money.
I have twenty pesos
somewhere.
Well, I don't know.
I can't find them.
I don't know where they are.
Go, go.
I'll tell you what.
Let's not clean anymore.
You can put covers
on the furniture.
How can we live with
covers on the furniture?
What are you saying!
- Do you want to buy peppers?
- No.
Wait, let me see.
Yes, it's okay.
- Did you buy detergent?
- Yes, I did.
Well, I owe you the money.
I can't find the 20 pesos.
So we get this wonderful
mud, and you can see
how Maria Rosa
is working with it.
Using ascending movements,
it can be applied to eyelids
because it's absolutely
hypoallergenic.
This is going to stimulate
the whole of the
cellular memory of the body.
What does this mean?
That you will undergo
a process of
rejuvenation.
Now we have to let it dry from
five to eight minutes.
Would anyone like
to give it a try?
Yes!
Okay, hands up.
And now, the most
important moment of the day.
Let's introduce our new
biothermal experts.
A round of applause
to welcome
Beba Pujol, from
the "Orchids Unit"!
Beba, come here, please.
Welcome, welcome!
It's okay, Dora.
Can you pour me a whisky?
I'm so excited!
I've become a member
of a cosmetics company.
They have mud, creams.
I left a sample for you there.
Try it. Your face will be
fantastic after using it.
This is definitely
going to sell well.
By the way,
the game is on Friday.
Friday is my day off.
Well, Miss Sarah
can't make it on Thursday.
There's nothing we can
do, Dora. Please.
I'm going out with
Miguel on Friday.
How noisy these kids are!
I'd like to put a sleeping
pill in the birthday cake.
What are you doing, Dora?
What are you doing?
You can't help
doing this show.
I'll leave everything ready
for you to prepare your own tea.
I'm going to get
my things ready.
I'll clean this.
You pay me if you want.
I'm leaving.
I'd like to know how
you're going to make a living.
Is Miguel going to
keep you both?
He's not right man for you.
I've told you several times.
The janitor would be right,
now that he is a widower.
You would have
a good life with him.
You could come here
just a few hours.
It's a good idea,
isn't it?
Come on! You're always
listening to the news.
You know that Alejandro
Korn isn't Belgrano, darling.
Everybody knows you
and respects you here.
And you don't need
further education to know that.
Come on, Dora! I know
you like Luisito.
He spent some nights
in your room.
This house isn't like the one in
Matinez. You can hear every sound.
What happened?
Pay it with part of
the money you owe me.
Dora...
Everything's going
to be okay.
After the game, on Friday,
I'll pay you your March salary.
I may even pay you
half your April salary.
Here you have the
sample I told you about.
Apply it to your face.
It's really great.
It has oligoelements
dating from the Tertiary Era.
A very good product.
Oh, God!
Shit!
Bitch.
I'll pay it
with your salary.
Dora!
Dora! Where are they?
Those things to put...?
The bandages.
Don't touch me!
Bring me a whisky.
Where are you going?
I'm looking for the bandages.
I'll take the whisky after that.
I asked for it now.
Don't touch me.
- I'm going to disinfect it.
- What's that?
Some alcohol.
- Alcohol? It'll sting.
- No, it won't.
You have a splinter.
It hurts!
I did get it now.
How can you be so rough?
Dora, another whisky.
There's none left.
Give me the telephone.
- Aren't you having dinner?
- No. Go to bed.
I'd like to make a call
to Madrid, Spain.
Person to person.
Guillermina.
Her mother.
Okay.
Three, one nine, one
one, six, two.
Okay, I'll leave a message.
This is a message for
Guillermina. It's her mother.
Guillermina, I want
to talk to you.
But you're not in.
Well.
Give me a call,
will you?
Bye. This is mum. Bye.
- Were there any leaks?
- Yes.
The roof must be fixed.
- Did she pay you?
- No.
- Did you get anything?
The first thing I' like
to do when she pays me
is to buy the floor.
If she ever pays you...
Don't speak like that!
Don't come on Friday.
There is a game.
Okay.
Cristian, come help the lady.
Beba, show me.
This mud, which is wonderful.
You can apply it to your eyes.
Mud?
Hi, Irma.
How are you? Are you
having your hair dyed today?
There's a great selection
of colours. Have a look.
The creams I gave you.
- I'll buy the feet treatment.
- Great.
It's the one I need.
I can't buy the rest.
I would buy them all,
but I'm a bit hard up.
Can you pay Beba?
- No, no way.
- What do you want to do?
I'll come with Dora on Friday
to have our hair done.
That's it. We're even.
- Can I leave some samples?
- Yes, sure.
- How's your daughter?
- In Madrid.
Lucky her!
This is Beba Pujol.
Leave your message
after the beep.
Hello, Dora.
Are you there?
Hello? It's me, Dora.
Dora?
Well, I'll be late today.
Don't prepare tea.
Hello.
Hello?
Guille!
Fine, fine.
Putting your mother's things
in some sort of order.
No, she's not in.
We called you because
we had no news from you
and we were a bit worried.
Are you eating well,
darling?
Well, as usual.
It's not as bad as they say.
This is a quite
neighbourhood, anyway.
My house? We finished
the two bedrooms
and we want to buy
the floor next.
It's going to be beautiful.
Are you coming for Christmas?
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
But it's better for you
to stay and get those papers.
My mail?
Wait a second.
I'll get a pen.
- Charge it to the gentleman.
- Sure.
Hello, madam.
Victor's busy at the moment.
Madam. Madam.
Well, what we can you
is change the stick.
We can put one
like the one...
Victor, has
Guillermina called you?
Excuse me.
What's the matter?
She hasn't called me either.
She's fine.
What do you need?
I don't know.
I'm not feeling well.
I fell alone.
What about lunch tomorrow?
Silvia will call
you a taxi.
Dora, I'm home.
I'm home.
Today was a great day.
These cosmetics
sell so well!
Here, Dora, I'll pay
you for the detergent.
Please buy some drinks
for the game.
Let's organize everything.
Madam, do you have
any of that mud left?
- Yes.
- It's good.
Very good!
I'll give you some.
- Shall I apply it for you?
- Yes, I'd like that. Thank you.
Come here.
Here it is.
Come to my room.
- Guillermina called.
- What did she say?
She wanted to talk to you,
to know if you were ok.
And what did you tell her?
That we are all fine.
She's worried
about the things she
reads in the papers.
- And how is she?
- She seemed to be fine.
Is she coming for Christmas?
She's not coming.
She always talks to you,
and never to me.
I'm not feeling well.
Hold me.
- Oh, madam.
- Hold me.
- Come, madam.
- Oh God.
Come on, make an effort.
No, no, no.
To Guille's room.
Shall you prepare
something sweet to drink?
No, no. Stay here.
You could take this room.
The closet is bigger,
more comfortable.
The bathroom has a tub.
I mean it.
- Where are you going?
- To my bedroom, madam.
- National or imported?
- National.
It's for cooking.
I'll get it.
- Beba Pujol?
- Yes, come in.
Leave it there.
- I need your signature, please.
- Dora, please.
It's too much.
I can give them back
in ten days if I don't sell them.
The Queen of Spain.
What do you think?
And like this?
Like Mirta Legrand?
No way. You would
have to bleach it.
I mean the hairdo.
- This.
- Ivanna Trump?
Does Armandito still
live in Kentucky?
Yes, but he's being
transferred to Saudi Arabia.
Saudi Arabia,
Bin Laden's country.
He would be in better shape.
Your turn, Meme.
Beba, how much
do you pay Dora?
It's rude to
ask that kind of question.
I want to know because
I'm hiring a new girl.
I think I'm overpaying her.
You can't compare Dora
to a beginner!
- Isn't Dora great?
- Yes, great.
Her complexion I mean.
Show them, Dora.
It's because of a cream.
I became a member of
this marvelous company.
- They have a mud...
- Mud?
- Yes, mud.
- Mud.
Yes, mud. It's called mud.
It's really great.
Come here, don't be shy.
I want you to touch her face.
So that you can see
how good the mud is.
- Touch her face.
- How smooth!
- Remember how she used to have it?
- Yes, yes, yes.
Come here,
show me your face.
- How nice!
- Incredible.
It's anti-age.
There's one for the
eyelids as well.
- Do we have to keep this?
- No, your cleanse it later.
- You cleanse it with what?
- Water, darling.
Dorita, can you call me
a taxi? I'm very tired.
Sure, madam.
Madam, have you paid
the pending invoices?
It must be the storm.
Go downstairs and
get a taxi in the street.
Go, go.
Put it right so
I don't get wet.
Leave that.
You can do it tomorrow.
I'm leaving tomorrow, madam.
Dora!
Dora, open the door!
You were going without
even saying goodbye?
I didn't want to
bother you, madam.
I left you a note
on the fridge's door.
I'll be picking up my stuff
on Monday.
Well, I'll pretend you
didn't say anything.
You think it over
during the weekend.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
Excuse me.
How are you?
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Have I kept you waiting?
- No, no, it's okay.
- Did you play?
- Yes, a little bit. Not too good.
Wine, please.
But it does you good.
I want to ask you a favour.
I need some money.
- How much?
- Five thousand.
The business is not
going that well.
It's high time you moved
to a smaller apartment.
You have too many
fixed expenses.
Dora can come only a few
hours, or she can retire and...
I'm not going to discuss
that with you.
Beba, the Torres are there
Please, don't make a scene.
Why don't you sell
the earrings?
Because I want to wear
them at Guillermina's wedding.
Guillermina is never going
to get married.
Not with a man anyway.
How dare you
give me advice?
You wasted mum's money
with your cinemas
in Florencio Varela,
the carton boxes factory,
the printer of stickers,
the fragrance laboratory,
the tanning lotions...
Beba, we both did some
very bad businesses.
I don't want to think about it!
The printer! To make
- football players stickers.
- Sure, they were good.
- Did you go dancing yesterday?
- No.
- Do you want to go now?
- Ok, let's go.
Miguel, I'm going to
quit my job.
You should stay.
It's hard out there.
I'm wasting my time,
she can't pay me.
Madam?
I'm here, madam.
Ms. Beba.
- Hello.
- Good morning, madam.
Do you have time
for a cup of tea?
- Did you give it a good thought?
- That's what I'm doing.
The seven salaries
I owed you.
This is a bonus for
your work in all these years.
Thank you.
So that you don't say
I'm ungrateful.
How can you do this to me?
When I need you most?
That must be Miguel.
Yes, come in.
- Excuse me, good morning.
- Hello.
If you need someone for
a painting job, let me know.
Yes, yes.
I need a recommendation
letter, madam.
Here's the address.
- See you later, Luisito.
- Bye, Dora.
- Did it open?
- Get a taxi.
Yes, it opened.
To Constitucion Station.
What would you recommend?
This one is better,
it's more classy.
Those are cheaper,
but they are of
a poorer quality.
- Is this resistant?
- Yes, it's the best.
I think the other
one is better.
Let's not spend so much.
It's just the floor.
This is classy.
Excuse me,
I'll be back in a minute.
- I don't know.
- Look, it's better.
Why don't you get
a new job first?
We're running out of money.
Miguel, be careful
when you do it.
I left you some food in the fridge.
Try to keep everything clean.
Yes, my love.
- Can I help you?
- I'm looking for Miguel.
Miguel's busy,
come next week.
Hello.
The people from the Energy
Company have just come.
They left this letter.
Oh, I must have
forgotten to pay it.
If they come again, tell them
I've already gone to the bank.
- Bye.
- You need coins.
- One ticket, please.
This is overdue,
you have to pay it
in two days.
Pay at least fifty per cent
or you won't be able
to sing the agreement.
You can pay the rest
in installments.
Can you make an exception?
Shit.
Thank you.
I'm testing her
for a week.
She cooks, washes, irons...
So far she's so dedicated!
She used to work for
the Archbishop of Misiones.
- She was fired.
- Was she?
She must have
done something wrong.
I think you should
talk to her, instruct her.
You don't want her to...
Your turn.
You know Beba paid
for Dora's two abortions.
And Dorita wasn't
as half as pretty.
Did you, Beba?
- It seems that Luisito, the janitor...
- Stop it.
We haven't had news from
Guillermina in a long time.
- How is she?
- She's great. We are very close.
Everything's going
to be fine.
What?
That everything's
going to be all right.
She will come back.
- Oh.
- She can't live without you.
She will come back!
I don't give a damn.
And if she doesn't, hire
another one, like Sarah did.
I'm fine. Don't worry
about me. I'm fine.
Come on! I know you.
What are you doing here?
Let me make the bed.
Why don't you look
for a job?
Dora? Dora?
Can you take care of Jenny?
I have to go to work.
Okay, just a few hours.
You know, I don't work for
Ms. Beba anymore.
- If you know of a job...
- Okay.
Bye.
Yes, I called before.
Did they tell you
about the arrangement?
It would be a thousand balls
and thirty gloves.
- Do you want a drink?
- No.
Ok, fine. Pesos or
dollars, it's the same.
No, the price is okay.
But it was me that sold it.
Sure. I see.
Well, don't worry.
Roberto, coffee please.
Miguel!
What are you doing?
You have to work on the floor!
It's Sunday today!
Come on, I'll prepare
some mates for you.
These creams I'm selling,
they are all natural.
Are you going to
buy anything?
No money, only food.
Dora!
- Nice clothes!
- A present from Ms. Beba.
They say food appeals you
through you eyes,
if a dish is nice,
people will eat it.
Ms. Beba taught me
everything I'm telling you.
Mary, is the champagne
in the fridge?
- White whine? Red wine?
- Yes, everything's ready.
Madam, this is Dora.
- Nice to meet you, Dora.
- Nice to meet you.
- Sir.
- No, thanks.
- Miss.
Sir.
Dora! Get the dogs!
- Mary, the dogs!
- Yes, I'm going.
- How's everything, Mary?
- Fine, fine.
Who's that?
It's me, Dora.
Dora!
I can't find the keys, Dora.
Go to the back door.
Hello, Dora.
Darling.
If I had known you were coming,
I would have dressed better.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
Come in, come in.
You needn't have, Dora.
Just a little something.
- Stockings.
- I hope you like them.
Hold on a sec.
One little candle.
Don't forget to
make a wish.
- Happy birthday.
- Thanks.
Don't cut it, save it
for your friends.
What friends, Dora?
Delicious.
I should be going, madam.
One keeps so many
things in so many years!
I have a bag of things
for you and Miguel.
Clothes, creams and mud.
Do you really have
to go so soon?
Yes, I'm waiting for a call
from the employment agency.
I'm trying to get
a job near here,
so I have a few extra
hours for you.
Take a piece for Miguel.
Thank you, madam.
Let's go.
This is the recommendation
letter you asked me to write.
Thank you.
I'll walk you to the door.
I hereby certify that
Miss Dora Dominguez
has worked for my family
for twenty-eight years,
always with faultless behaviour.
She's hard working
and competent,
as well as honest and respectable.
It's her own decision to leave this job.
Beatriz Pujol.
Buenos Aires,
November 4, 2001.
Have you seen Miguel?
No, I haven't seen him.
Miguel!
Let's go home!
- In a minute.
- Come back. I'll be waiting.
Are you renting it
with the furniture?
I don't care, it's the same.
Be careful with the glass.
Come on, it got stuck.
Madam, this piano is
too big for this door.
No.
Wait.
Ms. Beba!
Come in, it's too hot here.
I'm sorry I came
without any notice.
You don't need
to give me notice.
Would you like
something to drink?
An iced tea with a few
lemon drops would be nice.
What a classy floor!
Yes, but Miguel didn't
buy enough.
Well, it's only details
that you're missing.
Madam, can we take
the things off the van?
- Yes, put the there.
- Where?
Just there.
We'll see later.
I'm moving to a
smaller apartment.
I thought you could make
good use of some things.
You house is very nice.
I imagined it bigger.
Sit down, if you want.
It'll take time to cool
in this heat.
Okay.
Madam, how could you...?
Don't worry, Dora.
I'll take it again when
I move to a larger place.
This way.
It's out of tune.
Don't worry.
I'll put a cover on it.
- Where's Miguel?
- He went to San Luis.
Buenos Aires is hell.
There's such a nice
breeze here.
It's too late. Why don't
you stay here tonight?
Madam, where shall
we put the bed?
Leave it inside.
I miss you so much, my love.
I can't understand it.
My life's empty without you.
I miss you so much, my love.
What can I do?
I miss you so much
I'm going crazy.
Sometimes I think
you'll never come back,
but I love you and
I have to wait for you.
Fate takes me to
the place where
my love will find
you some day.
Oh, my divine love...
you have to come back soon.
I miss you so much!
My life's empty without you.
I miss you so much
I'm going crazy.
Sometimes I think
you'll never come back,
but I love you and
I have to wait for you.
Fate takes me to
the place where
my love will find
you some day.
Oh, my divine love...
you have to come back soon.
The pain is strong
and I bear it
because I live
thinking about your love.
I want to see you,
have you, kiss you.
And give you my entire heart.
Oh, my divine love...
you have to come back soon.