- Dr. Slamon? Hi.
- Hello.
It's Jamie MacGraw. Work-Study sent me.
My student assistant. Right, right.
I'm right up here on the left.
- Okay.
- Come on in.
- What are you, biology, chem?
- No. English lit.
- You're not a science major?
- No.
- No offense...
- Jamie.
Jamie. Right.
But I'm doing scientific research here,
and I kind of need an assistant
who understands what I do.
Well, this wasn't my first choice, either,
and no science majors wanted this job.
- What? None?
- No.
Well, tell me you at least
read science fiction.
Dr. Slamon's office, I mean, lab.
Jamie. Nice to meet you, too, Mrs. Slamon.
Hold on.
- Here.
- Hi.
No, I didn't forget. 6:30 at the latest, right?
Okay. Me, too. Bye-bye.
Could you hand me that splicer
over there, please?
No, no, no, to the left, to the left.
Left, left, left, left.
- Right there. Thank you very much.
- Well, thanks anyway.
You know what?
I don't really need a science major.
I just need someone to handle my calls,
do the paperwork.
Whatever it takes so I can concentrate
on my patients and HER-2.
HER-2?
Yeah, it's a growth gene I'm using to try
and create a drug to treat breast cancer.
- Like chemo?
- No. No, no, no. It's nothing like chemo.
See, chemotherapy works
on the principle of killing cancer cells,
and almost the patient, with poison and just
hoping the new cells grow back cancer-free.
That doesn't make sense to me.
What I'm trying to do
is something that's never been done before.
Take a sort of super-protein from the body
and target the bad cells
and turn them off like a light switch.
It won't cure the cancer,
but it'll shut it off, which is almost as good.
- That sounds really...
- Crazy. Right, I know.
Everyone says that, but it's not.
If we can learn how to shut the bad cells off,
that will lead us to a cure.
And, just so you know,
I'm not gonna remember your birthday,
or National Assistants' Day.
Not because I don't try or
because I don't want to. Hold this, please.
I just won't.
And I'm gonna constantly be after you
to stay late and come early,
even if I can't pay you on time.
You are trying to talk me
into this job, right?
Yes. But I want to be clear.
200,000 women a year
are diagnosed with breast cancer.
Getting HER-2 to work
could save a lot of those lives.
200,000 a year?
Grams is here!
- Good morning, Samuel.
- You're going to sleep in my room.
Well. It's a very small bed for two people.
I'm going to sleep with my mom.
- Hi, Mom. Thank you so much for coming.
- Of course, dear.
Although, why Charlie chose to go
on the road this particular week,
and why you wouldn't come
and stay at my house remains a mystery.
You do still have a room there, you know?
I want to be home. So does Sam.
Could we not go over this again?
I was merely pointing out that
it would be less stressful for all of us,
you, especially, to be in a house
that has adequate space and amenities,
like air conditioning.
This will be fine.
I'll just put my things away.
And you, young man, should do the same
with that bicycle of yours.
Why does she have to be here?
Because she's my mother
and your grandmother.
And next to you and Daddy,
she's all I've got.
Oh, Kate, I love that you put that up there.
It's official.
Your own shop on Melrose Avenue.
I can't believe it. I'm a real designer.
You've been a designer. The only difference
is that now you're a designer with overhead.
Chartreuse, what was I thinking?
- Kate, if nobody buys anything...
- That's not gonna happen.
So, get over here and make a toast.
- We got to commemorate the day.
- You don't miss a beat. Champagne?
- A good year, too.
- What are we going to toast to? Let's see...
I got it.
- To good friends...
- Yes.
- Hard work and to kicking some retail ass.
- Amen, sister.
It's official. You make
the best cup of coffee in the world.
- Yeah. You say that every day.
- I mean it every day.
- You decided about summer school?
- Someone else can teach it.
I'm going to spend the summer
sleeping in and getting fat.
And cleaning out the sun room
for my studio.
Finally. With your talent you should
be making art instead of teaching it.
Lilly. What are you doing here?
I need an excuse to say hello?
- This is your lab? This little room?
- I know. The janitor's closet's bigger.
But the chances of him curing cancer
are slim to none, so I got him there.
Lilly Tartikoff, old friend,
Jamie MacGraw, new assistant.
- Hi.
- Hello.
How's Brandon? Is he okay?
A star, who shall remain nameless,
is giving him indigestion,
and the Dodgers are in a slump.
But other than that, he's fine.
How's Donna? I owe her a call.
She's good.
When you call her, say hi for me.
Poor Donna.
At least I can tell my husband he has to
come home. It's not like he's curing cancer.
Here, don't say I never gave you anything.
That is every episode of Hill Street Blues,
which you always miss
because you're always here.
You've got to be kidding me.
Being married to the president
of NBC Entertainment has its perks.
You didn't have to do this.
Thank you so much.
You saved my husband's life. Thank you.
I'm sorry, but I promised Donna
I would get him out on time,
- and we still have our rounds.
- Good for you. Keep on him.
And you, lives need to be saved.
Get back to work.
- Bye.
Bye, Lilly. Thank you.
All right.
You heard her, let's get back to work.
- I'm sorry. I was trying not to wake you.
- That was thoughtful.
But I couldn't sleep after you promised to be
home five hours ago and never showed up.
The specimen refrigerator broke and...
- I am so not done.
- I'm sorry.
An hour-long recital.
I reminded you today, yesterday.
I even put Jamie on the case.
- I did everything but drive you there myself.
- I had to do the transfer myself.
- Your daughter was expecting you.
- There was no one I could call.
It's my work. If anything happened,
- I'd have to start all over.
- Start all over. I know.
I knew when I married you what I was in for.
But they just want their daddy there.
Not every time. But sometimes.
- I'll make it up to her on Sunday.
- That would be good.
Okay. I'm officially over it.
- You're sure?
- Yeah.
Because you know
I'm going to kiss you now.
You smell good.
You, wow, not so good.
So, how was she?
Honestly, she was the best sunflower
I think I've ever seen.
You know why? She gets that from you.
You weren't really waiting up for me,
were you?
No, I fell asleep reading.
And no offense,
but I really want to get back.
Then you won't mind if I go for a run?
'Cause I'm not gonna have time
in the morning.
- Yeah. That's not gonna happen.
- So not happening?
Okay. I didn't want to run anyway.
- You've done that a thousand times.
- Well, that's what science is.
But what exactly are you doing?
- I showed you the plan.
- No. You didn't.
That's the plan. Step one is discovery.
That's a one-in-a-million shot
linking the HER-2 protein
with cell growth in breast tissue.
I did that right here in this lab.
Step two is to create a drug from HER-2.
That's where we are right now.
I'm doing some of that work right here.
And they're doing the rest up at Genentech.
- And that's a drug company.
- Right.
- It's a biotech company up in the Bay Area.
- And biotech is...
Is looking for medicines
based on molecular biology.
Step three is the Mouse Protein Experiment.
I'll explain more about that
when we get a little bit closer.
Steps four, five and six
are the FDA clinical drug trials,
to see if the drug works
and how well it works.
Which would lead us to Step seven,
the Holy Grail, our drug is approved.
Hey, Blake. Blake.
You're not going to believe this new data.
I was trying to catch you before you got
on the plane. I've got some bad news.
Okay. How much are they cutting our budget
this time?
I'm sorry, Denny. The board has
decided not to continue with HER-2.
You did not just say that.
They think cancer research
just carries too much risk.
What? They're just deciding that now?
We spent six years on this!
Yeah. And they've been dragging their feet
every step of the way.
We're getting close. You know we are.
The board knows it, too.
Try to see their perspective.
Continuing will cost millions of dollars
and the drug might not work.
But it might!
- Take a look at the new data.
- I'm a believer based on the old data.
It's a hard pill, Denny,
but you got to swallow.
We can't stop.
Not until we know what we have.
- Dinner's ready.
- I need to finish.
What's going on?
You haven't said two words all day.
Genentech is dropping HER-2.
- So you'll take it to another drug company.
- I can't.
Genentech owns the rights.
- But you developed the drug.
- It doesn't matter, okay?
I did it using one of their genes,
so it belongs to them.
Honey, you have been in this position
before and you always work it out.
Really not in the mood
to be cheered up right now. Okay?
I don't care.
I don't. It's Sunday,
the one day of the week that's ours.
And on Sunday, I don't care about cancer,
HER-2 or Genentech.
Just our family.
That was our deal from day one.
So, stop feeling sorry for yourself,
put a smile on that cute face,
and come in for dinner.
Daddy!
You're just in time
for the 10:00 tune-up special.
Well, if I were staying, I'd take you up on it.
You should stay. It's his first birthday.
We can have another cake
at dinner tomorrow.
A yard full of screaming children
is not my cup of tea.
Come on, it'll be fun.
I hardly get a chance to see you.
- Really? And that's something you want?
- Just as much as you do.
- If she's sleeping, just let her.
- Sleeping? This hour?
She's tired. Taking care of two boys
is a lot of work, you know.
You mean three.
Yeah.
Your film looks fine. Lie down, please.
Lift your left arm.
Have you noticed any lumps
or anything unusual since your last visit?
- No.
- Right arm.
Are you doing your weekly self-exams?
- Like clockwork.
- Good.
You're fine. See you in six months.
Wham, bam, thank you, ma'am, to you, too.
I'm sorry.
I've been paging you and paging you.
You need to jump on a plane.
- Blake called and he said it's urgent.
- Good urgent? Bad urgent?
He wouldn't say. But it's gotta be good.
You're right.
I've got the smallest budget at UCLA,
the smallest lab and no Genentech money.
How could it be worse?
It's gonna be good. You're due.
See you soon.
I don't believe it! How in the world
did you get the board to change its mind?
- Oh, simple. Just committed career suicide.
- You committed what?
I can devote 20% of my time
to any project I want.
I chose HER-2.
It did not go over very well, believe me.
And if we screw this up,
I'm pretty sure I'll be free to leave.
We won't screw it up.
God help me for believing in you and this.
I'd sleep a lot better at night if I didn't.
But listen, you're going to have to take
that lead foot of yours off the gas.
We're going to have
a lot less lab time and money.
- Got it.
- I'm serious.
However slow it's going now,
ratchet that down by half.
You know what? It really doesn't matter.
I mean, we're still in the game, right?
Which is more than we could say
two days ago.
Realistically, though,
how soon till we get a bigger budget?
Get out. Get out.
Put the globe back and get out.
So, did you decide on the teaching job?
I'm too busy around here. The paycheck
would have been nice, though.
- Come on. You're a doctor's wife.
- A university doctor.
He gets a teacher's paycheck.
I'm not complaining.
It's just we're going to have to win
the lottery when it comes time for college.
Well, if you do win and you need
a bad influence, I know just the stores.
Maybe one spree.
I'd give the rest to Denny for his research.
No. Let Genentech pay for that.
I can't count on them. They're constantly
threatening to cut his funding.
But he's trying to cure cancer.
Who wouldn't support that?
Well, if they get behind the drug and it fails,
it could bankrupt the whole company.
They're terrified.
- Well, he never said anything to me.
- You know Denny.
He could break his arm
and you wouldn't know it.
He's really suffering.
- Don't say anything.
- I won't.
I've made a decision.
I'm going to raise money for your research.
You're going to what?
Last night
I was sitting in my Beverly Hills home,
with my wonderful husband
and my beautiful daughter,
and I was suddenly overwhelmed
with how much I've been given.
I need to start giving back.
And I'm going to do it through you.
Very, very generous of you, Lilly,
but I can't let you do that.
You need the money.
What, you're going to cure cancer in here?
Lilly, the fact that you would even think
about doing something like that for me
means more than I can say.
But I can't let you do that. We're friends.
Are you kidding me?
You spent
I don't know how many days and nights
away from Donna and the kids
with Brandon's chemo
and helping me get through it.
You saved him. That makes us
more than friends, Denny. We're family.
Yes. Which is why I can't take your money.
It's not going to be my money.
I'm going to raise it.
- No.
- No?
Look, Mr. "I Don't Care if I Work
in the Smallest Lab in the Universe,"
I'm offering you money for your research.
Now, if you don't want it, I'll go find
some other deserving doctor who does.
Great. Now can we be done
with this conversation?
You absolutely stink at accepting gifts.
Get over it!
You're this close to losing HER-2 because
some executives are running scared.
Well, screw them. The cavalry is here.
And you are going to have your own money.
It's a promise.
Goodbye.
Brandon, good to see you.
Hi.
Thank you very much.
- Wow, Brandon knows everyone.
- Yes, and if he doesn't, they know him.
But don't worry.
He'll be here before the appetizers.
- Is that an actor?
- No. Better. That's Ron Perelman.
- Who?
He's one of the richest men in America.
He owns Revlon.
I'll be back in two minutes. Hopefully five.
- Ron Perelman?
- Yes?
We haven't officially met. I'm Lilly Tartikoff.
So you're Lilly. Is Brandon with you?
Almost. He's making his way to the table.
I thought I would take a minute to say hello.
Well, I'm glad you did.
These are my friends,
Peter and Bindy Hawn.
Lilly is on our Products Advisory Board
and for the past two years has been sending
me suggestions for our ad campaign.
I used to be on that board. But I don't recall
anyone ever sending in a suggestion.
No one did. Until Lilly.
Ask for my opinion, you're going to get it.
I don't want to take your time.
I wanted to ask a favor.
- Of course.
- Do you see the man at that table there?
That's Dr. Dennis Slamon.
He's on the verge
of discovering something very important.
It's a new kind of drug for breast cancer.
And he needs money.
I'm sure he does,
but this is neither the time
nor the place to discuss it.
All I want
is a chance to tell you about his work.
Call my office. We'll discuss it over lunch.
HER-2 is a growth gene that controls the...
- The...
- Growth of cells.
Give me that. Give it to me.
You don't need that.
Have you been here the last two hours?
I'm not a memorizer.
Well, I don't want you to memorize it.
I want you to understand the concept.
- Lilly, just be conversational.
- No one is more conversational than I am.
But this is the Revlon Foundation Board.
I get one shot to get you more money.
- I have to know what I'm saying.
- What you're saying is very simple.
HER-2 is a gene
that controls the growth of cells
in the breast tissue of a third of all women.
And when those women get breast cancer,
it's a very aggressive form.
And there's no treatment available,
not even chemo.
So most of them will die.
But if my drug is successful,
it's going to offer hope to these women
for the first time, saving 40,000 lives a year.
That's enough to fill the Rose Bowl
every other year.
Maybe if we gave you some lipstick
and a wig...
Lilly, you'll be fine. Just tell them
that I'm at a make-it-or-break-it point.
If I had more money,
I could do the work more quickly.
And if the drug works, and I think it will,
we can get it approved
and on the market five to six years faster.
Six years times 40,000 is
a quarter million lives potentially saved.
By Revlon.
Okay?
Okay. Once more, from the top.
Andy, just the man I wanted to see.
Denny, you know I'm a believer in HER-2
and one of your biggest supporters.
- But the answer is no.
- I haven't asked you anything yet.
Have you ever asked me
for anything besides more money?
Last week I asked you about your dog.
Right before you hit me up
for more equipment.
- Which I still need, by the way.
- And which you're not going to get.
That's not your call, Reinhart.
No. But I was in the meeting
and half the board members agree with me.
An antibody approach to cancer
is never going to work,
which makes HER-2
a terrific waste of time and money.
So half of them agree with me?
Wow. You see,
I thought it was way less than that.
Thanks for the encouragement, Carl.
We're late.
I promise next time we'll talk, okay?
I'll be back on Thursday.
You're going to be glad you kept this going.
You'll see.
- Matt spilled his cereal on Daddy.
- I did not.
How many times have I told you
not to play at the table?
A hundred.
- Could we please not fight?
- Two hundred.
That was Lilly.
She just finished the meeting at Revlon.
She did it.
You mean Ron Perelman said yes?
- Yeah.
- Honey, that's great!
How much is he gonna give you?
$50,000? 100,000?
No. $2.4 million.
It's the biggest amount ever given
to a researcher without restrictions.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Wait. You're sure?
They're just giving it to you?
There are no strings attached?
Lilly has to throw a fundraiser
every year to make more.
- More money?
- More money.
Nicole, sweetheart. It's me. Mom.
Where's Charlie?
He's downstairs
taking care of the paperwork.
The biopsy was malignant.
I know. I know, sweetheart.
But you're going to be fine.
Mom.
You just sleep now, sweetheart.
And when you wake up,
we'll get good news.
Mom.
Don't worry. I'll be right here
waiting for you. Charlie, too.
Lie down, please. Lift your left arm.
- Hello to you, too.
- Sit up, please.
The film shows a fast-growing mass
in your left breast.
From the looks of it, it's cancer.
- But I was just here six months ago.
- As I said, it's fast-growing.
How old was your mother
when she was diagnosed?
- 30.
- And you are?
30.
I'm referring you to an oncologist,
Dr. Banks.
Well, if it is cancer, what are my options?
Mastectomy, radiation, chemotherapy,
whatever Dr. Banks prescribes.
But that's what they gave my mom
15 years ago and she died.
They don't work for everyone.
But they're still the standard of care.
- There's got to be something else.
- Not yet. Good luck.
Honey, come in here.
What's up, baby?
I found a lump in my breast.
Are you sure?
- Yes, it's cancer.
- You don't know that.
Yes, I do.
Lilly, Lilly.
- This is surreal.
- I passed surreal a long time ago.
Good to see you both.
- Thank you for this.
- Tonight is just the beginning.
Hi.
- Hi.
Can you believe it? Everybody came.
I've been sick to my stomach
for five months worrying that they wouldn't.
- You look beautiful.
- You both look like movie stars.
Thank you.
Okay. I've got to work the room.
I will see you at the table.
- Great.
- Okay.
And tonight is making us $400,000 more,
so that ought to keep you in test tubes
a bit longer.
- And get you a bigger lab.
- Wow!
I'll see you. Hi.
I just got to say,
I'm really stoked to be working here.
- That's great.
- When does the HER-2 trial start?
After we do the Mouse Protein Test, which
we're waiting for Genentech to approve.
Mouse protein?
HER-2 is a protein and they grow it in mice
because it's illegal to grow in humans.
And mouse protein
is the most like human tissue.
So it adds another step, because
they have to test to make sure it's safe.
What if Genentech says you can't test it?
They won't. I'll be back at 2:00.
Don't mind him. We've just been
waiting to hear for six months.
If they say no, then it's over.
Could you go next door
and get the boys, please?
I was hoping we could have a cup of tea.
Maybe in the backyard. It's such
a beautiful day. Not too hot, not too cold.
- Okay. That would be nice.
- Excellent. You sit down. I'll get it.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be silly.
How hard is it to make a pot of tea?
- That you're gonna lose someone again.
- I am not losing you.
I think it would be easier for everyone
if we just accept it
and enjoy the time we have left.
Oh, yes, by all means.
Let's take the easy way out.
It's just your life we're talking about.
- Since when did I raise a quitter?
- I have stage-four cancer, Mom.
We haven't run out of doctors yet.
No, we haven't.
Just tell me we're beyond the "K's," right?
- We're well into the "M's."
- Okay, good.
I'm going to go change and...
- Cream or lemon?
- I think it's cream today.
I hate chemo. I hate chemo.
Your mom's on line two.
Hey, Mom, what's up?
Hey, what's up?
I've been behind you and Denny for
a long time, so I'm going to ask you flat out.
Are we ready to take HER-2 to the next step?
100%.
Okay. I'm approving
the Mouse Protein study.
Call Slamon and give him the go-ahead.
Tell him he needs to hurry.
He'll be ready, Andy. Believe me.
Hey, you okay?
My mother was just diagnosed
with breast cancer.
I'm sorry.
Did you get Ricky to sleep?
Listen to this.
"UCLA is looking for volunteers
with advanced cancer
"to test an experimental drug."
It says to call a Dr. Slamon.
There's no harm in calling.
You do qualify for the study.
And I know your time is very, very precious,
so I want to thank you
for giving a week of it to me.
I'd be lying if I didn't tell you
I'm hoping for a miracle.
Hope is a good thing. I do it all the time.
I want you to remember
that this is only a test
to see if the drug that was grown in mice
can be tolerated by people.
Now, that means
I can only give you one dose.
But if it works like I think it will,
it might give you a little bit more time.
And we're talking about
the time you have left.
So I want you to take a day or two
and think about it.
And whatever you decide,
is the right decision. Okay?
I don't need to think about it.
Good morning, everyone.
Today is a historic day.
We're here to do something
that has never been done before.
To inject a drug that was grown
in mouse protein into people
to see if it's safe.
I have every faith
that it will not harm you in any way.
And hopefully, if the drug works
like I think it will, it'll give you more time.
- Good morning, Nicole.
- Good morning.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Congratulations. You just made history.
- Good morning.
We've got a reaction. Nicole Wilson.
Miss Mouse Ears.
You just finished the Mouse Protein Test
four months ago.
In corporate time that's like five minutes.
Yeah. That's just long enough
for them to forget about us.
We have to start the Phase One Trial.
They have to say yes.
Truth? I think most of them wish
they'd never heard of you or HER-2.
Yeah? Tell me something I don't know.
- Hello.
- Denny, nice to see you.
Unnecessary. We have everything we need
to make our decision.
I just want to remind you
of a couple of things first.
HER-2 is the most promising drug
this company has ever seen.
I stood right here and I did something
that has never been done before.
I shrank a cancer tumor
with six drops of our drug.
No poison, no chemo. Just the antibody.
Well, it's a big leap from shrinking a tumor
in a dish to curing cancer, Doctor.
This isn't a cure. It's a treatment to shrink
cancer tumors and make them inactive.
Which is better than chemo and radiation
because it has no side effects.
I wish we could know without
an official study that the drug will work.
But if we test it and have a bad result,
it will be the Interferon disaster
all over again.
It's the only cancer drug we ever developed
and it almost ruined us.
You developed that
based on no hard evidence.
I have shown you real data.
Real data that HER-2 can work.
We can't base our decision
just on the science.
We have a responsibility to the company.
And spending millions on HER-2 means we
aren't spending it on more promising drugs.
When you put all the pieces together,
the potential downside is just too severe.
Well, clearly, you don't have anyone
with cancer in your life.
How lucky for you. Well, I do.
I speak to cancer patients
and their families every day,
and I hope for their sake that one day
there's a better treatment out there
than the current slash and burn
that exists at the moment!
When I was a kid,
I watched a doctor save my father's life
and I knew in that moment
that I wanted to do what he did
because when you save someone's life,
you're not just saving them,
you're saving everyone around them.
And now, when I look into a woman's eyes
and tell her that her cancer is terminal
and she tells me,
"What other treatments are available?"
and I tell her, "We don't have any,"
I know that we do.
- But you don't know HER-2 will work.
- I do know! I know!
Don't throw this chance away!
Maybe you've been sitting
behind a desk for too long.
Maybe I've been on the front lines
longer than I should have,
but for God's sake, don't forget who we are!
We're not businessmen.
We're doctors.
Approve the Phase One Trial.
- You guys are fast.
- We could still use some help.
I was working on my masterpiece.
You look beautiful.
Not too bad for someone who wasn't
supposed to make it till Christmas, huh?
- Let's put this right in the middle.
- Like that.
That's us!
So pretty.
What are you doing?
Loving you.
- But, Mom, I've got soccer.
- Mother's prerogative.
- Ellie?
- Hi. Do I know you?
- I'm Josh.
- Thank you.
- I'm meeting a friend.
- Yeah, me.
- Kate set us up.
- Oh, gosh.
- Look, I'm sorry. I don't date.
- You do eat?
- Look, Josh...
- We're here, so why not?
We'll eat fast. We don't even have to talk.
The cancer is back. I'm scheduling
another round of chemotherapy.
No.
No more chemo. We've decided.
It's a quality of life issue.
I understand. I'm very sorry.
There is an outside chance.
A colleague is going to be testing
an experimental drug.
I'd like to send your slides.
Whatever.
Hey. I've been waiting for you.
I got some news. The board voted yes.
- We're moving to Phase One?
- Yeah, but there's trouble.
- They put Reinhart in charge.
- Reinhart?
Why? He doesn't even believe in HER-2.
- But you know what, a go is a go, so...
- Let me finish, Denny.
He's bringing in these so-called
"thought leaders" to head the study.
- He's not including you.
- But it's my study.
It's Genentech's study
and they put Reinhart in charge.
I'm sorry. I went to bat for you,
but it's his call.
Hang on a second.
You have to change his mind.
They want superstars,
breast cancer specialists who've run
these big clinical tests before. You haven't.
Come on. You need me.
This isn't just me protecting my turf here.
This is me
protecting everything we've worked for.
There are three arms of the study.
San Francisco, New York, Los Angeles.
I'll go back to him,
see if I can get him to give you LA.
I've already set up a network of doctors
who're gonna refer their patients to me,
- so tell him that.
- Keep screening for participants.
I'll see what I can do.
- Hello.
- Barbara Bradfield?
- Yes.
- Yes, this is Dr. Slamon at UCLA.
I'd like to talk to you
about joining the HER-2 Trial.
What's HER-2?
It's an experimental drug.
Dr. Brown sent me your slides.
Right.
Thanks, but we're leaving in the morning
for Mexico. I'm trying a food cure.
- All due respect...
- I'm not expecting a cure,
just some quality time with my family.
Ms. Bradfield, if you'd just delay
your trip for a day I think I can...
Does this trial involve chemo?
- Some, yes.
- I'm not interested.
I refuse to die bald and throwing up.
Good luck with your study.
Good luck to you, too.
- Slamon.
- You're back in.
- LA is yours.
- Reinhardt signed off?
Yeah. Now, go home and get some rest.
You're going to need it.
Yes! Yes!
- Once again, Blake saves the day.
- Oh, God.
I owe him big time.
- How was your day?
- Good.
- Did you find anyone?
- One woman, best candidate I've ever seen.
She's not interested, though.
Going to Mexico for a food cure.
- There's a misnomer for you.
- Did you talk to her?
As much as I could.
She's looking at the end of her life,
so how she spends that time is her call.
But, you know, I can't get over the feeling
I might be able to help her.
And selfishly, it's bad for the study
because I get 15 women
and I need to make them all count.
So, I don't know.
Hey.
It's not always gonna be like this,
these crazy hours.
Yes, it will. But that's okay.
We just miss you.
- Hello?
- Hello, Barbara, this is Dr. Slamon.
I'm sorry to be calling this early.
Barbara, don't go to Mexico.
It's a death sentence.
I think I can save your life.
- They're all here.
- All 15?
All 15. So, as we say in show business,
- break a leg.
- I'll see you out there.
No. I have another ball to plan.
You can take this from here.
Hey, Lilly. I just wanted to say,
you know, without you, this would...
Thank you.
I really mean it. Thank you so much.
- Good morning.
Welcome to the Phase One kickoff party.
- I'm very happy to see all of you.
- Not as happy as we are to see you.
So, the drug you'll be taking
finally has a name,
Herceptin, which is a combination
of "Her" from HER-2,
and "ceptin" from intercept,
which is what the drug is designed to do,
to intercept growth signals
from reaching the cancer cells
so they don't grow.
It's pretty simple when you think about it.
Now, for the next three months,
we'll be meeting here every Tuesday at 9:00
for the infusion
and a checkup to monitor your progress.
First two weeks,
you'll be receiving cisplatin,
a traditional chemotherapy drug.
Every third week, you'll get the Herceptin.
Now, since cisplatin is a chemotherapy,
you'll have the traditional side effects
like fatigue and nausea.
But on the weeks you receive the Herceptin,
you'll feel great.
No side effects.
Finally, I want to thank all of you
so much for coming here.
I appreciate your hope and your belief
and your sacrifice.
- Thank you.
- I don't take that lightly.
Okay, any questions before we begin?
Yeah, I do. Just one.
I hope everybody here is hungry.
I know. The baker was gay,
so he hadn't seen boobs in a while.
My nipples aren't black like that.
Well, they're not.
Dr. Slamon.
I'm late for a consult.
You'll have to call my office.
Please. I drove three hours to see you.
You'll have to make an appointment.
I'm sorry.
My daughter participated in the
Mouse Protein Experiment, Nicole Wilson?
Nicole, right. Miss Mouse Ears.
She was the very first one.
Yes, exactly. Well, her doctor
told us you're testing your new drug.
- Right.
- I'd like you to include her.
Believe me, I would if I could,
but she just doesn't meet the criteria.
Well, nonsense.
She's a perfect candidate.
One shot kept her alive for two years.
- I'm sorry, Miss...
- Aldredge.
Ms. Aldredge, right. But the eligibility
requirements are very strict.
Well, then don't put her in it.
Just give her the drug.
The FDA accounts for every dose.
I'm very sorry.
My daughter is dying!
You have the power to save her.
I don't.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Aldredge. I do understand
what you're going through, but...
Have you lost a child, Dr. Slamon?
Then don't presume to know
what I'm going through.
I promised my husband as he lay dying
that I would take care of our little girl.
For 24 years, I have kept that promise,
and you will not stand in my way
of keeping it now.
I can't help you.
Then get your superior
out here immediately.
There is no superior.
It's my study and I don't have a choice.
If I break the rules,
they're going to shut it down.
She's only 28. She has two little boys.
She's all I've got, Dr. Slamon.
Please don't take her from me.
Please help me. I can't lose her, too.
Dr. Slamon, we need you right now, sir.
I'm very sorry.
Hey.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Hi.
Will you show me that picture
that you drew for me?
I just really want to see it.
Okay, Daddy.
You know, Barbara,
maybe this week will be better.
Maybe the chemo won't make you so sick.
Well, that would be nice,
but I don't think it's in the cards.
Hey. You never know.
If I could just get home, I wouldn't care.
Really? You don't like puking your guts out
into your purse at the mall?
Must you be so graphic?
Well, I'm just being real.
I mean, that's really what it is, right?
I mean, nothing's more real than this,
this and puking.
And it really does just cut through
all the crap.
Yeah, well, next week will be better.
We get the Herceptin. No side effects.
No, I am so ready.
Do you hear that, cancer?
You're going down.
You make this all worthwhile.
Sorry.
- Hold on a sec.
- What? Well, what are you doing?
It's been months. I want to see you.
You want to see a scar? You're a freak.
I love every inch of you,
including the breast that isn't there.
Sex with me in the dark,
or sex by yourself with the light on,
your choice.
How about a flashlight?
- Come here.
- Does that hurt?
- No.
I just, I don't know, like looking at it.
Just reminds you that you're sick.
I don't need a stinking tumor
to remind me that I'm sick.
Let's think good thoughts today, Tish.
Positive energy creates healing.
Wow. Is that what I've been doing wrong
my whole life?
Tina, do you have an herb for that
with some aromatherapy?
No, but we could do
some guided meditation.
That's just too complicated for me.
- Good morning.
Okay, so after two weeks of chemo,
who's ready
for their first dose of Herceptin?
- I am!
- Me!
- Okay. All right, let's start with you, Sally.
- Sally?
- How's that cough?
- It's almost gone.
That's good.
- It's yellow.
- All right.
I'm gonna get more than you.
Hey, Dr. Slamon. It's Fran Visco,
President of
the National Breast Cancer Coalition.
Yeah, I remember you. You gave me a grant.
You were one of the very few.
Hey, do you mind walking?
- I have a patient.
- Oh, not at all.
Wow, you have a good memory.
That was over eight years ago.
You know, I've been getting a lot of calls,
and I know you can't really speak about it,
but how's Phase One going?
A lot of calls?
Yeah, the breast cancer community
is very tight-knit, and so they talk.
- Off the record, it's going well.
- So there will be a Phase Two?
Off the record, yes.
Good. Before you start
planning Phase Three, call me.
You're gonna need
a perspective that those scientists
who haven't been through that cancer mill
don't have themselves.
Thank you, Fran. And I will call you.
So, I bought this
to boost our immune systems.
You mix it once a day in hot water,
and you drink it down, just like tea.
- What is it?
- Dried sea horses.
- Sally's late again.
- Forget the cancer. This'll kill me right here.
You know,
I know I'm always joking with you,
but I swear to God, your tumor has shrunk.
- It has, hasn't it? It is, right?
- It has.
- Let me see. Let me see.
- Look.
Oh, my God. It's shrunk!
Now, Tina, I know you didn't
have time to leave the hospital
and go find some sea horses. What is this?
I mean, that came out of the back of a dog.
No, it did.
Sally passed away this morning.
Not from the drug,
but as a result of her advanced cancer.
Carol will be in to get you started.
- I'm all right.
- It wasn't your fault.
Her death, no.
- What happens next, though, that's all me.
- What's all you?
I put them all in one room,
so they wouldn't feel alone.
Now they'll know when one of them dies.
Great planning.
- You couldn't have known.
- But I should have.
Every single one of them
has stage-four cancer.
Some of them are lucky to be alive.
I chose the room, the chairs, the program.
I just spent so much time
trying to get it right.
You didn't know. Next time you will.
Tell that to the women
who are looking at the empty chair.
Kate! Turn down the music.
What are you doing here?
I was in the neighborhood,
thought I'd fall by,
see if you want to go to Vegas this weekend.
And while we're there,
get married.
- Ellie.
- Josh.
I told you,
marriage is about happily ever after,
- and I don't know that that applies to me.
- Maybe the cancer's gone.
Not the cancer, my cancer.
And, yes, it's gone,
- but it can come back.
- If it does, we'll deal with it.
I love you, baby, but I can't marry you.
- You really mean that.
- But it doesn't change anything.
For you. Me, I want a future.
No matter how long that might be.
I know it's bad news
or you would have told me on the phone.
Well, actually, the news is good.
Your response to the Herceptin
is more successful
than I ever thought possible.
It not only stopped your tumor
from growing, Barbara,
it made it disappear.
- My tumor's gone?
- Your tumor's gone.
Now, you still have cancer,
but this is an exceptional result,
amazing, even.
I'm sorry, I was...
I was expecting the worst.
Well, it's nice to get
some good news for a change.
Yeah.
Now, here's where we are.
We're almost done with Phase One,
and I'm inviting you
to continue treatment in Phase Two.
- Whatever you say, I'm there.
- Good.
Now, you're gonna have to sit tight
for about six weeks until we begin.
- But I'll still be getting my Herceptin?
- No.
I can't give it outside of the study.
That's FDA rules.
We have to apply to begin Phase Two.
Don't worry, now. It's just a formality.
What if my tumor comes back?
If it does, I don't think
it's gonna grow fast enough to be a danger.
And once you start the Herceptin again,
it'll shrink. It'll be fine.
I have to ask you not to tell the others.
Not all of them
are gonna be continuing to Phase Two.
- Who's not coming?
- I need to tell them first.
Yeah.
Yeah, of course.
Fresh from my garden. Echinacea, for colds.
- Works like a charm.
- Thank you.
I know I'm here for my official results,
but I already know.
- Dr. Slamon, I feel so much stronger.
- You are doing better.
But?
I'm sorry, Tina.
You won't be moving on to Phase Two.
Not moving on?
But you said last week I was improving.
And you are.
But for the study, for its ultimate success,
I've been given
a set of standards by the FDA.
I need to narrow the group down
to the ones who are having
the most clear and measurable response.
That's me. I've gained weight,
and I'm not in pain at all anymore.
- You can see that.
- I know that.
But the goal, and we talked about this,
has been to get Herceptin approved.
Now, in my heart,
I want you to continue, Tina.
But in science,
it comes down to the numbers.
And for the next phase,
and I'm sorry, but your numbers,
they're not high enough.
Please. Please, Dr. Slamon.
I have three children and a husband.
Look, we'll pay whatever it costs,
and nobody has to know.
I wish I could do that.
I can't.
I've never begged for anything in my life.
But I'm begging you, Doctor, for my life.
I'm sorry, for you,
for your family, I'm sorry.
Sorry. How many... How many lucky ones?
Five.
Well, I am happy for them.
Thank you, Doctor.
- How could you do that?
- It's part of my job.
You just sent her home to die.
That's how it works.
- That's not fair.
- No, it's not.
- That's not right.
- It's not a question of right or wrong.
I don't think I can do this anymore.
But we will.
We have to stop meeting like this.
- Fran, what are you doing here?
- I was speaking to a group of nurses.
And you? Yeah, that's right. You work here.
Hey. You were supposed to call me
about Phase Three.
And I will, as soon as I hear
that we're moving on.
- We just finished Phase Two.
- Six months ago.
I told you. I'm watching. I'm listening.
Trust me.
When I get the go-ahead, I will call you.
I don't want to be notified.
I want to be involved.
- I hear you loud and clear.
- Okay. Call.
- Do I have a deal?
- We have a deal.
- Call! Okay.
- I will.
I called you five times.
When were you gonna call me back?
When I had an answer.
You just called me yesterday.
Yeah, and last week
and the week before that,
and the month before that,
and five months before that!
When are we gonna start Phase Three?
When Reinhart is done designing it
and when the board decides to pay for it,
- which at this point is not a sure thing.
- That is ridiculous.
Herceptin works.
We proved it in Phase One and Phase Two.
Why do I sound like a broken record here?
Yes, Denny, One and Two were successful,
but we still have not proven anything!
That is what Phase Three is for.
Acceptable clinical proof!
- That's my point!
- Don't yell at me!
Then get the board off its overly-cautious
ass and get us the go-ahead.
You know what, don't lecture me, either.
I'm not lecturing you, Blake.
For crying out loud, how many times
do we have to go through this? I have...
Barbara and Dean are waiting.
Sorry I'm late.
I feel good. Please don't tell me I'm not.
You're cancer-free.
What?
There's not one sign of cancer in your body.
- None.
- How?
Part of it's the Herceptin.
The rest, I don't know.
- But the cancer's still there...
- Barbara...
- it only takes one cell.
- You're cancer-free.
I read the results myself,
and I made them retest.
Cancer-free.
Free of cancer!
Cancer-free!
All I wanted to hear were those words,
and I never thought I would!
And now I don't know what to do!
What do I do?
Well, to be honest, all of the other women
responded like I thought they would,
they improved,
but your cancer's gone, completely.
So, as for what I would do, just be grateful.
And by the way,
you don't have to come here anymore.
Except to say hello.
- Do you think she misses us?
- I know she does.
Just like we miss her.
- Can I put it on the tree?
- I was just going to ask.
- Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Mom.
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
I'm sorry. After four years of remission,
your cancer is back.
The cancer has spread
to your lymph nodes and your liver.
You'll need to get your affairs in order.
Wow. People actually say that.
"Get your affairs in order."
How long do I have?
Four months, maybe five.
How about chemo?
You've run that course. I'm sorry.
You mean to tell me,
in this world-class research hospital,
that's my only option? How can that be?
Well, there is one possibility.
It's a Phase Three Trial
and if approved, it'll start soon,
but you have to be HER-2 positive.
- Am I?
- I don't know.
But we'll find out.
- Carl.
- My afternoon's all booked.
I'll make it fast. I just have a few ideas
about the trial design.
You've never designed a drug trial before.
No, but I know more
about Herceptin than anyone.
Yeah, thank you. I've got this under control.
Come on, Carl. Please, just hear me out.
To be honest, Denny,
I don't want or need your input.
Look. I am the one
who's been in the trenches,
trying to find the women that you need
to enroll in your mess of a trial,
but I can't because your requirements
are too strict.
- In your opinion.
- It's not just me.
Ask your "thought leaders." You are
running Phase Three into the ground!
- We're done here.
- Okay.
- If we could just simplify...
- I said we're done!
When is the last time you told a patient
she was going to die?
Monica Stein. Cindy Lopez. Jane Hart.
Sarah, Joan, Linda.
Those are just the women
that I had to tell this week!
All of them are HER-2 positive,
and all of them were excluded from the trial
because they've all had
one too many courses of chemo!
Well, it shouldn't make a difference!
They should be eligible.
Is there room in there for two?
As long as you don't flip me over
like last time.
O ye of little faith.
There. See? I'm not a total klutz.
It's over.
The trial's gonna fail.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is.
Reinhart's design will see to that.
Twelve years.
Twelve years I've been fighting it, for what?
A drug company
that just wishes I'd go away?
Promises I can't keep to patients
who are counting on me?
All the time I missed
with you and the kids.
All for nothing.
You're my long-distance runner.
You know what you're gonna do?
You're gonna go to sleep,
and you're gonna wake up,
and you're gonna fight your fight
until you win.
That's who you are.
- Hello.
- It took a year and a half,
but we're back on track.
- Reinhart has been transferred.
- Wait, who's taking his place?
I don't know, but get this,
whoever it is has marching orders
to save the study.
Can you believe it? I'll call you later.
- Yes!
- Yeah, I'm calling to see
if I've been approved for the study.
My name's Ellie Jackson. No, I'll wait.
What do you mean,
no one's looked at my paperwork?
You've had it for two months.
Yes, I know it's July,
but I'm not on vacation.
I have to be approved
before the study starts,
so that I can start on the first day.
Because I don't have that many days left.
Thank you.
Okay, I'll cut to the chase.
We're trying to save the Phase Three Trial,
and we don't have enough participants,
and we're hoping you can help.
So, let's see, I could write a cover letter
and send out the information packets
to the 3,000 names on my Rolodex
in exchange for which you'll give me
and another breast cancer advocate
a say in the trial design.
Yes.
And compassionate access to the drug,
for the women
who do not qualify for the trial.
- We'd like to do that, but...
- No buts.
There are women out there
with no other medical option,
except for an experimental drug,
which does seem to work,
but they can't have access to it.
And the FDA allows compassionate access
in Phase Three studies.
Even so, there's a very limited amount
of the drug available.
Make some more.
Tumor cell is sort of blanketed
by the HER-2.
If you would come up with, kind of,
your top-three priorities, that would help.
I don't have one good slide here.
I can't believe that.
Come on. Let's go.
We got to get more of these out. 16.
Hi. I'm here for the Phase Three trial.
It took me all summer long,
but I just got approved.
Ellie Jackson. Welcome.
We're happy to have you,
except you're early.
I can just go get a cup of coffee.
No, I didn't mean today.
We don't start until next week.
- That'll be too late.
- It's just a week.
The trial was just approved.
We aren't ready yet. Come back next week.
I have been chasing people
and committees around this hospital
for three months
trying to get approved for this study,
to save my life.
And every time I manage
to get somebody's attention,
they can't help me
because they're not ready.
They don't have my paperwork
or they're moving, or they're on vacation,
or they're sitting at home
waiting for the cable guy.
I get it.
Life goes on. People have jobs.
Things happen.
Well, cancer happened to me.
And I'll be damned if I'm gonna die.
Not because there weren't people
here to help me,
but because they weren't ready.
I'm dying in front of you right now.
And if you have help to give me,
I need it now.
I need it right now!
Find Dr. Slamon.
Thank you.
Hi, Ellie. Dr. Slamon.
- I'm sorry about the scene out there.
- Don't apologize. Are you kidding?
Do you know how many fits
I've had to throw around here myself?
It's ridiculous.
All right.
It's official.
You are the first subject
in Phase Three. Congratulations.
- Thank you, Dr. Slamon.
- No, Ellie.
Thank you.
Carol's gonna be in shortly, all right?
- Okay.
Congratulations, runners and walkers,
you are halfway there.
Please visit the water tables,
and we'll see you at the finish line.
- Have you seen Lilly?
- I guess she's around here somewhere.
Dr. Slamon?
- Hi.
- Hello.
I just wanted to tell you, thank you.
- Well, thank you. Thank you.
- Thank you so much.
Dr. Slamon. Thank you for fighting for us.
- All these people know Dad?
- Yeah, and they're thanking him.
- For what?
- Helping them or someone they love.
Dr. Slamon, I just wanted to say thanks
for giving my mom more time.
- Who's your mom?
- Nicole Wilson.
Well, I think I should be thanking you.
Your mother was the first.
We wouldn't be here without her.
- Thank you, Doctor. Thank you.
- Thank you so much.
Hey, buddy.
- This is Slamon.
- I'm coming down today.
Meet me outside your building at 4:30.
Don't be late.
Blake, why don't you just
come to my office?
Just be there.
Look, you're late. I got a plane to catch.
Look, I read all the data last night.
I wanted you to hear it from me.
- Well?
- Congratulations.
We proved Herceptin officially works.
More than anyone ever imagined,
except for you.
I got to get to DC.
I'm showing the results to the FDA.
- Do you need me to go? I can go.
- Denny, I think I can handle this one.
- Don't tell anyone but Donna.
- What about Lilly?
And Lilly.
- Good work.
- You, too.
What are you doing home?
- I just saw Blake.
- Did you invite him over for...
I love you, Mom.
All right! Yeah!
Yeah!
Run!