== Sync, corrected by Alice ==
== www.addic7ed.com ==
[ Jazz music playing ]
♪ Just in time
♪ I found you just in time
♪ before you came, my time
♪ was running low
♪ I was lost
♪ the losing dice were tossed
♪ my bridges all were crossed
♪ nowhere to go
♪ now you're here
♪ now I know
just where I'm going ♪
♪ no more doubt or fear
♪ I found my way
♪ for love came just in time
♪ you found me just in time
♪ and changed my lonely life
♪ that lucky day
♪ now you're here
♪ now I know
just where I'm going ♪
♪ no more doubt or fear
♪ I found my way
♪ for love came just in time
♪ you found me just in time
♪ and changed my lonely life
♪ that lucky day
[ Laughter ]
Richard: "I fell for you
the moment I saw you...
All those years ago
at a party in Hollywood."
[ Up-tempo music playing ]
"You were everything
I ever wanted."
[ Splash ]
"And even when you looked at me
with utter disdain,
I still thought
you were just luscious."
[ Birds chirping ]
"With my undying love --
Richard."
Elsa, put this in the post,
would you?
And if you see my wife,
tell her I'm going to lie down.
[ Sighs ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
Joe: Places, everybody, please.
We're going for a take.
I've always loved
getting Richard's letters.
He writes so beautifully,
he could've been a writer.
Could've been,
should've been.
I wrote every day
for -- what -- 20 years.
Even wrote today.
Thank you.
We were destined
to meet.
"Cleopatra."
Most people don't remember,
but we started
shooting the film in England
without dear Richard.
And then
filming suddenly stopped
because Elizabeth
fell terribly ill.
Yes, I had to have
a tracheotomy.
Had to buy a 69-carat diamond
to cover that scar.
[ Chuckles ]
Of course, I'd seen her before,
at a party in Hollywood.
Yes, apparently,
I was very cool.
Suddenly, I got a phone call --
"Fly to Rome."
I was terrified.
Excuse me.
Where is everyone?
Am I
on the wrong stage?
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ Talking continues ]
Joe: Ah.
Elizabeth, you look rapturous.
Uh, listen,
this is your first encounter
with this young upstart
from Rome,
so make sure
he knows who you are.
I don't want to see "smitten"
right away, okay?
All right,
places, everybody.
Places, everybody, please,
and we're going for a take.
Excuse me,
Mr. Mankiewicz.
Mm-hmm.
Where would you like me?
Oh. Richard,
I'm so sorry.
Yes, if you can enter
from over here.
Fine.
Um, I thought
I might pause around here.
That's wonderful.
Yes, and, again, sorry.
Won't happen again.
Uh, get me a fill there,
please.
Uh, Richard.
It's gonna
take a minute.
Could you do me a favor?
Keep Elizabeth occupied.
- Sure.
- Good man.
Hello.
In case
you haven't guessed,
- I'm Mark Antony.
- Richard Burton.
Oh, I'd shake your hands,
but my nails.
Oh, yes -- likewise.
Has anyone ever told you
you're a very pretty girl?
Elizabeth: No,
I didn't like him right away.
I think she thought me, uh,
terribly forward.
Uh, I was thoroughly confused
by Elizabeth
when I first met her.
She, uh, was a creature
I'd never...
Never encountered before.
Richard:
Where's my brother Ifor?
Richard.
Everything okay?
Find out where Miss Taylor
is dining tonight.
You promised to meet
Sybil and the kids for dinner.
I said, find out where
Miss Taylor is dining tonight.
[ Indistinct talking ]
Driver:
Grazie, signor.
Well,
this should be the place.
Why is it so hard for us
to find where she's dining
but the press
already know?
'Cause she bloody tells them.
That's why.
[ Mid-tempo music playing ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Woman: No.
Woman # 2: Why?
The table
next to Miss Taylor's, please.
Signor,
it's impossible.
[ Sighs ]
The table
next to Miss Taylor's, please.
Of course.
Woman: Oh, my God.
Waiter:
Ah, signor, scusi.
We have a much better table
for you right here.
Ah, thank you.
Follow me.
It's right here.
This way.
[ Laughter ]
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
He's supposed to be
an orator --
the great shakespearean actor
Richard Burton.
[ Laughter ]
But, please...
Has anyone ever told you
you're a very pretty girl?
He said that?
You know, Ifor,
I had the misfortune
of meeting
the rudest actress today,
who walked away
in the middle of my sentence,
obviously incapable
of recognizing
a shakespearean pause,
because I said to her,
"Has anyone ever told you
you're a very pretty girl?"
Then I paused,
and she walked away...
Before I could add,
"Well, they would be a fool.
"You are not a pretty girl,
though you once were.
"You are now
a beautiful woman
"with the depths of the ocean
in your violet eyes
"and the promise of a ripe plum
"and your soft, firm lips
and your spilling,
white-hot bosom."
But, of course, she didn't
get to hear a damn word of that.
He is a bit rude,
but [Inhales] that voice...
Well, I'm glad
that's over.
Sara:
He should be a singer.
Oh, mother, haven't we got
enough of those already?
Sybil: Ifor!
Ifor!
He's due on set
in 20 minutes!
Richard, come on.
Wake up.
[ Mutters ]
Where the hell were you, Ifor?
What time did you two come home?
[ Grunts ]
We ran into Elizabeth Taylor
at a restaurant.
Richard tried to be friendly,
but she was rude.
[ Grunts ]
Then he really
started drinking.
Richard tried
to be friendly?
Man: And places.
"Cleopatra," scene 142,
take 4.
Joe: And...Action.
Oh, Mark Antony.
How prompt of you.
If I had not been,
it would've been forgivable.
Damn, sorry again --
unforgivable. Sorry.
All right. Cut!
And we're gonna go
right back in.
Man:
Back to places, please.
I think that Richard and I
should run our lines a moment.
Sure.
In private.
If I'm not mistaken,
I think you might need
a little bit of this.
[ Groans ]
Vodka.
Hair of the dog.
Yeah, I need
the dog's whole coat.
That bad?
Won't you join me?
I have heard it said
it's bad to drink alone.
I already am,
though not quite so much vodka.
[ Sighs ]
So, shall we
run those lines?
Oh, no, I think
we'll both be fine now.
So, is there anything else
I can do for you?
[ Sighs ]
Is that
what you thought?
Another notch on the belt?
Please.
I've heard all the stories
of the Welsh Don Juan --
all the leading ladies
except Julie Andrews.
Well, if she can resist you,
then so can I!
Oh, you misunderstand.
You're quite safe with me.
I never go after
dumpy women.
Please leave.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Go easy, Richard.
"Go easy"?
Oh, I'll go easy,
all right.
Oh, here she comes --
the Queen of the Nile.
Hi.
You must be Sybil.
I've heard
so much about you.
I'm Elizabeth.
This is my husband, Eddie.
Won't you join us?
Oh, God, no.
I know how hard it is
for a devoted couple
to get a little private time.
Enjoy.
Ciao.
Sara: Elizabeth.
[ Door closes ]
What now?
It's time to go to work.
What scene is it?
It's your first love scene
with Antony.
A love scene?
With him?!
[ Sighs ]
Richard:
A love scene with her?
[ Sighs ]
Well, it's not exactly
coal mining, is it?
Least you know where you are
with a seam of coal.
[ Indistinct talking ]
And places.
[ Talking continues ]
Joe: Are we ready?
Sorry, Joe.
May I just please have a moment
to compose myself?
Certainly, Richard.
Quiet, everyone.
So, now
you're a method actor.
No.
But now I have to act
that I am in love with you...
And that
you are in love with me,
and that's not easy.
Help me.
Please.
That I could love you,
an exquisite Queen -- simple.
But that you could love me,
a jobbing soldier...
[ Gasps ]
Are you staring
at my chest?
Why not?
It's the very heart of you.
It's everything you promise --
love, sex, and nurture.
And I'm gonna pretend
that it's all mine.
[ Clears throat ]
Excuse me, Richard.
Uh, I think you're supposed to
finish the speech
and then kiss her.
[ Laughs ]
Oh.
Sorry, Joe.
[ Laughs ]
I'll do much better
next time.
[ Laughs ]
[ All murmuring ]
Who's gonna tell Sybil
this time?
Forget about, Sybil.
What about Eddie?
[ Indistinct talking ]
Oh, Mr. fisher.
I think you'll find Miss Taylor
in makeup.
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ Talking continues ]
Mrs. Burton.
I think you'll find
Richard's in wardrobe.
Over this way.
Oh, thank you.
So, you have plans
for dinner tonight?
Well, I thought
we'd go somewhere quiet.
"We"?
"Us," stupid.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Whatever you say, dumpy.
[ Chuckles softly ]
Oh!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
What the hell is this?
Mr. Zanuck,
let me be clear --
our department had nothing to do
with these photographs.
Who in the hell shot this?
Well, it's just kids
on motor scooters.
Rome is infested with them.
They call them "paparazzi."
"Paparazzi"?
It means
"little buzzing insects."
I-I think Fellini
actually coined the word.
Like I care.
I have a publicity department
precisely
so that photos like these
do not, not, not get published.
Capiche?
Yes, sir.
- Fix it.
- Yes, sir.
This was the scandal.
It wasn't just
that we were having an affair.
No, movie stars had affairs
all the time.
Before us, they never really wrote
about affairs between married people.
And, of course, we were married,
and we had children.
[ Laughing ]
I was the monster
that broke up
America's sweethearts.
She's talking about Eddie fisher
and Debbie Reynolds.
They know
who I'm talking about, Richard.
And, of course,
Eddie had been best man
at Mike Todd's wedding,
so...
So shoot me.
Do I sound defensive?
Because I'm not.
Eddie chased me, and I was
stupid enough to give in.
Yes.
And you were vulnerable
after Mike's death.
Besides...
How were you to know
that I was going to come along?
[ Laughs ]
Like you had any idea of what
was going to hit you, Buster.
With her?!
You think I'll stay
and have this pushed in my face
every day?
But, Sybil --
Don't!
No more lies!
I've put up with years
of your wandering.
But at least you didn't
make a fool of me in public.
I look at these
and can only imagine
you think
I'm a worthless idiot!
[ Paparazzi shouting ]
Have you heard
about the news, Eddie?!
I went to New York
to do a show.
Now I'm back
to see my wife.
Have you seen the pictures
in the paper, Eddie?!
Guys...
What about pictures?!
...forget about it, huh?
You never seen
publicity?
[ Indistinct shouting ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
You would!
No, don't, don't.
No, no, please.
Hold your liquor.
Eddie!
The prodigal returns.
Come.
Sit.
Have a drink.
Here.
We've just been
talking about you.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm sleeping
with your wife.
What'd you say?
Yes, it's been
in all the papers.
I'm sleeping
with Elizabeth.
Liz?
Ed...
In fact, Eddie,
I'm glad you're here,
because I have a question
for Elizabeth,
and --
and it does concern you.
Dear Elizabeth,
Queen of the Nile,
here we both are, two schoolboys
begging for your hand,
and my question to you
is this...
Who do you love --
him or me?
- What are you doing here?
- Richard.
No, serious question.
It deserves a serious answer.
So, Elizabeth,
answer us now.
Who do you love --
Eddie or me?
I can't hear you,
Elizabeth!
Who do you love --
Me or Eddie?!
[ Sighs ]
You.
A little louder, please,
for the room.
I love you.
[ Sighs ]
[ People murmuring ]
Sara: Elizabeth!
Elizabeth,
not that I'm counting,
but if I'm not mistaken,
you just ended -- what --
your fourth marriage?
Who's counting?
It might be a record
for a 29-year-old.
What am I
supposed to do?
I love the man --
end of story.
And cut.
All right, places, please.
All right, then,
I think we can --
where...
Woman:
Miss Taylor.
You let them leave?
[ Tires squeal ]
"His flashing eyes,
his floating hair.
"Weave a circle
round him thrice,
"and close your eyes
with holy dread.
"For he on honeydew
hath fed
and drunk
the milk of paradise."
Who knew
Italy could be so hot?
[ Sighs ]
Last one upstairs
is a goof.
Goof? What kind of a word
is "goof"?
I can see we're gonna have to
teach Miss Taylor
some better English!
We could go
to the pool.
I don't need a pool.
I've got a whole ocean in you.
[ Chuckles ]
"License my roving hands.
"Let them go...
"Before, behind,
between, above, below.
"Oh, my America,
my new-found-land, my kingdom,
safeliest
when with one man manned."
[ Sighs ]
More!
I want more.
"More."
I'm starting to feel
that may be your favorite word.
[ Laughs ]
Would you prefer "less"?
No.
[ Laughs ]
[ Sighs ]
No electricity,
and it's as moldy
as a rugby player's sock.
- Yes, but it's ours, which
makes it perfect. - Perfect.
[ Laughs ]
Miss Taylor!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Turn this way, please!
Look over here, please!
You call yourselves
journalists?!
Why the hell do you want
more photographs of us?!
Elizabeth,
come on inside!
One picture, please.
Please!
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ Laughing ]
You flashed them
your bum.
We'll see if they'll run that.
I don't think so.
Are you kidding me?
That's going to be the most
popular postcard in Rome.
[ Laughing ] No.
Miss Taylor's derrière,
sir. Mmm.
Screw it.
They want a show,
let's give them a show.
[ Indistinct shouting ]
[ Bells jingle ]
Signora Taylor.
Wow!
Que bellissima.
Come va?
- Ah, Signor Burton.
- Gianni.
[ Speaking Italian ]
What can I
help you with?
Hmm.
Richard...
Look how beautiful.
Well,
since we're here...
Really?
Can I choose something?
Anything you like.
Anything?
For you, Elizabeth,
anything.
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Oh.
[ Gasps ]
Thank you, Gianni.
Niente.
I'm the one you should
be thanking, not him.
Thank you.
[ Laughing ]
Elizabeth:
It's always about the jewels.
Men just don't realize it
till it's too late
and we have them all.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Signor Burton, your wife
attempted suicide, yes?
What did you say?
Suicide, yes!
Elizabeth,
I'm sorry.
I have to go
to Sybil.
[ Shouting continues ]
Know why she did it?
- Mr. Burton?
- You know I love you.
Mr. Burton,
were you having some problems?
[ Speaking Italian ]
Why did she do it?
Where are you
going now?
Katie.
[ Sighs ]
Off to bed.
Where were you?
Lost in the middle
of an ocean.
"Lost in the middle
of an ocean"?
What kind of poeting bollocks
is that?
You have a family here
that's drowning!
I love Elizabeth.
Tough.
You're already taken.
We were meant
for each other.
That's what she said
to Conrad Hilton,
Michael Wilding, Mike Todd,
and Eddie bloody Fisher.
Look around you, man.
This is your family.
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Door opens ]
[ Footsteps approaching ]
Well, she's alive.
But I fear I am dead.
I can't.
I'm sorry,
but it's as simple as that.
I can't.
[ Breathing shakily ]
[ Exhales sharply ]
I won't live
without you!
Elizabeth!
[ Crying ]
Elizabeth?
[ Sniffles ]
Elizabeth!
[ Crying ]
You can go.
[ Sniffles ]
This shouldn't take
too long.
Don't talk like that.
You know I can't turn my back
on my responsibilities.
[ Sniffles ]
That's why
I'm removing myself.
I don't want to be
your responsibility.
Don't.
[ Sniffles ]
I already have.
[ Crying ]
Elizabeth?
I already have.
How many were in here?
Elizabeth,
how many did you take?
[ Crying ]
[ Sniffles ]
All.
All of them.
Come here. Come here.
[ Moans ]
Come here, now.
[ Crying ]
Come here.
[ Woman speaking Italian
over P.A.]
Help me!
[ Doctors speaking Italian ]
Somebody,
please help me!
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Groans ]
[ Woman speaking Italian
over P.A. ]
Mr. Burton,
she will be fine.
But she does not want
to see you.
Joe:
How you doing?
Almost ready.
That's...
Not what I was asking.
Only one more scene,
and we're done.
Joe.
Mm-hmm?
When you wrote this,
were you thinking
about Antony and Cleopatra
or me and Richard?
Antony and Cleopatra,
of course.
Of course.
What happened to you?
You did.
Joe: And cut!
And that's a wrap.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Man: All right!
Woman:
Oh, my God, we did it!
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you!
Just so happy.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Lovely.
Brilliant.
It's brilliant.
Mwah!
Such a -- mwah! --
Brilliant movie.
Will you give us
a minute?
Do you have
anything lined up?
[ Sighs ]
I think I need a break --
a long break.
Me too.
And?
You mean Sybil.
It will be hard,
but she's agreed to try again.
Elizabeth,
you already knew that.
So you've come to rub my face
in it, then, have you?
[ Sighs ]
It's for the children,
Elizabeth.
I can't do it
to the children.
[ Sniffles ]
You knew you could never
leave them!
You were playing!
I was just another notch!
Damn it! How dare you
speak to me like that!
My heart is broken,
and you have the smashed pieces!
Please...
Please,
don't make this any harder.
Have you spoken
with Eddie?
I have no reason
to speak to Eddie!
[ Inhales sharply ]
You look at me
like you loathe me.
[ Exhales sharply ]
I don't loathe you.
I hate you!
No.
[ Sniffles ]
No, you don't.
[ Voice breaking ] No.
I don't.
[ Crying ]
[ Door opens ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Exhales sharply ]
[ Birds chirping ]
Mom, mom!
Come play piggy in the middle.
What's
piggy in the middle?
[ Both laugh ]
Never mind.
[ Sighs ]
I'm bored!
I'm so bored!
[ Sighs ]
What? I'm bored.
Hell, what do people do
when they aren't working?
Don't ask them, dear.
They are working.
Of course they are.
What am I supposed to do?
I've done 29 pictures
since I was 9.
29!
I've never learned how to do
just absolutely nothing!
I don't even know
how to play these games.
[ Sighs ] Would you like
to go for a drive?
Perhaps you'd like
to read this.
A fan letter?
Sort of.
It's from Richard.
When did that come?
Two days ago.
It was posted in Celigny.
I didn't know
he was here.
You said
you didn't want me to --
Well, I do want.
I do.
Could I have some privacy,
please?
Of course.
[ Sighs ]
Shall I wait?
No, it's okay.
You could come back
in a few hours.
Okay, sweetie.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Richard.
You look wonderful.
Don't say anything.
I know I look terrible.
Please -- sit.
Can I get you anything?
Uh, uh, coffee,
hot chocolate, tea?
A cappuccino would be nice,
please.
Cappuccino.
Thank you.
So, how are
your children?
Um, bored with me.
How's your family?
Uh...
Ifor's fine.
Uh, the rest
of the siblings -- good.
But, um...
I'm in hell.
[ Chuckles ]
"Hell" is
as good a word as any.
Thank you for coming.
I didn't know if you would.
Tell me,
will this pass?
Because it doesn't feel
that it will.
I don't know.
Damned if I know.
Thank you.
[ Sighs ]
So, tell me --
are you gonna see him again?
Maybe.
[ Door closes ]
I'm so sorry I'm late.
Oh, don't be silly.
Of course you're not.
[ Chuckles ]
Drink?
Yes, please.
I...
I brought you a gift.
And I have one for you.
John Donne.
The 1635 edition?
This must've cost you
a fortune.
A million thank-yous.
Now, my gift
is not nearly good enough.
Oh, stop it.
That's not the point.
Well,
it's English country gardens.
I remember you said
you missed them.
Thank you.
That's very thoughtful.
I'll enjoy this.
I've enjoyed not filming,
as well.
I'm not sure
I want to go back -- ever.
[ Chuckles ]
What?
I have taken a film.
Well I had to...
I couldn't sit around here doing this.
They'd find me
floating facedown in a lake.
What film? Where?
London, uh, "The V.I.P.s" --
silly title, really.
I play a rich man whose wife
is running around on him.
Perfect role for me,
though.
I get to sit around
looking all gloomy
and drink
like a proverbial fish.
Method acting.
[ Chuckles ]
Who's going to play
the lucky wife?
The producers
want Sophia Loren.
Hmm. Do they, now?
Richard Burton
and Sophia Loren.
I think la Loren
should stay in Rome.
[ Book thuds ]
Well, you heard me.
That role is mine.
But Miss Taylor,
we couldn't afford you
even if I wanted you,
and I don't want you.
Do you want people
to see the picture?
Of course.
Well, then,
you'll want publicity,
and trust me --
Taylor/Burton brings publicity.
Maybe that's not
the kind of publicity I want.
Then you're a fool.
You pay me and fire
all of your P.R. people,
because, buddy,
you won't need them.
You'll save money
and have a huge hit.
I'm sorry, but no.
[ Receiver slams ]
I'm not hiring
Elizabeth Taylor!
Your suite,
Miss Taylor.
Thank you.
[ Knock on door ]
What's that?
Uh, that would be
to the adjoining suite.
[ Gasps ]
Hello, lumpy.
[ Laughs ]
Man: There you are.
Enjoy your evening.
Woman: Thank you.
Very welcome.
[ Telephone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
Oh, God! That's the seventh time
it's rung!
You know it's Sybil.
Where is she?
[ Ringing stops ]
Our house, North London.
I told her I needed to be
near the film, which means you.
[ Laughs ]
[ Ringing resumes ]
Oh, hell's bells!
All right,
I've had enough!
What are you doing?
I'm going over there now.
I want a divorce!
Damn it!
Well, hurry back.
I want more.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Tires screeching ]
Sybil!
[ Groans ]
Richard.
- Richard.
- Ifor.
I wondered when
you'd finally come home.
I've been calling
the hotel.
I didn't realize
you were here.
I've come
to speak to Sybil.
She's asleep. Why don't you
talk to me instead?
Fine.
Look at the state of you,
acting like a teenager.
"Oh, I love her.
Oh, she was meant for me."
Don't you talk to me
about Elizabeth ever.
- All right, let's talk about you.
- Fine.
An affair born in betrayal
will end in ashes.
Oh, Ifor,
we're not in chapel now.
This is real life.
Let me tell you
what real life is --
family, loyalty,
commitment.
You think
I don't know that?
Then behave like you do
and act like a bloody grown-up!
[ Sighs ]
Right.
[ Engine shuts off ]
[ Sighs ] Get in.
[ Sighs ]
[ Cries ]
Elizabeth:
I was so mad at Richard.
[ Sighs ]
I had left Eddie,
but he wouldn't divorce me.
At least I never saw him
or spoke to him.
Richard was so torn.
What are you looking at?
Hmm?
Out.
I guess I never had anyone
say no to me before.
Sara: I'm going to get you
some coffee.
Of course you are.
Who's the most beautiful girl
in the world?
It's Minnie Mouse.
[ Laughs ]
People would say that...
[ Sniffles ]
...it was just because
I couldn't have him
that I wanted him,
and that wasn't true.
People say
all different things.
What?
They're ready for you
in five.
Which damn scene is it?
It's, um, scene 93.
Well, that doesn't
tell me anything.
Uh, I-it's the "getting back
together with your husband" scene.
[ Laughs ]
What is this --
some kind of torture?
He treated me like a queen.
And I loved his voice.
God, how I loved his voice.
Richard,
the drunken court Jester.
[ Laughs ]
God, no.
You were my king.
[ Sniffles ]
Elizabeth,
where are you?
[ Sniffles ]
I'm here, my love.
[ Indistinct talking ]
Richard:
Have I lost you?
You haven't lost me.
I've lost you.
[ Sighs ]
[ Talking continues ]
It's 8:00 a.m.,
and they're drinking?
Oh, for God's sake.
Let's go for a take
while they can still walk.
"The V.I.P.s,"
scene 145, take 1.
Atmosphere.
And action!
Let us go home, Paul.
No --
not out of pity.
No,
What, then?
[ Sighs ]
Need.
My need or yours?
Perhaps both.
And...Cut!
Oh, yes, that was very nice,
but if we could just do
one more --
- Nice?
- Why?!
Well, I just felt that --
yes, well,
if you had felt anything,
you wouldn't be asking me
to do it again.
I was perfect.
[ Scoffing ] Oh.
You were perfect?
I wasn't?
No, I-I wasn't
talking about you.
That's my point.
You just told him how perfect
you were, but I wasn't?
Richard Burton, the great
shakespearean actor,
was perfect,
but academy award winner
Elizabeth Taylor was what?
Crap?
Just for once,
Miss bossy boots Taylor,
this was not about you.
Oh, well,
now it damn well is!
- You spoiled, self-centered, little brat!
- You drunken -- you're a Welsh lout!
[ Gasps ]
[ Door slams ]
[ Knock on door ]
Go away, you harridan.
You're impossible.
But Elizabeth
wants to play.
I need to get
into Mr. Burton's suite.
i'm sorry, but we can't
iopen other guests' rooms.
Oh, you do know I'm shagging him
senseless, don't you?
[ Sighs ]
Thank you.
I'm sorry,
but I must wait.
Thanks.
[ Sighs ]
The wall covering --
it's silk!
Silk?
Please -- Richard Burton
deserves a Van Gogh
more than all your silk.
Thank you.
I can't compete
with all this.
Well, she didn't buy me
with a Van Gogh.
Don't be daft.
I don't care
about things.
Oh, don't you?
Are you sure
Welsh boy Richard Jenkins
didn't want all this?
Fans at the door.
Photos in the papers,
the hotel suites.
The fame.
[ Sighs ]
It's what you wanted.
[ Breathes shakily ]
And it's all you got.
I'll give you
your divorce.
That should fill
a few more newspapers.
Goodbye, Richard.
[ Door opens ]
[ Cork pops ]
[ Blows ]
You're free!
Drink to that.
But what if your
little songbird, Eddie,
decides to drag things out
forever?
It's already been
months.
Tonight,
we forget Eddie.
Come on, let's get a party
together. It'll be fun.
- Ohh...
- Let's go out for dinner.
I'll call Leo and the Harrisons,
and you call Wallace and Edward.
Come on. It'll be fun.
Come on.
[ Groans ]
That was
my fifth couple,
and they're at home
with a sick child.
My last shot
had in-laws staying.
[ Groans ]
Struck out.
You know what?
Damn them all.
We're going out.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Don't look now,
but someone's child's
had a miraculous recovery.
Oh, apparently,
Eugene's feeling better, too.
What's wrong with people?
It's what's wrong with us.
Apparently, people don't want
to be seen with us.
Apparently, no one in London's
ever had an affair.
Let me guess --
your niece?
Hypocrites, all of you.
Richard: It isn't
that we're having an affair.
It's that
we've abandoned our children.
We're pariahs.
Oh, stop. We have not
abandoned our children.
We will
all be together soon.
- You promise?
- Promise.
What?
Imagine bringing up children
in this madness.
Oh, they'll find
someone else to stalk.
- You think?
- Yeah, I think.
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Knock it off,
you parasites!
[ Sighs ]
Miss Taylor, Mr. Burton,
a moment.
Come on in.
Would you like a drink?
I know he would.
No -- on duty.
Thank you.
So, congratulations. I hear
your film is almost finished,
and, of course, that means,
as of a week Friday,
the production will not
be paying for this hotel.
So, my question is, will you be
staying in both suites?
I'm not going back
to Los Angeles.
Divorce or no divorce,
I'm staying with you.
So --
Should we line up
another film?
No,
I'm done with films,
at least until
all this madness is over.
Oh, you really don't have to
decide this minute,
but it's really about
the one suite or two.
Do you want
to do another film?
Not really.
Never wanted to do them in
the first place, if I'm honest.
Oh! Well, then go back
to your beloved the-a-ter,
you big thespian.
Perhaps I will.
"Our will and our fates
do so contrary run
that our devices
are still overthrown."
Now, if you had've
seen my Hamlet --
Did you see my Hamlet?
Oh, God.
I hope he hasn't.
Show me your Hamlet now.
- There's my Hamlet.
- As I was saying --
[ Laughs ]
Actually,
that's a great idea.
We should do "Hamlet"
in New York.
No. The critics
would take their knives out.
Oh, forget the critics.
New yorkers love us.
There -- it's settled.
Go to New York.
Thank you so much
for your help.
We'll be here
until we go to New York.
But, to answer my question,
will you need one suite or two?
It's none of my business,
your personal arrangements,
but -- but, then,
it is my business.
Aha!
You see,
what he's trying to say
in a very polite
English way
is, will we be
living in sin?
One suite is sinful,
whereas two is more discreet.
We'll be living in sin.
But it's nice
to have both.
[ Horns honking ]
Richard:
Let me be cruel, not unnatural.
I will speak daggers to her
but use none.
My tongue and soul in this
be hypocrites.
How in my words
somever she be shent.
To give them seals never,
my soul, consents.
Man: All right, good.
That will be all
for today.
What did you think?
I thought
it was wonderful.
No, I want your opinion.
Well, I can't tell you
a thing about acting.
Did I ever tell you
I learned everything
about film acting from you?
I was all over the place
in front of a camera
until I saw
your stillness.
Thank you.
But I still wouldn't tell you
anything about stage acting.
And you were great.
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Man:
God will punish the immoral!
God will punish
the immoral!
You're immoral!
You are immoral!
You are bad
for our families!
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Horn honks ]
"Repent your ungodly ways" --
that's a new one.
You're going to hell!
You obviously haven't
read the news today.
No less than the Vatican has
made a pronouncement about us.
The Vatican -- right.
[ Horn honking ]
[ Shouting continues ]
The Pope.
What?
We're guilty
of erotic vagrancy?
[ Honking continues ]
And a danger to the very
institution of marriage?
Yes, and, apparently,
Kate's school is a bit unhappy
with our behavior, too.
I'm so sorry, Richard.
[ Honking continues ]
You must talk to Eddie.
For God's sake, he's been
dragging this thing out forever.
He simply must
give you a divorce.
You're right.
This stops now.
[ Shouting, honking continues ]
Just need your signature.
You know,
I've got something to add.
He's been doing a number
in his act for over a year --
Cleo,
the nympho of the Nile.
Mm-hmm.
Well, it stops now.
I'll be damned if he's going to
make a dime off of me
after we've divorced.
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Hi.
Um, we have a reservation
under "Smith."
Hmm.
Here you are,
Mademoiselle Smith.
Thank you, sir.
No, Irene's
bringing a dress,
and Richard's trying hard
to find a minister
that will
actually marry us.
It's harder to find someone
to marry us than I thought.
I have a unitarian.
How are you with unitarians?
Are they legal?
As a king's seal.
Oh.
Then unitarian it is.
Do you,
Richard Walter Burton,
take Elizabeth Rosemond Taylor
to be your wife?
I do.
And do you,
Elizabeth Rosemond Taylor,
take Richard
to be your husband?
I do.
By the power
invested in me,
I now pronounce you
man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
That's it?
"That's it?"
[ Chuckling ]
It took us two years.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Happy?
More than.
Perhaps now
they'll give us some peace.
[ Chuckles ]
Clerk: Enjoy the play.
Man: Thank you.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Richard:
Where is my bloody wife?
[ Woman gasps ]
God, that woman knows
how to make an entrance.
I fear I will not live
to hear the news from England,
but I do prophesy the election
rights on Fortinbras.
He has my dying voice.
So tell him
with the occurrents
that have solicited
more and less.
The rest...
Is silence.
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Cheers and applause continue ]
Come!
In the words
of the immortal bard,
there will be
no more marriages!
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Cheers and applause
intensify ]
[ Mid-tempo music playing ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Ifor.
Richard didn't tell me --
Will you accept
my apology?
For what?
I was wrong about you.
You've made him
very, very happy.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you.
Just...don't break his heart,
please.
Trust me -- he'll break mine
before I break his.
- Elizabeth.
- Yeah.
Elizabeth, you simply have to
meet this man.
This is
Ernest Lehman.
I'm a writer.
"Sweet Smell
of Success."
"North by Northwest" --
we love your work.
Well, thank you.
I wish you'd write
something for me.
Actually,
I have something --
"Who's Afraid
of Virginia Woolf?"
Oh, I love the play!
But we could do it
together.
Well,
you start a new film --
"The Spy Who Came in From The Cold."
Yes, but I could do this one
after that.
I'm afraid you're a little
too masculine for George,
and I can't quite see it.
And I can't imagine the two
of you fighting like that.
Oh. Well, do you hear that,
my little sugar tart?
He can't imagine
us fighting.
Well, it doesn't matter,
because why would anyone hire
a vomiting vat of vodka
like yourself?
Well, at least when I vomit,
I make mellifluous sounds,
unlike your little
mouse-crap squeaks.
- Oh, mellifluous?
- Yes.
Mellifluous?
What was he -- some Roman
homosexual that you buggered?
[ Laughs ]
Mellifluous,
bring me my wine.
That's wonderful,
darling.
See, you have to understand --
we enjoy fighting.
[ Laughs ]
We really do.
We're masters of the art.
I guess we could wait
until after Richard's film.
...Laurence Olivier
for "Othello,"
Rod Steiger
for "The Pawnbroker,"
and Richard Burton
for "The Spy
Who Came in From The Cold."
The envelope, please.
And the winner is...
Lee Marvin for "Cat Ballou."
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Up-tempo music playing ]
[ Applause ]
It means nothing.
Mm. That's easy for you to say.
You've already got one.
And I'm here
to make sure
you remember
that it means nothing.
I lost to Lee Marvin.
[ Both laugh ]
I mean, I love Lee,
but "Cat Ballou"?
He beat Rod and Olivier, too.
[ Sighs ]
It's a farce.
I deserved that.
If you really want one,
I'll give you mine.
Don't patronize me.
I don't want yours.
I wanted that one.
I'm trying
to cheer you up.
Well, don't!
[ Sighs ]
Be a big sulk, then.
Okay.
Be a big, pathetic,
sad sulk, then!
Damn it, woman,
can't you see that this hurts?!
No. No.
[ Sighs ]
Forgive me.
Please.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Oh, they give you the prize
years ago. m'dear.
There isn't an abomination award
you haven't won.
Oh, God.
[ Laughter ]
- ...puke.
- What?
You make me puke!
Well, that wasn't
a very nice thing to say.
You're fantastic.
Oh, thank you.
Yes, that's my gal --
the very essence
of a frumpy fishwife.
...a simp.
You haven't even got...
What about you?
You're castrated
and going to seed and tallow?
Tallow?
That's ripe coming from you,
my little butterball.
At least people like butter.
They eat it up.
Let's get
the hell out of here.
I like it here.
You just don't like it when I get
all of the attention, do you?
I don't like it when you get
all of the attention?
Then why the hell
did I marry you?!
I hope that was
an empty bottle, George.
You can't afford
to waste good liquor.
- Prick.   - Elizabeth, you can stop.
The crowds aren't watching.
Like I care
who's watching!
Elizabeth, stop it!
This is not you!
Oh, yeah?
What's me?!
Is that me?!
Is that me?
[ Gasps ]
Oh, God.
Is that how I look?
Why would anyone want
to print a photo like that?
They used to only print
the nice, glamorous ones.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
I look like quasimodo.
[ Laughs ]
You know, they're paying more
now for the ugly ones --
candid shots.
Why? [ Sighs ]
Who would want that?
I don't care.
I will love you even if you get
as fat as a hippo.
No, you wouldn't.
Try me.
[ Mariachi music playing ]
[ Telephone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
[ Groans ]
All right, I'm coming.
Hello?
Are you sure?
Thank you.
[ Pan clattering ]
Wake up!
Wake up, wake up!
Wakey, wakey, wakey, wakey!
Come on, sleepyheads!
Wakey, wakey!
I have great news,
my lords and ladies.
Miss Elizabeth Taylor
and Mr. Richard Burton are...
Both nominated
for academy awards!
Yay!
That's fantastic, Richard --
two years in a row.
It's incredible.
And I'm already thinking
about what I'm going to wear.
[ Laughter ]
Richard.
You go.
I can't --
not after last time.
I just, uh...
Oh, no. We'll all stay here,
then, right?
We'll make a night of it.
[ Pan clattering ]
[ Laughs ]
Mommy,
can we dress nicely?
Of course we can,
my love.
I understood it.
I did.
Let's face it.
Those awards...
Four out of five people
are humiliated.
What worried me
was that Richard
wouldn't be there
if he won his Oscar.
And then when everyone on
"Virginia woolf" started to win,
it just...
Haskell WEXLER for best
cinematographer -- deservedly.
Yes, and Sandy Dennis
for best supporting.
Wonderful Sandy.
Woman:
And the envelope, please.
And the winner is...
Elizabeth Taylor...
[ All cheering ]
And then...
Man: For best performance
by an actor,
the envelope, please.
And the winner is...
Paul Scofield,
"A Man For All Seasons."
[ Click ]
Congratulations, Elizabeth.
Now you have two.
But now
I need to be alone,
because I am
a very, very poor loser.
Come on, guys.
Come on.
Scofield stayed
in the theater.
So what?
Probably lives in a damp flat
in east London.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, come on.
It's not like
you lost your job or any--
how the hell would you know
what I lost?!
I'll tell you
what you're going to lose.
Her.
I was wrong, you know.
I thought
you were too good for her,
but she's too good
for you.
She's just won
a bloody Oscar,
and you can't enjoy it with her
because you're moping.
Can't you see I'm afraid
I'm not enough for her?
[ Seagulls squawking ]
"Enseamed"?
That's not a word.
Richard --
just the man we need.
Will you tell them
that "enseamed" is a word?
Elizabeth is right.
"Enseamed" is a word.
It means, um...
"Greasy."
Good morning, Bernard.
What brings our esteemed
business manager to Mexico?
Good news, hmm?
Why don't you guys
go in for a swim?
Off you go.
So?
I have, uh,
prepared some statements.
Yeah, well,
skip the paperwork.
Out with it, man.
Give it to me straight.
Don't be mean to Bernard.
He works hard for us.
I don't dispute it.
It's just that when it is
good news, he sends a telegram,
and when it's bad news,
he slinks in like an undertaker.
Bernard, ignore him.
Tell me.
Since Richard
wants it straight...
You're broke.
Oh, and here I was thinking
it was something serious.
How can we be broke?
How is that possible?
That's...Everything.
But if Richard takes
"The Comedians"...
"The Comedians"?
When were you offered that role?
I'm turning it down.
Richard, they offered you
3/4 of a million.
But it's with Sophia.
[ Chuckling ] Oh.
Screw Sophia.
I will do it.
Already asked.
They can't afford you.
Well,
I'll cut my fee in half.
Tell them I'll do it
for half a million.
Will we be all right
then?
For a while.
But after taxes, hotels,
uh, travel, staff...
And we need more staff
for security.
The paparazzi
have found us.
More staff?
Now, if you were
any kind of a manager, Bernard,
you'd be able
to find us somewhere
where we'd never
had to pay any taxes
and where the damn photographers
would never find us.
Now you're asking
the impossible.
The only place you two
will get any peace and quiet
is in the middle
of the bloody ocean.
Bernard,
you are a genius.
Richard: Okay,
now you can open your eyes.
[ All gasp ]
Our new home.
[ Laughter ]
Well, come on.
All aboard, all aboard.
Make yourselves at home.
Don't drown.
A boat --
live on a boat.
A yacht, mother.
There is a difference.
Yes,
it's much more expensive.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ Both laugh ]
Who's that?
My photographer.
[ Seagulls squawking ]
Damn and blast it.
I thought we got a yacht
to get away from the press.
But he's not press.
He's my photographer.
"My photographer"?
What are you --
potentate, royalty?
There have probably been
more photographs taken of you
than anyone else
on earth.
Why would you
want more?
Because
his are beautiful.
No.
You are beautiful.
He just knows
how to point a camera.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
Will you stop that?!
He doesn't speak English,
Richard.
Trust me --
he understood that.
Are you jealous?
Why? Should I be?
No, of course not.
Because if you so much
as stroke his hand,
I'll never speak to you
again.
Same goes for you.
Bit young for you,
isn't he?
Stop it.
Skinny, too.
You'd all but flatten him.
Ooh, I'd be careful,
Richard.
You could stand
to lose a few pounds.
Yes, but at least mine doesn't all
pool in my fingers, Miss pudgy digits.
What?
What?!
Boopsy.
Boopsy,
Richard wants to play.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, don't cry.
I'm not crying!
I'm trying not to stick you
with a knife
in your fat,
blubbery stomach.
Well, knife away!
Throw me overboard!
Now you can feel
my pudgy hands now!
Hey, these are not
pudgy hands!
They are fat,
and they're pudgy!
I love these hands.
Are you sure?
1,000%.
Do you want
to make them beautiful?
But they are...
Beautiful.
Do you want to make them
more beautiful?
I need a ring.
A big ring.
Auctioneer:
$700,000 raise Mr. Onassis.
I have $750,000 on the phone.
I now have $800,000
with Mr. Onassis.
$850,000.
$850,000 on the phone.
$900,000.
$950,000.
$950,000 on the phone.
Yes.
Now $1 million
with Cartier, Paris.
And 50.
I have $1,050,000
on the phone.
The bid stands at $1,050,000
[ Gavel bangs ]
Sold to...
...Mr. Richard Burton.
[ Indistinct talking ]
[ All gasp, murmur ]
Woman:
Oh...My...Goodness.
Now, that is a ring.
Richard here told me
that my hands looked fat,
so, of course,
I made him buy me something
that would make them
look small.
[ Laughter ]
Come on.
We must get a drink in you.
[ Sighs ]
Here you are.
Don't worry. It's not like this
around here all the time.
Normally, it's just, uh,
us and the children,
well, nannies and the crew,
and there's --
there's a couple of cooks.
[ Laughs ]
And, of course,
my brother, Ifor,
and Bernard,
our business manager.
Come here, Bernard.
I'm trying
to explain to Bernard
that since
this whole yacht costs
only -- what --
$30,000 a year to run,
think of all the money we save
on hotels and houses.
Plus, there's no taxes,
you see.
Don't tell anybody,
but we --
we can take the dogs
anywhere we want.
Can't we?
We just leave them on the boat.
[ Sighs ]
Two Bloody Marys.
Thank you, Jacques.
[ Coughs ]
I've ordered breakfast.
[ Groans ]
[ Sighs ]
Do you know
it's December?
You're joking.
The children have been
complaining
it's not
at all christmasy.
The children
are complaining?
Well, we'd all
like to be in the snow.
I supposed we could open up
the house in Switzerland.
[ Sighs ]
Mr. Burton.
I have not seen you in...
- Almost two years, I think
-  Yeah.
Are you back?
Miss Taylor?
Elizabeth and the children
arrive tomorrow.
We are
the advance guard
come to open the house
for Christmas.
Bloody weather
you're having.
Tomorrow
will be beautiful.
Some wine to start?
Richard:
Ah, good old Bernard,
calculating exactly
what Christmas will cost.
Don't look at me.
Talk to Elizabeth.
You're as bad
as each other.
I've never seen two people
piss it away so bloody quickly.
Oh, that's good, coming from one
of the dozens of family members on salary.
I work for my money.
As, dear brother, do I.
Oh, no.
Don't you get up.
You finish up here.
I'll go open up your house,
and then I'll come back for you!
Very well, good man.
You can always count
on Ifor.
[ Sighs ]
[ Keys clatter ]
[ Switch clicking ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Clattering ]
[ Grunts, moans ]
[ Woman speaking French
over P.A. ]
[ Telephone ringing ]
I'm...very sorry.
[ Gasps ]
It's his spine.
He'll never walk again.
[ Laughter ]
[ Funk music playing ]
Can you please
shut that thing off?!
[ Music continues ]
[ Laughter ]
Can I please
get some peace and quiet?!
[ Volume decreases ]
[ Splash, music stops ]
[ Door slams ]
What is your problem?
Nothing.
Now I drowned it.
Our guests
are trying to have fun.
Yes, and so was I --
until you ruined it!
Oh, Richard,
I'll ruin it.
Ah!
That's my next job.
"Bluebeard"?
"Bluebeard" -- utter claptrap,
but for the money, I will dance.
You know, he murdered
several of his wives.
I'm beginning
to identify with him.
And who plays these wives?
Hmm?
Let me guess --
they're all 12 years old.
No.
They've only cast Raquel Welch
and Virna Lisi so far.
Oh, so you're gonna do
this piece of crap
and then
grope all these girls.
This is a job.
What do you think
pays for all of this?!
Witch, that's a book!
Oh! Witch?!
Yes!
You put a spell on me,
didn't you?!
I should've stayed on the stage,
like Scofield,
instead of
wasting my talent on you!
- Oh, on me?!
- Yes!
- On me?!
- On you!
I love it
when you get angry, Richard!
Oh, really?
This is what Richard Jenkins
would've wanted.
You know, there's only one way
to deal with witches,
and that's to burn them
or to drown them!
Ooh, Elizabeth!
Elizabeth!
[ Pounding ]
[ Birds chirping ]
Elizabeth?
Something
to cheer you up.
You bought me
the whole library.
All 1,000 volumes.
[ Horns honking ]
I love this little plane.
We should have one.
I'll catch you up.
By the way, how much would a
plane like this one set me back?
- Used, like this?
- Yeah.
A million.
Will you take a check?
Richard, no.
Oh, I'm going to
give up drinking.
Think of all the money
that will save us.
[ Sighs ]
[ Dog barks ]
Elizabeth:
Two academy awards,
and they drop me
from the top 10 movie stars.
It's like you have breasts
and turn 40 in this business,
and it's bye-bye.
Cheer up, Elizabeth.
I just bought you a plane.
Well, your big-boobed Raquel
made the list.
Don't blame me. I'm only
doing this rubbish for you.
Read it.
It's unplayable.
Oh, boo-hoo.
What you need
is a huge 40th birthday party.
Oh, stop reminding me
that I'm 40.
You look fabulous. You'll make
them all sick with envy.
[ Sighs ]
That'll get me another job.
Okay, last time --
Do you or do you not
want to be the centerpiece
of a splendid,
magnificent party?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Richard just threw it at me.
He said,
"here's another trinket."
Champagne?
No, thank you.
I'm giving it up for lent.
Here we are.
[ Gasps ]
[ Applause ]
Guests:
Happy Birthday!
Happy Birthday.
Man:
Make a wish, Elizabeth.
Happy Birthday,
darling.
You'd think she was still
a movie star.
Richard: Elizabeth.
Elizabeth.
[ Crying ]
Oh.
You're still a star.
Hey, you are
the biggest star.
I'm a joke.
No!
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no.
You're my love.
[ Crying continues ]
Shh.
Shh, shh, shh.
[ Crying continues ]
[ Door opens, closes ]
Richard,
I'm so sorry.
It's Ifor.
H-he died.
No.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Get away from me.
Elizabeth:
Look, I'll be honest --
I didn't like Ifor
when I first met him.
But it's okay.
You and I
have talked about it.
He just seemed a bit too old
to be Richard's brother --
too dour, too judgmental.
I used to call him Richard's
little Welsh-village conscience.
You know,
we became friends.
And I realized
that he was just trying
to protect Richard
the whole time.
And he was a good man.
He was gentle.
I may be your ocean,
but he was your anchor.
He was the only man
I ever admired.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
I hear
you're on your third bottle.
Have you met Nathalie?
She has
the most exquisite hands.
Richard, stop this.
Let me help.
I killed him.
I killed my brother.
Can you help that?
Well, can you?!
No.
So...Run along.
Go home.
Play with your jewelry.
There's nothing
Elizabeth likes more
than playing
with her jewelry.
[ Sniffles ]
I'm taking the plane
to London.
Miss Taylor.
He's screwing
Nathalie Delon?!
Miss Taylor!
[ Glass shatters ]
May we speak with you
a moment?
[ Glass shatters ]
Miss Taylor, please!
[ Breathing heavily ]
Yes, get me
Aristotle Onassis.
Now -- yes!
[ Indistinct talking ]
Man:
There she is. Liz!
Hey, Liz!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Smile please, darling.
"An affair born in betrayal
will end in ashes."
[ Sniffles ]
[ Crying ]
What have I done?
[ Inhales deeply ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Sighs ]
Elizabeth:
What did I think?
What did I feel?
The truth is,
practically nothing.
You know, people forget
that Richard and I
were together for 12 years.
We did over 40 films together
in that time.
Richard more than me,
but...
Still, I think
that we were just exhausted.
You know,
I think we needed a break.
[ Ringing ]
Richard: Hello?
I just got
the divorce papers.
Are you sure
we're doing the right thing?
Yes.
Yes,
I'm afraid we are.
[ Crying ]
Did I desert you?
No.
I was the deserter.
I from myself.
We should've just...stopped.
Lived on a farm in Wales,
on a boat -- something.
I don't know.
Somewhere that we didn't
have to perform.
Then maybe, just maybe,
I think we could've survived.
Did I expect him
to date again?
Of course.
I did.
More than that?
[ Voice breaking ] No.
No.
That broke my heart.
Elizabeth: I really do
like it here, though.
Freshen your drink,
darling?
Thank you.
Honey,
did you hear about Richard?
Oh, yes,
dating a princess Elizabeth.
That's what you get after a queen.
[ Chuckles ]
But did you think
he'd get engaged so quickly?
Oh, honey,
it's so Richard.
He bought that cheap ring
for the beauty queen
from -- what -- Texas,
and now
proposing to a princess?
He really is
drinking too much.
Mm.
Elizabeth, I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Oh, yes, I've -- I've had
trouble with my back lately.
It keeps going to spasm.
I'll be fine in a minute.
Darling, be a dear.
Get the car
and one of my pills.
Woman on P.A.:
Please dial 311.
I've come bearing gifts.
Henry.
Jewelry?
Oh, Henry, how sweet.
Would you like
to try them on?
Sorry, darling,
but it's a little difficult
when I'm upside down.
[ Laughs ]
Richard made the front page
again.
Broke off
his engagement.
Henry, my love,
would you call the nurse?
I think I should try
a few steps today.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, Dr. Miller.
I was just telling Henry
that I'm feeling
so very much better.
What?
Your blood tests.
Look, I-I'm not saying
it is colon cancer,
but it's serious enough
that I need to run more tests.
I'll be back
in a couple of hours.
Last chance.
Is there anything
I can get you?
Just say the word.
Anything?
[ Voice breaking ]
Richard.
Woman on P.A.:
Dr. Rick to Maternity.
Dr. Rick to Maternity, please.
Hello, Boopsy.
[ Laughs ]
Hello, Burty.
Miss Taylor.
Oh. Mr. Burton.
Oh.
Have you met Richard?
So, any news?
Yes,
and it's all good.
It was
a false positive.
[ Exhales deeply ]
Elizabeth,
you are okay.
In fact,
fit as a fiddle.
Thank you.
Elizabeth...
I've been sitting here,
thinking about
how I may lose you
and wondering how I could
let you out of my life
for an hour,
let alone a day.
Elizabeth,
will you marry me?
Again, please?
Man: Well, here's to the newlyweds.
All: Hear, hear!
Thank you very much.
Thank you, sir.
Well done,
Mr. Taylor.
Maybe you'll have
better luck this time.
Oh, the Liz and Dick show
doesn't need luck, no.
No, what it needs
is a new script.
I was right.
The audience ate it up.
They love, they drink,
they fight, they fornicate,
they marry, they divorce,
they marry again.
Really -- how long
can this show run?
But for the poor performers,
the marriage was over in months.
They know the lines, but
they just keep coming out wrong.
So painful to remember.
So tiring.
I suddenly feel
so very tired.
Do you mind
if I lie down for a moment?
Woman: Richard?
Richard?
[ Helicopter blades whirring ]
Which dress do you think is
better for the Stony party?
[ Whirring continues ]
What's going on?
Oh, don't tell me it's
another one of those damn fires.
Mother?
What is going on?
[ Hangers clack ]
Um, it's Richard.
He's dead, hon.
Oh, my God!
Elizabeth!
Oh, sweetie!
Reporter:
A few questions!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
So, when's the funeral
gonna be?
[ Shouting continues ]
Just one question,
please.
Sir, please!
At the request
of Richard's widow
and to avoid a media circus,
Miss Taylor will not attend
Richard Burton's funeral
and will not
be making a statement.
Thank you.
[ Bell tolling, birds chirping ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Indistinct talking ]
I'll get the police.
[ Camera shutters clicking ]
Please, please --
have some respect.
Please.
[ Voice breaking ] Do you know how
rarely we were ever truly alone?
[ Speaking French ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
Madame! Madame!
Oh, God, do you have
your pictures now?!
Do you?!
Can't you leave us alone?!
[ Man speaking French ]
[ Crying ]
Forever an ocean.
[ Voice breaking ]
I think
we balanced each other out.
I think the balance was
what really meant the most.
[ Chuckles ]
I think that we both
understood each other.
And I don't think
we'd ever had that.
[ Voice breaking ] And without
him, I didn't know what to do.
[ Sniffles ]
I could feel
that he really loved me.
[ Sniffles ]
He just loved me.
== Sync, corrected by Alice ==
== www.addic7ed.com ==