The black hole, where gravity's pull is
so intense that even light can't escape.
Sometimes I feel that way when
I'm at a boring dinner party.
Listen, next week we have the big quiz.
But if you want tenure, you
need to learn to play the game.
Cozy up to Dean Fairchild.
Kiss his ass.
Remember, I'm not only the dean,
I am also the editor of The
Astrophysics Quarterly Review.
- I'm leaving you, Henry.
- No, Christine,
I will get published. You'll see.
Who am I kidding, they're just
gonna choose Associate Professor
Brodfard Gilroy's work,
like they always do.
- Drink, Henry?
- No, thank you, Dean Fairchild.
I try not to drink bourbon before lunch.
Ouch. Do I detect sarcasm?
"A hit, a very palpable hit!"
Hamlet, act five, scene two?
"The Devil hath power to
assume pleasing shape."
"Though it be madness, yet
there is method in't."
"I am but mad north-north-west.
When the wind is southerly, I
know a hawk from a handsaw!"
Jeez, Henry. Keep your shirt on.
We're trying to have a little fun.
My paper is better than anything
that could be conceived by
your feeble brain, Brodfard!
Oh, what's wrong, Henry?
Are you gonna whine or are you gonna win?
Oh! Ow! Ow!
Are those our professors?
I hope your writing is better
than your left hook, Neumann.
I just want people to see my ideas.
Well, perhaps you can start
a newsletter or something.
You utter moron.
That son of a bitch!
I know I'm not very good
at playing the game.
Maybe that's because science
isn't a game to me.
I don't care who jerked off next to
who in the faculty lounge last week.
I'm a damn good astrophysicist
and I will not let anyone
take that away from me.
Not Brodfard Gilroy, and
especially not you.
You back-slapping, booze-swilling,
glad-handing fuck dick of a shit butt!
Get out!
Oh, my God.
Don't beat yourself up.
It happens to everyone.
Just take this as an opportunity
to relax and reflect.
I know a great real estate agent.
She specializes in summer
rentals up near Waterville.
Call her, Henry.
This is the only
unit still available
that's within your price range.
Definitely has a rustic feeling to it,
but it's perfect for someone
looking for a little solitude.
We just had a married
couple in here just now.
I guess it didn't work out.
It's too bad, too.
I really liked them. It's so sad.
Did you know that more than 50% of
married couples get divorced these days?
Boy, oh, boy. Times sure have changed.
Anyway, listen to me jabbering on.
Believe me, I know you have better
things to do with your time
than listen to me go on
about gosh only knows what.
Quite a storm on the way.
They say it's a nor'easter.
Anyway, listen to me gabbing on.
I should mention that
there is a summer camp
right through the trees over there.
Nice enough people.
Sometimes they make too much noise, but
kids will be kids, don't you know?
Anyhoo...
I do have two other people
interested in this property,
so if you are serious about renting,
I'm going to need a deposit.
It's perfect. I'll take it.
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
Hey, Wooders!
Don't forget, we got our special mid-day
entertainment starting in about an hour.
That's right, original bad
boy of hypnotism, Jackie Brazen!
-Jackie is back by popular demand...
...and everyone who saw him
last year tells me this show is hot.
-HO-T.
Which kind of makes me want to
break out some BTO a little bit later.
That's Bachman-Turner Overdrive
for those of you who prefer the
non-abbreviated way of doing things.
We're like Burger King here on CFW.
You can have it your way.
Guys. Everybody, focus up.
Eyes up here.
- We have some very sad news.
- Yeah.
Tragedy has befallen
our humble theater.
Leaps were leapt. Bones were broken.
Dreams were deferred.
Earlier today, Abraham Mendel saved
the lives of Danny and Becky
by breaking their fall.
Sorry, man.
Danny, Becky, you were our leads.
- And we will never forget you.
- Never.
- But we're fine.
- Yeah, we weren't injured.
Yeah, well, you made a mistake,
and mistakes aren't tolerated
here, so you're out.
But the show must go on!
And in that spirit, Ben will
be stepping in for Abraham
and performing with McKinley
in the zoot suit number.
It is time for this actorly
vessel to cross the footlights.
- Adieu, my princess!
- Aw.
Adieu and exeunt.
It's kind of our thing.
Anyway, we have to replace the
leading lady and the leading man.
I need help from a
professional director. Claude?
Ah!
Let the auditions begin!
Hi, I'm Lisa. I'm from
Freehold, New Jersey.
I'm 16, and I'm gonna sing
"Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star."
♪ Twinkle, twinkle, little star ♪
♪ How I wonder... ♪
Thank you.
That's all we need to hear.
Are you sure? I'm happy to do another song.
You weren't good, okay?
Is that what you want to hear?
You want me to gut you like
a fish for everyone to see?
Is that what you want, little girl?
Because let me tell you something.
The truth stings, okay?
Like salt on an open wound.
You were an abomination!
Your audition stunk up this
room like a dusty wet fart!
You don't have it!
You don't have it, honey.
And I hope to hell you're
good at something else,
because you sure as shit are not
gonna make it in show business.
So that, to answer your
question, is the truth.
What was her question?
I'll take a tin of Skoal and, uh...
two combs.
Candy! Yeah!
Candy!
Are you gonna buy anything?
What, old man?
I can't hear you over the music.
He asked you politely if you
were going to buy anything.
"He asked politely if
you were gonna buy anything."
- Who the fuck are you, asswipe?
- Yeah, asswipe, who the fuck are you?
I'm the Falcon,
President Reagan's hired assassin...
asswipe.
My uterus.
Oh, man.
Keep the change.
You kids stay in school.
Jonas?
Oh!
- Hey, there...
- Hi.
Gail, my fiancée.
What were you talking
to Beth and Greg about?
- What do you mean?
- I overheard you.
What'd you hear?
Something about sludge, the government...
codes.
- A can.
- Mmm-mmm.
What was all that stuff about?
Oh, yeah, that was, uh...
Jonas, is there anything I need to
know about you before we get married?
Like, anything at all?
No... nothing.
Oh, my... I'm so sorry, Jonas!
I thought for some reason that you would,
like, catch it and spin it around or...
God, what am I doing? I
think I'm just scared.
It's okay to be scared.
Getting married's scary.
But you want to know what?
- I'm not scared.
- You're not?
I remember the first
time I laid eyes on you
at the Portsmouth Marriott
doing the hustle.
I knew right then and there, you were
gonna be the girl that I married.
It wasn't the hustle. It
was the electric slide.
"That was my Mama's scarf.
The scarf she wrapped around her neck.
It was given to her by her aunt
Margaret who lived in Boston."
Hey, Katie.
I was thinking about watching you
ride a horse later. Is that cool?
Sorry, Andy. I'm auditioning to
replace Becky in the musical.
And if I get the part, I'll
be rehearsing all day.
That sounds like a drag.
I hope you don't get it.
Trees look weird if you squint at 'em.
Being in the play is a lot of fun.
In fact, you could audition
for the lead role.
I bet you'd be a great performer.
I'd rather pick dingleberries
out of my Aunt Frieda's butt
than do that stupid shit.
Well, it's just something to think about.
It's a really good musical. There's
all sorts of fun pyrotechnics
and dancing and singing and...
the two leads have a big kiss at the end.
Anyway, I'll see ya later.
Think I just caught the acting bug.
Next!
I have to call my service.
Claude, do you think, maybe, we're
being a little too hard on them?
I mean, after all, it's just a summer camp.
Let me tell you a little story, Susie.
One night, I was having drinks next
to the brilliant Jerome Robbins
while he was having drinks with
the late, great Gower Champion.
And do you know who else was
in the restaurant that night?
No.
Jack...
Hofsiss.
- Holy shit.
- "Holy shit" is right.
I call winner.
In your face, douche!
Hey, is it cool if we play?
It's not like we own the tetherball
court or anything.
Kevin, can you show me?
- Appleblatt?
- Okay.
The point is to get the ball all the way
around the pole, so you hit it like this.
Okay. So, like this?
Ow!
Stop laughing at her. It's not funny.
Happens all the time. See?
He is such a dork.
Kevin, what's your major malfunction?
Come on, Amy, let's go.
My name is Robbie Klein and I'm
from Shaker Heights, Ohio.
My name is Jeremy Barofsky.
Sarah Rachel Winkleman, 16.
♪ I feel it coming like a tidal wave ♪
♪ I'm in over my head ♪
♪ Drowned deep down in your ocean ♪
♪ Washed up and left for dead ♪
Next.
♪ Give me heart attack
Heart attack of love ♪
♪ Heart attack of love ♪
Next.
"And my relief must come
from loathing her!"
- Next.
- Hey, how's everybody doing?
It looks like a full house tonight.
Next!
- Next. Next.
- Next.
♪ And can you feel it in the air? ♪
Next.
Next!
♪ Give me a heart attack ♪
♪ Heart attack ♪
I'm sorry.
Next!
Katie Finnerty, 16.
♪ Feel it coming like a tidal wave ♪
♪ I'm in over my head ♪
♪ Short it out, make your own revolution ♪
♪ Just dance and let them stare ♪
♪ Heart attack love ♪
♪ Give me a heart attack ♪
♪ Oh, you love me, ya hate me ♪
♪ You gimme, gimme heart attack! ♪
All right, now we're getting somewhere.
Okay, settle down, everybody!
Settle, settle.
Beth!
We are very pleased to welcome Kennebec
County's number one hypnotist,
Jackie Brazen!
What are we doing, Beth? We're
sitting on a time bomb here.
What are we gonna do? We're
running out of time.
All right, all right! Camp Firewood!
We have to keep up normal
appearances for as long as possible
until we can figure out a way to stop
Xenstar and the United States government.
Are you ready to get
unconscious and uncanny?
Let's get uncanny!
I'm gonna need a few victims...
I mean volunteers!
Pick me! Pick me! Pick me!
Pick me! Pick me!
Whoa, whoa. Slow down, big fella. I'm
gonna need you to slow way down.
More like... a turtle.
Oh, my God.
He's acting like a turtle!
Turtle!
- What?
- I like the new look.
- Really?
- No, you look like a doink.
- Okay, can we go?
- I just need you to trust me, Greg.
I'm just really worried
about that toxic sludge.
Rhonda! Who's next?
And can someone please blow me away?
- Logan.
- That's me!
Hello, I'm Logan.
I'm 16 years old. I'm
from Tarrytown, New York.
My favorite musical is Annie,
my favorite season winter,
and my favorite actor is, of
course, the great Ben Vereen.
It's a 16/4 with a loop at the hook.
Freeze the bars and mute the quarter-tones.
If it ever feels like we're
dragging, we're not.
It's just that kind of tune.
What did you guys think of lunch today?
I thought the sloppy
joes were pretty great,
but the coleslaw was a little eggy.
I think we can do better.
♪ Everything has a season ♪
♪ Everything has a time ♪
♪ Show me a reason and I'll
soon show you a rhyme ♪
This kid is a pro.
He started auditioning the
moment he walked into the room.
He's the one.
We should tell him before
he books something else.
No. Never let them know you like them.
♪ Children belong where they can ramble ♪
♪ Eagles belong where they can fly ♪
♪ I got to be where my
spirit can run free ♪
♪ Gotta find my corner ♪
♪ Yeah, of the sky ♪
Uh, Logan?
Uh, listen, can you hang
around for a while?
Absolutely. Did you guys like it or...
I don't know.
Wow.
What an education.
- Uh, how can I help you, ma'am?
- Hi.
This is a little bit
awkward, but I was wondering
if I could look up any public records
on my fiancé, Jonas Jurgensen?
For no reason. Probably nothing.
Just to reassure myself.
It's always good to be thorough.
Jonas Jurgensen, date of
birth June 21st, 1952.
Resides at 1048 Walnut Street.
And...
- he's dead.
- What?
Oh, that can't be.
I am so sorry. I read that wrong.
- It's actually 1408...
- No, after that.
- That he's dead?
- That's impossible.
Uh, checking...
Oh...
No, it says it right here.
He's definitely dead.
But...
If Jonas is dead, then
who am I about to marry?
Do the funky chicken.
You're a constipated wiener dog.
You're a one-celled organism.
Dibs on her.
Dibs on her. Dibs on her.
You can't call dibs on every girl, Drew.
That's against the rules.
Yes, you can, 'cause I just did.
Eat my dick, Captain Fuck Pants.
We should take turns. Kevin, you go first.
Oh.
- Okay, I call dibs on...
- You're a sexy, sexy alpaca!
I call dibs on that Amy chick.
What? No. It was my turn.
Bullshit. We're going counter-clockwise.
It's my turn, and I call dibs on Amy.
Ladies and gentlemen, I ask you,
is he a man or is he a pogo stick?
Pogo stick!
- Oh. Hey.
- Hey.
- McKinley, right?
- Yeah.
Oh, Ben. I'm the producer.
Well, was the producer.
I guess you and I are doing the zoot suit.
Yeah, we're doing the zoot suit.
Who came up with this contraption?
I guess the trademark is that both
actors get into the zoot suit
and then they play the zoot suit together.
- I know. I made the costume.
- No, you didn't.
Hand to God. I've been into sewing
since I was eight years old.
Oh, my God. I had no idea
you were that creative.
- Oh, really?
- Uh-uh.
Oh, I just thought it was so
obvious that I'm creative.
I mean, I just thought,
'cause you're creative
that you would know that I'm creative.
Oh, I see, Ben.
You don't realize that
you're creative, too.
It's all right.
Whether or not you're creative,
I think you're really talented.
Well, I think you're really
talented, too, obviously.
I mean...
Flatterer.
- I have some mask work to do.
- Okay.
- I'll catch up with you later?
- All right.
We gotta try this on, don't we?
No time like the present.
You're insane, Graham. Ayn Rand?
She's not attractive.
Her talent, Warner. I'm
attracted to her talent.
Well, she certainly has a brilliant mind.
But who needs a woman with a mind?
That's so true!
Hi, boys.
- Blake.
- Courtney.
Your collar's looking particularly
popped this afternoon.
So, um, word around camp is that
you and Katie are on the rocks.
Well, you heard wrong. We've never
been stronger, Katie and I.
'Cause, see, I thought I heard she
wasn't coming to TigerForm tonight
so she could eat hot dog wieners with
those peasants from Camp Firewood.
Katie will be at TigerForm tonight.
You'll see.
You'll all see!
Jeez, okay.
Don't have to get in such a snit.
He's like my father when he
gets into the Planter's Punch.
Well, if anything changes...
you know where to find me.
I'll be on the boat with Whitney.
Rowing crew.
If we can find a coxswain.
She is a minx.
Socialist!
It says here, in 1973, a plane
was on its way to Malta.
But that plane crashed.
There were five passengers on the flight,
four of whom were burnt to a crisp,
their bodies unidentifiable.
But one passenger's body was never found.
It seems that your fiancé
left that crash unharmed,
and then he took the identity of
one of the passengers who died.
What are you saying?
Your fiancé's name isn't Jonas Jurgensen.
- Then what is it?
- Gene Jenkinson.
Who is Gene Jenkinson?
It says here, he was in the Vietnam War,
and he loves to cook.
There's not much else.
Oh, Gail... I hate to see
you in pain like this.
Thank you, Jeff.
- Please, call me by my middle name.
- Which is?
Also Jeff.
Jeff, it is.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the two new leads for Electro-City are...
Katie Finnerty and Logan St. Bogan!
Oh, my God!
Excuse me. Oh, my God.
Okay.
Um, so many people to thank. My parents,
Roger and Wendy.
My voice coach...
Sir Maxwell Dickinson.
My speech instructor, Dan Larson MacLeod.
My tap guy...
Is it too late to audition?
- Yes, Andy, it's too late.
- No...
No, it's not.
Let's see what you got, kid.
Claude?
You cannot recast.
You literally, mere seconds
ago, cast me in the role.
- Stuff it, Logan.
- Oh, fuck you!
Fuck you!
Take your time, son.
Whenever you're ready.
Andy has never done anything
on the stage before.
Raw clay can be good, Susie.
Sticks to your hands
when it's on the wheel,
but it glazes like a dream.
This is a song I wrote.
It's called "Champagne Eyes."
♪ These champagne eyes, they're trouble ♪
♪ My thoughts are on the ceiling ♪
♪ My gun is shot and wet ♪
♪ No surprise ♪
Wow.
♪ The lights are out, the money's gone ♪
♪ One breast is badly listing ♪
♪ Still you waltz around
with champagne eyes ♪
♪ Forever waltz about on champagne eyes ♪
♪ And still we walk around... ♪
Champagne eyes.
It's all I got, um...
I'm sorry I wasted your time.
Well, I won't lie to you, Andy.
You have talent.
But you're rough around the edges.
- So, did I get the part?
- Oh, you got the part, all right, mister.
But what about me?
I'm the best damn hoofer
you got, and you know it.
Don't worry, Logan.
You will play the part of the Warden.
The Warden? But
he only has one song.
Well, I suggest you make it a doozy.
Remember, no small parts.
Awesome.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the show is cast.
Hey.
So I guess we're gonna get
to do some hard neckin'.
Not everything's about making out, Andy.
I hope you learn to take
something seriously for once.
I hope you all had fun this afternoon,
and I also hope you learned a
thing or two about the mind.
To paraphrase the late Albert Einstein,
"We cannot solve our
problems with thinking.
We can only solve our problems by doing."
Mr. Brazen?
I'm sorry, we didn't mean to scare you.
We just want to tell you
how amazing that was.
Well, thank you very much.
The way you got Malcolm to eat all those
pieces of bread like that was hilarious.
Right on. Very fun.
And that was like four
entire loaves of bread.
He's gonna have the most
raging stomachache.
- So funny.
- Right on.
Very fun.
Well, good luck with your
show at Camp Snow Ledge.
Thank you. I will go do my
show at Camp Snow Ledge now.
If you'll excuse me...
- Ow, ow...
- Let's get out of here.
Ow, ow, ow...
What are you doing?
There is no Camp Snow Ledge.
I made that up.
- You mean...
- Yes.
You lied to Jackie Brazen?
No, I mean, I think the
government is on to us...
Run!
- Come on.
- I'm moving as fast as I can.
- Hurry up.
- You hurry up.
- Faster.
- I'm running. You run.
- I'm running.
- You call that running?
That's not running. I'm running.
Don't stop. Stay with me.
www.addic7ed.com