Hey, don't let the
heat out, boy!
I didn't expect
to find you here. What happened?
Her dad caught us
in the parlor.
You need lessons, son.
Sally's a nice girl, though.
Nice and common.
Common as dirt, like me.
My dear wife spent the
evening writing home.
Morning, Miss Drury.
That stupid boy's got
them all soaked, Mr. Lewis.
That's mine, I think, Mr. Lewis.
A little read before church.
I'll pluck your ears off.
Jimmy, I'm trying to better myself.
Now let em get on with it, you horrible man.
Jimmy, gimme that paper!
Give it to him,
for Heaven's sake.
Jimmy, I can't think.
She can't think.
You've never thought
in years, have you?
At why don't you leave all th
and sit down for a bit?
You look tired.
Oh, I won't be much longer.
Yeah. She's a beautiful girl, isn't she?
That's what they all tell me.
Wrap it up, will you?
Stop ringing those bells!
There's somebody going mad in here!
I don't want to hear them!
miss Drury will be up in a minute.
I don't give a damn
for miss Drury!
In any case, she's
probably in church by now
swinging on those
bloody bells.
Why sneer at people
who go to church?
Listen, that nice
old gentlewoman doesn't fool me,
even if she takes in you.
She's a foul-minded robber.
She bleeds us white
for this place as it is.
What about mummy?
How does mummy spend
her day of rest?
We usually go...
"Thank you, dear vicar,
for the nice, cozy sermon."
And then she tramples off
over better men's graves,
home to an orgy of curry.
Mummy and daddy, and brother Nigel
if he's up from town.
You know her brother Nigel?
No, I don't.
Well, you've never heard so
many well-bred commonplaces
come from beneath
the same bowler hat.
The platitude from outer space...
that's brother Nigel.
Why don't you dry up, boy?
Wouldn't you say that
was her private property?
I like to know when
I'm being betrayed.
Letters from her mother,
letters in which I'm not mentioned,
because my name is just a dirty word.
And what does she do?
She writes long letters back to mummy
and doesn't mention me at all,
because my name is just
a dirty word to her, too.
The little woman's family.
God help m e, I'll go out of my mind
if he doesn't stop
in a minute.
Why don't you?
That would be
something, anyway.
Don't let the Marquess of
queensberry manner fool you.
They'll kick you in the groin
while you're handing
your hat to the maid.
Jimmy, please don't go on.
they're either militant,
like her mummy and daddy,
militant, arrogant, and full of malice,
or else they're vague, like Nigel...
and her.
Nigel and Alison.
They're what they sound like:
sycophantic, phlegmatic, and pusillanimous.
Big words.
Would you like to hear what they mean?
No, not interested.
Soapy, stodgy, and dim.
Sounds like
a musical act.
Ladies and gentlemen,
those old favorites,
your friends and mine,
soapy, stodgy, and dim.
bringing quips
and strips for you,
Ladies and gentlemen,
as I was coming to the theater tonight,
a man comes up to me and he says...
Have you seen nobody?
Have I seen who?
ave you seen nobody?
Of course I haven't seen nobody.
Kindly, don't waste my time.
Ladies and gentlemen, a
little recitation entitled
"She was only a gravedigger's daughter
but she loved lying under the sod."
Are you quite sure you haven't
seen nobody?
Of course I haven't seen nobody.
Will you kindly go away?
Can't you see I'm trying to
entertain this lady here?
The lady pusillanimous.
I can't find nobody
anywhere. See...
Well, then, shall we dance?
Come here often, do you?
Only in the mating season.
All right. Very funny. Very funny.
not until you apologize
for being nasty to everyone.
Do you think bosoms
will be in or out this year, my dear?
Your teeth will be out
in a minute.
We'll see about that.
Look out, for Heaven's sake!
This place gets more like a zoo every day.
Proper coward, he is. See?
Are you all right?
Well, does it look like it?
She's burned her arm.
You think I did it on purpose?
Clear out of my sight!
Here, come and sit down, eh?
Now, let's have a look.
That's gonna be painful.
What shall I do with it?
It's nothing much.
A bit of soap on it will do.
There's some in the kitchen.
Now, give us your arm.
I'm gonna do it
ever so gently.
That better?
You're a brave girl.
I don't feel very brave.
I really don't
care for...
I don't think I can take much more.
I think I feel rather sick.
All over now.
I don't think I could
live on my own again,
in spite of everything.
Pretty rough and pretty
ordinary, really.
I'd seem worse on my own.
And you get fond
of people, too.
Worse luck.
I don't think I want anything more
to do with love.
Not anymore,
I can't take it on
You're too young to start giving up.
Too young and too lovely.
I keep looking back
as far as I remember,
and I can't think
what it was like to feel young...
really young.
Jimmy said the same
thing to me the other day,
and I pretended not to be listening,
because I thought it would
hurt him, I suppose...
but I knew just what he meant.
Oh, I suppose it would
have been so easy to say,
"Yes, darling,
I know what you mean,
I know how you're feeling."
it's those easy things that seem to be
so impossible with us.
I'm wondering how much
longer I can go on...
watching you two tearing the
insides out of each other.
You wouldn't seriously
think of leaving us?
What is it, lovely?
I'm frightened.
How's things?
Lousy.
I got the lot here, boyo.
Humbugs, mint lumps, jelly babies.
14 pounds of jelly babies.
What do you want to
get all those for?
Kids have got a craze on.
They'd better have.
What's this?
You know the regulations.
All foodstuffs 18 inches off the ground.
He was just unloading.
These sweets is human food.
I could have your license for that.
Porter... easy, isn't it?
I should be more careful
in future, if I was you...
not so cocky.
Comrade Hurst...
Commissar of the Kinley
Urban District Council.
I'd like to kick him in the teeth.
Mister, six pen's worth
of jelly babies, please.
You see, Cliff, you gotta study the market.
I hope she didn't make
a mess of your nice coat.
No, it's all right.
How old is she?
Only 15 months.
But she's that big...
Are you going in, Miss?
She doesn't take to 'er?
Funny how they know about people.
just relax a minute.
I'll put something on that burn.
- How did you do it?
- On the iron. I was careless.
Does your husband know about the baby?
In the next few months,
you're going to depend
a great deal on his
help and consideration.
- What's his profession?
- He has a sweet stall in the market.
I thought you told me once
he was a university graduate.
Is it too late to do anything?
I didn't hear
that question.
I hope you won't ask it again
- of anyone.
Or try to do
anything foolish.
I'm getting hungry.
You're a bloody pig.
I'm not a pig. I just like food,
that's all.
Like it? You're like a sexual maniac,
only, with you,
it's food.
You'll end up in
the news of the world, you wait.
"James Porter, age 25,
was bound over last week
after pleading guilty to interfering
with a small cabbage and tins of beans.
The accused said he hadn't been
feeling well for some time
and had been
having blackouts."
Hey, there's ma Tanner.
It's good to see you.
You look wonderful, ma.
Hello, son.
How are you?
Keepin' well?
You have got it nice.
- You approve?
- Yes.
Does you justice?
You bet.
- How long do you got, ma?
- Well, I'm only up for the day.
I came up to see me old man's grave.
Well, let's go and have a drink.
Oh, can you leave?
Yeah, and a bite to eat.
He's hungry.
He's runnin' off with me.
You want to watch him.
Who's the old girl, there?
She was his landlady,
set him up in this stall.
Oh, I do love a
port and lemon...
proper charlady's
tipple, isn't it?
Well, how's everything going, jim?
The stall is doing fine.
I know that, son.
You'll have paid
me off soon,
and I shall be able to
retire to the south of france.
I owe you a lot, ma.
You don't owe me
nothing, son.
Sometimes I've wondered
whether I did the right thing.
Oh, look who's here.
We was just
talking about you.
Jimmy, I wanted to talk to you.
Let me get you a little something.
Your hubby's been
doing the honors up to now
Come on, dear. It'll buck you up.
I don't want a drink, really.
That's whatshe's used to.
you're rig ht on for m, aren't you?
Look down your nose at her again and I'll-
l just couldn't bear to be touched
you made that
perfectly plain.
Did I?
She's only here
for a few hours.
Why don't you go ahead
and really spoil them for her?
- What about you, ma? Not taking anything?
- No, better not. This will do me.
I was just going to have a
look at me husband's grave,
make sure it's
been kept nice.
You know, if you don't
keep your eye on things,
people pinch the flower vases,
and the grass grows
all over the place.
I wouldn't like him to
think I neglected him.
That's quite a walk to the cemetery
up that steep hill.
Yes, especially
with my feet, dear.
Blimey, look at the time.
I'd better be goin' along.
Good thing you
reminded me.
There's no need
to go yet, ma.
There's plenty of time.
But I've got to buy me flowers yet,
and I promised my sister
I wouldn't be late back.
You sit still, dear,
and finish your drink.
Well, I've
- she's signing the pledge, ma.
I wish I'd done that years ago.
This way, ma.
now, who's got nice flowers?
I'll get 'em for you, ma.
No, I got to buy 'em.
I'll see you in a minute, ma.
I went to the doctor this morning.
So I see.
did you tell him
what happened?
But I didn't go.
did you te ll him I did it deliberately
"I'm terrified
of him, doctor.
Can't you think of a nice,
quiet asylum
where we can safely
lock him up?"
But it needs
doctors to certify a person.
Better get another before
that heals up.
what is it, lovely?
Nothing.
I said "what is it?"
you see,
I'm pregnant.
Two choc ices, please.
We don't sell them. Try down there.
Have you told Jimmy yet?
I tried to just now.
Hey, lovely, you've g ot to tell him.
Oh, you've done wonders with it, son.
Now, what's the time?
You've got plenty of time yet.
Oh, we had lots of fun, him and me,
bein' alive, you know,
just being alive.
That's enough for an
old girl like me,
chewin' the cud and havin'
a nip of what you fancy.
Wouldn't do if we was all
like that, would it, mate, eh?
Would it, mate?
What do you
really want, Jimmy?
There, now, it's
going to rain.
Look at me keeping you
out here in all this.
Upsy-daisy.
He was quite happy
in his own little way, you know.
He was doing
what he wanted
mind you, I don't reckon
he'd ever been a Henry Irving,
but you know what I mean.
Helena?
Yes, that will be
perfectly all right.
Yes, come along in about half an hour.
Thank you, Miss Drury.
If Mr. Lewis doesn't
mind giving up his room.
Oh, no. It's all right by me.
But no one seems to care about
Poor Arnold's supper. Do they, darling?
come along.
That was good
of you, Cliff.
Forget it, darling.
Always wanted to sleep on the landing.
Who is this Helena?
She's going to be working at the theatre
for the next couple of weeks.
Actress, is she?
Yes. So, when she telephoned...
I needed someone to talk to
do you understand, Cliff?
All right, darling.
Hey, lovely, does Jimmy know this Helena?
Yes. He hates her.
I took up a lot
of your time.
Oh, can you manage?
fine.
I better shift the
ladies, I suppose.
I mean, if she's a bit proper.
How's it feeling now?
It wasn't anything.
There's no need.
I mean it.
I did do it on purpose.
There's hardly a moment
when I'm not watching and wanting you.
Nearly years of being
in the same room with you,
and I still can't stop
my sweat breaking out
when I see you doing
something as ordinary as
leaning over an ironing board.
Trouble is you get used to people.
Even their trivialities
become indispensable to you.
Indispensable.
And a little mysterious.
I think I must have a lot of old stock.
And nobody wants it.
What shall we do tonight?
What would you like to do?
Drink?
No, I know what I'd like to do now.
Well, you'll have to
wait till the proper time.
There's no such thing
you're very beautiful.
Beautiful great-eyed squirrel
hoarding, nut-munching squirrel,
with highly-polished,
gleaming fur
And an ostrich feather of a tail.
How I envy you.
Bears and squirrels are marvelous.
Marvelous and cute.
What the hell's that?
That's a dance squirrels
do when they're happy.
What makes you think that you are happy?
you know, there was something
I was meaning to tell you.
Alison.
Your friend...
she's arrived.
Downstairs.
What friend?
Helena charles. I... I meant to explain.
She telephoned.
She's going to play at
the theatre next week.
I see.
She said, "Can I come over?"
and you said, "My husband, Jimmy,
if you'll pardon my using such a dirty word,
will be delighted to see you.
He'll kick your teeth in!"
- I asked her to stay.
- You did what?
Well, she couldn't find
anywhere else to stay.
That I don't believe.
So I said she could come here
until she fixes
somewhere else.
Did you tell her to wear her armor?
She's going to need it.
Why don't you
shut up, please?
My dear wife,
you have so much to learn.
If only something...
something would happen to waken you
From your beauty sleep
if you could have a child
and it would die.
Let it grow.
Let a recognizable human face emerge from this
little mass of India rubber and wrinkles.
Oh, please, if only
I could see you face that.
You know, I've never had
the great pleasure of lovemaking.
When I didn't desire it myself.
It's not that she doesn't have
her own kind of passion, she does.
She just devours me whole every time,
as if I was so me over-large rabbit.
and then lies back,
like a puffed-out python to sleep it off.
That's me
- that bulge around the navel there.
It's me, if you're wondering what it is.
You'd think this indigestible mass
would stir up some kind of tremor,
from those distended, overfed tripes
but not her!
She'll go on sleeping and devouring
until there's nothing left of me!
Good evening.
Evening, Miss Charles.
Did you manage all right?
I'm quite enjoying it.
I don't think I shall ever get used to
having go down
to the bathroom
every time I want water for something.
It is primitive, isn't it?
Oh, God, I wish he'd
lose that damned trumpet.
Well, I imagine it's
for my benefit.
Miss Drury will ask us to go soon.
I know she will.
Listen to him.
Do you know she was
actual ly taking that dog
Into the bathroom?
I think she was going to bathe it.
You mean Arnold!
Oh, that's better.
Does he drink?
Oh, he's not an alcoholic,
if that's what yuo mean.
Oh, that trumpet!
It's almost as if he wanted
to kill someone with it,
and me, in particular
never seen such hatred
in somebody's eyes before.
It's slightly
horrifying.
These go here?
Horrifying.
Oddly exciting.
- Why did you?
- Marry him?
There must be about
six different answers.
I met him at a party.
He'd come there on his bicycle,
and there was oil all over his jacket.
It had been such
a lovely day.
Everything about him
seemed to burn.
His face, the edges of his hair glistened,
and his eyes were so
blue and full of the sun.
So you took him on.
There never seemed to be any choice.
Did he love you?
A howl of outrage went up from my family.
Well, you can see their point.
And that did it.
He made up his mind to marry me,
went into battle with the
ax swinging round his head,
frail and so full of fire.
I've never seen
anything like it.
A knight in shining armor.
Except that his armor really
didn't shine very much.
Oh, God, now he's
started her up.
Mr. Porter!
Arnold's having a heart attack!
Stuff that flamin' thing
away somewhere, will you?
You like it, all right.
Anybody who doesn't like jazz
has no real feeling for music or for people.
Rubbish.
See what I mean?
I thought of the title of a new song.
It's called...
"You can quit hanging
around my counter, Mildred,
'cause you'll find my position is closed."
Very good.
Glad you like it.
If I can slip in
a religious angle,
it might be a big hit.
Don't you think so?
Why do you try so
hard to be unpleasant?
Do you have to be so offensive?
You think I'm being offensive?
Now?
She underestimates me, doesn't she?
I think you're a very tiresome young man.
"Oh, dear, oh, dear, my wife's friends.
Pass lady bracknell the cucumber sandwiches."
I'm going out to the jazz club.
You want to come?
Chris barber's
second night.
What about you?
You want to come?
I'm going out with Helena.
That's not a direction.
That's an affliction.
I feel so tired.
I dread him coming
into the room.
Listen, darling, you've got to tell him.
Either he learns to behave
like everyone else or...
Or you've got to get out
of this menagerie.
He doesn't know what love
or anything else means.
You see that bear and that squirrel?
Well, that's him,
and that's me.
You mean to tell me he's a bit fey
as well as everything else?
There's nothing fey about Jimmy.
It's the one way we have
of escaping from everything.
A sort of a silly symphony for people
who can't bear the pain of
being human beings any longer.
Won't it work?
Only if you blow it, dear.
Why don't you get in there
and liven things up a bit?
Is the funny thing
I think I can understand, for instance,
how Alison's daddy felt
when he came back from India.
The old edwardian brigade made
their brief little world
look pretty tempting.
High summer, long days in the sun,
slim volumes of verse,
bright ideas, bright uniform.
A romantic picture.
Phony, too, of course.
It must have rained sometimes.
I must say, it's
pretty dreary
living in the American age.
Unless, of course, you're an American,
perhaps all our children will be Americans.
That's a thought, isn't it?
I said, "That's a thought!"
forget about Helena.
She's only trying to help.
That unmarried
mother superior.
Black-hearted, evil-minded,
and vicious.
Oh, you've done it all.
I shouldn't have let you.
You've got to take
care of yourself now.
Everything seems
very different
with you here now.
Does it?
Before, I was on my own.
Now you've got me.
You're not sorry you asked me to stay?
No, of course not.
Cheer up, boyo.
You look like a laxative commercial...
before.
Up early today, aren't we?
I wanted to get everything done
before I had to go to rehearsal.
Alison mustn't tire herself.
Looking after one man is enough,
but two is quite an undertaking.
Cliff looks after himself.
Well, I can't say I've noticed it
let's put you in your
place, you welsh trash.
Are you a good actress?
Since we're going
to be stuck with you
for two solid weeks, I
only hope it's worthwhile,
that it adds to the sum of human happiness.
My egg's hard. Is yours?
I haven't seen yet.
Can't cook, either, can you?
what's this play of yours called?
"The forgotten heart".
Yes, I remember.
"A penetrating examination of love
and personal relationships."
Ran for two years in the West End.
Could you do that?
The bloke who wrote that
was never in a woman's bedroom...
not even his mother's when she found out
the truth about him.
Coming to rehearsal this morning, Alison?
Well, I've got things to do
they'll keep.
What are you two plotting?
Don't you think we've had enough
of the heavy villain?
Are you going to let yourself be taken in
by this saint in Dior's clothing?
Shall I tell you the
simple truth about her?
She is a cow.
I wouldn't mind that so much,
but she's in danger of becoming
a sacred cow, as well.
I'll help you wash up before I go.
Your slip is
showing, dear.
Behold the ball
that ben hogan lost.
My name is Johnny Kapoor.
My name is Jimmy porter.
This is Cliff Lewis.
Nice market here.
I applied for a license.
Let's see your stock
they'll sell a
t these prices?
Cheap stuff, eh?
Where'd you get it?
From a warehouse?
It is not stolen.
There's yo ur license. Fill it in.
And just keep your nose clean, that's all.
I've got my eye on some of you smart boys
that's right, Porter
One of these days...
let's see what
you've got here.
Look, Jimmy, what about this red shirt?
Match your eyes.
Hello, lovely.
Can I have some money, Jimmy?
What for?
I'm meeting Helena for lunch.
Well, let her pay.
don't make me feel like a pauper.
I want you to meet a n ew friend of mine
this is Mr. Kapoor. My wife.
Her family spent many years in India
grew to love the country and the people
Then I am most delighted.
How do you do?
You two should have a lot
to talk about sometime
Yes, perhaps.
Still the master race.
Here. Take memsahib out for tiffin
how about this one, then?
Cliff, how's your heart this morning?
what do you mean?
You fancy watching dame
Helena fl og herself to death
Take sight of my pitch, for me, will you?
Yes, sir.
See you, Johnny.
Look at this, then. Hey,
hey, come and look at this
real cheap.
Do you want to buy?
There are other stalls here,
same line of business.
But you sit in that great, beautiful,
impossible house of yours in somerset
buried in your trollope.
Who wrote this filthy thing?
Jimmy, what are you here for?
But, Ann, I've tried to understand.
We could be doing something
useful together, Ann.
Won't you come back?
Go on, Annie girl, have a go.
Oh, Jimmy, please don't interrupt again.
You'd better go, Henry.
Cut.
Ladies and gentlemen,
as I was on my way to the theater tonight,
passing the stage door,
a man comes up to me.
I say... here.
Have you seen nobody?
Have I seen who?
What's going on?
Who are you?
Ladies and gentlemen, a
little recitation entitled
"She was only a monkey's daughter,
but my, how she handled her nuts." Thank you.
Will you kindly go away?
I can't find nobody anywhere,
and I'm supposed to give him this case.
- Nobody?
- Yes.
Jimmy, get out of here!
Now let me get this straight,
sonny boy...
Nobody, nobody, came.
Who's that down there?
Nobody.
Then give
him his bloody case.
Who do you think you're?
I'll deal with this.
What do you mean by this?
- Who are you?
- Well, I'm her landlord, guy.
Yeah, she promised
us an audition...
Is he your landlord?
No. Yeah. I'm
staying with them.
Now, keep out of this.
Instead of paying rent,
she promised an audition.
Joke over, boyo,
let's go.
No, of course, if you
want to pay rent instead,
after all, I mean, it's up to you.
I know they don't pay
you much in this place,
but fair is fair.
It's not funny
any more, eh?
I demand my right!
I want my lolly!
As a member of the
delinquent classes,
I want my money!
You impertinent little phoney.
Messing in people's lives,
and you don't know
what any of it's about.
For your own sake,
don't ever do that again.
I've no public-school
scruples about hitting girls.
If you slap my face,
by God, I'll lay you out.
You would. You're the type.
You bet I'm the type.
I'm the type that
detests physical violence.
Jimmy, come out
of it, quick.
One of these days,
I may write a book about us all.
it's all here,
and it'll be written
in flames a mile high,
and it won't
be recollected
in tranquility, either,
picking daffodils with auntie wordsworth
it'll be written
in fire and blood.
Going out?
That's right.
On a Sunday evening in this town?
Where on Earth have you got to go?
She's coming
with me to church.
You're doing what?
when I think of what I did,
what I had to endure...
Yes, we all know what
you did for me.
You rescued me from the
clutches of my family
and all my friends.
From the clutches of mummy, at least
you know, mummy and I
took one quick look at each other,
and from then on, the
age of chivalry was dead.
Don't let's brawl, boyo.
It won't do any good.
Why not?
It's the only thing left
I'm any good at.
Jimmy boy.
There is nothing, no limit,
to what the middle-class mother will do
in the holy crusade
against ruffians like me.
She's probably
in that cistern by now,
taking down every
word we say.
Can you hear me, mother?
Just about fit
her in there.
You're an old cow,
and you ought
to be dead!
Shut up!
You've no right
to talk about her
mother like that.
I've every right,
haven't I?
She's an old cow
and she should be dead.
Well, what's the matter with you?
Why don't you spring to her defense?
Jimmy, don't.
if someone said that about me, she'd react.
She'd spring into her well-known
lethargy and say nothing.
and what's the matter with you
I just feel quite
sick, that's all,
sick with contempt
and loathing.
We'd better go.
I'll get my things.
What are you
trying to do to me?
Trying to twist my arm
off with your silence?
I've given you just everything.
You... you judas.
You phlegm.
She's taking you with her,
and you're so bloody
wet, you let her do it.
All I want is
a little peace.
She wants peace.
One of us is crazy...
mean and stupid
and crazy.
Which is it?
Is it me?
Standing like an
hysterical girl,
hardly able to
get my words out?
Or is it her,
sitting there, putting on her shoes,
to go out with that... that... aah!
One of these days,
you may want to come back.
I want to be there that day.
I want to stand
up in your tears
and splash about
in them and sing.
I want to be there
when you grovel.
I want to be there, I want to
watch it. I want the front seat.
I want to be
there when you...
when your face is
rubbed in the mud.
There's nothing
else I can hope for.
else I want any more.
There's a call
for you downstairs.
it can't be anything good, can it?
God, what's the matter with him now?
It's as if you've
done him wrong...
and you just sit there
and do nothing!
That's right. I just sit here.
What sort of a man are you?
I'm not the district
commissioner...
Listen, Helena,
this has always been a battlefield
and I'm pretty certain
that if I hadn't been here
everything would have been over
between these two long ago.
I love these two people very much.
and I pity all of us.
I don't understand
you or him or any of it.
Listen, Allison, I'm going to
call your father.
I'm going to ask him
to come up and fetch you home.
Now, you'l l go when he
comes for you, won't you
Yes, I'll go.
I expect he should
be here by 4:00.
Perhaps, after
you've gone...
Jimmy will come to his senses
and face up to things.
We'll be late
if we don't hurry.
Ma Tanner.
She's had a stroke.
How bad is she?
They didn't say much.
I think she's dying.
You ever seen anybody die?
No, I haven't.
For 12 months, I
watched my father die
when I was ten years old.
He'd come back from the
war in spain, you see.
All my mother could think
was that she was married
to somebody who
was on the...
on the wrong side
in all things.
Perhaps she pitied him.
I was the only
one who cared.
Hour upon hour...
I sat in that little room.
And he would talk, you know.
Pour out all that was left of his life
to a small, frightened boy
who could barely understand
half of what he said.
All I could feel was the despair,
and the bitterness,
the sweet, sickly smell of a dying man.
See, I learned at an early age
what it is to be angry... angry.
Helpless.
The train leaves
in half an hour.
You're coming with
me, aren't you?
I need you to
come with me.
Let's go.
I brought you these.
You know
what done this?
Too many...
port and lemon...
You know, you're not
supposed to talk, you know.
You've got to do things...
That's what you're
made of.
Nurse!
Don't...
...let yourself down.
Nurse. Come quick! Quick!
Don't let yourself down!
Wait outside,
please.
Staff nurse.
Hell!
My? Know what he said about mum
he said she was an overfed
overprivileged,
old cow.
And what did he say about me?
He doesn't seem to mind you so much.
In fact, I think h
e rather likes you.
"Poor old daddy
just one of those sturdy, old plants
left over from t
he edwardian wilderness
that can't understand
Why the sun isn't shining anymore?
Why did you ever have
to meet this young man?
Daddy, please don't
put me on trial now.
I've been on trial every
day and night of my life
For the past two years,
but why should he
have married you,
feeling as he did
about everything?
Perhaps it
was revenge.
But why you...
my daughter?
What is it?
"An old plant left over from
the edwardian wilderness."
I think the last time the sun shone
was when that
dirty little train
steamed out of that crowded,
suffocating indian station,
and the battalion band
playing for all it was worth.
I knew in my heart it was all over then
- everything.
You're hurt because everything is changed,
and Jimmy's hurt because
everything is the same.
Something's gone wrong
somewhere, hasn't it?
It looks like it, my dear.
This is a
big step you're taking
Is it really what you want?
I was going to come
and help you pack, but...
Well, it looks as though
you've done it all.
Well, Helena,
we may as well go.
Alison's mother will
be worried, I know.
She's not very well.
I'm so sorry. I hope
I didn't upset her
with my telephone call
- We were very grateful that you did.
- Do be careful of of the second step.
Helena, what about your case?
Oh, she isn't coming with us.
She's still playing at the theater.
Can't get into my new digs till tomorrow.
Well, I'd better
put this in the car.
Oh, look.
They're coming
so you're really going then?
Should think Jimmy'll
be back pretty soon.
You won't wait?
Who's going to tell him?
Don't you think you ought
to tell him yourself?
Bit conventional, isn't it?
I'm a conventional girl.
This place is gonna be really
cockeyed now, you know that?
Look after him
for me, please.
Don't worry about anything
at all. Everything'll be fine.
I hope you're right, that's all.
what do you mean, I'm right?
It was Jimmy.
Here. You give it to him.
He's all yours. Oh, no, Cliff.
And I hope he rams it up your nostrils!
One of those, is it?
How could she be
so bloody wet?
Deep loving need of me...
she couldn't say, "rotten
swine, I hate your guts.
"I'm going away,
and I hope you rot."
What are you
doing here, anyway?
You'd better keep
out of my sight,
Or I'll kick your head in.
If you'd stop thinking about
yourself for just one moment,
I'll tell you something
I think you ought to know.
Your wife is going
to have a baby.
Well, doesn't that
mean anything?
Even to you?
If you'll permit me
to interrupt your...
female wisdom,
there's something
perhaps you ought to know.
I don't care if she's
going to have a baby.
I don't care if
it has two heads.
Well, do I
disgust you?
Go on. Slap my face.
I've just come back from
seeing somebody I love very much
go through the sordid
process of dying.
And you expect me to be overcome with awe because
some stupid, cruel girl is going to have a baby?
Well, now the
performance is over.
Now, you leave me
alone, and get out,
you evil-minded
little virgin!
Kill the lights.
That's all.
Thank you, darling,
have a nice weekend.
How was it?
It was a funeral...
no flowers, no word, no sign.
What do you mean?
I mean Alison.
The injustice of it
is almost perfect.
The wrong people going hungry,
the wrong people...
being loved.
The wrong people dying.
I shan't be long.
Why does one spend half of Sunday
reading the newspapers?
Have you read about
the grotesque
And evil practices
going on in the midlands?
About the what?
"...and last week, a well-known debutante
related how, during an
evil orgy at market harbor,
she killed and drank the
blood of a white cockerel."
I bet fortnum's are doing a
roaring trade in sacrificial cocks.
Sounds madly depraved.
Yes. Terribly "us", isn't it?
Do you ever go in for that kind of thing?
Not lately.
Oh, it sounds like your cup of tea...
Cup of blood, I should say.
Well, we could try it if you like.
Yes, for a start, we could
roast him over the gas fire.
After all, the whole point
of a sacrifice is that you
get rid of something you
never really had any use for.
You'd make an admirable sacrifice.
Afterwards, we could have
a loving cup of his blood.
Can't say I fancy it much. I've seen it.
It's like tomato sauce
- ever so common.
Now, yours would be
much better, wouldn't it?
Sort of a pale cambridge blue.
What are you laughing at?
Nothing. I never
used to be sure
when he was being
serious or when he wasn't.
I don't think he knows himself
half the time.
when in doubt, mark it down as an insult.
Hey, I thought of the
title of a new song today.
It's called, my mother's in the madhouse,
that's why I'm in love with you.
Come on, maestro. Take it away.
There's a certain little lady,
now, you all know
who I mean,
she may have
been to rodean,
but to me she's still a queen.
Someday, I'm
going to marry her.
When times
are not so bad,
Her mother doesn't care for me.
So I'll have to
ask her dad.
Don't be afraid to
sleep with your sweetheart.
Just because she's
better than you.
Those forgotten
middle classes,
May have fallen
on their noses.
But a girl
who's true blue?
The angels up above
Will know that
you're in love?
So don't be afraid to
sleep with your sweetheart.
Because she's better than you.
They call me Sydney! Just
because she's better than you.
Hey, be careful now.
I'll show you terrible destruction!
I'm sending some
of her things on.
"My dear Alison,
I hope that what I wrote
before didn't hurt you too much.
I know now it's
true, in spite of myself.
I do love him."
She was a jolly, super puppy,
weren't you, Dinah?
She's 15.
We ought to have
her put down.
Nonsense, my dear. There's
nothing the matter with her.
All she needs is a walk.
Feel like coming?
Better not. I don't
want to upset Dr. Blair.
He seemed happier
the last time you saw him.
The usual... lecture about
taking care of myself,
but I don't think they'll
be any more trouble.
He's been kicking
like mad today.
He?
Yes, I always say he.
I wonder if it will be like its father.
Would mummy hate it?
I've often thoug ht your
mother went too far over Jimmy
but you didn't
approve of him.
Of course not.
I think you take after me,
my dear.
you like to sit
on the fence
because it's comfortable and more peaceful.
Sitting on the fence...
I married him, didn't I?
Are they strong?
They're cough drops, you know,
not a miracle drug.
And you're no flaming
faith healer, either.
Jimmy, can I have a bit of
money to finish shopping?
But of course
business slack today?
There's nothing much doing
want to go to the pictures?
Well, Cliff will look after
the shop. Won't you, Cliff?
Why not?
Meet you there in 10 minutes?
They wouldn't take these
jelly babies back, you know?
Got too many.
The kids had a craze on.
You don't like
Helena, do you?
you didn't seem very
keen yourself once.
It's not the
same, is it?
Of course it isn't
the same, you idiot.
Today's meal is always
different from yesterday's.
The last woman is never
the same as the one before.
Nylons, he calls them.
Look at that, inspector.
There's no foot in it. Never has been.
Inspector, I have not
seen this lady before.
These are
not my nylons.
Give me your license.
Shut up, you. Let's
hear what he's gotta say.
Keep out of th is! Let's hear his side!
Are you sure you bought them from him?
Yes. When?
When did you buy them?
Two weeks ago, market day.
Two weeks ago? But I was sick
that time. Do you remember?
What's he trying to say
that he wasn't here to sell them.
Look it up in your record book.
Go on.
Well, if it wasn't him,
it was one of his friends.
They're all the same.
Here. Take it.
Stupid clod.
Letting him walk all
over him like that.
What do you want?
Penny ranger bar, mister.
I don't think I shall
stay here much longer.
Why not?
I don't know.
The sweet stall's all right,
but I'd like to
try something else.
Well, you're highly
educated and it suits you,
but I need something a bit better.
Well, it's your business, I suppose
and another thing...
be easier for Helena,
just the two of you.
You'd better go,
hadn't you?
She'll be waiting.
I'll come back later
to help you clear up.
We'll talk about it then.
Anything wrong?
Cliff tells
me he's leaving us.
Yes, I know. He told me last night.
I always seem to be at the end of the
queue when they're passing out information.
Sorry he's going.
He's sloppy and irritating,
but he's got a big heart.
You can forgive somebody
almost anything for that.
Perhaps you do,
perhaps it means something to have your...
general lie back
in your arms,
even though
he's heartily sick
of the whole
campaign...
tired and
hungry and dry
Don't let anything go wrong.
You're either with me
or against me.
I've always wanted you...
Tell her majesty to send a gunboat.
Look, if you don't want to
watch the film,
don't spoil it
for those that do.
Don't like this country, why
the hell don't they get out?
God, Jimmy, what's
going to become of us?
I don't know.
Do you know what Alison once said?
You were born out of your time.
I think I know what she means
sometimes I think you feel
You're still in the
middle of the French revolution.
Jimmy, can't you give
up that damn sweet stall
and do something else?
I don't know. There are so
many things that you could do.
Such as being a
literary gent?
Porter, the lion
of the pen club?
Laughing Porter,
the tv panelist?
Lord Porter,
leaving number 10?
The personality cult of Porter.
Let's examine it, that
glittering, meteoric cause.
While the rest of the world
is blown to bits about us,
what's the only thing that matters?
Me! Me!
What's the matter with you?
He's been chucked
out of the market.
We've got
to fight them.
Pinch-bottom hurst,
the town clerk,
the mayor himself
- the whole fascist gang.
Why? There are plenty of other towns.
Damn it, man, don't you
want to see justice done?
I am most interested in justice,
but I am not in the habit
of expecting it to apply to me.
Now, listen, Hurst got
you on a pure technicality.
He tried this afternoon and failed and-
Go on. What
did Hurst do?
You took his license away from
him without any real reason.
Ever since he landed here, he's been
at the sticky end of your personal spite
now, listen, sir.
I watched it!
Before you make a bigger
fool of yourself,
there's something
you ought to know.
This time, it was
their complaint-
some of your
friends there.
They informed on him?
Why? What's the idea?
You don't want
him here.
What's he done?
Seen his prices, son? We've got to eat.
You're lucky, lad. He
might have sold sweets.
Kapoor.
Mr. Hurst, come and h ave a drink with us.
What'll you have?
You'll have a shot?
I should move on now.
As I said, goodbye.
What made you come to this
bloody country, anyway?
I came, because in india I was an outcast...
an untouchable.
Any idea what
you're going to do?
Not much.
Sounds just
like you.
Shouldn't think you'll last
five minutes
without me to explain the score to you.
Right, shouldn't
think so.
You're such a
scruffy beast.
I bet some respectable
little madame will...
gobble you up in 6 months,
marry you, send you to work,
and you'll end up
clean as a new pin.
I'm stupid enough for that, too.
I seem to spend my
life saying goodbye.
My feet hurt.
Try washing your socks.
Here's your train.
funny thing is
you've been loyal, generous, a good friend.
I'm quite prepared to see you go off
and make a home
for your own and...
all because I want...
I want something.
Something from that girl
which i... I know in my heart
she's incapable
of giving.
You're worth half a dozen
Helenas to me, you know that?
If you were in my place, you'd do
the same thing, wouldn't you? Right?
Oh, thanks, Helena.
Very decent of you.
Write now and again, and not
jus t dirty postcards, eh?
Give Miss Drury
a kick somehow, eh?
darling, what do you say
we get out of this business
and start from scratch? What do you say?
I'd say that's
wonderful.
We'll do that. Let's
go and have a drink.
We'll get pleasantly tiddly,
then I'll take you home
And make such love to you
you'll forg et about anything at all.
Why not champagne?
British railways
special cuvee.
Two double scotch, please.
Friend of yours
to see you.
Watch where you're going.
Miss, do you want
these drinks?
Ten shillings. Ta.
I think this is what
you need, what we both need!
How long have you been here?
An hour or two.
I must be mad,
coming here like this
I'm sorry, Helena.
So many times, I managed
to stop myself coming here
right at the
last minute.
Even today, when
I got on the train,
I panicked. I felt like a criminal.
I told myself
that when...
when I got here, I'd turn
round and go straight back.
Alison, what's happened?
I lost the child.
I feel so ashamed.
Helena, don't bring
out the book of rules.
You're his wife,
aren't you?
Please don't make me
feel like a blackmailer.
Whatever made me come here,
I never intended to make a breach
between you and Jimmy.
You must believe that.
I believe it, all right.
That's why everything seems
more wrong and
terrible than ever.
You talk as though you'd
swindled him out of me.
You talk as though
he were a book
you pass to whoever
wants it for five minutes.
you loved him, didn't you?
You wrote and told me.
And it was true.
Helena, it's no use.
You must go back to him.
I'll catch the
next train.
Kitty, have the next one with us
Go away.
And your friend.
Alison, I don't like
to leav e you like this.
I'll be all right. Goodbye.
Alison, are you...
you didn't have a return ticket.
I forgot. I meant to get one.
Alison, it's all over.
I'm leaving.
I've just come
to get my things.
She's persuaded
you this time?
Not at all.
She's been very ill, Jimmy.
She's lost...
my child, too, you know.
I suppose none of this could
ever really have worked.
But I do love you, Jimmy.
I shall never love anyone
as I've loved you...
But I can't go on.
I can't take part in
all this suffering.
It's no good fooling
about with love, you know.
You can't fall into
it like a soft job
without dirtying
up your hands.
It takes
muscle and guts.
If you can't bear the thought of
messing up your nice, tidy soul,
you'd better g ive up the whole
idea of life and become a saint,
because you'll never
make it as a human being.
It's either this world
or the next.
I didn't know about the baby.
I don't exactly
relish the idea
of pain and
suffering, but...
it wasn't my first loss, you know.
It was mine.
Remember that time we first met...
At that grisly party?
You didn't really notice me at all.
I couldn't take my eyes
off you all evening.
You seemed to have such a...
wonderful relaxation of spirit.
I knew that was
what I wanted.
Then after we were married, I discovered
it wasn't relaxation, after all.
To relax, you've got to
sweat your guts out first.
You never had a hair out of
place or a bead of sweat anywhere.
I know I'm
a lost cause,
but I thought if you loved
me it didn't really matter.
It does matter!
I was wrong.
I don't want
to be neutral.
I want to be
a lost cause.
Nd?
Don't you understa
it's gone- that helpl
ess human being inside my body
re, I thought it was so
safe and secure in the
but it's lost.
All I wanted
was to die.
I was in pain,
And all I could think
of was you and what I'd lost.
I thought if...
if only he could
see me now...
so ugly and stupid
and ridiculous.
I thought "this is what
he's wanted from me,
"this is what he wants
to splash about in.
I'm in the fire,
and I'm burning,
and all I want is to die.
It's cost
him his child
and any others
I might have had."
No, don't.
No, please don't.
You'll be
all right.
We'll be together
in our bear's cave,
our squirrel's drey,
and we'll live on honey and nuts
- lots and lots of nuts.
You'll keep those
big eyes on my fur
and help me to keep
my claws in order,
because I'm a bit of a
soppy, scruffy sort of bear.
And I'll see that you
keep that sleek, bushy tail
gleaming as it should,
because you're...
you're a very
beautiful squirrel.
But you know, you're none too bright,
either, so we'll have to be careful.
Cruel steel traps
everywhere,
just waiting for rather
mad, slightly satanic,
very timid
little bears.
Poor squirrels.
Poor bears.