This is UNSC FFG-201
"Forward Unto Dawn".
Requesting immediate evac.
Survivors aboard.
Prioritization code:
Victor-0-5-dash-3
dash-Sierra-0-1-1-7
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
UNSC FFG-201 "Forward Unto Dawn".
Requesting immediate evac.
Survivors aboard.
Locked on to frequency, tracking coordinates.
Crossing now.
Play it again, please.
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday. This is
UNSC FFG-201 "Forward Unto Dawn".
Have a lock.
Shall I play it again sir?
Sir?
Commander Lasky?
Cryo-pods opening.
Lasky? You okay?
Are you alright?
Lasky, let's go.
Hastati Squad: 4 minutes to rendezvous point.
Copy Vickers. Time of 4 minutes.
Will you be able to shoot
with those hands?
We'll find out.
- Come on!
- Axios!
10 seconds. Closing in.
Lasky, come on, let's go!
We're under heavy fire!
Vickers, checkpoint!
Covering.
Move it.
Take cover. Checkpoint.
- Test, checkpoint.
- Uh, 50 seconds.
Go.
Silva, Sullivan, Lasky - where are you guys?
RV in 15 seconds.
Are you ready?
I'll see you at the party.
- Sully!
- We have to leave him!
- Lasky, what the hell!?
- Come on!
Lasky!
10 seconds.
- Lasky, hurry up!
- Landing in 3...2...
...1.
Enemy inbound.
He'll be on us in 35 seconds.
Fresh mags in your weapon,
prepare to attack.
- What?
- Our objective is to neutralize the insurrectionists
and acquire the target.
We move on my mark.
30 Seconds.
We should flank them and force a surrender.
We're too close to flank and
Innies never surrender.
It would be more like a "circle round".
There's still time.
We can make it.
25 seconds. Guys.
It's our best move.
20 seconds.
No, we're sticking to my plan, okay.
On my mark.
- It won't work.
- You're not in charge any more, Lasky.
- Tom just do what he says.
- 15 seconds.
They're my orders.
I don't care.
10 seconds.
5 seconds.
Axios!
Lasky!
Hastati Squad leader on the field.
Exercise paused.
Let me guess, Lasky -
you ignored orders.
It's just...
another strategic casualty, sir.
Unacceptable.
Game over.
Shoulder your weapon, cadet.
Your little escapade kept Hastati Squad
from achieving its objective...
...again.
Great job, Lasky.
Exercise complete.
0 wins. Hastati defaults.
Shit.
Robot tagme?
Yeah, once from two meters.
Twice from one.
I'm still numb from all those stun rounds.
I'm always numb.
Hastati!
Port ARMS!
General Black, sir!
Let me remind you, cadets...
...this academy bears the name
of the Roman general
Gnaeus Domitius Corbulo.
Because he represents honor, valor,
allegiance.
General Corbulo
was to take his own life
in the name of the Empire.
Corbulo did not
hesitate nor question.
He loyally obeyed, screaming "Axios!"...
...as he fell upon his own sword.
Axios:
I...am...
...worthy.
But I'm afraid, cadets, today
you have proven to be anything but.
We are at war with insurrectionists. Terrorists
who would like nothing
more than to see all of us dead.
Had this been a real fire fight,
the rebels would have likely killed
every member of Hastati Squad.
Every single one of
you at this academy
was sent here because your
parents are the upper echelon
of the United Nations Space Command.
Because all of you are its future.
And I expect you to act like it.
Understood, sir!
Well, what are you waiting for?
Lead them on tour, Orensky.
Axios!
Hastati...
...right face.
Double march.
- Sully, please, enough.
- No, seriously I'm on to something here.
The comms are messed up and
I'm decoding something kick-ass.
- Nobody wants to hear it, Sully.
- ONI's hiding stuff from us, I'm positive.
They've got secrets.
Stop stepping on our dicks, Lasky.
Hey, ease up, Gingerbread.
No, Sully, Vickers is right.
My combat scores suck because of you.
Don't both, Junjie. He's gone soft.
- He's an Innie lover now.
- Dimah, that order didn't make any sense.
It doesn't have to make sense.
Just follow it.
I'm trying to survive here, okay?
You need to respect the chain of command.
The UNSC isn't the enemy.
The Innies are.
Spoken like a true believer.
Yeah, well, at least I believe
in something these days.
Cadet Thomas Lasky: report to
Colonel Mehaffey's office immediately.
- No, we're sticking to my plan, okay. On my mark.
- It won't work.
- Tom, just do what he says.
- They're my orders.
I do not care.
Pause.
You don't care? You do realize
your helmets transmit everything.
No excuse, sir.
You continue pulling down your squad, you're
going to end up with a lot of enemies.
Yes, sir.
I served under your mother,
I know what she's like.
And I sure as hell don't need to tell you that
Colonel Lasky's not going to let a son of hers
leave this academy without a diploma.
I wouldn't know what mother thinks, sir.
I never see her.
It's been a long war.
Your mother holds a lot of hands.
So I'm told, sir.
You know, Thomas...
...I've seen a lot of cadets come through here.
Many have suffered like you.
Pain like that cannot be forgotten.
But you can learn how to tolerate it.
I'll do my best, sir.
That will be all.
- How long have you had the blisters?
- Been on and off for a few weeks, but...
...these are from yesterday.
Any other symptoms?
It's getting hard to breathe.
Okay, let's keep an eye on them.
Cryo-training can take its toll.
Get out of my room. What the hell, man?
Eric, get your filthy
hands off me before I belt you.
Hey.
I'm not a virgin.
You really shouldn't be looking
at that stuff, Sully.
Score.
Hey, little bro. Hello from Jericho 7,
it's Day 131 of deployment.
Uh, so I gotta show you something.
Alright, Mom's going to flip when she sees this.
But, whatever.
It's still a little raw.
But we got a big job on an Innie stronghold next week.
Wanted to get it done before then.
- Anyways.
- So, you haven't been court-marshaled yet then?
I'm not apologizing.
Yes you are.
- "At least I believe in something?"
- I do believe in something.
- Yeah, so do I.
- Like what?
Just not in stupid orders that
lead to needless violence.
Negotiating isn't an option anymore, Tom.
So we're brainwashing kids and then
sending them in to exterminate a bunch of
...over-taxed farmers.
- Farmers?
That's who you think they are?
You have no ideas what the Innies are like.
I have a pretty good idea.
Well, then you should know
how much they hate us.
And that they're not going to stop
fighting until we're all dead.
Can you blame them?
Yeah.
I can. I blame them
for a lot of things.
And you should too.
Uh, I'm staying safe.
I'm doing my job.
I just want to remind you to do your job.
Oh, and by the way.
Nice checkmate, bro.
Yet again.
Okay, new game.
Your move.
And hang in there.
I know it's tough with Mom
being gone all the time.
Being alone.
She loves you. So do I.
Miss you, buddy.
I miss you too.
Lights out. Doors closing.
We've been floating endlessly in space
for 1,651 days
6 hours and 19 minutes.
Over four years aboard
this ship with nothing to do.
No tasks to complete.
For over four years...
all I have done...
is think.
For over four years...
all I have done...
is think.
What are you dreaming in there?
Come on, JJ. The robot's gonna be pissed.
Shut up, Sully.
I got it!
Your shirts on backwards, asshole.
Go! Go, go, go!
Get there quick!
Go! Keep moving!
Are you tippy-toeing?
Wake up, Hastati!
Move it!
Faster!
Wake up!
A little early for General Black,
don't you think?
Why are you stopping?
Are you waiting for your fancy mommy
to come and finish it for you?
That looked like slow motion to me.
Wake up, Hastati.
Don't like being up at 0400?
Tomorrow it will be 0300.
Weapons check!
Weapons check.
Orlin, lights.
Cadet.
Cadet!
You're already dead, son.
Orlin, cadets Silva's time?
51.07 seconds,
cadet April Orenski.
Not good enough today, cadet Vickers.
I believe cadet Silva's time was
just shy of the Academy record,
held by Cadmon Lasky.
Now that was a real soldier.
A soldier who did not give up.
Tomorrow, you will engage in the
last major exercise of this term.
Hastati Squad's future at this Academy
will depend on its performance.
Score.
- Where did you get this?
- Dimah.
You could get in a lot of trouble.
Now you can't tell your
mom about this, okay?
I won't say anything.
Advisory: select communication systems
will be down for system maintenance
at 0400.
Cadet Vickers.
Yes, sir!
You realize that you
and Lasky are the reason
I had to run the tour
yesterday with you noobs.
And why we all had to get up at 0400.
Yes, sir.
So, as you can imagine,
I'm pretty hungry.
And I do love this Academy's kiesh.
Nice, April.
Sir.
So hand them over.
Both of you.
With such a renowned pedigree I sure
expected you to be a better soldier, Lasky.
Sir.
You're dismissed.
Must be tough on your mom...
...knowing her real son
is never coming home.
Oh, Lasky and Vickers!
Officer on deck!
Outside.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Answer me.
Nothing, sir.
Well, maybe there's hope for you yet.
Sir?
There's a soldier inside of you,
Thomas. I can see it.
Everyone can see it.
You need to see it.
I know your brother did.
Yes, sir.
Now go get yourself
cleaned up before class.
Axios!
Hey, bro.
Hello from Arcadia.
The jungles of Arcadia.
So what can I tell ya?
Tell him how you got your new nickname!
- What? No.
- Jack: I'll tell him.
Jack, come on, I got it,
I swear. I'll tell him. I'll tell him.
Alright, you're especially gonna love this.
So we make a drop in the rain
forest, a couple weeks ago.
We see this river, me and the boys,
we decide to take a dip.
Ridge warns us all not to not drink the water.
Ridge: Yeah, I did.
Of course, the first thing I do
is to get a mouthful.
I almost ruin my body suit,
couple times.
So now they call me, uh, "Volcano".
Marines: Ha, ha! Volcano!
The "Pincer Movement":
The strategy used in Earth's second
Punic War against the Roman Republic...
...at the battle of Cannae.
Orlin, begin.
Lesson beginning.
Red represents the Romans' troops,
blue, Hannibal's.
Hannibal placed his spear-men
and slingers at the front.
Behind him, his swordsmen
flanked by cavalry.
When the Romans attacked
Hannibal's swordsmen retreated.
To the Romans that seemed to be
due to their force but in reality
Hannibal had ordered the retreat.
As the Romans continued
to drive the swordsmen back
Hannibal's cavalry galloped in from behind.
Once the attacking pincers connected,
the Romans where completely surrounded.
This is an actual strategy?
It does seem a little basic.
The Romans outnumbered Hannibal's
troops by over 10,000 strong.
And yet, they were defeated.
Why?
Hubris.
Never underestimate your opponents.
Never underestimate what
they'll sacrifice for victory.
Questions?
Yeah.
How do we apply this?
Yeah, we don't have horses.
True, we don't. But what do we have instead?
ODSTs.
Exactly.
They drop behind enemy lines.
Attack from the rear.
Neutralize.
Or die trying.
It's a question as old as war itself:
"If someone is trying to kill you...
...are you not to rise against him...
...and kill him first?"
You were hanging on her every word.
Why wouldn't I?
I just hear the drum beat of endless war
and that doesn't make me an Innie lover.
Tell me how wrong I am.
Look.
You want people to change?
You want this war to end?
Yeah, of course.
And you're gonna need
people to follow you.
Tomorrow, Hastati Squad will
try not to embarrass itself
...yet again.
You are a unit.
Your lives are in each other's hands.
This morning's victor,
cadet Silva, knows this
because her parents gave
the ultimate sacrifice
and died on the battle field.
Let success in tomorrow’s exercise
be not just for our honor
but for those who have
fallen so you can be here.
All cadets, please be advised:
New mandatory curfew tonight at 2100.
Final combat exercise of this term:
Hastati versus Zuma
Floats, prepare for cryo-injections.
Attention!
Today's mission is to capture the flag.
I expect a better outcome than last time.
Permission to speak, sir.
Speak.
I'd like to take point, sir.
Okay, Lasky. Let's see if
you still got it in you.
But for your sake you better hope
you can pull some magic out
of your ass or you'll be running
tour for the rest of the year.
Understood, sir.
Hastati Squad,
one minute to RV point.
On my mark...
3, 2, 1.
Mark.
Come on, pick it up.
Cover.
Move in!
No sign of Silva!
- Let's go!
- Move, move!
Keep moving!
Zuma's out here. Watch your back!
Move in!
At RV point.
- I'm here.
- Arriving.
Equal numbers.
Deadlock to green.
What's your plan?
We're waiting.
Why are we just sitting here?
If we have equal numbers we just fight it out.
Yeah, just be patient.
Amazing freak.
Okay, they're moving.
Take off your helmets.
What?
That's pretty wild-card Lasky.
We'll be flying blind.
Trust me.
Eyes up. Eyes up.
We're gonna flank them.
They're all together.
Found 'em!
Huh?
Now!
Chyler, cover!
Lasky?
I hate you.
- Cortana!
-  Stop it. I've made up my mind.
Maybe if I'm going to die aboard this ship,
then Chief will suffer
the same fate as me.
- Cortana stop...
-  You sacrificed everything...
- for him.
- Control yourself.
I can't.
This isn't right.
Something is...
Something set us down.
Something. Interesting.
I need to think.
Thinking is what's killing you.
What happened?
You passed out during a training exercise.
My chest feels like it's on fire.
Turns out the cryo blisters
and your difficulty breathing
are an allergic reaction
to the psydoprethaline.
It's a drug we inject
to keep ice crystals
from forming in your
cells during cryo sleep.
Occurs in about 1 in
every 50,000 or so.
So I won't be able to breath
every time I wake up from cryo sleep?
The intensity of your allergy
is still undetermined.
I'll know more in a few hours.
I want you to take it real easy
the rest of the day, cadet.
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Hey bro.
I'm on Andesia, it's a jump away from home.
It's day, uh...
...496.
I'm sorry I didn't com yesterday.
Couldn't. We got pinned in a
firefight for seven hours.
Uhh, I must've killed
a dozen Innies though.
Mom would be proud.
We're doing really good work here.
We're doing a good thing.
Rich didn't make it.
You remember Rich from back home.
He was right there next to me and then...
...wasn't.
A pineapple and I'm flying
in four different directions.
I had to shave it all off for Rich.
He said it made me look tough.
Anyways, uh...
...I gotta go, bro.
I can't wait to get home.
We'll see ya. Cadmon, out.
What are you doing?
Why do you torment yourself with these?
Are you okay?
- Whoa.
- I've been better.
Wh, what did Dr. Hughes say?
That it's nothing.
Really?
You know we won today.
Your strategy worked.
That's just me, being a leader.
Lasky, wake up.
Oh, hey, Chyler.
What's up, Sully?
Get in here,
you guys gotta see this.
You look like crap.
Alright, so feast
your eyes on grade "A"
classified non-licit intelligence
vids I pieced together.
Super pain in the ass to do but...
so worth it.
This is beyond top secret.
I've never seen something
encrypted so hard but I cracked it.
Wow.
- It's crazy, huh?
- Yeah.
Wait, wait, wait, wait
now here comes the best part.
-  Watch his hand.
- Target acquired.
They're coming!
That thing is like
two feet taller then we are.
Pretty crazy, huh?
Now check this out.
We've got an unknown hostile.
Pulling back.
- Uh, no way!
- Now who do you think they're running from?
Are they fighting together?
Okay now,
here comes the bast part.
- Whoa.
- What is that thing?
Now what do you think that is?
It is now 1800.
All cadets report to the mess hall.
What do you think that thing was?
Definitely not an ODST.
Then what could it be?
Maybe some upgraded ODST armour.
Come on, did you not see
the size of that thing?
That's not ODST.
Guys, look, you're missing the point.
What matters is that our soldiers were
fighting alongside the Insurrectionists.
Why would we protect the enemy?
Cadet Lasky.
Colonel Mehaffey would like to see you.
How are you feeling?
Uh, my chest burns, sir.
Quite a bit.
This is for you.
Seems like you have a choice to make, Thomas.
I don't understand, sir.
It appears Dr. Hughes' test has
revealed that the level of your allergy
to psydoprethaline is serious enough
to warrant a medical discharge.
If you feel that you are unfit for service
all you need to do is sign the
release and bring it to the tether.
When would I leave?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
You know, Thomas...
...your memories...
...and choices are all you'll have left.
At the end of the game the king
and the pawn go into the same box.
You have to decide what you're
willing to sacrifice.
Axios.
Thomas.
It is with a heavy heart that I
must inform you that today, your
brother Cadmon was shot down by
Insurrectionist forces on Andesia.
All of his squad perished.
I've been told that it was
a quick and painless death.
There are no remains to bury.
With this in mind I have decided that you
shall not leave Corbulo to attend services.
Lasky!
Lasky, move over I gotta
show you something.
Now's not a good time, Sully, okay.
No, it's important.
Now what the hell is that?
Hm?
Whoa.
It's off line.
I'm screwed, man.
It's ONI.
They must have flagged those coms.
I gotta talk to Dimah.
Dimah! Did you tell your mom?
Chyler?
Hey.
I thought I'd give your spot a try.
That com didn't make any sense.
Hating the enemy is all I've ever known.
Did you tell Mehaffey about it?
No.
What's that?
Apparently I'm allergic to war.
What does this mean?
You're leaving?
Yeah, tomorrow if I sign it.
Are you going to?
I don't know.
- Chyler.
- Oh, it's okay.
I know you don't want to be here.
I just thought...
...that maybe...
I'll miss you.
What is that?
All cadets, report to the tether.
I don't know.
To the tether!
Now!
This is not a drill!
Let's go, let's move,
let's move, come on!
- Let's move it cadets!
- Go, go, move it cadets!
Go, go, go!
Go to your squads. Now.
Keep moving, cadets!
Tyler, Lasky. The rest of the squad's
already at the tether. Let's go.
Hastati!
This way. Hurry up.
Right here. Right here.
Lasky, Chen, let's go.
Okay. Hold tight. Stay in line.
What is this? Insurrectionists?
I have no idea.
When we're assigned a number we're
going to get on to the tether, okay.
What the...?
Why are ODSTs dropping here?
I don't know.
Because we're under attack.
This is not good.
ODSTs dropping is never good.
This is ridiculous.
I can get us on this wagon.
No, no, no. We will hold our position.
Guys, come on.
No, Tchakova, that is a direct order.
Suit yourself.
- Dimah.
- No, Dimah.
Get back in line right now.
Return to your squad, cadet.
I'm getting on this wagon.
It's full. Wait for the next one.
My mother is Secretary of Fleet-Com.
Your choice, marine.
Go.
Wagon full. Send her off.
This is taking too long, April.
Maybe we should bum-rush like Dimah.
No. No, no, no, no, we'll be fine.
What the hell are those things?
Go!
Oh my God. What is that?
Tom, come on.
- Come on.
- What was that?
I don't know.
Come on, come on! Run!
I don't recognize...
I can't...remember
so much of myself.
I'm lost.
I'm scared.
Who's there? It apears to be
an alient construct.
The data confirms it was
not built by the Covenant.
There's no need
for more anayzing.
We are in danger.
Come on!
Chyler?! Hastati?!
Get to the dorm! Go!
- Colonel Mehaffey?
- Go, go, go, go!
Tom!
Come on, let's go!
Tom, is that you?
The dorms!
What's happened?
Doors are locked!
Over here.
We might squeeze in.
Oh my God.
Dimah, she's dead.
Colonel Mehaffey.
Yeah, and we will be too
if we don't do something.
- Comms are offline.
- It's a whole new war.
That sounded close.
- It's invisible.
- What the hell's invisible?
One of those things is
inside and it is invisible.
We gotta get out of here.
No, no, no, no, no.
Screw that. We stay here.
Where we gonna go?
No, no, no. We're gonna, we're
gonna go to the training room,
we're gonna get decked out,
we're gonna get some weapons.
I'll take point.
Come on. Come on, line up.
Alright.
Tell us when.
Tell us when, alright?
Now!
Go. Go, go, go, go.
Hurry. Wha...
Guys?
Why'd you stop, JJ?
JJ!
Oh my God!
Move! Go, go, go, go!
Lasky, send a distress beacon.
Chyler, help me get the weapons.
- It's locked.
- My code isn't working.
- Do it again.
- Try it now!
Lasky, door.
- Lasky! Door!
- Yeah! I'm, I'm trying.
April, come on!
Mayday. Mayday, mayday.
This is cadet Thomas Lasky,
I repeat. Mayday, mayday!
There's been an atack on Corbulo Academy.
Excessive casualties.
I repeat. Excessive casualties!
I don't have access to the live rounds.
I, I think the beacon's down as well.
We're dead.
Okay, alright. Think, think.
Think, think, think.
We can't stay in here, April.
We can't go out there!
Come on, Vickers. Harder!
Harder, Vickers.
Hide.
Okay, go.
Lasky, go for the door.
We can't leave Vickers.
Where is it?
He's right here.
Hey!
Guys, run!
Vickers!
We don't have much time.
Let's go.
Kelly, inform command
I have four survivors.
Take your team north.
Rendevouz at evac alpha
for pelican extraction.
We'll meet you there.
Chief out.
How did you find us?
A distress beacon.
Why did he come for us?
You're the only survivors.
In the school?
On the planet.
We've got 15 minutes to
get to the evac point.
Armour up.
It's, it's locked.
Stay quiet.
Do not leave. No matter
what you hear outside.
Wait. Who are you?
Call me "Master Chief".
I knew those ONI
vids were bad news.
Now we're the only ones alive.
- Sully, shhhh.
- What the hell is going on?
We're all following a giant robot.
Who knows if he's even coming back?
He's gonna come back.
I beleive him.
You okay?
I don't know.
Here you go, put your helmet on.
Hey. Hey.
You're gonna be fine.
Thanks.
Who's the best shot here?
You, probably.
Chyler is.
I'm good.
I am too.
Cadet Lasky, can you drive a warthog?
Yeah, sure.
Good.
That's where we're headed.
Shooters on the left and right.
Driver in the center.
Stay close to me.
It's your best chance at survival.
Sully, keep up.
Sully, come on.
Wh, where,
where'd they all go?
Get down!
Get to the hog, I'll draw their fire.
Where'd he go?
Chief?!
Cover me.
Lasky, go!
You okay?
I've got Sully. Go.
Moving. Cover me!
Chyler! I'm out. Gimme Sully.
I got you.
Come on!
April, go!
Come on, Sully.
Go!
Come on, Chyler!
Drive!
"Wake me when you need me",
he said.
Lasky!
It's harder than it looks!
Hang in there, Sully.
- Sorry
- You're doing fine, just keep it steady.
Bear right, cadet.
There's an access directly ahead.
Faster, cadet. 4 minutes to the Pelican.
We have to get off the planet.
Controlled bursts.
Don't spray and pray.
Cadet, two o'clock.
Chyler, cover!
Covering!
Kelly,
track our position for evac.
I think we're clear.
Nice job.
Everyone okay?
Hand me the bio-foam
then man the gun.
Come on.
God, come on.
This will help you walk.
We're almost there.
Tom.
Come on.
Chief! Chief!
Chyler's been hit!
I'm out of bio-foam.
We have to get her
to the Pelican now.
They're retreating.
Why would they do that now?
We're being hunted.
Keep moving north.
You'll see my team. Run as fast as you
can and don't stop for anything...
...including me.
- Can you walk?
- I'll try.
Just keep breathing.
Just hang in there, okay?
Hang in there.
- We gotta get us somewhere.
- How about the blind?
Yes. Let's go to the blind.
Oh my god!
Guys, go!
Sully,
you with us?
Yeah.
Hang in there, Chyler.
We're going to get you
outta here, okay?
April, stun rounds.
This will numb the pain.
Hang in there,
Chyler.
Hang in there, Chyler.
Come on, hang in there.
It's okay, Tom.
I'm sorry.
Chyler...
I need your ammo, cadets. It took
everything I had to bring that thing down.
We don't have any.
Just stun rounds, sir.
Thanks.
Guys.
There's another one.
Move. Now.
You have to leave her, Tom.
Sorry.
Lasky,
come on!
come on! Come on!
There!
Kelly,
negative. Need more time.
Cannot make it to the rendezvous.
You have to hold the Pelican.
I won't leave them!
Chief, out.
I'll engage. Get to the
Pelican as fast as you can.
No, sir.
I'll be the decoy.
Lasky, no.
You sweep them from behind.
Cadet.
Lasky?
- Axios!
- Lasky!
Lasky!
Lasky?
Lasky? Lasky?
Bring it down, Kelly.
Come on.
- We have three survivors.
- I've alerted command.
Let's go.
How old are all of you?
That's classified.
Well done, soldier.
Shall I play it again, sir?
No...
...that won't be necessary.
The captain has ordered us into
emergency slip-space protocol.
Prepare for cryo.