Looking for Jackie (2009)
Uploaded by huytran911@yahoo.com
artistic name of Jackie in China
Lung Chan / Yuen + dragon from his teacher.
Attack!
Be careful!
Big brother!
Don't be afraid, I'm here.
Attack!
Cut!
Director! Director, How's it?
How about this scene?
Let's get ready for the next angle.
-Okay!
How's it director?
Brother Jacky, well done.
You can go and rest awhile.
Okay! Good job.
Master.
How is it?
You drink You drink.
-Well done.
-You drink.
-I still have.
Don't worry. I still have mine.
Good bye! Good bye!
Well done everyone!
Big brother, well done.
Everyone well done.
Good bye, big brother.
Bye! Bye!
Everyone well done.
Thank you!
It's fine. Don't worry.
Bye, big brother.
Not bad,
There's some minor details that
you need to pay attention.
Okay.
The next scene will be this.
Everyone pay attention.
We're filming the next scene.
Where's the disciple?
The next scene will be brother Jacky
taking in a disciple.
Quick! Where's the disciple?
Where's the disciple?
Before I can complete my boxing routine,
Suddenly a person grab hold of me.
Telling me,
You are the one,
that I've been searching so hard
for to train as a gifted boxer.
Quickly becomes my inner circle disciple.
The next scene will be Jacky Chan
selecting a disciple.
Where's the selected Jacky Chan disciple?
Who is the one supposed to act?
The Jacky Chan disciple.
Me! Me! Me!
The one chosen yesterday.
Who's the one?
To be Jacky Chan disciple.
Don't push. Don't push.
Don't push!
Wake up!
Granny!
I was dreaming about Jacky Chan.
Let me have another
minute to finish my dream.
My young master,
you're already awake.
Going back to sleep also you
won't be able to see him.
Quickly get up.
Faster.
Today is the last day of schooling.
After school today the report
card will be released.
Next new semester you'll
be a secondary student.
How can you still be so confusing.
Let me sleep awhile more.
In a blink you're already
16 years old.
Why're you like a child being
so sleepy head.
C'mon. Do it on your own.
Fix it yourself.
Get up quick.
I'm making breakfast.
Granny, how come it's
oatmeal porridge again.
Listen to granny.
Oatmeal porridge is staple diet.
It's nourishing.
Yeah, granny.
During the New Year can I not
go to grandmother's house?
Being disciplined strictly by your
grandmother is for your benefit.
Who asked you to fail in
your Mandarin test.
Peking is too cold.
Let me tell you, even if you
refused you too must go.
Your mum has already book the
airline ticket for tomorrow.
Well, I' not going.
Granny,I'm not going.
I'm not going.
My name is Cheong Yat-San.
I'm born in Peking.
When I was 10 years old,
I followed my parents,
to this beautiful South
East country.
South East Asia,
I'm studying at International school,
a Form 3 student.
# Similar sky, similar earth,
similar ancestor
# Still have the righteous spirit within
# Wandering spirit of a dragon tales
# How improbable, no win or loss
# Flesh and blood after leaving the body
# Thousand years of glory,
sky and earth within to keep
# God is faster than kick and punch
# Mankind shadow is not crooked
# Master kungfu is fabulous
# Conflict is comprimising
# Generous personality
# Glorious spirit descended
to future genaration
# All master's descendants
# Posseses various kindness attributes
# Success without failure
# Can compete together with the sky
# Master is responsible
# Practising master arts
bring harmony
# Except martial arts
# Being human must be content
and never changing
# All master's descendants
# Posseses various kindness attributes
# Success without failure
# Can compete together with the sky
# Master is responsible
# Practising master arts
bring harmony
# Except martial arts
# Being human must be content
and never changing
Stop!
Master. one more time.
Master. one more time!
Okay, Let me tell you all
this is a reward.
Cheong Yat-San, come out.
Me?
Come, let's try.
Young kid, you show a lot
of improvement.
Not at all.
Ear! Ear! Ear!
Master Kam is looking for you
earlier on.
I heard that your Mandarin result
is not so satisfactory.
Go! Master Kam is looking for you.
There's a brook in front of my home.
I need to cross the brook everyday to
go to the city for martial arts practise.
Everyday! Everyday.
My biggest ambition is
to see Jacky Chan everyday.
"Knife point!" ( Word should mean saw him)
"Knife point." (Saw him actually)
Saw "knife point"
What are you doing?
Are you laughing at me?
Do you know who I am?
Who are you?
I'm Jacky Chan's disciple.
Apologize to me quick.
I'll not!
Apologize to me!
Classmate Cheong Yat-San.
Master Kam, how're you?
Go for your lesson.
Those classmates
humiliated you in front of everyone
should be faulted.
Classmate Cheong Yat-San
How do you want me to
describe you as a teacher.
You only got a C in your objectives test.
There's only 1 page for composition.
The grammar is so embarassing.
Not proficient and multiple mistakes
plus incomprehensive meaning.
Teacher, what are you saying
that I'm not answering?
Wrongful meaning to your sentences.
Meaning your grammar
can't capture the essence of the words.
Cheong Yat-San
You're a International School student,
You must be proficient in Mandarin.
I believe there's no meaning in
learning proper Mandarin language.
I want to be like my hero Jacky Chan.
Famous throughout.
I really don't understand.
I fail in Mandarin test
because of a few wrong grammars.
I can understand Master Kam
grabbing hold of me but
the classmates are also against me.
One day when I find Jacky Chan
learn true martial arts,
I will teach them a good lesson.
Cheong Yat-San!
Cheong Sup-San (Meaning 13)
Cheong Sup-San! Cheong Sup-San
Who're you calling San? Soo Lee-Yuk
Calling you!
Getting 13 points and failing.
How about it?
-Who're you saying about?
-Talking about you.
You talking about me.
Damn you!
Cheong Yat-San, why're you
hitting people? Attack!
Attack!
Don't run. Hold still!
Don't beat!
Let's see wether you give up or not.
I didn't insist
I heard that
Master Jacky fight since as a child.
You dare to mention it.
Always Jacky Chan, Jacky Chan!
Look at your Mandarin.
Always failing in exams.
How embarassing!
I have decided
to follow Master Jacky Chan to
learn martial arts.
Then follow by learning Mandarin.
Don't blame your granny ignorance.
Your parents
care only in their research and
doctorate
Never at home.
Let your grandmother teach you.
You refused  to go to Peking.
I'm at a lost for idea.
I'll have to get a refund for the
ticket tomorrow.
What's this?
Granny, Jacky Chan is shooting in Peking.
I  look thru Jiapu.com
Instantly I found the family
surname Yuen lineage.
I've decided
I need to change to be Yuen
family descendants.
After that, I'll look up Jacky Chan
in Peking.
Allowed our Immigration
to conduct searches.
Please open your back pack.
Remember, don't buy counterfeit.
Respect the copyright act and
follow the laws.
Wishing you all an enjoyable visit
to China.
Thank you!
Hey kid, you've not
say where you want to go.
Yeah...almost forget.
Go to this place.
You can't look at this.
Using a mobile phone while
driving is illegal
You just need to tell me
Ching Sek Temple.
No! No!
There's no place by that name.
I think you want to go to
Ching Sek Sanctuary.
It must be that place.
Ching Sek Sanctuary?
Correct!
Let's go there.
Okay, let's go.
How far is Ching Sek Sanctuary?
Outskirt?
Let's go!
Okay!
Ching Sek Sanctuary
Let me tell you,
you worried about Yat-San
not coming...
when Yat-San is here, you
disciplined him.
He's just a kid.
You can't be too strict with him.
Can't be too strict.
Am I that strict?
I just asked him to
jog for an hour and draw for 2 hours.
Playing the piano for 3 hours.
4 hours of revision.
Don't let him muck about with you.
What's wrong with that?
Our grandson...
is a simpleton.
How can he be someone in the future?
How to be successful?
I'll answer the phone.
How're you.
In-laws.
In-laws...
have Yat-San arrived yet?
What? Yat-San is in Peking?
Is he alone?
Hello? hello, in-laws
How're you.
Have Yat-San arrived yet?
What? Yat-San doesn't want to
come to Peking.
What? Haven't arrived?
How can that be.
He's taken the 9 am flight
It's almost dark.
He should be arriving soon.
Hey, what're you doing?
Talking about you
Are you just looking around or
come to pray?
If you need to pray it'll have
to be tomorrow morning.
If you want to sight seeing,
$20 please.
I didn't come for prayer or visit,
Then what are you doing here?
Let me ask you something
Look here.
Is it this place?
That is Tham Sek temple.
Here is Ching Sek Sanctuary.
There's a lot of difference.
Let me have a look up there.
You can't go up.
Let me go up and have look!
You can't come in.
You rascal.
Don't you know about rules?
Unreasonable!
Ill manners
You want to go in?
You've to ask me first and wether
I agree to it.
You can't go in.
Let me go in.
Let me in! Let me in!
Useless
Who's useless?
Master, he's attempting to break in.
I'm not. She's just accusing me.
You... kid,
not here for sight seeing
neither for prayer
What're you here for?
I'm looking for Master Jacky Chan.
Kid, martial arts weakness
can be learn,
bad manners
will lead you to learn nothing.
At such a young age
you should learn about manners.
You resemble a ruffian hero.
Even if Jacky Chan is here
he wouldn't accept you.
Chi-Ha, let's go.
Master say
it's cold out here so she
allowed you to come in.
Master say to give you more blankets.
Why're you sulking?
It's ugly.
Actually you're quite nice looking
especially your eyes.
Can you talk about other things?
I say your eyes is nice looking.
You can't say that.
Say Say Say Say Say
-Say Say
-Don't say Don't say
Okay Okay
Stop it.
What's with your teeth?
My teeth?
Eating bun!
Little rascal!
Eat bun Eat bun
You imp!
Stop that! It's itchy.
You imp You imp
Eat bun
Let go!
You let go.
You let go first
You release first
I'm not releasing.
Then I'll not release too.
We're both twisted
Who's afraid of who.
Are you releasing or not?
Let's release together.
1, 2, 3 Let go.
Let me asked you a question
More simply,
When I arrived at the temple
you were returning from outside.
Why weren't you guarding
the main entrance?
Have you gone out to play?
None of your concern.
Okay, I'm a busybody.
Which house does your master stay in?
I'm going to tell her.
You didn't guard the main
entrance properly today.
You went off to play.
Priest Priest Priest
I want to let her know.
There's a phrase of the holy
scripture that I don't understand.
I need your guidance.
Master, I've already explained to him.
Chi-Ha, go to bed early.
What were you doing in the afternoon?
You want to know?
Tomorrow morning follow me up
the hill outback.
Crazy. It'll be too cold.
Don't you want to look for Jacky Chan?
Don't regret it if you don't go.
Master Jacky Chan is outback
up the hill.
Let's go.
Faster faster or it'll be too late.
Quick!
Fast fast fast fast
Don't move! Hold still!
Hey kid, what're you doing here?
Are you Master Jacky Chan brothers?
Are you from the Yuen descendants?
I've saw you in Jiapu before.
In Jacky Chan lineage there's your photo.
Please tell me where's Master Jacky Chan.
I want to meet him.
Director!
Why don't you put on some makeup
before coming on the set?
This little kid...
is he a fan follower or an actor?
It's unbearable.
Yeah...
is your master training in a
secluded area?
She will not come out if there's
nothing happening?
What about it?
How about like this,
You...
go about your acting,
while I guard the main gate for you.
Can you do it?
Definitely can!
But you've to agree on one condition,
I want you to enquire from Master Yee
where is Master Jacky Chan now?
Straighten. Eyes front.
Head, okay!
It's a wrapped.
Returned the props please.
Hurry up!
Let's eat.
Brothers, quick.
Well done Well done
Everyone did a good job today.
Returned the props at the back.
Master Yee Master Yee
Wait awhile, Master Yee
This kid is really...
Are you hurt?
Get up Get up
Master Yee,
What's the matter?
Can I take a photo with you?
Ok!
No problem.
That's too good.
Little miss,
you acted quite well today.
Really?
Little rascal, you're being lazy again?
Who is lazy?
It's just too cold,
would anyone be coming to
sight seeing?
What're you doing then?
I'm just covering myself. It's cold.
How is it?
How did the filming go?
Let me show you a photo.
Yeah, have you asked him already?
Where is Master Jacky Chan?
Did you ask?
I was too excited.
I forgot to.
Please stop crying.
Don't be like this. Nothing'll happen.
I was at fault.
You've been working so hard
guarding the main gate for me.
And I have forgotten what
I'm supposed to do for you.
Forgotten, so let it be.
Worst come to worst,
I'll look for him myself.
I don't believe I can't find him.
I'm so stubborn.
Stumbling my way, I managed
to gate crash into this temple.
Before I take leave,
I only realised,
that Chi-Ha is a theater troupe disciple.
She is only on holiday observing
the life style here.
From the outlook she seems aloof,
but she has the kind heartedness
of the caretaker
who by the way is her aunt.
They're very kind to me.
I can't wait here any longer.
I have a more important
mission that I must attend to.
That is finding Jacky Chan.
Hey, rushing to buy ticket.
2 tickets.
Is it for this afternoon ride at 5 pm?
Yes!
1 ticket to TungChow.
Thank you! I...
Queue up over there.
Immediate, please immediate.
Faster please.
I want to go there.
Where do you want to go?
Where is this temple?
Our temples for tourist is numerous.
Which one do you want to go to?
That's the one.
Here!
It's Tam Sek temple.
Eighteen soft and fifteen hard currency.
There should be no mistake this time.
Okay!
Where's my wallet?
Cigarettes, Melon Seeds and
Chewing gums!
Cigarettes! You want to buy a
pack, handsome?
I don't smoke.
A youngster and not smoking.
Good Good
Chewing gum for a dollar.
I don't eat.
It cost a dollar and fifty outside.
I don't want to buy.
Your wallet is missing.
What do you mean?
There's an alley behind the station.
You 'll find an empty well.
Wait for me there in an hour.
Cigarettes! Melon seeds!
I can't take the time
off as business is brisk.
Can you manage it?
I'm falling asleep already.
Come!
Let me tell you...
the money in the wallet,
will be gone.
You most probably will recovered
your IDs and bank card.
Why do you want to help me?
It's because you're handsome.
Can you really help me to
recovered my things?
If you can't, I'll just leave.
If you don't believe me,
you can leave then.
Don't you regret.
Stop kidding.
Judging from your face, you most
probably will not be able to find it.
I'm leaving.
Sister Yung!
How're you, sister Yung?
Give me back the wallet.
Are you hungry?
Let's go and eat something.
What? You're worried
that I'll harm you.
What's your name?
Cheong Yat-San.
How old are you?
Sixteen!
Did baldie took your wallet earlier on?
Why don't you knock before entering?
Brother Hung, why are you back already?
Take a look at him.
Does he resemble Little Chuen?
Why did you beat her?
Release me.
Brother Hung, he's just a kid.
Let him go.
Give it to me.
What is this?
These are...
Damn rascal.
I heard that you're Jacky Chan disciple.
The movie star Jacky Chan,
He's quite wealthy.
Are you Yat-San? What!
Listen to me.
Listen clearly, Two hundred
thousand and not a bit less.
You, you..what do you mean?
I'll killed him if you report to
the police.
What do you mean?
Enough! Enough!
Come! Get up.
You're not hurt?
I'm alright.
Listen here,
the skill you possesed as a
policeman is not enough.
It's not enough.
You need to use your brain,
you know.
Captain, rest assured.
We'll tried our best.
Listen, 200 thousand in cash.
Put it at the train station hall.
Placed it in the dustbin near
the noodle restaurant.
Or else I'll killed him.
In my judgement,
he's not a professional kidnapper.
We'll make the arrest ourselves.
We don't need to inform special forces.
Get a few men on the scene.
Okay. Use your judgement.
Changed into plain clothes.
Okay!
Take care of the granny.
Thank you! Thank you!
Don't struggle anymore.
You can't escape.
I'm not struggling.The legs
of the chair is broken.
I hope that you're not
angry with me.
It's all because of my younger brother.
He's older than you slightly.
He look quite like you.
When I saw you today,
it reminded me of him.
Then you can go and search for him.
Last month, my brother and
brother Hung went to rob a train.
He felled down on the track.
The reason why I've brought you here,
is to dine with you.
Do you've his photo?
He's name Little Chuen and
older than you by a few years.
These past few years,
for the sake of my
younger brother,
please forgive me!
How nice it would be to
have a sister like you.
I'm a lone child.
That's why I was constantly
being bullied.
I came back to Peking to avoid
being harassed.
I want to be Jacky Chan disciple.
After learning martial arts,
I want to defeat,
all those guys who bullied me.
Have you ever given thought,
after defeating all those guys,
what does it all means?
I've been long waiting for you.
Who're you?
Where do you want to escape?
Brother Hung Brother Hung
Run!
Brother Hung!
Brother Hung, are you hurt?
Go away!
You crazy, picking up things.
Brother Hung, what's happened?
What's the matter?
The police knew.
Pack up and run.
Faster!
Where's the guy?
You betrayed me?
Brother Hung, it's for your own good.
Let's all surrender.
Stop beating!
You stopped beating him.
I didn't hear it.
Sister Yung!
Baldie!
Watch where you're going.
You also didn't see me.
You rascal, get away from me.
I'm on duty doing official business.
Don't block me from calling the police.
What did you say?
Reporting to the police for what?
I'm the police.
You're the police?
I'm the hostage.
What're you joking about, kid?
Hey! Hold still.
Police!
Don't move.
Just like that, Sister Yung have been
detained at the police station.
I think she's quite pitiful.
I want to beg leniency from
the police.
Just let it be.
Released her.
Madam Policewoman,
please released her.
She didn't do me any harm.
She's pitiful.
Just release her.
Okay, don't you worry.
Let me send you home.
I can't go back yet.
I'm searching for Master Jacky Chan so
that I can learn martial arts from him.
Learning martial arts?
Yeah, that's my ambition for
coming to Peking.
To learn martial arts from
Master Jacky Chan.
I'll returned home and
maintain the safety there.
Wait for me!
Don't move away.
I'll send you home immediately.
Hey, what're you doing?
Hey! I asked you to wait for
me and you're running about.
I don't want to go home.
Why?
I just don't want to go home.
My grandmother like to
control me, why should I go home.
You're just a young kid.
She should look after you.
I'm not going home.
Come! Return home.
You just speak to your
grandmother regarding all matters.
I don't want to go home. I want
to look for Master Jacky Chan.
Why don't you stop dreaming.
Even if you found Jacky Chan,
he'll not care about you.
Says who? I don't believe.
Why is this child like that.
Why keep dragging your feet.
Get down from the car.
Okay! Stay at my place then.
Your grandfather will pick you
up tomorrow.
Really can't tolerate you.
Come in!
The toilet is in front.
The lock is broken.
Remember to knock on the
door when going to the toilet.
You can sleep on the sofa.
I'll send you home tomorrow.
Just for one night.
This water cup is mine.
You can't use this.
Ther's another new one inside.
Take off your dirty clothings.
It's smelly.
Take off already?
Then my butt will be exposed.
What if the butt is exposed?
I've seen a lot of child's butt.
Hey!
I don't want to wear
woman clothing.
Nonsense. It's belong to my husband.
How's your grandmother?
Don't you want to see her?
My grandmother is a busybody.
She wants me to jog an hour everyday.
Two hours for drawing.
Piano lesson for 3 hours.
The most horrible is...
4 hours of revision.
International film star Jacky Chan,
will auction all his old clothings with
the proceed given to the disaster area.
Since winter is coming,
the thicker clothings are
required to prevent the cold.
Reknowned film star Jacky Chan
tomorrow,
will chaired the charity auction.
All charity raised from the auction,
will be given to the children
orphaned by the disaster.
Monies raised will be used to
purchase blankets and clothings.
Even if you found
the real Jacky Chan,
will you be able to learn martial arts?
Let me tell you,
cinematic martial arts are all fake.
It's only make believe.
Nice to see but not practical.
That's not true.
Master Jacky Chan martial arts is real.
I've seen TV programme,
the programme mentioned,
actor's filming martial arts scene,
normally used a double.
Only Master Jacky Chan don't
use a double.
He performed his own stunts.
He has numerous wounds on his body.
Do you know?
What does that amount to?
If he met a bad guy with gun
and knife,
it's of no use.
You're useful, is that okay?
In actual Master Jacky Chan,
has beaten many baddies with
gun and knife.
What about you?
Have you caught any baddies?
If you're so capable go
and catch one now.
Catch me a thief.
It maybe, if you saw the thief,
you'll be in trouble.
Kid, let me tell you,
don't blabber away.
I've caught many thieves before.
You didn't see it only.
Bullshit! Who doesn't know how to.
You...
only know how to bully young
kid like me.
She man!
Just you say one more time.
Huh!
Ran away?
Okay Okay! I'll be there.
I just received info that
brother Hung ran away.
I need to go on duty.
You stayed at home.
I'll be back soon.
Don't you wander about.
I'll send you back to your
grandmother place.
It's good that she finally leave.
I need to get away from
here as soon as possible.
The TV programme mentioned
what mall again?
Go and look for Jacky Chan!
But my clothings,
is being soak in the washing machine.
Hey! I got it.
Is this that area?
Must be. Come heer!
Young rascal. Come here!
Can you please tell us how to
go here?
Let me have a look.
This is what area?
That's why we are asking you.
This must be what area?
This is written by my grand-daughter.
I don't know this.
This here...
area where about is it?
This I think...
You young rascal of a police
No matter how I look at it
your uniform seems to be on
loan from someone.
How old are you this year?
I'm 16 years old.
Already 18 years old.
That's mean to say,
the policeman nowadays
must be university graduate.
That must be. What's
wrong with you then.
Granny, let me have a look.
This is Ka-Hon area.
-Correct! This is the area.
-Correct.
-It's just in front there.
Thank you. That's just too good.
Young rascal!
Learn proper Mandarin.
Ka-Hon area!
Hey!
I've a name and it's not hey.
Fine. What time is Jacky Chan coming?
What's your concern?
I want to meet him.
I want to be his disciple.
Are you a policeman?
Hold still!
You hold still!
Sister, someone help!
Help!
Someone help!
Jacky Chan Jacky Chan Jacky Chan!
Quickly!
Be careful.
-Don't worry!
-Thank you!
Aiyah!
Easy! Easy!
Be careful!
Stop in front for a while.
Sister! You must be strong.
Be careful abit!
Auntie! Auntie!
Slower.
Auntie, I beg of you.
You must save her.
Stop in front for awhile.
Slower!
Thank you. Be careful!
Save her, auntie.
Sister! Sister!
Please wake up.
How're you?
How's her condition?
This is our captain.
-How're you?
-Thank you!
-Don't mention it.
Doctor, how's her condition?
He's the one who save her.
Yes Yes Yes!
How come he still look like a child?
Don't be funny?
How's her condition?
She's lucky she arrived here quickly,
after our emergency treatment,
she's out of danger.
Can she be discharged?
Not right now.
She 's got a head concussion.
Furthermore she has 2 broken ribs.
She needs to be hospitalized.
Further observation and treatment
are required.
Let me take a look then.
This child is so anxious.
You can't see her now.
What she needs now is quiet
and rest.
Nothing will happened.
Rest assured!
Aiyah! Where're you going?
Don't run.
Never thought after all the hardship,
almost meeting Master Jacky Chan,
I just managed to
catch only a glance.
Can't say that I regretted,
for I did managed to rescued
another hero.
The same night,
a police patrol car send me
back to my grandmother house.
Peking night scene is really beautiful.
To me, I don't appreciate it at all.
My heart still linger on
at the police woman in the hospital.
Greeting's friends!
Everyone fine.
Thank you for watching China
News report.
I'm Ching-Wei!
Our National Cinema Extravaganza
Center ceremony
in Peking is being materialised.
This major events,
Cinema Extravaganza Center
opening is being attended by
our leaders and Jacky Chan,
Wu Yee-Hsin, Chen Kai-Ge and others
leading film people of the industy.
Together they went thru a heart felt moment.
Lord Yang, Wong Siew Tong,
Johnny Woo,
Jacky Chan, Chen Kai-Ge are
there for the opening ceremony.
Natioanl Cinema Extravaganza
Center opening ceremony
is officailly concluded.
Grandpa, where is this place?
Where is this?
Both of you are looking for who?
We want to look for Jacky Chan.
Is he in there?
How do you know that
Jacky Chan is here?
We just come here and tried
our luck.
Yes! Yes!
The news now is difficult to hide
from people.
You see, Jacky Chan arrived yesterday
and I was the one who received him.
Today, the whole world already
knows about it.
It's true.
It's true!
At least we didn't come in vain.
Can you let us go in?
Where do we buy the tickets?
Where?
This is not a tourist
attraction, furthermore...
In that case why not let
my young grandson in?
Him having a look will not
cause you to lose anything.
Correct!
But people wanting to
meet Jacky Chan is a lot.
No! They're a lot of children
wanting to meet Jacky Chan.
If everyone is allow in
then it'll be a havoc.
Granny, let me speak for myself.
Okay! Let me tell you,
You're really enthusiatic about movies.
You must love movies.
Let me figure out a way for you.
Do you know where's the
Northern theatre?
Over there, they're hiring actors.
You can get in thru there.
You can applied at Fei Tang
but it's far from here.
You can mix in as an actor.
Then you can be here acting.
Is it?
Yes. I'm willing to be an
actor just to meet him
Finally, I too was transfer here.
Stable income and get to
meet film stars everyday.
Is that true?
True! Why should I bluff you?
You see!
Here!
Isn't that Jacky Chan?
Is it?
That's right!
This is when I was receiving
Jacky Chan yesterday.
This is his autograph.
I even managed to shake hand
with him.
Let me tell you.
This is Johnny Woo.
Red Cliff!
Big production.
All of them mega production.
What're they acting in?
Sitting over here...
The actress name is Wang Hei-Foong.
Next to her is Yew-Mui!
Why is she called Yew-Mui?
Because her father surname is Yew.
It's not a stage name.
The one sitting there is Pak-Ping.
She is acting as Suet Pow-Chai!
She's so fair that
I can tell her apart with just one look.
The one on the far side I couldn't
see her clearly.
Because the car passed too quickly.
That one is acting over the stage
there in the movie "Red Dream".
The director of that movie is
Lee Siew-Hong, he's a friend of mine.
Everyday I received him.
They're just finishing work.
Having dinner over there.
They travelled by car early
in the day and not walking.
The area is too big.
Just too big.
Then...
Are there having a fight
scene with Jacky Chan?
What're you saying?
Can Lam Tai-Yuk have a
fight scene with Jacky Chan?
Exactly! How to fight?
Not even a match.
Her health actually
is not that good.
Can you hear that?
You don't even know about the
movie "Red Dream."
-You have to really learn.
-Yes Yes Yes
Based on what you don't know
how can you integrate into
the society?
If you get to meet Master Jacky Chan,
he also wouldn't like it.
Just look at yourself in the future.
Granny, can you stop nagging?
So troublesome!
Haven't I told you already,
I've a mouth. I know how to ask.
I've legs. I'll go find him myself.
Can you please not nag me?
Don't keep on following me.
Little San!
How can you speak to
your granny in such a way?
You can't do that.
This child...
Actually I felt bad too.
I know,
the way I speak to granny is wrong.
However there're no alternatives.
My heart is not with me.
It has gone...
to that place the guard was
talking about.
Gone to...
the place where there are a lot of
Wang Po-Keong.
I decided to look for him there.
I believe,
I'll be able to find my master,
Jacky Chan!
Famed director Ha Tai-Tong is
starting a new movie.
Every actor's will get 60.
Those who are willing please register.
Our casts will be lead by Yang Sui-Fa.
Actor's fees will be 80 a day.
I'll come! I'll come! I'll come!
Next film will be Jacky Chan
looking for a disciple.
Start shooting immediately.
From the selection yesterday,
who is Jacky Chan disciple?
You then.
And you and you.
The three of you.
Let's go!
Is it ready?
It's ready but there are no props yet.
Why is it not ready yet?
Faster Faster Faster!
Actors Actors Actors!
Quick get in position.
In position!
His make-up, disciple.
Is your make-up ready?
Quick Quick Quick!
We're starting filming.
Director, I'm ready here.
Chin higher, higher.
Quick disciple.
Come up!
Act properly.
Okay, let's start rolling.
Okay, ready!
Let's roll, 1, 2, 3.
How's it?
That was marvelous! Marvelous!
Next scene then!
Sister escaped later on...
Please get brother Jacky Chan.
This scene involved Jacky Chan
leg shot.
Move sideway!
Okay!
After that the 3 guys fall face
flat on the ground.
Hey you three, you three.
Lie down on the ground
and don't move. Play dead.
Act as a corpse?
I won't get to meet Master
Jacky Chan then.
Stop talking. Act properly.
Little Kan Little Kan Little Kan!
Little Kan!
Stop!
What's the matter with the kid?
What's up! What's up!
Such a long frame and disrupt
by you.
Didn't I tell you already,
You're dead. Lie down
and close your eyes.
I want to meet Jacky Chan.
Jacky Chan!
You think you can meet
Jacky Chan just like that?
This is a studio not a place
for chasing after a star.
Changed to another kid.
No need to film from
the front, just the back.
Director! Director!
Will Master Jacky Chan be
appearing afterward?
Kid, it's filming,
not award presentation.
If you want to meet Jacky Chan,
when the film is shown then
you come over, okay.
Assistant director, calculate his pay!
Send him back to the
Northern corridor!
Let's go!
It's so huge.
Peking Theater Industry.
Grandma!
This area is for VIP.
You're not allowed in here.
Comrade, I need to go to the toilet.
I can't find it.
Let me use the one here.
No! No! No!
This area is reserved
for mega star to rest.
If I allowed you in,
I'll get terminated.
I beg you please,
since I'm so elderly.
I can be your grandma.
I'm rushing to act in a film.
Please make an exception.
Granny, who are you looking for?
Please excuse me.
I'm looking for someone
but am in the wrong place.
Never mind.
Ah,yes!
Do you know where Jacky Chan is?
Is there something you
need to deal with Jacky Chan?
Actually it's nothing.
Just that my grandson,
wants to meet with Jacky Chan.
He came all the way from South
East Asia.
He pester me everyday that
he wants to meet Jacky Chan.
I'm at my wits end.
You disguised yourself
just to look for Jacky Chan.
Don't mention it.
So...
because he's just a kid and not
raised by me,
his parents are very busy,
and he thinks that I,
control him too much.
I just want to communicate with him,
There's a generation gap.
He tells me nothing.
I felt that I owe him something.
I just want to do something for him.
Just to make him happy.
If possible so that he can
tell me how his heart felt.
Later on I discovered that,
he likes Jacky Chan and
would like to meet him.
I have no idea so...
What does your grandson
wants to do with Jacky Chan?
Yeah, what does he wants to do?
I too would like to know.
Granny, you...
Aren't you going to the toilet?
Why are you here?
Go away!
Okay!
Come and use my toilet here.
I...Okay!
You haven't finish telling me
your grandson story.
Please beg on my behalf
to the director.
I came all the way  to Peking
to look for Master Jacky Chan.
So that I can meet him just once.
I've been bullied at school.
I came to Peking to be his disciple.
So that he can teach me martial arts.
Can you please tell the director.
-I just want to meet him once.
-I pity you too.
But I've no way.
Take your pay and go home early.
Okay! Go home early, quick.
Excuse me!
Brother, don't you feel cold?
You still here?
Yeah, I want to meet Jacky Chan.
Will he meet you?
Yes!
Why would he?
Why not?
I'm standing here,
holding his poster.
I am holding it up,
so that he can see me.
He definitely will meet me.
Forget it.
Kid's such as you are alot.
Be good! Go home.
Listen to uncle, brother!
Just listen to big brother.
Go home and learn to be
good. It's already very late.
Go home and be good.
Are you the one looking
for Master Jacky Chan?
Come, get in the car.
How's it?
It's okay.
You've arrived.
Master Jacky Chan!
My name is Cheong Yat-San.
I want to be your disciple.
There're alot of people who
wants to be my disciple.
You tell me,
why do you want to be my disciple?
I go to school in Indonesia.
I failed in Mandarin
and also History test.
All my classmates, they
teased me about it.
Then,
I got angry and so was
involved in a fight with them.
They gang up and bullied me.
I want to come to Peking,
to look for you
to be my master.
To learn your true martial arts.
Then I'll go back to school
and seek revenge on them.
You're my idol.
I've love you since I was a child.
I want to meet you.
Kid, you're wrong.
These are all my disciples.
I teach them martial arts,
not for fighting or bullied people.
You told me just now,
you even failed in your Mandarin.
Let me ask you,
do you know where your home is?
Respecting the elders and
kindness is a Chinese traits.
Your grandma came to
look for me personally.
How do you treat her?
Do you know your grandma name?
Human must have will and spirit.
The same goes for a country.
You're a descendant of China.
You even failed in your Mandarin
test.
Of course people will
look down on you.
Kid, remember...
I'll not take you in
as my disciple today,
Go home and learn.
Passed your Mandarin exam,
then only come to look for me.
I've confidence in you.
You'll surely succeed.
Why haven't he arrived yet, really!
Don't be anxious!
You see, the call came
half a day earlier,
why haven't he arrived yet?
Really!
You see, he's here.
Granny! Granny!
Yat-San! Yat-San!
Master Jacky Chan send me home.
Really, that's good.
Old folk,
Master Jacky Chan,
how're you?
How're you!
My mission is accomplished.
Bye! Bye!
Master Jacky Chan!
I just want to take a photo with you.
Okay!
But you must use my camera.
Once you passed in your exam,
I'll send you our photo.
Granny! Grandpa!
There is Jacky Chan lineage in Jiapu.
But...
you tell me,
what does our ancestor's do?
Granny, what does your granny do?
You should know.
Cheong Yat-San,
Cheong Yat-San, congratulations
on passing your secondary.
Just you guys see,
this time when I went to China,
and returning after becoming
Jacky Chan disciple,
none of you...
dare to bullied me.
Cheong Yat-San.
We don't want to bullied you.
Because your Mandarin result is
so poor,
not willing to lose,
we just want to teach you a lesson.
Correct! Today you got 80 points,
we congrats you.
Yeah!
Yes!
Okay! Okay! Okay!
I feel...
you're all afraid,
that I'll used Jacky Chan
true martial arts,
to beat you.
Bullshit!
I'm not bull-shitting.
I'm going to call Jacky Chan now.
Okay!
Just you see!
You've reach the voice mailbox.
Master Jacky Chan,
where is he?
No sound!
Don't say anything.
Master Jacky Chan,
I'm Cheong Yat-San.
I got 80 points in my Mandarin test.
Why is there no sound?
Master Jacky Chan,
Let's go! Let's go!
He's bluffing.
Let's go! Leave him alone.