1
00:02:25,367 --> 00:02:26,827
[ DOG BARKS ]

2
00:02:34,042 --> 00:02:35,711
[ THEY WHISPER ]

3
00:02:38,839 --> 00:02:40,089
I heard a dog.

4
00:02:40,090 --> 00:02:43,843
Did you? Must be outside.

5
00:02:43,844 --> 00:02:46,013
[ DOG BARKS ]

6
00:02:47,181 --> 00:02:48,432
Dad!

7
00:02:50,392 --> 00:02:53,519
We were going to hide him
till tomorrow but...

8
00:02:53,520 --> 00:02:56,439
he didn't want to go along
with the plan, did you?

9
00:02:56,440 --> 00:02:58,441
Happy Christmas, sweetheart.

10
00:02:58,442 --> 00:03:01,360
What are you going
to call him, love?

11
00:03:01,361 --> 00:03:03,030
I don't know yet.

12
00:03:06,158 --> 00:03:07,700
Hey there, boy.

13
00:03:07,701 --> 00:03:09,368
Do you want to take him out?

14
00:03:09,369 --> 00:03:12,206
Come on, then.

15
00:03:15,959 --> 00:03:18,045
Let's go. Get some clothes on.

16
00:03:26,803 --> 00:03:27,930
Hey, boy.

17
00:03:45,364 --> 00:03:48,574
What, sick? 'Apparently
he's on his deathbed.'

18
00:03:48,575 --> 00:03:50,369
Yeah. What, again?

19
00:03:52,120 --> 00:03:54,330
Yeah.

20
00:03:54,331 --> 00:03:56,624
No, of course.

21
00:03:56,625 --> 00:03:59,752
Yeah, in ten. In ten.

22
00:03:59,753 --> 00:04:01,921
Right, cheers.

23
00:04:01,922 --> 00:04:04,131
Sorry, Goose.

24
00:04:04,132 --> 00:04:07,552
I'll make it up to you, I promise.

25
00:04:07,553 --> 00:04:09,972
Linda, I have to go into work, love.

26
00:04:12,891 --> 00:04:16,936
Honey, have you seen my keys?
No, sorry.

27
00:04:16,937 --> 00:04:18,939
I can't find them anywhere.

28
00:04:27,906 --> 00:04:31,742
Er... Goose, have you seen
my keys, mate? No, Dad.

29
00:04:31,743 --> 00:04:34,996
Oh, Lind, you're going to
have to drive me in, love.

30
00:04:34,997 --> 00:04:36,665
Really?

31
00:05:19,208 --> 00:05:21,709
He'll be fine.

32
00:05:21,710 --> 00:05:23,045
Yep.

33
00:05:28,800 --> 00:05:32,345
[ MUSIC: "Wonderful Christmas time"
by Tom McRae ]

34
00:05:32,346 --> 00:05:33,596
Ah!

35
00:05:33,597 --> 00:05:35,766
[ INCREASES VOLUME ]
Hey!

36
00:05:40,270 --> 00:05:42,356
No, it's too sad! Ah, ah!

37
00:05:59,873 --> 00:06:01,541
Take Langford, it's quicker.

38
00:06:01,542 --> 00:06:03,710
Know-it-all!

39
00:06:05,379 --> 00:06:06,755
[ GLASS SMASHES ]

40
00:06:30,195 --> 00:06:31,655
[ CHURCH BELLS CHIME ]

41
00:06:46,587 --> 00:06:49,506
[ MUSIC: "I Wish It Could Be Christmas
Everyday" by Wizzard ]

42
00:07:54,100 --> 00:07:56,500
You all right, mate?

43
00:08:08,800 --> 00:08:10,500
Hey.

44
00:08:14,000 --> 00:08:15,399
Anthony?

45
00:08:15,400 --> 00:08:16,999
You OK?

46
00:08:17,000 --> 00:08:19,199
[ HE SIGHS ]

47
00:08:19,200 --> 00:08:20,600
It's snowing.

48
00:08:22,800 --> 00:08:25,599
Not in Manchester, mate.
It just rains.

49
00:08:25,600 --> 00:08:27,100
A monkey.

50
00:08:29,200 --> 00:08:30,200
Snowing.

51
00:08:33,800 --> 00:08:36,100
With an angel's head.

52
00:08:38,100 --> 00:08:39,799
Snowing monkeys?

53
00:08:39,800 --> 00:08:41,900
Yeah, I'll watch out for them!

54
00:09:09,900 --> 00:09:12,100
Hey! Mutt.

55
00:09:40,400 --> 00:09:42,299
Come on, Mutt.

56
00:09:42,300 --> 00:09:45,200
[ MUSIC: "Stop The Cavalry"
by Jona Lewie ]

57
00:09:49,400 --> 00:09:52,499
What you doing, Nan?

58
00:09:52,500 --> 00:09:55,200
Well, it's not going to cook
itself, is it, darling?

59
00:09:57,300 --> 00:10:00,400
That's the washing machine, Nan.

60
00:10:02,000 --> 00:10:03,499
Oven's there.

61
00:10:03,500 --> 00:10:06,600
And it's only Christmas Eve.

62
00:10:08,800 --> 00:10:11,200
Christmas Eve? Yeah.

63
00:10:16,200 --> 00:10:17,699
Nan!

64
00:10:17,700 --> 00:10:19,699
I'll help you...

65
00:10:19,700 --> 00:10:20,999
tomorrow.

66
00:10:21,000 --> 00:10:22,500
I will.

67
00:10:27,900 --> 00:10:30,300
Oh, and put it back in the fridge.

68
00:11:04,200 --> 00:11:06,499
[ KNOCKS ON DOOR ]

69
00:11:06,500 --> 00:11:08,499
All right!

70
00:11:08,500 --> 00:11:11,199
Please stop. Please.

71
00:11:11,200 --> 00:11:13,699
[ KNOCKS CONTINUE ]

72
00:11:13,700 --> 00:11:15,400
Who is it? It's me.

73
00:11:16,900 --> 00:11:19,099
Come on, Frank, it's freezing.

74
00:11:19,100 --> 00:11:20,999
I'm coming.

75
00:11:21,000 --> 00:11:22,400
Silly little...

76
00:11:26,400 --> 00:11:28,199
Nice pants. Thanks.

77
00:11:28,200 --> 00:11:31,499
What have I told you before?
No dogs.

78
00:11:31,500 --> 00:11:34,150
Oh, come on.
He'll freeze to death here.

79
00:11:34,151 --> 00:11:36,899
Look, I've got the hangover
from hell, all right?

80
00:11:36,900 --> 00:11:38,599
Besides, I've just tidied up.

81
00:11:38,600 --> 00:11:40,200
OK, Mutt. Won't be long.

82
00:11:41,800 --> 00:11:42,900
Tidied up?

83
00:11:54,300 --> 00:11:58,699
Still no luck, then?
No, I've looked everywhere.

84
00:11:58,700 --> 00:12:00,699
I tell you what, Goose.

85
00:12:00,700 --> 00:12:04,500
If I didn't have bad luck,
I'd have no luck at all.

86
00:12:14,700 --> 00:12:18,300
Come on, then.
Let's see what you've got.

87
00:12:44,200 --> 00:12:46,099
It's mint.

88
00:12:46,100 --> 00:12:49,699
It's plate.
You can pick these up anywhere.

89
00:12:49,700 --> 00:12:51,600
Yeah?

90
00:13:04,300 --> 00:13:05,800
[ MAN COUGHS ]

91
00:13:07,200 --> 00:13:09,099
You all right, pal?

92
00:13:09,100 --> 00:13:10,699
Don't think so.

93
00:13:10,700 --> 00:13:13,199
Oh, yeah. Why is that, then?

94
00:13:13,200 --> 00:13:15,100
I don't know.

95
00:13:16,500 --> 00:13:17,900
I think maybe...

96
00:13:21,900 --> 00:13:24,200
Maybe I'm not... here.

97
00:13:26,100 --> 00:13:28,399
Hear that, Millsy? Fella ain't here.

98
00:13:28,400 --> 00:13:32,199
Millsy. Windmills.

99
00:13:32,200 --> 00:13:35,899
Windmills go backwards,
forwards, in Ireland.

100
00:13:35,900 --> 00:13:37,999
Bit early for that, is it not?

101
00:13:38,000 --> 00:13:41,600
Yeah, been drinking... paraffin.

102
00:13:43,400 --> 00:13:45,299
Used to make chewing gum.

103
00:13:45,300 --> 00:13:47,800
Not from Manchester, are ya? No.

104
00:13:50,700 --> 00:13:52,199
Don't think so.

105
00:13:52,200 --> 00:13:54,899
He don't know where he's from.

106
00:13:54,900 --> 00:13:56,600
Check your wallet.

107
00:14:01,300 --> 00:14:05,300
Got... Ooh, matches.

108
00:14:07,600 --> 00:14:09,100
Matches?

109
00:14:11,100 --> 00:14:12,600
A sock.

110
00:14:15,400 --> 00:14:18,900
More matches. Must be a heavy smoker.

111
00:14:21,300 --> 00:14:23,200
Poker chip.

112
00:14:25,500 --> 00:14:27,300
Pez. Pez.

113
00:14:33,400 --> 00:14:36,400
And... that's it.

114
00:14:38,400 --> 00:14:40,100
Is that gold?

115
00:14:50,100 --> 00:14:51,800
How did you do that, you madhead?

116
00:14:53,300 --> 00:14:56,700
Don't pull, you numpty.
You'll break the strap.

117
00:14:58,800 --> 00:15:00,499
[ SIREN WAILS ]

118
00:15:00,500 --> 00:15:01,900
Come on.

119
00:15:14,000 --> 00:15:17,899
This stuff's all right but, I
mean, this is rubbish. You what?

120
00:15:17,900 --> 00:15:20,599
How many times have
I got to tell you?

121
00:15:20,600 --> 00:15:23,099
No-one wants a straight
mobile any more.

122
00:15:23,100 --> 00:15:26,199
Not unless it's a free
gift with one of these.

123
00:15:26,200 --> 00:15:28,700
And this... You serious?

124
00:15:34,900 --> 00:15:37,899
I'll give you 50 quid, as
it's Christmas. For the lot?

125
00:15:37,900 --> 00:15:39,799
It's a fair price. It's not.

126
00:15:39,800 --> 00:15:42,099
It's not, Frank.

127
00:15:42,100 --> 00:15:45,899
What are you doing? I'm going to go
see what Kermit'll give us.

128
00:15:45,900 --> 00:15:48,899
Now, you listen to me,
you stay away from Kermit.

129
00:15:48,900 --> 00:15:51,099
You understand?

130
00:15:51,100 --> 00:15:52,899
He's a nutter.

131
00:15:52,900 --> 00:15:54,899
You can't tell me
what to do, Frank.

132
00:15:54,900 --> 00:15:56,400
You're NOT my dad.

133
00:16:00,700 --> 00:16:02,000
All right.

134
00:16:04,200 --> 00:16:06,299
I'll give you 70 quid. 100.

135
00:16:06,300 --> 00:16:07,999
80.

136
00:16:08,000 --> 00:16:09,799
I want a 100.

137
00:16:09,800 --> 00:16:13,000
You haven't really got the hang
of this haggling thing, have ya?

138
00:16:16,600 --> 00:16:20,300
All right. I'll give you 100.

139
00:16:22,300 --> 00:16:28,399
But you have got to promise me to
stay away from Kermit, all right?

140
00:16:28,400 --> 00:16:29,800
Promise?

141
00:16:33,900 --> 00:16:35,600
Go on, then. Get out of here.

142
00:16:37,300 --> 00:16:39,399
[ FRANK CHUCKLES ]

143
00:16:39,400 --> 00:16:41,899
It's all there, Goose.

144
00:16:41,900 --> 00:16:44,799
You're the one who
always said count it.

145
00:16:44,800 --> 00:16:46,900
Yeah, but I didn't mean
with me, though, did I?

146
00:16:52,500 --> 00:16:54,899
What are you doing tomorrow? Why?

147
00:16:54,900 --> 00:16:56,699
Come on over, if you want.

148
00:16:56,700 --> 00:16:59,899
Can't guarantee the turkey will
be cooked but it'll be clean.

149
00:16:59,900 --> 00:17:02,700
I don't know. I've got things to do.

150
00:17:04,600 --> 00:17:06,700
Thanks, though.

151
00:17:22,600 --> 00:17:24,000
Mutt?

152
00:17:30,600 --> 00:17:31,900
Mutt?

153
00:17:37,700 --> 00:17:39,300
Mutt?

154
00:17:41,400 --> 00:17:42,600
Mutt?

155
00:17:45,600 --> 00:17:49,199
Have you seen my dog, mate?
He's white, with a black patch.

156
00:17:49,200 --> 00:17:51,000
No, I'm sorry.

157
00:17:53,900 --> 00:17:54,900
Mutt?

158
00:17:56,600 --> 00:17:57,900
Mutt?

159
00:18:01,700 --> 00:18:04,499
Have you lost something? My bangle.

160
00:18:04,500 --> 00:18:07,000
I must've dropped it
when I was out earlier.

161
00:18:09,100 --> 00:18:11,400
And I was wondering if that's it.

162
00:18:15,000 --> 00:18:16,700
Can you see it?

163
00:18:20,400 --> 00:18:22,500
The lady's lost her bangle.

164
00:18:24,400 --> 00:18:26,699
A snake, gold.

165
00:18:26,700 --> 00:18:28,599
A gold cobra.

166
00:18:28,600 --> 00:18:31,199
Quiver. Sorry?

167
00:18:31,200 --> 00:18:35,699
A quiver of cobras.
A murder of crows.

168
00:18:35,700 --> 00:18:37,300
[ CROWS CAW ]

169
00:18:38,500 --> 00:18:40,800
A pomp of Pekingese.

170
00:18:47,100 --> 00:18:49,199
A quiver of cobras?

171
00:18:49,200 --> 00:18:51,799
Is that what they're really called?

172
00:18:51,800 --> 00:18:53,399
I think so.

173
00:18:53,400 --> 00:18:55,199
You sounded like you knew.

174
00:18:55,200 --> 00:18:57,600
All these things on
the tip of my brain.

175
00:19:00,700 --> 00:19:03,500
Bangle. What are you saying?

176
00:19:14,100 --> 00:19:17,399
Ah. Scissors.

177
00:19:17,400 --> 00:19:21,299
Invented by Leonardo da Vinci.

178
00:19:21,300 --> 00:19:23,800
Well, thank you for trying.

179
00:20:44,700 --> 00:20:47,599
The wedding. He gave it to
you at a wedding. How can you...

180
00:20:47,600 --> 00:20:50,799
There's a garden. It's your garden.

181
00:20:50,800 --> 00:20:52,599
A boy comes in...

182
00:20:52,600 --> 00:20:55,799
Comes in through the window.

183
00:20:55,800 --> 00:20:57,299
And he takes it.

184
00:20:57,300 --> 00:21:00,099
He takes the bangle.

185
00:21:00,100 --> 00:21:02,900
How could you possibly know?

186
00:21:09,400 --> 00:21:10,700
I don't know.

187
00:21:22,600 --> 00:21:24,100
[ DOG BARKS ]

188
00:21:30,500 --> 00:21:31,700
Mutt?

189
00:21:35,700 --> 00:21:37,000
Mutt?

190
00:21:40,000 --> 00:21:41,200
Mutt?

191
00:21:53,300 --> 00:21:56,299
What are you doing?

192
00:21:56,300 --> 00:21:58,099
That's an odd question.

193
00:21:58,100 --> 00:22:01,399
You're going to work? Yep.

194
00:22:01,400 --> 00:22:04,399
Today?

195
00:22:04,400 --> 00:22:08,099
There's someone I have to see
before the holidays. Henry.

196
00:22:08,100 --> 00:22:12,599
It'll only be an hour or two.
Fine. I'll go on my own, then.

197
00:22:12,600 --> 00:22:15,499
Don't be like that.
I have responsibilities.

198
00:22:15,500 --> 00:22:18,100
What about your
responsibility to me?

199
00:22:21,200 --> 00:22:22,600
To Milly?

200
00:22:26,900 --> 00:22:30,899
Look, if I'm running late,
I'll text, meet you there.

201
00:22:30,900 --> 00:22:32,000
OK?

202
00:22:35,300 --> 00:22:36,300
Bye.

203
00:24:52,300 --> 00:24:53,700
[ HE SIGHS ]

204
00:25:08,300 --> 00:25:10,499
Mutt?

205
00:25:10,500 --> 00:25:12,100
[ DOG BARKS ]

206
00:25:13,300 --> 00:25:14,700
Mutt?

207
00:25:18,300 --> 00:25:21,300
Oh, have you seen my dog, Stu?
No, Goose. Sorry, mate.

208
00:25:25,400 --> 00:25:26,900
[ DOG BARKS ]

209
00:25:40,900 --> 00:25:42,500
All right, young man?

210
00:25:49,200 --> 00:25:52,099
I'm Anthony.

211
00:25:52,100 --> 00:25:53,800
An-tho-ny. An-tho-ny.

212
00:25:55,100 --> 00:25:56,599
I am An-thon-y.

213
00:25:56,600 --> 00:25:59,999
Anthony. I'm Anthony.

214
00:26:00,000 --> 00:26:03,399
Mutt?

215
00:26:03,400 --> 00:26:05,300
Argh!

216
00:26:10,200 --> 00:26:11,999
Aglet.

217
00:26:12,000 --> 00:26:14,199
You what?

218
00:26:14,200 --> 00:26:17,500
The hard bit on the end of
your lace is called an aglet.

219
00:26:21,200 --> 00:26:24,300
And this bit is called the glabella.

220
00:26:26,100 --> 00:26:27,899
Joins your eyebrows up.

221
00:26:27,900 --> 00:26:32,099
Someone, somewhere, came up
with a word for everything.

222
00:26:32,100 --> 00:26:35,499
Owls got three eyelids.
Each one's got a name.

223
00:26:35,500 --> 00:26:37,300
It's not just names.

224
00:26:39,400 --> 00:26:44,200
I know that Mel Blanc's tombstone
says, "That's all, folks."

225
00:26:45,900 --> 00:26:49,799
Coke'd be green if they
didn't color it brown.

226
00:26:49,800 --> 00:26:53,499
And
hippopotomonstrosesquippedaliophobia

227
00:26:53,500 --> 00:26:55,600
is the fear of long words.

228
00:26:57,700 --> 00:26:59,000
Lost something?

229
00:27:01,500 --> 00:27:03,799
Maybe. My dog.

230
00:27:03,800 --> 00:27:05,199
Mutt?

231
00:27:05,200 --> 00:27:06,899
Yeah, you seen him?

232
00:27:06,900 --> 00:27:10,399
No, you were shouting "Mutt".

233
00:27:10,400 --> 00:27:11,899
Brilliant.

234
00:27:11,900 --> 00:27:14,199
I had a dog when I was your age.

235
00:27:14,200 --> 00:27:15,699
Yeah?

236
00:27:15,700 --> 00:27:18,499
Or maybe I never had a dog.

237
00:27:18,500 --> 00:27:22,000
There's a lot I'm not quite
too sure about these days.

238
00:27:24,700 --> 00:27:26,000
Like this. Look.

239
00:27:28,100 --> 00:27:31,100
You see, I don't really
feel like an Anthony.

240
00:27:33,100 --> 00:27:36,199
You don't know what you're called?

241
00:27:36,200 --> 00:27:37,300
No.

242
00:27:40,800 --> 00:27:43,999
Other stuff seems to have got
in the way. The aglet stuff?

243
00:27:44,000 --> 00:27:45,400
Yeah.

244
00:27:46,800 --> 00:27:48,299
And then I saw you.

245
00:27:48,300 --> 00:27:50,999
Oh, yeah!

246
00:27:51,000 --> 00:27:52,900
And it seemed like a pattern.

247
00:27:54,300 --> 00:27:56,900
Because you stole the bangle.

248
00:28:01,400 --> 00:28:02,899
She lost the bangle.

249
00:28:02,900 --> 00:28:04,799
You stole the bangle.

250
00:28:04,800 --> 00:28:06,400
You lost a dog.

251
00:28:08,700 --> 00:28:10,800
It's a pattern.

252
00:28:12,600 --> 00:28:14,100
It's a pattern!

253
00:28:16,600 --> 00:28:20,000
[ MUSIC: "I Wish It Could Be Christmas
Everyday" by Wizzard ]

254
00:29:21,900 --> 00:29:23,299
What do you want?

255
00:29:23,300 --> 00:29:26,399
Mrs Thornhill, I'm Henry Penvell,

256
00:29:26,400 --> 00:29:28,899
Richard's probation officer.

257
00:29:28,900 --> 00:29:32,499
There's no Richard here.

258
00:29:32,500 --> 00:29:35,600
No. It...

259
00:29:45,900 --> 00:29:47,699
Can I help you, dear?

260
00:29:47,700 --> 00:29:51,399
It's your grandson, Richard.

261
00:29:51,400 --> 00:29:54,099
He missed his appointment
with me this morning.

262
00:29:54,100 --> 00:29:56,599
Richard?

263
00:29:56,600 --> 00:29:57,900
My grandson?

264
00:30:00,000 --> 00:30:01,599
Oh, you mean Goose.

265
00:30:01,600 --> 00:30:03,799
No-one calls him Richard.

266
00:30:03,800 --> 00:30:06,799
No, he's not here.

267
00:30:06,800 --> 00:30:09,699
This is serious, Mrs Thornhill.

268
00:30:09,700 --> 00:30:11,200
The terms of Richard's...

269
00:30:12,900 --> 00:30:15,799
The terms of Goose's
supervision order clearly state

270
00:30:15,800 --> 00:30:18,399
he must not miss any
of his appointments.

271
00:30:18,400 --> 00:30:21,800
It really is very serious,
Mrs Thornhill.

272
00:30:24,100 --> 00:30:28,099
And then he goes,
"She lost her bangle."

273
00:30:28,100 --> 00:30:30,999
"And you stole it."

274
00:30:31,000 --> 00:30:33,199
What do you reckon?

275
00:30:33,200 --> 00:30:34,699
Copper? Nah.

276
00:30:34,700 --> 00:30:37,199
Manchester's finest have
got better things to do

277
00:30:37,200 --> 00:30:39,599
than hang out with
kids on Christmas Eve.

278
00:30:39,600 --> 00:30:41,399
They'd get themselves arrested.

279
00:30:41,400 --> 00:30:44,299
So this bloke, did he have a name?

280
00:30:44,300 --> 00:30:45,800
Yeah.

281
00:30:47,600 --> 00:30:48,799
Anthony.

282
00:30:48,800 --> 00:30:50,299
Though he said it wasn't.

283
00:30:50,300 --> 00:30:52,099
So, then, how do you know it was?

284
00:30:52,100 --> 00:30:55,199
Cos he had a name badge on.
It said, "I'm Anthony".

285
00:30:55,200 --> 00:30:58,799
Oh, ho-ho, no!

286
00:30:58,800 --> 00:31:01,699
What? I know him.

287
00:31:01,700 --> 00:31:04,599
I bumped into that joker last night.

288
00:31:04,600 --> 00:31:09,100
You know, he did have a dog collar.

289
00:31:10,700 --> 00:31:14,199
You're winding me up. No, no! He
had a dog collar round his wrist.

290
00:31:14,200 --> 00:31:16,100
He did. You serious? Yeah.

291
00:31:18,200 --> 00:31:21,699
You think he took Mutt? I dunno.

292
00:31:21,700 --> 00:31:24,899
But I remember someone
saying that...

293
00:31:24,900 --> 00:31:29,299
There was this geezer who used
to nick dogs and then, when the
owners put up reward posters,

294
00:31:29,300 --> 00:31:31,299
he'd give 'em back, claim the money.

295
00:31:31,300 --> 00:31:34,499
Come on, then. We better go see.

296
00:31:34,500 --> 00:31:36,499
What's with all this "we" business?

297
00:31:36,500 --> 00:31:38,599
He might be a total nut job, Frank.

298
00:31:38,600 --> 00:31:42,000
All the more reason for
leaving well alone.

299
00:31:43,200 --> 00:31:45,499
Dad would've come.

300
00:31:45,500 --> 00:31:50,300
Ooh, you are a manipulative
little git, you know that?

301
00:31:55,900 --> 00:31:58,700
I was just making Goose
a sandwich for his lunch.

302
00:32:00,300 --> 00:32:02,800
Would you like one? No, thank you.

303
00:32:08,300 --> 00:32:13,199
Mrs Thornhill, do you know
when Goose is going to be...

304
00:32:13,200 --> 00:32:16,600
Erm...

305
00:32:18,600 --> 00:32:19,699
Tea?

306
00:32:19,700 --> 00:32:21,699
You've already asked.

307
00:32:21,700 --> 00:32:23,200
No, thanks.

308
00:32:26,500 --> 00:32:28,899
Do you have any idea
where Goose might be?

309
00:32:28,900 --> 00:32:30,999
Went out with Mutt this morning.

310
00:32:31,000 --> 00:32:32,800
Right, so you said.

311
00:32:36,500 --> 00:32:38,999
He may have had an appointment,

312
00:32:39,000 --> 00:32:41,200
with his probation officer.

313
00:32:43,400 --> 00:32:46,700
That's... that's me. Remember?

314
00:32:50,700 --> 00:32:54,200
He's usually back for his lunch.
I'm just doing him a sandwich.

315
00:32:55,900 --> 00:32:57,599
Would you like to stay?

316
00:32:57,600 --> 00:33:01,099
Thanks. I can't, I'm afraid.

317
00:33:01,100 --> 00:33:03,000
Not today.

318
00:33:05,400 --> 00:33:06,800
Not a good day.

319
00:33:08,300 --> 00:33:09,700
It's not, is it?

320
00:33:13,000 --> 00:33:15,899
You're not very well,
are you, Mrs Thornhill?

321
00:33:15,900 --> 00:33:17,999
No.

322
00:33:18,000 --> 00:33:19,800
I don't think I am.

323
00:33:22,800 --> 00:33:26,699
Do you remember if anybody has been
to see you since the accident?

324
00:33:26,700 --> 00:33:29,399
Erm, anyone like me?

325
00:33:29,400 --> 00:33:32,299
Anyone like you? Hm. No.

326
00:33:32,300 --> 00:33:34,899
I think I'd remember
someone like you.

327
00:33:34,900 --> 00:33:37,400
Don't worry.

328
00:33:39,400 --> 00:33:40,800
It must be hard for you.

329
00:33:42,700 --> 00:33:44,599
Looking after someone like Goose.

330
00:33:44,600 --> 00:33:46,300
He is a bit of a handful.

331
00:33:48,200 --> 00:33:53,100
But, in time, all things
grow towards the sun.

332
00:33:55,000 --> 00:33:57,300
My mother always used to say that.

333
00:33:59,100 --> 00:34:00,400
Yeah.

334
00:34:06,600 --> 00:34:08,000
Frank.

335
00:34:10,200 --> 00:34:12,499
You leave this to me, all right?

336
00:34:12,500 --> 00:34:14,599
Oi!
[ FRANK WHISTLES ]

337
00:34:14,600 --> 00:34:17,300
How's it going with the
monkey angels, mate?

338
00:34:18,900 --> 00:34:19,999
Yes.

339
00:34:20,000 --> 00:34:23,399
Angel with a monkey's head. Yes.

340
00:34:23,400 --> 00:34:25,299
Don't know.

341
00:34:25,300 --> 00:34:27,299
Ri-ight. Told ya.

342
00:34:27,300 --> 00:34:29,199
You do something with his dog?

343
00:34:29,200 --> 00:34:31,599
I don't think so.

344
00:34:31,600 --> 00:34:34,000
So what's that on your wrist?

345
00:34:35,300 --> 00:34:38,199
You nick dogs, then, do you?

346
00:34:38,200 --> 00:34:40,599
Why would I do that? For the reward.

347
00:34:40,600 --> 00:34:43,199
There's a reward? No.

348
00:34:43,200 --> 00:34:46,199
Then why would I take your dog?

349
00:34:46,200 --> 00:34:49,599
And how do you know about this
bangle? I saw him take it.

350
00:34:49,600 --> 00:34:52,899
No, you never. Yes, I did.
How do you mean?

351
00:34:52,900 --> 00:34:58,099
An Indian woman,
I touched her hand...

352
00:34:58,100 --> 00:34:59,899
You have a torch.

353
00:34:59,900 --> 00:35:02,699
Bangle's on the chair.
You take the bangle.

354
00:35:02,700 --> 00:35:05,399
Wait. Rewind.

355
00:35:05,400 --> 00:35:07,799
What do you mean, you saw it?

356
00:35:07,800 --> 00:35:10,100
I just did.

357
00:35:17,600 --> 00:35:19,199
Oh, come on, Frank!

358
00:35:19,200 --> 00:35:22,099
Come here, Goose. Oi!

359
00:35:22,100 --> 00:35:25,700
All right. Show us, then.

360
00:35:27,900 --> 00:35:31,099
Give him your hand.
See if he knows what you lost.

361
00:35:31,100 --> 00:35:33,599
Lost.

362
00:35:33,600 --> 00:35:35,400
Everybody's lost something.

363
00:35:50,400 --> 00:35:54,199
[ TV: ] This is a marvelous story.
I remember reading this as a boy.

364
00:35:54,200 --> 00:35:56,599
It was bought during
the war for six pence.

365
00:35:56,600 --> 00:35:58,899
Six pence was a lot of money then.

366
00:35:58,900 --> 00:36:00,799
Well, yes.

367
00:36:00,800 --> 00:36:05,599
Now, the thing is, Raven Publishing,
they weren't around for very long

368
00:36:05,600 --> 00:36:09,399
and the artist they commissioned
to illustrate their Wilde series...

369
00:36:09,400 --> 00:36:12,499
I mean, the illustrations
are marvelous, aren't they?

370
00:36:12,500 --> 00:36:17,299
The artist was Walter Crane
but sadly Raven went bankrupt
almost immediately afterwards.

371
00:36:17,300 --> 00:36:19,099
Really? Yes.

372
00:36:19,100 --> 00:36:23,299
So, how much is it worth?

373
00:36:23,300 --> 00:36:29,099
Well, I think you'll be fairly
surprised to discover just what

374
00:36:29,100 --> 00:36:34,900
a first edition of The Happy Prince
by Oscar Wilde will go for
at an auction today.

375
00:36:37,100 --> 00:36:39,999
I haven't really given
it much thought.

376
00:36:40,000 --> 00:36:43,799
Well, in this condition, I'd
estimate it at roundabout...

377
00:36:43,800 --> 00:36:47,299
Well, somewhere in the
region of... £40,000.

378
00:36:47,300 --> 00:36:49,000
[ SHE GASPS ]

379
00:36:51,700 --> 00:36:52,899
How much? 40,000.

380
00:36:52,900 --> 00:36:54,799
Thank you for bringing it in.

381
00:36:54,800 --> 00:36:56,300
£40,000!

382
00:36:57,800 --> 00:36:59,700
£40,000!

383
00:37:01,400 --> 00:37:02,999
Oh, my...

384
00:37:03,000 --> 00:37:04,700
Oh, God!

385
00:37:14,900 --> 00:37:17,399
The Happy Prince, Oscar Wilde,

386
00:37:17,400 --> 00:37:18,900
1888, £40,000.

387
00:37:23,700 --> 00:37:25,599
Where is it, mate?

388
00:37:25,600 --> 00:37:27,500
I've looked everywhere.

389
00:37:29,800 --> 00:37:33,899
It's just a wind-up, Frank. Everyone
knows you lost that book. Please.

390
00:37:33,900 --> 00:37:35,600
Please.

391
00:37:43,100 --> 00:37:46,199
"High above the city,
on a tall column,

392
00:37:46,200 --> 00:37:49,799
"stood the statue of
The Happy Prince.

393
00:37:49,800 --> 00:37:55,000
"He was gilded all over with
thin leaves and fine gold.

394
00:37:56,500 --> 00:38:00,999
"For eyes, he had two bright
sapphires and a large...

395
00:38:01,000 --> 00:38:03,899
"He was very much admired, indeed.

396
00:38:03,900 --> 00:38:09,600
"'He's as beautiful as a
weathercock', remarked one
of the town councillors."

397
00:38:14,100 --> 00:38:16,999
He's as beautiful as a weathercock.
Yes.

398
00:38:17,000 --> 00:38:18,499
[ BANGING ]

399
00:38:18,500 --> 00:38:20,999
Australia? Bloody Australia?

400
00:38:21,000 --> 00:38:22,300
What do you expect?

401
00:38:24,500 --> 00:38:28,599
You're taking my daughter to the
other side of the world forever.

402
00:38:28,600 --> 00:38:32,299
Please, Frank.
I can't do this anymore.

403
00:38:32,300 --> 00:38:34,599
Not anymore. Not since...

404
00:38:34,600 --> 00:38:38,199
What are you saying,
it's all my fault?

405
00:38:38,200 --> 00:38:40,100
You're just like all the others.

406
00:38:43,500 --> 00:38:48,299
"High above the city, on a tall
column, stood the statue of
The Happy Prince.

407
00:38:48,300 --> 00:38:51,699
"It is not to Egypt that I'm
going, said the swallow.

408
00:38:51,700 --> 00:38:54,699
"I'm going to the house of death.

409
00:38:54,700 --> 00:38:57,800
"Death is the brother
of sleep, is it not?

410
00:39:08,900 --> 00:39:12,399
"Bring me the two most
precious things in the city,

411
00:39:12,400 --> 00:39:15,200
"said God to one of his angels.

412
00:39:17,700 --> 00:39:19,500
"The angel brought him..."

413
00:39:22,500 --> 00:39:23,900
Good night, Dr Clarence.

414
00:39:27,400 --> 00:39:30,199
"High above the city,
on a tall column,

415
00:39:30,200 --> 00:39:32,400
"stood the statue of
The Happy Prince."

416
00:39:38,800 --> 00:39:40,600
Dr Clarence?

417
00:40:03,000 --> 00:40:05,299
Well, he can't get many patients.

418
00:40:05,300 --> 00:40:08,099
He got himself struck off.
How'd you mean?

419
00:40:08,100 --> 00:40:11,699
When he retired, he said if someone
had a heart attack in the street

420
00:40:11,700 --> 00:40:15,099
and he went to help, he could get
sued if he was still a doctor.

421
00:40:15,100 --> 00:40:17,599
Got himself struck off
and no-one could touch him.

422
00:40:17,600 --> 00:40:21,199
They don't come much
stubborner than Dr Clarence.

423
00:40:21,200 --> 00:40:22,500
Hi.

424
00:40:23,700 --> 00:40:27,199
What have you got to
be so happy about?

425
00:40:27,200 --> 00:40:31,199
Er, I was just wondering, you didn't
happen to accidentally pick up

426
00:40:31,200 --> 00:40:33,799
a book of mine, did you,
from the pub a while ago?

427
00:40:33,800 --> 00:40:35,799
The Happy Prince?

428
00:40:35,800 --> 00:40:37,599
Oscar Wilde?

429
00:40:37,600 --> 00:40:40,750
I would have thought Nuts was
more your sort of thing, Frank.

430
00:40:40,751 --> 00:40:42,499
Sentimental value, you know.

431
00:40:42,500 --> 00:40:44,399
And it's worth £40,000.

432
00:40:44,400 --> 00:40:46,300
Yeah. Thanks.

433
00:40:49,300 --> 00:40:51,000
I suppose you'd better come in.

434
00:40:53,300 --> 00:40:54,600
Come on.

435
00:41:13,700 --> 00:41:16,400
Don't worry. I'm sure
Professor X will find it.

436
00:41:28,000 --> 00:41:29,300
Please.

437
00:41:32,000 --> 00:41:34,100
He's joking, ain't he?

438
00:41:36,600 --> 00:41:38,799
Put them there.

439
00:41:38,800 --> 00:41:40,100
Mate!

440
00:41:43,500 --> 00:41:47,599
So, Oscar Wilde? Yes.

441
00:41:47,600 --> 00:41:50,900
I remember I thought it looked
a little unusual at the time.

442
00:41:50,901 --> 00:41:56,099
They were Walter Crane
illustrations, weren't they? Yeah.

443
00:41:56,100 --> 00:41:58,199
Oh, that would be valuable.

444
00:41:58,200 --> 00:41:59,500
You got it?

445
00:42:01,100 --> 00:42:03,200
What makes you think I have?

446
00:42:07,300 --> 00:42:09,099
What? He touched Frank's hand.

447
00:42:09,100 --> 00:42:10,899
Said you picked it up in a pub.

448
00:42:10,900 --> 00:42:12,399
Oh, were you there?

449
00:42:12,400 --> 00:42:14,000
No, he saw it in his head.

450
00:42:15,900 --> 00:42:17,999
Oh. Yeah, I know.

451
00:42:18,000 --> 00:42:21,400
You haven't heard of anything
like it before, have you?

452
00:42:23,500 --> 00:42:25,799
Well...

453
00:42:25,800 --> 00:42:28,599
It doesn't... feel right.

454
00:42:28,600 --> 00:42:32,299
Plus, he's completely forgotten
who he is and everything.

455
00:42:32,300 --> 00:42:36,499
Except for the stuff
about owls and aglets.

456
00:42:36,500 --> 00:42:39,099
Aglets? [ BOTH: ] Aglets.

457
00:42:39,100 --> 00:42:40,799
The hard bit on the
end of your lace.

458
00:42:40,800 --> 00:42:44,299
Very interesting. It's
really not that interesting.
Oi! What?

459
00:42:44,300 --> 00:42:46,700
I'd really like to know
what's happening to me.

460
00:42:49,400 --> 00:42:51,500
Sorry, I'm not a doctor.
Not anymore.

461
00:42:53,800 --> 00:42:54,899
Oh.

462
00:42:54,900 --> 00:42:58,000
But, well...

463
00:43:00,700 --> 00:43:04,700
Well, occasionally dreams
and reality can get a bit muddled.

464
00:43:06,200 --> 00:43:08,300
You think I'm crazy?

465
00:43:10,500 --> 00:43:13,399
I don't feel crazy.

466
00:43:13,400 --> 00:43:15,199
Inside.

467
00:43:15,200 --> 00:43:17,699
I'm not saying you are.

468
00:43:17,700 --> 00:43:22,099
It can happen to patients
who've been in a coma, as well.

469
00:43:22,100 --> 00:43:24,399
It's called Hypnos.

470
00:43:24,400 --> 00:43:27,499
From the Greek. Hypnos was
Morpheus's father, son of...

471
00:43:27,500 --> 00:43:28,800
Nyx. Night.

472
00:43:31,100 --> 00:43:34,099
So I've been in a coma?

473
00:43:34,100 --> 00:43:35,500
It's... possible.

474
00:43:37,500 --> 00:43:39,599
As I say... Yeah, and as I say,

475
00:43:39,600 --> 00:43:42,999
none of this Greek mythology
is getting me Mutt back.

476
00:43:43,000 --> 00:43:46,399
Mutt. Mutt's his dog.

477
00:43:46,400 --> 00:43:49,200
I thought I had something
to do with lost things.

478
00:43:51,700 --> 00:43:53,399
Bangles.

479
00:43:53,400 --> 00:43:55,899
Books.

480
00:43:55,900 --> 00:43:57,999
Dogs.

481
00:43:58,000 --> 00:44:02,099
You see, everyone I've
met has lost something.

482
00:44:02,100 --> 00:44:03,500
Except for you.

483
00:44:28,900 --> 00:44:31,599
"My dearest Rafe,
it breaks my heart...

484
00:44:31,600 --> 00:44:34,099
"I just can't do this any more...

485
00:44:34,100 --> 00:44:37,799
"somewhere along the way we
started to drift apart...

486
00:44:37,800 --> 00:44:39,900
"If I tried, we'd both know...

487
00:44:42,900 --> 00:44:46,099
"It hurts too much...
the distance between us...

488
00:44:46,100 --> 00:44:48,300
"Please believe that I wish..."

489
00:45:15,500 --> 00:45:17,500
"You'll always have
my heart, Rafe."

490
00:45:22,000 --> 00:45:24,000
It's still there.

491
00:45:26,100 --> 00:45:28,199
It's under the floorboards.

492
00:45:28,200 --> 00:45:30,799
My book's under the floorboards?

493
00:45:30,800 --> 00:45:33,699
I'm not sure I...

494
00:45:33,700 --> 00:45:35,200
Leave it.

495
00:45:37,400 --> 00:45:39,700
If that's what you think is best.

496
00:46:10,600 --> 00:46:11,900
Here.

497
00:46:14,800 --> 00:46:16,600
From my wife.

498
00:46:19,900 --> 00:46:21,400
She said she left...

499
00:46:22,900 --> 00:46:25,399
All this time...

500
00:46:25,400 --> 00:46:28,400
And I thought she'd
gone without a word.

501
00:47:02,400 --> 00:47:04,799
I was so angry.

502
00:47:04,800 --> 00:47:06,400
So stubborn.

503
00:47:11,100 --> 00:47:13,100
Too stubborn to look for her.

504
00:47:14,500 --> 00:47:16,799
Too stubborn...

505
00:47:16,800 --> 00:47:19,000
to tell her how much I loved her.

506
00:47:21,100 --> 00:47:22,700
To tell her she was...

507
00:47:28,500 --> 00:47:30,200
everything to me.

508
00:47:43,700 --> 00:47:46,100
Frank.

509
00:47:48,700 --> 00:47:51,599
There is a kind of system.

510
00:47:51,600 --> 00:47:53,699
It's in the hall.

511
00:47:53,700 --> 00:47:55,499
By the phone.

512
00:47:55,500 --> 00:47:57,000
Thanks.

513
00:48:11,300 --> 00:48:12,999
Who are you?

514
00:48:13,000 --> 00:48:15,400
I wish I knew.

515
00:49:20,500 --> 00:49:22,999
So I give back the bangle?

516
00:49:23,000 --> 00:49:25,300
Then what?

517
00:49:27,000 --> 00:49:29,699
You find me Mutt.

518
00:49:29,700 --> 00:49:31,500
You think so?

519
00:49:37,300 --> 00:49:39,299
40 grand! 40 beautiful grand.

520
00:49:39,300 --> 00:49:41,199
You know what I'm going to do?

521
00:49:41,200 --> 00:49:44,299
I'm going to buy a BMW.
7 series? How much are they?

522
00:49:44,300 --> 00:49:46,799
25 if you're lucky. Sweet!

523
00:49:46,800 --> 00:49:49,699
Five grand'll get me out of
debt and get me some new togs

524
00:49:49,700 --> 00:49:53,399
and that'll still leave me...
Ten grand. Ten grand
for a rainy day.

525
00:49:53,400 --> 00:49:56,399
I'd buy a big umbrella! Yeah,
a really big umbrella.

526
00:49:56,400 --> 00:49:57,799
Perfect.

527
00:49:57,800 --> 00:49:59,899
What's that supposed to mean?

528
00:49:59,900 --> 00:50:02,699
It means you know your mind.

529
00:50:02,700 --> 00:50:06,399
So I'm going to drive round to
her place, dressed to the nines.

530
00:50:06,400 --> 00:50:08,199
A... No. No.

531
00:50:08,200 --> 00:50:11,799
I don't want to know what dressed to
the nines means where it comes from.

532
00:50:11,800 --> 00:50:15,599
I'll take for a posh curry,
tell her I'm out of trouble,

533
00:50:15,600 --> 00:50:18,299
out of debt and finished
with all the dodgy stuff.

534
00:50:18,300 --> 00:50:21,900
And if she doesn't like that...
She can shove it. She can shove it!

535
00:50:21,901 --> 00:50:23,799
A man with a plan.

536
00:50:23,800 --> 00:50:27,299
Sorry, mate.
What is your problem? Hmm?

537
00:50:27,300 --> 00:50:29,799
Don't look at me with
your spooky eyes.

538
00:50:29,800 --> 00:50:32,799
You're not exactly a man with
a plan yourself, are you?

539
00:50:32,800 --> 00:50:34,799
Don't know who you are.

540
00:50:34,800 --> 00:50:38,899
Falling asleep in the street
and touching people's hands
and going all mystic on them.

541
00:50:38,900 --> 00:50:41,899
You're weird, you know that?
So just shut it, all right?

542
00:50:41,900 --> 00:50:44,199
I didn't say anything. No.

543
00:50:44,200 --> 00:50:46,199
Well, she's my wife, not yours.

544
00:50:46,200 --> 00:50:49,599
You didn't marry her, did you?
Don't know. Can't remember.

545
00:50:49,600 --> 00:50:52,099
Trust me. You didn't.

546
00:50:52,100 --> 00:50:53,400
I would've noticed.

547
00:51:08,400 --> 00:51:10,199
So what are you going to do?

548
00:51:10,200 --> 00:51:13,599
I'm going to show her the book,
prove I'm not a loser.

549
00:51:13,600 --> 00:51:16,799
She doesn't think you're a loser.
What do you know?

550
00:51:16,800 --> 00:51:18,600
She thinks you're a good father.

551
00:51:20,300 --> 00:51:21,800
I saw.

552
00:51:33,500 --> 00:51:35,399
Watch this.

553
00:51:35,400 --> 00:51:37,799
What's going to happen?

554
00:51:37,800 --> 00:51:40,000
He's going to ring the doorbell.

555
00:51:49,200 --> 00:51:51,799
Frank. What a nice surprise!

556
00:51:51,800 --> 00:51:54,099
Do you know what this is?

557
00:51:54,100 --> 00:51:57,699
This is a first edition of
The Happy Prince by Oscar Wilde,

558
00:51:57,700 --> 00:52:00,399
illustrated by Walter Crane.

559
00:52:00,400 --> 00:52:03,199
And it's worth £40,000.

560
00:52:03,200 --> 00:52:05,500
And you know what I'm
going to do with it?

561
00:52:14,600 --> 00:52:17,199
I'm going to give it to you. What?

562
00:52:17,200 --> 00:52:18,899
It's for Australia.

563
00:52:18,900 --> 00:52:21,199
So you can start a new
life for yourselves.

564
00:52:21,200 --> 00:52:23,799
Whatever you want.

565
00:52:23,800 --> 00:52:26,199
Frank, are you all right? Yeah.

566
00:52:26,200 --> 00:52:28,399
Yeah, I feel fine, actually.

567
00:52:28,400 --> 00:52:30,999
40,000?

568
00:52:31,000 --> 00:52:33,500
Are you sure this isn't one of...
It's rare.

569
00:52:35,400 --> 00:52:36,700
It's really rare.

570
00:52:41,700 --> 00:52:44,199
You used to read it to me. Yeah.

571
00:52:44,200 --> 00:52:49,000
All that time we were
scratching around for money,
it was right under our nose.

572
00:52:49,001 --> 00:52:52,999
And you're just giving it
to us to go to Australia?

573
00:52:53,000 --> 00:52:55,399
Happy Christmas!

574
00:52:55,400 --> 00:52:57,599
I'm going to miss you.

575
00:52:57,600 --> 00:53:00,100
Both of you. Dad!

576
00:53:03,700 --> 00:53:07,099
Come on. Come inside.

577
00:53:07,100 --> 00:53:10,199
Come inside. Let's talk about this.

578
00:53:10,200 --> 00:53:13,100
Just... just give me a minute.

579
00:53:24,400 --> 00:53:27,000
There's 150 quid. It's all I got.

580
00:53:29,200 --> 00:53:33,099
The bangle - I sold it, to Noel.

581
00:53:33,100 --> 00:53:37,099
Now don't let him rip you off, OK?
He only gave me 40 quid for it.

582
00:53:37,100 --> 00:53:39,599
40 quid?

583
00:53:39,600 --> 00:53:41,399
But you gave me 100.

584
00:53:41,400 --> 00:53:45,700
Yeah, well, someone's got to look
out for you, haven't they?

585
00:53:47,700 --> 00:53:49,000
Thanks.

586
00:54:29,600 --> 00:54:31,399
Prepare for slime on a stick.

587
00:54:31,400 --> 00:54:34,599
Here's hoping we've got enough.

588
00:54:34,600 --> 00:54:38,700
Otherwise we going to have to
dazzle him with some fact
about ducks and trousers.

589
00:54:41,000 --> 00:54:43,499
I don't know any facts
about ducks and trousers.

590
00:54:43,500 --> 00:54:44,899
Oh.

591
00:54:44,900 --> 00:54:47,199
Hang on.

592
00:54:47,200 --> 00:54:50,700
Donald Duck's dad is
called Quackmore Duck.

593
00:54:53,500 --> 00:54:55,599
Nothing about trousers.

594
00:54:55,600 --> 00:54:56,700
Knew it!

595
00:55:09,600 --> 00:55:11,199
Ding-dong!

596
00:55:11,200 --> 00:55:12,800
I'll be right with you.

597
00:55:26,600 --> 00:55:27,899
What do you want?

598
00:55:27,900 --> 00:55:30,199
I want to buy that bangle back.

599
00:55:30,200 --> 00:55:32,499
The one Frank sold you.

600
00:55:32,500 --> 00:55:34,299
I don't know anyone called Frank.

601
00:55:34,300 --> 00:55:36,399
No? No.

602
00:55:36,400 --> 00:55:39,199
And I think you ought to leave.

603
00:55:39,200 --> 00:55:41,300
I did say "buy".

604
00:55:44,600 --> 00:55:46,799
I don't know what
you're talking about.

605
00:55:46,800 --> 00:55:49,499
Maybe I'll just give
the cops a bell, then.

606
00:55:49,500 --> 00:55:52,699
Tell them where you got
that carriage clock from.

607
00:55:52,700 --> 00:55:54,299
[ NOEL LAUGHS ]

608
00:55:54,300 --> 00:55:56,499
How dare you?

609
00:55:56,500 --> 00:55:58,799
I have receipts for everything.

610
00:55:58,800 --> 00:56:03,599
Not that, you don't, cos I snagged
it out of a house on Ashford Road.

611
00:56:03,600 --> 00:56:06,799
Right, get out. Go on, get out now.

612
00:56:06,800 --> 00:56:08,899
Or that pocket watch?

613
00:56:08,900 --> 00:56:10,700
Or that tankard?

614
00:56:12,100 --> 00:56:14,000
[ MUSIC BOX PLAYS ]

615
00:56:17,600 --> 00:56:19,199
[ PHONE RINGS ]

616
00:56:19,200 --> 00:56:21,899
"Emergency. Which service, please?"

617
00:56:21,900 --> 00:56:25,200
Police. Yeah, all right! All right.

618
00:56:27,400 --> 00:56:30,099
I sold it. You're lying.

619
00:56:30,100 --> 00:56:32,199
No. Oh, whatever.

620
00:56:32,200 --> 00:56:37,500
Of course, I might be able to
remember who I sold it to...

621
00:56:39,400 --> 00:56:41,000
if the price was right.

622
00:56:52,700 --> 00:56:55,100
How much? Probably all of it.

623
00:56:57,000 --> 00:56:58,500
All of it? I think so.

624
00:57:00,600 --> 00:57:01,900
Here.

625
00:57:03,600 --> 00:57:05,600
Good lad.

626
00:57:10,600 --> 00:57:12,899
Come on, then. Tell us.

627
00:57:12,900 --> 00:57:18,700
Well, now, I sold it to a
woman with some orange flowers.

628
00:57:21,400 --> 00:57:26,099
That's it? Well! For 150 quid,
that's all I get?

629
00:57:26,100 --> 00:57:27,499
You wanted to know.
[ GOOSE SIGHS ]

630
00:57:27,500 --> 00:57:30,499
It's OK. I know who she is.

631
00:57:30,500 --> 00:57:34,100
How do you know who she is?
Thank you very much. Come on.

632
00:58:00,300 --> 00:58:04,699
How did you do that? Don't know.
Must have learnt it somewhere.

633
00:58:04,700 --> 00:58:07,999
Like the fascinating facts?
I suppose so. Come on.

634
00:58:08,000 --> 00:58:13,199
Anyway, you say you know who this
woman is. Yeah, I just saw her.

635
00:58:13,200 --> 00:58:15,899
You saw her? Yeah, just saw her.

636
00:58:15,900 --> 00:58:19,699
She was getting on the bus.
She had the flowers. You what?

637
00:58:19,700 --> 00:58:20,800
Number 47.

638
00:58:26,200 --> 00:58:28,699
It's Christmas.
She could be going anywhere.

639
00:58:28,700 --> 00:58:31,499
You don't go just anywhere
with a bunch of flowers.

640
00:58:31,500 --> 00:58:35,099
At Christmas, you do.
Not with flowers.

641
00:58:35,100 --> 00:58:36,400
We'll see.

642
00:58:37,900 --> 00:58:41,499
Yeah. And maybe we won't
This bus goes everywhere.

643
00:58:41,500 --> 00:58:44,100
Well, haven't you ever
wanted to visit everywhere?

644
00:58:48,500 --> 00:58:50,150
Can I ask you a question?

645
00:58:50,151 --> 00:58:51,400
That is a question.

646
00:58:53,200 --> 00:58:56,699
What's it like to see...

647
00:58:56,700 --> 00:58:58,200
to see lost things?

648
00:59:02,100 --> 00:59:04,300
It's like being in a dream.

649
00:59:06,900 --> 00:59:10,899
It's not your dream.
It's someone else's dream.

650
00:59:10,900 --> 00:59:13,000
Not supposed to be there.

651
00:59:17,700 --> 00:59:21,199
It's like you're an intruder.
Don't sound too nice.

652
00:59:21,200 --> 00:59:22,800
No.

653
00:59:26,100 --> 00:59:28,999
Can I ask you a question? Mm.

654
00:59:29,000 --> 00:59:31,100
Why are you called Goose?

655
00:59:33,800 --> 00:59:38,699
Well, back when I was a kid,
I ran away from home.

656
00:59:38,700 --> 00:59:42,999
And when they found me,
they said it was cos I was cold.

657
00:59:43,000 --> 00:59:46,599
After that, me dad called me Goose.

658
00:59:46,600 --> 00:59:50,099
Said I tried to fly
off for the winter.

659
00:59:50,100 --> 00:59:51,399
Hmm.

660
00:59:51,400 --> 00:59:53,300
Never did like being cold.

661
00:59:54,900 --> 00:59:57,100
Me neither.

662
00:59:59,600 --> 01:00:01,199
And who is Frank?

663
01:00:01,200 --> 01:00:04,399
He's my uncle.
Well, sort of my uncle.

664
01:00:04,400 --> 01:00:07,200
Your sort of uncle?

665
01:00:09,300 --> 01:00:11,899
Him and me dad,

666
01:00:11,900 --> 01:00:13,599
they were friends,

667
01:00:13,600 --> 01:00:16,499
from school, in London.

668
01:00:16,500 --> 01:00:19,500
And when they grew up,
they both became...

669
01:00:24,600 --> 01:00:27,400
firemen. They both became firemen.

670
01:00:30,500 --> 01:00:33,999
But? Something happened.

671
01:00:34,000 --> 01:00:36,099
Something bad.

672
01:00:36,100 --> 01:00:38,100
Frank don't really like
to talk about it.

673
01:00:42,400 --> 01:00:44,000
Flowers.

674
01:01:04,500 --> 01:01:06,400
Mum and Dad are here.

675
01:01:12,300 --> 01:01:15,100
Once upon a time there was
a man called Thomas Edison.

676
01:01:15,101 --> 01:01:17,299
He was afraid of the dark.

677
01:01:17,300 --> 01:01:21,700
And there was a man called Walt
Disney. He was afraid of mice.

678
01:01:24,000 --> 01:01:27,900
Thomas was afraid of the dark
and he invented the light bulb.

679
01:01:30,400 --> 01:01:35,699
But Walt was afraid of mice
and he invented the most famous
mouse in all the world.

680
01:01:35,700 --> 01:01:37,499
What do you mean?

681
01:01:37,500 --> 01:01:41,999
I mean that sometimes you have
to go towards the things that

682
01:01:42,000 --> 01:01:44,799
make you want to run away.

683
01:01:44,800 --> 01:01:47,200
Dad would have run towards anything.

684
01:01:52,300 --> 01:01:54,000
Come on, then.

685
01:02:35,700 --> 01:02:36,800
It's the same day.

686
01:02:40,300 --> 01:02:42,400
The same day that Mum
and Dad got killed.

687
01:03:15,200 --> 01:03:19,000
We can't just go and ask her for the
bangle. She'll think we're nuts.

688
01:03:20,700 --> 01:03:22,800
Wait here. Why?

689
01:04:28,300 --> 01:04:29,400
Milly?

690
01:04:37,700 --> 01:04:39,600
Milly?

691
01:04:42,100 --> 01:04:45,100
Where are you, naughty little...

692
01:04:51,000 --> 01:04:55,400
Milly?

693
01:05:02,300 --> 01:05:04,899
Please. Please do something.
Help her.

694
01:05:04,900 --> 01:05:07,799
Sir, step off the ice, sir.
We'll take it from here.

695
01:05:07,800 --> 01:05:11,099
Daddy? It's all right, poppet.

696
01:05:11,100 --> 01:05:14,199
It's all right. The nice man's come
to help you, all right?

697
01:05:14,200 --> 01:05:15,799
Sir, please.

698
01:05:15,800 --> 01:05:17,900
Daddy. All right.

699
01:05:19,500 --> 01:05:21,000
Daddy, don't go.

700
01:05:25,200 --> 01:05:28,299
Sweetheart, what's your name?

701
01:05:28,300 --> 01:05:30,399
Milly. Milly?

702
01:05:30,400 --> 01:05:32,500
That's a pretty name.
How old are you?

703
01:05:35,400 --> 01:05:38,799
Six. Six? Gosh, you're a
big girl, aren't you?

704
01:05:38,800 --> 01:05:42,299
I've got a little girl.
She's called Gemma.

705
01:05:42,300 --> 01:05:45,699
Stay there. Look at me.
I'm coming for you.

706
01:05:45,700 --> 01:05:47,300
[ ICE CRACKS ]

707
01:05:50,600 --> 01:05:52,800
Don't worry. Look at me.

708
01:05:55,300 --> 01:05:57,099
Milly, reach out to me.

709
01:05:57,100 --> 01:05:59,799
It's all right.

710
01:05:59,800 --> 01:06:01,199
It's going to be fine.

711
01:06:01,200 --> 01:06:02,899
[ CRACKING INTENSIFIES ]

712
01:06:02,900 --> 01:06:04,600
Reach out to me.

713
01:06:09,600 --> 01:06:11,400
Oh, please. Come on.

714
01:06:27,400 --> 01:06:28,900
Come on. Come on.

715
01:06:36,600 --> 01:06:38,100
Arrrgh!

716
01:06:41,600 --> 01:06:43,100
Milly.

717
01:06:50,200 --> 01:06:52,200
Milly.

718
01:06:53,900 --> 01:06:56,599
What do you...

719
01:06:56,600 --> 01:06:58,099
Is this some sort of sick joke?

720
01:06:58,100 --> 01:06:59,300
The bangle.

721
01:07:01,100 --> 01:07:02,899
It wasn't Noel's to sell.

722
01:07:02,900 --> 01:07:05,800
Bangle? How do you know?

723
01:07:07,400 --> 01:07:10,199
Who are you people?
Have you been following me?

724
01:07:10,200 --> 01:07:12,199
Yeah.

725
01:07:12,200 --> 01:07:13,599
Why?

726
01:07:13,600 --> 01:07:16,499
Why have you been following me?
What do you want?

727
01:07:16,500 --> 01:07:18,900
It was my dad.

728
01:07:21,000 --> 01:07:24,199
My dad who should have
come to save Milly.

729
01:07:24,200 --> 01:07:26,200
He could have saved her.

730
01:07:28,200 --> 01:07:30,799
He could have saved anyone.

731
01:07:30,800 --> 01:07:33,599
What the hell do you think...

732
01:07:33,600 --> 01:07:37,499
I knew it was you as soon
as I saw the grave.

733
01:07:37,500 --> 01:07:39,300
I knew it was you because...

734
01:07:41,300 --> 01:07:44,999
he's bringing
everything back together.

735
01:07:45,000 --> 01:07:48,599
Bringing everything together
so we can make it right.

736
01:07:48,600 --> 01:07:52,500
He is. I hid my dad's car keys.

737
01:07:54,300 --> 01:07:59,099
And if I didn't, he would
have gone some other way.

738
01:07:59,100 --> 01:08:02,299
Or something else would've happened.

739
01:08:02,300 --> 01:08:04,100
But him and Mum wouldn't have died.

740
01:08:05,800 --> 01:08:08,299
I didn't mean for them to die.

741
01:08:08,300 --> 01:08:09,999
Don't worry.

742
01:08:10,000 --> 01:08:12,799
It wasn't your fault, sweetheart.

743
01:08:12,800 --> 01:08:14,399
It was.

744
01:08:14,400 --> 01:08:17,200
Accidents happen. They do.
I forgot to lock the gate.

745
01:08:19,100 --> 01:08:23,100
I was usually so careful but
I forgot to lock the gate.

746
01:08:29,000 --> 01:08:30,100
The bangle.

747
01:08:32,500 --> 01:08:34,699
I stole it.

748
01:08:34,700 --> 01:08:37,400
And I need to give it back
so I can get my dog back.

749
01:08:39,100 --> 01:08:40,699
Please. Can I have it?

750
01:08:40,700 --> 01:08:44,000
I've got money.
She doesn't want your money.

751
01:08:46,100 --> 01:08:48,400
She got it for Milly.

752
01:08:55,100 --> 01:08:59,199
She kept begging me that she wanted
a bangle for Christmas.

753
01:08:59,200 --> 01:09:00,799
Her friend had one and...

754
01:09:00,800 --> 01:09:03,699
And when I saw it in the window,
I just went in and bought it.

755
01:09:03,700 --> 01:09:04,900
I knew she'd love it.

756
01:09:09,100 --> 01:09:10,700
How stupid is that?

757
01:09:16,100 --> 01:09:18,899
It would be nice to believe that,

758
01:09:18,900 --> 01:09:23,400
though, that there was someone
who could make things right again.

759
01:09:27,600 --> 01:09:30,600
But I hadn't really imagined
that he'd look quite like you.

760
01:09:32,300 --> 01:09:35,300
I know I'm a crazy, mad woman.

761
01:09:37,700 --> 01:09:38,900
Here.

762
01:09:41,100 --> 01:09:43,299
Here.

763
01:09:43,300 --> 01:09:45,699
I will give it to her.

764
01:09:45,700 --> 01:09:47,299
I promise.

765
01:09:47,300 --> 01:09:49,599
It's good that there's
someone who thinks

766
01:09:49,600 --> 01:09:52,499
there could be a little
magic around at Christmas.

767
01:09:52,500 --> 01:09:54,200
Stop!

768
01:09:56,100 --> 01:09:59,699
Helen, I don't know what sort of
sob story this little delinquent's

769
01:09:59,700 --> 01:10:02,099
been telling you but I
guarantee you 100 percent,

770
01:10:02,100 --> 01:10:04,199
whatever it is, it isn't true.

771
01:10:04,200 --> 01:10:07,999
Mr Penvell? Henry? Do you know...

772
01:10:08,000 --> 01:10:09,499
How do you know Mr Penvell?

773
01:10:09,500 --> 01:10:13,399
This... This is who I was
supposed to be seeing this morning.

774
01:10:13,400 --> 01:10:16,499
But, surprise, surprise,
he didn't show up.

775
01:10:16,500 --> 01:10:19,599
I lost Mutt.
I had to get him back.

776
01:10:19,600 --> 01:10:21,400
Is that the best you can do?

777
01:10:24,000 --> 01:10:25,999
What's that? Give it to me.

778
01:10:26,000 --> 01:10:28,699
Henry, don't talk to
me like a child.

779
01:10:28,700 --> 01:10:31,099
Now, maybe you do know...

780
01:10:31,100 --> 01:10:34,899
Goose. I'm sure
you do know Goose,

781
01:10:34,900 --> 01:10:38,799
but have you ever actually
listened to what he has to say?

782
01:10:38,800 --> 01:10:43,399
Helen. Helen. I speak with
him on a weekly basis.

783
01:10:43,400 --> 01:10:49,699
That's not what I asked. I'm sure
you do speak with him but have you
ever actually LISTENED to him?

784
01:10:49,700 --> 01:10:54,899
I'm not going to have this
conversation in front
of an offender, OK?

785
01:10:54,900 --> 01:10:57,600
Now give me that. Hmm?

786
01:11:01,700 --> 01:11:05,399
You're coming with me,
you little oik! Henry!
Henry, he's just a child!

787
01:11:05,400 --> 01:11:08,999
A child whose parents died.
Helen, really?

788
01:11:09,000 --> 01:11:13,299
Really? I deal with these people
all the time. "These people"?

789
01:11:13,300 --> 01:11:17,399
Oh, my... Have you always been
like this? So full of bile?

790
01:11:17,400 --> 01:11:19,899
Or is this just since...
Don't!

791
01:11:19,900 --> 01:11:22,099
Don't what?

792
01:11:22,100 --> 01:11:24,399
Don't mention our daughter?

793
01:11:24,400 --> 01:11:26,100
Don't mention Milly?

794
01:11:29,800 --> 01:11:31,600
Milly.

795
01:11:35,400 --> 01:11:37,100
I haven't got time for this.

796
01:11:38,600 --> 01:11:39,600
Argh!

797
01:12:11,100 --> 01:12:14,999
I've never known it
snow here at Christmas.

798
01:12:15,000 --> 01:12:16,600
I have.

799
01:12:18,300 --> 01:12:19,800
You have?

800
01:12:21,200 --> 01:12:22,500
Yes.

801
01:12:24,300 --> 01:12:26,900
And I think I know
where all this ends.

802
01:12:28,200 --> 01:12:29,799
Where it all ends?

803
01:12:29,800 --> 01:12:30,900
Yeah.

804
01:12:39,900 --> 01:12:41,699
Charles?

805
01:12:41,700 --> 01:12:45,399
Is that Charles? Are you coming?
Hi, it's Henry Penvell.

806
01:12:45,400 --> 01:12:50,399
Yes, I'm sorry to call you. Er, I
appreciate that it's Christmas Eve.

807
01:12:50,400 --> 01:12:54,699
Listen, I've had my,
uh, young offender...

808
01:12:54,700 --> 01:12:57,899
Yes. Please, I'd like that.

809
01:12:57,900 --> 01:13:00,000
I'd like that very much.

810
01:13:21,700 --> 01:13:23,100
Nan! Is Mutt home?

811
01:13:27,700 --> 01:13:31,799
Richard, your probation officer
called. Can we have a word?

812
01:13:31,800 --> 01:13:33,400
Come on. Hey!

813
01:13:37,700 --> 01:13:40,699
All right, Richard,
where were you this morning?

814
01:13:40,700 --> 01:13:42,099
Why do you need to know?

815
01:13:42,100 --> 01:13:43,499
Empty your pockets.

816
01:13:43,500 --> 01:13:45,899
He's a good boy, really.

817
01:13:45,900 --> 01:13:47,999
Don't worry, Mrs Thornhill.

818
01:13:48,000 --> 01:13:50,599
We all want what's best for Richard.

819
01:13:50,600 --> 01:13:53,099
Goose. He's called Goose.

820
01:13:53,100 --> 01:13:54,500
For Goose.

821
01:13:56,200 --> 01:13:58,799
Yes.

822
01:13:58,800 --> 01:14:02,299
The kettle's just boiled.
Will I make us a cup of tea?

823
01:14:02,300 --> 01:14:04,300
Oh, that'd be nice.

824
01:14:07,300 --> 01:14:11,599
There's a lady from social
services coming in a bit.

825
01:14:11,600 --> 01:14:16,299
With a doctor. Is someone sick?

826
01:14:16,300 --> 01:14:19,899
The doctor just needs a little
chat with you, that's all.

827
01:14:19,900 --> 01:14:22,299
With me?

828
01:14:22,300 --> 01:14:24,199
I need you to empty your pockets.

829
01:14:24,200 --> 01:14:26,499
I hate doctors.

830
01:14:26,500 --> 01:14:28,999
Empty them, before
I do it for you!

831
01:14:29,000 --> 01:14:30,700
Will you excuse me a moment?

832
01:14:32,500 --> 01:14:34,499
You all right?

833
01:14:34,500 --> 01:14:36,999
Yeah, it's fine. Come on, lad.

834
01:14:37,000 --> 01:14:38,200
Empty your pockets.

835
01:14:41,600 --> 01:14:44,199
That's a lot of money. Oi!

836
01:14:44,200 --> 01:14:46,599
And where did you get this from?
A friend gave it me.

837
01:14:46,600 --> 01:14:49,699
Carry on. That's it.

838
01:14:49,700 --> 01:14:51,799
It is.

839
01:14:51,800 --> 01:14:53,700
Oh!

840
01:15:03,300 --> 01:15:05,600
Right, I'll do it myself.

841
01:15:07,500 --> 01:15:09,200
All right! All right.

842
01:15:19,700 --> 01:15:20,900
Oi!

843
01:15:22,700 --> 01:15:27,200
Oh, and a friend give you this,
too, as well? It's... It's to get...

844
01:15:29,100 --> 01:15:31,400
You wouldn't understand. Try us.

845
01:15:36,300 --> 01:15:40,600
OK. Yeah, I did steal it.

846
01:15:43,400 --> 01:15:44,800
But I want to give it back.

847
01:15:46,900 --> 01:15:49,299
Ten out of ten for originality.

848
01:15:49,300 --> 01:15:51,499
You should try that
on the magistrate.

849
01:15:51,500 --> 01:15:52,800
Excuse me.

850
01:15:54,700 --> 01:15:56,799
Anyone for Battenberg?
Er, not right now.

851
01:15:56,800 --> 01:15:58,000
Come here.

852
01:16:11,600 --> 01:16:12,800
You all right, mate?

853
01:16:19,500 --> 01:16:22,000
Hi, Officer, do you
want a mince pie?

854
01:16:32,300 --> 01:16:34,500
[ BANGLE RATTLES ]

855
01:16:36,000 --> 01:16:37,499
There!

856
01:16:37,500 --> 01:16:39,300
Come here!

857
01:16:41,700 --> 01:16:43,100
Get him!

858
01:16:44,800 --> 01:16:46,200
Oi!

859
01:16:57,100 --> 01:16:58,800
Richard, come on!

860
01:17:02,100 --> 01:17:03,400
Argh!

861
01:17:06,400 --> 01:17:08,500
Ho ho ho!

862
01:17:25,500 --> 01:17:28,099
This one.

863
01:17:28,100 --> 01:17:30,099
Are you sure?

864
01:17:30,100 --> 01:17:31,500
Yeah.

865
01:17:34,300 --> 01:17:37,500
Deja... something.

866
01:17:43,200 --> 01:17:45,500
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]

867
01:17:50,600 --> 01:17:51,900
You?

868
01:17:53,700 --> 01:17:55,300
You got it?

869
01:17:57,400 --> 01:17:59,900
The boy who stole it
is bringing it back.

870
01:18:04,200 --> 01:18:06,799
You were right, though.

871
01:18:06,800 --> 01:18:10,499
I've remembered. I didn't drop it.

872
01:18:10,500 --> 01:18:12,400
I left it on my chair.

873
01:18:14,600 --> 01:18:16,400
Come. Come in.

874
01:18:34,300 --> 01:18:35,500
There are lights.

875
01:18:38,000 --> 01:18:39,400
How did you know?

876
01:19:00,800 --> 01:19:04,700
I put them in for Diwali. They
look so good, I kept them
in for Christmas.

877
01:19:12,800 --> 01:19:14,800
This is where it ends.

878
01:19:49,000 --> 01:19:50,899
I'm sorry.

879
01:19:50,900 --> 01:19:52,200
I really am.

880
01:19:54,300 --> 01:19:57,500
I can see you are. Thank you.

881
01:20:01,800 --> 01:20:03,700
Shiva, the cobra.

882
01:20:06,200 --> 01:20:09,700
People think he's the god of
destruction, but he isn't.

883
01:20:11,300 --> 01:20:16,499
Shiva just knows that sometimes
you have to destroy...

884
01:20:16,500 --> 01:20:19,199
to begin again.

885
01:20:19,200 --> 01:20:21,700
To make the world a better place.

886
01:20:23,600 --> 01:20:26,499
But, but I don't want to begin again.

887
01:20:26,500 --> 01:20:29,399
Not without my mum and dad.

888
01:20:29,400 --> 01:20:32,399
And the world's not a
better place with me in it.

889
01:20:32,400 --> 01:20:36,699
It's worse. Because if it
wasn't for me, they...

890
01:20:36,700 --> 01:20:38,800
they... would still be alive.

891
01:20:40,400 --> 01:20:46,099
Now give me back my dog. I gave it
back. Now tell me where Mutt is.

892
01:20:46,100 --> 01:20:47,699
That's what you said. Is it?

893
01:20:47,700 --> 01:20:50,399
You're just saying that
because you can't.

894
01:20:50,400 --> 01:20:53,899
Cos there is no magic. Cos you're
a nutter. And I'm going into care.

895
01:20:53,900 --> 01:20:55,799
You're right.

896
01:20:55,800 --> 01:20:58,599
Dogs run away and get knocked over.

897
01:20:58,600 --> 01:21:00,399
You're right.

898
01:21:00,400 --> 01:21:02,100
Mums and dads die.

899
01:21:04,200 --> 01:21:05,399
Children die.

900
01:21:05,400 --> 01:21:07,499
And then...

901
01:21:07,500 --> 01:21:13,499
then it's just us and we're all
alone and the lost things stay lost.

902
01:21:13,500 --> 01:21:17,099
But, maybe, if you do the right
thing, someone, somewhere

903
01:21:17,100 --> 01:21:18,800
gives you a second chance.

904
01:21:20,800 --> 01:21:22,899
Give me your hand.
It's just a trick.

905
01:21:22,900 --> 01:21:24,599
Give me your hand.

906
01:21:24,600 --> 01:21:26,299
A stupid trick.

907
01:21:26,300 --> 01:21:27,999
I saw you. You can do tricks.

908
01:21:28,000 --> 01:21:30,399
Goose.

909
01:21:30,400 --> 01:21:32,899
Trust me.

910
01:21:32,900 --> 01:21:34,600
Trust yourself.

911
01:21:47,400 --> 01:21:49,300
You see, I've remembered my name.

912
01:21:58,300 --> 01:22:02,699
I... I don't understand.

913
01:22:02,700 --> 01:22:03,900
You will.

914
01:22:07,300 --> 01:22:09,000
[ GOOSE GASPS ]

915
01:22:43,100 --> 01:22:44,500
Many years from now...

916
01:22:46,500 --> 01:22:49,500
in the shadows far below
the city...

917
01:22:52,300 --> 01:22:55,599
amongst the forgotten
and the lost,

918
01:22:55,600 --> 01:22:57,300
lived a man.

919
01:23:06,900 --> 01:23:09,999
He was a conjurer and a clown.

920
01:23:10,000 --> 01:23:11,699
[ CAR HORN ]

921
01:23:11,700 --> 01:23:13,999
Cars honk in the key of F.
You know that?

922
01:23:14,000 --> 01:23:16,300
[ PEOPLE CHUCKLE ]

923
01:23:18,500 --> 01:23:21,400
A thief and a villain.
[ SIRENS WAIL ]

924
01:23:32,000 --> 01:23:35,599
But when the people of the town
stopped to watch his show,

925
01:23:35,600 --> 01:23:38,699
he never let them
see beneath the mask,

926
01:23:38,700 --> 01:23:42,699
that life had taken from him,

927
01:23:42,700 --> 01:23:45,299
bit by bit,

928
01:23:45,300 --> 01:23:47,899
piece by piece,

929
01:23:47,900 --> 01:23:49,300
everything.

930
01:23:56,600 --> 01:23:58,100
Your first night out?

931
01:24:01,700 --> 01:24:04,399
Lost me job today.

932
01:24:04,400 --> 01:24:07,299
Mam threw me out.

933
01:24:07,300 --> 01:24:08,900
Said I was a waste of space.

934
01:24:11,100 --> 01:24:13,000
Just like my dad.

935
01:24:19,100 --> 01:24:22,500
And, some nights, he'd sit
and think back to where
he'd come from.

936
01:24:24,400 --> 01:24:27,500
Before every room had four
grey walls and bars.

937
01:24:29,700 --> 01:24:32,499
When he had a different life.

938
01:24:32,500 --> 01:24:35,199
When he had a different name.

939
01:24:35,200 --> 01:24:38,500
The name his father gave
him when he was a child.

940
01:24:40,100 --> 01:24:44,799
The name his father gave him
because he didn't like the cold.

941
01:24:44,800 --> 01:24:47,799
His real name.

942
01:24:47,800 --> 01:24:50,099
Goose.

943
01:24:50,100 --> 01:24:52,799
Goosey goosey gander.

944
01:24:52,800 --> 01:24:55,599
Goose.

945
01:24:55,600 --> 01:24:57,399
Goosey goosey gander.

946
01:24:57,400 --> 01:25:04,200
Goose. Goosey goosey gander.

947
01:25:05,900 --> 01:25:08,300
Goose. Goosey goosey gander.

948
01:25:20,500 --> 01:25:22,200
Give me your jacket.

949
01:25:31,000 --> 01:25:32,400
Are you sure?

950
01:26:01,400 --> 01:26:03,000
Anthony.

951
01:26:05,900 --> 01:26:07,000
Richie.

952
01:26:10,000 --> 01:26:11,000
Richard.

953
01:26:13,200 --> 01:26:18,899
And, really, this man's story
should've ended one freezing night,

954
01:26:18,900 --> 01:26:20,500
as the snow began to fall.

955
01:26:22,500 --> 01:26:26,299
Except this man, this conjurer,

956
01:26:26,300 --> 01:26:29,300
performed one last trick.

957
01:26:31,400 --> 01:26:34,899
He stole himself a second chance,

958
01:26:34,900 --> 01:26:37,300
with a simple act of human kindness.

959
01:26:59,400 --> 01:27:01,899
Hey!

960
01:27:01,900 --> 01:27:03,400
Mate.

961
01:27:12,000 --> 01:27:13,000
Richard!

962
01:27:17,700 --> 01:27:18,900
I know who I am.

963
01:27:22,000 --> 01:27:23,100
I'm Goose.

964
01:27:25,300 --> 01:27:27,400
[ DOG BARKS ]

965
01:27:36,000 --> 01:27:38,900
Am I dreaming? Maybe.

966
01:27:40,500 --> 01:27:43,199
You're not here.

967
01:27:43,200 --> 01:27:44,999
Are you?

968
01:27:45,000 --> 01:27:46,700
[ DOG BARKS ]

969
01:27:48,400 --> 01:27:50,899
We were going to hide him
till tomorrow but...

970
01:27:50,900 --> 01:27:54,799
he didn't want to go along
with the plan, did you?

971
01:27:54,800 --> 01:27:57,499
Happy Christmas, sweetheart.

972
01:27:57,500 --> 01:28:01,100
Mutt. Huh! What, you've got
a name for him already? Yeah.

973
01:28:02,800 --> 01:28:06,500
Mutt. He... He's called Mutt.

974
01:28:08,800 --> 01:28:10,500
Well, hey there, Mutt!

975
01:28:12,700 --> 01:28:14,100
Shall we take him out?

976
01:28:17,100 --> 01:28:18,299
Yeah.

977
01:28:18,300 --> 01:28:20,500
Come on, then.

978
01:28:22,300 --> 01:28:24,200
Get some clothes on.

979
01:28:29,700 --> 01:28:31,900
[ PHONE RINGS ]

980
01:28:39,300 --> 01:28:41,200
Paul?

981
01:28:46,500 --> 01:28:48,600
Honey, have you seen my keys?
No, sorry.

982
01:28:50,300 --> 01:28:53,400
Well, I can't find them anywhere.

983
01:28:55,900 --> 01:28:57,200
Where are they?

984
01:29:02,600 --> 01:29:04,300
Goose, mate, have you seen...

985
01:29:07,000 --> 01:29:09,300
See you later, Dad. See you later.

986
01:29:34,300 --> 01:29:36,999
? Simply?

987
01:29:37,000 --> 01:29:39,100
? Having?

988
01:29:42,500 --> 01:29:46,200
? A wonderful Christmas time...?

989
01:29:49,500 --> 01:29:51,100
Water rescue team required.

990
01:29:53,600 --> 01:29:55,699
Daddy?

991
01:29:55,700 --> 01:29:58,199
It's all right, poppet.
Help her!

992
01:29:58,200 --> 01:30:02,399
Sir! Sir, you can step off the ice
now. I'll take over from here, sir.

993
01:30:02,400 --> 01:30:04,599
It's all right, poppet.

994
01:30:04,600 --> 01:30:08,599
The nice man's come to help you,
all right? Sir, please. All right.

995
01:30:08,600 --> 01:30:10,500
[ ICE CRACKS ]
Thank you, sir.

996
01:30:15,100 --> 01:30:18,100
? A wonderful Christmas time...?

997
01:30:21,400 --> 01:30:23,299
Stay still.

998
01:30:23,300 --> 01:30:25,000
[ ICE CRACKS ]

999
01:30:30,900 --> 01:30:31,900
Stay still.

1000
01:30:38,600 --> 01:30:39,900
Mate!

1001
01:30:43,400 --> 01:30:44,900
Milly?

1002
01:30:55,400 --> 01:30:57,000
Oh! Thank you!

1003
01:31:05,000 --> 01:31:07,200
Oh! Thank you. Thank you so much.

1004
01:31:22,000 --> 01:31:23,200
♫  The party's on

1005
01:31:25,100 --> 01:31:26,100
♫ The spirits up

1006
01:31:28,600 --> 01:31:30,000
♫  We're here tonight

1007
01:31:32,400 --> 01:31:33,900
♫  And that's enough

1008
01:31:35,100 --> 01:31:38,600
♫  Simply having

1009
01:31:41,200 --> 01:31:44,900
♫  A wonderful Christmas time

1010
01:31:49,000 --> 01:31:50,500
♫  The moon is right

1011
01:31:52,300 --> 01:31:54,200
♫  The spirits up

1012
01:31:56,400 --> 01:31:57,800
♫  We're here tonight

1013
01:32:00,300 --> 01:32:02,999
♫  And that's enough

1014
01:32:03,000 --> 01:32:06,800
♫  Simply having

1015
01:32:09,300 --> 01:32:13,300
♫  A wonderful Christmas time

1016
01:32:17,100 --> 01:32:24,399
♫  The choir of children sing
their song

1017
01:32:24,400 --> 01:32:30,600
♫  Ding dong, ding dong
ding dong, ding

1018
01:32:42,400 --> 01:32:46,300
♫  Simply having

1019
01:32:49,500 --> 01:32:53,900
♫  A wonderful Christmas time

1020
01:32:57,000 --> 01:32:58,100
♫  The word is out

1021
01:33:01,200 --> 01:33:02,800
♫  About the town

1022
01:33:05,000 --> 01:33:06,800
♫ To lift a glass

1023
01:33:11,700 --> 01:33:13,400
♫  And that's enough.

1024
01:33:15,600 --> 01:33:17,600
Merry Christmas.

