1
00:00:47,180 --> 00:00:50,616
A LOVE TO HIDE

2
00:0:57,227 --> 00:00:57,854
Good as new, M me de Marny.

3
00:01:00,496 --> 00:01:02,827
Léopoldine.

4
00:01:05,065 --> 00:01:06,726
Take this to madame's car.

5
00:01:07,000 --> 00:01:08,331
Yes, Monsieur Jean.

6
00:01:10,770 --> 00:01:13,534
Charming girl.
How's your brother?

7
00:01:13,773 --> 00:01:16,503
Jacques is still in the sanatorium.

8
00:01:17,911 --> 00:01:19,173
But he seems better.

9
00:01:19,412 --> 00:01:20,902
He'll be home for Christmas.

10
00:01:21,014 --> 00:01:24,848
Tuberculosis so young ! Poor child.

11
00:01:30,056 --> 00:01:32,581
I'll park the van and be up.

12
00:01:39,799 --> 00:01:42,768
- For your brother. Don't forget.
- I won't.

13
00:01:43,203 --> 00:01:45,034
Stop worrying, Mom.

14
00:01:46,039 --> 00:01:47,199
A last delivery

15
00:01:47,440 --> 00:01:48,839
and I'll be home for dinner.

16
00:01:49,075 --> 00:01:51,202
If your father sees it. . .
Don't forget.

17
00:01:53,780 --> 00:01:54,838
U p you go.

18
00:01:55,081 --> 00:01:56,378
I'll lock up.

19
00:02:16,402 --> 00:02:17,426
Sara?

20
00:02:20,240 --> 00:02:21,764
What are you doing here?

21
00:02:22,976 --> 00:02:24,568
What happened?

22
00:02:30,450 --> 00:02:32,111
They killed them all.

23
00:02:42,929 --> 00:02:44,055
Look at me.

24
00:02:46,032 --> 00:02:49,900
You look better now.
You're not cold?

25
00:02:54,007 --> 00:02:55,497
You're safe here.

26
00:02:57,443 --> 00:02:58,808
What happened?

27
00:03:02,315 --> 00:03:04,510
I got here last week.

28
00:03:05,718 --> 00:03:07,686
With my parents and sister.

29
00:03:08,955 --> 00:03:11,753
We've been housebound for 2 years.

30
00:03:13,493 --> 00:03:15,290
Father lost everything.

31
00:03:17,463 --> 00:03:20,626
The bastards took the lot:
Factory, house. . .

32
00:03:23,570 --> 00:03:27,631
Last month,
he said he'd found a smuggler.

33
00:03:29,042 --> 00:03:31,169
One of his old foremen.

34
00:03:33,980 --> 00:03:37,347
He gave him all he had left
and we came to Paris.

35
00:03:39,652 --> 00:03:43,144
<i>Tonight we should have gone</i>
<i>to Normandy then England.</i>

36
00:03:43,823 --> 00:03:46,621
<i>Why did he do it, Jean?</i>

37
00:03:46,859 --> 00:03:49,487
<i>Hadn't we given him enough?</i>

38
00:03:50,330 --> 00:03:53,663
<i>I knew something was wrong</i>
<i>when I heard footsteps.</i>

39
00:03:53,900 --> 00:03:56,698
<i>The smuggler usually came alone.</i>

40
00:03:57,937 --> 00:04:02,306
<i>There were 5 or 6 of them.</i>
<i>They killed everyone.</i>

41
00:04:02,842 --> 00:04:06,539
<i>My parents, my sister, everyone.</i>

42
00:04:08,681 --> 00:04:11,343
<i>Yours was the only address I had.</i>

43
00:04:12,885 --> 00:04:14,853
Come on, don't be afraid.

44
00:04:16,055 --> 00:04:18,888
This is a friend's house.
You'll be safe.

45
00:04:19,125 --> 00:04:20,683
He's a great chap.

46
00:04:21,361 --> 00:04:22,692
H is name's Philippe.

47
00:04:35,875 --> 00:04:38,002
Tomorrow, 6 o'clock, same place.

48
00:04:44,083 --> 00:04:45,380
Didn't you hear me?

49
00:04:45,618 --> 00:04:48,212
- What were you doing?
- Sleeping.

50
00:04:50,123 --> 00:04:50,851
This is Sara.

51
00:04:54,827 --> 00:04:57,261
Do we come in or stay out here?

52
00:05:02,669 --> 00:05:04,068
This is so risky!

53
00:05:04,304 --> 00:05:06,135
Did the concierge see you?

54
00:05:06,406 --> 00:05:09,204
- You can't trust anyone.
- And me?

55
00:05:09,442 --> 00:05:10,932
Leave it out!

56
00:05:16,449 --> 00:05:17,609
Look. . .

57
00:05:18,785 --> 00:05:20,650
Sara's a childhood friend.

58
00:05:20,987 --> 00:05:23,080
She's a Jew.
Her family's been killed.

59
00:05:23,323 --> 00:05:25,223
What could I do?

60
00:05:25,458 --> 00:05:28,723
I do German High Command's laundry
every day.

61
00:05:29,862 --> 00:05:31,420
Think I'm proud of it?

62
00:05:31,698 --> 00:05:34,997
- Now I can do something useful.
- Not just like that!

63
00:05:35,268 --> 00:05:37,828
And you know how to hide Jews?

64
00:05:38,438 --> 00:05:42,135
All you do is go back and forth
to the print shop.

65
00:05:42,775 --> 00:05:45,403
If you won't help Sara, I will.

66
00:06:01,861 --> 00:06:03,158
Stay here tonight.

67
00:06:04,864 --> 00:06:05,831
Where is it?

68
00:06:22,548 --> 00:06:26,507
I can't stay.
I'm expected home for dinner.

69
00:06:27,120 --> 00:06:29,111
Philippe will look after you.

70
00:06:29,589 --> 00:06:31,648
Eat something, then sleep.

71
00:06:32,492 --> 00:06:33,686
Promise?

72
00:06:35,995 --> 00:06:37,394
I'll be back tomorrow.

73
00:07:01,687 --> 00:07:03,382
You seem to know Jean well.

74
00:07:03,790 --> 00:07:07,487
We met on holiday in La Baule,
when we were kids.

75
00:07:08,728 --> 00:07:10,559
We met there every year.

76
00:07:13,032 --> 00:07:15,262
He was the first boy to kiss me.

77
00:07:16,469 --> 00:07:17,936
Did you love him?

78
00:07:20,473 --> 00:07:22,236
I think I still do.

79
00:07:27,146 --> 00:07:28,340
<i>Dear Jean. . .

80
00:07:28,581 --> 00:07:32,278
<i>It seems an eternity</i>
<i>to our next holiday.</i>

81
00:07:32,552 --> 00:07:34,782
<i>Dad says I'm unbearable.</i>

82
00:07:35,154 --> 00:07:36,746
<i>Know what I do every day?</i>

83
00:07:36,989 --> 00:07:42,427
<i>I cross the day off on the calendar</i>
<i>and think of the next one.</i>

84
00:07:42,662 --> 00:07:45,688
<i>Mom says it's because</i>
<i>I'm becoming a woman.</i>

85
00:07:46,098 --> 00:07:48,692
<i>Every night I dream I'm yours.</i>

86
00:07:55,508 --> 00:07:57,703
I'm off. See you later.

87
00:08:01,180 --> 00:08:03,114
Morning, M me Lavandier.

88
00:08:06,319 --> 00:08:10,722
I n a sanatorium with T B. . .
Dad can't stop telling lies!

89
00:08:10,957 --> 00:08:13,323
He'll end up believing them !

90
00:08:14,193 --> 00:08:16,753
- Biscuits, soap. . . Is that it?
- All right!

91
00:08:16,996 --> 00:08:18,293
Mom did her best.

92
00:08:19,599 --> 00:08:21,066
I need to get out!

93
00:08:21,634 --> 00:08:24,228
- Pass on the word. . .
- Only 2 more months.

94
00:08:24,470 --> 00:08:26,404
Everyone's taking bribes!

95
00:08:26,639 --> 00:08:28,607
Dad can cough up to get me out.

96
00:08:28,841 --> 00:08:31,776
- He says you've to pay your dues.
- I haven't killed anyone!

97
00:08:32,011 --> 00:08:34,138
Hey, calm down, Lavandier.

98
00:08:35,448 --> 00:08:37,473
I was trafficking.
Like everyone.

99
00:08:40,119 --> 00:08:41,416
Anyway. . .

100
00:08:41,654 --> 00:08:43,246
Still kickboxing?

101
00:08:43,489 --> 00:08:44,922
It's no good without you.

102
00:08:45,691 --> 00:08:47,488
Any cute girls at the shop?

103
00:08:48,294 --> 00:08:49,192
Not my type.

104
00:08:49,462 --> 00:08:50,793
Bet they're mine!

105
00:08:51,030 --> 00:08:53,362
Don't mind upsetting Dad
for the girls!

106
00:09:02,341 --> 00:09:03,535
Stop.

107
00:09:04,877 --> 00:09:07,209
- Sara's asleep.
- I don't care!

108
00:09:57,630 --> 00:09:59,928
Can you stay here alone today?

109
00:10:00,800 --> 00:10:03,826
We'll buy butter and eggs
to give you strength.

110
00:10:04,070 --> 00:10:05,435
What for?

111
00:10:13,980 --> 00:10:15,504
You've not eaten for 3 days.

112
00:10:17,383 --> 00:10:19,010
I won't let you die.

113
00:10:19,619 --> 00:10:22,019
- And if I want to leave?
- I refuse.

114
00:10:23,656 --> 00:10:24,850
I'm all alone.

115
00:10:25,458 --> 00:10:28,916
You have me. I'm here for you.

116
00:10:29,595 --> 00:10:31,222
Do it for me, Sara.

117
00:10:32,131 --> 00:10:33,428
Because I love you.

118
00:10:34,567 --> 00:10:35,795
Do you swear?

119
00:10:36,769 --> 00:10:38,236
I swear.

120
00:10:39,405 --> 00:10:40,394
Coming, Jean?

121
00:10:40,640 --> 00:10:41,607
Coming.

122
00:10:55,421 --> 00:10:57,446
- Blast!
- What's up?

123
00:10:57,823 --> 00:10:59,154
A puncture.

124
00:11:02,128 --> 00:11:04,119
But the eggs aren't broken.

125
00:11:04,363 --> 00:11:06,763
Let's walk. I've no repair kit.

126
00:11:13,039 --> 00:11:14,063
Come on.

127
00:11:58,350 --> 00:12:01,683
Why did you tell Sara you love her?

128
00:12:04,090 --> 00:12:05,489
Because I do.

129
00:12:07,359 --> 00:12:09,190
Not the way I love you.

130
00:12:11,497 --> 00:12:14,398
But I've never felt this
for a woman.

131
00:12:17,103 --> 00:12:18,070
She needs us.

132
00:12:18,704 --> 00:12:20,035
I need you, too.

133
00:12:20,272 --> 00:12:21,739
She won't get by without us.

134
00:12:22,775 --> 00:12:24,902
Promise you won't let her down.

135
00:12:26,112 --> 00:12:27,306
Promise?

136
00:12:29,782 --> 00:12:30,976
I promise.

137
00:13:52,698 --> 00:13:54,325
Will you kill them too?

138
00:13:55,167 --> 00:13:56,429
- Why?
- Look. . .

139
00:13:56,669 --> 00:13:58,603
- Let me explain. . .

140
00:13:59,171 --> 00:14:01,639
He sold out on us. Run !

141
00:14:05,110 --> 00:14:06,634
I've nothing against Jews.

142
00:14:06,879 --> 00:14:08,176
I help them.

143
00:14:08,447 --> 00:14:11,075
And I wanted to help your father.

144
00:14:11,951 --> 00:14:13,748
I used to work for him. . .

145
00:14:13,986 --> 00:14:15,851
Shut up!

146
00:14:16,889 --> 00:14:18,015
I can't. . .

147
00:14:18,991 --> 00:14:22,859
You're a monster
but I can't do it!

148
00:14:23,128 --> 00:14:26,120
You're filth.
Like the rest of your race!

149
00:14:26,799 --> 00:14:29,165
Look! You haven't got the guts.

150
00:14:32,805 --> 00:14:33,965
You bitch !

151
00:14:38,978 --> 00:14:40,639
Where the hell is she?

152
00:14:41,513 --> 00:14:43,538
The curfew's about to start.

153
00:14:46,185 --> 00:14:49,279
I n her situation
you don't go out without papers!

154
00:14:52,191 --> 00:14:55,558
- Where were you?
- You put us all at risk!

155
00:14:57,062 --> 00:15:00,156
Why couldn't I kill him?

156
00:15:00,599 --> 00:15:03,534
What happened, Sara?

157
00:15:03,769 --> 00:15:05,134
What happened?

158
00:15:05,371 --> 00:15:06,998
I couldn't kill the smuggler.

159
00:15:08,040 --> 00:15:09,871
Not even to avenge them.

160
00:15:10,109 --> 00:15:11,701
Why am I such a coward?

161
00:15:13,245 --> 00:15:16,578
You're not a coward.
Now hush. . .

162
00:15:17,616 --> 00:15:19,550
Everything'll be all right.

163
00:15:19,852 --> 00:15:21,251
It'll be all right.

164
00:15:25,057 --> 00:15:26,922
Rise and shine, flower!

165
00:15:29,561 --> 00:15:31,586
I want you to eat today.

166
00:15:31,864 --> 00:15:33,855
Philippe's out getting bread.

167
00:15:37,736 --> 00:15:41,502
There's some butter left.
So you'll eat, okay!

168
00:15:42,608 --> 00:15:44,405
Here's breakfast!

169
00:15:50,716 --> 00:15:52,047
Present for you !

170
00:15:52,284 --> 00:15:54,047
- For me?
- Yes, for you.

171
00:15:55,220 --> 00:15:58,712
A new I D card.
It's on official paper.

172
00:15:59,091 --> 00:16:00,854
You were born in Alsace.

173
00:16:01,093 --> 00:16:03,960
The civil list burnt
with the town hall in 1940.

174
00:16:04,964 --> 00:16:09,526
You're now Yvonne Brunner.
Your new life starts today.

175
00:16:10,002 --> 00:16:11,867
Where did you get it?

176
00:16:12,304 --> 00:16:13,931
The less you know the better.

177
00:16:14,173 --> 00:16:17,142
P RO F E S S I O N : LAU N D RE S S

178
00:16:35,627 --> 00:16:36,753
Hello, Yvonne.

179
00:16:37,096 --> 00:16:40,998
No point wrapping M me Cohen’s,
she hasn't been in for 3 months.

180
00:16:41,367 --> 00:16:43,562
This blouse'd suit me.

181
00:16:44,136 --> 00:16:47,970
We won't see her again.
She must have taken off.

182
00:16:48,207 --> 00:16:50,937
- That's stealing.
- Yvonne's right.

183
00:16:51,176 --> 00:16:55,237
Even if she returns in 10 years,
her blouse'll be here.

184
00:17:03,222 --> 00:17:06,521
Keep your distance
from that Yvonne Brunner.

185
00:17:09,128 --> 00:17:12,791
I won't have the boss's son
dating an employee.

186
00:17:13,032 --> 00:17:16,092
She's a friend.
And as she speaks German. . .

187
00:17:17,803 --> 00:17:19,794
Don't disappoint me
like your brother.

188
00:17:21,006 --> 00:17:24,772
I've decided to leave
the business to you.

189
00:17:26,478 --> 00:17:30,380
And as future boss,
you must set an example.

190
00:17:30,716 --> 00:17:32,513
You could've told me, Armand.

191
00:17:33,419 --> 00:17:36,980
Have you thought about him?

192
00:17:38,223 --> 00:17:39,884
You amaze me!

193
00:17:40,826 --> 00:17:44,626
Hiding Sara Morgenstern
under Dad's nose. Some nerve!

194
00:17:44,863 --> 00:17:46,728
I thought she'd be safe there.

195
00:17:47,699 --> 00:17:50,190
Mom and Dad only saw her once
in 1936.

196
00:17:50,436 --> 00:17:51,835
They don't recognize her.

197
00:17:52,204 --> 00:17:56,140
If Dad knew he was hiding a Jew. . .
Him, a fan of Pétain !

198
00:17:56,375 --> 00:17:57,569
Don't say anything.

199
00:18:01,747 --> 00:18:03,510
Does she still love you?

200
00:18:04,683 --> 00:18:09,017
I'll meet you when you come out.
Till then, be good.

201
00:18:29,775 --> 00:18:30,833
Come on.

202
00:18:34,313 --> 00:18:37,874
Monsieur Jacques, I'm so happy.

203
00:18:38,117 --> 00:18:40,449
I was so worried about your health.

204
00:18:40,719 --> 00:18:44,246
You look a bit pasty.
Bad weather in the mountains?

205
00:18:44,490 --> 00:18:45,957
Hello, Monsieur Jacques!

206
00:18:46,825 --> 00:18:50,022
It's not the return
of the prodigal son,

207
00:18:52,131 --> 00:18:53,723
but of the black sheep.

208
00:18:53,966 --> 00:18:56,457
You're an employee
like the rest now.

209
00:18:56,768 --> 00:18:59,703
You'll obey your boss:
Me, your father.

210
00:19:00,305 --> 00:19:04,571
And when I retire,
you'll obey your brother Jean.

211
00:19:04,810 --> 00:19:06,801
I'm leaving him everything.

212
00:19:07,079 --> 00:19:07,875
Here!

213
00:19:08,914 --> 00:19:11,712
Today's deliveries.
They're your job.

214
00:19:11,950 --> 00:19:13,542
Jean will stay with me.

215
00:19:14,953 --> 00:19:15,942
Get going !

216
00:19:28,767 --> 00:19:30,564
This is Yvonne Brunner.

217
00:19:30,802 --> 00:19:32,565
She helps Mom on the counter.

218
00:19:33,138 --> 00:19:34,264
Yvonne what?

219
00:19:34,506 --> 00:19:35,302
Brunner, sir.

220
00:19:37,376 --> 00:19:39,310
Delighted. I'm Jacques.

221
00:19:40,279 --> 00:19:42,679
The youngest.
I was in a sanatorium.

222
00:20:06,371 --> 00:20:06,996
All right?

223
00:20:23,989 --> 00:20:25,183
What did you eat inside?

224
00:20:25,924 --> 00:20:28,859
Nothing. I lived on hate.
Come on.

225
00:20:31,997 --> 00:20:33,225
Damn !

226
00:20:37,736 --> 00:20:39,465
Help me up.

227
00:20:42,107 --> 00:20:45,634
- One day I'll give you a beating.
- Just try.

228
00:20:49,014 --> 00:20:51,414
I missed our brotherly punch-ups!

229
00:20:55,187 --> 00:20:57,485
You scraped me. Look.

230
00:20:58,857 --> 00:21:01,325
Mind you, women love it.

231
00:21:08,033 --> 00:21:10,661
I covered for you again
with Dad today.

232
00:21:11,370 --> 00:21:15,704
What are you up to?
Disappearing, reappearing. . .

233
00:21:15,941 --> 00:21:17,704
Not up to no good, I hope.

234
00:21:17,943 --> 00:21:21,879
Stop the preaching,
St Jean of the Laundry!

235
00:21:22,114 --> 00:21:24,082
Dad's cast you as the good guy:

236
00:21:24,316 --> 00:21:26,079
Perfect son, worthy heir. . .

237
00:21:26,318 --> 00:21:29,378
But I have my role too:
Black sheep!

238
00:21:29,621 --> 00:21:30,747
I'm made for it!

239
00:21:30,989 --> 00:21:32,581
I don't care what Dad says.

240
00:21:32,824 --> 00:21:35,622
Even when he says
he'll leave you everything?

241
00:21:36,261 --> 00:21:37,922
You didn't tell me!

242
00:21:38,163 --> 00:21:39,255
I'll share it.

243
00:21:39,498 --> 00:21:40,692
Spare me your pity.

244
00:21:41,166 --> 00:21:44,567
You've never needed to fight.
So leave me alone!

245
00:21:54,513 --> 00:21:56,947
I was almost happier in jail.

246
00:21:57,182 --> 00:21:59,980
My family's awful,
even my brother watches me.

247
00:22:00,252 --> 00:22:03,881
You here to weep or work?
How many addresses you got?

248
00:22:04,489 --> 00:22:07,788
I didn't snitch
and I did a year inside.

249
00:22:08,026 --> 00:22:10,426
So I'd like a token of gratitude.

250
00:22:10,662 --> 00:22:11,890
How much?

251
00:22:13,832 --> 00:22:15,823
30% on all we fence.

252
00:22:16,101 --> 00:22:19,127
And first pick
of antiques and artworks.

253
00:22:19,371 --> 00:22:20,804
Too greedy.

254
00:22:21,173 --> 00:22:23,971
I have to grease the palms of cops,

255
00:22:24,209 --> 00:22:27,007
of concierges, of Jerries. . .

256
00:22:27,312 --> 00:22:28,472
All pigs!

257
00:22:28,714 --> 00:22:30,147
15 %. . .

258
00:22:30,682 --> 00:22:32,172
Furniture, yes, but no art.

259
00:22:33,652 --> 00:22:34,846
O K, take note.

260
00:22:40,492 --> 00:22:45,327
Marny. Unseen for 4 months.
8 rue Chaussée d'Antin. 3rd floor.

261
00:22:45,964 --> 00:22:49,297
Strauss. 18 rue de la Boétie.
No sign for 2 weeks.

262
00:22:49,534 --> 00:22:52,628
I've delivered there.
He's got masterpieces.

263
00:22:52,971 --> 00:22:55,166
Moskovitz.
32 rue du Faubourg Poissonière.

264
00:22:55,407 --> 00:22:57,637
Not seen since the last round-up.

265
00:23:23,235 --> 00:23:24,133
Wait!

266
00:23:24,369 --> 00:23:27,065
First to St Cloud
chooses the night out.

267
00:23:27,339 --> 00:23:30,706
- I win, we go to Graff's.
- No way! And Yvonne?

268
00:23:30,942 --> 00:23:33,467
- We're supposed to be a couple.
- Silly!

269
00:23:33,712 --> 00:23:35,145
- Are you jealous?
- Me?

270
00:23:35,914 --> 00:23:38,906
Just a bit possessive.
Because I love you !

271
00:23:44,423 --> 00:23:46,050
Wait for me!

272
00:23:55,367 --> 00:23:58,530
- Where are you going?
- To apologize for leaving her.

273
00:23:58,770 --> 00:24:02,433
Hurry up. Remember I won
and we're going to Graff's.

274
00:24:29,968 --> 00:24:31,458
My favorite boy!

275
00:24:31,803 --> 00:24:34,203
Seen how well we're doing?

276
00:24:34,673 --> 00:24:39,940
Since the competition vanished
we're now a free zone for queers.

277
00:24:40,178 --> 00:24:41,611
I must see the Baroness.

278
00:24:41,847 --> 00:24:44,611
He's a sinister one.
Did I shock him?

279
00:24:45,450 --> 00:24:49,045
You've just arrived and Handsome
has already spotted you.

280
00:24:49,488 --> 00:24:51,649
He is handsome, but he's all yours.

281
00:24:51,923 --> 00:24:55,256
He's over me.
You dance with him.

282
00:24:56,127 --> 00:24:58,322
He's Von Berg,
an influential officer.

283
00:24:59,598 --> 00:25:01,998
Do it for me, as a friend.

284
00:25:04,436 --> 00:25:08,463
Remember, thanks to men like him
Graff's is still open.

285
00:25:25,390 --> 00:25:30,794
<i>I n this world</i>
<i>my only joy, my only fun is my man</i>

286
00:25:32,631 --> 00:25:38,331
<i>I've given all my love</i>
<i>I've given all my heart to my man</i>

287
00:25:40,205 --> 00:25:45,268
<i>And even at night when I dream</i>
<i>it's of him, of my man. . .

288
00:25:46,011 --> 00:25:47,706
You can't count on me.

289
00:25:47,979 --> 00:25:50,311
No more official stamps
from the Prefecture.

290
00:25:50,916 --> 00:25:52,383
But you're the Prefect.

291
00:25:52,651 --> 00:25:56,985
Not for long. I'm finding it hard
to hide my disobedience to Vichy.

292
00:25:57,522 --> 00:25:58,784
Don't drop us.

293
00:25:59,024 --> 00:26:01,549
My superiors and inferiors
are gunning for me.

294
00:26:01,826 --> 00:26:05,455
Believe me, I'll be more useful
in the underground.

295
00:26:05,697 --> 00:26:09,463
Another thing. Don't come back.
It's too risky.

296
00:26:09,935 --> 00:26:10,993
Notice anything?

297
00:26:12,404 --> 00:26:13,393
New faces?

298
00:26:13,672 --> 00:26:16,470
New? I know them all.

299
00:26:18,610 --> 00:26:22,341
The bad boy in the cap is Durieux.
Vice Brigade.

300
00:26:22,581 --> 00:26:25,311
Next to him is Rambrun. Also Vice.

301
00:26:25,550 --> 00:26:27,916
The gray suit in the armchair. . .

302
00:26:28,219 --> 00:26:31,484
One of them.
Look, he's taking notes.

303
00:26:35,560 --> 00:26:38,051
Tell laundry boy to watch his step.

304
00:26:38,897 --> 00:26:41,422
Go and rescue the rash young thing.

305
00:26:42,033 --> 00:26:46,094
No hard feelings: You left me
for him and I'm protecting him.

306
00:26:46,371 --> 00:26:47,736
It's a sign of love.

307
00:27:12,897 --> 00:27:16,230
Are you looking for
a one-way ticket to the camps?

308
00:27:16,468 --> 00:27:19,028
Have fun, sure,
but not with a German !

309
00:27:19,270 --> 00:27:20,294
Enough.

310
00:27:21,006 --> 00:27:24,305
The Vice Brigade is here.
You want to be in their files?

311
00:27:24,576 --> 00:27:26,100
Don't treat me like a kid.

312
00:27:26,344 --> 00:27:27,436
Anyway, what files?

313
00:27:27,679 --> 00:27:30,307
Like the ones for the Jews.

314
00:27:31,116 --> 00:27:35,746
I'd rather not dance with a Jerry,
but you were with the Prefect!

315
00:27:35,987 --> 00:27:37,420
Aren't we a couple?

316
00:27:37,656 --> 00:27:38,884
You're pathetic!

317
00:27:41,192 --> 00:27:42,159
I'm going !

318
00:27:42,527 --> 00:27:44,757
- Yvonne will be bored.
- Go back to her.

319
00:27:44,996 --> 00:27:47,430
Be consoled. And screw her too!

320
00:27:48,166 --> 00:27:49,633
You've got all night!

321
00:28:28,873 --> 00:28:32,036
- Remember our first cigarette?
- I'll say.

322
00:28:32,510 --> 00:28:37,538
I can still see your folks combing
the beach, fearing you kidnapped.

323
00:28:38,583 --> 00:28:41,552
We were doubled up
behind the dunes.

324
00:28:44,989 --> 00:28:47,184
It was rolled with corn paper.

325
00:28:47,559 --> 00:28:50,995
It was so strong we turned green.

326
00:28:51,229 --> 00:28:52,321
Remember?

327
00:28:54,165 --> 00:28:58,499
I never thought it would end up
being a pleasure.

328
00:28:59,070 --> 00:29:00,628
Or even a fond memory.

329
00:29:12,350 --> 00:29:13,408
I'm sorry.

330
00:29:16,087 --> 00:29:17,418
Is it me?

331
00:29:17,689 --> 00:29:19,316
It's not your fault.

332
00:29:20,725 --> 00:29:22,158
I'm in love with Philippe.

333
00:29:24,462 --> 00:29:25,986
But you came back for me.

334
00:29:30,435 --> 00:29:32,369
Your love disturbs me.

335
00:29:33,705 --> 00:29:36,367
Your way of looking at me,
talking to me. . .

336
00:29:37,776 --> 00:29:39,175
I'll never be all yours.

337
00:29:39,744 --> 00:29:41,371
I'm not asking you to be.

338
00:29:42,947 --> 00:29:44,847
I don't care if you're not all mine.

339
00:29:45,083 --> 00:29:47,916
You don't care right now.

340
00:29:48,386 --> 00:29:51,878
But once Philippe is home
and I go to his bed,

341
00:29:52,123 --> 00:29:53,784
will you be able to bear it?

342
00:29:54,425 --> 00:29:56,950
No. And it's understandable.

343
00:30:00,165 --> 00:30:02,929
- It doesn't matter.
- It does.

344
00:30:07,605 --> 00:30:10,369
Not if the one I've always loved
is with me.

345
00:30:11,176 --> 00:30:13,701
With others too, but also with me.

346
00:30:16,347 --> 00:30:18,315
I'd make you sad, Sara.

347
00:30:20,752 --> 00:30:22,913
I love you too much to do that.

348
00:30:24,255 --> 00:30:27,122
You're beautiful, desirable,

349
00:30:28,359 --> 00:30:30,759
the only woman I could want,

350
00:30:31,496 --> 00:30:33,396
the only one I could love. . .

351
00:30:34,999 --> 00:30:36,557
But I'd ruin you.

352
00:30:48,780 --> 00:30:50,645
I want you to stay beautiful.

353
00:30:51,716 --> 00:30:53,809
I want you to be happy.

354
00:31:28,887 --> 00:31:30,980
Nothing happened, Philippe.

355
00:31:33,591 --> 00:31:35,616
Nothing ever will.

356
00:31:36,861 --> 00:31:38,226
There's only you.

357
00:31:40,565 --> 00:31:42,499
I'm so scared of losing you.

358
00:31:45,036 --> 00:31:46,833
I love you.

359
00:31:57,916 --> 00:31:59,747
Now listen to me. . .

360
00:32:02,020 --> 00:32:05,353
The Baroness warned me:
We mustn't take risks.

361
00:32:05,590 --> 00:32:07,353
Darlan has criminalized us.

362
00:32:07,592 --> 00:32:10,026
Why? We haven't hurt anyone.

363
00:32:12,964 --> 00:32:14,090
I know.

364
00:32:52,170 --> 00:32:53,865
Who was that chap?

365
00:32:54,105 --> 00:32:56,596
- Who's jealous now?
- I'm not. I'm worried.

366
00:32:56,841 --> 00:33:00,242
I'm not stupid.
I know you made Yvonne's papers.

367
00:33:00,478 --> 00:33:02,241
Where? At the print shop?

368
00:33:02,480 --> 00:33:04,641
- Never you mind, dear.
- Well I do.

369
00:33:04,916 --> 00:33:08,613
You don't need a Prefect ex
to know they're after resisters.

370
00:33:08,853 --> 00:33:12,414
Don't mistake courage for rashness.
For Yvonne's sake.

371
00:33:12,657 --> 00:33:14,090
Don't you agree?

372
00:33:14,759 --> 00:33:16,056
Then you're rash too.

373
00:33:16,294 --> 00:33:18,762
I may be "sweet Yvonne",
but inside I'm Sara.

374
00:33:18,997 --> 00:33:22,592
I want to destroy the Nazis

375
00:33:22,834 --> 00:33:24,802
So, I've been helping Philippe.

376
00:33:25,269 --> 00:33:26,896
Don't worry.

377
00:33:28,473 --> 00:33:30,100
I won't put her at risk.

378
00:33:30,341 --> 00:33:32,138
You're resisting by hiding me.

379
00:33:32,677 --> 00:33:37,671
We didn't want this war,
but it's ours. So be quiet.

380
00:33:40,184 --> 00:33:42,414
You'll do what you want, anyway.

381
00:33:58,803 --> 00:34:01,829
N O J EWS

382
00:34:06,177 --> 00:34:08,543
It's either that or close down.

383
00:34:08,813 --> 00:34:10,610
No work to do?

384
00:34:16,654 --> 00:34:17,450
M me Benaim !

385
00:34:18,723 --> 00:34:21,521
Wait. Your laundry's ready.

386
00:34:32,070 --> 00:34:33,662
- Here.
- How much?

387
00:34:34,105 --> 00:34:35,163
Nothing.

388
00:34:36,007 --> 00:34:37,167
Thank you.

389
00:34:52,390 --> 00:34:55,553
Never do that again, do you hear?
Never!

390
00:35:20,751 --> 00:35:23,584
Ten addresses today?
Business is booming !

391
00:35:25,423 --> 00:35:27,414
How about that favor I asked?

392
00:35:27,892 --> 00:35:29,257
I kept my word.

393
00:35:31,429 --> 00:35:34,057
It cost me an arm and a leg !

394
00:35:34,298 --> 00:35:36,630
10 pounds of beef
straight from Nevers,

395
00:35:36,901 --> 00:35:38,300
via my brother-in-law!

396
00:35:38,669 --> 00:35:42,469
You're too fat anyway.
Careful, it looks suspicious.

397
00:35:54,018 --> 00:35:55,144
Wait!

398
00:35:57,321 --> 00:36:00,415
- You're not walking home in this?
- I'm fine.

399
00:36:00,658 --> 00:36:04,059
Jean's with Dad at the town hall.
I'll walk you home.

400
00:36:04,295 --> 00:36:05,990
Thanks, but don't bother.

401
00:36:06,998 --> 00:36:09,990
Don't upset me.
We're friends, right?

402
00:36:10,768 --> 00:36:12,099
Come on then.

403
00:36:21,145 --> 00:36:23,136
Thanks for walking me home.

404
00:36:23,381 --> 00:36:24,746
- I'm going up. . .
- Wait.

405
00:36:27,218 --> 00:36:28,947
This is for you.

406
00:36:34,158 --> 00:36:35,489
Perfume, on rations?

407
00:36:37,128 --> 00:36:39,995
Since when did women
start questioning gifts?

408
00:36:40,231 --> 00:36:43,997
Sorry. I'm not used to it.
I even forgot to thank you.

409
00:36:44,235 --> 00:36:45,827
Invite me up to apologize.

410
00:36:46,904 --> 00:36:51,136
I can't, I don't live alone.
It's my cousin's place.

411
00:36:51,375 --> 00:36:53,002
Great. I'd like to meet him.

412
00:36:53,244 --> 00:36:58,147
Sara, in jail I dreamt of
a woman like you inviting me in.

413
00:36:58,382 --> 00:37:01,351
Plus, I'm soaked.
I'll catch my death, Sara!

414
00:37:01,586 --> 00:37:03,486
Look, my name's Yvonne.

415
00:37:03,721 --> 00:37:05,518
- Yvonne!
- Sorry. . . Yvonne.

416
00:37:09,026 --> 00:37:10,118
Evening.

417
00:37:11,862 --> 00:37:16,231
Philippe, Jacques Lavandier,
my employers' youngest son.

418
00:37:17,268 --> 00:37:19,031
Philippe Leroux, my cousin.

419
00:37:20,271 --> 00:37:23,001
Can we go up to get acquainted?

420
00:37:24,242 --> 00:37:25,504
Good idea.

421
00:37:35,019 --> 00:37:38,716
- I've got a drop of hooch left.
- Great. Thanks.

422
00:37:42,093 --> 00:37:43,583
I'll get changed.

423
00:37:43,928 --> 00:37:45,520
I'll get the glasses.

424
00:37:46,030 --> 00:37:49,727
- Pretty cousin, M . Leroux.
- Philippe to friends.

425
00:37:50,534 --> 00:37:53,435
How is it a woman
from a rich family in Alsace

426
00:37:53,671 --> 00:37:56,697
has a workman cousin?
A printer to be precise.

427
00:37:59,277 --> 00:38:03,407
Family histories
are full of untold secrets.

428
00:38:03,881 --> 00:38:05,872
Yours is no different, right?

429
00:38:06,117 --> 00:38:09,883
I'm a workman, sure.
But Yvonne's a laundress.

430
00:38:10,888 --> 00:38:12,685
It's wartime for everyone.

431
00:38:12,923 --> 00:38:15,721
Some get rich, others lose the lot.

432
00:38:15,960 --> 00:38:17,427
Bad time for the honest.

433
00:38:25,970 --> 00:38:27,870
Are you one of our customers?

434
00:38:30,308 --> 00:38:31,969
Yvonne insisted.

435
00:38:32,243 --> 00:38:35,474
She thinks even workmen
should have clean linen.

436
00:38:47,792 --> 00:38:51,785
It's lovely! It'd suit me
better than M me Levy-Rosenthal.

437
00:38:52,029 --> 00:38:55,055
She'd look like Mother Hen in it.

438
00:38:55,299 --> 00:38:58,757
Mind you, we haven't seen her
for 6 months.

439
00:38:59,370 --> 00:39:01,895
Take it. Bring it back Monday.

440
00:39:02,139 --> 00:39:04,505
I doubt old Levy-Rosenthal
will be back.

441
00:39:04,775 --> 00:39:06,333
Thank you, Monsieur Jacques!

442
00:39:06,610 --> 00:39:08,168
I'm off then.

443
00:39:10,281 --> 00:39:12,511
Enjoy your Sunday.
See you on Monday.

444
00:41:01,392 --> 00:41:02,723
See you tomorrow.

445
00:41:08,332 --> 00:41:10,391
Stop it! Are you mad?

446
00:41:11,735 --> 00:41:12,895
Scared?

447
00:41:32,623 --> 00:41:33,487
Stop!

448
00:41:39,663 --> 00:41:40,652
Are you sick?

449
00:41:41,031 --> 00:41:42,089
What was that?

450
00:41:43,434 --> 00:41:46,096
You're a fag, a poof, a queer,
and I'm sick?

451
00:41:46,504 --> 00:41:48,563
You revolt me! You know why?

452
00:41:48,939 --> 00:41:50,406
Not because you're a poof.

453
00:41:50,641 --> 00:41:54,407
Because you're a liar and coward
who passes himself off

454
00:41:54,645 --> 00:41:55,771
as the perfect son !

455
00:42:44,495 --> 00:42:45,894
I loved you.

456
00:42:46,864 --> 00:42:48,957
You were everything to me.

457
00:42:49,199 --> 00:42:51,667
And that makes no sense now.

458
00:42:57,207 --> 00:42:59,198
Tell me I'm still your brother.

459
00:43:00,110 --> 00:43:01,543
Please.

460
00:43:05,583 --> 00:43:08,916
I couldn't tell you. I couldn't.

461
00:43:11,055 --> 00:43:13,546
For years
I thought I was a monster.

462
00:43:16,727 --> 00:43:19,821
I was 12 when I first tried
to talk about it.

463
00:43:20,297 --> 00:43:22,663
To Father Kermadec in La Baule.

464
00:43:24,902 --> 00:43:28,770
He said I should die of shame
rather than admit my perversion.

465
00:43:30,374 --> 00:43:34,708
He showed me pictures so I'd confess
to sins I hadn't even imagined.

466
00:43:34,945 --> 00:43:38,540
- Two demons on top. . .
- Shut up, I don't want to know!

467
00:43:38,782 --> 00:43:41,080
I detested myself for years.

468
00:43:41,318 --> 00:43:43,377
Hated myself, disgusted myself.

469
00:43:43,621 --> 00:43:45,020
I was ashamed.

470
00:43:46,890 --> 00:43:48,721
I tried to change.

471
00:43:50,394 --> 00:43:52,555
To go with women.

472
00:43:54,765 --> 00:43:56,027
It wasn't me.

473
00:44:00,404 --> 00:44:02,429
Then I met a boy. . .

474
00:44:04,642 --> 00:44:08,305
I realized it wasn't wrong,
I couldn't change.

475
00:44:09,113 --> 00:44:11,707
Couldn't change?
You can choose!

476
00:44:11,815 --> 00:44:12,941
Choose?

477
00:44:17,121 --> 00:44:19,589
Did you choose your blue eyes?

478
00:44:20,090 --> 00:44:22,991
Same here.
I didn't choose to love men.

479
00:44:28,699 --> 00:44:30,667
Philippe Leroux and you. . .

480
00:44:30,968 --> 00:44:32,663
How long has it been?

481
00:44:33,337 --> 00:44:35,168
- 4 years.
- Jesus!

482
00:44:36,707 --> 00:44:38,265
I can't believe it.

483
00:44:38,642 --> 00:44:40,610
I didn't notice a thing.

484
00:44:41,979 --> 00:44:45,073
I bet you laughed
when I talked about girls!

485
00:44:48,952 --> 00:44:50,647
Tell me you forgive me.

486
00:44:53,157 --> 00:44:54,784
Tell me, please.

487
00:44:59,196 --> 00:45:01,664
It's not easy lying to my brother

488
00:45:03,067 --> 00:45:05,297
who I love more than myself.

489
00:45:12,676 --> 00:45:15,270
"Till death us do part"
still stands.

490
00:45:24,054 --> 00:45:27,023
I thought you'd chickened out
in that brothel.

491
00:45:27,257 --> 00:45:29,020
You were so proud of yourself.

492
00:45:29,259 --> 00:45:31,523
You're a damn fine actor.

493
00:45:31,829 --> 00:45:34,195
- Yvonne knows?
- Sure. She lives with him.

494
00:45:34,431 --> 00:45:38,333
Doesn't stop her loving you
or making eyes at you.

495
00:45:50,614 --> 00:45:51,478
To Jean !

496
00:45:52,082 --> 00:45:53,845
Happy birthday, bro!

497
00:45:58,455 --> 00:46:01,015
That's not all.
I've another surprise.

498
00:46:04,094 --> 00:46:06,654
Jacques, you shouldn't have.

499
00:46:31,388 --> 00:46:32,912
- Where'd he get it?
- Who?

500
00:46:33,157 --> 00:46:34,624
Who? Your brother!

501
00:46:34,892 --> 00:46:38,453
Champagne, beef, cigars,
not to mention records!

502
00:46:38,729 --> 00:46:40,219
Black market, I suppose.

503
00:46:40,464 --> 00:46:43,456
He's gone overboard as usual.
For me.

504
00:46:43,734 --> 00:46:45,964
It's his way of showing
he loves me.

505
00:46:46,937 --> 00:46:49,098
- If you say so.
- Stop.

506
00:46:54,178 --> 00:46:56,373
Stop! What's got into you?

507
00:46:57,080 --> 00:46:58,741
- Come on !
- Stop it!

508
00:47:02,019 --> 00:47:03,111
You drive me nuts!

509
00:47:03,353 --> 00:47:05,048
Seeing you with Jean !

510
00:47:05,322 --> 00:47:07,552
Little looks. . .
I could kill you both !

511
00:47:07,791 --> 00:47:09,884
Stop it! What's wrong with you?

512
00:47:10,127 --> 00:47:11,822
She's all uptight.

513
00:47:12,095 --> 00:47:13,221
What's wrong?

514
00:47:13,463 --> 00:47:15,988
I treat her like a queen !
Why reject me?

515
00:47:16,667 --> 00:47:18,897
You don't like real men?
Only poofs?

516
00:47:19,136 --> 00:47:20,603
That's enough !

517
00:47:21,004 --> 00:47:22,403
Now get out!

518
00:47:23,340 --> 00:47:25,740
And stop talking rubbish !

519
00:47:45,963 --> 00:47:47,453
We can't end the night on that.

520
00:47:48,565 --> 00:47:49,532
Let's dance.

521
00:47:49,800 --> 00:47:50,824
It's over.

522
00:47:51,068 --> 00:47:52,626
No. I want to dance.

523
00:47:53,170 --> 00:47:54,865
Yvonne's right. Dance with her.

524
00:47:55,138 --> 00:47:58,938
I want to forget the war,
forget your brother and party.

525
00:47:59,176 --> 00:48:01,872
I'll just watch.
If I don't fall asleep.

526
00:48:04,982 --> 00:48:07,007
I don't want this to stop. Ever.

527
00:48:09,419 --> 00:48:11,683
I can't love anyone but you.

528
00:48:11,922 --> 00:48:13,651
Don't be silly, Yvonne.

529
00:48:14,725 --> 00:48:16,989
If only you wanted to.

530
00:48:17,694 --> 00:48:19,389
I'd be yours.

531
00:48:20,397 --> 00:48:22,388
I'd give you children.

532
00:48:23,400 --> 00:48:26,892
What? Who else will?
Philippe?

533
00:48:27,571 --> 00:48:29,562
I'd do it for you.

534
00:48:29,907 --> 00:48:31,499
I'd give you a son.

535
00:48:37,347 --> 00:48:40,214
I'm not angry,
because you're drunk, Sara.

536
00:48:40,918 --> 00:48:42,044
Sadly drunk.

537
00:49:03,307 --> 00:49:06,572
I hope you've a good reason
for waking me up.

538
00:49:11,214 --> 00:49:13,079
I need a favor.

539
00:49:13,317 --> 00:49:14,944
Good God, a favor!

540
00:49:15,218 --> 00:49:16,913
Now what is it?

541
00:49:17,154 --> 00:49:20,590
Perfume for a dolly-bird?
A dress while we're at it?

542
00:49:21,591 --> 00:49:22,717
Arrest my brother.

543
00:49:22,960 --> 00:49:23,927
But why?

544
00:49:24,161 --> 00:49:25,389
Because I'm asking.

545
00:49:25,629 --> 00:49:27,859
I did a year without snitching.
I deserve it.

546
00:49:28,098 --> 00:49:31,124
I don't disagree.
I just want to know why?

547
00:49:31,435 --> 00:49:33,300
I love rotten families.

548
00:49:33,971 --> 00:49:36,064
Rotten through with secrets.

549
00:49:36,306 --> 00:49:37,796
And on what charge?

550
00:49:38,642 --> 00:49:40,200
Say you got a tip

551
00:49:40,444 --> 00:49:44,039
that he's in the Resistance.
It's hard to disprove.

552
00:49:47,417 --> 00:49:48,782
Release him the next day.

553
00:49:49,286 --> 00:49:51,117
Bring him to the laundry.

554
00:49:51,355 --> 00:49:53,915
Tell him he's lucky
his brother has contacts.

555
00:49:54,791 --> 00:49:55,951
Touching !

556
00:49:56,193 --> 00:49:58,821
The bad apple wants to be a hero.

557
00:49:59,096 --> 00:50:00,961
- Like Greek tragedy.
- Right.

558
00:50:01,198 --> 00:50:04,895
It'll cost you a wad of addresses.
Tragedy's my wife's game.

559
00:50:08,538 --> 00:50:12,269
He's at a friend's,
but he'll go home before dawn.

560
00:50:12,609 --> 00:50:14,076
He passes the university.

561
00:50:17,881 --> 00:50:22,341
Agreed? I get him released.
And don't hurt him.

562
00:50:22,619 --> 00:50:25,110
Don't worry.
I'll just make the call.

563
00:50:45,642 --> 00:50:47,007
I have to go.

564
00:50:50,547 --> 00:50:53,107
Watch it. The curfew's still on.

565
00:50:57,187 --> 00:50:59,121
Happy birthday again.

566
00:52:02,986 --> 00:52:04,419
What are you doing?

567
00:52:22,405 --> 00:52:24,373
Can anybody hear me?

568
00:52:27,644 --> 00:52:29,305
Where are you taking me?

569
00:52:30,847 --> 00:52:35,045
- I've done nothing to the Germans.
- Shut it! Who asked you?

570
00:52:41,691 --> 00:52:44,125
Call my home. Lavandier.

571
00:52:44,361 --> 00:52:47,455
Turenne 24-36.
They'll tell you I'm innocent.

572
00:52:48,165 --> 00:52:51,328
Speak when you're spoken to!
Understand?

573
00:52:51,601 --> 00:52:53,592
Easy. We're releasing him later.

574
00:52:53,837 --> 00:52:56,169
- Why arrest him then?
- I'll explain later.

575
00:52:56,439 --> 00:52:59,602
The reputation of the French Police
depends on us.

576
00:53:01,111 --> 00:53:04,410
Well, ladies,
a nice evening of cottaging?

577
00:53:04,648 --> 00:53:05,580
A bit chilly?

578
00:53:05,815 --> 00:53:08,750
Your punter. . .
Isn't that Jean Lavandier?

579
00:53:08,985 --> 00:53:12,079
Born 3rd October 1915,
Paris 3rd district?

580
00:53:12,322 --> 00:53:13,584
He's in the poof file.

581
00:53:13,823 --> 00:53:15,654
Cavorting with a Jerry officer.

582
00:53:15,892 --> 00:53:17,917
I've got a case against him.

583
00:53:19,062 --> 00:53:19,858
I'm innocent!

584
00:53:20,797 --> 00:53:21,491
I'm innocent!

585
00:53:21,965 --> 00:53:23,091
Who's that?

586
00:53:23,333 --> 00:53:24,357
Your German cousin?

587
00:53:25,835 --> 00:53:27,325
We know everything.

588
00:53:27,571 --> 00:53:31,007
Witnesses saw you
feeling each other up at Graff's.

589
00:53:31,241 --> 00:53:34,438
It's no time to be
a German officer's plaything.

590
00:53:34,678 --> 00:53:37,841
I'm not his plaything.
I didn't sleep with him.

591
00:53:38,081 --> 00:53:39,514
You're in the fag file!

592
00:53:39,749 --> 00:53:41,979
You're the shame of the new France.

593
00:53:42,219 --> 00:53:46,212
As you love Jerries so,
you can get to know them better.

594
00:53:47,424 --> 00:53:49,654
He's never been this late.

595
00:53:49,893 --> 00:53:52,225
God, I hope nothing's happened !

596
00:53:53,029 --> 00:53:55,725
I could cover for Jean in the shop

597
00:53:55,999 --> 00:53:59,059
and do the deliveries
this afternoon.

598
00:53:59,703 --> 00:54:01,227
When did you start caring?

599
00:54:09,412 --> 00:54:12,870
Inspectors Maurier and Cazenaud.
M and M me Lavandier?

600
00:54:13,116 --> 00:54:14,640
Is it about Jean?

601
00:54:15,452 --> 00:54:17,682
He's being held for questioning.

602
00:54:17,921 --> 00:54:20,151
What for? There's been a mistake.

603
00:54:20,624 --> 00:54:24,993
I don't think so.
He's the lover of a German officer.

604
00:54:42,779 --> 00:54:44,440
What's with this German officer?

605
00:54:44,714 --> 00:54:47,683
You were supposed
to release Jean tonight!

606
00:54:48,251 --> 00:54:49,513
Don't mess this up!

607
00:54:49,819 --> 00:54:53,846
Mess up?
You played with fire and got burnt.

608
00:54:54,758 --> 00:54:58,285
You should've known he liked
being occupied by the occupiers.

609
00:54:58,561 --> 00:55:01,052
They'll occupy themselves
with him now!

610
00:55:02,565 --> 00:55:05,227
How many addresses do you need?

611
00:55:05,769 --> 00:55:08,932
Not even a hundred will do.
The Jerries don't care.

612
00:55:09,172 --> 00:55:12,733
But try hard
and I'll put in a word.

613
00:55:24,321 --> 00:55:29,782
A lieutenant-colonel
in the German Army.

614
00:55:30,293 --> 00:55:33,091
Johann Von Berg.

615
00:55:34,331 --> 00:55:36,322
You hit the jackpot.

616
00:55:36,599 --> 00:55:37,429
I don't know him.

617
00:55:37,667 --> 00:55:40,636
Our French friends
were most cooperative.

618
00:55:40,870 --> 00:55:43,998
You met him at Graff's
on 30 August this year.

619
00:55:44,107 --> 00:55:45,404
I didn't sleep with him.

620
00:55:48,478 --> 00:55:52,608
We want to know
about your pillow-talk.

621
00:55:53,016 --> 00:55:57,453
<i>Arsch fickers</i> like you,
dirty little bum bandits,

622
00:55:57,687 --> 00:56:01,646
always talk during and after, right?

623
00:56:02,692 --> 00:56:05,490
Don't try to protect dear Johann.

624
00:56:06,396 --> 00:56:10,355
We know all about
your obscene, unnatural tryst.

625
00:56:10,633 --> 00:56:13,158
I only met him once.

626
00:56:14,537 --> 00:56:15,765
I didn't sleep with him.

627
00:56:16,673 --> 00:56:17,970
If it's a lie,

628
00:56:18,208 --> 00:56:21,371
why did Von Berg
put a bullet in his head?

629
00:56:23,413 --> 00:56:24,505
He was a pederast!

630
00:56:25,582 --> 00:56:26,981
A traitor!

631
00:56:28,051 --> 00:56:29,814
All pederasts are traitors!

632
00:56:31,654 --> 00:56:35,647
Did you go to his place
or to yours?

633
00:56:37,494 --> 00:56:40,793
What did he say
when you sodomized each other?

634
00:56:50,073 --> 00:56:53,702
This has gone far enough.
Only you can help Jean.

635
00:56:53,943 --> 00:56:56,810
You know collaborators. Call them.

636
00:56:57,046 --> 00:56:58,240
I did. No good.

637
00:56:59,582 --> 00:57:01,573
Then I'll see what I can do.

638
00:57:18,701 --> 00:57:22,068
Jean's being transferred
to Tourelles tomorrow.

639
00:57:22,305 --> 00:57:25,103
We must know someone there.
It's a French jail.

640
00:57:25,375 --> 00:57:27,036
Don't kid yourself.

641
00:57:27,277 --> 00:57:30,371
It's French-run
but under Gestapo control.

642
00:57:30,613 --> 00:57:33,343
He had an affair
with a German officer. . .

643
00:57:33,583 --> 00:57:34,880
But it's a lie!

644
00:57:35,118 --> 00:57:36,710
Easy does it.

645
00:57:38,288 --> 00:57:40,916
It's no longer a question
of true or false.

646
00:57:41,424 --> 00:57:45,224
Only the German officer
could save him,

647
00:57:45,462 --> 00:57:49,057
and he shot himself
to avoid the camps.

648
00:57:54,170 --> 00:57:55,797
I'm sorry.

649
00:58:14,958 --> 00:58:19,122
Here. 32 addresses.
More later, as they disappear.

650
00:58:19,362 --> 00:58:21,159
All I want is my brother.

651
00:58:21,431 --> 00:58:22,921
Don't get your hopes up.

652
00:58:23,600 --> 00:58:24,726
What must I do?

653
00:58:25,268 --> 00:58:29,398
I might suggest poking your mother
to get a replacement.

654
00:58:29,639 --> 00:58:31,971
But normal.
Not a fairy like this one.

655
00:58:34,210 --> 00:58:35,575
Listen to me.

656
00:58:35,812 --> 00:58:37,507
Your brother shames the nation.

657
00:58:37,780 --> 00:58:39,111
Poofs dirty our race.

658
00:58:39,349 --> 00:58:42,477
It's time for France, like Germany,
to cleanse itself.

659
00:58:42,719 --> 00:58:45,347
Your rotten brother and his kind
need re-educating.

660
00:58:45,622 --> 00:58:47,783
And if not, exterminating.

661
00:58:54,330 --> 00:58:56,093
You're sick, Breton !

662
00:59:19,656 --> 00:59:20,623
The stink!

663
00:59:23,893 --> 00:59:25,190
Is it you?

664
00:59:25,728 --> 00:59:28,026
You must be wondering. . .

665
00:59:28,264 --> 00:59:30,960
Who turned you in? Why?

666
00:59:34,237 --> 00:59:37,673
Well, sweetie,
family's not always what it seems.

667
00:59:54,390 --> 00:59:55,186
Come in !

668
01:00:01,030 --> 01:00:02,088
How can I help?

669
01:00:02,365 --> 01:00:04,993
- My brother's here. Jean Lavandier.
- So?

670
01:00:05,435 --> 01:00:09,599
I'm 4 months pregnant by him.
I work at his parents' shop.

671
01:00:10,039 --> 01:00:12,564
He's wrongly accused
of being a pederast.

672
01:00:13,109 --> 01:00:15,077
M Ile Brunner and I can testify.

673
01:00:15,311 --> 01:00:18,041
He and I lost our virginity
in a brothel.

674
01:00:18,414 --> 01:00:20,439
Has he offered to marry you?

675
01:00:20,717 --> 01:00:24,016
Yes, sir. We're very much in love.

676
01:00:24,887 --> 01:00:27,788
Our parents agree.
My mother signed this letter.

677
01:00:35,832 --> 01:00:37,026
Grangier. . .

678
01:00:38,167 --> 01:00:42,069
Bring prisoner Lavandier
and Captain Locarner to my office.

679
01:00:44,440 --> 01:00:46,806
We'll clarify all this.

680
01:01:01,991 --> 01:01:06,587
I'm sorry, but the prisoner
was moved to a transit camp.

681
01:01:06,963 --> 01:01:09,090
He'll leave for Germany
this evening.

682
01:01:09,365 --> 01:01:10,593
He's on the list.

683
01:01:11,300 --> 01:01:12,733
It's a night train.

684
01:01:28,484 --> 01:01:30,577
You can't stop there!

685
01:01:30,853 --> 01:01:33,014
Here, take this.

686
01:03:50,493 --> 01:03:51,755
I'll get him out.

687
01:03:52,929 --> 01:03:54,988
They're only going to
re-educate him.

688
01:03:55,598 --> 01:03:57,793
He'll be back once he's changed.

689
01:03:58,935 --> 01:04:00,129
I n about 3 months.

690
01:04:00,636 --> 01:04:02,069
Silence!

691
01:04:02,338 --> 01:04:04,932
I don't want him mentioned again
at this table.

692
01:04:58,327 --> 01:05:01,660
Only get off if I call your name!

693
01:05:13,943 --> 01:05:17,344
I said only get off
if I call your name.

694
01:06:02,892 --> 01:06:05,360
I n the truck. Move it!

695
01:07:18,567 --> 01:07:20,194
You speak French?

696
01:07:21,570 --> 01:07:23,936
- Where are we going?
- A labor camp.

697
01:07:28,677 --> 01:07:29,666
What's that?

698
01:07:29,912 --> 01:07:32,472
Like the yellow star,
but for German homos.

699
01:07:32,715 --> 01:07:34,979
I'm from Alsace, I'm German now.

700
01:07:35,217 --> 01:07:36,809
I must wear a pink triangle.

701
01:07:37,053 --> 01:07:39,021
Pink for girls, to humiliate us.

702
01:07:41,891 --> 01:07:43,381
Where are you from?

703
01:07:43,893 --> 01:07:45,155
Paris.

704
01:07:45,828 --> 01:07:47,728
You're lucky.

705
01:07:47,997 --> 01:07:52,297
Frenchmen get blue stripes.

706
01:07:52,535 --> 01:07:54,901
Better? We're going
to the same place.

707
01:07:55,171 --> 01:07:56,661
But we're not all equal.

708
01:07:56,906 --> 01:08:00,069
We homos with our pink triangles
are worse than dogs.

709
01:08:00,342 --> 01:08:02,902
We die twice as fast.
So you're lucky.

710
01:08:04,413 --> 01:08:06,040
I'm Rudy.

711
01:08:07,049 --> 01:08:08,516
I'm Jean.

712
01:08:20,963 --> 01:08:23,989
Isaac Levy, right?
You live in the 18th.

713
01:08:24,867 --> 01:08:26,391
What are you doing here?

714
01:08:26,635 --> 01:08:29,866
Where are you going?
Can I see your papers?

715
01:08:34,777 --> 01:08:36,608
Yvonne Brunner. . .

716
01:08:37,313 --> 01:08:39,440
- From Alsace?
- Yes. Eiswiller.

717
01:08:39,715 --> 01:08:43,242
My fiancé and his family live here.
I work with them.

718
01:08:43,486 --> 01:08:45,010
Here.

719
01:10:34,997 --> 01:10:36,362
It's Yvonne!

720
01:10:47,409 --> 01:10:50,469
Help me.
We'll put her in Jean's room.

721
01:11:14,303 --> 01:11:16,203
Philippe. . .

722
01:11:16,438 --> 01:11:18,269
He was looking at me.

723
01:11:18,540 --> 01:11:21,839
- Why do they kill everyone I love?
- No talking. Rest.

724
01:11:22,077 --> 01:11:24,068
What will we tell Jean?

725
01:11:27,883 --> 01:11:29,180
She's boiling.

726
01:11:29,418 --> 01:11:32,216
Water will bring her fever down.

727
01:11:35,391 --> 01:11:36,915
It's Sara.

728
01:11:37,159 --> 01:11:39,024
Sara Morgenstern.

729
01:11:39,261 --> 01:11:42,856
Remember? Her parents
had a villa in La Baule.

730
01:11:47,002 --> 01:11:49,402
You mustn't tell your father.

731
01:11:51,840 --> 01:11:54,536
She'll stay as long she needs.

732
01:11:55,244 --> 01:11:57,109
She's your fiancée.

733
01:11:57,446 --> 01:11:58,936
She lives and works with us.

734
01:12:00,182 --> 01:12:03,049
We'll do nothing
to attract attention.

735
01:12:51,800 --> 01:12:53,290
Silence!

736
01:12:53,535 --> 01:12:54,866
Re-education class.

737
01:13:24,433 --> 01:13:26,230
Start running !

738
01:14:02,771 --> 01:14:05,535
I n you go, girls.
Dry yourselves off.

739
01:14:10,946 --> 01:14:11,844
From Hans.

740
01:14:12,080 --> 01:14:14,776
Your warrant officer's spoiling you.

741
01:14:18,420 --> 01:14:20,115
Let it go. You know her.

742
01:14:20,389 --> 01:14:23,187
I know she's a collaborator,
that's all.

743
01:14:29,331 --> 01:14:30,764
Officer Stroeger.

744
01:14:30,999 --> 01:14:33,763
If you'd like to go through
to my office.

745
01:14:42,177 --> 01:14:45,578
I hope you bring good news
about Steiner's laundries.

746
01:14:45,814 --> 01:14:51,775
Yes, the Aryanization Commission
seemed to appreciate your report.

747
01:14:52,020 --> 01:14:55,786
Of course, there are
a few details to finalize.

748
01:14:56,024 --> 01:14:57,321
Of course.

749
01:14:57,593 --> 01:14:59,458
I n only a matter of days,

750
01:14:59,761 --> 01:15:04,824
Boulogne Laundries will be yours.

751
01:15:25,053 --> 01:15:28,147
Yvonne, it's me. It's Jacques.

752
01:15:28,490 --> 01:15:29,855
Can I come in?

753
01:15:55,751 --> 01:15:59,448
How could you? They're killing Jean,
and you deal with them !

754
01:15:59,688 --> 01:16:02,657
You disgust me. You're a pig.

755
01:16:03,025 --> 01:16:06,358
I won't stay here
in the same room as you.

756
01:16:06,595 --> 01:16:10,326
Don't talk to me like that.
Don't judge me!

757
01:16:10,866 --> 01:16:13,027
I do it to find out where Jean is.

758
01:16:13,268 --> 01:16:16,704
I pay for favors,
to get us out of this hell !

759
01:16:21,209 --> 01:16:22,870
I'm sorry.

760
01:16:24,846 --> 01:16:26,814
But I miss him so much.

761
01:16:27,583 --> 01:16:30,051
Every day I think of him.

762
01:16:31,119 --> 01:16:33,986
Every day I see his eyes
on that platform.

763
01:16:34,756 --> 01:16:37,657
I can't take any more!

764
01:16:43,031 --> 01:16:44,726
I miss him too.

765
01:16:59,982 --> 01:17:04,043
Stay away! Don't touch me!
I'm all right now.

766
01:17:05,821 --> 01:17:08,688
Don't go down or they'll kill you.

767
01:17:09,224 --> 01:17:10,452
Hang in there!

768
01:17:16,064 --> 01:17:18,589
Don't touch me! Keep away!

769
01:17:18,834 --> 01:17:20,301
Do like them.

770
01:17:21,003 --> 01:17:25,201
Never go near a pink triangle.
Don't talk to an <i>arsch fickerl</i>

771
01:17:40,288 --> 01:17:41,380
Leave him !

772
01:17:47,362 --> 01:17:49,159
Strip naked !

773
01:18:47,556 --> 01:18:48,853
Kill me!

774
01:19:03,071 --> 01:19:08,373
How many of you will abandon
your vile perversion

775
01:19:08,610 --> 01:19:11,078
to become men worthy of the name,

776
01:19:11,346 --> 01:19:14,747
ready to serve the Reich
and our great race?

777
01:19:20,689 --> 01:19:22,748
So you won't be cured?

778
01:19:23,959 --> 01:19:26,427
You refuse to be re-educated?

779
01:19:27,195 --> 01:19:30,164
I'm an <i>arsch fickerl</i>
I like men !

780
01:19:30,398 --> 01:19:33,231
You want to die like your comrade?

781
01:19:34,703 --> 01:19:36,830
Then I'll send you to Dachau.

782
01:19:37,072 --> 01:19:43,011
Our doctors will see to you there.
You'll change, you'll see.

783
01:19:49,751 --> 01:19:52,276
No more.
We've nothing to celebrate.

784
01:19:52,420 --> 01:19:53,887
I disagree.

785
01:19:54,122 --> 01:19:57,580
We're free and alive.
It offends life not to enjoy it.

786
01:20:02,664 --> 01:20:03,892
Let's drink.

787
01:20:04,232 --> 01:20:05,790
To those we miss.

788
01:20:06,067 --> 01:20:07,762
To life and hope.

789
01:20:08,637 --> 01:20:11,697
We need to be happy.
We must fight for that.

790
01:20:37,365 --> 01:20:41,495
A pleasure to meet a friend
spared by such painful times.

791
01:20:41,770 --> 01:20:43,897
See, I didn't forget you.

792
01:20:44,673 --> 01:20:45,970
No introductions?

793
01:20:46,441 --> 01:20:49,433
- Let's go.
- I wouldn't if I were you.

794
01:20:49,678 --> 01:20:51,475
One word from me and it's over.

795
01:20:51,713 --> 01:20:54,773
Dining here with a Jewess

796
01:20:55,016 --> 01:20:56,643
wanted for attempted murder. . .

797
01:20:56,885 --> 01:20:59,285
You like taking risks, young man.

798
01:20:59,521 --> 01:21:03,685
I have friends among the diners.
Let's not cause a scene.

799
01:21:03,959 --> 01:21:05,790
- How much?
- Be reasonable.

800
01:21:06,027 --> 01:21:08,518
You won't have enough.

801
01:21:09,064 --> 01:21:12,795
I'm sure your young friend here
can do better.

802
01:21:13,034 --> 01:21:17,494
If he can afford a meal here,
he can afford all Paris.

803
01:21:18,707 --> 01:21:22,268
Tomorrow at noon.
The foyer of the Salle Favart.

804
01:21:22,744 --> 01:21:24,371
I know a restaurant nearby.

805
01:21:24,813 --> 01:21:26,041
There!

806
01:21:26,314 --> 01:21:28,805
Thanks to your friend's sang-froid,

807
01:21:29,050 --> 01:21:31,644
we'll all have a splendid evening.

808
01:21:34,856 --> 01:21:35,982
I wish I'd killed him.

809
01:21:36,858 --> 01:21:37,847
No fear, I'm here.

810
01:21:38,193 --> 01:21:39,490
Don't worry.

811
01:21:47,002 --> 01:21:48,799
A very old friend.

812
01:22:40,455 --> 01:22:43,788
Work won't get done
with you looking out the window.

813
01:22:44,059 --> 01:22:47,085
Not that it's my business.

814
01:22:47,329 --> 01:22:51,789
You're engaged to the boss's son,
you can do as you please.

815
01:23:07,582 --> 01:23:08,549
Are you hurt?

816
01:23:08,783 --> 01:23:10,273
It's his blood, not mine.

817
01:23:12,921 --> 01:23:15,287
I couldn't let him blackmail us.

818
01:23:21,763 --> 01:23:23,754
You risk nothing now.

819
01:23:24,432 --> 01:23:25,922
No one will hurt you.

820
01:23:26,601 --> 01:23:27,795
Ever.

821
01:23:38,346 --> 01:23:41,179
Wait, no questions. You'll see.

822
01:23:52,227 --> 01:23:53,592
Explain.

823
01:23:57,165 --> 01:23:59,292
Boulevard Malesherbes. . .

824
01:23:59,801 --> 01:24:02,167
Saint Augustin. . .
Come and see.

825
01:24:04,072 --> 01:24:06,006
Parc Monceau over there.

826
01:24:08,243 --> 01:24:10,302
The classy area, Yvonne.

827
01:24:11,212 --> 01:24:14,477
If you want, it's yours. . . Ours.

828
01:24:15,850 --> 01:24:17,317
I can't.

829
01:24:19,521 --> 01:24:21,113
I can't love any more.

830
01:24:21,356 --> 01:24:22,823
Listen to me.

831
01:24:23,491 --> 01:24:25,891
I'll do all I can to get Jean back.

832
01:24:26,694 --> 01:24:29,686
But let me love you.
You know I'm dying to.

833
01:24:30,532 --> 01:24:33,626
I'll make you happy, Sara.
I've love enough for two.

834
01:24:33,868 --> 01:24:35,859
I'll love you like a man.

835
01:24:39,340 --> 01:24:41,331
I want you to be mine.

836
01:24:43,945 --> 01:24:44,843
Marry me.

837
01:24:46,414 --> 01:24:48,678
I'm sure it's what Jean would want.

838
01:25:26,254 --> 01:25:27,721
Hello, Herr Stroeger!

839
01:25:27,956 --> 01:25:30,288
I have excellent news.

840
01:25:33,595 --> 01:25:37,463
The Commission has accepted
your candidature.

841
01:25:37,732 --> 01:25:40,701
You're now the official owner

842
01:25:40,935 --> 01:25:44,371
of Boulogne Laundries,
my dear Jacques.

843
01:25:46,641 --> 01:25:49,576
There is one formality. . .

844
01:25:50,345 --> 01:25:52,074
The payments were made?

845
01:25:52,313 --> 01:25:54,076
Just as you said, yes.

846
01:25:54,315 --> 01:25:57,045
Half in Bern, half in Monaco.

847
01:25:57,285 --> 01:25:59,549
I will say it wasn't easy.

848
01:26:03,324 --> 01:26:05,224
Perfect.

849
01:26:05,460 --> 01:26:09,055
You're a remarkable
businessman, old chap.

850
01:26:09,964 --> 01:26:13,297
- Any news of my brother?
- Yes.

851
01:26:13,868 --> 01:26:16,098
He's been transferred to Dachau.

852
01:26:18,273 --> 01:26:19,570
A concentration camp.

853
01:26:20,008 --> 01:26:22,340
From which there's no return.

854
01:26:23,478 --> 01:26:27,915
From what I could learn,
he refused to be re-educated.

855
01:26:28,950 --> 01:26:30,975
Don't let it upset you.

856
01:26:31,219 --> 01:26:32,618
On the contrary,

857
01:26:33,121 --> 01:26:34,418
thank the Fuhrer

858
01:26:35,023 --> 01:26:37,924
for cleansing your family.

859
01:26:38,226 --> 01:26:40,285
And for making it rich.

860
01:27:25,273 --> 01:27:30,336
Live in the present, dammit!
If not for me, then for the baby!

861
01:27:30,578 --> 01:27:33,172
You'll never take away my memories!

862
01:27:37,719 --> 01:27:38,981
What is it?

863
01:27:40,688 --> 01:27:42,053
The baby?

864
01:27:42,457 --> 01:27:43,981
Come on, come on. . .

865
01:28:04,979 --> 01:28:08,073
I didn't want to lose it.
It came early.

866
01:28:08,449 --> 01:28:11,384
Our son's fine. He's out of danger.

867
01:28:11,919 --> 01:28:13,284
It's a boy?

868
01:28:19,827 --> 01:28:22,227
- Armand. After father.
- No. Jean.

869
01:28:22,664 --> 01:28:24,564
To keep hope alive

870
01:28:24,799 --> 01:28:27,097
and stop people forgetting him.

871
01:28:33,775 --> 01:28:34,901
Yes, Jeannot. . .

872
01:28:35,143 --> 01:28:37,304
Give him to Yvonne.
It's his bedtime.

873
01:28:37,578 --> 01:28:40,206
It's his baptism,
we want to enjoy him.

874
01:28:41,115 --> 01:28:42,878
Give him to Valentine.

875
01:28:44,285 --> 01:28:46,446
Valentine, can you take him to bed?

876
01:28:55,163 --> 01:28:57,996
I hesitated long,
but the day has come.

877
01:28:58,266 --> 01:29:02,259
Jacques, for these past two years
I can't praise you enough.

878
01:29:02,503 --> 01:29:04,562
Lavandier Laundries has prospered

879
01:29:04,806 --> 01:29:06,569
despite difficult times.

880
01:29:06,808 --> 01:29:09,072
You've assured
the family's future.

881
01:29:09,310 --> 01:29:12,336
You've paid off
all the errors of your past.

882
01:29:13,014 --> 01:29:16,279
It's time for your mother and I
to retire

883
01:29:16,517 --> 01:29:18,348
and pass the business on to you

884
01:29:19,053 --> 01:29:20,486
and to Yvonne.

885
01:29:21,389 --> 01:29:23,482
I'm so proud of you.

886
01:29:25,860 --> 01:29:27,327
Quite a reaction !

887
01:29:28,496 --> 01:29:29,963
Are you blind?

888
01:29:30,198 --> 01:29:33,326
Don't you wonder how Jacques
bought Boulogne Laundries?

889
01:29:33,568 --> 01:29:36,628
I n line with the laws of France.
As Pétain said. . .

890
01:29:36,871 --> 01:29:39,806
De Gaulle landed with the Allies
over a month ago.

891
01:29:40,041 --> 01:29:42,669
So your Pétain better start packing !

892
01:29:46,781 --> 01:29:48,112
Your wife's impossible.

893
01:29:50,084 --> 01:29:51,608
What's more, she's Jewish.

894
01:29:52,587 --> 01:29:55,715
Her name's Sara Morgenstern.
Yvonne's a false name.

895
01:29:57,091 --> 01:29:58,854
Your grandson's a Jew.

896
01:29:59,494 --> 01:30:00,825
Say nothing, Armand.

897
01:30:01,329 --> 01:30:04,560
Not one word.
Or you'll never see me again.

898
01:30:27,121 --> 01:30:28,748
Jacques Lavandier?

899
01:30:29,023 --> 01:30:30,183
That's me.

900
01:30:30,425 --> 01:30:32,757
You're under arrest, pal.

901
01:31:12,900 --> 01:31:14,299
Jeannot's well.

902
01:31:15,336 --> 01:31:17,531
He's grown. He misses you.

903
01:31:17,772 --> 01:31:18,796
Do you?

904
01:31:19,073 --> 01:31:20,700
Your wife will testify.

905
01:31:20,942 --> 01:31:23,638
Hiding and marrying an Israelite
is favorable to you.

906
01:31:23,778 --> 01:31:26,645
I'll say you dealt with the Germans
to save your brother.

907
01:31:27,415 --> 01:31:29,576
I want you to see your son grow up.

908
01:31:30,451 --> 01:31:34,785
So, other than purchasing
the laundries

909
01:31:35,022 --> 01:31:38,423
run during the occupation
by the Gestapo,

910
01:31:38,659 --> 01:31:41,958
you are also accused
of pillaging the assets of Jews,

911
01:31:42,196 --> 01:31:43,925
clients of Lavandier Laundries,

912
01:31:44,165 --> 01:31:48,932
by organizing burglaries
of their abandoned homes.

913
01:31:51,439 --> 01:31:53,066
Say it's not true.

914
01:31:55,676 --> 01:31:59,476
I dealt with the occupiers
to save my brother,

915
01:31:59,714 --> 01:32:02,012
Jean Lavandier, deported in 1942.

916
01:32:02,517 --> 01:32:05,645
I paid bribes to obtain information.

917
01:32:05,887 --> 01:32:08,412
But my contacts
became more and more greedy.

918
01:32:10,858 --> 01:32:13,452
I did what I had to, Your Honor.

919
01:32:16,030 --> 01:32:17,861
That's how I traced my brother.

920
01:32:18,132 --> 01:32:20,760
To Dachau.
Since then I've had no news.

921
01:32:21,002 --> 01:32:24,165
Your Honor, many people tried
to buy back deportees.

922
01:32:24,405 --> 01:32:28,842
But they didn't all wheel and deal
with Nazis, M . Lavandier!

923
01:32:29,076 --> 01:32:30,543
Be seated.

924
01:32:32,513 --> 01:32:35,141
Prosecutor, you have the floor.

925
01:32:35,383 --> 01:32:37,613
You're lying, Lavandier!

926
01:32:37,852 --> 01:32:42,312
Not only did you collaborate
for two long years,

927
01:32:42,557 --> 01:32:46,323
you also committed an ignoble act.

928
01:32:46,561 --> 01:32:48,324
Bring in the witness.

929
01:32:59,707 --> 01:33:01,174
Name and profession.

930
01:33:01,409 --> 01:33:03,639
Geoffrey Breton, Police Inspector.

931
01:33:03,878 --> 01:33:08,542
Presently detained on remand
for active collaboration.

932
01:33:08,783 --> 01:33:13,311
Tell me, Breton,
do you recognize the defendant?

933
01:33:13,554 --> 01:33:15,681
Yes. We were in business together.

934
01:33:15,923 --> 01:33:17,720
On 3rd October 1942,

935
01:33:18,726 --> 01:33:20,557
if memory serves me right,

936
01:33:20,795 --> 01:33:23,195
he asked me to arrest his brother.

937
01:33:23,898 --> 01:33:26,366
I arrested him at 4 am.

938
01:33:31,606 --> 01:33:32,504
Silence!

939
01:33:53,127 --> 01:33:55,425
Police! Open up!

940
01:33:59,400 --> 01:34:01,231
M me Yvonne Lavandier?

941
01:34:01,669 --> 01:34:05,628
It's my duty to inform you
your husband, Jacques Lavandier,

942
01:34:05,906 --> 01:34:09,433
hanged himself in his cell.
I'm very sorry.

943
01:35:44,672 --> 01:35:47,869
Where did you come from?
Do you understand?

944
01:35:48,209 --> 01:35:49,904
- Which camp?

945
01:35:50,177 --> 01:35:52,645
- You were in Dachau?
- Dachau.

946
01:35:54,281 --> 01:35:58,012
He speaks German.
Can you check his ID?

947
01:36:14,135 --> 01:36:17,536
No point staying here,
there are no more trains.

948
01:36:36,157 --> 01:36:40,457
See. . . That's Jean.

949
01:36:44,632 --> 01:36:47,465
Valentine! Take the child, please.

950
01:36:53,507 --> 01:36:55,941
Yvonne! It's the Red Cross.

951
01:36:58,345 --> 01:37:00,540
What do they say? Where is he?

952
01:37:21,802 --> 01:37:23,895
Jean, it's me, Sara.

953
01:37:27,441 --> 01:37:29,466
Look at me, Jean.

954
01:37:29,710 --> 01:37:31,610
It's over, I'm here.

955
01:37:32,213 --> 01:37:33,771
Speak to me.

956
01:37:38,352 --> 01:37:40,650
What's wrong with him? Is it shock?

957
01:37:40,888 --> 01:37:44,187
Madame, his chances of survival
are very slim.

958
01:37:44,458 --> 01:37:45,982
I'm sorry.

959
01:37:46,694 --> 01:37:49,788
But he survived the camps.
Why should he die now?

960
01:37:50,030 --> 01:37:51,463
Care for him, he'll get well.

961
01:37:51,866 --> 01:37:53,800
There's nothing we can do.

962
01:37:55,302 --> 01:37:57,202
He's had a lobotomy.

963
01:37:59,974 --> 01:38:03,466
They performed them on homosexuals
in the camps.

964
01:38:03,711 --> 01:38:06,874
Your brother-in-law underwent
several experiments.

965
01:38:07,414 --> 01:38:10,349
I'd like to tell you
he'll get better,

966
01:38:10,584 --> 01:38:12,711
but he's in a dreadful state.

967
01:38:12,987 --> 01:38:14,215
He was tortured,

968
01:38:14,488 --> 01:38:16,615
given hormone injections. . .

969
01:38:16,857 --> 01:38:21,624
From the scarring,
I'd say the lobotomy was last.

970
01:38:21,862 --> 01:38:25,491
He only has a few weeks to live.
You can do nothing.

971
01:38:25,833 --> 01:38:29,701
If he must die,
then it will be among family.

972
01:38:40,948 --> 01:38:42,813
See, nothing's changed.

973
01:38:45,052 --> 01:38:47,316
Oh, yes!
I added photos of Philippe.

974
01:38:49,356 --> 01:38:51,347
Your mother thinks he's handsome.

975
01:38:58,032 --> 01:39:01,832
She doesn't care who you love.
She loves you as you are.

976
01:39:11,245 --> 01:39:12,769
Let's put Trenet on.

977
01:40:06,533 --> 01:40:08,763
Go and get some rest.

978
01:40:22,116 --> 01:40:23,845
Sit with him.

979
01:40:35,362 --> 01:40:37,523
I'll make him some soup.

980
01:40:41,402 --> 01:40:44,166
What did they do to you, son?

981
01:40:46,040 --> 01:40:47,769
What did they do to you?

982
01:42:28,675 --> 01:42:30,370
All right, Grandma Sara?

983
01:42:31,111 --> 01:42:33,375
Don't worry, Gran, we're with you.

984
01:42:38,118 --> 01:42:41,747
Mom, wait for us.
You're really impossible!

985
01:42:43,857 --> 01:42:46,291
<i>Deportation memorial</i>

986
01:42:51,632 --> 01:42:53,497
Hello, Sara.

987
01:42:55,602 --> 01:42:58,230
Sorry, you must wait
for the ceremony to end.

988
01:43:00,774 --> 01:43:03,106
We've been waiting
for over 50 years!

989
01:43:03,944 --> 01:43:05,775
O K, you can let them in.

990
01:43:31,405 --> 01:43:34,704
Minister, the cars are here.
This way, please.

991
01:44:08,242 --> 01:44:11,973
- Sorry, I can't let you through.
- It's only a bouquet.

992
01:44:12,212 --> 01:44:14,305
The crypt is officials only.

993
01:44:15,415 --> 01:44:17,383
You can stop me going in.

994
01:44:17,618 --> 01:44:19,848
But you can't stop me remembering.

995
01:45:14,308 --> 01:45:18,540
It was not until 2001
that the deportation of homosexuals

996
01:45:18,779 --> 01:45:22,215
was officially recognized
by the French State.

997
01:45:22,449 --> 01:45:26,112
The deportation of German
homosexuals began in 1933

998
01:45:26,353 --> 01:45:28,321
with the Nazis' rise to power,

999
01:45:28,588 --> 01:45:31,648
then spread to occupied
or annexed countries.

1000
01:45:31,925 --> 01:45:34,393
According to
the US Holocaust Memorial

1001
01:45:34,628 --> 01:45:38,155
100, 000 homosexuals were arrested
between 1933 and 1945.

1002
01:45:38,432 --> 01:45:40,423
10,000 to 15,000 died in camps.

1003
01:45:40,667 --> 01:45:43,636
The 1942 law
criminalizing homosexuality

1004
01:45:43,870 --> 01:45:45,838
was upheld at the Liberation.

1005
01:45:46,106 --> 01:45:48,097
It wasn't repealed until 1981.

