'North Sea, Texas'
It is...
...good.
Agreed.
A, b, c, d, e, f, g,
h, i, j, k, l, m, n, o...
Open eyes.
Put it on the chair, Marie.
And help me undress.
Lily of the valley.
Thanks, Marie, you can go now.
What are you doing in my room?
Hey, Pim...
Come down, you fool.
Mom's not angry.
Look what I found, children.
A little boy.
Hush, it's over now.
Get Pim a glass of water.
It's ok.
Here you go, Mister.
You smell good.
You smell really nice.
- It's Yvette’s perfume.
It's time to go home, now.
But the puzzle's not finished yet.
I know your mother doesn't worry,
but I don't want her...
Just a bit longer.
You better go now.
Bye, Pim.
Here.
Hi, Mirza.
Here. That's pretty good.
'My left hand is the maid'
You'll see when I turn eighteen.
It'll be a shiny motorbike
instead of a bicycle.
Eighteen.
Look. A Suzuki 380 GT.
You can ride on it.
- I?
It's hot.
Pim, just imagine. 380cc.
When you turn fifteen,
you can have my bike,
for your birthday.
Thanks, Gino.
Wow.
Pimmy. You bastard.
The door.
The bell's ringing.
For you. From me.
A boy needs a knife.
Étienne.
Wasn't yesterday your birthday?
It's tomorrow. Fifteen.
Is that you, Étienne?
- Yvette.
Here. It's yours.
A boy needs a knife.
What do you say?
'Thank you, Étienne.'
Good dog.
Have some sardines later.
I will.
- Yes, thanks.
Behave yourself. Lock the doors.
You're a big boy.
We'll be back tomorrow.
So do you like it?
Your knife?
Thanks a lot, Étienne.
It's me.
Hello, 'me'.
You want some lemonade, Pim?
The latest news.
The latest news of the
day before yesterday.
Your boss is taking
my mother to Lille,
to the Accordion Festival.
They're staying over night.
When you tempt the devil...
My mother doesn't like that guy.
She's only interested in his car.
Silence is golden, Pim.
That's why we're so rich.
Mom, can Pim sleep over?
Can he?
Of course. It's not good to be on your
own all night in an empty house.
You can sleep in my bed.
It's summer. We'll sleep out in
the dunes. In a tent, Pim and me.
A gift from my mother.
From my boss.
Not bad.
Now we both have a knife.
It's my birthday tomorrow.
That's why.
No one needs to know about this,
Pimmy. It's just between us.
Hip Hip Hurray.
- Cheers.
- Cheer.
For your birthday.
Pencils. Thanks, Sabrina.
I don't have a 4B.
Coffee?
Pim?
Yes.
Dreamer.
Did you sleep alright in the tent?
We should do it more often.
Mom made pancakes, can you believe it?
Of course, like always.
Can Pim come to Aunt Ginette's?
No, that's impossible.
Right. They’re a different
species, those French.
I'm going to lie down.
No kiss from you, then?
You're making pancakes? I could...
When I learn the steps, I'll show you.
Pim?
- Yes?
Dreamer.
I use a glue stick. It's cleaner.
The bike.
Beauty and the Beast.
- Watch what you say, man.
What are you thinking?
You forgot to bring the tent.
Well...
- Wait.
Here. Happy birthday.
Thanks.
It's me.
- Hi, 'me'.
You want some lemonade, Pim?
- We gotta go, Pim and me.
Not on the Motorway.
- Ok, Mom.
Let’s go.
- Already?
I gotta go.
- Where to?
La Panne.
Can I come?
- No.
Why not?
- You just can’t.
Not together?
We'll go together next time.
- Promise?
I promise. Come on.
Not a word to anyone, ok?
Back already?
- Yeah. Gino's bike broke.
Étienne, couldn't you...
- Of course, what's the problem?
Oh, well, it's the carburettor.
The carburettor? We'll just
change it. I'll take a look.
Is Gino at home?
- Yes,... well,... no.
It's not necessary. Don't go.
It's no problem...
- It's not necessary!
Gino can do it himself.
- Pim.
What have you got against Étienne?
A little politeness please.
Well, I'll pick you up on Saturday
for the Accordion Final. Yvette.
We're going to Texas after.
We'll be back around eleven.
Ta-ta.
A, b, c, d...
...e, f, g...
Gino.
It's me.
Hello, my boy.
I’m just mending my dress...
Gino went to Dunkerque.
Why doesn’t he find a
girlfriend who lives closer?
The missus wanted to
go dancing. In La Panne.
Her name is Françoise.
You want some lemonade?
It's orange.
Gino and dancing.
Children grow up.
Shell I open the white?
The orange is flat.
He might bring her back later.
Françoise.
Françoise. She wears white sandals.
On a bike?
Don't tease the boy, Sabrina.
Such a bike is expensive,
even second hand .
And the salary of an
apprentice is small.
All Mom does is work.
But it's always been Gino's dream.
And you can save money
on so many things.
Sugar, for instance.
- Mom.
Just between us, Pim...
The sugar,
I collect them off the trays in the cafe.
The doctor doesn’t allow me sugar, but...
Mom.
they throw them away, those packets,
even when they haven't been opened.
Do you want a sandwich, Pim?
And yesterday, for
the first time, Gino...
...worked at the Burger Bar.
Friday nights and all day Sunday.
It pays rather well.
And Étienne says he's
doing well at the garage.
He learns quickly, our Gino.
And if there's a problem with
the bike, he can fix it himself.
He has golden hands, that boy.
Gino will be back late.
What do you expect? He's eighteen.
And that girl loves to dance.
Well, the paperboy has to go.
I'm going to bed.
I've been tired lately.
You don't want anything to drink?
You're going to Café Texas?
- Yeah.
When the cat's away...
Your mother's not here yet.
Did you give her the papers?
Is Marcella still as crazy?
Where's your mother playing tonight?
Is it far?
La Panne.
From now on he can bring
me the old papers.
He's a good boy.
Something to drink?
Well? Still no girlfriend?
Grenadine.
Oh, her name is Grenadine?
Certainly not from around here.
No no no, he doesn't
know yet. Right, my boy?
So, you don't look at girls?
Tell us. Which one of us do you like?
Go on, tell us.
Go on, read the magazine.
Or do some drawing, little boy.
Ta-da.
- Better late than never...
Everything ok, my boy?
He can draw you later.
- Sure.
Come on, Pim. Who haven't you drawn?
Me, he hasn't drawn me, yet.
It's too hard. You're too beautiful.
Was it crowded in La Panne?
- Oh la la.
Hey. Stop it.
Here. A beer for a big boy.
Your mother agrees.
It... She...
Forget it.
Gino.
I'm gonna tell Mom.
Keep your mouth shut, ok?
This doesn’t work.
It takes two. Come on.
Don't be shy.
It's... wait.
What's the matter?
I'm not a dancer.
Do you think I'm pretty?
Yes.
Then hold me.
Sabrina, I...
Strange boy.
Thank you, Pim.
Tell me, what's her name,
that little French girl?
Gino's girlfriend.
I don't know.
Maybe he'll bring her to the fair.
Étienne says that she's cute.
Tell me. Are you going
to spend all night drawing?
Normal boys your age go
out with their friends.
Or with a girl.
Oh la la.
Normal women your age
no longer go out.
'Room for rent'
Sabrina.
Yes, water is included in the
price. Electricity and heating, too.
The bell.
The doorbell rang.
I didn't...
- I'm sure it rang.
Wait here.
Nobody there.
Here, have one.
- I don't smoke.
Very wise.
Have you heard from the gypsy
who rented the room before?
Zoltan? No.
He disappeared one day.
Flew off, like a bird.
With the Funfair.
That's happiness, my child.
North in summer, south in winter.
Venice, Paris, Le Pirée, Lima, Capri...
Foreign countries and foreigners.
Do whatever you want, no worries,...
...no children.
The room is fine.
Where's Pim?
- At a party. That's all he said.
Is he quiet at home, too?
You think he's quiet?
- Yes.
I don't think so.
I often hear his voice.
That boy lives in another world.
I try to read his thoughts.
Draw, draw, that he can do.
But I almost never see his drawings.
Sometimes I worry, Sabrina, you know?
I only have one son.
Pim is a dreamer.
Tell me... What's her name?
Françoise. But it's
not certain that she...
Well...
Tell her you liked the room.
Why didn't she come to
see it herself? Is she shy?
What kind of work is
she looking for here?
There's no more work here
than in Northern France.
Oh yes, no visitors in the
room. Tell your brother.
Does she speak Dutch?
You don't even know that?
Plenty of rest, the doctor says.
Get Pim a drink.
Fortunately I still have my
daughter, now that Gino has left.
The house has become so very big.
He moved in with her.
They both work at a
restaurant in Dunkerque.
Washing dishes? Mopping the floor?
I don't know.
He didn't even come to the hospital.
- Gino doesn't like hospitals.
Well, I'm off.
Pim.
That Étienne. What was he
thinking, bloody idiot?
At the hotel in Lille,
we fooled around a bit.
It was just a little fun.
But I said it mustn't happen again.
When we came back from Dunkerque,
he parked his car in a picnic area.
He couldn't keep his hands off me.
I bit him.
Come inside, Mom.
You'll catch a cold.
Yes.
Mirza. Mirza.
Zoltan.
You're here.
Hello, Yvette.
I'm back.
Pim will show you the room.
You can hang your clothes
here, on the hooks.
Grown up now.
That's normal, I'm sixteen.
Did you give Zoltan a clean towel?
A towel, yes.
The extra money will come in handy.
He's rented the room before.
He was only a boy then.
He's a man now.
Finally we can take
down the damn posters.
I can't believe Françoise
wanted to rent it.
You still drink red wine?
Zoltan.
- Pim.
Pimmy.
I remember.
Shall I play a tune for
you gentlemen? A waltz.
Mirza.
Where were you all night?
Well, my friend. You little rascal.
Make yourself a sandwich.
There's some jam left.
I'll clean up.
It's Friday. I'm going out.
Hush.
He'll be back.
Hi, Pim. Is your mother working today?
She is working.
What do you want to
drink? Some grenadine?
He's probably a Romanian.
No, he's a Bulgarian
in search of happiness.
Grenadine.
Why doesn't he sleep in the caravan,
at the bumper cars?
Oh, just ignore him, Pim?
Here. It's on the house.
And when the fair ends,
is he going to stay?
Better a big car than a big guy, Julien.
Life's short too short.
Just shut up, now.
Tonight, spaghetti.
Then you know more than me.
Pimmy? A towel, please.
Ok.
There's vanilla ice cream for dessert.
Dessert?
- Yes, dessert.
The Cologne Fair, it's worth seeing.
Pimmy, you wouldn't believe your eyes.
It's very large, there's always work.
We'll play this tomorrow.
You are my audience.
Yeah?
Gino.
Yeah.
Ok, what is it...
Sabrina.
Sabrina has a crush on you.
I can see it. She's crazy about you.
But you already know that.
You're going to be seventeen, Pimmy.
Seventeen.
You gotta...
We both gotta...
Sometimes you have to make a choice.
I was going to tell you about Françoise.
Pimmy, wait.
We can still be friends.
We were children. Kids.
It was just play.
Imagine, you and Sabrina.
It would be fantastic.
I'm leaving. There is a fair in Cologne,
Zoltan will take me there with him.
The gypsy?
You're beautiful when you're jealous.
- Who's jealous?
You think I was in love with you?
Pim.
Be quiet.
Bring me a drink, Pim.
No no no, wine.
Wine.
Zoltan, you look good.
Yes, I'm going out.
Some wine, Zoltan?
Thank you, Pimmy.
Thank you.
Pimmy, see you later.
- See you later.
Bye.
What a fool.
The boy is completely lost.
He slept the whole
afternoon on the sofa.
He just woke up.
You don't need to tell me, I live here.
Here.
You can sleep in Gino's room tonight.
And tomorrow. And the
day after tomorrow.
Your soup's getting cold, Sabrina.
Pim really can't come to live with us.
He's always been part of this family.
Yeah, I'd noticed.
That didn't bother you before.
- That's in the past.
Little Pim found his way.
When the gypsy was living with
them, we never saw him.
You knew that Pim and Gino...
- He's staying here.
That boy has never had a true home.
Some mother. Gone with the wind.
Yvette.
Even your father wasn't
immune to that man-eater.
That rhymes.
Yvette Mimosa. With her seductive
manner and her accordion.
That blonde slut thought
she could have them all.
When one left, he was
immediately replaced.
She was unfaithful, Miss
Provocative. That hasn't changed.
Oh, my handsome Stefano.
You don't have a picture, Mom?
All women have a picture of...
Stop asking me.
I should check my kidneys.
I have the right to know
what my father looked like.
Sabrina, I... I can...
Is he still alive, at
least? I just want to know.
No, I don't know. And don't speak
to me in this tone of voice, ok?
I used to be better at this.
Shall I make tea?
Where are you going?
Nowhere. Out for some air.
Put on your coat.
- It's summer, Mom.
But it feels like autumn. And stop
at the butcher's on the way back.
Who said I was coming back?
- Half a pound of sliced bacon, Sabrina.
So quick.
My bag.
Where are you going?
What are you looking for?
Can I help you?
Your father.
Look.
Mom?
Mom.
A, b, c, d, e,
f, g, h, i, j, k, l, m,
n, o, p, q, r,
s, t, u, v, w, x, y, z.
The sea.
Where's Françoise?
She didn't feel well.
What a bitch.
Want some water?
Sure.
'House to let'
Ms. Desmet said there are still
things belonging of your mother,
and he asked what to do with them.
Ditch them.
Make yourself a sandwich.
Perhaps I can bring back some Takeaway.
Dreadful weather.
Can I come in?
Hush, Mirza.
Horrible rain.
- You can say that loud.
Your sister's not here.
On Monday, Tuesday and...
I came to see you.
Here.
Do you want something to drink?
- Beer.
I'm living here temporarily.
So you know.
It's temporary.
What do you want from me?
I was waiting for you.
Here, a gift is forever.
Keep it in a knot,...
...and you'll never forget me.
Stay.