I've really got to use
My imagination
Mm, to think of
good reasons
To keep on keepin' on
Keep on keepin' on
- Got to make the best of.
- Best of, best of
- A bad situation.
- Bad situation
Ever since that day
I woke up and found
that you were gone
Gone, gone
Darkness all around me
Blackin' out the sun
Old friends call me
But I just don't feel
like talkin' to anyone
Emptiness has found me
And it just won't let me go
Go right on livin'
But why, I just don't know
Ladies and gentlemen,
the moment we've all
been waiting for,
the one, the only
Linda Lovelace!
- What's your name?
- Linda Lovelace.
I meant what's your real name?
- That's my real name.
- So, what did you do
before you were the first ever
pornographic film superstar?
How does it feel to
be the poster girl
for the sexual revolution?
The pornographic
film Deep Throat
has become one of
the most popular
and profitable Blue
movies of all time.
Today a Manhattan criminal court
judge ruled the film obscene
and ordered it removed from
theaters in New York City.
This is kind of a strange country, isn't it?
Judges can see Deep Throat,
- but they can't listen to those tapes.
- Deep Throat,
a trendsetting film that brought
pornography into popular culture.
How did you become Linda
Lovelace in the first place,
if you were born
as Linda Boreman?
I think you can be a star,
and I don't mean just
an adult-movie star.
I mean a real star.
Is your name Linda Lovelace?
So tell me,
who's the real Linda Lovelace?
Just give me some
kind of sign, girl
Oh, my baby, to show me that
you're mine, girl, oh, yeah
Just give me some
kind of sign, girl
Oh, my darlin', to show
me that you're mine, girl
All right so if
you do want me
Give me little sweet talk
If you don't want me
Don't lead me on, girl
But if you need me Show
me that you love me
And when I'm feeling down
- No! Patsy! Come on.
- Jeez! Come on, Miss Holy Holy.
- You want to get tan lines?
- Mm.
You're gonna thank me later.
So have you slept
with that guy yet?
- No. Patsy, come on.
- Don't be such a prude.
- You're 21 years old.
- Prude?
How am I a prude?
I think I've learned
my lesson that one time,
thank you very much.
There are other things
that you can do.
Ugh. I don't even know how
to talk to you anymore.
Seriously, that's disgusting.
That's disgusting.
- Linda!
- Shit, is that your Mom?
I thought you said
she was work.
- Linda.
- Take this, please.
- Yeah.
- Put it out.
Linda, are you out back?
Honestly, what is this,
a nudist colony?
- What are you wearing?
- Ma!
Get in the house.
I'm gonna be out all night
Okay? 'Cause everybody's
going fast.
- Ready?
- Ready.
- Careful.
- All I can see is your butt.
Oh, my God!
Cool band. They're missing
something, though,
- don't you think?
- Like what?
- Go-go dancers.
- You volunteering?
Never met a girl
who makes me feel
- Come on, babe.
- The way that you do
- Move your hips!
- You're all right
Whenever I'm asked what
makes my dreams real
- I tell 'em you do.
- Feel it!
So fee fi fo fum
Look out, baby
'Cause here I come
Now I'm bringing you
a love that's true
So get ready Get ready
- 'Cause here I come.
- Get ready
'Cause here I come
- Actually, like...
- Do that again.
- I know.
- You enjoyed it.
I need, like, a week off.
- You two move pretty good up there.
- Thanks.
You ever think about doing
that professionally?
Yeah, right.
Yeah! Dancing girls in Vegas, they
make two or 300 bucks a night.
What? Ha. Someone would pay
that much to see me dance?
I would.
I'm Chuck Traynor, by the way.
- I'm Patsy.
- Linda.
- You guys smoke grass?
- Yeah, sure.
Patsy, I have to go home now.
It's a little bit of grass.
Come on, babe.
Okay.
I'm good.
In accordance with your hopes,
mindful of your concerns,
sustained by your prayers,
- thank you, and good night.
- Thanks, honey.
President Nixon addressing
the nation live from...
Bye, Mom. Bye, Dad. See you later.
I'm going.
Linda!
Where do you think you're going?
The beach.
It's dark.
And what on Earth
do you have on?
- It's a party.
- And whose party is it?
Uh, I'm going with Patsy and her boyfriend Ray.
It's a friend of his.
- And what does this Ray do?
- I don't know, Ma.
It's not like I made him
fill out a questionnaire.
Mm-mm.
I think Patsy said he was
a bartender, all right?
But I did tell them that I had
to be home by 11:00 on the nose.
Any later, and I'll
call you, swear to God.
See you, sweetheart.
How long have we been
Traveling, my friend?
The French Connection.
You know that one?
- The one with that guy?
- Exactly.
My God, I was so stoned
when I saw that.
I couldn't figure out
what was going on.
I kept expecting there
to be subtitles.
- Yeah, there weren't.
- No, I know.
They were speaking American.
No, but by the time
I figured that out,
it was, like, halfway
through the movie.
Hey, guys. Let's
go skinny-dipping.
No! I gotta go, so...
- What?
- Yeah.
You're such a drag.
We're gonna go. Wooh!
Come on. I'm going in!
Jump in!
- You don't dig the ocean?
- No.
I don't know.
- Ow.
- What?
- You bit me.
- I did?
- Yeah.
- No, I didn't.
It's cool.
You don't think I'm a drag?
Well, I don't think
you're a drag at all.
- No?
- No way.
Thanks for the ride home.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Come on!
You haven't said a word
since we got in the car.
You can tell me.
What is it? What's going on?
Okay.
- I got pregnant.
- Mm.
And I had a baby last year,
and that's why we moved
here from Yonkers.
Where's this... Where's
this baby now?
I don't even know.
My mom put him
up for adoption.
She told me I was signing
circumcision papers.
- Damn.
- Yeah.
I'd like to meet your folks.
- Really?
- I think they'd dig me.
No, they don't dig anybody.
They don't even dig themselves.
Listen, I'll make you a bet.
You have me over for dinner,
and by the end of the night,
if they say, "What a
lovely young man,"
- then I win.
- What do you win?
You spend the night at my house.
And if they don't,
what do I win?
You spend the night
at my house.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay. Right there.
Lord, make us
thankful for these
and all our many blessings.
Amen.
- Amen.
Chuck, I'd like to
thank you again
- for those lovely flowers.
- My pleasure.
Linda tells us that you
were in the service.
Yes, ma'am, Marine Corps.
Mr. Boreman was
in World War II.
Oh, yeah? You in the Corps?
- No, Army. Italy, mostly.
- I was stationed in Korea.
I won a couple of
marksmanship competitions,
but that's about all
the action I ever saw.
I bet you would have
been brave, though.
The guys that served
with your father,
they're some of the bravest
men that I ever met.
So, what do you do now?
- I own a bar and restaurant.
- That's interesting.
What kind of bar
and restaurant?
Just good food and
pretty waitresses.
What do you do for
work, Mr. Boreman?
I was a cop in New York
before we moved to Florida.
Now I do security
at the airport.
Mr. Boreman has a
million stories, Chuck.
Is that right?
Johnny, you better go in the
kitchen and warm his milk.
Milk. Okay.
Mugs are above the sink, Linda.
- Jesus.
- Forget about them.
- Yeah, right.
- Yeah.
Where are you? Where
are you right now?
- I'm with you.
- Yeah.
Yeah, that's my girl.
You're my girl, hmm? Right?
Yeah.
They don't eat with
their hands, you dope.
- Say it.
- I... I'm...
I'm your girl.
How's it coming
out there, Linda?
Uh, almost there, Ma!
What time's the movie get out?
- I told you, 10:30.
- Be home at 11:00.
I know.
Seems like a nice young man.
Oh, right. Um...
Hey!
Just cut it out.
What are you so uptight about?
- My scar. It's gross.
- Come on. Foxy girl like you
should love to
show off her body.
Come on. Come on. Let me see.
Come on. Let me see it.
- It's gross.
- Please?
This is it? This little thing?
Ah.
It's ugly. I hate it.
Why? 'Cause it's different?
'Cause it's not perfect?
All those uptight
idiots in the suburbs.
All those cookie-cutter robots
that your mama goes
to church with.
I fooled around and fell...
Screw 'em.
'Cause this and you,
mm, are beautiful.
A girl that I liked
- I'd get out my book...
- Hey. I love your freckles.
You're late.
Come on, baby.
Yeah!
Wooh Baby
Lord, Lord, Lord...
To... Keep going. Keep going.
Boom.
And here we go.
You put a lot of
Margarita mix in there.
Uh, yeah. Okay.
To keep a flower growing
Margarita?
- Thanks.
- Hey.
Hey.
Mmm.
- You like porno?
- I like some.
You like 'em.
- No.
- I can tell.
- Yeah, you do.
- I don't.
- Yeah.
- I don't actually.
Trust me.
- I love your XXX.
- What are you doing?
- Hey!
- But Linda won't mind. She's cool.
Okay?
I wouldn't go in
there if I were you.
Oh, baby
We're making love
and I like it
- Oh, my God.
- Home movie.
My parents took one of me once,
but it didn't look like this.
I bet.
I've never seen
a porno before.
Is it turning you on?
Good girls don't
do that stuff.
Oh, 'cause you're a good girl?
I can tell you're
such a good girl.
That's what I love about you.
You're such a good girl.
Come on.
I don't want to.
You know, maybe that's 'cause
you're not any good at it.
- Come on. You're gonna love it.
- Really?
- Yeah. I'm gonna like it?
- Choking myself?
I could teach you. Remember how
I got you to quit smoking?
Yeah. You gonna hypnotize me?
It's the same mind-body
control technique.
Yeah?
Out of sight. Ah!
Hey, your mind has control.
Come on. A little more.
There you go.
Take it in. That's right.
Don't forget to breathe.
Come here.
Don't forget to breathe, Okay?
You got it. Okay? Go.
Oh, yeah.
When I die and they
lay me to rest
Gonna go to the place
that's the best
When I lay me down to die
Going up to the
spirit in the sky
Spirit in the sky
It's where I'm gonna
go when I die
When I die
When I die and they
lay me to rest
I'm gonna go to the
place that's the best
Prepare yourself you
know it's a must
Gotta have a
friend in Jesus
So you know that
when you die...
Congratulations,
Mrs. Chuck Traynor.
I've never done it with
a married man before.
- Me neither.
- Good.
That's where you're
gonna go when you die
When you die
When they die and
they lay you to rest
You're gonna go to the
place that's the best
- Hello.
- Hi. It's me.
Where are you? I've been
really worried about you.
Get some money,
and come get me.
- I'm in jail.
- Ha-ha. Very funny.
Here you go, ma'am.
Oh! Okay.
What happened, Chuck?
What did I say?
But this is different.
Wooh!
You said never ask
about your work.
That's right.
Some girls were turning
tricks out back.
What do you mean by...
Prostitution?
Yeah. Linda, it's a titty bar.
What do you think these girls live off?
Minimum wage?
Wait. The cops gonna
come ask me questions?
No. No, no, no,
no, no, no, baby.
Wives can't testify
against husbands.
Hey.
Look, all I need is money.
Look, after paying your
bail, I have, um, $32, $33.
Linda, real money.
It's the IRS and the Miami PD,
and it's all just
that shakedown.
- Do you have enough?
- "We."
Baby, do we have enough, right?
- No, we don't.
- Mm-mm.
- Not yet.
- So, what are we gonna do?
Mary had a little lamb, whose
fleece was white as snow,
and everywhere
that Mary went...
...the lamb was sure to go.
Yeah, right?
That... That was great.
- Did I tell you, or what, right?
- You did. You told us.
Sweetheart, there's a
little diner on the corner.
Why don't you run down, grab
us four coffees, regular?
- Okay.
- All right?
- On the corner?
- Yeah.
- Thanks a lot, darling.
- Beautiful work.
Jesus fucking Christ, Chuck.
What the fuck was that?
Does she even know what
she was auditioning for?
I know. I know. She's new at this professionally.
I could show you this thing.
Well, Chuck, she's really cute.
She's adorable.
She's like a sexy Raggedy
Ann or something.
- Cute freckles.
- Really dug her freckles. It was very...
But, you know, for this industry, I don't...
I don't know.
You don't know what, Jerry?
Go ahead. Be honest.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
No, look, the point is, we
traffic in fantasy here.
Yeah, she's very real, the kind of
girl you sit next to her in class.
You see her out on the street,
you want to ball her.
But, you know, you've seen the girls
that come in and do this now.
I mean, they've all
been to the surgeon.
I mean, you can't light
your cigarette around 'em.
You're afraid their
tits are gonna go up
like the Hindenburg
or something.
Linda has tits.
She does. Nice ones, too.
Not the point.
It's not like the old days, you
know, where you just point a camera
at two people screwing,
and you call it art.
I mean, the audiences
expect a lot more.
She's beautiful, but,
you know, more pizzazz.
- We need more pizzazz.
- No offense.
I'm gonna show you what
Jerry's talking about.
- No, I...
- Nicky, come here for a sec.
I want to show you this... I want
to show you this movie we made.
Now, this is the
prototype, right?
People want blonde
hair, huge tits,
and a nice, beautiful
round ass.
It's the harsh reality of
our chosen profession.
- Dynamite work, Nicky.
- Thanks, Butch.
I'm gonna show you this.
Chuck, we are
making a movie here
on 35 millimeter. Jerry
even wrote a script.
- 42 pages. You hear that?
- 42 fucking pages.
This thing is gonna
be in theaters,
and, look, people
want what they want.
Chuck, your girl,
she's cute, she's skinny.
She's got no hips.
It's like making a war movie
without the fighting.
Tits and ass,
that's the action.
Chuck, I don't want to bum you out.
Can she type?
Maybe I could find some
work for her in the office.
Look at this! Look at the...
I don't care about this.
Listen to me.
I know she doesn't have it.
Chuck.
- Look at that!
- We just saw what she could do.
- She acted? Couldn't act.
- Look what she can do.
- Look! See?
- Whoa, Butchie.
But... Are you...
Did you see this?
Look at this. Look at this.
Are you seeing this?
- Holy shit.
- Oh!
Wait. Is that real?
Is she actually doing that?
Yeah, right.
Ho ho! Oh, my God!
Yeah, can she do that
with a big cock?
- No offense.
- She can do that with anything.
Ah, that's far out. That is...
You see that?
That is art, baby. That's art.
If you ain't
getting your thing
Like you ought to be
Somebody else be getting
your thing for you
Better listen what I'm
saying now, fellas
If you ain't
getting your thing
Like you ought to be
Somebody else be getting
your thing for you
- Anybody want a hit?
- Jerry?
- Yeah?
- Not a cloud in the sky.
What's with all the
fucking lights?
Shadows, Butchie, shadows.
Your shadows are costing
me hundreds of dollars.
You want to turn the lights off?
You want it to look like shit?
No problem. I'll
turn 'em all off.
Fucking artist, huh?
- Bad toupee.
- Wants to make a movie without lights.
How long have you
been a makeup person?
Oh, I'm not a professional.
I mean, not in makeup, anyway.
You know, when you get to
be my age in this business,
it helps to have as
many skills as you can.
I don't have any skills.
That's not what I heard.
There she is. Here's
our star, huh?
What'd I tell you?
The girl next door.
Linda, this is our
financier, Anthony Romano.
It's very nice to meet you.
Sweetheart, let me
tell you something.
If what these guys
are saying is true,
this is gonna be the best
investment of my life.
I can't wait to see your work.
Yeah. Oh, and this is Dolly.
- This is Linda's costar and makeup artist.
- A pleasure.
- I have many skills.
- Yeah? Do you?
Let's let the stars get
back to work, huh?
All right. We'll
see you later.
Easy there, sister. Don't
cover her freckles.
Okay.
Hey. What are you doing?
Her freckles are her thing.
- All right?
- Okay.
Be cool.
You look good.
All right. Just not
too much, Okay?
- You hear me?
- Yeah, I hear you.
Wow, he's pretty intense.
I used to have an old
man like that once.
You know, I should probably...
...do something about those.
Mr. Damiano will be really pissed
if I just leave 'em like that.
- I'm so clumsy.
- I know, sweetie.
We all are.
There's just got to be more
to life than screwing around.
Than screwing around.
Sex, I don't enjoy it.
Linda? Harry.
We're getting it on
in the next scene.
Oh, hey. It's
nice to meet you.
I thought your name was Dick.
My stage name used
to be Dick Long,
but it sounded kind of
obvious, so you know...
Yeah. I agree.
This is a great
business, isn't it?
Anyway, I just
thought I'd come by
and introduce myself before
we started going at it.
You Okay?
I'm a little nervous.
I've never had lines
to talk before.
We got the best
job in the world.
We just tune everybody
out, live in the moment,
like we're the only two
people on the planet.
Tune everybody out.
- Live in the moment.
- Exactly.
You're gonna do great.
And I cannot wait
to get it on.
Action!
- Whoa. Whoa. You all right?
- Yeah.
You Okay? Yeah?
You're just gonna
drive normally.
You know what we're
doing, right?
- Mm-hmm. Right.
- Okay.
It's just I don't know
how I normally drive.
- You...
- I just drive, you know.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
Just drive,
and pretend we're not here, Okay?
Whatever you'd normally do.
All right, we rolling?
Let's roll.
Doing beautiful,
baby, beautiful!
All right, sound, speed.
And action.
It's not that I'm
turned off to sex.
I enjoy it. In fact,
I could spend the rest
of my life getting laid.
Then what seems to
be the problem?
Well, I don't know.
Something's different.
I mean, there's just
got to be more to it
- than just a lot of little tingles.
- Little tingles?
- I want to hear bells ringing.
- Bells?
- Dams bursting!
- Dams bursting?
- Bombs going off!
- Something.
- Nurse, Mrs. Lovelace is done with her bubbles.
- Thank you, Dr. Young.
- Open your mouth for me.
Wider. Ah.
- Ahh...
- Ah, ah, ah.
- Ah? Ah? Ah?
- Ah.
Well, there it is!
There it is, you
little bugger!
- What?
- Your clitoris.
It's down in the
bottom of your throat.
Oh now, now, Mrs. Lovelace.
There, there. Listen. It's
better to have a clitoris
deep down in the bottom of your throat
than to have no clitoris at all.
That's easy for you to say.
Suppose your balls
were in your ears.
Well, then, I could
hear myself coming.
And cut!
That was great.
That was great!
- That was fantastic, really.
- We good? Yeah.
Great work, everybody.
That's a wrap.
2 days down. 5 to go.
Nice work.
You see?
You see that? That's
gonna be a problem.
- I need you to do me a favor, Chuck.
- What's that?
I need you to go to Miami,
pick up some film tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Tomorrow? Why?
- Why?
- Yeah.
Because the stores
are all closed,
and if we run out of film
tomorrow, we're screwed.
But tomorrow's Linda's big day.
She needs me.
- Send somebody else.
- Okay.
How about I send
Linda for the film,
and you can spend tomorrow
with Harry's cock
- down your throat?
- Man.
You got no movie without
my girl, right?
- You know that, right, Butchie?
- Yeah.
And we ain't got no movie
without no film neither.
Yeah.
All right, this is it, everybody.
Here we go. Places!
Camera! And action!
You can try it on me.
You'll like it.
Well, what do I have to lose?
Not bad. We're all
gonna win Oscars.
Cut. Cut. Cut. Whoa! Harry?
- Mm!
- What's the matter?
What's happening?
What'd you...
- I don't... I'm... I...
- He came.
- Yeah. He what? He came?
- You came? Get outta here.
What is this,
your Junior prom?
I know. I didn't...
I just wasn't...
- Just give me 3 minutes.
- I can go again. I'm really sorry.
- Did I do something wrong?
- No.
- Wooh-hoo!
- No, thanks.
Hey! Hey, this is silk!
- Oyster?
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- How you doing?
Hey, oyster man! Yeah, come here.
We gotta talk.
- Oyster, sir?
- Best oysters in Miami. Come here, baby.
You know, these are natural
aphrodisiacs, honey.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, they make you horny.
I'm always horny.
Marry me.
No girl for you?
I can fix that.
- No, thanks, Charlie.
- Hey, Linda.
Why don't you come sit
on Mr. Romano's lap?
I'm having an interesting
conversation, Chuck.
Why don't you sit on his lap?
All right, come on.
Party's moving up to my room.
Where you going?
- Up to my room. Come on.
- We're going upstairs anyway.
Help me, help me
Let me hold it, baby
Hey, quiet.
Quiet. Quiet.
Oh, my God, that...
that's unbelievable.
- Who's in the next room?
- That's Linda and Chuck.
Girl should be in the
fucking Olympics.
I'm a little nervous.
Let's try this. Forget I'm even here.
Forget about all this stuff.
Just be yourself.
Okay, um, I don't think
for the movie poster,
we can be so anatomical.
Just don't want to disappoint
anybody... I guess.
Tell me about the
role you're playing.
A girl whose clit...
- I know all that.
- Okay.
Um, tell me about the
person you're playing.
Well, at first,
I'm closed up like a flower...
- Mm-hmm. Yeah?
- ... bud.
And, um...
And then, gradually,
the petals start to... to open,
and... and then...
...I finally learn about myself,
and I learn how to...
- ...to enjoy sex.
- Beautiful.
Then I feel free.
Don't worry. They're
just Polaroid shots.
Oh, I know. It's not that.
It's just...
You made me beautiful.
All right, all right, all right.
Hey, what's the matter?
Your girl is gonna be a star.
Yeah, great, but who
the hell's Lovelace?
It's a dynamite name.
You got to admit that.
What about my name?
Linda and I are a team.
- What's wrong with Traynor?
- Nothing. Chuck Traynor.
- Good name for a producer.
- So I'm a producer now? That's funny.
I thought I was a
production assistant.
A girl like Linda,
you want to see her name in lights.
Like "Linda Lovelace."
That's gotta go up on
a billboard, right?
"Lovely lace, Lovelace."
- You're gonna be filthy rich.
- Me? No. You're gonna make a fortune.
- Ah. Come on, Charlie.
- You don't think
the investors deserve to
make a little bit of money?
That's not what I'm saying.
And, you know, my
name isn't Charlie.
- Chuck.
- You got it.
Your girl's gonna be a star.
That's the value, man, and
you, you own the product.
- Two consenting adults.
- $6.00.
- Is it all guys in there?
- What do you care?
Keep on truckin', baby
Will you pass me a
cigarette, hon?
Do you mind if I
smoke while you eat?
Hey, did you hear
about Goldstein?
His magazine gave us 100
percent on the Peter meter.
Looks like we got a
full-blown big-titted hit!
What's the Peter meter?
Did they say anything about
how the film was shot?
Who gives a fuck, Jerry?
A hit's a hit.
Well, then, I could
hear myself coming.
This is Chief Rocker
Frankie Crocker,
on WNYJ Radio, New York City.
We're back with the star
of the scintillating skin flick,
Deep Throat, Linda Lovelace,
and the film director,
Jerry Damiano.
- Hi.
- Hello. Hello, New York.
Now, Jerry, you were saying
earlier how you as an artist
were able to Transcend
the pornographic medium.
Yeah. Well, you know, it
wasn't that difficult to do.
I mean, it was... The industry was
getting pretty stale, you know.
Everything was just screwing, screwing,
screwing, and then cut to a money shot.
You know, how many times you
supposed to look at that?
This film is becoming
bigger than that, right?
I mean, this is a phenomenon.
Baby, that's bad
So hard to bear, yeah...
I went to see Deep Throat 'cause
I'm fond of animal pictures.
I thought it was
about giraffes.
Feel like I'm on fire
And I'll keep on
trucking, baby
Linda, right here. Big
smile, Miss Lovelace.
I gotta keep on truckin'
I got to get your
sweet lovin'
How does it feel to be
the poster girl for the
sexual revolution?
It's just a goof.
To me, it's... it's a movie,
like any other movie,
only it has so many
better things in it.
- Like what?
- Like me.
Now now
Keep on truckin'
Yes, I got...
Now, Linda, I mean, what do you want
to do with the future here, baby?
I hope to make
movies, real movies,
and maybe do a play.
I want to be an
actress, you know.
The Mississippi River.
What's the only thing that has a
bigger mouth than Linda Lovelace?
Right here!
- Please, Miss Lovelace!
- Linda!
- Linda.
- That's what I call a welcoming committee.
- Right on.
- Linda.
- Hi, Mr. Hefner.
- Hef, please.
Welcome to your party.
How about I trade you
- two blondes for a brunette?
- Yeah.
Hear your mama come
You're the best
that she ever had
You come with me.
Yeah, mama won't you ride...
- Look at this.
- Butchie Peraino.
- Big fan of yours, Mr. Hefner.
- Thanks.
Anthony Romano, Mr. Hefner.
Love the magazine. Love the article
about the swinger parties.
Thank you. You, Harry, I'm
a big fan of your work.
It is truly an honor, sir.
Oh, I used to tell people
that I had the best job
in the world until
I saw what you do.
We'll see you
gentlemen inside.
- Look at these two cool cats.
- Mr. Sammy Davis Jr.
- Miss Lovelace.
- Sammy Davis Jr.
Better not miss this show.
- They love you.
- Makes me feel sort of tingly all over,
and then nothing. There's
got to be more to sex
than just a lot of
little tingles.
There's gotta be bells ringing
and dams bursting and bombs
going off, something!
You wanna get off, or you
want to wreck a city?
I think you can be a star.
I don't mean just an
adult-movie star.
I mean a real star.
Oh, I wish I could
believe that.
Well, trust me. I
see tons of girls
go through this town every year.
Most of them...
...go just like that.
I hear bells ringing...
...and dams bursting,
and bombs going off!
- Fabulous.
- Very sexy, right? Right?
No question. We're
getting laid tonight.
- We got a hit. We got a hit!
- No question.
Ladies and gentlemen, the moment
we've all been waiting for,
the one, the only,
Linda Lovelace!
Are you ready for this?
I want to set the
record straight.
All right, the first few are
just to establish a baseline,
so just answer yes or no.
Is your name Linda Lovelace?
Can we start with
an easier question?
All right. Are you currently
working on a book
- about your life with Chuck Traynor?
- Yes.
Are you taking this polygraph at
the request of the publisher?
Yes.
Were you married
to Chuck Traynor?
- Chuck, you're hurting me.
- I know. I know. I know.
- Chuck...
- Sh!
Chuck! Easy.
Chuck!
Stop it. Stop it, Chuck.
Chuck, s...
Oh, shh.
Hey.
Oh, God, that was
fucking far out.
Hey, come on.
Baby, you're my wife.
Don't trip out.
Hey.
You really hurt me, Chuck.
That was passion.
I love you.
Where's my girl?
You're my girl, right?
- Right.
- Yeah? Say it.
Say it.
- I'm your girl.
- Don't...
Hey. Hey.
What do you mean by...
Prostitution?
Wives can't testify
against husbands.
All just that shakedown.
All I need is money.
Baby, do we have enough?
It's just you and me.
We can't miss.
Hold up
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah
Who's that girl
knocking 'em dead
Whenever she's in town?
This is sure as shit more fun
than the convention, huh?
What do you do for a living?
I sell medical supplies.
How about you?
- Uh, I'm a part-time gynecologist.
- Really? Oh, that's so funny.
We're actually coming out with a new
set of stirrups that make it a lot...
I get it. That's
very funny, yeah.
- Should I take some drink orders?
- Yeah, yeah. What do you want?
- Oh, wow. A Cuba Libre would be great.
- Two Cuba Libres.
Don't worry about that. I got it.
Here you go.
Boy, she's... she's great.
- Mm-hmm.
- You guys married?
- Yeah, she's gonna be a star.
- Wow.
Hey, is that what
I think it is?
It is if you think it's coke.
Do you, uh, think I
could get a little?
You let people use your, um,
medical supplies for free?
- Okay. No, I get it.
- Yeah.
Yeah. Um... Well, how much?
How much for what? The
pussy or the blow?
- Seriously?
- Seriously.
Would you let it ride?
Would you let it...
It's your lucky day. I'm
gonna go get Linda.
Try, try, try Let it ride
Hey, look at me.
Try, try, try
Let it ride
- Hi, Ma.
- For the love of Christ, it's 2 am.
I know. I know.
Don't wake your father.
You want something to eat?
I got leftovers.
- You're a bag of bones, Linda.
- No, I'm not hungry, Mom.
So, what'd you wake me up in
the middle of the night for?
I was really hoping that,
uh, I could, um...
...move back in
here for a while.
- Here?
- Yeah.
No. You know that's
not possible.
- Why not?
- How would it look for a married woman
to move in with her parents
apart from her husband?
He hits me, Ma.
I can't say I'm surprised.
What did you do?
What do you mean, what'd I do?
What did you do to
make him angry?
He didn't just hit
you out of the Blue.
I guess I didn't do
what he wanted me to.
You took a vow,
a very serious vow.
Can't I just stay, like,
a few days, Ma, please?
And then what? You
gonna get a divorce?
What do you think
we are, Protestant?
Ma, you just don't understand.
Linda, I was...
I was 18 years old when
I had your sister,
unmarried...
...and all alone,
before I met your father.
I'd suffered long and hard.
How dare you come here and
tell me I don't understand.
I understand.
Now, God gave you a husband,
who provides for you.
And you...
Look at me.
Go home to Chuck.
Be a good wife.
Listen to him, and obey him.
Can't I just stay for a
little while, Mom, please?
Just please?
Mom, I just need,
like, a day, please.
- If you knew...
- That's enough.
- Hello?
- Dorothy, it's Chuck.
Hi, Chuck.
- I'm sorry. It's late.
- Yeah.
I'm looking for Linda.
You know where she is?
Yah!
I can't do it.
I can't do it anymore.
Yeah?
You can't do what?
Everything. I can't do it.
You're doing the movie, Linda.
You know me, right?
Huh? You believe me?
Right? You believe me?
Do you believe me?
Okay.
'Cause I worked
too fucking hard
to get you this part.
Now, you watch.
This movie is gonna make us.
You and me, Okay?
Oh.
Oh, there, there,
Mrs. Lovelace.
It's all right. Listen. It's
better to have a clitoris
deep down in the bottom of
your throat than to have
- no clitoris at all.
- That's easy for you say.
What if your balls
were in your ears?
Well, then, I'd
hear myself coming.
And cut!
That was great. That was great!
That was fantastic.
- We good?
- Yeah, we got it.
Great work, everybody.
That's a wrap.
2 days down. Five to go.
Here's your damn film.
Why don't you sit on his lap?
Who's in the next room?
Man, I don't think
that's them balling.
Oh!
If I tell you to sit,
stay, screw, fuck,
you'll do it, hmm?
Woman
- Take me in your arms.
- Hi!
- Hey.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God,
you look so beautiful.
And you look like a
poodle with a perm.
I'm kidding. You
look beautiful.
- Hey, Chuck.
- Hey, Patsy.
You look older.
All right, hurry it up. You
guys want to be quick?
I got some real important people
we gotta meet up with later.
Yeah. Picked out some dresses.
They're in the changing room.
Go on.
Wow, you look stunning.
Linda, can I be honest
with you about something?
- Yeah, of course.
- I'm worried about you.
- Why? Because of the movie?
- No.
I don't care about the movie.
It's everything. It's Chuck.
It's the people you...
Don't be crazy.
What is going on?
It's Chuck, isn't it?
Just tell me so I can help you.
Please? Please?
Do you know how lucky I am?
I mean, a... a girl like me
landing a guy like Chuck?
I'm nothing without him.
Jesus, Linda, you know
we're in a hurry.
Sorry.
Okay.
- Hey, little toast. - No, no.
- I'd like to propose a toast.
- All right, Harry.
- Oh.
To Linda, for sharing with me
the ten best minutes of
my professional career.
I heard it was the best ten seconds
of your career on the first day.
- Leave it to the broad to get honest.
- What about me?
You fucked me. If the movie's
such a hit, where's my cut?
I told Linda we're gonna double
her salary on Deep Throat 2.
She's gonna get $2,500.
How about that?
- You told Linda?
- Yeah.
Let me see the picture. It's
a full-on irregular pose.
No.
No. No! Chuck. Chuck, no!
Chuck, it's freezing! God!
Chuck!
It was stupid. I spoke
to Butchie Peraino
about my salary for the sequel.
I never spoke to anybody
about money after that,
that's for sure.
Did Chuck control
your finances?
Yes, he controlled everything.
I never saw a penny, not even
after we moved to Malibu.
Yeah, but the price
break doesn't...
I get pitched this
shit all the time.
It's gotta be something special.
- These are special.
- Could you make it glow?
- Huh?
- Like glow in the dark?
Yeah, that'd be groovy, right?
And it should say
"Lovelace" on the side,
and then Chuck Traynor
on the other side.
- Why would you want your name on the side?
- It's America, man!
Why wouldn't I want my name
on the side of a dildo?
You got it. I'll send
'em out right away.
- All right. Okay.
- Thanks.
Talk to you later.
All right, where'd
we leave off?
Uh, part about the first
time I screwed Linda?
"Chuck pushed me back."
His fat, rock-like
muscle tore into me.
- "Oh, my God, I said"
- What do you think?
- Sounds good.
- But you got a problem with it.
It's just that your
rock-like muscle
seems to play an
inordinately large role
- in Linda's autobiography.
- "Inordinately."
- How'd you get here?
- Mr. Hefner sent me.
Right. And how about the next
time I want your opinion,
I'll ask you what my
cock tastes like.
Yes, sir, boss. Reckon it
tastes like a pina colada.
Anthony.
- Hey, Chuck. How you doing?
- Look who's here.
- Hi, Anthony.
- Look at you. Look at you.
You're like a... You're like a
regular California girl. Come here.
- I thought you were in Vegas.
- Yeah. I just came back from the pa...
- What, are you kidding me?
- It's gonna look more like her.
Come outside. I want
to show you something.
Great to see you, kid.
- Jesus.
- Gonna put freckles.
Ah, Jesus.
How you been? Good to see you.
I bet you $10 the only thing
rock-like on that
man is his brain.
You're gonna get
us into trouble.
Baby, look at us. I think
we're already in trouble.
Good afternoon. Lovelace Enterprises.
Marsha speaking.
Nice car, Chuck. Must have
cost you a few dimes.
- I know why you're here.
- I should hope so.
I need a couple more weeks.
We got the Linda Lovelace blow-up dolls.
We got all the sex toys.
Hey, you're getting, like,
5 times your money back.
Man, you want a blow-up doll?
I got a couple in the house.
I don't want a fucking blow-up doll.
I want my 25 grand.
You'll get it. You're in on the
ground floor. We got the...
We got the Playboy
spread coming out.
- Mm-hmm.
- She's a brand name.
She's like Betty
fucking Crocker.
No, she's Linda
fucking Lovelace.
Listen to me. You
want to pay us back,
you get her doing
what she's good at.
Now, I got Deep Throat 2,
3, 4 lined up, ready to go.
- No...
- Now, this is big business we're talking about,
not some fucking nickel-and-dime
shit you're talking about.
See, that's where you're wrong.
This isn't small-time.
I'm meeting this guy
at Hef's party, Okay?
This guy, he owns half
the adult bookstores
on the West Coast,
millions in merchandise.
Linda, like, sweet
talks this guy, right?
Or better yet, she
sweet sucks this guy,
we're made in the shade!
Come on. You worry too much.
We're talking about
money, Chuck.
I always worry about money.
Well, what do I have to lose?
You know how sometimes...
life imitates art?
I think, um...
I think this is one
of those moments.
Chuck seems to have
left with the car.
Yeah. I see he hasn't changed.
- Well, come on. I'll give you a lift.
- Really?
Hey, why don't
we go someplace?
Let's grab a drink somewhere.
- You don't want to?
- It's probably best just to take you home, Linda.
- I'm sorry.
- Okay.
Chuck!
Hello?
Hi, Daddy. Did I wake you?
No. No, no, no. We're
just getting up.
It's late out there, huh?
It's Linda.
Well, who else would it
be at this time of day?
I just got home from a party.
Yeah, why am I not surprised?
No, Daddy, it was
a business party.
But I met Sammy Davis Jr.
- Who's Sammy Davis Jr.?
- You know who he is. He's that colored guy,
you know, "Mr. Bojangles."
- She's right.
- I know who he is, Dorothy.
I was just joshing.
Your mother, she, uh...
Every time that Johnny
Carson mentions your name,
she changes the channel.
I saw your movie.
I don't even know who
that was up there.
That's certainly not
my little girl.
I had to walk out.
Was it something that we did?
I keep thinking
that it has to be.
I gotta go, Daddy.
I'll tell your mother you
said you're all right.
I love you.
I'm sorry, Chuck. I looked
everywhere for you.
You lost us a movie
deal tonight,
just sitting up onstage
taking bows like...
...Princess fucking Grace.
- I'm sorry, Chuck.
- 50, maybe 100,000.
- To do another fuck film?
- No, Linda, it's Shakespeare.
I told them you do a
great English accent,
particularly with a
cock down your throat.
Hey. Hey! Hey!
I'm sorry, Chuck. I'm...
I'm not doing any more porn...
ever.
We're going to a party.
Come on.
- We just came from a party.
- Yeah.
All right, here it is.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Welcome to the party.
- Good to see you.
This is Mr. Shapiro. He's a
big-time Hollywood producer.
I'm a huge fan. I've seen
Throat, like, 10 times.
You look like... Let's go inside.
It's cool. It's...
In fact, I'm shooting
something right now.
- It'd be perfect for you.
- All right.
Oh, is that what this...
Is this an audition?
Linda Lovelace audition?
No, no.
- Give me a second.
- Absolutely. Sure.
Just give us some privacy
for a minute. Okay.
You just sit down right here.
Just have a seat.
You will sit here and
say nothing, Okay?
Keep shaking
everything you got
Rock and boogie
Chuck!
- Ah, man, you know what?
- What?
- No. - No, no, no.
- Come on. Come on.
What are you gonna do?
No, it's gonna be 6 times the money. Hey!
Listen to me! Come here.
Come here.
- This is crazy.
- Come here.
Come back in here. Shh!
Shut your mouth, Okay?
- You're gonna do this, you understand me?
- What?
You're gonna do...
Just shut it.
You're gonna do this,
and there's nothing you
or Hugh fucking Hefner can
do about it, all right?
- We're Okay?
- Okay.
Okay, Okay. I'll talk to her.
Chuck.
You know what? I don't
think this is gonna...
- Oh, no, no. This'll work fine.
- No.
Just... Yeah, it's just...
Okay, all right. That's...
- Baby, got a good one.
- Chuck! Chuck!
No...
Aw, man. Hi.
You all right?
Hey! Hey!
Linda! Linda! Hey!
Oh, honey, honey, honey, honey!
Stay down. Stay down.
Oh, my God.
Oh, Jesus. Get up.
Get up.
Oh, shit.
Step away from the lady!
- Sir, step away from the lady!
- She's my wife.
- Step away from the lady now!
- Look, I'm her husband.
- Is that true, ma'am?
- Yeah.
Ma'am, are you Okay?
Wait a minute. I know you.
You're that chick, right?
- That's Linda Lovelace.
- Blow-job girl?
Sir, take her home, and
get her cleaned up, Okay?
- You have a good night.
- Yeah.
Uh, hey, Miss Lovelace?
Uh, think I could
have your autograph?
Hi, operator.
I'd like to make
a collect call.
I wanted to talk to you
about the money Chuck owes.
You mean, uh, the money
you and Chuck owe?
Chuck always
handled the money,
so I've never seen any of it.
Okay, Linda, listen to me.
Just do another movie.
Call it whatever you want, Really
Deep Throat, I don't care.
One more movie, and
youse both out of debt.
The world wants to
see you, Linda,
but they only want to
see you do one thing.
You do another movie,
I'm gonna make sure
it's a classy production, and you're
gonna have any director you want.
I'm gonna bring Harry back. Come on.
It'll be like old times.
Jesus.
I just can't do it anymore.
- Here you go. Thanks.
- Thank you.
Hello? Linda?
- Shh. Shh.
- Can I help you?
Linda, it's Chuck, and I told
you I wanted to say I'm sorry.
- This is the hotel operator.
- Oh.
Um...
Traynor. Traynor's room.
Could you spell that, please?
Traynor, T-r-a-y-n-o-r?
- T-r-a-y-n-o-r?
- Yeah.
Checking.
I'm sorry. I don't see
a guest by that name.
Try Boreman. B-o-r-e-e-m-a-n?
- B-o-r-e-e-m-a-n?
- Um...
Any other... another name?
Uh, Lovelace?
I'm sorry. There isn't a
guest under that name.
Hello?
You stupid bitch.
Fuck.
Linda? Linda?
Linda?
Hey, Charlie.
Um... I thought you said
Linda was staying here.
She was. We switched
rooms this morning.
You're gonna have to find yourself
a new porn star, Charlie.
Um...
Hey. Hey, man. Is...?
No. No, no, no, no.
- Turn around. Turn around.
- No.
Aah!
Fucker. You're not gonna...
You're not gonna see her!
You're not gonna
think about her!
Hello?
This is Linda Marchiano.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
Okay. Okay, bye.
That was my publisher.
I passed the polygraph.
They believe me.
You really want this?
I just really want people to
know what happened, you know.
Well, we'll explain
in just a moment, uh,
why she is no
longer this person.
I hope she won't be offended
if I identify her by the name
that really has
become world-famous,
a woman who starred in
what has been called
the Gone With the
Wind of pornography.
Would you please welcome
Linda Lovelace?
Linda Lovelace's book
is titled Ordeal,
and it really was.
This is the...
This is the grimmest book
I've ever read in my life.
I mean, you've been
beaten, knocked around,
I mean, every liberty
in the world.
How'd you get involved
with all that stuff?
I mean, how could a nice girl like you...
How do you answer that?
Well, I had the misfortune
of meeting Chuck Traynor.
But it didn't start out
like you're describing.
He was a... a gentleman
when I first met him.
He was always opening doors for
me and lighting my cigarettes,
and he was very charming
when he wanted to be.
And I was young, you know.
I was...
I was 21 when I went
to live with him.
And it wasn't until after that that
things just started to change.
Uh, he started talking about
different sexual things,
things that I had never
heard of before,
things that I couldn't
imagine, you know.
I didn't want to. You
know, I was raised...
I was raised to
obey my husband,
to please him, for
better or for worse,
- so that's what I did.
- Dear God.
Linda, I have read
your book, Ordeal,
and I still find it very
hard to relate to you
and to believe that you have
become a changed person.
I expect people to
have great difficulty
realizing how hard it
was for me to get out,
but I think people
who have known fear
will understand it,
though, immediately.
Linda, do you think this
book will help bring about,
you know, any change for other girls
that are in this predicament?
I do have that hope. I... God
forbid there's somebody out there
that's going through
what I went through.
And maybe they can get the
courage to get out of it.
I hope this book helps
her to realize that...
...that you can come out of
this a complete person again.
Linda, you really were, and are, but
especially in the early seventies,
you were quite a celebrity.
Everybody talked about you.
All conversations about you
include a normal statement
that comes out dirty
because of the context.
That's an awful way for you...
That's gonna follow
you forever.
You know, I spent
exactly 17 days
in the pornography industry,
and somehow these 17 days
are supposed to define who I
am for the rest of my life,
but I hope that
people can see me
for who I really am.
I mean, Linda Lovelace was
a fictitious character.
My name is Linda Marchiano.
I can finally be myself.
I'm a mother and a wife,
and that is where
I found my joy.
Go ahead. We'll give you
a minute, all right?
Okay.
You made it.
I love you, Mom.
Oh, let's not make a
federal case out of this.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Hey, how are you?
- Good.
Let's get you
something to eat.
Good to see you. How you doing?
What have we got here?
Oh. Good to see you, man.
How you doing?