LOVE SICK
I met Alex on the first day
in college.
At first,
it was only a background
with a thousand questions,
requests and stupid.
I was somehow indifferent to it,
and I had no idea,
that was going to happen.
Caution!
Do not forget to tell mom
sent me to summer
clothes next week.
Good.
We will contact you via Mrs. Penes.
It is not Penes, Dad.
This is Mrs. Benes.
I would still catch Christine.
Bucharest crazy city!
What floor?
On 3rd.
Useless. If they were at home,
they would say.
I think I heard something.
Interestingly, this building
aseismic.
Even higher I die.
Hello. This is us.
Hello, welcome.
Its my father. He brought me here.
Nice to meet you.
Do not leave them in the hallway.
Take them into the room.
We have two garment bag
and several books and all.
Come on.
And the table.
Come into the room
Straight from the bags.
I'll put them in a corner.
They will not bother you.
It consumes a lot of electricity.
If this is a problem,
Dad can take back.
God forbid! Why it back?
This is a decent house, after all.
Yes, it's very nice.
Can we put these bags
in the room?
Of course. Over there.
My God, what I was thinking!
Where do you want to put the table?
It is needed for the reception?
This is just a small table.
I need for the exams.
Who will suffer?
You will help?
It is better to bring it together.
My daughter is a good girl.
It does not cause any problems.
I've never rented out rooms.
But my pills consumed me,
so that wriggle as I can.
That's life.
Alexander, my girl.
Your mother did not want you to
I lived on campus.
Never mind. I'm just happy that I got rid
cockroaches in my dorm.
Lord, Bucharest dirty city!
Let's just bring the table,
and then let's go eat.
Look, here's what the doctor
at the clinic gave me.
Look.
They are absolutely useless.
I did a survey
tests, x-rays, a whole lot.
You can not get them
free at your clinic?
The tests are expensive.
We can go to the table?
Come, my dear.
It is better to carry through the main entrance.
There's more space.
I do not want the neighbors to see you.
But what can you do?
Nothing.
Higher.
All is ready?
Hey!
I called you.
I'm Kristina,
friend of Alexandra.
You're her father.
Yes.
Let me help you.
Now it is easier?
Oh yeah.
Why does not the elevator?
He does not work.
Similarly, elevator repair.
Higher.
It's you again.
I have to lock the door.
There are so many bullies.
Come in.
It's not as cool as in a dormitory.
I've never lived in a dormitory,
because I'm from Bucharest,
but it was not easy for Alexandra.
We never told you,
but my mother was crying all day,
when we visited you.
She said that you live in the mud.
Kiki, you do not ask Ms. Benes,
to make room for me?
You have not agreed to?
Aunt Lucretia!
At least it's a decent house.
You need a whole wardrobe?
It is enough for clothes.
Oh, what a mess!
Aunt Lucretia,
Could you do a wardrobe?
Okay, honey.
I will take things.
And still it is necessary to release the shelf for books.
We will carry out old documents
to another room.
Women's magazine
Flacara for 1966.
Just lure for any insects!
You're lucky, Christina
recommended for you.
If not for her, I would not
take the room.
You are going home today?
Yes, but I do not want to go at night.
My brother, as usual.
Well, Alexander, if you do not want,
so I took some things,
I have to go.
I'd like to see your village.
Although I am not a family member.
Please anytime.
Kiki!
Who's there?
Kiki! You are welcome!
Tell him to quit.
I do not even know it.
Why did not you tell him?
Kiki, go out, please!
Let's bury the hatchet!
Sandhu, give it to me!
Come to me, and I will kill you!
What is this noise?
Sandu. We bickering with him.
Look a layer of dust.
Wait a minute. I think we
We have to decide in the first place ...
I asked Christine to tell a girl
I want to pay
for the six months ahead.
By October.
Like this?
May June July August,
September October.
In November.
November, right.
I was so angry with him.
I'm glad you came.
How about I finish here
and then we'll go have a drink?
No, I'll go to your father.
I said I wanted to go
to your parents.
What for?
We will go there in the summer.
Okay. We'll talk tomorrow.
You want me to I went with you?
I will not come at the first workshop.
We paid for the six months ahead,
so do not worry about it.
You did not help me
expand the book?
I'll get a scolding from her mother,
if you arrive late.
Well, I can not do it alone.
You'll be fine here.
Heavy student life.
But good, too!
This is French. Dubois.
Say, that girl ...
Is it not strange?
I do not know.
I do not think so.
It was the first night when
I slept at Alex with her.
I fell asleep drunk
from drinking beer,
and I dreamed that we were both
running in the rain,
as it were a race.
In the morning I woke up
and I looked at her.
She slept peacefully.
I smelled,
the smell of her sleep,
and I wanted
to see her every morning.
I'm leaving,
so I do not spoil your plans.
Stop.
I'm talking about your boyfriend Alex.
Alexandra is a girl!
Oh yes?
Well, then I'll wait and see.
Perfectly!
Are you happy?
I understand,
Why are you doing this.
As my mother said, it will take time,
to heal those wounds.
And what says the Pope?
You can sneer all you like,
but it will not change my feelings for you.
My feelings
We have changed.
If you want, let's start from the beginning.
I want you to leave me alone
and ceased to complicate my life.
I'm sorry, but it is not so simple?
I said,
we no longer see,
so be it.
Here is how? Why
we do not see?
Because I
sick of you.
I'm worried about how to
exam. And all red.
Do not touch my shirt.
This friendship is very important to me.
Alex - that's all that I
Now you need.
I like her.
She's really special.
I'm not interested.
You do not care what I want?
Do not call me more.
I want it all to stop.
And if you love me,
You will do as I ask.
Do you want this?
Yes.
Promise me that
perform my request.
If this is what you want,
I just disappear.
I asked you to stop all this.
I understood you.
The question is, are you ready
to the consequences?
Hey.
I hope I'm not late.
This is Alex.
Alexandra.
And this is my brother, Sandu.
Did you call me?
It was hard to hear.
I was on Kogalniceanu Square.
I took a taxi.
What are you drinking?
I will drink tea.
We drank some poison.
To what?
No, stay. I'm going.
So what do you want tea.
And you, Kiki?
You said that you go to work?
Your brother is also named
Alexander?
Why is too?
Your name is Alexander.
Did you quarrel?
No.
You look upset.
no need to complicate things.
We have no quarrel. We buried the hatchets.
Good. Here's what I bought you.
I hope, you like it.
I think they are beautiful.
I saw this and thought, earrings
about you. And I bought myself a ring.
What ring?
They are worn in the nose Indians
from Papua New Guinea.
This is my glass.
Too late.
So what? When I see you again?
on Sunday.
When?
Sandu.
You're cruel. Can I call
your birthday?
So far, Sanda.
That's how it should be worn.
That's cool.
Let's see fit
Does it to you.
That's great, but it does not go
the fact that I wear.
You do not like the earrings?
They do not fit in my clothes.
I do not want to go home.
Where shall we go?
To the cinema?
Let's take the cake.
Would you?
Are you still upset?
Why?
You look sad.
No. I'm happy that you came.
And I feel that I want
something sweet.
Wow, this old lady!
what happened?
I wanted to boil water for tea,
and she began to show me
how to turn off the faucet.
What I should not delay
it too much
otherwise I can rip it
and then flooded the bottom neighbors
and they are your friends.
I do not care who I flooded.
I have to boil the water.
I do not want to go home today.
You do not mind,
today if I stay with you?
Of course.
One moment, I'll make tea.
No, forget about the tea.
Stay here.
Then I just turn off the stove,
otherwise I will kill Benes.
Oh, you still made the tea.
Yes.
Careful, it's hot!
You're so thoughtful!
You'll make a good wife.
You have fun here!
How nice!
Let's just close
home for a week.
I did that.
When I lived with parents
summer, I spend days
I read in the garden.
Do not you bored?
Do not you want to go
the club with the guys?
No.
Where are your earrings?
You do not want to wear them?
Look in my bag.
In fact, I prefer the ring.
Take him.
Will you wear earrings.
They will approach you.
Your face is rounder.
My ears are not pierced.
What do you mean?
All the girls pierced ears.
And you did not wear earrings?
Never worn!
You're not allowed to?
No, my mother did not want to do
it hurts me when I was little.
And you want to look good
without earrings?
You know, I can
pierce your ears.
I do not want to pierce your ears!
As you want.
It can not hurt.
Calcined needle lighter,
Immerse yourself in the spirit, and
I quickly made a hole.
You do not even feel it!
No I do not want.
They did not fit.
I have a round face,
and I'll be like a monkey.
I'd rather admire them
on you.
And you really know how to do it?
what?
To pierce ears?
You've done this before?
Go find the needle!
Come on.
Well, if I do not die from this ...
Leave thread.
I did not find alcohol.
Why and thread?
You'll find out.
Lie down.
Wait, I do not see.
It does not hurt.
Do you have wool here?
Done.
Wait a bit!
Firmly hold. Come on.
No more.
Do you want to there was only one hole?
I do not want more earrings.
Look at me.
Everything will be fine. Tomorrow you will come
college these assholes get.
Come on!
I do not want them to
fell.
What is this noise?
Mother of God!
What are you doing over there?
Alex pierces ears.
Go to your room.
All is well.
Christine, my dear,
ears pierced now?
You could not wait until tomorrow?
Take your shit out of my ears.
Hold on tight!
Do you have any alcohol?
You many want?
Just moisten a bit
cotton wool.
God, why did I agree?
You were very brave.
I did not think I was so brave.
It should be wet with alcohol.
Otherwise it may fester.
Thank you, Aunt.
You were very nice.
Now I'll put Alexander to bed.
See you tomorrow morning.
Attach it.
that still hurts?
It was not even hurt.
Oh, how are you.
That you are now so brave.
You should see your face.
Are you sleepy?
Come on, put your head on my knees.
Hello.
I have not done.
What time is it now?
10:20
We still have half an hour.
I think we will go
in the movie 1 1:00.
You said today
we go to a lecture Mihailescu.
Come next week.
Next week
you say the same thing.
I want some more work here.
What it is?
Lecture on folklore.
We have to write a report for the workshop.
But it's not your handwriting?
I took it from the fat woman,
which is terribly painted.
What?
You smell nice.
What kind of perfume?
I do not know what kind of perfume.
I gave them to my mother.
And I use Love me.
Smell the smell?
I thought it was your natural smell.
Let's take the book home.
I will help you in the evening to write.
And you can ask
pick up this book?
Mom needs this Alexandra
book tomorrow.
Well, I'll write.
But tomorrow bring.
I talked to Sandu.
Sends you greetings.
He will come for lunch on Sunday.
Good.
Bye.
Good luck. Good luck!
You lose that?
Nothing.
I do not really want to.
You want to go to a lecture?
Why are you doing it?
Come with me.
Did not We decided to go to the movies?
Let's not quarrel.
Now you make me
do what you want,
and it is right?
Why did not you tell me,
you do not want to go?
I will not go. I arrived in Bucharest
to go to university.
Look at you!
I am guilty because I want to,
that we were together?
I am guilty, because let me
depend on you.
Why are you angry?
Do you want us to
Mihailescu went to a lecture?
No, I'll go to the movies.
No, we will go to a lecture
and write down all that he says.
We can go to the movies
at 2:00 hours.
From this control and the next two
hours diligent note-taking
I wanted to climb the walls.
From anger, I am ready
I was screaming.
I could not understand how so
It happened that I fell in love with her.
Look, Alexander.
If this man card
Management appear here,
please tell him that you
my niece.
I do not want us to have a problem.
What management department?
Say you are my niece.
You're as niece to me,
Christina.
I just know
you less than her.
It may appear
Anytime.
Just as 30 years ago,
when I was here with my Nick,
who had just returned
from a business trip,
and the guy card
just knocked on the door.
He wanted to check our documents.
And he recorded us as lovers!
He wrote us a penalty,
and we were forced to cancel
That year our trip to the resort.
A year later,
Nick returned to his wife
and left me alone to pay
these penalties.
That is why I warn you.
Oh, you are so elegant. yours
parents can be proud of you.
You're not like the vulgar
girls I see on the street,
they wear these pants,
showing her navel.
Mrs. Parvulescu
He invited me to dinner.
Well, it means we have agreed.
You say that you are my niece,
just came to visit.
Yes, Aunt Lucretia, do not worry.
I will not let you down.
Bye, honey.
Hello!
I'll take it to the kitchen.
They are almost ready.
Come to my room.
what?
you have to change your shirt.
Strange bathroom.
What is that?
I want to open a haberdashery.
No, really!
When I was little, I had
girlfriend, I really liked.
We loved to climb under the desk,
marshaled armies of buttons
and fought with each other.
One day she took a manicure
scissors, lifted his shirt,
and I wanted to cut off my nipples.
Why?
I do not know. She said she wanted
give them to me.
However, her nipples
It looked like two small hearts.
Why do you have two beds?
One was Sandu.
I was afraid to sleep alone.
Christina! Lunch is ready!
Hello.
Hello! I'm so glad you came,
Alexandra.
Sit down.
Take it, please.
Oh, no! This place Sandu.
You sit next to Christina.
My father would sit at the end of
table, and I'll sit next to the door.
I have not done everything.
So how do you like in Bucharest?
It is already a year ago came.
I lived in a dormitory.
And why did you move?
I did not like it.
Girls, you would have seen,
situation in the '70s,
when we went to college.
If we could get a bed
and a table to cut sausage,
we were delighted.
Now other times.
Christina, what is this fat sack
on the sink?
That I brought. There's eggs and a little
larded meat from my parents.
They do it very well.
Oh, dear, you should not do.
They sent it to you, not
for us. Please take it back.
In addition, we do not eat fatty foods.
Kristina, bring it back,
Alexander did not forget to pick up.
Your parents do
agriculture?
No, my father is a veterinarian,
and my mother a teacher.
Christina, please.
But they keep chickens, and last year,
Dad decided to have pigs.
Then I might have met your mother
when he led inspection of the schools.
We then spent a great job.
I know the area by heart.
Where are you from?
PetroSiti.
Well, so far I have not been.
It Sandu.
Hello!
Sandhu, my boy, put
slippers, for God's sake?
what are you watching?
And you can not keep silent.
What are you doing?
Sandhu, do not take food hands
in front of a guest!
Relax, mom
OK, eat.
I'll leave at 5:00 o'clock.
It's poisonous swill
we drank the last time?
Why do you call it
This poisonous swill?
You did it like that.
Sam then drank half a bottle.
No, he is not an alcoholic.
He drinks in moderation.
He's not an alcoholic.
He just drank without measure.
Leave the boy alone.
Toast!
During the visit of Alexandra
Bucharest.
Yes, Miss Alexander.
And for my new passport.
what is it?
And you thought I was going
abroad under the bus pass?
You can not help but dig
hands in a bowl?
Just put the food itself to the plate.
I do not want to eat after you.
I do not want to be infected with herpes.
What we are sensitive!
Interestingly, and where are you going
go with your passport?
In Pitesti.
Do not be rude to his father!
I do not want to talk...
but I had already guessed.
You're acting like a little boy.
Salad of eggplant is very tasty.
How did you do?
I'm glad you liked it.
I added a little onion and
mayonnaise, for a more delicate taste.
Delicious!
This blouse.
This was Christine.
Correctly?
I bought for her.
This is Christina.
I borrowed it. It suits her,
is not it? She's beautiful.
On you it looks better than
my sister. You can have it.
She went without a bra.
Why are you kicking me, Mom?
How strong!
This is because you are not used to
to such.
Of course!
Yes, it is already used to everything.
Do not exaggerate!
Although,
Here is proof of courage.
Christine, did you do it?
Yes.
It is better to consult a doctor.
It infected.
She did not need a doctor.
A week later, they are completely healed.
This must be one of those
trinkets that you wear in your ears.
Girls go through hell
for the sake of beauty.
We need to spread antiseptic.
A weakly You get pierced?
what do you mean?
Your phone is ringing!
Stop arguing with each other.
You behave as if you do not
brother and sister.
This Coca-Cola?
No, do not open it.
I will take it,
drink later with Alex.
As you wish.
Christine, tell me the dish,
you are welcome.
I forgot to tell you, I was talking to
Mrs. Negulesko recently.
She arranged for me
visit to her cousin
in Switzerland for two months.
You want to leave?
Yes, I'm leaving, as
I realized I could not do the piercing.
And you go with the old woman?
Christina, please
Mrs. Negulesko not old.
It looks good,
Lord have mercy.
What luck, it will be
wonder boy in her company.
What other services
you will perform?
Stop grinning.
You know, I hate it.
Stop grinning idiot!
What are you accept, say,
nonsense in front of everybody?
Shame on you,
say nasty things to her sister.
Do not honk me that it is time to
stay. I know what I am saying.
What are the signals?
Just calm down and sit down.
If you ate, I'll take
plates and bring the soup.
Christina, you do not want
sleep tonight at home?
No, I do not want to bother.
What if Ms. Negulesko come?
You're going to sleep at home.
Have We not your family?
No, I'll sleep in Alexandra.
You get up and leave right now.
I'm already ...
Get up and go away, you bastard.
This concerns you.
Alexander, you help me?
Christina, you too.
We wanted more
time to spend together.
We loved to wander
around these buildings
with peeling plaster
and old balconies,
sagging with age.
I have not told her
I love her.
In fact, I do not know yet
what I feel.
We went to the movies
and we spent the whole day there.
We did not go out into the street.
And turns sleeping.
I only remember the smell of her skin.
When we are bored city
we just went to the mountains.
We rent a room with faded sheets
and looked out the window at the passers-by.
I liked to listen to her, lying on
stomach, his head in his hands,
watch it
perfectly manicured fingers,
with neatly trimmed nails.
We did not think that parted and
We did not think about the bad,
since then we have lived with ease.
We were like carefree children
and just had fun,
We lived to the fullest.
Where are you going?
Take a shower.
Good. And how long?
You want to go first?
I have a meeting at 11 o'clock.
I saw a cool swimsuit,
Sandu has to buy it for me.
You go away for a long time?
Why you do not want
go to the sea?
My parents will kill me,
if I do not go home.
You want to go in that hole!
It's not quite a hole. It is beautiful there.
There is a large courtyard garden behind the house
and the forest on the mountain,
even the river, where you can swim.
A milk-honey river there?
Do not laugh at me!
You are angry at me?
If you loved me,
you would not say that.
what?
Nevermind.
Do you want your parents
I guessed that we're together?
They did not guess.
And what we will have a vacation?
Hiding from parents
for the trees?
Hide in the corners?
Why hide?
You want to see your mother,
I shove my tongue in your mouth?
Why do you say that?
No, really,
What is a vacation?
If kissing in front of my parents
make you happy,
we could do it.
I need to pee.
Close the door.
Hi, this is Sandu.
Leave your message.
Today, June 10, I called
say, Happy Birthday.
Although you no longer love me,
I still love you,
and I want you to call me too
on my birthday.
But love is not that
remember someone's birthday.
I love that I can not live without you.
Why are you torturing me?
Why are you afraid?
You want to kill me, do you want,
that I bled for you?
You're just a beast.
And I have nothing for you!
I am your shadow!
Although not the first my congratulations,
you know perfectly well,
that it has value only.
Happy Birthday, my dear!
I wish you happiness!
Till. I love you.
Till!
You can go.
If you hurry,
we have time to time.
You said that you have a meeting
with your brother?
We can not go together?
I thought, what do you want
one go.
You want me to go with you?
Do not I mean it?
I'll buy it
and you, too, something good.
I dont know!
Whenever I see your brother,
I want to escape.
I promise that we will not last long.
Surprisingly, as yet
later you can not come?
I'm not too late.
We were late because of me.
You do with it.
As if you do not know it. Let's go to.
Did you get my message?
I thought we agreed ...
You changed my mind.
I do not know what to say.
I can not wait for you
until you svistnesh.
I can not bear it!
Let's talk later.
As you want.
This.
Want to see how
it will be on me?
Go. I'll wait.
what are you doing? Bored?
I do not like shopping.
And she loves.
I once waited for her for over an hour,
yet she chose shoes.
She has strange tastes.
I like.
She's special.
Yes, it is true.
Christina? Christina!
What?
Are you ready?
Give me a sec!
So how is it? What do you think?
Great!
I'll get it to you.
Seriously, it suits you.
Come on, tell me how you?
I do not believe him.
I dont know.
These beads on ...
Now so fashionable!
Although you're right.
If a bead come off,
then all the rest followed her.
Just buy it and all.
He is beautiful.
Okay, I'll pay.
Straight ahead, on the left
and at the end.
Still far?
No, almost there.
I'll be right back.
Only it is listed.
I'm at.
I will wait.
Number 47, reception.
It is on the way.
Already dizzy.
I did not eat anything today.
This Becks, it is normal.
From his head does not hurt.
Let's drink, then sleep.
Tomorrow to get up early.
Do you regret that we were going?
silly,
Why should I regret?
I've been thinking ...
My house is not so good.
The main thing that
no one will bother us.
You're right.
Why we used to
We did not think about it.
About what?
About everything.
I told you my dream?
I dreamed that we moved
in my dorm room,
and we had a cat.
One day someone knocked
and you opened the door.
There was a guy.
Sandu, I guess.
No, not Sandu. What a strange guy.
I do not know how to describe it.
Anyway, he came
and began to demand that we
get rid of the cat.
It should be managed.
Probably.
Go on.
What?
What happened next?
Nothing. The cat ran away
between the legs,
but we have been assured,
that he would return.
He was a tramp.
Rolling Stone is usually returned.
Yes.
Like us?
Tomorrow I'll pick you up,
when I'm ready.
Here are a few sandwiches
and coffee.
I could not find a thermos.
So many packages!
What is it?
A little bit of cheese...
God knows
what they will feed you there.
No, I have no place. We just
stop somewhere to eat.
And you shall eat all the small stuff!
This is Dad.
Ready?
I took the keys.
Without the key, it will not start.
Did you check the oil, gasoline?
No.
Christina, now the car
on your account.
Mom, mobile
it does not work.
I'll call you.
Or call Sandu ...
Dad brought a little low-fat cheese.
Take it.
Mom, I will not take it!
Check gasoline and oil.
And do not leave the car
unattended.
I understood everything.
Till!
Be careful on the road.
Good luck!
what are you doing?
Benes asked me to make tea.
what happened to you, Aunt?
I can not get up, Christine. Look.
what's the matter?
My legs do not obey me.
We must go now.
But what exactly does it hurt?
I felt some weakness,
when she got up from the bed.
I would have fallen,
if I had not leaned against the wall.
But you fell.
No, I came here to watch TV.
God bless you.
Drink diclofenac.
Does he help me?
Yes.
Well, come, my dear.
I talked to my nephew,
he will come to take care of me.
You are a long time?
Until the beginning of August.
See you when you get back,
if I do not die at that time.
Do not worry, you probably
just ate something not fresh.
Maybe mackerel?
Mackerel! Of course!
All right, we're leaving.
And turn off the light in the hallway!
It would be great if she died
and we would be living here alone.
She will not die.
Leave him alone, she shut down.
Two hours later, I knew everything about Alex,
when she was a little girl.
I imagined her, awkward,
shy, dreaming about the future.
This cultural center
and the supermarket together.
Like the shopping center,
there is also a night club with a disco.
Turn right.
Here?
Yes.
Hello!
Welcome!
This is Christine.
Hello! Welcome!
Hey. Good to see you home, baby.
Nice to meet you.
Welcome.
Petrik, let me help you.
Well, girls, let's go into the house.
Petrik, we will be in the house.
You bring luggage.
You ate something?
Yes.
Rosie, feed the girls.
They drove for a long time.
We already ate.
And I would drink coffee.
Of course.
Thank you.
As the road?
Perfectly.
It took about two hours.
When you went from Bucharest?
Somewhere in the 11 hours.
But we traveled
around Targoviste
because of one-way traffic.
And Alex Did not show the way?
I showed I did so.
Well, the road Targovishte
generally a nightmare, bumps, potholes and all.
Cold?
Little.
I kindle the fire.
Kiki will sleep in my room ...
Christina.
We have prepared the guest room.
Nothing Petrik.
They will be so comfortable.
All is well. Cabbage will be ready
after half an hour.
Go until unpack things.
And come back.
Voila!
I want to sleep.
Let's go to drink coffee.
Forget the coffee.
I sleep better.
What about my room?
Fine, how are you.
Can?
Dad, there was light.
I'll bring you our.
Where is my?
Your mother took when control
I checked out of school.
You can bring it to me?
Of course. Now.
Your parents are so funny,
like taking Prozac.
Let's hear the tale.
Let's see what you have here.
Little Fairy,
Grain of rice ...
This one.
The player works?
I forgot to ask.
Naturally. In this house
everything works like clockwork.
Once upon a time lived
the Emperor and Empress.
LOCAL FIRE STATION
Both were young and beautiful.
But one thing was sad,
they could not have children.
After a long search,
they found the wise wizard,
who gave the Empress
magic potion.
And one day, in the palace
there was a child's cry.
We felt like two
inseparable sisters,
spending holidays
in the house of her ancestors.
We do not think about nothing.
We did not know jealousy,
bitterness and envy.
We just wanted to be together.
Let's go to.
Cute Chick.
in my ears ringing.
Where are we going?
to the bar to drink.
What'll you have?
There is a menu? No, wait.
What do you have to drink?
We have all.
I see you city.
We have all,
What would you like.
You want to see the menu?
And do you have?
Look cocktail Christina.
10,000 lei.
He has 12,500.
Let it.
What does it look like?
No? Then let two Becks.
How about a cigarette?
Snagov, Carpathians or imported?
I think we could Snagov
and in Bucharest to take.
Do you want to Snagov?
No, the Carpathians.
The first time I came
in this bar.
It's just cool.
I want to move to your town.
Everything here is so cool.
A cigarette?
I forgot.
Can you bring them?
Now.
Firework!
On this glass lip prints
all those who ever drank out of it!
people used to
not care about hygiene.
Cleanliness has made us weaker.
It suppresses our desires.
At first, you feel the smell of a loved one,
and then everything else.
And the smell of my skin?
Strong.
Here.
What does it mean much?
You smell like torn
flower in a vase,
which has long been one
I did not change the water.
You smell like a dream, like
in the morning when you wake up
after a very long sleep.
Do you like Sandhu?
I mean, as a woman?
He's a nice guy.
Good looking.
He is my brother.
Brothers and sisters
sometimes they fall.
Like Rene.
Like what?
Rene at Chateaubriand.
History of hopeless love.
This is the story of hopeless love,
it is not real.
If the writer believed in it,
that Rene and his sister
We would have had a chance.
But he wrote a story
for all
it was sad.
No you're wrong.
Although, it seems doomed,
his love for his sister
It could be the same,
as in any normal relationship,
if he was willing to accept,
in happiness as in misfortune,
there are some nuances.
You speak as if this
Rene was a real story.
I do not think it's even
not a love story.
This is just an example
romantic virtues
with a simplified look
the world.
Just remember, it's all nonsense.
Freud is already analyzed.
His mother died in childbirth,
sister committed suicide.
And wherein,
God is just.
There are either black or white.
The story of love has no chance,
if the author does not believe in it.
And besides, if you tell
the story monk
it becomes a confession,
and it means to
morally
that you condemn him,
in spite of your feelings.
Understood?
But, leaving the author
abstraction,
do you think the relationship
between Renee and Emily
based on a true story
or invented?
What do you think?
I was wondering if
we analyze and condemn
these relations,
in fact they can not be
somewhat dirty.
You think like a saint!
Let's go to.
You can not look for an excuse
relations
that are considered indecent.
It should be remembered in history
her biographical elements,
because from the moment of birth,
heroes lived
under the shadow of death.
And his sister took over
the role of mother.
This ultimately leads us
for older
and more beautiful stories.
I like this story.
Want to take a walk
or play football?
Previously, I played well!
Look, here home
not far away.
I see you have a romantic
mood today.
You do not care Chateaubriand?
In fact, this story
very obscene.
It angers you,
but you can not judge, because
it is based on noble feelings.
Go on.
I like their recklessness,
irresponsibility,
in which they justify
their sexual impulses
seeking answers to them
a change in their nature.
It is as if I said,
that city life
It made me love you.
There's nothing real
of Rene and Emilia.
I know from experience,
all very different.
You mean your experience
with Sandu?
As with any relationship,
one person can be
normal, and the other immoral.
But this does not make
immoral relations in general.
Who among you is immoral?
Sandu.
You do not know how he is.
He is capable of anything,
if he wants something.
Tomorrow he leaves for Switzerland
and leave me alone,
because he wants to.
Okay it does not matter.
But you're not alone.
Are you with me.
And along with it.
Can you take off your jacket?
I want to see your chest
in the moonlight.
I was very hurt when
You went with your brother.
When?
When I waited for 20 minutes
you are in a taxi.
Did I do something,
that upset you?
No. Today I am very happy.
You do breast augmentation surgery,
if I ask you?
You mean to increase them?
More less...
I just want to know you'll do it.
Come on, Sanduta!
You want me to have
They have big breasts?
No, because I have a little.
But still?
Maybe for you. But I will
unpleasant if someone else will touch me.
And how do you go
to the gynecologist?
Never he was not.
It's horrible.
It is not nice ...
For me, the breast, as accessories.
The same as earrings.
It is a pity that we had not met before.
Alexandra!
There's someone at the gate.
There Sandu.
I gave the address of your parents.
Maybe they told him,
where to find me.
Kiki!
Would you call it here?
Come on! He is calling you.
I will not go.
Tell him I'm not here.
Tell him that I went to Bucharest
yesterday.
Why?
I do not want to see him.
Hey.
Good afternoon.
This is my mom.
This brother of Christina.
Rosalia Dragneya. Nice to meet you.
Sandu.
Where is my sister?
I have a week trying to get through to her.
She is not responding.
She's here, but asked me to
say that it is not.
Very funny.
True,
she does not want to see you.
Well, call it a minute.
Kiki, come out!
Christina!
Kiki, let's talk!
Do not make a scene.
Come here for a minute.
Speak!
I came to pick you up in Bucharest.
What for?
Why You turned off the phone?
If I have important news?
What kind?
Maybe I died or became ill.
Sandhu, we agreed,
and you break the contract.
You have come here with no warning,
and even accusing me of something.
And you bring it all with you.
Mrs. Negulesko lent
me his car,
because you took my dad's.
It does not matter.
Why did you come here?
Hello!
Why do we stand here.
Come into the house.
Say what you want to say.
I asked you not to come.
Why did they quarrel?
I do not know, Mom.
Brother and sister
cursing, bad ...
Hello. Excuse me.
Do you have a toilet?
Yes.
Where?
behind the house.
Thank you. I hope you do not mind.
Of course.
And who is it?
The chief of her brother.
Good morning!
I would now be sat omelette
with dill and pepper.
Girls Have you had breakfast?
Yes.
Good morning.
I'm sorry to trouble you.
We talked and decided everything.
You must forgive Christina.
She rides with me.
You are leaving?
No!
that means no?
I do not go anywhere.
What do you say to me
a minute ago?
Even less than a minute?
You're crazy?
You sick pervert
are you not in control.
Do you think I was driving 200 km in this hole,
that you made a fool of me?
Why did you come?
Just a quarrel with me?
Go away and leave me.
what?
Pack your bags
or I'll knock you out of this shit!
Yeah, right now! Get out from here!
You know, you can not do without me
a month to live.
Take your old woman
and the wali in his Syrlandiyu!
Get your things, or I swear to God,
You get away from me!
Who the hell are you?
Get away!
Mind your own business!
Who is this hell?
Kiki, I'm a pervert?
Tell everyone, even listen to!
Am I first touched your pussy
or you first grabbed my cock?
Well, tell me!
Who started it?
You dare curse in my yard?
Dont touch me,
farmer!
You talk with me
in my own backyard?
Get out, you pervert!
Your daughter is a pervert!
She was just a lesbian,
they fuck with my sister!
Who is it?
I am a brother of Christine, you asshole!
Dont touch me!
Sorry for the noise.
Look at you. Until then
you down? Below is nowhere to go.
Go.
Christina! You are welcome!
Let's go, I said. Now!
Kiki, come out.
They left.
Leave me alone.
Oh please.
I can not. Leave me.
Alexander, baby,
Who are these people?
This is Christine.
And Sandhu, her brother.
I know who she is.
What I want to know how
did you meet such people.
You're our girl,
and we trust you.
I did not do anything.
We think you'll be okay
behave in Bucharest.
you will not be friends
with bad people.
I can not take it anymore.
You made us a laughing stock!
Leave it now.
It's enough.
We raised you as best they could.
And you went to Bucharest and
pierced ears.
Why Alexander? Just say
me why? I do not understand!
I gather things.
Petrik, go down.
I will go, or this crazy
anything will do.
You want me to go with you?
No, that's my business.
You are free?
Yes. Where are you going?
Lipskani.
Sit down.
I can not get to Lipskani.
Where do you land?
I thought about it and let you know.
Good.
You can drive
through Drumul Taber?
I can drop off you to the slopes,
if you want to.
And where in the Drumul Taber?
Poiana Montelui.
Good.
Who's there?
Hello, Aunt Lucretia.
Hi, honey. what happened?
I'm back.
You scared me to death.
I heard a noise outside the door,
and I thought it was thieves.
I greeted him loudly.
You said you come back
a month later?
He returned earlier.
Good. I did not touch anything in the
your room, everything is the same.
Christine did not come?
No, I am also waiting for her.
To report it,
I almost died,
because it took diclofenac,
she said.
I had terrible diarrhea.
I was lucky that his nephew came,
He took me to the hospital, otherwise ...
I can put products
in the refrigerator?
Of course, luggage.
So you were in the hospital?
No, God forbid!
If I'll go to the hospital,
I'm just going to die.
My longest visit to the hospital
I was 70,
when I had an operation on his legs,
I could hardly walk.
Otherwise, I would have died.
Tell me, what about the money?
But my father paid
October?
Yes, but I struck out you
from the list in the public service.
Bring me to the list.
And then striking out again?
Why delete?
My mom put me a cake.
Want to?
I sugar may rise.
But you will not leave again?
I'll stay here till the end of the period.
You can stay and after the deadline.
I'm talking about vacation. You do not
dogulivat collect them?
I dont know.
I watched when you were here.
You are a good girl.
Never drive a boy.
And if you
pay money,
regularly every month,
I can make you an offer.
I will think about it.
I know it's expensive for you,
but I can do a little bit cheaper.
You and Christine
such a cute girl,
I feel good with you.
I will think about it.
Hey.
You are alone?
You will die in the stench.
I am a country girl.
To all familiar.
Stop saying that you
rustic, you do not like that.
What are you doing?
Chicken with vegetables
and kiwi sauce.
Where did this come from?
On TV I saw.
I'm tired of all this crap.
What the shit?
Delicious.
So, what are you doing?
What did I do?
I do not even want to remember.
It was a nightmare for me.
I was with my brother,
I put up with his bad mood.
You know, it's hard.
Do you realize how awful
it was for him
go, God knows where, and miss
all their chances
on the future life?
Anyway, it is still
calmed down.
It is good that you have everything in order.
I was worried about you.
And you do not want
ask how I'm doing?
I do not blame you,
but your indifference kills.
You will be surprised to learn,
I was looking for you.
I came for you in Bucharest.
I went to your brother,
to your parents.
Your mother did not tell you,
I'm asking about you every day?
However, it does not matter.
I do not communicate with their parents.
We had a falling out.
You could call me.
I wanted to see you.
Well, it does not matter.
You're right.
It is important that I came back.
And we can go there,
where you left off.
There's nothing to go on.
I packed your things.
They are bagged in the room.
Why are you doing it?
Here they are.
Do not do this.
I had things to do.
I'm sorry, really.
Perhaps I was wrong.
I know that was wrong.
I wanted to call you,
Sandu but he's just come into a rage.
Let's continue, please.
I do not believe you anymore.
You lied to me
and continue to lie.
As you no honesty drop.
You have no idea what it is.
Benes also at home?
Let's go somewhere to talk?
There is nothing to talk about.
I've been thinking about this.
I was an idiot.
It was clear from the outset,
I just love you too.
I love you!
Why are you angry?
A month ago, I was wrong.
That's what you left me.
I mean, I left you?
I'm telling you, I had a problem.
You will always be problems.
You can not live without them.
And now you want to ruin everything?
Do you want me to suffer?
Why do you want to leave me,
if you know how it hurts?
Please, go away.
I can not go! I do not want!
I do not believe you. I do not believe,
that you really want it.
You want that I
I asked for forgiveness?
I promise I will not, I swear,
this will not happen again.
You want that I
I knelt?
Look, I'm on my knees.
How can you say,
that it will not happen again?
You look me in the eye
while lying.
Can not you see?
You are welcome...
You have broken my heart,
you know?
I have emptiness inside.
There is nothing there.
And whatever you say
not correct the situation.
I want to forget you.
Take your things and go.
If I'm gone, I'm not going back.
You are threatening me?
You and so do not come back.
You're somewhere else.
You can not be honest.
I was honest with you.
I said I love you,
I love you too.
I'm still loving you.
When we arrived
in your parents' house,
Do you think it was a lie,
everything I told you?
I told you that?
And you remember?
There's nothing to remember.
I could not get back to you
after all that happened there.
I had to leave,
so that later it was easier.
You do not have to suffer.
What has happened does not matter.
You know perfectly well that this is not so.
Take your things.
It pains me to see them.
Now what do I do?
We will not see each other again?
You want to
I promised it to you?
Okay. While you're here,
I move to Sandu.
If you do not want to see,
then we will not.
I promise, you will not see me,
I will keep my promise.
You want to end it all,
as if nothing had happened.
You say that you forget everything,
Do you think we really forget?
I thought, you know
what I'm doing.
I did everything that we could
be happy together.
Tell me you do not want,
that we were together?
You do not want to see me?
Well, we do not see each other again.
Never.
Take things.
For most people, we just
good friends,
who were able to find their place
in this world,
only some
know something about us.
And only we, only,
who knows all about us.
We have no idea,
that was between us,
but it was something good.
In memory of my grandmother Lila
Subitry: yagulena