It says a couple that kisses on
graduation day...
will stay together forever!
Wait! Look at that!
A kiss?
My first kiss?
I enjoyed this year the most
out of the past three years.
I suffered this year the most
out of the past eighteen years.
You and I are not so good
at studying.
But we should find something
that we are good at.
If I find something and become big...
will you love me?
She finally...
realized who cares about her the most.
Kin-chan, sorry to keep you waiting!
Irie and Kotoko are destined
to be together.
- Don't be silly.
- You, cold-blooded man.
But you love this cold-blooded man,
don't you?
Irie-kun and I kissed, didn't we?
Come with me.
What is it?
I'm... going to quit loving you.
I see.
So you'll forget about me?
Then let's see if you can
forget about me.
Sorry.
I've been feeling kind of shy
since that day.
I just couldn't be honest.
It was a dream.
I've been waking up to these
kind of dreams since that day.
But... not even a second kiss.
The relationship between Irie-kun and I
hasn't made any progress.
And the short spring break
is now over.
Starting today,
Irie-kun and I are college students.
Tonan University
The day of the Entrance Ceremony
Hey.
Yes.
How long are you going to follow me?
Are you going to the science
and engineering department?
That's right.
I'm in the literature department.
Bye bye.
And so you came to the science and
engineering department to spy on Irie?
You haven't made any progress
since high school, Kotoko.
The quality of Kotoko never changes.
But I see only men in the science
and engineering department.
It looks like you don't have to
worry about girls around Irie.
You are safe, Kotoko.
Kotoko, look at that girl.
Wh-who is that beautiful girl?
Wow, I can see sparkles around her
on this campus full of men.
Irie-kun.
Naoki Irie!
Have you chosen your elective course?
No, I haven't.
What should I choose?
Whoa!
What? Jinko and Satomi!
Do you need something?
I was wondering what kind of desks are used
in the science and engineering department.
She's hopeless.
Is she your girlfriend?
No way.
'No way?'
We kissed...
but still 'No way?'
What's going to happen to
my college life?
Subtitles by DramaFever
[Mischievous Kiss]
[Love in Tokyo]
You kissed?
You are too loud.
How can I not be loud after
hearing this?
Episode 6
A rival emerges!? Love with a lot of trouble.
That Irie kissed you?
But from what I just saw,
it doesn't seem like it at all.
I know.
Serves you right.
I can't understand what Irie-kun
is thinking at all.
Stop being a wimp.
You gave your precious first kiss to Irie.
She's right.
You have to be tough.
We are freshmen in college.
Plus it's spring time.
The season to meet new people.
If you just sit around and do nothing,
the beautiful girl is going to get Irie.
Aihara
- Welcome.
- Ai-chan!
Thank you for inviting us.
We need to congratulate Naoki
and Kotoko for their first day of college.
Please have a seat.
Thank you. Let's sit down.
I'm so excited.
This restaurant has very good taste.
Right?
Ai-chan said the highest quality of
Japanese paper is used for this paper.
Oh really?
You can't make it dirty.
And these chopsticks are the
highest quality too.
So you can't make them dirty either.
We can't eat then.
I will eat it with my stomach.
Welcome.
Kin-chan?
Oh, you look different.
I didn't recognize you at all.
You look better this way.
Thank you, Madam.
But why are you working at Aihara?
I started working as an apprentice here
to become a professional chef.
I see. You are good at cooking.
Compared to a real chef's food,
my food is not good enough.
But I will work hard and become a
better chef than your father.
And I will be the best chef in Japan.
I won't lose against you.
I will become a professional chef
and make a lot of money...
and I will come and get you.
Be prepared for that!
Kinnosuke, how long are you
staying there?
I'm sorry. I will be quick!
Kotoko, please do this for me?
These are so uneven.
I can't give them to customers.
- I'm sorry.
- Let me show you.
- Fold each one carefully.
- Yes.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Kin-chan.
You found what you want to do.
I'm impressed. Good luck.
Yeah. Good luck with your
studying at school!
Jinko and Satomi too.
Cut it by pushing the blade
of the knife.
Yes.
This is too thick.
You can take a bath now.
Um, Irie-kun.
What?
Who was that girl from the science
and engineer department?
Oh, Yuko Matsumoto?
You already know her full-name?
I won't forget if I hear it once.
Is it possible that Matsumoto-san likes you?
Huh? Are you jealous?
Oh no...
Come to think of it,
she certainly is beautiful.
She has a great body.
And she is smart.
She said she was once in the fifth place
on the national exam.
Why did a person like that
attend our school?
Who knows?
Maybe she has another purpose.
What's this? I thought you were
going to forget about me.
Oh, that's right.
We kissed, didn't we?
Now you can't forget about me?
Could this be...
the second kiss?
I've been teased.
Irie-kun doesn't care that we kissed.
Not fair.
So that girl's name is Yuko Matsumoto?
She is beautiful and smart.
She is like a female version of Irie.
Well, I guess I can say
Irie and her are a good match.
Please don't say such an
ominous thing.
But you have to be realistic.
Obviously she is going for Irie.
You are in big trouble.
Eat some food and feel better.
What should I eat?
Kotoko.
Kotoko?
You haven't ordered yet?
I was spaced out. Sorry.
- We will be sitting down, okay?
- Okay.
Well, Lunch A is hamburg steak.
Lunch B is deep fried shrimp.
You can't think without
saying things out loud?
Can I get one Lunch A?
I would like to...
They don't have Lunch F.
I'm getting Lunch A too.
Two Lunch A's.
Why is there such a difference?
Excuse me, Sir.
Do you have any complaints?
Are you complaining about the
fairness of my servings?
You've got some nerve.
Kin-chan?
What are you doing?
You said you found what you
wanted to do.
You're not working at
my father's restaurant?
I am working at his restaurant at night.
And for lunch, I'm
working at this cafeteria.
I will learn how to
cook inexpensive food and...
food from the high-end restaurant as well.
Isn't it amazing?
Also, I have to protect Kotoko
from that evil guy.
What do you say, Mr. Genius?
Are you so surprised
that you can't say a word?
I'm very impressed...
that a man can change
his life according to one girl.
I can't do that.
What did you say?
I'll leave you two alone now.
Please enjoy.
I bet you got scared of
my love power.
Right, Kotoko?
But in a way, Kin-chan is right.
A man gets attracted to
a woman who stays close.
Kotoko, you should learn
from Kin-chan.
Yeah. Although you two
are in the same college...
he's in science and engineering
and you're in the literature department.
You have different campuses.
It's not going to be the same
as it was in high school.
Yuko Matsumoto from the same department
has a big advantage.
On top of that, she is beautiful
and has a perfect body.
Oh no...
There you are, Irie.
- Sudo-san, good to see you.
- Good to see you.
Who is that old man?
Don't know.
Is he a senior?
Or a professor?
You know why I'm here, don't you?
If you would like...
No, if you would really like...
Join our club.
I have no intention of joining
any clubs.
Please don't say that.
We've known each other since
elementary school.
I will be waiting for you after school.
Okay?
Adios!
Kotoko, your chance has come.
You should join the same club as Irie.
You can still be with him even though
you're not in the same department.
That's right. This is your chance to
drive Yuko Matsumoto away!
That's right!
I will do that.
I'll take your fried shrimp.
So good! So good!
So good!
Irie-kun, are you going to join a club?
What club are you going to join?
I won't tell you.
Why not?
Because I feel like you're going to
join the same one.
That is...
He knows what we're thinking.
He surely is a genius.
I'm not giving up.
Let's do it.
That bearded old man said he would
be waiting for him after school.
That means if I follow him, I'll be able to
find out what club he's going to join.
Anyway, I didn't know there were
so many different kinds of clubs.
I wonder which club Irie-kun
is joining.
That room!
May I join this club?
The Anime Study Group?
Um, is Irie-kun here?
Irie?
Who is that?
Is that the man who came in
for a second and left?
Please excuse me.
You're late.
I said we should go together.
You decided that on your own.
But it doesn't matter since we are
going to join the same club.
The same club?
Let's go inside.
Fine.
Excuse me, I would like to
join this club too.
Well, who are you?
Who is your referral?
I don't have a referral, but...
I really want to join this club...
[Tonan University Tennis Club]
Join this tennis club.
I thought if I entered Tonan University,
I would definitely join this tennis club.
Nice to meet you all.
It's all right, Captain.
Anyone with enthusiasm is welcome.
What is your name?
I'm Kotoko Aihara.
Kotoko-chan! Come in, come in!
I'm Sudo. I'm in charge of
new members.
We're just about to start a
welcome party for our new members.
You stand on this side.
Let me start explaining.
If you have any questions,
please ask Sudo.
I will tell you anything but my
cell phone number.
How about this?
Wow, is this for me?
I'm glad that you're going
to play tennis.
I was pretty good when
I was young.
You were?
Yes, I taught Naoki when he
first started playing tennis.
Naoki, don't you think
Kotoko-chan's tennis outfit is cute?
What do you think?
I don't think it's a good idea to start
with picking your outfit.
You're doing great!
You and Naoki joined the same club.
That means you two are in love.
It's nothing like that.
Irie-kun is popular.
What?
Mrs. Irie.
Do you think Irie-kun likes girls
who are beautiful and smart?
Don't tell me that there is a girl
like that around Naoki?
Wow. I didn't know he was
that popular.
He is so blunt.
But don't worry, Kotoko-chan.
For now, go to the science and
engineering department all the time and...
approach him.
That's the only way.
No matter what kind of girl she is...
you are the best girl for Naoki.
Well...
I know because I've been watching you
while we've been living together.
Okay? I'm rooting for you!
Here. Hold this racket.
Right. And make a pose.
You look so good.
Swing it! Receive!
Good. Now I am going to
get my love.
Great, Kotoko!
What are you doing?
Serve.
Good, Kotoko.
Nice.
All right, new members.
Today is the first day of practice,
so we are going to have a little test.
We will just take a look
at your skill.
Please try to do your best.
Yes.
What?
A test? No one told me that!
Your opponent is Sudo from Junior year,
who is in charge of new members.
I'm Sudo. Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm glad that it's Sudo.
You don't know anything.
What are you talking about?
Sudo seems to have changed.
Then... Wada, you go first.
What? I'm going first?
You thought it would be
in alphabetical order?
I'm a man who likes to do
things unexpectedly.
Wada, come to the court.
What are you standing there for?
He's called 'Sudo the Demon.'
Next.
Yano.
Come.
Yes.
When Sudo-san holds a racket,
his personality changes.
He's been known for that since
he was in elementary school.
Normally he is gentle.
Miyamoto! Come!
Yes.
Matsumoto-san is really good.
She made it to the last four in the women's
singles division when she was in high school.
She was smart enough to go to
any university she wanted.
Tonan University has an
excellent tennis club.
How do you know all that?
She asked me for advice when
she was choosing her school.
I met her at the national tournament
in the first year of high school.
Irie-kun didn't know me in the
first year of high school.
I was just looking at him from afar.
That means Matsumoto-san's relationship
with Irie-kun is longer than mine.
I feel like I'm going to lose.
I'm impressed, Matsumoto.
Good job.
Thank you very much.
Next.
Naoki Irie.
Come.
Yes.
Finally the day has come.
Indeed.
Please go easy on me.
I would never go easy on you.
Irie-kun is amazing.
That's it.
Irie, get off the court.
Wait, Irie. One more time.
Sudo, today is only a test.
No, I want to play again.
Naoki Irie is unbelievable.
Exactly what the rumor said.
But look at Sudo's face!
He is furious.
I feel bad for the next person.
Next.
Kotoko Aihara! Come!
Yes.
Don't walk like a snail!
Excuse me!
I've never played tennis before.
Shut up!
Here I come!
Yes.
What's wrong with her?
Hey, don't run away!
Hold your racket!
Open your eyes!
- Let's go!
- Yes.
Oh no, Aihara has fainted.
- Here.
- Ouch, ouch, ouch.
Are you okay, Kotoko-chan?
Same as usual, Kotoko is so uncool.
Yuki.
You shouldn't go to practice tomorrow.
New members are not allowed
to miss practice in our club.
It'll be okay.
I'll get used to it soon.
You shouldn't push yourself
too much.
Yes.
Do you have any other injuries?
I think I'm okay now.
I just have sore muscles.
Aihara
In Preparation
Boss, what should I do with these?
Wash them and peel the skin off.
Yes.
Hey, Kinnosuke.
Yes?
So you are working at the
university during the day?
Yes, I am.
How is Kotoko at the school?
She is pretty much the same
as how she was in high school.
She can't be the same.
She is getting older and...
Um, like...
a boyfriend or something...
I am making sure that not a
single man can approach her.
Then how about Naoki?
Boss, don't worry.
I will protect her from that evil man.
And since their classes
are in different buildings...
I feel like their distance has gotten
larger than it was in high school.
After all, I see justice being done.
Hey, Kinnosuke.
Yes?
Can you pass on my message?
Ouch.
Kotoko, is your face okay?
It hurts!
I hear Tonan tennis club is
very intense.
Because it's so hard,
many new members quit.
Every year only a few would
stay by the end.
Really? Are you sure you
can continue?
I'll do anything to be close to Irie-kun.
Just quit.
- Here.
- Kin-chan.
Kotoko
Love
Only for Kotoko? It's not fair
Be quiet, or I will rub my butt.
It's a special cake from me.
Hey, Kotoko.
You should quit playing tennis.
There is no need for you to injure
your pretty face and keep playing.
I want to do my best since
I already started.
My father taught me that
I should never give up halfway.
Kotoko.
You are so dedicated.
By the way, I have a
message from your father.
He wants you to come to
Aihara tonight.
- Why?
- I don't know why.
He says he wants to have
a talk with you.
Have some.
Let's eat!
You are both eating too much.
- Oops!
- What do you mean by 'oops?'
- And you ate the 'love' part.
- So tasty!
You ate the 'love' part.
What are you doing?
Hurry up!
Bring your hips all the way down.
You are not putting enough
spirit into this.
If you are like that, we don't
need you in the tennis club.
Just quit already!
You want to quit?
No, I don't.
Right?
The river is running.
The forest is alive.
We are all...
- Alive.
- That's right.
Take a break.
- The break is over.
- Seriously?
You don't deserve a break.
Next, do one hundred sit-ups.
- Yes.
- I couldn't hear you.
Yes!
Is this supposed to be
a tennis club?
All we do is muscle training.
And both Irie-kun and
Yuko Matsumoto aren't here.
What in the world is going on?
Ouch.
I'm sorry, Kotoko.
Could you please throw it to me?
Wait. Hey!
You're a new member too, so
why are you practicing in the court?
What about the muscle training?
Oh, didn't you know?
Performance is the most important
thing in Tonan tennis club.
So if you passed yesterday's test, even a
new member is allowed to play in the court.
Is that true?
In that case, Irie-kun is...
Irie-kun has even more privileges.
He joined the club with two conditions,
he can play only when he feels like...
and at the official games.
No way. Does that mean he's not
coming to the practices?
Then why did I join the tennis club?
Oh! I heard that you are
living in his house.
But you don't know anything
about him.
I guess that means your
relationship with him is only that level.
Aihara.
Are you goofing off again?
Run one hundred laps around
the track as punishment!
- Thank you for the food.
- Thank you for coming.
Kotoko, you're here.
Hey Kinnosuke, when did I say
you could leave your position?
There are many dirty dishes.
I'm sorry, Bro.
I will see you at school!
What's wrong, Kotoko?
I have sore muscles.
What?
Anyway what did you want
to tell me?
Well...
We will use the private room
for a little while.
Yes.
Are you all right?
It looks so delicious!
Thank you for the food.
It tastes even better after exercising.
You were never good at playing
ball sports.
I know you are not
interested in playing tennis.
Are you doing it for Naoki?
Why are you asking me this
all of a sudden?
Listen, Kotoko.
It's been almost a year since
we moved in with the Irie family.
I've been thinking a lot about this.
I don't think we should be depending on
their generosity for too long.
I know Iri-chan and Mrs. Irie
are treating you well.
To be honest with you,
I did hope that you and Naoki would...
I thought that you two would
be together in the future.
Father.
But I've watched you two
for a long time...
and Naoki seems to have
no interest in you.
I don't think this plan would work.
Let's go back to living on our own.
Just the two of us.
What do you say, Kotoko?
Of course I want to respect
your feelings too.
But I found a nice place nearby.
I want you to consider my feelings too.
I... hate to see you getting hurt.
But if I move out of Irie's house now...
There will be nothing left to
connect Irie and I.
What are you gazing at?
Irie-kun.
Are you going home now?
Where did you go?
I don't need to tell you
where I went.
How about you?
It's late.
I went to my father's restaurant.
Your father's?
Yeah.
Did you go there to see that guy?
That guy?
Never mind.
My father said he found
a nice place to live.
What?
Our new home.
He said he hasn't signed a lease yet.
It's been almost a year since
we started living with your family.
That's why he thought about this.
That's why...
So you are moving out?
If that happens...
will you miss us?
Irie-kun?
Finally, I can go back to living
the way I used to.
I don't understand.
I don't understand...
how you feel, Irie-kun.
What should I do?
Subtitles by DramaFever
Starring
Honoko Miki
Yuki Furukawa
Starring
Yuki Yamada
Original Comic
"Itazurana Kiss" by Kaoru Tada
Executive Producers
Katuski Yoshiharu (SPO Entertainment Inc)
Kenji Nishibuchi (Fuji Television Network, Inc.)
Executive Producers
Yoshikuni Murata (Hakuhodo DY Media Partners Incorporated)
Takeshi Moriya (Atmovie Inc.)
Planning
Yuki Sakurai (SPO Entertainment Inc.)
Opening Song
'Update' by Sabão
Ending Song
'Takaramono (Thanks for All)' by Sabão
Script
Uiko Miura
Producer
Takeshi Moriya
Director
Masakazu Abe
Production by
Atmovie Inc.
Presented by
"Itazurana Kiss-Love in TOKYO" Partners
I gave up on Irie.
No way!
We will play doubles.
Your partner is Kotoko Aihara.
- No.
- Don't ever get in my way.
Irie's feelings might change if
you succeed by working together.
Are you trying so hard to play tennis
because you want to stay with Irie?
We will definitely win.
Got it?
How can you stay calm after giving
someone you love...
so much trouble?
Everything will end.