Previously on AMC's
Low Winter Sun...
I look at you two,
and know what I see?
A couple of skinny white boys
playing gangster.
We're not trying to inch in
on your territory.
Sorry...
We believe Brendan McCann
and Anton Bobek
were killed by Billy Hobson
and an accomplice.
That accomplice
then murdered him.
If you go looking for her,
it is only gonna blow back on us.
Show respect.
You shouldn't have lied
about who you're with.
You should have come clean
about Skelos.
( gunshots )
No, no, no!
Please...
( beeping )
( female reporter speaking
in foreign language )
Woman:
Wet it.
( voices cheering on TV)
( TV announcer
speaking English )
( in Romanian ) Turn the volume down.
( in Romanian ) Sure.
( TV announcer continues )
Hey, what I tell you?
Why some pervert want to watch
me piss anyways?
I don't know.
I don't care.
It's the way it is.
- Hey.
- I moved it.
Good.
You have 10 minutes.
Get ready.
( trickling )
( TV announcer continues )
Hi there, I'm Sasha.
What's your name, sweetie?
Agnew:
Katia, it's Frank.
- Hi-- - I can't believe it.
I've looked all over for you.
Hello? Hello?
I'm sorry...
- Hello, Katia?
- I can't-- I can't hear.
Something with the computer.
Katia, hello--
Creepy stalker guy.
( "Hustlin'" plays )
♪ I ain't no quitter ♪
♪ I'm in for a pound ♪
♪ Ain't nobody ♪
♪ Gonna hold me down ♪
♪ Hustlin' in the Motor City ♪
♪ Hustlin',
just tryin' to get down ♪
♪ Down, down, down. ♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
( TV playing )
We out of trash bags, Maya?
Had some in the office.
Steven:
What do we do now?
Damon: We open at noon.
That's what we do.
Who gives a camel's ass about
the bar right now, man?
Maya: We all do.
Business as usual.
What?
Read it.
_
Damon. Might wanna
come out here.
No, no, no, no.
This is bullshit.
You didn't kill McCann, man.
Yeah, eat a dick, Gus.
It's gotta be Skelos.
Still business
as usual, boss man?
Maya: All right, it's
been a long night.
Get cleaned up,
lay low for a while.
What's the word, Cable?
Uh-oh, here comes trouble,
coffee in tow.
It's that French Vanilla
crap you like so much.
You only bring me coffee when
you're not sportin' a warrant.
Yeah, well, you know how it is.
With budget cuts, we can't
afford warrants no more.
This is already my second smoke.
I can't stay for a third.
I need some information
on a URL.
Tracking down a lead.
Is it a secret lead?
Yeah, something like that.
Does this involve
that detective friend
of yours that was murdered?
All right, hey,
for something like this,
I mean, with all due respect,
you gotta come stronger
than French Vanilla.
Oh, what's this?
Oh, sweet.
Thanksgiving.
Badass, man.
I mean, they suck, but they
might suck less this year.
( chuckles )
Yeah.
- Text me the info.
- All right.
Bro, these are upper deck.
Her grades ain't great, I know.
Which is cool, 'cause I ain't goin'
to no lily Jesus school anyway.
- She takes after her mother.
- No, I don't.
Just with a better attitude,
you know?
Your father was a lot like
you when he first enrolled.
Became one of our
better students.
Is she involved at all
in athletics?
- Uh, no.
- Has she made her sacraments?
I don't think she's even
married yet, far as I know.
Okay. She's done
her baptismal.
I made sure of that.
No communion, no confession
when she was in grade school?
Geddes:
No.
That's...
that's gonna set her back.
Geddes: I didn't do any of that
stuff till I was older either.
And frankly,
between you and me,
I think the idea of having
an eight-year-old child
confess to anything
is straight-up bunk.
I mean, what's an
eight-year-old done wrong
that they need forgiveness from above?
Really?
Okay, look,
I will confess to this...
I have done wrong by this girl.
She is a better person than me,
and if I can come here,
then she should be able
to come here.
Father Rayburn: Perhaps we
should talk tuition, then.
Geddes: I went online. 8200?
- There are payment plans--
- Never mind about that.
There.
Whoa.
We good?
Hey...
do not act the idiot in class.
( class bell rings )
Father.
( ringtone chimes faintly )
_
Youth: Yo, yo, yo, ghosty comin'.
Check it.
What's up?
S'up?
Why aren't you guys in school?
- We's sick.
- Sick?
( coughs ) Damn, for real, dawg.
Crazy sick.
Kid:
We got bronchitis.
Ain't nobody got time for dat.
- T around?
- Who?
( man grunting )
Hey.
- Jesus. Damn, Frank.
- Here.
You gotta give
a brotha a heads up
you creepin' around like
that, know what I'm sayin'?
- Damn, this heavy.
- It's foam, T.
Where's it goin'?
In the truck?
Uh, here's good for now.
- Here?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Train: Might not
be able to tell,
but I ain't hit the gym much.
Tell me what you got.
Hell, OG busted,
runnin' dirty snatch a few blocks away.
Hash too.
Come on Train, I'm Homicide. I
don't give a shit about that.
Yeah, yeah, I know...
I'm tracking down a cop killer.
I don't congregate
with those types,
know what I'm sayin'?
Streets talking at all about
a pusher named Billy?
Got smoked.
Went by "Boot"?
Coke, heavyweight?
Hey.
Hey, Jamal...
You know I tossed you a bone
letting you slide in the past.
And I do appreciate it.
I know they're working for you.
But if I ever get proof that
they're your dope boys,
I'm runnin' you in, okay?
It's straight,
Jamal. Go.
I ain't gonna say the what's,
when's, and why's of nothin'.
Somebody slangin' some 'caine.
I guess it's from
Lowdown's crew.
Lowdown?
I dunno, I ain't said nothin'.
But I guess there
was some weight.
Smack talk about some
robbery or somethin'.
Smoked somebody's ass,
but I don't know.
Okay.
Good.
Baby? Baby?
What?
This is crazy.
I'll call my buddy Fats.
He'll take it.
Okay.
I just...
I can't believe I did all this.
You didn't do all this.
Really?
Nobody else was shootin' their
load to make the decisions.
You kept things goin'.
No.
We were right.
Things just moved too quick.
We shoulda been,
shit, ten steps ahead.
Well, we will be.
From now on.
'Cause things are probably gonna
get worse before they get better.
( music plays within )
( knocking )
( dog barking )
Isaiah around?
How'd you jack up your hand?
A-K's pecker's
too big.
That's not what the
Woodward honeys are saying.
Isaiah:
Well, God and damn.
A real Homicide detective
as I live and breathe.
Keeping us safe?
- Good to see ya, Frank.
- You too, Isaiah.
- 'Round here, it's Reverend.
- You know, I'm not a religious man,
but even I think a title like that
oughta have some kind of plausibility.
Does to those who
entrust me with it.
Would you take a walk?
He's a big boy.
He don't need your help.
We know what's up.
What's that?
No games.
We know.
"Boot" here got smoked
in a trap house.
Suddenly one of your guys
is pushing weight.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Well, you need to know
what I'm talking about.
Because we think he
killed Brendan McCann.
Whoever killed him,
is also involved,
you know what I'm saying?
This ain't no B-on-B
crime that's gonna go away.
Now, I'm coming with respect.
I know a lot of guys
looking to find out
whoever's involved
in McCann's murder.
I may not be able to come with
so much respect next time, see?
Drop a name.
Any heat on you drops with it.
You got a lot
of crabgrass there, Nate.
They got the good stuff on sale
at the corner-- clear that right up.
I'll get some today.
Thank you.
Truth is,
I don't know anything about
McCann or some drug dealer who's slippin'.
Both of 'em shoulda been
more careful, I guess.
Let me disseminate,
see what shakes loose.
( car engine starts )
Any of you punk-ass
hood rats
know why a Homicide detective
is rollin' up on me?
Belongs to these two.
That guy was driving.
Does look like a Challenger,
doesn't it?
Oh, Dani Kahlil.
Check-plus smiley-face.
Frank know?
Frank know what?
I found a homeless person in the
neighborhood where Billy was killed.
She saw a Challenger parked
outside the trap house.
No kidding.
A plate?
No, but I found a Challenger
parked outside Abusauan's store
around the corner that morning.
- This look like my boy, you stupid bitch?
- Excuse me?
You came to my house,
acting like y'all care.
Then you saying he a killer?
A cop killer?
- Miss--
- Uh-uh. You too.
There with your girl. How you feel
if somebody call her a killer?
Okay.
You sayin' that my boy
was with a camel and killed a cop?
That's what you tellin' me?
He hated Chaldeans.
He could barely tolerate whitey.
Kahlil: I am sorry what
happened to your son,
but this is not
how you deal with this.
Shut your mouth.
Kahlil: Your son is a
person of interest.
Rosyln:
Person of interest, my ass.
Just give me a sec, huh?
So Frank was real smooth
sneakin' outta there like that, huh?
That's one way of putting it.
How ya been?
Fine.
I mean, you and Frank.
Me and Frank?
C'mon.
I am a detective, D.
I see how he looks at you.
You guys hang after the fight?
No.
There's nothing's going on there.
Make sure everyone else
knows that too, please.
Sewing circle around here.
Come on, we all do it.
I hit LC, who hit Hernandez,
who hit Shana,
who I think hit the boss.
It's what we do.
Share it all.
Including STD's.
Well, you know what they say,
incest is okay
as long as you keep it in the family.
So, who's Frank hooked up with?
That is a good question.
My man keeps
his biz on lockdown.
Did you catch a nickname,
anything?
Clerk:
I told you, nothing.
The idiot was bitching about
the price of Pall Malls.
Hey, Habib.
You remember if the cheap son of a
bitch's buddy pawed these mags?
I dunno, they all do.
And they don't even buy 'em.
Great. So you won't mind if we take
'em for fingerprints then, will ya?
Just be cool,
we'll return 'em to you...
at some point.
( engine stops )
( car horn honks )
Hey, man, what's up?
Is Michael home?
No, I thought he was with you.
Nah, nah, he hooked up with this
DTF black chick last night.
He was totally sprung.
They left together.
It's all right.
I'll just keep callin' him.
He does this all the time.
Thanks, man.
( tires screech )
You got us there.
I closed it.
It's what partners do.
We're partners, huh?
Better you than some rook with
a hot dog hangin' out his ass.
Thanks.
Oh, I figure you got a year,
eighteen months left.
Everybody knows
this is just a pit stop for you.
So, whatcha thinking?
FBI? CIA?
Maybe get yourself a
decent pay over there.
Now I'm confused.
Are you trying to sleep
with me or get rid of me?
I'm just saying I'm glad you're
here for McCann's murder.
Well, technically
I'm on Billy's murder.
And it's not making sense.
Why?
So...
Billy and the other guy from the
sketch killed Anton and McCann?
Yeah.
Mr. X in the sketch is the key.
And then Mr. X
killed Billy?
Well, he won't be Mr. X
once we lift these prints.
So if Mr. X killed two people
with Billy, dumped the bodies,
then what the hell's he doing
hanging at a liquor store
with another white guy before
he goes back to kill Billy?
I dunno. Maybe there were
three people involved.
Maybe Mr. X is a
sociopath who can
stroll up for some beef jerky
after he's already killed two brothers.
All I'm saying is I seen some
straight crazy over the years
that you just can't explain.
That's why we follow
the evidence.
How'd it go?
( sobs )
And buy cheap ones.
Tampon too good,
absorb natural fluid.
Get toxic shock.
And get cigarettes.
And pot pies-- beef.
And come right back.
Okay.
( distant siren wails )
( woman laughing )
( laughing )
Katia.
( in Romanian ) One minute.
How are you?
Okay.
What you doing here?
After I saw you
like that last night, I...
Like what?
Scared.
I wasn't scared.
It was my computer.
Look, I know what happened
the night Joe took you to Windsor.
You don't need
to be afraid anymore.
Okay?
I'm gonna fix it.
How did you end up here?
I don't know.
This where I work now.
Why didn't you call me?
Did you get my messages?
They took my phone.
But you could've called me
from anywhere.
I don't know.
I left Detroit and...
I didn't know what to say.
Well...
it's okay now.
Your friend can say
you ran off,
gone without a trace.
Nobody's the wiser.
- Then what?
- Huh? Then what?
Yes, then what?
Then it's just us.
What's that mean?
Mean we move
into your house together?
Go on dates,
with your cop friends?
What? No, no...
I'm not going back to Detroit.
I have to go.
I'm sorry.
- Katia--
- Stop.
We talked about this.
Whatever debt you
have with whoever, I can fix it.
Everything's gonna
be okay, I promise.
- Please, go home.
- Look, you don't need to be scared.
I can keep you safe.
That's not it.
Then what is it?
You're a good man, Frank.
But you were a trick.
What?
I'm sorry.
It's my job.
To make you feel good.
You know how many men say
they run away with me?
This isn't like that.
Name one thing I like.
Come on, Katia,
you like...
you like lots of things.
My name is not Katia.
_
Missed ya last time. The phone
number you gave me was disconnected.
Ahem.
Sorry-- sorry about that.
Do you have access
to a phone regularly?
Counselor:
You know, if you can't
be here physically, it's okay.
We can do sessions
on the phone.
Okay.
How's the sleep been?
Still waking up a lot?
Is the medication helping?
I don't know.
Have you been
taking it regularly?
Sometimes.
Well, you gotta be
diligent about that, okay?
Nick?
What's on your mind?
Nothing.
( engine starts )
( radio blares, stops )
( doorbell chimes )
_
( horn honks, tires screech )
( horn honks )
( dogs barking, radio plays )
( growls )
( car engine starts )
( engine starts )
( store doorbell chimes )
Yo.
( gunshot, rustling )
( dog barking )
( engine starts )
( barking )
( knocking )
Frank?
Hey, Dani.
Can I come in?
Where have you been?
You know.
Here. There.
Half the department's
been looking for you.
Hey, look, you found me.
I just needed to clear my head.
About what?
Everything.
Can I come in?
Yeah, come in.
You look like shit.
Well, you don't.
Here.
Thank you.
Frank, what are you doing?
I, uh...
I'm sorry about the other night.
It's fine.
You didn't do anything wrong.
I shouldn't have
behaved like that. I...
I mean, I've been
thinking about it.
I've been thinking about you...
Frank, you're not
in great shape.
I'll take care of it, man.
Don't worry.
I'll call ya.
It was the smart play.
But it had to be done,
right, baby?
Yeah, baby.
It had to be done.
I thought I'd let you sleep.
I gotta get
cleaned up for work.
Why'd you really come over
here last night, Frank?
Was it just to get some?
If it is, it's okay.
It's what we do, right?
( footsteps fading )
I'd get to my purpose fast.
I shot Billy and I used your
drugs to open the blind pig.
Is that all?
Lowdown's coming after me.
Now, why would he do that?
Because they robbed me
and they stole your drugs.
And they killed Michael.
So we hit back.
It's unfortunate when something
you worked hard to attain
is taken from you, isn't it?
Yes.
Did you see your friend die?
Were you there
when it happened?
Yeah.
Now you need me--
to protect you?
After your transgressions.
I'll give you double the
taxes on the International.
Plus I'll help you
get your drugs back.
That's of no interest to me.
You already got
the cops thinking...
you already got the cops
thinking that I killed McCann.
Aren't we even now?
You really thought I didn't know
what you were up to, Damon?
You thought you were
better at this than me?
You're only up on two feet because
your old man knew his place.
But now...
looks like we have
a situation, don't we?
I know where you dumped
the guy from UAW.
And his buddy, too.
People would look
at that Ty Cobb statue
a lot differently
if they knew, wouldn't they?
Yeah, others know too.
So if anything
happens to me or Maya,
your decrepit old ass
will die in a cell.
Hey, bad news.
No usable prints
from the magazines.
Mm-hm.
Where were you?
What, are you writing a book?
Geddes: Just like to know why you
vanished for a day and a half.
When you sign my checks,
I'll tell you.
Skelos:
It took a lot of guts,
demanding to meet
in public like that.
And why?
The reason for all this?
To avenge a perceived slight
against Dad.
Oh, how beautiful,
how poetic.
It's the stuff of Aeschylus.
The irony though,
Damon's ambitions are more reflective
of myself than his father.
I mean, his father
was a hard worker--
Till you scraped everything and he had
nothin' left but a bloated liver, right?
Skelos: He at least he
knew where he belonged.
You, on the other hand,
strive for more.
Which got your dumb ass
in a whole heap of trouble.
Damon: I'm fine with
having beef with you.
Poppa T got
what he had coming to him.
Which I will never forget.
Damon:
Don't.
Skelos: Well, the
way I view things,
there's no real protection
for anyone without peace.
We taking the pig.
The big screens, the fryers,
the whole nice set-up.
Skelos'll keep supplying--
knowingly, this time.
That's fine. Screw it.
Take the pig.
Suits your kind
better anyway, right?
I will take over the
International as well.
I'm sorry.
I know it was your
family's business.
Yeah.
This could be one of
those game day spots.
Am I right?
Get some jerseys, some ferns,
all that kind of nonsense.
Make some bank.
- I like that.
- Mm...
Lemme do that.
I got it, Ma.
April, get your butt in here
and start setting the table.
They don't waste
any time, do they?
So, how was it today?
- All right.
- Hey, don't leave that out.
Well, what is it?
Dishes or this?
It'll be your ass
if you keep mouthing off.
Well, did you make
any friends yet?
- They're kinda nerdy. - Why? 'Cause
they're not throwing gang signs?
Please. They give you communion
or confession dates yet?
Gotta pass some
stupid prayer thing first.
- I will quiz you.
- Yay.
You know what?
You just go through the motions,
but don't become
no damn Catholic.
Ma, she'll decide
what she wants.
Still don't know how
you got to afford it.
That's because my boy
saves his pennies.
Something your mama never did.
At least you won't
have to deal with Sister Agnes.
Made my life hell,
pun intended.
Agnes? She teaches civics, she's
like a hundred and twelve.
Jesus, don't nobody
leave that place?
What up, dawg?
What you got for me?
Help yourself.
So what you got?
Got somebody you might wanna
look into about this.
This from you or Lowdown?
A-K just
a messenger.
Well, who is it?
You want some coffee?
Maybe some pop?
I know it's late,
but--
I'm fine, thanks.
And thanks again for
allowing me to come over.
I don't know what
else to tell ya.
They're runnin' that sketch
pretty hard, aren't they?
Yeah.
Find anything?
Well, that depends.
What you described...
is that what you saw?
Well, at this point,
to tell you the truth...
I don't know
what the hell I saw.
Looked like two men.
One dark, one light--
not sure about ethnicities
or none of that.
They put a body in that car...
and they put that car
in the river.
By the time I was done
talking in that interview,
I didn't know which end was up.
( beeps )
It never really
came across to me
like it was
a Middle Eastern guy, though.
Could be anybody, I guess.
( computer signal pings )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com