- Bye. Good luck.
- Thanks. Same to you.
- How much?
- 2.20.
You know of any trucks
heading for Salvador?
One just left.
Looking for a ride, babe?
You going by truck?
Boat.
It's a pleasure, sir. Take care.
You headed for Salvador?
Yeah.
Maybe I could catch a ride with you.
- And what do we get?
- What do you mean?
You know.
For 50 plus the ride,
you get what you want.
The works?
50 just for the basics.
What about 30 plus the ride?
40.
40's cool, right?
- 40 for both of us.
- That's what I'm saying, for both.
What do you say?
Let's do it.
I'm up.
Make yourself at home.
Pardon me, sir.
- What's the score?
- 1-0.
Take the helm.
You moan like hell.
You howl like an ambulance.
And you're the werewolf
with the little meat.
Cool!
You going to hang out a while
in Salvador?
Yeah, maybe I'll grab myself a gringo.
You from around here?
No, from Vitória.
Vitória up north?
Vitória down south.
No way!
Cool!
You know the place?
He doesn't know shit.
He's never been out of the state.
Hold this for me.
Give me the cigarette.
Hold it straight.
Got 100 says he'll drop in 12!
100 says he drops in 40!
That white rooster is a killer!
Come on, Whitey!
Come on, Whitey, give him hell!
Give him hell!
I'm paying 20 to 10!
Come on, you bunch of sorry-asses!
Come on, Whitey!
40 to 10, you dogs!
Who wants to bet more?
What the fuck
is wrong with him, Deco?
I'm paying 40 to 10, motherfuckers!
Hey, brother, you with the big head!
Hey, you big head!
40 to 10, my ass!
I'm paying 100 flat on the Whitey!
What the hell? Are you crazy?
That fool's got 100
on the white chicken!
I got 100 on the Black Cock!
I'm going to make soup
out of your chicken!
Come on!
And I'm taking 100 from that sucker!
Come on, Whitey, come on!
Go, Black!
Let's see who's the fool!
Go, go, go!
Go, Whitey!
Go!
All right, man, pay up!
Fuck, my rooster had it in the bag!
- In the bag, your ass!
- Fucking ninja rooster.
- You crazy?
- Whitey is a samurai, bro.
You ask me, that Black Cock
was doped up.
If I'd known he was doped up...
The gentleman is offering me a ride
to Salvador.
- What?
- I'm going to take it.
I'll get there faster by truck.
- Hey, Deco, check this out.
- What's wrong, babe?
See you around some time.
Where you going?
Give me a shot of rum.
Hey, you.
You up for a rematch?
No, thanks, brother, we're cool.
You his husband or just his boyfriend?
What's wrong with you?
Hey, man, chill out, you hear?
You won your bet,
and now you're fucking with us?
Just joking.
Hey, man, stop fucking with us, hear?
Chill, man.
Do I know you?
Cool.
Just messing around.
Have a drink. It's on me.
After all, I'm paying for it
with your money.
Drink up, and we'll bet again.
What are you sad about?
You're alive.
It's the rooster that's dead.
Come on, bottoms up, darkie!
Hey, that's a good one, bottoms up!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You looking for trouble, man?
- You just hanging?
- What's your problem?
Back off, man.
Don't push my brother.
You're fucking with us, so chill out.
Go sleep it off, man.
Look what I found.
I'll beat the shit out of him.
Chill out, man.
Come on, let's split this dive.
How much do we owe here?
Check, please.
I got 50 on the white rooster!
What the hell you looking at?
Think I'm pretty?
- I don't want you staring at me!
- Fuck off, motherfucker!
Relax, man.
Let's go, brother.
How much do we owe here?
Fucking buzzard!
You son of a bitch!
Holy shit!
Come on, Naldinho!
Wait here.
I'm going to cast off the boat.
- I'm losing it!
- Sit there.
Just sit here.
I'm right here, my brother.
Easy, easy!
Help me untie the boat!
Let's go, babe.
Hold him right there!
- Are you going to stay?
- Wait a second.
Help me! Easy!
Help, for Christ's sake!
I'm bleeding like hell.
Easy, we're almost there.
Fucking hole in my stomach.
Hold my hand.
Come on, Deco,
get me out of here, brother.
I don't want to die!
Relax. Just hold my hand.
Don't let go of my hand.
Just breathe.
Marinalva!
Marinalva! Marinalva!
Wait a second!
It's Naldinho, Marinalva!
He got stabbed! Open up!
If he's all fucked up, why don't you
take him to the hospital?
We got into a fight in Cachoeira!
Open the goddamn door!
I don't want to get involved.
Marinalva! Marinalva!
For Christ's sake, open up!
Faster, faster!
Come on!
Careful with his head.
Watch the leg! Watch the leg!
Take care of him
while I call a doctor.
Hey, Doc.
What is it?
An inch to the side,
and he'd have been a goner.
I'll settle the rest with you
next week.
Who do you think I am,
Mother Teresa?
Dois Mundos!
- What's up, champ?
- I'm cool.
- You checking out the market?
- You got it.
Hey, my friend,
you know of any cargo jobs?
Business is slow.
Nothing that I know of, but if
anything shows up, I'll let you know.
Cool.
Dois Mundos, I need a little up front.
Can you help me out?
An advance?
With business slow like this?
But I do have a little job
on the side, know what I mean?
Brand-new piece, never been fired,
but you only get paid after the job.
No, Dois Mundos. I'm clean now.
So now you're Mr. Pussy?
- Here's the sucker.
- Fool!
Making like a heavyweight.
She split this afternoon.
She's gone.
Left some food for us.
Must not have enjoyed your slapping
her monkey last night.
What the hell, brother?
You did it with her?
You two didn't even
wait for me to get better.
Hey, you find any action?
No, nothing, zero.
Marinalva came around this morning
for the rent money on the room.
Tell her to stick the rent
up her fat ass.
Shit!
Marinalva has a huge ass!
Sorry-ass piece of huge ass!
- Hey, Franciel!
- What's up, Deco?
Baldy.
Where you been?
Looking for work.
You know of anything?
I need somebody to spar with Franciel.
You up for it?
Stop by to talk it over.
Right.
Peace!
You crazy, drinking?
You're on antibiotics.
What's wrong, Deco?
You're pissed because of her?
You mad, Naldinho?
Dig it, Rufino.
Deco's in love with that whore.
In love with a hooker.
Piss off, Rufino.
I didn't ask for your opinion.
Hey, Fua, he's pissed
'cause the whore split on him.
He's lucky.
I had it worse with a whore
called Michelle up in the Amazon.
I started sniffing and feeling her up,
and look
at the size of the cock I found!
We used to hang out here
when we were kids.
It was cool.
Deco used to eye the dames
taking their brats swimming.
When they weren't looking,
I'd grab their stuff, right, Deco?
We'd split up that street over there.
Shit, we only got caught once, right?
'Cause you were
sleeping on your feet.
Sleeping on my feet?
Dig, bro, just standing there
like a fool.
You are always showing off.
I wasn't sleeping
on my goddamn feet.
Just standing there
like a mummy, bro.
Hey!
Hold this.
So many pothead bitches
fucking for free,
the gringos never
come around anymore.
We have to go door-to-door.
Where do you know them from?
He's my cousin.
And him?
He's the son
of my aunt's cleaning lady.
You take the girls back and forth
from the ships and get 5%.
5%?
10%. 5% for each.
And you can pick up some action
on the side.
And you cover for gas, right?
Right, she covers the gas.
Good evening!
So? How much?
40.
40 is too much! Too much!
No, no, no, good price, 40.
Too much money, muchachas. 20.
Look, muchacho.
20, only blow job.
30, all included.
Okay, muchachos. Deal, 30.
Come here.
Can you see from there?
Help!
Holy shit!
Look, man!
Holy fuck!
What is this, man?
What's this shit?
Karinna!
Hey, man, we need a doctor!
A doctor, understand?
Get on the radio, man!
Call a fucking doctor!
Take it easy!
No fucking cops on board, you hear?
Shit, man, the woman's dying!
Get a fucking doctor, man!
The woman's dying,
and you're pissing around!
Here, take her to the hospital!
What the fuck? Keep it, man!
Did I ask you for money?
I'm telling you to call
a fucking doctor!
Don't take the money, Deco!
Help! Help!
You just going to let the girl
die here, is that it?
Help!
I'll beat the shit
out of that white-ass gringo!
Easy! Take it!
That's all I've got!
The drinks are on me.
He's buying for me.
Hey, the man's buying!
He's got money!
150!
For a while, I thought
you were really having an attack.
I just felt sorry for that little
whitey, shaking like a leaf.
That sorry-ass captain was worse.
Fuck! All he could say was,
"Look, muchacho!"
"Look, muchacho"
must be that fool's mother.
"Look, muchacho!"
Come on! Stop!
Break it up!
Go take a breather.
What's wrong with you, Deco?
Next week there's
a tournament in Muritiba.
If you want,
I can arrange a fight for you.
50-50.
Thanks.
Hey, you leaving?
- Yeah.
- So early?
In just five minutes,
a super-sexy number by Brenda,
the princess of Xanadoo.
Got a smoke?
Thanks.
What's up, babe?
What's up?
I'll have a Cuba Libre, please.
When you going to ditch that sucker?
What's it to you?
So we make a little love,
nice and wet.
Hanging with you two is just for fun,
but I've got bills to pay.
The usual trick is 37.
If you want something sexier...
- Sexier?
- Yeah.
How much is the sexiest?
60.
60?
Let's do it.
Want to turn off the light?
Hey, brother.
I was going to call you,
but you were out cold,
so I let you sleep.
Dois Mundos came around earlier.
Says he's got some cargo for us
to take to Cachoeira.
Cachoeira?
If you're waiting for Karinna,
she's going to be a while.
The fat john is a V.I.P.
Pays good, but it takes him an hour
just to get it up.
Dois Mundos says there's somebody
making an offer on the boat.
We sell the boat for shit,
and then what?
They're hiring the sailors back
to work for them.
We do the hard work, and they just
sit on their asses sipping scotch.
Okay, brother.
I hear what you're saying.
Deco, you're my main man.
My respect for you is worth
more than a piece of pussy.
Hell, brother, my respect for you
is worth more than all the pussy
in the world.
Show me a huge piece of pussy,
and I'd take your friendship any day.
Come here.
Let me give you a kiss.
- Come here.
- No way! What the hell?
Come on.
You're my main man, bro.
Got it?
Hey.
Going to offer me a drink?
Serve one up, Fua.
Thanks.
You pissed at me?
Pissed about what?
Beats me.
You never came back
to see me again.
I didn't leave anything behind
over there.
Where you been, bro?
Around.
- Hey, Naldinho!
- Just getting a trim.
Hey, Dois Mundos, let's take care
of some business, brother.
Sit up.
- How old are you?
- 20.
Job?
Dancer.
Address?
I'm moving.
No address right now.
When was your last period?
You know you're pregnant?
You can get dressed now.
I want to come back here
and find the engine running.
If you're not here waiting for me,
I'll come after you, hear?
You think I'm going to run, brother?
Go with the Lord, man!
The car will be running
when you get here!
Hey, man, give me some
of that headache medicine.
3.50.
What, man?
The medicine, it's 3.50.
- You're short.
- What, man?
You gave me 2.30.
Come on, freak, open the door!
Don't look at me!
Open the door,
and don't look me in the face!
You crazy?
Open the door!
Don't look at my face!
- I need the key!
- What key, boy?
- Open the door!
- The key to open the door!
Open the fucking door.
Nice and slow.
Come on.
- Don't look at me.
- Take it easy.
Grab the money!
Get over there!
Don't look me in the face!
Business has been slow!
Business slow, my ass! I saw a dame
leaving here full of medicine!
- Give me the money!
- She paid with her credit card!
I'm going to blast your face!
- I swear to God, she paid on credit!
- Don't bullshit me!
I came here for the goddamn money,
and I want it now!
Shit, brother.
Relax, brother. Were you hit?
Let me go.
What the fuck, fool?
Clean yourself up.
Let me go.
Relax.
Look at me!
Relax! Look at me!
- You alone here?
- I'm all alone, man.
Edvan, relax, brother.
I'm not going to hurt you, okay?
It was an accident.
What do you want?
You got that shit the old granddaddies
have been taking?
What?
That pill they take to get it up.
Don't look at me!
- Get the pills!
- Easy! Which one do you want?
Give me the most expensive shit
you have. Stuff it in my backpack.
I'm helping you. Take it easy.
Damn!
Stuff that shit in my backpack!
Got two great products, one for
balding and another for losing weight.
I'm not asking you anything!
Just put what I told you in the bag!
It's worth 100 a box, man!
- One box?
- Sure, man.
So fill up the bag. Move it.
Stuff it all in there!
Sit down! I said, sit down!
Piss-pants!
What the hell is this?
That's what I'm asking you,
what the fuck?
Belongs to Dois Mundos.
What do you want this piece for,
Naldinho?
Brother, this shit is fucked up!
I'm going to do a number
on a drugstore.
Dois Mundos has the place staked out.
No cops, nothing! Piece of cake!
- I'm giving this shit back.
- No way!
- Not until I do the next drugstore!
- I sure am!
Give me the piece, brother!
Give me the fucking piece!
Give it to me!
Let go!
Give me the piece!
Let go, brother!
Fucking shit!
Sorry, man.
Sorry for what, man?
You want to get messed up?
Go ahead, fool!
Messed up in your shit again! Do it!
It's over for me, man!
History!
Let's have a round of applause
for Karinna, our blonde volcano!
Can I get some change?
In a few minutes,
another number by Sirlene,
our delicious black panther!
Hey! Want to go upstairs?
Not now, babe.
I'm paying tonight.
Come on.
No, don't take it off.
Don't take it off.
I was thinking...
I've got some new action.
I want to take you out of here.
Action?
I pulled off a job.
We can sell the stuff
and chill for a while.
What job?
Some medicine shit.
You got it?
I'm like Santa Claus
for all the limp dicks.
Give me that.
Hot...
Blonde...
What about the boat?
We're going to sell it.
I'd rather leave everything as is.
Why?
Because of everything.
Because of him?
What do you want?
- I don't know.
- You have to decide.
I can't stay away from you,
or from him either.
You have to decide!
Get out!
Get out of here!
I came here to talk.
Can we go for a walk?
I'm working out.
So stop by the club for a beer.
I'm splitting tomorrow.
So I'll wait for you over there,
and we'll talk after you work out.
Don't be upset.
I hate to see you
and Naldinho fighting.
Me and Naldinho have known
each other since we were little.
We're not crazy to fight over a bitch.
I don't want
anybody's warmed-over leftovers.
Chill, you and your little boyfriend.
I'm tired of sorry-ass fools who don't
give me a thing and think they rule.
Get the fuck out of here,
before I smash you in the face.
Out!
Hey, chubby, what's your name?
Marcelo.
Marcelinho.
Come here. Buy me a drink.
Today's my birthday.
Help yourself.
Get lost, girl.
Go dance on your own turf.
Hey, Karinna, you okay?
I'm fine.
Beautiful.
They didn't find any gunpowder
on your hands. Only on the gringo's.
But there was coke in the cabin,
so we'll be calling you back
for more questions.
You're in deep shit.
Am I free to go now?
Sure. They paid your bail.
- Who?
- What do you mean, "who"?
Who paid my bail?
Valmir Gonzalves dos Santos.
Valmir?
I heard what happened to you.
You got into deep shit.
The cops are fucked up.
You all right?
I just want to split here.
Where to?
Anywhere.
The precinct captain's
got the heat on me here.
I'm living in a little flat
Dois Mundos lent me.
Cool.
It's nice.
You could move in with me.
Better not.
Why?
Move in with me.
Look at the man who's asking you
to move in with him.
Come on.
I'm pregnant.
Pregnant?
Really?
Cool.
Move in with me.
I'll take care of you...
...Karinna.
Got another fight for you,
day after tomorrow.
It's a kid, son of a hardware store
owner from around here.
Important.
What's my cut?
400.
You can hit him all you want
until the third round,
but then you have to take a dive.
Don't get me wrong,
but I think I'll pass.
You keep 500, and I'll take the rest.
Then we'll get another fight.
You're not a kid anymore.
Take the fight.
Dois Mundos lent me all this.
I'm going to pay him back.
Make yourself at home. It's free.
The bed's beautiful.
All white.
Does it still hurt?
No.
What about here?
It doesn't hurt anymore.
It's all better.
What about here?
- Yeah, there it hurts.
- Really?
It hurts?
Hurts like hell.
I picked up two more fights for you.
Saturday in Arapiraca
and Sunday in Maceió.
Fua, if you'd gone to school,
you wouldn't cook like this.
That's all there is, slop of the day.
The special.
Want some more?
What's up?
Pour it on!
- More?
- More.
You disappeared?
Here I am, man. What's up?
I need to have a word with you.
Later, brother.
- You know who's been around?
- No.
Your main man, the boxer.
Came to me wanting to sell the boat.
Just telling you because you're cool.
If I was you...
Right, fellas?
Hey, Fua! Give me a beer!
I stopped by the club asking for you,
and they said you were here.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm thinking of selling the boat,
and I thought we could...
Better not.
Why?
You'd end up killing each other.
I'm pregnant.
- I could...
- I'm splitting.
Is that what you want?
In just a few minutes,
short, hot, and horny, Sirlene!
Sirlene?
What?
The girls were saying
you're heading up north, right?
Day after tomorrow, I'm catching
a ride on a truck to the Amazon.
They say a blow job
is worth a gold nugget up there.
What's a nugget?
A little gold pebble.
I was thinking
of heading north myself.
Maybe I could go with you.
I've had it with those two.
They're going to end up in a mess.
Karinna.
Zilú told me.
About what?
The baby.
How long?
A month, tops.
Stop around tomorrow,
and I'll get you some pills, okay?
Cool.
Dois Mundos, what's up?
I came by to have a word with you.
Wait a second, bro.
Can't you see I'm eating?
Listen.
Man, I'm splitting this week,
and I just stopped by to pick up
that money of mine.
What money?
From the medicine, Dois Mundos.
That's rent on the apartment.
Brother, if you pay me
what you owe me,
I'll pay you the rent, Dois Mundos.
You trying to rip me off?
It's her.
- She's what, man?
- It's her.
Go fuck yourself, Dois Mundos.
What do you mean, "it's her"?
You dissing me?
- What the fuck is wrong?
- Bro, you sleeping on your feet?
He doesn't even have
to keep his eye on the babe.
- Somebody else already does.
- What's your point?
She was hanging out
with the boxer, real tight.
I'm going to blast you, motherfucker!
Don't mess with me, Dois Mundos!
Let go of me!
What's wrong, man?
What the fuck, Dois Mundos?
Even you?
The man's just telling you,
because he's your brother, man.
What the hell, brother?
Even you?
Go, man. Check it out!
Why'd you do it, brother?
I didn't do anything.
- She's expecting my child, Deco.
- Your child, my ass!
Fuck off!
Sit down.
Sit down!