Leni Riefenstahl  Tiefland
What do you want?
Mr. Mayoral, the stream has been diverted
So what?
It has been dry for one year now. We need water for our fields.
Is that water yours?
It belongs to us all, Sir. It comes from above
So
Mr. Mayoral, we beg you, let the stream flow freely again
No, the Marquis needs that water for his bulls
Be careful. Don't be so nervous
I hope he'll come today
Should I send someone at the castle to ask?
He'll come today
Try to look a bit more joyful, Amelia
He can get my money also with the way I look now
But he is the Marquis of Roccabruna, don't forget that
The Marquis is a beggar.
Someone should finally tell him.
Be careful! If not everything will be over.
When I'll be there, the first one I'll throw out is Don Camillo
Today he asked for his commission again
After the wedding! Give him half of his commission now.
It will be a great honor for the family
when you will be the marchioness
In fact it's too much money for this honor
Mr. Marquis, it's time.
The mayor has been waiting in vain three times already.
Is there no other solution?
The Mayor of Huesca is a rich man
I don't like that woman
But the Mayor is very rich and Donna Amelia is his only daughter.
00:14:11,756 -- 00:14:15,322
Next week, parts of your debts have to be paid.
And there is no money left.
What about moneylenders?
Impossible not the ones in Barcelona nor those in Madrid.
And besides, everything here is in pawn.
But why do I have so many debts?
How is that possible?
If you don't trust my words,
I can also leave.
Nonsense, Camillo
But tell me: what about the rent the peasants pay?
Since you had this weir built, the peasants have
no more water. So their harvests are really bad.
I can't let my bulls die.
The best bulls of the province.
The province? The whole kingdom you mean.
Well then let's go!
Do you like the food Pedro?
Why don't you come more often?
I like to be alone in the mountains
You cannot remain alone all your life.
I really love to be alone
Did you find that pelt?
Or did your sheep kill the wolf?
Found?
Don't laugh like that, stupid girls.
Pedro, here's some flour. Do you still have salt?
Then I'll give you some to take with you
Pedro, which one of us all do you like?
None!
Do you already have a girl?
And how does she look like?
Is she prettier than I?
Yes
Don't leave so quickly Pedro!
Here is the salt
Thanks Josefa
Don't you want to leave that pelt here?
No, I'll come back when Don Sebastian is at home
Bye bye
Bye bye. Come back soon!
Please, the sixty-year-old Malaga wine!
Immediately Sir!
Very old.
Can I ask you for a glass of water?
Water for the Marquis!!!
May I ask you for your arm?
With pleasure
The Marquis is in a good mood I hope?
Of course everything will work out well
It would be a happy marriage
What a lovely night
But the Marquis seems thinking
Would you share your thoughts with me?
I was just wondering how I could express myself
Oh something special?
Very
I have been thinking about it for days.
I beg you, express yourself.
I am wondering
how I could enlarge my bull breeding
The bulls your real passion.
Is it profitable?
I don't keep bulls to earn money.
But I wanted to ask something else, Donna Amelia:
would you want to become my wife?
Your wife?
Ah I understand You need money.
Well, I'll think about it.
My child, what happened?
Leave me alone
Sir
My best regards to Donna Amelia
Are you leaving already?
Bonsoir
Music please!
The Marquis will pay for this!!!
He'll pay for this
But my child calm down.
I'll have him on his knees.
It will be finished with his arrogance
when he knows who has his promissory notes
the beggar of Roccabrona
You are laughing, but I'll have to fix it!
Let's go
Wait for me
Don Sebastian!
What do you want?
I'm bringing you a wolf's pelt.
Did you kill the wolf?
yes Sir, I killed it.
I'll give you one Deuro for every wolf you kill
Go back to your sheep.
Come to the castle tonight. She should dance for me.
Wait here!
Welcome in my house
At your service, Sir
Go to the kitchen, there you can eat
And you come with me.
He little friend, come!
You cannot expect that you will sit at the same table as them.
Do you like it here?
What's your name?
Martha
Martha Tell me about yourself Martha.
There is not much to tell, Sir.
We wander along the roads
and stop when we find inns,
then I dance there.
Where did you learn to dance?
I never learnt it
So it's a natural talent.
And this guy is you lover?
No, Sir
You cannot fool me!
Yet it is the truth.
I'm just happy to be able to dance
But you are not letting me have a drink alone?
Come Drink with me.
To your beauty!
Oh Sir, I know where it is
Yes?  Then get up
Pedro!
Nando!
- I'm glad to be in the mountains again
- Do you come from the low land?
Yes,
but here, I feel a free man.
Do you have anything to drink?
I have plenty of milk.
Where are your sheep grazing?
At the lake
- Do you have many lambs?
- Sixteen!
I had twelve but the golden eagle took two
Were you in Roccabrona?
You have changed Pedro
since I was here last.
That's a while ago.
Changed, you say
Yes Nando,
before I was happy that
the sun was shining only for myself
and the sloes were scented only for me.
Now, I would like to share
everything that is nice
and makes me happy
with a woman.
Do you anything about women?
I never was with a woman
You'll find women only in the lowland.
And the lowland is bad.
The women there are possessed by the devil
I know one and I'm even prepared to fight with the devil
Yes, I know one.
Come
Choose something
Make yourself beautiful
That's the way you should look for me!
You're to good to wanderand dancing in inns.
The old guy, the musician, he's not your father is he?
Does he beat you?
I won't let you go back to him.
I want you to stay here.
Say you want stay
I love you
and want you to love me too.
Listen here. You have beaten that girl.
I'll have you whipped out for that.
When you're still here in an hour,
the dogs will kill you.
Go!
Hurry up!
I can't give you more. Only one bucket per person.
Good day Don Sebastian
- Is everything all right?
- Yes Sir.
You devil!
Here we believe that the devil can take possession of people.
He's good to you, as good as he can be.
But the peasants call him the wolf.
How could we help the peasants?
You can't, I can't. None of us can.
I'll talk to him.
- He'll beat you
- No, he'll not beat me.
I have a surprise for you.
I want to give you this.
Now it's yours.
I have a request
Anything you want!
The peasants have been waiting for hours
I know what they want
Talk to them
That's my request
All right, I'll do it.
Well
Sir, the village is in distress.
The well has run out.
We must have water!
Ah! You must
Our cattle die of thirst, the fields are dry.
The corn is burned.
If you don't give the water,
we cannot pay the rent.
Then I'll have chased away
Sir!
Will you give us the water?
Go
What do you want?
I have to talk to you.
Take this for the rent.
I want to help you.
Goodbye.
- Natario, did you fix it?
- Yes.
The millstones are turning again
Yes, the millstones are turning again
Today is our lucky day.
We can pay the rent.
That foreign girl gave us this.
Who?
The girl from the castle
Don't you know it belongs to that monster?
We do not need charity.
We just want our rights,  do you understand?
Our rights!
You did not pay attention to what happened, why?
You swine.
You should watch out! Go! These idiots all the same.
What are you going to do?
Natario! Natario!
No more water.
The monster!
Donna Martha has a good hart.
She's very generous with the gift you give her.
Natario, the miller brought the necklace back.
He said he doesn't need charity.
Martha!
You are not wearing the necklace.
Did you lose it?
No.
What did you do with it?
Answer me!
I gave it to the miller
so he could pay the rent.
What?!
Here Put it on.
You have been seen at the weir last night.
And you own rent to the Marquis, one year of rent.
Now it's enough.
You'll be thrown out.
Martha!
Camillo!
did you see Donna Martha?
Donna Martha?
- She left the house
- When?
A few hours ago.
Ask my men to search for her.
All right.
Any idea where she could be?
Did you beat her?
One day you'll be able to rule, Donna Amelia
First there has to be a wedding.
That's why I came.
Let's see the debts of Aviedo ten thousand.
And another for Aviedio, six thousand.
But sixteen thousand were was already paid
How much is outstanding?
Here I have..
I know very well.. if it's a lot, it's too much for me.
And here two creditors: both ten thousand
Thank you so much!
And then here.. two, eight, nine thousand
Every time it's more.
You promised me to get rid of that slut.
But Donna Amelia, please
You keep telling me he'll throw her out like all the others.
I'm still waiting!!!
Maybe she will become the Marquise of Roccabruna
There is no reason to get upset. She left already.
- Really?
- Yes, I succeeded
You? Maybe he got tired of here?
Mmm with a helping hand
Well, let's go back to business.
How much is the total?
A grand total of 35.000.
All right. Tomorrow it will be paid.
But it's the last time
Your words sound hard, Donna Amelia
50.000 for a Marquisit's...
A bargain
Sir, we found this in the hills at Campo Verde
- Anything else?
- That's all, Sir.
We really looked everywhere.
If you can't find her I'll have you flogged.
Water water
The peasants the peasants
Calm down
calm down
I am with you.
Come here!
Dona Martha !
Oh she's hurt.
Caramba!
- I'm coming with you
- You stupid boy!
she's from the castle.
- What do you wish?
- Sir, just a few small things.
These are my promised notes..
So Maybe next year if the harvest is good.
I'm afraid
I cannot wait till next year
What does that mean?
I'll have to foreclose
My dear Mayor
I think there is a solution
Of course!
But the insult my daughter
has suffered this
must be made good.
So?
You must keep your promise to marry her.
But first that woman must go!
Out!
- Sir
- Out!
We'll see who throws whom out
Damn...
Well, any advice?
You're always so clever.
There is no advice I can give.
Does he mean it?
Yes..
Giving up Martha no way
Don Sebastian...
You don't have to get rid of Donna Martha.
- There is a solution
- What kind of solution?
Donna Martha could be married off.
Are you crazy?
We'll find her a husband.
He doesn't have to be a real husband.
Pay someone from the village to give his name.
Donna Martha will be near to you.
It will not bother Donna Amelia
and you will be free of debt.
Not bad.
That's the solution!
We'll house the young couple
in the house with the mill.
It's not too far away.
Does anyone live up there?
Only the shepherd.
Yes, the shepherd.
His man brought you back
Josefa!
I want to leave
Wherever you go, you can't escape him.
Let us alone.
I need to talk to Martha.
Why did you run away?
Where you afraid?
There is no reason for that.
Pleas Sir, let me go.
No, we shall stay together forever. Here.
- Forever?
- Yes.
You think I'm the wealthy master of Roccabruna.
But I absolutely don't own anything, everything is in pawn.
A rich marriage is my only way out.
You want to marry?
Then I'll be free.
You will also marry
- I?
- I've already chosen a husband for you.
Oh no!
It's just a mock marriage.
You'll bear his name, nothing more.
In reality you will remain my wife.
And that man?
He gets the mill in return.
I'll never let you go.
Never again.
You hear?
I need you.
I'll rather kill you than let you go.
Pedro! I have news for you.
What's the matter?
Don Sebastian told me to come to you.
He wants you to become a miller.
What?
In the lowland?
- A miller?
- Yes. An order of Don Sebastian.
And you're getting married,
to the woman his men found in your hut.
What??? What did you say?
The woman who was in my hut?
Yes, you have to marry her
Have you seen her? Do you know her?
No.
I was told you saved her, that's all.
As a reward she'll be your wife.
- You, old man.. are you making fun of me?
- Of course not!
Son Sebastian ordered me to tell this to you.
And I must take your place here.
What's happening?
Are you out of your mind?
You know Nando,
I never thought I'd see her again.
I was walking in Roccabruna.
At the tavern I heard music and then
I saw her for the first time.
She was dancing.
She was so lovely Nando.
I forgot everything.
And now she's to be my wife?
Our master is very kind.
How can I thank him?
Pedro, you do not know the lowland.
People are different there.
Not good.
Nando I'm not afraid.
Goodbye.
Don't cry
don't cry
The bridegroom is downstairs
Send him away
Tell him to wait in front of the church
Yes
I'll come to see you tonight
tonight.
Martha!
finally you came.
Friend! A toast to love!
Three cheers for my beautiful bride!
Martha!
My dear Martha
I'll make some fire.
Why don't you look at me?
Come, sit here next to me.
Leave me alone
Leaving you alone?
Don't touch me.
But what's the matter?
Don't you like me?
I despise you
You despise me?
But why?
You took the mill
I preferred my hut!
Why did you marry me then?
Because I love you
Me?
You love me?
Yes.
She's not yours, stupid guy!
- what did you say?
- Let me go.
Come here.
Beg her pardon. He insulted you.
I beg you let him go
I should let him go?
Please, for my sake
If you want
You fool! You fool!
- Oh I was looking for you
- My dearest Amelia,
I'm sorry but I have to go
and meet someone for my cattle
But I don't like to be alone without you
Pedro.. Pedro Come in.
Come, don't leave me alone
But didn't you tell me to leave you alone?
Forget it
And that you despise me?
Do you know something I don't?
Maybe that's why they all laugh at me?
If you love, don't ask me anything
Whom can I ask? You know something.
Why are they laughing?
Everyone knows something I don't know.
But now I want to know:
why are they laughing?
Why am I a fool? Why? Why?
You Is there someone else?
Yes
It's our wedding night
- Let me go!
- That's the way I like you best
Try and take my wife if you dare.
Get out; I'm the master here
You are the wolf
FIN
English Subtitles:
text from http://users.skynet.be/deneulin/Tieflandst.html
timing by Lena Bolshakova (lena_bolshakova@mail.ru)
time marks mostly from French Subtitles by J.B.P. (2007, ptr4fr@yahoo.fr)