I knew Matthew Smith for 15 years
before the night of his final show.
Everyone remembers
his talent and face.
But the Matthew I knew was
strange, funny, and
unbearably insecure.
Matthew didn't show up for
that show 10 years ago...
Or any other show after that.
He left us all behind.
He left me, his girlfriend,
speeding off into the night,
completely and utterly totaled.
♪ Sitting on the floor
in the bathroom ♪
♪ spinning bowie around ♪
Hey, El?
Gonna go crazy.
Yeah, I was that, uh... that maybe
we shouldn't do this anymore.
You're breaking up with me?
Well, you know, breaking up would imply
that we were actually going out, I guess.
We have been going out for
three months.
No, you've been coming over to
my apartment after shows for
three months... you
know, which is awesome.
I like having sex
with you, but...
Oh, wow.
...to date, I suppose one
would go out on dates.
That's what I'm saying.
It's just I like you, and
it's not that you're older.
At this point in my life, it's
just like I want something more
than just, like, casual sex,
and... and it doesn't
seem like you do.
Now I sound like a dick.
What I'm saying is that...
Yeah, you sound like a dick.
Okay, you're leaving.
Hey, look, let's, like, still be
friends, and just
don't slam the...
♪ Even though I know
that I've done wrong ♪
♪ oh, I'd still
waste your time ♪
♪ a safe-haven child
cryin', lovin' ♪
♪ try to keep it together ♪
♪ oh, yeah ♪
♪ now, everybody wakes
up and holds on ♪
♪ nobody just like them ♪
♪ no ♪
♪ starin' at her eyes
'cause I need them ♪
♪ no, but they can't
see my pain, no ♪
♪ seizure comin' like
a rush of blood ♪
♪ pressure breaks and you start
to black out ♪
♪ wake up 'cause
you're mad inside ♪
♪ no one else sees a blackout,
no, like you do ♪
♪ yeah, yeah ♪♪
♪ so, what you want with me? ♪
♪ Oh, please just let me be ♪
♪ just leave me simply singin' ♪
♪ yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ oh, my God ♪
♪ here we go again ♪
♪ there's a hole in my head ♪
♪ all black and shining ♪
Hi, darling.
Just Doris calling to remind
just Doris calling to remind
you that the rent was due yesterday.
I'm sure it's in the mail.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Miss Ellie, it's your boss.
I need to talk to you, dear.
Kurt, where's Courtney?
Or, Courtney, where's Kurt?
♪ I, I, I, I ♪
Oh!
♪ Do you know what I mean? ♪
I would love to have him
shoot the cover,
but, you know...
Miss Ellie's here. I got to go.
I need to talk to you.
All right, well, you know, keep
up the good work.
I want to feature this guy.
Yeah. Who is it?
Lucas stone.
Why do you got to keep on
featuring all these nobodies?
You know, I thought stax was all about,
you know, discovering new talent.
Isn't that why you hired me?
I probably said that when
stax was still a beloved,
neolithic music magazine.
Neolithic music magazine.
Things change.
Mm-hmm.
No.
I've been surveying the
territory, and from where I'm
sitting, things are
looking pretty bleak.
Well, I think you're
underestimating our readers.
You clearly have not been
attending the same shareholders
meetings that I have.
Thank God.
Honey, I need you to go after
a bigger piece of
the readership.
You used to be my go-to gal.
Your last story... got
like two comments.
One of them was spam.
Apparently, that means the
world wide web finds your
current sensibility neither
controversial or... I don't
know... interesting.
Matthew Smith.
Last month's anniversary issue,
every artist we polled called
this one of the top-five most
influential records.
Yeah, I'm... I'm aware of that.
Well, I think it
justifies a story.
The lasting the lasting impact."
Giles... you discovered him.
You broke him, for
Christ's sake.
I know that there was a personal
element, but for God's
sake, it was 10 years ago.
You got to have enough distance
by now.
He's probably dead.
He's not dead.
He's just an asshole who's gone.
Even better.
The truth behind the truth
behind the mystery."
You are in a unique
position to do this.
You're sitting on a
huge fucking story.
The professional side of you
has got to understand that.
I am not sitting on a story,
okay?
I'm just not... picking at a
scab.
Okay, well, I cannot have you
ignore what's happening here
anymore.
We got to put a shock through
the system, and everybody's
got to do their part.
Don't make me do this.
You have to reclaim your
place at this magazine.
I mean, I do not get paid
enough to go there again.
Right.
I don't want to relive this.
So quit.
Mm. I can't quit my job.
It's always pride.
So write it.
Are there any other choices?
No.
Excuse me?
Do you want another?
But doesn't part of you
want to know what happened?
I'm trying to think what
I'd do if Angela just...
I mean, I couldn't handle it.
I'd have to know.
Well, how about this idea?
Let's not talk about it anymore.
Oh, now you're heading out?
Yeah. I've got a, uh,
singer to interview.
Well, hey, um, don't
sleep with him.
I'm a professional.
Okay. There's a name for that.
♪ Well, she always ♪
♪ wears blue jeans ♪
♪ she falls heavy like a freight
train going down, spittin'
grease ♪
♪ and it's just like ♪
Oola neat.
♪ What my father told me ♪
♪ he said, "son, never trust a
woman who drinks whiskey neat ♪
♪ she'll never kiss you ♪
♪ she'll never miss you ♪
♪ these rock 'n' roll
girls" ♪ Ellie, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Hey.
Hey. You're the guy
from the other night.
Yes, the business card
instead of a buck.
Ah. I'm not always so cheap.
Pull up.
Okay, so, this is weird.
This is, like, my
first real interview.
Are you really as naive as
you seem?
I don't know. Am I?
Let's find out.
Okay, do you mind if I...
Yes, please.
Okay.
Record away.
This is all very professional.
Hello.
So... Uh, when did you
start writing music?
This morning.
See? Nobody... I have never
met anyone who can do that.
Me either.
Uh, so, performing on the street...
I mean, who does that anymore?
Does that? People do that.
I do that.
You do do that.
I don't know.
I love to play, you know?
Mm.
And, uh... I'm really
broke, so, uh, the
money helps.
But, uh, you know, business
cards are also welcome.
Oh.
Thanks for that.
Just, uh... you're welcome.
...hard to pay for the rent
on business cards.
Mm-hmm.
Hard to pay for groceries with
it.
Oh, no, no.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You just... this cannot happen.
I'm... Drunk
and I am leaving.
♪ There but for the
grace of God go I ♪
♪ there but for the
♪ oh, no money in his pocket ♪
♪ and no hope in his eye ♪
♪ oh, but who am I ♪
♪ but ♪
♪ but for the grace of God? ♪
♪ And there are those
who, when they pray ♪
Jesus Christ.
Were you asleep?
It's 3:00 in the morning.
I remember a guy that used to
say the party was just getting
started at 3:00 A.M.
May I help you?
Well, I've decided to do the
no.
I decided that you do the
Matthew piece.
Okay, well, I'm agreeing to it.
I am just so overwhelmed.
Fucking nut-job.
Matthew, man... he was
intense, but in a fucking sexy
way.
I mean, we broke up three times,
but we always got back together.
I mean, he had his shit.
He had his demons.
But he... and he was talented,
as everybody knows.
But there is no way... there is
no way that he would have jumped.
Matthew... he was scared of heights...
Is... Is scared of heights...
Who was scared of heights?
Oh, this musician who's been
lost for years and years...
And years and years.
Really? Lost? Huh.
Charlie.
Ellie.
Ellie klug.
Okay.
It is good to see you.
Oh.
Coming in for an obligatory hug.
The timing wasn't
right when we dated.
I was emotionally unavailable.
Oh, yeah, that's, uh...
That's probably it.
I do think that your lack of
open-mindedness affected your
judgment of me.
I'm much cooler now.
Hmm?
Miss, could I get a clean
glass, a bottle of
water, and a whole lime?
No.
Is she a friend of yours?
She's closing up.
We're going to a gig.
A gig? Huh.
A gig.
What kind of gig?
Uh, a music show.
A music gig.
Nah. That's not my scene.
Good.
What style music is it?
Alternative rock.
Hmm. Alt rock.
You may call it
that if you wish.
Okay.
"Okay" what?
I'll tag along.
♪ Even if it was a mistake ♪
♪ I can't forget your face ♪
♪ even if it was just a day ♪
♪ you won't forget the one
who's making you shake ♪
♪ ahh, making you shake ♪
♪ you shake ♪ ♪ ahh, making you shake ♪
♪ you shake ♪ Charlie, what do you do?
I'm retired, but until
recently, I was in the
jewelry business.
Really?
Yeah, we had pieces crafted
from Mexican pesos, bits of
Caribbean currency, seashells.
Sold them online.
I got tired of it, so I dumped
the business last year.
Before that, I had a software
company and made about
$300 million on an I.P.A.,
so I can pay the rent.
Yeah, but you were rich
before that, right?
It's true.
I come from one of the oldest
families in north America, but
truth be told, we lost our
fortune in the panic of 1907.
1907.
Anyway, lately, I've
been taking some
documentary-filmmaking
classes, and I love it.
I really think it's what I'm
meant to do in this world.
I do.
What do you do again, Ellie?
I'm a music critic.
Ugh! That would be the
worst job for me.
I hate music.
All music you hate.
Is the bear a catholic?
I mean, really.
I think he might be.
I mean, you like music?
Okay, well, I'm beat.
I am so exhausted.
Uh... it was really great seeing
you, Charlie, but we... okay.
...dana... do we?
Yeah.
You know what?
Maybe we could get
lunch sometime.
I haven't seen you in five
years, and, uh, it could
be nice to see you again.
Uh, I say... yes!
I should be clear
about one thing.
Uh, I'm off dating, so...
Great. That takes the pressure
off of me to do all the
work in bed.
Do you want to... you want to...
Or do you want to write it?
You know what? I'll get it.
There's a crispness to my
writing that I enjoy.
"Ellie... klug."
Good night, girls.
So, uh... the design
on this site is so...
Just sad.
There was a time, my little
friend, when it was actually
difficult to build a website.
What are you finding?
There's a message board where
people post sightings.
All these people claim
to have seen him?
Claim to, yes.
Here's one for you this year.
Should I e-mail?
It does not look like it, but
we can comment on his post.
Send him my e-mail,
ask for more info.
No, no, no. Wait, wait. Don't.
Yeah, do, do.
Ellie?
I meant to call you.
Yeah?
I, uh... I just... I-I
couldn't write the feature.
Couldn't... couldn't
write it this month?
What do you mean?
It just felt wrong... somehow.
Felt wrong?
What are you... what
are you saying?
You're not gonna write it?
Okay. Is this because we kissed?
Whoop!
Uh, could you answer
that, please?
Ellie klug's desk.
Wow. Well, that sucks.
It's giles.
Hey, can I call you back?
What's up?
How's the story going?
Well, I can't do it if you
keep talking to me, can I?
Okay. I didn't know
you had a son.
Ha ha. Very funny.
Back to work.
I don't even get, like, a
blurb?
I don't even get, like, a little
side blurb, like, the blurb
underneath the blurb?
What do you want me to do?
I don't know.
Apologize, maybe.
Okay. Okay.
I'm sorry. I really am sorry.
Well, apology accepted...
Hesitantly.
Do you want to go out
sometime?
Hey, look, if you're not gonna write
the story, we might as well, right?
What? No.
Yeah.
Listen, whatever you
think is gonna happen...
Yeah?
...is not gonna happen.
No? So, you're gonna crush my dreams and
then you're not gonna give me a date?
Oh, you seem fine to me.
I'm not fine.
I'm broken.
So... who's, uh...
Who's the looker?
That is not intern-level intel...
Sir.
He says that's Matthew.
Could be anybody.
He's in Washington... Hobart, I
guess.
He wants 1,000 bucks.
Oh, I know. I know.
I know we don't do that, so...
don't do what?
Hmm? Pay for sources.
Pay for sources? What are we?
The national enquirer?
We don't pay for sources.
I can't believe you'd
actually make...
That kind of suggestion.
I could get fired.
Uh... he wants cash.
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ oh, yeah ♪
♪ hey, there she goes ♪ ♪ the
girl who don't wanna talk to me ♪
♪ but that's okay ♪
♪ just gonna annoy you ♪ ♪
till you make out with me ♪
♪ yeah, till you
make out with me ♪
♪ you know you want to ♪
♪ just make out with me ♪
♪ baby, just make
out with me-e-e ♪
So, listen, I've been doing a
lot of serious thinking, and,
uh, all joking aside, I-I think
I'm willing to give you a second
chance.
Clearly, all those years of
playing music have left you with
a serious hearing problem.
Come on. What is it?
Is it me? Is it my music?
Is my face funny-looking?
I mean, what? Give me something.
Nope. Yeah.
I don't know.
"No, yes, I don't know."
What? I didn't get any of that.
Musicians, I mean, men...
Toxic to me, and you're both, so it's...
it's... it's not
personal.
It's not personal.
How can you say
that's not personal?
Shit.
Hey.
I need your help.
Shoot.
I need you to come with me
tomorrow morning to interview
this guy who says he knows where
Matthew is.
I can't.
I got groundwater thing.
Oh, come on.
Don't make me go alone.
And Angela's finally going with
me, and you know she hates
my "causes."
Hello? Excuse me.
Yes. I see you. Yeah.
Oh, no! Fuck!
Shit!
I promise it's gonna be fine.
No, I am gonna get fired
or... fucking sued or both.
Giles isn't gonna
do that to you.
He already basically said
that I'm irrelevant.
Ellie, please call and
get it over with.
Oh, yes, and in other news...
Who's Lucius?
It's... can you read?
It's Lucas.
Lucas. I'm sorry.
It's the singer that I
didn't do the story on.
He keeps... and I keep...
Well, what'd he say?
Did you listen to it?
Should you listen to it?
Well, then delete it because you
know how it plays out.
What about that guy?
What guy?
The rich guy from the... the
fundraiser at the bar.
Oh, God. Charlie?
Yeah, he likes you,
and he's got money.
And... and he can help you.
No. No way.
No... no way.
I am not doing that.
Well, you should.
I have some pride.
So, you think he's still
alive.
Yeah, I do.
He just ditched you?
Well, I mean, not
ditched, but...
And then disappeared, never
to be heard from again?
Yeah, except maybe for this
guy who says he saw him in
a bar a few months ago.
Wow.
This is really
interesting to me.
Okay. I'll give you the
money to find that guy.
You will? Oh, really?
Mm-hmm.
But it's conditional.
Okay?
Lately, I've been taking some
documentary-filmmaking courses
at a local junior college.
I've been looking for something
that really speaks to me.
Speaks to me... right here.
Okay, so you want to do a
story about Matthew.
No. I want to do a
documentary about you trying to
find Matthew.
No, no, no.
I don't want to be
in your documentary.
And I don't want to
just give you $1,000.
What do you think?
Jesus. What's this?
What the hell is this?
Well, anyone who makes movies
has one of these, so this one is
I did.
They just delivered it.
What do you think?
Uh... permission
to board granted,
my lady.
You know how to drive, right?
What are you doing?
Interviewing you.
What? Now?
Why not?
It's for the documentary.
Because I'm basically driving
a submarine on wheels and I'm
not exactly a strong
driver, so...
Well, let me just tell you...
You are piloting this submarine
on wheels brilliantly.
Interview 1, take 1...
Ellie klug.
And... action.
Okay.
Uh... so... so, Matthew Smith's
music is unique in that it was a
blend of... cut! What is that?
That's, uh... I mean, I don't
really care about that.
Is that, like, music
criticism or something?
Yeah, that's what I do.
Right.
Well, I don't care about that.
And I'm fairly certain that
anybody that views this
documentary won't care, either.
You know what?
I think I'm just gonna focus on
the road here... if
that's okay with you.
Okay. Hostile interview.
Cut.
You know what?
I'm just gonna get some, uh,
various shots of the landscape.
You know, we call it "b" roll
in, uh, filmmaking.
It's for editing.
You're not gonna understand it.
It's over your head.
This better be the right way.
How you feeling?
Uh... anxious.
You know, it'd be good for me and
the documentary film that we're
shooting if you could expound
on your feelings and whatnot.
I don't want to
expound on it, okay?
I'm anxious.
It's been a long time.
Okay. There he is. That's him.
That... that's Matthew?
What? No.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Joshua?
- Yes.
You, uh... you guys
want to have a seat?
No. I'd invite you in, but, uh,
the place is kind of a mess.
So, that... that... that
video you sent, where
was that recorded?
Yeah. Um... can I ask...
Did... did you
bring the money?
I'm sorry to ask up front like
this.
It's just I've been burned
before, you know?
So I thought if we'd just get
this out of the way, then we'll
be more comfortable.
Sure. Uh, well, actually,
maybe I can give you, uh, half
now and then half when your
information leads to Matthew.
Okay, yeah. Sounds fair.
Okay.
Great. Thanks.
So, I mean, what was it about
this guy that made you
think it was Matthew?
Hang on a second.
Hang on.
Whoa.
What's this about?
Oh, we're making a
documentary about this.
Great.
Rolling.
Let me, uh... let me
tidy up the scene for
you.
So... you said you knew where...
where Matthew was?
Oh, yeah.
He, uh... he lives close by.
Where is he, exactly?
Uh... do you want me
to just go get him?
You know what?
I'll... I'll go get him.
Just stay put.
He lives like 10 minutes
away, 10 minutes's walk.
Uh, so I'll just grab him
and come right back.
Should we come with you?
Uh, no.
Well, he doesn't know I'm coming,
so I'll... I'll just grab him.
We'll be right back.
Just, uh, hang tight.
Just make... make
yourself at home.
Be right back.
We trust you... sir!
Oh, great. Lucas.
Is it all the way out?
Yes.
Does it look cool?
There's so many switches in
here, it's like a spaceship.
Kidding me?
Charlie?
What's going on here?
Uh, we're just... we're just waiting for...
for Joshua to
come back.
Joshua?
The guy that lives
in that trailer.
He was just here.
Don't no one live in that
trailer, 'cause I know who live
in my trailer.
It sure looked like he lived
in there.
This is your trailer?
I'm gonna need you
off my property.
Okay.
Well... yep. Yep. Yep.
We're out of here.
Have a great night.
Maybe we should call the police.
What are they gonna do?
Apart from arrest me for being
completely... naive and stupid.
Well, the good news is... you
can take your time paying me
back.
Of course, I'll have to charge
you interest.
Please tell me you're joking.
Charlie?
Yes, I'm joking.
But we're not gonna quit,
okay?
This is nowhere near the end of
it.
Uh... this is a complete and
utter dead end.
We have the video.
The video is just
some stupid bait.
You can't even see who's really
playing.
Come on.
Listen to me.
You have an obligation to your
story, to your magazine, and,
most importantly, to me to
complete a documentary film that
we set out to make.
And I don't have
enough footage, okay?
I have like three minutes, and
most of it is him running
away up that hill.
Well, I-I am not an
investigative reporter.
I am a music critic.
I don't know what the
hell I'm doing, so...
Then let's find
someone who does.
This is a note he... he left me.
This is the last
communication he had with you?
Yes.
"Babe, well, it's been a run,
honey, a real run, a sprint at
times.
Does this got to be?
Yeah, for me, and I say for you.
I'm in a dark place.
You know, what comes
up must come down.
I know you understand.
Matthew."
What do you think?
What is he talking about?
I don't know.
It's just... it's him.
But he says, "I know
you understand."
Well, I don't.
I don't think it's useful.
Don't you want to analyze
it or something?
Why?
I don't know.
Just, like, figure out where
the paper was manufactured or
analyze his handwriting.
I don't know.
What? Do you think it's
not his handwriting?
No. It is.
You know what?
We have a video.
It's crude, but it's a
documentation of sorts.
Okay, yeah.
Okay, I have this
video of him singing.
Well, it sounds like him.
Maybe you can take a look at it,
maybe you can take a look at it,
like, isolate the
voice or something.
I-I think you have some wrong
expectations about what I do.
I follow people.
Living people.
Would you like this back?
You don't need it?
No.
You know, I think maybe I
should take on your case.
You can't take on the case because
you're not a private detective, Charlie.
We need to go back to the
beginning, back to the
scene of the crime.
And this one... it's a move that
I invented.
It's a pistol whip.
A gunslinger whip.
A gunslinger tilt.
You ready?
Action.
How old were you when
you met Matthew Smith?
I was 16.
In the interest of
documentary filmmaking,
just elaborate.
I was 16 when I met
Matthew Smith.
Here at this camp.
Mm... that was a little
dry, emotionally.
Want to try it again?
This is where we had
our first kiss.
Really? How was it?
Too much tongue.
I mean, neither of us knew what
we were doing.
We got much better
at it over time.
That was it? Just kissing?
Yeah. That was a big
deal for me back then.
I wasn't exactly... confident.
Nobody here was.
Why?
Why weren't you confident?
It was, uh... it was...
It was a weight-loss camp.
Weight-loss camp? Hang on.
You met at fat camp?
It's not funny, Charlie.
Fat camp.
Fat camp is a little funny.
Stop saying "fat camp."
Well, did they call it
something else, like
k-a-m-p p-h-a-t?
Come here.
This is where we he
wrote his first song.
Performed it at talent night.
Oh, God, it was
really beautiful.
Yeah?
What'd you do?
I cried.
No, f-for talent night.
Oh. I, uh... I hula-hooped.
Did you terrify small children?
Shut up.
After camp, you know, we said
we'd stay in touch.
Yeah. He wrote me these...
Really beautiful letters.
Is that enough?
You know, I got to figure out
how to get this footage on
to my new editing system.
Or you know what?
Maybe I can just edit on here.
That was weird.
I don't think you're letting
yourself see the new me.
Charlie, neither of us are new.
Pbht!
I just think that
you and I could...
Okay, don't do take this
personally, but I'm not looking.
Seriously, I'm... I'm not.
That's cool.
It's totally cool.
That's a gracious rejection.
I don't know why I'd
take that personal.
I'm gonna hit the hay.
I'll take the rear bunk.
And you're in the,
uh, forward deck.
Okay. Solo.
Good night.
Night.
Ready? Ready?
And... action.
This is where Matthew first
started playing.
Man, he loved it here.
I used to, uh... I used to sneak
out of college to come see him.
Then we'd go on the
road together and...
Yeah, it was a lot of fun.
Actually, you know what?
It... it wasn't that much fun.
Everybody wanted him, and it was
like I got into some kind of
fucked-up conga line.
Was this the place?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Uh, they found his car over
there.
That's a long way down.
No one could survive that...
No one.
Charlie.
I'm sorry. My bad.
I think that Matthew may have
been left-handed.
Yeah, he was.
Really?
Mm.
So, did you know Matthew Smith?
I knew him.
I mean, I didn't know him,
know him, but I-I-I knew him.
I mean, if I've seen the inside
of his house, I've seen the
inside of his house, but a lot
of people have seen the
inside of that guy's house.
He was hugely talented.
Hugely.
What does... what does what does...
what does Matthew Smith's music mean to
you?
He was a huge influence on my
music, all my friends's music...
Maybe all music, I
mean, music itself.
People talk about cobain,
but fuck cobain.
He could have been so much more.
He could have been our
generation's... voice.
There's people that kind of
come and go in the music scene
whose "ghosts" always
live on, you know?
And he's definitely one of them.
I mean, you guys... you guys
were pretty tight, right?
We got wasted a couple times.
And did he ever seem like he,
you know, just wanted to...
...disappear?
What the hell do I know?
I bounce drunks.
Lucas.
There she is. How you doing?
Yeah, good.
Uh, Lucas... uh, this is Lucas.
Lucas, this is Charlie.
He's making a documentary
I'm helping him with.
How's it going?
Good.
Um... man, you never
called me back.
Yeah. I just, uh... yeah.
These things happen.
Hey, you should, uh... you
should at least have one of
these.
Here, you too, man.
No, sir.
When did you get these made?
Uh, last week, actually.
These look really good.
Yeah?
Yeah. Good for you.
Thanks very much.
Hey, if you guys are free
tonight, you should come down
the street.
I'm playing a little gig on the
stage, so not just a sidewalk
and drunk people yelling at me.
Yeah, sure. Why not? Yeah.
Do you want to?
Of course.
You should come, too, man.
Wait. What?
You... you want to
come, Charlie, or...
Now?
We're... we're quitting?
I think we're good for tonight.
I mean, if you guys are doing your
thing, you know, maybe I'll see you.
I don't want to...
Let's go. Go with you now.
All right, cool. Then...
Hey, see you later, Doug.
Um, good luck with the doc, man.
What just happened, man?
Thank you, guys.
Um, okay, this is a new one,
and, uh, I haven't really played
it before live, so
we'll see how it goes.
But, uh, I wrote it
for someone special.
I know that sounds cheesy, but,
uh, it's true.
♪ Yeah, she ♪
♪ caught me by surprise ♪
♪ well, she ♪
♪ she wants to feel the eyes ♪
♪ oh, well, she ♪
♪ was as restless as moonlight ♪
♪ oh, now, she ♪
♪ wasn't daylight
turned into night ♪
I want you to be my permanent
alarm clock.
Sure. Just follow you around...
...singing all the time.
Yeah.
Wow. Someone singing songs
written about me.
Hasn't happened in a long time.
Actually, um, I didn't... I
didn't write that one about you.
Oh, my God.
No, I-I-I wrote it for this,
uh, guy I met in prison.
His name's Bobby. "Big Bob."
Big Bob?
Big bog.
Big Bobby.
Big Bob was a sweetheart.
Here we are.
Wow.
Yeah.
What are we gonna do today?
I don't know.
Well, you know what?
I-I think we should do something
really stupid.
Like, really stupid.
Let's do this!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Terrible, terrible idea.
Oh, my God.
You're a madman.
What was that?
Put something on. Here.
I can't feel my testicles.
That outfit is... fantastic.
Man, you got a lot of records.
And, by the way, who the
hell still has cds?
I do.
That is a lot of cds.
Man, it is crazy that you
used to hang with him.
Like, you used to hang
out with Matthew Smith.
Yeah, well... that's insane.
Dude's, like, my idol.
No kidding.
And why did he kill himself?
It's like if I had half the
talent that this guy had...
That is the best song.
"Inside"? I love that song.
I used to listen to that song on
repeat in eighth grade.
Hi. You guys ready to order?
Uh... the salad.
The dressing.
Yes?
Does that have dairy?
I can check for you.
I'm extremely
lactose-intolerant.
If it has dairy, uh, I can't
have it anywhere near me.
Okay.
Also, I will have the toast,
but you'll need to burn that
because I cannot
ingest live gluten.
Okay, so, I'll... I'll just
take the, uh... the burger,
medium-rare, please.
Thank you.
So, I met a sound specialist
who thinks he might be able to
do something with the video.
Hmm.
I think I might be a better
investigative journalist than I
am a documentary filmmaker.
Well, Ellie, I think I have
found the woman that I am going
to spend the rest of my life
with, until they crank my coffin
into a coffin-sized hole.
Wow. That was fast.
Love happens, it happens.
Are you shocked?
I'm... I'm... no, I'm happy
for you.
Thank you.
Yeah, I really am.
Her name is Charlotte.
She's fun. She's beautiful.
She's young.
She's amazing.
And I know she's the one.
I have a way of telling now.
Oh, really? How?
I've devised a system that
can apply to any couple.
It goes like this.
If the relationship can be
summed up in a single sentence,
it will never survive.
I'll give you an example.
The previous relationship, our
single sentence was, "she is the
lost child to my father figure."
In another one, I was the exotic
aesthete to her
midwestern homebody.
Exotic aesthete?
And with another, "she is my
every sexual fantasy, but she
just wants her bare bottom
spanked."
Right. So, you're saying it
works with you and Charlotte
because there's not one
sentence that describes you.
Exactly.
And what about you and Matthew?
I was the carpenter to his
unfixable... fixer-upper.
"Can't save nobody."
It's a famous saying.
An enormous earthquake hit
kabanjahe, Indonesia,
two days ago.
There are probably over 500
animals that have died.
Most of these animals will,
unfortunately, go without proper
burial.
We need to aid these souls, help
them transition into the next
stage of their existence.
So please remember
today, heart to heart...
Soul to soul... paw to paw.
Charlie has told me all about
your search for Matthew Smith.
I was a huge fan of his
in junior high school.
You know, originally, I
volunteered to help Ellie find
Matthew because I wanted to have
sex with her.
Jesus! That's not... that's
not true.
It's fine.
I'm not threatened.
You shouldn't be.
Look at the house.
Look at how she's
completely made it over.
It's just aglow with love and
warmth and that dream catcher.
She's got a great eye, not
unlike my mother... except, you
know, Charlotte's
alive and gorgeous.
That sounds like your sentence.
Oh, come on.
By the way, what are you and...
LA... lagary... Lucas.
His name is Lucas.
What are you and Lucas doing
I don't know.
Well, Charlotte and I have
something wonderful
to celebrate.
Don't we, my dear?
Celebrate?
Her lips are like
tiny sugar pillows.
♪ Endless love ♪
That's lovely.
Oh, my God.
That thing is huge!
Look at that.
That is beautiful.
You guys are coming, right?
Uh... to the wedding?
Yeah. Yeah. When is it?
Next week.
Oh, God.
What? Uh, wow.
That's... it's really great.
That's really kind of...
Exciting.
Well, when you know,
you know, and we know.
So, I'm chartering a jet and
we're flying over, and
you got to come with us.
You have a private jet?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, we'll... we'll fly
on your private jet, sure.
Of course, you know, I've
really been trying to get
Charlie to enjoy objects more.
I just... I think it would be
good for him, you know, because
we're in such a golden
era of materialism.
And we all have a slot to fill
in the world, and until you
learn to fill that slot, you're just...
you're fighting against
the natural order.
You'll never be
completely at peace.
I've been studying
all about this.
Oh, wow.
So, there's... there's, like,
papers written on this?
Oh, yeah, tons.
Are they written in crayon?
That's really insulting.
No, they're not in crayon.
Charlie has rich-man's guilt.
I do?
Mm-hmm.
Even your... your documentary
filmmaking is an effect
of your misalignment.
Right.
Documentaries... they're
a platform for the poor.
They should be by poor people,
for poor people,
about poor people.
You know, I once saw this
little film online, and it was,
uh, made by a monkeys, about
monkeys, for monkeys.
That's not true, is it?
The whole thing's like 10
seconds long, and it's just
this shaking camera with
occasional glimpses of, like, a
banana and other monkeys.
And then the camera breaks.
That's... not funny at all.
That would be animal cruelty.
Right.
It was just a funny little...
It's just a... video.
The golden age of materialism?
What?
She's kind of crazy, right?
Thank you for being nice.
Yeah. When am I not nice?
You're the one who
can't fake it.
You look really cute tonight.
Thanks, baby.
What's going on?
Are you nervous about your
meeting?
Hmm? No.
You don't need to be.
I mean, he's gonna love you.
No, it's gonna be good.
Thank you for hooking that up.
Of course.
You don't have to thank me.
You're up, champ.
Thanks, bud.
Glory hole is stall 3.
Wow.
It's exciting, isn't it?
What?
Love.
Me, Charlotte.
You, Lucas.
You guys are gonna have a
great time at the wedding.
And I'm gonna tell Charlotte to
throw the bouquet at you as hard
as she can.
So, what is going on?
What do you got for me?
Well, yeah, it's coming along.
Ellie, your deadline
is next week.
Can I just get a little, tiny
progress report, please?
Okay. Uh, well, if you... if
you have to know, the truth is...
I, uh...
I'm kind of seeing somebody, so
my time is... oh,
for God's sake.
I could give a shit.
Honey, the story.
What... what's going
on with the story?
You know, what happened with the
Internet guy?
What Internet guy?
The guy that I gave $1,000 to
because he knew
where Matthew was.
That guy.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, that guy.
Uh... Funny thing.
People on the Internet... they
aren't always honest.
Huh.
And I want to state for the
record that I had my
doubts from the beginning.
So, what else have you tried?
What do you mean?
Like, have I found Matthew?
Is that what you're asking?
'Cause, I mean, you said it...
He may not even be out there.
Did our conversation just
have no effect on you
whatsoever?
Because here's the deal, honey.
I just... I cannot cover for you
anymore while you self-destruct
over some idiot
fucking musician.
My magazine is on the line here.
Okay, I need you to do three
things, all right?
Get your shit together.
Find Matthew.
Write a very good
story about it.
Or what?
You'll fire me?
That's right.
Hey. Come on in.
I was just running.
Really weird.
It was good.
The meeting was
really, really...
Oh, God, yeah. What happened?
I think, uh... I think I'm flying to L.A.
tomorrow, yeah.
Oh, my God.
And they want to set up a
bunch of meetings and
shows and, uh...
Wow! Ahh! That's amazing!
Crazy!
I cannot believe it.
Wow. Wait.
Uh, when... when
will you be back?
Uh... I don't know.
Oh, um... Charlie's wedding.
Yeah.
What... what day is it?
Saturday.
But he's gonna fly us over on
Friday.
So, that's fine.
I'll just fly in and
meet you Saturday.
Okay.
Yeah. What was that?
What?
What was that?
I'm gonna make the wedding.
I know.
I am.
And I'm gonna call you every
day.
Okay.
Name a day, any day.
Monday.
I'm gonna call you Monday.
Name another day.
Thursday.
Yeah, Thursday's bad for me.
Fuck you!
I'm gonna call you Thursday.
I'm glad we're back to work
on the, uh, documentary.
Nice to have the distraction.
What's the latest on the, uh,
wunderkind?
I figured it out.
I am the industry-wise
transition girlfriend to his
soon-to-be model-fucking
teen heartthrob.
Ooh. Your sentence.
I'm sorry.
This is, uh... well, this is the
house where Matthew grew up.
Who do you think lives there
now?
Apparently, nobody.
I mean, no one answered
when I knocked.
I know how to break
into his room.
Done that before.
This used to be easier.
There is a door here...
That's unlocked.
Let's just... let's
go in this door.
It's exactly as I remember it.
It even smells the same.
Luckily, for the documentary,
I don't have smell-o-vision.
This is where I
lost my virginity.
Maybe that shouldn't go on
record.
Oh, no. That's great.
That's just the kind of, uh,
detail we're looking for in
hard-hitting documentary
filmmaking.
How was it?
Eh. What do you expect
for the first time?
How was yours?
Oh, man.
I lost my virginity
about 200 or 300 times.
Uh... just answer the question.
All right.
If you must know, I was 14.
It was our 46-year-old
Jamaican housekeeper.
What?!
She was very tender.
She had a lot of moles.
Okay, thank you.
Hey, I'm gonna leave you and
the ghost of Matthew
alone for a second.
I got to pee.
Holy shit.
I don't know he had these.
Hey, I just found a bunch
of issues of stax.
I think he was a subscriber from I think
he was a subscriber from way back.
His mom must have... shit.
Ellie?
Mr. Smith.
What are you doing in my house?
Uh, I just... I-I knocked on the
door, and there... there was
no answer, so I...
So you broke in.
Well, I thought you
might have moved or...
Oh, for the love of God.
Check it out... potty cam.
Who the hell is this?
This is, um... this is
Charlie.
He and I are making a
documentary together.
A documentary?
Oh. On that?
This is cutting-edge
Japanese technology, sir.
I am... I am so
sorry we broke in.
Obviously, it was a very stupid
idea.
I just want to apologize again.
I mean, it must be unpleasant to
be reminded of everything.
Yeah.
You guys know the way.
Yes.
And you have a beautiful home.
It's really lovely.
He always hated me.
Really? Why?
Yeah. I don't know.
He... he didn't want Matthew
to be famous, and I think he
thought I encouraged Matthew
too much with his music.
He held me responsible when...
He rebelled and left home and,
eventually, when he...
Would you come back with me
to my house?
I have something for the wedding
being delivered.
Ooh! Your tux?
No.
The ring?
What? Cake?
No.
Lingerie?
What is it?
$2,400. It's all there.
Is it one of those things
you can't get water on?
Uh, it's galagos bush baby.
He's endangered, though, right?
'Cause that's the
more expensive one?
Yeah, it's a girl,
actually, but, yes.
Does she get lonely in there?
Galagos is not puppies.
They don't want love.
They just want to be left alone.
Lucky them.
Oh, Lucas, it's, uh...
You-know-who calling you
again... and again and again.
Uh... just call me.
When do you start serving?
Good. Come in.
Oh, you look so nice.
Thank you.
You look quite elegant yourself.
Oh, yeah, that's me.
Have a seat.
What's happening?
Oh. I just needed to talk
about something before I
actually go through with this.
I'm not a religious guy, so I
hope you don't mind sitting
in for my confession.
I'd be honored.
It's dark and sordid.
Really?
No, not at all.
I'm excited.
You know, after I got
divorced, I went through...
A period of... failed
relationships.
And now, recently, I see you and
Lucas, realize that something's
missing in my life.
So I did something out
character, something
I'd never done before.
I called an escort service.
You'd never done that before?
No, no.
I was always too afraid that
something would go wrong.
Worry about diseases or...
Of course.
They're everywhere.
No, it was more the
protocol of it all.
If you don't take up all your
time, do you get to snuggle
for the rest of the hour?
Or if you need more
time, do you pay extra?
If you run over, is there a
bell, and they just
shove you off of them?
There's a bell?
As it turns out, there was
not a bell, which was a relief.
But one night...
...there was a knock at the
door, and I opened it.
And... and there
stood Charlotte.
Wow.
I thought she was a socialite.
Like, all the charity work
and... she loves animals.
She has a big heart.
She wasn't cut out
for that life.
She said that I was her first
client as a prostitute.
I'm not naive, but... yeah.
Anyway, I love her.
And, uh... I'm gonna marry her.
I don't know, Ellie.
I know I'm not a deep guy, but
I'm not a shallow guy, either.
Eh, what can I say?
Life's pretty weird.
I got to agree.
So, here before your family
and friends and everyone who
knows you best, I pronounce
you husband and wife.
You may kiss the each other.
Where's Lucas?
I haven't heard from
him in two days.
Well, just pick somebody out.
There's a lot of guys here, a
lot of available man cake.
You can do a lot of damage
with some of these guys.
Charlie.
Come on. Piece of man cake.
You see that big hunk of
rock 'n' roll man back there?
Are you calling him rock 'n'
roll because of his hair?
No, seriously, that's
my buddy Craig.
He's a good guy.
I'll hook it up.
No. Charlie, no.
Why not?
He's a good guy.
You and Craig.
Charlie, no.
You and Craig!
Yes, I have the jaw
of a superhero.
Yes, I could light up a
dark room with my smile.
Yes, I have the hair
of an '80s rock star.
But this... this is what
I'm really proud of.
This is God-given.
I can't do anything about this,
but this, I feel, is... is
something that I've... I've earned
through hard work and determination.
And I'll tell you something else
that I think is going to impress
you.
What is that?
I am 14 credits away from an
online degree... from the
university of Phoenix no less...
To be a therapist.
Wow.
A licensed,
accredited therapist.
Okay. I am gonna let you give
me a free like five-minute
consultation.
How do you feel about that?
Oh, yeah.
Okay, so, I have this
boyfriend... or maybe had.
And, uh, well, he was supposed
to meet me here.
But I think the gig is up.
Ah! See?
Now, why do you call it a gig?
See, gig is a very
temporary term.
It's very, uh, transient.
It's here today, gone tomorrow.
I think that you get on that
stage knowing that you're going
to get off that stage quickly.
Quickly, like maybe after a
couple of songs, hmm?
Are we, uh... are
they still serving?
I mean, either whiskey or cake
or... something sweet.
Oh, here we go.
Charlie, what is this?
Well, Charlotte, it's
something that I know you've
always wanted and thought you
would never, ever get
in this lifetime.
From the galapagos islands in
the South pacific...
It's so beautiful!
Oh, God. Is it dead?
Oh.
Oh, shit.
Hey. Surprise.
What are you doing here?
Uh... this... this was our
plan... I thought.
You didn't... you
didn't even show.
You didn't call me back.
Yeah, well, I got held up.
Well, some of us know some of
us.
Um, who is this?
He's sort of my... therapist.
Great.
You two should probably talk.
No, no, no.
You stay right there.
I mean, what could possibly be
said that could make this any
better, you know?
Yeah, all right.
So, I should stay?
No.
Well, I heard about you and
Lucas... and Craig.
I don't even want
to talk about it.
Look on the bright side.
At least you didn't give a dead
animal to somebody on
their wedding day.
Guilty.
Come on.
It's a new day.
You know what you need to do.
You need to go back to work.
Need to get started looking for
Matthew again, get back in the rv.
Or, you know what?
Just take a trip somewhere.
It's on me.
How about that?
Charlie... that's
fucking ridiculous.
I'm just trying to help you
out.
I know you feel bad about last
night, and I'm... I just
want to be your friend.
You're only my friend 'cause
you had a thousand bucks
when I needed it.
I didn't mean that.
Came out the wrong way.
Did it?
Charlie... oh, fuck.
Charlie... pbht.
"Ellie, I think we could have
been something special,
but what's done is done.
Here's the money you wouldn't
let me return."
Holy shit.
"It paid for my demo, so thank
you.
Take care.
Lucas."
Ellie, your deadline came and
went weeks ago.
You know, this business,
it's fickle enough.
I would be absolutely justified
never publishing another word
from you, based on the way
you've been screwing me around.
♪ I would come back and admit
that it wasn't your fault ♪
♪ and I'm tried and unwilling ♪
♪ to be the only one
who was wrong ♪
♪ and I would sail back to you ♪
whiskey and a beer.
♪ And I would sail back to you ♪
♪ I'll be sailing on
your deep blue eyes ♪
Hey, you cannot be going dark
on me like that.
Yeah.
No, this is what I
was worried about.
What?
No guy, just you wallowing.
I'm working!
I was getting so close
to figuring this out.
Okay, what is this shit?
This song.
It's Matthew. It is.
And he's singing... singing about me...
I mean, us.
Listen.
♪ I'll be sailing on your... ♪
I tracked the I.P. Address
where this e-mail came from,
when the guy sent me this, but
it's just some fucking library
computer.
And I just... ugh!
I know that I'm just not
thinking of something.
I mean, he's out there, singing
about me, wanting
me to find him.
Okay, but, Ellie, don't you
think he'd just call you?
Him?
No.
God. He was such a dick.
Hey, listen... don't...
Fuck you.
Oh, wait. Fuck me?
Yeah, fuck you.
Oh, all right, cool.
Um, listen... you need to stop
this shit, okay?
Excuse me.
Hey. I am working.
Okay, it's not work, all right?
You're in crazy town!
Listen to me.
Listen!
All right, you
have to stop this.
Okay.
Please, please, please let go,
please let go, please let go!
I want you to look at him...
Okay?... and remember him for
the shithead that he was.
Is!
Was/is.
Holy shit.
Yeah.
Holy fucking shit.
Yeah, tough stuff.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Oh, my God.
Wait. What?
Oh, God.
Where's Charlotte?
Have a seat.
Before you apologize... and I
assume that's why you're here...
I have something I'd
like to say to you.
Okay.
I only had good
intentions toward you.
I didn't deserve to be treated
the way I was treated.
I know, I know.
I... I was totally out of line.
Sometimes I can be a jackass.
Mm. Yeah.
I wasn't necessarily asking
you to agree with that specific
point.
I am really sorry, Charlie.
Really sorry.
Thank you.
I believe you.
So, you asked about Charlotte.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, Charlotte
and I are done.
Wow. What happened?
We had some issues.
What kind of issues?
You know, "issues."
You couldn't get it up?
Why is that always
the assumption?
No.
I could get it up.
But there were some
bigger issues.
Like what?
That she was already married.
No.
Yeah.
Wow.
I don't know... what to say.
There's no logic to love.
It's just a painful, brutal
process of trial and error.
And you just go through it again
and again and again.
And again and again and again.
And again.
Well, I think I might have something...
that will take your
mind off Charlotte for a
little while, at least.
Okay.
Think I've... I
really found him.
"Him"?
Matthew.
Matthew?
Really?
Mm-hmm. I've rented a car.
And I would very much
appreciate your help.
I'm ready to hit the road again.
Okay. Remember in Matthew's
house, he had all these back
issues of stax?
Mm.
Right? So, according to the subscriber
database, it's never been dropped.
Just the address was
changed to the bar.
So, his mom got him the
subscription back in high
school, but I think he's just
kept it in her name
all this time.
Mm. Huh.
This is good.
This is good investigative
journalism.
Good.
Why, thank you.
You're welcome.
Check these out.
Got them on an online spy store.
See?
A camera and a microphone.
And no matter what I look at,
you can see it on the screen.
Like, look.
Gonna pan right...
And then pan left.
Stop looking at my tits.
Okay.
I just happened to be
looking over there.
I was... I like your scarf.
How is it you don't like music?
It's not so much that
I don't like music.
Um... it's just
hard to find a song
that doesn't annoy me.
Well, what do you like?
I remember liking a
Canadian artist.
Leonard Cohen?
No.
Neil young?
Rufus Wainwright?
No.
Okay. So, listen, when we're finished
with all this, you should come over to my
apartment, and I'll... I'll play
you some stuff. I'll...
Bryan Adams.
I remember, on the album cover,
he's doing this... this pose,
like a guy... like, running
across the street.
I thought that was kind of cool.
Mm. Mm.
Well, that's it. That's a start.
Wait.
Someone's going in.
Oh, yeah, it's the bartender.
Should we go?
No, no, no. Just give her...
Give her a few minutes.
I have been thinking,
what was our sentence?
Hmm?
What was our sentence
when we were dating?
I know... two dates doesn't...
It doesn't really count
as dating anyway.
Anyway, let's go.
We should probably...
First?
I think you should.
And, you know, settle in,
and then I'll wander in.
She won't know we're together.
Okay. All right.
Remember, I'm filming.
How could I forget?
Hi.
What can I get you?
Could I get a clean glass, a
bottle of water, and a
whole lime, please?
A whole lime?
Please.
Hey.
I'm actually looking
for someone.
I was hoping you could help me.
His name's Matthew...
Matthew Smith.
Matthew Smith?
Mm-hmm.
Matthew Smith...
Isn't that the dude that killed
himself over at the falls?
Well, I mean... yeah, but...
He...
I was told, you know, he used to
play here a lot and...
Probably. I...
I don't know.
Sorry.
Okay.
No, no. Thanks.
Thanks anyway.
Hey.
Yeah.
I'm just gonna mosey along.
There she is.
Let's go.
You're really good at this.
You know that last night,
when they found his
car out by the falls?
I fucking... I just drove
out there like a maniac.
And I stood there with the cops,
just waiting.
I feel like that's
what I'm still doing.
So... should we wait
a little longer?
Just until the morning?
Yeah, it's much better to
confront the demons of your past
in the harsh, unforgiving light
of early dawn.
Yeah.
Definitely.
So... we have this item.
This is an ancient weapon,
purely designed to protect you
from the detritus of your
relationships past.
It's a powerful weapon.
Do you require a demonstration?
So... mm. Mm!
Mmmm!
It makes your face light up like
Satan's concubine.
You are so weird.
Ellie.
Ellie, wake up.
Is that Matthew?
Is that him?
I can't tell.
What do you want to do?
Do you want to go?
No.
This is... this is weird now.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Well...
Please turn the camera off.
Thank you.
Hi.
What... oh, God.
I... I don't even...
Hey, Matthew, we're gonna go...
Oh.
Sara, this is Ellie.
Hi.
Hey, there.
I'm Charlie.
I, uh... I saw your dad.
Wow.
Yeah.
I haven't seen him in
a long, long time.
I don't think he was
very happy to see me.
He's not very happy.
I heard your... your new song.
Heard the new song?
Yeah, you played at a bar
around here somewhere.
No.
No new songs.
You look great, kid.
So, do you guys... want to
come in for coffee or something?
I would really enjoy
some delicious coffee.
Thank you.
We can't stay.
We can't stay, actually.
It's really nice to meet you.
Bye, Matthew.
We can go to the park.
Yeah? Yeah? Yes?
You all right?
Yeah.
Talk about it in a sec.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you're heavy.
You may want to hang on to this.
Everything's still
in it that I shot.
If you want it, you can have it.
♪ I'm gonna run to you ♪
♪ yeah, I'm gonna run to you ♪
♪ 'cause when the feeling's
right ♪ ♪ I'm gonna stay all night ♪
♪ I'm gonna run to you ♪
We all have someone
like Matthew Smith.
We spend thousands of hours
wondering, imagining, and
re-creating our time with them.
We look backwards to
avoid going forwards.
But at a certain point, it's
time to stop singing that old
song and write a new tune.
I'd be... pretty
embarrassed to walk in
here if I were you.
Your deadline?
It came and went weeks ago.
I had to push a total piece-of-shit
story to the cover because of you.
I need people I can
rely on, Ellie.
This business is fickle enough.
I mean, your story, it's...
It was okay.
It was pretty good.
It's good.
You know, it's very good.
I recognize this... this chick.
Are you sure you want to reveal
this much about yourself?
It's just as much about your
defects as it is about Matthew.
I mean, it's like a
goddamn confession.
Yeah, well, I've...
I've decided to...
Embrace my defects, so...
Part of the package.
I got to admit, you really had
me going with all that, you
know, "Matthew is alive" stuff.
Yeah, well, we can all close
the book on that one now.
So, I'm thinking about using
it to, um... launch our
first digital issue.
Wait. What?
Oh, yeah. The last paper edition
went out last month, but
I know that you're not concerned
with such mundane... matters.
Did I tell you that they want
me to add a lifestyle section?
What does that even mean?
I have no fucking idea.
I'm serious.
I'm proud of you.
I mean, you could've had
reporters swarming to do a story
and labels trying to get him to
sign a new record deal, but
you took the high road.
Yeah. What is wrong with me?
There's a lot wrong with you.
No, but that's...
You know, the list is getting...
Oh, thank you.
...smaller.
♪ Ellie's growing up ♪
Oh, Jesus, I hope not.
Do you want to get food?
Uh, no, thanks.
I'm... I'm gonna go
out for dinner later.
With who?
Lucas.
You're... what?
With Lucas?
"Lucius Lucas" Lucas?
No, this is... this is Lucas.
♪ ...was a day that... ♪ ♪...Was
a day that... ♪ I hate it.
We hate him, right?
He's good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He is. He's talented.
Super-talented.
You don't have to do this.
I'm really happy for him.
No, I'm saying... that's what
I'm saying.
That's what I was saying.
I was like, "oh, my God, Lucius.
So stoked for him.
This song..."
You are an ass.
I'm serious.
♪ Sunday morning ♪
♪ got the hazy, hazy jeans ♪
♪ I turn to you and
inhale where you lay ♪
♪ took a wander
through the garden ♪
♪ to awake the long, long day ♪
♪ and then roll for a while
on Violet flower bed ♪
♪ oh, you kiss my lips again
and again and again ♪
♪ and then again and then ♪
♪ we would watch the
sun comin' up easy ♪
♪ while the rain
came tumbling down ♪
♪ and it washed our
bodies so cleanly ♪
♪ we could see them rise up off
of the cold, cold ground ♪
♪ I seen the sun
comin' up easy ♪
♪ while the rain
came tumbling down ♪
♪ oh, and it washed our bodies
so clean that we could ♪
♪ feel them rise up off of the
cold, cold ground ♪
♪ yeah, yeah ♪
♪ it was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪
♪ yeah, it was in
love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪ yeah!
♪ It was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪ yeah!
♪ It was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪
Yeah!
♪ It was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪ yeah!
♪ It was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪ yeah!
♪ But that sun is
comin' up easy ♪
♪ yeah, it was the
sun comin' up easy ♪
♪ yeah, we watched the
♪ oh, we watch the
sun comin' up easy ♪
♪ oh ♪ ♪ it was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ oh, I ♪
Whoo!
♪ It was in love I was created ♪
♪ and in love is
how I hope I die ♪
♪ my friends become my foes,
and my foes become my friends ♪
♪ I tend to fall in love
with the girls my
boyfriend ends ♪
♪ I don't work 9:00 to 5:00 ♪
♪ but I'll always
work the weekends ♪
♪ and each time I'll
get the world ♪
♪ in my fingers,
something happens ♪
♪ I'm working
backwards, forwards ♪
♪ and left to right ♪
♪ and I'm pretty
darn hardheaded ♪
♪ but I can't make up my mind ♪
♪ I'll take a tragedy
over a fairy tale ♪
♪ but only when the sun is
shining ♪ ♪ I'll be the voice of hope
in your darkest hour ♪ ♪ I'm
an expert in the silver
lining ♪ ♪ I'll be there when you need me
for all the big things ♪ ♪
but I'm really pathetic at
perfect timing ♪
♪ and that's the way it seems
to go for me ♪
♪ I go to bed at 8:00
and wake up at 4:30 ♪
♪ most day, I drink like a fish
and tend to be too flirty ♪
♪ I am a perfectionist
but only when things get dirty ♪
♪ I cannot stand small talk
but I'm great at being wordy
♪ ♪ and I'd rather leave you
first ♪ ♪ but then I'll be begging you
to come back ♪
♪ and when I get real quiet ♪
♪ you know I'm about to attack ♪
♪ I'll take a walk in the
rain or a drive in the dark ♪
♪ but only when
everyone's celebrating ♪
♪ I'll dig in to your
pain and tear it apart ♪
♪ but only to help the heart
that's breaking ♪ ♪ I
like to figure things out
and make everything right ♪ ♪
but I'm secretly thrilled when
everything's changing ♪
♪ and that's the way it seems to
go for me ♪ ♪ if you fall for the part
that's brooding and dark ♪ ♪
you'll never discover the
rest of my heart ♪
♪ and I want you to see
that there's so much to see ♪
♪ just before I declare
you never knew me ♪
♪ he sweat the small stuff like
the world around was over ♪
♪ I calm him down and we make
breakfast for each other ♪
♪ our friends all thought we fit
so perfectly together ♪
♪ he likes what he can't have
and I sure like bad weather ♪
♪ I may have left him first ♪
♪ but I think he'd been
leaving for sometime ♪
♪ I feel like begging
him to come back ♪
♪ but I can't make up my mind ♪
♪ I'll take a boxing match
over the quiet night ♪
♪ but only to make
for better dreams ♪
♪ I'll back the
underdog in any fight ♪
♪ but only to fight for
something worth keeping ♪
♪ I'm in it to win it
most of the time ♪
♪ and if it goes down, I'll
be kicking and screaming ♪
♪ and that's the way it seems to
go for me ♪
♪ yeah, and that's the way it
seems to go for me ♪
♪ whoa-oh, and that's the way it