I can tell you now
what the Maestro needs
The request he is planning
to put in writing for Your Majesty...
...this is what my husband told me...
...regards a certain sum he would need...
...to be able to extinguish his old debts
and look to the future with more serenity
Otherwise, he would rather leave Munich
He would need 200,000 gulden
Did you say 200,000?
200,000 gulden
Part of the sum could be paid
in cash and the rest in shares...
...with monthly repayments
I will have to ask for a loan
from the State Treasury
I will also need the approval
of Pfistermeister and von Worden
I will let the Maestro know
They promise the moon, they swear
friendship and love, and then...
Are these the great patrons of our days?
This is just a brainless youth
The last eccentric
of a family of eccentrics
He will give you everything you want,
I am sure
My love... Cosima
My love
What kind of country is this?
A nation of policemen?
Pfistermeister uses the police
to invite my guests
They are then followed and spied on
by the police
And the letters that my guests write and
receive, are brought to me as trophies
This is outrageous!
These are just standard precautions,
Sire
Fully justified in this case,
as Wagner is a foreigner...
...and he is on the records
as a revolutionary
If Richard Wagner was not an artist...
...he would be a saint
His genius has a moral and purifying
quality. His art redeems us
He is an antidote to the evil
and corruption of our society!
Richard Wagner is a man
who will be remembered eternally
Because art is the absolute truth
What an artist leaves behind
are not his weaknesses...
...for as shocking as they can be,
but his work
Your Majesty is right, of course...
...but if I may say so...
...it can be dangerous to allow the
guardians of the law to make exceptions
Their point of view is different from ours
For them, Richard Wagner...
...does nothing but waste
the taxpayers' money
Madame von Bulow is not his muse,
but an adulteress
And her husband is a despicable
opportunist who pretends not to know...
...the relationship
between his own wife and Wagner...
...because he does not want to lose
his job
These are just slanders!
No, Sire. It is the truth
As these letters clearly show
Your Majesty has to understand
something
Maybe Wagner's detractors are
insensitive to art...
...but they are not liars
Maestro Wagner and Mr. and Mrs.
von Bulow are in the waiting-room
They wish to see you
about a very urgent matter
Let them in
His Majesty the King is waiting for you
Thank you
Your Majesty told me to ignore
what the papers were writing about me
Criticism, verbal attacks, insinuations...
...insults of the press in general.
I followed Your Majesty's advice
I have suffered everything in silence
And I would keep quiet,
if I was the only one involved
But it is not just about me anymore
Your Majesty, in the "Fushbutter"
there was an article claiming...
...that my wife is Richard Wagner's
mistress
I have challenged the editor to a duel
This is very serious, Your Majesty
Yes, you are right. It is very serious
Because we are all accomplices
Mr. von Bulow, who knows that his wife
is Wagner's mistress...
...but feigns ignorance
Otherwise he would have
to throw her out...
...and give up his prestigious post
as the Maestro's conductor
And me, I know everything...
...because my friend Wagner
does not hide anything from me
Me - his friend, his patron...
...especially in such a delicate situation,
which affects his private...
...and public life...
Me - friend, admirer and confidant...
...obviously I am the accomplice
of my favorite
It is only an evil slander.
Unacceptable, Your Majesty
Only Your Majesty can help us
resolve it
If only Your Majesty could write a letter
to Mr. von Bulow...
...a simple letter expressing your
admiration and friendship...
...once the letter is published
in the papers...
Lohengrin is ready to defend Elsa...
...but it is easier to fight in a duel
than to write a letter
If I may, Your Majesty,
I have written a draft
"Dear Mr. von Bulow...
..."having had the chance
to fully appreciate...
..."the noble and generous qualities
of your esteemed spouse..."
Fine
I understand
I will copy it
and it will be delivered tomorrow
Your Majesty does not wish
to read the rest?
No, it is not necessary
I am sure it is absolutely fine
Your Majesty, I am very grateful
I have only done my duty
Wagner knows how much I value
true friendship
His Majesty the King
has entrusted me with the task...
...of ordering you to leave Munich
as soon as possible
Here is His Majesty's message
"Dear friend...
..."as painful as this is...
..."I find myself forced to ask you
to follow Minister Lutz's orders
"My love for you will be forever unaltered
"And I beg you to remain friends with me
"I did not have any other options
"Until death, yours faithfully, Ludwig"
Do not say anything
I can confirm that His Majesty,
the King of Bavaria...
...has been suffering from a form
of mental instability...
...since the year 1866...
...on the eve of our unfortunate
participation to the war of that year
The position taken by our monarch
against the government...
...which supported our alliance
with Austria...
...provoked a dangerous feeling
of general discontent
Gentlemen, you have to wait a bit longer
Your Majesty is required at the castle
Come in
Your Majesty,
His Majesty Prince Otto
- Did they get offended?
- I doubt it. They are waiting for me
They think you are not here
Let them wait
- Come
- We are going back to Munich tonight
And tomorrow...
I have to go back to the front
Do you find it hard?
Yes, I do. I hate the smell, the dirt...
...the cries of soldiers when they are
operated on without chloroform...
...because they have run out of supplies
- What do they want from me this time?
- They want you back in Munich
You are the King
We are losing the war
Look!
The four quarters of the moon...
...like when we used to go fishing
at night-time as children
Yes. And you would get upset
if I had more luck than you
Because I was the King
I did not want this war
I want everybody to know!
Yes
What is the matter?
I do not know. My eyes are stinging
Maybe it is because
I am not able to sleep anymore
And when I do sleep, I dream
of not being able to sleep
I dream of not being able to close
my eyes, and so I stay like this, always
Whether I am awake or asleep, I keep
my eyes open. That is why they sting
You are not well
Stay here in Berg with me
I cannot and you know that
I must go back to the front
It would be dishonorable
towards our allies too
They are our cousins, after all
Our enemies in Prussia
are our cousins too!
We keep everything in the family -
wars, weddings, babies...
We are incestuous and fratricidal
Without knowing why
You are the King. If you did not want
the war, you should have prevented it
That is what I did. And I do my best
to make my opinions clear
As far as I am concerned,
this war does not exist
Tell the generals that the King
does not know that there is a war
- Who is there? Who are you?
- It is me, Your Majesty, Volk!
Why are you not at the castle?
Who gave you permission to go out?
I thought Your Majesty
did not need me anymore
A waiter must not leave the apartment
while on duty
Did you not know that?
Yes, Your Majesty
Nevertheless, you came here
You left your job to have a swim!
I could not sleep
Are you not afraid of being caught
by patrolling squads?
Usually, I hear them coming
and I hide in the canes
- Can you swim?
- A little, Your Majesty
I never go where I cannot touch
the bottom, especially when I am alone
- Are you cold?
- Yes, a bit
Take this
Help me
Help me, I beg you
It is extremely important and urgent!
Captain Durckheim asks
to be seen by Your Majesty
Come in!
We have been defeated, Your Majesty
We have surrendered
- Are there many casualties?
- No
Your Majesty,
the enemies' forces were stronger
Our troops were demoralized
We do not have too many casualties...
...but to keep fighting would have led
to a pointless massacre
I am happy it is over,
and it did not last long
Seven weeks, Your Majesty
But they seemed like an eternity
for those who were fighting
Any news about my brother Otto?
He went back to Munich.
He was very demoralized
You are very fond of my brother,
am I right Durckheim?
Yes, Your Majesty. I am very fond of him
One day, Otto will be your king
Very soon
Because I...
His Majesty Prince Otto
is deeply unhappy
He is so young...
...but it is as if he has got to the end
of his life without having lived it
His ambitions are dipped
in bitterness
They have turned into sorrow and fear.
He is extremely lonely
He does not sleep
for more than two hours a night
He is unable to rest. He was
desperately looking for happiness...
...in something unreachable...
...and security...
...in what falls outside the rules
What's wrong with that?
The world around us
is unbearable and miserable
Men are only after material security,
nothing else
They are ready to lose their lives
in order to achieve that
I want to be free! Free to look
for happiness in the unreachable
But unlike my brother,
I try to act upon my thoughts
That is why I abandoned this silly war
that I was not able to prevent
I am not a coward! I hate lies
- I want to live in truth, always
- Forgive me, Sire
Allow a common man
to express his opinion
Your Majesty said
that he wants to live in truth
But I think what you meant
is that you want to live as a free man...
...following your instincts
and your tastes...
...without hypocrisy or lies.
Am I right?
In my opinion, the truth...
...doesn't have anything to do
with this search for the unreachable
When freedom is a privilege of the few...
...it does not have anything to do
with real freedom...
...the same freedom that belongs
to every man...
...and that each of us
has the right to hold on to
We live in a world
where there are no innocents...
...where nobody has the right
to judge anybody
I am speaking as a friend.
The generosity...
...that Your Majesty showed me
when we were both younger...
...gives me the courage
to speak my mind...
...as men do with each other
I am a soldier who was left alone
on the battlefield...
...at a time of danger and bitterness
But I do not feel neither contempt nor
rancor for the king who abandoned me
Instead, I feel great pity
My king thinks he has made
a brave decision...
...but he is mistaken if he thinks
he can find happiness...
...outside the rules and the duties of men
Those who love life cannot afford
to search for the unreachable...
...but have to be extremely careful
This is true even for a monarch
Even for a monarch, because
the great power that a monarch has...
...is limited by the boundaries
of the society of which he is part
Who could ever be able to follow him
outside those boundaries?
Certainly not the weak and humble
whose only worry is to find security...
...both material and moral
The same security Your Majesty
was talking about with such contempt
The only ones following him
will be those...
...who see freedom
as a search for pleasure...
...beyond any moral boundary.
No...
...you surely do not want this
Being followed only
by despicable servants...
...exploiters, traders of illusions...
No, I do not believe it. Your Majesty
cannot like such a breed...
...who would take advantage of his
generosity and would try to deceive him
Why would a young person,
who has a whole life ahead of him...
...not be tempted to find
a different reason to live?
Even if it is difficult because it is
the one of common people...
...who accept mediocrity
It takes a lot of courage
to accept mediocrity...
...for somebody who is pursuing sublime
ideals beyond this world. I know it
But it is the only way to be saved
from a terrible loneliness
- I need to talk to my mother
- Her Majesty is resting
Wake her up! What are you waiting for?
- Yes
- Hurry!
Her Majesty the Queen
is waiting for Your Majesty
I apologize for waking you up
at this time...
...but I needed to tell you something
immediately
I have decided to get married
I knew this would be good news for you
Are you not going to ask me
who the chosen one is?
I was waiting for Your Majesty to tell me
I fully trust Your Majesty's judgment
I want you to go immediately...
...to Possenhofen...
...to ask Duchess Ludovica
for the hand of Princess Sophie
I am sure Sophie will be
the perfect spouse for you
I have already asked Father Hoffman
to come here. See him straight away
I would like you to inform him
of my decision...
...and to go with him to Possenhofen,
because Sophie is Catholic
Ludwig
- Your Majesty
- My dressing-gown, hurry!
Hurry!
As soon as Father Hoffman arrives,
take him to my dressing room
Yes, Your Majesty
Reverend Father Hoffman
is already here
Your Majesty
- What happened?
- Did you see my son?
Yes, just now as he was leaving
- He did not say a word. He seemed...
- Happy
He is full of joy
Ludwig wants to get married
He wanted me to let you know
He also wants you to come with me
to ask for the hand of the young girl
This is only fair,
because the princess is Catholic
And the request made by a Protestant
mother may not be enough
- He wants to get married?
- Princess Sophie, Elisabeth's sister
Is it not wonderful news?
Father, I feel like I am waking up
from a nightmare
A nightmare you have not helped me
much with, to tell you the truth
- Please, take a seat
- Thank you
It must be a big relief
I hope...
...that His Majesty has found
a stable balance
Many young men struggle
to find balance within themselves...
- An inner harmony
- He has found it
What matters is that he found it
and is getting married
I am surprised that His Majesty has
never mentioned to me his intentions
I was saying that I hope...
...that he has weighed carefully
the decision he has made
Because this choice...
...involves not only him...
...but also his spouse who,
with the blessing of the Lord...
Enough, Father Hoffman!
What matters is that they get married...
...and that the wedding is celebrated
as soon as possible
This is exactly what we all hoped for
- Am I right?
- Of course. It is a relief for all of us
And for the country
We will probably need
the papal dispensation...
...given the close relationship
between the two
Of course. I am sure
there will not be any problems,
- Their parents are cousins too
- Exactly
That is the reason why people believe
that in the Wittelsbach...
...and in the Hohenzollers family, there
have been many cases of anomalies
But as far as I know,
young Sophie enjoys good health
And His Majesty the King has never
given us any reasons to worry
We should mention certain timidities
and indispositions of His Majesty...
...so that Sophie can help him
and be understanding
Like her sisters,
Sophie will quickly learn...
...that a woman in her position does not
only have rights and privileges...
...but also duties. Many duties
My dear
- Sophie, are you happy?
- Yes, indeed
This is one of the best days of my life,
Ludwig
My dear Durckheim,
these family reunions are very tiring
My best wishes
I am very, very happy. Really
Thank you, Otto
Well done, Otto.
You are always so nice
- Nene, Matilde, ma tante...
- Elisabeth!
I am very happy too
Congratulations, mon beau-frere
My dear Otto, you are so nice
Everybody is happy. And the station
looked beautiful, with all those flags
Father
You did not think I was going
to show up? I did not either
Everything is always so complicated
So, ma tante, I have heard you will do
refurbishment work at the residence
The old residence will be renovated.
Who will be in charge of the work?
Sophie, let your voice be heard.
Sophie is not like me
I can only say if I like something or not
after it has been done
I must have a warm drink,
if you will excuse me
Thank you. I can do it myself
I was dying for a cup of tea
- We will not be living at the residence
- Will you not?
Only for a short while. As little as
possible. Until the new house is ready
What are these?
Something I have been thinking about
for a while
I would like to build a castle
Remember the Graswang Valley?
Above Oberammergau. There is also
another place that I like just as much
Maybe even more
Herrenchiemsee. I am still not sure
We could go there tomorrow, by horse
Remember Bad Ischl?
It will not be tiring, quite the opposite
So you can give me your advice
Sadly, I will not be here tomorrow.
I will be on my way to Zurich
I stopped by just to see Sophie
and give you both Franz's best wishes
And mine, of course
With the wedding approaching,
His Majesty gave the go ahead...
...to the building works
for his damned castles
I was in charge of making the King
experience certain things...
...that he was thought to be
totally new to
It was all so complicated
They told me so many things about you.
They recommended you
Who did?
Your Majesty sent his aide-de-camp
to the theatre to invite me for dinner...
...and I suddenly found myself
at the center of a big State affair
Closed carriage, curtains down
I was taken to a place full of offices
And then?
Do you want to know? Are you curious?
Thank you
There were some gentlemen
I think one of them
was sent by the archbishop
A very indiscreet person
And another one was sent...
...by Her Majesty the Queen Mother
Oh, my God, Your Majesty!
Are things always so complicated
when a king wants to make love?
For us actors it is much simpler.
A gaze is all we need
A sign like this
I have been told this too -
that you are very shy
Then they asked me a lot of questions
Even about my health
- Really?
- Really outrageous
Scandalous. And in the end...
...they appealed to my discretion
Although it doesn't apply to them,
obviously
They want to know how things went
Are you going to tell them?
With Your Majesty's permission,
I would like to deceive them all
They are too indiscreet
Curious.
We...
...could make love...
...and say that we have not done it
Or we could not do it,
and say we have done it
Yes, we must satisfy their curiosity
Let's tell them something
that will shock them
For example,
that Your Majesty spanked me
- Will they believe you?
- Your Majesty, I am a great actress
The truth is... that you will surely
go back to them
And you will tell them what did not
happen between us in every detail
- Is that why they pay you?
- No
- Is that why you do it?
- No, Your Majesty. No!
- Yes, they are paying you
I am sure of it
Why would you not accept?
If you do not do it today,
somebody else will do it tomorrow
Do you think I do not know
what happens around me?
I know it. I am surrounded by people
who check everything I do
Not to protect me, but to ruin me
I have not understood yet
how they will do it, but I know they will
This is their aim
I can only watch...
...fascinated, while they move
quietly and cautiously
It is as if I was watching them...
...while they build the scaffold
on which they will hang me
No. No, Your Majesty.
This is not true
- This is not true at all
- Go away
And get them to pay you
Ask for a good sum,
more than you deserve. Go, Madame
- Prostitute!
- Your Majesty!
Why? What have I done?
Not like this, please. Please
Your Majesty, rescue me! Help me!
Rescue Madame von Buliowski,
and send her home, now
Your Majesty! Help me!
The jewels that the queens of Bavaria
have been wearing for 700 years
But I will give you a better present.
It is a secret, you cannot tell anybody
I will introduce you to Richard Wagner
Our engagement is more tiring
than a military campaign
It is a martyrdom...
...that Sophie bears
without a single complaint
She is the perfect fiancée
And she loves your music
Do you know what she is afraid of
right now?
That I ask her
to sing something for you
She is afraid of your judgment, not
only as a singer but also as a fiancée
She is convinced that by asking you
to meet her, I sought your approval
- When are you coming back?
- Soon, Sire, soon
And I will not be hiding. I will come back
with my wife and a new opera
You will save me from much sorrow,
much loneliness
Sophie is delightful...
...very pretty and sweet
For the first time I saw love
for Your Majesty in somebody's eyes
I have decided to postpone the wedding
by a month or two
I wish it had already happened. I can
already hear the crowd screaming...
...the banquets, the ceremonies,
both here and at the church
It is like a nightmare,
it keeps me awake at night
My uncles, my aunts,
my cousins from all over Europe...
...the kisses, the hand-shakes,
the wishes...
...the hugs
You can open your heart to me,
Your Majesty
My affection for you is the same as
it was the day you called me to Munich
I have not forgotten you saved me from
poverty, welcomed me into your arms
I took up your invitation right away
because I realized you needed me
Forget what happened in the past
You can betray friends,
even their trust...
...and still love them.
Be magnanimous, try to forgive
I know that nobody else can advise you
like I can...
...because my words are born
of a very honest and deep feeling
What is bothering you, my friend?
I understand many things, but I cannot
speak if you do not ask me to
My name is Richard Hornig
I worked for the King for 10 years
I became part of his staff
by chance, when His Majesty...
...in one of his moments of rage,
threw out a squire called Volk
And so I replaced him
During my years at the service of the
King, I never betrayed his trust
And I do not have any intention
of doing it today
Apart from this -
nothing in his behavior...
...was different from what everybody
considered...
...suitable behavior for a king
Wait here
- Take this! Are you able to put it up?
- Yes, Your Majesty
- Good. Very good
- I learnt it when I was in the Army
- I have not seen you before
- I started few days ago, Your Majesty
- And what did you do before?
- I worked in a farm
I looked after horses
- Light the fire
- Right away, Your Majesty
Take off your gloves!
- What are you waiting for?
- Have you got any orders for me, Sire?
If you want, you can sleep here tonight
Yes, Your Majesty