1
00:02:05,515 --> 00:02:09,190
At the Berlin Conference in 1885
Africa was divided.

2
00:02:09,355 --> 00:02:12,313
Congo, became the personal property
of Belgian King Leopold I.

3
00:02:12,955 --> 00:02:16,107
On June 30, 1960, the nationalist
Patrice Lumumba, 36, became

4
00:02:16,276 --> 00:02:19,234
The first Prime Minister
of the new independent state.

5
00:02:19,396 --> 00:02:20,749
He would last only months.

6
00:02:21,356 --> 00:02:24,712
This is a true story.

7
00:03:07,958 --> 00:03:10,756
Nobody knew about that night
in Katanga.

8
00:03:11,558 --> 00:03:15,790
Nobody was allowed to know.
Their mission was clear.

9
00:03:17,239 --> 00:03:20,868
Retrieve three bodies
and then disappear.

10
00:03:22,399 --> 00:03:26,836
No grave, no memory...

11
00:03:30,439 --> 00:03:33,511
Even in death they were afraid of me.

12
00:04:28,322 --> 00:04:29,880
Will you help me?

13
00:04:57,243 --> 00:05:00,600
The children may not
know everything that happened, do you?

14
00:05:02,884 --> 00:05:04,078
They probably wouldn't understand.

15
00:05:10,044 --> 00:05:11,716
Tell them not ...

16
00:05:13,164 --> 00:05:14,756
Say nothing.

17
00:06:21,648 --> 00:06:24,765
You acted in the name of Congo,
but not your party

18
00:06:25,048 --> 00:06:27,004
Is not representative.
- It's now Lumumba's turn.

19
00:06:27,768 --> 00:06:29,486
Let him continue talking.

20
00:06:30,048 --> 00:06:31,117
Right,

21
00:06:31,288 --> 00:06:35,201
The MNC does not represent
every Congolese. Not yet.

22
00:06:35,368 --> 00:06:37,882
But Tshombe of CONAKAT
Katanga does not represent all of Congo.

23
00:06:38,168 --> 00:06:41,286
Our party is big,
yours is nothing.

24
00:06:41,449 --> 00:06:42,598
There are 250 parties

25
00:06:42,889 --> 00:06:45,767
in Congo.
Plus those founded by the Belgians.

26
00:06:46,049 --> 00:06:49,439
Mr. Kasavubu could take power
but he does not have support in Accra.

27
00:06:50,089 --> 00:06:52,398
But what am I to do give out visas?

28
00:06:52,809 --> 00:06:55,164
Why did the government go it alone?

29
00:06:55,329 --> 00:06:56,523
Ask them.

30
00:06:56,809 --> 00:06:59,403
So you could sell your Polar
beer to the Minister.

31
00:06:59,729 --> 00:07:02,244
He could have 51% of the vote.

32
00:07:02,850 --> 00:07:03,680
I did not know.

33
00:07:03,970 --> 00:07:06,359
You know many things,

34
00:07:06,530 --> 00:07:08,521
starting with the protocol.

35
00:07:11,410 --> 00:07:13,366
Is this a joke?

36
00:07:14,370 --> 00:07:15,769
Not at all.

37
00:07:16,730 --> 00:07:21,406
Please read the full text of my speech,
not in newspapers.

38
00:07:22,251 --> 00:07:26,005
I should talk about you
and your rich province.

39
00:07:26,411 --> 00:07:29,448
But I do not see the Congo
as tribes and provinces,

40
00:07:29,851 --> 00:07:32,968
but as a whole.
We need to move beyond provincialism.

41
00:07:33,131 --> 00:07:35,008
Do we have to hear your speech once again?

42
00:07:35,371 --> 00:07:37,566
Do you think you're still in Accra?

43
00:07:38,411 --> 00:07:42,371
You are two people, I
represent many more.

44
00:07:42,652 --> 00:07:47,123
We have 10,000 people. I could get CONAKAT
not to mention Tshombe if you like.

45
00:07:47,852 --> 00:07:49,365
At the next Pan-African
Conference

46
00:07:49,532 --> 00:07:52,888
I will be happy to
talk about your big party.

47
00:07:53,172 --> 00:07:55,970
He derides.
- Your irony is inappropriate

48
00:07:56,612 --> 00:07:58,125
and insulting.

49
00:07:58,412 --> 00:08:00,403
I can only say:

50
00:08:00,692 --> 00:08:01,886
Read my speech.

51
00:08:02,693 --> 00:08:05,491
Or not. But there will be no rewrite.

52
00:08:06,573 --> 00:08:09,167
You travel a far to sell your beer.

53
00:08:09,813 --> 00:08:14,250
Stay away from my region.
Because we do not forget.

54
00:08:25,894 --> 00:08:28,203
Yes, I made some mistakes.

55
00:08:28,494 --> 00:08:30,849
And it would all end badly.

56
00:08:31,054 --> 00:08:33,568
We thought it our destiny
to decide our country's fate

57
00:08:33,854 --> 00:08:37,733
but other, more powerful enemies
were in control.

58
00:08:44,215 --> 00:08:46,012
Why did they fear me so much?

59
00:08:46,175 --> 00:08:50,054
When they eventually killed me,
they made me more important.

60
00:08:50,375 --> 00:08:54,971
I was but one vote for the dream
of freedom and fraternity.

61
00:08:55,255 --> 00:08:58,884
Words they could not accept.
But they were just words.

62
00:09:26,377 --> 00:09:28,845
Everything was nevertheless a good start.

63
00:09:30,217 --> 00:09:31,616
Do you remember?

64
00:09:32,217 --> 00:09:34,572
I came from Stanleyville

65
00:09:34,737 --> 00:09:37,695
A colonial
administrative clerk, third class.

66
00:09:39,377 --> 00:09:41,811
I was 30 and at the height
of my career.

67
00:09:47,378 --> 00:09:50,450
But my job was not
What I had imagined,

68
00:09:50,618 --> 00:09:53,451
But I suppose I shouldn't look
a gift horse in the mouth.

69
00:09:54,138 --> 00:09:54,888
Patrice Lumumba.

70
00:09:55,578 --> 00:09:59,412
You can speak to the people.
Such a person we need.

71
00:09:59,698 --> 00:10:01,416
The people here are hard.

72
00:10:01,578 --> 00:10:04,092
After the triumph of Kasavubu

73
00:10:04,779 --> 00:10:07,498
some businesses flourished,
But not ours ...

74
00:10:07,779 --> 00:10:10,247
We are on our last legs.

75
00:10:11,659 --> 00:10:14,173
If you can do things to help business resume ...

76
00:10:14,339 --> 00:10:18,378
It is even said
that our beer causes impotence.

77
00:10:18,539 --> 00:10:20,416
That is how far they will go.

78
00:10:21,019 --> 00:10:23,613
If you can save the business

79
00:10:23,779 --> 00:10:26,578
You will get a salary of Deputy Director.

80
00:10:26,820 --> 00:10:27,969
Good salary, right?

81
00:10:29,420 --> 00:10:30,819
It's very good, Director.

82
00:10:31,140 --> 00:10:33,700
Within a month we will
need to see improvements.

83
00:10:34,820 --> 00:10:36,492
Can I do what I want?
- If you want ...

84
00:10:37,820 --> 00:10:39,572
Come closer, my friends.

85
00:10:40,980 --> 00:10:42,299
Test, it's free.

86
00:10:42,460 --> 00:10:45,213
Girls?
- Beer, slyboots.

87
00:10:45,381 --> 00:10:47,736
And not just beer. The best!

88
00:10:47,901 --> 00:10:50,210
The King of beers. Polar!

89
00:10:50,381 --> 00:10:53,612
I sold beer. Why not?

90
00:10:53,781 --> 00:10:56,739
Polar or Primus, they all left me cold.

91
00:10:57,661 --> 00:11:00,653
I was in the capital,
that is what was important.

92
00:11:00,941 --> 00:11:03,694
I love Primus.
Long live King Kasa.

93
00:11:04,301 --> 00:11:06,099
Here is the competition.

94
00:11:06,262 --> 00:11:07,695
Long live Congo!

95
00:11:07,982 --> 00:11:09,381
Long Live Free Congo!

96
00:11:10,022 --> 00:11:11,614
Long live independence!

97
00:11:12,302 --> 00:11:14,179
That's strong language. Come here.

98
00:11:14,342 --> 00:11:16,139
Take a Polar. At my expense.

99
00:11:17,222 --> 00:11:20,100
When I met Joseph,

100
00:11:20,262 --> 00:11:22,696
he was an army sergeant
but also an aspiring journalist.

101
00:11:22,982 --> 00:11:24,540
And you?
- Joseph-Desire Mobutu.

102
00:11:25,182 --> 00:11:26,059
To our health.

103
00:11:26,343 --> 00:11:27,537
To our future!

104
00:11:28,103 --> 00:11:32,460
He was not Mobutu Sese Seko
Kuku Ngwendu Wasahanga,

105
00:11:32,623 --> 00:11:33,738
Father of the Nation.

106
00:11:34,943 --> 00:11:36,740
Not yet.

107
00:11:38,743 --> 00:11:42,258
Congo was still
a Belgian colony.

108
00:11:42,623 --> 00:11:44,102
Lumumba?
- Here I am.

109
00:11:44,423 --> 00:11:45,981
Along there.

110
00:11:59,344 --> 00:12:00,174
Name?

111
00:12:01,624 --> 00:12:03,296
Lumumba. Patrice, Emery.

112
00:12:03,704 --> 00:12:05,695
You 're judicial file.

113
00:12:08,265 --> 00:12:10,176
And you hope to travel?

114
00:12:21,585 --> 00:12:22,859
Is that my visa?

115
00:12:23,865 --> 00:12:27,541
Yes, you're lucky. Or have good connections.

116
00:12:32,386 --> 00:12:35,264
Fork on the left!

117
00:12:35,746 --> 00:12:39,534
Indigenous children
learn to work and study,

118
00:12:39,826 --> 00:12:42,135
but are only interested
in relaxation.

119
00:12:42,306 --> 00:12:44,695
I do not speak Flemish!

120
00:12:45,386 --> 00:12:46,535
Can you open this?

121
00:12:47,066 --> 00:12:48,944
If the teacher loses the pedals,

122
00:12:49,107 --> 00:12:51,621
take over the primitive methods ...

123
00:12:51,787 --> 00:12:53,140
Like only a small handful of others

124
00:12:53,747 --> 00:12:56,181
I got my card identifying me
as a "civilized person".

125
00:12:58,387 --> 00:13:02,505
She showed me just how to buy alcohol
in the European quarter.

126
00:13:03,107 --> 00:13:04,779
Throughout the DRC?
- It wsa very Congo.

127
00:13:05,067 --> 00:13:08,743
For political Lessons
we used the gym,

128
00:13:08,908 --> 00:13:12,423
the association of employees,
the association's indigenous staff

129
00:13:12,588 --> 00:13:15,102
and the Congregation
of the Virgin.

130
00:13:15,468 --> 00:13:18,699
No collaboration,
but civil disobedience.

131
00:13:18,868 --> 00:13:21,018
80 years is enough!

132
00:13:21,188 --> 00:13:23,827
First the slave trade, the ivory trade

133
00:13:23,988 --> 00:13:26,263
and then killing for rubber.

134
00:13:26,428 --> 00:13:30,104
Now we sell diamonds, copper, manganese and zinc.

135
00:13:30,269 --> 00:13:32,988
Everyone knows
that independence is imminent.

136
00:13:34,829 --> 00:13:37,389
Uhuru! Viva! Viva!

137
00:13:47,869 --> 00:13:49,223
Independence!

138
00:13:57,670 --> 00:13:58,944
Do you remember it now?

139
00:13:59,750 --> 00:14:01,229
The year 1959?

140
00:14:02,310 --> 00:14:05,029
With its enthusiasm,
the anger and its violence?

141
00:14:05,670 --> 00:14:10,142
What nobody predicted was
that everything would change.

142
00:14:10,791 --> 00:14:13,863
MNC in the middle.
We will see that later.

143
00:14:14,191 --> 00:14:16,751
It's King Baudouin. Come and listen.

144
00:14:16,911 --> 00:14:18,981
They will admit.

145
00:14:19,151 --> 00:14:21,346
... that everything leads to this one decisive step

146
00:14:21,511 --> 00:14:24,708
In the life of
Our African peoples.

147
00:14:25,791 --> 00:14:29,785
I owe it to
my illustrious predecessors,

148
00:14:29,952 --> 00:14:32,705
the pioneers of our work in Africa ...

149
00:14:32,872 --> 00:14:35,864
Do they keep anything on hand.

150
00:14:36,032 --> 00:14:39,229
No, they've lost the north.

151
00:14:39,712 --> 00:14:41,145
Then they have lost.

152
00:14:41,752 --> 00:14:45,461
De Gaulle has admitted
that little Belgium has no choice.

153
00:14:45,872 --> 00:14:47,464
We're going to eat them!

154
00:14:48,192 --> 00:14:53,221
You know, Maurice, they will think
you were are cannibal.

155
00:14:53,393 --> 00:14:55,349
A what?

156
00:14:55,513 --> 00:14:57,390
Someone who eats human flesh.

157
00:14:57,553 --> 00:15:01,432
If that is so,
I will begin immediately.

158
00:15:01,593 --> 00:15:04,551
We decided for Congo

159
00:15:04,713 --> 00:15:08,501
without delay,
and without haste ...

160
00:15:08,793 --> 00:15:09,862
Run!

161
00:15:31,275 --> 00:15:33,584
... that without which
a democratic regime

162
00:15:33,755 --> 00:15:36,792
there is nothing more than deceit and tyranny.

163
00:15:42,435 --> 00:15:43,550
Let him go!

164
00:15:45,155 --> 00:15:46,827
To do this you will pay!

165
00:16:04,476 --> 00:16:07,195
6 months later

166
00:16:56,479 --> 00:16:57,468
Look.

167
00:16:59,919 --> 00:17:02,831
The director was right.
He is smuggling out messages.

168
00:17:04,759 --> 00:17:05,874
Bastard!

169
00:17:06,199 --> 00:17:09,748
"I strongly protest ...
I demand my release

170
00:17:10,919 --> 00:17:14,151
as leader of MNC I am a delegate
and participate in

171
00:17:14,480 --> 00:17:16,471
the Round Table
In Brussels. "

172
00:17:16,640 --> 00:17:18,710
The pretentious monkey!

173
00:17:20,560 --> 00:17:23,393
Do you think we are so stupid
as to release you

174
00:17:23,680 --> 00:17:28,674
while show subversive behavior
the very reason you're here?

175
00:17:31,680 --> 00:17:35,435
You sit for two years and we
take care of you, boy.

176
00:17:35,601 --> 00:17:37,910
Do you see yourself in Brussels?

177
00:17:38,961 --> 00:17:40,440
What would you say to the King?

178
00:17:42,841 --> 00:17:45,275
What would you say to Bwana Kitoko?

179
00:17:51,961 --> 00:17:53,600
He wants to be minister.

180
00:17:54,682 --> 00:17:56,832
They all want to be minister.

181
00:17:57,682 --> 00:17:59,434
Want to be decorated?

182
00:18:01,002 --> 00:18:03,118
We'll decorate you.

183
00:18:03,882 --> 00:18:07,397
Want to be called Excellency?
Is that it monkey?

184
00:18:07,722 --> 00:18:09,792
Should we say Sir?

185
00:18:25,763 --> 00:18:28,152
We found this.

186
00:18:29,603 --> 00:18:33,642
Why is he bleeding?
- As usual. He protested.

187
00:18:35,244 --> 00:18:38,475
We intervened
and he defended himself.

188
00:18:39,124 --> 00:18:41,399
Mr. Lumumba,
I've received orders from Brussels.

189
00:18:42,484 --> 00:18:45,044
The Minister of Congo has requested

190
00:18:45,204 --> 00:18:48,276
that you are present at
the Round Table Conference.

191
00:18:49,244 --> 00:18:52,042
You are free to go.

192
00:18:52,604 --> 00:18:56,598
Tomorrow there is a plane to Brussels.
Take it.

193
00:19:07,965 --> 00:19:10,035
Patrice, welcome!

194
00:19:18,726 --> 00:19:20,284
Good to see you.

195
00:19:20,606 --> 00:19:22,722
How are you?

196
00:19:24,926 --> 00:19:28,601
Will you go and meet Mr. Kasavubu?
- I will meet all Aboko representatives.

197
00:19:28,886 --> 00:19:31,639
How is your relationship with Mr. Kasavubu?
- Very good.

198
00:19:31,806 --> 00:19:35,436
Do you want to meet with European investors?
- Of course.

199
00:19:37,167 --> 00:19:39,601
What are your expectations?
- They are high.

200
00:19:39,767 --> 00:19:42,645
Will you meet with the Belgian Ministers?

201
00:19:43,527 --> 00:19:46,837
I'm just a poor woman.
There are millions of us.

202
00:19:47,007 --> 00:19:50,158
In their name I salute a freedom fighter.

203
00:19:50,327 --> 00:19:51,362
Thank you, ma'am.

204
00:19:51,967 --> 00:19:54,003
Do you think the MNC has a chance?

205
00:20:05,448 --> 00:20:08,758
Were you wounded on board?
- In prison. It's nothing.

206
00:20:08,928 --> 00:20:11,761
Tell me about Brussels.
- It's a beautiful city.

207
00:20:11,928 --> 00:20:16,207
I mean the Round Table.
- Everyone is talking about you.

208
00:20:16,809 --> 00:20:18,879
Which room?
- Room three!

209
00:20:19,049 --> 00:20:20,926
There are no more oranges.

210
00:20:21,089 --> 00:20:22,283
Three Flamingos in 1926.

211
00:20:25,929 --> 00:20:28,443
Who goes to the third floor?
- Send Mathieu.

212
00:20:28,689 --> 00:20:30,520
I do Bomboko.

213
00:20:31,689 --> 00:20:32,917
What you see in this clown?

214
00:20:33,089 --> 00:20:34,522
He has class.
- No, gratuities.

215
00:20:34,849 --> 00:20:36,522
Make way!

216
00:20:36,970 --> 00:20:38,528
There's work to be done.

217
00:20:43,970 --> 00:20:48,168
No, no, no you can not leave now.
It's not over yet.

218
00:20:48,410 --> 00:20:50,924
Back to top.
- Let us go.

219
00:20:53,170 --> 00:20:56,846
Mr. Lumumba will meet you at 7 pm
Not now.

220
00:20:57,011 --> 00:21:00,003
What do you mean
"Vague impulses independence"?

221
00:21:00,651 --> 00:21:02,881
It's a reality.

222
00:21:05,291 --> 00:21:07,282
Yes, it is stretchable.

223
00:21:08,331 --> 00:21:12,006
It is not our fault
that the date is not yet known.

224
00:21:17,852 --> 00:21:21,162
Mr. Kasavubu,
how nice to meet you.

225
00:21:27,252 --> 00:21:29,288
I say that it is a crime.

226
00:21:29,652 --> 00:21:32,883
You attach too much importance to a word.

227
00:21:33,052 --> 00:21:36,089
Independence. A word?

228
00:21:36,252 --> 00:21:38,972
God is a word
but I believe it.

229
00:21:39,133 --> 00:21:42,011
So we will end up giving the Congo to the Communists.

230
00:21:42,173 --> 00:21:43,970
As France did in Algeria.

231
00:21:44,613 --> 00:21:48,003
Anyone without a political mandate
is to leave.

232
00:21:48,373 --> 00:21:49,522
Men ...

233
00:21:53,573 --> 00:21:56,167
Joseph, did you hear me?
- I do not understand.

234
00:21:56,653 --> 00:22:00,613
I am a MNC deputy.
- But aren't you studying in Belgium?

235
00:22:00,894 --> 00:22:01,565
Yes, but ...

236
00:22:01,814 --> 00:22:04,453
This is for delegates from Congo.

237
00:22:04,734 --> 00:22:07,123
I am a MNC deputy.

238
00:22:08,014 --> 00:22:11,324
Joseph, it is the Rules
of the Common Front.

239
00:22:20,615 --> 00:22:23,527
Let them experiment
with freedom.

240
00:22:24,335 --> 00:22:27,452
Either way they will give Africa
one of two lessons,

241
00:22:27,615 --> 00:22:30,766
The European example
of united, hardworking nation ...

242
00:22:31,495 --> 00:22:34,646
or the other primitive, that
has been surpessed will return.

243
00:22:35,495 --> 00:22:37,053
And then ...

244
00:22:38,255 --> 00:22:39,371
And then?

245
00:22:41,016 --> 00:22:44,247
We have an army, militias,

246
00:22:45,016 --> 00:22:48,133
planes, tanks.

247
00:22:48,536 --> 00:22:50,572
We have the two largest parties.

248
00:22:50,736 --> 00:22:54,092
We should take a common
position.

249
00:22:55,336 --> 00:22:59,091
You think to show a compromise?
Independence on June 15?

250
00:22:59,257 --> 00:23:01,327
The minister will refuse.

251
00:23:03,257 --> 00:23:06,294
Would you like us to give way on a date?

252
00:23:06,457 --> 00:23:09,130
A Common Front would give us
more coverage.

253
00:23:11,377 --> 00:23:13,333
They want to save time.

254
00:23:14,177 --> 00:23:15,735
Why?

255
00:23:15,977 --> 00:23:19,653
Do they need to prepare their retreat?
Or to plot against us?

256
00:23:19,978 --> 00:23:21,331
Conspiracy dismantlement?

257
00:23:21,498 --> 00:23:23,454
Union Miniere in Katanga.

258
00:23:23,658 --> 00:23:26,411
The copper, the diamonds ...

259
00:23:26,658 --> 00:23:28,853
They will leave that to our government?

260
00:23:29,018 --> 00:23:32,454
We have no government.

261
00:23:32,618 --> 00:23:34,256
Wait for the elections.

262
00:23:35,378 --> 00:23:37,255
We're not there yet.

263
00:23:40,659 --> 00:23:42,058
I ask you

264
00:23:43,299 --> 00:23:45,893
What should they do with independence?

265
00:23:46,699 --> 00:23:49,657
It's not a nation, it strains already.

266
00:23:51,579 --> 00:23:53,695
The Lulua's hate the Baluba's

267
00:23:54,139 --> 00:23:56,016
Baluba's hate and the Bakongo's.

268
00:23:57,179 --> 00:23:59,568
And canthe Bakongo and
the Bengala's tolerate eachother?

269
00:24:00,820 --> 00:24:02,538
The colonial administration
holds them together.

270
00:24:03,060 --> 00:24:05,574
And when that disappears.
- What then?

271
00:24:05,940 --> 00:24:10,172
We must not make the same mistake as the French.
With their African executives.

272
00:24:11,220 --> 00:24:13,211
Judges, police, the postal service.

273
00:24:13,860 --> 00:24:16,454
All high positions are held by Belgians.
Without them, there will be chaos.

274
00:24:16,660 --> 00:24:18,059
Good, good.

275
00:24:19,420 --> 00:24:21,013
It is June 30 then.

276
00:24:21,501 --> 00:24:23,935
Independence's a fact.

277
00:24:24,501 --> 00:24:30,371
There remains one question:
will she be federalist, as you want,

278
00:24:30,541 --> 00:24:32,497
or unitarian, as I want.

279
00:24:32,661 --> 00:24:35,698
I will make a press release
and we will both sign.

280
00:24:36,701 --> 00:24:39,169
Let me read the text first.

281
00:24:44,022 --> 00:24:47,298
Do you know the latest hit?

282
00:25:11,063 --> 00:25:14,373
Leopoldville, May 1960

283
00:25:21,824 --> 00:25:23,815
We won.
Their coalitions failed.

284
00:25:25,384 --> 00:25:28,023
We did well?
- Even better than Abako.

285
00:25:28,784 --> 00:25:30,183
In Leopoldville too?
- Of course not.

286
00:25:30,664 --> 00:25:33,497
What is "president", Daddy?
- Nothing. Eat.

287
00:26:19,866 --> 00:26:22,061
We must continue.
Until the end.

288
00:26:22,226 --> 00:26:25,185
You do not know what you say, Maurice.

289
00:26:25,747 --> 00:26:29,501
Anyway.
Half a revolution is not possible.

290
00:26:31,227 --> 00:26:33,821
We must throw out the Flemish.

291
00:26:34,547 --> 00:26:36,503
Expropriate the missionaries.

292
00:26:36,947 --> 00:26:40,019
Chase out all the parasites
All the officer castes.

293
00:26:40,187 --> 00:26:41,586
And who will replace them?

294
00:26:41,867 --> 00:26:43,586
They can go to hell!

295
00:26:44,708 --> 00:26:45,697
We did not need them.

296
00:26:55,228 --> 00:26:56,866
You will not have it easy.

297
00:26:57,028 --> 00:26:59,906
I know,
but one thing must be clear.

298
00:27:00,228 --> 00:27:04,381
Should I show a government form
or is it to be an information circular?

299
00:27:04,629 --> 00:27:08,099
an Information Round with an eye
to forming the government second.

300
00:27:08,269 --> 00:27:10,066
I do not understand it yet.

301
00:27:10,229 --> 00:27:13,027
The independence ceremony
is on June 30.

302
00:27:13,189 --> 00:27:17,102
If we have no government,
as my unofficial mission is ...

303
00:27:17,269 --> 00:27:20,659
It's an official mission.

304
00:27:20,949 --> 00:27:24,659
Let me organize things
as I was told

305
00:27:24,830 --> 00:27:26,388
by His Majesty.

306
00:27:26,550 --> 00:27:30,179
Information first, then formation.

307
00:27:30,350 --> 00:27:32,068
All in good time.

308
00:27:33,750 --> 00:27:35,103
I will do my best.

309
00:27:35,830 --> 00:27:38,264
But remember, time is short.

310
00:27:38,830 --> 00:27:42,459
Good luck, Mr. Information.

311
00:27:47,071 --> 00:27:51,144
I accuse Minister Ganshof
and the duplicity of the Belgian Government,

312
00:27:51,311 --> 00:27:53,222
which I consider as dangerous

313
00:27:53,391 --> 00:27:57,020
to me and the government I
want to form.

314
00:27:57,711 --> 00:28:01,021
Brussels prefers a Congo
without a leader on June 30

315
00:28:01,311 --> 00:28:03,267
Instead of a Lumumba government.

316
00:28:04,351 --> 00:28:06,024
In these circumstances

317
00:28:06,192 --> 00:28:09,025
there will be no head of state to
on June 30.

318
00:28:09,192 --> 00:28:11,228
Neither from my party nor our allies

319
00:28:11,392 --> 00:28:14,350
The appointment will need
Mr. Kasavubu approval.

320
00:28:15,632 --> 00:28:18,510
CONAKAT, but not Tshombe.

321
00:28:18,832 --> 00:28:20,868
The coalition will not stand days.

322
00:28:21,032 --> 00:28:24,388
Even as Commissioner of
the Katanga province?

323
00:28:24,552 --> 00:28:26,145
We can find better.

324
00:28:27,033 --> 00:28:31,311
For Finance I accept your candidate.
But I want Thomas Kanza

325
00:28:31,473 --> 00:28:33,350
as Minister at the V.N.

326
00:28:33,513 --> 00:28:37,791
His father was last year
expelled from our party.

327
00:28:44,073 --> 00:28:45,985
It gives me no pleasure.

328
00:28:46,234 --> 00:28:50,386
The son is not the father.
He'll do a good job.

329
00:29:16,355 --> 00:29:17,470
Gentlemen ...

330
00:29:19,715 --> 00:29:21,592
Today is the day.

331
00:29:34,996 --> 00:29:37,715
The Nationalist Block which I chair,

332
00:29:37,876 --> 00:29:41,630
will put forward the candidacy of Mr. Kasavubu

333
00:29:41,796 --> 00:29:44,435
for the post of President
of the Republic.

334
00:29:45,076 --> 00:29:49,309
I never disputed
that it deserves that title.

335
00:29:50,437 --> 00:29:54,749
My first act will be the appointment
Mr. Lumumba

336
00:29:54,917 --> 00:29:58,466
as Prime Minister of
the Government of National Unity.

337
00:29:58,717 --> 00:30:03,029
Unity, which is what the Congo
now needs.

338
00:30:23,158 --> 00:30:27,471
Is it not true that Katanga is not
represented in the government?

339
00:30:27,639 --> 00:30:29,550
Do you not fear separation?

340
00:30:29,719 --> 00:30:33,598
Katanga is represented.
More than Tshombe in Katanga and Munungo.

341
00:30:33,759 --> 00:30:35,238
No more questions.

342
00:30:35,599 --> 00:30:37,908
Congo is united and will remain so.
Is that enough?

343
00:30:39,919 --> 00:30:43,036
United or not, we want to emphasize this.

344
00:30:43,319 --> 00:30:45,275
And money! And comfort!

345
00:30:45,439 --> 00:30:48,591
And no more Flemish people who give orders!
No more bullying!

346
00:30:48,960 --> 00:30:53,192
It's enough!
Moreover, we must cut their grass

347
00:30:53,480 --> 00:30:55,710
and our wives do their dishes.

348
00:30:56,000 --> 00:30:57,831
We get so little bit and we do everything.

349
00:30:58,080 --> 00:31:00,753
Come on. Sit with us.

350
00:31:01,160 --> 00:31:03,594
We can not directly change anything.

351
00:31:03,880 --> 00:31:07,509
I asked for a general amnesty to the king
and promotions for you.

352
00:31:07,680 --> 00:31:10,673
June 30 will be shown to be a memorable day.

353
00:31:10,841 --> 00:31:14,470
Without distinction of rank,
province or tribe.

354
00:31:14,641 --> 00:31:16,199
For the unified nation.

355
00:31:16,361 --> 00:31:17,589
United!

356
00:31:45,202 --> 00:31:47,272
I'm going to sleep. Until tomorrow.

357
00:31:52,963 --> 00:31:55,557
It's Tshombe and the full CONAKAT party.

358
00:31:55,723 --> 00:31:57,918
I'll go back to Elizabeth City.

359
00:31:58,283 --> 00:32:01,559
Yesterday I waited all day
for the list of ministers.

360
00:32:01,723 --> 00:32:03,759
You promised me that you'd send them to me.

361
00:32:03,923 --> 00:32:05,914
We sent them on.
- Liar!

362
00:32:06,083 --> 00:32:07,880
What's he saying?
- Slow down, Maurice.

363
00:32:08,283 --> 00:32:10,673
Apparently you already know the list?

364
00:32:10,964 --> 00:32:14,877
A lot of extremists.
We will use all the means of

365
00:32:15,164 --> 00:32:18,076
the unified structures of
the country to fight.

366
00:32:18,364 --> 00:32:19,513
All resources?

367
00:32:20,924 --> 00:32:23,882
And you will deny the democratic vote?
- I suppose you'd prefer Communism.

368
00:32:26,564 --> 00:32:28,953
Communism ...
We are no more communist than you

369
00:32:29,244 --> 00:32:31,634
Do not argue with them, Thomas. They are fascists.

370
00:32:32,405 --> 00:32:34,441
I do not like that tone!

371
00:32:48,445 --> 00:32:50,164
That's independence.

372
00:32:50,446 --> 00:32:52,323
Well, we're not done.

373
00:32:55,326 --> 00:32:56,475
What a lot of dust!

374
00:32:58,686 --> 00:33:01,439
Can we be that bad that we
cannot leave a few paintings?

375
00:33:01,606 --> 00:33:05,440
But they are owned by the Belgian state.
It's a direct order.

376
00:33:10,126 --> 00:33:12,516
Run for your life. The Bantus are here.

377
00:33:14,367 --> 00:33:17,086
Sire, they give away your Congo
and make a pigsty.

378
00:33:20,607 --> 00:33:22,996
They even showed them the wine cellar.

379
00:33:25,047 --> 00:33:27,277
The governor has not bored of it.

380
00:33:38,768 --> 00:33:41,760
Does no one answer the phone?

381
00:33:50,848 --> 00:33:53,602
No, Governor Cornelis
does not live here anymore.

382
00:33:54,369 --> 00:33:56,883
He does not live here anymore.

383
00:33:57,049 --> 00:34:01,167
This is the residence of Patrice Lumumba,
Prime Minister of Congo.

384
00:34:07,569 --> 00:34:09,878
Already five months
I have not slept.

385
00:34:11,569 --> 00:34:13,561
Are you tired, Daddy?

386
00:34:27,690 --> 00:34:29,362
Give me that.

387
00:34:32,491 --> 00:34:35,369
Read this and tell me what you think.

388
00:34:39,651 --> 00:34:43,360
What time is it?
When will the car be here?

389
00:34:43,931 --> 00:34:47,970
It cannot happen, Sir!
And not because I chair the ceremony,

390
00:34:48,331 --> 00:34:50,891
but because it's provocative.

391
00:34:51,051 --> 00:34:52,451
Who provoked the first?

392
00:34:52,692 --> 00:34:55,570
I have the speech of the King
and the President is not in support.

393
00:34:56,812 --> 00:34:59,280
They've refused an amnesty,

394
00:34:59,452 --> 00:35:02,524
A symbolic gesture

395
00:35:02,732 --> 00:35:05,121
that is essential for the ceremony.

396
00:35:05,932 --> 00:35:07,684
I appointed you as President
of the Senate

397
00:35:07,972 --> 00:35:11,726
because I thought you had character.
Am I to be made wrong?

398
00:35:11,892 --> 00:35:14,043
You need him to give the word.

399
00:35:14,213 --> 00:35:17,762
Kasa Once is finished,
Patrice takes the microphone.

400
00:35:17,973 --> 00:35:20,407
They should stay and listen.

401
00:35:20,573 --> 00:35:24,532
You want the King, General Janssens,
the bishop ...

402
00:35:24,693 --> 00:35:26,490
The King, the General, the Bishop ...

403
00:35:26,653 --> 00:35:28,371
That I forgot.

404
00:35:28,533 --> 00:35:32,367
Exactly. Let them
listen to the truth.

405
00:35:32,533 --> 00:35:35,492
That's something different. For everyone.

406
00:35:41,534 --> 00:35:42,489
Good.

407
00:35:43,494 --> 00:35:46,964
Patrice, do you really have to say?

408
00:35:47,574 --> 00:35:50,008
The independence of the Congo

409
00:35:50,614 --> 00:35:55,848
is the continuation of a process that resulted
from the genius of King Leopold I,

410
00:35:56,695 --> 00:36:00,324
by him with growing
courage a process started

411
00:36:00,735 --> 00:36:04,250
and was continued with conviction
by Belgium.

412
00:36:05,855 --> 00:36:11,134
When Leopold I began this enormous work,
now completed,

413
00:36:11,735 --> 00:36:14,694
He did not do so as the conqueror

414
00:36:14,856 --> 00:36:17,051
but as an advocate
of civilization.

415
00:36:17,536 --> 00:36:20,130
It's up to you, gentlemen,

416
00:36:20,456 --> 00:36:23,846
to prove that we were right
to trust you.

417
00:36:24,736 --> 00:36:27,773
Avoid the name of the King.

418
00:36:28,056 --> 00:36:29,933
Avoid rapid reforms

419
00:36:30,096 --> 00:36:33,771
and not replace Belgian institutions

420
00:36:34,056 --> 00:36:37,493
unless you are certain
you can do better.

421
00:36:37,897 --> 00:36:42,049
Gentlemen, the eyes of the world
are on you.

422
00:36:42,697 --> 00:36:45,575
May God protect the Congo!

423
00:36:58,178 --> 00:37:00,533
Excellencies, dear compatriots,

424
00:37:02,458 --> 00:37:04,574
Now, officially, the Republic of Congo

425
00:37:05,418 --> 00:37:07,056
appears on the world map,

426
00:37:07,738 --> 00:37:10,377
a fully independent and sovereign ...

427
00:37:10,818 --> 00:37:12,729
Patrice, it's too dangerous.

428
00:37:13,978 --> 00:37:15,856
You've improved.

429
00:37:16,019 --> 00:37:18,010
You know what you're doing?

430
00:37:19,899 --> 00:37:23,289
Do you really think you can tackle them?
- You heard him.

431
00:37:23,659 --> 00:37:26,935
We must respond.
What will our children remember?

432
00:37:27,099 --> 00:37:28,930
Kasa answers.

433
00:37:29,099 --> 00:37:32,011
Listen to what he says.

434
00:37:32,899 --> 00:37:34,093
Sire,

435
00:37:35,540 --> 00:37:39,533
your presence
on this memorable day

436
00:37:40,220 --> 00:37:43,735
proves once again your concern

437
00:37:43,900 --> 00:37:47,131
for the people you loved
and protected.

438
00:37:47,780 --> 00:37:49,850
We will not disappoint you.

439
00:38:21,862 --> 00:38:24,581
My dear compatriots,

440
00:38:25,502 --> 00:38:29,131
victors
of the independence struggle,

441
00:38:30,502 --> 00:38:35,178
For this independence of the Congo,
even as it is celebrated today with Belgium

442
00:38:35,342 --> 00:38:38,892
a friendly country with whom
we deal as equal to equal

443
00:38:39,903 --> 00:38:42,815
no Congolese worthy of the name
will ever be able to forget

444
00:38:42,983 --> 00:38:45,497
that it was by fighting
that it has been won

445
00:38:49,343 --> 00:38:50,776
a day-to-day fight,
an ardent and idealistic fight,

446
00:38:51,063 --> 00:38:54,976
a fight in which we were spared
neither privation nor suffering,

447
00:38:55,143 --> 00:38:57,339
and for which we gave our strength
and our blood.

448
00:38:58,424 --> 00:39:03,339
We are proud of this struggle,
of tears, of fire, and of blood,

449
00:39:03,504 --> 00:39:05,256
to the depths of our being,
for it was a noble and just struggle,

450
00:39:05,504 --> 00:39:07,859
and indispensable to put an end
to the humiliating slavery

451
00:39:08,024 --> 00:39:10,538
which was imposed upon us by force

452
00:39:10,704 --> 00:39:12,740
because we were black.

453
00:39:13,224 --> 00:39:17,012
Who could forget the shootings
which claimed so many victims,

454
00:39:17,184 --> 00:39:19,574
the cells in which those
were locked up

455
00:39:19,745 --> 00:39:22,339
who escaped the bullets
of the soldiers

456
00:39:22,505 --> 00:39:24,541
that were used
to dominating us?

457
00:39:26,345 --> 00:39:27,858
All this, brethren,

458
00:39:28,345 --> 00:39:29,619
has made us suffer

459
00:39:30,745 --> 00:39:33,305
and our wounds are too fresh
and painful to erase

460
00:39:34,465 --> 00:39:37,377
them from our memory.

461
00:39:38,106 --> 00:39:42,099
All this, brethren,
we proclaim loudly,

462
00:39:42,346 --> 00:39:44,576
is now forever and ever
behind us.

463
00:39:45,546 --> 00:39:48,618
The Congolese Republic
has been declared.

464
00:39:48,866 --> 00:39:51,334
Our country belongs to our children.

465
00:39:52,306 --> 00:39:55,104
We are now all able to benefit
from social justice

466
00:39:55,386 --> 00:39:57,980
and our children will benefit
from our country.

467
00:40:02,867 --> 00:40:04,459
Your Majesty,

468
00:40:04,627 --> 00:40:07,744
Excellencies, Ladies and Gentlemen,

469
00:40:07,907 --> 00:40:12,697
compatriots, fellow strugglers,
black brothers

470
00:40:12,867 --> 00:40:15,097
that is what I have wanted to say.

471
00:40:15,587 --> 00:40:18,545
Long live independence
and African Unity!

472
00:40:18,748 --> 00:40:20,739
Long live the independent
Congo and its sovereignty!

473
00:40:53,349 --> 00:40:55,988
There! Let's get him
And teach him a lesson!

474
00:40:57,469 --> 00:40:58,424
Treason!

475
00:40:59,950 --> 00:41:00,860
Get out!

476
00:41:07,630 --> 00:41:08,983
Accelerate!

477
00:41:19,270 --> 00:41:20,101
Let's go!

478
00:41:39,831 --> 00:41:42,392
These are but isolated incidents.

479
00:41:42,552 --> 00:41:46,306
Hardy also has a rebel camp.
The officers have been taken hostage.

480
00:41:47,072 --> 00:41:49,028
They want you

481
00:41:49,432 --> 00:41:51,741
They say they want to kill you.

482
00:41:52,072 --> 00:41:53,027
Unbelievable.

483
00:41:54,272 --> 00:41:56,228
What about Jones?

484
00:41:57,432 --> 00:41:58,626
Silence.

485
00:41:59,032 --> 00:42:01,786
Get your reports.
We will carry out all investigations calmly.

486
00:42:02,593 --> 00:42:04,549
Minister Mpolo.

487
00:42:07,233 --> 00:42:10,703
The Force Publique has 25,000 men.
They have stations

488
00:42:11,113 --> 00:42:13,388
aligned along the same wavelength.

489
00:42:13,593 --> 00:42:18,064
They know everything in each camp
before their officers.

490
00:42:18,353 --> 00:42:20,071
They are crazy!

491
00:42:20,874 --> 00:42:22,227
What do they want?

492
00:42:22,954 --> 00:42:24,865
They want promotions!

493
00:42:25,274 --> 00:42:26,912
I know, I heard them.

494
00:42:28,274 --> 00:42:33,223
If I may, Prime Minister, they are tired.
Five months on end:

495
00:42:33,554 --> 00:42:36,352
riots, celebrations ...
- The Flemish General,

496
00:42:36,594 --> 00:42:40,553
Janssens, puts them against us.
And he is against African officers.

497
00:42:40,714 --> 00:42:44,264
Let us shoot him.
- There is no replacement.

498
00:42:44,755 --> 00:42:46,313
I suggest Senator Lundula.

499
00:42:47,555 --> 00:42:51,389
And you, Mpolo as Colonel.
Let us take a vote.

500
00:42:51,755 --> 00:42:54,189
I will not vote for someone
who wants to shoot anyone.

501
00:42:54,475 --> 00:42:56,193
Even that is not military.

502
00:42:56,715 --> 00:43:00,424
Mr. Prime Minister,
I was 7 years in the Force Publique.

503
00:43:01,716 --> 00:43:04,469
I do not deny his qualities,

504
00:43:04,756 --> 00:43:07,987
but I think I am more proficient ...
- An excellent suggestion.

505
00:43:08,556 --> 00:43:12,151
The new commander
must come from its own ranks.

506
00:43:14,076 --> 00:43:15,270
What is that?

507
00:43:22,557 --> 00:43:24,229
Let us in!

508
00:43:25,517 --> 00:43:27,314
We want the minister to speak first!

509
00:43:32,277 --> 00:43:35,747
They are crazy! What do they want?
Where is the military discipline?

510
00:43:35,917 --> 00:43:37,066
There they are!

511
00:43:45,158 --> 00:43:45,795
Excellence ...

512
00:43:46,558 --> 00:43:49,197
We do nothing. We have a petition.

513
00:43:50,158 --> 00:43:52,069
We want an answer. Directly from you.

514
00:44:02,598 --> 00:44:05,955
Give me the petition.
I will study it.

515
00:44:06,119 --> 00:44:08,189
No, Sir! We want an answer now!

516
00:44:11,119 --> 00:44:13,997
"We wish our military to be
disciplined to carry out our mission

517
00:44:14,679 --> 00:44:19,036
and accuse General Janssens
of unfair behavior.

518
00:44:19,759 --> 00:44:24,311
We demand honesty and impartiality,
which is impossible

519
00:44:24,840 --> 00:44:27,400
with officers in the Congolese army."

520
00:44:27,680 --> 00:44:29,955
You mean white officers?

521
00:44:30,240 --> 00:44:32,435
We do not want them!
- Black officers!

522
00:44:33,080 --> 00:44:34,069
No officers!

523
00:44:36,200 --> 00:44:38,839
I understand that you want equality and justice.

524
00:44:39,480 --> 00:44:41,596
But I do not yield weapons.

525
00:44:44,441 --> 00:44:46,955
I ask you to return
to your barracks.

526
00:44:47,401 --> 00:44:49,596
We have a strong,
obedient army.

527
00:44:54,161 --> 00:44:55,480
We've heard it all!

528
00:44:55,761 --> 00:44:58,195
Jones speaks so!
- Answer now!

529
00:44:58,961 --> 00:45:01,839
You are not even in mutual agreement.

530
00:45:03,962 --> 00:45:06,112
I understand your indignation.

531
00:45:08,442 --> 00:45:11,479
And I will got to
Leopold and speak to the camp,

532
00:45:11,882 --> 00:45:14,112
in the morning. You have my word.

533
00:45:17,202 --> 00:45:19,636
Now I ask you to return
to your barracks.

534
00:45:24,483 --> 00:45:25,882
Come on then, shoot.

535
00:45:35,563 --> 00:45:36,962
You will come to Camp Leopold?

536
00:45:37,723 --> 00:45:39,156
I promise you

537
00:45:45,124 --> 00:45:48,560
We have 15 white officers hostage
and their wives.

538
00:45:49,844 --> 00:45:51,072
If you do not come,

539
00:45:52,804 --> 00:45:53,998
We will murder them.

540
00:46:15,725 --> 00:46:18,285
Gentlemen, the meeting is not over.

541
00:46:29,206 --> 00:46:32,118
Hey, you there!

542
00:46:32,326 --> 00:46:33,998
Damn Flemish!

543
00:46:39,166 --> 00:46:40,599
Wait!

544
00:46:48,447 --> 00:46:49,926
Maxence, come in!

545
00:46:50,087 --> 00:46:54,399
They do not scare me.
I will write down their numbers.

546
00:46:54,887 --> 00:46:56,525
You'll see what happens!

547
00:46:59,207 --> 00:47:00,526
Idiot!

548
00:47:03,647 --> 00:47:05,080
You hear me, motherfucker?

549
00:47:10,488 --> 00:47:12,080
Dork!

550
00:47:12,848 --> 00:47:14,520
Losers!

551
00:47:15,488 --> 00:47:17,922
You're a disgrace' to the regiment.

552
00:47:19,128 --> 00:47:21,323
You are not alone.

553
00:47:21,488 --> 00:47:25,686
There are assholes everywhere,
across the province.

554
00:47:26,609 --> 00:47:29,407
In Madimba a
white woman was raped.

555
00:47:30,209 --> 00:47:31,642
They were shot!

556
00:47:32,889 --> 00:47:35,119
You shame the Force Publique.

557
00:47:36,369 --> 00:47:39,759
You are arrested.
Take them away!

558
00:47:51,610 --> 00:47:53,362
Let me be clear.

559
00:47:56,170 --> 00:47:59,640
Independence is for the citizens.

560
00:48:00,090 --> 00:48:03,480
For soldiers there is only discipline.

561
00:48:07,250 --> 00:48:10,527
Before June 30 you had
white officers.

562
00:48:11,171 --> 00:48:13,969
After June 30 you still
have white officers.

563
00:48:15,491 --> 00:48:20,849
It may be that the politicians said something
else, but they lied.

564
00:48:21,811 --> 00:48:24,325
I have always told the truth.

565
00:48:24,491 --> 00:48:27,608
And if you do not understand
I will write it for you.

566
00:48:29,692 --> 00:48:32,764
After independence

567
00:48:32,932 --> 00:48:36,720
equals
for independence.

568
00:48:37,212 --> 00:48:38,884
What are you saying, white?

569
00:48:40,092 --> 00:48:43,607
So you will not go.
They have deceived us.

570
00:48:43,892 --> 00:48:45,371
They lied.

571
00:48:48,133 --> 00:48:49,885
We will not go.

572
00:49:03,533 --> 00:49:05,205
Are you coming to bed?

573
00:49:05,373 --> 00:49:07,409
I must finish.

574
00:49:07,693 --> 00:49:10,083
You will sleep again at your desk.

575
00:49:10,334 --> 00:49:11,847
Do not worry.

576
00:49:12,654 --> 00:49:14,963
How can I not worry?

577
00:49:15,694 --> 00:49:17,969
You sleep no more than 2 hours a night.

578
00:49:19,454 --> 00:49:23,129
I will start to think
that you are actually using marijuana.

579
00:49:23,534 --> 00:49:25,092
They say that?

580
00:49:25,254 --> 00:49:28,964
You have no idea what
the servants tell me.

581
00:49:44,375 --> 00:49:47,253
You have to be strong
for the children.

582
00:49:51,976 --> 00:49:54,206
If something were to happen to me ...

583
00:50:10,497 --> 00:50:13,136
General, you know why you're here?

584
00:50:13,697 --> 00:50:14,925
I wait until you tell me.

585
00:50:15,257 --> 00:50:18,010
And I await your explanation.

586
00:50:19,377 --> 00:50:22,414
I got the telegram.
- That's obvious.

587
00:50:22,577 --> 00:50:24,215
Excellency!
- Excuse me?

588
00:50:24,537 --> 00:50:26,289
You say, Excellency.

589
00:50:27,817 --> 00:50:30,127
I want to know what you mean by:

590
00:50:30,978 --> 00:50:33,617
"I myself do not contradict
nor repeated.

591
00:50:34,738 --> 00:50:39,528
Please consider this
as a final warning. "

592
00:50:41,698 --> 00:50:45,486
A General in Belgium
obeys his superiors

593
00:50:45,778 --> 00:50:47,211
So speak?

594
00:50:47,378 --> 00:50:50,928
Excuse me, sir.
In Belgium there is order.

595
00:50:51,539 --> 00:50:55,327
Here we are heading for disaster,
and there is chaos.

596
00:50:55,499 --> 00:50:58,138
Because your men and
your methods are tired.

597
00:51:00,659 --> 00:51:03,332
The Force Publique has to change
like the rest.

598
00:51:03,499 --> 00:51:06,218
I expect your resignation.

599
00:51:06,379 --> 00:51:08,097
Mr. Lumumba ...

600
00:51:09,099 --> 00:51:11,739
Excellence ...
- I've said what I have to say ...

601
00:51:12,220 --> 00:51:13,209
General.

602
00:51:51,341 --> 00:51:52,661
Get out!

603
00:52:01,862 --> 00:52:04,456
Flemish or Walloon?
- Walloons.

604
00:52:06,582 --> 00:52:08,538
100 francs.
- Why?

605
00:52:09,182 --> 00:52:10,934
What's going on?

606
00:52:12,063 --> 00:52:14,054
Nothing.
- Why, sir?

607
00:52:39,624 --> 00:52:41,819
The Belgian ambassador.

608
00:52:42,784 --> 00:52:44,581
Let him through the garden.

609
00:52:52,144 --> 00:52:54,261
Do you have news, Mr. Ambassador?

610
00:52:54,425 --> 00:52:57,576
Nothing that you do not know.
It's bad.

611
00:52:59,265 --> 00:53:01,381
You were chased out of Camp Leopold.

612
00:53:01,545 --> 00:53:03,820
But order will be restored.

613
00:53:03,985 --> 00:53:06,021
I do not know what order you want,

614
00:53:06,185 --> 00:53:11,100
but I still cannot watch
while my countrymen are murdered.

615
00:53:11,865 --> 00:53:15,620
If you do not have the means, I do,

616
00:53:15,786 --> 00:53:17,504
and they are at your disposal.

617
00:53:19,386 --> 00:53:21,377
An intervention?
- The situation is serious.

618
00:53:21,906 --> 00:53:23,703
You can ask assistance from Belgium.

619
00:53:24,306 --> 00:53:27,696
You have the right.
- I have a different opinion.

620
00:53:27,986 --> 00:53:32,138
If you refuse, I will have to
consult with our Atlantic partners.

621
00:53:33,306 --> 00:53:36,105
Do you understand?
- Not yet.

622
00:53:36,707 --> 00:53:38,584
But this is what I've decided.

623
00:53:40,747 --> 00:53:45,582
First, General Janssens
should leave Congo within 24 hours.

624
00:53:45,827 --> 00:53:49,422
Secondly, you should warn him
and guarantee his departure.

625
00:53:49,707 --> 00:53:54,099
Thirdly, you are responsible
for his actions during his departure.

626
00:53:55,948 --> 00:53:59,782
He served Congo, Your Excellency.
He deserves respect

627
00:54:00,068 --> 00:54:01,660
and courtesy.
- Courtesy!

628
00:54:03,748 --> 00:54:07,707
It's the fault of the Belgians:
the uprising in the Camp, in this City

629
00:54:07,868 --> 00:54:10,428
Camp Leopold, Elizabeth City ...

630
00:54:10,588 --> 00:54:13,386
You spread rumours
of a Soviet invasion...

631
00:54:13,548 --> 00:54:16,347
Since the beginning
You've worked to conspire against me.

632
00:54:16,509 --> 00:54:19,546
And now you threaten me with the U.N. and NATO

633
00:54:19,709 --> 00:54:22,781
In the middle of the night
to the Prime Minister!

634
00:54:23,029 --> 00:54:25,941
Tomorrow I will hold a press conference

635
00:54:26,109 --> 00:54:28,748
and make your conspiracy, threats
and insults public.

636
00:54:28,909 --> 00:54:31,184
I've been advised
to go to Brazzaville,

637
00:54:31,349 --> 00:54:35,980
but count me out.
Belgians will murder me there.

638
00:54:37,590 --> 00:54:41,583
I complain and you become angry.
Allow me but I find that strange.

639
00:54:41,910 --> 00:54:44,299
Then, I would ask you to leave.

640
00:54:50,270 --> 00:54:53,182
I hereby absolve General Janssens.

641
00:54:53,390 --> 00:54:55,825
For his own good and safety.

642
00:54:56,551 --> 00:54:59,349
I ask him the travel by air
at the first available opportunity.

643
00:55:00,511 --> 00:55:04,868
I appoint Major Victor Lundula to
Supreme Commander of the Force Publique

644
00:55:05,031 --> 00:55:08,023
I have also promoted Joseph Mobutu
to colonel.

645
00:55:08,231 --> 00:55:11,780
The Force Publique is now
The Congolese National Army.

646
00:55:11,951 --> 00:55:13,862
The Belgians are worried.

647
00:55:14,271 --> 00:55:16,547
How will you fight the atrocities?

648
00:55:17,392 --> 00:55:19,462
These difficulties are inevitable.

649
00:55:19,632 --> 00:55:23,307
They are caused by a few
agitators and a big misunderstanding.

650
00:55:23,712 --> 00:55:28,342
I have decided to stop them
President Kasavubu and myself

651
00:55:28,512 --> 00:55:32,824
I will make a journey of peace
throughout the country.

652
00:55:32,992 --> 00:55:35,108
Are you going to Katanga?
- Everywhere.

653
00:55:35,272 --> 00:55:39,471
Elisabethville, Coquilhatstad,
Stanleyville, Luluaburg ...

654
00:55:40,113 --> 00:55:42,183
But I warn the
Belgian Government

655
00:55:42,593 --> 00:55:45,585
the situation
must not be misused

656
00:55:45,913 --> 00:55:48,825
for a military intervention or
to encourage riots.

657
00:55:49,593 --> 00:55:52,187
Only had work can make us move forward.

658
00:55:53,553 --> 00:55:55,350
Those who refuse to see

659
00:55:56,033 --> 00:55:59,344
and sabotage us,
are enemies of the people.

660
00:55:59,514 --> 00:56:02,426
What does Mr. Tshombe say about it?
- Will you go to U.N. ?

661
00:56:07,914 --> 00:56:12,226
"Katanga, our beautiful and prosperous
Province, the largest source ...

662
00:56:12,914 --> 00:56:15,951
... The main source
of our wealth. "

663
00:56:19,075 --> 00:56:22,067
What time is it in Elizabeth City?
Just as late in Luluaburg?

664
00:56:22,235 --> 00:56:25,113
No idea. I only hope that this
is the last stop.

665
00:56:27,035 --> 00:56:28,263
We've travelled everywhere, all in 10 days.

666
00:56:29,115 --> 00:56:30,867
I'm tired of this plane.

667
00:56:32,635 --> 00:56:35,513
Congo is too big for us.

668
00:56:35,675 --> 00:56:38,668
Do not say that. Congo is big

669
00:56:38,836 --> 00:56:41,987
and requires great things.
But it is not too large.

670
00:56:42,996 --> 00:56:45,556
"Who says secession, says treason."

671
00:56:49,796 --> 00:56:50,831
We're descending?

672
00:56:50,996 --> 00:56:54,955
Airport Elizabeth City
refuses to let us land.

673
00:57:05,677 --> 00:57:08,111
I repeat, you can not land.

674
00:57:08,757 --> 00:57:10,349
Orders from the government of Katanga.

675
00:57:10,517 --> 00:57:11,711
What government?

676
00:57:11,877 --> 00:57:14,516
This is it. Secession.

677
00:57:15,077 --> 00:57:20,675
We can receive President Kasa Vubu,
but the traitor Patrice Lumumba

678
00:57:20,958 --> 00:57:23,916
will never set foot in Katanga.
- That's Munongo.

679
00:57:24,078 --> 00:57:25,909
Begin our descent.
- Impossible.

680
00:57:26,078 --> 00:57:27,636
Do what I say!
- Impossible.

681
00:57:27,798 --> 00:57:29,834
They have placed a truck
on the runway.

682
00:57:29,998 --> 00:57:33,354
We can not but go back.

683
00:57:45,639 --> 00:57:48,073
We have underestimated Tshombe.

684
00:57:51,719 --> 00:57:53,675
He does not do this alone.

685
00:57:54,599 --> 00:57:56,749
The Belgians have encouraged him.

686
00:57:58,279 --> 00:58:00,396
What do we do now?

687
00:58:00,560 --> 00:58:03,518
We can choose
war, shame, resignation

688
00:58:03,680 --> 00:58:06,035
and the loss of 70%
of our resources.

689
00:58:06,200 --> 00:58:10,079
We have no choice.
We must suppress the uprising.

690
00:58:11,960 --> 00:58:15,509
By Union Miniere, the entire financial
world is involved.

691
00:58:15,680 --> 00:58:20,197
Imagine. The whole of Katanga.
It's 16 times bigger than Belgium.

692
00:58:21,361 --> 00:58:24,671
They do not get such a gift.
We will call on the U.N..

693
00:58:26,881 --> 00:58:28,553
Is that the best solution?

694
00:58:29,281 --> 00:58:32,193
For a military operation
the Russians ...

695
00:58:32,361 --> 00:58:37,196
The Russians, and have them say that I a
Communist puppet. The CIA would surely murder me?

696
00:58:41,322 --> 00:58:42,072
What a calm.

697
00:58:43,882 --> 00:58:46,157
It is wonderful, the silence.

698
00:59:14,283 --> 00:59:17,719
Why are we going to Njili?
We said Stanleyville.

699
00:59:18,283 --> 00:59:20,354
I got other directions.

700
00:59:20,524 --> 00:59:24,278
You are under our command.
We decide not you.

701
00:59:24,804 --> 00:59:27,477
I am Belgian, Excellency.

702
00:59:43,605 --> 00:59:44,924
Attention!

703
00:59:47,605 --> 00:59:50,756
Mr. President, Where do you
want the troops to take up position?

704
00:59:53,645 --> 00:59:55,158
Is it a trap.

705
00:59:56,165 --> 00:59:59,475
It is strange that the President
has these troops to behold?

706
01:00:00,005 --> 01:00:01,519
No way!

707
01:00:03,646 --> 01:00:05,876
Go provide a car.

708
01:00:06,326 --> 01:00:07,236
Mr. President,

709
01:00:07,526 --> 01:00:10,598
our troops are here
in order to honor and protect you.

710
01:00:11,246 --> 01:00:12,679
You need them to take up position.

711
01:00:12,846 --> 01:00:15,485
We refuse. You are no longer with you

712
01:00:15,646 --> 01:00:17,204
Mr. President,

713
01:00:17,366 --> 01:00:21,360
We welcome you with the honor
you deserve.

714
01:00:22,487 --> 01:00:24,079
Never mind. Go away.

715
01:00:24,527 --> 01:00:28,839
Mr. President, you do not speak
against "one" Belgian officer.

716
01:00:29,087 --> 01:00:32,636
Look at those women.
They were raped by your troops.

717
01:00:32,847 --> 01:00:37,079
Our men were assaulted.
You shame Africa and the world.

718
01:00:38,647 --> 01:00:41,845
We are here to protect our citizens.
There should be no flow of blood.

719
01:00:42,088 --> 01:00:45,239
If blood is flowing tonight,
you are responsible.

720
01:00:49,688 --> 01:00:51,121
Murderers!
- Bastards!

721
01:00:55,968 --> 01:00:57,367
Murderers, sadists!

722
01:00:58,088 --> 01:01:00,807
You raped nuns
and white women!

723
01:01:09,209 --> 01:01:10,722
The humiliation would not end.

724
01:01:11,809 --> 01:01:16,041
They were ready for anything.
Even sacrificing their own citizens.

725
01:01:16,769 --> 01:01:20,159
They needed someone to blame
for all this.

726
01:01:20,889 --> 01:01:25,122
They had, at any cost,
the rebel silenced.

727
01:01:33,050 --> 01:01:34,403
Hands on your head!

728
01:01:34,690 --> 01:01:35,725
Out!

729
01:01:37,610 --> 01:01:39,441
Get down!

730
01:01:40,970 --> 01:01:41,766
Paratroopers!

731
01:01:42,330 --> 01:01:45,209
The Belgian paratroopers are everywhere!

732
01:01:46,051 --> 01:01:47,848
The white officers have
hidden the ammunition!

733
01:01:48,451 --> 01:01:52,808
They removed the paratroopers there!
Send troops to the airport!

734
01:01:53,051 --> 01:01:54,643
Let the Russians come are not countries!

735
01:01:54,931 --> 01:01:56,887
They've evacuated their families!

736
01:01:57,451 --> 01:01:58,930
They will kill us all!

737
01:02:23,533 --> 01:02:25,171
Is this photograph necessary?

738
01:02:25,333 --> 01:02:27,289
Do not worry.
We'll pay for everything.

739
01:02:29,013 --> 01:02:31,402
It will be in every ministry,

740
01:02:31,693 --> 01:02:32,569
every school

741
01:02:32,853 --> 01:02:34,127
every store and bar.

742
01:02:36,493 --> 01:02:37,608
Excuse me.

743
01:02:39,493 --> 01:02:42,087
We will not make it.
We follow him in two months.

744
01:02:44,414 --> 01:02:47,133
Fix it?
- It's war, Patrice.

745
01:02:47,494 --> 01:02:49,610
The U.N. is talking about genocide.

746
01:02:49,774 --> 01:02:51,844
The U.N. is manipulated
the U.S.A..

747
01:02:52,014 --> 01:02:54,767
Anyway,
There are hundreds of deaths.

748
01:02:55,094 --> 01:02:58,689
You had Kasai recaptured
with no organized massacre.

749
01:02:59,054 --> 01:03:00,931
And what have you achieved?

750
01:03:01,094 --> 01:03:03,528
Most of leaders
have fled to Katanga.

751
01:03:04,295 --> 01:03:06,934
We checked Kasai.
- It was one massacre.

752
01:03:08,695 --> 01:03:11,687
War means killing, kill
or be killed. That's the price.

753
01:03:11,855 --> 01:03:12,970
Who pays?

754
01:03:13,375 --> 01:03:14,808
Always the same!

755
01:03:14,975 --> 01:03:17,091
So far I've got you covered.

756
01:03:18,295 --> 01:03:20,286
But I do not support such atrocities.

757
01:03:22,775 --> 01:03:24,892
Mr. Prime Minister ...
- Enough comedy!

758
01:03:34,296 --> 01:03:37,493
I am a soldier and an officer.
I have proven this.

759
01:03:37,816 --> 01:03:39,932
I took over the Force Publique.

760
01:03:40,096 --> 01:03:43,293
I follow orders ... if any.

761
01:03:43,816 --> 01:03:45,614
And if there are none ...

762
01:03:47,577 --> 01:03:49,169
I make my own decisions.

763
01:03:53,017 --> 01:03:56,054
Women, children,

764
01:03:56,977 --> 01:04:00,367
old people. Trapped in a church
and killed?

765
01:04:01,057 --> 01:04:02,968
Is that what you decided?

766
01:04:06,378 --> 01:04:07,447
Answer!

767
01:04:08,458 --> 01:04:10,972
No, obviously not.

768
01:04:12,858 --> 01:04:14,450
But this is war.

769
01:04:14,938 --> 01:04:17,054
And a war is always dirty.

770
01:04:18,578 --> 01:04:20,569
It makes people crazy with fear.

771
01:04:22,298 --> 01:04:26,417
And at such times
orders are useless.

772
01:04:28,379 --> 01:04:29,255
You let it happen.

773
01:04:30,299 --> 01:04:32,290
You have not executed the guilty.

774
01:04:32,459 --> 01:04:34,689
Do you know what that will cost?

775
01:04:35,499 --> 01:04:38,491
I will be held responsible.

776
01:04:40,939 --> 01:04:42,770
You will isolate me even more.

777
01:04:42,939 --> 01:04:45,612
You're not alone. I'm on your side.

778
01:04:53,780 --> 01:04:55,691
You're not by my side.

779
01:04:56,620 --> 01:04:58,417
You stand behind me.

780
01:04:59,700 --> 01:05:02,976
I do not want a murderer by my side,

781
01:05:03,140 --> 01:05:04,971
and certainly not behind me.

782
01:05:12,981 --> 01:05:14,653
What do you mean?

783
01:05:18,421 --> 01:05:20,332
You should go!

784
01:05:22,661 --> 01:05:24,219
Is that clear?

785
01:06:16,024 --> 01:06:17,616
That's it.

786
01:06:17,904 --> 01:06:18,734
Good.

787
01:06:20,584 --> 01:06:22,017
Very well. Directly.

788
01:06:28,425 --> 01:06:30,893
The president can see you now.

789
01:06:35,065 --> 01:06:38,262
Mr. Timberlake, nice to see you.

790
01:06:38,785 --> 01:06:41,424
I tried to reach you
at the embassy.

791
01:06:41,585 --> 01:06:44,577
I am far away.
- Everyone is lately.

792
01:06:45,305 --> 01:06:48,183
My government has a proposal.
- A proposal?

793
01:06:48,746 --> 01:06:53,137
I want to listen, but I doubt
the reliability of the U.S..

794
01:06:53,666 --> 01:06:56,783
You've probably heard the Bantu proverb:

795
01:06:57,066 --> 01:06:58,738
"The hand that gives, prevails."

796
01:06:59,226 --> 01:07:03,014
And your hand to me seems
far too heavy. Excuse me.

797
01:07:05,346 --> 01:07:07,382
Mr. Prime Minister ...

798
01:07:08,546 --> 01:07:10,981
I am very worried.

799
01:07:11,707 --> 01:07:14,540
The Congolese army ...
- I know.

800
01:07:14,907 --> 01:07:17,580
The slaughter in Kasai.
I am appalled.

801
01:07:17,747 --> 01:07:20,102
I'm talking to the guilty.

802
01:07:20,267 --> 01:07:21,985
The Congo is not.

803
01:07:22,147 --> 01:07:25,059
The problem remains with Katanga.

804
01:07:25,227 --> 01:07:28,742
Our undisciplined troops
have committed atrocities

805
01:07:28,907 --> 01:07:32,742
and U.N. betrays us
by giving passive support to the Belgians.

806
01:07:34,028 --> 01:07:37,816
Ghana supports us, along with Guinea
but they have no money.

807
01:07:47,348 --> 01:07:49,066
Do you have a solution?

808
01:07:51,149 --> 01:07:52,582
The Russians.

809
01:07:53,749 --> 01:07:57,105
They promise us airplanes,
military advisers ...

810
01:07:57,469 --> 01:07:59,027
And troops for Lundula.

811
01:07:59,669 --> 01:08:02,263
He will replace Mobutu, whom I distrust.

812
01:08:02,429 --> 01:08:05,501
Were you not afraid that the Russians
would bring you into disrepute?

813
01:08:05,789 --> 01:08:08,462
That was long ago.
We were already discredited.

814
01:08:14,150 --> 01:08:16,061
What a beautiful place.

815
01:08:17,070 --> 01:08:18,549
And so quiet.

816
01:08:19,910 --> 01:08:23,505
I must insist.
May I ask the Russians?

817
01:08:23,910 --> 01:08:27,266
I'd like to go with a better plan.
If you have one I'll run with it immediately.

818
01:08:36,311 --> 01:08:37,869
I have none.

819
01:09:52,395 --> 01:09:54,590
Joseph, now you have your own men ...

820
01:09:54,755 --> 01:09:57,315
As long as they are paid ...
- Paid and trained.

821
01:09:58,235 --> 01:10:01,432
We're investing in
Congo's future.

822
01:10:01,595 --> 01:10:03,904
The future for us all.

823
01:10:04,075 --> 01:10:06,589
I'll be honest with you

824
01:10:06,755 --> 01:10:10,589
Kasavubu has disappointed us.
And Lumumba is in charge.

825
01:10:10,875 --> 01:10:13,834
We need someone who
will work with us.

826
01:10:15,596 --> 01:10:16,665
I've been thinking.

827
01:10:18,076 --> 01:10:19,873
I think about it constantly.

828
01:10:21,596 --> 01:10:23,905
I guarantee you everything.

829
01:10:24,236 --> 01:10:26,431
Eisenhower?
- Kennedy.

830
01:10:34,677 --> 01:10:36,315
What will I win there?

831
01:10:36,997 --> 01:10:38,396
Everything.

832
01:10:44,437 --> 01:10:48,032
We interrupt our program
to air a statement from the President.

833
01:10:48,237 --> 01:10:52,469
Value compatriots,
Prime Minister Patrice Lumumba,

834
01:10:52,637 --> 01:10:57,348
appointed by the Belgian king
has denied his role.

835
01:10:57,598 --> 01:10:59,873
He has ruled in an arbitrary manner.

836
01:11:00,038 --> 01:11:05,158
He drags the country into
in a terrible civil war.

837
01:11:05,318 --> 01:11:10,392
Hence I think it is necessary
that it must end immediately.

838
01:11:10,718 --> 01:11:16,077
I ask the Congolese army and our
brothers to stop the killings

839
01:11:16,799 --> 01:11:19,233
and that the weapons across the republic

840
01:11:19,519 --> 01:11:22,033
to fall temporarily silent.

841
01:11:22,399 --> 01:11:23,593
Where's Justin?
- Gone to eat.

842
01:11:23,759 --> 01:11:25,317
And Dieudonné?
- Yet again.

843
01:11:25,479 --> 01:11:29,028
There's nobody here.
Take the car keys.

844
01:11:31,879 --> 01:11:33,916
Where are you going?
- Parliament.

845
01:11:57,041 --> 01:12:01,239
What is happening is outrageous!
Mr. Kasavubu

846
01:12:01,521 --> 01:12:05,070
can not dissolve what has been
elected by the people!

847
01:12:05,481 --> 01:12:07,949
We turned to no effort.

848
01:12:08,121 --> 01:12:11,796
For the moment the Congo
has enjoyed the admiration of the world

849
01:12:12,321 --> 01:12:17,157
Kasavubu has given us a heavy blow
and has dragged the Congo through the mud.

850
01:12:24,882 --> 01:12:27,032
Silence!

851
01:12:27,962 --> 01:12:30,112
The Prime Minister has the word.

852
01:12:42,483 --> 01:12:46,317
Mr. President,
respectable gentlemen,

853
01:12:47,723 --> 01:12:53,275
I speak to you because it is my duty
to inform you of events.

854
01:12:53,443 --> 01:12:54,876
Too late!
- Congratulations!

855
01:12:55,043 --> 01:12:57,638
I've never been against Kasavubu.

856
01:12:58,084 --> 01:13:02,953
In any case, because
He is president and because of my actions.

857
01:13:03,484 --> 01:13:05,759
It's true!
- Easy to say!

858
01:13:07,444 --> 01:13:10,720
Some delegates,
also in opposition, do not agree

859
01:13:10,924 --> 01:13:13,563
and say that he is a separatist.

860
01:13:13,724 --> 01:13:16,797
The danger they fear is a reality.

861
01:13:18,365 --> 01:13:20,242
He's right.

862
01:13:20,405 --> 01:13:26,753
If the elected representatives of the people demand
Kasavubu to leave, he is deposed.

863
01:13:26,925 --> 01:13:28,119
Do it!

864
01:13:29,725 --> 01:13:33,434
Millions were spent

865
01:13:33,805 --> 01:13:36,445
on radio campaign against me.

866
01:13:36,606 --> 01:13:40,485
Every day there has been
a psychological battle fought.

867
01:13:41,406 --> 01:13:44,239
In order to mislead the people
I have been named

868
01:13:44,406 --> 01:13:49,036
Dictator Lumumba, Lumumba Communist,
Lumumba Moscow etc.

869
01:13:49,966 --> 01:13:54,642
When we fought in the early days
for our independence,

870
01:13:54,886 --> 01:13:57,196
was I prompted by the Russians?

871
01:13:58,087 --> 01:14:02,638
Did I ask the Russians to
the independence negotiations?

872
01:14:04,207 --> 01:14:07,040
Who has given us 80 years of exploitation?

873
01:14:07,567 --> 01:14:09,398
We are not the imperialists?

874
01:14:10,287 --> 01:14:14,997
Queen Elizabeth is President of
the Belgian-Russian association.

875
01:14:15,207 --> 01:14:16,606
Does it show me to be a Communist?

876
01:14:20,528 --> 01:14:22,723
If they hold Lumumba in contempt,

877
01:14:23,568 --> 01:14:26,958
Lumumba then is the black sheep.

878
01:14:27,928 --> 01:14:32,399
But actually they go on to attack
the future of the Congo.

879
01:14:35,008 --> 01:14:36,646
Dear brothers,

880
01:14:37,289 --> 01:14:39,280
I appeal to your wisdom,

881
01:14:39,609 --> 01:14:41,247
your Bantu wisdom.

882
01:14:42,089 --> 01:14:44,967
The situation is worse than you think.

883
01:14:45,929 --> 01:14:49,888
We must unite, because
divided we cannot save our country.

884
01:14:51,089 --> 01:14:53,649
Let us forget our divisions.

885
01:15:15,930 --> 01:15:17,409
Pauline?

886
01:15:19,691 --> 01:15:22,524
Acute hepatitis.
We need urgent action.

887
01:15:40,212 --> 01:15:43,443
Have you seen her?
- A Treasure. She looks like you.

888
01:15:44,532 --> 01:15:46,011
What will she be called?

889
01:15:46,172 --> 01:15:48,481
I thought of Marie-Christine.

890
01:15:53,612 --> 01:15:55,170
They will bring her to Switzerland.

891
01:15:55,652 --> 01:15:58,212
They say it's her only chance.

892
01:15:58,372 --> 01:15:59,726
They hid that from me.

893
01:16:03,653 --> 01:16:05,962
I want my baby.

894
01:17:08,296 --> 01:17:10,173
You were not in Parliament.

895
01:17:10,336 --> 01:17:11,405
What is it?
- The thick ...

896
01:17:12,336 --> 01:17:15,055
The President wants me to arrest you.

897
01:17:15,536 --> 01:17:17,174
I wanted to warn you.

898
01:17:24,377 --> 01:17:27,813
And you say I'm involved
I am a soldier.

899
01:17:28,417 --> 01:17:31,136
I never butt in
on political conflicts.

900
01:17:31,297 --> 01:17:33,686
Have your men surrounded the house?

901
01:17:34,937 --> 01:17:35,892
A Security measure.

902
01:17:36,737 --> 01:17:40,093
I am not under arrest,
but my house is surrounded?

903
01:17:41,098 --> 01:17:43,453
For your own safety.

904
01:17:44,658 --> 01:17:46,694
Many people want you dead.

905
01:17:47,138 --> 01:17:51,689
My wife or my supporters,
Whom should I fear?

906
01:17:52,178 --> 01:17:54,567
Send your men away.
- Is that a request or will you show me a warrant?

907
01:17:54,858 --> 01:17:57,292
It's an order!
- Kasa you have been deposed.

908
01:17:57,978 --> 01:18:00,412
And for you, he is not president anymore.

909
01:18:01,939 --> 01:18:03,657
What would you do in my place?

910
01:18:05,259 --> 01:18:10,049
I know you. This decision
is not yours alone.

911
01:18:14,739 --> 01:18:16,695
Who stands behind you?

912
01:18:17,939 --> 01:18:18,849
Who?

913
01:18:21,580 --> 01:18:23,377
Out of this impasse

914
01:18:23,540 --> 01:18:27,419
the army has neutralized
President Kasavubu and

915
01:18:28,380 --> 01:18:31,736
Lumumba as Prime Minister.

916
01:18:33,820 --> 01:18:35,936
This is not a military coup,

917
01:18:36,500 --> 01:18:39,060
just a peaceful revolution.

918
01:18:39,780 --> 01:18:42,090
Will there be free elections?

919
01:18:49,621 --> 01:18:51,771
But politicians have been arrested?

920
01:18:51,941 --> 01:18:53,659
Is this a coup?

921
01:18:58,821 --> 01:19:01,494
No military power will take control.

922
01:19:02,542 --> 01:19:04,180
Again, this is not a coup.

923
01:19:04,342 --> 01:19:07,618
What are the Americans doing?
- Involved in a Peaceful Revolution.

924
01:19:08,382 --> 01:19:12,375
We are neutral Congolese
and foreign technicians,

925
01:19:12,622 --> 01:19:15,500
we chose them, to
ask for help to save our country.

926
01:19:16,422 --> 01:19:17,980
Long live General Mobutu!

927
01:19:18,142 --> 01:19:19,655
Not so fast.

928
01:19:21,222 --> 01:19:24,818
Where's Lumumba?
- Do you support the Belgians?

929
01:19:24,983 --> 01:19:26,814
How is payment reform going?

930
01:19:26,983 --> 01:19:28,814
Has Lumumba been convicted?

931
01:19:34,863 --> 01:19:37,855
The phone is still working,
but for how long?

932
01:19:38,743 --> 01:19:41,337
I will not wait until I am isolated.

933
01:19:43,384 --> 01:19:45,659
There's a simple solution.

934
01:19:45,824 --> 01:19:48,702
We go to Stanleyville
and start from scratch.

935
01:19:48,864 --> 01:19:49,535
Why?

936
01:19:57,704 --> 01:20:00,377
We are neutralized.
and I'm trapped

937
01:20:00,544 --> 01:20:03,183
and Mr. Kasavubu's a free man.

938
01:20:05,105 --> 01:20:07,858
Katanga? You're kidding.

939
01:20:10,225 --> 01:20:12,785
If you want to drown your dog ...

940
01:20:13,785 --> 01:20:15,582
then you don't torture
him with shallow water.

941
01:20:29,026 --> 01:20:30,778
Yes, I'm still here.

942
01:20:31,306 --> 01:20:32,534
Excuse me.

943
01:20:33,186 --> 01:20:35,905
I just read that my daughter
has died.

944
01:20:37,426 --> 01:20:39,462
I can not even go to her funeral.

945
01:20:50,027 --> 01:20:51,540
I cannot do anything.

946
01:21:25,829 --> 01:21:27,467
Thomas, it's you.

947
01:21:29,309 --> 01:21:32,665
I am determined.
We cannot tay here any longer.

948
01:21:33,909 --> 01:21:35,183
Yes, I know.

949
01:21:35,549 --> 01:21:38,541
I cannot stay here
under house arrest

950
01:21:38,709 --> 01:21:41,064
while my supporters are being killed.

951
01:21:43,149 --> 01:21:45,185
Are you safe?

952
01:21:48,150 --> 01:21:49,503
Listen ...

953
01:21:51,750 --> 01:21:53,820
One of us must make a sacrifice.

954
01:21:57,710 --> 01:22:01,180
I will definitely be arrested,
tortured and murdered.

955
01:22:03,870 --> 01:22:06,669
It's a sacrifice for the people.

956
01:22:09,151 --> 01:22:10,982
Well, Thomas.

957
01:22:12,711 --> 01:22:14,110
Do not worry.

958
01:22:19,111 --> 01:22:22,023
Forget what I just said.
It was a joke.

959
01:23:14,554 --> 01:23:15,907
Alphonse ...

960
01:23:16,354 --> 01:23:18,993
I've a parcel to get?

961
01:23:19,194 --> 01:23:21,105
I'll be right back.

962
01:23:29,475 --> 01:23:31,943
I smoke the American brand.

963
01:23:32,995 --> 01:23:34,144
Damn rain!

964
01:23:34,875 --> 01:23:36,945
Runs right past your neck.

965
01:25:56,722 --> 01:25:59,316
You must leave the main road.

966
01:25:59,482 --> 01:26:04,078
The checkpoint at Kasimba
saw a convoy.

967
01:26:04,842 --> 01:26:06,992
How far from here?
- 16 km.

968
01:26:07,362 --> 01:26:08,715
Maybe less.

969
01:26:09,202 --> 01:26:10,556
Thank you, comrade.

970
01:26:45,044 --> 01:26:46,477
There is no boat.

971
01:26:47,444 --> 01:26:49,514
We'll use the canoes.

972
01:26:49,684 --> 01:26:51,801
And how is it on the other side?

973
01:26:53,925 --> 01:26:56,723
We look for cars
or continue on foot.

974
01:27:03,685 --> 01:27:05,243
No Patrice, I'm not going first.

975
01:27:05,405 --> 01:27:06,758
Quick!
- I risk nothing.

976
01:27:06,925 --> 01:27:08,722
They're hot on our heels!

977
01:27:09,245 --> 01:27:10,758
I'll wait for the boat.

978
01:27:18,046 --> 01:27:19,274
We leave.

979
01:27:57,568 --> 01:27:59,047
Who are they?

980
01:28:01,368 --> 01:28:02,357
I cannot see.

981
01:28:03,088 --> 01:28:04,282
I must go back.
- No!

982
01:28:05,168 --> 01:28:06,601
That is pure madness!

983
01:28:08,488 --> 01:28:11,161
It is your task to reach Stanleyville.

984
01:28:11,328 --> 01:28:14,162
And let them take revenge
on my family?

985
01:28:14,449 --> 01:28:16,917
What will they say?
- That's suicide.

986
01:28:17,129 --> 01:28:19,484
They are not numerous. They will listen.

987
01:28:22,289 --> 01:28:24,405
You ungrateful creatures!

988
01:28:25,889 --> 01:28:27,641
This is pure madness!

989
01:29:10,611 --> 01:29:13,125
Chief, we wish you no harm.

990
01:29:13,451 --> 01:29:16,285
But if we return without you,

991
01:29:16,572 --> 01:29:18,085
we are slain.

992
01:29:18,252 --> 01:29:20,482
And now they will kill me.

993
01:29:20,652 --> 01:29:24,281
You still have regrets.

994
01:29:24,572 --> 01:29:27,245
I gave you the power
of the Force Publique.

995
01:29:28,132 --> 01:29:30,362
When I die, you are also dead.

996
01:29:30,652 --> 01:29:33,849
He's right.
- I'm for Lumumba.

997
01:29:34,012 --> 01:29:36,447
Stop this nonsense!

998
01:29:37,013 --> 01:29:38,810
Excuse me, Chief,

999
01:29:39,093 --> 01:29:40,606
but we recommend ...

1000
01:30:41,816 --> 01:30:43,454
Where were you arrested?

1001
01:30:48,096 --> 01:30:49,529
What about your children?

1002
01:31:55,939 --> 01:31:57,259
What?

1003
01:31:59,140 --> 01:32:01,017
Cannibal.

1004
01:32:56,702 --> 01:32:59,297
Very well, gentlemen, it's time to vote.

1005
01:33:00,943 --> 01:33:03,298
The proponents raise your hands.

1006
01:33:22,904 --> 01:33:26,135
Mr. Carlucci,
Will you cast your vote?

1007
01:33:26,944 --> 01:33:31,495
The government of my country does not intervene
in the affairs of a sovereign state.

1008
01:33:31,664 --> 01:33:32,858
We'll respect your decision.

1009
01:33:51,905 --> 01:33:54,214
This is the message:

1010
01:33:54,425 --> 01:33:58,976
"Ask permission from the jew
in order to receive. "

1011
01:34:08,386 --> 01:34:10,138
You?
- They arrested everyone.

1012
01:35:12,829 --> 01:35:15,024
Where are you taking us?

1013
01:35:37,790 --> 01:35:40,668
Katanga, 17 January 1961

1014
01:36:22,913 --> 01:36:25,222
I hope they do not ...

1015
01:36:58,194 --> 01:37:02,392
Internal bleeding.
Probably showing a perforated stomach.

1016
01:37:02,995 --> 01:37:04,792
Broken ribs.

1017
01:37:05,235 --> 01:37:08,864
If they are not brought in
for an operation,

1018
01:37:10,035 --> 01:37:12,344
it's only a matter of hours.

1019
01:37:20,035 --> 01:37:21,787
I warned you.

1020
01:37:24,236 --> 01:37:26,033
To never set foot in my country.

1021
01:39:49,643 --> 01:39:53,033
Civilians, soldiers,

1022
01:39:53,283 --> 01:39:57,674
on this memorable day,
the anniversary of our independence,

1023
01:39:58,123 --> 01:40:01,672
we greet you with joy and pride.

1024
01:40:02,443 --> 01:40:06,995
On behalf of the Government
we show a minute's silence

1025
01:40:07,284 --> 01:40:11,163
in memory of the man
we cry out as our National Hero:

1026
01:40:11,724 --> 01:40:13,874
Patrice Emery Lumumba.

1027
01:40:31,525 --> 01:40:33,993
You can pray as you wish.

1028
01:40:35,365 --> 01:40:38,277
Nobody knew about that night
in Katanga.

1029
01:40:39,765 --> 01:40:42,802
The children may not know,
do you?

1030
01:40:45,405 --> 01:40:47,362
They wouldn't understand.

1031
01:40:48,606 --> 01:40:52,724
Just tell them that I came
50 years too soon.

1032
01:40:58,006 --> 01:41:01,885
Tell them what we wanted
for our country,

1033
01:41:02,286 --> 01:41:04,436
was not wanted by others.

1034
01:41:29,488 --> 01:41:31,126
Dearest Pauline,

1035
01:41:31,768 --> 01:41:35,078
if you read this, I am dead.

1036
01:41:45,448 --> 01:41:48,521
Tell my children that Congo
has a great future,

1037
01:41:48,689 --> 01:41:51,920
that our dignity is
there to recover.

1038
01:41:53,009 --> 01:41:55,443
Tell them that during the fight

1039
01:41:56,009 --> 01:41:58,204
I had no time to hesitate

1040
01:41:58,369 --> 01:42:02,840
that the purpose for which we
gave our lives would be overcome.

1041
01:42:03,689 --> 01:42:05,008
Go get him.

1042
01:43:28,973 --> 01:43:30,248
Thanks.

1043
01:44:20,816 --> 01:44:22,966
Weep not for me, my companion.

1044
01:44:24,096 --> 01:44:26,974
History will be the final judge.

1045
01:44:27,816 --> 01:44:30,614
That history will not be
written in Brussels,

1046
01:44:30,776 --> 01:44:32,927
Paris or Washington.

1047
01:44:33,097 --> 01:44:37,090
It will be ours,
the story of a new Africa.

1048
01:44:41,057 --> 01:44:43,617
And on that day ...

