In Saint Tropez...
the moon wakes up with you.
She twists
counting the stars in the sky.
But there's a prettier star that's
not in the sky, but with me,
in Saint Tropez.
But there's a prettier star
that's not in the sky, but with me,
in Saint Tropez.
Twist, twist, everybody.
Twist, twist, it's going mad.
She dreams and wants to live
a long unforgettable night
in Saint Tropez.
People wonder why
you dance to the twist
wearing a lamé dress.
You wanna look ever prettier,
but fashion stays the same
if you dance to the twist.
You wanna look ever prettier,
but fashion stays the same
if you dance to the twist.
Twist, twist, everybody.
Twist, twist, it's going mad.
She dreams and wants to live
a long unforgettable night
in Saint Tropez.
People wonder why
you dance to the twist
wearing a lamé dress.
You wanna look ever prettier,
but fashion stays the same
if you dance to the twist.
Now don't forget you'll get
your teeth cleaned next Tuesday at 3.
Oh, yeah!
Do you have a cold?
Joe! Do you have a cold?
No, I'm alright.
Eddie, did we pick the
Chinese dressing gown?
It's in the silver trunk.
Every holy day in church,
No, thanks.
Have you gone taller again?
Growing a little every day.
when I offered my prayers to God,
a handsome and gallant young man
would keep offering himself to my gaze.
- I had a strange dream last night.
- What?
It's...
- ...it's boring.
- Tell me.
No, no, you're busy packing.
I'll tell you later.
You always tell me your dreams.
When people tell me their dreams
I find it very uninteresting.
I'll tell you later. We'll have lots
of time on the boat, OK?
Remember we have two hours
to get ready.
Will you tell me on the boat?
Mom, you never take me with you.
Our lips remained sealed,
It's not true, you know that.
I took you to Washington,
took you to Seattle...
Yes, but I wanna go to Europe,
I wanna go to Italy with you.
You can't.
Why not? I can do all
the things dad does.
I can make your reservations for you,
I can negotiate your contract for you...
Come on, that's what your dad does.
Yes, but I can do it better.
What about your school?
Let me come.
- No.
- Yes.
Alright, alright.
Are you drinking?
Yes, I am.
You know what I saw on cable last night?
I saw a Chinese TV show.
This old China man comes out.
And underneath him are subtitles.
In Chinese.
What's my tennis racket doing out here?
I was trying to hit the ball
into the river.
- The river?
- Yeah.
- Wanna see me hit the city?
- I bet you a buck you can't do it.
Dad, why don't you stay here with me?
You and I can have so much fun together.
And mom doesn't need you. She can get
somebody else to do all her junk for her.
Come on, you and me can go to the ball
park. We can have so much fun.
It's a fine idea, Joe,
we must do it.
- You mean it?
- Absolutely.
Joe, take this down for me
and put it in the blue suitcase.
I get it.
Jesus Christ! He leaves his gum
all over the place.
Are you talking to me?
No, I'm just talking to myself.
- I'm gonna take the car down to the garage.
- OK.
I'll be back in a few moments.
Douglas!
No!
Please, stop crying.
Would you please stop crying?
I can't stand these people.
Were those ducks or geese?
I can't spend another night
in the house, Joe. I can't.
I'm gonna leave on the
first available flight.
What about me?
You come with me, darling.
We spend the night in the plane,
we eat, we sleep, we'll...
- Don't make decisions for me.
- We wake up, we'll be in Italy.
- Italy?
- I'll go to rehearsal, I'll sing...
Darling, you can put your things
in the black trunk,
the dark trunk... You can put your music
in with my music, your records...
- I've got school.
- ...you can put your clothes...
...and bring your... Well,
there are schools in Italy.
Joe, you can go to school in Italy...
Yeah, but I got a big game coming up.
It's important to me. They need me.
A game?
You're making it
so difficult for me, Joe.
Please, please, darling, please.
- Let's get out of here.
- Could you take us home, please?
Yes, ma'am.
Assholes, get out of the way!
I knew it, I knew it!
I knew he'd fall.
Hey, give me a puff now!
Where are you from?
The Yankees lost 14 to...
Hey, give me the joint,
it's my turn!
Thanks.
Will you please stop the car?
Driver, would you please stop the car?
I think you're being real shitty.
What a dumb ass rat bastard!
Here, you guys take it.
I don't want it.
Arianna, where are you going?
Julian, what are you doing?
- Bye, Julian.
- Good luck, bye.
- I'm coming with you.
- Where?
- With you.
- I got some things to do.
Well, if you want, I'll go away.
I got nothing against you,
I mean, I don't even know you.
My name is Arianna.
I'm Italian.
My name is Joe.
I'm American.
Actually I've got a girlfriend,
in New York.
That's nice.
Lot of fantastic palm trees.
Kinda reminds you of LA, doesn't it?
- Never been there.
- Neither have I.
What's she like?
- Who?
- Your girlfriend.
She's a pain in the neck.
Actually, she's not really
my girlfriend.
Then, why were you
telling me about her?
I don't know.
Two.
Go away!
Why do we have to lock ourselves up
in a movie theater?
I have to take a wicked piss.
How do you feel?
I've never felt so wonderful
in my whole life.
Me too.
That's the kind of answer
a man likes to hear.
My father talks like that.
My father's dead.
You wanna go sit down?
- Wait.
- What's the matter?
I can't.
Hey. Get out the fire hose!
Would you mind playing this?
When did she learn Italian?
- I have to tell you something.
- I already know.
No, you don't.
You don't know anything.
it's your first time.
Everything seems so perfect now.
Right where it belongs.
I wish you could be a part of me.
You'd understand.
I want to understand.
I wanna be inside you.
- How?
- Help me get my jeans off.
- Plain Cokes or did you spike 'em?
- No, just plain. Would you like one?
No, thanks.
Christ! You don't have to pull
them all the way off.
Now yours.
There isn't any other song.
You look better
than Marilyn Monroe.
- And now?
- Now we kiss.
Now be inside me.
Here?
Do you know how?
I've never done it.
You're excused, I'm a virgin too.
Why should the Falls drag me down
here at 5 o'clock in the morning?
To show me how big they are
and how small I am?
To remind me they can get along
without any help?
I must go.
Look, I took your jeans
Why haven't you had it taken out?
I was born with it,
I wanna die with it.
Julian, will you walk me home?
Then there came a thrill of joy...
...to my heart,
to my heart.
A thrill of joy such
as only the angels feel!
Earth seemed a heaven
to my heart,
to my enraptured eyes.
Did you remember to turn off
the lights before we left?
Fucking assholes!
Yes, earth seemed a heaven.
Oh, Leonora, you are awake.
I know it by the flickering
of your lamp...
...as it shines down
from your balcony.
Ah, love's fire burns...
...in every fiber.
I must see you,
you must hear me.
I come to you.
To us,
this is our loveliest moment!
Troubadour!
I tremble with rage!
Alone upon this earth.
Unlucky in war.
Nothing but a heart
is the hope of the Troubadour.
Nothing but a heart,
a heart for the Troubadour.
Oh, listen!
I tremble!
But if he possesses that heart...
beautiful in its pure faith...
I despair.
The jealousy.
- The jealousy.
- Then he is greater than any king,
Then he is greater...
...greater than any king.
I am not mistaken. She is coming.
- My soul!
- What shall I do?
You are late tonight.
The beating of my heart marked
the passing moments.
Then at last gracious love
brings you to my arms.
Faithless.
Faithless!
That voice!
Ah, in the darkness
I have made a terrible blunder!
I thought it was you
I spoke to, not him.
You, whom alone my soul
entreats and desires.
I love you, I swear it,
with a great and everlasting love!
- You dare?
- I can desire no more!
Your blood, o wretch,
is scarcely enough to quench it!
You dared to tell him,
"I love you!".
and he shall live no more.
He shall live no more,
he shall live no more.
Your blood, o wretch,
is scarcely enough to quench it!
You dared to tell him,
"I love you!". You said, "I love you!".
You said, "I love you!".
He shall live no more.
- He shall live no more.
- You said, "I love you!".
Your blood is scarcely enough
to quench it!
Bravo, bravo!
Come on, out everybody.
Let her rest.
Out everybody, I said!
Give her time to change.
Come on, out.
Caterina! Your voice is beautiful.
You've never sung so well.
I know. I held that D flat
for nine measures.
I don't understand your B flat.
- D!
- D, B.
The only thing I know.
Since Douglas died
you are singing much better.
No smoking.
It's not just my voice.
I'm stronger, Marina.
Shall I remove your wig?
I feel so old.
Don't be silly. You are stunning.
Everyone adores you.
I've always been a big hit with fags.
Iole, you're hurting me.
I was great tonight.
It's all Joe's fault...
If he'd stopped growing,
I wouldn't be so old.
Right. What about tomorrow?
- What's tomorrow?
- Joe's birthday.
No! Shit!
How could I forget?
Oh, Marina, I'm terrible,
I don't remember anything.
- How could you?
- I hate birthdays.
You know, I was nervous tonight.
I was scared.
It's the first time I've sung
here in years
and I knew that that audience.
They were...
They were out to get me.
They were watching
every single thing I did.
You were truly great.
Extraordinary.
Truly fantastic.
Unforgettable.
No, no, no kisses, Fiorella.
They're dangerous for her voice, honey.
I want a lot of people
at Joe's birthday.
I want him to feel important.
I want him to feel loved.
I only want a few people at my party.
- Joe, you scared the hell out of me.
- Where have you been, Joe?
You promised me that you'd be here.
I needed you.
I don't even know how I got
through the performance without you.
I heard a 10 minute applause.
Actually, it was a standing ovation.
Joe...
You are naughty.
Mom, lay off, you are getting
lipstick all over me.
I only wanna have a few friends
at my party,
you know, like Bobby, Arianna...
Yes, I understand, dear,
just people who really love you.
People who really love me
don't forget my birthday.
How long have you been here?
I'll get it.
- Hello.
- Edward!
- Marina.
Where is Caterina?
Edward!
- I'll be with you in a minute.
- OK.
- It's hot here, isn't it?
- I think you need a drink.
- Hot, mm?
- So take your coat off.
How was I, Edward?
The plane was 2 fucking hours late.
I'm terribly sorry, Caterina,
but I missed the performance.
Edward, another drink?
She's so beautiful!
- Did you take the D flat tonight?
- You blew it, Edward.
Caterina, you know I adore you.
People who adore me don't miss
my opening nights.
Right, Joe?
Girls, girls!
Come up here.
Come, we're having a party.
It's beautiful.
It's a birthday for my son!
Oh, Joe!
The most beautiful girls in the street.
They were there like angels.
What a coincidence.
They'll come up, they'll sing for you.
They're so beautiful!
Mom, don't shit me.
You know you arranged it.
Joe... When I was 15 I was like you.
I was miserable.
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you a little secret now
about my life.
You know what I did once?
I locked myself up in the bathroom
and I tried to kill myself.
Mom...
This music... makes me wanna cry.
Come on, mom... Mom!
Come here!
Girls, you are in the wrong place.
In the sixties...
...believed in things!
Oh, Joe, come on, dance!
I don't wanna, leave me alone.
- Why? Come on, dance.
- I hate it.
- It's your birthday!
- I hate dancing!
Dance!
Let's steal it away!
My parents thought they understood me,
but they didn't, of course.
I'm thirsty!
- God, I hate her! I could kill her.
- Come on...
She's such fun,
she's fantastic.
- What is this thing?
- It's an Italian Frisbee.
Look at Julian,
look at Julian dancing.
Is she pathetic!
She's just happy,
and you're ashamed of her.
Ashamed? What do you mean ashamed?
Come on, let's get out of here.
Where is Joe?
Once I had an old banjo,
the strings were made of twine.
And the only tune that I could play
was Trouble on my Mind.
Shady Grow, my little love.
Shady Grow, my chain.
Shady Grow, my little love,
I'm bound to go away.
Precious seems my Shady Grow,
standing in my door
with shoes and stocking in her hand
and her bare feet on the floor.
I like to hold your arm.
Your mother...
Your mother!
Happy birthday to you!
Would you please slow down?
How are you doing?
Concetta.
Close all doors.
Why do you do it?
Finally put up the curtains.
Good morning.
Am I disturbing you?
No, no.
Carry on, please, carry on.
Would you talk to me, Joe?
I hate that color...
Excuse me...
I hate that color.
I don't like it.
Pity, 'cause...
'cause it's beautiful.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, no...
I'm leaving...
I'm really leaving.
When did you start?
Yes, Concetta?
No, I'm not in for anybody.
Not even for Marina.
Could I have a light?
Who gave you that stuff?
That fat-ass little hippie
friend of yours?
- What are you doing?
- Ma'am, the piano.
Ah, yes, come right in.
Please, put it here.
It's so beautiful!
It's so black! I was expecting it.
So beautiful!
I get new pianos when I move,
and I feel so guilty, because
they're so terribly heavy...
Truly heavy, yes...
And so beautiful.
Please, a broom.
- Wow!
- Ah, yes...
It just exploded...
Like a bomb.
You want it?
And what would I do with it?
When I look at you
and your friends.
You scare me.
I feel like I'm on Mars.
I'm done.
Maybe it's because you're
all unhappy.
Or neurotic. I don't know.
I don't find it very touching.
I think it's awful.
The worst is you're just too young.
Maybe my mother felt the same way
about me and it's just the same thing.
Am I boring you?
I come from a world where...
where singing and dreaming
and creating, they mean something,
it's not just...
Oh, Jesus!
You know how long it's been since
you've told me one of your dreams?
You sing!
Joe, Joe, happy birthday.
Joey, Joey, 15 years old.
- Show me!
- No!
- Yes!
- Fuck off!
I wanna see that!
You bastard!
Come on, you wanna fight?
- Bastard!
- Fucking bitch!
Fucking bitch!
Fucking asshole!
Every holy day in church,
when I offered my prayers
to God,
a handsome and gallant
young man
would keep offering
himself to my gaze.
Our lips remained sealed,
but our eyes spoke
what our hearts meant.
Hidden by darkness,
yesterday he came to me:
"I'm a student
living in poverty..."
San Lorenzo's monster,
today I kill you,
tomorrow I'll be sorry.
San Lorenzo's monster, today I kill
you, tomorrow I'll be sorry.
- Who taught you? You look like a nurse.
- What?
Do you know what happened today?
Billy Martin's left the Yankees.
Retired.
God, he was great!
He brought the Yankees
two world championships,
one world series...
You know baseball? No,
you wouldn't know. You're Italian.
All you guys ever do
is play soccer.
He was the greatest manager
since Casey Stengel.
I don't know why he left.
I don't know.
Why he had to leave?
Come here!
Two beers, very cold.
I don't want a beer,
I want an ice-cream cone.
Ice-cream.
But you're American.
I was in New York long time ago.
Hey, I'm from New York
too, from Brooklyn!
I was a bartender there. I used
to make drinks, cocktails, you know?
Manhattan, Martini, chuc, chuc...
- Where did you find him?
- Out there.
- Now let's talk.
- What?
Tell me all about you.
So, don't you talk?
- I'm listening, you know?
- He's American.
Listen to the ground.
There is movement all around.
There is something goin' down
and I can feel it.
On the waves of the air,
There is dancin' out there.
If it's somethin' we can share,
we can steal it.
And that sweet city woman,
she moves through the light,
controlling my mind and my soul.
When you reach out for me
yeah, and the feelin' is bright.
Night fever.
We know how to do it.
We know how to show it.
Here I am.
Now let's dance old fashion,
like a man and a woman.
How do you say it in English?
Cheek to cheek.
I'm...
I'm looking for someone.
What?
I can't find them.
What the fuck is he saying?
What are you saying?
Come here, gorgeous!
Giuseppe!
Happy birthday, Joe.
I really miss dad.
You don't miss him, do you?
Mom.
I'm cold.
Joe, come on.
Come on, I'll put you to bed.
Right over here you'll have a good sleep.
Two steps. That's a boy.
That's a baby.
I don't remember buying you
those sexy underpants, Joe.
- I bought them.
- Where?
Somewhere around Piazza de Spagna.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Fuck, I can't pee.
I'll help you.
Do you remember when you were little
and you'd wait to pee
till you got a new bicycle?
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, God!
- How long will he sleep?
- 3 to 4 months.
No, sleep.
When he'll wake up,
he'll feel weak.
He will be very hungry.
Give him something to eat.
And talk to him.
Talk to him a lot.
I'll leave some milk for him
in case he wakes up.
He'll wake up in about 24 hours.
You know how to get out?
Don't worry, you owe me nothing, but
there's something you could do for me.
- What?
- I'd like to take a picture.
A picture?
Thanks.
Bye.
Yes?
- Hi!
- Sshhh! Joe's sleep.
- Sleep?
- He is sick.
Poor thing.
- Let me say hello to him.
- No!
What's wrong with you, Caterina?
Sit down.
What are you trying to do?
Put your legs here.
You are so goddamn American!
I can't!
Enough!
Why don't we go away someplace
for a week?
To Morocco.
Let's go alone.
Just the two of us.
What do you think?
You need a lover.
Cunt!
I don't wanna sing anymore.
What?
- I don't wanna sing anymore!
- No, Caterina, no...
Don't cry...
Don't cry, please.
I don't wanna sing anymore, Joe.
I have to talk to you later.
- Who are you?
- I'm Mustafa.
- Are you Joe's friend?
- Yes.
What do you want?
I was thinking to steal your car.
I wanna talk to you.
Not here...
At my house.
Take the stairs.
Lock well the door.
Please, sit down.
Beautiful, ah?
Be right back.
Prepare you mint tea,
Arab style.
The best you ever tried.
Look, forget....
Forget the Arab tea.
Do you sell the stuff
to my son?
Do you?
Sit down.
Why do you do this?
I must eat.
That's bullshit, you know?
It's really an excuse.
Why don't you get a job?
Get a job!
You don't get a job
because you hate to work.
You really believe I haven't
looked for work?
You're right. I hate to work
because there is no work.
You have something stronger
that I can put in the tea?
I'm sorry, my religion
doesn't allow alcohol.
You're religious, ah...
I see.
- Did you do that?
- Yes, he's walking, you see?
- Yeah, it's good.
- Do you know where he's going?
No. Where?
You know? You're his mother.
You didn't know him better than I.
I don't know.
He's coming here.
Does he come here often?
Yes... Even when
he doesn't need to buy.
He lays on the bed and talks and talks.
We're friends.
- What does he talk about?
- Everything. You.
He's different from the others.
- Different?
- He's very lonely. You know that.
- How much is that cost?
- 200 thousand liras a gram.
What? Are you kidding me?
That's... that's... absolutely awful.
It's poison!
It's more expensive than caviar,
diamonds or truffles.
I only get a small 10 per cent.
Where does Joe get that kind of money?
He steals it from you,
haven't you noticed?
- You like Joe, don't you?
- Very much.
- He's your friend.
- Yes.
I have... a thought, an idea.
A proposition to make you.
I'll give you money.
I'll give you lots of money.
I'll write you a check.
Only promise me that you'll tell...
...Joe that you don't have
any more of this.
Don't worry.
I'm closing the shop.
I saved some money
to buy a plane ticket.
I'm going back to my country.
You're happy?
Don't blush.
Don't talk to me that way.
I could be your mother.
My mother blush too.
Here, take it.
Wait... wait.
Take it. You'll need it.
No, I don't want it, no!
Take it.
Joe will need it.
Ah, they're beautiful.
Far from you,
there's no joy for me.
- Joe!
- Hi.
- Lipstick?
- No.
Good. I'm preparing you
a delicious dinner.
Ma!
Good, good...
It's a French style souffle.
- In candle light?
- Fancy.
Fancy!
You now have 19 minutes
and 45 seconds to get dressed.
- 19 minutes?
- And 45 seconds!
Come on, come on, come on...
You like your new watch?
Thank you.
Oh, my God!
Shit, the souffle.
God, this souffle looks awful.
It's genius, Joe!
It's... it's an inspiration.
It's a master piece.
I don't know how you did this.
I never could have done this.
It looks like an Italian Frisbee.
Maybe...
Ma, just 'cause you're my mother
doesn't mean you have to eat it.
Put a little salt on it, darling.
God, it's awful.
It sucks.
I fucked it up.
Let's have some champagne, Joe, OK?
God, I hate to open champagne bottles.
It's like an explosion,
like a missile going off.
Tell me when it's over.
To Joe.
You wanna know why I take dope?
'Cause I don't give a shit.
I see.
I just don't give a shit.
About what?
About me?
What are you talking about?
I don't give a shit about anything!
Why?
Why, Joe?
I've got nothing to lose.
That's because you've got a mother
who gives you everything.
No, no, ma, that's not it. If you
didn't give me the money I'd steal it.
I believe you.
I need two fixes a day.
I can't watch you
killing yourself.
If I don't have it, I get sick.
I get cramps, I sweat,
I chill all over...
Then I take a shot
and everything is beautiful.
It all goes away.
Shooting up makes me feel wonderful.
How can I help you?
Leave me alone.
Just go away!
I don't like you helping me.
Leave me alone.
Oh, God, I'm sick!
I don't have any more of the stuff.
You never could understand me.
Joe, come here.
I can help you, Joe.
I bought something for you.
What?
- Where did you get it?
- Mustafa.
Oh, God.
Thank you.
Here, hold this.
Careful, careful.
Thank you.
Take it easy.
No, back and forth,
back and forth. That's it.
Back and forth, come on.
Thank you.
Fucking shit, I don't have
any more goddamn needles!
I'm gonna die.
Damn it!
You forgot the needle!
Don't call the doctor, please.
God!
What have I done to you, Joe?
What have I done to you?
Don't leave me alone, please.
I'm sorry, Joe.
- Hi.
What are you doing here?
Sit down. I prepared you
a delicious breakfast.
She's gone out of town.
To Parma.
I know.
He won't recognize you.
Maestro!
I came a long way to see you.
I'm sorry I stopped writing you.
You don't know who I am, do you?
I spent so much time in this room...
I feel dizzy.
You were a tyrant.
I didn't believe in myself.
You taught me how to use my voice.
How to take care of it.
That it was beautiful.
All that mattered was my voice.
And you're vane,
you are!
You're very selfish.
Ahhh, you're looking for the spotlight.
The piano's been covered.
What's this?
Where's the piano?
Do you remember when you told me
one day I'd hate my voice?
I don't wanna sing anymore.
I have rehearsals for Ballo.
I don't wanna go.
I hate my voice. That's what I came here
to talk to you about.
I needed to talk to you about it.
I'm finished.
I don't wanna sing.
Can you hear me?
Hear me! Listen to me!
I've gotta talk to you.
May the wind be gentle.
May the wind be gentle,
may the waves be calm,
may all the elements
respond favorably to our wishes.
I used to sing this to my son
when he was a little boy.
- See you soon.
- Kiss. Hurry. Hurry.
I'm so glad to see you!
How did you find me, darling?
- Marina.
- Thank you for coming.
This is where he kissed me
the first time.
- Who?
- Your father.
- Where?
- Here...
- Here, where?
- Here.
I bet I can find it.
The house that we lived in.
It had these two enormous,
gigantic walnut trees.
We lived there for about... a year.
Then we moved to the sea, near Rome.
I think it's this way.
- Are we lost?
- Not at all.
Not at all.
What is it, do you see the house?
- No, I know where we are!
- Where?
That is the farm where
he used to get fresh bread.
Mom, I'm hungry.
I haven't eaten since last night.
I couldn't find our house,
but look where we are.
Joe, this is Verdi's house!
This is where he lived,
this is where he wrote everything!
All his operas.
He lived inside there.
He'd look out the window...
...and he'd see a little
old hunchback peasant.
Then Rigoletto is what he'd write.
Or he'd look out and he,
I don't know, he'd see
the Po river and it would be
the Nile to him...
He saw Egypt, he saw Venice,
he saw everything,
he saw the world in this little house.
- You'd like to come and see it?
- Not particularly.
Not particularly?
Joe!
This is my roots, Joe.
This is my family you're talking about.
How can you be like this?
He's like a father to me.
You don't care about anything!
You're a lost person.
A junkie.
That's all.
Are you fucking crazy?
Are you nuts?
What are you trying to do?
Kill me?
Would you relax, Joe? It's not
a major accident, it's a flat tire.
It'll take two minutes to fix.
Howling.
God!
- Mom, do you want me to help you?
- No.
Go listen to the jukebox box.
And stop staring over my shoulder!
It makes me nervous.
Some times, being your mother
can be a real pain in the ass.
Stop! Shit!
You just wait!
Stop!
- A problem?
- Yes.
Castro.
I wish I had a pair of his boots.
Now I'll tell you something
that will shock you as American.
- I... I'm communist.
- What do you mean?
You are American, I'm communist.
Stop the car! Stop.
No, stop!
- Stop!
- I offend you?
Be calm.
Go ahead.
Here I am.
See, this is culatello.
You don't understand my language,
but I tell you all the same.
- A bottle of Sauvignon.
- This ham... I'm coming.
This ham is done here only...
and has to be cured in the mist,
in the open air, and after 2 years...
- 6 year ago, in Cuba... Cuba...
- Yes! Cuba! Cuba!
- This is from last year.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
- Fidel... Castro.
- Yes, Fidel!
Same boat, 2 men.
Fidel and me. You get me?
Fishing, fishing.
I fished a fish this big.
Sure, and Fidel very little fish.
Very jealous.
I bet!
- Beautiful man, handsome.
- Strong.
Very, very jealous for my big fish.
Thank you.
Beautiful, black, sexy...
God, what an asshole.
Is that for us?
No... no... he's a punk.
He's a little punk.
You're strong too.
Look at those shoulders.
See those strong arms!
You've done a lot of sports?
- A little, before.
- What?
- But now...
- Not now?
- No?
- Now yes or no?
Excuse me, I'd like you
to try this wine.
A very little sandwich
for a very strong man.
Ah, thank you.
I'll show you a game.
It's Sauvignon,
Treviano and malvasia.
You're dirty.
Bravo! Very well,
you didn't break a single glass.
- This is pure malvasia.
- The bill.
Three thousand.
I'm sorry, but that's my son.
Do you have a room?
They dragged her in bonds
to her terrible fate.
Carrying my child,
I followed her in tears.
In vain the poor woman
tried to stop and bless me!
Shouting filthy oaths,
they stabbed her with their daggers...
...as they drove her to the flames,
the murderers!
I didn't want to touch him.
I wanted to be touching you.
You're right.
He was an asshole.
He was a jerk.
I'm scared too.
My baby! My baby!
Your back is so soft.
- Let's not fight anymore!
- Your face is a mess.
I'll clean it up.
- It's good.
- Hold still.
I love you, Joe!
- I love you, Joe!
- No, you don't.
You hate me. You never loved me.
You always hated me!
You're fucking crazy!
You're sick, you're sick!
You never loved me
and you'll never love me!
You hate me, you hate me, you hate me!
You're a fucking bitch!
You bitch!
If only we could have found our house...
It was so important to me.
I wanted you to see it.
I wanted you to know.
This is very hard for me to say, Joe.
I wanted to tell you.
I tried to tell you.
I didn't know how.
I thought that if we could see
the house that we lived in.
The house that we lived in
with your father.
Not with Douglas.
But with your real father.
Make a right.
We're here.
- What?
- We're here.
Go.
Go, go, go.
Continue, please.
That's it.
Now let's see, boys.
Let's see what you did.
Bigfoot, Bigfoot,
you stepped on my star.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Teacher, someone came.
Your shoes.
Your shoes...
Put them there. Look.
Put them there,
with the rest.
Come closer,
I didn't hear you.
You'll tell me later, right?
Let's see what this planetarium
looks like.
Let's see.
Listen, Bigfoot...
Fill that gap in front of you.
There, right in front of you.
Come right in.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Calm down.
Come, let's make room.
Mind your feet,
you'll ruin everything.
Yes, yes, you can
take it home.
It's the last day of class...
and when you're back
from the holidays
you'll find...
Why are you laughing, Luigi?
Come on, be nice.
When you're back from the holidays,
you'll find right up there
your sky, which I find very beautiful,
in memory of your work
and your imagination.
I don't want to bore you any longer.
Happy holidays for everyone.
A kiss...
Happy holidays. Bye.
- Happy holidays, Palmiro.
- Thanks, all the same to you.
He made this moon with 3 eyes,
2 noses and one mouth.
And he stole your shoes.
Why do you say he stole my shoes?
Maybe he made a mistake.
I brought your shoes back.
Wait, I'll go take yours.
I mean,
I'll go and get yours.
- Will you drink anything?
- No, thank you.
- Are you English?
- American.
Here they are.
Here.
Do you like my shoes better than...?
Do you want my shoes?
You used to speak English
a lot, didn't you?
Many years ago.
I know certain American songs.
You remember you had a son?
I'll play something for you.
Thank you.
He never forgot you.
He looked for you everywhere.
Didn't you wanna know where he was?
All he wanted to do was to find you.
It drove him crazy.
After a while he started shooting up.
Heroine.
You know?
We'd shoot up together,
then we'd look for you.
We looked for you, man!
You don't believe me?
Look!
Where is my son now?
He's dead.
He died right in the street.
Nobody came to help.
He OD'ed.
Overdosed.
Get out.
Get out, please.
- And Caterina, where is she?
- She's rehearsing at Caracalla.
Mom.
Love and dancing prosper
in these happy halls..<
...where life is only
an alluring dream<
An alluring dream.
Night of sweet moments,
of passion and song..
Of passion and song...
Why do you not stay your flight
above the waves of pleasure?
It's fine like this, thanks.
Renaldo, Francesco, Stefano,
what did we say?
They're killing each other here.
Let's remember what we'd said.
Excuse me, what are you doing here?
We're at work. Out!
Let's remember what we had said.
Renaldo, Oscar's song.
Keep calm.
At least you can
tell me how he's dressed.
You'd like to know
how he is dressed...
...when that's the very thing
he wants to hide.
Oscar knows but won't tell.
Marina!
Where's my mother?
You'd like to know
how she is dressed...
Where is she?
Guess.
Concealment is in vain, Amelia.
You are that angel!
I love you, yes, I love you and in tears
...I throw myself at your feet...
...while an avenging knife...
...lurks in hiding for you.
You will be a corpse tomorrow...
...if you stay here.
Save yourself,
go, leave me, flee...
Five minutes.
Five minutes, please!
Five minutes!
Will you please remain silent?
Please, turn down the volume.
Edward, you never get anywhere on time.
They wouldn't allow me to come in here.
Look what an incredible present I found.
It's a score of Ballo
autographed by Callas.
Isn't it incredible?
Caterina is beyond all that now.
I suppose this must be
a very tricky theater.
How's she been singing?
She's not singing.
She's speaking her role.
- That's very unusual for her.
- You don't understand anything.
Now you're in love
with your father?
You really screwed me up.
- I'm half Italian.
- You're American.
It says so on your birth certificate.
You were born in New York.
Your father was Douglas.
You know you'll go to jail
for forgery.
They'd never arrest me.
I'm crazy.
- I really am.
- You're kidding.
I'm teasing, darling,
I'm teasing.
Why did you break up?
He hated... me.
My, my voice.
He wanted... something different.
He was...
...selfish.
He was in love with his mother.
To your places!
- To your places!
- To your places, please!
Everyone in place!
I have to go.
Everyone to your places!
Break is over!
Please, to your places!
Yes, I understand, but tell me
what the finale's feeling is.
But, are you ready to sing or not?
Caterina...
Look, Caterina, you're a woman
who's deeply in love...
...and tries to fight this conspiracy
no matter what...
- Come, come on.
- But let me finish talking.
It's terrible.
To see me?
Is it true?
- But, what?
- Our son.
He's right there.
Joe, Mustafa's gone.
Once more,
farewell.
For the last time,
Farewell.
Take this farewell of mine too!
Help! Help!
Oh, heaven!
He has been slain!
- By whom?
- Where is the assassin?
Here!
Renaldo!
Death and infamy to the traitor!
Let the sword of vengeance
cut him down!
Death and infamy to the traitor!
No.
Let him go!
You, listen to me for a moment.
Mercy for everyone.
I am master here.
My pardon...
...absolves you all.
Merciful God, spare so great
and generous a heart for us.
He is a ray of Thy divine love,
merciful God,
on us poor souls on earth!
He is a ray of Thy divine love,
Farewell forever,
my children.
Farewell, beloved country.
Farewell,
my children, forever.
I am dying!
My children,
forever.
Farewell!
Night of horror!