[locusts buzzing]
- IN THE REAL WORLD,
I FEEL LOST.
THERE'S ONLY ONE PLACE
I FEEL OKAY.
IT'S A PLACE INSIDE ME...
WHERE I CAN HIDE
FROM EVERYTHING.
- [echoing]
WOODY.
WHY DID YOU LEAVE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- DOES DADDY LOVE US?
- YES.
YES.
VERY MUCH.
WOODY.
[Woody laughs]
- WOODY!
- [grunts]
[muttering]
- WHAT YOU GONNA DO?
I'M THE MAN.
I'MA KILL YOU!
YOU WANNA DIE, RIGHT?
HA HA.
OH, YOU WERE SCARED.
I KNEW IT.
I SAW IT IN YOUR EYES.
YOU WERE SCARED.
- WOODY.
VINCENT.
BREAKFAST IF Y'ALL WANT IT.
[TV in background]
- DANG, UNC.
YOU LOOK LIKE A MILLION DOLLARS.
- OH, YEAH?
THAT'S WHAT'S UP,
LITTLE HOPPER.
- SO, UH, YOU GONNA GIVE ME
A RIDE TO SCHOOL TODAY?
- YOU DO ALL YOUR HOMEWORK?
- YUP.
- ALL RIGHT, I GOT YOU.
- [whispering] THANK YOU.
- [whispering] YOU'RE WELCOME.
- THANKS, MOM.
- YOU'RE WELCOME.
LET'S SAY OUR GRACE.
DEAR GOD...
THANK YOU FOR THE FOOD
WE ARE ABOUT TO RECEIVE.
AND LORD,
I THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR BRINGING MY SON HOME
TO HIS FAMILY.
AMEN.
- AND ONE MORE THING, GOD.
PLEASE
BRING MY MOTHER HOME TOO.
- AMEN.
- GRANDMA, YOU THINK WE COULD
GO DOWN SOUTH THIS SUMMER?
- WELL, BABY, YOU KNOW
GRANDMA'S EYES GOT REAL BAD.
AND...I AIN'T SUPPOSED
TO BE DRIVING AT NIGHT.
- PLEASE?
EVERY SUMMER,
YOU SAY WE CAN DO IT.
BUT THEN WE NEVER GO.
PLEASE.
UNCLE V COULD DRIVE.
- BABY...
YOUR MOTHER LOVES YOU.
YOU HEAR ME?
SHE'S JUST DOWN
IN NORTH CAROLINA TRYING TO...
TRYING TO WORK SOME STUFF OUT.
- BET IF SHE SAW ME,
SHE'D WANNA COME BACK.
UNCLE V,
CAN YOU PASS THE HONEY?
- MA, I NEED YOU TO SIGN THESE.
- I DON'T REALLY UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
AND...WHO IS MICHAEL WOODS?
- THIS GIVES ME PERMISSION
SO I CAN GET A LOAN ON A HOUSE
SO I CAN GET
MY BUSINESS STARTED.
THAT'S ALL IT IS.
WHAT YOU ALWAYS TELL ME?
WELL, IF YOU DON'T WORK
YOU DON'T EAT.
- I KNOW WHAT I USED
TO ALWAYS TELL YOU.
BUT SPEAKING OF WORK, DID YOU
CALL MISS TINY ABOUT THAT JOB
DOWN AT UMBC?
- I AIN'T TRYING TO WORK
FOR NOBODY.
I'M GONNA BE MY OWN BOSS.
- I GET IT.
[emotional music]
♪
- THE BENZ IS STILL HOT,
HUH, MAN?
- YUP.
- ♪ SO LET ME LIVE
OR LET ME KNOW ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T SEE
OUT YOUR WINDOW ♪
♪ NOTHING CAN MESS UP
OUR FLOW ♪
♪ IF WE BUILD...
- IS THAT SUPPOSED
TO BE JESUS?
- YEAH.
- JESUS AIN'T BLACK.
- MINE IS.
LOOK LIKE YOU.
MAKE YOU FEEL ANY BETTER?
- SO WHAT'S UP
WITH YOUR REPORT CARD?
I SAW IT.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- I GET DISTRACTED EASY.
- DISTRACTED?
WHAT YOU DISTRACTED BY?
YOU DON'T PLAY NO SPORTS.
YOU DON'T LIKE GIRLS.
- I LIKE GIRLS!
- YOU LIKE GIRLS.
IT'S NOT WHETHER YOU LIKE GIRLS.
DO THEY LIKE YOU?
- YEAH, THEY LIKE ME.
I BE HOLLERIN' AT SHORTIES
ALL THE TIME.
- OH, YEAH?
WHAT YOU BE SAYING TO 'EM?
- HUH?
- WHAT YOU SAY--TO GET THE
SHORTIES YOU GOTTA DO SOMETHING.
WHAT YOU DO?
- I'M GOOD WITH COMPOSITION.
- COMPOSITION?
WHAT?
- I LIKE TO WRITE STORIES.
DRAW PICTURES.
LIKE A COMIC BOOK.
man outside: YO!
- WHAT UP, PIMP?
YOU DREW THAT?
- YEAH.
- ONLY THING,
YOU DREW MY GUNS TOO SMALL.
LOOK AT THIS.
OH!
[laughter]
YOU CAN PUNCH IT
HARDER THAN THAT.
UGH, UGH, UGH, UGH.
YOUR UNC GOT SOME GUNS ON HIM.
MAN, YOU TALENTED, BOY.
- THANKS.
- MAKE SURE YOU DO
YOUR HOMEWORK,
TAKE CARE OF YOUR BUSINESS
YOU GOTTA TAKE CARE OF.
YOU FEEL ME?
- YEAH, I DO MY HOMEWORK.
- SO I'LL BE BACK HERE
AT 3:30, ALL RIGHT?
- ALL RIGHT.
- WHO'S THAT?
- KENISHA BARTON.
FINEST GIRL IN MY SCHOOL.
- SHE CHECKING YOU OUT.
GO HOLLER AT HER, WOOD.
LOOK, SHE LOOKING AT YOU.
WHAT YOU HIDING FOR?
- UNCLE, PLEASE STOP.
YOU'RE EMBARRASSING ME.
- NO, I AIN'T EMBARRASSING YOU.
YOU'RE EMBARRASSING YOURSELF.
I AIN'T LEAVING
TILL YOU HOLLER AT HER.
[school bell ringing]
SHE LOOKING RIGHT AT YOU.
[car horn honking]
- WHERE YOU GOING?
I GOTTA GO TO SCHOOL.
- DID YOU OR DID YOU NOT SAY
"I BE HOLLERIN' AT SHORTIES
ALL THE TIME"?
SPEAK UP!
- YEAH.
- THEN YOU LIED TO ME.
YOU AIN'T GOTTA LIE
TO YOUR UNC.
YOU AIN'T GOTTA BE SCARED
OF NOTHING.
ESPECIALLY NOT NO GIRLS.
PAY ATTENTION TO ME.
YOU WITH ME TODAY.
- FOR REAL?
- I'M GONNA TEACH YOU
REAL WORLD SHIT.
- LIKE WHAT?
- WHAT IT TAKES TO BE A MAN.
HANDLE YOUR BUSINESS
ACROSS THE BOARD.
YOU CAN HANDLE THAT?
- YEAH.
- YOU CAN WATCH MY BACK.
- LIKE A BODYGUARD?
- SORTA.
BUT YOU JUST WATCH YOUR UNC.
- ALL RIGHT.
- FIRST THINGS FIRST,
WE GOTTA GET YOU FRESH.
COSMO!
- WE OPEN UP AT 9:00.
- IT'S VINCENT.
- VINCENT WHO?
-  VINCENTVINCENT, MAN.
- OH, VINCENT!
[laughing]
[buzzer]
- I'M TALKING ABOUT FRIDAY NIGHT
OR MONDAY MORNING.
- NAH, I NEED THIS TODAY.
WE ABOUT TO HANDLE
SOME BUSINESS.
- ALL RIGHT.
SON, WE ABOUT TO PUT YOU
IN SOME FINE THREADS.
YOU GONNA BE SUITED
AND BOOTED,
AND READY TO RIDE.
- SO HOW'D THAT FEEL?
- GOOD. JUST A LITTLE DIFFERENT,
THAT'S ALL.
- YOU LOOKING TIGHT
RIGHT NOW.
LIKE A LITTLE BUSINESSMAN.
- HA.
SO, UH...
HOW'D YOU GET OUTTA JAIL
SO EARLY?
GRANDMA SAID I'D BE IN COLLEGE
WHEN YOU GET BACK.
- NAH, MAN.
I GAVE MY TIME BACK.
MOTHERFUCKIN' JUDGE
GAVE ME 20 YEARS,
GAVE HIS ASS 12 BACK.
- SO HOW'D YOU GET UP
IN THERE ANYWAY?
MAN MAN SAY YOU SCARED
TO COME BACK AROUND
'CAUSE YOU GOT A LOTTA BEEFS
FROM BACK IN THE DAY.
HE SAY PEOPLE WANT YOU KILLED.
- NIGGAS ALWAYS TALKIN' SHIT.
DO I LOOK SCARED TO YOU?
- NO.
- ALL RIGHT THEN.
- WAS MY FATHER SCARED OF YOU?
- HE HAD NO REASON
TO BE SCARED OF ME.
- WHY YOU GOT TWO PHONES?
- MAN, YOU ASKIN'
A LOTTA QUESTIONS.
I GOT ONE FOR BUSINESS,
ONE FOR BROADS.
YOU CAN HOLD THIS ONE.
- THANKS!
- ALL RIGHT, SHORTY.
LOOK.
WHEN WE COME THROUGH, DON'T BE
LOOKING DOWN AT YOUR FEET.
'CAUSE THE WAY YOU WALK
LET PEOPLE KNOW EVERYTHING
THEY NEED TO KNOW ABOUT YOU.
WHEN YOU UNC COME THROUGH
I GET RESPECT.
man: WHAT UP, PIMP?
- HEY, HOMIE.
- HEY, HEY!
HEY, MY MAN!
- WHAT'S UP?
HOW YOU BEEN?
- ARE YOU GOOD?
- YEAH, YOU KNOW
I'M GOOD, YOU KNOW?
ARE YOU GOOD?
- WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
- AH, SOME OF THOSE SANDTOWN
NIGGAS BANKED ME, JACK.
YOU BELIEVE THAT SHIT?
- YEAH?
- YEAH, MAN.
JUMPED ON ME.
BUT I'MA GET THEM
MOTHERFUCKAS.
I KNOW JUST WHO THE FUCK
THEY IS,
AND I KNOW JUST WHERE THEY AT.
- YO, WOOD, THIS IS COFIELD.
- HEY, WHAT'S UP, SHORTY?
YOU WANT ONE OF THESE OYSTERS?
- GET YOUR LITTLE BALLS READY
FOR THEM YOUNG LADIES.
- HE DEFINITELY AIN'T READY
FOR THAT.
I GOTTA TEACH THIS MAN
SOMETHING.
WE GOTTA TEACH HIM.
WOOD.
WHO THAT?
- THAT'S KINK.
HE'S ONE OF ENOCH BOYKINS'
BOYS.
HE RUN WITH THAT CREW.
- THEY KNOW ME?
- THEY DON'T KNOW YOU.
THEY PEEPING YOU 'CAUSE YOU GOT
THAT TIGHT-ASS SUIT ON,
LOOKING LIKE YOU A DETECTIVE.
YOU JUST A NEW FACE,
THAT'S ALL.
- YEAH.
IF ANYBODY COME AROUND
ASKING ABOUT ME,
YOU DON'T KNOW NOTHING,
HEAR?
- MAN, THEY AIN'T YOUR PROBLEM.
NOW, FISH BEEN LOOKING
FOR YOUR ASS.
HE GOT LIL BABY
SHAKING PEOPLE UP.
SPECULATION IS...
THEY DON'T KNOW HOW YOU GOT OUT.
AND YOU KNOW HOW FISH GET DOWN
WHEN HE UNCOMFORTABLE.
- WHAT'D YOU SAY?
- I TOLD HIM I AIN'T SEE YOU.
I MEAN, BALTIMORE--
BALTIMORE GOING CRAZY RIGHT NOW.
LOOK.
THIS SHIT JUST STARTED 'CAUSE
LIL BABY BEEFING WITH ENOCH.
A COUPLE OF GUYS
OUTTA CHERRY HILL.
MAN, OVER THE WEEKEND,
EIGHT MURDERS--ALL ENOCH.
- YEAH, I AIN'T LOOKING
FOR THAT KINDA TROUBLE.
- TROUBLE'LL FIND YOU
IN YOUR SLEEP.
SHIT.
THIS AIN'T SO EASY
TO COME BY NO MORE.
THE RECORD CLEAN THOUGH.
NO PRIORS, GOOD CREDIT.
YOU'RE SET.
YOU KNOW.
NOW, WHETHER IT WORKS FOR YOU,
THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
- GOOD SHIT.
- ALL RIGHT.
- GOOD SHIT, MY MAN.
- I KNOW IT IS.
- [chuckles]
- BUT YOU KNOW.
BUT HIT ME.
HIT ME THE RIGHT WAY THOUGH.
- MAN, LOOK, I'M A LITTLE
LIGHT ON CASH.
- I DON'T KNOW WHY I KNEW
YOU WAS GONNA SAY THAT SHIT.
"I'M LIGHT ON CASH."
AND I KNOW YOU JUST COME HOME,
SO DON'T GIVE ME
THAT GODDAMN EXCUSE.
- YOU KNOW I'M ABOUT TO BE
ON MY FEET REAL SOON.
YOU FEEL ME?
- YOU'S ABOUT TO BE ON YOUR FEET
REAL SOON, MOTHERFUCKER, JACK.
- LOOK, THIS IS WHAT I'MA DO.
I GOT YOU THESE RAVEN TICKETS
RIGHT NOW.
MONDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL.
AGAINST THE STEELERS.
THIS YOU.
- OH, SHIT.
- THAT'S YOU.
UH-OH, GOOD SEATS TOO, BABY.
ALL RIGHT.
- I GOT YOU.
- ALL RIGHT.
WELL, FUCK THEM STEELERS.
I KNOW YOU GOT ME.
- HEY, WOOD.
LET'S GO.
- THAT MAN REALLY LIKE
THE RAVENS, HUH?
- YEAH, HE BLEED PURPLE.
YOU LIKE THE RAVENS?
- YEAH.
WHY YOU AIN'T TAKE ME
TO THE GAME?
- NAH, SEE THAT WAS BUSINESS.
SOMETIMES, YOU AIN'T GOT
ALL THE CASH.
YOU GOTTA THROW IN
SOMETHING THEY LOVE.
FAIR EXCHANGE
AIN'T NO ROBBERY.
[camera clicking]
- A MAN OVER THERE WATCHING US.
- LET HIM LOOK.
YOU GOT YOUR SHIRT TUCKED IN?
- YEP.
[blows raspberry]
- QUIT MAKING THAT NOISE
AND SIT UP.
HEY, MAN,
PUT YOUR FOOT DOWN.
- AH, MR. WOODS.
- HEY, MR. BARNES.
HOW YOU DOING, SIR?
- GOOD,
THANKS FOR DROPPING IN.
WHAT, NO SCHOOL
FOR YOU TODAY, YOUNG MAN?
- AH, TODAY IS OUR DAY.
I'M JUST TAKING HIM OUT
AND SHOW HOW BUSINESS OPERATES.
- AND YOU ARE HERE...
TO TRY AND GET A LOAN
FOR $150,000.
WHAT'S THE PROPERTY WORTH?
- $250,000.
- DO YOU HAVE THE EXECUTIVE
SUMMARY THAT I ASKED FOR?
- OH, YEAH.
MR. BARNES,
I BELIEVE THERE'S
TWO KINDS OF PEOPLE
IN THIS WORLD.
OWNERS AND RENTERS.
I WANNA OWN SOMETHING.
- AND WHY IS IT
THAT YOU WANNA OWN
THE MARYLAND CUP
FACTORY BUILDING?
I MEAN, THAT PLACE
IS BARELY STANDING.
- IT'S LOCATION.
LOCATION, MR. BARNES.
THERE'S NO PLACE
ALONG THE HARBOR
WHERE PEOPLE CAN GO
FOR BIG CRABS AND LIVE MUSIC.
WE'RE GONNA RESTORE THE FEELING
OF PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE
BACK IN THE '50s.
LIKE THE WAY OUR PARENTS
USED TO DO IT.
I GET THE BEST CRABS
FOR THE CHEAPEST PRICE.
- HOW SO?
- IT'S ALL IN THE PLAN.
- "ALL IN THE PLAN."
I DON'T KNOW, YOU REALLY THINK
WE NEED ANOTHER CRAB SHACK?
THERE'S GOTTA BE 100 OF 'EM
IN BALTIMORE ALONE, HUH?
- IT'S NOT ONLY CRABS.
I MEAN, WE'RE CREATING
AN EXPERIENCE
WHERE YOU GET TO CELEBRATE
LIFE'S GREATEST MOMENTS.
ANYTHING FROM WEDDINGS,
PROMS, CONCERTS.
WE COULD EVEN HAVE
BAR MITZVAHS THERE.
- WELL...
YOUR...CREDIT REPORT
SEEMS TO BE...
GOOD.
YOUR BUSINESS PLAN IS...
INTRIGUING.
- [chuckling]
- SO, MR. WOODS--
- CALL ME MIKE.
- MIKE...
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I'M JUST GONNA--
JUST GONNA TALK
TO THE BANK MANAGER.
- I THOUGHT
YOU WERE THE MANAGER.
- WE HAVE A LOT OF MANAGERS
AROUND HERE, EXCUSE ME.
- PUT YOUR FOOT DOWN, BUDDY.
WHEN DID YOU BECOME
SO HARD-HEADED?
PUT YOUR FOOT DOWN, MAN.
SIT UP STRAIGHT.
- WHY YOU
IN HERE LYING?
- I'M DOING WHAT I NEED TO DO
TO MAKE IT HAPPEN.
- ALL RIGHT.
- MR. WOODS.
WE GOT A PROBLEM HERE.
THERE'S SECOND MORTGAGE
ON THAT PROPERTY.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- MR. WOODS,
YOUR LOAN IS DELINQUENT
AND IN SERIOUS DEFAULT.
- WELL, HOW MUCH DO I OWE?
- IT'LL TAKE $22,000
TO BRING YOUR LOAN UP TO DATE.
- OR WE BEGIN FORECLOSURE
PROCEDURES ON MONDAY.
AM I TO UNDERSTAND
THAT THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
YOU'RE HEARING ABOUT THIS?
- YEAH, THIS IS THE FIRST TIME.
I DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
- SORRY.
- MR. BARNES.
HEY, MR. BARNES,
HOLD ON ONE SECOND.
WOODY, COME ON.
WHAT IF I CAN GET THIS MONEY
BY MONDAY?
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN
APPROVE THE LOAN?
- IF YOU CAN COME UP
WITH $22,000 BY MONDAY MORNING.
- YEAH, 22,000.
22,000 IN CASH.
- WELL, WE'D HAVE TO RESUBMIT
THE APPLICATION
AND DO ANOTHER APPRAISAL.
BUT...I DON'T SEE--
I DON'T SEE WHY WE COULDN'T.
- ALL RIGHT, MAN.
I'LL BE HERE FIRST THING MONDAY.
- [chuckling]
I LIKE YOUR STYLE.
- THANK YOU.
- YOURS TOO, YOUNG MAN.
- HAVE A NICE DAY.
- LET'S GO, UNCLE V.
COME ON, MOVE IT.
CHOP, CHOP!
LET'S GO!
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T PAY
FOR THOSE FLOWERS?
- FLOWERS FROM THE EARTH, MAN.
GOD OWN THESE.
[elevator chimes]
COME ON, WOOD.
HOW YOU DOING?
- HOW YOU DOING?
CAN I HELP YOU?
- YEAH, I WAS LOOKING
FOR BEVERLY FREEMAN.
- OH, BEV.
SHE'S AT LUNCH RIGHT NOW.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO HAVE A SEAT?
- YOU KNOW WHAT, I HAVE
TO HANDLE SOME BUSINESS,
SO MAYBE--
WHAT TIME DOES SHE GET OFF
TONIGHT?
- SHE USUALLY GETS OFF
AROUND 7:00.
- 7:00.
CAN I LEAVE THESE
FOR HER?
- SURE YOU CAN.
- THANKS.
ALL RIGHT.
CAN YOU MAKE SURE
SHE GETS THESE?
- I WILL MAKE SURE.
- THANKS FOR LOOKING OUT.
- HAVE A GOOD DAY.
- YOU TOO.
I LIKE YOUR SMILE.
- HA HA!
LOOK AT THIS UGLY MOTHERFUCKER.
[chuckling]
HEY, MAN, LOOK AT YOU.
ALL IN SHAPE AND SHIT.
- YEAH, MAN.
AH, YOU KNOW, I BEEN
GETTING IT IN--THAT YARD WORK.
- IS THAT
YOUR NEPHEW THERE, MAN?
- YEAH, I'M TEACHING HIM
THE WALK.
- YEAH, BABY.
- SO YOU HIT SOME TODAY OR WHAT?
WHAT YOU DO?
- SHIT, MAN, I'M BORED AS HELL
OUT HERE MOST OF THE TIME.
HEY, YOUNGBLOOD!
THEY CLAWS IS SHARP!
GO AND TAKE THOSE AND RUN 'EM
BY THE PORCH FOR ME, YOU HEAR?
FOR THE OLD MAN, OKAY?
YEAH, WE GOT A LITTLE MONEY
IN THIS LITTLE TRUCKIN' BUSINESS
DOWN ON THE EASTERN SHORE, MAN--
REAL NICE.
MY BOY, HANK, MAN, BRINGS
BY CRABS ALL THE TIME, MAN.
IN FACT, ME AND FISH GONNA PUT
SOMETHING TOGETHER TONIGHT, MAN.
IT'S GONNA BE SLAMMIN'.
YOU KNOW IT'S GONNA BE NICE.
- WHERE HE AT?
HE IN THE HOUSE?
- NAH.
NO, MAN.
YOU KNOW, LITTLE BROTHER'S
BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU, MAN.
HMM.
MAY HAVE BEEN BEEN BEST
IF YOU WOULDA CALLED
BEFORE YOU COME BY.
BUT HEY, THERE'S A WHOLE LOTTA
SENSELESS MURDERS
GOING ON AROUND HERE, MAN.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHO TO TRUST NOW.
WHAT YOU NEED TO DO...
IS GET ON DOWN TO THE GYM
AND TALK WITH HIM, OKAY?
- ALL RIGHT.
- ALL RIGHT?
[both laughing]
- YEAH, V.
- HEY,
WITH THIS BIG OL' TRUCK,
YOU NEED
TO KILL A DEER WITH THAT,
BECAUSE YOU AIN'T GONNA DO SHIT
WITH THAT RIFLE.
- HEY, GET ON OUTTA HERE!
[both laughing]
HEY, MAN, COME ON BACK
AROUND 8:00, MAN.
- OKAY.
AND BRING LITTLE BARACK
WITH YOU TOO.
LOOK AT HIM--
CLEAN AS TACK, BOY.
[chuckling]
LOOK AT YOU, BABY.
YEAH.
HEY.
[overlapping chatter]
- YOU GOTTA MOVE
FASTER THAN THAT.
FAST, FAST, FAST, FAST, FAST.
KEEP IT GOING, KEEP IT GOING,
KEEP IT GOING!
- GOT A GOOD TEAM HERE, COACH.
GOT A GOOD TEAM.
I LIKE IT.
- COME ON, COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON, COME ON, COME ON!
THAT'S IT, THAT'S IT,
THAT'S IT.
STEP IT UP.
- ALL RIGHT.
- WHAT'S UP, MAN?
- ALL RIGHT!
- CHECK OUT NUMBER THREE.
GOT THAT NBA BODY.
QUICK FIRST STEP.
EXPLOSIVE TO THE RACK.
- YEAH, HE DEFINITELY NICE
WITH THE ROCK.
- BUT HE'S GOT THAT JUMPER
YOU HAD.
- HE AIN'T GO THAT.
DON'T NOBODY GOT THAT.
HOW MUCH YOU INTO HIM FOR?
- 100 SO FAR.
- YOU GONNA BE THERE DRAFT DAY,
FRONT AND CENTER, HUH?
- JUST WANNA SEE THESE BOYS
MAKE IT.
I HAD MY SHOT.
THAT LESLIE'S BOY?
- YEAH, THAT'S WOOD.
- LOOK JUST LIKE HIS MOTHER.
'SUP, YOUNG FELLA?
FISH.
HEY, LOOK A MAN IN THE EYE
WHEN YOU SHAKE HIS HAND.
FIRMER GRIP ON THAT.
YOUR MOTHER
WAS A SPECIAL LADY.
- YOU KNOW MY MOTHER?
- HEY, I NEED YOU
TO CHECK THIS.
- ALL RIGHT,
GET BACK ON DEFENSE.
COME ON!
COME ON, NOW.
- IT'S A GOOD PLAN.
- BRANDON, YOU GOTTA MOVE
YOUR FEET, SON!
- COME ON, VJ.
PICK IT UP, MAN.
YOU GOTTA PLAY A BETTER DEFENSE
IF YOU WANNA WIN.
- MAN, BALL, YOU.
LET'S GO!
LOTTA MONEY WENT OUT
ON YOUR BEHALF.
YOU AIN'T EVEN
CALL MY LAWYER BACK.
WHERE YOU COMING FROM?
- I DID EIGHT YEARS FOR US.
I AIN'T SAID
NOTHING TO NOBODY.
I'M OPENING MY OWN SPOT.
I GOT A LEAD ON THIS--
ON THIS WAREHOUSE.
40,000 SQUARE FEET.
EAST SIDE OF CANTON HARBOR.
YOU KNOW,
I CAN GET IT DIRT CHEAP.
- HOW MUCH IS THIS
GONNA COST ME?
- 40 GRAND
TO GET IT STARTED.
- SO YOU NEED 25.
- [laughs]
YEAH, 25'LL DO.
- UH-HUH.
WELL, 25 GRAND
IS A LOTTA MONEY.
YOU RUN THE STREETS, V.
NOT RESTAURANTS.
- HEY, MAN,
WHEN I WAS LOCKED DOWN,
I USED MY TIME WISELY.
THESE NUMBERS DON'T LIE.
I JUST NEED THIS MONEY
BY MONDAY
OR THE DEAL GONNA FALL APART.
- MY MONEY'S LEAN NOW.
HOUSES AIN'T FLIPPIN'
LIKE THEY USED TO.
- COME ON, FISH.
YOU GOT 200 STACKS
IN THE SAFE RIGHT NOW.
- MAYBE EIGHT YEARS AGO.
AMERICA AIN'T A COUNTRY,
IT'S A COMPANY.
WE MOVE KNOCK-OFF
PRESCRIPTION DRUGS NOW.
LOWER PROFIT,
BUT IT BRINGS LESS ATTENTION.
PEOPLE AIN'T GOT
NO HEALTH CARE.
AIN'T GOT NO MEDICINE.
THEY'RE SUFFERING!
- MAN, YOU SOUND LIKE
YOU RUNNING FOR MAYOR.
- MAKE A PLAY FOR ME,
VINCENT.
HOLLA AT LIL BABY.
MAKING A DROP
IN CHERRY HILL TODAY.
YOU REMEMBER JAMISON?
- THAT CRAZY NIGERIAN DUDE--
I AIN'T MESSIN' WITH THE CAT.
- I'LL TEXT LIL BABY.
I'LL ARRANGE IT.
- LIL BABY, MAN, HE BRINGIN'
A LOTTA TROUBLE RIGHT NOW.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
HE DO CAUSE
A LOT OF UNWANTED PROBLEMS.
BUT HE'S FAMILY...
JUST LIKE YOU
HANDLE THIS FOR ME.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT YOU RESTAURANT
TONIGHT AT DINNER.
YOUNG WOOD.
COME AROUND THE HOUSE TONIGHT
AROUND 8:00 FOR SOME CRABS?
IS THAT COOL WITH YOU?
- ALL RIGHT.
- COME ON, WOOD.
WOOD, COME ON.
- AH, COME ON!
- YO...
DUDE HERE,
HE WAS MY LITTLE MAN.
HE USED TO SIT
RIGHT IN THAT SEAT.
HE A COWBOY.
HE'S STILL MY MAN.
WHAT UP, PIMP?
GO GET THAT SHIT.
- GO GET THAT SHIT?
WHERE THEY DO THAT AT?
YOU DON'T RUN SHIT
'ROUND HERE.
THIS AIN'T LIKE BACK
IN THE DAY.
- I'M AROUND HERE FOR FISH.
- NO, THAT'S DEAD, NIGGA.
YOU AROUND HERE FOR ME.
- MAN, GO AHEAD ON WITH THAT,
LIL BABY.
- [scoffs]
NIGGA CALL ME LIL BABY.
THEY DON'T CALL ME
LIL BABY NO MORE.
THEY CALL ME REG.
- THAT'S WHAT IT IS?
- HEY, LIL MAN.
YOU RIDIN' AROUND
WITH A CRUDDY MOTHERFUCKA.
- HOW SHERIE DOING?
HOW SHERIE DOING?
FUNNY THING ABOUT YOU,
I DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW THE FUCK
YOU GOT OUTTA JAIL.
- OH, YOU GONNA POINT
THAT GUN AT ME?
- OH, THIS?
HMM.
NAH, NIGGA, THAT AIN'T POINTIN'
A GUN AT YOU.
THIS POINTIN' A GUN AT YOU.
- GO GET THAT SHIT, REG.
TOOK CARE OF THAT, YO.
YOU'S A WILD MOTHERFUCKA.
4:00. PRESTON APARTMENTS.
CHERRY HILL.
MOTHERFUCKA
ASK ME ABOUT SHERIE.
LUCKY I DON'T BLOW
HIS MOTHERFUCKIN' HEAD OFF,
LOOKIN' LIKE THE FEDS
COMING UP IN HERE.
- WHAT DID I TELL YOU?
IF YOU SHOW WEAKNESS,
THEY GONNA GET AT YOU.
YOU CAN'T LET 'EM SEE FEAR.
EVER!
- ALL RIGHT.
- HAND ME THAT BOOK BAG.
YOU HUNGRY?
[radio chatter]
WHAT ABOUT WAYNE?
YOU LIKE WAYNE?
- YEAH, HE GOOD TOO.
- YOU EVER LISTEN TO SOME 'PAC?
- TUPAC?
- YEAH.
MY MAN RIGHT THERE.
TUPAC.
HE'S THE GREATEST.
THROW THAT AWAY FOR ME.
- THAT WAS PRETTY GOOD, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
[radio chatter]
SHIT, OPEN THAT.
HURRY UP.
PUT IT UNDER THE SEAT.
- DON'T FUCKIN' MOVE.
- YO, V, LET ME TALK TO YOU
FOR A MINUTE.
- HOW LONG Y'ALL BEEN
FOLLOWING ME?
- COME ON, NOW,
HOLLA AT ME REAL QUICK.
COME ON.
- SIT YOUR ASS
RIGHT FUCKIN' THERE.
- BOY, YOU SAT DOWN
FOR A MINUTE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU HOME.
- I'MA STAY HOME.
- HA, YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
'CAUSE THERE'S BEEN A WHOLE
LOTTA BODIES PILING UP
SINCE YOU BEEN BACK.
- MAN, THAT AIN'T MY PROBLEM.
- NAH, V,
IT'S EVERYBODY'S PROBLEM.
I JUST GOT A CALL YESTERDAY.
DOWN ON PENROSE AND PAYSON.
FIVE BODIES--
BULLETS IN THE HEAD,
NO SHOES ON THEIR FEET.
YOU DON'T WANT THAT TO HAPPEN
TO LITTLE MAN, DO YOU?
- WHAT YOU WANT?
- YOU DON'T ASK THE QUESTIONS.
WE ASK THE MOTHERFUCKIN'
QUESTIONS.
- LOOK, THERE'S A DRUG WAR
GOING ON IN BALTIMORE,
AND YOUR BOY LIL BABY'S
AT THE CENTER OF IT.
AND WE KNOW THAT.
WE JUST NEED SOME HELP
CONNECTING THE DOTS.
- I AIN'T GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH NONE OF THAT, MAN.
I'M ABOUT TO GET THIS RESTAURANT
BUSINESS JUMPING OFF.
- WHO IN BALTIMORE
GONNA GIVE YOU A PERMIT?
HOW THE FUCK YOU GONNA GET
A LIQUOR LICENSE?
- THEY GAVE YOUR ASS A BADGE.
- WE KNOW YOU KILLED PEOPLE,
VINCENT.
- LOOK, LOOK, LOOK.
HELP ME.
HELP ME OUT.
AND I'M GONNA HELP YOU
GET THEM DOORS OPEN.
I WANT YOU
TO GIVE ME A CALL...
IF YOU THINK OF ANYTHING.
- ALL RIGHT.
- BE SAFE, KID.
- HEY.
THAT DON'T CONCERN YOU.
- HOW DO YOU EXPECT ME TO LEARN
IF YOU DON'T TELL ME NOTHING?
- ALL RIGHT.
YOU SO CURIOUS,
GO AHEAD AND OPEN IT.
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE TRYING
TO BE ALL BUSINESSMAN AND STUFF.
- IT'S ALL IN THE PLAN.
I'MA TAKE CARE OF US.
ESPECIALLY YOUR MOTHER.
- HOW YOU KNOW WHAT'S BEST
FOR MY MOTHER?
- I JUST TALKED TO HER
LAST WEEK.
I TOLD HER I WAS GONNA
TAKE CARE OF YOU.
SAID I WAS GONNA TAKE YOU DOWN
THERE ONCE I GET THIS MONEY.
- FOR REAL?
- GOTTA TRUST ME, WOOD.
HOW MANY BAGS IN THERE?
- FOUR.
- GOOD.
GET IN THE DRIVER'S SEAT.
- WHAT?
- EVERY MAN NEED TO KNOW
HOW TO DRIVE.
ALL RIGHT.
PUT YOUR SEATBELT ON.
MOVE UP.
MOVE UP CLOSER TO THE WHEEL.
COME ON, MAN.
MOVE BACK, MAN.
YOU LOOK LIKE YOUR GRANDMA.
THERE, PUT TWO HANDS
RIGHT THERE.
NAH, PUT ONE HAND UP TOP.
- HERE?
- MOVE IT UP.
YEAH, RIGHT THERE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU SEEN YOUR UNC
DRIVING LIKE THAT?
YOU KNOW TO PUT
THE HAND UP THERE.
- YEAH.
- [chuckling]
CHECK THIS OUT.
THIS IS PARK, THIS IS REVERSE.
THE "N" IS NEUTRAL.
THAT'S DRIVE--LET'S GO.
[brakes screech]
WOOD, WHAT YOU DOING, MAN?
WOOD, MAN...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'LL WHUP YOUR LITTLE BUTT
YOU CRASH MY RIDE.
- I HAVE TO DO IT AGAIN,
I'M SORRY.
- SMOOTH, SMOOTH.
HOLD ON, HOLD ON,
HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
GO STRAIGHT, GO STRAIGHT.
TURN HERE.
GOOD.
BOY, YOU'RE KINDA NATURAL
WITH IT.
MAN.
YOU PRETTY GOOD.
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD, YO.
YOU WANNA BE A GOOD DRIVER,
YOU GOTTA PAY ATTENTION
TO THE ROAD.
YOU GOTTA STAY FOCUSED
AND BE AWARE.
YEAH, EVERYTHING'LL BE--
EVERYTHING'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
UM...I DEFINITELY WILL HAVE IT--
[horn honking]
I'M ON THE PHONE, MAN!
YO.
YEAH, YEAH.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
BUT THIS IS WHAT--
[horn honking]
THIS IS WHAT I'M GONNA DO.
[laying on horn]
I'M ON THE PHONE, MAN!
YEAH. NO, I DEFINITELY
SHOULD HAVE THINGS IN ORDER--
HEY, WOOD!
WHAT YOU DOING, MAN?
WOOD!
WHAT'S UP WITH Y'ALL SHORTIES
IN THESE SKINNY JEANS, MAN?
- THAT'S THE STYLE NOWADAYS.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU INTO?
- YEAH, BUT I'M NOT INTO
THAT TIGHT-TIGHT STUFF.
I JUST WEAR LIKE SEMI-TIGHT,
WHERE YOU CAN GET THE WRINKLES.
- YEAH, DON'T BE WEARING THEM
TOO TIGHT, MAN.
THEY MIGHT HURT YOUR BALLS.
- [laughs]
YOU CRAZY, UNC.
- KENISHA BARTON.
[both laugh]
YOU EVER SHOT A GUN BEFORE?
- NO.
BUT I USE MAN MAN'S BB GUN.
WE PRACTICE ON DEAD RATS.
- THIS AIN'T MAN MAN'S BB GUN.
SLIDE DOWN.
LOOK. THAT'S YOUR TRIGGER FINGER
RIGHT HERE.
ALL RIGHT, DON'T PUT IT
ON THE TRIGGER YET.
'CAUSE YOU LEARNING.
EXTEND THAT ARM.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YEAH. JUST A LITTLE HEAVY.
BUT I COULD--
I CAN HANDLE IT.
- EXTEND IT.
YEAH.
- LIKE THAT?
- YEAH.
NOW, EYE DOWN THE MIDDLE.
PULL THE TRIGGER.
[echoing voices]
- HEY, SOME LITTLE KID
OUT HERE.
SOME MAN WITH A SUIT.
- OPEN THE DOOR, SHORTY.
- OPEN THE DOOR UP!
[electronic music]
- WHAT'S UP, SHORTY?
NAME'S WOODY.
- AREN'T YOU A CUTIE?
- WHERE'S JAMISON?
WHAT UP, Y'ALL?
- YOUR ASS IS LATE.
- WE HAD TO HANDLE
SOME BUSINESS, MAN.
- NEWT...
COME HERE.
- WHAT ABOUT HIM?
- YOU KIDS GO IN THERE
AND PLAY WITH THAT XBOX.
YOU KEEP YOUR EYES ON HIM.
I DON'T WANT
NONE OF MY SHIT MISSING.
- YOU KNOW HOW TO PLAY?
- YEAH, I'M REAL GOOD.
- IT DON'T MATTER,
I'LL STILL WHIP YOUR ASS.
- MY NAME'S WOODY.
- MAN, AIN'T NOBODY ASK YOU
YOUR DAMN NAME.
PICK UP THE CONTROLLER.
THIS GONNA BE EASY.
- HEY, TURN THAT SHIT DOWN!
ANGEL.
ALMOND MILK.
AL-MOND MILK!
- WHATEVER.
- DON'T MAKE ME KNOCK
ON YOUR DOOR.
PLEASE SIT DOWN,
VINCENT.
[chuckling]
YOU'RE WELL-DRESSED
ON THE OUTSIDE, VINCENT.
BUT WHAT ABOUT THE INSIDE?
- HEY, CAN YOU
MAKE THIS SHIT QUICK, YO?
- [cackling]
I BET YOU STILL PUT
DEAD THINGS IN YOUR BODY.
ME?
[patting himself]
ONLY LIVING THINGS.
[chuckling]
AND MY SHIT--IT FLOATS.
YOU GUYS ARE CRAZY.
WHAT THE FUCK IS WRONG
WITH LIL BABY?
HOW MANY TIMES I TOLD HIM,
"YOU CAN'T COUNT MONEY
WITH GUNS IN YOUR HANDS."
- I AIN'T THINKING
ABOUT LIL BABY.
CAN YOU HURRY UP, YO?
- RELAX.
IT'S GOOD.
NOW WE WAIT TILL THIS SHIT
HITS MY BODY.
[phone chimes]
VINCENT.
HA!
[chuckling]
VINCENT, MY BROTHER.
[sighs]
[phone chimes]
YOU USED TO BE A GENERAL
IN FISH'S ARMY.
A GUY LIKE YOU IS NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE SOME FOOT SOLDIER.
- I GOT MY OWN PLANS, MAN.
I'M HERE DOING A FAVOR FOR FISH.
- [chuckling]
SHIT, NIGGA.
YOU GOT NO PLANS.
YOU ARE A WANDERING RAT
IN A MAZE
LOOKING FOR CHEESE.
[clicking teeth]
BUT THERE'S NO CHEESE.
I MEAN, WHEN HAVE YOU KNOWN
FISHSTICKS TO DO A FAVOR
FOR ANYBODY ELSE, HUH?
- [chuckles]
HEY, YO.
YOU SUCK, MAN.
HEY, YO,
YOU WANT SOME LEMONADE?
- HEY!
- YO! I'M TALKING TO YOU!
MAKE THE KID
SOME OF YOUR SUGAR WATER
AND SIT YOUR ASS DOWN.
YOU ARE STARTING
TO IRRITATE ME.
- THAT SHIT AIN'T
HIT YOU YET, YO?
- RELAX, MY BROTHER,
VINCENT.
AH. OH!
OH.
AHH, VINCENT.
THIS IS SOME GOOD SHIT, MAN.
AH.
THIS...
THAT IS SOME GOOD SHIT.
HEH.
THAT IS SOME GOOD SHIT,
VINCENT.
HA!
THAT IS SOME GOOD SHIT.
- LET ME GET THAT PAPER.
- OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
DID YOU THINK MAYBE
YOU ARE NOT SENT HERE
TO GET THE MONEY?
- GET THE GUN!
[gunshots]
[grunting]
- WOODY, GET THE GUN, MAN!
SHOOT HIM, WOOD!
SHOOT HIM!
[gun fires]
[muffled] WOODY!
WOODY, SNAP THE FUCK
OUT OF IT!
SNAP THE FUCK
OUT OF IT, WOODY.
HELP ME FIND THE MONEY!
HELP ME FIND IT, WOODY!
- [grunting]
[brakes screech]
FUCK THESE NIGGAS!
THIS NIGGA'S TRYING TO KILL ME.
FUCK.
MAN, NOW,
STOP ALL THAT CRYING.
- WHAT HAPPENED? WHY DIDN'T
THEY GIVE US THE MONEY?
- WASN'T NO MONEY.
IT WAS A FUCKING SETUP.
SHIT. FUCK.
- THEN WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
- WE?
IT AIN'T NO WE!
YOU LEFT ME OUT THERE!
YOU FROZE UP ON ME!
LIKE A LITTLE BITCH, MAN!
YOU ALMOST LEFT ME
TO GET KILLED!
- I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
- YOU DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO?
I TOLD YOU WHAT TO DO!
WHY DIDN'T YOU DO WHAT I SAID?
- I SHOULD BE WITH MOM,
NOT YOU.
- MAN, YOUR MAMA
DON'T CARE ABOUT YOU!
SHE DON'T CARE!
SHE AIN'T THINKIN' ABOUT YOU.
- I HATE YOU!
- MAN...
HEY, WHAT-WHAT--
YOU BETTER CALM DOWN.
YOU KNOW WHO YOU'RE
FUCKING WITH RIGHT NOW?
WOODY!
WHERE YOU GOING, BOY?
COME HERE!
WOODY!
WOODY, COME HERE!
WOODY.
COME HERE. COME HERE.
COME HERE.
- LET GO!
- COME HERE, COME HERE.
COME HERE.
COME HERE, MAN.
- GET OFF!
I'M TELLING THE COPS EVERYTHING!
- CALM DOWN.
- OW!
- HEY, HEY.
CALM DOWN, CALM DOWN.
- GET OFF ME!
- HEY, YOU WANNA SEE YOUR
MOTHER AGAIN, HMM?
CALM DOWN.
- LIL MAN.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YEAH.
WE GOOD.
WE WAS JUST PLAYING A GAME.
- YOU HAVEN'T BEEN HURT
IN ANY KINDA WAY, HAVE YOU?
- NAW, NOT AT ALL.
- TAKE THIS OUT OF MY STATION.
- YES, SIR.
- I'M REALLY TIRED,
I'M GOING HOME.
- WE AIN'T GOT NO HOME, MAN.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER--
SHE CAN'T TAKE CARE OF YOU.
I'M ALL YOU GOT.
- IF YOU'RE ALL I GOT,
WHY YOU HIT ME
AND PUT ME
THROUGH ALL THIS TODAY?
- I AIN'T GOT NOBODY EITHER.
PEOPLE I THOUGHT I TRUSTED, MAN,
I CAN'T TRUST--
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY--
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT THEY WERE DOING.
I DON'T KNOW.
TELLING YOU, I DON'T KNOW.
- THEN WHY'D YOU SAY THAT
ABOUT MY MOTHER?
- I LOVE YOUR MOTHER.
I LOVE YOU TOO, MAN.
WOOD, I LOVE YOU, BRO.
I'MA TAKE CARE OF YOU.
I JUST NEED THIS MONEY, MAN,
I NEED IT.
I NEED THIS MONEY.
I PROMISE I'LL TAKE YOU
TO NORTH CAROLINA.
- TONIGHT.
- THAT ONE'S GONE.
- YEAH.
BALTIMORE'S
A BEAUTIFUL CITY, MAN.
- YOU'RE NOT JUST SAYING THAT
'CAUSE YOU'RE FROM HERE, RIGHT?
- [chuckling]
NAW, I LOVE THIS PLACE, MAN.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
- UGH.
- SEE THAT BUILDING
RIGHT THERE?
- WHERE? RIGHT THERE?
- YEAH, THE WHITE ONE.
THAT'S MY GAME CHANGER.
THAT'S IT.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
WHEN I SEE MY MOTHER,
I'MA TAKE HER OUT TO FAIDLEY'S.
YEAH. I'M GONNA
GET HER EVERYTHING.
FATTEST CRABS
YOU COULD POSSIBLY THINK OF.
SHRIMP, CRAB CAKES.
- BET YOUR MOTHER'LL
LOVE THAT.
YOU KNOW, A LONG TIME AGO,
A BOAT SAILED THIS HARBOR...
WITH A YOUNG SLAVE.
HE WAS ABOUT YOUR AGE.
HE WAS SPECIAL, THOUGH,
'CAUSE HE TAUGHT HIMSELF
HOW TO READ AND WRITE.
HE TAUGHT OTHER SLAVES
HOW TO READ AND WRITE TOO.
YOU KNOW WHO I'M TALKING ABOUT?
- YEAH.
FREDERICK DOUGLASS.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW ABOUT HIM?
- WE LEARNED ABOUT HIM
IN SCHOOL.
HISTORY CLASS.
- OH, THAT'S TIGHT.
IT'S GOOD THEY TEACHING
Y'ALL THAT.
- YEAH.
SO ANYTIME
YOU START FEELING LIKE...
YOU CAN'T MAKE IT...
THINK ABOUT YOUR ANCESTORS.
THAT'S WHAT'S IN YOUR SPIRIT.
YOU HEAR?
- THINK MA
STILL LOOKS THE SAME?
- BET SHE LOOK BETTER.
- NO WORD ON
WHO PUT OUT THE HIT.
COULD BE FISH.
COULD'VE BEEN JAMISON HIMSELF.
UH...AND THEN THERE'S
LITTLE BABY.
- I KNOW HE GOT PROBLEMS
WITH ME.
BUT HE AIN'T GONNA TRY
TO GET ME KILLED
UNLESS FISH SAY SO.
THIS GODDAMN BAG--IT'S A NOOSE
AROUND MY NECK.
I GOTTA GET IT OFF.
SO WE IN BUSINESS?
- LOOK, I'MA TELL YOU.
YOU KNOW, IT'S HARD
GETTING THESE YOUNG BOYS
TO BUY FROM SOMEBODY
THEY AIN'T FAMILIAR WITH.
ENOCH IS YOUR ONLY CHANCE
OF GETTING ANY MONEY TONIGHT.
- MAN, I DON'T FUCK
WITH YO LIKE THAT.
HE PROBABLY KNOW WHO I AM.
SO I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY
YOU TRYING TO PUT ME IN THAT.
- WHAT'S YOU BEEFIN'
WITH ENOCH FOR, UNC?
- HIS LITTLE BROTHER, MAN,
HE WAS ALWAYS TRYING
TO DO TOO MUCH.
HE TRIED TO MOVE IN
ON SOME OF MY CORNERS.
THEN HE GOT KILLED.
AND ENOCH HEARD THAT I DID IT.
- OH, COME ON.
HE DON'T KNOW WHO YOU IS.
YOU KNOW, YOU AIN'T NEVER
CROSSED PATHS.
- MAN, WHAT TYPE OF GAMES
YOU TRYING TO PLAY WITH ME?
- NOW, HOLD,
HOLD RIGHT THERE NOW, HOLD.
NOW, I AIN'T TRYING
TO PLAY NO GAME.
NOW, I OWE ENOCH SOME MONEY.
HE TOLD ME IF HE CAN GET
THE SHIT ON DISCOUNT,
HE'D WIPE THE SLATE.
- SEE THAT'S THAT BULLSHIT
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
- AIN'T NO BULLSHIT.
YOU TAKING THIS SHIT ALL WRONG.
I MEAN, LISTEN.
ENOCH IS A BUSINESSMAN.
ALL HE CARE ABOUT
IS HIS SCRATCH, HIS MONEY.
HE AIN'T THINKING ABOUT YOU.
- I'LL SELL IT FOR YOU.
I KNOW WHAT'S UP.
- YOU KNOW ENOCH?
- NO, BUT WHAT I DO KNOW--
AIN'T NOBODY WALKING UP
ON THE CORNERS OF PARK HEIGHTS
WITHOUT HIS SAY-SO.
HE DON'T KNOW ME.
- SHIT.
BOY'S GOT A POINT.
IF HE CAN KEEP
THE FOCUS ON HIM...
THEN THERE'S A GOOD CHANCE Y'ALL
CAN WALK OUT OF THERE WITHOUT--
WITHOUT HIM NOTICING YOU.
- YO, YOU WANT THE MONEY
OR NOT?
- 40,000.
THEY GONNA TRY TO CUT YOU SHORT.
HOLD TIGHT...
FOR 40,000.
- HIT YOUR HEADLIGHTS.
- WHAT Y'ALL WANT
WITH ENOCH?
- WE GOT SOMETHING
FOR YOU TO COUNT.
- YEAH?
WHAT ABOUT MAIN MAN RIGHT HERE?
WHY YOU DOING ALL THE TALKING?
- NAH, HE'S JUST MY PROTECTION.
- HOW Y'ALL KNOW
COFIELD ANYWAY?
- WHO DON'T KNOW COFIELD?
HE BE LOOKING OUT
FOR ME AND MY FAM.
- WHY Y'ALL DRESSED
FOR YOUR FUNERAL?
MAKES ENOCH UNCOMFORTABLE.
- NAH, WE JUST HAD TO HANDLE
SOME BUSINESS EARLIER.
- WHO ENOCH TALKING TO THEN?
- TALKING TO ME.
I'M THE ONE LOOKING
TO MAKE THE DEAL.
- YOU LOOK FAMILIAR.
WHERE ENOCH KNOW YOU FROM?
- NAH, MAN,
I'M FROM P.G.
I BE IN AND OUT
OF BALTIMORE.
- THROW THE BAG OVER,
LITTLE MAN.
WHERE YOU GET THIS KINDA WEIGHT?
SHIT GOTS TO BE HOT.
- WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS
IF YOU WANT IT OR NOT.
- I NEED TO KNOW THE HISTORY
OF WHAT'S IN THE BAG...
AND WHAT TROUBLE IT MIGHT
BRING ENOCH.
- NOBODY COMING TO CLAIM THAT
SHIT, IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN.
- YOU CAN GET 20 FOR IT.
- COME ON, MAN.
YOU COULD GET MORE FOR IT
OUT HERE.
FAIR EXCHANGE
AIN'T NO ROBBERY.
- YO, I'M SURE I KNOW YOU.
YEAH.
YOU USED TO RUN
OFF OF PARK HEIGHTS.
- NO. NO, MAN.
IT'S YOUR WORLD.
- OH, IT'S MY WORLD.
WHAT ABOUT THE NAME
BUTTA BOYKINS?
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU TALKING ABOUT.
- YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
PAY ATTENTION.
THINK ON IT.
BLACK BENZ.
YOU KNOW IT.
- NAH, MAN.
- BELVEDERE.
- YO, WE JUST--
- THINK HARD.
LOOK, THINK HARDER, NIGGA.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE FUCK
I'M TALKING ABOUT, DON'T YOU?
- OH, YO, WE JUST HERE
TO GET THIS PAPER, YO.
- WHAT ABOUT A BLACK BENZ
THAT SPED UP ON BELVEDERE
AND SHOT MY BROTHER
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE MOTHERFUCKING STREET?
[Enoch's boys yelling]
HUH? YOU KILLED MY BROTHER?
[overlapping yelling]
- MAN, SHOOT THAT NIGGA, DOG!
- THINK I AIN'T SEE YOU PULL UP
IN THAT BLACK BENZ?
YOU KILLED MY BROTHER.
- NO, MAN.
- NOW YOU GONNA COME BACK
IN MY FACE...
HUH?
- NO, MAN.
I'M TELLING YOU
THAT AIN'T ME, MAN.
I BEEN TELLING YOU.
[groaning]
- YOU SHOULD'VE LEFT BALTIMORE,
VINCENT.
- HIS NAME IS MIKE WOODS!
- SHUT UP!
- HIS NAME IS MIKE--
- CHECK MY WALLET!
CHECK IT.
- DON'T FUCKIN' MOVE!
SHIT.
GET 'EM UP.
SOMEBODY KILLED MY BROTHER.
ON THE STRENGTH OF COFIELD,
YOU GET 25,000.
GIVE THE LITTLE MAN HIS MONEY.
YO.
NEXT TIME, A LOT SMOOTHER,
ALL RIGHT?
- ALL RIGHT.
[door alarm pinging]
- WHAT UP, SHORTY?
- DON'T.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WHAT YOU MEAN,
WHAT I'M DOING?
I'M HERE.
- HOW COULD YOU DO THIS TO ME?
- HOW YOU FEELING?
I MISSED YOU.
- WHY?
DON'T. PLEASE DON'T.
DON'T--DON'T DO THAT.
- YO, HOLD UP A SECOND.
YOU OKAY?
- YEAH, I'M FINE.
YEAH.
- COME ON, WE GOTTA GO.
WE GOT DINNER PLANS.
ALL RIGHT.
WATCH YOUR FEET.
WHAT UP, BOY?
YOU GOOD?
GOOD TO SEE YOU, MAN.
[fighting]
NO, NO!
STOP!
[crying]
STOP IT!
- YOU AIN'T ME, NIGGA!
- STOP IT!
[crying]
STOP IT!
- COME ON, UNCLE V!
COME ON!
- STOP! STOP!
[crying]
- WAIT.
HOLD IT, HOLD IT!
STOP THE CAR, WOOD.
COME ON, WOOD.
- YOU REALLY GONNA TAKE ME
TO NORTH CAROLINA?
WE CAN GO NOW.
CAN I TRUST YOU?
- I PROMISE.
- ALL RIGHT.
[doorbell]
- [speaking indistinctly]
[bag unzipping]
- I SMELL THAT OLD BAY.
[chuckling]
SCHOOL BAG--REAL SMART, BABY.
GO AHEAD.
- IT LOOKS LIKE Y'ALL HAVE
HAD YOURSELVES A DAY.
HA HA!
ARTHUR!
- YEAH, BABY.
- GET VINCENT HERE A BEER.
- SURE ENOUGH.
- PUT ONE IN THIS
LITTLE HOPPER'S HANDS TOO.
WELCOME HOME, MAN.
[Fish and Arthur
chuckling]
- YOU SURE ARE A BALTIMORE MAN
NOW, WOODY.
- HEY, MAN, GET THE REST OF 'EM
AND PUT 'EM IN, ALL RIGHT?
- MM-HMM.
- YOU ENJOY THAT BEER,
YOUNG MAN.
MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME.
V...
LET ME HOLLA AT YOU.
MAN, YOU MY OLDER BROTHER,
AND YOU STILL CAN'T CRACK A CRAB
WITHOUT MAKING ALL THAT MESS.
HERE.
YOU GOT TO COVER IT.
THEN YOU CAN JUST...
GO AFTER, GO AFTER, GO AFTER IT!
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
AND THE CRAB STAYS
RIGHT THERE IN FRONT OF YOU.
- I JUST DON'T HIT TO HIT.
YOU KNOW, BABY?
YOU KNOW THAT, BABY.
THAT'S OUR LIFE, BABY.
YEAH.
- WHERE YOU BEEN, BOY?
LET ME CHECK YOUR POCKETS.
YOU BEEN WALKING
AROUND MY HOUSE.
I'M JUST TEASING, MAN.
SIT DOWN.
- YOUNG BARACK.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
DOWN TO BUSINESS.
- YOU AIN'T NEVER CRACKED
NO CRAB?
- GRANDMA ALWAYS DO IT FOR ME.
- BOY, YOU FROM BALTIMORE
AND YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW TO CRACK NO CRAB?
- TAKE OFF THE LEGS FIRST.
YOU SEE SOME MEAT ON ONE OF 'EM
YOU GET IT OFF.
EAT THAT, HUH?
AND YOU CHECK TO SEE
IF IT'S MALE OR FEMALE.
THIS A MALE.
YOU SEE THAT?
- THE FEMALE, STAY AWAY FROM IT
IF YOU CAN,
'CAUSE SHE'S FULL OF SHIT.
- DON'T TELL THAT BOY THAT.
- YOU WANNA GET
THE DEAD MEN OUT.
YOU DON'T WANT NONE
OF THAT MUSTARD EITHER.
UNLESS YOU WANNA EAT
THAT SHIT.
SEE THAT? THAT'S MEAT.
NO, NO, NO, SHORTY.
YOU GOTTA CRACK YOUR OWN.
- HELL, YEAH.
YOU SEE THE SCARS
ON MY HANDS?
I BEEN COOKING LIVE CRABS
ALL MY LIFE.
YOU BEST BELIEVE
THEM LITTLE BITCHES KNOW
WHEN THE HOT WATER'S COMING.
- YOUNG WOODY,
HE'S LYING TO YOU.
TELL YOU HOW HE GOT THOSE SCARS,
IS HIS EX-WIFE CHASING HIM
DOWN SOUTH BALTIMORE WITH
A SWITCHBLADE AFTER HIS ASS.
- I'M TRYING TO TELL HIM
LIKE IT IS.
A BOY DESERVES THAT.
- WE ALL DO.
- REMEMBER WHEN VINCENT
WAS WOODY'S AGE?
- HMM.
- LITTLE PUNK LISTENED
TO ANYTHING I TELL HIM.
- YEAH, THAT TIME
YOU TOLD HIM
HE HAD TO EAT
THE WHOLE CRAB SHELL.
- HIS CRAZY ASS
TRIED TO EAT IT.
- YEAH.
THERE WAS A TIME YOUR WORD
MEANT EVERYTHING TO ME.
- YEAH, WELL...
I BEEN LOOKING OUT FOR YOU
SINCE YOU WAS HIS AGE.
- THAT REALLY WORKED OUT.
- COME ON, VINCENT,
LET IT GO.
- I TREATED YOU
LIKE YOU WERE ONE OF MY SONS.
- YOU WERE ALWAYS TALKING
THAT FAMILY SHIT.
YOU DON'T REALLY LOOK OUT
FOR NOBODY BUT YOU.
- HMM.
THIS PARANOIA'S EATING AT YOU
LIKE CANCER.
I AIN'T YOUR ENEMY, SON.
- WHO MY MOTHERFUCKIN' ENEMY?
'CAUSE JAMISON AIN'T HAD
NO MOTHERFUCKIN' MONEY.
SO WHO MY ENEMY?
- I'D HAVE KILLED YOU
A LONG TIME AGO...
IF I REALLY WANTED TO.
- HEY, COME ON.
IT'S NOT SUPPOSED TO GO DOWN
LIKE THAT NOW, OKAY?
- WOOD, GET OUTTA HERE.
- YOU DON'T THINK I REMEMBER
ALL THOSE SIDE DEALS
YOU TRIED TO DO?
- I AIN'T NEVER STOLE
FROM YOU, MAN.
I AIN'T NO THIEF.
- FOR YEARS,
I LOOKED THE OTHER WAY.
YOU THINK I'M STUPID, V?
YOU DON'T THINK I KNOW
WHAT'S GOING DOWN...
ON MY STREETS?
- NIGGA, THOSE STREETS
WOULD'VE ATE YOUR OLD ASS UP
IF I WASN'T OUT THERE
FOR YOU.
THEM STREETS WOULDA
ATE YOUR ASS ALIVE!
I PUT THAT WORK IN.
I DID THAT SHIT, MAN.
AND YOU KNOW IT.
I DID IT.
SO YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE ME
OUT HERE HANGING--YOUR SON?
YOUR SON.
FAMILY.
ALL THAT BULLSHIT YOU BE
TALKING TO EVERYBODY.
THAT SHIT AIN'T WORKING, YO.
THEM DAYS IS OVER.
- YEAH, YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
I TAUGHT YOU EVERYTHING
I KNOW.
- WHAT YOU TEACH ME?
WHERE THAT SHIT GET ME?
- IF YOU HAD JUST
FOLLOWED INSTRUCTIONS,
YOUR ASS WOULDA STAYED
OUTTA JAIL.
- YOU LEFT ME HANGING!
SELFISH-ASS MOTHERFUCKER.
- VINCENT, VINCENT.
PUT THE GUN DOWN.
YOU AIN'T GONNA SHOOT
NOBODY, NOW.
- I'M TIRED OF YOUR SHIT, MAN.
- VINCENT.
HEY, HERE--
[thud]
UHH!
- YOU KNOW WHAT YOUR PROBLEM IS,
VINCENT?
YOU BELIEVE
YOUR OWN BULLSHIT.
YOU'RE THE SAME PERSON THAT GOT
YOUR OWN SISTER ON DRUGS.
- SHUT UP, MAN!
- YOUR OWN SISTER.
- I TRIED TO HELP HER KICK
THAT SHIT.
- STOP LYING TO THAT BOY.
- WHAT DID YOU DO TO MY MOM?
WHAT DID YOU DO TO MY MOM?
- WOOD, PUT THE GUN DOWN.
- TELL ME WHAT YOU DID TO MOM.
- PUT DOWN THE GUN, WOOD!
- TELL ME!
- WOOD, PUT THE GUN DOWN!
- WHAT'D YOU DO?
- PUT DOWN THE GUN, WOOD!
- TELL ME!
- WOODY!
- MAKE HIM TELL YOU, WOOD!
- WHAT YOU DOING?
GUN DOWN!
- TELL ME WHAT YOU DID
TO MY MOM?
- YO, WOOD!
PUT IT--
[gunshot]
- [panting]
[dog barking in distance]
- [coughing]
[panting]
WOODY.
WOO--
[coughing]
- UNCLE V, COME ON.
DON'T DIE ON ME.
[crying]
COME ON.
NO.
UNCLE V!
- [hyperventilating]
WOODY, WOODY.
GO IN MY POCKET.
I TRIED.
- WHAT DOES THIS MEAN?
- I TRIED. I TRIED.
- WHAT, UNCLE V?
UNCLE V!
WHAT?
[crying]
UNCLE V!
HELP!
HELP ME!
HELP...
- [chuckling]
- THAT SHIT'S NOT FUNNY.
- CAN I GO HOME NOW?
- YOU WERE INVOLVED IN
A TRIPLE HOMICIDE TONIGHT, KID.
THIS AIN'T DETENTION.
THIS A POLICE STATION.
- LOOK, WE CAN'T CHARGE YOU
WITH ANYTHING.
NOT YET.
NOW, TOMORROW, I WANT YOU
TO COME DOWN HERE
AND ANSWER
SOME MORE QUESTIONS.
UNDERSTOOD?
- ALL RIGHT.
NOW, GET YOUR BOOK BAG
AND WE'LL TAKE YOU HOME
TO YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S.
- WHAT ABOUT THAT?
- DON'T YOU WORRY ABOUT THIS.
- HEY, KID,
FORGOT SOMETHING.
- [yawns]
- I LIKE THAT PICTURE
YOU DREW.
- THOSE YOUR DAUGHTERS?
- YEAH, MY ANGELS.
ABOUT A FEW YEARS YOUNGER
THAN YOU.
TELL YOU, EVERY NIGHT
I GO HOME...
WATCH 'EM IN THEIR BED,
SLEEP.
ONLY GOD KEEP 'EM SAFE.
- CAN'T PROTECT 'EM
FROM BAD PEOPLE.
- [sighs]
YEAH, I KNOW.
I CAN'T HELP TRYING THOUGH.
YOU FEEL ME?
GOT YOUR WHOLE LIFE
AHEAD OF YOU.
YOU'RE YOUNG.
YOU CAN STILL DO SOMETHING
WITH YOUR LIFE.
COME ON, I GOTTA TALK
TO YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
- I THINK IT'S BEST
THAT I TELL HER.
PLEASE?
- ALL RIGHT.
I'LL BE BACK IN THE MORNING,
10:00 A.M.,
TO PICK BOTH Y'ALL UP.
- ALL RIGHT.
- MY UNCLE USED TO SAY
THERE'S TWO TYPES OF PEOPLE
IN THIS WORLD--
OWNERS AND RENTERS.
BUT THE QUESTION IS...
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA OWN?
DO YOU THINK
I'LL EVER FIND YOU?
[crying]
- ♪ SO LET ME LIVE
OF LET ME KNOW ♪
♪
♪ YOU CAN'T SEE
OUT YOUR WINDOW ♪
♪
♪ NOTHING CAN MESS UP
OUR FLOW ♪
♪
♪ IF WE BUILD THEM,
AYE, FROM LOVE ♪
♪
- ♪ WHERE YOU GOING
♪ YOU KNOW THAT
YOU'RE ALREADY HERE ♪
♪
♪ WHERE YOU GOING
♪ YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE
ALREADY HERE ♪
♪
- ♪ I WOKE UP
IN THAT CHILDHOOD DREAM ♪
♪
♪ BUT I VAGUELY
REMEMBER SCENES ♪
♪
♪ NOTHING ELSE MATTERED
TO ME ♪
♪
♪ NO, NOTHING REALLY
MATTERS AT ALL ♪
♪
- ♪ WHERE YOU GOING
♪ YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE
ALREADY HERE ♪
♪
♪ WHERE YOU GOING
♪ YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE
ALREADY HERE ♪