Subtitles by DramaFever
When Soo Jin
was abandoned alone at the tree
in front of the orphanage...
she was...
never able to forget...
how she was back then.
And as she grew up,
she remained that child.
I never knew that having
to leave Hye Na behind...
I had to do what
I dreaded doing most...
to my own child,
with my own hands...
and that was so...
so, so painful.
A woman only truly
becomes a mother...
when she offers her all...
to another tiny creature.
If I were to turn back time
and go back to that moment...
I would probably take
that child's hand...
and run away again.
The only thing that Hye Na's biological
mother did, was give birth to her.
But she's not a mom.
My Soo Jin...
is her real mother.
Defendant Kang Soo Jin.
I sentence you to
36 months of probation.
Furthermore, during your probation
as a protective measure
you are hereby forbidden from
interacting with Ms. Kim Hye Na.
[Episode 15]
Why did you discharge yourself
from the hospital?
Does this mean that you've
given up on living?
You're saying that you won't use
the breathing machine
and are refusing CPR
and chemotherapy?
How could yo do this to us, Mom?
Yi Jin.
Your mom has the right
to do that if she wishes.
She's struggled all her life
for your sake.
They said that her receiving
treatment now...
will do nothing more than
prolong her life a bit more.
So?
Are you two saying that
you're giving up on Mom?
I can't do that.
I'm going to save Mom!
I'm going to use any means necessary
changing her diet
or whatever, to save her!
- Big Sis.
- Yi Jin.
I've decided that this will be
the place where I will die.
I don't want to die in an ICU
that feels like a storage closet.
I hate the look in the eyes of the people
who work at the hospital.
There's not a single honest person there.
Their concerned faces remind me of
the faces of department store workers.
I just want to die in my own house
while I can still think clearly.
Can't I do that, my daughter?
"Everything is as it was before."
"The hands on the clock,
which moved with a tick tock sound"
"were also the same as before."
"But when the children stepped
over the threshold"
"they realized that they
had become adults."
Soo Jin.
When I die...
go to your mother.
And change your family registry,
so you're registered as her child.
And if I were you,
I'd also change my name.
To Nam Soo Jin.
What are you saying?
I told you, right?
I promised you
that I'd let you go
if your mom showed up.
I know that...
you were never truly my daughter.
I thought that you would be
if I just loved you more and more.
But I was thinking only of myself.
Go.
Go, and...
act as if none of this ever happened.
As if you were never abandoned...
or abandoned anyone.
Live your life like that.
I am Kang Soo Jin.
That's who I've always been,
and that is who I will continue to be.
I have never not been
your daughter, Mom.
You know as well as I do...
that I just failed to mature
and grow up for too long.
Please don't kick me out, Mom.
Give me a chance.
I know that you're only saying this...
because you feel bad for me
since I'm dying.
But it's still nice to hear.
Today, I'll tell you about Tae Hwa,
a boy at the facility I live at.
Tae Hwa is six years old.
He can't talk to strangers.
His big sister died three months ago,
and was buried in the hills.
One day, Tae Hwa was kicked out of his
home while only dressed in underwear
so he was sitting in front of
a kimbap store, crying.
And the lady there
came out and asked him
"Child, why are you crying?"
"Are you hungry?"
"I want to eat fried pork chops.
I want to eat kimbap."
"I want to eat spicy rice cakes."
That's what Tae Hwa wanted to say.
But apparently, he couldn't
say that, and he just cried.
But thankfully, that woman
gave him some fried pork chops
and some kimbap,
and some spicy rice cakes, too.
And she reported this to the police,
so he was allowed to come here.
[I want to eat fried pork chops.
I want to eat kimbap.]
[I want to eat spicy...]
Tae Hwa is going to be
adopted soon.
So he has been practicing talking a lot.
Because it'll be bad if he can't
talk to his new mom and dad.
I won't get adopted.
I definitely won't let that happen.
And if it does, I won't say
a single word until the day I die.
Here, take this.
It's the money I saved,
plus my New Year's money.
Make sure you succeed, okay?
Thanks.
I'll do my best.
Take care.
- All right.
- Come here.
Take care, now.
- Bye, now!
- Goodbye.
[Train ticket from Mooryung to Seoul]
29,000 won.
Mom wants to talk to you, Big Sis.
I'll take care of that.
Okay.
All right.
This is Jinsu-dong,
where we live, right?
- Yes!
Teacher.
Yes, Hye Na?
I want a map.
Really?
I'll have to get you one, then.
- Me, too!
Hey.
Hyun Jin reads "King Lear"
as if she's reading the news.
It's the scene where
the old king is dying.
[Top Secret: Do Not Open]
"Now, our joy,
although the last, not least..."
"what can you say to draw
a third more opulent than your sisters?"
"Speak."
[Top Secret: Do Not Open]
[Baek Yi Yeon]
[Certificate of Adoption]
[Child Name: Baek Yi Yeon]
[Birth Parent's Name: N/A]
[Adoptive Parent Name: Kang Young Shin]
"Better thou hadst not been born"
"than not to have pleased me better."
"Is it but this..."
"a tardiness in nature"
"which often leaves the history unspoke"
"that it intends to do?"
Soo Jin!
The baby is here!
This is your older sister, Baby.
This is Soo Jin, your big sister.
Hi, Baby!
This is our home now.
You, me, and Mom are going to
live here together.
Come and eat, Big Sis!
"The jewels of our father"
"with wash'd eyes Cordelia leaves you."
"I know you what you are."
Big Sis!
Come eat lunch.
Yi Jin.
I'll let her go after
she finishes Act 1.
I'll be done soon.
"And like a sister am
most loath to call..."
Hyun Jin!
What is she doing
in her room?
- Happy birthday to you!
What did you wish for?
That the baby could
be our baby.
What do you mean by that?
Yi Jin is already our baby.
I don't want Yi Jin
to be adopted like me
I want her to be your real daughter, Mom.
If the baby finds out later...
that her real mother
abandoned her...
what will we do then?
Are you worried that she'll have
a difficult time later, like you did?
All right.
Let's say that Yi Jin is a child
I gave birth to myself.
Nobody will know
unless we say something.
You can keep this a secret, right?
What is this?
Where... did you get this?
Who is that?
That's... not me.
[Baek Yi Yeon]
[Certificate of Adoption]
Big Sis.
Was this fun for you two...
all this time?
How could you toy with a person
like this for their entire life?
Yi Jin.
It wasn't like that.
I was the one who asked Mom to do it.
Because I didn't want you
to end up like me.
After I was on that TV program with Mom
everyone pitied me,
no matter where I went.
I didn't want you to end up like that.
I wanted to protect you
more than anyone else.
But you knew that...
the one thing I was proud of
was that I was Mom's biological daughter.
How did you feel...
as you watched me,
living like that?
What were you planning to do
if I ever found out?
I was being inconsiderate.
I think that I thought
I could protect you forever.
But that's not protecting me, Big Sis!
That's ruining me!
All of you, get out.
I need to talk to Yi Jin.
No, stay in here.
All of you.
Just say it in front of everyone.
And don't say that I'm
your real daughter if you raised me.
Tell me the truth.
I don't want to be played
like a fool any longer.
From the moment that I first saw you
I thought of you as my baby.
And that's why the adoption process
was so difficult for me.
And I had to wait
for a very long time.
Do I not have the right
to be your real mother
for the sole reason that
I didn't give birth to you?
Even though you were my first baby?
Even though I raised you with my own
hands, from the very beginning?
Even though I'd completely forgotten
that I didn't give birth to you?
Yi Jin.
Please, hold Mom's hand.
Let's hold hands and talk
like before, okay?
Come now, my good daughter.
Mom.
I got a map.
And I figured out the way.
I packed my bag...
and I just need a bit more money.
29,000 minus 14,000 won is...
I think I only need about
20,000 won more.
How do I get that?
I think the baby is happy
because you're feeding her.
Do you like your Big Sis, Yi Jin?
Oh, you're so happy!
Soo Jin, come over here.
Ring, ring, get out of the way.
I want her to be
your real baby, Mom.
If the baby finds out later
that her real mother abandoned her...
what will we do then?
I asked Mom to do it.
Because I didn't want you
to end up like me.
I didn't want you to end up like that.
I wanted to protect you
more than anyone else.
Yi Jin.
I'm going to make
soybean paste soup and grill some fish.
Okay.
I'm still angry.
I'm angry at Mom...
and I'm angry at you too, Big Sis.
And I'm angry at myself, most of all.
I'm sorry.
So when I make food and call you down,
come and eat immediately.
So you can eat it while it's still hot.
You know that I seldom apologize, right?
Yes.
But, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry that I hurt you.
As I was growing up...
I was always worried that I fell short...
as your daughter, Mom.
That's why...
I think I was wishing that...
I was a daughter you'd given birth to.
All the moments in which I was so proud
of you while you were growing up
so much so that I felt as if
my heart would burst...
I remember all of them.
The first day that
you called me "Mom."
The sight of you, as you
competed in a piano competition
without being nervous at all.
I was so nervous that day
that I took two anxiety pills.
And the twins.
The day you insisted that
you'd have a natural birth
after keeping them in your womb
for as long as you could.
Remembering that makes me
tear up more than anything else.
Hug me please, Yi Jin.
This is a secret
from Big Sis, but...
Soo Jin has never made me
that happy before.
If I didn't have you...
how would I have gotten by
all these years?
Also...
you're the one who takes
after me most in our family.
I'm sorry, Mom.
You're the person who's in
the most pain right now, and yet...
Oh yeah.
Hurry and eat this.
It'll only taste good if you eat it
while it's still hot.
Did you refrain from
putting any salt in it today, too?
I used all natural ingredients
and natural seasonings
so it doesn't need any salt.
It tastes good.
All right, slowly!
Good job!
Be careful!
Enjoy the movie!
Hey!
Hey, wait!
I'm not going to do it!
- He's so funny!
- Wow!
I would like to formally greet you.
Well, um, it's nice to meet you.
- Mom, why do we need to see him?
- Son, he will...
Won't you take a seat?
I'm comfortable standing.
You should really sit down.
Take a seat.
I'm not, either...
am I?
Your biological daughter, I mean.
You knew?
I only thought that
that might be the case.
I see.
But you know
that wasn't important to me at all.
Because the three of us...
received tons of love
from you while growing up.
You're not curious about
your birth parents?
No.
You must be scared.
I...
was always happy...
being your daughter...
and being my older sisters'
youngest sister.
If...
I can just continue living
this way, I don't--
Jae Beom...
was always by our side,
as you know.
He was so good to us.
And it was all thanks to that
that I was able to raise you three.
Let's stop here.
One thing at a time, please.
Today, I found out that I'm
not your biological daughter
so tell me the rest another time.
Tell me everything else slowly.
What's the matter?
Did something happen?
Your mom...
asked Hyun Jin to come see her.
She's going to tell her.
That poor punk, Hyun Jin...
I feel so bad for her.
If she finds out that
a guy like me is her father...
she'll be so humiliated.
How will she be able to go on?
Did you live a shameful life?
You literally did everything and anything
for the sake of our family!
I...
have never thought of
Hyun Jin as my daughter.
I mean, she doesn't
take after me at all!
She's so smart, and so kind.
Merely watching her from the sidelines...
was more than enough for me.
Oh, man.
Man, what do I do?
Oh, I have no idea.
Should I leave the house, or...
will we be able to live on, like this?
It'll take some time
but she'll understand, and accept it.
Soo Jin.
Please help my Hyun Jin.
Please help her...
so that she isn't too shocked.
Help her, okay?
Can I come in?
Did you...
know about this, too?
Vaguely.
Soo Jin.
At first, Mister would bring
you over in the morning
and take you back home at night.
But after a while, you started
living at our house.
And Mom told me...
that, from now on,
you were my younger sister.
And that we should tell
people that from now on, too.
I think that...
it was too difficult for
Mister to raise you on his own.
So Mom told him that you should
be raised with the rest of us.
And around the time that
you were in kindergarten...
I think you officially
became our younger sister.
I was so happy.
You were so pretty...
I even got up in the middle of
the night sometimes to look at you.
We all loved you so much.
We loved you for being you...
and didn't care about
whose daughter you were.
Are you disappointed?
No.
I'm okay.
Because I'm the same as my older sisters.
I just...
feel so bad for Mr. Jae Beom.
He took me to school and picked me up
every morning and night...
and he was so happy
during my graduations.
And when I was hired
at the newspaper...
Mister cried.
Mister would always do something
for me on my birthday...
and I hated that so much, but...
if anything, I think I knew.
That I was...
quite an important person to Mister.
That I could...
cause Mister pain.
My silly younger sister.
But...
I don't think I'll be able to start
calling him "Dad" right away.
Tell Mister that...
I want us...
to be the same as we were before.
All right.
Are you okay?
I'm talking about Yoon Bok.
You miss her, don't you?
I convince myself every day...
that it couldn't be helped.
Yoon Bok has to live her own life now.
Yes, she does.
I miss you.
Your eight-year-old self.
Your nine-year-old self.
You, as you were back then, every day.
What time is it now?
2:30.
I have a favor to ask of you.
It's kind of a difficult request.
But you must do this for me.
Because it might be my last request.
What is it?
Go and meet with Jung Jin Hong.
And go for a drive.
I've already told him you would.
What?
I'm not good at lying,
so I'll just be honest with you.
I asked the woman
who gave birth to you...
to come, and in a very polite way.
I just don't want you
anywhere near here.
Go on a drive and go
far, far away from here.
I don't want to do this, either.
I don't want to, but...
I need to sort out
my affairs before I die.
[Mooryung Station]
Thank you for coming.
What do you mean?
I'm the one who should be thankful.
I've been wanting
to formally pay you my respects.
But I was too ashamed.
I was curious...
about what kind of person you were.
And where my Soo Jin's...
eyes, nose, and lips...
come from.
Her stubborn nature.
And her cold and
unaffectionate personality.
Her intelligence, and cleverness.
It must have been so rough on you.
Thank you.
So, so much.
There's no need for you to thank me
for having raised my own child.
To be honest, I have a favor to ask,
which is why I asked you to come.
Yi Jin is quite angry.
She can't accept the fact that
Mom is going to pass away.
Hyun Jin is sad.
She's someone who accepts
everything without resisting...
so she is quite sad.
And, as for me...
I'm full of regret.
While I was spending time
with Yoon Bok...
I thought of Mom.
I wondered how my mom lived her life.
And thought about how much
she must have cried because of me.
And whether things were
difficult or upsetting for her.
When I told Mom all that time...
to give me up, to let me go
and that I didn't need her...
Mom still held on to me.
She didn't give one inch...
and was always there.
Now, when I look at Mom...
When I see my lioness-like mother,
who was always full of fiery energy...
reduced to such
a withered, sickly state...
it feels like it was all my fault.
When I die...
please become my Soo Jin's mother.
As I am at death's doorstep...
I feel so sorry for my kids.
But a thought occurred to me...
that, even if I die...
my Soo Jin, at the very least,
will still be able to have a mother.
I don't know how I'll make
you feel by saying this...
but Soo Jin is all grown up now
so I don't think that
she needs a mom anymore.
She and I crossed paths
for only a short while
but you truly raised your daughter
to be a great person.
The reason why I lived nearby...
was because I had nowhere to go
after I got out of jail.
It wasn't so that I could have
a relationship with Soo Jin.
You two are so alike.
I understand now, after hearing you talk.
To be honest...
I was jealous of you.
I've wanted a child
ever since I was younger.
But it didn't work out.
The only regret that I've had in life...
was that I did not give
birth to my Soo Jin.
And the person I was most envious of...
was the person who did give birth to her.
Do you know what my plan is?
I'm sure that you two
will meet up after I die.
It's only natural.
Because you two are tied together
by the toughest bond in the world.
You two will end up meeting...
so...
let's just let it be...
that you two are meeting
because I asked you to.
To fulfill my request.
That's the only way I will be at peace.
I'm the one who has the upper hand, here.
After all, I got to enjoy the most
precious moments of Soo Jin's life...
and I'm just handing over the husk
after sucking out all of the sweetness.
I...
brought something.
I thought it'd be best for me
to give it to you
than to hold on to it myself, Ma'am.
You're back?
She's going to be staying for dinner.
And she's going to be trimming
my hair a bit for me, too.
Call Jae Beom and tell him
to come by for dinner.
I haven't seen him around at all.
Did he go somewhere?
I'd like it if everyone
could be here today.
Wow, isn't she so cute?
- Look at this.
- Take a look at this.
Soo Jin was at her prettiest
when she was a baby!
What was this, Big Sis?
You look so cute!
I want to see.
I want to see, too!
Hey, don't fight!
You don't remember this, do you?
I didn't want to forget your face
so I took you to a photographer's
studio to get your photo taken.
All right, face this way!
Smile.
All right, I'll be taking it now.
One, two, three!
You're so young, and yet
you're so good at cooking!
Oh, I've been cooking since
I was 15 years old, you see.
Big Sis didn't come home that often
and I thought she might come home
if I made some delicious food for her.
I know, Yi Jin.
I know that the fact that I
ran away from home abruptly
and didn't come back home much...
upset you quite a lot.
I know that you were mad at me
for a long time because of that.
Is that what it was?
I was just so happy that Big Sis
made food for me out of nowhere.
Looks like this only
ended up benefiting me.
I didn't want to go out
for dinner, or order food.
I wanted all of us
to sit and eat together.
You know, so that we would have
a real homey feeling.
My Yi Jin is quite skilled at cooking.
No matter how many people come over
she's able to set up a feast just
by rummaging through the fridge.
Try doing that in other places, too.
Feeding the needy and such.
Also, to be honest, I thought that
you girls liked those things.
Going out for dinner
or ordering food, I mean.
Mom.
I was happy just as long
as you were by my side.
You have a magical power, after all.
Even just by saying,
"Look at that pebble over there"
somehow you make that pebble
seem so magical.
When Mom sat at the end of the table
and said things like "King Lear died
today and Norah ran away from home"
I thought that King Lear and
Norah were real people.
I feel like it must have been
really fun when you were all young.
When we were younger, Big Sis
was like our mom.
She gave us allowance
and looked over our homework.
And cut all of our fingernails
and toenails for us.
And she'd find the kids bullying
us at school, and hit them.
It was fun.
I liked the fact that
it was the three of us.
Yeah.
And...
you were just like a father
to us, Mr. Jae Beom.
It would have been so much tougher
for us if you hadn't been around.
All right, then.
It was so delightful to have
everyone get together like this.
But I'm tired now, so...
can you walk me to my room, Soo Jin?
Yes.
Please enjoy yourself to your
heart's content before you go.
All right.
I'm going to be listening
while I'm sleeping.
Make sure you laugh loudly
and have a great time.
Bye, now.
I have no idea...
how to tell you
something like this, but...
Go ahead.
I'll listen.
I'm sorry that I...
kept running away.
You were always there, which was why
I could run away with peace of mind.
Why didn't I know that?
Please forget all about
the despicable things...
that I said or did.
There are so many things
that I want to do for you.
I'll do everything for you.
You don't have to do anything.
So, please...
for just a bit longer...
Soo Jin.
I've packed all of my things.
All of the things...
that I did with you.
I haven't left out a single moment.
I'll take all of those memories with me.
Because they're too precious to me.
I'm ready.
So let me go now.
It was a pretty decent life.
I have no regrets.
Except for just one thing.
Yoon Bok.
The fact that I said mean things
to Yoon Bok, and made her leave.
I shouldn't have done that.
After all, when it comes to that child
the one who is having the
hardest time right now is you.
Samhwa Barber Shop.
After walking past the playground
and Moa Mart...
Who is it?
Mom!
Yoon Bok!
How did you get here?
Um, I got a map.
I got to Mooryung Station
by looking at a map.
And then, after taking a train
to Cheongmyeong Station...
- By yourself?
- Yes.
I even bought myself hot chocolate
from a vending machine.
You can't go around
alone like that!
What if something
terrible happened to you?
It's too dangerous!
Mom.
Didn't you miss me?
I missed you so much, Mom, that...
Of course I missed you!
Why would you think that
I didn't miss you?
- Yoon Bok!
You took the train by yourself?
Yeah.
Weren't you scared?
Nope.
You really are amazing.
So kids find a way to their moms
no matter what, huh?
I apologize.
I'll let her sleep here for tonight,
and bring her back tomorrow.
Yes.
You can call this number.
I apologize.
This is delicious, Aunt!
Eat as much as you want, but slowly!
All right.
You're going to send her back tomorrow?
That tiny child came all this way.
But she has to go back
after just one day?
Can't we wait a few more days
before we send her back?
I'm already scared...
about not being able to let her go.
Starting next week
I'm going to go live in a group home.
"Happy Child Group Home."
I'll have three older siblings
and two younger siblings.
And I'll be right in the middle.
So you're going to be living
in a group home, huh?
It's nice that you're
right in the middle.
But...
I have to call the person there "Mom."
Do you think...
that I'll be able to do that?
Yeah.
You'll be able to do it.
Try doing it slowly, bit by bit.
That's how we were at the beginning, too.
Then, will you not be
my mom anymore, Mom?
There are a lot of kids
who have several moms.
And I'm one of them.
Granny Finger, Sister Clara...
and your grandma, here.
They're all my moms.
Then, does that mean...
that you could have another kid, too?
I don't know, Yoon Bok.
I really have no idea
how to answer that question.
If you're asking me if I'll love
another child instead of you...
then that's a definite no.
People who truly love each other...
can never be truly separated.
Didn't it feel like I was by your side
even when I wasn't?
Yes.
When I was eating curry...
when I was reading books...
before I fell asleep...
and when I saw birds flying in the sky.
And...
always.
It was the same for me.
Whenever I ate fried pork chops.
When I opened my eyes in the morning.
When I saw a train passing by.
Always.
But, Mom...
That's...
not truly being together.
just a lie.
You're right, Yoon Bok.
It is a lie, but...
but we're good at lying.
Just like how you think of
the things you like...
I'll think of you.
So I'll be able to keep
myself from crying...
even when I want to cry.
And, before long...
Do you still have Mommy's key?
One day...
we'll meet again.
Just like how Mommy and
Granny Finger met again.
Grandma?
Yoon Bok?
Are you all right?
Is that really you, Yoon Bok?
Yes.
Am I already dead?
You're not a ghost, right?
I'm not a ghost.
I took the train here.
I see.
Want me to get Mom?
No.
Let's just have it be the two of us.
Yoon Bok.
Can you stay with me for a while?
I'm so cold and lonely tonight.
Want me to hug you?
To be honest, I wanted to be alone.
Because I had a lot to do.
What kinds of things do you need to do?
Say farewell.
I've...
lived so many lives...
so there are many people
that I need to say farewell to.
And who are you saying farewell to today?
Emily, from "Our Town."
I've been involved in theater
since I was nine years old.
That's the same age as me.
That's right.
At that age...
I already knew what I wanted to do.
Dancing and singing.
And making everyone...
look at me.
Doing that was so fun.
But...
when I turned 19...
standing on a stage...
suddenly became so scary for me.
It was so cold...
and scary...
and it left me feeling suffocated.
I felt as if I would faint.
It hadn't been long since
my mother passed away.
It was my first performance
without my mother.
I was playing the role of Emily.
A young mother, who leaves
behind a four-year-old child...
and dies.
Emily dies...
and goes to the afterlife.
There, she runs into her
dead mother-in-law.
"Mother-in-Law."
"We can go back..."
"to that world."
"I feel it."
"I know it."
"I returned to the farm
for a brief moment."
"And, just as I did in the old days..."
"I sat the child on my lap,
as if I were still alive!"
And at that moment...
I felt that my mother...
was by my side.
That my dead mother...
occasionally came...
and visited my home.
I suddenly understood
the feelings of a mother...
who died and left her child behind.
After that day...
I've never once...
felt scared, like I did on that day.
But, tonight...
I felt just as I did back then.
Cold...
lonely, and out of breath.
I'll hold your hand, Grandma.
I want to become an actress, too.
Really?
I feel like it'd be so fun
to become someone else.
And you're so cold, Grandma.
Yoon Bok.
Over there...
on the table...
is a book. Bring it here.
[Our Town]
Read me my lines.
"Goodbye."
"Goodbye, world."
"Goodbye to our town, too."
"Mom, Dad. Take care."
"Goodbye to clocks ticking."
"And Mama's sunflowers."
"And food and coffee. And
freshly ironed dresses and hot baths."
Are you sleepy, Grandma?
Yeah.
I want to give you something.
I'll go to Mom's room
and bring it for you.
It's something that you really need.
This is my mom, from when
she was 8 to 10 years old.
"Goodbye..."
"world."
"Goodbye."
"Goodbye, our town."
"Mom."
"Dad."
"Goodbye."
"Goodbye to clocks ticking."
"And Mama's sunflowers."
"And delicious food..."
"And coffee."
"And freshly ironed dresses..."
"and hot baths."
"And sleeping and waking up."
"Oh, Earth, you're too wonderful..."
"for anybody to realize you."
"Goodbye."
Mom.
[Call Me Mother]
Subtitles by DramaFever
I want to just stay here.
She's getting adopted again?
It made me feel really bad.
She looked really down, too.
Can a sensitive child like Yoon Bok
handle having so many moms?
I looked into whether or not
I could adopt her.
I believe that we can convince them
since you are already
Hye Na's mother, Ms. Soo Jin.
I want to adopt Hye Na.
How could it be possible
for a kidnapper to adopt a child?
Can two people who were
once mother and child
be truly separated?