When shall we three meet again?
In thunder, lightning, or in rain?
When the hurly-burly's done.
VVhen the battle's lost and won.
Where the place?
Upon the battlefield,
there to meet with Macbeth.
Fair is foul, and foul is fair.
Hover through the fog and filthy air.
Doubtful it stood,
as two spent swimmers
that do cling together
and choke their art.
'The merciless Macdonwald
from the Western Isles
'of kerns and gallowglasses
is supplied.'
And fortune,
on his damned quarrel smiling,
showed like a rebel's whore.
But all's too weak,
for brave Macbeth -
well he deserves that name -
disdaining fortune,
with his brandished steel
which smoked with bloody execution,
like valour's minion
carved out his passage
till he faced the slave
which ne'er shook hands
nor bade farewell to him
till he unseamed him
from the nave to the chops
and Hxed his head
upon our battlements.
And, to conclude,
victory fell on us.
Valiant Macbeth.
Worthy gentleman.
Great happiness.
Whence cam'st thou, noble Prince?
From Fife, great King,
where Norwegian banners flout the sky
and fan our people cold,
assisted by that most disloyal traitor,
the Thane of Cawdor_
God save the King!
No more that Thane of Cawdor
shall deceive our bosom interest.
Go pronounce his present death
and with his former title
greet Macbeth.
I'll see it done.
What he hath lost,
noble Macbeth hath won.
So foul and fair a day
I have not seen.
What are these?
Live you or are you aught
that man may question?
Speak, if you can.
What are you?
Macbeth.
Hail to thee, Thane of Glamis.
Hail to thee, Thane of Cawdor.
All hail, Macbeth,
that shalt be king hereafter.
Good sir,
why do you start and seem to fear
things that do sound so fair?
My noble partner
you greet with present grace
and great prediction
of noble having and of royal hope
that he seems rapt withal.
To me you speak not.
Hail, lesser than Macbeth
and greater.
Not so happy yet much happier.
Thou shalt get kings
though thou be none.
So all hail, Macbeth and Banquo.
'Banquo and Macbeth,
'all hail.'
Stay, you imperfect speakers.
Tell me more.
Say from whence you owe
this strange intelligence
and why, upon this blasted heath,
you stop our way
with such prophetic greeting.
Speak, I charge you.
The earth hath bubbles as the water has,
and these are of them.
Whither are they vanished?
Into the air,
and what seemed corporal
melted as breath into the wind.
Would they had stayed.
Were such things here
as we do speak about?
Or have we eaten on the insane root
that takes the reason prisoner?
Your children shall be kings.
You shall be king.
And Thane of Cawdor too.
Went it not so?
To the selfsame tune and words.
The King hath happily received,
Macbeth,
the news of thy success.
As thick as hail
came post from post
and every one did bear thy praises,
in his kingdom's great defence,
and poured them down before him.
And we are sent to give thee
from our royal master thanks.
And, for an earnest of a greater honour,
he bade me from him
call thee Thane of Cawdor.
The Thane of Cawdor lives.
Why do you dress me
in borrowed robes?
Treasons capital, confessed and proved,
have overthrown him.
Do you not hope
your children shall be kings
when those that gave
the Thane of Cawdor to me
promised no less to them?
That trusted home might yet
enkindle you unto the crown
besides the Thane of Cawdor_
But 'tis strange,
and oftentimes,
to win us to our harm,
the instruments of darkness
tell us truths,
win us with honest trifles
to betray's in deepest consequence.
This supernatural soliciting
cannot be ill,
cannot be good.
If ill, why hath it given me
earnest of success,
commencing in a truth?
I am Thane of Cawdor_
If good, why do I yield
to that suggestion
whose horrid image doth unfix my hair
and make my seated heart
knock at my ribs
against the use of nature?
Present fears are less
than horrible imaginings.
If chance will have me king,
why, chance may crown me
without my stir.
Hail, Macbeth.
O worthiest cousin.
More is thy due
than more than all can pay.
The service and the loyalty I owe
in doing it pays itself.
From hence to Inverness,
and bind us further to you.
I'll be myself the harbinger
and make joyful the hearing of my wife
with your approach,
so humbly take my leave.
My worthy Cawdor.
"They met me in the day of success
"and I have learned
by the perfect'st report
"they have more in them
than mortal knowledge.
"When I burned in desire
to question them further,
"they made themselves air
into which they vanished.
"Whiles I stood rapt in the wonder of it
came missives from the King
"who all-hailed me
"Thane of Cawdor,
"by which title before
these Weird Sisters saluted me
"and referred me
to the coming on of time with,
"'Hail, king that shalt be."'
Come,
you spirits that tend on mortal thoughts,
unsex me here
and ill me from the crown to the toe
top-full of direst cruelty.
Come to my woman's breasts
and take my milk for gall,
you murthering ministers,
wherever, in your sightless substances,
you wait on nature's mischief.
Come, thick night,
and pall thee
in the dunnest smoke of hell,
that my keen knife see not
the wound it makes,
nor heaven peep
through the blanket of the dark
to cry, "Hold, hold!"
Hie thee hither
that I may pour my spirits in thine ear
and chastise
with the valour of my tongue
all that impedes thee
from the golden round.
Thy letters have transported me
beyond this ignorant present
and I feel now
the future in the instant.
My dearest love,
Duncan comes here tonight.
And when goes hence?
Tomorrow, as he purposes.
O never shall sun that morrow see!
Glamis thou art, and Cawdor,
and shalt be what thou art promised.
Yet I do fear thy nature.
It is too full o' the milk
of human kindness
to catch the nearest way.
Thou wouldst be great.
Art not without ambition
but without the illness should attend it.
To beguile the time,
look like the time.
Bear welcome in your eye,
your hand, your tongue.
Look like the innocent flower
but be the serpent under't.
He that's coming must be provided for
and you shall put this night's
great business into my dispatch
which shall,
to all our nights and days to come,
give solely sovereign
sway and masterdom.
We will speak further.
All our service, in every point
twice done and then done double.
Give me your hand.
Conduct me to mine host.
We love him highly and shall continue
our graces towards him.
By your leave, hostess.
My plenteous...
up!
Up!
My plenteous joys,
wanton in fulness,
seek to hide themselves
in drops of sorrow.
Sons,
kinsmen,
thanes,
and you whose places
are the nearest,
know that we will establish our estate
upon our eldest, Malcolm,
whom we name hereafter
the Prince of Cumberland.
'The Prince of Cumberland.
'That is a step on which I must fall down,
or else o'erleap,
'for in my way it lies.'
If it were done when 'tis done,
then 'twere well
it were done quickly.
If the assassination
could trammel up the consequence
and catch with his surcease success,
that but this blow might be
the be-all and end-all here.
But here upon this bank
and shoal of time
we'd jump the life to come.
Does anybody know
what this is?
But in these cases
we still have judgement here.
That we but teach bloody instructions
which return to plague the inventor.
This even-handed justice commends
the ingredience of our poisoned chalice
to our own lips.
He's here in double trust.
First, as I am
his kinsman and his subject,
strong both against the deed.
Then, as his host, who should
against his murderer shut the door,
not bear the knife myself.
Besides, this Duncan
hath borne his faculties so meek,
hath been so clear in his great office,
that his virtues
would plead like angels,
trumpet-tongued against
the deep damnation of his taking-off.
I have no spur
to prick the sides of my intent
but only vaulting ambition
which o'erleaps itself
and falls on the other.
We will proceed no further
in this business.
Was the hope drunk
wherein you dressed yourself?
Hath it slept since?
And wakes it now
to look so green and pale
at what it did so freely?
From this time
such I account thy love.
Art thou afeard to be the same
in thine own act and valour
as thou art in desire?
Wouldst thou have that
which thou esteem'st the ornament of life
and live a coward in thy own esteem,
letting "l dare not" wait upon "I would"?
Prithee, peace.
I dare do all that may become a man.
VVho dares do more is none.
What beast was't, then,
that made you break
this enterprise to me?
When you durst do it,
then you were a man.
And to be more than what you were,
you would be so much more the man.
I have given suck
and know how tender 'tis
to love the babe that milks me.
I would, while it was smiling in my face,
have plucked my nipple
from his boneless gums
and dashed the brains out
had I so sworn,
as you have done, to this.
If we Should fail?
We fail.
But screw your courage
to the sticking place
and We'll not fail.
When Duncan is asleep
his two chamberlains will I
with wine and wassail so convince
that memory, the warder of the brain,
shall be a-fume
and the receipt of reason
a Iimbeck only.
When in swinish sleep
their drenched natures lie as in a death
what cannot you and I perform
upon the unguarded Duncan?
What not put upon his spongy officers
who shall bear the guilt
of our great quell?
I am settled
and bend up each corporal agent
to this terrible feat.
Take my sword.
Take thee that too.
A heavy summons lies
like lead upon me
and yet I would not sleep.
Merciful powers,
restrain in me the cursed thoughts
that nature gives way to in repose.
Is this a dagger
which I see before me?
The handle toward my hand.
Come,
let me clutch thee.
Art thou not, fatal vision,
sensible to feeling as to sight?
Or art thou but a dagger of the mind?
A false creation, proceeding
from the heat-oppressed brain.
Thou marshall'st me
the way that I was going
and such an instrument I was to use.
Mine eyes are made the fools
o' the other senses.
Or else worth all the rest.
I see thee still.
There's no such thing.
It is the bloody business
which informs thus to mine eyes.
Now, o'er the one half-world,
nature seems dead
and wicked dreams abuse
the curtained sleep.
Witchcraft celebrates
and withered murder
moves like a ghost.
I see thee yet,
in form as palpable
as this which now I draw.
Whiles I threat, he lives.
Words to the heat of deeds
too cold breath gives.
The spring,
the head,
the fountain of your blood is stopped.
The very source of it is stopped.
Here lies Duncan,
his silver skin laced
with his golden blood.
There the murderers,
steeped in the colours of their trade.
Had I but died
an hour before this chance,
I had lived a blessed time.
But from this instant
there's nothing serious in mortality.
All is but toys.
Renown and grace is dead.
The wine Of life is drawn
and the mere Iees is left
this vault to brag of.
Live you?
Or are you aught
that man may question?
I have done the deed.
Why did you bring these daggers
from the place?
They must lie there.
VVhat hands are here?
'They pluck out mine eyes.'
Will all great Neptune's ocean
wash this blood clean from my hand?
No,
this my hand will rather
the multitudinous seas incarnadine,
making the green one red.
My hands are of your colour,
but I shame to wear a heart so white.
A little water clears us of this deed.
How easy is it then.
To know my deed
'tvvere best not know myself.
Good Macduff_
Good morrow, noble sir.
Good morrow, both.
Is the King stirring, worthy Thane?
- The King, is he stirring?
- Not yet.
He did command me
to call timely on him.
I have almost slipped the hour.
I'll bring you to him.
I'll make So bold to Call.
- Goes the King hence today?
- He does; he did appoint so.
The night has been unruly.
Where we lay,
our temples were blown down
and, as they say,
Iamentings heard in the air,
strange screams of death.
'Twas a rough night.
Confusion now
hath made his masterpiece.
Most sacrilegious murder
hath broke open
the Lord's anointed temple
and stole thence
the life of the building.
The life?
Mean you His Majesty?
Bid me not speak. You see.
Speak yourselves.
Awake!
Ring the alarum bells!
Malcolm!
Banquo!
Ring the alarum bells.
Shake off your downy sleep, man.
Death's counterfeit.
You come and look on death itself.
Huh?
Murder!
Treason!
What's the business?
Our royal master, he's murdered.
Murdered?
Murdered!
Those of his chamber,
their hands were all badged with blood.
Wherefore did you so?
Hm?
Who could refrain
that had a heart to love
and in that heart
courage to make love known?
How it does grieve Macbeth.
Did he not straight, in pious rage,
the two delinquents tear
that were the slaves of drink?
Was this not nobly done?
AY-
'Twould have angered any heart alive
to hear the men deny it.
I say he has borne all things well.
Ls't known who did
this more than bloody deed?
Those that Macbeth hath slain.
Alas, the day.
What good could they pretend?
Malcolm, the King's son,
is stolen away and fled,
which puts upon him
suspicion of the deed.
'Tis most like
the sovereignty will fall upon Macbeth.
He is already named.
'Thou hast it now.
'King, Cawdor,
Gmm&
'all as the weird women promised.
'And I fear
thou playedst most foully for't.
'Yet it was said
it should not stand in thy posterity.'
But that myself should be
the root and father of many kings.
If there come truth from them,
why, by the verities on thee made good,
may they not be my oracles as well
and set me up in hope?
But hush.
No more.
Hail, Macbeth.
Hail, Macbeth. Hail, Macbeth.
'To be thus...is nothing,
'but to be safely thus!
'Our fears in Banquo stick deep.'
And in his royalty of nature
reigns that which would be feared.
'Tis much he dares
and to that dauntless temper
of his mind...
...he hath a wisdom
that doth guide his valour.
How now, my Lord?
Why do you keep alone?
We have scorched the snake,
not killed it.
She'll close and be herself
whilst our poor malice remains
in danger of her former tooth.
Things without all remedy
should be without regard.
VVhat's done is done.
Come, gentle my Lord.
Sleek o'er your rugged looks.
Be bright and jovial
among your guests tonight.
Thou know'st that Banquo,
and his Fleance, lives?
You must leave this.
He chid the sisters
when tirst they put
the name of king upon me
and bade them speak to him.
Then, prophet-like,
they hailed him father to a line of kings.
Upon my head
they placed a fruitless crown
and put a barren sceptre in my grip,
thence to be wrenched
with an unlineal hand,
no son of mine succeeding.
If it be SO,
for Banquo's issue
have I Tiled my mind.
For them
the gracious Duncan
have I murdered,
put rancours
in the vessel of my peace
only for them.
To make them kings,
the seed of Banquo kings!
VVhat's to be done?
Be innocent of the knowledge,
dearest chuck,
till thou applaud the deed.
Full, full of scorpions, is my mind.
Thou marvell'st at my words.
Hold thee Still.
Things bad begun
make themselves strong by ill.
Come, seeling night.
Scarf up the tender eye of pitiful day
and, with thy bloody and invisible hand,
cancel...
And tear to pieces that great bond
which keeps me pale.
Get up!
Tonight we hold a solemn supper, sir,
and I'll request your presence.
Let Your Highness command upon me
to the which my duties are,
with a most indissoluble tie,
forever knit.
Ride you this afternoon?
Ay, my good Lord.
We should have else desired
your good advice in this day's council,
but we'll take tomorrow.
Is't far you ride?
As far, my Lord, as will fill up the time
'twixt this and supper,
go not my horse the better.
Fail not our feast.
My Lord, I will not.
We hear our bloody cousin
is bestowed in England,
not confessing his cruel parricide,
filling his hearers with strange invention.
But of that tomorrow.
Hie you to horse.
Adieu, till you return at night.
Goes Fleance with you?
Ay, my good Lord.
Our time does call upon's.
Farewell.
Within this hour, at most,
I will advise you
where to plant yourselves,
acquaint you with the perfect spy
o' the time the moment on't,
for it must be done tonight,
and something from the palace.
Always thought
that I require a clearness.
And with him,
to leave no rubs
nor botches in the work,
Fleance, his son
that keeps him company,
whose absence is no less material to me
than is his father's,
must embrace the fate
of that dark hour.
Fly!
Fly, Fleance! Fly!
Hail, Macbeth! Hail, Macbeth!
Hail, Macbeth!
You know your own degrees.
Sit down. At first and last,
the hearty welcome.
Our hostess keeps her state
but in best time
we will require her welcome.
Pronounce it for me, sir,
to all our friends,
for my heart speaks
they are welcome.
Your Majesty.
Be large in mirth, anon,
we'll drink a measure
the table round.
There's blood upon thy face.
'Tis Banquo's then.
Is he dispatched?
My Lord, his throat is cut.
He's good that did the like for Fleance.
If thou didst it,
thou art the nonpareil.
Most royal sir,
Fleance is soaped.
Then comes my tit again.
I had else been perfect,
whole as the marble,
founded as the rock,
as broad and general as the casing air.
But now I am cabined, cribbed, confined,
bound in to saucy doubts and fears.
My royal Lord,
you do not give the cheer.
Thanks for that.
Sweet FSYTISYTIDFHHCSF!
Now, good digestion wait on appetite
and health on both.
Here had we now
our country's honour roofed,
were the graced person
of our Banquo present,
who may I rather challenge
for unkindness
than pity for mischance.
His absence, sir,
lays blame upon his promise.
What is't that moves Your Highness?
- Which of you have done this?
- What, my good Lord?
Thou canst not say that I did it.
His Highness is not well.
Sit, worthy friends.
Pray you, keep seat.
The tit is momentary.
Upon a thought he will again be well.
If much you note him,
you shall offend him
and extend his passion.
Feed and regard him not.
Are you a man?
Ay, and a bold one that dare look on that
which might appal the devil.
O proper stuff!
Prithee, see there.
Behold.
Look, Io! How say you?
This is the very painting of your fear.
This is the air-drawn dagger
which you said led you to Duncan.
Why do you make such faces?
If I stand here, I saw him.
My worthy Lord,
your noble friends do lack you.
Blood hath been shed ere now,
in the olden time.
The time has been that,
when the brains were out,
the man would die
and there an end.
But now they rise again
and push us from our stools.
This is more strange
than such a murder is.
I do forget.
Come.
Love and health to all.
Our duties and the pledge.
Avaunt and quit my sight.
Let the earth hide thee.
Thy bones are marrowless,
thy blood is cold.
Thou hast no speculation in those eyes,
which thou dost glare with.
Think of this,
good peers...
...but as a thing of custom.
'Tis no other.
I pray you, sit still.
You make me strange,
even to the disposition that I owe
when now I think
you can behold such sights
and keep the natural ruby of your cheeks
when mine is blanched with fear.
- What sights, my Lord?
- I pray you, speak not.
He grows worse and worse.
Question enrages him.
Stand not upon the order of your going
but go at once.
Good night,
and better health attend His Majesty.
A kind good-night to all.
It will have blood.
They say blood will have blood.
What is the night?
Almost at odds with morning,
which is which.
How say'st thou
that Macduff denies his person
at our great bidding?
You lack the season of all natures.
Sleep.
'I will to the Weird Sisters.
'More shall they speak.
'For now I am bent to know
by the worst means the worst.
'For mine own good,
all causes shall give way.
'I am in blood stepped in so far that,
should I wade no more,
'returning were as tedious as go o'er.
'Strange things I have in head
that will to hand,
'which must be acted
ere they may be scanned.'
I conjure you, by that which you profess,
howe'er you come to know it,
SFISWGI' ITIS.
Speak, I charge you.
Be lion-mettled, proud,
and take no care who chafes,
who frets, or where conspirers are.
Macbeth shall never vanquished be.
Until Great Birnam Wood
to high Dunsinane Hill
shall come against him.
Beware Macduff.
Beware the Thane of Fife.
Dismiss me, enough.
- Beware Macduff.
- Beware the Thane of Fife.
Beware the Thane of Fife.
- Beware Macduff.
Be bloody,
bold, and resolute.
Laugh to scorn the power of man,
for none of woman born
shall harm Macbeth.
Then live, Macduff.
What need I fear of thee?
But yet I'll make assurance double sure
thou shalt not live.
Saw you the Weird Sisters?
No, my Lord.
Came they not by you?
No, indeed, my Lord.
Infected be the air whereon they ride
and damned all those that trust them!
'Who was't came by?'
'Tis two or three, my Lord,
that bring you word.
Macduff has fled to England.
- Fled to England?
- Ay, my good Lord.
The flighty purpose never is overtook
unless the deed go with it.
The very firstlings of my heart
shall be the Hrstlings of my hand.
Be it thought and done.
Hell is murky.
VVhat's done cannot be undone.
Skirr the country round.
Hang those that talk of fear.
The castle of Macduff I will surprise,
seize upon Fife,
give to the edge of the sword
his wife, his babes,
and all unfortunate souls
that trace him in his line.
No boasting like a fool.
This deed I'll do
before this purpose cool.
Murder!
I have done no harm!
No!
No, please, my babies!
Bring me no more reports.
Let them fly all.
Till Birnam Wood
remove to Dunsinane
I cannot taint with fear.
What's the boy Malcolm?
Vvas he not born of woman?
The spirits that know
all mortal consequence
have pronounced me thus:
"Fear not, Macbeth.
"No man that's born of woman
shall e'er have power upon thee."
Then fly, false thanes,
and mingle with the English epicures.
Why are you silent?
This tyrant,
whose sole name blisters our tongues,
was once thought honest.
Now is the time of help.
Your eye in Scotland
would create soldiers,
make our women fight
to doff their dire distresses.
Be it their comfort
we are coming thither.
I have words
that would be howled in the desert air
where hearing should not latch them.
My ever gentle cousin.
Stands Scotland where it did?
Alas, poor country,
it's almost afraid to know itself.
It cannot be called our mother
but our graves.
What's our newest grief?
Let not your ears despise my tongue
which shall possess them
with the heaviest sound
that ever yet they heard.
How does my wife?
Your castle is surprised,
your wife and babes
savagely slaughtered.
What man, hm?
V\/hat man?
My children too?
Wife, children, servants,
all that Could be found.
He has no children!
All my pretty chickens
and their dam,
in one fell swoop?
Dispute it like a man.
Oh...
Oh, I will do so.
But I will also feel it as a man.
Sinful Macduff!
They were all struck for thee.
Be this the whetstone of your sword.
Let grief convert to anger.
Blunt not the heart, enrage it.
Gracious England hath lent us
ten thousand men.
Our power is ready.
Our lack is nothing but our leave.
Front to front
you bring thou
this fiend of Scotland and myself,
and within my sword's length
you set him.
If he scape,
heaven forgive him too.
'Great Dunsinane
he strongly fortifies.
'Some say he's mad.
'Others, lesser, that hate him
'do call it valiant fury.'
But, for certain,
he cannot buckle his distempered cause
within the belt of rule.
Those he commands
move only in command.
'Nothing in love.
'Now does he feel
'his secret murders
sticking on his hands]
Yet here's a spot.
Out, damned spot!
Out, I say!
Hell is murky.
Fie, my Lord!
Fie!
A soldier and afearcl?
What need we fear
who knows it
when none can
call our power to account?
Yet who would have thought
the old man to have had
so much blood in him?
The Thane Of Fife had a wife.
Where is she now?
What?
VVill these hands ne'er be clean?
No more o' that, my Lord.
No more o' that.
You mar all with this starting.
Here's the smell of the blood still.
All the perfumes of Arabia
will not sweeten this little hand.
Wash your hands.
Put on your nightgown.
Look not so pale.
To bed.
There's knocking at the gate.
Come.
Come, come,
give me your hand.
VVhat's done cannot be undone.
To bed.
The devil damn thee black,
thou cream-faced Icon.
Where got'st thou that goose look?
There's ten thousand.
Geese, villain?
Soldiers, sir.
Go, prick thy face
and over-red thy fear,
thou lily-Iivered boy.
What soldiers, patch?
The English force, so please you.
Hang out our banners
on the outward walls.
The cry is still, "They come!"
Our castle's strength
will laugh a siege to scorn.
Here let them lie
till famine and the ague eat them up.
Doctor.
The thanes fly from me.
What rhubarb, cyme
or what purgative drug
would scour these English hence?
Hear'st thou of them?
Ay, my good Lord.
Your royal preparation
makes us hear something.
If thou couldst, Doctor,
cast the water of my land,
find her disease
and purge it
to a sound and pristine health.
I would applaud thee to the very echo
that should applaud again.
The Queen, my Lord, is dead.
She should have died hereafter.
There would have been a time
for such a word.
Tomorrow,
and tomorrow,
and tomorrow
creeps in this petty pace
from day to day
to the last syllable of recorded time.
And all our yesterdays have lighted fools
the way to dusty death.
Out.
Out, brief candle.
Life's but a walking shadow,
a poor player
that struts and frets
his hour upon the stage
and then is heard no more.
It is a tale told by an idiot,
full of sound and fury,
signifying nothing.
VVhat is that noise?
It is the cry of women, my good Lord.
I have almost forgot the taste of fears.
The time has been
my senses would have cooled
to hear a night-shriek
and my fell of hair
would, at a dismal treatise,
rouse and stir
as life were in't.
I have supped full with horrors.
Direness, familiar
to my slaughterous thoughts,
Cal'\l'1Ot OnCe Start me.
Thy story, quickly.
Gracious my Lord,
I should report that which I say I saw,
but know not how to do it.
Seyton!
I am sick at heart when I behold.
Seyton, I say!
This push will chair me ever
or dis-seat me now.
I have lived long enough.
My way of life is fallen into the sere,
the yellow leaf.
And that which should
accompany old age as...
_uhonoun
love,
obedience,
troops of friends,
I must not look to have,
but, in their stead,
curses,
not loud,
but deep, mouth-honour, breath,
which the poor heart would fain deny
and dare not.
Seyton.
All is confirmed, my Lord,
which was reported.
I'll fight till from my bones
my flesh be hacked.
- Give me my armour.
- 'Tis not needed yet.
I'll put it on!
And now a wood
comes toward Dunsinane.
Ring the alarum bell.
Arm, arm, and out!
Tyrant, show thy face!
There is nor Hying hence
nor tarrying here.
I 'gin to be aweary of the sun
and wish the estate o' the world
were now undone.
Blow, wind.
Come, wrack.
At least we'll die
with harness on our back.
'They have tied me to a stake.
'I cannot fly.
'But, bear-like,
I must Tight the course.
'VVhat's he that was not born of woman?
'Such a one am I to fear, or none.
'Why should I play the Roman fool
and die on mine own sword?'
Whiles I see lives,
the gashes do better upon them.
Turn, hellhound.
Turn.
Of all men else
I have avoided thee.
But get thee back.
My soul is too much charged
with blood of thine already.
I have no words.
My voice is in my sword.
Thou Iosest Iabou r.
As easy mayst thou the intrenchant air
with thy keen sword impress
SS make me bleed.
Let fall thy blade on vulnerable crests.
I bear a charmed life
which must not yield
to one of woman born.
Despair thy charm
and let the angel
whom thou still hast served tell thee
Macduff was from his mother's womb
untimely ripped.
Accursed be the tongue
that tells me so,
for it hath cowed
my better part of man.
I'll not Tight with thee.
Then yield thee, coward,
and live to be
the show and gaze of the time.
I will have thee,
as our rarer monsters are,
painted upon a pole,
and Ul'ldl\Nfitl
"Here may you see the tyrant,
"Macbeth ."
I will not yield
to kiss the ground
before young Malcolm's feet
and to be baited
with the rabble's curse.
Though Birnam Wood
be come to Dunsinane
and thou opposed,
being of no woman born,
yet I will try the last.
Before my body
I throw my warlike shield.
Lay on, Macduff.
And damned be him
that first cries,
"Hold, enough!"
He's worth more sorrow,
and that I'll spend for him.
He's worth no more.
Hail,
King of Scotland!
Hail, King of Scotland!