Gonzalo...
...eat it all.
Okay, thanks.
Mom?
Bye, honey.
Eraser.
Look...
Good morning... boys.
Those of you aware that...
...the bulletin board is to be read.
Will have noticed
certain changes here at school.
You have new classmates.
They live near the school,
so most of you have probably seen
many of them around.
Well?
They live around the corner!
- Yes?
- I know that one.
His mother does our laundry.
Hi, Christian.
Good. Now you're classmates.
I hope you give them a warm welcome,
as you would a brother
or a new friend.
All right boys, please be seated.
Hold on.
I don't want the new boys
sitting together.
You. Yes, you.
Get your things
and sit over there.
Liven up!
- How about You. What's your name?
- Pedro Machuca.
- Speak up. I can't hear you.
- Louder!
- Pedro Machuca!
That's more like it.
Make yourself heard,
Machuca.
Go sit down.
Over there.
You,
there.
You, there...
And you...
over there.
Right.
All alone?
How's that sandwich, Infante?
Tasty. You want it?
Take it.
The priest screwed you.
Who will you copy from now?
Thatjerk.
Hey!
Machuca!
Hey, Machuca!
Come on!
Let's have some fun.
Hey, Machuca. My name's...
Gaston Robles!!!
Just kidding.
Go ahead, be unfriendly.
I don't care.
But I want my desk back.
- Why?
- It's none of your business.
- To be near my friend.
- Let him move.
We're doing you a favor.
You're getting a free ride.
Our parents pay for your tuition.
And you want to make the rules?
- No way.
- Complain to the priest.
The priest, you shithead?
His name is Father McEnroe.
Hello, my honeypie!
That's enough, Mama.
Cut it out.
- What took you so long?
- I came straight here.
- Really?
- Yes.
Anything new at school?
No, nothing.
You have much homework?
Hey, you dummy!
- Are you listening to me?
- Yes.
- The Martians landed in Santiago...
...this morning.
I know.
- We have an errand to run.
- No, not again.
- Yes, again.
- I have homework.
- You can do it there.
NO CIVIL WAR
THE LONE RANGER
CHAPTER ONE
We had a good time, right?
Did you like Roberto's gift?
My little man...
Lucy, I brought some things.
I had a lucky day.
- Hi, Lucy.
- Hi, sweetie.
Hello, hello.
I got a great tip
at the black market.
- Anything yummy?
- Yeah, lentils,
milk, shaving cream,
- oil, sardines.
- We're overstocking.
We have plenty of oil already.
With things as they are,
you never know.
This situation can't last, can it?
No, it can't.
What are you eating,
you pig?
- Jello.
- You're gonna get fat.
- Such a pretty...
- Leave her alone.
- Here, let's see.
- No, give it to me!
Give it over here.
Dad,
it's the Gold Collection, first issue.
When the Lone Ranger meets Toro.
This is a great chapter.
Toro uses Indian medicine
to heal his wound.
You found this
at the black market?
What a ridiculous question!
It's late.
Time for bed.
It's a school night.
Good night, Dad.
Good night.
...the first Chilean president
ever to visit the Soviet Union.
Good night
Ajoint press release signed today
at the Kremlin confirms
#USSR support... #
What ajerk
Good night.
Can't she do any better?
Why? I think he's good-looking.
NO RUNNING - NO SPLASHING
NO FIGHTING GAMES
Stop running! Do as I say!
Boys!
Remember,
this pool has a chemical
that turns pink
when it comes into contact
with urine.
So please be careful. Please!
Jump if you're wearing
a black shirt!
You!
Out of the pool!
You will learn
to respect each other.
Even if it's the only thing
you learn at this school.
I don't care who you are
or where you were born.
You will respect each other here!
Is that clear?
Yes, Father McEnroe.
Good. Enjoy yourselves.
Jump in.
The water's great!
RESIGN
DO IT FOR CHILE
RIGHT WING BEWARE
HERE COME THE RABBLE
THE OLD CAPITALIST ECONOMY
IS DEAD
Gonzalo,
I'm waiting, honey.
- Afternoon.
- How's little mama's boy?
- How is it now?
- Fine.
Do you like it?
No.
- Stunning.
- Thank you.
And now?
Even worse.
The boy's in a bad mood.
If you don't mind my saying so,
you look gorgeous.
Thank you.
I mind you saying so.
Gonzalo, what's your problem?
You loved the designs before.
- You're not the one paying.
- Neither are you
Hey! You jerk.
What's with this guy?
Move over, shithead.
Does it hurt, Infante?
- No.
- Come on, I want to show you something.
Come on, man.
Come on.
Nothing's gonna happen.
Don't worry.
Why so serious?
Relax, man.
We got him ready for you.
Go on, hit him.
He threw dirt at us.
Don't be chicken.
Hit him!
This is how we do things
here in Vitacura.
What's your problem?
Go on, hit him.
Go on.
Go on, hit him!
Don't be chicken!
Hit him!
Are you afraid?
Be a man for once in your life!
Coward!
Coward! Coward!
Let me go, dammit!
Come back, you coward!
- Faggot!
- Learn how to fight, you pussy!
Fuck off!
Look at those two pussies.
They should get married,
Faggot!
Hi.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
- You're not leaving?
- No, my ride's not here yet.
You want a lift?
No, it's okay.
Come on. Hold on a second.
Hi, Uncle!
Can we give my friend a lift?
All right, but quick!
Dad, there's no room!
Yes, there is!
Come on, hurry!
Shut up, midget.
The little princess
is too good for us.
Where to, Strawberry Face?
That's a pretty nice school.
It's a private school.
Sorry, no offense
Where to, Sire?
The corner of Bentjerodt
and Hernandez.
Nice neighborhood.
Look! Fatso's got his seat
up his ass!
Stop it, Dad.
Strawberry Face
is cracking up!
Is he your dad?
No, a neighbor.
Peter, do whatever Silvana says.
Only one carton at a time.
If they're imported,
never more than two.
- Where are you going?
- To work.
A snob like you
wouldn't know.
That's enough.
Let's get to work.
And don't confuse the flags.
It happened to Silvana last time.
That was scary!
I wasn't scared.
Here's your stop, Strawberry Face.
- How far are you going?
- To Parque Forestal.
- That's on my way.
- You sure?!
- Yeah. I can do some shopping.
- You got cash?
Enough chatting.
We're late.
Hello, Lucy?
Is Mama home?
Tell her I went to a friend's house
to do homework.
I'll be home later.
Bye.
20 years to get there,
3 years to screw it up!
Strawberry Face.
Get me 3 packs from the truck.
One Hilton, two Monarchs.
The box in front.
And be careful.
Flags! Flags!
Chilean flags!
Did you lock the truck?
Give the Hiltons to Silvana.
Allende, Allende,
the country's not for sale!
Flags! Flags!
Here.
- You still here?
- Willy said to give you this.
- Gonzalo, you're helping us?
- How's it going?
- I sold everything.
- Give me the cash.
I had to lower the price.
What's this?
- It's for me.
- You're a smart-ass.
Jump if you're not a commie!
Jump, kids, jump!
Jump!
Now what?
Now we go
to the real demonstration.
C-C-Y!
Chilean-Communist-Youth!
Power to the people!
Flags! Flags!
Here.
Allende, the people
are behind you!
Flags! Flags!
Chilean Flags!
Socialist Party flags!
Allende, the people
are behind you!
- How's it going, snob?
- Fine.
Jump if you're not a mummy!
What's a mummy?
- Rich and spoiled, like you.
- What?
Rich and spoiled, like you.
Go on, jump!
Jump!
Get out, honey.
- Evening, Amador.
- Come in, Madame.
Thank you.
I'm so sorry.
I'm late.
I couldn't come any sooner.
It's good to see you.
- How are you?
- Fine, fine.
Sit down, honey.
You're not hungry?
No.
What happened, Chief?
The people at his school
are nuts.
The kids will end up
killing each other.
What school is that?
- Or did you tell me?
- Saint Patrick's.
Saint Patrick's.
I went there, too.
- Silly.
- Best school in all of Chile.
I heard things have changed there.
That the priests have turned red on us.
Is that true?
Like the rest of the country.
The kids are more restless, though.
Aren't they?
- Mama!
- Why didn't you go to Buenos Aires?
- I didn't have to.
My family's coming
this weekend.
To celebrate my wife's birthday
They're coming?
I thought
they wouldn't set foot in Chile
while Allende was president.
It's only a few days.
How absurd.
You can't compare Santiago
with Buenos Aires.
She'll have an awful birthday,
poor thing.
I don't understand.
We'll go to Vina, to the casino.
Wonderful.
How's the book I gave you?
I don't like the Lone Ranger.
You don't?
You want another book?
No.
I'll get you another next time,
just in case.
All right?
Make yourself at home.
Thank you.
RIGHT-WINGERS BEWARE
Thanks, Infante.
See you.
Hey! I can take you home
if you want!
No, thanks. Here's all right.
Can I?
- Okay.
Hi, Mama.
- I brought a friend.
- Some nerve!
Go on home, I'll make a snack!
See you there!
Why are you two so quiet?
Aren't you hungry?
Is there a bathroom?
Of course there is.
That shack back there.
Pedro, go with him.
- Go with him!
- He can go by himself!
Give me your cup.
Your friend seems nice.
Were you hiding him?
Clean yourself up.
You're a mess.
Hi.
Is it yours?
Yes.
Be careful.
We're all thieves here.
It'll vanish in a flash.
- Hi.
- You could knock at least.
I was outside with the snob.
His name's Gonzalo.
Hey, give me a hand.
- She's got the hiccups.
- Pat her on the back.
Guys, come sit over here.
- So tell me, snob.
- Gonzalo. His name's Gonzalo.
- Cut it out, Silvana.
- I didn't say anything.
- Hey, Peter.
- What?
How's school with the snob?
I mean Gonzalo.
- You're such an ass!
We're learning English.
Seriously.
It's not so hard. Is it?
Not really.
Okay, say something.
Even I know that one.
Something else.
Something else...
Okay, say...
"My sister Rosita is cute."
And say...
"Salvador Allende
is the President of Chile."
You're pulling my leg.
If you don't believe me,
don't ask.
Do you know this one?
What does "I love you" mean?
I quit. Ask Gonzalo.
Do you know?
I love you.
Your friend here knows.
What's the big hurry,
blondie?
- Who is it?
- Patricio Infante.
How are things?
- Hi there, Cesar.
- Patricio! Nice to see you!
What's new?
And the little gringo?
He's grown! Have a seat.
- How's everything?
- Fine. We're doing our best.
Cigarettes! Good.
I'll take some.
Any ham?
Sure. Excellent quality.
NO CIGARETTES
NO MILK - NO MEAT
NO EGGS - NO FLOUR
Toro.
We'll study together
next time.
Okay?
Robles.
Machuca.
Infante...
Gomez.
- How did you do?
- Seven.
Boys...
On your mark,
get set,
go!
Second...
Machuca.
Third...
Are you upset?
If you'd gotten a 7,
they'd have caught us for sure!
"For sure."
What a drag.
It's my sister's birthday.
- All these assholes are coming over.
- So what?
My parents are going out.
I have to stay in
and play the cop.
- How old is she?
- 16.
They don't like leaving her alone
with her boyfriend.
- I can come if you want.
- To my place?
It's no big deal.
I was only offering to help.
Hi.
Happy birthday.
Thanks.
Hold it, hold it!
- Say hello!
- Hello.
- New friend?
- Yes.
One of the new kids, right?
- What's your name?
- Pedro.
- Pedro what?
- Pedro Machuca.
Machuca...
- Cut it out!
- Okay, okay.
Get out of my face!
- What do they call you?
- Peter.
Peter...
Come on, stop it.
Cut it out.
These people
have such weird names.
Leave him alone.
- Stop it.
- Cool it.
- You know what this is?
- No.
For self-defense, look.
I told you.
He's an asshole.
Forget about it.
Is all that yours?
Yeah.
More or less.
I get hand-me-downs
from a cousin.
Adidas!
Lucky you!
"Made in Germany."
You want to try them?
- Can I?
- You can borrow them.
Your dad's really cool.
No, they were a gift
from a friend of my mom's.
- From Buenos Aires.
- She has nice friends.
I'd like to meet one.
- What are you staring at?
- Nothing.
- Come on, tell me.
Tell your friend
not to eat everything!
Have a drink with me.
Come on!
Come on.
You can keep it.
Go on, take it.
Your mommy isn't home.
Invite me again sometime.
Your friends are so chic...
I didn't hear you complaining
about the #filet mignon. #
Not to mention the Chivas.
There's no better aphrodisiac
than a good whisky.
Stop it, you're too drunk.
- Don't be vulgar.
- I'll show you vulgar.
Let go. Don't touch me.
The kids are asleep.
- You'll wake them.
- Vulgar?
- I'm the vulgar one now.
- Let me go.
You know what? Your friends
are the ones who are vulgar.
Now they're vulgar.
Stupid sluts talking nonsense
and jerks who only care about money.
How much money they make...
Now that's vulgar.
At least they're proud
of something.
Proud of something?
Like you, right?
What does that mean?
- You know exactly what I mean.
- No, I don't.
If you have something to say,
say it. Be a man, for once.
Otherwise shut up.
- Just please don't involve Gonzalo.
You've gone too far
with this.
Me? I've gone too far with it?
Open the door!
Maria Luisa, open the door!
- Open up!
- No way. Sleep somewhere else.
Good morning.
It smells like men in here.
Who's he?
Afriend.
- What's your name?
- Pedro, ma'am.
Pedro.
I'd never seen you before.
He's new.
In your class?
Yes.
You have beautiful eyes.
Thanks.
And you?
You trying to get away from me?
Did you have fun at the party?
Not really. It was boring.
Liar.
Do you like the present?
- What present?
- Didn't you see it?
No.
This.
It's from Roberto.
Take it.
I'll leave it here,
in case you're interested.
Kids, time for breakfast.
Wow, look!
You're so lucky!
Let me borrow it.
Not that one.
You can borrow this one.
Okay, mister. There you go.
Keep it down, one at a time!
One at a time, please.
- 3 cans of condensed milk.
- 2 per family.
My nanny said I could get 3.
Tell her to stand in line herself.
There you go.
Shall I wrap it for you?
That's 50 Escudos.
- Hey, snob.
- Hey.
- What's up?
- Just hanging around.
Condensed milk!
- Give me some.
- No, the can is not open.
- Come on, open it.
- No
- Guess which hand.
- I can't.
- Come on, you have two.
- It's not open.
- Open it.
No, I can't.
- Try it, it's delicious.
- Thanks.
Stop it!
You're not breastfeeding!
Drink it slowly
so you don't swell.
Slowly.
Why go to school
if you don't learn anything?
Besides, Peter's a lazy bum.
You don't need to study
to be dumb.
With all that money
the priests are wasting on him.
- What school do you go to?
- I stopped going.
I got bored. I have to work
and take care of the house.
What about your mama?
- No, she doesn't.
- Doesn't what?
She left.
Where to?
Look.
Close your eyes.
You kiss good for a kid.
Did you like it?
You want more
Come here.
Asshole!
- Hi.
- Hi, Peter.
What was that?
Stop!
I need at least one
- to take home.
- You want some?
Come on, let him try.
Have a seat.
Two lollies.
Thank you.
Hey, give it here.
Hey, Machuca.
Come and get it.
Forget it.
I'll buy you another.
Listen to your girlfriend.
Women know best.
They're in love!
Peter, you want it?
Come and suck it.
Let go of him!
You disappoint me.
You all disappoint me.
What kind of arrogance
has gotten into you?
Look at yourselves.
Please!
You.
You insist on acting like
an animal.
It's all about you
and only you.
And the others?
Don't they count?
Hasn't this school
taught you anything?
And you.
You.
You think you can gain their respect
with you fists?
Tell me.
What will you do
after you hit your classmate?
Will you strangle him
until he can't breathe?
Until he's dead?
And then what?
Will you eat him?
And you.
What's so funny?
That's enough.
- Your glass.
- Not the kids, Patricio.
Why not?
They need to learn.
Otherwise they lose control.
That's enough.
When I was a baby,
they'd dip my pacifier in wine.
That kept me quiet.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Dad, will you be traveling
more often?
A bit more often.
Especially to Rome.
The FAO office is there.
- What language do they speak there?
- Italian, dummy.
Why?
He wants the Lone Ranger.
So?
- And you want a Neil Diamond record.
- Yeah, please, Dad.
- It's...
- So you want me to turn smuggler.
- It has a blue cover and...
- I could use a pair of new shoes.
- Really?
- Really.
Let's all move to Italy.
What?
Let's move to Rome.
I could easily get a transfer.
Considering the situation here...
It's not all that bad, but...
We'd be better off there.
I'd be making dollars.
Socialism may be best for Chile,
but not for us.
Well, not yet.
- I mean it, let's move!
- Yeah, Mama. It would be fun.
You don't even speak Italian.
Who cares?
- What do you say?
- Come on, Mama!
Mama! Mama!
What is it?
- What?
- There are people outside.
They're hunting dogs
and killing them!
Calm down! It's all right.
There's no danger.
Go watch TV.
Go on.
Your mama'll be right out.
CIVILWAR
Gonzalo, I hope you have money
for the movies.
I won't pay for you.
- Of course I do.
- When I have money,
I won't spend it
on stupid things.
I'll open a shop.
I'm sick of selling
- in the street.
- I want to be a priest.
Like Father McEnroe.
A priest? What for?
To help people.
Especially the poor.
You mean to help yourself.
For the cash.
What about you, Gonzalo?
I don't know.
Maybe a priest, also.
See? That's two of us.
Are you crazy?
You two don't even go to church.
So? What does that matter?
It doesn't?
You know who a priest marries?
Priests don't marry.
- Yes they do.
God. And forget about sex.
You guys are too horny for that.
Look who's talking!
You're the horny one!
Come on, run!
I want to show you
something wonderful!
What a boring movie!
Gonzalo, look.
Gonzalo.
Look over here, man.
Stop reading that.
It's bullshit.
And you can't even dance.
White men and Indians
are never friends.
Sure they are.
It's possible.
- What do you want?
- Where's the money?
- There's none left.
- Where's the rest?
Hold it, stay there.
Come here.
- Give me that!
- Let go!
Let go! Let go!
Shame on you!
Pushing me around like that!
Who's that?
Afriend.
Afriend, right.
Some friends you have.
Know where your friend will be
in 5 years?
Starting college.
And you'll be cleaning toilets.
In ten years,
your friend here
will be working
at his daddy's company.
And you'll still be
cleaning toilets.
In 15 years, your friend will own
his daddy's company.
And you? Take a guess.
You'll still be cleaning toilets.
Some friend.
He won't even remember
your name by then.
- Your friend.
- I think you better leave.
- At this rate,
you'll just get
drunker and drunker
and in two years you'll be dead.
Don't you dare touch her!
Let go of her!
Leave!
Go find some booze.
Your friend better go home.
Go on, kiddo.
Go home.
You, go find your father.
Mama!
Go on, do as I say.
Be a good boy.
Kids and drunks don't lie,
do they?
Sometimes they do.
We praise you, oh, Lord.
Dear parents,
I'd like to take a break
from the Gospel
to discuss
what is happening
here at the school.
Father, I'd like to say something.
The recent violent behavior
at the school
is unacceptable. My son gets in fights
every day. The new kids
are constantly
provoking our children.
Father. To a certain extent, we're all
responsible for what's happening.
Silence, please.
In my opinion,
the blame rests with you,
Father.
You're trying to brainwash
our children by mixing them
with people
they don't need to know.
You're manipulating them,
and we won't stand for it.
All parents were informed
in advance
about the measures
the school intended to take.
Those who don't like the school
can leave the school.
Why don't you leave,
you communist priest!
Hold on, wait a second.
The father represents the sentiment
of a considerable group here.
Those of us who want
equal opportunity
and a democratic education
for our children.
Go on, clap.
Father, this madness
will bankrupt the school.
We'll soon have returns
from the farm
managed by the students.
That will cover the small deficit
we're operating under.
Father, you know I donated
30 pigs to your farm.
Pigs I brought from my own farm, which
the communists want to steal from me.
I heard the pigs are dying because
they're not receiving vaccinations!
These things happen.
It's part of the process
your children are going through.
Excuse me, Father,
for turning my back on you...
Look, I don't think
this is a good thing.
This sort of paternalism,
frankly,
because people don't want
to receive things...
for free, without having done
something to deserve them.
- We've earned everything we have!
- They're hard-working people!
Paternalism is what you're doing,
speaking for others as if they couldn't!
I speak on behalf of
a great majority of people.
Father, what's the whole idea
of mixing pears and apples?
I'd like to know why it is
you try so hard...
Let me finish.
Why mix pears and apples?
I'm not saying we're better or worse,
just different.
When I was a child...
I lived on a farm
next to San Nicolas.
My father took care of the cattle.
If something happened
to an animal,
it was docked from our food
at the end of the month.
The reason didn't matter.
My father was always to blame.
I came here to Santiago
when I was 15...
because I didn't want my children
to be blamed for everything.
But I can see things here
are the same.
Everything is always our fault.
That's just how it is.
No one will blame you for
not changing.
Sometimes I ask myself,
when will things change?
When will we dare
to do things differently?
That's my opinion.
Save your bitterness!
Get the hell out of here!
Get these Marxists out of here!
Nationalists!
- Present!
National Front,
freedom and country!
Nationalists!
- Present!
National Front,
freedom and country!
Nationalists!
- Present!
National Front,
freedom and country!
National Party flags!
Chilean flags!
Flags!
Flags...
SOCIALIST PARTY
Communists, bastards!
Living off the state!
Maria Luisa.
- Why come if you're not protesting?
- Come on, make some noise.
Okay, that's why I came.
Living off the state!
Communists, bastards!
Here.
Hey, you have to pay!
Pay me, you asshole!
Pay me, you shithead!
Who do you think you are?
Up yours, motherfucker!
Pablo, hi.
What are you doing here?
What if Patricio saw you?
I'm married, not retarded.
You didn't bring my daughter,
I hope.
No, of course not.
See you.
Who do you think you are?
What was that?
She spat on your car.
Hey, you little bitch!
Clean it up!
What's your problem,
you fucking snob?
Look what you did, you scumbag!
Fuck you, snob!
Calm down.
She's just a kid.
She's just a kid!
Hey!
You fucking little bitch!
Fuck you, snob!
I was sticking up for you,
you little shit!
Go back to your shantytown!
You're all fucking snobs!
Go home, you scumbag!
You fucking lowlife!
Your mama didn't look happy.
That was your mama?
Was that your mama?
Answer me.
Your mama is a real shitbag.
The whore.
Fucking snob.
Cocksucker.
Whore.
Whore, whore,
Where were you?
Let's get out of here!
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
They're all dead, Father.
They were sick.
- Pack some sweaters, please.
- Which ones?
All of them.
- Why? It's summer in Europe.
- End of summer.
All of them.
Don't, give me that.
A little girl smoking...
Let her smoke,
she's old enough.
- Just one.
- Fine.
- Your ties?
- Yes.
What are you looking for?
The camera.
Are you taking it with you?
Of course, it's a trip.
Rome, Italy, the Vatican...
I won't be working
the whole time.
4th drawer,
you put it there yourself.
You mean the 2nd.
The 4th, in back.
- Shall I close it?
- Yes.
Careful, careful...
Not so hard, asshole!
- What?
- You bit me, man!
I didn't mean it.
- Yeah, sure.
A kiss of mine'll make it better.
Better my ass, you jerk!
- Get off me!
- You ruined it for both of us!
You shithead! Why'd you go
and bite her?
What have you got in your mouth?
A razor blade?
Learn how to kiss,
carrot head.
Don't tease the snob,
he might start crying.
Give me my bike back.
Don't be stupid.
Give it back!
- Thanks for the bike!
- No, give it back, shit!
Give it back!
Come on, give it back!
Fucking rabble!
Sons of bitches!
What did you say?
My mother isn't a bitch.
Go on, hit me.
Hit me.
My little boy.
Stop seeing that old fucker.
...bravely risking his own life,
the second person to enter the room
as shots rang
from inside the palace,
stray bullets flying everywhere.
Apparently the gun was
a gift given by Fidel Castro
directly to the President.
It is the gun he used
to kill himself.
The inscription, "To Salvador, from
your brother in arms, Fidel Castro."
Where exactly did you find it?
It was in Mr. Allende's hand
when we entered his office.
Hello, Mama? Yes.
When will you be back?
But Mama...
Bye.
The armed forces
have restored order,
with unanimous support,
after having endured three years of
the Marxist cancer.
Eat your sandwich
and drink your milk
No, thanks.
- Was Mama all right?
- Looks like it.
Both moral and social,
which could no longer
be tolerated.
The armed forces
and order itself
today have responded,
driven purely by
patriotic duty and nothing else,
to save the country
from the unyielding chaos
of Salvador Allende's
Marxist government.
Move on, faster.
Hurry up.
Go on, keep moving.
Faster.
Faster, keep moving.
You, over there.
Inside.
Let go of me!
You, inside.
You, smart-ass!
What are you doing
to the children?
This is not a barracks!
This is humiliating!
Go on, keep moving.
Army bastards! Go back
to the barracks!
- You okay?
- What do you care?
Good morning, boys.
Ma'am.
- Good morning.
Mrs. Gilda,
you left this
in the Teacher's Lounge.
Thank you very much.
Boys,
I'm Colonel Sotomayor,
the new Principal
of the school
As you all know,
strange things have been
going on here at the school.
Inappropriate things.
We're here to fix that.
To put everything in order.
So that once and for all, you can
devote yourselves to your studies
and nothing else.
As far as the students
who don't pay,
they should be advised
that we don't want
lazy people here,
nor criminals of any kind.
So we're gonna do
a little house cleaning.
As you can see,
the priests are gone.
And they should be forgotten.
Which means if rumors about them
continue to circulate,
I'll assume you're the source.
Is that clear?
Yes.
Good.
Hang this in back
for everyone to see.
The following students...
Hamilton,
Kucevic, Orellana,
Vildosola
and Parraguez,
gather your things
and go to the office.
Right now?
Yes, darling. Right now.
- Where are they going?
- They're expelled, stupid.
Remember, Lord, your Church
spread across the land,
Pope John Paul,
and especially our honorable
government the Junta.
Let your light guide them
as they rebuild
this torn country.
This place is not sacred anymore.
The Lord
is no longer here.
Teachers, have the students
return to their classrooms.
Mama?
Come in.
How was school?
Fine. Where's Mama?
She went out.
She'll be back later.
And my sister?
She isn't back yet.
Go get changed.
I don't want the laundry
to pile up.
I'll make you a snack.
Get out here,
you fucking communist!
Fucking military!
Bastards!
No, Juana!
Stay out of this!
- Stay back!
- Shut up!
Can't you see I have a baby?
You like flags, asshole?
Go on, eat them!
Hold this bitch!
Leave her alone,
you fucking bastards!
Dad!
Shut up!
Everyone to the truck!
To the truck!
Turn around, you piece of shit!
Eat it, you fucker!
Shut up, bitch!
Turn around, you scumbag!
Get down, you fuck!
Hold it right there!
All the women in the truck!
Turn the fuck around!
Turn around, dammit!
Where do you think you're going?
No! I don't live here.
I have nothing to do with it.
- I live across the river.
- Don't lie to me.
Get moving!
- I don't live here!
Look at me!
Go on, scram.
You're supposed to die!
- Hi, Lucy.
- Hi, Gonzalo.
...with a friend. We were eating fries
and everything spilled.
On the table.
And they snubbed us...
No, don't step on the carpet!
Over there, please.
Through that door.
Hi, sweetie.
Are you okay?
Are you happy?
I'll be right back.
FIFA TELLS THE WORLD
THAT LIFE IN CHILE IS NORMAL
Thanks.
In memory of
Father Gerardo Whelan,
Principal of Saint George's School
in Santiago from 1969 to 1973.