You gotta put the fuel
in first, dickhead!
Uh, fuel from the lawnmower.
- Oh, sweet.
- Here's a better one.
Fuckin' fuel, fuel, fuel.
Come on, Bug.
Pour it in. Come on, guys.
Where's the rag?
Give me that.
And be careful, now, Bug.
Light it up.
Oh! Here we go, boys!
Here we go!
Come on, give it here.
Oh! Mad bastard!
Come on, Bullet! Come on!
Gotcha!
Bullet! Jeez, boy!
What were you thinking?
Eh?
Uncle Texas!
What the hell? What's going on?
Bullet! It WAS you! What the fuck
do you think you're doing?!
- What do you care?
- What?!
What... what's happening?
What's... what's going on?
You stink.
Nella.
Nella, give me back
my fuckin' cigarettes, hey?
Fuck off, you mob!
My son could be going to jail!
Uncle Tex...
what's gonna happen
to my baby?
Got to find a place
to hide my head
A shady billabong
Crash out on a cyclone bed
Maybe time will right the wrongs
But nothing really matters
In the season of the lullin'
Yeah, nothing really matters
When you're rolling on the run
Drifting off in dreamland
Cops and journos on my trail
Trying to pin me down
with slander
Trying to haul me off to jail
But nothing really matters
In the season of the lullin'
No, nothing really matters
When you're rolling on the run.
Raise your arms.
Turn around.
What's this, then?
Well, what do you reckon it is?
You know the rules.
Fuckin' men in uniform, unna?
Your brother's waiting.
He's my blood, bro.
Just like you.
Mum won't even let him talk to me.
They brought him in here
to visit you, or what?
What do you reckon?
Mum and Candy grow him up now.
They probably tell him his dad's dead.
- So, how old's yours now?
- My what?
I thought you went up there
to visit him.
Yeah. I was gonna.
But it's a long fuckin' way.
I've just got one thing to say to you.
Don't leave it too late, Thomas.
Here.
I made it myself.
Woodwork class.
Yeah, well, I can see that.
It's Dylan's birthday this weekend.
He turns six.
Oh, no. No, bro. No way.
Come on, bro. Just take it to him.
He's at Mum's.
True, brother, Mum don't like me
more than she don't like you.
TJ. Kudda.
Please.
Shirl...
what's all this stuff here?
That's for that Five Rivers men's group
you wanted to start up.
What do they need?
Uh, just the infrastructure cost.
Oh... pretty much, we need...
sausages and...
- Yep.
- bread and...
butter and tomato sauce and...
Yeah.
They like an informal
environment, you know?
Just somewhere to sit down and talk
and have something to eat.
That's all they need.
How's the homework going, bub?
Good.
Won't be long, bud.
For fuck's sake!
Mum! Shithead's here.
- G'day, Mum.
- What do you want?
I've been to see Mick.
What do you think you're doing?
Don't you go bringing
your dirty business around here.
You know, I went to see Mick.
He made this for Dylan
for his birthday.
Solid, huh?
- He's got a nerve.
- What the fuck...?
I don't want you boys
around my grandson.
Come on. Mum!
Get!
Fuck!
- What are you guys doing?
- Nothing.
Got any drink?
- Nah, not mine.
- Nah, it's the last one.
Come on, give me a fuckin' drink.
What the fuck? Get the fuck off me.
I just want a fuckin' drink of beer!
- It's fuckin' hot out here.
- Fuckin' too bad!
Well, the boys are down there.
Want to go see them?
Yeah.
Thank you, boys, for coming.
You blokes had a good feed?
Yeah? That's good.
This is our first...
men's group meeting,
and I'd like to welcome you all here.
The reason I wanted to get this going
is to bring men together,
sit down and have a talk.
You want to talk about
marriage problem,
you know, alcohol problem,
all that sort of thing.
And this is about... making you...
sort of, feel a little bit important,
so you don't feel like
no-one care about you.
Well, to kick it off,
I might just sort of ask
if anyone want to say anything.
Any of you boys want to...
talk about something that...
that you want to get off your chest?
- Hey!
We only just started
and we've run out already.
Bring that stuff inside.
Hey! Spider! Howthe fuck are you?
Yeah, good, brother.
- TJ, look who's here.
- Spider.
- How are you going, mate?
- How are you going, bud?
- Yeah, always good, yeah.
- When did you get out?
- About two months.
- Solid. Staying under the radar?
They've got a tight leash on me,
the parole dogs. You get that.
What were you pushing in there?
Weights?
- Me best, son.
- Yeah, straight out.
Come on!
You've got to pay attention.
Youse are getting flogged.
Eh? They reckon you're the man
around here, mate.
I find it very hard to believe.
Shot!
- You DO want it!
- No, I don't!
You've been acting
like this all night!
- Get outta my fuckin' house!
- You're just a fuckin' slut!
What do you fuckin' think
you're doing?!
- Oi!
- Fuck off!
- Come here!
- Don't touch me!
Come here!
Don't miss that.
Oh! Look at that one.
- Just letting you catch up.
- The 50's in the wallet, Eddie.
The 50's in the wallet, mate.
Hey, hey, hey!
Settle down, settle down!
- Come on, come on!
- Hey, hey, hey! Let go!
Another lucky shot, mate. Jesus!
You're playing the game
of your life, mate.
You're playing
the game of your life.
Huh? You're on fire.
Hey! Nella! Nella!
Come on! Break it up!
You bastard!
You useless prick!
Fuck you! Hey?
TJ, what are you doin'
picking on your little mate?
Hey?
Fuck! TJ!
Get out of here,
you fuckin' arsehole!
Get out of here, you fuckin' bastard!
Get him! Get him off me!
Fuck him up, bro!
Fuck him up!
Fuck him up, brother!
- Uncle Texas!
- Bullet! Get back in the yard!
Uncle Texas! Uncle Texas!
Damien! Damien, that's enough!
- Uncle Texas, look here!
- Joseph, that's enough.
- Uncle Texas, look here...
- Nella, get back in that yard!
Now, you two, fuck off now!
Otherwise somebody's getting
locked up.
Get out of here. Now!
Alright, that's it. Nella!
No! No! Fuck you! Fuck you!
Fuck you, arsehole!
Keep going, boys.
Keep walking down that way.
You mob, get.
Bullet.
Get back down to my place.
You're not staying here tonight.
Go on.
Look, Aunty, I hate to do this to you...
But, TJ, why do you
want to go all the way up there?
You haven't even
been there before. Hey?
'Cause I got fuckin' nowhere else to go.
Oh, TJ, you're such a mess.
Listen to you.
You've just gotta sit down
and sort yourself out for once.
Aunty, I know what I've gotta do
and I'm doing it.
But... Mum won't even see me,
and... I've got no money.
- TJ, TJ.
- Are you able to help me out?
Listen, TJ, I'll put
some money into your account.
But please be careful up there, bub.
Yeah, Aunty.
Just remember I love you
and my prayers will always be with you.
You know, Aunty, I love you so much.
You've always been there for me.
You got swimming today, babe?
- Yeah.
- Yep.
How was your night, babe?
Oh, flat out.
- Bloody chaos.
- Yep.
Had a big blue
at bloody Nella's place last night.
Stupid. It's just madness.
I wonder when that lot's gonna stop.
Knock knock!
Everybody OK?
Alright.
Oh.
Nella!
Hello?
Who this?
Hello? Hello?
Anybody there?
Oh, come on! What was that?
Go on, son, get it.
Come on, bud.
Come on, Bullet.
Come on, Bullet, come. Come play.
What's the matter?
What's the matter, mate?
I don't want to go away
from you guys, Grandpa.
Well...
I don't want you to go either,
mate, but... you know...
you've got to think
about what you done.
I mean, lighting fires -
people get locked up for that, mate.
You know? I mean...
You've got to take some responsibility
for your actions, you know?
Well, what's that camp gonna be like?
Two weeks out there is better
than six months in jail.
And they'll teach you how to act
a bit more like a man.
One, two, three, four...
Moonlight glitter on the bay
Like teardrops rolling in the waves
Rumba
Ukulele play
Songs of yesterday
Calypso
Can you limbo?
Cha-cha, old-time disco
Hula-hula, wobbly nura
Pretty girls and frangipanis
Moonlight glitter on the bay
Like teardrops rolling in the waves
Rumba
Ukulele play
Songs of yesterday
Six guitars, a thousand stars
Is a long, long way
from the smoky bars
'Pearly Shells' and 'Old TI'
Rattling with the spoons
late into the night
Matchstick picking
on a fishing line string
Play the melody
just to make 'em sing
Under the mango tree
With those pretty girls
and frangipanis
Moonlight glitter on the bay
Like teardrops rolling in the waves
Rumba
Ukulele play
Songs of yesterday...
Any smoke, my boy?
Here, last one, yeah?
Thank you, my boy.
You look... you're not from this country.
From down Perth way. Down south.
Jumbardu.
- Jumbardu. Any tubacca?
- Any smoke?
Nothing! Only last one
this young fella bin have 'em.
You good young fella.
Thank you for smoke.
No worries, Uncle.
Calypso
Can you limbo?
Cubba-cubba, old-time disco
Hula-hula, wobbly nura
Pretty girls and frangipanis
Moonlight glitter on the bay
Like teardrops rolling in the waves
Rumba
Ukulele play
Songs of yesterday
In the moonlight
Rumba
Ukulele play
In the moonlight
'Pearly Shells' and singing
Under the mango tree
In the moonlight.
Nella.
Is she there?
Is Nella there?
So tell me exactly what he said now.
Exactly what happened.
Well, the phone rang. I answered it.
This bloke was there.
He was asking for you.
I told him you weren't here.
I said, "Who's this?"
He said, "It's TJ.
"Tell her I'm coming up".
And did he say where or when?
Nuh. He just said he was coming.
Fuck.
Same time you know
he's talking shit, but, eh?
Yeah.
He been ringing up again.
I heard Mum and all them mob
talking.
Little firebug.
And what did they say?
They just reckon he coming here.
Your proper dad?
What do you reckon he'll be like?
Mum reckon he... Mum reckon
he a bit of a wild fella.
She don't like him that much.
I wouldn't mind meeting him.
Hey.
Hey, g'day, mate.
How far you going?
Hey, gully.
That Yagoo round?
Righto, boys. Just out here.
What, they think
we're gonna stop for them?
What the fuck is going on here?
They'd better move.
I don't think
they're gonna move!
Come on, come on!
Get out of the way!
- Come on!
- Move, move!
Jesus!
- What the fuck?
- Hang on. Pull up. Pull up!
That's Uncle Black.
What's that old bugger doing out here?
What's all that about?
Oh, here we go.
We can't fit 'em all in.
Jesus, we nearly run you mob
over. What's wrong with you?
Next time, bro.
We can't fit you all in.
You'll have to try
the next car coming there.
Hey, Uncle Black,
what you doin' here?
Trying to go home.
I want a lift to Five Rivers.
Hop in. Jump in the back.
Hello, my boy.
I think I know you.
Hey.
You got a smoke?
They've been, sort of,
smoking ganja and drinking
and running amok, you know?
One boy there - petrol-sniffer.
Keep an eye on that one.
And that other boy there with
the black shirt with that...
- Yeah, yeah.
- My little granny, that one.
I don't want you and Harry
to pull up on him.
Be a little bit fuckin' hard
on him, you know?
- Oh, yeah.
- Don't ease up on him.
Look at this shit!
I don't even want to go
outside anymore.
Bullet's gone to the fuckin' camp
'cause he's a run-amok kid
and everything's just falling apart.
Why do you think that is?
Why do you think your son
is running around at night
like a madman?
'Cause he's a little shit!
I feel like slapping you, girl.
You want to wise up.
And you want to wise up real quick.
OK.
No, don't be rough with the swag.
You're gonna sleep on that.
OK, take your stump and sit down.
OK?
Hey, you know...
you know why you're here?
'Cause you've been mucking around.
That's why you're here. You know?
What about you?
What are you in trouble for?
You been chasin' girls? Huh?
Stealing in a shop.
Robbing a shop?
I don't know what
we're gonna do with you.
What about you, Bullet?
What have you done wrong?
- Lighting fire.
- Lighting fire!
You know, that's a serious thing too.
Well, we're gonna be walking
through countries.
Over these creeks, over them hills.
There mightn't be any water, but...
we'll survive.
You see lovely country, you know,
when you get up on top
of the hill, looking down.
Sleeping in the bush,
you can hear the dingoes
howling at night.
And get up in the morning and
you hear the birds calling out.
People call it desert,
but to us, it's lovely to see the place
our grandfathers
and grandmothers come from.
We're trying to save you blokes
from going to jail, you know?
That's why you're here.
You alright, my boy?
Hello, young fella. You look worried.
What's the matter, my boy?
You got trouble anywhere?
Young fella, you must be got
family trouble, look like.
I wouldn't know where to start.
Wouldn't know where
to start to tell you.
I got a little man inside of me
with an axe.
And that little man,
I like to keep him quiet...
but sometimes I've got
no control over it.
I fuckin' just wish there was...
I got this fuckin' little man
inside of me...
with this fuckin' axe.
This is very, very hard country.
As we move along, we've got to
find something to eat.
And that's the only way we're
gonna survive here, you know?
Don't think there's no tucker.
We've got to find it.
You can get a goanna.
You can get a snake.
You boys know
that we've got nothing on us,
so, um... we've got a long way to go.
Oh! Shit.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Get him.
I remember very, very clear...
this old grandfather of mine,
a bloke called Nebatabiji.
I remember this day,
he's carrying me.
I must have been about five, six.
And he was a big man.
He had dogs running out,
chasing kangaroos.
And this one kangaroo
come straight for him.
And the kangaroo must have been
coming about 100 miles an hour.
He got the spear
hooked up on a woomera.
Threw it from the hip shooter.
He got that kangaroo
right through the chest.
And I said to myself, "Jingo!
"One day, I'm gonna be like this man".
So I grew up trying to be
somebody like him.
Hey, look at them mad bastards!
Hey! That my gully car.
My nephew car.
Pull up! Pull up!
- Hey, what happening, gully?
- Hello, gully.
Oh, we just here making a bit of dust.
- How you like that?
- We can come with you?
- No worries. Yeah.
- Jump on!
Oh! Shit.
Bloody good, yeah! Whoo!
Fuckin' oath. Fuckin' oath!
We go dancing tonight
or what, Unc?
Mama says
she want to dry her eyes
She don't like crying
Trying hard to forget
her younger days
Kids are wonderin'
why she doesn't sing along
Maybe she's dying...
Come on, Wazza!
Let's have a party here!
Come on, Wazza.
Let's run amok, brother!
Fuckin' car!
Oh!
- What was that?
- Whoa, pull up!
Pull up, pull up, pull up!
Oh, shit.
He might fuckin' blow up,
the bastard! Come on!
Come on, get out!
Get out of there, Wazza!
- It's ruined now!
- Fuck!
Get out of there!
Oh, fuck!
There goes the ride, boys.
We'll be fuckin' walking from here.
You can have a little bit
of rest here today.
Another walk tomorrow morning.
And tomorrow morning, a long walk.
Must be something...
something in you, eh?
Something bothering you?
I don't know.
Why are you so angry?
I guess it's my mum.
She not really round much.
She always out drinking.
Alright. But, um...
you gonna straighten up?
If you keep on doing this,
you're not going to be with your family.
You're gonna be locked up
all the time.
Hello, hello, my brother.
Hey, bro.
What happened here?
Those young fellas give us lift,
me and this young fella here.
And then it blow up on us.
Is that Wazza's car?
Yeah.
Where's all the piss?
All got burnt up in his motor car.
We can get a lift?
Yeah.
Alright.
Jimmy!
How are you, fella?
What are you doing up here, mate?
Just cruising. Passing through.
You don't look like
you're from up these parts.
You look like
a bit of a sheep-eater to me.
What the fuck's that
supposed to mean?
What I mean by that...
is, what the fuck
are you doing up here?
I might be looking for work.
Might go work out in the mines.
Might be up here on a holiday.
Working on my tan.
Scratching my balls in the sun.
When I see fuckin' shit, I know shit.
And you look like
fuckin' shit to me, pal.
I'm not gonna go there.
You're just trying to get
a rise out of me
so you've got a reason
to lock me up.
I know coppers like you.
Yeah? I've been in the city
with coppers. You know?
Yeah, well,
you're up here now.
Five Rivers is my fuckin' turf.
And I don't like
when fuckin' cunts come up here
and think they can hide away
up this end of the world.
You fuck up up here, pal...
and you'll fuckin' deal with me.
Look, I've got a young fella
up here I'm visiting.
Yeah?
My son, actually.
I mean, if you're running
from something...
I'll find out, pal.
Jesus! Fuck!
What's wrong with this fella here?
What's he doing?
I don't know, my boy.
Are you here to see Nella?
Yeah.
Well, I know who
your fuckin' boy is, then, boy.
I really know who your son is.
Put your head under the water.
- Yep. Alright.
- Ready... go!
Get him! Grab him by the tail!
Run!
Whoo!
Last day today, boys.
We'd better hurry up.
You want to see your girlfriend?
Come on, get in front.
Don't let the old fella lead you.
I'm glad I'm going home.
I'm gonna have a shower.
Hello, hello, my countrymen!
Look who's back.
Hello again!
What, you been swimming, eh?
Thomas.
You need to sort out
what you come here for.
So don't go wandering, eh?
Hey, Black. See you, brother.
- See you, mob.
- See you, brother.
- How are you going?
- Hello.
Got to find a place
to hide my head
A shady billabong
Crash out on a cyclone bed
Maybe time will right the wrongs
But nothing really matters
In the season of the lullin'
Yeah, nothing really matters
When you're rolling on the run
Drifting off in dreamland
Cops and journos on my trail
Trying to pin me down with slander
Trying to haul me off to jail
But nothing really matters
In the season of the lullin'
No, nothing really matters
When you're rolling on the run.
Hey.
So, what, did you expect
some big welcoming party, did you?
I just want to see him, Nella.
Reckon we should be counting
our fuckin' blessings?
The great man has arrived?
I've come a long fuckin' way.
So you should!
And you're 13 years late!
He's not here.
He's not sitting around waiting for you
just 'cause you phoned
and said you were coming.
- Yeah, well, good...
- I only made that mistake once.
Yeah, well, good to see you all
fuckin' glamorous and perfect
with your fucked-up lives here.
This place is a shithole.
Well, no-one asked you to come!
You know, me and you had
that great time all those years ago,
but all you've fuckin' done since then
is lie to me and fuck up that boy.
He don't give one shit about you.
Have you got any idea
the fuckin' shit I've been through
the last couple of fuckin' years?
I don't care!
I don't give a shit, Thomas!
Just go.
You're not here to be real
and you're not here
to be no father, so fuck off!
Yeah, well, I'm not gonna listen
to this fuckin' shit anyway!
Yeah, good.
There you go, TJ.
Cheers.
- Cup of tea?
- Ah. Thank you, sis.
How are you, my boy?
He don't need me.
He better off without me anyway.
You right, Grandpa?
Yep.
This is mammoditch place here,
Uncle, this country.
That's a Noongar word.
It means 'the best'.
Bet you fellas have got a big mob
of sacred places round here.
Oh, big mob round here, my boy.
On our river down in Perth...
our sacred site,
where the Wakkal, he had
his final resting place there...
they built a road... there,
and a bridge.
The whitefellas even built
a brewery on it.
Right on the freshwater spring.
I used to go there
when I was a little fella.
Throw rocks at that poxy place.
But this country here,
it's like medicine.
This is my son's country.
He's here now?
Yep.
So he's... really here?
Yes, bub.
Mmm.
But, Mum, you said that he not...
I knowwhat I said, bub.
And you don't have to see him
if you don't want to.
But he is here.
Do you reckon he'll like us?
Course he will, baby.
But why'd he come now?
Nella!
I want to see him!
Nella, you can hate me,
but I want to see my son.
You fellas can talk
to each other, you know.
You want to go for a walk, mate?
That's alright with you?
Hmm?
All I'm saying is just have
a little bit of patience.
He come long way, you know?
At least he's here.
Yeah, it's just... it's hard.
'Cause he's been running around
for 13 years,
acting like he doesn't care,
and now I don't know
what to expect from him.
And, what, you're perfect?
Well, at least I've stopped drinking.
Good.
Anyone?
Fair enough.
Maybe a bit too soon, eh?
Maybe as we go along,
people can start feeling comfortable
in saying something.
We'll try again next week, eh?
It's good.
So, where's
TJ and Bullet today?
Watching the footy.
That's what my husband
used to do with his sons.
Watch the footy!
- That's true, Aunty.
- That's right.
They might have even said
a few words to each other by now.
Catfish swimming
In the brown water mud
Salt water running
Through the fresh river flood...
You know what?
I heard you've got to watch out
for the crocs, eh?
You get pretty big crocs up here?
- Mmm.
- I've never seen a crocodile.
You've got a deadly haircut there.
Who does your hair?
Me and my mates cut it.
Solid.
Rivers and lakes
Where the rain comes down
We're gonna wash them blues away
When the rain comes down
On a hot summer's day...
Hey.
TJ. How are you going?
Yeah, Elvis.
And a-one, two,
one, two, three, four...
Dust flies up and it's dry as hell
Fire breaks out like a magic spell
Twisting and a-turning
like some big old snakes
Veins through the land,
rivers and lakes
When the rain comes down
Gonna wash
them blues away, yeah
Oh, when the rain comes down
On a hot summer's day, yeah.
I'll see you during the week.
I'm sure you'll be here.
Got to go. Goodnight.
Somebody's gotta work.
See you mob tomorrow.
- See you, girls.
- Goodnight, Uncle.
Thank you.
- Friday night, eh?
- Friday night in Five Rivers.
Fuckin' alright.
Last sip of wine
Last cigarette
I've lived a full life
I have no regrets
Oh, man, my patience is tired
My brain's always wired
Oh, the pain in our hearts
Tore us apart
How we gonna find a fantasy?
Something special
just for you and me?
Kinda happy
but it still feels sad...
I see you've still got the tatt.
Been trying to scrub it off for years.
Want some of this?
I don't drink.
You're joking.
I'm not gonna bite you.
I'm the father of your son.
Oh, come on.
This is a bad idea.
No, it's not.
It's just two people dancing.
For the want and more
A strain on the core
Oh, now, the hold and the truth
Is something aloof
How we gonna find a fantasy?
Something special
just for you and me
Kinda happy
but it stills feels sad
Kinda sane but a little mad...
Mmm... I can't do this, eh?
What do you mean, you can't do this?
I mean I fucking can't do this, TJ!
I can't be with you.
Fuck.
So, that's what it is, eh?
I'm not fuckin' good enough for you?
What are you fucking...?!
Fuck off!
Oh, typical fuckin' TJ.
Got to start smashing shit up.
- Get!
- Hey, mate.
Get out!
Baby, put it down.
It's alright. He's gone.
Bullet?
Will you rise
or will you fall?
Will you walk or will you crawl?
Will you dream in black and white
When you're sleeping cold tonight?
Will you bend or will you break?
Will you give or will you take?
Will no angel shine no light?
I need to get out of here, Aunty.
I need to come back home.
I'm sorry, my boy,
but I can't do it anymore.
I'm tired. I'm sick
of worrying about you.
Just book my bus fare.
I gotta get out of this shithole!
You're a grown man now.
You've got to stand
on your own two feet.
Fuck ya!
I know there's a bag of shit
in your pocket. Hand it over!
Or this fella's gonna cop it.
And this fella, that fella, and you!
Hand it over now!
Would you fail or would you leave?
Would you stand your ground
and fight
When I'm sleeping cold tonight?
Way, oh, way
Way, oh, way, oh, way, oh, I.
You little cunt!
What did I tell you?!
I warned you, gave you
all the possible chances,
and you fucked it up.
Who the fuck
do you think you are?
Just one of those fuckin' coppers
who thinks his fuckin' shit
doesn't stink.
Is that right?
- Hey? You don't know me, pal.
- Fuck!
Fuck you. I always wanted
to flog a copper.
Well, come on, then! Get up!
That's what you want?
That's how you want it?
I was gonna cap that, you little prick!
We've all been through the shit
up here, bro.
And I don't want my family
putting up with no more.
That's your ticket out of here.
The bus comes in half an hour.
I know I might come across
as a bit of a hard bastard,
but, you know... amongst
all the chaos and bullshit...
somebody's got to be strong
for everyone, you know?
But you're my grandson's father.
And you belong to us now.
If that's what you want.
Bullet, open the door!
Go away! Leave me alone!
Come on, baby.
I don't want to see you.
I don't want to see anybody!
Bullet!
That's enough, baby.
Come on. Come out.
Baby, come on.
Nella.
This is your damage.
You fuckin' fix it.
Just leave me alone!
Hey, mate.
Go away. Leave me alone.
Bullet, it's me, mate. Your dad.
I hate you, you dog.
I hate you.
Come on, mate. Let me in.
I said go away. Are you deaf or what?
Go on, get!
Hello?
Deadly, unna, them birds?
What did you come here for?
I come here to see you.
You seen me.
Now you can go.
No, mate.
I don't believe you.
I know.
But you will.
I, uh... just want to share that...
I've had a pretty...
pretty hard week.
A few things with my family.
Had to sort a few things out.
Little... few things
with my grandson and...
My... my boy's been
like a son to me. I've...
You guys know...
I've grown my grandson up
from a... from a baby,
and... we all need a man in our life.
A father... father figure.
Um... I've never had
that opportunity, but...
I'm glad that my grandson's
father's here to be with him.
Mmm.
But it's good to see
his father turn up here,
and... I'm sort of...
proud that he's here to see his son.
Yeah.
Got to find a place
to hide my head
A shady billabong
And crash out on the cyclone bed...
I grew up basically going to...
well, getting locked up.
I basically got locked up
before I was 10 years old.
Getting locked up.
I was in that process
before I was 10 years old.
I grew up, um, witnessing
domestic violence.
I've consequently been through
some relationships
with domestic violence.
And it's hard when you're there.
Um, and if you're... you know...
if you end up
being one of those women...
that can step outside and look
at what's actually going on
and realise that you don't want
that for your life...
And even if you've only been
locked up for one night...
and you wake up in a prison cell...
and you're coming down off
the drink and the drugs and...
You know, and then they read
in your sheet, they...
When they release you,
they're saying to you...
You know, you're obviously
signing your release papers,
and it's like, "Oh, assault," you know?
And then you're like, "Fuck,"
and start thinking about that
poor bastard lying in hospital
that you beat the crap out of,
you know?
And he's just gonna be going around,
"Well, I just got beaten up
by a drunken blackfella".
You know?
And then there's a...
You know, I'd have...
You know, I'd start crying.
Then it went to drinking really bad.
And it was a choice.
I think the biggest thing for me
was my kids.
I got to a point where... I thought,
"Well, if I really love my kids,
I should give it another go,"
you know?
And maybe change my ways, get a job.
Here I am in denial about
so many things, and I'm a man.
Fuckin' bullshit, you know.
I wasn't... You know, I haven't...
I've only just started to become a man...
in the last fuckin' three years,
you know?
Because I was blaming other...
blaming, you know?
And a bit of that poor fella me
would come out in my drinking...
and then I'd, like, turn that
into rage, you know?
That's why a lot of those kids
go the wrong way,
walking the street
and doing what they want to do,
trying to find something,
and something they find,
maybe the wrong people,
they mix up with,
and that is the people
that get into trouble.
It is different when they get out there
in a different environment, you know?
You know, once you get 'em
away from town,
they're different kids.
They love it.
And that's why I like taking them out.
The first sergeant I worked with,
he said to me one day,
he said, "The best copper
is an ex-crim".
'Cause you think like them, you know?
You know what they're thinking
and you can...
Body language,
you know all that shit,
because you've done all that crap.
And you can only do that
sober or clean, you know?
You can't...
No use getting drunk and then
getting emotional, you know?
You've got to get emotional
and cry when you're sober,
and go through that
over a long period of time.
I'm the kind of woman that
clashes with a mad bastard,
because I can be pretty mad
myself, so... yeah.
Yeah, the biggest fight
I've ever had in my life...
is within myself.
And the hardest fight is with me.
And, yeah, I'm still fighting.
I'm still having that fight.
A mad bastard, he's not really,
really mad. He's in between.
He can be a good man
when he's sober..
and he can be a mad bastard
when he's drunk.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But it might seem to be mad,
but... it's not.
But it's just a good...
good name for that movie.