Are you the doctor?
Yes. Climb on.
Rouault's one of the richest
around here.
He broke his leg after a night's
drinking.
It's that way.
His wife died 2 years ago.
His daughter runs the house now.
Wait.
Follow me.
Oh, excuse me!
The doctor, father.
Doctor, I've broken my leg.
Let's have a look at it.
It's a neat fracture, nice and
clean.
I'll make you a splint.
We'll need to have some little
pads made too.
Can you do that, Emma?
This should do it.
- Will it take long to set?
- Two months.
Perhaps less. I'll call back to see
you...
in three days.
Emma, show the doctor out.
Good-bye, mademoiselle.
I'd like to know your name.
Charbovari.
Pardon me?
Charles Bovary.
See you in three days, doctor.
M. Rouault. What a surprise!
Look. A doctor in Yvetot couldn't
have done better.
Even one in Rouen!
Here.
Here's what I owe you.
I don't owe you this but I'm happy
to give it to you.
You're a widower too, I hear.
Yes, for eight months now.
When I lost my poor wife...
I'd go to the fields to be alone.
I'd fall at the foot of a tree,
crying...
and raving at the good Lord.
When I thought of others holding
their dear wives...
I nearly went crazy.
I'd hit the ground with my stick. I
couldn't eat.
You won't believe me...
but the idea of going to the cafe
sickened me.
And then, slowly...
one day followed another...
spring followed winter and
autumn came after summer...
it faded away...
it drained away bit by bit...
it went away.
Stir yourself, M. Bovary.
You'll see, you'll get over it.
Yes, I'm sure I will.
Come and see us.
My daughter...
talks of you sometimes...
she says you've forgotten her.
We'll ferret out a rabbit for you,
to cheer you up.
Monsieur Charles! How kind to
come and see us.
Father's running around all over
the place, thanks to you.
Let me offer you a drink.
No, thank you.
Really.
Come on, let's drink. I'm thirsty.
I'm disturbing you...
I've had dizzy spells for a month
now.
Would sea-bathing do me good?
Sea-bathing?
That's good... for dizzy spells.
At the convent, I'd pretend to
faint.
The nuns would all rush over.
Why did you do that?
To be fussed over.
Come with me.
I like music, but the classes were
so dull.
This was a prize for arithmetic...
and this one for reading.
This one too.
My poor mother was so proud of
me with my laurels.
On the first Friday of the month...
I pick flowers from the garden for
her grave.
I'd like to live in town.
At least in winter.
There again, summer days are so
long, they're even duller.
Don't you think?
Maitre Rouault!
M. Bovary!
I've something to say to you.
Tell me then... Perhaps I already
know what it is.
M. Rouault...
There's nothing I'd like better...
and I expect the lass agrees...
but we must ask her opinion.
Now, this is what we'll do:
I'll go home but don't bother
coming.
All the workers are there for
supper.
It would be a shock for her.
But so as you won't fret, if it's
yes...
I'll push the shutter back against
the wall.
You can see it from behind the
barn.
Are you happy?
Yes. But I'd have liked a midnight
wedding, by torch-light.
It's a fine day.
That it is!
Charles, you have to cut it.
Go on, Charles, cut it.
Cut it, cut it!
I'm counting on you, dear...
to make my Charles happy at last.
He's so deserving.
I'll put the trap away. Wait here.
Nastasie, this is Madame.
Emma, this is Nastasie, the
housekeeper.
I haven't cooked.
That was wise. We aren't hungry.
You can go to bed, Nastasie.
Do you want to see my surgery?
I'll see it tomorrow.
I want to go to bed.
Nastasie!
Madame's hungry and so am I. What
can we have?
I've made soup.
Good but we need a choice.
Some chocolate or tea.
We haven't any.
Emma!
What do you want to eat? What
would you really like?
I don't know, I don't mind.
Some soup?
Yes, soup. That's fine.
You're later every day.
Yes, I know. But it's a good sign.
I've more and more patients.
You must be tired.
A little, yes.
Come and eat. I've made some
gruel.
Where's Nastasie?
It was late. I sent her to bed.
I don't want to keep her.
She's too old.
As their life together became
more intimate...
a growing detachment distanced
her from him.
Charles'conversation was as flat
as a pavement.
It's going to rain.
His borrowed ideas trudged past
in colourless procession...
without emotion, laughter or
dreams.
Well, I think so.
O God, why did I get married?
Home already?
I still have two patients to see.
I've come...
I sent your bills to M. Pommier
and Mme Loubet.
That's good.
Remember the Marquis
d'Andervilliers?
The abscess in his mouth...
He asked us for some cherry-tree
cuttings.
I never saw him.
No, but you will see him.
Just think, he's invited us to his
ball.
Us?
Yes. To his grand ball!
It is true? Is it really true?
Yes, honestly. In two weeks time.
Charles! Tell me, will I have a
pretty dress?
Of course.
Monsieur and Madame Bovary.
Don't rumple my dress.
Are you happy?
My shoes will be awkward for
dancing.
Dancing? They'd laugh at you! A
doctor doesn't dance!
Look! Champagne!
I'll get some.
That's kind.
- Castellane.
- Bovary.
Oh! Just right!
You danced well. You were very
graceful.
There are even more mysterious
sights:
Vesuvius at dawn, the rose
gardens of Genoa...
the Coliseum by moonlight.
Moonlight's beautiful everywhere.
You're radiant, dear Berthe.
Romulus and Miss Arabelle were
two lengths ahead.
I jumped the ditch. That's how to
win 2,000 pounds in England.
You're luckier than I. My horses
are running to fat.
Could you pick my fan up from
behind the sofa, sir?
Maxime, for pity's sake, it's too
hot.
Your wish is my command, my
dear.
Lucien!
Madame, may I?
Oh, but I'm hardly familiar with
the waltz.
I'll lead. You'll manage very well.
You, Vicomte!
She certainly knows how to waltz!
She probably has lots of practice.
We're among the last to leave.
Did you have fun?
It's the most beautiful day of my
life.
What is it?
I'm taking my boots off. My feet
are killing me.
The most beautiful day of my life.
The doctor from Yvetot didn't
agree...
With the treatment I gave old
Bouret.
The family looked pretty grim.
What did you answer?
Nothing.
What could I answer?
What?
You were humiliated by a man...
Who isn't your equal?
He didn't share my opinion nor I
his.
How dare he judge you! It's
shameful!
It doesn't matter.
Don't get so upset.
No, I won't stand for it!
What a pitiful man!
Secretly, she was waiting for
something.
Every day, on awakening, she
expected it.
She listened to every sound,
surprised when nothing came.
Then, at sunset, ever sadder...
she longed for the next day.
At that time, she hoped...
that the Marquis would give
another ball.
But September went by without a
letter or a visit.
She gave up music...
left her drawings and needlework
in the cupboard.
Sewing annoyed her.
"I've read everything," she'd say.
She sat holding the tongues in
the fire...
or watching the rain fall.
Charles had noticed his wife's
languor.
For a while, he didn't know what
to do...
then he made a secret decision...
hoping that what for him was a
great sacrifice...
would allow Emma's health to
improve.
Would you be sad...
to leave Tostes?
Why do you ask?
Because if you agree...
I've decided to open a practice in a
bigger town.
In Rouen?
No, not Rouen. Rouen's out of the
question.
In Yonville. It's almost a town.
It's at least four times bigger
than this place.
Are you sure?
If you want to, yes.
We'll start a new life.
I'll have to find new customers.
It'll be easy, I'm sure.
You're a good doctor, everybody
knows that.
Let's not take
Nastasie.
Careful, Felicite.
Yes.
Yes, ma'am.
My wedding bouquet.
- It was pretty.
- Yes.
Are you burning it, ma'am?
We're off...
to a new life.
When they left Tostes in March,
Madame Bovary was pregnant.
Be quiet, M. Homais, you pagan!
You've no religion!
One can worship God in a field...
or by gazing at the stars.
The Hirondelle's late.
My God is the God of Socrates,
Franklin, Beranger...
and Voltaire!
I can't believe in some old God in
his garden...
a stick in his hand, putting up his
friends in whales...
Who dies with a croak and revives
three days later.
It's quite absurd...
and opposed to all physical laws.
It indicates...
that priests live in total
ignorance...
and strive to drag people down
with them.
Here it is!
The Hirondelle!
Did you see Bourriches?
Is mother better?
You're late.
A passenger felt ill.
Forgive me for costing you
precious minutes.
Don't worry, madame. Let me
welcome you...
to our town. Good-bye for now.
Good-day, M. Homais.
M. Bovary, madame, I'm your
chemist, M. Homais.
I hope you had a good journey.
I'm pleased to welcome you to
Yonville.
Hippolyte!
Take in M. and Mme Bovary's bags.
You must be tired.
Our Hirondelle tosses you around
terribly.
That's true, but I like being shaken
up.
I like to move about.
It's so gloomy to be stuck in one
place.
M. and Mme Bovary, this is Leon
Dupuis...
clerk to our notary, Maitre
Guillaumin.
This is M. Bovary, our new doctor,
and his wife.
If you were like me, always on
horseback...
Medical practice isn't too hard in
these parts.
They pay pretty well.
Medically speaking, apart from
cases...
of bronchitis, enteritis, etc...
We have fevers at harvest time...
and, of course, scrofula...
due to the peasants' deplorable
conditions.
You'll have to fight superstition...
a lot of stubbornness...
They often resort...
to prayer, religion and the priest...
rather than coming to see the
doctor or the chemist.
The climate is temperate here.
We're sheltered from the north
wind by the Argueil Forest...
and from the west by St. Jean's
Hill.
However, this heat...
given off by the river's vapour...
and the herds of cattle...
which exhale ammoniac...
nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen...
Are there any walks here?
Very few.
There's the pasture...
up the hill at the edge of the
woods.
I sometimes take a book up there
at sunset.
Nothing's more wonderful than a
sunset.
Especially at the sea-side.
I love the sea!
Doesn't that expanse uplift your
soul?
Mountainscapes can be like that.
In Switzerland, for example...
And music?
I don't play but I like it a lot.
Don't listen to him, he's too
modest.
I've heard him singing in his room.
Leon lives just above my shop.
You were singing The Guardian
Angel like a professional.
What music do you like?
German.
It sets you dreaming.
Your house is one of the best here.
The advantage for a doctor...
is a rear door, so people can come
and go without being seen.
There's an arbour in the garden.
If madame likes gardening...
my wife isn't interested.
She much prefers reading in her
room.
I'm the same.
Reading by the fire, while a storm
rages...
isn't it lovely?
You forget, the hours pass...
you live with the characters.
You're right.
Have you ever found in a book...
the expression of your ideas...
and even the exact description of
your inner thoughts?
I have felt that.
It's my only distraction here.
Yonville has so few attractions.
It can't be worse than Tostes.
I belonged to a library there.
If you'll do me the honour, my
library is at your disposal.
I have Voltaire, Rousseau and
Walter Scott...
and every day The Rouen Beacon...
of which I am the local
correspondent.
If you'll excuse us, we shall
retire.
I talk and talk...
Mme Bovary must be exhausted.
Goodnight, madame, doctor.
A night in a strange place... How
exciting.
Goodnight.
Monsieur Homais!
It's over!
It's a girl.
During her convalescence, she
wondered about names.
She hesitated between Clara,
Amanda or Yseult.
Charles wanted her named for his
mother.
Emma was against this.
At last, she chose Berthe...
a name she had heard at the ball.
The baby was nursed by the
carpenter's wife.
One day, Emma felt a sudden need
to see her.
She set off for the nurse's abode
at the far end of the village.
- Good day, madame.
- M. Dupuis!
I'm going to see my baby but I feel
a little tired.
Are you busy? If not, you could
accompany me.
By nightfall, all Yonville knew.
Madame Tuvache, the mayor's
wife...
declared that...
Madame Bovary was
compromising herself.
Come on in. Your little one's
sleeping.
She's been sick.
I have to keep washing her.
Could you ask the grocer to let me
have soap when I need it?
I'll do that.
It's hard getting up at night.
I fall asleep in my chair.
A pound of coffee would last me a
month.
Forgive my insisting...
but my poor husband needs some
brandy.
I'll rub the baby's tender little
feet with it.
Some Spanish dancers, I forget
their name...
are coming to Rouen.
Will you go?
If I can.
Thank you for your company.
It was a pleasure, a real pleasure.
I'm so bored!
When Leon went to the Lion d'Or
to dine...
Mme Bovary trembled on seeing him...
and ordered...
dinner to be served.
Evening all!
M. Homais arrived during dinner.
He'd sit down between them...
and ask about the patients...
while the doctor inquired about
their resources.
Then they discussed the news...
which Homais knew by heart from the
paper.
At eight, Justin came for him to shut
up shop.
I think my lad's in love with your maid.
On Sundays, the chemist was host...
with Mme Homais and the children,
Napoleon and Athalie.
Leon never missed a Sunday gathering.
M. Homais played ecarte with Emma.
Leon stood behind her, giving advice.
Then the apothecary and the doctor
played dominoes.
Mme Bovary changed places; Leon sat
beside her.
She'd ask him to read poetry.
Leon recited in a slow voice...
which he carefully lowered in the love
passages.
"O, Time, suspend thy flight
"And you, auspicious hours
"Suspend your movement
"Let us savour
"The fast-fading delights of these
oh so happy days. "
He's charming! Charming!
He's surely in love!
But with whom?
Who can it be?
It's me!
If only Heaven had desired it!
Why isn't it so?
Who's to blame?
What is it?
M. Lheureux to see you.
M. Lheureux, the draper? What
does he want?
Madame, forgive me disturbing you
at home.
But I'm most distraught at not
having obtained...
your patronage as yet.
My modest shop can't attract...
a true lady of fashion.
I'd like you to know that you only
have to order...
and I'll supply all your needs...
in haberdashery, hosiery,
millinery and fancy goods.
I go to Rouen four times a month...
and I work with only the best
firms.
If you'll allow me...
I'd like to show you some
articles...
that are quite remarkable.
I don't need anything.
Just for the pleasure of looking.
How much is it?
A trifle, a mere trifle.
There's no hurry. Whenever you
like.
We're not Jews!
No, thank you, M. Lheureux.
I require nothing.
Well, we'll reach an understanding
later.
I've always got on well with the
ladies.
I mean, money doesn't worry me.
I'll even give you some if need be.
I wouldn't have to look far to find
it.
M. Bovary must have many
patients...
in this changeable weather.
I feel out of sorts myself.
I'll have to call on him...
about a pain I get in my back.
Well, good-bye, Madame Bovary.
As ever, your very humble servant.
Good-bye, M. Lheureux.
How good I've been.
Ma'am, it's Leon Dupuis.
Come in, M. Dupuis.
I have to go to Rouen on business.
Your subscription is up.
Should I renew it?
Why?
Because...
you're giving it up?
What? Music? Good Lord, yes!
I have a house, a husband...
I have much more important
duties.
Charles is so kind.
That he is.
M. Homais sings his praises.
He's a good man.
Indeed.
I've decided...
to take back Berthe and look after
her.
During visits...
Madame Bovary undressed the child to
show her limbs.
She'd say she adored children.
They were her comfort, joy and
weakness...
and she'd give herself over to poetic
outbursts.
Show your feet to M. Homais.
On Charles'return...
he found his slippers warming by
the fire.
His waistcoats were lined and
his buttons sewed back on.
She no longer resisted strolling
in the garden.
His suggestions were always
accepted...
and if she didn't guess his
wishes...
she submitted to them without a
murmur.
Why not tell the master?
It's just nerves. It would only
worry him.
It's like old Guerin's daughter
before I came to you.
She was so gloomy that if ever
you saw her...
you thought of a funeral shift in a
doorway.
They said she had a fog in her
mind...
that doctors and priests couldn't
help her.
Once she married, it went away.
With me, it came on after I
married.
Rascals! Always the same! Get
inside!
Hurry up! You too!
They've no respect!
How are you?
Not well. I'm suffering.
So am I! It's the weather.
Still, we're born to suffer, as St.
Paul says.
What does M. Bovary think?
I don't need earthly remedies.
Just you wait, Ribaudet, you
rascal!
I'd like to know...
That's Ribaudet, the carpenter's
son.
He's the ring-leader.
How's M. Bovary?
He and I must be...
the busiest people in the parish.
He tends to the body...
while I tend to the soul.
You relieve suffering.
You can say that! This morning...
I had to go and see a swollen cow.
They said it was cursed.
Will you stop that! You should be
ashamed!
As I was saying, farmers have a
hard life.
Others do too!
Oh, indeed! workers in the towns,
for example.
But women...
Ah, that's true!
I've known of mothers...
honest women, I assure you...
real saints...
who didn't even have bread.
But what of those, Father...
who have bread but no...
No fire in winter?
What does it matter?
What do you mean?
When one has warmth and food,
things...
Oh, my God!
What's wrong? Digestive trouble.
Go home, Mme Bovary, and have a
nice cup of tea.
No, no, it's...
I thought you were having a dizzy
spell.
You asked me something. What
was it?
I can't remember now...
Nothing.
You'll excuse me, Mme Bovary.
I have to deal with these urchins.
Poor things! It's hard showing
them the ways of the Lord...
as His Holy Son told us to do.
Take care, and my respects to
your husband.
Are you Christian?
Yes, I'm Christian.
What is a Christian?
He who is born baptised.
Mama...
Oh, leave me be!
Leave me alone!
It's strange how ugly she is.
Will you stop it?
I'm going mad!
I'm going mad! You poor dear!
Evening all!
Princess, what happened?
It's nothing.
She had a little fall.
Poor Emma was frantic with
worry.
I've some important news for you.
First, we stand a fair chance...
of having the Agricultural Show
here.
Really?
Yes, just think. The Prefect, all
the local authorities!
That will put us on the map.
That is important news.
And second?
It's a surprise. I'm losing my
tenant.
Leon is leaving for Paris next
week.
Heavens! Has he thought about it?
How will he live in Paris?
Will he get used to it?
Good Lord! Masked balls, dinner
parties, champagne!
He'll be in his element!
They have fun in the Latin Quarter!
If they've any social graces...
they move in the best circles.
Some grand ladies even fall in
love with them.
Afterwards, that enables them...
to make an excellent match.
I'll change plates. We've a tart.
Will you have some, M. Homais?
- It's me again.
- I knew it.
Is M. Bovary here?
No, he's out.
He's out.
I'd like to kiss Berthe.
Yes, of course.
Felicite!
Fetch Berthe for me!
Farewell, poor child!
Farewell, dear little one!
Take her.
It's going to rain.
I have my coat.
Good-bye, then.
Yes, good-bye... Go.
English style, then!
She now considered herself even
unhappier...
as she began to feel certain...
that her sorrow would never
end.
Could I see the doctor? I'm M.
Rodolphe Boulanger.
I'll fetch him.
Thank you for seeing us.
My valet needs bleeding, he has
pins and needles.
It'll purge me.
Good, let's do it.
Justin, get some bandages from
the drawer...
and bring the basin over.
Don't be afraid, my friend.
No, no, go ahead.
Look. It's like a little spring.
What red blood! Is that a good
sign?
Sometimes, they feel nothing at
first...
and then they faint.
I knew it.
Good Lord! Both of them!
Emma! Vinegar!
Hurry!
Hide the basin.
Sugar water.
You silly fool! A big lad like you!
You'll make a fine chemist!
Who asked you here? You're in the
way!
You know I need you on
wednesdays!
We've 20 customers in the shop!
I had to leave them to come and
get you.
Hurry up. Go and watch the jars!
Move out of the way.
Remarkable, a woman among these
fainting men!
Other people's blood doesn't affect
me.
But the idea of seeing my own
would make me faint...
if I thought about it.
You can stop worrying now you've
got what you wanted.
In any case, it gave me the joy...
of making your acquaintance.
Very nice, that doctor's wife.
Pretty teeth, a dainty foot, fine
clothes...
Where did that oaf find her?
She's probably bored with him.
While he's out, she mends his
socks!
She'd like to dance the polka in
town. Poor thing!
She's gasping for love like a fish
out of water.
A few gallant words and she'll
adore you!
How to get rid of her after?
Madame Bovary, you're quite
pretty and fresh!
I'll have her!
I'll have her! The Show's soon!
She'll be there.
The famous Show did indeed
arrive.
Everyone was merry...
but widow Lefrancois, talking
with M. Homais, looked...
very gloomy.
There's Lheureux.
He's selling the Cafe Francais.
He murdered old Tellier with his
bills.
what a terrible tragedy!
The cafe's sordid and I hate
Tellier...
but I don't like that wheedler
Lheureux.
Look, he's greeting Mme Bovary.
- Where?
- In the market.
I have a seat for her.
She's wearing a green hat.
She's on M. Boulanger's arm.
Quick, here's the apothecary!
A lovely day! Everyone's here! It's
an east wind!
Good-bye, M. Lheureux.
How you got rid of him!
Why be bothered by others...
as I'm here with you today?
Look at the daisies.
All those oracles for girls in love.
Should I pick one?
Are you in love?
Who knows?
Are you abandoning us?
Surely not. We'll be right back.
He can forget that! I much prefer
your company!
Here's the Prefect!
The Prefect couldn't come.
That's his main adviser.
Let's take a grandstand seat.
All this seems a great event for
them.
Oh, provincial mediocrity!
It stifles life and kills dreams.
You can see, dear lady, why I'm so
very sad.
I thought you were happy!
Outwardly, I am.
I must show a laughing face to the
world.
And your friends?
My friends?
What friends?
Who cares about me?
I miss so much by being alone.
If I had a goal in life, or
affection...
if I'd found someone, I'd have
overcome every obstacle.
You've no cause to complain.
You think not?
After all, you're free...
Rich.
Don't make fun of me.
That's not the Prefect!
It's Lieuvain, his right-hand man.
The decorations are very poor,
don't you think?
Obviously, the mayor was in
charge.
He's no artistic genius.
Gentlemen...
first of all let me say...
before talking...
of the object of today's
gathering...
and I'm sure these feelings...
will be shared by you...
allow me then...
to pay tribute to the Public
Services...
the Government...
the Monarch...
gentlemen, our Sovereign...
I should stand back.
Why?
I could be seen.
I'd have some explaining to do,
With my reputation...
- You exaggerate!
- No, it really is appalling.
From a certain point of view...
it's quite justified.
How?
Don't you know of tormented
souls?
They need dreams and action and
the purest of passion.
And so we throw ourselves into
fancies...
and madness.
We poor women don't have such
distractions.
They're sad indeed, if they bring
no joy.
Can it ever be found?
Yes.
You find it one day.
You find it when you thought it
lost.
Then new horizons open.
You confide everything in the
other...
sacrifice everything.
There's no talk, just intuition.
It's the person you've dreamt of.
However, you don't dare believe it.
You're dazzled as if coming from
shadows...
into the light.
Let's say it plainly...
no place is more patriotic than
the countryside...
more devoted to the civil cause...
in a word, more intelligent.
I don't mean, gentlemen...
that superficial intelligence...
that vainly adorns the idle mind...
but that deep and moderate
intelligence...
that comes from respecting the
law and observing one's duty.
Ah, time and again, duty!
Those words stultify me.
Duty is to know what is great, and
cherish what is beautiful...
and not to accept society's rules...
with their inherent ignominy.
But...
Passion is the one good thing on
earth.
It gives us heroism, enthusiasm...
music, poetry, art, everything!
But one must follow opinion and
its morality.
There are two moralities.
The petty, conventional one...
ever-changing and loud-mouthed.
The other, the eternal one is
around us and above us...
like the landscape and the clear
blue sky.
Continue!
Persevere!
Doesn't this conspiracy of Society
disgust you?
Doesn't it condemn every
emotion?
Noble and pure feelings are
persecuted and insulted...
and should two poor souls meet, it
keeps them apart.
But why worry as they will unite
in love one day...
because such is the destiny they
were born to.
The winner...
will lift up the loser...
and live in brotherhood with him.
So why was it that we met?
What chance caused it?
Over the distance, like two rivers
joining...
our paths led us to each other.
Overall prize!
Monsieur Bizet!
I've never known anyone more
perfect to be with.
Manure! Monsieur Caron!
Thus, I'll carry away your memory.
You'll forget me.
I'll pass like a shadow.
Best merino ram!
Shall I count for something in
your life...
in your thoughts?
Best pigs! A shared prize...
You're kind to listen. You know I'm
yours.
You may have noticed...
the priest's absence.
The church probably has different
views on progress.
I'll just tell the fire brigade to be
on their guard.
M. Boulanger!
A fine day, wasn't it?
A fine day indeed!
Let me past to see the fire
brigade!
Several weeks went by with no
sign of Rodolphe.
He thought, "If she loves me
straight away...
"she'll love me more if I keep her
waiting. "
He knew he'd been right...
when he arrived and saw Emma
turn pale.
Forgive me for not coming sooner.
I was busy.
I've been ill.
Nothing serious?
Well...
No.
I didn't want to come back.
Why?
Can't you guess?
Emma...
Monsieur!
I've decided to go away...
far from you.
Very far.
So far you'll never hear of me.
Some irresistible force has
brought me here today.
An angel's smile is too strong.
One is attracted by what is
beautiful, charming...
adorable...
I'm so pitiful.
You're a good man!
No, I love you, that's all. Didn't you
know?
Say it to me.
One word, just one word!
Good day, doctor.
Delighted to see you, M. Boulanger.
I came to see how madame is.
Ah, I'm always afraid...
the fits might come back.
I was wondering if horse riding
might help.
Indeed! Most excellent!
Good idea!
Emma...
I don't have a horse.
I can put one at your disposal.
You're very kind, but... no.
Thank you.
I came to tell you that my man
still has dizzy spells.
That's quite common. I'll call by.
I'll bring him. We won't trouble
you.
Good, I'll be waiting.
Madame...
Be careful, accidents happen. Your
horses might be skittish.
No, don't worry.
Enjoy your ride.
Safety first, remember!
Is our path now not the same?
No, you know it's impossible.
Let's forget it.
Where are the horses? Where are
they?
Where are the horses?
You scare me, you hurt me.
Let's leave.
I need you to live.
Your eyes, your voice, your
thoughts.
Oh, I'm wrong! I'm wrong! I must
be mad...
to listen to you.
Why?
What?
I saw M. Alexandre this afternoon.
He has an old filly, still in good
shape...
which we could have for a hundred
ecus.
I said we'd take it.
I bought it.
Have I done right?
I have a lover!
You, here!
Your dress is wet!
I love you, I love you!
It's time to go.
I never want to leave you!
What's wrong? You're suffering?
Speak to me.
You shouldn't come here, you could
compromise yourself.
I don't care.
Don't be silly.
I want to see you. I think only of
you.
Angel, I dream only of you. Don't
worry.
I'll come to you.
Emma!
Come to bed. It's late.
I'm coming.
Within six months, they treated
each other...
like a couple trying to keep the
love alive...
in their marriage.
I want you! I want to devour you.
That's when Emma repented.
Bring her to me!
I love you, my poor dear, I love
you!
Your ears are so dirty!
My ears aren't dirty.
She even wondered why she hated
Charles...
and if she shouldn't love him.
But he gave her no reason to do
so...
until M. Homais provided him
with the ideal chance.
Evening all! Look, Charles.
They talk about a new method for
curing club feet.
Tell me what you think. What if
you operated on Hippolyte?
What glory for Yonville.
Success is guaranteed, according
to the writer.
And what fame for you.
In my role...
as the paper's correspondent, I'll
write an article.
And articles get talked about. Who
knows?
You're a skilful surgeon. I
remember father's leg.
It's not the same thing.
Don't be so modest, Charles.
The family's honour is at stake.
Charles started studying
strephocatopodia...
strephendopodia,
strephexopodia...
along with strephypopodia...
and strephanopodia.
A campaign led by M. Homais...
tried to convince Hippolyte to
accept.
Perhaps you'll feel a slight pain.
It's just like being bled.
It's nothing to do with me! It's for
you, out of humanity.
To see you rid of that hideous
limp.
Wouldn't you like to run like
anyone else?
Women would like you better,
believe me.
You're a man! Suppose you'd had to
fight for France?
Are you all right?
You'll see, it's nothing. He'll just
cut the tendon.
There.
I didn't feel a thing.
See, I told you so.
The operation is a success.
A great day for our town!
Our town...
will always remember the name
of Dr Bovary.
"Our small town of Yonville has
seen a surgical experiment...
that is also a philanthropic act. "
"M. Bovary, a distinguished
practitioner... "
It's too much!
No, not at all!
"M. Bovary, a distinguished
practitioner...
has cured the club foot... "
I didn't use the scientific term...
"of Hippolyte Toutain, ostler at
the Lion d'Or. "
"The operation went like magic...
with only a few drops of blood on
the skin...
to show that the rebel tendon...
had at last yielded to the
surgeon's art. "
Help, M. Bovary!
Help!
He's dying!
M. Bovary! Quickly!
What is it?
What's wrong?
It hurts! God, it hurts!
It's so swollen.
It's nothing. It just needs some
air.
When will I be better? Save me.
Here, drink this. It will do you
good.
Look at my dress. See the...
Charles! How is he?
Getting worse. I don't understand.
Could you go?
Of course, gladly. But I can't cure
him.
Stop thinking. Just get up and
walk.
In any case, you smell bad.
I've brought fresh bandages.
My husband's on his way.
Does it hurt?
I lose.
Come for a drink?
You must be brave.
He really stinks.
I'm sure you'll be better soon.
Well, Hippolyte, I hear you're
suffering.
Good lad. You have to be brave.
This is a trial sent by the Lord.
Rejoice in your pain, as it is His
will...
and use it to make your peace
with Heaven.
There's black liquid and it's
swollen to the knee.
It can't go on. It's bad for
business.
Madame Bovary...
your husband must get another
doctor.
I'll send for M. Canivet, from
Neufchaftel.
He's a celebrity.
Good-bye.
I'll call again.
I saw the priest. What a nerve!
If he thinks his manoeuvres can
save him...
our troubles are far from over!
What do you think?
I don't know.
Amputate!
Excellent result!
That's the capital's ideas for you.
That's Paris! Cure everything!
Be clever without worrying about
the consequences!
That's not ourjob.
We're not scientists and fops!
We're practitioners and we don't...
operate on a healthy person!
Straighten a clubfoot! How can it
be done?
Why not a hunchback!
Amputate the leg...
to mid-thigh.
I took every possible precaution.
It's fate.
If that poor lad should die...
I'll have murdered him. Everyone
will know.
I'll be dishonoured.
You're getting on my nerves!
She remembered the privations
of her soul...
her dreams in the mud, like
wounded swallows...
the things she'd wanted and
denied herself...
everything she could have had!
But why? Why?
She repented her past virtue as if
it were a crime.
The thought of her lover came
back to charm her.
She gave herself up...
and Charles seemed as alien and
distant as ever...
as impossible and down-cast as a
dying man...
who was in agony before her.
Stand aside!
Kiss me.
- Kiss me.
- Let me go!
What's wrong?
You know I love you.
Enough!
Their love began again.
You've no idea how bored I am.
My husband is hateful.
I only feel repulsion for him.
My life is horrible.
Yes, dear. But what can I do about
it?
If you wanted...
What?
We could go away... somewhere
else.
You're truly mad!
Is that a new dress?
Buy Hippolyte a wooden leg.
Should I?
It's the least you can do.
That dress looks delightful.
I have a surprise for you.
I think this is what you wanted.
It's superb, M. Lheureux.
I'm happy you like it.
Mme Bovary, I regret this but...
an unfortunate chain of events...
bad debtors and important
purchases...
force me to ask you for the money
you owe me.
The total comes to 270 francs.
Forgive me, but it's quite urgent.
I wouldn't like to have to take the
goods back.
I'll pay you, M. Lheureux.
We can come to an arrangement.
No, I'll pay you.
Why buy me presents?
Because I love you.
It's embarrassing for me.
Don't be silly.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
Very much?
Definitely.
Then let's go.
Take me away! Four years of
suffering. I'm dying!
They torture me. Save me!
What do you want?
Take me away! I beg you!
And Berthe?
We'll take her too.
What a woman!
Well, will you take me?
Let me think. I have things to sort
out.
Will you take me?
Mme Bovary was never more
beautiful than at this time.
She had that indefinable
beauty...
which springs from joy,
enthusiasm and success...
and which is the harmony of
temperament and circumstance.
I'm here to see you.
I understood you were having
problems.
So I'm here to pay my debts.
I'll be needing a coat.
A long coat with a thick collar and
lining.
Are you going on ajourney?
No. I'm counting on you. As fast as
possible.
I'll need a small trunk, a light,
practical one.
Three feet by one and a half, the
standard model.
With a night-bag.
Perfect.
Take this. Use it to pay.
There's no need for that!
We know each other. I trust you.
I insist. At least take the chain.
Leave everything here.
As for the coat...
don't bring it to the house.
Give me the address and have it
made ready.
Is everything ready? Are you
sure?
Are you sad?
No, why?
Are you sad to leave this place
and start anew?
I have nothing here. You're
everything I have!
I'll be everything to you...
your family and your home!
You're so charming.
Is it true? Do you love me? Swear
it.
Do I love you?
Do I love you? I adore you!
Oh, Rodolphe, I'm too happy!
My darling Rodolphe.
Midnight!
It's tomorrow.
One more day.
You have the passports?
Forgotten anything?
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
You'll wait at the Hotel de
Provence at midday?
See you tomorrow.
Till tomorrow.
"Be brave, Emma, be brave.
I don't wish to ruin your life.
I was leading you to an abyss.
Oh Emma, forget me.
Why did I have to meet you? Why
were you so beautiful?
Is it my fault?
Heavens, no, blame only fate.
The world is cruel, Emma.
Everywhere, there would have
been awkward questions...
gossip and perhaps even insults.
I'll be gone when you read these
sad lines.
I must flee to avoid the
temptation of seeing you again.
Farewell.
Your friend, Rodolphe. "
He read the letter through.
He found it good.
Is madame in?
This is for her.
Give it to me.
No, I have to give it personally.
My master sent this, ma'am.
Give him a coin.
The master's waiting. The meal's
ready.
Emma! where are you?
Come on!
I knew it.
That vinegar would wake a dead
man.
Speak to us!
It's me...
your loving Charles.
Here's your little girl. Kiss her.
No one...
The poor thing.
- She's gone again.
- No, she's sleeping.
The fit's over. What could have
made her faint?
Be careful not to wake her.
One of my friends, Brideux, in
Forges...
owns a dog that has a fit when it
sniffs a snuff-box.
Isn't that strange?
A fever set in...
and for 43 days, Charles didn't
leave her side...
neglected his patients and stopped
sleeping.
Her strength...
returned when the paths...
were covered with autumn leaves.
Don't tire yourself.
Sit on the bench there.
No, not there!
You'll be all right.
Am I disturbing you? I'm here to
ask...
about Emma.
You know you're always welcome.
I was doing my accounts.
I don't know how...
to pay for all the medicine I've
had.
You owe me nothing.
I'm much obliged but I'm
embarrassed.
The season hasn't been too good.
I was so busy with the poor dear.
How is she?
A lot better but she still has
short relapses.
I have to be so very careful.
She's resting now. The priest's
with her.
Bournissien? I hear he's often
here.
I hope she's not turning religious
on us.
She tells me faith is a great
comfort to her.
In my view, you should take her
out...
take her to the theatre.
I'd come too if I could get away.
Logardy is giving a concert in
Rouen...
before leaving for England.
I didn't understand everything...
but I quite like it.
Would you like some barley
water?
Yes please. It's so hot.
I never thought I'd get away. Such
a crush.
Guess who I bumped into?
Monsieur Leon!
Leon?
None other. He's coming to pay his
respects.
You're back in Rouen?
Since when?
Be quiet or leave!
Come on, it's hot and I'm bored.
Stay a little.
Please, I'm stifling. Let's go.
True, it is hot.
Does opera bore you?
You can't imagine.
I returned from Paris last week.
I'm spending two years here to
learn the trade.
Business isn't the same here as in
Paris.
How's Berthe? And the Homais?
Berthe has grown a lot.
The Homais...
Are very well.
They seem satisfied...
but after Rubini or Gresi...
Lagardy isn't much despite all his
noise.
He's supposed to be good in the
last act.
It's a shame we left before the
end.
He's performing again in two days.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Unless you want to stay, my pet.
It could do you good.
Lagardy is quite sublime in the
last act.
I'm sorry I felt ill.
Stay! Come back on Sunday.
If you want to...
it means it's good for you.
Allow me...
Leon...
you shouldn't, really...
It's agreed, then? Tomorrow at
six.
Unfortunately, I have to go home.
But you, Emma...
It's just...
I'm not sure...
Think about it and we'll see.
Just sleep on it.
Now that you're back in these
parts...
I hope you'll come to dinner from
time to time.
You can count on it.
I have to go to Yonville on
business.
Good-night.
M. and Mme Bovary, please.
Number seven, but the gentleman
left.
Oh, Leon...
I'm pleased to see you.
I didn't say where we were
staying.
I found you.
You decided to stay?
Yes, and I was wrong.
One shouldn't acquire such tastes
when one's so busy.
I can imagine.
No you can't, you're not a woman.
If only you knew of my dreams!
And mine!
I've suffered too.
I'd wander along the Seine.
A print-seller had an engraving of
a Muse.
I'd stare at it for hours on end.
She looked like you.
I'd tear up my letters to you.
But why? Why?
Because I loved you.
I always thought so...
So...
So?
Why is it nobody has ever
expressed such feelings to me?
An idealistic soul is hard to understand.
If only we'd met sooner...
I've often thought that.
What a dream!
We could start now.
No, my friend! I'm too old... and
you're too young.
Forget me! You'll love others.
Not like you!
What a child you are.
Please, be good. I want you to.
Forgive me!
Heavens, it's late! I forgot all
about the concert.
Poor Bovary left me here for that.
I must go home tomorrow.
Really?
It's impossible. I've something I
must tell you.
Haven't you understood?
You speak well.
Please don't joke.
Let me see you just once more.
Not here anyway.
Wherever!
Oh, Lord.
Tomorrow at eleven in the
cathedral.
You're mad.
You're mad!
Till tomorrow.
Does the gentleman wish to visit
the church?
Does madame wish to visit the
church?
No, we don't wish to visit the
church.
Why not?
Because... I have other plans.
Thank you, you're so kind.
Come along.
Where are we going?
- Get me a cab.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, Leon, really...
I don't know if I should.
It's not done.
What?
It's done in Paris all the time.
- Where to, sir?
- Wherever!
Carry on! Carry on!
Move on!
Wait, Hivert! Wait! Wait for me!
Wait a minute.
My trunk's ready. I'll be right
down.
Madame Bovary...
you have to go to see M. Homais.
It's urgent.
I'll go home first.
No, it's very urgent, you have to go
right now.
Hippolyte will take your trunk.
Are you mad? Look what you've
done!
What's wrong?
I asked him to fetch a bowl...
for the extra red-currants.
So he went to the store to get it.
Do you know what we have in
there?
Did you see the bottle full of
white powder...
with the label saying "dangerous"?
Know what's in it, idiot? Arsenic!
And you took the bowl next to it!
Next to the arsenic? You'll kill us!
Us or a patient!
You want to see me in court, don't
you?
I wonder why I bother helping you.
I should have let you wallow in
your filth!
You're useless. You can't even
stick labels!
And you live the high life, without
a care!
You sent for me?
Clean that up. Hurry, you murderer!
You've something to tell me?
Ah, yes. Your father-in-law is
dead.
- My dear...
- Yes, I know...
If only I could have seen him.
How old was he?
Sixty-one.
My poor mother...
what will become of her?
Did you have fun?
Pretty bouquet.
Yes, I bought it from a beggar
earlier.
The next day his mother arrived.
Allow me, at this trying time...
to present my sincere
condolences...
and put myself at your disposal.
You're very kind but we need
nothing.
Excuse me but...
I'd like to have a word in private.
About that matter... you know?
Ah, yes! Of course...
Emma, my dear...
Could you... I don't want to leave
mother.
I'm sure your present sorrow...
will find some financial comfort
in the will.
I'm delighted for you and, I must
say, for your husband.
While you were ill...
he was in such a state!
I can tell you, now that you're
well again...
We had a few problems.
Problems? What sort of
problems?
You know. Those little fancies of
yours.
The travelling-cases, the coat...
We made it up. I can now suggest
another arrangement.
This misfortune will give him so
much to do.
I could renew the note he signed
for me.
He'd do best to transfer it to
somebody else.
You, for instance. A proxy would
make it easy...
and we could easily sort out our
matters.
Maitre Guillaumin has prepared
the papers...
to manage and administer his
business.
You could take out loans...
sign and endorse his notes...
Monsieur will do as he sees fit.
But I think...
Where's this from?
Maitre Guillaumin.
I don't trust him. Notaries are
renowned crooks.
We need a competent opinion.
But we don't know anyone.
We do... We could ask Leon.
Yes! That's a good idea.
We'll have to go to Rouen.
I'll write to him.
Charles, this can't be done by
correspondence.
No. Since I have to, I'll go.
You're so good.
The next day, she took the
Hirondelle...
to consult Leon in Rouen.
She stayed three days.
Three full, gorgeous, superb
days, a real honeymoon.
Don't move. Don't speak.
Look at me.
There's something so soft in your
eyes...
which does me good.
Child, do you love me?
You'll leave me, you'll marry. Like
the others.
What others?
Other men, of course!
You're all vile.
Do you ever think of Paris?
No. Well... a little, of course.
We could live so well there.
Aren't we happy?
Yes, it's true. I'm mad. Kiss me.
- Will you come?
- As soon as I can.
Will you promise?
Do you think I need to?
Be careful, anyway.
I swear I'll come.
I mustn't miss the coach.
It blew so strong that day...
Good day, Hivert.
Madame Bovary, what a surprise.
The trip will be a delight.
I've ordered...
a few fine pieces of cloth.
I'll be delighted to show you.
We'll see about that.
Get lost, you filthy vermin!
Leon showed the document to a
colleague.
Yesterday, I was too tired to
travel back.
You weren't ill?
No, I told you, I was tired.
He was worried. You could have
sent word.
I told him I'd need two days.
Two days, not three.
Mother, it doesn't matter.
Leon is positive that the document
is perfectly in order.
What document?
Nothing important, mother.
A sort of proxy...
to enable Emma...
to take care of household matters
more easily.
A proxy for your wife?
Are you mad?
Mother!
Not everyone's rich...
and no fortune lasts forever.
Was the carpet needed?
Why change the chair covering?
It's all vain fancy!
Silk for linings!
I'd be ashamed of such comfort...
and yet I'm old.
Enough, madame!
I'll tear the order up!
Mother, you're causing trouble
It's all show.
Shall I burn it?
Please do.
This arrangement suits me.
Sorry mother, but you're wrong.
You love her more.
You're right. That's how it should
be.
I'll leave tomorrow.
Have you sorted everything out?
In your best interests, I think.
I've a buyer for your house in
Barneville.
M. Langlois has offered 4,000
francs.
A good price.
I have half the amount here.
I can pay my debts.
I'd be sorry to take back...
such an important sum so
suddenly.
What?
One can put anything on bills.
Here...
sign this, keep it all...
and put your mind at rest.
With the date, please, the date.
What excuse did you give?
I said I had a piano class twice a
week.
That costs money.
But I'm rich!
He didn't question her and
accepted her whims.
He was more her mistress than
she his.
Her tender words and kisses
carried off his soul.
Where had she learned such
corruption...
so deep and concealed that it
was almost immaterial?
One day, they parted early...
and, walking along the
boulevard...
she saw the walls of her
convent.
Her early married life, walks in
the woods...
the Vicomte waltzing all passed
before her eyes.
Leon suddenly seemed as remote
as the rest.
Yet I love him.
No matter, she wasn't happy.
She never had been.
Nothing was worth this quest.
Everything lied.
What is it?
A man in black brought it.
He said it was most urgent.
Law and justice to Mme Bovary.
What sentence?
Within twenty-four hours...
- ... pay the sum of 8,000 francs.
- What?
Forced by legal means...
and notably by the confiscation...
of her personal goods.
By buying on credit, borrowing...
signing notes...
she had gathered for Lheureux...
a sum that he was eager to
obtain.
Have you heard the news?
I suppose it's ajoke.
What do you mean?
My little lady...
did you think I'd supply you with
goods...
and money, out of kindness...
till the end of time?
I must recover my outlay. It's only
fair.
But just think: 8,000 francs!
The court upheld it and passed
judgement.
Anyway, you know it's not me.
It's my accountant, Vincart.
But couldn't you...
manage to...
I can't do a thing.
You don't know Vincart. He's worse
than an Arab.
Look, I didn't know. It's such a
surprise.
Whose fault is that?
I slave like a nigger while you're
enjoying yourself.
Don't you lecture me!
It won't do any harm.
I beg you to do something.
You're trying to seduce me!
You monster!
Oh, come, come.
I'll tell everyone about you.
I'll tell my husband.
Leave your poor husband out of
this.
Don't you think I can tell him a
thing or two?
I know it's not funny.
But debts never killed anyone.
When one has friends, like you...
Where can I find the money?
You have friends, I tell you...
I promise I'll sign...
You've signed enough.
- I'll sell...
- You've nothing to sell.
I really don't care.
Good day, madame, Maitre Hareng,
the bailiff.
I'm to draw up the list of the
goods...
to be confiscated. My two
witnesses...
Latour and Passepoil.
I won't take this phrenological
head...
no doubt a professional tool.
Let's say nine pans, five dishes...
three pots, four chairs...
two torches.
Very pretty. Quite charming!
The law allows me to leave a
guard for the goods.
But I'll take the responsibility...
of trusting you.
Latour and Passepoil will
guarantee...
the lawfulness of the operation.
Not a word of this to my husband,
understand?
Not a word.
I never say anything, ma'am.
It's turned chilly.
- I must go to Rouen tomorrow.
- Really?
Why're you here?
Are you busy?
No, but I didn't expect you today.
I need to talk. It's urgent.
I need you. I need 8,000 francs.
What? You must be mad!
No, not yet, not quite. Listen...
But what...
You must find the money.
How can I?
What a coward you are!
I'm sure you're panicking.
Perhaps a thousand cus would do.
All the more reason. You can find
Try!
I'll love you so!
But where? How?
If I were you, I'd know.
Where then?
Your office!
Her eyes blazed with a hellish
recklessness...
and the lids narrowed with
sensual encouragement.
The young man felt himself
weakening...
before the silent will of this
woman...
pushing him to commit a crime.
He took fright.
How stupid I am!
Morel's back. His father's rich. I'll
bring it tomorrow.
Tomorrow at three. I'm sure he'll
lend it to me.
My friend Morel, I mean.
My dear, I really must be going.
Careful now. There's medicine in
there.
Delighted to see you. I didn't know
you were here.
You'll liven up the journey.
Often on a summer's day.
Girls dream of love so gay.
They should be locked up and made
to work.
Progress moves at a snail's pace!
We wallow in barbarity!
That's a bad scrofulous disorder.
Instead of getting drunk, you
should start a diet.
I know a good cream for you.
Well, I hope you'll do a show for
us now.
Ma'am! It's a scandal!
What's wrong?
There are bills posted on the
square.
Does my husband know?
No, he left early. I was just up.
If I were you, I'd go to see the
notary.
Do you think so? We hardly know
him.
I'd go anyway.
I should have the money later.
Seeing Maitre Guillaumin won't do
any harm.
You really think so?
My black dress.
I'll take the back door.
A thousand cus?
Why do you need such a sum, my
dear lady?
You should have consulted me.
There are a hundred practical
ways...
of investing.
Why did you wait?
I don't know.
Do I scare you?
You're usually brave.
I'm most devoted to you. You do
know that?
You're a pretty woman...
the glory of our town.
I'm most fond of grace and beauty.
What's your decision?
What?
The money?
You'll get the damn money.
You're
playing with my despair.
I'm to be pitied, not bought!
Stay!
- Well?
- Nothing. I'm desperate.
Perhaps there's someone...
No. There's nobody.
You said this afternoon perhaps.
Yes, perhaps...
The master will soon be in.
Yes, I know!
I won't see him. I couldn't stand it!
I can't forgive him for knowing
me! Never.
Mother Rolet! Mother Rolet, for
pity's sake!
I can't breathe!
I'll unlace you.
What time is it?
It'll soon be three.
The person I'm expecting may be
at my house.
I can't remember.
Run and fetch him.
But the babies...
I'll look after them. Please hurry.
I'm going, ma'am.
I'm going.
What?
Nobody. Doctor's crying. Everyone's
looking for you.
Are you ill?
Him! He'll save me.
He's kind, he's thoughtful...
he's generous.
Oh! It's you!
Yes, it's me.
Rodolphe, I need to ask some
advice.
Still the same.
Still as charming.
They're sad charms, my friend, as
you disdained them.
No, I'm sure I was right.
I couldn't lead you off like that.
No matter. I've suffered.
So have I, Emma. Such is life.
Has it been kind to you since we
parted?
Neither kind nor unkind.
We shouldn't have parted.
Yes, perhaps.
You think so?
If only you knew! I loved you so!
How could I part with the
happiness you gave me?
I almost died of desperation. I'll
tell you about it.
You fled from me.
You love other women, admit it!
I understand. You charmed them
just like me.
You're a man. You make women
love you.
We'll start again, won't we? We'll
love again.
I'm laughing!
I'm happy!
Say something!
You've been crying.
Why?
Forgive me. You're the only one I
really like.
I've been stupid and cruel. I love
you.
I'll always love you.
What's wrong? Tell me.
I'm ruined, Rodolphe. I need 3,000
francs.
My husband placed his money with
a crooked notary.
We borrowed because his patients
didn't pay.
Without 3,000 francs, the bailiffs
will come.
At this very moment.
Counting on your friendship, I
came to see you.
But...
I don't have it, my dear lady.
You don't have it?
This is my final humiliation.
You never loved me. You're as bad
as the others.
Poor people don't buy tortoise-
shell clocks!
Or watch trinkets! You lack
nothing!
You have a house and land. You
hunt, you go to Paris!
This can be turned into money. I
don't want it.
Keep it!
I'd have given up everything for
you.
I'd have begged, just for a smile
and a "thank you".
Without you, I'd have been happy!
Why did you do it?
You even told me right here you
loved me.
You should have sent me away. My
hands are hot from your kisses.
You swore love on your knees.
Two years of dreams!
Your letter tore my heart apart.
And I come to the rich, happy, free
man...
to ask help anybody would give.
I beg, bring back all my love...
and he turns me away for 3,000
francs!
I don't have it.
If God knows our needs, why
bother praying?
Be serious.
I admire Christianity. It freed
slaves...
created a much-needed moral
order. But the texts!
All cooked up by Jesuits!
The key! For the room where...
What?
Give it to me. We have rats at
home.
They're stopping me sleeping.
I have to ask.
Don't bother. I'll tell him later.
Bring some sodium chloride.
Come on, light the way.
Stop it!
Be quiet.
Why?
Don't say anything. To anyone.
They'd blame your master.
Thank God, you're here!
What's going on? What's happening
to us?
Why?
Tell me!
You'll read it tomorrow.
For now, I beg you, don't ask me a
single question.
I beg you, leave me.
My death isn't much.
I'll fall asleep...
and it will be over.
I'm thirsty!
I'm so thirsty!
- What's wrong?
- It's nothing.
More!
Open the window, I'm stifling.
It's extraordinary. It looks like
white gravel.
No! You're mistaken!
I'm cold.
I feel better. I'll get up later.
It's unbearable!
Tell me! What did you eat?
Answer me...
for God's sake!
There...
"Let no one be accused... " Oh, God!
Poisoned!
Help!
Calm down. We just need to give
her a strong antidote.
What's the poison?
Arsenic!
We need an analysis.
Do it, just do it. Save her.
Don't cry.
Soon I won't torment you any
more.
But why?
Who made you do it?
I had to do it, dear.
Weren't you happy with me?
Is it my fault?
I did everything I could.
That's true. You're a good man.
She hoped she was finished with
the treachery...
wickedness and consuming greed
that tortured her.
She hated no one, now.
Twilight descended over her
mind...
and, of all the earth's noises,
she heard only...
the intermittent sobbing of her
poor love...
as soft and faint as the last
echo of a symphony...
fading away.
Bring me Berthe.
You're not feeling worse?
How pale you are! You're sweating!
I'm scared.
That's enough!
It was blowing so strong that
day...
that it blew her petticoats...
far away.
The blind man!
Farewell! Farewell!
Pray, my son.
But I'm suffering!
God is great!
We must accept His will.
I hate your God!
The spirit of rebellion is still
within you.
Fate's the one to blame.
One evening, Berthe came to
fetch him for dinner.
He was sitting under the arbour.
She gently pushed him.
He fell to the ground. He was
dead.
12 francs and 75 centimes were
left after sale...
and that paid for Berthe's trip to
her grandmother's.
The old lady died that year.
Old Rouault being paralysed, an
aunt took her in.
She is poor and has sent her to
work...
in a cotton mill.
Homais'practice grows like
wildfire.
Authority respects him and
public opinion protects him.
He has just received the Legion
of Honour.