(CLARINET PLAYING)
(CRACKING)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
Just try it.   Just try it.
It's the only cure  for rheumatism.
It's magic, really.
The metal draws it out, do you see?
Yeah, I'll try it.    All right.
Thanks.  Good luck.
Oh, it has to be copper.
Right.
Well, Dracula is back.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm so pleased, so pleased to welcome you.
(PIANO PLAYING)
(MAN SPEAKING HINDI ON TV)
(DOORBELL CHIMING)
(GROANS)
(SPEAKING PUNJABI)
It's for me.
Mini cab.   Coming.
Mrs. Ahuja, darling,  if you would let me  have 10, for the taxi,
I'll let you have it  with the other 10 when  I give you the rent check.
I'd go in the tube, but  it looks nicer by car  the first time.
So, soon he'll be giving big concerts in the Albert Hall?
(CHUCKLES) Oh, yes.  She said he's a genius.
Thank you,  Mrs. Ahuja, darling.  You'll have my check tomorrow.
(SPEAKING PUNJABI)
Play. It plays from here.
(DOORBELL RINGING)    From here.
LADY EMILY:   The door is open.
Always open.  Thank you.
(KNOCKING)
MADAME SOUSATZKA:   Come in.
It's fine, dear.    Thank you.
Ah! Yes, Mrs...
Well, Manek's mother.    Hello.
GIRL: Ah, I'll see you Wednesday then, Madame Sousatzka.
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  Uh-uh-uh-uh!
GIRL: Oh, do I have to? I feel such a fool doing it.
We could never leave   the presence of an elder,   let alone a teacher
without a deep curtsy.
And an  "Au revoir, Madame,"
in French.
Au revoir, Madame.
A little deeper, please.  Au revoir, Madame.
All right, go on.
Shut the door.
I love  old-fashioned manners.
They're so gracious  and beautiful.
Hmm.
Thanks, Mr. Cordle.    That's fine.
Now, Mr. Jordan.
SUSHILA:  I've always  encouraged him,
and supported him,  Madame Sasoutzka.
Sousatzka.    Su-sat-zka.
(ENUNCIATING) Su-sat-zka.
As with all  talented students,
exceptionally  talented students,
his lessons with me will be paid for by the school trust.
What he makes  of this opportunity  is entirely up to him.
Oh, I'm sure    he will work    very hard.
And he is very grateful.    We both are, Madame Sasou...
Sousatzka. Sit down, please.
Ever since he was two,   it has always been just   he and I, alone in the world.
And his father?
Oh, his father's just a rat.
Milk?    Yes, please.
I don't care who knows it.
Everyone knows it anyway    in Delhi, and what sort    of life I had with him.
Until one day    I had enough.    That was it.
I just walked out  with my baby  and my suitcase.
Just one suitcase, mind you.
I, who had come with 50 suitcases full of my dowry of saris and jewelry.
Sugar? Only three.
Three.
We are not just    from here and there,    you know.
We're related to some   of the first families   of Bengal,
even through an aunty   to the Tagore family.
Thank you.
No one ever thought I'd have this kind of life.
There have been times,  I tell you frankly,
when I couldn't pay the rent    and I had to pack up    and leave at night.
But never mind about me.    My life is over.
I want everything now   for my son.
I live for the day when  he will be famous and rich
and give many,   many concerts all...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We are not talking  about concerts.
We are talking about your boy and his gift,
which I am here    to develop.
I cannot bear this attitude    of everything for sale.
A boy's talent,
this street.
Let's make money.  Cash, cash, quick,  quick, quick, quick!
Oh!
Forgive me, but I have  very strong feelings  on this subject.
Please don't think    I'm a commercial person.
(CLEARING THROAT) I'm very proud that my son is a genius and that...
(CLEARING THROAT)
You don't think he is a genius?
We don't use that word.
Mrs...  Sen.
Please call me Sushila.
Mrs. Sen...  (PHONE RINGING)
Sousatzka.
(WOMAN SPEAKING ON PHONE)
Yes.
Yes, I remember.
Yeah, well,    my secretary is    not in just now.
Let me have  a look at my book.
Yes, Wednesday at 2:00. That would be fine.
Very well.
Now I can take your son    on Tuesdays and Thursdays...
No, Tuesdays and Fridays.
Oh, but he helps me  on Fridays.
It's a very    busy day for me    with the weekend orders.
Hmm. Mrs. Sen,
whenever I take on  a new student,
I give  myself and my time,  totally and freely.
It is an absolute commitment  for both of us,
the student and myself.  Because, you see,
I teach not only  how to play the piano,
but how to live.
You'll be very proud  of your son.
Now there are two of us to care.
(CHOKING)
(CAR PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
Well, I'm just about   to sort out the old woman   in number 11.
Now, what's the problem?
Twenty-four?
Look, you got one  sitting tenant, right?
He's 70 years old,
he's sitting on  the first floor and  he won't budge, right?
Well, it's obvious, isn't it?
Offer him another grand  and if he still won't budge,  take the bloody staircase out.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
LADY EMILY:  Door is open.  Always open. Push.
Lady Emily.   It's me again,   John Woodford.
Oh! Oh, yes, of course.
Wonder if I might have a quick word.
Yes, indeed.    Come downstairs, please.
Don't forget the neck.
Two or three times a day.  Thank you.
WOODFORD: I was  thinking about what you  were saying the other day.
Well, I think we're talking the same language here.
This house is   evidently a millstone   around your neck.
And you obviously   need some help.
And that, Lady Emily,  is what I'm here for.
Well, I had  a word with my partner.  I think we can swing it.
I'm afraid you'll have    to give me a little    more time, Mr. Woodwood.
Woodford.  What?
It isn't always easy,   you know,
to part with the house  where one was born.
All of us need a bit  of a change sometimes.
Yes.
I used to dream that one day,   perhaps, I'd have a little   place by the sea.
Is that so?
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Oi, Manny,   are you coming out?
I can't. I got  a music lesson.
A music lesson?   Come on, man.
Well, I'll see you  tomorrow, all right?
(SIGHS)
Hello.
I believe it's me  you've come to see.
I watched you rolling about on those skates. You mustn't do that.
What if you fall  and something happens  to your hands?
I never want to see you  with those skates again.
Leave them there.
No, not on the chair.   On the floor.
Perfect height.
Mmm-hmm.  You see?
I know exactly.   I know you exactly.
Begin.
At the very beginning.
I want you to forget    everything you've    ever learned.
You begin with   the C Major scale.
Which hand?
Which hand, he asks? My poor child!
Do you think  you have two hands?
Both hands, for me    and the piano, are one.
Acting in total accord and perfect harmony. Begin.
You don't have to impress me  with how clever you think  you are.
You move around   far too much,   Mr. Virtuoso.
Perfect scales have    no beginning and no end.
Each note is as smooth and as even as these beads.
You see?    Mmm-hmm.
Forget the fingers.
Don't think for one moment that you play with your fingers.
If he'd thought    about his fingers,
he'd be at the bottom of the ocean, never to be heard from again.
What are these  10 poor little  worms? No!
This is where   the music comes from.
From the abdomen,
and it rises   higher and higher
from the depths  of your very soul.
Higher and higher   from the deepest   instincts
to the height of reason until it reaches here.
Do you see? Now begin.
Begin.
(PIANO PLAYING)    Just let it play.
Let it play.
Ebb and flow.    Each note    smooth and even.
That's it.
It begins to play.   Now, it begins to play...
Now, from the very depth    of your being...
Soft, soft...
Pianissimo, pianissimo.
Now very, very soft.
Yes, too delicate
to hear with these    clumsy human ears.
Mmm-hmm.
Now, remember. Remember the position of this shoulder, remember!
Mmm, yes!
Just a vibration.
Mmm. (SHUSHING)
Mmm.
Maman's special recipe.
MADAME SOUSATZKA: Allegro!
No! Allegro!    Allegro! No!
No, it's too heavy!
Bright, bright!    It's too heavy!
The fingers! Don't collapse the fingers!
Lace, lace. (GROANS)
You sound like   an old man shuffling
in his slippers.
No, light, light.
Skip, skip,    hoopla, hoopla.
(GROANS)
Light!
JENNY: Well, has he  listened to my tape yet?
I sent it in  two weeks ago.
Uh?
I told you,  Jenny Plover.
No, no, P-L-O-V-E-R.
Look, just tell him "Jenny."    He'll know who I am.
(HUMMING)
Yeah, well, we're all   very busy, aren't we?   Goodbye.
I knew it as soon  as I woke up this morning.
I just had a feeling.   It's gonna be a bad   month for me.
I know what'd  make you feel better.
Bubbly all round.
Why don't you run a bath  while I pop the cork?
I just had a bath.
Oh, have another.  I'm not dirty.
I am.
(MADAME SOUSATZKA SHOUTING)
Is that Madame's latest?   Yeah.
I've got my latest. We remixed it like you said.
Hope you like it.
(LIGHT ROCK PLAYING)
I think it's great.
Yep, it's good.
Go and run that bath.
Scorpio men,   one track minds.
And where were  you last night?
Out!
Out where?
Out! What's it to you?
(PIANO PLAYING)
(MADAME SOUSATZKA SHOUTING)
I had dinner  with a producer,  that's what.
Who was he?
Micky something-or-other.
Micky who?
Come on, you know  what I'm like with names.
You're great with names.  Micky who?
What's he done before?  What's the label?
(CORK POPS)
Well, what do you think?  (MUSIC STOPS)
Lovely! Terrific!
You've really improved it.
Really? Thanks! Cheers. Cheers.
(FAINT PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
He's good. How old is he?
Never mind about him.
Do you come here  to be with me or what, huh?
Or what?
Well, what do you think?    I told you it's great.    I really meant it.
Yeah!
Ronnie, you still owe me    a birthday present.
I was thinking,  we could go out  this afternoon.
I've seen this  gorgeous dress.
I can't this afternoon, love.   Jam-packed.
Sorry. I'll write you a check. How much is it?
Three hundred and fifty.
Okay. Get me a receipt.   I'll put it through expenses.
So what am I?    Business or pleasure?
Hey...
Come here.
You got lovely eyes,  do you know that,  Ronnie Blum?
You beast.
(PLAYING PIANO)
MADAME SOUSATZKA: (CLAPS HANDS) Stop! Stop! Stop!
How can the music   flow through the body   when you're so stiff?
Hmm? And what's this?
You're developing a hump,   like a camel.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, you're such a sissy.    That's enough for today.
It's high time you began  to work with Mr. Cordle  downstairs.
Come here.
I want to show you   something.
What do you see?
Hmm?
Me.    But who is me?
Is it Manek, a boy?
Or do you aspire    to something like this?
All dear friends of  Maman's,
of course. My mother's.
Every pianist that  played at Carnegie Hall
came to visit us in our  apartment on Riverside Drive.
Rubinstein.
I sat on his lap  and he made a little mouse  out of a handkerchief for me.
(CHUCKLES)
And, of course,   this is  Maman,
in her heyday.
She was such a great  pianist and teacher.
Who is this?
(SCOFFS) Just a student  who wouldn't listen to me.
This is what  I want you to be like.
Oh, great.
My poor child. Come.
Listen, what have   I told you so many times?
It is all one.
The way we dress,   the way we speak,   the way we play,
it's all connected.
Well, I'll see you on Friday,  Madame Sousootzka. Okay?
Sousatzka.
Sousatzka. Sousatzka.
Yes, Sousatzka.  It was  Maman's name.
Sousatzka.
You won't tell her,    will you?
(MOUTHING) No, no, no.
This is jasmine.
Grows in your beautiful  country, doesn't it?
I wouldn't know.  I've never been.
This is a new cloth   that's just come in, sir.   Do you like that?
No. No, no, no.  Something more classic.
Maman's family  lost everything  in the revolution, Manek.
The French Revolution?
Oh, my goodness,  dear boy, you're ignorant.
The Russian Revolution.
Then they fled to Paris  for 10 years and after that  to New York,
where  maman met  papa
and I grew up.
A blazer.    That's very classic.
(EXCLAIMS)  I don't like that.  This, I don't like.
Now, you see,  you need to develop style  to go with those looks.
Those beautiful looks.
I think we'll try this.
I can't wear that stuff.    I'd look silly.
Nonsense!  It'll help you be a man.  Fetch some ties.
You see,  maman
wore only white  till after  papa left,
and then she wore  only black because  she felt like a widow,
even though he was  living in the next block  with another woman.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GROANS) Silly boy!
So, after  papa left,    mama couldn't bear   to stay in New York.
But then she was  offered a position at  the Royal College of Music,
so we moved on to London.
How are you  doing in there?  Let me have a look, Manek.
I'll come out  when I'm ready.
MADAME SOUSATZKA:    Oh, everyone adored     mam at the Royal College.
It was, "What does    Elena think of this?
"How does Elena   feel about that?"
Her English was terrible,   but they adored her   Russian accent.
Ta!    Ah!
No, I want something more vibrant.
Vibrant?
I see.
No, no, no, no, no.    This is no concern of yours.
I'll take care of that.
Now, I'll teach you how to offer a lady your arm.
Yes.
Vibrant? You'll get vibrant.
(SUSHILA LAUGHING)
What's so damn funny?
Is this her idea of how    a young boy should dress?
You can see   she's never had   any children.
(MOCKING LAUGHTER)
CORDLE: Uncross your legs,  that's it.
And relax.
Now, don't think that  pain is a permanent  condition.
Most definitely not.
But, then,   nothing ever is,   is it?
Permanent?  (THUDDING)
Not pain nor pleasure.  (MADAME SOUSATZKA SHOUTING)
That's the human condition.  (PIANO PLAYING)
Or, shall we say,  the condition  of being human.
Just lift your head,   that's it.
You see, Madame and Beethoven make your muscles go like this.
But Mr. Cordle  makes them go  like that.
Now, just relax.
Relax, I said.
I can't help it, Mr. Cordle.
(THUDDING)
Oh, she really ought not to,    for her own sake.
(EXCLAIMS) Horrible!
You do not know   how to practice properly.
It's a mess.    Oh, it is simply a mess!
Gave you a hard time,   did she?
I'm going back to my old teacher.
She might  not be Madame Sousatzka  with a wonderful method,
but at least she doesn't  make you sick.
What is that ghastly perfume  she uses?
It makes me want to throw up  every time she comes near me.
I like it.
What, when she  comes near you?
Her perfume.
You must be joking!
What's it called,  "La Stinkeroo"?
Look, she's a bloody    good teacher.
She's a big hoax.
Madame Stinkeroutzka.
Does she know    you go on those?
Hope it's not a bad   time for you, Lady E,
but I'm at the mercy  of Mr. Lefranc, here.
He's the district surveyor, you know, from the Council. A very busy man.
LADY EMILY:   I didn't realize you'd   need to see it all again.
Do come in.
You won't mind if  Mr. Lefranc continues with  the mysteries of his trade
while I look around,   would you?
You have such    interesting things.
Very striking.
My great-grandmother.  Quite a famous beauty.
And this is   Mr. Lipescu,
my spiritual master.
Damp.
Yes, I did think it seemed a little colder this winter.
Yes, well, you want  to take the skirting  off the outside wall
and strip the plaster down to a meter and a half,
and replace it with your    waterproof rendering.
Ah, then,   just get it injected.
Silicon. It won't    be very expensive.
LEFRANC:  Yes, well, it depends  what you call expensive.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
So sorry to disturb you.
Manek.
I think you know Mr. Woodford.
And this is Mr. Lefranc  from the Council.
MADAME SOUSATZKA: Yes?
Oh, do please    just carry on.
Pretend we're not here.
LEFRANC: I have  this down as a bedroom.
A bedroom?
What ancient document   do you have there?   (GRUNTS)
This has been  a studio for 30 years.
First of my mother's,   Elena Sousatzka.
And now mine.
I see. I take it,  you have permission to run  a business from the premises?
This is hardly  a sweatshop.
Well, that's not the point.  You still need permission.
Don't be late, huh?
Call you.
Okay.  (PIANO RESUMES PLAYING)
Too many sitting tenants,    if you ask me.
Wouldn't touch it   with a barge pole.
You know where   Jenny's flat is.
Who's that?
He calls himself an artist's agent. (SCOFFS)
Snooping after   my students...
Go on.
No, no.
The message cannot come to the fingers
if you don't open the body and let it through.
Let me show you.
Yes, well, we'll go  over it on Saturday.
I've gotta help  my mother on Saturday.
I think you should be   staying here on   Fridays and Saturdays
so that we can    work together.
You can sleep there in the studio.
The weekend  belongs to me.
To your piano.
Can't your mother  get along without you?
Well, Saturday  is sort of a big day for  her with all the deliveries.
Well, if you'd rather be    a delivery boy than    a pianist...
Yeah, go. Go, go, go.
Don't you think you should be playing on this
rather than that apology of a piano your mother has for you at home?
It's not her fault.   She can't afford   anything better.
Well... Good heavens!
Who said it was? I know she does the best for you.
I know that.
All I'm saying is,
that you mustn't    waste your weekends.    You must stay here and work.
And work and work.
These are such  precious years  for you.
All I'm thinking of is  what's right for you.
It's you who    I'm thinking of.
Hmm?
I suppose I could  stay over Fridays.
Sometimes.
And Saturdays?
And Saturdays.
Now go.
I don't want you   wandering around the   dark streets, either.
Now, Friday night,   you tell your mother.
(DOGS BARKING)
(MAN GROANING) THUG 1: Get up!
You dirty queer!
THUG 1: Bloody poof! THUG 2: Kick him! Kick him!
THUG 1: I know   what you're here for!
Come on, you... Hey!
(THUG LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
Mr. Cordle! Oh!
Are you okay?
(GRUNTING) Yes.
Can you walk?  Mmm-hmm.
Are you sure?   Uh-huh.
I'll call an ambulance.  No, no, no, no.
I'm all right. It was
stupid of me. Very stupid.
I... I stumbled,    that's all.
My shoelace came undone.
Careless.
Most careless of me.
MANEK: Can't I call Madame    and ask her to get a doctor?
No, you're doing fine.
Does this    make you feel sick?
I hate the sight of blood.
I'm not hurting you, am I?
Not quite so tight. Not quite so tight.
How well you do it.
You're sure I'm not hurting you?
Quite sure.
Do I look very hideous?
No.
Now, dear boy, you must be getting home.
It's very late.
Don't worry, I shall be    perfectly all right.
So off you go.
By the way,   don't tell Madame,   will you, or Lady Emily?
You know how hysterical    women get over accidents.
All right.
And Manek...
Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SOBBING)
You're very late,   aren't you?
I had to get some things  for Mr. Cordle.
Just milk and stuff.
That's very good of you.    Thank you.
Good night. Good night.
CORDLE: Come in.
I do hope  I'm not disturbing you. Oh.
Lady Emily.
I just had to talk to you about the house.
(STUTTERING) Can't I  get you something?
No, thank you.
Please, sit down.
The Council say    it isn't safe...
Oh.
Whatever have you done  to your face?
I fell outside.
But it's really nasty.
I'm perfectly all right.
I think I should get...  Please don't fuss!
I'm sorry.
(GROANS)
Oh, I do apologize.
Thank you.
You really should be  more careful.
London isn't the place  it was in our youth.
At our age,  it simply isn't safe  to walk in the streets,
especially, after dark.
I so often dream  of a little place  in the country.
Perhaps, I really  should think of selling.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Ah. Door's open.  Always open.
You've come    to see Lady Emily    and Mr. Cordle?
I've come to see you.
You don't need  to see me, Edward.
Congratulations on your great success.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
Babu!
What do you want?
I've got a backache.
(QUIETLY SIGHING)
Just a little bit here,  Babu, please.
(SIGHING)
It's lovely.
Mmm.
You used  to like doing it.
You never got tired.
(SIGHING)
Don't come in like that.  (CHUCKLING)
As if I haven't seen  you a thousand times  in your bath.
Soaped and sponged  you all over.
See you're home by 7:00.
We're going  to Pratima  maasi's.
I told you I am staying the night.
I promised Pratima  we'd both come.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Now what's that for?
My friends aren't    good enough for you, eh?
Now, only those people   in that house.
They're lucky it hasn't fallen down yet.
And I only hope nothing happens when you're inside.
Babu, wait!    I'll be late.
Oh. Let her wait.
To ward off  the evil eye.
Goodness knows what    spell she's cast on you.
Mom.  (EXCLAIMS)
MADAME SOUSATZKA:   Now, Mr. Cordle,   you take this bread,
you see,    I freshly baked it    this morning.
LADY EMILY:  Oh, thank you.
You dunk it   into the sauce here,   that's how it works.
This is  Maman's recipe.
The English know    nothing about food.
(LAUGHING)  Oh, nonsense.
You shouldn't be going  to all this trouble  on your birthday.
No, I love to cook    on my birthday.
I do hope those two terrible men don't come and interrupt us.
No one can make you lose    the house you were born in.
Quite right.    Exactly.
Manek, don't eat  like a barbarian.
It isn't the house so much. It's the people I mind.
I don't want to lose  my dear little family.
Isn't she coming?    Oh, what's her name?
Who?  Jenny.
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  Jenny, well...
Jenny's going to be  a little bit late.
I said, "Jenny, you must  learn to be absolutely  on time with me."
And she said that's  because I have a rising  ascendency in Capricorn.
Oh, I'm Capricorn.
No, it's zodiac nonsense.
I control my life,    not the stars.
Oh, is that good  for him?
Of course.
But I haven't finished  the last one, yet.
Oh, stupid boy, listen.
The white wine goes   with the fish, yes?
The red wine with the meat.
You must learn    to become a man.    You see?
To our family.
ALL: To our family.
Family. Happy birthday!
Oh!  (ALL LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
Oh, I'm sorry   I'm so late.   I need you.
No, no, Manek! Where are you going?
You must ask the lady of the house before you leave the table.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, he's...
JENNY: Oh. "Invest in time."   (SCOFFS) That's a joke.
There.   What do you think?
They're great.
No, the cake, dummy.  I got it from  this bank commercial.
What's this one? Mmm?
Oh, that was a big launch  of a new health drink.
I'm the carrot.
See that banana?  I went to Australia  with him.
That's Tony.
Is this from a film?
Country Maiden  slimming crackers,  darling.
You look great.
So, are you a model?
Not really. I'm a singer. I write my own songs.
Look.
Let's see.
Come on.  How are you going to get it?
(LAUGHING)
Come on.  You're supposed  to be helping me.
Did it sell    many copies?
It got to number 94.    For a week.
Hey, that's really good.
God, how many  are there?
Ooh, I just stuck them in.  We better not count, eh?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  Do you remember last  year, Mr. Cordle, when I...
How old is she?    (SHUSHES)
How old are you?
How old do    you think I am?
Twenty?
Yeah, 20.
(CHUCKLES)
(ALL CHEERING)
Ooh!
A little more champers?
More champagne.    Oh, yes, more champagne.
(ALL CHATTERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
MADAME SOUSATZKA: Manek, don't eat like... Oh!
A moment, everybody.
Oh, here we go.
Once again  on this great day,
I give you  our dear friend,  our kind hostess,
our great pianist    and pedagogue,    Madame Irina.
Madame Irina!  Oh, Madame Irina!
No, Madame Sousatzka. Oh!
A celestial woman  in the heroic mode.
(HICCUPPING)
I hear her voice,  not to put too fine  a point upon it,
bellowing at her students.
Mr. Cordle,   I'm as gentle as dove.
Manek?
(CHATTERING)   Manek?
CORDLE:  Strong as the Valkyries.
In her blood,    is the strength    of America.
Her spirit, borne by  the mighty winds
that sweep  the Steppes of Russia.
(MUTTERING) Breath of autumn...
And yet,  she's as light and heady  as this champagne.
Ooh, not like   this cake.
It's horrid, isn't it?
May we always meet  and eat together
on this great day    wherever we may be.
And where would  we be but here?
Oh.  MADAME SOUSATZKA:  I will drink to that.
JENNY: Oh, hold it.
JENNY: Great!   MANEK: Great!
JENNY: This is    going to be good.
This is for you, Irina.
Oh!   From Edward.
From Edward   with love.
(CHUCKLES)
Mmm.  Oh!
Rachmaninov.  Oh.
Who's Edward?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Jenny, champagne.
Here.  (GLASS CLINKING)
Ah!
E flat.   What?
He has perfect pitch.
(CLINKS)   A.
(ALL LAUGH)
B flat.
Delightful.
G sharp and F.
Yes.
(HUMMING NOTE)
(PLAYS CHORD)
(GLASS CLINKING IN UNISON)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
(HUMMING TUNE)
Let it play. Let it play.
She's going to play.
(SIGHS)
(BOTH PLAYING PIANO)
ELENA: (HARSHLY)    You ought to be good...
You think you play a concert?
Did you have  a good time?
This is the day  that I miss  Maman
the most.
The most?
The most,   the most of all.
Wait here for me.
No, get back    to the car.
(RINGS DOORBELL)
Manek!
Babu!
(DOORBELL RINGING)
This better   be important.
I've brought your shampoo.
I don't believe it. You're mad.
You'll need it in the morning.
Who's that?
Oh, not that    fat Sunil.
Someone's got   to keep me company.
But why him  of all people?
Where are you sleeping?  Which room?
Breathe on me.  You've been drinking.
So what?
She's supposed    to teach you how
to play the piano,   not how to drink.
Your father did  enough of that.
Well, I hope nothing has happened.
No, she just came   to bring me   my shampoo.
Well, how thoughtful. At 1:00 in the morning.
Well, if he doesn't use   this very special shampoo   I buy for him,
his hair gets into  a terrible tangle.
Well, if there's no crisis, perhaps we could all get back to sleep.
Manek, you have    a hard day tomorrow.
You need all the rest   you can get.
Good night, Madame.
The door closes by itself.
There's no need to slam it.
People are sleeping.
Don't you dare let her  give you any liquor.  I'll tell her myself.
Go home. A boy your age?
She must be crazy.   She looks a little crazy.
Come on, Mum.  Please, go.
Uh-uh.
Babu!
Now what?
I forgot this.
(LAUGHS)
I'll be home Sunday.   We can go see a film   if you want.
Thank you.    Take care.
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
(SOFT TAPPING)
(ELENA YELLING IN RUSSIAN)
(CONTINUES YELLING IN RUSSIAN)
A triumph...
And courageous, completely  courageous and brave.
Irina, darling,    I didn't know    you were here.
(GASPS) Oh, my God!
There's somebody I want you to meet.    But, this is my...
(COMPLIMENTING IN FRENCH)
A refreshing change from last night.
Her Tchaikovsky simply  wasn't wild enough.
It might as well  have been Debussy.
BLUM: Well,  she's mostly in Japan.
It doesn't matter there,  I suppose. Excuse me.   What?
I'm sorry. Excuse me   just a moment.   Do you mind?
Many congratulations.  It was a wonderful  performance.
Would you mind just  signing my friend's...
My pleasure.
Wonderful surprise!    How are you?
I wanted to   surprise you.    Oh!
Thanks very much indeed.   We'll catch you later on.
Thank you. Excuse me.
If you want to get    to the front, you've got    to push. Always.
Ronnie Blum.   Manek Sen.
Ronnie!
Hello, Leo. What a marvelous evening.
Manek,   this is Leo Milev,
one of the truly great    piano teachers    of the world.
This is Manek, a young man with a big future.
Madame's latest.  Ah.
You should get Leo  to let you sit in on  one of his master classes.
WOMAN: Oh, I wanted   to surprise you.
How is the family?
Oh, they're well,   they're well.
I believe this is hers. She might not like to take it from me.
She still hasn't   forgiven me.
Oh, you mean Edward?    Uh-huh.
Where is Edward    these days?
He's in Ottawa,    and in precisely    half an hour
he'll be playing    the Bartok    Second Concerto.
How long is it since  you last saw each other?
Up in New York.  WOMAN: Up in New York.
Are you still  in the same place?
Could you excuse me?   Sure.
How are you?  You look gorgeous.
Oh. Oh.
It's really time to go, Manek.
Excuse me, Mr. Blum.
What did he say to you, Mr. Ronnie Blum?
He wants   to hear me play.
And what did  you say to him?
That he'd have to talk to you.
Quite right.
Is Ronnie  Jenny's boyfriend?
He won't last  five minutes,
because a greedy agent got hold of him and started him much too early.
I've seen it happen    over and over.
Fail once and  they'll drop you  like a hot potato.
This is one    of Leo Milev's students.
I saw you talking   to Leo.
What did he have to say?   What did Leo have to say?
He gave me this.
Oh.
Poor Leo. Frankly,  I don't like him,
but I feel sorry    for him.
In the middle   of a good career,
he lost the use of his arm.
What else did he have to say?
Did he talk about Edward?   What did he say, huh?
He said to   give you the bead.
No, not that.  Why do they all think  I still care about Edward?
Where is Edward now?
In Ottawa,    playing the Bartok    Second Concerto.
Oh.  Right now.
Bartok!  As though he could  ever play Bartok.
Bartok!
Ah, Madame Sousatzka!    (GASPS)
I did knock.
I'm glad to catch you  alone for a moment.
Look, would you care  to join me for  a spot of lunch?
I'm extremely busy, Mr. Blum.
Then I'll come straight  to the point.
I'd like to hear  Manek play.
Oh, that's impossible.
That's quite impossible.    Manek is no concern    of yours.
But why?
You teach him  how to play,
I, how to make a living.
Making a living as you put it, Mr. Blum,
is not what music   is all about.
And I have a rule    that none of my students    will appear in public
before he or she    is ready.
I see.
And who decides    when that is?
I decide, of course.
In every case   and in this case   especially.
Rubinstein, Lipatti,
Nadia Boulanger,
Schnabel.
I remember hearing him play when I was four years old, at the Albert Hall.
You see, we all have music  in our blood in a sense,  Mr. Blum.
Even you.
All of  our great-grandmothers  played Chopin.
Well, actually mine    ironed shirts    down the Mile End Road.
Manek's great-grandmother   played the sitar   or some such instrument,
and so now he has to  catch up on 600 years  of European music.
Well, I'm afraid    I can't wait that long.
(LAUGHING) Perhaps  you shouldn't wait at all.
(DOOR OPENING)
Ah, Manek!    Good, you're here.
Mr. Blum was   just leaving.
Hi. How are you?
Nice to see you again. Hello.
Yes, I was just telling Madame
how very much I'd like  to hear you play.
(MOUTHING) No.
What do you   want to hear?
Madame says I can't.
Why?
She forbids it.
Why can't I play    for Mr. Blum?
All right, then. Play.
Play! Play for anyone.
Play in the street  for all I care.
Don't let me stop you.
There's no need at all to respect my wishes or my feelings.
And go on,  sit in  Maman's chair!
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(MANEK PLAYING PIANO)
(KIDS CHATTERING)
(KIDS CHEERING)
Whoa!
(KIDS LAUGHING)    MANEK: Ouch!
It's just a little fever,   Madame Sousatzka.
Um, on antibiotics.
Yes, thank you, I'll tell him you called.
Goodbye.
(SIGHS)
What did she say?
I don't know why    you can't tell her.
If she knew   it was my hand...
She's mad enough at me  as it is.
I know she's mad.  Completely cuckoo.
Here, give me a hand.
Hello.   Good evening. Here.  Hello.
I'll take those.
Mr. Beechy would like   to see you upstairs.
Unfortunately, this was    returned by one of    our most valued patrons.
I can't imagine how it got there.
As you know, Mrs. Sen,    this has happened before.
You have my word  of honor, Mr. Beechy.  It won't happen again.
I'm afraid this has to be our last warning.
Oh, absolutely.  I'll see to it personally.
So kind of you.
Ah, this is my son,  the concert pianist.
Mum...  Anyway,  he soon will be.
Yes, you will,    my darling.
Thank you, Mr. Beechy.  Goodbye.
Stupid old man.
You nearly got  the sack there.
The kitchen  is bloody filthy.
Tomorrow, you and me  are going to clean it out.
Ah! They're all talk.
Mmm.
You must be mad buying them in that place.
You can get them    for half that    anywhere.
Mmm?
Not these.  These are the real things.
(LAUGHS)  Alphonsoes.
Mmm.
(MAN SPEAKING IN HINDI)
(DOORBELL CHIMING)
Hey.
Yes, I'm looking    for Mrs. Sen    and Manek, please.
Oh, yes,  Mrs. Sen and Manek.
They're upstairs.    Thank you.
You'll wait for me, then?   MAN: I suppose so.
Thank you.   Up here?
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Manek, it's Sousatzka.
(CHUCKLES)    What a surprise.    He'll be so pleased.
How is he?  Oh, much better today.
The temperature went down to normal for the first time.
And he ate    some rice and curds.
(GASPS)  What beautiful flowers.  Asters are my favorite.
Those are chrysanthemums    and lilies.
Oh.
I'm so sorry  about this mess.
We weren't  expecting anyone.
Oh! Manek! How are you?
Look, Manek,  what lovely flowers  she's got you.
Your mother tells me  you're feeling better.
Well, come here,    let me see you.
Come here.  I was worried.
Well, look at you...  (CHUCKLING)
(GROANS)
What is this? (GASPS)
What does that mean? It's nothing, Madame S.
What happened?
I don't even know   why I'm wearing this.
Why was I told lies?
I despise deceit.  Why did you have  your mother tell me lies?
Oh, it was just a little white lie
because we knew   you'd be so upset   about his hand.
See, not even a bruise.
How did you do this?  You did it with football  or some such sport.
You haven't been using  those skates again.
Manek, you promised me  that you would never, never...
They were a birthday present. And they save bus fare.
Will you promise now?
Yeah.
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  No, say it, that you will  never use them again.
That you will  throw them away.  Say it. "I promise."
I promise.
I think you'd better go and wash your hands. You look a mess.
I brought you   some books.
I think you'd best start  with  Crime and Punishment.
You remind me  of Raskolnikov,
those dark,  good looks of yours.
I hope you never  take an ax to me.  I'd hope not.
If you like it.
Thank you.
Isn't it terrible the way  they always stay babies,  isn't it?
Running here and there,  we have to stop them,
and say, "Don't do this. Don't do that."
I wanted to ask you,    Madame Sousatzka.
When do you think  he'll be ready  to give a concert?
Has he talked   to you about this?
No, he hasn't. I'm speaking to you about it.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Manek, I think  you should explain  to your mother.
I thought she understood,  but apparently not.
Explain what?
I asked when  you're going  to play a concert.
Oh, you...    Oh, I know I'm just    ignorant, of course.
Not a cultured person  or a music teacher,  just your mother.
It's what we've been  planning and working  for all these years.
Who's "we"?
My son and I.
Leave it now.  Leave it alone.
And what about  all the concerts  you're going to play?
Why else have I been  slaving and saving and...
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  Mrs. Sen, let me  be frank with you.
Manek's playing  is immature.
He doesn't think  before he plays.
Sometimes he shows off  like a child.
He's simply not    strong enough yet
to communicate    with an audience.
You mean,  he's not good enough?
No, I didn't say that.
I said he's not ready.
We just have  to wait and see.
And in the meantime  what am I supposed to do,
with all the debts   I have to pay?
Are you saying  that this boy should  give his talent,
his God-given talent to pay your debts?
My debts?  Are they just my debts?
Mom, just shut it.
No, really, are they   just my debts?
No, they're mine, too.
I'll see you tomorrow  at the usual time.
Please don't forget to put the flowers into water.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
Did you really mean that,   Madame S.?
Did you?
I'm glad I said it.   Yes, I am.
And, my God,    it's true.
It's high time you gave a concert.
I just can't keep waiting  till the day I die.
And of course it's  too much to expect you  to help clean up this mess.
Stop doing that.
(SPEAKING BENGALI)
As if I have   10 servants.
Does she own you?
And who does   she think I am?
Just nobody, nothing.
I'm not even  allowed to speak.
And why do you have to stay there every Friday?
You can jolly well stay and practice at home.
I have to use  a concert grand.  This one's no good.
Oh, I'm so terribly sorry.
I have no more jewelry    to sell for you.
It's all gone.
For your music,   for your piano,   and for you.
No, no, wait.
Here's your grandmother's   wedding necklace.
Maybe I should sell that as well.
I'm sick of it!
Babu, don't go.  Please.
I can't stand all this.
I'm sorry.
It's only because I love you so much.
You've got a funny way  of showing it.
Come back here.   Please.
I've brought you    a present.
Mmm.
You look beautiful.
You are beautiful.
Just like your father.
That's something   I can't take away   from that bastard.
Oh, don't start.
Oh, I'm not    starting again.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Blum Associates.    MAN: (ON PHONE)     Ronnie Blum, please.
I'm sorry,  he's on the other line.
BLUM: And he can be in Glasgow at 7:00,
go to the hotel and change  and still be on at 8:00.
Anyway, he's not 80.    Who told you he was?  (MAN LAUGHS)
He's 75.  MAN:  Well, if you say so.
All right, let me know. Bye.
Look, we still need    something special    for the final night.
Who have you got?
Well, at the moment  I'm trying for  the London Symphony.
It's not fixed.  It's looking good.
Oh, that would  be terrific.
We've got  a great room for them.
The acoustics are crystal clear.
And if you can book them,  well, I'm sure  there's a broadcast in it.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yup.   WOMAN: (ON PHONE)    Your wife's on the line.
Yeah. Tell her I'll ring her later at home.
The sponsors are    coming through well.
And I've got    one or two slots    up my sleeve.
Well, I've got    a young pianist up mine.
I'd really like him to play.
Yeah, well, who is he?  What's he done?
He's only 15, charismatic,  intensely musical.
And look at him.  His mother's a caterer  who does Indian food.
You mean, she's part    of the package?
(CHUCKLES)
What? Listen,   it might be   worth a thought.
Pull in Air India  as a sponsor.
He's never played  in public before.
I'm following my instincts  on this one.  (TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hi, how are you?
BLUM: Yup.  (MAN CHATTERING ON PHONE)
No, no, it's not going to work.
No, he's playing in Paris   on the night of the 29th.
Hi. You said 1:00.
Then he has to travel   to Chicago.
It's a bad time.
Yeah, it's always   a bad time.
BLUM: It will be 3:00 in the morning for him.
MAN: (ON PHONE)   Well, I can try and change it.
BLUM: Yeah, okay.  MAN:  Maybe the 3rd.
All right, let me know.  Thanks. Bye.
What do you think?
Mmm.
I meant the boy.
Oh.
Well, I'd have    to hear him.
Yes, sure, fine.
She's a pop singer.
Any good.   Ah.
She's a woman of many talents.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yeah.  WOMAN: (ON PHONE)   Raymond Sharp for you.
Yeah, put him on.
MAN: (ON PHONE)    They can't manage the 3rd.
No, well, look,  you'll just have to give
the poor old boy  a good night's sleep.
Fly him in   on Concorde...
JENNY: Coffee? Oh, no, thanks.
I had some earlier, it was ghastly.
Mmm.
I'm Vincent Pick.  Oh, hi. I'm Jenny.
Ronnie tells me    you're a singer.   Mmm.
He said some  nice things about you.
Oh, really? Well,  that makes a change.
He says I ought  to hear you.  Do you have some tapes?
Only some demos, I don't sound too good.
No, I'm sure  you sound much better  in the flesh.
(LAUGHS)
Why don't I hear you?
Perhaps we could  go to my office.
Have some lunch  on the way.
Now?
Oh, you cover the fare, and you cover his expenses
and you cover the hotel.
Why not?
(DIALING)
Kristoff.    Two for lunch.
(CAR APPROACHING)
Get that tape over to me  and I'll hear it.
Yeah, pull the other one.
Jenny?  Who is it?
It's me,    I've brought the single.
Oh, just put it  on the table.
Very flash car, that.
Jesus!    Can't do a thing    in this bloody house
without everybody   talking about it.
Sorry, you just can't  miss a car like that.
Nor the flashy bastard  driving it.
(SOBBING)
Oh, this stupid thing.
Oh, shit!
Sorry.
Do you want to  know something, Manek?
Forget about the music business.
Just do your school  stuff and get yourself  a proper job.
This is lovely.   Is it silk?
It's so soft.
You better go or Madame would be after me.
Oh, it's all right, she's in the bath.
Oh.
Can I come and  talk to you some more?
I mean, I can come  on Friday for tea  or something.
I don't have    to eat anything.
You know, just...
Saturdays.    Out.
By the way,    the single's brilliant.
I've told everyone I know   to buy it.
(LAUGHING) Go.
(DOOR CLOSING)
What are you wearing?
Jenny is a goodhearted girl, I'm sure.
But I'm afraid  she has no talent.
Poor girl.   It can't be easy for her.
Do you know how old she is?
No, never mind. Play.
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
Remember the talk we had  about the wholeness of music?
Whatever you do matters.
Well, it also includes  the friends you make.
Friends at school,  girls, women.
Whatever.  You need to discriminate.
It also includes  what you wear.
Someone gave it to me.
Ah, no.
Beethoven was not angry  when he wrote this.
Who gave it to you?
My mother.
Mmm-hmm. It plays.
It's playing.    I'm playing.
(CRUNCHING)
(CONTINUES PLAYING)
(PLAYING FALTERS)
Aha! You see?  What did I tell you?
So there's still something  left for you to learn,  Mr. Know-It-All.
No, no! Like this.
And you need a haircut.
(SCOFFS)  Elephant. Elephant.
And do you think   you're ready   to play in public?
This is all    you're good for.
(PLAYS EXERCISE)
And have you read any of the books I've given you?
Have you ever even  opened one of them?  Well, what do you expect?
How can you play  without some  basic culture?
Fuck your culture! (GASPS)
It's all these    dead creeps looking    at me when I play.
You'll never belong there.  You'll never be like them.
You're ignorant  and uneducated!
Well, at least I'm not dead.
Go on. Run!
That's the easiest way    for cowards and failures.
Run!
You see,   you're a failure.
You're a coward, and cowards always run!
Run, run, run, run, run, run!
(MAN SHOUTS)    Shut up!
MAN 1: Up your end.   MAN 2: Right. Got it.
Careful with that now.
WOMAN: Ooh. MAN 2: All right.
Bought that 40 years ago.  Imagine what it's worth now.
Careful, careful.
That's fine.
(MEN CHATTERING)
Lady Emily?
(MAN WHISTLING)
(MAN CHATTERS)
So they got    her out finally,    did they?
Yes.
Well, surely you're not staying?
Of course I'm staying.
My students will  just have to learn  to play louder.
They'll become inured  to all the people having
coughing fits  in the auditorium.
(CHUCKLES)
Come for tea?
Well, I wouldn't  mind one of your  mother's biscuits.
Come on.
Anyhow,  the law's on my side.
They can't get me  out of this house.
I want to ask you something.
A favor.
To take on a new student.
No. No, I can't.  Now, listen.
You'll like him.
I think he's    very talented.    No, I can't.
Too much. Especially now,   just as Manek is about   to make his breakthrough.
And you know how that is when you go from here to there. No.
How old is he?
The same age as you were    when you left me.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
I never left you.
You know that.
Even now,
today when I'm playing   in a concert,
you're somehow with me.
When things get tough,
when the piano behaves   like a monster,
and the audience is another monster,
well, then I hear you   yelling at me,
telling me    to get on with it.
And I listen,
and I know...
I know that all those    hours with you
have formed a little core of strength in me,
and that gets me    through it.
You know what  they say about me.
They say that I made  terrible scenes when  you left me for Leo,
that I went mad    like a jealous mistress.
That I, uh...
That I was in love   with you. (SCOFFS)
A 16-year-old boy...
(SCOFFS)
Well, of course I was in love with you.
Isn't every mother in love  with the son she creates?
So why shouldn't I love    in the same way?
(CRYING)
No.
(SOBBING)
(BARKING)
(DOG BARKING)    (EXCLAIMS)
Oh.
Is that macaroni cheese?
Yes.
And sago pudding.
Oh! Don't you adore being English?
(CHUCKLES)
Does it remind you   of your nursery?
Deliciously horrid.
Please. I really    can't manage it.
And their feelings    will be so hurt.
(CHUCKLES) But    I can't eat your dinner.
They're doing their best,
but they're not doing  my hip any good.
What I need
is a really   good osteopath.
You'll find a good man locally.
I'll look   in the directory.
There's only one  good osteopath,
and he lives in London.
Though I can't think  of any good reason why.  Can you?
Not really, no,
now you mention it.
No, please,  just a little more,  before Nurse comes,
for my sake.
Well, just for you.
Thank you, dear friend.
You know, one person   living in London,
and another  in a lovely place  by the river,
with two bedrooms,
doesn't make sense,    does it?
(DOOR OPENING)
Finished all  your nice dinner?
Delicious.  There's a good girl.
Oi, come on. Get out!
(BARKING)
Where is she?
She's very upset.
I've told her, who needs this job?
I'm here.
Does she take  one spoon or two?
Not enough milk.
(SIGHS)
Come on.
You know how  you hate cold tea.
(SNIFFLES)
They said I didn't meet  their standards.
What do they know about samosas and stuff?
I like them,
hair and all.
(SPEAKS BENGALI)
What are we  going to do?
I'll worry about that.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
You see, Manek,  this festival is a great  opportunity for you.
And then, after this,  we'll make sure you play  in competitions,
build your repertoire.  Thank you. We're thinking  long term here.
You do want to be  a concert pianist?
Sure, I do.
I just don't want   to jump in there   before I'm ready.
(SCOFFS) But, Manek,  you are ready.
I mean, my God,  I wouldn't normally  touch a kid of your age.
But from the moment I...  Here, let me.
From the moment  I first heard you play,
I was interested,   I was excited.
You're very advanced.   You know that?
That's not what  Madame Sousatzka says.
Now, I know this  is difficult for you  to understand, but...
She's a good teacher, a great teacher,
but she suffers from mixed motives.
It's an old story.
And she's limited in her experience.
She doesn't seem to know the world.
I could take you    to places... Here.
I could take you  to places where  they'd queue all night
to hear someone  as good as you.
Come on.
You've got the opportunity  to make a lot of money  doing what you enjoy most.
Well, what do you  think then?
About the festival.
I don't know  what to think.
One person says    you're great,    another...
(SIGHS) I don't know.
Is Jenny your girlfriend?
Well, it's funny   you should ask me that.
You see, Jenny and I  have a very special  relationship.
Now, I've got  a little surprise for you.
This should sort out    what you think.
(CAR HORN HONKS)
MAN 1:  Egg, bacon,
beans, sausages,
tomatoes...
MAN 2: All right,  that's fine there.
Is that it?
Not yet.
Move over to the piano now, mate.
Joanna...
Yup.
(FEEDBACK SQUEALING)
Hold on a second.
Minestrone, Irish stew,
one, two, one, two...
Give us a minute, Mr. Blum.
MAN 1:  Spaghetti.
Okay, fine. Thank you.
Lasagna.
MAN 2: Okay, mate, can you  go to the drums now?
All right.
You on half time again?
Cold pizza,
soggy chips.
Well, go on then.   Doner kebabs...
The piano, Manek.
Shish kebab. Kit-E-Kat.
Go on, it's all right.
Caviar.
Schnitzel.
That's fine, mate.  Let's take a break.
All right.
Shut the lights out.
Rock 'n' roll.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
What're you going to do now the house is being sold?
You're here to play  for me, not to gossip  about this house.
What's that?
Just looking at it.
You're not tired of  the Beethoven,  are you?
You tired of me? Hmm?
Look at me. Why so shy?  Oh, my goodness.
Come here.   Come here.
Ah.
You know that  when you hate me...
No, I know  sometimes you do.
That I do it all for you.
Hmm?
He hasn't been  calling you, has he?
That agent?
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
People haven't been trying  to get at you, have they?
What people, Madame S.?
It is impossible to have a serious conversation with you.
(PLAYING ROCK AND ROLL)
(CHUCKLES)
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  Can you manage?
Oh, yes, thank you.
It's very easy, really.    Once you get used to it.
I think he's going to be    quite a tall young man.
Yes.
Not just  physically either.
Mmm! I cannot tell you, Lady Emily, how he's developing.
His talent. Mmm.  His talent.
Of course I give him hell,  you know?
I don't make  life easy for him,  I can tell you.
(LAUGHING)
Well...
Young people are  so very sensitive.
One has to be   a little circumspect,   don't you find?
Mmm-mmm. An artist has  no right to be sensitive.  He has to be tough.
Do you know   what I think?
I think he's going  to be better than  anyone I've ever had.
Yes.
"Even the weariest river  winds somewhere safe to sea."
That's Algernon Swinburne.
You're far away.  You're thinking of something  entirely different.
I'm going to play for Ronnie Blum's festival.
Oh, that's wonderful.
I take it you haven't   told her yet.
You'll have to tell her.
She'll go    out of her mind.
She'll tear me to bits.
Possibly.
She has a very   excessive nature.
You just have   to put up with it.
(SCOFFS)
As one grows older,  there are many things  one has to put up with,
or do without.
I miss you,    and our little    sessions together.
Me, too.
Really?
Well, it'll be charming  to believe that you think  of me sometimes,
when I think of you  quite often.
(HUMMING MELODY)   Yes.
What is it?     Carmen.
(HUMMING MELODY)
Emperor. All right.
Ronnie Blum's asked me   to play at a festival,
and I'm gonna do it.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HONKING)
MADAME SOUSATZKA:  Come on!
(CONTINUES HONKING)
Hey, I think  it's self-service.
Here. Let me.
If it's only money,   why don't you play   in a cocktail bar?
(CLICKS TONGUE)
It's your mother.    That's all she ever    thinks about, money.
That's because  she never has any.
(SCOFFS) I've heard her  go on and on and on at you.
About how much she's  done for you, all her  sacrifices she's made.
No, she doesn't.
Don't lie to me, I've heard it myself.
It was she who went    to Ronnie Blum.
She had nothing  to do with it.  It was me.
I don't believe you.
You wouldn't    sell yourself    to that man.
Well, thanks for driving.
I'll see you tomorrow.
(SIGHS)
If this is really how it is,
this is what  you want to do,
then I can't teach you anymore.
I see.
Sorry, but I can't.
It'd be completely    against my principles.
That's better.  That's better.
It's lovely. Lovely.
Let's hear the murmurs  of the forest.
The wind whispering.
Watch your left hand.  Caress it, caress it.
Less rubato.
Less rubato still.
That's lovely. Lovely.  Surge ahead towards  the climax.
Ah, good. Now, breathe  between the phrases,  just as you talk.
That's fine.
Enjoy it, enjoy it.
Caress it now.   Caress it.
Lovely.
Manek, I believe
you have good potential.
And she's been teaching you well.
But I don't think  it would be right  for me to take you in
until after your concert is over.
What do you    intend to play?
Schumann Concerto.
I wish you well.
Thank you.
Oh, and, Manek, if afterwards,
after your performance,  you still want to come,
we can talk again.
(MANEK PLAYING PIANO)
(SIGHS)
(HORN HONKING)
WOMAN:    I've been here before...
MAN 1: No,  it's a lovely spot.
Have you seen round  the back of the house?
MAN 2: A day like this  lulls you into  the false belief
that this country  has a nice climate,  doesn't it?
(WOMAN LAUGHS)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Jason, the sponsor signs!  Where the hell are they?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Sorry. Sorry, my fault.
(CLEARS THROAT)   Slight hiccup with   the kitchen arrangements,
but I'm sure we can get... Hello.
Just a minute, just a minute.
I tell you what,   let's skip   the main course.
Let's go on to some  cheese, we can always  come back afterwards...
Whenever I see him, he'd come running up to me, shirt flapping, and say,
"Ronnie, Ronnie,  look how thin  I'm getting."
Oh, good.    I haven't missed dinner yet.    I'm absolutely starving.
Hello.
Excuse me.
Just a couple   of minutes.
Jenny, do you know   who those people are?
They represent one of   the largest merchant   banks in the world.
Really? Well, thanks  for the introduction.
Look, Vincent has  to play it very carefully.
Oh, well, I'm sure he'll do just fine.
Oh, I could have   been a pierrette.
They've got such    lovely costumes.
You don't want  to do that, Jenny.  It's demeaning.
(SCOFFS) Being with you  is demeaning, Ronnie Blum.
ANNOUNCER ON PA:    Ladies and gentlemen,
the main concert
of the evening with the
London Symphony Orchestra
is about to begin.
Will you please
take your seats?
Take your seats, please,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
There you are.
Just came  to wish you good luck.  You're gonna be great.
Thanks.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Sunil, don't do that.
I'm only tasting.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
ANNOUNCER:  That was
the overture o The Marriage   of Figaro  by Mozart.
The London Symphony
Orchestra was conducted
by Christopher Adey.
Now, this concert
from the Heaton Park
Music Festival,
which is being
broadcast live
on Radio 3,
continues with
the performance of
The Piano Concerto in A minor
by Robert Schumann,
which he dedicated to
his wife, the concert
pianist Clara Wieck.
Tonight's soloist,
Manek Sen,
is actually making
his debut at this
festival concert.
He's only 15 years old.
He was born in England
of Indian-born parents...
One deep breath.
...and he's a pupil at
the Ebury Bridge comprehensive
school in London.
He's studying the piano
with Irina Sousatzka.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES ON RADIO)
(PLAYING FALTERS)
The decay.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Manek, what do you think    you're doing? You must    come back.
I can't go back... You must come back.
Hardly anybody would have   even heard the mistake.
(CHEERING)
I thought his playing was a little too temperamental,
but that's youth.
Absolutely wild.
It was a triumph.
Oh, thank you.    Thank you so much.
I do hope your cooking  is as good as your  son's piano playing.
No, really?   He was marvelous.
Very successful day.
Boy, do I need a lager.
So do I.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
I cut eight bars.
It doesn't matter.
It simply doesn't   matter at all.
What do they know?  (SCOFFS) We know.
Tonight was a bad dream and now we go on. You and I.
Yes? My dear.
Tomorrow evening,  you come to my studio.
We'll make a celebration.   Just the two of us, huh?
And then  we'll begin again.
And we work. Oh! Mmm.
We will work.
(LAUGHS)    I will kill you yet,    my poor darling boy.
Hi.
Where's all your stuff?
Got rid of most of it.
Load of old junk, really.
(SIGHS)
Let me stay   with you tonight.
Manek, I don't even have a bed.
(SIGHS)
(MAN SHOUTING)
(CONSTRUCTION NOISES)
Have you had your breakfast?  You missed dinner.
Thanks.
I came to say    goodbye to you,
and to Jenny.
To all of you.
And to thank you for   everything, Madame S.
(MEN CHATTERING)
MANEK:  Dear Madame S.,
please don't be angry,
but I've decided to
study with Leo Milev.
I shall never forget
what you've taught me,
and I will always
be grateful.
I hope you understand
and will forgive me.
With love, Manek.
P.S. I hope it plays
as well for him
as it did for you.
EDWARD: Oh, there's  no need to be nervous.  Don't worry.
When I first came here, that was over 10 years ago,
I was more nervous  than you are now,  I'm sure.