Fifty years ago
Paris was a light-hearted city
the goal of many a traveler
but some came not
for gaiety but to work
to study at one of the world's
most famous university
the Sorban.
To its lecture room and classes
came students
from all over the world
and among them was a young girl.
She was poor. She was beautiful.
She had left her
homeland and family
and here in Paris, she was alone
haunted by
dreams and invincibly eager
To go out alone into space.
Go out alone.
In one hundred years
one hundred students
but when it is time
for you to think
you, too, will be alone
like the author of this equation
like Newton
let us say your Galileo.
Probably will not be your
good fortune to reach the sky
to catch the stars
in your fingertips.
To catch a star
But this you can share with them.
You can learn to
be alone with nature
with the ray of light
piece of earth
drop of rain
you can become aware
that the earth's swirling
about the sun
at the rate of
66,000 miles per hour.
Aware that the...
What... what's that?
You are feeling better? Sit.
Sit still a moment. You fainted.
I... I’m sorry I interrupted
the lecture so stupidly.
You can get the notes
from some other students.
Your name is Marie Scholoscka?
Yes. You are working
in two master degrees.
One in physics and one in mathematics.
You passed first in the...
mathematical examination
last year.
What did you have to eat today?
Eat?
Yes, eat.
I don't remember.
I have some lunch.
What did you have?
Salmon. All sort of things.
You have a pleasant room?
Yes, monsieur.
Good.
What time did you have that coat
Come along.
Come along, please.
This is rather unusual to have no
friends here in Paris.
I have little time for friends.
Usually, there's some young men.
I'm interested in physics
and mathematics.
Yes, so am I.
Yet, I have a wife and a home
a daughter
and two granddaughters
I'm afraid
I will not be up to that.
Your desire is to
go back to Poland and teach?
Yes.
Your parents are still in Warsaw
My father is a physics professor
He is old.
When I have my degrees
I shall go back and live with him.
You love Poland.
Oh, yes. I love Poland.
Physics and
mathematics and Poland.
Yes.
Eat your soup.
Thank you very much.
The Society of Natural Industry
has asked me
to recommend someone
to make a study of the magnetic
property of rare steel.
I would be glad to recommend you
if you wish.
There would be some
cumbersome costs
I don't know exactly what.
Oh, it wouldn't matter.
Really it wouldn't.
I would be so grateful.
Of course, that our cumbersome
equipment too cumbersome
for our laboratories, I'm afraid.
However, I know a scientist
of great merit
who works in the school
of physics and chemistry.
Perhaps he might have
recommendation available.
Come and have tea Sunday
with my wife and me.
I will ask him to come, too.
You probably know his name.
It is Pierre Curie.
Oh, thank you so much. Thank you
You have been very kind.
Not at all. Not at all.
Good bye then. Until Sunday.
Sunday. Good night.
Good night.
To catch a star
at your fingertips.
Ah. Madame Poirot.
You are Mdme. Scholoscka.
I knew it.
Yes.
We've been waiting for you.
My husband has told me
all about you.
Ah. Professor Curie. How nice?
Madame.
You two had met?
Have not had the honor
in the hallway.
This is Mdme. Marie Scholoscka.
professor Pierre Curie.
My husband said
you have no friends in Paris
but that's impossible, child
We must remedy that.
Please Professor...
Come in. Come in.
I'm sure you know everyone here.
In Paris
you must have many friends.
I want you to meet
all these charming...
May I introduce you to...
This is Mdme. Scholoscka...
What time?
Always hard to meet, gentlemen.
Dr. Curie
Good afternoon.
I had no idea that
it was going to be a party.
No... I believe you, monsieur.
They're pulling up suddenly
these parties
out of the goodness of
women's hearts.
My wife wishes the young student
of mine to make many friends.
Well, I... I'm very bad
at parties.
It's impossible for me to focus.
My mind won't follow the
most simple thought.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
You are quite alright.
Maybe I'll come back
some other day.
No... I want to talk to you
about this student of mine.
Perhaps we can find
a quiet corner
where we can talk.
Of course. Of course.
And as this student has
very little money, and is
I believe, extremely talented
I thought you might have
room available
at physics and chemistry.
Oh, I should be very glad.
Unfortunately at the moment
we are extremely
crowded ourselves.
In that case...
However, my workroom is
quite large.
I would hesitate to ask you
to share your own laboratory...
I have shared it
with students before.
You have?
Yes, and some of them were
very quiet and pleasant.
On the other hand
one fellow was most troublesome.
He used to whistle constantly.
Well, I can assure you that
this student is very serious.
Then I should be very happy.
I think you will find that
she is very sincere.
She?
Oh, my God.
These are my granddaughters.
Excuse me.
But...
Mademoiselle. Mademoiselle.
Bon Appetit. A coffee?
Yes, thank you. Tea.
That's coffee.
That's coffee, too.
Oh.
Please sit down, everybody.
Sit down. Wait a moment.
Come along... children.
It's time for your performance.
Would you excuse them, Dr. Curie.
They are going to play the piano.
Come along... There they are.
This is the student of whom
we were speaking.
Mme. Scholoscka.
Dr. Pierre Curie.
We have already met.
Dr. Curie is gracious
in consenting
for you to work
in his laboratory
I am very grateful.
Of course, I have no idea
that is...
Would you sit down, Madame?
Oh, would you please excuse me.
I feel my grandchildren are about
to entertain.
Would you care for tea?
Thank you. I've just had some.
It's coffee.
I appreciate very deeply
Dr. Curie
the privilege of working in
your laboratory.
Playing incredibly badly
don't you think?
Very badly, Dr. Curie.
Of course, I'm no judge.
Professor Poirot is an
excellent scientist.
Oh, good morning, Dr. Curie.
Good morning, David.
The furnace is taken down
and I'm beginning to set up
for room temperature readings.
I have the sulphates
all ready for you.
Thank you.
No one has arrived yet?
Here at the laboratory? Yes.
No, sir.
Are you expecting someone?
Well, a pupil of Dr. Poirot
who's going to do some work here
for a short time.
Yes, sir.
Her name is Marie Sc...
Funny, I was introduced
to her twice.
Scholoscka.
She's a girl.
I didn't find out in time.
Always the continuous struggle
against woman, David
When we wish to give
all our thoughts to some work
which is strangest to humanity
we always have to
struggle against woman.
Yes, sir. And women scientists
are particularly unattractive
I find, sir
Women's love in life is the
living of it.
In the world of
abstract research
she's a danger, destruction.
She's a natural enemy of science
There's no doubt of it, sir.
Woman and science are
incompatible.
Woman of genius are rare.
No true scientist
can have anything with women.
No, sir.
Anyway, David, put her over there
in that far corner.
Yes, sir.
And if you can
without being rude
inform her how important silence
is to laboratory work.
I do hope she doesn't whistle.
Oh, David.
Would you mind going to
the storeroom upstairs
and see
if there's a magnetometer.
She'll need
one for her experiments.
Oh, yes.
I... I'm very sorry, sir.
I beg your pardon
are you looking for something?
Yes. I'm looking for
Dr. Curie's laboratory.
You're here. But you're not...
I mean you can't be...
Excuse me, please.
No. You don't understand.
You see
I'm Dr. Curie's assistant.
Oh... then you can direct me.
Oh, I certainly can.
Certainly can.
Oh, just this way.
Thank you.
What do you think of that?
I run into you the first thing.
You know, Dr. Curie has asked me
look out for you.
Be sure to have
everything you want
so I'll just take everything
into my own hands.
Oh, here we are.
Here she is, Dr. Curie.
Run straight
into her the first day.
Oh. Good morning, Mademoiselle.
Good morning, Dr. Curie.
This time we met in rather a
less rude atmosphere.
Yes.
Well
that's just as it should be.
People interested in work
should be left alone.
You have met my assistant?
Yes. I don't think
I quite caught his name.
David. David Lagroue.
I'm sure that
David will see that
you're properly installed.
Thank you, Dr. Curie.
I appreciate this chance
more than I can say.
Not at all
Not at all, Mademoiselle
and I do hope
you'll be quite comfortable.
Over this way.
We picked out
a specially nice place
for you right over here.
You're going to have this
far corner all to yourself.
Of course
we would have it fixed up
for you had we known sooner
that you were coming
but we'll take care of
that right away.
How do you think
this is going to suit you?
Oh. It is excellent.
I understand you're a pupil of
Professor Poirot's?
Yes.
I've studied with him, too.
Wonderful isn't he?
Yes, he is. Oh, I'll give you
a little more light.
Please don't bother.
Oh, Dr. Curie wants you
to be comfortable.
I'm sorry, Dr. Curie.
Here's a paper and pencil.
You can make out a list for
all the things you need,
and I'll go and see
if I can get
a magnetometer for you.
Oh, I can take my coat off?
Oh. It's always
the way you should.
Your hat?
I'll hide it up
at the cupboard for you
I'm sorry, Dr. Curie.
Let me help you.
Thank you.
You know
my office is just upstairs.
I hope you won't
hesitate to call on me
if I can be of any assistance.
You're very kind.
You sure everything's alright?
Quite. Thank you.
Not at all.
If there is anything you'd like
to know about our equipment
I'd be glad to explain it to you
I want to give you some advice
on where to eat around here.
There's a very nice
little restaurant down...
Really, monsieur.
I don't think we should talk.
Why are you whispering?
I just think
you ought to know where to go.
Yes, but I...
I'll take you there later.
That's the best way and
It's too trouble.
Oh, no trouble at all.
I'll come back for you.
Good evening, Mademoiselle.
Good evening, Dr. Curie.
Miserable evening, hasn't it?
Yes, isn't it.
Oh, by the way
did David get you the
telescope scale
you asked for last week
Oh, yes. Thank you very much.
He finally look into it.
Good... Well, good evening.
But you have no umbrella
Mademoiselle
No, I haven't, Dr. Curie.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize.
Perhaps I can help you.
Oh, I don't want to trouble you.
Allow me. No trouble at all.
No trouble at all.
Thank you.
You're very kind.
Not at all, Mademoiselle.
May I ask you another question
Dr. Curie
in the same connection?
It's a simple matter, perhaps
but it puzzles me.
Yes, Mademoiselle?
In the semetry
L sub-Q and two L sub-Q
you include only those rotations
which are integral multiples
of two Pi L Q.
But two times
K over Q exclude
the identity transformation
if K is not an integer.
Yes. For final case, I guess.
But in a limited L sub infinity
a difficult seems to arise.
I don't see why it's
quite straightforward.
Well, if you consider the
matter rigorously...
Hmm. I have to look into that.
This is where I lived.
Good bye and thank you.
Of course...
Oh, good bye, mademoiselle.
And may I say your conversation
is very simplely
Thank you.
It's an extremely
dawning hypothesis.
Good morning, Mademoiselle.
Good morning, Dr. Curie.
I'm a little late this morning.
I have to stop
in at my publishers.
Oh.
To Mme. Scholoscka
my respect and
friendship of honor...
friendship of honor.
My book.
Oh, it's lovely.
One of the first copy
just off the press.
On semitry and
physical phenomena
Semitry of Electric Field
and of Magnetic Field
by Pierre curie.
That's something to be proud of.
I thought perhaps you might
like a copy.
Oh, I would very much.
Well, it's yours. It's yours
Mademoiselle.
Oh, thank you.
Not at all.
I've inscribed the book for you
mademoiselle
on the ply leaf.
I believe
that's the usual procedure.
I'm very flattered.
Not at all...
Come in. Oh, Dr. Becquerel.
I hope I'm not intruding
Dr. Curie.
But could you step over
my laboratory with me?
I think I've happened on something
of great interest.
Why? What is it?
Are you too busy to...?
Oh, no... Not at all.
I'll come at once.
Oh, aren't you coming
Mademoiselle?
Well, if I may?
You don't mind...
No. No. I'll be delighted.
I came upon it quite by accident
I think you'll agree that it is
very extraordinary...
What is this thing...
Well, what did you see?
You have taken
the picture of a key apparently.
Yes, the picture of a key.
But that picture
of a key was taken...
in a very extraordinary manner.
The picture of that key
was taken
in complete and total darkness
without light of any kind.
But, how was that possible?
Some months ago
I had the idea that perhaps
certain rocks and minerals
might store applied energy
from the sun
that if I left
the rocks and minerals
in the sun long enough
they might absorbed
some of its rays
and then later, give them out.
So I make some
photographic experiments
You see these rocks
they're all different kinds
of minerals
I labeled them as you see
and left them outside
in the sun for several hours.
Then I put them in this drawer
on photographic plates like this
and then I waited to see
if they would give out
any sunlight
they might have absorbed.
I see. And your experiment
was a success.
To the contrary, my experiment
was a complete failure.
Not one of the rocks
I have exposed to the sun
affected the plates in anyway.
See, there they are.
They're all black
every one of them.
Then how did you explain...
Now, look at this one, please.
That has been exposed
am I right?
Light has reached
Oh, yes. That has been exposed.
This plate was lying
in this drawer quite by accident.
I didn't even know it was there.
It's the drawer that I keep
some of my specimens in.
And when I was putting my rocks
back into the drawer
one of them must have fallen
on this plate
without my knowing it.
I discovered it yesterday.
This is the rock that
I have not yet exposed to the sun
it's a piece of mineral
called pitch blende.
To be sure
there could be no mistake
last night I myself
hide in this room
in complete darkness.
Took this rock, which had never
been exposed to the sun
and placed it
on a photographic plate.
I put this metal key
between the stone
and the plate like this
so that it would be photographed
if any light rays
came from the stone.
Half hour ago
I developed the plate.
This is the result.
You mean, then, that...
there is something about that rock
that gives off rays of its own.
Rays powerful enough to go
through black paper
and affect this photographic plate.
That, Monsieur, must be so.
Incredible.
It is incredible.
It's as if they were
a piece of the sun
locked up in here.
Strange. Very strange.
What could it be? What could be
the nature of radiation?
What could be the origin of it?
Perhaps we shall never know.
It was very kind of you
to take me
to Dr. Becquerel's laboratory.
Not at all...
Dr. Curie
I want to thank you
also for allowing me
to do my experiments here
in your laboratory.
I couldn't have done this
if it weren't
for Natural Science Industry
for allowing me of your kindness.
You finished that already?
Yes, I had to do it quickly
because I should not
have much time from now on
to come to the laboratory.
Why? What do you mean?
From now on, I shall spend
most of my time studying.
My examination's coming up
in less than two weeks, you know.
So soon? I haven't realized.
Yes. I have been here
six months.
It's the middle of June.
The term is nearly over.
How fast it goes.
Yes.
You know a short time ago
that tree was a skeleton.
I always used to look forward
to my summer in my country
but I'm only there
at stray moments now
when I go to visit my parents.
They have this small place
outside of Paris at Sol.
I used to take long walks
towards the woods there
with my brother, Jacques.
So nice to be walking
in the country.
My father loves to walk.
Your father?
Is he here in Paris?
Oh, no. In Warsaw
but we get out of the city
now and then.
Warsaw. But you're not thinking
going to Warsaw.
Of course.
But when?
As soon as
I finished my examinations.
But for how long?
Why for... Why, Dr. Curie.
You forget that if I passed
my examinations
I'm going back to Poland
to teach.
Well, I knew that...
wish I knew when we first came,
but everything is changed now.
You are making experiments
of your own
I know it.
I shall miss Paris, too.
But this is absurd, fantastic.
Why, it never occurred to me.
Oh, I...
I haven't planned on this at all.
How could you dream of
doing such a thing
abandoning science
when your making such progress.
My father is getting old.
He misses me.
If you stay on in Poland
you can't possibly go on
with your studies.
Anyone can teach
but you can do more
much more.
You have a talent
a definite talent
and it's your duty to use it.
We've so much to be done
so much to
that's still undreamed of.
Oh, Mademoiselle.
I beg you to reconsider.
Why, that's very kind of you
Dr. Curie
I'm really flattered.
I'm afraid
I can't give up the entire plan
that I have had for so long.
I thought, of course, you knew.
I do not understand
how anyone
with a scientific mind
can entertain the thought of
abandoning science.
I know.
But there are other things
that are important, too.
Dr. Curie?
Yes, Mademoiselle.
I've been meaning to ask you.
I supposed you wouldn't care
to attend my graduation?
Well, I should enjoy very much
seeing you get your degree
but, well, I have, ah...
there's such a crowd always.
Of course...
I understand perfectly.
I feel exactly
the same way myself.
Well
I should be coming in again
of course to see to a few things
Good bye, Dr. Curie.
Good bye, Mademoiselle.
We may well expect to hear
again and again.
It will always be
interested for you to look back
and try to recall
the personality of...
your classmate
who have won faith.
Above all
it's the mother of learning
And her children come through
all the corners of the world.
They come, they are nourished
and then
they returned to their homeland
to impart what
they have instilled to others.
Pride is not deflated by
what they take away.
The whole world is in fact
enriched by what they learned.
And am proud in particular gained
more than she gives
to the very earnest students.
Professor Constance, chairman of
the committee on scholarship
has gone over all the awards
and will read the name
of the successful candidates.
It is my pleasure to introduce
Professor Constance.
The names of those who have been
awarded degrees
will be read
in the order of merit.
For the degree
the master of physics.
First...
Marie Scholoscka.
Hello, Dr. Curie.
Oh, hello, David.
Isn't she wonderful?
First place in physics.
Did you know we have that
all that time in the laboratory?
Yes. It's very gratifying.
Here she was bright...
You haven't seen any of
Mmde. Scholoscka, have you, David?
Yes, I saw her.
Had a nice talk with her.
Congratulated her and everything.
She went straight home.
Had some packing to do.
Packing?
Well, she's leaving for Poland
on Tuesday.
Oh.
Good bye, Dr. Curie. Oh.
Awfully glad I run into you.
Good bye, David.
Ah! Dr. Curie.
How do you do, Professor?
Lovely, wasn't it?
Packing.
Yes... Wasn't it lovely?
Come in...
Dr. Curie.
How do you do?
I missed you at the
Graduation Exercises.
I looked all over for you.
You were there?
Yes.
Then you heard.
Yes. My congratulation
Mademoiselle.
Thank you. You know, I was...
never dreamed that I would...
I was even afraid that I might
may not...
Oh, I'm glad you were able to go.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you
I met David and he told me that
you were leaving Poland
on Tuesday
Yes.
I see.
Then you haven't reconsider
Mademoiselle.
I'm afraid not.
Of course. Of course.
Perhaps you might have.
You were packing?
Yes.
Oh, yes... naturally.
Well, then...
since you are leaving
so soon on Tuesday
I presume there'd be no time for
something I had in mind,
that is...
my father...
He is a doctor, you know.
He is very short only, you know.
but intelligent.
And my mother is quite gay.
I think you'd enjoy knowing
both of them.
But of course that would be
impossible
because you'd be busy packing and
doing one thing or another.
I had meant to
ask you down before
but it slipped my mind.
Still, I thought it would be nice
for you to take away with you
some of Paris' countryside
since we were speaking of
the country
the last time I saw you
that perhaps you might like
to come with me
to spend the weekend there.
It's not far
but still it's impossible
I see, because, I said before
you'd be busy packing
and preparing for your journey.
Yes, the idea's preposterous
on the face of it.
The idea is not
preposterous at all.
I should like to come very much.
You would?
Yes. Thank you.
Well, then.
I hate that girl.
Eugene.
I still hate that girl.
What do you do in Poland, anyway?
Spend all your time
at this stupid game
You must not mind my husband.
He never shouts at anyone
unless he likes them.
That's what I thought.
He had been shouting at me
all my life.
Well, what are looking
so gloomy about, Pierre.
It's your shot.
Ah, yes. Excuse me.
I heard you're going to Poland
on Tuesday.
Say, Monsieur.
Excellent country, Poland.
Thank you.
Of course, he hasn't been there.
You don't have to be there
to know
it's an excellent country.
Well, what are you waiting for.
Hit it. Hit it.
Well, I dare say
it's the best thing you can do.
You can go on
with your studies there.
Of course, not with a degree that
you could get here,
but you will do well
whatever it is.
Thank you, Madame.
I'm not paying you compliments.
I'm only telling you what I see
in your face.
It's all there
in people's faces.
Look at my husband.
A good man and a good doctor.
Look at Pierre.
A poet, but a poet with brains.
A poet in the laboratory.
Look at me, fat and foolish
but quite a good old soul.
It's true. Why should I mind.
Look at Monsieur and me.
Mitchell there
and young Master Mitchell.
We'll let them pass.
But then, look at yours.
Stubborn, determined, abstinent
and of course, intelligent.
And then, there's something else
that I can't quite
give a name to. Fiery, is it?
No... Flame-like.
That's a little nearer.
Flame-like then.
Something like a flame.
Once I'm sure I won
and what with that strike of
yours supposed I get out of it.
You're not paying attention.
It's no credit beating anyone
who does not pay attention.
Why, I tried to, Father.
Then you're just plain stupid.
Oh. Leave him alone.
No, sir. That boy has got to
learn to concentrate.
He'll never get anywhere
if he doesn't concentrate.
Did you ever hear
the fundamental law of physics,
known oddly enough as Curie's Law
Sheer luck.
I don't know how Pierre
ever stumbled on to it.
Oh, do be quiet, Eugene.
Croquet always makes me thirsty.
Want to drink?
Thank you, Father.
Yes,
that croquet always makes me thirsty.
Yes, it stirs up the thirst
in a man.
Nothing like a good drink
of lemonade
after a fast game of croquet
don't you think so, Pierre.
There.
I think you'll be comfortable here.
I'm sure I will.
This is Jacques' room
when he was home
Pierre's brother, you know.
Oh, there he is.
Where.
Oh, that. That's Pierre.
Oh, no. Really?
The other two are doctors
of course.
Crazy looking group.
I think it's charming.
Well. I hope you rest well.
Thank you. And thank you for
the lovely day.
I'd been very happy and...
You're very welcome, my dear.
If you care to
postpone your travel to Poland
we'd love to have you
stay with us for time.
It is very kind of you.
I like very much to stay
but I've already
written to my father
and he'd be expecting me.
It's no use, Mother, to talk
Mdme. Scholoscka
of staying on in Paris
It seems that she's determined to
return to Poland,
and apparently as far as
she is concerned
science is to be forgotten.
I did try to explain to you
why I have to return to Poland.
I thought you've understood.
I do understand and I'm sorry.
Well, good night, my dear.
Good night, Madame Curie.
Good night, Mademoiselle.
Pierre, you shouldn't
have spoken to her like that.
She's a very obstinate girl
Mother.
After all, Poland is her home.
What's that?
I'm just saying to Mother
she is a very obstinate girl.
Hmm, stubborn.
Exactly. That's what I mean.
Stubborn as they come.
Saw that the first minute
I clap her eyes on her.
Won't listen to reason.
Closes her mind like a clam.
Well, let's go to bed.
Good night, Mother.
Good night, son.
Good night, Father.
Good night, Pierre.
She's so intelligent about
other things
Good night.
Blind as a bat.
Who? Your son.
Mdme. Scholoscka...
What is it? What's happened?
Is anything wrong?
Dr. Curie.
I find it impossible for you to
leave Paris.
But what?
Please. I must talk to you.
I found myself in
a very peculiar position.
During these past two weeks
when you haven't
been to the laboratory
I found everything very confusing
It's impossible to do my work.
In short, I find it impossible to
go on without you.
But now, suddenly...
something has become
very clear to me.
I am helpful to you
in the laboratory, am I not?
Am I not? Didn't you say that?
Yes, of course.
A few times, I've been able to
give you suggestions
which you've found valuable
Of course.
Well, then, now.
Where as I was inclined to
be nervous and impatient
you were quite the opposite.
You have a clear mind
you were tenacious
you would never give up.
It's an excellent combination.
I might compare it with
the chemical formula NACI
Sodium Chloride.
It's a stable necessary compound.
So if we marry on this basis
our marriage would always
be the same.
The temperature would be the same
the composition would be the same
There would be no destruction
no fluctuation
none of the
uncertainties and emotions of love.
But...
I know how you feel about love
about men
I mean
and I respect that feeling.
It's also my own conviction.
For the scientist
there is no time for love.
I always believe science and
marriage to be incompatible
but it's stupid to believe
in generalization.
In our case, it would be a
wonderful collaboration.
A wonderful collaboration.
Don't you feel that?
I feel that.
And as for your father
from what you've said
I'm sure he would applaud
such a collaboration.
He might.
And as for Poland
what little good
you could make there,
you could make up here ten fold
on your own ground science.
What do you think I should do?
It would be a very fine thing
I believe
to pass our lives together
with our common scientific dream
to work together constantly
in our search
and any discovery that
we should make
no matter how small
would deepen the friendship
that we already have
for each other
and increase the respect that
we mutually feel.
I can imagine no respect
or friendship
greater than I have for you now.
I can imagine no future
so full of promise
than the one you offer.
Then I suggest that you stay
on in Paris with me.
I think you are right.
I should like to stay
in Paris very much.
Thank you.
We are engaged.
Engaged?
I'm sorry.
Oh, Pierre.
I'm so happy.
Oh. So very happy.
And I'm, too, my boy.
Very happy
Thank you, Mother.
Thank you, Father.
Oh, Pierre. I am so glad.
Good night, Mother.
Good night, father.
Good night, my boy.
Good night. Good night.
Good night.
Quiet, please...
Chaplain. Quiet, please.
Now, look right here, please
and hold absolutely still until
I count to ten.
Still.
One and two and three
and four and five
and six and seven and eight
and nine and ten.
How I wish you happiness
Mme. Curie.
Oh, David. Thank you.
You're the first one
who's called me that.
Good bye, Mme. Curie
and bon voyage.
Thank you, mademoiselle.
Good bye, my dear Marie.
Oh, Father dear. Good bye.
Oh, congratulations, lad.
Thank you. Thank you.
Congratulations.
Thank you, David. Bye. Bye.
Excuse me.
Now, where can I put
this chicken?
Mother
we don't need anymore food.
We're not going at the jungle.
Good gracious
what's this, Pierre?
What do you want the science book
on your honeymoon?
We want to read them, Mother.
Well, this is the last straw.
Mother, we want those books.
The chicken will do you fine
I assure you.
Science books on your honeymoon!
My boy, good bye.
Good bye.
Ready, Marie? Here they go...
You're very lovely, Marie.
Thank you, Pierre.
Music is lovely, isn't it?
Yes. Thank you.
Pierre.
Yes.
Would you hate to get back?
In a way, although I have a lot
of work that I must do.
What should I work on, Pierre?
What subject should I choose for
my doctors degree?
Is there anything that
particularly interests you?
Oh, yes. Yes, a number of things
but...
What is it? Why did you stop?
Oh, nothing.
It's just an idea that
went through my mind.
Well, what was it?
Do you remember that
Professor Becquerel showed us that rock
The pitch blende and the plate he
exposed to it?
Yes.
You know, Pierre.
I can't get that out of my mind.
Really? Why?
I know it's true
that the rays give...
not by something
in the pitch blende
I can't get over the feeling
that there's more to it than that
that there's something else
something beyond
Becquerel's explanation.
I don't quite understand.
Well, what are these rays
that given off
and why are they being given off.
It's an accepted principle
in science
that nothing can go on forever
without running dull, isn't it?
Yes.
I mean, the clock will run dull
if it isn't wound.
Afire would burn out if it's not
replenished.
Life will die if it is inflate.
Yet in these rocks
which are embedded
in the middle of the earth
millions of years
never seen the sun
Rays are constantly given off
more all by themselves.
What is this energy?
Where does it come from?
I supposed
I'm being very foolish.
Some of the greatest achievements
in science
come to the same type
of foolishness.
When an explanation is given
of something
and every one believes it
there may be one person somewhere
who can't quite accept it,
who instinctively says
I'm not sure that
this is sufficient explanation.
Maybe something beyond this.
It's that
kind of foolishness, Marie.
Well, I'm not that person
I'm sure.
How do you know? Perhaps you are
Perhaps Dr. Becquerel has only
set the gate a jar.
Maybe a long
and unexplored road ahead
I wouldn't even know how to start
Pierre.
I wouldn't know what to do.
I'm very glad we're married
to each other, Pierre.
Darling.
Hello, Marie.
My class kept me the day
with the most stupid questions.
Thought I would never get away.
Just tonight
when we're having guests.
I have a terrible problem.
I hope I got the things
you wanted me to get.
I lost the slip that
I made the notes on
and I couldn't remember
whether there was turnips
or carrots, so I got both.
Mother likes carrots
and Father likes turnips.
And here's some flowers
for the cook.
Thank you, Pierre.
What's the matter, Marie?
Oh, Pierre. I'm so discouraged.
Looks like this method of mine
is all wrong.
I wonder if I'm trying something
beyond me.
What is it exactly that's wrong?
I don't know.
My measurements.
they don't mean anything.
I know I must be making mistakes
some where...
but I don't know where it is.
I checked them and
I rechecked them two hundred times.
Maybe the electrometer
is not working right.
That's what I'm afraid of.
I wish you'd examine it for me
Pierre
I'll go over it tomorrow.
Let's forget it tonight.
Let's not talk, not even
think the laboratory
Promise?
I promise.
Well, Pierre. What is it?
Marie, about those measurements.
Do you think
anything could have happened
to change the capacity
of the electrometer?
Weren't we suppose to forget
the laboratory tonight?
Oh. I forgot. I'm sorry.
No more... I’m terribly sorry.
Here they are.
Where's my coat?
Here we are.
Hello, dear. Pierre.
Mother.
I smell turnips.
We got carrots for you.
Oh, how sweet of you.
Oh, I brought you
some of my new plum jelly.
Thank you, Mother.
She made it but I brought it.
Ah, thank you, Father.
Let me have your things.
Your coat, Father?
Yeah. You're not
treating her right, Pierre.
She looks pinkish.
Oh, it's silly.
Why you look lovely, dear.
Just the same, she's too thin.
And I say a woman without a child
is a parasite.
She feeds on life
but is not willing to
give life in return.
What is being her excuse
to have life.
Why would she ever born?
She's a blood sucker.
Now, don't call names, George.
Are you listening to me?
Of course.
A woman without a child
is a blood sucker.
We didn't mean you, my dear.
Oh, yes.
She's just the one I did mean.
But I'm going to have a child.
When?
Soon, I hope.
Oh, my dear. Marie.
Yes, dear.
Look who's going to say something
at last.
Are you sure the insulation is dry?
Yes, Pierre.
He's getting quite chatty lately
isn't he?
Don't bother them.
They're thinking of something.
I don't believe it.
Did you check
the ground connection?
I don't know.
I thought you gave it to me
in good order.
Well, sometimes it work loose
and you don't notice it.
Pierre, that could be possible
couldn't it?
Yes. Yes, of course.
The thing we must do is to check
that line completely
from one end to the other.
In that case
my measurements may be correct.
Yes.
Then all these months of work
couldn't have been wrong
after all.
That's right.
Pierre, that's it.
That must be it...
Yes, that must be it.
Alright. Alright.
Go ahead and check it.
Father, it's just that, well
Marie has so many setbacks
with her work.
That's alright.
Don't stop doing...
Please. Go ahead.
It's just that I've been
waiting for so many months.
It's alright, my dear.
I hope you won't mind
if I stay long enough
to finish my coffee.
Please do and we'll try to
get back before you go.
Thank you, my boy. Thank you.
Good bye.
You know, sometimes that son of
yours is not quite all right.
Nice having dinner with you.
You know, I'll never
come to this house
but for the sake...
It's Alright, George.
It happens every time.
Well?
It's alright.
Nothing wrong with it.
I was wrong.
I was sure we've found it.
Well...
I don't know. I'm sorry.
You tested all of the elements.
you're sure of that, Marie?
Yes, I'm positive, Pierre.
And you found that
only two of them...
uranium and thorium
gave off rays.
That's right.
Then
you measured the uranium and thorium
in the pitch blende ore.
And that's when I run
into trouble.
The pitch blende has more
radioactivity than I can explained
by the amount of
uranium and thorium had in it.
Would you like to show me
how you make your measurements
Marie?
You wouldn't mind?
Of course not.
Alright.
Here is what I've done
so many times that I lost count.
Here is crude pitch blende.
Now we know that
the rays came from the uranium
and thorium that are
in this pitch blende.
Those two elements
give off the rays.
Correct.
I put the pitch blende
in this mortar.
Has the mortar always been clean?
Always and grinded up.
Here is the ground pitch blende
throw in the uranium
and thorium in it
I also fill a disk level full.
Just like what I've done
every time.
Then I placed it
in the electrometer.
And I close the case
so there is no draft.
Good.
I charged the electrometer.
Now I will find out
how much energy to raise
in the pitch blende they have
is it right?
Right. Start.
Ready. Read.
Eight.
Same reading as I always had.
This pitch blende
with the uranium and the thorium
still in it comes to eight.
Now, here is pure uranium
I strike it
in the same amount of pitch blende.
This is exactly the same case
close the case
charged the electrometer
Now, we will find out
how much energy
the rays in the uranium have.
Right.
Ready. Read.
Two, same as always.
Done nothing wrong so far.
Not that I can see.
We know then that...
the pitch blende with
the uranium and thorium in it
comes to eight and that
the uranium alone reads two.
I am going to test the thorium.
From the same amount of pitch blende?
Of course, and put in exactly
the same case
close the case
charged the electrometer.
Now we find out how much energy
the rays in thorium have?
Right.
Ready. Read.
Two
I don't understand.
There must be a mistake.
When the uranium and thoarum are
in the pitch blende
the reading is eight.
But individually
they only total four.
Have you checked
all the other elements
in the pitch blende?
I checked every elements.
There is no the result.
Every elements in existence.
Uranium and thorium are
the only elements that give off rays.
Why do they give off twice
as much when they are
in the pitch blende as they do
as they were tested separately?
Where are those
four missing points?
That is what I don't understand.
I don't understand.
You make the chemical analysis of
what is content
in the pitch blende, didn't you?
Of course. Could I see it?
Yes.
Uranium oxide - 75%
Chlorium Oxide - 13%
Lead sulfide - 3%
Silicon dioxide - 2%
Calcium oxide - 3%
Barium oxide - 2%
Iron oxide - 1%
Magnesium oxide - 1/990%
other extraneous elements
1/1000%
Pierre Yes?
Our universe is composed of
definitely known substances
isn't it?
Elements are fixed forever
in earth unchanging
we know that, don't we?
All of our scientist
based on that
All of our science is
based on that. Go on
In the beginning
man used to think that the world
have only of four elements,
earth, air, fire and water.
They thought that everything
in their universe
could be made out of those.
Yes. Go on.
But They were wrong, weren't they?
They were wrong.
Now we know that
there are 78 elements
The elements over there
on the shelves
and we believe that there are
some elements still unknown
but we assume that...
these missing elements
have the same character
as those we know already.
That is right
Pierre
What if there is
a kind of matter in the world
we never even dream of?
What would that mean?
Marie, that would mean
that our whole conception of the
nature of matter would
have to be changed.
It is cold in here.
Tell me what you are thinking.
I don't quite dare.
Go on and say it now matter
how crazy it sounds.
What if we did not make a mistake
in our measurement?
What if the conception
of science is wrong?
What if there exists a matter
that is not in earth
but alive, dynamic?
Do we dare think that our
four missing points
these strange power
is of 1/1000%?
Pierre.
We have discovered a new element.
An active element.
The residue for pitch blende.
What was left over
After I extract
the uranium and the thoarum
it must be in there.
Where it is?
In the resin...
Close the curtains.
Ready?
Marie, if your four missing
points are here
our notion of the universe
will be changed.
Ready? Read.
Four.
Oh, Pierre.
Marie. This new concept.
If we can prove the existence
of this new element
it may enable us to look into
the secret of life itself
deeper than ever before in the
history of the world.
Madame Curie, you must realize
that the board
has given you repetition
every consideration. However...
the university has not an
extensive budget
for the creation of
new laboratories
and for the new equipment
you ask for.
You state that...
you and Dr. Curie had detected
the presence of a new element
an active element.
But unfortunately
you have given us
no convincing proof
of its existence.
We have demonstrated of
its existence experimentally.
We have carried on our
research intensely
except for five weeks
in the autumn.
In September
my daughter was born
and a week later
my husband has the misfortune to
lose his mother.
But the rest of the time, we have
devoted entirely to research.
And yet in this eight
or nine months
you have came no closer
to any proof
as to the existence of ah...
what is the name of it?
Ah, my wife has named it radium.
Oh yes, radium
I should like to ask
Dr. Curie a question.
Yes, Professor Roger
This work.
Will it require
quite a little time
will it not? Yes, of course.
But you are already
teaching at school
of physics and chemistry.
And Madam Curie is teaching at
the normal school at Sebra.
It would be
a formidable undertaking
under the best of circumstances.
Under these conditions
hardly seems promising.
And Madam Curie, in spite of
her acknowledged abilities is
if you would permit me
to say so young
inexperienced, and a woman.
Gentleman. If you please.
This remark seems to me
entirely irrelevant.
It is perfectly true
that Madame Curie is young
that she has not
had the experience
that most of us have had
and as you say she is a woman.
But let me impress upon you
gentlemen
that she is of most unusual woman
I might say her, ah
a most unusual woman.
You can't classify her
with that term
I have had the opportunity of
observing Madam Curie
very closely
and I can assure you, gentlemen
that she is remarkable scientist
as scrupulous as she is brilliant
and furthermore...
Of course, gentlemen
you understand
that I am looking upon
Madame Curie
with complete coolness
and complete detachment
as I would in judging
any other colleague.
We understand that
you are convinced
as to the reliability of
Madame curie's investigation.
Entirely, I have even put aside
my own research
to devote my entire time
to collaborating with her
in the isolation of
this new element.
Dr. Curie
much as we would like to
help you and Madame Curie
our budget does not provide the
purposes of this kind.
However, the suggestion was made
by Professor Roger
in which we have unanimously
concurred to offer you the use
of the shade across the courtyard
from the school of physics.
We are aware that this shade
is not the most suitable place for
your investigation.
Gentlemen
am I to understand that
you are offering us the old shade
across from the physics building?
The one, that was used as a
dissecting room
by medical students?
If this abominable shade is available,
it's only because no one can be
found who is willing to work in it.
The roof leaks. It has no floor
but the wet ground.
It can't be heated.
In summer, it is stifling
as a hot house
and in winter, it freezes.
And do you imagine that
I would permit my wife to work
under these appalling conditions?
If you do
gentlemen, believe me...
With my husband's permission
we should be very glad
to accept the shade.
We shall be very grateful
to have the shade.
This was the shade
across the courtyard
from the school of physics.
This was to be the laboratory
of Marie and Pierre Curie
The place was even worse than
they had expected.
There was no equipment.
They were at the mercy of
the worse extremes of the weather.
How could they do anything
worthwhile under such conditions?
If they'd know at the start
how long they will have
to work here and
what difficulties awaited them
would they have dare to begin?
Well, yes, they probably would.
They were that kind of people.
At first
it was sheer physical labor
beyond the strength
of either of them.
During those winter days
they carried on between them
the work of
the entire chemical plant.
The raw material was pitch blende
from the mines of
Bohemia tons of it
from which they plan to
extract all the known elements
until only a few ounces remain.
From this few ounces, radium
their precious element
was eventually to be isolated.
In the beginning
in spite of the bitter cold
the work had to be done
out of doors
because of the fire and fumes.
The first step was to
melt the crude ore
on a large oblong tank
till it was boiling like lava.
Then acid was poured in.
This was to
dissolve out the salts.
When this was done
the next stage was to melt down
the residue in separate cordon
another back breaking job
for the fire must not go out.
Night or day
either Pierre or Marie
had to be on hand all the time.
Dogged determination
kept them going
through month after month of
such arduous dangerous work
but even so
it began at last to tear on
both Pierre and Marie.
This was something they had to
fight continually
the gas fumes.
Eventually, months run into years
The kind of works changed
but Pierre had to build
or assemble their equipment
and with any material
that lay at hand.
What was left of
the original pitch blende
had now to be filtered and
re-filtered to
remove other elements.
And this work were not
quite so physically strenuous
was hard enough
specially during
the hot summer days.
And so the work went on
until presently
everything had been removed
from the tons of ore
except two final elements
one was barium and the other
which they had began to
think of it
in their heart
as their own element
was the precious illusive radium.
Pierre and Marie thought that
the end of their task
must surely be in sight.
All that was now left was to
separate these two survivors
barium and radium.
This was the problem to
separate barium
and radium somehow or other.
No separation.
No separation. No separation.
September the 12th 1899.
Reduction of pitch blende
nearly finish.
Only barium and radium remain.
The next separation
will give radium.
November the 8th, 1899.
First experiment. No separation.
November the 10th, 1899.
Second experiment. No separation.
July the 16th, 1900.
Four hundred
and fifty eight experiments.
Radium still refuses to separated
from barium.
Alright, then, radium wouldn't be
separated from barium.
We've done all we can
and more more than
most people would have done
thanks to your tenacity
but it's useless.
We'll never find a way
of separating.
Barium and radium
can not be separated.
How much longer do you think
we can stand this
insufferable heat
stifling in summer
and freezing in winter.
How much longer do you think
you can drive yourself like this?
And how much longer do you think
I can stand by
and watch you destroy yourself?
The world has done without
radium up to now.
What does it matter
if it is isolated
for another 100 years.
I can't give it up.
If it takes a hundred years
it would be a pity
but I am going to see how far
I could go, even my lifetime
We have never seen burns
quite like this before
they are very strange.
I can't ever remember
seeing anything quite like them
they obviously don't come from
any normal substance.
Madame Curie
how long have been making
your experiments with
this unknown element?
For the past three
three and a half years.
And have these burns
given you much pain?
No. They are irritating at times
but I never pay attention to them
until lately.
I see.
It is obvious that
you are dealing with
some remarkable powerful force.
As to what these burns
are exactly
there is no means of telling.
I don't wish to alarm you
Madame Curie
but it is possible that
these burns might become serious
might in fact develop malignantly
if you continue to expose them
excessively
to your unknown element.
It is not impossible
they may be developed
into a cancerous nature.
It is my advice, Madame
that you abandon your experiments.
Cancer.
No, Pierre.
He only said the burns
might develop malignantly
Like develop into cancer.
No. He said they might possibly
develop into a cancerous nature
but only if it excessively
exposed to our radium.
So if we're careful
there is nothing
to be frightened about.
But the very word frightens me.
You saw how it took my own mother.
We'll have to give up
our experiments
If we are dealing with
as powerful a forces
there is no telling what...
I wouldn't allow it.
I wouldn't let you take such risk
I won't permit you.
No, Marie. Pierre, please.
Listen to me, please.
There is something
I must tell you
and then you should decide
as you wish.
Very well, Marie.
As I left the doctor
I have been thinking.
This element of ours obviously
has a terrific power.
Power enough to
affect healthy tissue like mine.
Power enough to destroy tissue.
Pierre, if it has this power
why hasn't it also the power to
destroy unhealthy tissue?
You realize what that might mean?
It could heal.
By destroying unhealthy tissue
it could heal all men of diseases
Like cancer? You?
Yes, Pierre.
It might even do that.
We don't know what things
it might do for people.
But, Marie... Oh, Pierre.
Can't you see
how unimportant little things
like these are compared
to what it might mean?
It might prevent great sicknesses
even deaths. Pierre.
And so they went on
with their work
using every possible precaution.
Marie's fingers healed.
And though
they did not find a way
to separate radium and barium
in a single process
they did discover a method of
removing barium
little by little in
infinite decimal amounts.
Working on the theory
that once the whole of the barium
is removed
nothing could be left but radium.
Here we see the sort of
things they had to do.
This is called crystallization.
When the liquid evaporates
crystals are left.
This was the thing they had to
do over and over again.
It proved to be the most exacting
of all of the stages
of their long test.
For it continues for two years
and require thousands of
separate operations.
By now the residue
from all the various processes
they had worked at lay
in hundreds of
this small evaporating bowls.
Small, because larger quantities
would not evaporate so quickly.
Crystallizing
and re-crystallizing.
Each operation
they hope bring them
closer and closer to the heart of
the great mystery.
At last, they arrive
at the final crystallization
the one that contains the concentrated
results of all the others.
The last survivors out of
those hundreds of evaporating bowls.
I think I feel like crying
Professor Poirot.
Madam Curie, but I am afraid
I have come at a crucial moment.
No. No. We have finished.
We have nothing to do now
but wait.
I am delighted to see you.
There is nobody
we'd rather have waited
at this moment than you.
Thank you.
And I have brought with me
an very illustrious visitor.
No more illustrious than these
young folks will be.
The name of Curie will lead
all the rest.
Your taller, my boy, considerably
than I have imagine.
And you, Madame, so young,
so beautiful and so brilliant
I don't know which is
the greater miracle
you or radium.
Why don't you introduce me
Poirot?
I think I know.
Isn't it Lord Kelvin?
I absolutely refuse to
return to London
without meeting you both.
As long as
the greatest living scientist
believe in
the existence of radium
what the other thoughts
didn't seem to matter.
Here are the evaporating dishes.
How many crystallization
did you make
hundreds I suppose?
Tell him, Pierre.
Look here, sir.
Five thousands six hundred
and seventy-seven.
And the last crystallization is
in there, I supposed.
Five thousands six hundred
and seventy-seven.
And thus crystallization.
What a historic moment.
That little bowl
represents eight tons
of pitch blende
and four years of work.
In a few hour
the water will be gone
and only radium will remain.
Pure radium.
I am sort of tempted to
stay and see it
but it's New Year's Eve and
my family is expected me
in London.
Mine is just as well.
This great moment should
belong to the two of you alone.
You begin the year, my friends
that will mark your fame.
Goodbye.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Goodbye, Sir.
C'mon along, Poirot.
My train won't wait.
Goodnight, dear,
Goodbye.
I shall come back to Paris
next week
and see your radium
with my own eye.
You can send me
a telegram tonight
and describing it to me.
We have a coin over there.
We wrote something
out for this occasion
Bring out the old
bring in the new
bring out the false
bring in the true.
Good bye. God blessed you.
Good bye. Good bye.
What a wonderful man.
The really great men
are always simple and good.
Yes.
We're both very tired.
Shall we try to get some rest?
Very well
Sit here a while and
I cover you with this robe.
There.
Put that chair over.
I can't reach you
Yeah. That's better.
Let's try to doze off.
Pierre.
What time is it? I overslept.
I must be tired.
It is five.
Must be crystallized by now.
Must be there.
Our radium must be there.
C'mon.
Do you mind? You look first.
There's nothing there
not a trace of anything
not a grain.
Only a stain.
What had happened Pierre?
Where is our radium?
What have we done?
Where is it? What's happened?
Where is it, Pierre?
I don't know.
What did we do that was wrong?
What could we have done?
We've done nothing wrong.
I can't stand it, Pierre
Where is our radium?
We worked for
years and years and years
It must be there.
Four long years in this shed.
Four long years.
Is that you?
Yes, Father.
Well, something's got to be don
about that child of yours.
I think you ought to take it back.
I let her stand on my head
to let her eat her supper
and now she...
now she, now she won't go to bed
until her mother tells her story.
I like to know what's the matter
with my stories.
They are the same stories.
I'll go up to her.
Then what happened, Mommy.
I am sorry, Irene darling.
Mother just can't tell you
anymore tonight.
Oh, Mommy, please.
What is the matter, Mommy?
But, I wanted to know
what happen, Mommy
If you close your eyes tight
Daddy will tell you a story.
What's it about?
Well, ah, its about
ah, it's about a strange
and wonderful treasure
that was locked up
in an enchanted stone.
Is there a princess in it?
Yes, a princess.
A beautiful princes
with golden hair.
Is there a prince too?
No, not a prince
but a man who live all alone
until the princess found him.
Did they love each other?
Very much.
Alright, Daddy
my eyes are closed
Well, now, one day the princes
told the man
about this wonderful treasure
so they decided to go
and search of it together.
Now, no one had ever seen
this treasure
of course, but the princes knew
that it was there.
And she knew if they could get it
out of the stone,
it might let people see
wonderful things
that they had never
been able to see before.
So they worked very hard
for a long long time
to try and rescue the treasure
from the stone.
And they grew very tired
And at last, they knew that...
they would never be able to
free the treasure
from the enchant of the stone
but they weren't sad about it
because they knew that
no matter how many disappointment
they had
they would always go on together.
Having the courage
to take many disappointments
because they were together
and they live happily ever after.
She is asleep.
You know, we promised David that...
But I supposed you naturally
don't feel like...
Oh, I remember.
The New Year's Party.
But, of course
you don't feel like going.
Pierre, we promised.
Let's go.
I'd rather. Might help.
Good. Good then.
Happy New Year. Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Happy New Year, Marie.
Happy New Year, Pierre.
Try to put it out of your mind
Marie
and go to sleep
I can't.
I can't accept it, Pierre.
But, Marie, sometimes
there are things
you just must accept it
If I only knew why we fail.
I think that the failure itself
I wouldn't mind
so much about it
but the reason for it.
Months and months and months ago
you did find
the right process to use.
At the very end
why should it suddenly fail?
I don't know. I don't know.
Pierre, that stain on the saucer.
Yes.
We didn't even test it, did we?
No, we didn't.
What we are expecting to find
was a definite amount of radium
wasn't it?
Something we could see and feel.
Not as much as a pinch of salt
you said
Yes.
Pierre, what if it's...
a merely a question of amount?
What does so little radium
in proportion
to the amount of material
that we use
that we now we couldn't see it.
What if that stain?
Even with the merest
merest breath...
Go on.
Pierre, could it... be that
that stain is radium?
Pierre. It's there. Our radium.
It's there. It's there.
Pierre.
Pierre. It's there. It's there.
It's there.
Oh, Pierre.
Where are they?
Are they in Paris or go
wherever they are.
I am not going to tell you
where they are.
But, Dr. Curie
I am the representative
of the London Times
and there are
representatives here
from the presses of all the great
nations in the world.
Don't Dr.
and Madame Curie realize
they can't hide from the press?
The whole world is on fire
from their discovery.
The publics want to know
about them.
We have heard that
they had refused
to take in money for their radium
that they are giving it
to the world.
The Nobel Prize to a woman.
These are important matters
Dr. curie
and the world must be told
about them.
Yes, the public must know.
Did they give it for free?
Where are they now?
Gentlemen
all that I know is Pierre
and Marie are very tired.
They have been interviewed
so much that
I can't see there is any more to
tell that
the public would be interested in.
They're sick.
They've gone away
on a holiday to rest.
Now, it's utterly impossible
for any newspaperman
in the world to try to interview
Dr. or Madame Curie
at the present time
I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
I am from The Courier
the newspaper in Grandovland.
Do you think
I could see Madame Curie?
I'm afraid you can't see her.
They've come here to rest.
It's their first holiday
in five years.
You wouldn't want to disturb them.
Perhaps you could
tell me something about her.
I can't go back without
some sort of story.
Would you like to have something
for your paper
that very people know yet?
Oh, I certainly would.
Well. Put in your newspaper that
the University has granted Dr.
and Mme. Curie
a splendid new laboratory with
many rooms
the latest equipment
many assistants.
It will be presented to them in
a formal ceremony next week.
Next week?
There. Fair enough.
That's fine, Madame.
That's wonderful.
I don't know how to thank you.
I can tell you
I was scared of meeting Mme. Curie
but it was rather important to me.
You see
this is my first assignment
if I could have
gotten the interview
it would help a lot.
Well, monsieur.
You can tell your newspaper that
you got your interview
with Mme. Curie.
Madame. Good bye.
Are you... are you Mme. Curie?
Yes. And this is my daughter
Irene.
It's a new bicycle so she has to
show it off.
And now... Mommy...
Oh, yes. My baby. This is E.
She's been a good baby?
Very good, Madame.
Been very good, darling?
Yes. Wei, Madame.
Did she drink her milk?
Yes.
Alright... Wei, Madame.
Well, keep her out
in the airy deck.
Alright. Off you go.
Now she made a grand tour
of the garden
And now
you'll excuse me. Good bye.
Good bye.
Know what I'm doing? Pierre.
I thought you were asleep.
No. I'm walking through
the new laboratory.
Don't imagine it too grand.
It might not come up
to your expectations.
And at the moment, I'm walking down
the long white hall.
And I'm with you?
Yes, you are with me.
Now
I'm examining your work table.
I don't believe it's large enough.
How's yours?
Oh, yes. I haven't got there yet.
It will be exciting, won't it?
When we walk in the first time.
Yes. It will be wonderful to
get back to work again.
We lost so much time.
Oh, Pierre.
The time we spent here
hasn't been lost
We got our strength back.
Yes, that's true.
We were ill, both of us
more than we knew.
You know, when we first came here
I used to
have fantastically morbid
thoughts sometimes.
What do you mean?
Well, everyday that passed seem
so completely lost.
I have a feeling that
I didn't have much time to lose,
that my days were... well, it...
that I mustn't waste them
that I have to drive ahead quickly
in order to have time
to finish everything
I wanted to finish
It's odd how one's mind would...
Why, Marie.
What a horrible thought to have.
It's just because I was so ill.
How could such a thought
entered your mind.
Oh, darling.
Don't take it so seriously
It frightens me.
I'm sorry I mentioned it.
It was nothing.
It's because I was so worn out.
You know, Marie, how tired I was.
Pierre. If one of us
should ever go
the other couldn't go on alone.
Couldn't be expected of us
could it?
Oh, Marie. I've upset you.
Could it, Pierre?
You were wrong, Marie.
Whatever happens
if one should go
the other must stay on.
One must work just the same.
But I for one had no intention of
going anywhere
except to our
wonderful new laboratory.
Only one more week.
Just think of it.
After all this waiting
only one more week.
Pierre?
Yes, dear.
Come back here.
Ha?
Come back.
What is it?
I want to tell you something.
Sit down.
Well? What is it?
So hard.
I just can't find the words.
Pierre, are you proud of me?
Marie.
Because I'm so proud of you.
I'm so proud that sometimes
I think I'll burst.
You're a very great man, Pierre.
Not the way the world means.
Just you.
Your kindness, your gentleness
and your wisdom.
I love you, Pierre, so deeply.
I never dreamed...
I'm so thankful, Pierre.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
That's what I thought
you'll always know.
France sees it fit to bestow
the famous scientific couple
a truly great honor
in reward for their services
to science and to mankind.
Well, are you truly impressed?
The president and faulty of
the University of Paris
will present Pierre and
Mme. Curie with a fully
equipped laboratory
with which to carry on
their many experiments
they have opened the gateway to.
At 6:30 on 19th, April
that's today, you know.
There will be
a formal presentation
of the laboratory at which
the world famous couple
will appear.
Not bad, eh? Not bad.
Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning, Father.
Good morning
Good morning, children.
What's the matter
with this place today?
After all
it was no different than
any other day, isn't it?
This house is in a turmoil.
Everything is upside down
topsy turvy
nothing in its place.
Where is your mother?
I haven't seen her for hours.
I don't know how I'm going to
remember everything.
And, ah...
Where's my coffee? I'm late.
Oh. Thank you, Lucille.
Don't know
where your mother has gone.
The house without a woman
I don't understand.
Marie?
Mother's in there.
What's she doing in there?
Marie.
I wouldn't go in there, Pierre
if I were you.
She's having the last fitting
on her new dress
she's going to wear tonight
for the presentation.
It's supposed to be a surprise.
Oh, good. Good.
That's a very sound idea.
Yeah. Remember
I didn't tell you.
No.
Pardon me, is Dr. Pierre here?
That's him.
Oh. Mme. Curie would like to
see you.
You like it, Pierre?
It's for this evening
for the ceremony
You look very beautiful, Marie.
You really like it?
I do. Very much.
What color is that?
It's, ah, very deep red.
You want to have some kind of
a little ornament, haven't you?
Oh, nonsense.
Yes. Yes, you should.
Something... something bright.
I've seen them on women.
They look nice
Now you're making me
self-conscious.
Oh, I was thinking what a pity
evening dress becomes you so.
But there you are
we just haven't
had the time, have we?
Oh, look at that.
Our beautiful day ruined.
Oh, I was going to spend the day
in the park with the children.
Well, I must be off.
I have a hundred things
to do today.
I promise to go to the institute
I have to look at
the proofs of my paper
from my publisher
and endless thing.
I want to clean everything up and
start fresh from the laboratory
in the morning.
You mustn't be late.
You must allowed yourself
time to dress
Madame. Madame, the pins.
Oh. Oh.
Perhaps one day
I'll get a new dress suit.
You know I have had mine
since I got my Doctors degree.
Looks bad on me, isn't it?
No, Pierre.
You look very handsome in anything
Thank you, Marie.
Good bye. Good bye, darling.
They're always
calling for us at six.
I'll be here.
Don't forget your rubbers. No.
Or your umbrella.
Good bye.
Good bye, Pierre. Pierre...
Is there something I can show you
Monsieur?
I would like to buy a pair of
earrings for a lady.
We're going to a party tonight.
Yes, Monsieur.
Did you have anything special
in mind?
Well, I've seen women
wearing earrings
that I thought were very pretty.
Of course, I would like to
get something
that would match the lady's gown.
May I ask the color of the gown
monsieur?
It's dark red.
It's rather a special gown.
Not blow, of course, but...
What do you think of these
Monsieur.
They're amethysts
They're very lovely.
Oh, yes, aren't they.
And what are these?
Those are garnets.
Really? They're both lovely.
I hardly know...
It would depend on the shape of
the lady's face.
Is it oval or round?
I would say that
her face was oval.
Yes, oval.
And is she blond or...
Blond, definitely.
But not too blond.
I mean, she can't... well
just blond.
And her hair is sort of gold
you know
Gold?
Yes. And her eyes are gray.
Very calm gray.
The coloring is very lovely.
Sort of smooth skin
and nice delicate, coloring
and well I...
I don't know if it will be
of any help to you
but the lady is quite beautiful.
Lovely. You look very beautiful
my dear.
Thank you.
It's rather unusual to be praised
for the way I look.
I'm sure you could have
had that praise
from men if you'd had wished it.
Thank you, Father.
I don't understand
Pierre being late today of all days.
Well, you know, Pierre.
I brought in some wine.
I thought we might all drink
to that new laboratory
before you go.
Oh, that was thoughtful of you
Father.
That must be Professor Poirot
and Pierre's not here.
Let me.
Pierre?
Mme. Curie, it is my painful
due to inform you that...
your husband has been
the victim of a street accident.
He was instantly killed.
It came at such no pain.
Has she any better?
Just the same.
I can't get her to speak to me.
I'm frightened.
Is she in there?
Yes.
Forgive me, if I intrude.
I do so as Pierre's old friend
as your old friend and teacher.
Please try to
attend to what I say.
Try to hear my words.
Think what Pierre
what he should do.
How he would want you to live now.
It is my believed that
he would wish you
to continue his and yours.
My friend...
I know how much
the laboratory meant to Pierre.
I know how much hurt
if it wasn't to be yours.
It was his dream that someday
you and he
would stand there together.
I know it is very hard for you
to think of going on by yourself
when you have done
everything together so many years.
One must go on working
just the same.
You must find somewhere
within yourself
the strength to carry on
Pierre's work and you own. Ha?
Ten years ago
you told me so often that
you were impressed
by something I said
when you were a student
in my class.
I spoke of Newton and Galileo
and I said that probably none of
you would ever reach so high
to get the star
in your fingertips.
I was wrong.
I have, too, seen you reaching to
the high place of knowledge
and get your star
under your fingertips.
Marie, there are more stars.
The Faculty of Science
of University of Paris invites you
to attend the ceremony honored by
the presence of Mme. Curie
to commemorate
the twenty-fifth anniversary
of the discovery of radium.
Yes, she was famous now.
This frail, stubborn, eager woman
had carried on her great work
for a quarter of a century.
Mme. Curie.
Even now, after twenty-five years
of intensive research,
we feel there is a great deal
still to be done.
We have made discoveries.
Pierre Curie, in the suggestions
we found in his notes
and in thoughts
he expressed to me
has helped to guide us to him.
But no one of us can do much
if each of us perhaps
can catch some glimpse knowledge
which modestly
insufficient itself
may add to man's dream of truth.
It is by these small candles
in our darkness that
we see before us little by little
the dim outlines of
that great plan
that shapes the universe.
And I am among those who think
that for this reason,
science has great beauty and with
its great spiritual strength
will in time cleanse this world
of its evils
it's ignorance, poverty, diseases
wars and heartaches
Look for the clear light of truth
Look for unknown new roads
even when men's sight is
keener far from now.
Divine wonder will never fail us.
Every age has its own dream.
Leave then the dreams
of yesterday
You take the torch of knowledge
and build the palace
of the future.