[Final list of people
who passed the bar exam...]
[Kim Eun Chul]
I passed.
Son, how did you do?
Did you pass?
Here, my name.
[Final list of people
who failed the bar exam]
[Kim Eun Chul, Kim Eun Chul,
Kim Eun Chul, Kim Eun Chul]
What's going on?
This can't be...
I'm Kim Eun Chul.
I'm Kim Eun Chul with
an IQ of 157.
There's no way...
Nonsense!
Eun Chul, come and eat.
You think I can eat right now?
This is a nightmare.
A nightmare!
No!
I told you to come and eat.
R-I-C-E!
Rice!
Be quiet.
You ruined my condition
early in the morning.
What the heck...
Why is he yelling at me?
Episode 8 - Laundry to Comfort
the Worried Young Adults
[Day before the bar exam
8:15 AM]
Tomorrow's the first part of the test,
so be careful not to catch a cold.
Chew thoroughly, so
you don't get indigestion.
Here, princess.
Should I take out the
fishbones for you, Judge Kim?
Yes.
Madame Yang, you are always
jumping the gun.
He hasn't even taken the exam yet...
Who's this Judge Kim?
- Hey!
- What?
Darn girl...
Did you ever see your brother
fail an exam?
Why are you acting like an amateur?
You are such bad luck...
What's the point of passing? He left
twice already during the training period.
It's useless if he
does that again this time.
This time, he promised me
that he would finish up
his training at the judicial
research institute.
Right, Judge Kim?
Yes, don't worry.
Kim Bom.
Can you eat quietly?
I can't read in all this ruckus.
What can I do?
I have a fishbone stuck in my throat!
Why do you keep yelling at me?
Hey, stop eating, and go.
Let go of those chopsticks.
Let go!
Okay, fine.
I bet she'll come looking for a snack
after eating a small breakfast.
I'm such a good boyfriend.
Boyfriend...
Are you crazy?
You're not her boyfriend!
Maybe her future boyfriend.
You're here?
Red bean bun?
Can I eat it?
Eat slowly.
Thanks.
You should eat one, too.
So cute.
Why are you smiling?
Huh?
You're going to choke. Eat slowly,
nobody's going to take your food.
Wait.
Isn't this an indirect kiss?
You should drink, too.
You are so careless.
Take it off.
What?
I'll wash it for you,
so take it off.
What are you doing?
It's okay.
It's hard to get rid of
juice stains, take it off.
Please!
You shouldn't take off a man's clothes
in the middle of the day like that.
A man?
Aren't you still in your diapers?
He thinks he's a man...
Welcome.
Please dry clean this for me.
Yes, I'll take good care of it.
It's your academy fees.
I really hope you'll
get a job this year.
I'm sorry, Mom.
If you are late again
on the interest...
I won't go easy on you.
So scary.
What's that?
That's so nightmarish.
Wait.
Where did I see that girl before?
That'll be 7,900 won.
She works at that
convenience store.
But what's going on?
Is she being blackmailed
by thugs?
So scary...
And what was that ghost?
- [Day before the bar exam, 4:25 PM]
- It's time, why isn't he coming out?
It's Eun Chul.
Eun Chul!
I don't have time to talk to you.
Can you move?
Okay.
Since tomorrow is the exam day...
I just came to give you this.
I paid 300,000 won to get that
talisman, so you can pass the bar.
That will guarantee that
you pass the exam.
I hate superstitions like this.
Take it back.
It's not superstition.
He's so good.
He knew that when I was young,
I almost
drowned when I was playing
in the ocean.
And he knew that I got
bad grades in school.
Everybody has an experience of
almost drowning in their childhood.
And after conversing with you
for a few minutes
anyone can tell that you got
bad grades in school.
He even knew that there's
a man in my life.
He said he's either younger than me,
the same age as me, or older than me.
What else could he be if he's not
younger, the same age, or older than you?
Nothing else?
Anyway, I don't need a talisman.
Go return it or do whatever
you want to do.
I'm going.
Eun Chul.
Hey... what are you doing?
This...
You want me to sew this onto
Eun Chul's underwear behind his back?
If that's too hard,
put it in his backpack.
Such a waste of money...
You paid 300,000 won
for a piece of paper?
Piece of paper?
You are going to
bring bad luck.
You better sneak it in there.
If you don't, and Eun Chul
fails the exam, I'm going to blame you.
Fine.
She paid 300,000 won for a talisman?
I told her never to spend
more than 30,000 won on a guy.
Did you look into what I asked?
Chauffeur Park.
Why is this font in
Times New Roman?
Don't you know that I don't
like that font?
- I told you to use Arial!
- I'm sorry, Madame.
- I'll redo it.
- That will take forever.
Don't you do anything right?
Go.
Kim Bom...
27-year-old sister...
Owns a laundromat...
Kim Eun Chul was Bom's brother?
It sucks that he's jobless,
but even his family has no roots.
I'm so upset.
I'm home.
Baby...
It must be hard getting
business management lessons.
I have something to say,
come have a seat.
What is it?
My baby...
You are already 27...
You are so quiet and ladylike,
you never even got to date anyone.
Mommy is very upset about that.
I'm so shy...
You know I can't even look
a man in the eyes.
I don't care about dating.
That's why I'm trying to
set you up with a man
Set up?
I don't want to be set up.
You are like an orchid
in a greenhouse, baby.
A bee has to come and find you.
A flower can't go around
looking for a bee.
I'm only looking at high class
men who graduated
from good schools and come
from good families.
You just wait.
I don't know.
I want to focus on my
business management classes for now.
Please keep that in mind.
Baby...
What do I do?
I can't even tell my honey about this.
That convenience store where
she works was around here somewhere.
Give me back my money.
Let go.
Give me my money.
Let go of this.
I told you I can't return the money
spent on appeasing the spirits.
You said I would get a job
if I did as you said.
You didn't get a job
because you weren't devout enough.
Seriously...
You should try to
appease the spirits again.
- I'll do it for 5 million won.
- You think I'll get fooled again?
Just give me back my money!
If you feel wronged,
sue me.
My money...
Are you okay?
Thank you.
You should drink it
while it's still warm.
My grandmother once said...
When you are cold both
inside and out...
You should warm up your
inside first.
I see.
I seem pathetic to you, don't I?
Not at all.
In life, misfortunes happen.
I failed and failed again
at getting a job.
I was at the end of a cliff.
That's when somebody held out his hand.
I thought that he was trying to help.
My father died when I was young.
My mom raised me and my
sister all by herself.
I wanted to get a job soon,
and take care of my mother.
I'm sorry, but you didn't get the job.
I tried so hard for several years,
but I still couldn't get a job.
The spirits are against you.
Of course, you can't find a job.
What?
You should come visit.
That's when they approached me.
Let's see...
God of rice cakes...
You see how it fell right off?
If you pay to appease the spirits,
it'll stick right on.
I'll really be able to get a job then?
For the past year, I've helped
numerous people find jobs...
- How many exactly?
- 1387 people.
You heard?
Including you, that
would be 1388.
I gave him 10 million won.
I even borrowed money
from a loan shark to pay him.
Please.
In the end, I failed.
He pretended to hold my hand
at the end of a cliff...
but he just pushed me off.
Did you try reporting it to the police?
This is complete fraud.
I tried.
But they said they can't be prosecuted.
Who can I blame?
I'm the dumb one for
believing in their lies.
I wish I could die right now.
Don't say that.
I'll get that money back for you.
Then you will be able to work
on finding yourself a job.
Why would you do that?
Huh?
Look.
I was cheated by that guy, too.
I'll get that money
back for you no matter what.
Thank you for your kind gesture.
It's time for me to work.
I need to get going.
- [Day before the bar exam, 8:40 PM]
- I'm home!
I want to get Eun Chul married off
as soon as he becomes a judge.
Please look for a good match for him.
Of course.
At least that much.
For those who commit crimes listed in
sections 329 to 332, up to half
of those crimes can be punished by...
Where did I put it?
Is Young Mi making you do that?
Yeah, Young Mi told me to
put it in when you weren't looking.
You do whatever
she tells you to do?
Eun Chul, are you okay?
Go and throw out that
talisman right now.
Still, Young Mi thought of you,
and spent a fortune on this.
Get out.
Fine.
He didn't get cut
from the training institute.
My son quit and left.
It didn't fit him well.
- [National Diplomatic Academy, 2 years ago]
- Mr. Kim Eun Chul.
Don't you know the
meaning of a group project?
I gave you a warning
last time, too.
But again, you've handed in a report
that you worked on by yourself.
I had no choice because I
couldn't agree with the group.
Did you even try to
come to an agreement?
From what I heard...
You made a rash decision
saying that you
can't work with people
below your level.
I was speaking the truth when I said
they are low level people.
Mr. Kim Eun Chul.
I hope you know that your
evaluations are one of the worst.
Your rash and uncooperative attitude
is unfit for diplomatic work.
That idiotic dictator...
I heard he didn't participate
in the group project again.
He thinks he's better
than everyone else.
Even if he goes through the training,
he won't get any job offers.
Of course not.
What's the use of being smart?
He's got no social skills.
He'll just continue to act
like a loser, and get cut.
You quit and left?
They may have passed the
foreign service
officer exam, but they are
at such a low level.
I could never work
in that environment.
You said even the Minister of Foreign
Affairs called and asked you to stay.
He did.
My colleagues wanted me to stay, too.
Then maybe you should
have just stuck around.
Even when you took the public
officer qualification
exam, you left during the
training period.
Mother.
I want to take the bar exam.
I think that's a worthwhile place
where I can prove my skills.
I need to respect your decision.
But what am I going to
do about the academy fees?
Whatever...
I can take out a loan, or tell Bom
to take money out of her account.
But...
You are going to finish
your training there, right?
Yes, Mother.
This will be the last time.
Don't worry.
Okay.
I have faith in you.
You must become a judge
or a prosecutor, okay?
Okay, no matter what.
- I must...
- You must...
He'll definitely finish
the training period this time.
Please find a good match for him.
Of course, we care about her education.
Her husband will be a judge after all.
Of course.
I heard it's on the 10th
floor of this studio building.
It must be there.
He's done for today.
Goodbye.
I'm not here to get
my fortunes told.
I have something to say
to that quack, so move!
What's with this girl?
What the heck?
Let's see...
I won't get the job
this time, either?
Don't be disappointed.
If you call upon the spirits,
you'll have no problem getting a job.
What's wrong with you?
Can I get a job too,
if I call upon the spirits?
- This girl just keeps...
- Let go!
Your problem is not
getting a job.
What's the use of making money?
Because of all the men
crowding around you...
You won't be able
to save any money.
You need to appease the spirits.
Men are crowding around me?
I've never had a single boyfriend
in all my life.
I mean after you find a job.
Not now.
I'm the CEO of a laundromat
right now!
- CEO?
- What's this?
- He got everything wrong.
- I thought he was good.
This person is a total fraud.
He lies and says that you'll get a job
if you just pay to call upon the spirits.
He's a total crook.
So go before he takes all your money.
Hurry, and get up!
- Hurry, and leave.
- Listen, girls...
Go...
Get out!
Go, go...
What's wrong with you?
How dare you walk into my work
place and ruin everything?
Me?
I'm Park Ji Young's friend.
You cheated my friend.
Give me the 10 million won
you took from her right now!
Why are you taking it out on me?
It didn't work because
she wasn't being devout enough.
Jerk!
You are nothing but a crook that takes
money from those trying to find jobs.
What did you say?
You should experience how it feels
to get strangled, too.
Min Soo!
This psychopath is going to kill me!
- Die!
- Min Soo!
Let go of this, and talk.
- What's wrong with this woman?
- Mind your business!
Jerk!
What are you looking at?
Just give me the money!
I wanted to live a quiet life.
That jerk!
I should have beaten him up
until he gave me the money.
Still, violence is wrong.
If it's hard to resolve this alone,
why don't you ask for help?
Help?
From who?
Young Mi?
No, that artist guy.
Grandma, he's a total baby.
Baby.
He can't help with anything.
They say everything has a use.
He's better than nothing.
I'll think about it.
Anyway, can you give me the power
to look into the future?
Why?
You want to open up a fortune
telling business on the side?
It's not that.
I want to let Ji Young know
when she'll find a job.
And I'm a little worried
about Eun Chul, too.
Right...
Tomorrow is the bar exam.
Yeah.
Mom is already calling him 'Judge Kim'
and totally jumping the gun.
I think he's feeling pressured.
I usually can't tell you
but I'll tell you just this once.
Got it?
What?
What did you say?
I didn't hear anything.
I said I would tell you just once.
I'll see you again, granddaughter.
How can you do this?
Tell me again before you go...
Grandma...
She left again.
[Day of the exam, 7:30 AM]
He studied so hard
for the past year.
Eun Chul, get yourself
something good to eat.
What's this?
He's still holding onto the
talisman that Young Mi bought?
He acts all cocky...
But I guess he's got no other
choice when it comes to getting a job.
What were you doing?
Nothing.
You're not going to eat?
I don't feel like eating.
Still, you can't go on an empty
stomach to take a test.
I'll make some warm citron tea.
You should drink it before you go.
My hopes and dreams, you've always
done well on even the hardest exams.
I'm not worried at all.
Don't make any mistakes,
and get home when you are done.
Eun Chul, I had a really
good dream last night.
I think you'll pass with
flying colors.
Okay.
Eun Chul!
Eun Chul...
Drink this before you go.
I made it with honey.
Yeah, you should drink something
to warm yourself up.
Wretched girl...
Why the heck did you break the
cup on his exam day?
Why did you do that?
Nice job...
Ki Joon.
Ki Joon, what brings you
here so early in the morning?
I came to wish Eun Chul
good luck on the test.
I guess you are busy.
I'm not busy.
Come on in.
Okay.
He saw me getting beat up by
Mom so early in the morning.
How embarrassing.
Bom, wait up!
You're going to work early.
How is the laundry business?
Not bad.
That hospital gown you
washed for me...
it became like new.
You've got an expert's touch.
Since I was young,
laundry was a hobby for me.
I'm really good at
taking the stains out.
Laundry was your hobby?
That's very unique.
What's your hobby?
I like playing instruments...
and watching movies.
- I like watching movies, too.
- Yeah?
We should go watch a movie
together sometime then.
Have a good day!
Wait.
When?
Let's decide the exact date and time
to the second right now.
Now.
Right now.
Mrs. Kim.
From a family of
doctors or professors...
Is it so hard to find a doctor,
prosecutor, judge, lawyer...
or high ranking civil servant
who graduated from a top school?
Madame, if the man has all
those qualifications
he would be very picky about the girl's
family and education.
What's wrong with our family?
And Young Mi may not
have gone to college, but...
Mrs. Kim.
Mrs. Kim, why is it so hard
to get in contact with you?
Did you have a chance to find
a good match for Eun Chul?
Excuse me, Mrs. Kim is
talking to me right now.
Why are you being so mannerless?
Is that so?
I'm sorry.
I'll mind my manners, and
just talk to her for one minute.
Did you find a good match?
I'll make sure to reward you.
Yes!
This works out.
This is exactly what you've
been wanting.
Her son graduated from Seoul University
and he will soon pass the bar exam.
That's great.
This must be fate.
Not all law school students become
prosecutors and judges.
How can you try to match
my daughter to that bum?
He's so low class.
How dare you call my
precious son a bum?
Oh my...
Your temper hasn't changed
at all since then.
Not changed since then?
I know I've seen this woman before.
We saw each other nine years
ago inside
the conference room at
Culture Girl's High School.
Your daughter was such a bad
influence on my daughter.
She got suspended because of her.
So upsetting...
Yeah. Now that I look at you,
you are that nasty woman.
Let's only speak the truth.
Everyone knows that Young Mi
was the school thug.
- Who was the bad influence on whom?
- What did you say?
- That's such nonsense...
- And...
I would never marry my son off
to a low class
loan shark family even if it means
he'll never get married.
Stop dreaming.
Why are you doing this?
Loan shark family?
Low class?
Our family financially backed the Korean
army during the Japanese occupation.
We are a respected family.
...
Is that why your daughter walks
around, collecting
money wearing a skirt the size
of my hand?
What the heck...
How disrespectful...
Are you insulting
my baby's style?
Honey...
Something really bad happened to me.
Yeah, come pick me up.
Okay.
What the heck.
Mrs. Kim...
I will never become an in-law with
that family, please find another girl.
I can't believe her...
Honey, where are you?
Why is my stomach
hurting all of a sudden?
No.
Get a hold of yourself, Kim Eun Chul.
Get a hold of yourself.
I'll have to take out a loan, or tell
Bom to take money out of her account.
This is the last time.
Don't worry.
I have faith in you.
You must become a judge
or a prosecutor, okay?
Hey!
Are you okay?
Get a hold of yourself!
Look here!
Hello?
Hey!
Her phone is turned off.
Did Park Ji Young come
out to work today?
Yes.
Do you know where she is?
She was sitting alone on top
of the building steps awhile ago.
I don't know about now.
It's almost time for her shift.
I wonder where she went...
Okay, thank you.
[Will]
Ji Young!
No!
Don't come near me.
Ji Young, why are you doing this?
Don't do this.
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
It's not like I don't
understand how you feel.
But this isn't right.
Think about your
mom and sister.
No.
If I want to help my mom and sister,
I need to disappear.
Ji Young.
The loan sharks went to look
for my mom at her work this morning.
She was so shocked, she fainted.
If I die, at least she won't
have to pay back the loan.
I have a way to get that money back.
So, don't do this scary thing.
Please just trust me.
I'll make sure you get
all your money back.
So, please come down.
It's too dangerous.
Are you okay?
Let's go.
Let go of me!
I need to go.
Calm down.
You can't go.
Let go!
- I need to go in to take the exam.
- Calm down.
You can't go in during the exam.
That's the rule.
This exam means
everything to me...
I can't give up like this.
I can't give up!
I need to take that exam.
I bet he won't even give
me back a penny.
How am I going to get him
to give me 10 million won?
This mouth is the problem.
So why did you make
such a bold claim?
What else could I do?
I had to save her life first.
She even wrote out her will, and she
was about to jump from the rooftop.
What do I do?
It's no use suing that quack.
Of course, you don't have
10 million won, right?
Should I borrow it from Young Mi?
But why are you so fervently
trying to help this customer?
You know her?
Huh?
Yeah, I know her.
You see...
She's my friend's in-law's
cousin's sister.
If it's that close...
you should definitely
help her out.
The best thing would be to make
that quack cough up the money himself.
I know.
I have a good idea.
Hey!
Let's do that right now.
Let's go.
Let's go...
I'm almost finished with
taking care of my son.
I made him into a judge.
It would be perfect if I can
get a doctor daughter-in-law.
I'm getting so annoyed
thinking about it.
How dare she try to match him
up with a daughter of a loan shark.
Wait until Eun Chul becomes a judge...
I'll get him to investigate that family,
and punish them!
The rice is ready.
Let's see...
What time is it?
Oh my God.
It's almost time for my
hopes and dreams to come home.
Rib eye roll...
Rib eye roll!
Yeah, I'm on my way to deposit
the money we got today.
Okay, I'll see you there.
Nice.
You can't go in during the exam.
That's the rule.
Son!
You shouldn't have come out,
it's so cold.
Son, of course I should come out
when you just took that exam.
You went through so
much in this cold.
Right...
Did you do well on the exam?
Of course.
I don't even need to wait
for the results from the first round.
I'm going to start preparing
for the second round right away.
Of course, Judge Kim.
Right...
I wanted to nourish your body...
So I went and bought
some rib eye rolls.
Let's go.
I didn't know it would be this
easy to fool people when we started.
It's best to target those
who are in despair.
Yeah! But don't you think we've
stayed too long in one location?
I think we might get caught for fraud,
we should move to a different region.
- We should.
- Yeah.
I don't feel good about that girl,
Park Ji Young, catching onto us.
- I don't have a good feeling about it.
- Let's go.
It's you again?
I can't return her money.
And tell that girl,
Park Ji Young, or whatever...
She should sue us
if she feels wronged.
Sue?
She can't do that even if
she wants to.
My friend...
She died.
Because of the loans she took out
to pay you...
she threw herself into the
river in her hometown.
When was that?
Last night!
How could this happen?
- That was her will.
- Will?
Mother, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, my sister, Ji Hee.
I won't let that fortune teller
get off easy for doing this to me.
I'm going to get my revenge
on him in my death.
What do we do?
Hey, are you trying to
threaten us with this?
You killed an innocent person.
I can't let you sleep
in comfort.
I didn't kill anyone!
Return that money to Ji Young's
mom right now.
Otherwise...
my friend's restless spirit
will put a curse on you.
Hey, something's weird here.
What?
I mean...
She said the girl died last night,
but she called early this morning.
She was crying and asking back
for the money.
I'm sure you are mistaken.
Did you fall asleep drunk last night?
No, this is weird.
Let's give back all that money,
and go back to our hometown.
Shut up.
There are no such things as ghosts.
Stop talking nonsense.
Look for a new house
for us to move into tomorrow.
Feels so crummy...
I should be careful who I
cheat in the future.
Is the lightbulb out?
I told him to change the bulb.
Cold!
Seriously, why is there water here?
I told Min Soo to clean
up before leaving.
Let's see...
Where's that towel?
What's this?
They're footsteps.
She left a will last night,
and threw herself into the river.
No way...
No way.
Min Soo probably just left
in the middle of cleaning up.
I should change.
Let's go.
[I'll get my revenge.]
Cellphone!
Cellphone...
Why isn't this turning on?
Why isn't the power
turning on?
What's this?
Please turn off...
Turn off.
Please turn off.
What's this?
Why isn't the door opening?
Min Soo?
Is it Min Soo?
Even if it's in my death,
I'm going to get
revenge on the one who did this to me.
My friend's restless spirit
will put a curse on you.
He won't be able to do anything
bad ever again.
What a tragic end
to a crook...
He's getting what he deserves.
Thanks to you, I was able to
get all my money back.
It's not easy to help out
someone you hardly know.
I don't know how to thank you.
No...
That bastard...
Those crooks need to
be taught a lesson.
That way, there won't be
any more victims like you, Ji Young.
Yeah.
You were probably freaked out
to pretend that you were dead...
And I'm sure it felt strange
giving me your will...
I'm sorry for asking you
to do those things.
Don't worry about that.
If it weren't for you, I would never
have been able to get back on my feet.
Right...
I finished dry cleaning your clothes.
You said you have
an interview today.
You should wear this.
Thank you.
I'll get going.
Good luck on your interview.
Ji Young, fighting!
Bye.
Pretty...
I'm sure if I wear black stockings,
it'll cover up the burn scars.
This is a perfect outfit to wear on a
movie date with the man of your dreams.
This would be perfect for Bom.
Should I get it for her?
No...
You are not her boyfriend,
Yong Soo Chul.
Stop overdoing it.
Ki Joon.
Who's she?
Bom!
You came early.
Yeah.
I'm sorry for not
letting you know earlier.
My girlfriend really
wanted to see this movie.
I brought her out
so I can introduce her to you, too.
I heard a lot about you
from Ki Joon.
I'm Yoo Min Young.
Bom?
Bom.
Huh?
It's nice to meet you.
Yes.
Let's go in.
It's time.
Wait.
I just remembered.
I... left the stove on at home.
I should hurry back.
Nobody's home?
No, nobody's home.
I should hurry back.
I'm sorry.
Bom...
Bom, we should watch
a movie next time.
Watch where you are going.
Bom!
Bom, are you okay?
Watch where you are going.
Bom!
Bom, are you okay?
How can you do this?
You want me to look
for their couple ring?
You are so cruel, Grandma.
I feel so bad for him.
He's wandering around,
not able to tell
his family that he messed up
on the exam...
What are you doing?
Why do you want to know so much?
It has nothing to do with you.
Butt out.
How can I butt out
when I like you?
- Baby...
- Hey!
Where's my son?
Stop right there.
You can't make someone
like you.
I don't know who will be
in your fate...
But don't hope for another's
love to suffer
just because your own love hurts.