Anton!
-Where's your brother?
-I don't know.
Don't touch strange dogs, ok.
-Anton!
-Over there!
Anton?
Are you mad?
Those papers are full of germs!
We've been looking for you for over
an hour! What if we'd left without you?
It's a baby magpie.
Its foot is broken.
It's dying.
Look at it.
Poor thing.
Stop making a scene.
Someone will save it.
-We don't have time.
-We can't just leave it here.
We can.
Come on, move!
-Mummy...
-Gran's dogs will devour it.
Would you have saved people
during the war?
Spare me, Anton.
You win.
It's a stowaway.
Don't say a word about it.
The conductor can stop the train.
Gently... Open it!
Go away,
I'm cleaning.
-When'll you tell her?
-I don't know.
-I won't decide now.
-You should have told her.
-I should have.
-It's an ambush.
Take Récif.
Give him to Gulven.
Gulven!
-Come and get Récif.
-Hold her.
Ready.
Look, it's your daughter.
Your little daughter!
I'll tell Léna myself,
as soon as she gets here...
Give her your
neurological report too.
-Cut the schoolyard blackmail...
-Shit! Are you happy now?
Trying to drive me mad?
It's bad enough
and you make it worse!
I don't understand you, Annie.
Because it doesn't concern you.
-Clean the barbecue.
-You said we weren't using it.
I don't want you
within 20 yards of me!
Got out everything you need?
I finish packing tonight.
Very nice...
Things are hotting up.
Take this.
It makes me feel sick.
In your struggle for family harmony,
I'm on your side.
Don't yank my chain, young man.
Help me out here.
Get the kids inside.
We'll see to it.
-Talk to your big sister.
-Once the damage is done.
-What'll you say?
-I'll tell her that her patients...
need her more than her two brats.
That she must return post haste
to her crummy hospital
and that she can't go near
the canal,
unless accompanied by at least
two members of the community...
Your father can never face
the facts.
I've never known him face
Interested in what I'm saying?
I don't know.
Not one bit.
You don't touch birds.
Everyone knows that.
Nor eggs in nests.
Puppies or kittens are the same.
If they smell of humans,
the mother lets them die.
-Enough.
-They need to know.
-Is the bird going to die?
-No, it won't die.
We were careful.
We used a handkerchief.
Do birds have a soul?
No, Anton, birds are birds.
Is it still alive?
Yes, petal.
-Can I look in the bag?
-I just did.
Why not show her?
Has it croaked?
You said not to touch it.
A bird's temperature is 51 C.
That makes them pure spirits.
Is the bird dead, Mummy?
No, it's alive.
It's just fine.
Spare us the religious guff.
-Frédérique asked me.
-Enough!
Don't mention the bird to Gran!
30 years ago,
Léna was three and a half.
She was born in January.
January 12th, 1974.
With Léna here,
life changed.
My wife changed.
She wanted another daughter.
Frédérique was born.
Even now,
I have the strange impression
that Frédérique
is my wife's daughter only.
Hers alone.
Gulven, however,
is definitely the son
of my whole family together.
This year, for her birthday,
Léna asked me in secret to stand surety
for an apartment that she wanted
to rent in her own name.
One Tuesday morning,
I pulled up
outside her old building.
I had driven from Guerlédan
to Paris.
I waited until her husband left,
then I hurried up to join her.
She had hidden two packed suitcases
under the children's beds.
She was dumping her husband
and the hospital.
She had also decided
the children would stay with her.
-What's she like?
-Elise? Ok.
I warned you.
You'll be doing relief work
in September?
Shit,
they can't keep a secret!
No, I won't
and I'm not missing
the new school year.
You want to look after
your kids now
but you can't only do that.
You need to work.
Why couldn't
I only do that?
It may not help,
having a mother
entirely at their disposal...
You're wrong,
it suits them.
I was absent for years,
away for birthdays or Christmas.
-Not anymore.
-Christmas matters now?
It used to make you sick.
Enough.
Ready.
Mom, look at all those cows!
How do Mum and Dad rate Elise?
She asked for a nutcracker
to eat whelks.
Why are they always loopy?
-Who's loopy?
-Gulven's new girlfriend.
Don't tell him that!
It's José!
Come on, get out.
Look, it's Auntie Léna!
-You're happy.
-Not much luggage.
We're only here for the weekend.
-She's glad to see you.
-Hi.
How are you?
Hi.
Remember Elise?
Spare me her life story.
Welcome.
Mum, can I have your room?
-No way.
-Why not?
Because it's my room.
You three kids share a room.
I can't read there.
Read in my room
before you go to bed.
You don't read,
so sleep in their room.
I said no.
-Fuck!
-Anton, watch your mouth!
I'll see to it.
If you want,
you can go to Rome instead of me.
Take Mum while
I mind your kids.
A 12-hour coach journey?
No way.
No one made you go.
Hi, doggies.
The kittens! The kittens! The kittens!
We're off to Mrs Jégo's.
To see her kittens.
-Don't bring one back!
-Your bag's on your bed.
-Where's Frédérique?
-Upstairs with Gulven and Elise.
Wait for us, boys!
Shit!
Drowning or burial.
What'll I tell the kids?
They'll look everywhere.
Cremation.
It's crazy
you can't even keep a bird alive.
What do you mean?
The thing was already half-dead.
I'm not touching it.
Black bird, evil spirit.
I can see to it.
Mind if we keep this in the family?
We're losing a bird
and, above all, a game of Cranium.
Want to climb up?
Don't move.
It's the tale
of a poor and hideous woman
with a daughter your age,
Augustine.
Her husband had abandoned her
to sail the seven seas
and she found herself
with no food to eat.
So she made a pact
with the devil.
She offered him her child
in return for some gold coins.
Lucifer accepted
and put a handful of gold coins
-on the rim of the spring.
-What's the rim?
The rim is the stone edge
where Augustine is sitting.
So the devil grabbed the child
to carry her off.
But when the woman tried
to pick up the coins from the stone,
-she burnt her hands horribly.
-Why?
Because the coins
came from the flames of hell.
Trust the devil
to play a trick like that.
With a cry, the poor woman
dropped the coveted gold
and the coins lodged forever
in the granite of the rim.
She had lost everything:
the gold and her child.
-Are the coins still here?
-Yes, they're still here.
Wet the rim to see them.
There are 14.
Want to try?
Step back.
-See them?
-No.
You need to wet it a bit more.
Can we see anything?
At the bottom, maybe.
Charge!
You're back already?
-Pretty kittens?
-Not great, except a ginger one.
-The ginger's one are rare.
-We're looking for gold coins.
-What coins?
-The devil's.
-Was he sweet?
-Yes.
You're going back there?
-We'll take it back to Paris?
-Maybe, if you really want to.
-You're not getting a cat?
-Hurry before she gives it away!
Come on, you slowcoaches!
Shit! Use the lock!
Sorry.
-Can I do my teeth?
-Of course.
How long have you been with Gulven?
-Seven months exactly.
-Not bad.
So, how do you find my parents?
Well, a little...
-a little cold.
-Cold?
I'd have picked
any adjective but "cold".
They're not at all cold.
They have failings, true.
But cold?
Shit, you've got a nerve!
You started without me!
You know the beginning is what
I like in sex but look at you...
Your scars still really show.
I'm proud of them.
Here and here...
And, sister dear,
it's something I share with Elise.
She had pneumothorax too.
Show her your scars.
It's ok, Gulven.
-Show her your scars!
-No.
Can't you wait until I get out
before you strip?
You miss it, don't you,
you raunchy mama...
A man's body against yours...
Move, stupid!
You smell of sex!
You smell of worn-out old sex.
-You're not asleep, José?
-No.
You had a nightmare?
You've done a pee?
Are you nuts?
Coming for a smoke?
I don't want a sister.
You won't get one
if you don't want one.
Hail, Mary, full of grace...
Your feet are wrinkled.
-The Lord is with thee...
-What are you doing?
Resisting my anti-Christian approach
to popular art?
No, please, don't smile.
This house teems
with permanently smiling people
who don't need your blessing,
believe me.
I want to die.
Don't say that.
I know you don't
love me anymore.
Who is it then? Armel?
I do love you.
You make my life hell.
I'm ashamed of us.
You try to make me flee you.
What do you see in a guy
called Armel?
-He lent me a book.
-A guy lends you books.
This is absurd.
I can borrow books from people.
Even in Iran women
can borrow books.
Sometimes I wonder if this kid is mine.
Stupid! Get out! Get out!
Look at this. Six weeks old.
Beautiful.
-Hi.
-Ok?
-And you?
Your cat pissed
by the fridge.
Where is it?
They're all down at the lock.
Not the best place for a cat.
Anton doesn't agree.
Couldn't anyone stop him?
Can't you eat quietly?
"Puss in Boots" at 6 a.m.
may not be good for my pregnancy.
Augustine was up.
She can't decide
when the whole house wakes.
Mum was already up packing.
Your kids tyrannize you, you know.
I'm dumb, I have to be.
Mothers are stupid brainless cows,
except for you, of course,
you're perfect.
I'm just saying
they take advantage of you.
Have you ever analysed
"they take advantage of you"?
You play the tough guy
by making your heart arid.
A tough guy? Me?
You've totally lost it.
Honestly...
Six months ago,
you were a wreck, now you lecture me?
Hurry, girls, it's eleven-thirty.
You know we're eating at twelve.
We leave at three!
-Who'll get the bread?
-I'll go.
You're not washed.
Frédérique...
Don't ask her,
I said I'll go.
At least comb your hair.
I'm the old mother rabbit
of Guerlédan...
I have nothing to eat...
My tummy's empty.
I fancy eating some nice fish.
Or, if not, I could eat children
who stink of fish!
We don't smell of fish!
Why are you here?
-Hello.
-Hello, Nigel. Why are you here?
Your mother summoned me.
No way!
Mummy!
Can you put me down?
What's Nigel doing
in your garden?
I invite whom
I want to my home.
Bread, Mummy...
-Go outside.
-Not too much. Lunch is in five minutes.
You think you're clever?
I offered the house to Nigel
while we're in Rome.
He needs to see his children.
And you need to stir up the shit!
You have an interview
with your sister's boss on Tuesday.
You can fill in at the bookstore
during her maternity leave.
Focus on yourself, Léna.
Only on yourself.
You're both crazy.
Don't be silly,
we sorted it all out.
Hide these fast.
It's not the season.
I don't want them!
I'm too busy to gut them now!
Nigel can grill them tonight
as a treat for the kids.
-Just put them in the bin!
-Take me to the station.
-Operation Evacuation?
-Discreetly.
You can't.
Our coach leaves at three.
Tell your grandkids
you threw their mother out.
You always complicate things.
I'll get the car keys.
I'll wait for you outside.
Can you get my bag?
In case I bump into the kids...
When are you going to grow up?
We can't talk about this, Mum.
You've always sided with Nigel,
with order.
You have such a poor imagination.
-Ever heard of altruism?
-Shut up!
Stay for lunch.
If it's too tough,
leave when we do.
If I leave, I leave now.
If not, I go with the kids.
Here.
-You don't know what you want.
-I do.
I want you to be happy.
Let me know
if your coach misses a bend.
Your wife's a real bitch.
She told me something
she found funny.
She said it after I complained.
She told me
I reminded her of a hyena.
Pull over, please.
-You want to pee?
-Pull over.
Frankly, the hyena isn't
the nicest animal in Africa.
Or anywhere else, in fact.
I thanked her for her bitchy remark.
"What bitchy remark?"
"What you just said,
calling me a hyena."
She started sighing.
A very demonstrative sigh.
Then she said she found it amusing.
I answered that I found it mean
rather than amusing
and so I was wondering
why she was being so mean to me.
She hesitated before answering,
as if she were asking herself if the time
had come to tell me the whole truth
-or not.
-What truth?
That she doesn't love me.
I don't need you confiding in me.
-Besides, I'm not interested.
-Let me finish the hyena story.
She hesitates and that's when
I make the mistake of smiling,
a faint smile, but a smile even so
expressing complicity, sharing...
She withdraws into her shell
and simply says,
"Hyenas lurk near corpses
they haven't had the guts to kill.
"You're like them.
I feel you lurking."
Lights out, good night.
I don't understand!
She isn't saying I lurk.
That's absurd.
She's saying I don't have the guts
to end it between us.
She's saying I won't leave.
-She thinks...
-Enough, Mathias!
I'm willing to help, but not now.
Just answer one question for me.
Just one. Ok?
Answer me yes or no.
Has she said she's seeing
another guy?
What's going on?
Mathias was showing me something.
Gran said you'd
gone back to Paris.
She was wrong.
Don't worry.
I'm not worried.
When do you leave?
-I'm here.
-Thank you, dear.
Here comes my most beautiful child!
What are you up to now, Lena?
And Augustine?
She's eating with José
-so she can have a nap during our lunch.
-She gave up naps two years ago.
Forgot something?
Ah, Léna just the woman.
Under friendly but firm duress
I've offered Nigel my room
since it's geographically closer
to your offspring.
I don't want this to prevent me
from testifying against him
during your divorce proceedings.
Sorry, Nigel...
I forbid you to joke
about my divorce, ok?
-Yes.
-Relax, Léna.
Mummy!
Is it good, sweetheart?
How could you?
It seemed a good idea.
Michel!
The pregnant one...
No, Frédérique, my second daughter.
My grandchildren...
Frédérique!
Mrs Roland...
Shit, it's scary...
They're all so old!
No older than Dad and Mum.
I hope I die first.
Don't be so dumb,
they'll have a great time.
Can't you be negative for once?
Honey...
We're waiting for you.
Mind driving us to the station?
Of course not. When?
-The 7 p.m. train?
-Yes.
-Coming back with us?
-No, I'll stay a bit.
-You'll miss that interview.
-I won't.
Just say so.
-I don't need the hassle.
-I'll get the 10:20 train.
-If Nigel will drive me there.
-No problem.
What about Elise and Gulven?
They're staying till Tuesday.
Then they're off to a rock festival.
-Can I tell them?
-Yes.
Elise will give me her hand.
We're getting married!
Why are you the only one
who still plays with dolls?
-Back off! Congratulate him!
-Congratulate him for what?
I forbid you to get married!
Excuse her, Gulven.
It's her hormones!
Right...
Let's calm down.
They won't get married.
Are you crazy?
You close it up like
a retirement home!
-Where are you going?
-For a drink.
-I'll be gone later.
-Ok, kisses.
Have a safe trip.
-Ok, honey?
-Hit the road, Jack.
It's this one. It has your name on it
but I don't understand it.
-Where's it from?
-Gulven found it.
He wanted Elise
to hear the family hymns.
"Without moving but with the intensity
of his gaze..."
We're only making plans for Nigel,
We only want what's best for him
Wer're only making plans for Nigel,
Nigel just needs this helping hand
And if young Nigel says he's happy,
He must be, he must be.
He must be happy in his work.
And if young Nigel says he's happy,
He must be happy..
Excuse me.
I can't talk now.
We're putting the kids to bed.
I'll call you after I drive Léna
to the station.
Kids, say goodbye to your mother.
We need to get to the station.
I've changed my mind.
I'll stay a day or two,
in total harmony,
unless your slut spoils it.
-You're staying, Mum?
-What do you mean?
Your mother asked meto
look after our kids
because you need to retrain
as a book-seller.
So?
I work from time to time,
you know.
I try not to show it but, all the same,
don't push me too far.
A holiday with my ex-wife
at her parents'...
-I'm not ready.
-Sorry.
I thought you came
because you missed the kids.
The kids, yes.
You're the one pretending
nothing has changed!
-You wear me out!
-You're right.
I must be mad.
Good for the asylum!
-Don't act neurotic.
-You think I'm neurotic?
The hysterical mother,
with her clutches, her fatal embraces.
Anton and Aug
need a week away from you.
Create a little distance.
I'm an irresponsible mother?
I never called you irresponsible.
You mix everything up.
You're dishonest, Léna.
-Scared and dishonest.
-Right, I'm out of here.
You asked to be alone with the kids
until the divorce.
So you could live out
your shitty affair!
Six months without seeing them.
It was sick but I kept quiet!
I intend to make
the most of this week.
Why did you have to come here?
You get two days
with them next week.
How fucking generous! Two days!
Get dressed, Anton.
Come on, sweetheart.
Daddy's driving us
to the station.
-We're going home.
-Isn't it bedtime?
Hurry up. Put your things
in your backpack.
We've had enough slamming doors today.
I'll split instead.
I'm sorry kids.
It's your mother's call.
What do we do?
We don't move.
Can you still
hear me after that?
Now then, this gun dates from 1849.
1849, does that ring a bell?
No? All right...
It was the battle that pitched Garibaldi
against the French.
Any more and I'll kill that old bat
with eternal stones.
Run, you idiot,
or they'll see us!
We'll have a wonderful view
of St Peter's
and a surprise awaits us:
a lighthouse.
Tell me words of love.
In Italian or in French?
I don't care. I need
a little sentimentality, darling.
What does that mean?
You're most impolite,
young lady,
to demand sweet nothings like that
and reckless to arouse a man like me
in an almost deserted park.
"Stronzo"!
I hug you in my two arms.
And I want to flee with you,
my love.
I don't want to die, you know.
I can't feel my right
cheek anymore.
The neurologist warned us.
Facial paralysis,
diminished eyesight...
-We aren't there yet.
-It looks as if we are.
Let's not panic.
Maybe it's temporary.
Want to see a doctor here?
No, there's no sense in it.
It won't help.
I have all the medication I need.
-What are you doing?
-Calling the kids.
I don't want you telling them!
Frédérique first.
Her answering machine, of course.
It's Mum.
A quick hello from Rome
to tell you that it's sunny
and that Dad and I
are going to live here till we die.
No, I was tidying up.
I never said I'd repaint
their room.
So what do you want?
Good.
No, I'm not going.
Because I'm in Guerlédan.
Nigel has left.
None of your business.
I don't want to talk about it.
Well...
I have to go and do the shopping.
Give Dad my love.
Want to talk about it?
You just feel weepy
or is it worse?
You've reached Frédérique and Mathias.
Leave us a message.
Frédérique, it's me again.
Call me as soon as you can.
Léna's in Guerlédan.
I just spoke to her.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm ok, sweetheart.
Want to go to the park with Dad?
Yeah, okay.
Don't shout, Mum.
I told you your voice is amplified.
It's their problem, Mum.
Yes, I'll talk to her.
Remember to get me a gondola.
No gondolas in Rome?
Ok, have fun and take care.
Anton sends his love.
Give her a kiss.
Goodbye, madam.
You made our old mum
cry again?
She loves it.
I still want to be
an anaesthetist.
-You can't be now.
-You're wrong.
Since going on leave,
I haven't contacted the hospital.
But they'll end up firing you.
-I'll do something else.
-Simon!
-Good to see you!
-I saw you this morning.
You're right!
You know my big brother, Simon.
I made good time. I was thinking...
Do you have hens here?
-Gulven?
-Yes?
Can you come with me? Excuse us.
Be right back.
I'm not stupid, ok.
-What?
-Why did you invite Simon?
I didn't think you'd mind.
He's on his way to the festival.
-Well, I do mind!
-You've met him before.
Thank you, I remember.
What's the problem?
At my move, Simon stayed
to assemble the furniture.
That was kind of him.
It took forever to get rid of him.
No...
Wait...
I didn't know.
He knows.
I don't need this kind of trap.
We'll have dinner,
then he'll leave tomorrow.
You're too silly, Gulven!
How many people will
you send packing?
My life pisses you off!
The way I think pisses you off.
-I should just vanish for good.
-I never said that.
That's exactly
what you just said.
And you're probably right.
-Get lost!
-You get lost!
Asshole!
Loser.
-What's wrong?
-She's completely mad.
Good morning
Good morning.
I didn't mean to stir up the shit.
Not you!
I'll find a hotel
nearby and split.
Thanks for making me
look like a hysteric.
I was glad to see you.
It was an opportunity.
Wait there,
I'll get changed.
Let's hide.
Hold on...
You're too much.
Give me a second chance.
It's as simple...
-It's as simple as that?
-No, it's not simple.
Léna, you never called me.
You never sent a sign via my sister.
It's not simple.
Goddammit,
I don't fall in love often!
Sorry, I'm getting carried away
but I can't help believing in it.
-There was no reason to.
-Sorry, there was.
You kissed really well
and you seemed to want it too.
It doesn't matter
nothing happened.
You're mad at me
because it didn't?
What was I supposed to do?
You strip, you strip me,
but then forbid me to touch you.
-I don't know why I scare you.
-You don't.
Go out to dinner
and leave me with the kids.
Afterwards, I'll be in bed.
And, tomorrow, you'll leave.
I'm scared.
Hold on.
Don't panic.
What are you doing?
I can't read in our room.
Aug's sleeping
Think it's smart
hiding here to read?
Hiding?
The house isn't far.
Let's go back.
Let me read you a story.
Anton...
Please.
Tell me on the way back, ok?
Ok.
It's the story of Katell Gollet,
which means Katell the Lost.
She was beautiful
and lived with her father.
Her beauty was matched
only by her perversity.
What does that mean?
She loved dancing and debauchery.
So her father wanted
to marry her off.
But Katell had no desire
to shorten her youth with marriage.
So she told her father,
"When I find
"a handsome partner able to dance
"for twelve hours with me,
he'll win my heart and my hand."
Many young men try their luck.
But Katell rejects them all one by one.
Soon, it is Minek's turn
to dance for Katell.
He is 17,
with bright blue eyes.
Like the other boys, 650
Minek knows her bad reputation.
People say she's dissolute
and unable to love.
Even so,
Minek falls in love with her.
Since he is handsome
and a good dancer,
she takes him to the local fête.
Before marrying him,
she wants to see
if he can make her dance for hours.
The procession climbs a hill
to the fête.
At the head,
four nubile women
bear a statue of the Virgin.
Katell has told her father
she wants to come by cart.
On reaching the top,
she leads Minek over to the singers.
She starts the celebration
before the priest says mass.
Hello. I'm looking
for my sister, Léna.
She's downstairs waiting for you.
Through here...
-Enjoy lunch.
-See you later.
Be back by 2.
It's as cold as a fridge in there.
I see the link
between undertakers and florists now.
She keeps the air-con on?
Does she pay you decently?
It keeps the flowers fresh.
Otherwise, the answers are:
Yes, no and yes.
-I wouldn't last a day.
-Good, because I work there.
I didn't mean that.
You did.
Are we going far?
A little bit.
Just across the park.
It's full of flowers.
I know, flowers...
You're obsessed, aren't you?
What are the flowers
supposed to hide?
Don't be fucking nosy.
Vulgarity doesn't suit you.
"Marry fashion and you'll soon
be widowed," Cromwell said.
Cromwell?
The English guy with the round hat
and puritan views.
I'm considering divorce.
I'm...
I'm sick of his jealousy
and his mediocrity.
Divorce, it sounds odd,
like talking
about someone else.
After our so-called honeymoon
in Annecy, I told myself:
real life will never begin.
I didn't really care.
Focusing on work passes the time.
It's taken me 10 years.
I have no illusions now.
Loving but lucid.
That's my untenable motto.
You already had someone last summer...
Have you told Mum?
No.
-When will you tell her?
-Later.
I'll let her savour
your divorce first.
-Who is he?
-Please. That's not really the issue.
It is. For me it is.
It hurts me here.
I feel betrayed.
Don't you always
feel betrayed?
What?
You're not always
the one who's hurt.
You think you're
alert and attentive
but you'd be surprised
by what goes on in front of you.
What are you trying to imply?
You haven't eaten.
NOTORlOUS
Your sister's very friendly.
She gives off a form of energy.
I love that kind of attitude.
-Is she much older?
-I'm the older one.
I'd never have guessed.
We've just had an order for a delivery
to the cemetery.
-I'll let you go.
-To the cemetery?
Yes, of course.
The family wants the bouquet
to be there by five.
I'm thinking of something...
a little wild,
a little bushy.
Do I have to? I'm going
to the wholesale market tomorrow.
Sorry, Léna, I don't want to know.
Just manage. I warned you
that this job could be tough.
I know but today
I have to pick up my kids.
I thought I'd be gone by four.
I know. A month from now
they'll have the flu,
epidemics, chickenpox, head lice,
holidays every other week...
Don't tell me about
your children.
I hate children!
I'm the only person for miles who
doesn't ant to hear about children.
Sorry.
You swore I'd never
know their names.
Anton and Augustine.
Nigel?
It's me.
We had a shrike.
Have you ever had one?
A strike is worth
a trip to the park.
-What was it for?
-I can't go to the park,
I have loads of homework.
Yes?
What do you mean, no key?
Anton has one on a string.
He forgot it? I don't believe it!
Are you ganging up
to make my life hell?
Work something out!
It's easy without a key.
You're a right little bandit!
No, no television!
Mum says we must adapt
to anything:
-life is just anything.
-She should know.
Life's like that
when you do just anything.
"What any visitor
would have seen
"was a string..."
Eating here?
Unless you're expecting someone.
Have you eaten?
Please,
don't overdo the generosity.
This is already
humiliating enough.
It's as if we weren't divorced.
We've been to court, shit!
It's as if that didn't count.
As if it didn't exist.
You're here, totally at home...
Forgive me for making dinner
and looking after the kids.
Who called me? Who had a delivery?
Who forgot the key?
You had no food.
I've done two washes!
No one asked you to.
You do it to piss me off!
I won't pay for the slightest favour.
"I've done this, you owe me that."
Admit you're a selfish asshole
and I'd recognize your talents.
Ok, I'm out of here.
I'm not asking you to leave.
Have dinner with me.
I know this is kind of you but...
Forgive me,
a demon was talking through me.
I had a vision of our lives earlier:
two tiny mounds of mud.
You can't make bouquets all your life.
You can be so excessive...
-Aren't you tired of it?
-I've never been excessive.
Always criticizing...
It's a passion.
But that's why I love you.
How's Myriam?
You're still together?
I know, you can love two women.
It's different.
I'm a fool to think otherwise.
I know that, but too bad.
The idiot is sick of your hypocrisy,
common sense, wisdom, concessions,
modernity...
I'm old-fashioned!
I can't manage anymore, Nigel.
I'm here.
No, you're not.
And that's only natural.
Why can't I manage when others do?
You're not doing so badly.
Stop worrying about yourself.
If you dare to say this is a good time
to have sex, I'll murder you.
You should get an au pair.
-With what money?
-Mine.
I'd rather have sex
than touch your money.
You talk a lot about sex...
-Because I'm not getting any.
-Sure.
Believe what you want.
I know other guys screw you
and that kills me.
-It makes me sick imagining you...
-Don't imagine anything.
How are your hospital colleagues?
First my sex life, now my colleagues.
You have to be going?
You're an absurd woman, Léna.
I wouldn't trust myself
if I were you.
Well...
Get out!
-Let me put my coat on.
-Do that outside.
Stop it!
Don't touch me.
-Don't touch me!
-You're hurt...
Get out!
I don't want to see you again!
Anton...
What's wrong?
I fell.
Rise and shine, Anton!
It's almost eight!
What are you doing?
Rest, dear,
I'll see to everything.
Do you have to shout like that?
I love saying "rise and shine".
I don't know why.
What are they doing?
Think I'll find a washer?
I'm no good at relief work.
Stop it.
You're being useful for once.
Look at this... Cat food everywhere!
Disgusting.
Where is the damn animal?
With you?
Hello, sweetheart.
Did you sleep well? Sit down.
-Can I have my bottle?
-Eat your cereal!
I have a bottle. It's quicker.
You're too big to play
the baby now!
-Mum says...
-She says a lot but doesn't do much.
All talk and no action!
No bottles for you.
You'll get duck lips
and buck teeth!
You're always mean about Mum.
You come to help
but all you do is criticize.
Catch him!
What are you waiting for?
Too late. He knows the way anyhow.
He hasn't eaten a thing.
The world disgusts him.
He'd like to be a Cathar.
What?
The Cathars were always innocent
and always pure.
Others wanted to kill them
for showing them up.
I'm going for a walk.
-Can you walk on your own?
-Of course.
-Dad can come.
-Where are you going?
For a walk, on my own.
I won't be long.
You haven't had breakfast!
See you later.
She's not 10 anymore,
you can't make her stay in.
She's in no state to go out.
Hey!
-Could you get Anton?
-Of course.
-What's wrong?
-You left in a rage this morning?
What did they tell you?
Can I eat at
the canteen with you?
-I need to talk to you.
-We never talk.
Strangers can't come
to the canteen.
I'm your mother, stupid!
I came here to see you.
You really have a screw loose.
You've grown so big.
See, you've nothing to say to me.
Come and meet me after school.
We'll go to the park.
I promise.
I love you so much...
You're stressing me.
See you later.
Anton!
-What are you doing here?
-Shouldn't I be asking you that?
I'm pretty much a regular here now.
That table there gets
a lot of light
and the owner loves me
like his own son.
Gérard?
He's doing transference onto me.
Does he have children?
How are you?
-What do you want, darling?
-A shot of whisky.
He calls you darling?
Yes, for a long time now.
On sunny days,
he kisses me on the lips.
The traitor...
Doing that to his own son.
Are you spying on me?
A little.
Are you still a walking wreck?
I need strength.
Can I help you?
-What time do you call this?
-Sorry I'm late.
-Where's your collar?
-Mom...
-There's someone with me.
-Hi.
-Good night.
-Are you eating here?
How damn elegant!
No, he'll watch us.
Quiet, the kids are asleep.
Anton was wiped out.
You've been letting him
stay up too late.
His pyjamajacket is torn.
Thanks for the advice.
-Sorry, this is all I have.
-It's fine. I love Bart Simpson.
I smell burning.
Ooh!
-What do you prefer?
-What?
-I've eaten.
-Come on.
-The gratin.
-Coke?
-Yes.
Take it.
Michel, my father.
I thought
I'd become the invisible man.
That would be relaxing
after a day's work.
Your apartment's
a plumber's paradise.
There's enough work here for two
for a month at least.
-There are leaks...
-Enough, dad.
I do everything badly,
but no one gives a damn! Forget it.
Maybe this young man doesn't know
what he's walked into.
-You're despicable.
-I'm Simon.
-You can call me that.
-Welcome, Simon...
since Simon is here.
-What do you do?
-Dumb question!
I invite whom I want.
With you here,
I feel I've been evicted!
Your plate.
I don't have much crockery left,
between Nigel's place and the move.
Don't you like braised endives?
No one does in the real world.
What kind of codswallop is that?
People love endives
if you cook them right.
The way you talk!
No cheese platter?
Cheese after gratin?
With cheesecake to follow?
Give me strength...
-Let's not wait for them.
-Exactly, they shouldn't have left.
Sorry, but I'm suffocating.
You always have been.
What can we do about it?
You blame your macho father,
your mother's guilt trips,
your pushy sister,
your self-centred husband...
But what about you?
There's enough oxygen
for everyone.
No, it's all been used up.
You're just used
to not breathing.
Your petty life and gestures,
Dad's whims...
The diktats of some,
the problems of others...
You think it will end one day...
and that you'll be free,
but it never ends.
You've wasted your life.
I won't settle for that.
I'd rather...
You'd rather what?
Go out with some adolescent?
Simon?
He's only five years younger than me!
-And your children who...
-Stop judging everything I do!
What can I do with a thing like this?
It should be embedded.
It's not standard. It's useless.
It needs two weeks' work...
-I'm going.
-Michel is explaining how...
I know. Let's go.
Sorry, Michel.
Thank you.
Don't worry about it.
Life without drama is pointless.
For this family's
women at least.
What drama do I put you through?
What a nerve!
I'm just mending the electricity...
We all have parents. Who cares?
I care.
-They're not so bad.
-Don't talk about it.
It's crazy, lightning flashes
from your eyes when you speak.
What shall we do?
I don't know.
-I knew you'd do that.
-So why do it?
I don't know. Let's walk.
As a girl, I thought things had to
remain possible as long as possible,
with no decisions made.
That way, I'd be free
and not make mistakes.
My life wouldn't be cramped.
I found my parents' life
so pathetic,
so petty, so submissive.
When Gulven talks about you,
and he often does,
he always says you're a rebel,
an unwitting revolutionary
who just wants to seem normal.
-That's so complicated!
-I don't think so.
You try so hard to get things right.
You're so demanding you screw up.
And you're so scared
of pushing others aside,
of overshadowing them,
or of making them jealous maybe...
Really? You noticed that?
If I were a man,
my life would be simpler.
Less of an ordeal.
If I were a man
I'd be a captain
-I'm serious.
-I don't think so.
You submit to too many people.
You know, my sweet,
your life
cannot be summed up by what you are
nor by what you can have,
but by what you are ready
to give up.
It sounds like
an old wives' saying
but it's true all the same.
We all need something
that we can give up.
What if I don't want
to give anything up?
In that case, my dear, tough!
You know,
I loved kissing you!
Really loved it.
I love your mouth.
And...
I really liked eating
from children's plates.
We get on well.
Are you tired?
I don't want to pressure you...
but I'm naked under the sheets...
and...
I'm a bit cold.
I'm on the other side.
Good night, Simon.
-Yes.
-Nigel, it's me.
-I need...
-What's wrong?
I need to see you.
Has something happened to the kids?
No, it's me. Can you let me in?
Can you let me in, please?
I'm not alone.
Let's meet tomorrow.
Léna?
Are you still there?
I'll live the rest of my life
without you!
Don't kiss me, please.
I won't ask you where you slept.
Been seeing this Simon long?
We don't have to talk about him.
But...
I imagine you brought him here
to let me know about him.
Try using words,
it might help me.
My marriage is a closed case.
You had to sleep with Simon
to realize?
Such tact...
You know what I mean.
Have you ever wanted to leave Dad?
Loads of times.
But my marriage helped me
to avoid doing it.
-Because of us...
-No, not you.
I've always set you aside
from the love in my life.
I'm married to your father,
not to you.
You don't love Dad anymore?
Not the way I used to.
Perhaps I don't love him anymore,
compared to how I view love.
But I live with him.
And I'm very happy.
I never expected
to spend my life with Nigel.
I told you that.
But I'm sure I loved him.
Don't say anything. I'm slow.
Anton...
It's too early to be up.
What's wrong?
Want to sleep in my bed?
We'll be going now.
How are you doing, Anton?
Think you can get up?
Ok, we'll carry you down.
Goodbye.
We're going with them.
Go and wash, dear.
-Is he ok?
-Yes, don't worry.
-Ok, sweetheart?
-Let's go.
I'll go and see Léna.
-I'm not wanted up there.
-Nigel's here, is he?
We're waiting for his father.
What's keeping him?
Hello there.
-Packing for both?
-Nigel's taking them.
Léna agrees.
She couldn't manage.
The kids need to be together.
Anton will be under observation
until this evening.
You can help pack the toys.
-No.
-What?
I want no part of this.
Part of what?
-Part of what?
-I'm not talking to you.
She's crazy and driving
my kids crazy.
They're in danger.
-Don't exaggerate.
-Why did I trust her?
Hold on, didn't you bang some chick
behind her back?
Yes, and I don't regret it,
believe me.
All I regret is not taking the kids
with me right away.
-Where's Léna?
-I sent her to shower.
Don't talk like that!
Nice and clean now?
He tried to kill himself
to get at me.
I'm no use to him.
-I couldn't protect him.
-Cut it out!
I'm serious.
You protect José.
He trusts you.
Anton is afraid for me.
That's not normal.
What's not normal
is the Yank taking your kids.
He looks after them better.
That's no reason.
I'm so ashamed...
Mum, you told us to accept injustice
in order to fight it.
The story of Solomon
and the baby...
You said children
always come back.
Remember the day I lost you
in the Huelgoat woods?
The Huelgoat woods?
When did we go there?
We went there a lot.
This was when you were tiny.
Before Gulven was born.
It was a Sunday.
I'd had a row with your father.
I took you off in the car
with our cat. Mao, I think.
He ran off
and you wanted to look for him.
Night was falling...
I don't remember.
You must.
The Trembling Rock.
With that guy,
Nicolas Gronski.
Dad couldn't stand him.
He drove like a maniac.
What did we do?
I set off to look for Mao
with Mr Gronski
and we left you at the rock.
We soon found Mao
but we couldn't find you again.
I was terrified.
Mum!
Léna, come back!
And?
We finally found you.
It was nearly midnight.
Léna, you were
reading Hugo to her
with your trusty
flashlight.
Thank God she was.
You could have stayed
and let the guy look for Mao.
Actually,
Gronski wasn't very bright.
After that,
he never came to the house again.
He wrote me some sweet
letters though.
Mathias wrote beautiful
letters too.
He'd talk of my two coats.
"You belong to two worlds,
with two coats, and only I see them."
Want some good news?
The divorce is off.
You were getting divorced?
-You didn't tell Mum?
-It was a secret, wasn't it?
I love you so much, sister.
-Don't you want a bath?
-I just had a shower.
-I'll get lunch then.
-No, we're going.
You must think
about what you really want, Léna.
-Can we leave you?
-Yes.
Come on, Mum, out.
Bye, dear.
Augustine and Anton won't forgive you
for leaving without them.
They wouldn't have
forgiven me anyway,
but it would have been
for something else.