♪ Fixed and Synced by
bozxphd.Enjoy The Movie ♪
(GASPS)
(SIGHING HAPPILY)
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Okay, Ellie, I got her.
(GASPS) The Christmas rock.
Just got her out of storage.
I wanted to surprise Peaches.
Where is our sweet little angel?
Huh?
Incoming ! (LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
There's your sweet little angel.
Sorry, Dad.
Yeah ! Whoo-hoo! It's on !
(LAUGHS)
You guys need to chill out.
(INHALES)
(SCREAMS)
(EXHALES) ELLIE: Peaches.
(GASPS) The Christmas rock!
I love it! I love it! I love it!
I love it! I love it! (KISSES)
No, no, no, don't.
(GROANS) Too late.
(MUFFLED) I'm stuck.
(GRUNTS)
This is the same Christmas
rock I had when I was a kid.
It's an heirloom that's been
in our family for generations.
Tonight when Santa comes
by with his presents,
he'll see this rock and know that a
very special little girl lives here.
MANNY: (SINGING) Oh, Christmas
rock, oh, Christmas rock
(GROANS)
You're 30 tons of
granite And every...
You know you're singing
to a rock, right?
It's a Christmas
tradition for the kids.
Don't sabers have
Christmas traditions?
Oh, yeah !
Every year my dad would bring home the
biggest, fattest gazelles he could find
and then we'd all rip into their.
. .
(CLEARS THROAT)
(QUIVERS)
. . .our presents.
And we'd play games
with the gazelles
and dance with them and not eat them.
The end.
Merry Christmas, my mammals.
Wow! That's some crazy rock.
Step away from the stone.
Why? You'll break it.
(LAUGHS) Sid can't break a rock.
Don't tempt him.
Uncle Sid, we need this so that
Santa can find us tonight.
What, this? Oh, pfft.
(STUTTERS) He could
go right past it.
You need something bigger,
taller, sparklier.
Something with a pizzazz.
Um, a tree!
A Christmas tree?
(SCOFFS) Do you know how
ridiculous that sounds?
There's millions of
trees out there, Sid.
How would anyone
notice this one?
Well, we could decorate it.
Crash, Eddie.
Whoo-hoo! (LAUGHS)
(SCATTING)
Sweet!
(LAUGHS)
(GAGS)
And, voila!
It does look pretty good.
Ah, it'll never catch on.
It's beautiful.
Hmm. It needs a certain
razzle-dazzle on top.
Something that says Sid.
(GASPS)
Ooh.
And just like that, a
tradition is born.
Huh?
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Hey!
(BOTH GASP)
Seriously, what did you
think was gonna. . .
Yep. That says Sid, all right.
(GROWLS)
Okay, okay. Let's just
keep it together.
It really is about the spirit
of Christmas, isn't it?
You're about to be a
spirit of Christmas, Sid !
Manny, please. I'm so sorry.
You know what, Sid, I'm the
least of your worries.
You gotta answer to Santa.
Santa? Santa Claus?
He is never gonna forgive this.
You just got yourself on Santa's.
. .
Uh, ah, Santa's Naughty List.
(GASPS)
Santa has a Naughty List?
Yeah ! Yeah !
And if you're not good, then
he puts your name on it.
We're never good.
Then why start now?
(GROANS)
Well, if your name's
on the Naughty List,
you don't get Christmas.
(GASPS)
But no! Why me?
Besides the fact that it's my fault.
(CHUCKLES)
The Naughty List? Where did
you come up with that?
Relax. Sid's gullible but
he's not that gullible.
He knows this Santa
stuff is just for kids.
What? You don't
believe in Santa?
Um, I, well. . .
Of course, he believes.
That's the magic of Christmas.
If anyone deserves to be on the
Naughty List, Dad, it's you !
She sure told you, didn't she?
Well, too bad, I'm a grown-up.
Grown-ups don't believe
in the Naughty List.
(SOBBING)
I'm not getting Christmas.
(INDISTINCT MUMBLING)
Don't cry, Sid.
Why not?
Your tears are freezing solid.
Huh?
(GRUNTS)
(CRIES)
(ICE CRACKING)
(SCREAMS)
(CLASSICAL WALTZ MUSIC)
(MUSIC ENDS)
(SCREAMS)
Why am I on Santa's
Naughty List?
Why? Why?
My guess, because he
doesn't have a loser list.
Well, thanks for
trying to cheer me up.
I still feel terrible.
Pull it together, Uncle Sid.
We've got work to do.
But I'm still sulking.
No time. We're
going to the Pole.
The North one?
Yep. We're gonna find Santa
so I can prove to my
dad that he's real.
And we're gonna get
you off that list.
And us, too!
We may be naughty but we
still want Christmas.
Peaches, honey, you
can't come with us.
This is a very
dangerous journey.
The North Pole is a desolate
land of ice and snow.
This isn't exactly Miami.
Come on, Uncle Sid,
I want us all to have
Christmas together.
Hmm. I don't know.
It's wildly irresponsible and
impulsive but let's do it!
Northward, ho!
CRASH AND EDDIE: Ho ho ho!
(SIGHS) Uh, guys, let's
follow the northern lights.
North. Get it?
Northward ho! Santa ho!
Ho ho ho!
SID: (SINGING) On the
ninth day of Christmas
My true love gave to
me Nine fleas a-biting
Eight pounds of ear wax
Seven frosty fingers
Six frosty fingers
ALL: Five rotten...
SID: Eggs?
Huh. I think we just
marched off the Earth.
No, it's a white-out.
We'll be safe as long as we all.
. .
stay together.
Peaches, where are you?
Uncle Sid? Peaches?
Huh?
Eddie? Where are you, Eddie?
Oh, wait. I'm Eddie.
(WHIMPERS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Okay, everyone, grab hold of
your buddy and follow me.
I have an excellent
sense of direction.
Wait.
(SNEEZES)
Bless you. Thank you.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
Ha! Did you see what
I just did there?
(HUFFS) Pa-pow!
You're a reindeer.
Yeah, I know.
You can fly!
I know!
You're amazing ! I know!
Check it out, Sauerkraut. I
can hover, roll and zing.
Zing? Zing ! Bam !
(SCREAMS) (CHUCKLES)
(COUGHS)
What's your name?
My name is, um, uh, Prancer.
Prancer?
(LAUGHING)
It's a family name.
Oh, don't listen to them.
You saved our lives and
we'll never forget you.
Have a merry Christmas.
Are you sure you
don't need my help?
Oh, no thank you. You've
done more than enough.
Look, we'll take it from here.
(SCREAMS)
The reindeer comes with us.
Uh, what do you think?
You want an honest answer
or a Christmas answer?
Uh, Christmas answer.
It's gorgeous.
ELLIE: Manny? Huh?
Have you seen Peaches? I
can't find her anywhere.
And Sid, Crash and
Eddie are gone, too!
Last I saw them, they
were trying to figure out
how to get off Santa's
Naughty List.
What Naughty List? I made it up!
We gotta find them.
Diego, can you pick
up Sid's scent?
I can but it makes my eyes burn.
BOTH: Do it! (SIGHS)
(SNIFFS)
(GAGS)
Got it.
(GROANS)
So, Prancer, how long will it take
us to get to the, uh, North Pole?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! You can't
walk to the North Pole.
It's too far.
But I can fly you there.
No sweat, on Air Prancer.
Oh, oh, no, we couldn't.
No, no, no, no. My
family raised me
to be good to strangers and there's
really no one stranger than you guys.
Huh?
Shotgun !
(ALL CHEERING)
We've run into a little
turbulence, folks.
Please fasten your seatbelts.
I'm not too heavy, am I?
No, no. You're light
as a feather.
A 788 pound feather.
(GAGS) Do you come
equipped with barf bags?
Peaches! Peaches!
Manny, where's Diego?
(MUFFLED MUMBLE)
Diego! Buddy, are you okay?
(SCREAMS)
Glad you didn't kiss me?
Are you sure this is North?
I don't know. I. . .
(INHALES) I'm all scrambled.
Wait, tracks!
Uh, Diego?
The geomagnetic whatever,
it's messing with my
sense of direction.
Oh, well, that's just great!
We're completely lost, my
little girl is missing and. . .
Manny, honey, everything's
gonna be fine.
How?
Just believe in the
magic of Christmas.
Oh, this is silly.
Just try it. It's
not gonna work.
Do it for Peaches.
(SIGHS)
I believe.
Manny, look! The
northern lights!
North. Get it?
Um, that was just a
coincidence, right?
Who cares? I'll take it.
Let's go.
(GROANS)
(ALL GASPING)
We must be getting close.
Sugar plums!
Peppermint bark!
Yellow snow, my favorite!
Don't, just don't.
HEAD MINI SLOTH: Halt! None shall pass.
(ALL GASP)
Oh. Oh, hi, little guy.
So, who are you?
We are the Santourage.
We keep intruders out so Santa can
do his work without interruption.
(GASPS) I knew he was real !
You've gotta let us see him.
It is forbidden !
Turn back, I command you.
Bye! (GRUNTS)
Oh, yeah? You and what army?
(GRUNTING)
Oh, that army.
Hasta luego. Feliz Navidad.
But you gotta let me in.
I'm on the list!
He must not be disturbed
or we won't get presents.
You have been warned.
Unleash heck!
(GASPS)
Bring it on, you
little fleabags!
You're no match for the power of.
. . (ICE CRACKING)
flight.
Everybody, grab a leg and pull !
(YELLS)
Ow! Huh?
(GRUNTS) Huh? Uh. . .
Run !
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(SINGING) You better watch
out You better not cry
Better not pout I'm
telling you why
I am coming to town
Yes!
Oh, I'm making a list
And checking it twice
(WHISTLING)
(RUMBLING)
Ah, nutmeg !
Ho ho, no!
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GROANING)
(SID SCREAMS)
Oh.
Sid?
Sid, where's Peaches?
Peaches! Peaches!
SID: Where are you?
Over here!
Wait, wait. The
reindeer fly up here?
This one does, cuz.
(COUGHS)
Peaches! Daddy!
Oh, baby, we were so worried about you.
(KISSES)
Oh, you. . .
You are so grounded !
Sorry, Daddy.
I'm talking to Sid.
SANTA: Frolicking fruitcake!
(GASPS) It's Santa!
Just 'cause there's a fat
guy, doesn't make him Santa.
I'm not fat! It's this
suit, it's very poofy.
Manny, it is Santa!
And he's just as old and
decrepit as I imagined.
And, oh, so jolly.
Oh, look at this mess.
Two hours to Christmas and
everything's ruined !
My toys, my sleigh !
All my hard work.
Um, would this be a good time to talk
about getting off the Naughty List?
Sid, there's no such thing.
There is now, Manfred.
Thanks for the idea.
Wait, wait! How do you know my.
. .
. . .name?
Santa?
Hey, what did we do?
Ahem.
Oh, right. Destroyed Christmas.
Peaches, you were. . . I
mean, I mean, I was. . .
That's Santa!
Standing right there.
He's real !
Duh !
There's gonna be a lot of
disappointed kids tomorrow morning.
Ow!
There's gotta be a
way to fix this.
Dad, it's impossible!
There's only eight of us.
(GRUNTS) And 800 of them !
Wait, us? You mean, as in, us?
You never thought to give the
old fat boy a hand, huh?
Come on, Peach.
You taught me to believe.
What do you say?
Hit it! Ow! Not me!
(SINGING) Deck the halls
with moss and rock weed
BOTH: Fa-la-la-la-la
BOTH: What's a hall?
'Tis the season...
What's a season?
Fa-la-la-la-la
Just play along.
I can fix this, Mr. Santa
We can fa-la-la-la-la-along
Give a sloth a chance
Now, can't you?
Too many "la's" are in this song
I have no idea why
I just did that.
That's a toy! And that's a toy!
And this? This is no
good for anything.
Sid has got the proper spirit
Fa-la-la-la-la
Hey, not too bad.
Beautiful ! Don't
let Sid near it.
Fa-la-la-la-la
Come on now, Dad.
We can do it lf we hurry
Lend a claw Lend a paw
Everyone
Even if you're small and furry
All together we can get it done
A ball of twine? Who's
gonna want that?
Whoo! (CHUCKLES) All right!
What do we do with this?
Oh, why don't we put it here.
(KISSES) Hey!
Something about that mistletoe.
. .
This shall go down in the annals
Fa-la-la-la-la
And we're not through
Peace and goodwill
towards all mammals
Oh, you shouldn't have.
Just for you.
Things were looking
grim and tragic
But we got busy
and pulled it off
Now we found some
Christmas magic
All because of each
and every sloth
"All because of each
and every sloth"?
All because of each
And everyone
I can't believe it.
These presents!
The decorations! This sleigh !
Ain't she fly?
I bet the mini sloths could help you
make presents every year! Right, guys?
Well, we're gonna need hats.
Cute hats.
In fact, it looks like you got enough
toys for every child on Earth.
Every child? Around the world?
I wish I could, but
I don't see how.
(LAUGHS) Santa, I'm giving you the
biggest Christmas gift of all.
Me! You're flying Air
Prancer tonight.
Oh, that's the
spirit, Prancy boy!
Time to put this
deer in high gear.
Vroom, vroom !
(GRUNTS) Um. . .
Up, up and away!
(GRUNTS) Come on !
Saving Christmas here we go!
Anytime you're ready.
I can't believe it!
I failed.
(SIGHS) Huh?
This family doesn't
give up that easy.
All right, Dad !
Come on, Prancer. We
have to keep trying.
You're the only flying
reindeer we've got.
Unless you know 10 others.
You're right. I can't
do this alone.
Wait, where you going?
Perfect.
Wow! Heck of a day, eh, Santa?
Come on ! Ho ho ho.
Oh. Still on the
Naughty List, huh?
(GRUNTS)
Okay, so we traveled
about 30 feet so far.
If we keep up this pace, we should
make it around the world in what?
Let's say just under 8000 years?
(ALL GROANING)
Bah, humbug !
Hey, guys! Manny's right!
Nothing's impossible
if you pull together.
Meet my family.
Dasher, Dancer, Vixen,
Comet, Cupid, Donner. . .
Whoa!
PRANCER: . . .and Blitzen.
(SNIGGERS) Blitzen?
And I thought Prancer was bad !
(LAUGHS)
(CRASH AND EDDIE SCREAMING)
Nice name.
It suits you.
Thanks, Prancer.
I thought I was such a hotshot,
but sometimes you gotta
have a little help.
That's what this herd
has taught me. . .
Stay.
(KISSES) (GROWLS)
(SID SCREAMS)
. . .among other things.
Now, let's do this.
Ha-ha! Yeah !
Hey, Manfred, nice job!
I got Christmas!
See what happens when
you believe, Dad?
I gotta say, I'm kinda
digging the holiday magic.
(CHUCKLES) Merry
Christmas you two.
SANTA: Ho ho ho!
All right! Whoo-hoo!
Yeah !
Merry Christmas!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(CRYING)
(DECK THE HALLS PLAYING)
English - US - bozxphd