THAT MAN FROM RIO
Eight days of leave.
Yes, eight days.
12:00 o'clock break.
- Ooo
I'm starving.
Smell this cheese.
- Wonderful.
Professor! Professor!
- Yes?
A phone call for you.
- I'm not here.
They've robbed the museum!
What?
What? The museum?!
I'll come right away.
She didn't eat again.
- She didn't eat again.
See you later.
- Yes, adios Lebel.
Will you go out? - Of course.
- Yes, you have a girlfriend.
What if she has someone else?
- Impossible! If she has... than... And it's over!
Would you really hit a woman?
- Listen, my friend. Nobody is worthy of this.
In eight days on 14:40 train.
You bet! Don't be late.
Later, Lebel.
- See you, Dufourquet.
No one can enter.
- I'm Agnes de Villermosa.
That's all?
- Yes, I finished. Thank you.
There are no surface wounds.
I believe, it's a heart attack.
Poor man most likely died of fear.
- You must agree, Professor...
...that something here smells funny.
He didn't touch the golden crown
or the necklace with rubies.
Most likely he's a crazy collector.
- The statuette is something really special.
It's priceless.
The civilization that made it has disappeared.
Disappeared? - The Maltek civilization.
- Maltek? And what has this to do with that? - Everything.
And who are the Malteks?
People of the Amazon rainforest, who were destroyed
by barbarians. - Barbarians?
Conquistadors. Europeans. You, me...
- Me?
Have you been there? In the rainforest?
- Yes, I will show you.
Photo taken three years ago.
On the day that the expedition ended.
Yes, I see you.
You're here.
- No, here.
And the other two?
- Villermosa, who died after we returned.
And Di Castro.
The Brazilian who financed the expedition.
Each one of you came back with your own doll,
and yours now got stolen.
Exactly.
- We won't get anywhere that way.
The Malteks were interested in secrets and hypnosis.
Do you know what was their best weapon?
- Swords, spears?
Poison.
That's nonsense.
- What if not all of them disappeared?
Yes... Indians dead for the last 300 years
came to Paris...
...only to steal a lousy piece of wood.
With the help of hypnosis. Obvious!
The statuettes are cursed.
I gave mine to the museum.
That's why they came here.
Villermosa kept his and died from a poisonous arrow.
Why didn't you tell me, Martin?
- But I did, three years ago.
Agnes, you came. - Of course.
- Whom do I have the honour...
The daughter of Mr. Villermose.
- I didn't know. But of course.
Excuse me, miss.
Do you know where is the statuette of your father?
- We never found it.
Father hid it before he died.
- Ah, I see. Thank you.
I will accompany the lady.
- I'll wait.
Look, I found something. An arrow.
Everyone ridiculed me and told me
that the Malteks have died.
Those morons think that I'm mad.
The rainforest swallowed the Malteks...
...submitted to green oblivion...
It's nice that you dropped by.
You always come if something goes wrong.
Thank you.
I would take such a little girl for a daughter at once.
I'm not a little girl anymore.
You always call me that way.
Only once every six months.
- Haven't I changed at all?
You've changed a lot. You are more...
- Feminine? Ha ha ha
Quite a little different, no?
- Yes, truly.
So?
I still age alone.
How is your aunt?
- Come for a visit, you'll find out.
Bye!
Why would they kidnap the professor?
- Because of the statuette, of course.
The story repeats itself.
- It interests me, what's with these statuettes.
They haven't found the statuette of Mr. Villermose?
- No. - No, no, no.
After the expedition my brother,
her father, hid the statuette.
After that, poor him...
Dreadful thing, madam.
Adrien! - Free for a whole week.
Did you get the postcard? Well, I'm here.
Greetings, auntie!
Whom do I have the honor...
- My pleasure. Well, until later.
We'll come back in a week.
Don't wait for me. - No.
Not now, the police is here.
Police?
You say that your father hid the statuette.
- Yes.
And Agnes knows where he hid it.
- At that time we lived in Rio...
She was only 14.
- He hid it at the top of the aviary.
An aviary in Brazil?
- I remember. At three in the afternoon everyone was sleeping.
I also went to take a rest...
when I saw from the window...
...how father dug a hole
and put the statuette in it.
He wore gloves and was all sweaty.
If we were to go there, I'd find it for sure.
Draw the location, I'll send it to the Brazilian police.
- I don't know exactly.
I would have to be there.
- Miss, your car is blocking the traffic.
My car? Let's see.
It is blocking. I'll be there right away.
- You forgot about me?
I haven't forgotten about you, young man.
Come here.
Whom do I have the pleasure...
- Soldier Dufourquet, 3rd squadron.
A pilot, then. You don't look like one. A relative?
- No.
Fiance? - Not yet.
- What are you here for?
Agnes is a friend of mine.
- Oh, is she? - Yes, she is.
What are you saying?
Why did they kidnap the professor?
- The professor? Oh yes!
I'll tell you.
I kidnapped him.
- Listen. We'll be friends...
...if you don't make fun.
- Do you want details?
I stood at the window, the night was coming down...
...when two sinister men in black
stepped out of the car.
They walked slowly towards the professor,
reached him...
...and kidnapped him.
Shit! They kidnapped her!
Stop him!
Your ticket, please. - I must stop...
- You can get a ticket from the machine.
Get in line, like everyone else.
Agnes!
Thank you, sir.
General, general? Should I bring you a newspaper?
Yes, please, miss.
You didn't bring one miss?
Still, you are charming.
At your orders, general.
- At rest!
Like Charlesroi!
Sir, your boarding pass. You have to go there.
Agnes!
- You have to go there.
All passengers embarked.
Listen... - Sit down, sir.
- Listen to me me, please.
Please...
- Buckle up yourself. I will help you.
Dear passengers, welcome on the plane
to Rio de Janeiro.
Rio!
Can I help? - No.
- Do you need anything? - No.
You seat...
- It is here.
If Lebel could hear this!
Sir?
- I have to talk to the captain.
We can not disturb him.
- It's a serious matter.
They have kidnapped this girl.
- Which one?
The one who sits between those two men.
- Wait, please.
You passports, please. Thank you.
Thank you.
That's what the mister says.
- Do you know him?
No.
- Agnes, after everything...
Return to your seat. We do not want any problems.
- But Agnes...
I will notify the police in Rio.
They will put things in order.
I can explain...
Could you hold for a moment,
we need to check your passport?
You speak English? - No.
- French? - No.
Italian? - No.
- Only Portuguese? - Yes, yes. - Forget it.
This is Rio.
Americano? Liz Taylor, Cadillac,
Hollywood, Cape Canaveral.
I know all America.
Polish it well. And the other one.
Francaise? Tour Eiffel, de Gaule,
Brigitte Bardot... I know.
Five cruzeiros.
I don't have any.
Go your way.
Fifty.
Here. - Thanks
What am I doing here?
What is your name?
- Sir Winston. - What?
Sir Winston.
- Bye Sir Winston.
Where are you going?
- I'm looking for a girl. - Girls!
I know where. Let's go.
No, my girl Agnes.
- Agnes? Is she pretty?
Lost in Rio. They kidnapped her
and I don't know where she is.
Wait.
Here, here!
What's wrong?
Call the ambulance.
Hey. What's a matter with you?
Please mister, it's mine.
- Yes, yes.
If you don't mind, give it back. It's mine. Give it back!
- Stay away!
What did you see? - Let's go.
Miss Villermosa.
- She isn't here.
A French woman, she came with two local losers.
Tell me only the number of her room.
I may not tell you this.
- Right, I'll find it out on my own.
If you insist, sir, we'll have to kick you out.
Don't worry, I'll still find her.
My dear!
- What?
Don't you remember me? - No.
So you know Pickwick?
Of course I know this old saber.
After you, madam.
I'm glad that you like him.
- Yes, yes.
It is very kind of you.
- No problem.
Pickwick, now we'll have our nice
afternoon cup of tea.
What would he do without his tea.
You know how children are. - Yes.
We'll be delighted to see you again.
- Oh, thank you.
Goodbye, goodbye. - I hope to see you soon.
- Goodbye, goodbye.
Agnes, do you hear me? Wake up.
What have they done to you?
Wake up!
- What do you want?
Let's go, do you hear me?
- Stop shaking me!
These scumbags drugged her.
Look at me, Agnes.
Get up.
Smile, walk.
Agnes, go to the door and don't stop.
Where is she?
Where are you going?
Walk.
Goodbye.
- Let's go
Did you get the friends?
Wake up.
Wake up!
These lousy scumbags!
How pleasant.
And this looks like waves.
Agnes!
Of course these are waves.
And this is a sea.
Because we are in Rio.
- Rio?
Yes, Rio de Janeiro. Brazil.
Do you understand?
- Brazil! Brazil.
Stop!
- Some man.
Don't you remember me?
- No. I don't care who you are, forget it.
Get yourself together. - You look handsome.
Something like this never happens.
She doesn't know me anymore.
- What a nice surprise.
Pleasant music, no one on the beach.
Thank you, handsome. - Stop it already.
These scumbags!
What does he say?
We shouldn't sleep on the beach, we must go.
I'm sleepy.
We go to my house.
Come, sweetheart!
You live here?
- Yes. Come!
She is beautiful!
- Believe me, she's heavy.
Bring me pink sheets.
- Do you hear her?
She always wants
what I don't have.
If I say something
it's like talking to the wall.
She doesn't listen at all.
Woman means that she waits for you at home.
The woman is tender, understanding.
When you come home in the evening...
...you see her in the living room
playing the piano. Or the harp.
Love at home for whom it has.
This water still doesn't know how to boil.
I'm chasing her around the world.
Is this normal? - I know. Scotch?
Chin, chin!
Where am I?
Adrien! What are you doing here?
Where am I? Agnes!
A... Agnes. Everything is alright.
Finally you are back to yourself. Look.
What is this? How beautiful.
- Rio.
Rio? - It's quite simple.
Yesterday I arrived with Lebel in Paris.
I went to your place...
- Dreadful!
Wonderful. - What will it be? Dreadful or wonderful?
- The ice cream is wonderful, what happened is dreadful.
You are nailed. Better stop this.
Do you think that I'm having fun?
They can shoot me for this.
You and your statuettes, Indians
and professor Batactan...
Catalan. Don't mix the poor man into this.
- Alright, why did they kidnap him.
And you... - They didn't dare?
- Don't get upset.
There's more reasons to kidnap me.
Only I know where the statuette is hidden.
You aren't clear?
- So?
I plan to tell them where the statuette is.
They made a mistake.
Where are you going?
- Come, come!
Where?
- Just come along.
We lived here with my father.
You don't like it.
- Yes, yes, beautiful. - Look!
The dog house.
What a sweetheart he was.
His name was Pilou.
Bernard, with a blind eye.
The chambermaid broke it with the broom.
- Beautiful...
How beautiful. - You didn't come to look around.
- You're right. Wait here.
I stood here when father came from the house.
Go to the end of the garden.
Further back. Go, go...
To the left.
You're clumsy.
Where are you? I don't see you.
- Here. - Further back.
Quickly, quickly!
Straight. Go! Stay!
That's good. I remember
that he stood here.
Where is the aviary?
- This all is an aviary.
At the time there weren't so many plants.
- This is life: from seed to plant.
Give me the shovel.
No, no, no, no.
Yes.
- Shovel.
Come on, I'm waiting!
Isn't it wonderful?
Run.
You asked for it!
Adrien! Help me!
Adrien, save me!
The statuette!
What's the problem?
- I'm warning you, don't point a gun at me.
Are you crazy? We need it.
- Adrien, what did I tell you? -  I'm going.
Why do the bad guys always win?
- They still don't know with whom they play.
There's a surprise waiting for them.
Where did they go?
- You know, I can't tell you this.
- I don't know, miss.
They have two statuettes. There's one left.
- Di Castro's.
Is he from Rio?
- Yes, I think.
Most probably he's in the phone directory.
How do you spell it? - The way you pronounce it.
- As a member of the expedition he's next.
But I won't allow this.
- Stop talking and search. - Aha, di Castro.
Mr. di Castro is on the ship.
There he is. - Easy.
- We must be fast.
We have to warn him.
- We have to get such a boat.
What if we are already too late?
What if they already killed him, stabbed him?
The ship is his grave on the water.
- You're right, let's go.
Damn! Only your mouth works.
- Watch your language.
You're right, I'll go alone.
Wait! Are you crazy?
You'll attract attention.
- I'm not afraid of the water.
Did you learn to swim?
- No, why? - I will go.
Don't worry.
Just don't move until I come back.
I'll be back right away.
- I'm not good enough anymore.
Is anyone here?
Hands up.
- I will explain...
Towards the shore, darling.
I gave up my country, family,
army and friends, crossed the ocean...
...so that I could see miss Agnes,
to kick the nosy pot lids.
Is this normal?
Adrien, try it, it's not difficult.
- I'd rather die.
You dared a lot to leave me alone.
Did you find di Castro?
No.
- Wasn't he on the ship? - No.
Is there something wrong? - No.
- You're angry, aren't you?
You have Rio at your feet.
You can manage alone quite well.
This is for you. Bye, darling.
In 4 days I have an appointment with Lebel...
...at the station under the clock. It was nice.
If I start something, I finish it.
The statuette! - Mr. di Castro.
- You know him?
I know him.
- Where is he?
He went by plane?
- Where? - To Brasilia.
Adrien, did you hear? He's in Brasilia.
We can still catch him.
Why not? It's not far, we'll get the subway.
Do you have a ticket? Here.
Smell it.
If you loved me, you wouldn't make fun.
- I still haven't proven my love to you?
Words don't prove anything.
How far is Brasilia?
- Thousand, two thousand kilometers.
We'll need a car.
- I know. - Exactly!
You have to choose the color.
- Pink with small green stars.
Look at this little house! Butterflies!
What is this? Look.
- Pole. - No, that.
Telegraph pole.
For all this you see poles.
- Leave me alone.
You are ridiculous. How could you be insensitive
to the beauty of the world?
Listen! A deserter in a stolen car
with a hysterical woman...
...is a moron or a drug addict,
but is not insensitive. So what am I?
Let's go. - If I want to.
- I'll get out? - If you want to.
You always get what you want.
Pull!
- That's what I'm doing.
Where does it lock? - Find it out.
- Why should I be doing everything?
Pay attention! Don't let it lose!
- But I hold it!
Get up, what are you doing?
- Yes, sergeant. At once, sergeant.
On the floor! On your feet!
How sweet you are in your underwear.
Angry?
Answer me!
Come back!
This is the police.
Sir, could you, please, arrest me?
I deserted...
...lost my uniform and flew
with the stolen ticket of some invalid.
I fought with men
of all colors and nations...
...and I drive around in a stolen
pink car with little green stars.
I'm also guilty of public indecency.
Sir, the handcuffs! Please.
Soldier Dufourquet, third squadron.
French air force. Do you understand?
No, eh?
Only Rio and Brasilia.
Ah, Brasilia? 50 km.
- Too bad that I don't smuggle something.
Look!
- Yes, I know. Butterflies with ears.
Stop, the green car. It's the professor.
Stop, it's Catalan!
Who, Catalan?
- The professor is alive. We must save him.
Let's do it!
Hold the steering wheel.
No! No! No!
Quickly, so you don't end up there.
Professor!
- You'll hug him afterward.
Let's go, fast! Step on the gas.
Agnes! How come you are here?
They kidnapped me... and Adrien,
my fiance, saved me.
He has a leave.
- Keep your eyes on the road! - Thank you.
Don't mention it.
- What have they done to you?
First they kidnapped me.
- And we meet on the road to Brasilia.
Where are we going?
- To warn di Castro.
- To warn him?
We must warn him before they get him.
I was afraid that they had killed you.
- No, no.
Only I know the secret of the statuettes.
Secret! I haven't come to play
cowboys and Indians.
I still have three days of leave left.
- Don't think only about yourself!
Everywhere there'll be windows,
everywhere only glass.
So that it will be bright, full of glare
and transparent light.
Like a butterfly wing.
Such shall be the building.
I insist.
Let's go!
Norbert!
Let's go to my place for a drink.
We'll talk there.
This is my hiding place.
Not at all.
Ah, my fountains. Not really from Versailles,
but still cool. I hate these plants.
We'll throw them out!
No, no, no!
There won't be such crashing in my house.
Go!
The statuette is safe.
This is the jewel in my collection...
...my most precious memory.
My youth.
And you? Still single?
You still wear a suit too small?
Do you like the new Brasilia?
- Very much. - And Brasilians?
How strong it is!
- I know her since she was in diapers.
Everything grows: the world grows
and shoots sprouts...
...that grow like my city.
This was wilderness three years ago.
Then some of us got together...
...and this is what happened.
- You are wonderful!
Only you haven't changed, Norbert.
I followed your work about the Malteks.
Wonderful.
You are still such a dreamer, no?
- You don't believe me? - I'm a busy man...
...and I don't have time for daydreams.
But you aren't... - A loser?
Come on. You are wonderful!
- Mario, the statuette.
We shouldn't bore the guests.
- They won't mind at all.
Would you like to see the statuette?
Here it is!
Imitation.
- Bravo! The eyes of an expert.
It's fake.
I have a few of these.
The real one is hidden. - Where?
- Did you think in the living room?
Where so many people pass by?
- Good. And me?
Is there a problem?
- Our friend is in an unusual situation.
He must be in Paris on Monday.
- Come, you have my word.
I will arrange everything.
Tonight there will be a hydroplane
available to Mr. Catalan. - Tonight?!
Correct, in the morning before daybreak.
Tonight you are my guests. - My leave...
- That's not important. I know that you are reasonable.
I'll introduce to you my wife.
Norma!
Friends from France.
We'll quickly prepare something...
...and have entertainment.
That's you!
- Unbeatable.
They call me so because I always win.
Cheers. Agnes, your eyes spill out.
- Spill out? - Full with anger and promises.
- Really?
- Your eyes are whispering, murmuring.
Stop throbbing! I hate noise.
Where did we stop?
- My eyes are spilling out.
You are frightening me.
- I hope, dear.
I took off.
The flames from the ship were high.
Suddenly I notice that I burn.
And I'm 5km above ground.
It was just for laughter.
What is so funny?
- He's lying.
Before the flight to Rio he still hadn't been in mid air.
- Just a second, girls.
Just a second, girls.
You're witty.
- Don't neglect me.
Be glad for what I still do for you?
- I'm not joking.
I think that I love you.
- There's really no dragon which I have to kill for you?
It's over with the dragons.
- Whom do I shoot? Save? I can retire.
The slippers, mom!
- This will come. Kiss me.
Only if you'll be happy.
Mario, show me the statuette.
- My friend...
...drink a bit. You didn't drink at all.
- No.
Are you afraid that you'll be poisoned?
Like the father of Agnes.
- Why are you saying this? - You're nervous.
This is expected after all that happened.
- Is the statuette really safe?
Sure.
- I'd like to see it. - You're joking.
You're right that you want reassurance.
As long as I guard it, it's not in any danger.
Trust me. Come.
Come on, come.
After you.
Do you still believe in Maltek's treasure?
- More than anyone else.
And the answer is in the three statuettes?
- As if you didn't know.
Enter.
Wonderful.
- I keep here the best pieces. My treasures.
And the statuette?
So?
Yes.
I waited three years for this.
Three years of preparations.
You make fun of me
that I wear a suit too small.
But this loser will soon be
richer than you.
Wait below.
We lead! - You try.
- Are you having fun?
Where were you?
- Here, Agnes.
Where is di Castro?
- He left because he was tired.
I already said goodbye so we can go.
No, as long as we're winning.
I missed!
Forget about this stupid game.
I have to tell you something.
20 points. - I tell you for the last time.
- I'll throw one more time...
...and then we'll go.
I promise.
It hurts!
- My patience has a limit.You won't play with me...
...like with your own foolish lovers.
- Nobody complained. - How unfortunate!
You won't make a scene.
- It's your turn, Agnes.
I'll do it.
Agnes!
Wait, Adrien calls.
Agnes, don't worry! I'm coming!
A call for you. Mother is calling.
Calm down, don't panic.
What's written in the book?
Pull the control lever.
Slowly.
Slowly, slowly.
Agnes!
Everywhere there's only water.
Man would need a pontoon.
I'll jump.
No, that's not for me.
I thought it over.
Now!
I got him, the devil!
Also a Frenchman? It's a small world.
Where from?
Besancon.
- And they say that we stay only at home.
Where are we going?
- We're going to drink.
More?
- Yes.
You'll like it here. They have everything:
girls, drinks and music.
Paradise, my friend.
True paradise.
Where are these two going?
- The gorillas? - Yes.
They go to Loli, like everyone.
Come, I'll show you.
Do you like her?
This is Lola.
In this golden throat there's a hidden character.
The girl rules the town.
She has a business head.
Drink.
Listen.
Calm down, drink something.
Good luck comes your way.
- With your help.
Help is worthy of gold.
- He's very effective, right?
I know how to choose men.
- The boat is wonderful.
Give me money for the crew.
Your fairy tale is very expensive to me.
- A few more days...
...and I'll repay you a thousand times.
I don't believe you any more.
Things I make for you.
These statuettes are the key to the secret.
And only I discovered it.
Look.
One...
Two...
Three.
The key is in the light.
Listen:
"At the source of the river, the sun melts the rocks".
"And when you enter the holy pit,
the dead light will become alive".
Diamonds, tons of diamonds.
The famous treasure of the Malteks.
Of course.
- You still don't believe me?
I know what it will be when you find the stones.
- I'll give you a half. - And Agnes?
What is she doing here? - Quiet!
- First you kill her father...
...and then you show up with her.
- Only she knew where the statuette was.
You needed her in Rio, not here.
- Enough! Don't mention her anymore.
Never!
- Alright, alright.
He's here?
- What's wrong?
Some Parisian followed us.
- I'll arrange it.
Is there anybody from Paris here?
- Me!
You, right?
- Yes, madam.
It's me.
- Come on, Chita!
You hog!
You from the right, me from the left.
Hey, Manuel!
Could you help me? Thanks.
Don't leave me alone!
Agnes!
You are a monster!
Do you really believe in this?
What do you think?
I'm enchanted!
After the discovery, my work
became appreciated, it's fascinating!
I needed a lot of time.
You don't believe in my secret
and you don't see these beauties.
Besides, you're still in love with this poor Adrien.
Forget him. Come with me!
Together we'll become right and enjoy glory!
I had to use force, it came to that.
What should I do with you?
Could you tell me?
I don't know.
Think about my proposal.
See you tomorrow.
Adrien!
I love you.
And do you?
What me?
We are going to the spring with the boat.
Two come with me, the others not.
That's it. No doubt, we arrived.
Wait. - I can't anymore.
- A few more minutes...
...and this will be the end of my effort.
2, 3, 4...
Here!
Where is Catalan?
Agnes!
Do they still shoot deserters?
- Because I still have two days.
More than enough.
Have you seen Lebel? - No.
- He'll be late.
Run, run! Jump!
Look, what... - Wait. I was running so fast!
Let me catch my breath.
I brought you something. - Nice.
If you would know what I went through.
What happened?
- I walked for three hours, three hours!
From where?
- From home. I've crossed whole Paris.
What an adventure.
Synchronised by
Donlon