-Name.
-Seol-woo Kim.
-Age.
-I was born in 1609. Age, 409 years.
Do you have a girlfriend?
I love...
you.
-What an amusing man.
-My gut feelings are never wrong.
He's dangerous as well.
That's why he's useful.
INTERROGATION IN PROCESS
There are three types of South Korean
secret agents.
White, which operates publicly
with their own names.
Black, which operates nameless
and in the dark.
Then it's Ghost,
which are planted more deeply
with fake identities
and operate discreetly.
I want you to be a Ghost
operating internationally.
What do you say?
-Sure.
-I like how quick you are.
Let me give you a piece of advice
for the first and last time.
Don't trust anyone.
-I don't even trust myself.
-Good.
LOCATION: ITALY, CITIZENSHIP: ARGENTINA
NAME: JULIAN FERNANDEZ MARTINEZ
LOCATION: GERMANY, CITIZENSHIP: SLOVENIA
NAME: ALEXANDRO SERGEEVICH PUSHKIN
GARBO LIEBERT, AGE 65, BUDAPEST, HUNGARY
CHAIRMAN OF GB CONSTRUCTION
ANNA MARIA (ANNA LIEBERT), AGE 21,
ATTENDS BPEST UNIVERSITY IN BUDAPEST
LOCATION: FRANCE, CITIZENSHIP: U.S.A.,
NAME: JAMIE LUCAS
EPISODE 1
If you were in charge of marketing
for the Relief Organization,
which picture would you use?
The picture that shows despair
and reality?
Or the picture with hope and dreams?
Your choice.
Well, I think the picture with
the sad child would get more donations.
So you think we need to use a strong image
to get people to open up their wallets.
Then what about next time? Do the images
have to get stronger and stronger?
-Well, if it's for marketing...
-Do you think that's morally right?
Would you still make the same decision
if you were the family of that child?
Miss Anna Liebert?
Helping someone is more complicated
than you think.
When you're out there, dilemma never ends.
Have we met?
No.
Then how do you know my real name?
No one is supposed to know.
Not even the professors.
There is always a woman behind every case.
Love is a useful deception and tactic
to a secret agent.
However, whereas I am with someone
who is high on the romance,
I feel loneliness and indifference.
Anna Maria. Real name, Anna Liebert.
The only daughter of the mafia boss.
He adores his daughter
and was in the secret police
during the dictatorship.
Inferior races
have their special physical abilities.
Just like a secret police officer
would say.
He won't let me interfere,
since I know his secret.
Do you think so?
He'll remove me
from his daughter's side for sure.
He was with the secret police after all.
I wonder if he'll move as we hope.
People don't change that easily.
I have a guest.
I'll call you when I'm back.
I'm willing to go quietly,
but you probably won't be that nice.
You're the cop.
Who must I be,
if I'm facing off against you?
That's right. You guessed right.
I'm a villain.
The worst there is.
CAPTAIN IRON 2, THE RETURN OF DARK DEATH
You're a villain, but you aren't evil.
So are you really the antagonist?
Hollywood contracts are strict
regarding spoilers.
I understand.
We can't leave out how you rose
to international stardom.
In the Chinese 3D movie in which
you played Wu-jing Sha... There it is.
When The Magical Journey to the West
became a box office hit,
you rose to stardom.
Many are saying
it was an unexpected stroke of luck.
To be clear, I rose to stardom
because I did well.
It was possible because of our agency,
Do-ha Cha's imaginative planning too.
Okay. I understand.
Let's move onto Dark Death,
which was released yesterday.
I would like to know
why you chose a superhero movie.
It was the pay.
Would you like to walk
the Cannes' red carpet?
The movies I liked as a child
had characters who could do
a 540-degree spin kick.
My goodness.
Yes.
Shooting a gun from each hand
with a matchstick in his mouth...
If you're ever in Russia, contact me.
Okay.
-Bye.
petrov has been broken out of prison.
MARCH 15 SQUARE
Lieutenant Eun-oh Ko met with
Major petrov of the Russian Army
and came to an agreement
to share military technologies.
The two armies plan to discuss
the development of weapons
as well as training methods.
When working undercover, how you end it
is more important than how you start it.
I'm going to check
that we're not being followed.
Meet me at the back entrance
in 20 minutes. I love you.
The sympathy of a woman in love is safer
than a bulletproof vest,
but the wrath
of a woman betrayed by her love
is deadlier than a time bomb.
The best way to end a relationship
that has served its use
is death.
November 7th, 11:00 a.m.
Greenwich time. Agent K.
Budapest mission complete.
Please wake up.
I can't move.
I can't move. I just can't move.
You need to get up. It's past seven.
No. I know the time. Your watch is fast.
No. We have to be in Yangsu-ri by nine.
We'll be late even if we leave now.
Hey. If I'm late,
you can just drive faster.
You can go 100km per hour.
Even if I do, we'll be 20 minutes late.
Then go 150km. That means I can sleep
for ten more minutes.
See how quickly I calculated that?
I'm a genius.
I hate the gong.
Croissants from Itaewon Bakery.
A salad with baby greens
and organic apples from Apgujeong Cafe.
Fresh drip Jongro Coffee
made three minutes ago.
Also, here is your dessert.
-What's the dressing?
-I got you oriental dressing.
Jongro Coffee is the best at waking me up.
The cup design looks different.
A branch opened in Hannam.
All the better, now that it's close by.
-Get me Jongro Coffee.
-It is Jongro Coffee.
I want Jongro Coffee from Jongro,
not Jongro Coffee from Hannam.
We don't have time. You have many scenes
to shoot today. If you're any later...
Are you planning to make your actor
skip breakfast?
What if my blood sugar level drops
and I faint?
Also, what if I have to get surgery?
Then the shoot will be delayed even more.
No... the movie will be canceled.
Well, you just got the movie canceled
just because you didn't get
Jongro Coffee from Jongro.
It's just a different color.
Go.
Go!
Hello.
Why are you so late?
I'm sorry. We tried to rush, but...
Sheesh.
-Hello.
GREAT ACTOR, UN-GWANG YEO
What a nice day.
-Hey.
-Hello.
We had to take a detour
because Mr. Yang got lost.
Everyone makes mistakes once in a while,
but he makes them often.
Mr. Yang. Apologize sincerely.
I'm sorry.
In exchange, I'll make sure
not to make any mistakes,
so that we can do it
all in one take, okay?
I'm counting on you.
-I'll have to work really hard.
-Good luck.
I'll repay you for your faith in me.
-Seriously...
-How's your debut preparation going?
-Great, of course.
What you showed me last time was awesome.
Jongro coffee from Jongro.
BIG STAR, UN-GWANG YEO
Come at me!
DELINQUENT BROTHERS
Here. Organic Cheongdam Lemonade.
-Hello.
Is it from Cheongdam?
It's not from Cheongdam Lemonade
in Yeouido, right?
-What are you babbling about?
-I don't know.
Maybe it's because he is an action star.
He's so fit and doesn't he have
a great figure?
He's more beautiful than a flower.
Hey.
-I'm sorry.
-Get your act together!
Hey. It's okay. It's okay.
I'm good at that.
I'm awesome at blocking hits.
Don't let it get you down.
Okay, let's go.
Let's take it from the top.
-From the top.
-Okay.
Here.
How can someone be so perfect?
-A perfect fake.
-He's human.
He is humanity's enemy.
He may be an alien.
My Love From The Star?
-Soo-hyun Kim or Un-gwang?
-Un-gwang, obviously.
-Un-gwang or ten million dollars?
-Definitely the latter.
At least you're not
in critical condition yet.
Un-gwang likes money.
Here he comes.
Why did you skip
the Top Ten Corporations Luncheon
at the Blue House and come here instead?
My promise to my son comes first.
Why did you send your son to a
public school rather than private school?
I want to raise a child who gets
almost everything regarding education.
I will raise him to be a child
who knows how much the bus fare costs
and knows how to share with others.
Some question if you're doing this
because you want to enter politics.
Let me make it clear that politics
is not for me. I'm here as a dad.
There she is.
Hello.
Honey.
-Hi.
-Good job.
Don't smile too much. When Jae-young
comes out, pick him up naturally.
Okay.
Here he comes.
-Honey.
-Mom!
-Come here.
-Did you have fun?
What?
Are you really going to stand against me
and Songsan, Congressman Kim?
You don't belong in the political world.
You took a box home from this room
frequently when my grandfather was around.
Just because he passed away,
did you bury those memories as well?
You make it sound
like I took bribes or something.
Do you have evidence to back that up?
All I did in this room
was eat a few hot meals
that your grandfather had prepared for me.
Then you should accept mine, too.
It's more satisfying
than the Seoul mayoral elections
in which you would come in third
at best anyway.
Your sweet granddaughter is studying
in Chicago, is she not?
-Is that a threat?
-It's a gift.
Goodness.
I don't know about this.
In consideration of my long relationship
with your grandfather,
I will withdraw from the election.
You have no spirit, you filthy pig.
You know people take pictures
at the dining table nowadays, right?
There is a new king,
so there are new rules too.
We've lost touch with Ghost Agent Y.
I think he's been taken out.
Are you saying his cover was blown?
His cover was perfect. He was able to go
deep and gain the trust of those involved
with Songsan's chairman,
Mr. Mo's slush fund.
But they still got him.
That means we have a traitor
on the inside.
Was it Congressman In-soo Baek's
secret organization, the Baek Infantry?
We can't trust anyone on the inside.
I'll call in an international agent.
Do you have someone in mind?
Yes, sir.
Hello. Thank you.
Room service.
What now? What? What is it now?
What are you up to now?
What's with the mustache?
-Is it obvious?
-Yes. Very.
Darn it.
Just go back to being an agent then.
Quit being a prosecutor.
I can't. My wife will kill me.
Then why did you follow me here?
To give you your mission. My mission
is to follow you and manage you.
I'm your commanding officer.
-Me?
-Yes.
-Goodness. I'm on vacation.
-It's urgent, that's why.
Okay. Look. You know the code, right?
Your birthday, 0906.
Half the hotel staff must know.
That's right.
Goodness.
What is it?
I think Agent Yoon's been taken out.
He disappeared
after sending a text message.
Container 8675 to Incheon October 4th.
Look for three wood carvings. Y.
"Look for three wood carvings."
Yes. We're tracking the container
as per the clue he sent.
-What's my new identity?
-We're looking.
Where is the mission?
Somewhere nobody knows you.
Okay. Look here.
-Would you like some?
-I'm fine.
This is the last one.
You must really want some.
-Here.
-There is a way.
Cut. Okay.
-Was that okay?
-Yes, it was good.
-The emotions were good.
-Thank you.
You looked good together.
Next is the kissing scene.
We'll be zooming in,
-so make it hot.
-Okay.
-Stunt team. Get ready.
-Yes, sir.
Let's use a stunt double.
A stunt double?
You said it's a kiss scene.
We should use a stunt double then.
You did all the action scenes yourself
without using a stunt double.
So why do you...
I can hit things with my head
or a car, but not my lips.
I don't do that.
Okay?
I'm speechless.
-It must be true.
-What is?
That he can't kiss actresses.
That feels nice.
Good job for today.
Sure.
I was a bit pissed off earlier,
but it's okay. I understand.
-What?
-Not being able to kiss a woman.
-Me?
-I won't tell anyone,
so don't worry.
-What are you doing?
-Teaching you the facts.
I don't do kissing scenes,
but I'm a good kisser.
My phone.
Who is it?
What? The agency. The agency.
-Hi, Ms. Cha.
-Where are you?
I'm talking to Director Hong
about the movie.
-It's running longer than expected.
-Okay.
You should continue talking,
I'll call you later.
-This isn't right.
-Why? Is something wrong?
I feel like something will happen.
I feel like something big
and ominous is approaching.
What are you talking about?
What is that?
Hey, stop! Stop! Stop!
-What's going on?
-Stop! Hold on. Stop!
-Stop! Hey!
-What's wrong with her?
Stay still.
Hey, Ms. Cha!
What do you think you're doing?
Who is she? She must be crazy.
Hello, Director Hong.
You got a whole bunch of plastic surgery
within those few hours.
She really must be crazy.
Hey, Ms. Cha. First, calm down.
We should talk about it
and resolve it rationally.
You shouldn't resort to violence!
-Whatever.
-What?
I promised you the last time
you got caught, didn't I?
That if I catch you again,
you and I will both die.
But I realized it wouldn't be fair
for me to die,
so I'll just kill you.
Hey. Ms. Cha. Calm down, will you?
Hey. Hey, calm down.
Hey. Hold on. Hold on.
Is she your manager?
-She wouldn't really drop us, would she?
-She could.
She used to be in my fan club.
She's totally capable.
A fangirl? Ms. Cha!
I never made a promise or anything.
-Goodness. Hold on!
-Can't you let me off...
-Please?
-That self-centered witch.
-I ought to just...
Hey!
Hey! Where are we going? Hey.
Hey! Ms. Cha!
I mean it.
We were only talking about the movie.
I said it was Director Hong
in case you got it wrong...
Do-ha. We're not late to a shoot.
Why are you speeding?
You'll blind the drivers on the other side
if you keep the high beam on, Do-ha.
Please calm down. Please.
Fine, I did it. I did. I kissed her.
This old man wasn't thinking.
It's my lips' fault. These wretched lips.
Why are you so extreme?
I know you're in your prime.
A man in his 40s is perfect financially,
physically and professionally.
Love isn't a sin.
Is it?
I guess not.
But a star like you dating is a sin.
You shouldn't have gotten caught.
Do-ha.
Do-ha!
Ever since you went
to Jae-young's kindergarten,
the media has been very favorable.
You have such a good sense.
I've lived my entire life in politics,
but I'm learning from you.
It's thanks to my wife.
She used to be a celebrity,
so she knows what the public wants.
May I have her join my campaign staff
for the mayoral election?
Congressman Kim won't be greedy
any longer.
Thanks to you,
I think this election will go smoothly.
This is the land on Jeju Island.
It should be the amount you mentioned.
If you add it to your campaign fund,
you can write up a receipt, right?
Just kidding. Go ahead and use it.
But no matter how wealthy I am,
I won't keep having money
that I can't get receipts for.
I'll do whatever it takes
to find the missing wood carvings.
They are the details of the slush fund
my grandfather saved for 40 years.
Without them, I have to keep bribing
people like Congressman Kim.
My connections from
the NIS are working on it.
Discreet operations like these
are my specialty.
Please give it your all.
INTERNATIONAL ARRIVALS
ARRIVED
Ghost Agent K has begun tracking it
based on the text message
the missing agent sent.
How interesting.
-A ghost agent. A nameless shadow.
-Right.
-What a great concept.
-It totally is.
But what did K do before?
DOUBLE LIFE (TITLE)
He couldn't have taken a test
to join the NIS.
I don't know.
He's coming, so ask him yourself.
The nameless shadow agent
whom no one has ever seen
-is coming here?
-Yes.
How did you contact the shadow?
I texted him.
I'll call him if it's urgent.
If he doesn't answer, I'll go to him.
You're terrible.
The aim of this movie is to show
the real world of secret agents.
What I'm telling you is real.
-Were you really with NIS?
-I was.
I can't pay you for the scenario
consultation if you keep this up.
Why don't you believe me?
Look. See?
He texted me to meet at 3:00 p.m.
Goodness.
-That's him contacting you?
-Yes.
There he is. Over here.
Introduce yourselves. He is Suk-yoo Kwon,
a director who consults scenarios with me.
This is whom I told you about. Mr. K.
Goodness. Mr. K.
I've heard so much about you.
He's a fraud, so watch yourself.
Okay, then. I'll leave now
and let you two talk.
-Why?
-I'm busy.
Mr. Kwon. Hey. Mr. Kwon.
Damn it.
-Can't you please...
-Have a seat.
Hey. He won't believe me
even if I told him the truth anyway.
I can tell him many times.
He'll say I made it up.
-Where's the first wood carving?
-Yes.
The location of the first wood carving
that we found by tracking the container
is in Russia.
The oil tycoon, Chairman Victor.
The arms dealer
Chairman Victor's secret safe.
But he's so strict about security,
that everything's hidden,
including the location of his house.
What?
You're wondering about the plan?
Of course, we have one.
The fan meeting of Korean star,
Un-gwang Yeo.
A fan meeting?
UN-GWANG YEO
UN-GWANG YEO'S PROFILE
"Name, Un-gwang Yeo. Age 43.
Started as a stunt man
and is now an actor.
He debuted in 2011
in A Detective's Enemy."
UN-GWANG YEO'S PROFILE
JONGRO COFFEE, JONGRO BRANCH
"Jongro Coffee, Jongro branch"?
JONGRO COFFEE, CAFE
Is this in English?
He's a foreigner. It's Chairman Victor's
secret birthday party.
Secret, my ass.
What am I supposed to do at an old man's
birthday party? What are you thinking?
He isn't just any old man.
Victor is a chairman.
He's one of Forbes'
top 30 richest men alive.
That's right.
Someone like that is your fan.
If you go and shake his hand a few times
and take a few pictures with him,
he's going to invest
in some Hollywood movies.
Then will I be the sole lead
in Dark Death?
Yes, if you go and wish Chairman Victor
a happy birthday.
Come on. If an old man asks for a favor,
of course, I should pay my respects.
I haven't lost my humility.
Every single fan is precious.
Look at this. My goodness.
This is very expensive and precious.
It's so warm.
Okay. Then I'll set it up.
-Good boy.
-Yes.
Seriously,
I love how simple you are.
As the lead character in Hollywood...
Of course, you should go.
We'll go with this.
What a nice camera.
I'll only delete Un-gwang's photos.
-Who are you?
I know every reporter. Whom are you with?
You don't want to say who you are,
but you're working hard taking pictures.
You're a paparazzi, aren't you?
Even if he is a celebrity, you can't take
his pictures like this. That's the law.
What is this?
You looked pretty.
I'm dumb, so I want to remember.
If I catch you again, I'll press charges.
No negotiations or settlements.
FORMAT CARD
DELETE ALL FILES?
DELETING
Use a lighter camera.
NOLBOO RESTAURANT
The youth unemployment issue
certainly is a problem.
Young people are making a living
by being a paparazzi.
So you let him go?
You know I hate the authorities.
What's the point in sending him to jail?
He'll just meet bad people
and become an even worse person.
Hey. With a face like this,
you should've gotten his number
and see how things play out.
Even when a man says, "You looked pretty"
to someone he just met?
Exactly. How many men who look like that
would tell you that you look pretty?
Tell me.
NO IMAGES
I'll delete only Un-gwang's photos.
RESTORING DELETED FILES
DELETED FILES RESTORED
RESTORED FILES
RESTORED FILES, PICTURES
Do-ha Cha.
What are you doing? Are you working?
I thought you were taking the day off.
Something was nagging at me,
so I was examining the plan.
What was?
-Who's that?
-Un-gwang Yeo's manager.
There's always a beautiful woman
where there's a plan.
-So what's nagging at you?
-Nothing much.
What is all that?
Manual for Going Undercover
and the movies he was in.
He did these too?
WE DID IT IN SECRET
That one is awesome.
Would you like to walk
the Cannes' red carpet?
Cannes' red carpet? Well, let's see.
The movies I liked as a child
had characters who could do
a 540-degree spin kick.
Or they could send the evil villains
straight to hell.
I liked such spectacular
martial arts movies.
Also, shooting a gun from each hand
with a matchstick in his mouth
and giving his life, his youth,
for justice.
Extreme action romance noir!
Those are the kinds of movies I liked.
I see. You seem very excited
when you talk about movies that you like.
Someone said that before.
Pardon?
I must have wanted to prove
that I could become a Hollywood superhero.
Because I...
am an action actor.
I see. Thank you.
Your passion for action is incredible.
According to next year's lineup
of Hero Comics movies,
there is a movie in which
Dark Death Scorpion...
Hello, madam.
Should I ring up everything
from here to there?
I don't need a lot of clothes.
My body looks better the less I have on.
I see.
You know, right? You're my friend,
but you're quite annoying.
-I haven't seen this before.
-It's this season's main item.
I'm going to make it the main item
in the photo spread with Un-gwang.
A black jacket on Un-gwang.
-You should reconsider.
-Why?
-Don't you think he'll wear it?
-It'll be hard to get him to.
I would like to get fitted
for the evening gown I saw last time.
It's been waiting for you
in the fitting room.
Come with me, madam.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I know you're a busy man.
I'm sure you called because it was urgent.
I had a request to make too.
Why don't you go first?
-Any pictures of the wood carving?
-None.
Is the information on the secret safe in?
Obviously, I have nothing.
How about the floor plan
of Chairman Victor's house?
You must know where the house is, right?
Agent Yoon was very thorough.
He hid it so well
that no one would ever find it.
I'm out.
That's why you need to make sure
his fan meeting works out.
-But look...
-Grab Un-gwang Yeo's hand
and go. That's the only way.
If this falls through, we have no way in.
CHAIRMAN VICTOR
CHAIRMAN OF VIC ENERGY
KOREAN STAR
INVITATION REQUIRED FOR ENTRY.
GUEST LIST
Tug.
-Done.
-Stop that.
Do I look good?
Let's go.
How does your skin look better with time?
I was born this way. What should I wear?
-Come with me.
-Sure.
Mr. Jang!
Let's grab a drink.
Maybe I should've stayed with the NIS.
You're looking good,
now that you are a senior manager.
Why do you keep coming?
You should've just stayed then.
I can't. My wife hates hospitals
and the NIS office the most.
Everyone thinks you retired
and became a prosecutor.
It's suspicious if you keep coming.
This is the safest place.
They can't bug this place either.
Did you find anyone on the list I gave you
that seemed suspicious?
Here. Take a look.
I looked as much as I could
through my prosecutor connections,
but none of them killed Agent Yoon.
We'll have to find Songsan's chairman's
ledger that he hid and look at the names.
By the way, I took care of what you asked.
Okay. Then we'll proceed
with the fan meeting as planned.
My money.
I'll pay you back double the amount
if there's a problem, so don't worry.
Look. There is definitely a hole. But...
-Awesome.
-It's fine, right?
-Incredible.
-That's a real pen.
How did he do that?
There was definitely a hole.
I'll try with a coin this time.
It's gone.
It's back.
It's gone again.
Over here.
-What happened?
-My bad.
-You're so cute.
-Right?
You're definitely not a magician.
You're so super cool.
Isn't that the paparazzi?
-What is this?
-You looked pretty.
He's so persistent.
Did you really come all the way here?
I practiced that so much.
That's so cool.
What's his deal? What is he doing?
Maybe it's a fake bill.
What the...
No, it's real.
Is he a pickpocket?
Why that...
-Amazing. So cool.
-I know.
Hey. Where did that pale,
whatever-looking man go to?
-Did you see him too?
-Isn't he so dreamy?
Isn't he breathtakingly gorgeous?
What the hell?
-He's so cool.
Seriously.
That looks great on you.
The bright color looks good.
Red is my color. You never have to worry
about what color to dress me in.
A strong red is always the answer
for Mr. Yeo.
Right? It looks good to you too, right?
Why is that woman here?
Me? I'm the client.
Songsan took over this brand.
You look good in red as always.
-I won't wear this. I refuse!
-Sweetie, that's not it.
Switch the main item
or I won't do the shoot.
Should I just leave?
I'll pay the penalty. How much is it?
Good. Okay.
Good.
Bravo. Looking great.
It was exactly as you said.
I wondered what you meant
about dressing him in red first,
if I wanted him to wear black.
He'll probably never wear red ever again.
Hey!
Are you okay?
Yes.
-Okay, then.
-Okay.
I've got you. I saw everything.
Well, well.
See? Look at this.
My wallet.
What's going on?
You were a paparazzi last time
and now you're a pickpocket?
-Jung-hye, call the guards.
-Okay.
What's going on?
He stole our staff's wallet.
He's a pickpocket.
That's not all.
Earlier, I saw him taking this.
Yes, this.
This is an entry card
he stole from our stylist.
Also, this passport,
he stole from Mr. Yang.
Let's see. Everything is in here.
This passport belongs to Un-gwang?
Who are you?
Are you his fanboy?
Ms. Cha! What are you doing?
Take your hands off of him!
Sir, he stole Un-gwang's... It hurts!
Let me go.
Hey.
Let...
Damn it.
As you had guessed,
Mr. Yeo's security is terrible.
Yes, well...
I am your head of security as of today.
Okay.
He's the type that Un-gwang hates.
When the VIP is about to be late,
his bodyguard should take care of it.
A bodyguard's top priorities
are the VIP's life and safety.
What kind of a bodyguard makes a bomb?
I'll die and disappear
once this mission is completed anyway.
He acts strange.
What did you misunderstand?
"You looked pretty"?
What he says is strange.
I've got you.
Fire him. Right away.
You're fired.
Subtitles by Netflix
Translated by Jeong