Go ahead and turn your head
a little bit.
I'm going
to clean this off.
And let me just take a look
at it a little bit closer here.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to put
a little bandage on that.
Does this hurt?
I'm fine.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
How you doing, Lyle?
I'm David Monroe.
I'm the staff psychologist here.
Punk.
Did you get your ass kicked?
- No.
- No?
What's that?
Was it cigarettes?
You smoke out, huh?
Yeah. I've done that before.
- Angel dust?
- Never.
Speed? Methamphetamine?
- Crank? 'Shrooms?
- No, no, no.
So, were you high today?
- No.
- Didn't get high today?
Get up.
Fuck off!
You just pissed?
Kind of like
how you feel right now?
It's kind of coming off
of you in waves, Lyle.
Where's my mom?
OK. I'll be back in a second.
What the fuck is this?
Just stay cool
for a minute, Lyle, OK?
Let me explain. You committed
criminal assault today.
No, that's bullshit.
What were going to do right now
is take a trip to the unit.
Now, how you get there
is up to you.
- I'm not fucking crazy.
- I'm not saying that...
but you can walk
with Charlie...
- Mom, what the hell?
- Or they can carry you.
Mom, just tell them
I'm not crazy!
- That's the way it's gonna go.
- Mom!
- Guys...
Come on, just relax.
Come with us.
Come on, chief.
- Hey, fuck you!
- Take it easy!
- Come on!
- Fuck off!
Mom, tell them I'm not crazy!
Mom!
- Mom!
- Sorry, Lyle.
Don't fucking touch me!
Mom!
No! Get off me!
Get off me!
No problem.
Who are you?
Kenny.
Everything OK?
What is that?
It's a medicine pouch
my dad gave me...
to protect me from evil,
bad things.
How old are you?
Almost thirteen.
Why am I fucking shoeless?
We get them back
for recreation.
And so my mom said
we couldn't go downstairs...
and I said, you know,
"Why not? What's the problem?"
You know?
She said, "Oh, well...
"you know, young ladies
don't hang out on the streets...
"at 5:00 in the morning."
So, I was like, "Fuck that,"
you know? "I'm going outside."
And so I went to go outside,
and she grabbed me.
And I said, "I want
to get the fuck out of here."
And she went pfft!
And smacked me across the face.
And, you know, what,
just because she's my mom...
I'm not supposed
to hit her back?
So... you know, I turned around,
and I went crack.
And then, you know,
she threw me into the wall...
and I slammed my head
and fell on the floor.
And she was just like...
Is this the first time that you
and your mother had a fight...
where it became physical?
Yeah. That was the first time
she actually, like, hit me.
- And you hit back?
- And the last time.
- And the last time?
- Yeah.
Why do you say that?
Well, because I don't think
she expected me to hit her back.
You know?
I mean,
an eye for an eye, right?
I mean, if somebody hit you,
you'd hit them back, right?
I have. It hasn't always
solved the problem.
All right, but at that moment,
you're not thinking that.
That's what we're talking about,
though, is, in those moments...
how to, you know,
apply your brain.
I mean, that's why you're here
with us right now, right?
Does that sound like
anything that's happened...
with anybody else
at their house?
- It's happened with everybody.
- Yeah.
You got to stand up
for yourself.
- Parents included.
- Parents are the worst.
You know, I do one little thing
and the motherfucker gets mad.
Next thing I know, I'm in here
with you crazy motherfuckers.
You know what I'm saying?
It's bullshit.
I'll knock a motherfucker out.
I don't give a fuck.
Bitch, I swear to God.
Don't look at me like that.
- Why don't you lick me, dyke?
- You guys. Hey, Mike...
I don't want to hear that
out of your mouth again.
I don't care what
the excuse is, all right?
You all know we have
someone here new with us.
This is Lyle Jensen.
He's going to be here with us.
Just show him the ropes.
Let him know
how we do things here.
Show him your arm.
This is bad-ass.
That shit is nasty.
That's fucking sweet.
- You like it?
- It's fucking gross, yo.
OK, OK. Tracey...
you want to talk to us today?
- I'm Tracey.
- No shit, genius.
Shut the fuck up.
What is wrong with you, OK?
OK, who wants to level drop?
Go ahead, Tracey.
I'm working on my self-esteem.
Thank you, Tracey.
Lyle, you want to try it?
Why are you here?
You want to tell us
why you're here?
Lyle is working on
his anger management.
I heard Lyle got
in a fucked-up fight...
with a baseball bat
and, like, killed some kid.
- Hell, no.
- Yeah, I heard that, too.
That's bullshit. Look at him.
What you weigh,
about a buck twenty?
You had to get a baseball bat?
Did they take your lunch money?
Mike. You want
to talk about it, Lyle?
Big bad-ass fighting machine.
Do you know how close you are
to a level drop, Mike?
You've gotten one
already last week.
You want one this week, too?
Come on, Lyle.
I'll fucking kill you.
Come on. Come on, then.
Get the fuck up.
- Guys.
- Baby.
- Mike.
- All right.
OK. Maybe later.
Give it up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Go ahead.
What?
That's what I thought.
I'm not crazy.
I'm not crazy. I'm...
Here, here, here.
- Traveling. Give it up.
- It went out.
Bullshit. Give me the ball,
you little faggot punk.
- Yo, dude, Mike, relax, dude.
- Are you calling me a liar?
- It hit the fence. It's out.
- Man, give me the fucking ball.
It went the fuck out.
All right,
let's go, little man.
Dudes, dudes, like techs
all over the place. Relax.
Come on.
Fucking relax.
Let's play. Come on.
OK, let's play.
Hey, be cool.
Break it up.
Hey, break it up,
break it up, break it up.
I'm gonna fucking
kill you, bitch!
What the fuck was that, huh?
You want to fight,
let's fucking fight!
- He started it!
- Come on! I don't care!
Fucking bitch shit, huh?
You fuck...
All right. Just chill. Goddamn.
Damn it!
He fucking started it, man.
I don't care who started
this shit, man.
Get up against the...
Get the fuck off!
- Relax.
- Get the fuck off!
Yeah, come in. It's open.
Hey, Lyle,
you mind sitting down?
Did you lock him up?
Yeah. We'll give him
a couple hours to cool off.
Are you going to lock me up?
I wasn't planning on it.
Michael's a big guy.
You're lucky the staff
showed up when they did.
He's a fucking pussy.
How'd you feel
during the fight?
I mean, you must've had
a pretty good rush.
Can I get out of here soon?
You got work to do, Lyle.
You don't think you chose
the actions that caused you...
to be in this room right now
sitting in front of me?
I didn't choose to be here.
You didn't choose to bash
that kid's head in...
with a baseball bat?
Yeah, you can give me the silent
treatment if you want to, and...
you know how to do it.
You're good at it.
I'm sure you've done it before,
and it's worked for you.
Sooner or later, you're going
to have to think about yourself.
There's not much else
to do here.
Lyle jumps up,
flies over to them...
and he's just, like,
boom! Boom! Boom!
Fucked him up, man.
Fucked him up.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the ultimate fighting champion
of the Northwood psycho ward.
That was bad-ass.
Did he bust you down?
Did he give you a drop?
Because I was totally
arguing your case.
Foosball anarchy!
What are you...
Bad-ass.
Rumble!
Get up.
Fuck off!
Get him off me!
Oh, shit!
Fuck! Let me go!
Dude, this one time, a girl
got put into isolation, right?
They juiced her up bad.
But when she woke up,
she was pissed...
and she started
kicking the door, right?
And they didn't even care
at first 'cause, like...
they didn't think
anything of it.
But she just kept kicking
the door and ramming into it...
and she knocked it
off the hinges, dude.
Bullshit.
- It opened, dude.
- No way.
Yeah, dude,
she just ran out.
- Seriously?
- She knocked it off.
Is she, like,
Big Bertha or something?
Do you just cut yourself
for no reason?
No, there's always a reason.
It probably had to be
seventh grade.
I remember.
I was taking a shower.
And I tried O.D.'ing
before that.
I was taking a shower, you know,
just shaving, and I cut...
and I didn't stop.
I just let it keep going
up my leg.
And it was the most relief
I'd ever felt in my life...
and so I just kept cutting
since then.
On your thighs?
I have an anarchy sign
right there.
It looks like someone
branded your leg.
Get back in your room.
Honey, wake up.
Tracey, you're dreaming.
Come on.
OK, you can go.
I got her.
Get back to your room.
All right.
OK, there you go.
There you go.
It's OK to cry.
Mike, do we dare venture
into Mike world?
What's goin' on?
What's up? Why are you here?
Mainly 'cause my dad's a bitch.
What are you workin' on?
I get into fights.
I like to fight. You know?
I like to smoke.
I like to drink.
I smacked this fool
over the head with a bottle...
gave him six stitches.
You don't think you have
anything to work on?
No, other than getting rid
of my parents.
I friggin' have
the responsibility...
of a 20-year-old, but my parents
still cram shit down my throat.
Yeah.
Like, they want to make
me do all these things...
that I shouldn't
be doing at sixteen...
paying bills and shit...
but they still treat me
like a sixteen-year-old...
"Be home at 10:00 at night."
I'm, like...
Kenny.
Yeah?
You want to talk?
Why are you here?
I did stuff
that I shouldn't have done.
Chester the molester.
Shut your big,
fat fucking mouth...
- Why don't you make me?
- I'll fucking make you.
Yeah? Go ahead. Why don't
you get on your knees...
and suck
my motherfuckin' balls?
Get up, motherfucker.
Come on, get up.
Sara, what are you doing?
Come on.
What are you, a pussy? Get up.
I'm not fucking scared.
Go ahead, bitch. Go ahead!
What you gonna do?
What are you,
so fucking tough...
Kenny!
I found out that even though
this kid was only fourteen...
he already tried
to kill himself twice.
That means that...
OK, you're so depressed,
you're gonna kill yourself.
It's, like, yeah,
we've all been there.
But then you actually do it.
Right? You try it... twice.
And you still fuck it up.
You're gonna realize
you're such a loser...
you can't even get it right
on the second try.
Fuck, man.
That's some fucked up shit.
I was happy for the kid
after I heard that shit.
Wake up.
Kenny.
It's Chad.
Tell me you're not naked.
Yeah. What?
Dude, you wanna go
play some ball?
Hey, can you
tell this fuck to get up?
He's fuckin' depressing me.
Nah, he's gonna
be there all day.
You're going, right?
- Yeah.
- Sweet.
Kenny, we're gonna
go play ball.
You want to play?
Hey.
Get up.
Ken, get up!
All right.
I'm gonna count to three...
and if you don't get up...
I'm gonna kill you.
Don't think
I won't do it, either.
One...
two...
Did they tell you?
Did you write
these questions, Dave?
These questions were handed down
to me by Yoda, actually.
Sara?
"How do you deal
with your anger?"
Well, obviously,
not very well.
That's why I'm here, but...
Is there anything that makes you
feel calm when you're angry?
Now it's painting...
that relaxes me.
That's good. That's productive.
Mike?
"If I had a million dollars,
I would..."
Bitches and hos.
I'd buy myself
a big old fat house...
just throw a big-ass party
for me and all my homeboys.
Hope I can come.
Kenny?
"What do I like the best
about myself?"
I don't know.
"What's your favorite word,
and why?"
My favorite word is "why."
The word never ends.
That's what I like about it.
Like, my uncle told me that
I was gonna come back in here.
And I was just, like, "Why?"
And he would say, "Well,
because blah blah blah blah."
And I said, "Why?"
And he said...
"Well, because
this and this and that."
You know? It's just...
there's no answer.
I think it's a fun word.
Yeah, when used properly...
and I bet you get a lot
of mileage out of that.
It's always used properly.
Why?
Fuck you.
Lyle?
"Who is the most important
person in your life?"
I don't really think...
I've met that person yet.
But honestly, I think
it's just as well 'cause...
I mean, I almost hope that...
I almost hope that I never do
meet him 'cause if I do...
I know they'll just
fuck me over.
Lauren?
"What is your family like?"
My family is like people
who live in a hotel.
We don't know anything
about each other.
When we see each other,
we're cordial...
and we say hi,
but that's about it.
Tracey.
"What's the last dream
you can remember...
"and what do you think
it means?"
I was floating
in the ocean...
and it seemed like I'd been
shipwrecked or something...
but there was no other people.
And I couldn't move.
So, it was like
I was an inanimate object.
I was just floating...
with the swirls
of the ocean, and...
the ocean was filling in
the big cavity...
and I just went down with it.
Ended up in this mud slide...
and I just was, like...
part of this massive force.
Tracey, can I talk to you
for a second?
Yeah.
You're still not smoking,
are you?
All right. I'm just
checking on you, man...
because you said you quit.
You know I quit.
You got everything
in your head.
- Don't worry about it.
- I'm not worried about it, man.
- Oh, yeah? How's he doing?
- He's doing all right.
Everybody's angry nowadays.
You OK with this whole
roommate situation?
I mean, it doesn't freak
you out or anything?
It's pretty serious stuff,
actually.
He was in a youth ward
for a while...
and they had
to transfer him here.
Wandering hands,
you know what I'm saying?
Lyle? You up?
Yeah.
Do you like The Undertaker?
What, the wrestler?
He's the...
the scary one, right?
Like, the goth dude?
That's who he used to be.
Then he changed.
I think he's, like,
a Harley guy now.
Yeah.
Boys.
How's everybody feeling today?
Anything I can do for you guys?
Damn. The whole fucking bottle?
Did you pass out?
No, I just started hooking up
with this guy I didn't know.
Open up.
Let's see, Chad.
Open.
I didn't even like him.
So, why did you fuck him
if you didn't like him?
Chad. Open your mouth, Chad.
That's a good job.
This place sucks ass.
It's, like,
ignorance is bliss...
and this place
is fucking Disneyland.
What do you listen to?
Slipknot, Korn.
I like some punk, though.
I like Minor Threat. Right?
I hate ravers.
I can never go to those things.
Man, they're all this tall
and have really big clothes on.
That's one of the best
fucking shows I've ever seen.
Zach was, like,
going off, man.
Were you in the pit?
Were you in there?
I've never seen a pit like that.
I saw people putting
mouth guards in...
before that show started.
I was just, like,
"Yeah, man, that's L.A.!"
You know?
Rage Against the Machine show.
You know what
I'm talking about, right?
Those big, huge pacifiers
they have around their neck.
They look like idiots. I swear.
That was, like,
the baddest ending.
Everybody was thinking they were
gonna do "Freedom" last.
And then they did
"New Years Day"...
and it was, like...
God, people were just
getting nuts, man.
Like that end part, right?
With the guitar, right?
And it's...
The place was just, like...
It was so fucking...
Dude, I'd be so fucking dead
without music.
Man, I miss getting high.
I would rather feel like
total shit sometimes...
and God the rest of the time...
than just, like, OK
all the time, you know?
Fuck mediocrity.
So, what, your parents
make you come here?
No, I don't live
with my parents.
My dad's gone, and my mom
has the same thing I do.
She's, like, fucked up,
manic-depressive, agoraphobic.
Right?
All right?
Yeah, go ahead.
Like, I live with
my uncle now...
Uncle Cole.
He's, like, this
fucking rich asshole.
He has all this money
and no kids...
so he thinks if he puts me
in here enough...
it'll fix whatever's broken...
'cause he doesn't want some
freak inheriting all his money.
What?
You're inheriting
a bunch of money from him?
How much?
Like what, a million dollars?
Yeah, something like that.
I don't know.
I can't believe
you're fucking rich, man.
We could fucking
take that money...
and just get the fuck
out of here.
You're so fucking stoned.
No, I'm serious.
Just... you and me
just, like, go...
travel the world.
I don't know.
Just get the fuck
away from here...
and get away from, like...
my mom and your uncle, right?
Go to Europe, right?
Dude, you and me
could go to Europe.
We could go to fucking Paris...
and just fuck hookers
or something.
Go to Amsterdam.
Dude, you know how fucking cool
it'd be to live in Amsterdam?
Just wake up,
do whatever you want.
No one to tell you
any kind of bullshit.
It's, like...
This shit's legal there.
Did you know that?
You can just go to cafes
on the street and buy it.
Go there and, like...
and have, like,
a real life, you know?
Are you scared?
No.
Then why not?
OK. Fine.
You mean, go live in Europe?
- Yeah.
- Fuck, yeah!
What?
- Nothing.
- Dude...
why are you smiling like that?
Are you fucking lying?
I turn eighteen next week,
you know?
I get a good chunk
of my trust fund.
Like, a hundred grand, dude.
No bullshit.
A hundred grand.
Don't fucking
tell anybody that.
OK.
Jesus. Put that in here.
We got to get out of here.
It's community music hour.
I hate that fucking song.
Shut the fuck up, bitch!
These just came.
Look at those. They're pretty.
She's not even here anymore.
Hey, Chad?
What's goin' on?
Did you take your meds today?
I definitely think that
Amsterdam is the way to go.
We can live there cheap,
stay there until we get bored...
and then move on, right?
Hey, I'm using that.
Do you like it?
Yeah, I do. Yeah.
They need a credit card.
1973...
1737...
The name on the card
is Cole Merritt.
What are you drawing?
It's this guy on a cross.
Is his name Jesus?
No.
It's not Jesus. See? He's got
all that hair on his chest.
Jesus didn't have
any hair on his chest.
She makes me wear really big
clothes and sweaters and stuff.
It's so fucked up.
I mean,
she's your mother, right?
It's not a competition.
You know, Calabasas is full
of fucking JAPs...
and little daddy's girls.
I didn't exactly have
the debutante thing goin' on.
One day I saw her at McDonald's
with the nose job crew.
Amsterdam.
That was before I knew my place,
so I sat down.
My friend rolls her eyes,
and she says, "What?
"You actually think
you're good-Iooking?
"'Cause you walk around
like you're all hot...
"and you're really not."
Then the whole table
started to laugh.
And I cried
for about three days...
and then I fuckin' resurrect.
You know?
I just realized that everyone
I knew was fucking full of shit.
And that's when I started
doing whatever I wanted...
and not giving a flying fuck
what people thought.
Fuck!
So I don't really have
any friends.
I don't need any.
We're friends.
Yeah.
That's the stupidest thing
I've ever heard in my life.
Don't fucking call me stupid.
I didn't say
you were stupid, butch.
I said your opinion was stupid,
because it is.
Wolverine has got steel plates
in his bones...
So what?!
And Batman has just
a little fucking belt...
and a little fucking cape.
What the hell
is he gonna do with that?
Batman is so much smarter...
and so much more intelligent
a fighter...
Who gives a fuck?
He knows eight different
martial arts.
He's, like, a ninja.
- Batman is a fucking homo.
- Batman is not a homo!
Batman bangs the hottest chicks
in Gotham City left and right.
He's a player!
Superman could
take them all down.
Really.
You all need
to check your heads.
Shut up.
Hold it. I think that Lyle
brings up a good point.
Let's talk about this logically
for a second, OK?
Now, Batman is
an intelligent cat. No doubt.
And he is a damn good fighter.
I'll give you that.
But he's just human.
- Oh, my God.
- Wait a minute. Let me finish.
Now, Wolverine is a flat-out
animal when he fights...
and he's got the skills
to pay the bills.
He's got unbreakable
adamantium bones...
razor-sharp retractable
adamantium claws...
he's got mutant healing powers.
He's a bad-ass.
No doubt. He would kill Batman.
I'm sorry. Every time.
But, in a straight-up brawl,
Sara, toe to toe...
you know who's gonna
take home all the cookies...
if Superman's involved.
It's gonna be the big blue
boy scout every time.
No doubt. He would tear
Wolverine's head off...
he would tear
Batman's head off...
and use them
like ka-nick-ka-nacks.
These guys aren't even real.
What the fuck? God!
OK, OK. Well,
let's jump into reality, then.
You want to talk about reality?
Let's talk about real fights.
Yeah. Hell, yeah.
Oh, you like that?
- Yeah, dawg.
- Why?
I don't know. It's kinda
like fucking, you know?
It's just fun.
It's fun?
What's so fun about it?
I can't explain it, y'all.
You know, or you don't.
I guess that's fair enough.
What do you think
about fights, Lyle?
I think you're an expert
on the subject.
He's totally an expert.
Just ask that kid
from his school, man.
- 52 stitches, broken arm...
- Shut the fuck up, man.
Jaw's wired shut.
Might never see...
Hey! Shut the fuck up.
You want to talk about it?
There's nothing to say.
You certainly had something
to say on that day.
Don't you think
that's why you're here?
I don't know why I'm here.
You tell me,
'cause I feel fine.
Please. If you were fine,
you wouldn't be sitting here.
Why don't you just
tell us what happened...
so we can stop assuming?
I mean, what...
did you just freak out?
It's not a big deal.
I did that one time.
I took a hammer...
and I smashed all the windows
on the minivan.
No, I had a reason. I don't
just do shit for no reason.
What was your reason?
It's none of your
fucking business.
You know, I sure can't
make you tell me, Lyle...
but I would really
like to know...
what you think justifies
hurting someone...
to the point where
you almost kill them.
I'm just curious
how someone...
as seemingly
intelligent as you...
could hurt another
human being that bad...
and have no remorse
for it whatsoever.
He deserved it.
Well, I bet Chris Woods
would say it differently...
if his jaw wasn't wired shut.
What did he say?
He said something mean.
My dad beat me up a few times
when I was a kid.
And this guy Chris
knew about it.
He thought
it was really funny.
Now he doesn't think
it's so funny.
If you say you wouldn't
do the same thing...
you're fucking lying.
Or just a pussy.
Do you remember your dad, Lyle?
Yeah.
How did you feel about him?
Did you love him?
He was my dad.
No feeling
one way or the other?
Just a genetic bond?
My mom never hits me.
She just is always saying...
really, really
horrible things to me.
It sounds kind of stupid
next to Lyle's, but...
if anyone said
anything about it...
I'd want to hurt them, too.
That's not stupid.
Go ahead.
Say more about that, Tracey.
She tells me how stupid I am,
how I'm a slut...
and she wishes I wasn't born.
Anyways, I kind of understand
what Lyle means.
It's really none of
anybody else's business.
I wasn't sure if that was a bird
or that crazy dude over there.
That guy is insane.
That's what they say
about all of us though.
What happens to you at night?
It's like I'm...
surrounded with...
badness, like in a war
or something.
In here?
It happens everywhere.
Did you get raped?
If you ever want someone
to kill him, I'll do it.
Thanks.
I'm scared of you sometimes.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, it makes a lot of sense.
I'm scared of myself sometimes.
This one time,
my mom and I were in a fight.
And we were just yelling
at each other, and, like...
she was standing
with her back...
to a cabinet in the kitchen.
And I just...
I kind of like
punched through it.
You know, beside her.
I didn't want to do that.
Then she started crying.
She said,
"You look just like him."
I'm not.
It's OK.
I'll never hurt you.
Then, boom... I'm just standing
right in front of myself...
except it's not totally me.
And I look down...
and I'm holding,
like, this bad-ass knife,
and it's all, like,
sharp and everything...
and clean.
I can, like, see myself in it.
And all of the sudden,
like, Chad 2 turns around...
and takes off running,
so I take off after him.
And then I get him,
and I fucking jump on him...
and I pounce on his ass, and
I get him down on the ground.
And now he's got a knife, too,
so I'm just like...
And there's fucking blood
all over the place.
And he smiles at me.
And all the blood
goes back in his body...
and all the stab wounds,
like, all close up and shit.
He gives me a second
to catch my breath...
takes off running again,
so I go after him again...
stab him, like, 200 times.
The cuts all close up,
blood all goes away.
I just know it's going
to go on forever.
That's it.
What do you guys
think it means?
I think it means Chad needs
to be on 24-hour watch.
It means your shit
is fucked up, yo.
No, that's not what it means.
What does it mean, Lyle?
It means nothing changes.
Lyle, things change
all the time.
Yeah. When you have a problem,
you fix it.
Then you get another problem.
You fix that.
Then another problem.
It's like this place,
you know what I'm saying?
You get out, you come back.
It's true. The same shit just
keeps happening over and over...
and then we die.
That's just the way it is.
Is that the consensus?
OK, look, let's cut to it.
I want each of you to tell me
something right now...
that gives your life meaning.
Something that excites you,
that turns you on...
that you find value in.
Anything but drugs...
I don't want to hear
any drug stories.
Anybody can jump in.
Sara, please help me out.
I'm dying over here.
Freedom.
Doing whatever you want and not
giving a fuck what people think.
OK.
I play Playstation.
Any particular game you like?
I like "Resident Evil 2."
Anything where you can use
your imagination, right?
That could give
your life meaning.
Just keeping it real,
you know what I'm saying?
Looking out for my boys...
and fucking up punks
who get in the way.
So, friendship, camaraderie.
Yeah.
Or love.
Love? Thank you, Tracey.
Boom. OK?
Love. That's very important.
- Sex is meaningful.
- You've had sex?
What about you, Lyle?
What gives your life meaning?
I don't know.
So, what kind of progress do
you feel you've made since you...
Come on, man, give me a break.
You know I got to ask this.
I've learned how to jerk off
with little or no privacy.
So, Sara,
what kind of progress...
do you feel you've made
since you've been here?
Fine progress.
Big Mike.
- My nigga.
- What's going on?
So, what kind of progress
do you think you've made...
since you've been here, buddy?
Just bangin', yo.
You're going to turn eighteen
in a couple days.
That means you're going to be
responsible for yourself...
more or less.
- How do you feel about that?
- Great.
Is this what you think
being black is, Michael?
Wearing baggy clothes and
talking a lot of shit...
fucking up?
Can I get out of here
this week or what?
You getting along
with Lyle OK?
So, what kind of progress
do you think you've made...
since you've been here, Lyle?
Well, I'm recommending
that you go home Friday.
Good.
So, what kind of progress
do you think you've made...
since you've been here?
None whatsoever.
So, what, you think
you're the only one...
who's ever been
fucking depressed?
Look, this is freedom.
See these birds?
They're flying away.
I mean, look at the color.
How can you call it suicidal?
Because he killed himself
right after he painted it.
You have no idea
of the kind of color...
that can come out
of depression.
All the great artists
are fucked up.
Boo-fucking-hoo.
Look at the birds.
Look at the sky.
Look at the yellows.
This painting, it has borders.
It ends here, here,
here, and here.
All paintings are like that.
So what?
You're just seeing what
you wanna see, and that's it.
That road is going nowhere.
Lyle?
Yeah. What's up?
Does your dad buy you
a lot of things?
My dad's dead.
Do you have a stepdad?
Why?
My stepdad's coming tomorrow.
Oh, yeah?
Is he cool?
He buys me stuff sometimes.
I'm getting Playstation 2.
Cool, cool.
My dad...
Well, I broke my arm
pretty badly...
and I had to go to the hospital
for a few days.
He came and picked me up.
And...
he drove me right to the bike
store and got me a bike.
What kind of bike was it?
It was a Mongoose BMX.
It was a cool bike.
There was this one day I got
on it and just kept going...
riding on it
till I got to the beach.
The bike had this squeak
in the chain...
that was really annoying.
I was just listening to
the squeak the whole trip.
When I got to the beach...
I was just cruising along,
like, looking at the ocean.
The squeak...
it kept getting louder.
And I just got off the bike...
and I smashed it
into a street lamp.
Broke the shit out of it.
Kenny.
Have a seat.
As you know,
this meeting today...
is so that
your stepdad can see...
what kind of progress
you've been making...
and see how close you are
to actually going home.
You do wanna go home,
don't you, pal?
You know, your mother and I
have been thinking.
We'd like to take you
up to Pine Bluff...
maybe do a little waterskiing.
Can I wake board?
Absolutely.
OK, I'm gonna
leave you two alone.
Kenny, I'll be right outside
the door if you need anything.
Dave?
Yeah.
What's going on?
You wanna tell me something?
Is there something
you wanna say to your stepdad...
while I'm still in the room?
Can I talk to you outside
in the hallway for a moment?
I spent a lot of fucking
money on this place.
Mr. Jenkins, please.
I think it would be best
if we talk outside.
I would at least like to be able
to talk to my son.
I appreciate that...
and I would like for that
to happen as well...
but this may not be
the proper time for...
- What do you people do here?
- Mr. Jenkins...
Look at him. Is this
what you call mental health?
- I've took him out of a bad...
- Mr. Jenkins!
I believe
I've made a mistake...
so let's do this
at another time.
Would you please
accompany me to my office?
Fine.
It's just not the day for it.
Sorry, Dad.
Mr. Jenkins.
Mr. Jenkins!
- Mr. Jenkins!
- Let go!
Get off of him! Come here!
Get off me...
get out of here!
Go on, get out of here
right now!
Get out of here right now.
Get off the premises.
Get off the premises right now!
Kenny?
He's gone, OK, Kenny?
He's gone.
Hey.
I'm really sorry.
What are you sorry for?
Just, like,
about Kenny and all.
Yeah?
Why are you sorry about that?
Are you his dad?
Did you rape him?
- I'm just sorry.
- That's a stupid thing to say.
Sorry doesn't mean anything.
You think sorry
means anything at all?
You think it does anything?
Are you that fucking stupid,
you think sorry does anything?
No.
Maybe if you got
some fucking sleep at night...
instead of screaming...
you'd realize that everything
is just fucked...
and sorry doesn't mean anything!
Sorry doesn't mean shit!
It doesn't mean fucking shit!
What do you think about that?
Answer me! I said,
what do you think about that?
I said what the fuck do you
think about that? Answer me!
Well, you all know
what happened with Kenny.
You probably have
some strong opinions...
emotions about it, so...
as always, this is
the place to air them.
How the hell are we supposed
to trust you guys...
when shit like this happens?
That's a valid question.
All I can say
is that sometimes...
things happen
that are beyond our control.
So, where is he?
He's in another wing
of the hospital.
He's being taken care of.
You didn't have
to let his dad in.
Well, it obviously went about
as badly as it could've gone.
No shit.
Just shut up, Lyle.
It's not his fault.
It's OK. Lyle can be upset.
It's all right.
Kenny's a sweet guy. It hurts.
He never hurt anybody.
Nigga, please. He used to fuck
around with little kids, yo.
That's just payback,
you know what I'm saying?
No, Lyle, no! Wait a minute!
No! Stop! No! Mike! Mike!
- Let go. I got him.
- No, no. Sit down. Sit down!
Sit down right now, Lyle!
OK. Do you feel better now?
Did you fix Kenny now?
Is Kenny all better now?
How about you,
you all better now?
Do you think you're the only
one who gets pissed off...
and wants to fucking rage?
I can break shit.
I can scream
like a motherfucker!
All day long!
Now what?
Kenny's still fucked up,
and I'm still miserable.
I guess I gotta
break some more shit.
Get up, Lyle.
Get up right now, Lyle. Get up!
OK?
Didn't work.
I'm still pissed off.
Maybe I need to fuck
something else up now, huh?
Maybe I need to punch somebody
in the fucking face!
Is that the solution?
No, that ain't
the solution, man.
So what do I do?
I just get on
with my fucking life...
and I try to make
something of it.
Why are you here, man?
Why are you alive?
Do you want to be alive?
Life is a struggle, Lyle.
That's it.
It's a struggle.
That's the way it fucking is.
Can you handle that?
Can you handle that, Lyle?
I'm gonna be in my office.
You guys sit here
and figure out why you're here.
Who wants some?
There's one player.
Aw, yeah.
That's a good block.
Oh, good pass!
Good pass.
It don't get
no sweeter than that.
Yeah, Mike.
It was on the way down.
All right, first of ten,
by one. Peace.
Since y'all like to bang bodies.
No fouls.
Time, time, time...
Go ahead, man.
Work it out.
Yo, Braveheart, can we play?
Play. Play the game.
Shit. What? Man. Good job.
Yeah!
I got Lyle, you got Chad.
Let's do this.
That's not legal.
What the fuck's
wrong with you, man?
wrong with you?
Give me some!
Great game, tough guy.
Sorry about that.
It's all right.
It was a good day
today, huh? Fun?
I had fun.
Sorry I freaked out on you, man.
That wasn't cool.
It's fine.
So, you still think you're ready
to walk out of here at any time?
Yeah.
Well, what was that
in group today?
You're so full of shit.
You wanted to hit him, too.
That's totally
irrelevant, Lyle.
Everybody wanted to smack him
upside the head, but you did it.
He deserved it.
No. Fuck that, man. Come on.
The way your dad treated you,
did you deserve that?
That was different.
'Cause the people
that you beat deserve it?
Lyle, what about you?
You burn yourself
with cigarettes.
You cut yourself.
You slam your head into walls.
We both know
you don't deserve that, man.
Lyle, wherever you're going,
you are still gonna be there.
Then what?
What am I supposed to do?
Come sit down.
No.
Lyle, I'm not gonna give you
some hokey bullshit speech...
and tell you that if you come to
some epiphany about your dad...
you're gonna make
a breakthrough...
and everything's gonna be
pizzas and blow jobs.
Because the fact
of the matter is...
it's quite possible that
you're gonna have this rage...
within you somewhere
until you die, man.
Either you're gonna learn
how to live with it...
or you're just gonna go on
like you've been doing...
until you kill yourself
or kill somebody else...
maybe somebody
that you care about.
It'd be like couples that got,
you know, hooked up...
and they've been together.
No techs, no nurses or anything
in the whole place...
and so all the kids
are going crazy...
and all the little couples
are sitting there making out...
while they have the chance
and everything...
'cause there's
no one around watching.
At Vista, they had,
like, little sensors...
they put in the halls,
so if you opened your door...
it went, like...
and you couldn't
get out of the room.
When I was at Vista,
this girl...
her friends snuck in a lighter,
and, at 2:00 in the morning...
she went by one of the doors,
and she lit the match.
And the fire escape went off,
and the doors unlocked...
and she got out.
Chad, do you remember
how you were feeling...
when your uncle admitted you
in the hospital?
I do.
And I don't wanna see you going
through that same thing again.
Tegretol or Depakote?
Same program. Tegretol.
Just give me pills, right?
And that'll just
take care of everything...
and just solve
all my problems...
and all the problems
of the world.
Give everybody pills.
We can all fucking be
the exact same person.
This is
a treatable disorder, OK?
But not if
you don't want it to be.
Come on.
It's not up to debate.
You're taking your meds.
That's it.
All right.
Blow them out.
Make a wish, man.
What about that one?
You gonna blow that one out?
It's still lit.
Go on and try it again.
- Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday, Chad.
Happy birthday.
Here you go, man.
Tracey, you gotta
let her go, honey.
You got my number, right?
- Yeah.
- OK.
Take care of yourself.
Bye.
OK.
It's OK, Tracey.
You'll be OK.
OK?
Happy birthday.
You all right, man?
Yeah, man.
Thirteen blackbirds
baked in a pie
Baked in a pie,
So, we're still cool, right?
You and me?
What do you mean?
Are you talking about the trip?
'Cause the thing is,
dude, like...
who gives a fuck
about Amsterdam, you know?
What are you talking about?
I mean, do you think
that's gonna change anything?
Do you really think that's gonna
make things any different?
I mean, what are you
gonna be doing?
You're gonna be
breathing different air?
eating different food?
Of course there's a difference.
Here you wake up
in a fucking bullshit place.
You can't go anywhere.
You're trapped here.
This is fucking hell, man.
So what, then,
you're gonna go over there...
and then everything
is gonna be cool?
Even if you are as happy
as you could possibly be...
pretty soon you gotta
let go of it all...
because that's just
what happens.
What?
Come on.
Why don't you just go, man?
It's a gift, man. Just go.
Thirteen blackbirds
baked in a pie
We're going, you and me.
You and me are going.
So...
guess what?
I ain't getting released
this week.
You want to know why?
Because you suck cock.
Think you're pretty
fucking funny, don't you?
You and Chad, you think
you're pretty fucking funny.
I ain't getting released
because of your punk ass.
If we were outside,
I'd just bust a cap in your ass.
Game.
But now I'm stuck in here
for another week.
Nigga, I should
kill you right now!
Do it.
Come on.
Just you and me, yo.
No little faggot friends
to help you, huh?
Suck that.
Hey, where you going?
Come on.
It's just me and me in here.
That's what I thought. Pussy.
What are you doing?
Reading.
No, this.
What are you doing with this?
Don't touch me.
Cut this shit out, man.
You're gonna blow everything.
Blow what?
I'm gonna be dead in 60 years,
and so are you.
That's stupid, man.
You're getting
out of here tomorrow.
out of here tomorrow...
and you're gonna
fuck everything up now?
Leave.
That's fine, but you know that
it doesn't have to be that way.
Guys.
I'm sorry.
It's your choice.
Fuck you, then.
Chad's all fucked up.
He's cutting on his arm.
Oh, my God.
Hey, buddy.
How we feeling today, huh?
It looks like you're
having a bummer of a day.
I'd hate for you
to leave us like that, man.
Chad?
Anything I can do for you?
You can admit that you hate us.
Maybe you need
a little time alone, Chad.
Good.
Jesus Christ!
Get J.C. right now!
Get the fuck off!
Charlie, Charlie!
Come on, go outside!
Go outside!
Get out of here!
Go! Charlie, go!
Get the fuck off me!
Chad.
You don't wanna do this.
- Chad.
- Fuck!
Chad.
How we doing today, Charlie?
You seem to be having
a down day.
Chad, don't...
OK.
Chad, look at me.
Don't do that, OK?
What's going on?
Chad, talk to me.
Chad, wait a minute.
Chad, Chad.
Chad... don't.
Don't!
Chad!
Oh, God.
Oh, shit.
Charlie, hold on.
Tracey, wake up.
It's just me.
OK, I'm sorry.
Are you cold?
A little bit.
Did you see it?
Fucking Chad.
There's ten...
and I'm out.
What you got in your hand?
That's the game.
Let's go again, man.
You plan on going home tonight?
You know,
if I get in that car...
I'm not gonna stop
until I run out of gas, man.
He almost cut
his head off, man.
On my watch.
It was my watch, too.
Well, we fucked up today.
That kid wasn't taking
his medication.
Did we know that?
It wasn't your fault.
You're good at this job, man.
What's up?
How you been?
Wake up.
I can't stay long.
I just wanted to
stop by and say hey...
see how you're doing.
So I'm gonna take off.
I'm going to Europe...
Amsterdam.
It should be
pretty cool, right?
Ken!
Kenny!
Dude, I know you can hear me.
I can tell.
I can tell you can hear me.
All right.
I'm going to count
to three, OK?
And if you don't say
something to me...
by the time I get to three...
I'm going to kill you.
One...
two...
two and a half...
I brought you something.
Come on, dude, I know
you were looking for this.
I'm sorry.
I'll see you again, OK?
Hey, have you seen Tracey?
Naw, dog.
You rape that
screaming ass bitch yet?
You know she wants some.
I was just looking for you.