1
00:00:19,228 --> 00:00:21,771
(FOOTSTEPS)

2
00:00:49,216 --> 00:00:50,425
MAN: Li!

3
00:00:54,096 --> 00:00:56,723
Hello!

4
00:00:56,807 --> 00:01:00,476
Ni hao. Welcome to America.

5
00:01:00,561 --> 00:01:02,228
Oh, it's so wonderful
to see you.

6
00:01:02,312 --> 00:01:04,188
- You alright?
- Yes. Yes.

7
00:01:04,273 --> 00:01:07,024
Yeah? I've got some people
for you to meet.

8
00:01:07,025 --> 00:01:08,443
This is Cynthia Dodds.

9
00:01:08,527 --> 00:01:10,111
She's the general manager
Of the company.

10
00:01:10,195 --> 00:01:11,779
Pleased to meet you, Li.

11
00:01:11,864 --> 00:01:14,031
And Mason Daniels.
He's on our board.

12
00:01:14,116 --> 00:01:16,117
Howdy! Welcome to Houston.

13
00:01:16,201 --> 00:01:18,578
And Betty Lou Bayless.

14
00:01:18,662 --> 00:01:21,122
It's lovely to meet you,
young man.

15
00:01:21,206 --> 00:01:22,623
- And Lori Lawley.
- Hi, Li.

16
00:01:22,708 --> 00:01:24,208
I've heard so much
about you from Ben.

17
00:01:24,293 --> 00:01:25,710
Lori's one of our
principal dancers.

18
00:01:25,794 --> 00:01:27,670
- This is my husband, Dilworth.
- 'Knee-how', Li.

19
00:01:27,755 --> 00:01:30,006
Welcome to Houston,
home of the Oilers.

20
00:01:46,190 --> 00:01:48,649
Li: Upon my soul.

21
00:01:48,734 --> 00:01:50,985
Have you been learning English, Li?

22
00:01:51,069 --> 00:01:54,447
Oh, yes, Ben.

23
00:01:54,531 --> 00:01:58,409
- I learn from this.
- Oh, fantastic!

24
00:01:58,494 --> 00:02:01,954
- Uh, 'fantas... '
- Fantastic. Fantastic.

25
00:02:02,039 --> 00:02:05,249
It means wonderful,
very good, great.

26
00:02:05,334 --> 00:02:07,043
Oh.

27
00:02:10,631 --> 00:02:13,090
Fantastic.

28
00:02:33,862 --> 00:02:36,197
Big... big house, Ben.

29
00:02:36,281 --> 00:02:38,699
Um... you have a big family?

30
00:02:38,784 --> 00:02:40,868
No, no, it's just me.

31
00:02:40,953 --> 00:02:43,329
And this is your room.

32
00:02:53,841 --> 00:02:54,757
Alright?

33
00:02:54,842 --> 00:02:58,886
Um... this all me?

34
00:02:58,971 --> 00:03:00,513
Yes, it's all yours.

35
00:03:06,937 --> 00:03:09,397
(CHILDREN SHOUT)

36
00:03:40,804 --> 00:03:42,346
Yaaa!

37
00:04:25,974 --> 00:04:27,391
(TEACHER SHOUTS
IN CHINESE)

38
00:05:46,054 --> 00:05:49,306
(BOYS SHOUT)

39
00:06:43,361 --> 00:06:45,738
- You get settled alright?
- Yes.

40
00:06:45,822 --> 00:06:49,241
Oh, God, we really must do something
about that suit.

41
00:06:49,326 --> 00:06:52,078
It's me, Ben.

42
00:06:52,162 --> 00:06:53,996
Yes, that's you.

43
00:06:54,081 --> 00:06:55,873
Bobby's around. You'll see him.

44
00:06:55,957 --> 00:06:59,502
But Mary, alas,
has gone back to Australia.

45
00:07:00,670 --> 00:07:03,714
Uh... niang, dia?

46
00:07:03,799 --> 00:07:07,343
Um... mother... um, father?

47
00:07:07,427 --> 00:07:11,597
Oh, no. That's Vice President Bush
and his wife, Barbara.

48
00:07:11,681 --> 00:07:13,557
She's patron of
the Houston ballet.

49
00:07:13,642 --> 00:07:15,184
Would you like a muffin?

50
00:07:15,268 --> 00:07:18,062
Mu... muffin?

51
00:07:18,146 --> 00:07:19,230
Yeah.

52
00:07:19,314 --> 00:07:23,901
Um... horse... horse...
m... muffin?

53
00:07:23,985 --> 00:07:26,403
Crap? Shit? Horse...
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)

54
00:07:26,404 --> 00:07:27,404
Horse shit?

55
00:07:27,405 --> 00:07:28,656
Yes. Yeah.

56
00:07:28,740 --> 00:07:30,074
No!

57
00:07:30,158 --> 00:07:31,826
This is a muffin.

58
00:07:32,869 --> 00:07:33,994
Here.

59
00:07:43,713 --> 00:07:46,966
BEN: It's Gershwin, guys.
You've got to feel it.

60
00:07:47,050 --> 00:07:48,717
Just invest a little more.

61
00:07:48,802 --> 00:07:51,178
Li, you're doing fine.
You'll pick it up. It's alright.

62
00:07:51,263 --> 00:07:54,723
And... slow plié.

63
00:07:54,808 --> 00:07:59,353
And stretch it out, right?

64
00:07:59,437 --> 00:08:01,147
And... up with the accent.

65
00:08:01,231 --> 00:08:02,773
Up with the accent.

66
00:08:02,858 --> 00:08:06,026
Up, and down on the floor.

67
00:08:06,111 --> 00:08:08,362
Lovely. Hold.

68
00:08:08,446 --> 00:08:10,239
And hold.

69
00:08:10,323 --> 00:08:11,282
Alright.

70
00:08:13,910 --> 00:08:15,494
That's alright.

71
00:08:15,579 --> 00:08:18,539
Incredible physique.

72
00:08:18,623 --> 00:08:20,958
If you do say so yourself.

73
00:08:28,925 --> 00:08:31,719
CHILD: Some brown ones?

74
00:08:31,803 --> 00:08:33,512
MOTHER: OK, one last one
and that's enough.

75
00:08:45,609 --> 00:08:47,067
Let's see.

76
00:09:06,546 --> 00:09:08,672
(RINGS BUZZER)

77
00:10:29,504 --> 00:10:33,632
(BICYCLE BELLS CHIME)
(PEOPLE SHOUT)

78
00:10:39,514 --> 00:10:42,474
(ROUSING MARTIAL MUSIC PLAYS)

79
00:12:48,309 --> 00:12:51,270
(GENERATOR RATTLES)

80
00:13:06,327 --> 00:13:08,745
(GENERATOR SPUTTERS)

81
00:13:59,172 --> 00:14:02,591
(FIREWORKS POP)

82
00:14:02,675 --> 00:14:05,636
(DRUMS PLAY)

83
00:15:34,642 --> 00:15:37,603
(TELEVISION PLAYS
IN BACKGROUND)

84
00:15:53,369 --> 00:15:55,078
What's wrong?

85
00:15:56,873 --> 00:15:58,373
Hmm.

86
00:15:58,458 --> 00:16:01,918
My father work very hard,

87
00:16:01,919 --> 00:16:07,883
have 50... 50 dollar... one year.

88
00:16:07,967 --> 00:16:13,555
And you spend 500... one day.

89
00:16:13,640 --> 00:16:15,932
Why you... why you do this?

90
00:16:17,894 --> 00:16:23,732
Li, you know, I'm not
trying to influence you.

91
00:16:23,816 --> 00:16:26,360
It's just what people
wear here, that's all.

92
00:16:26,444 --> 00:16:30,238
I think that's probably why your
government gave you this suit.

93
00:16:30,323 --> 00:16:33,116
It's just a trifle out of date,
that's all.

94
00:16:33,201 --> 00:16:35,577
I must give suit back.

95
00:16:35,662 --> 00:16:38,955
Well, you can give these back
when you go home.

96
00:16:38,956 --> 00:16:40,415
These can be yours to have

97
00:16:40,500 --> 00:16:42,125
while you're here
at summer school and...

98
00:16:47,215 --> 00:16:50,300
Why bird on?

99
00:16:50,385 --> 00:16:53,470
(CHUCKLES) "Don't let
the turkeys get you down."

100
00:16:53,554 --> 00:16:57,265
It's not a capitalist thing,
Li, it's just...

101
00:16:57,350 --> 00:16:58,767
Honestly, it's just
a bit of nonsense,

102
00:16:58,851 --> 00:17:00,852
like a lot of things in America.

103
00:17:03,398 --> 00:17:04,815
What it mean?

104
00:17:04,899 --> 00:17:08,193
It means there are times
when you just have to be strong.

105
00:17:18,496 --> 00:17:21,331
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)

106
00:17:24,544 --> 00:17:27,212
(CHINESE SONG PLAYS)

107
00:18:35,948 --> 00:18:38,909
(CALLS INSTRUCTIONS
IN CHINESE)

108
00:20:10,668 --> 00:20:12,544
(BOY SOBS)

109
00:20:37,570 --> 00:20:39,946
(SOBS)

110
00:21:00,843 --> 00:21:03,136
(FARTS LOUDLY)

111
00:21:09,810 --> 00:21:13,229
(BRIGHT PIANO MUSIC PLAYS)

112
00:21:15,691 --> 00:21:18,234
(TEACHER CHAN
CALLS INSTRUCTIONS)

113
00:21:37,254 --> 00:21:39,089
- Ni hao.
- Ni hao.

114
00:21:44,804 --> 00:21:45,762
Mm.

115
00:21:50,267 --> 00:21:51,726
Oh!

116
00:22:01,487 --> 00:22:04,864
(TEACHER CHAN CALLS
INSTRUCTIONS)

117
00:22:57,460 --> 00:23:00,253
(TEACHER CHAN
SPEAKS CHINESE)

118
00:23:00,337 --> 00:23:03,506
(PIANO PLAYS
SLOW MELODY)

119
00:23:05,259 --> 00:23:08,595
(CALLS INSTRUCTIONS)

120
00:23:46,926 --> 00:23:48,384
(CHUCKLES)

121
00:24:44,108 --> 00:24:48,069
('LET'S GROOVE'
BY EARTH, WIND AND FIRE PLAYS)

122
00:25:00,040 --> 00:25:01,457
Here you go, Li.

123
00:25:01,458 --> 00:25:03,376
Thank you.

124
00:25:03,460 --> 00:25:05,461
What is this?

125
00:25:05,462 --> 00:25:07,422
It's just Pepsi. Give it a shot.

126
00:25:13,262 --> 00:25:15,096
I know, I know. It's...

127
00:25:15,181 --> 00:25:18,016
Yeah, I know. It gets
up your nose a little.

128
00:25:21,604 --> 00:25:22,562
Whoo!

129
00:25:22,646 --> 00:25:24,272
- Bobby?
- Yeah?

130
00:25:24,356 --> 00:25:26,316
Lori - she good dancer.

131
00:25:26,400 --> 00:25:27,775
Oh, yeah, she is.

132
00:25:27,860 --> 00:25:30,737
But for a principal ballerina,

133
00:25:30,821 --> 00:25:34,240
she makes
a lousy disco dancer.

134
00:25:34,325 --> 00:25:36,326
Hey, you wanna dance, Li?

135
00:25:36,410 --> 00:25:37,785
- No.
- Aww!

136
00:25:37,870 --> 00:25:39,412
Allow me.

137
00:25:49,173 --> 00:25:52,050
Dilworth, you like ballet?

138
00:25:52,134 --> 00:25:55,511
I like ballerinas, Li. Very agile.

139
00:25:58,515 --> 00:26:00,516
Chairman Mao, huh?

140
00:26:00,517 --> 00:26:03,311
Yes, I love Chairman Mao.

141
00:26:03,395 --> 00:26:05,688
He do many good thing.

142
00:26:05,773 --> 00:26:08,399
Can't say I feel the same
about our new president.

143
00:26:08,484 --> 00:26:10,860
You love president?

144
00:26:10,945 --> 00:26:13,571
(LAUGHS) No, Li,
I don't even like him.

145
00:26:13,656 --> 00:26:15,782
Shhh!

146
00:26:17,493 --> 00:26:19,202
You not scared?

147
00:26:19,286 --> 00:26:21,079
Scared? No.

148
00:26:21,163 --> 00:26:23,414
This is America, Li.

149
00:26:26,543 --> 00:26:29,545
(CALLS INSTRUCTIONS)

150
00:27:56,383 --> 00:27:57,342
Arabesque.

151
00:29:15,462 --> 00:29:18,423
(PEOPLE CHANT)

152
00:29:40,112 --> 00:29:43,739
(ELEGANT ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYS)

153
00:30:17,441 --> 00:30:20,401
(MUSIC CLIMAXES)

154
00:30:27,159 --> 00:30:29,535
(MUSIC ENDS)

155
00:31:53,370 --> 00:31:55,871
(BOTH EXCHANGE GREETINGS)

156
00:33:08,612 --> 00:33:12,448
(CHINESE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYS)

157
00:34:18,598 --> 00:34:21,851
(MUSIC SWELLS)

158
00:35:10,108 --> 00:35:12,234
(MUSIC ENDS)

159
00:35:22,788 --> 00:35:25,122
(BOY CHATTERS QUIETLY)

160
00:36:24,432 --> 00:36:25,391
(WHISPERS)

161
00:36:34,568 --> 00:36:37,987
(APPLAUSE)

162
00:36:42,200 --> 00:36:45,369
(BRIGHT ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYS)

163
00:36:45,453 --> 00:36:47,872
Oh!

164
00:36:59,843 --> 00:37:02,845
(APPLAUSE)

165
00:37:10,729 --> 00:37:13,564
(WILD APPLAUSE
AND CHEERING)

166
00:38:24,552 --> 00:38:26,929
NEWSREEL NARRATOR:

167
00:39:19,441 --> 00:39:21,900
I'm Shi Dao from
the Ministry of Culture.

168
00:39:21,985 --> 00:39:23,569
Oh, thank you.

169
00:39:23,653 --> 00:39:25,070
Ben Stevenson.

170
00:39:25,155 --> 00:39:26,655
- Welcome to Beijing.
- Thank you.

171
00:39:26,740 --> 00:39:28,490
Let me introduce Mr Wang.

172
00:39:28,575 --> 00:39:30,451
- (SPEAKS CHINESE)
- Hello.

173
00:39:30,535 --> 00:39:32,119
Director for Beijing Academy.

174
00:39:32,203 --> 00:39:33,829
- Mr Hung...
- (SPEAKS CHINESE)

175
00:39:33,913 --> 00:39:35,330
BEN: A pleasure to meet you.

176
00:39:35,331 --> 00:39:36,707
These are
my principal dancers,

177
00:39:36,791 --> 00:39:38,125
Mary McKendry
and Bobby Cordner.

178
00:39:38,209 --> 00:39:39,585
- Hello.
- Welcome to Beijing.

179
00:39:39,669 --> 00:39:41,086
- Thank you.
- Thank you so much.

180
00:39:41,171 --> 00:39:42,796
- Music, please. Thank you.
- (TRANSLATES)

181
00:39:42,881 --> 00:39:44,548
('PRELUDE 1: ALLEGRO
BEN RITMATO E DECISO'

182
00:39:44,632 --> 00:39:46,091
BY GEORGE GERSHWIN PLAYS)

183
00:39:53,058 --> 00:39:54,600
Lovely. Alright, thank you.

184
00:39:54,684 --> 00:39:57,436
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- Let's, um... Lovely. Not bad.

185
00:39:57,520 --> 00:40:01,315
Let's try that just from
the beginning and copy them.

186
00:40:01,399 --> 00:40:02,441
Right?

187
00:40:02,525 --> 00:40:05,027
Five, six, seven, eight.

188
00:40:05,111 --> 00:40:07,112
(HUMS TUNE)

189
00:40:07,197 --> 00:40:09,656
And five, six, seven, eight.

190
00:40:09,741 --> 00:40:11,825
And one, two and three. Lovely!

191
00:40:11,910 --> 00:40:13,827
Lovely. That's very good. Alright.

192
00:40:13,912 --> 00:40:15,454
Let's try it with music, shall we?

193
00:40:15,538 --> 00:40:17,247
(MUSIC RESUMES)

194
00:40:19,709 --> 00:40:21,543
Lovely. Yes, turn, turn, turn.

195
00:40:24,047 --> 00:40:25,964
Travel, travel, travel, travel!

196
00:40:26,049 --> 00:40:27,883
(WOMAN TRANSLATES)

197
00:40:27,967 --> 00:40:30,427
Back in, back in.
Energy, energy.

198
00:40:32,972 --> 00:40:34,598
Right. Ready for the jump!

199
00:40:34,682 --> 00:40:37,434
(HUMS TUNE)

200
00:40:39,270 --> 00:40:41,814
Yes, yes, yes!

201
00:40:41,898 --> 00:40:43,315
Very good, very good indeed.

202
00:40:43,399 --> 00:40:44,817
Alright, back to the top.

203
00:40:45,819 --> 00:40:49,113
They're so light in the air
and so strong.

204
00:40:49,197 --> 00:40:50,572
But there's no emotion.

205
00:40:50,657 --> 00:40:52,324
They're not connected,
I'm not engaged.

206
00:40:52,408 --> 00:40:53,784
Amazing technique.

207
00:40:53,868 --> 00:40:55,327
Well, yeah, but, you know,

208
00:40:55,411 --> 00:40:57,704
they remind me more of athletes
than dancers.

209
00:40:57,789 --> 00:41:01,458
All except... There's one,
perhaps two. Certainly one.

210
00:41:01,543 --> 00:41:04,461
I think I know who you mean.

211
00:41:04,546 --> 00:41:07,422
BEN: And from
the port de bras, yes?

212
00:41:07,423 --> 00:41:09,133
And développé.

213
00:41:11,636 --> 00:41:13,554
Right, Li, get ready
to come in for the lift.

214
00:41:13,638 --> 00:41:15,806
- (WOMAN TRANSLATES)
- Mm-hm.

215
00:41:19,435 --> 00:41:21,228
Oh, that's really not working.

216
00:41:21,312 --> 00:41:25,315
Uh... Mary, would you
stand here for a moment?

217
00:41:25,400 --> 00:41:28,068
Shing Hua, stay here
for one moment, alright?

218
00:41:28,153 --> 00:41:30,612
Mary, you do it. Li, would you partner
Mary, please?

219
00:41:30,697 --> 00:41:33,740
And, from the beginning, yeah?

220
00:41:33,825 --> 00:41:35,242
(WOMAN TRANSLATES)

221
00:41:35,326 --> 00:41:37,035
Alright?

222
00:41:37,120 --> 00:41:39,621
It's alright, I won't bite.

223
00:41:39,706 --> 00:41:42,291
- Could you tell him?
- (TRANSLATES)

224
00:41:42,375 --> 00:41:45,502
Right. Come on, come on.

225
00:41:45,587 --> 00:41:47,880
There we go.

226
00:41:47,964 --> 00:41:49,381
Ni hao.

227
00:41:49,465 --> 00:41:51,258
I'm Mary.

228
00:41:51,342 --> 00:41:52,384
Ni hao.

229
00:41:52,468 --> 00:41:55,429
(DRAMATIC STRING MUSIC PLAYS)

230
00:42:35,553 --> 00:42:40,515
Minister, you have some
really wonderful dancers here.

231
00:42:48,900 --> 00:42:51,151
We've run the summer program
for several years now

232
00:42:51,236 --> 00:42:53,528
and we've been
very successful.

233
00:42:53,529 --> 00:42:54,947
Yeah, I see.

234
00:42:55,031 --> 00:42:57,115
It's a tremendous success.

235
00:42:57,200 --> 00:42:58,659
I think they're talking about us.

236
00:42:58,743 --> 00:43:00,452
Probably.

237
00:43:13,132 --> 00:43:15,717
Because it would be wonderful
for the Houston Ballet.

238
00:43:15,802 --> 00:43:18,595
The decision would
have to be made

239
00:43:18,680 --> 00:43:20,305
by the party, Mr Stevenson.

240
00:43:20,390 --> 00:43:22,849
Oh, of course,
I understand. Yes.

241
00:43:22,934 --> 00:43:24,101
Alright.

242
00:43:27,730 --> 00:43:29,648
BOBBY: How'd it go?

243
00:43:29,732 --> 00:43:31,149
Well, they're going to
consider it.

244
00:43:31,234 --> 00:43:32,985
I expect they'll take it
to the highest level.

245
00:43:33,069 --> 00:43:34,486
MARY: Well, how long
will that take?

246
00:43:34,570 --> 00:43:37,030
It's not up to me. It's up to
the Chinese Government.

247
00:43:37,115 --> 00:43:38,573
WOMAN: We're ready for photograph,
Mr Stevenson.

248
00:43:38,574 --> 00:43:40,701
Alright.

249
00:45:51,457 --> 00:45:54,418
(GENTLE PIANO MUSIC PLAYS)

250
00:46:06,055 --> 00:46:07,722
Hi.

251
00:46:10,435 --> 00:46:14,771
Um... I can go if you
want to use the studio.

252
00:46:14,856 --> 00:46:17,691
No, um, stay.

253
00:46:17,775 --> 00:46:19,317
Watch.

254
00:46:23,156 --> 00:46:25,657
Arabesque.

255
00:46:25,741 --> 00:46:29,995
Um... foot... stretch.

256
00:46:30,079 --> 00:46:31,997
Oh, I can't.

257
00:46:32,081 --> 00:46:34,499
Um, my ankle, I broke it.

258
00:46:34,584 --> 00:46:38,044
Right here. They put a rod in it.

259
00:46:39,505 --> 00:46:42,716
When they took the cast off
my calf had shrunk two inches.

260
00:46:42,800 --> 00:46:45,719
It's fine now, I think.
It's just my confidence.

261
00:46:47,346 --> 00:46:49,723
I'm sorry, you don't understand.

262
00:46:49,807 --> 00:46:53,977
Um, I-I understand.

263
00:46:54,061 --> 00:46:56,229
- You do?
- Uh...

264
00:46:56,314 --> 00:46:57,564
No.

265
00:47:00,776 --> 00:47:02,903
- En pointe. En pointe.
- OK.

266
00:47:04,530 --> 00:47:05,947
This, turn out.

267
00:47:06,032 --> 00:47:07,782
Yeah.

268
00:47:07,783 --> 00:47:09,075
Better.

269
00:47:09,160 --> 00:47:10,785
I'm Elizabeth, by the way.

270
00:47:10,786 --> 00:47:12,704
Everyone calls me Liz.

271
00:47:12,788 --> 00:47:14,289
- Liz?
- Yeah.

272
00:47:14,373 --> 00:47:15,874
Like Li.

273
00:47:15,958 --> 00:47:17,709
Everyone call me Li.

274
00:47:17,793 --> 00:47:19,878
Yeah, I know who you are.

275
00:47:19,962 --> 00:47:21,421
Li Cunxin.

276
00:47:21,506 --> 00:47:23,423
- 'Schwinsin'?
- Mm.

277
00:47:23,508 --> 00:47:25,967
That's really beautiful.
What does it mean?

278
00:47:26,052 --> 00:47:29,346
Um, it mean...

279
00:47:29,430 --> 00:47:32,724
...'keep my innocent heart'.

280
00:47:34,185 --> 00:47:37,604
Um... you dance with company?

281
00:47:37,688 --> 00:47:39,231
Oh, no. No.

282
00:47:39,315 --> 00:47:41,900
I was in the corps of...
'Nutcracker' once,

283
00:47:41,984 --> 00:47:45,695
but that's as close as
I've come to getting a contract.

284
00:47:45,780 --> 00:47:49,491
This is my second time
in the full-time program

285
00:47:49,575 --> 00:47:51,952
trying to get Ben to notice me.

286
00:47:52,036 --> 00:47:54,037
(LAUGHS)

287
00:47:57,124 --> 00:47:58,625
- Li: Ben?
- BEN: Yeah?

288
00:47:58,709 --> 00:48:04,130
Today, in street, someone speak me

289
00:48:04,215 --> 00:48:07,050
word I not understand.

290
00:48:07,134 --> 00:48:09,844
Um, not find in here.

291
00:48:09,845 --> 00:48:11,221
What was it?

292
00:48:11,305 --> 00:48:13,181
Um... 'chink'.

293
00:48:15,434 --> 00:48:17,435
What it mean?

294
00:48:17,520 --> 00:48:21,022
Um, let's see.

295
00:48:24,277 --> 00:48:25,860
Do you know when
you're in the theatre,

296
00:48:25,861 --> 00:48:28,655
and everyone is getting seated
and the curtain is closed,

297
00:48:28,739 --> 00:48:30,615
if the stage light is on,

298
00:48:30,700 --> 00:48:32,826
and the curtain parts
just a tiny little bit,

299
00:48:32,910 --> 00:48:36,121
then the light from the stage
shines through

300
00:48:36,205 --> 00:48:38,748
what we call a chink
in the curtain.

301
00:48:38,833 --> 00:48:41,084
So if someone calls you
a 'chink', Li,

302
00:48:41,168 --> 00:48:43,003
what it means is that...

303
00:48:43,087 --> 00:48:46,423
...they see the light
that's there inside of you.

304
00:48:46,507 --> 00:48:49,801
Oh! Oh... fantastic.

305
00:48:53,556 --> 00:48:55,890
And trace the leg,
follow the line.

306
00:49:00,813 --> 00:49:02,731
Nice, Lori.

307
00:49:04,442 --> 00:49:06,443
Pull back. Just feed her out.

308
00:49:08,362 --> 00:49:11,281
And extend the leg. Lovely.

309
00:49:13,951 --> 00:49:15,493
Good, good.

310
00:49:15,578 --> 00:49:19,831
Yeah, yeah.
Very good. Very good. Alright?

311
00:49:40,519 --> 00:49:43,396
Li: In Chinese, we say 'will go',

312
00:49:43,481 --> 00:49:47,859
'go today', 'go tomorrow',
'go yesterday',

313
00:49:47,943 --> 00:49:52,614
'you go', 'I go', 'she go',
'we all go'.

314
00:49:52,698 --> 00:49:55,533
- (LAUGHS) Right.
- Much, much easier.

315
00:49:55,618 --> 00:49:58,953
English changes all time.

316
00:49:58,954 --> 00:50:00,246
You're doing very well.

317
00:50:00,331 --> 00:50:04,501
(SPEAKS CHINESE)

318
00:50:04,585 --> 00:50:05,960
Thank you.

319
00:50:13,594 --> 00:50:16,221
Chinese official not come here.

320
00:50:16,305 --> 00:50:17,639
What do you mean?

321
00:50:17,723 --> 00:50:20,475
- She lau ban.
- Lau ban?

322
00:50:20,559 --> 00:50:23,269
Um... boss person.

323
00:50:23,354 --> 00:50:25,980
In China, class enemy.

324
00:50:27,316 --> 00:50:29,234
She looks like an opera diva.

325
00:50:31,612 --> 00:50:33,738
What? What is it?

326
00:50:35,366 --> 00:50:39,577
I am with you, American girl.

327
00:50:39,662 --> 00:50:40,745
Mm-hm.

328
00:50:40,830 --> 00:50:42,747
Make trouble for Ben.

329
00:50:42,832 --> 00:50:43,832
No.

330
00:50:43,916 --> 00:50:47,168
It's OK. No-one has to know.

331
00:50:48,337 --> 00:50:52,132
Um... here. Try this.

332
00:50:52,216 --> 00:50:53,591
What is it?

333
00:50:53,676 --> 00:50:57,262
It's, um, vegetable from sea.

334
00:51:01,350 --> 00:51:02,517
Good?

335
00:51:02,601 --> 00:51:06,438
- God, it's so hard to chew.
- Hard to chew.

336
00:51:06,522 --> 00:51:09,816
- Yeah, like English!
- (LAUGHS)

337
00:51:22,163 --> 00:51:23,204
Um...

338
00:51:23,289 --> 00:51:26,791
Thank you very much,
Elizabeth... um, Liz.

339
00:51:28,544 --> 00:51:31,045
Thank you, Li.
I had a nice night.

340
00:51:31,046 --> 00:51:33,423
Nice night?

341
00:52:01,452 --> 00:52:04,496
(HUMS)

342
00:52:04,580 --> 00:52:06,498
(KEYS JINGLE)

343
00:52:09,919 --> 00:52:11,795
Hello!

344
00:52:11,879 --> 00:52:14,380
Hi.

345
00:52:14,465 --> 00:52:16,466
Where have you been?

346
00:52:16,550 --> 00:52:20,637
Uh... I go Chinatown.

347
00:52:20,721 --> 00:52:24,015
Um... movie - watch movie.

348
00:52:24,099 --> 00:52:28,603
- A kung-fu movie?
- Yes, Ben. I go bed now.

349
00:52:28,687 --> 00:52:30,647
Nice night.

350
00:52:30,731 --> 00:52:32,315
Goodnight.

351
00:52:32,399 --> 00:52:34,818
Huh?

352
00:52:34,902 --> 00:52:36,736
GOOD... night.

353
00:52:36,821 --> 00:52:40,907
Oh, yes. Uh... good... night.

354
00:52:40,991 --> 00:52:43,368
Very good.

355
00:52:44,954 --> 00:52:46,538
Fantastic!

356
00:52:47,832 --> 00:52:50,792
(DRAMATIC PIANO
MUSIC PLAYS)

357
00:53:00,970 --> 00:53:02,345
(MUSIC ENDS)

358
00:53:02,429 --> 00:53:05,723
Alright, yeah, just a little more
over the shoulder next time.

359
00:53:05,808 --> 00:53:08,268
I want to take it from the lift.

360
00:53:08,352 --> 00:53:09,769
- Just a little more sustained.
- Sure.

361
00:53:09,854 --> 00:53:11,354
OK? Because I think
you have time musically.

362
00:53:11,438 --> 00:53:12,856
- Oh, yeah.
- Alright.

363
00:53:12,940 --> 00:53:14,732
So seven, two, three,

364
00:53:14,817 --> 00:53:16,192
eight, two, three...

365
00:53:16,277 --> 00:53:19,988
(HUMS TUNE)

366
00:53:20,072 --> 00:53:24,242
And up with the accent,
and hold a little longer.

367
00:53:24,326 --> 00:53:26,160
- Argh!
- Bobby!

368
00:53:26,161 --> 00:53:27,579
What have you done?
What's happened?

369
00:53:27,663 --> 00:53:29,581
Oh, God.

370
00:53:29,665 --> 00:53:31,249
Argh, sorry.

371
00:53:31,333 --> 00:53:33,209
- Oh, Christ.
- LORl: They'll bring you some ice.

372
00:53:34,461 --> 00:53:37,005
What about one of
the principals or soloists?

373
00:53:37,089 --> 00:53:39,173
Well, they're all away
on vacation.

374
00:53:39,174 --> 00:53:40,633
David Trembath's
at Galveston.

375
00:53:40,718 --> 00:53:42,468
Well, he can make it
here in time, surely.

376
00:53:42,553 --> 00:53:45,096
- Li's better than he is.
- It's tonight, Ben.

377
00:53:45,180 --> 00:53:48,808
And Li's just a student here.
The union won't allow it.

378
00:53:48,893 --> 00:53:52,061
Ben, this is the biggest night
on the arts calendar.

379
00:53:52,146 --> 00:53:55,148
How's he supposed to learn
'Don Quixote' in three hours?

380
00:53:55,232 --> 00:53:56,691
He already knows the solo.

381
00:53:56,775 --> 00:53:58,860
All he has to learn
is the pas de deux.

382
00:53:58,944 --> 00:54:01,029
Everybody who is anyone
is gonna be here tonight,

383
00:54:01,113 --> 00:54:02,488
including the Vice President.

384
00:54:02,573 --> 00:54:03,990
Yes, I know, but Li told me

385
00:54:04,074 --> 00:54:06,492
he once danced for the great
Madame Mao - we're alright.

386
00:54:06,577 --> 00:54:08,828
But he's Chinese.

387
00:54:10,873 --> 00:54:12,123
What I mean is...

388
00:54:12,207 --> 00:54:15,043
I mean, he can't play
a Spaniard, can he?

389
00:54:15,127 --> 00:54:16,920
Well, unless I'm mistaken, Betty Lou,

390
00:54:17,004 --> 00:54:18,379
I distinctly remember

391
00:54:18,464 --> 00:54:20,924
Marlon Brando playing
a Japanese villager.

392
00:54:21,008 --> 00:54:22,967
Oh, I loved that movie!

393
00:54:24,136 --> 00:54:27,805
CYNTHIA: Ben, what if he's not up to it?

394
00:54:31,226 --> 00:54:32,852
He's up to it, Cynthia.

395
00:54:32,937 --> 00:54:34,437
And keep the Spanish feel,
keep that attitude.

396
00:54:34,521 --> 00:54:36,272
When you come out of
the à la seconde

397
00:54:36,357 --> 00:54:38,274
just do it with as many
pirouettes as you can.

398
00:54:38,359 --> 00:54:39,901
And be sure to finish
on the music.

399
00:54:39,985 --> 00:54:41,235
That's...

400
00:54:42,237 --> 00:54:44,238
It's not too late, Li.
I mean, we can cancel.

401
00:54:44,239 --> 00:54:45,698
Um, no.

402
00:54:45,783 --> 00:54:47,951
- Um, I can do this, Ben.
- No, you can do it.

403
00:54:48,035 --> 00:54:51,120
I know you can do it. Go from
the top of the pas de deux?

404
00:54:51,205 --> 00:54:52,580
- The beginning?
- Yes. From the beginning.

405
00:54:52,665 --> 00:54:53,665
OK.

406
00:54:53,749 --> 00:55:00,171
And... tombé, pas de bourrée,
glissade, lift, pirouette.

407
00:55:00,255 --> 00:55:02,757
Tombé, arabesque, soutenu,

408
00:55:02,841 --> 00:55:05,218
get close to her,
ready for the one-arm lift.

409
00:55:05,302 --> 00:55:09,305
OK.

410
00:55:09,390 --> 00:55:12,725
MAN: When the show starts, if you can't
see there, you can...

411
00:55:12,810 --> 00:55:13,726
WOMAN: Oh, thanks.

412
00:55:13,811 --> 00:55:15,478
MAN: I hate the opera.

413
00:55:15,562 --> 00:55:16,980
WOMAN: But they have
the ballet too.

414
00:55:17,064 --> 00:55:19,273
MASON: I just hope
it all works out.

415
00:55:19,274 --> 00:55:21,776
MAN: (OVER P.A.) Ladies and
gentlemen, take your seats.

416
00:55:21,860 --> 00:55:23,444
Tonight's performance of
'Die Fledermaus'

417
00:55:23,529 --> 00:55:25,405
will commence in two minutes.

418
00:55:28,909 --> 00:55:30,827
REPORTER: Vice President Bush
and his wife, Barbara,

419
00:55:30,911 --> 00:55:32,245
are attending the opening of

420
00:55:32,329 --> 00:55:33,830
Houston Opera's
summer season

421
00:55:33,914 --> 00:55:35,873
'Die Fledermaus',
by Johann Strauss.

422
00:55:35,958 --> 00:55:38,209
Stars of the Houston Ballet
are also...

423
00:55:38,293 --> 00:55:41,004
- CYNTHIA: Oh, hi.
- BEN: Hello.

424
00:55:42,297 --> 00:55:44,716
You better be right,
Ben Stevenson.

425
00:55:47,136 --> 00:55:49,721
Consul Zhang,
so glad you could make it.

426
00:55:49,805 --> 00:55:52,765
(ORCHESTRA PLAYS OVERTURE)

427
00:56:27,342 --> 00:56:32,430
Lori, um... woman dancer
called, um... 'ballerina'.

428
00:56:32,514 --> 00:56:34,599
What you call man?

429
00:56:34,683 --> 00:56:38,644
'Danseur noble'.

430
00:56:38,729 --> 00:56:40,605
Not nice, not like 'ballerina'.

431
00:56:40,689 --> 00:56:43,983
OK, well how about
Big Ballerino?

432
00:56:44,068 --> 00:56:45,610
Ballerino.

433
00:56:45,694 --> 00:56:47,111
I like.

434
00:56:47,196 --> 00:56:49,322
All set, Big Ballerino?

435
00:56:49,406 --> 00:56:51,157
All set, Big Ballerina.

436
00:57:03,378 --> 00:57:05,922
(GERMAN ACCENT)
Ladies und gentlemen,

437
00:57:06,006 --> 00:57:09,092
I would like to present to you all

438
00:57:09,176 --> 00:57:13,596
two very special guests
from sunny Spain.

439
00:57:13,680 --> 00:57:16,641
(BRIGHT MUSIC FROM 'DON QUIXOTE'
BY L. MINKUS)

440
00:57:19,978 --> 00:57:21,395
(MUSIC STOPS)

441
00:57:26,902 --> 00:57:28,444
(AUDIENCE TITTERS NERVOUSLY)

442
00:57:28,529 --> 00:57:30,571
Oh, come on.

443
00:57:35,369 --> 00:57:38,329
(CHINESE STRING MUSIC)

444
00:58:00,811 --> 00:58:02,687
- (SIGHS)
- (ORCHESTRA RESUMES)

445
00:58:41,810 --> 00:58:42,852
Not bad.

446
00:58:57,242 --> 00:58:58,868
(ORCHESTRA PLAYS ROUSING MUSIC

447
00:58:58,952 --> 00:59:00,703
FROM 'DON QUIXOTE'
BY L. MINKUS)

448
00:59:24,853 --> 00:59:26,812
Oh, boy.

449
00:59:54,132 --> 00:59:56,342
Fantastic!

450
00:59:56,426 --> 00:59:58,511
AUDIENCE MEMBERS: Bravo! Bravo!

451
01:00:01,974 --> 01:00:04,558
(MUSIC RESUMES)

452
01:00:56,445 --> 01:00:57,903
(MUSIC ENDS)

453
01:00:57,988 --> 01:01:00,614
AUDIENCE MEMBERS: Bravo! Bravo!

454
01:01:15,047 --> 01:01:16,464
How 'bout that, huh?

455
01:01:16,548 --> 01:01:18,424
Bravo!

456
01:01:34,316 --> 01:01:36,400
OK. Oh, wait, wait, wait.

457
01:01:36,485 --> 01:01:37,902
There's a card.

458
01:01:38,987 --> 01:01:40,321
OK.

459
01:01:46,912 --> 01:01:49,372
(READS) "The lucky carp
wind chime.

460
01:01:49,456 --> 01:01:54,210
"Legend has it that
as the carp swims upstream,

461
01:01:54,294 --> 01:01:55,920
"it has to leap..."

462
01:01:56,963 --> 01:01:59,006
"...over many obstacles,

463
01:01:59,091 --> 01:02:02,676
"and with the final leap,

464
01:02:02,677 --> 01:02:06,972
"it turns into
the celestial dragon."

465
01:02:14,815 --> 01:02:17,483
Li, wait.
Slow down one second.

466
01:02:17,567 --> 01:02:20,319
Um...

467
01:02:22,697 --> 01:02:24,073
I'm a virgin.

468
01:02:24,157 --> 01:02:26,575
Um... a virgin?

469
01:02:26,660 --> 01:02:29,286
It means I've never
done it before.

470
01:02:29,371 --> 01:02:31,539
Done what?

471
01:02:31,623 --> 01:02:34,500
I've never had sex before.

472
01:02:36,086 --> 01:02:37,503
You know what sex is?

473
01:02:37,587 --> 01:02:39,296
Yeah.

474
01:02:39,381 --> 01:02:41,549
One, two, three, four, five, sex!

475
01:02:41,633 --> 01:02:43,217
(LAUGHS) No. No.

476
01:02:43,301 --> 01:02:44,927
- No?
- No, no.

477
01:02:45,011 --> 01:02:47,763
It's how a man and a woman
make a baby together.

478
01:02:47,848 --> 01:02:49,807
You want to make a baby?

479
01:02:49,891 --> 01:02:51,600
No! No.

480
01:02:51,685 --> 01:02:54,478
No, no, no, no. No!
That's not what I'm trying to say.

481
01:02:54,563 --> 01:02:58,399
No. What I'm... what I'm...

482
01:02:58,483 --> 01:03:00,443
Never mind.

483
01:03:01,695 --> 01:03:04,780
('SUPERFREAK'
BY RICK JAMES PLAYS)

484
01:03:19,171 --> 01:03:21,714
So the roster for the opening week
of 'Swan Lake'

485
01:03:21,798 --> 01:03:25,384
will be posted today, but Li
will be guesting Bobby's role.

486
01:03:25,469 --> 01:03:27,011
You've got to be kidding, right?

487
01:03:27,095 --> 01:03:28,762
No offence, Li,
but I'm Bobby's understudy.

488
01:03:28,763 --> 01:03:30,431
Of course you are, David.

489
01:03:30,515 --> 01:03:32,725
It's just an opportunity for Houstonians
to see Li dance

490
01:03:32,809 --> 01:03:34,268
before he goes back, that's all.

491
01:03:34,352 --> 01:03:35,769
Alright?

492
01:03:35,770 --> 01:03:38,814
In fact, I have applied
to the Chinese Government

493
01:03:38,899 --> 01:03:41,692
for permission for us all
to tour China next year.

494
01:03:41,776 --> 01:03:43,277
- MASON: That's right.
- LORI: I'll be in that.

495
01:03:43,361 --> 01:03:45,779
- BOBBY: Oh, yeah, me too.
- Hey, you just stay injured.

496
01:03:45,780 --> 01:03:48,324
It'd be a first for
an American company.

497
01:03:48,408 --> 01:03:51,452
('SUPERFREAK'
CONTINUES PLAYING)

498
01:04:01,171 --> 01:04:02,796
(HUMS)

499
01:04:02,797 --> 01:04:04,340
More kung-fu?

500
01:04:04,424 --> 01:04:06,759
Yes. More kung-fu.

501
01:04:06,843 --> 01:04:08,636
Fantastic.

502
01:04:08,720 --> 01:04:09,720
Goodnight.

503
01:04:09,804 --> 01:04:10,804
Goodnight!

504
01:04:15,936 --> 01:04:19,188
(HARPIST PLAYS CADENZA
FROM 'SWAN LAKE' BY TCHAIKOVSKY)

505
01:05:09,364 --> 01:05:11,198
CONSUL ZHANG: Thank you
for coming, Mr Stevenson.

506
01:05:11,283 --> 01:05:12,741
BEN: No, not at all.

507
01:05:14,494 --> 01:05:17,288
CONSUL ZHANG: I received a telex
from Beijing last night.

508
01:05:18,331 --> 01:05:19,915
I'm sorry, but the request

509
01:05:20,000 --> 01:05:22,293
for Cunxin to have
his stay extended

510
01:05:22,377 --> 01:05:24,003
has been refused.

511
01:05:24,087 --> 01:05:25,421
But I thought...

512
01:05:37,976 --> 01:05:40,352
Is there anything we can do?

513
01:05:40,437 --> 01:05:42,688
No, Mr Stevenson, there isn't.

514
01:06:03,835 --> 01:06:06,545
Li, don't worry. I'll...

515
01:06:06,630 --> 01:06:10,049
You'll be able to come back.
I'll make sure of it.

516
01:06:11,593 --> 01:06:13,135
I'll do everything I can.

517
01:06:14,888 --> 01:06:16,347
I promise.

518
01:06:33,698 --> 01:06:35,824
Ben not understand.

519
01:06:35,909 --> 01:06:38,160
He's too much
in love with China.

520
01:06:38,244 --> 01:06:41,288
In China, not so easy.

521
01:06:41,373 --> 01:06:46,043
Tell you what to do,
where to go, what can say.

522
01:06:47,420 --> 01:06:48,962
Maybe I can't come back.

523
01:06:52,884 --> 01:06:57,388
You know, I must dance
political ballet in China,

524
01:06:57,472 --> 01:07:01,392
but I dance better here.

525
01:07:01,476 --> 01:07:06,105
Because feel more... free.

526
01:07:16,950 --> 01:07:19,243
MAN: Well, there are several
options available for you

527
01:07:19,327 --> 01:07:22,538
to stay in the United States,
if that's your wish.

528
01:07:22,622 --> 01:07:24,123
Seeking political asylum is one,

529
01:07:24,207 --> 01:07:26,375
but that's the last option
I'd recommend

530
01:07:26,459 --> 01:07:28,627
because it means
you'd have to defect.

531
01:07:28,712 --> 01:07:31,505
Li: No, no defect.

532
01:07:31,589 --> 01:07:32,965
LORI: Li's worried about his family.

533
01:07:33,049 --> 01:07:35,259
He doesn't want to make things difficult
for them.

534
01:07:35,343 --> 01:07:37,678
He also wants to be able
to go back and see them.

535
01:07:37,762 --> 01:07:41,932
OK, well from what
I've read and heard about you,

536
01:07:41,933 --> 01:07:44,226
I'm certain we'd be
able to qualify you,

537
01:07:44,310 --> 01:07:47,187
based on your extraordinary skills
as a performing artist.

538
01:07:47,272 --> 01:07:49,022
DILWORTH: What would
be involved, Charles?

539
01:07:49,107 --> 01:07:51,400
Well, we'd have to get
supporting statements

540
01:07:51,484 --> 01:07:54,278
and a petition signed
by an employer,

541
01:07:54,362 --> 01:07:55,821
the Houston Ballet Company,
no doubt.

542
01:07:58,742 --> 01:08:02,870
Alternatively, if you were
in a relationship

543
01:08:02,954 --> 01:08:04,872
or planning to
get married soon,

544
01:08:04,956 --> 01:08:06,707
and your spouse was
a US citizen,

545
01:08:06,791 --> 01:08:08,542
well, there would be
no issue whatsoever

546
01:08:08,626 --> 01:08:10,502
because the Chinese Government

547
01:08:10,587 --> 01:08:12,921
recognises international
marriage laws.

548
01:08:14,048 --> 01:08:16,175
Are you in a relationship, Li?

549
01:08:16,259 --> 01:08:18,969
Uh, do you have a girlfriend?

550
01:08:18,970 --> 01:08:20,304
No, he doesn't.

551
01:08:20,388 --> 01:08:23,682
Uh, yes, I have, um,
American girlfriend.

552
01:08:23,767 --> 01:08:26,226
- You what?
- How about that! Who is she?

553
01:08:26,311 --> 01:08:27,728
LORI: Really?

554
01:08:27,812 --> 01:08:29,271
Well, first of all,

555
01:08:29,355 --> 01:08:31,774
I would strongly advise against
a marriage of convenience,

556
01:08:31,858 --> 01:08:34,610
unless of course it was
a serious relationship you're in.

557
01:08:34,694 --> 01:08:37,988
If there's one thing worse
than an immigration problem,

558
01:08:38,072 --> 01:08:39,865
it's a marriage problem.

559
01:08:39,949 --> 01:08:41,533
Is it a serious relationship, Li?

560
01:08:41,618 --> 01:08:43,994
LORI: Is it serious,

561
01:08:43,995 --> 01:08:45,412
Li?

562
01:08:45,497 --> 01:08:47,456
BEN: On behalf of the Houston
Ballet Company

563
01:08:47,540 --> 01:08:50,584
and all of us who've had

564
01:08:50,668 --> 01:08:52,795
the privilege of
seeing you dance, Li,

565
01:08:52,879 --> 01:08:55,756
I'd like to say how exciting
it's been having you here.

566
01:08:55,840 --> 01:08:59,426
You came as a student,
and leave here as a star.

567
01:09:08,102 --> 01:09:12,356
Um... just...

568
01:09:14,234 --> 01:09:15,651
Thank you, Ben.

569
01:09:15,735 --> 01:09:20,447
And...

570
01:09:20,532 --> 01:09:22,241
...thank the audience.

571
01:09:25,411 --> 01:09:27,412
Thankyou, America.

572
01:09:41,386 --> 01:09:44,805
(DINERS CHATTER)

573
01:09:46,432 --> 01:09:47,474
WOMAN: Mr Stevenson,

574
01:09:47,559 --> 01:09:49,184
we're ready for the photograph
with Consul Zhang.

575
01:09:49,269 --> 01:09:51,687
- BEN: Excuse me.
- MAN: Of course.

576
01:09:52,730 --> 01:09:55,148
I don't know.
Has anyone seen him?

577
01:09:55,233 --> 01:09:56,775
I'll just ask you
to step in together.

578
01:09:56,860 --> 01:09:58,026
Great.

579
01:09:58,111 --> 01:09:59,486
Thank you.

580
01:09:59,571 --> 01:10:01,530
Consul, Anita Jones.

581
01:10:01,614 --> 01:10:03,156
Anita's the arts editor
for the 'Houston Chronicle'.

582
01:10:03,241 --> 01:10:05,868
- I'm pleased to meet you.
- Pleased to meet you too, sir.

583
01:10:05,952 --> 01:10:08,287
Mind if I get a few words
from you about Li

584
01:10:08,371 --> 01:10:10,539
and what it means to China
to have had him here?

585
01:10:10,623 --> 01:10:11,540
Of course.

586
01:10:11,624 --> 01:10:13,083
- Excuse me.
- Sure.

587
01:10:13,167 --> 01:10:16,086
I see it as another
positive step in...

588
01:10:16,170 --> 01:10:18,714
He's not at the theatre.

589
01:10:18,798 --> 01:10:21,675
- Did you try my place?
- Sure. No answer.

590
01:10:21,759 --> 01:10:23,802
Sir, we're ready to serve.

591
01:10:24,846 --> 01:10:27,681
Do you mind if we just wait...
just a little longer?

592
01:10:27,765 --> 01:10:29,725
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you. Thank you.

593
01:10:29,809 --> 01:10:31,602
- They're starting to wonder.
- Well, I know.

594
01:10:31,686 --> 01:10:33,186
Maybe you should say something.

595
01:10:33,271 --> 01:10:34,813
I don't know what
I'm going to say.

596
01:10:34,898 --> 01:10:37,024
Mr Stevenson, it's for you.

597
01:10:42,447 --> 01:10:44,114
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)

598
01:10:47,535 --> 01:10:49,661
What the hell is going on, Dilworth?

599
01:10:49,746 --> 01:10:51,246
Where's Li?

600
01:10:59,881 --> 01:11:02,174
Li, you can't stay here.
It's out of the question.

601
01:11:02,258 --> 01:11:04,885
Ben, um...I'm married.

602
01:11:04,969 --> 01:11:06,970
- You're what?
- I'm married.

603
01:11:07,055 --> 01:11:08,430
I not go back to China.

604
01:11:08,514 --> 01:11:10,057
No, you can't be married.
Don't be ridiculous.

605
01:11:10,141 --> 01:11:11,558
I mean, who did you marry?

606
01:11:13,478 --> 01:11:14,436
Elizabeth.

607
01:11:14,520 --> 01:11:16,146
Elizabeth? Elizabeth who?

608
01:11:19,859 --> 01:11:22,319
- Oh, you conniving little bitch.
- Stop!

609
01:11:22,403 --> 01:11:24,404
Ben, I love her.

610
01:11:24,489 --> 01:11:26,698
You are going back, Li!

611
01:11:26,783 --> 01:11:29,952
If you love China, you go back.

612
01:11:30,036 --> 01:11:31,620
I... I stay.

613
01:11:31,704 --> 01:11:33,622
You are not married!
He's not married!

614
01:11:33,706 --> 01:11:35,415
For God's sake, Ben,
calm down!

615
01:11:35,500 --> 01:11:36,416
Li...

616
01:11:36,501 --> 01:11:39,878
Li, Consul Zhang will think

617
01:11:39,963 --> 01:11:41,797
it's all my doing,
just to keep you here.

618
01:11:41,881 --> 01:11:43,548
Please, don't do this to me.

619
01:11:43,633 --> 01:11:46,093
I-I not go back.

620
01:11:46,177 --> 01:11:47,594
You have to. You have to.

621
01:11:47,679 --> 01:11:49,721
Don't you understand,
it's gonna ruin everything -

622
01:11:49,806 --> 01:11:51,181
everything I've worked for.

623
01:11:51,265 --> 01:11:54,726
I can't believe
you'd be so selfish.

624
01:12:01,776 --> 01:12:05,529
Li, no-one is
making you do this.

625
01:12:05,613 --> 01:12:09,658
Mr Foster, I want
no trouble for Ben.

626
01:12:09,742 --> 01:12:13,203
I must tell Consul Zhang
I make decision, not Ben.

627
01:12:13,287 --> 01:12:15,205
That's all very well,
but the consulate

628
01:12:15,289 --> 01:12:17,833
is Chinese territory
for all intents and purposes.

629
01:12:17,917 --> 01:12:20,210
I explained that to him
already, Charles.

630
01:12:20,211 --> 01:12:22,379
MAN: Please have a seat.

631
01:12:24,215 --> 01:12:26,049
- Well, well.
- Mmm!

632
01:12:27,593 --> 01:12:29,052
Right.

633
01:12:34,642 --> 01:12:37,853
I don't know how you
could be so foolish!

634
01:12:37,937 --> 01:12:39,938
- Hi there, I'm Li's attorney.
- A lawyer?

635
01:12:40,023 --> 01:12:41,398
And you should know better!

636
01:12:41,482 --> 01:12:43,650
I had no idea Li was
gonna bring a lawyer.

637
01:12:43,735 --> 01:12:45,485
Let's try to keep things
positive, shall we?

638
01:12:45,570 --> 01:12:47,070
LORI: I couldn't agree more.

639
01:12:47,155 --> 01:12:49,239
Thank you for coming.
So many of you.

640
01:12:49,240 --> 01:12:51,575
Consul, how are you? I'm...

641
01:12:51,659 --> 01:12:54,536
I know who you are, Mr Foster.
Pleased to meet you.

642
01:12:54,620 --> 01:12:56,830
My staff tell me you are

643
01:12:56,914 --> 01:12:58,999
a member of the US China
Friendship Association.

644
01:12:59,083 --> 01:13:00,459
Yes, I am.

645
01:13:00,543 --> 01:13:03,295
I was in China 18 months ago,
as a matter of fact.

646
01:13:03,379 --> 01:13:07,049
Vice Consul Ian is happy
to discuss legal matters

647
01:13:07,133 --> 01:13:10,802
If you would be so kind
as to go with him.

648
01:13:10,887 --> 01:13:14,056
Mr Stevenson, perhaps
you could accompany them.

649
01:13:14,140 --> 01:13:16,850
- Yes, I'd be happy to.
- I'll be right back, Li.

650
01:13:21,230 --> 01:13:25,358
Now, if you'd please allow me to speak
with Cunxin alone.

651
01:13:25,443 --> 01:13:27,569
No, I'm gonna stay with Li.

652
01:13:27,653 --> 01:13:30,280
CYNTHIA: (LAUGHS)
Well, don't you have balls!

653
01:13:30,364 --> 01:13:32,657
Well, it seems like
I need them.

654
01:13:32,742 --> 01:13:34,201
DILWORTH: I'm staying too.

655
01:13:34,285 --> 01:13:36,369
CYNTHIA: We have been
asked to leave.

656
01:13:37,622 --> 01:13:40,749
Dilworth,
I speak to Consul Zhang.

657
01:13:40,833 --> 01:13:42,292
It's OK.

658
01:13:42,293 --> 01:13:46,088
(SPEAKS CHINESE)

659
01:14:29,674 --> 01:14:31,133
What did he say?

660
01:14:32,176 --> 01:14:34,261
It's OK. We'll wait.

661
01:14:34,345 --> 01:14:35,303
OK.

662
01:14:35,388 --> 01:14:41,268
I'm interested to know
how and when, exactly, was it

663
01:14:41,352 --> 01:14:44,104
that Li Cunxin arrived
at this decision?

664
01:14:44,188 --> 01:14:47,315
With all due respect, sir, that is
not what we're here to discuss.

665
01:14:47,400 --> 01:14:49,067
I'm only too happy to discuss it.

666
01:14:49,152 --> 01:14:50,902
I think we should...

667
01:14:53,322 --> 01:14:55,490
Would you care for
some refreshments?

668
01:14:55,575 --> 01:14:59,369
No, thanks. If you'll excuse me,
I'll get back to my client.

669
01:15:00,454 --> 01:15:03,498
Please sit down, Mr Foster!

670
01:15:03,583 --> 01:15:05,917
Uh...

671
01:15:07,086 --> 01:15:08,879
- (SPEAKS CHINESE)
- No!

672
01:15:11,924 --> 01:15:13,383
What's going on?

673
01:15:13,384 --> 01:15:15,844
- Help! Someone help!
- DILWORTH: What's going on?

674
01:15:15,928 --> 01:15:18,388
Now, I'm not gonna
put up with... Goddamn!

675
01:15:18,472 --> 01:15:20,724
ELIZABETH: Li! Li!

676
01:15:20,808 --> 01:15:24,853
Help! Li! Li!

677
01:15:26,689 --> 01:15:29,900
Li! Li!

678
01:15:29,984 --> 01:15:32,110
Open this door, goddamn it!

679
01:15:32,195 --> 01:15:35,906
- Come back here!
- ELIZABETH: Li! Li!

680
01:15:35,990 --> 01:15:38,158
(SPEAKS CHINESE)

681
01:15:38,242 --> 01:15:40,994
No! Help! Li!

682
01:15:41,078 --> 01:15:42,454
Li!

683
01:15:42,538 --> 01:15:44,456
- What do we do?
- For God's sake!

684
01:15:45,958 --> 01:15:47,417
What's happened? Where's Li?

685
01:15:47,501 --> 01:15:48,919
- ELIZABETH: They took him!
- DILWORTH: Upstairs!

686
01:15:49,003 --> 01:15:50,545
LORI: There was
at least five of them.

687
01:15:52,089 --> 01:15:53,757
What have you done with Li?

688
01:15:53,841 --> 01:15:57,344
Please, I must ask
all of you to leave now.

689
01:15:57,428 --> 01:15:59,179
Excuse me, Consul,

690
01:15:59,263 --> 01:16:01,765
but I believe someone just
dragged my client out of here.

691
01:16:01,849 --> 01:16:06,394
Mr Foster, you told us you're
a supporter of US-Sino relations,

692
01:16:06,479 --> 01:16:09,731
and what is best
for US-Sino relations

693
01:16:09,815 --> 01:16:12,192
is for Li Cunxin
to return to China.

694
01:16:12,276 --> 01:16:13,652
Please, let me
try and convince him...

695
01:16:13,736 --> 01:16:16,071
CHARLES: Well, that's all
Very well but for one thing, sir.

696
01:16:16,155 --> 01:16:18,156
We may be on the territory

697
01:16:18,241 --> 01:16:20,617
of the People's Republic
of China, sir,

698
01:16:20,701 --> 01:16:22,869
but in this country,
what you're doing -

699
01:16:22,954 --> 01:16:24,371
wherever you're doing it -

700
01:16:24,455 --> 01:16:27,040
is called kidnapping,
and it's against the law.

701
01:16:33,673 --> 01:16:36,299
Well, he's just walking...
You just drove him away.

702
01:16:36,384 --> 01:16:38,677
- I think we should just leave.
- No!

703
01:16:38,761 --> 01:16:41,263
How can you even say that
after what we just saw?

704
01:16:41,347 --> 01:16:42,722
Li is a Chinese national.

705
01:16:42,807 --> 01:16:46,059
I think we should just go
and let the Chinese deal with it.

706
01:16:46,143 --> 01:16:47,560
DILWORTH: Weren't you
even listening?

707
01:16:47,645 --> 01:16:49,062
The course of Li's return to China

708
01:16:49,146 --> 01:16:50,522
has most likely already
been mapped out.

709
01:16:50,606 --> 01:16:53,984
All they need is for us to leave so they
can go through with it.

710
01:16:54,068 --> 01:16:56,278
Go through with what, how?
What are you talking about?

711
01:16:56,362 --> 01:16:59,447
Remove Li in the early hours,
heavily sedated I suspect,

712
01:16:59,532 --> 01:17:01,741
and putting him on
the first plane back to China.

713
01:17:48,789 --> 01:17:50,957
(PHONE RINGS)

714
01:17:51,042 --> 01:17:55,003
MAN: Who the hell is
calling me at this hour?

715
01:17:57,381 --> 01:17:58,465
Uh-huh.

716
01:17:58,549 --> 01:18:00,258
It's Charles Foster, Judge.

717
01:18:00,343 --> 01:18:01,926
Sorry to wake you.

718
01:18:02,011 --> 01:18:03,511
This better be good, Charles.

719
01:18:03,596 --> 01:18:06,973
Yes, well,
the Consul General of China

720
01:18:07,058 --> 01:18:09,559
is holding a ballet dancer
against his will.

721
01:18:09,560 --> 01:18:11,061
I need to get
a restraining order.

722
01:18:11,145 --> 01:18:15,899
Do I have the right to restrain
the Consul General of China?

723
01:18:15,983 --> 01:18:18,485
Sir, I sincerely hope so.

724
01:18:34,377 --> 01:18:36,127
CONSUL ZHANG: There are
members of the press outside.

725
01:18:36,212 --> 01:18:37,587
- Mm-hm.
- You're a lawyer.

726
01:18:37,671 --> 01:18:39,881
Will you make them go away, please?

727
01:18:41,509 --> 01:18:44,886
Consul, not even
the President of the United States

728
01:18:44,970 --> 01:18:46,554
can make the press go away.

729
01:18:46,639 --> 01:18:49,265
Did you call them, Mr Foster?

730
01:18:49,350 --> 01:18:50,725
No.

731
01:18:50,810 --> 01:18:53,311
I suspect they want to know
what's happened to Li.

732
01:18:53,396 --> 01:18:56,731
My advice to you is
they don't have to know.

733
01:18:56,816 --> 01:18:58,817
What's happened
can be our secret.

734
01:18:58,901 --> 01:19:01,361
But if you continue
to hold Li here,

735
01:19:01,445 --> 01:19:02,862
you're gonna put our secret

736
01:19:02,947 --> 01:19:05,365
on the front page of
every newspaper in the world.

737
01:19:14,375 --> 01:19:15,959
I'd like to use your phone again,
please.

738
01:19:18,629 --> 01:19:20,463
Phone?

739
01:19:20,548 --> 01:19:21,464
(PHONE RINGS)

740
01:19:21,549 --> 01:19:23,091
MAN: Mark Gibson,
China desk officer.

741
01:19:23,175 --> 01:19:24,634
Yes, this is Charles Foster.

742
01:19:24,635 --> 01:19:26,636
There's been an incident
at the Chinese consulate

743
01:19:26,637 --> 01:19:27,679
in Houston.

744
01:19:27,763 --> 01:19:30,432
Please alert the ambassador
in Peking immediately.

745
01:19:30,516 --> 01:19:33,935
Mr Foster, there's no need
to make any more calls.

746
01:19:34,019 --> 01:19:37,272
- Please hang up the phone.
- Where's Li? I want to see him.

747
01:19:37,356 --> 01:19:39,649
May I have your attention, please?

748
01:19:39,733 --> 01:19:41,651
I'm pleased to inform you

749
01:19:41,735 --> 01:19:45,613
that Li Cunxin has decided
to return home to China.

750
01:19:45,698 --> 01:19:47,365
You may all leave now.

751
01:19:47,450 --> 01:19:50,201
If you don't mind,
I'd like to hear that from Li.

752
01:19:50,286 --> 01:19:51,995
LORI: Yeah,
he's just saying that!

753
01:19:52,079 --> 01:19:55,457
If you do not leave voluntarily,
you will all be removed.

754
01:19:55,541 --> 01:19:56,916
DILWORTH: Oh, yeah?
Just try.

755
01:19:57,001 --> 01:19:59,878
We are not leaving
until we see Li!

756
01:19:59,962 --> 01:20:04,591
Mr Stevenson, but you assured me
you are not at fault.

757
01:20:04,675 --> 01:20:07,469
I'm not. And I'm not saying
I don't want Li to go back.

758
01:20:07,553 --> 01:20:11,639
I'm just saying...
well, let me see him.

759
01:20:17,730 --> 01:20:19,772
WOMAN: Just gonna
have to wait. Oh!

760
01:20:20,816 --> 01:20:22,233
'Houston Chronicle', Mr Foster.

761
01:20:22,318 --> 01:20:23,985
Is Li Cunxin being held
inside the consulate?

762
01:20:24,069 --> 01:20:25,945
I'm not making any statements
at this time.

763
01:20:26,030 --> 01:20:27,489
- Are you his attorney?
- Thank you.

764
01:20:41,712 --> 01:20:44,214
(SIGHS)

765
01:20:46,383 --> 01:20:47,926
You know, when I was little,

766
01:20:48,010 --> 01:20:50,178
my aunt had a cat
named Chairman Miaow.

767
01:20:50,262 --> 01:20:52,639
I could never figure out why.

768
01:20:52,723 --> 01:20:55,517
Miaow.

769
01:20:55,601 --> 01:20:58,561
- Chairman Miaow.
- Oh, for God's sake, Dilworth!

770
01:20:58,646 --> 01:21:00,980
Here, kitty-kitty!

771
01:21:01,065 --> 01:21:03,358
A Chinese puzzle
is taking place in Houston,

772
01:21:03,442 --> 01:21:06,986
involving an exchange student
from Peking, an American girl,

773
01:21:07,071 --> 01:21:09,656
the government of
the People's Republic of China

774
01:21:09,740 --> 01:21:11,324
and the Department of State.

775
01:21:11,408 --> 01:21:14,369
(REPORTERS
ALL TALKAT ONCE)

776
01:21:18,999 --> 01:21:20,750
NEWSREADER: His attorney
is believed to have

777
01:21:20,834 --> 01:21:22,252
contacted the Vice President

778
01:21:22,336 --> 01:21:24,796
to put pressure
on the Chinese Government in Peking

779
01:21:24,880 --> 01:21:27,006
in order to effect his release.

780
01:21:27,091 --> 01:21:28,841
I hope you don't get me
into trouble, Charles,

781
01:21:28,926 --> 01:21:30,426
or you're gonna be sorry now.

782
01:21:30,511 --> 01:21:32,011
I hope so too, Judge.

783
01:21:32,096 --> 01:21:34,097
I just need you to sign
this restraining order.

784
01:21:34,181 --> 01:21:36,516
Let's say we worry
about that later, hmm?

785
01:21:36,600 --> 01:21:38,685
You better take a look at this.

786
01:21:45,442 --> 01:21:48,653
(REPORTERS CLAMOUR)

787
01:21:51,657 --> 01:21:53,449
Excuse me, please. Thank you.

788
01:21:58,747 --> 01:21:59,914
MAN: Yes?

789
01:21:59,999 --> 01:22:01,708
I have an order I'm serving

790
01:22:01,792 --> 01:22:03,668
under authority
of the US Marshal.

791
01:22:03,752 --> 01:22:05,128
We open at nine o'clock.

792
01:22:05,212 --> 01:22:07,046
Would you please tell
Consul Zhang

793
01:22:07,131 --> 01:22:08,673
that Charles Foster is here?

794
01:22:08,757 --> 01:22:09,882
Wait.

795
01:22:09,967 --> 01:22:11,426
- Mr Foster?
- Not now!

796
01:22:12,761 --> 01:22:15,722
Sir, you should know
the Vice President

797
01:22:15,806 --> 01:22:17,348
has had discussions with
Premier Deng Xiaoping.

798
01:22:17,433 --> 01:22:20,268
We expect instructions will soon be
issued from Peking,

799
01:22:20,352 --> 01:22:22,020
via the Chinese Embassy
in Washington.

800
01:22:22,104 --> 01:22:25,064
(CLOCK TICKS)

801
01:22:33,449 --> 01:22:36,409
(SIGHS DEEPLY)

802
01:24:40,325 --> 01:24:41,284
(MAN CALLS OUT)

803
01:25:44,348 --> 01:25:47,308
Li?

804
01:25:47,392 --> 01:25:50,311
Come to bed, please.

805
01:25:50,395 --> 01:25:53,689
You can't keep doing this
night after night.

806
01:25:55,108 --> 01:25:56,526
They're watching.

807
01:25:56,610 --> 01:25:59,028
There's no-one, Li.
No-one's watching.

808
01:25:59,112 --> 01:26:02,156
Come on, come back to bed.

809
01:26:32,563 --> 01:26:34,188
Hello, Li.

810
01:26:35,440 --> 01:26:36,899
Hello, Ben.

811
01:26:40,779 --> 01:26:43,322
Um, we go to Florida.

812
01:26:43,407 --> 01:26:47,827
Liz's mother, she live there,
in West Palm Beach.

813
01:26:47,911 --> 01:26:51,998
Hmm. What are you going to do
when you get there?

814
01:26:53,458 --> 01:26:54,876
Get job.

815
01:26:54,960 --> 01:26:56,419
What, in a supermarket?

816
01:26:56,503 --> 01:26:59,463
No, I go for audition. Liz too.

817
01:26:59,548 --> 01:27:02,884
Oh, no, Li. It... Oh!

818
01:27:04,094 --> 01:27:06,178
It's not that easy, you know.

819
01:27:06,263 --> 01:27:08,764
I mean, it takes time
to get established.

820
01:27:08,849 --> 01:27:10,975
And I know this isn't
your home,

821
01:27:11,059 --> 01:27:13,436
but right now,
it's the next best thing.

822
01:27:13,520 --> 01:27:17,148
You don't know a soul in America,
outside of Houston.

823
01:27:17,232 --> 01:27:20,818
Of course,
you're a brilliant dancer

824
01:27:20,903 --> 01:27:22,778
and you're very popular here,
so I'd be lying

825
01:27:22,863 --> 01:27:24,947
if I said I was doing it
entirely for you.

826
01:27:27,075 --> 01:27:27,992
Elizabeth?

827
01:27:28,076 --> 01:27:30,411
(STAMMERS)

828
01:27:30,495 --> 01:27:31,746
She's just...

829
01:27:31,830 --> 01:27:34,749
She's not good enough
to dance with the company, Li.

830
01:27:36,585 --> 01:27:39,337
But, you know, the company
is having open auditions.

831
01:27:39,421 --> 01:27:41,839
We're required to do that once a year.
They're coming up.

832
01:27:41,924 --> 01:27:46,093
- Alright?
- Alright, I'll think about it.

833
01:27:47,137 --> 01:27:48,888
Alright.

834
01:28:02,861 --> 01:28:04,278
What did he want?

835
01:28:05,656 --> 01:28:10,534
He, um... offer me
a contract, as soloist.

836
01:28:10,619 --> 01:28:13,079
- Soloist?
- Yeah.

837
01:28:13,163 --> 01:28:16,832
Wow! Did he say
anything about me?

838
01:28:18,585 --> 01:28:20,544
Yes.

839
01:28:20,629 --> 01:28:23,047
He said you can
go for audition.

840
01:28:23,131 --> 01:28:24,840
- Audition?
- Yes.

841
01:28:24,925 --> 01:28:27,510
Liz, you very good dancer.

842
01:28:27,594 --> 01:28:29,762
The open auditions.

843
01:28:29,846 --> 01:28:34,475
Yes. Maybe we dance
in the company together.

844
01:28:34,559 --> 01:28:36,686
Be good, no?

845
01:28:36,770 --> 01:28:39,146
Mm-hm. Yeah.

846
01:28:40,941 --> 01:28:43,943
- If you still want go to Florida...
- No.

847
01:28:44,027 --> 01:28:46,570
No, this is a great
opportunity for you.

848
01:28:46,655 --> 01:28:48,239
Are you sure, Liz?

849
01:28:48,323 --> 01:28:49,824
Yeah, I'm sure. Yeah.

850
01:28:51,326 --> 01:28:52,785
Congratulations.

851
01:28:54,246 --> 01:28:58,040
('DANSE DES CYGNES'
FROM 'SWAN LAKE' PLAYS)

852
01:28:58,125 --> 01:29:00,167
Keep it crisp.

853
01:29:02,170 --> 01:29:03,671
Lori, try not to pull focus.

854
01:29:05,298 --> 01:29:06,757
You're a unit.

855
01:29:10,262 --> 01:29:11,971
Alright, Lori?
Lori, you're standing out.

856
01:29:12,055 --> 01:29:13,597
Back to the top.

857
01:29:13,682 --> 01:29:15,891
Come on, once again.

858
01:29:28,196 --> 01:29:29,613
Li: Lori?

859
01:29:31,700 --> 01:29:33,409
LORI: He just put me back
in the corps.

860
01:29:33,493 --> 01:29:34,952
Li: What for? Why?

861
01:29:35,037 --> 01:29:37,747
I think he's trying to get me
to walk away from my contract.

862
01:29:37,831 --> 01:29:40,082
No! You prima ballerina.

863
01:29:40,167 --> 01:29:42,001
Not anymore.

864
01:29:44,379 --> 01:29:47,173
LORI: Mary McKendry,
Ben's favourite.

865
01:29:47,257 --> 01:29:49,467
He got her back from
the Australian Ballet.

866
01:29:50,510 --> 01:29:52,511
You must have met her
in China.

867
01:29:55,932 --> 01:29:58,100
She's gonna be doing
Swan Lake with you.

868
01:29:59,144 --> 01:30:02,438
Lori, Ben do this to you
because you help me.

869
01:30:02,522 --> 01:30:05,149
No, Li, that's not true.

870
01:30:06,943 --> 01:30:08,652
Yes, it is.

871
01:30:08,737 --> 01:30:10,404
I cause many problems.

872
01:30:10,489 --> 01:30:15,284
For you, for Ben, for Liz.

873
01:30:15,368 --> 01:30:17,036
For my family.

874
01:30:18,497 --> 01:30:20,289
Have you tried
contacting them?

875
01:30:21,458 --> 01:30:23,709
I write letter. Nothing.

876
01:30:23,794 --> 01:30:25,461
What about calling?

877
01:30:25,545 --> 01:30:27,213
No.

878
01:30:27,297 --> 01:30:31,801
Making too much trouble,
maybe danger for my family.

879
01:30:31,885 --> 01:30:33,469
Better not.

880
01:30:33,553 --> 01:30:36,764
Better they forget
their sixth son.

881
01:31:15,971 --> 01:31:17,555
(COCKS GUN)

882
01:31:17,639 --> 01:31:18,556
(GASPS)

883
01:31:18,640 --> 01:31:20,057
(BANG!)

884
01:31:20,142 --> 01:31:21,559
(CHIME RATTLES)

885
01:31:23,478 --> 01:31:25,479
You're OK. You're OK.

886
01:31:25,564 --> 01:31:27,523
Shh, shh, shh.

887
01:31:28,900 --> 01:31:30,484
It was just a dream.

888
01:31:31,528 --> 01:31:33,487
Just a dream. Shh.

889
01:31:33,572 --> 01:31:37,408
(DRAMATIC ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYS)

890
01:33:08,333 --> 01:33:09,833
Hi.

891
01:33:13,463 --> 01:33:15,756
I come home, right?

892
01:33:15,840 --> 01:33:18,008
Big mess.

893
01:33:18,093 --> 01:33:21,053
What's... Rice in sink.

894
01:33:21,137 --> 01:33:22,513
That's no good.

895
01:33:22,597 --> 01:33:24,014
So that's why you're angry.

896
01:33:24,099 --> 01:33:27,393
Want me to cook and clean
for you? I'm not your mother.

897
01:33:27,477 --> 01:33:29,979
Here, I got you some noodles.
No, you not my mother.

898
01:33:30,063 --> 01:33:33,691
My mother, she work
very hard, all day, all her life.

899
01:33:33,775 --> 01:33:35,192
What you do?

900
01:33:35,277 --> 01:33:37,444
What do you think I do?

901
01:33:37,529 --> 01:33:40,406
Everything is fine for you.
You have your career.

902
01:33:40,490 --> 01:33:42,116
It's not fine, Liz.

903
01:33:42,200 --> 01:33:44,159
You not understand!

904
01:33:44,244 --> 01:33:45,869
No, you don't understand.

905
01:33:45,954 --> 01:33:47,454
I want to dance, Li!

906
01:33:47,539 --> 01:33:48,956
I have my dreams too.

907
01:33:49,040 --> 01:33:51,417
At least you can go to sleep
at night thinking about yours.

908
01:33:51,501 --> 01:33:54,336
In night, I think of
my family in China.

909
01:33:54,421 --> 01:33:56,630
I worry, Liz. There's no sleep.

910
01:33:56,715 --> 01:34:00,134
Just nightmares
and terrible feeling all the time.

911
01:34:00,218 --> 01:34:02,803
Well what about my feelings, huh?
What about me?

912
01:34:02,887 --> 01:34:05,681
You don't understand.

913
01:34:05,765 --> 01:34:08,767
No, stop telling me
I don't understand.

914
01:34:08,852 --> 01:34:10,853
I want to dance, Li.

915
01:34:10,937 --> 01:34:14,565
I've tried to be what you want
me to be, and I can't do it!

916
01:34:14,649 --> 01:34:17,192
I can't do this anymore.

917
01:34:27,203 --> 01:34:29,538
I'm going to San Francisco
to audition.

918
01:34:30,582 --> 01:34:33,917
I need to get into a company.
You understand, don't you, Li?

919
01:34:36,004 --> 01:34:39,089
Yes, I understand.

920
01:34:43,762 --> 01:34:45,220
When we got married...

921
01:34:47,057 --> 01:34:48,974
...was it because you loved me

922
01:34:49,059 --> 01:34:51,268
or was it because
you wanted to stay?

923
01:34:55,273 --> 01:34:57,858
Bec... because...

924
01:34:57,942 --> 01:35:00,069
...because I love you.

925
01:35:05,492 --> 01:35:07,117
I love you too.

926
01:35:41,319 --> 01:35:44,405
WOMAN: It's been
five long years since Li Cunxin

927
01:35:44,489 --> 01:35:47,408
made his dramatic leap
to freedom in Houston, Texas

928
01:35:47,492 --> 01:35:48,992
from communist China.

929
01:35:49,077 --> 01:35:50,494
He's here in Washington

930
01:35:50,578 --> 01:35:52,913
and he'll be dancing at
the Kennedy Center tonight,

931
01:35:52,997 --> 01:35:55,666
and we're thrilled to have him
with us on the show today.

932
01:35:55,750 --> 01:35:57,668
Welcome to Washington, Li.

933
01:35:57,752 --> 01:35:59,545
Thank you.
It's great to be here.

934
01:35:59,629 --> 01:36:02,131
Li, you've toured with
the Houston Ballet Company

935
01:36:02,215 --> 01:36:03,882
and danced all over the world,

936
01:36:03,967 --> 01:36:06,009
but your freedom
came at a price.

937
01:36:07,470 --> 01:36:08,929
Yes, it did.

938
01:36:09,013 --> 01:36:11,473
I haven't been allowed
to go back to China since.

939
01:36:11,558 --> 01:36:13,642
But your entire family is there.

940
01:36:13,643 --> 01:36:15,185
Yes.

941
01:36:15,270 --> 01:36:16,645
Have you heard from them?

942
01:36:16,729 --> 01:36:18,647
Do you even know
how they are?

943
01:36:18,731 --> 01:36:20,983
No, I haven't heard from them.

944
01:36:21,067 --> 01:36:24,069
How do you survive,
not knowing?

945
01:36:24,154 --> 01:36:28,490
I carry a picture of them
wherever I go.

946
01:36:30,243 --> 01:36:32,953
And when I dance,
I dance for them.

947
01:36:33,037 --> 01:36:35,998
(SLOW, MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYS)

948
01:37:12,827 --> 01:37:15,913
I saw you dance together
in New York.

949
01:37:15,997 --> 01:37:18,624
I've never seen
such exquisite partnering.

950
01:37:18,708 --> 01:37:21,335
Thank you very much.

951
01:37:21,419 --> 01:37:23,253
You made it look so natural.

952
01:37:23,338 --> 01:37:24,838
That's because he is.

953
01:37:24,923 --> 01:37:28,550
Well, it does help to have
the right partner.

954
01:37:39,020 --> 01:37:42,606
Li, there's someone here
who wants to see you.

955
01:37:42,690 --> 01:37:46,026
Hello, Cunxin.

956
01:37:46,110 --> 01:37:48,779
I'm working at the embassy
in Washington now.

957
01:37:48,863 --> 01:37:52,074
You have made us
very proud tonight.

958
01:37:52,158 --> 01:37:54,576
Thank you. Thank you.

959
01:37:54,661 --> 01:37:56,328
Excuse me.

960
01:37:56,412 --> 01:37:58,539
Your mother and father
are well.

961
01:37:58,623 --> 01:38:00,749
I took the liberty of checking.

962
01:38:02,293 --> 01:38:04,086
You don't know
how much that means to me.

963
01:38:05,171 --> 01:38:08,340
If I have a dream, it's to be able
to go back one day.

964
01:38:08,424 --> 01:38:10,467
I know.

965
01:38:11,844 --> 01:38:14,054
Is there any chance?

966
01:38:14,138 --> 01:38:17,266
I'm afraid not enough time
has passed, Cunxin.

967
01:38:17,350 --> 01:38:20,727
But I will see what I can do.

968
01:38:20,812 --> 01:38:24,022
Thank you.
I really appreciate that.

969
01:38:24,107 --> 01:38:25,315
Thank you.

970
01:38:34,325 --> 01:38:37,286
(ORCHESTRA
TUNES INSTRUMENTS)

971
01:38:41,791 --> 01:38:43,500
Ladies and gentlemen,

972
01:38:43,585 --> 01:38:45,919
I'm sorry, there's going to be
a slight delay.

973
01:38:46,004 --> 01:38:49,089
We have some VIPs coming in
from out of town,

974
01:38:49,173 --> 01:38:52,384
and when they arrive,
which won't be long now,

975
01:38:52,468 --> 01:38:54,511
I'm sure they'll be forgiven.

976
01:38:54,596 --> 01:38:56,263
So thank you very much

977
01:38:56,347 --> 01:38:58,390
for your patience
and understanding.

978
01:39:00,018 --> 01:39:01,810
(KNOCKAT DOOR)

979
01:39:01,811 --> 01:39:04,354
Uh, Li, we're just holding
the curtain for 15 minutes.

980
01:39:04,439 --> 01:39:05,439
Why?

981
01:39:05,523 --> 01:39:06,898
There's some VIPs arriving.

982
01:39:06,983 --> 01:39:07,941
OK.

983
01:39:17,410 --> 01:39:18,619
Thanks.

984
01:39:22,999 --> 01:39:24,416
Hey.

985
01:39:24,500 --> 01:39:25,917
- Good luck.
- Thank you.

986
01:39:29,756 --> 01:39:32,716
MAN: (OVER P.A.) Ladies and
gentlemen, five minute call.

987
01:40:06,209 --> 01:40:09,670
Just along here,
ifyou'll follow me.

988
01:40:15,134 --> 01:40:17,219
WOMAN: I think that's his family.

989
01:40:17,303 --> 01:40:19,388
WOMAN 2: Oh, isn't that wonderful?!

990
01:40:28,648 --> 01:40:30,190
Ni hao.

991
01:40:30,274 --> 01:40:31,692
I'm Ben Stevenson.

992
01:40:31,776 --> 01:40:33,402
I'm so glad you're here.

993
01:40:33,486 --> 01:40:34,611
Ni hao.

994
01:40:34,696 --> 01:40:36,113
Please, come to your seats.

995
01:40:48,251 --> 01:40:49,918
What's that for?

996
01:40:50,002 --> 01:40:51,837
Don't know.

997
01:40:53,506 --> 01:40:54,923
Here you are.

998
01:40:58,010 --> 01:40:59,761
(SPEAKS CHINESE)

999
01:40:59,846 --> 01:41:01,930
Oh, xie xie!

1000
01:41:10,940 --> 01:41:12,858
(ORCHESTRA PLAYS
'THE RITE OF SPRING'

1001
01:41:12,942 --> 01:41:14,401
BY IGOR STRAVINSKY)

1002
01:44:36,479 --> 01:44:39,773
AUDIENCE MEMBERS: Bravo! Bravo!

1003
01:44:45,404 --> 01:44:48,823
(WILD CHEERING
AND APPLAUSE)

1004
01:44:52,620 --> 01:44:54,579
- Fantastic!
- He was superb.

1005
01:45:42,336 --> 01:45:44,129
(SPEAKS CHINESE)

1006
01:45:52,972 --> 01:45:54,723
(PARENTS BOTH
SPEAK CHINESE)

1007
01:47:28,234 --> 01:47:31,194
(MAN SHOUTS IN CHINESE)

1008
01:47:32,988 --> 01:47:35,949
(CHILDREN SHOUT)

1009
01:48:02,351 --> 01:48:04,018
You've met my parents.

1010
01:48:05,771 --> 01:48:07,605
This is my oldest brother.

1011
01:48:11,735 --> 01:48:13,278
This is my fifth brother.

1012
01:48:36,427 --> 01:48:37,635
Cunxin!

1013
01:48:39,013 --> 01:48:40,638
Ni hao.

