I'm Agatha Weiss. I asked for a limousine.
A great.
There were more.
Been here before?
I have to collect yourself first.
This is 45 per hour, minimum 2 hours.
Tenez, 200 dollars.
You have a map of the stars homes?
It is waste of money, except to see a cheesy TV.
Where are you from?
Jupiter.
Florida.
You are in LA for...?
I just see family.
You drive stars?
I had Al Gore once.
Surely the most famous.
J'ai aussi eu Tatum O'Neal pour son reality-show.
Chuck Lorre.
He created a Half Men.
A lot of producers, filmmakers.
Juliette Lewis.
She is a Scientologist.
I think convert. It's good for my career.
Are you an actor?
Actor, writer.
I know Carrie Fisher.
Really?
- But how?
- Met on Twitter.
We are very friendly.
I help for his new novel.
It could become an HBO film.
What is this place?
I thought it was on the map.
There was a big house.
The childhood home of Benjie Weiss.
How do you know?
J'étais sa baby-sitter.
The evil babysitter, it was me.
Strange!
My agent wants me to play in Babysitter 2.
It is still not clear but
Jakob Leitner, my personal trainer, got me an audition.
It is very influential. We were together in Beverly.
Fingers crossed.
Cheers!
I'm not hoping for you to come.
Why is that?
You're so caught.
Not for you.
J'ai adoré Bad Babysitter.
We made $ 780 million worldwide.
People tend to forget.
You do not have iPad?
Arnold, Trouve's an iPad. A mini.
We'll cram shit in 3D.
We have jackets in satin.
With "I was a naughty babysitter" in gold letters.
How did you get AIDS?
I do not have AIDS, it is a non-Hodgkin lymphoma.
You know what...
I'll make a movie about your life.
Ryan Gosling will play my role. And I yours.
We will go together at the Oscars.
- Non-Hodgkins?
- Désolé.
- What is this disease, damn!
- Something to blood, I think.
This is the "no" that annoys me. You did or you did not.
You were serious?
We could show Ryan. He will like.
We could show Ryan?
You arrive only to wipe your ass.
It would be very moving.
I even have a title: A Life of shit.
No pie in the sky!
Dixit le grand euthanasiste!
Rabbi of life and death.
Le Grand say. Le Grand zen archer.
I found your nickname: the Holocaust Museum!
Stop, Benjie.
Stop?
I have a better idea.
Show me your pussy!
I know you have one.
Kind of Jew motherfucker!
- They offer how much?
- Five million.
Plus 10%.
That request Genie?
Eight.
20% of revenues.
What do you think?
We have them by the balls.
Super.
When is the hearing?
This is not an audition.
That is true.
And that's when the urine test?
We see them Friday at 10 o'clock.
They want to make sure you're clean.
But the agreement depends on the match?
- They protect their franchise.
- It's me, the franchise.
Tu veux manger, Stafford?
I listened to a tape of the Dalai Lama.
Forget his politics. This guy is a pro.
Free Tibet! But Tibet is overpriced.
I even kept the receipt from Amazon.
Buddhists say a prayer...
- Genie will be there?
- She does not prefer.
I want her to come.
"Do eaters, what they eat and eating
"Are completely without ego."
I go into my room.
Name, mum...
Do not do me wrong...
Do not enter my room...
quand je dors.
Do not enter my room when I sleep.
I will not let you do.
Kind of bitch!
Tu me fais mal.
But how?
Did I hurt you?
I was your girl
and yet, you have hurt me.
Why, Mom?
Your parents beat you? It's not an excuse.
Stop forgive Havana.
I do not care what they did. They would have killed you.
I'll get you killed...
How dare you do that to a child?
How could you do this to me, your daughter?
I want to be free, Clarice.
Clarice, mom, free me!
I want to be free.
I want to win back the stolen years.
Please...
I now rely on a special item.
All that is stored in the thighs.
Regains years, Havana.
Regains the years stolen from the little girl.
Rebecca, stop. You're a patient here.
I want to help you, not...
You do not think I fired?
I think you do not want to.
You need help.
Will not you help me?
Not like that...
We should think about what we do.
Granted on all flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
I write your name
Miss Havana?
Miss Genie is there.
How are you, darling?
It's going... I had a very hard session with Stafford.
You're so brave!
I do not feel brave.
I need a slave.
Et ta fameuse adage?
I had to fire her.
- But why?
- She stole me.
My God... Incredible!
She stole money from me, a ring and Vicodin.
My God!
And you caught in the act?
- You called the police?
- I have threatened to do so.
And she's in the hospital?
With all the cameos slaves.
They have their special wing.
I'll call Carrie.
No. Love her all you want but do not fuck with that.
Ça fierce brown.
I have to see her at a party. It will give me names.
Well...
Et pour Stolen Waters?
They are all at Sundance.
Everyone except me!
It was the best reading of my life.
I'm totally amazed!
I know.
The only thing that worries might be
to cast a star in a supporting role.
But everyone does!
It's a film, rather minor, your mother has turned
il ya 30 ans.
It could be great.
It's a reinvention.
It's an art film.
Who do you think has had the idea of ??watching my mother
Stolen Waters si elle vivait?
That's me!
I gave the idea to Damien there 4 years.
I know.
I deserve the role and being credited as a producer.
Worth an Oscar for Supporting Actress,
this is a second chance...
and it is Damien Javitz.
It raises the actors!
And I was great.
Sterl always does?
Il m'est redevable.
I introduced him to Harvey, who produced.
I've talked to Harvey,
who will talk to Damien. But you know...
Harvey sera toujours Harvey
Sterl and can talk...
You know we did everything to.
But ultimately, it's an art film.
You'd be great in this role. But in case you've forgotten,
your mother is dead but a cult actress.
Et Damien Javitz
is not PT Anderson.
- There are so many movies...
- Really?
- Des blockbusters.
- Où ça?
Où ça, Genie?
The other day, Jacob said,
as I know a lot of celebrities,
I should become an agent.
You know what it feels like to tell you that?
All I'm doing
in my life and in my analysis,
it is for this role.
Ça ne va pas?
I have cramps.
- Ça va bien?
- Non, ça va mal.
The mother-daughter incest, it's too 80s.
I'm not Anne Sexton.
The shock will subside.
What there was, Havana?
You thought it would be the sixth sense? The dead speak?
You want to know what the dead?
You know what the Hell?
A drug-free world!
But what is happening?
Le pire porn cliché, Vana,
this fantasy child rape! Screws, whore!
Or die.
It's not a little pathetic to want to be me on the screen?
You hate me,
but you're desperate to be me!
You want this role, but you will not get it.
You do not even have the talent.
I had and I was young and beautiful.
You? With your tits hanging and your old worn hole?
It stinks even more than me!
Who is this?
This is non-Hodgkins.
What are you doing here?
On my school notebooks
On my desk and trees
Snow on the sand
I write your name
I'm going to make this film...
You are there for that?
Arnold said that t'a?
Granted on all flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
I write your name
On my school notebooks
On my desk and trees
Snow on the sand
I write your name
Granted on all flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
I write your name
Freedom
See you at school with Bad Babysitters.
I'm stuck?
Not at all. You're the first.
Your holidays are hectic.
Rather productive.
It has not been easy
for any of us.
But he learned a lot.
Absolutely.
I myself went through this drug trip.
Not at your age, of course, but...
We all did stupid things, right?
It has happened to you young.
Benjie has matured a lot.
A lot.
In Praise the Heavy, I was getting 300,000 a week.
I was 9 years old.
It is not amazing?
The crazy money.
For all.
It was well worth.
You have many fans.
I was beyond...
Mother Teresa péterait sinkers before such dough.
She has already lost it.
She died. You can not fart higher!
We have a warrant. Cristina knows.
And you too.
We must protect the franchise.
We played it tight...
Arnold, your team was great.
Nothing in the tabloids.
An adult into rehab, it can boost a career.
A kid is different.
We understand, Jeb.
Although Drew has benefited.
Friends,
we're on your side. It must be understood.
We would not be here without a dose of confidence.
- There are already a budget?
- 58.
But it is confidential.
We lost it. But we did not count on it.
Emma Watson is signed for the young mother.
We will have fun though.
One must know how Benjie was detoxified.
Benjie went into a private home.
That the partner of my husband.
Your mother is really great.
She knows bumping without a trace.
Whore.
One ever again humiliate me like this.
Never.
It's over, baby.
On les a.
Damien finds me too old?
Et le casting? Sarah Horowitz?
Havana, the character is simply younger.
This is Sarah Horowitz who gave me my first role.
He must have seen me in this horror on TNT.
Do not work for money.
We can not all be as malignant as you.
Tu stuck me soutenir, Sterl?
You will speak to Damien?
You know I do.
Il pense à Azita Wachtel.
She was nominated for an Oscar and she is Canadian.
You know the reputation of this Wachtel?
It would leave producers piss him in the ass.
It's good to know.
You know him well, Damien...
This is the third time I called in vain.
Your reading was great.
The tea in the dit?
He said it was "very strong."
He really said?
Yes.
I must have this role. It would be awesome together.
I thought it already was.
Diandra?
But it is very old!
She is 23 years old! 16 on IMDb.
- How do you know she is 23 years old?
- Large pierced lips.
Please take 23 years for that?
It is tattooed on his ass.
She is post-menopausal!
Cool, girls, right?
- Rhett, you told him?
- You will not believe it.
It's too weird. I will not tell you.
It's starting to like me.
It's a crazy...
She posted 6,000 messages on my Facebook in 2 months.
You're going to marry?
- Fuck it, Rhett.
- Lick it for its rules.
- Do not be vulgar.
- He does not like that.
It can not... because you're menopausal.
Ta gueule!
Calm down!
We discover a technician sold him my shit
pour 3000 dollars.
Disais Tu, ta merde?
Your entendu as well. Ma merde.
It is a high-end shit.
It is made from rice Nobu.
Directly to your trailer?
When the guy is emptying...
What does she do?
It stores it... just in case.
- Where is she the money?
- A brown box...
Benjie, you're disgusting!
I offer daily specials when I get the shits...
- Liquidation of stock.
- Everything must go.
One of...
Who is this?
- Starla Gent. Chanteuse country.
- Elle a gagné The Voice?
She made second. It's a fucking bitch.
And a great actress!
Javitz gave him your role.
Ta gueule!
I wonder if Blake Shelton pissed in the ass.
To Sam, elle you plait?
You can kiss it, you know.
She wants to play in your film. And she has good Vicodin.
It's been almost 90 days.
- What?
- That I'm sober, asshole.
My God, what a stench!
This bitch the TV was in the toilet.
What's her name?
As if a corpse had farted.
It's not Sterl Carruth?
Oui, avec Havana Segrand.
We have the same agent.
How old is she?
Totally menopause.
Beyond.
Almost dead. Older than my grandmother.
No, it's a GMB, Grandmother fuckable.
- They fuck together?
- Genre fucking compassion.
As nurses who violate the old to the hospital?
His mother did not die in a fire?
Comme Jack Cassidy.
Who is it?
Swinger deviation. The father of David Cassidy.
- And who is it?
- The brother of Shawn Cassidy.
You know that his mother was a very cool actress.
Clarice Taggart?
A & E did a documentary on it. It was very cool.
She was young.
What's this?
Hi, Damien, what's happening?
Yes, I know.
I am ready to wear two earrings.
Master
I'm with my kids and I tell them a story.
Can I call you?
Yes, I remember you. Right away.
Cite mon nom quand tu parles.
You're so crazy.
Suck me and say something about you.
Je t'aime discussion.
You were a little girl so pretty... But you were lying.
How could you become this monster who lies?
What's going on?
Explain to me.
I'm sorry...
I was not comfortable.
I'm not terrible, as dyke.
You should take a Klonopin.
I know a man
who lives by the sword of Damocles we call AIDS.
"When my time comes," me-he said,
"I'll be ready.
"My bags are packed, the threshold of the door."
I love it.
I really like.
There is a moment in our lives and our therapy
when our eyes linger on luggage near the door.
After crying.
After suffering.
After dried up fountains of memory
and bloodied our hands on the remains of our parents.
I thought Garry Marshall would be there,
it was a meeting, not a hearing.
They gave me the wrong route. I had to walk two terminals.
Upon arrival, I stank.
And the casting director did not even calculates me.
She passes me by without saying hello.
And she told me that Garry perhaps even expected me.
This is Garry Marshall, not Bertolucci. His films are not even more money.
And I know Garry well.
She said they will shoot me.
And me. "Sorry, but I need makeup"
And she said: "Well, you do it or not?"
Like this!
And I can not go, Jacob!
I'm so tired and it's so pathetic...
This is Carrie?
In addition, Jacob more.
Salut, Carrie!
How are you?
When I get back in touch with myself, I'll tell you.
It was crazy.
Tu as fini le tournage?
We return to Prague tomorrow to redo some scenes.
You make the Javitz?
I hope. Did you hear something?
Genie told me that you have prepared yourself.
It would be so great that you play your own mother.
Every girl should be so lucky, right?
You know Damien?
We just had dinner together in Tangier.
If you see him, tell him to get involved.
Genie m'a parlé of Adagio.
- You've had a long time?
- Three years.
Still Looking an assistant?
Yes. You became my agency hiring.
Do me a favour.
Ça va sembler this bizarre,
but I want you to see a girl he met on the Internet.
I'm so nervous.
It's okay. Want some tea?
Thank you. Yes.
Your home is so beautiful.
The walls are so thick and the wind organ...
They come from a monastery in Dharamsala.
I met the Dalai Lama, this is a very cool guy.
He laughs a lot.
It's like a guy with whom you would want to hang out,
but it's impossible because it is the Dalai Lama.
Thank you for tea.
Maria is in the hospital. My housekeeper.
One of his daughters is sick. It must have 40 kids.
So you know why you're here.
Thanks to Carrie.
You have known about the Net?
She was looking for someone on Twitter, for a novel.
About a girl who had been burned.
I answered and it was seen at a Star Wars convention.
It must have been strange for you.
She is so great and so funny.
We're a little crazy, we each finished the other's sentences.
You came to see her?
I just wanted to see Hollywood.
She invited me to the Four Seasons for breakfast incl.
Il y avait Zooey Deschanel.
And Sally Draper, the girl from Mad Men. It was awesome.
You have a family?
Florida. That's where I'm from.
Agatha...
We can talk about burns?
I worked in a planetarium.
I was 12.
There was a short-circuit
and I remained inside...
like a bitch.
It's not a glamorous job.
I've never known glamor.
Basically, the job would be
to shop and arrange the small stuff.
Miss Segrand, I'll be the most loyal, most skilled
and the best imaginable personal assistant.
You have a car?
You know how to drive?
I have a license in Florida.
I can rent a car. Genre...
une Mustang?
Carrie est marrante.
She knew we had to be.
You know how my mother died?
In a fire.
I think you're beautiful.
And you know who you look like?
Inside?
Havana Segrand.
- There is a race.
- What is it?
Un tour d'Hollywood. Appel cash. Holly Crest Hotel.
On my school notebooks On my desk and trees
On the sands of snow I write your name
On any given flesh On the front of my friends
On each outstretched hand I write your name
Freedom
You have survived a fire?
I never knew what had happened.
I think I was drunk and I fell asleep.
What will you do in Hollywood?
Your money will fly away if you ride in a limo...
In fact, I have a job.
Ah oui? Où?
You connais Havana Segrand?
Reputation, yes.
I am his personal assistant.
Carrie Fisher is the connection?
Eh bien oui...
Havana lent me a car.
You want to have dinner together?
Pas ce week-end.
Is dois...
scénar my work.
I have a great movie idea. One could write a whole.
The theme of incest. But it's a bit overrated.
Sexual abuse: the new religion!
In fact, my parents were brother and sister? It's a secret.
It could be like that... confession.
Sounds a bit jaded, but also indie film.
I would like to play. With you, if you want.
It would be pretentious
if we keep the mythological side.
Écoute, Agatha...
I think you're crazy.
Yes. So what?
I mean...
What I'm saying is...
I already dating someone.
I wish you success.
I do not want your money.
Kiss my ass.
It was like a dream, but damn, it seemed so real!
Continue.
A daughter, whom I had met in the hospital.
He was sent to an iPad, but they said she was dead.
She came in my room at home.
It was fucking me quite a fright.
I may be dreaming.
Do I get mad?
Do not.
The time has come to confront you with some things.
Ma s?ur?
Yes.
She always wanted to get married.
It was his play.
It was the ceremony.
It's strange, is not it?
You think I'm crazy, like it?
Do not.
More...
must be able to resist.
Mom and Dad had gone to a party.
I must have been six or seven years.
That night, when everything happened,
we did the wedding ceremony.
She gave me the so-called vitamins.
And I woke up in the hospital, I had a stomach wash.
Firefighters had taken me and I've never reviewed.
You asked your parents?
They never talk about it.
This daughter of the hospital...
Harriet, what should I do?
What should I do if it comes back?
You call me.
I'm afraid when I see it.
It looks real. I do not want to be hospitalized.
My career is already pretty crappy.
You have experienced trials as a child.
Do I have a split personality?
I do not see it.
What does she want me, bitch?
When you went out of your hiding and you have expressed your fear,
Mom did not appreciate.
But what may be called, there is treatment.
She wants me to fail. I will not yield.
This is my little Vana.
Rends-lui hommage.
The "divinity of Imago" as Jung called.
For us, it is the "magical child".
And that child will not fail.
Lie down.
I hired a girl.
This is crazy.
Why is it crazy?
It is disfigured.
Following a fire, it has serious burns on his face.
Where does it come from?
The Floride.
This is crazy.
She showed up at my door.
I feel that in this engaging, I found myself.
People do not come into our lives by chance. We are convened.
Two women associated with fire.
I bet those visions will disappear.
You really think so?
You welcome mom home.
You dis him: "Maman,
"Between, you do not scare me.
"I'm invested.
"The soup is served.
"This is my home, Mom.
"I built upon my affliction and my hopes.
"And you can not hurt me.
"I am a magic child. So between.
"My home is your home."
Now take a deep breath.
Breathe!
And if she comes here?
She will not come.
What is she doing here?
Tourism, perhaps.
It's not funny.
We have always responded differently, you and me.
It needs to get fired.
Then what?
If it works for Havana, we know where she is.
And it saves time.
And if she saw Benjie?
It's the tabloids that worry me.
I have my class do.
On my school notebooks
On my desk and trees
Snow on the sand
I write your name
On any given flesh On the front of my friends
Son?
One second.
Between.
I saw the light.
I can not sleep.
Me neither.
Tu lisais?
A little, scénar.
It's hard, without a partner.
Mom gives me the answer.
But I like to know the replicas first.
That's what makes you a pro.
I would like to talk to you.
I take nothing.
Not even Seroquel. I have a good sponsor.
It is clean and sober for twenty years.
Il a eu Robert Downey Jr, Demi Lovato...
Do not.
Is your? s heart.
She may be back...
à Los Angeles.
She called?
Not yet.
I thought she was in jail.
At the hospital...
far from here.
But it is free, white
and 18 years old. We had to release it.
I negotiate a removal...
An expulsion?
Too bad you did not get a hast at birth.
You have brought a judge to motherhood.
Did you may have tried.
We tried lots of things.
We mostly tried to do our best.
It's in your book.
It's your big thing.
"Do your best."
It's supposed to be positive.
I do not know anything about this girl.
If I ever knew who she was...
I do not know if it is unsafe.
I knew this day would come.
I thought she would be low profile.
It was stupid.
But I want you to tell me if she tries to see you.
I'll tell you, if she goes.
We like to share, remember...
Some sleep, son.
And by the power of a word I start my life
I was born to know you
To name you
Freedom
Havana, ma chérie...
I do not know if you read it,
but they announce that Damien chose Azita.
This is hardly a surprise, but...
I am furious about the method used.
It makes me lose face.
But that's my problem, not yours.
I'm so sorry, darling.
Damien called me.
It's hard to say this on your answering machine...
I do not want you may learn by the other.
I think you have nothing to regret.
And I always thought.
I know that was important to you.
But we need you to put it behind you.
Then, forward!
I send you six scenarios.
There are plenty of awesome projects on the horizon.
Remind me when thou dost.
I embrace you.
The year will be tremendous!
I made a hole so we can see everything.
View all?
Money back guarantee.
I want to see her back zin.
Cut!
Mr zin will harvest all the laughs.
It only appears in four scenes.
And he steals all! Little shit.
Appeals Genie.
I want it to turn this little shit.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to talk to you. It can wait.
Encore et sa le studio parano the drogue?
Do not. Study the Ni ni sa parry.
On t'attend, Benjie!
Fuck you put it!
I want to eat.
My blood sugar drops when I turn back with zin shit.
You can put a burrito in the microwave? Just two minutes.
Ça va?
Very well.
I thought you worked your scenario.
I would. I have bills to pay.
Comment va le show-biz?
Ça va.
I got a call to Blue Matrix.
Tu regardes?
I do not like soaps SF.
C'est genre Battlestar Galactica,
more post-11-Septembre.
I do not believe it! I spent 18,000 dollars. Let's go!
Havana is Jerome.
Health.
It is a driver.
Brilliant.
He comes to audition for Battlestar Galactica.
In fact, Blue Matrix.
I am one of your fans.
Thank you.
Good luck!
My God!
Azita!
Sydney told me you were here.
I was going to call you. Congratulations!
Thank you. It excites me.
You'll be sublime.
And you'll love work with Damien.
It's so awesome.
I feel so good. And your mother was exceptional.
It'll be a fun challenge for me.
It will not be an imitation.
You know who will play mother?
Mom.
Hathaway.
How are you?
You adorerais Anne.
You know her? She's great.
Get on your character.
For a split second...
I thought accepting the role. Crazy, right?
You aura du...
I was at the "therapy at all costs."
As cute!
Your name is...?
This is Micah. Say hello to Havana.
Micah... tu es trop chou.
This is my timid.
It will break the hearts? c.
- Glad to have seen you.
- Me too.
In 10 minutes?
Merci, A.
Been output.
I love your new slave.
It's a horrible sentence, right?
You have a lot in common.
This horrible type first.
"I'm invested, Mom.
"The soup is served.
"I am a magic child. So between.
"My home is your home."
What do you want?
This bravado...
It's silly. Sorry.
It is only...
I feel nervous about your touch.
It's funny, but I have lost the habit of people.
I do not want to hear that.
These "incidents" of which you speak in talk shows,
these are false memories.
Liar!
Since the first day.
It's your stepfather who brought you these things. I should have seen it.
His first wife had told me he was like that.
You had to blame me for not having you protected.
Do not approach me.
You want it for that night.
"This is my home, Mom.
"I built on my pain and my hopes
"And you can not hurt me."
"Sorry.
"I was not comfortable.
"I'm not terrible, as dyke."
Are you okay?
I have the flu.
I need cigarettes.
American Spirit.
Go get me some medicine.
Ambien, Vicodin, Xanax,
Zoloft... and Astragalus
and goldenseal.
Et du thé Yogi.
Agatha...
You know Stafford Weiss? The therapist?
Do not.
Of course not.
Why? I repeat what I said a fucking corpse.
I need Tampax.
Et du Cozy Shack.
It is sold in trays, such as tapioca.
A Gate riz.
And truffles of the Maison du Chocolat.
You'll find it all at Neiman.
Come into the garden. I have to move some plants.
They are there since the earthquake.
I want to move here.
Do not worry about the tiles, we will remake them.
They have the heavy air.
Do not make me look like the bad mother. You are strong.
You already have gloves. Put all your weight into the effort.
Do it rotate like that. Do it rotate.
The door was open.
What the hell?
- It's not even past the JT?
- What?
The boy died of Azita Wachtel.
But I just see them!
He was with his father in Ojai and he drowned.
My God! But how?
In the pool.
She was not there?
I do not know. Nobody yet has the details.
But here's what we'll do. I know, it's horrible.
You could replace it.
But how?
Azita is in the hospital. She lost her head.
Sedated.
- They can run without it.
- It will not resume work.
- They turned a lot?
- Just days.
The cast called me three times.
Sarah? Thou hast remembered?
Yes. They make an offer.
Damien called?
No, but he must be devastated.
They did not make any offer without the approval of Damien.
Azita should. She is expected to resume shooting.
Go to the funeral and resume the movie.
I know it's limit, but do you want the part?
I need to talk to Damien.
Bon. But it just happened.
I could not reach anyone.
It must be said that if cated, we will win everything.
Unless they have someone else.
I'll call you when I know.
I send flowers?
You're not supposed to know.
Keeps flowers for Damien when we sign.
Come on, sing!
That's the little Micah! For the miracle!
About this Micah?
Fire and water. It is fire and him water.
Adieu!
Adieu, Micah!
Water and fire. Say it.
Excuse me.
Looking Jerome Fontana. There is a call for him.
It is a Vorbalid?
Try makeup.
What are you doing here?
Havana is in the canteen. I was looking for.
It's supposed to be a burn?
No, it's a birth mark, something like that.
You have 30 minutes. Asks a makeup artist to remake you that.
There was a tarp for the pool,
but the engine was being repaired.
He could not swim.
The father heard the phone
and he thought it was Azita. He left a second...
It's always the way it happens.
I mean, that's what we hear.
Azita en tu?
Yes, I went to her house.
I told him that you would play the role. It relieved.
Finally, apparently.
I do not feel comfortable...
Go to her house to tell her that! But we're close.
I was going to call you
to speak to you of my decision to take...
Azita, but it was such madness...
I understood, Damien. I have no problem with that.
Moi, si.
I do not like this approach.
I loved your reading.
Tu le sais.
I had reservations about the relationship with your mother.
But the film that I shoot
is so different from the original script.
In fact, it looks like there at all.
What is reproached.
The script is amazing.
Thank you.
I want you strong paths, despite the circumstances.
Nothing happens by chance.
That's what I think.
I'm glad you're here.
Victoria Rabbit. Star Channel. Are you ready?
The interview was 16 hours.
Genie did you not say?
Can you give us 15 minutes?
But we have been waiting for...
Why not talk to my co-star Jim Carrey Jr?
Here it is!
Hey, Mr. turd will zin, you want to be on TV?
Yeah.
Your ass back here.
Hello. Me is Roy.
Hé, Benjie!
Putain! Tire-toi!
All is well. I came to ask forgiveness.
How did you get in?
I work for someone who is shooting here. Havana Segrand.
You want me wrong, Agatha?
I mean you no harm.
Tu es mon petit frère.
If you try, I'll kill you. Do you understand?
Tu as faim? Un burrito?
I leave immediately.
Havana Segrand...
This is not bullshit?
It's really good. We have the same agent.
How thou art come to work for it?
Through a friend. Carrie Fisher.
For a disfigured schizo,
you're doing pretty well here.
They know you're there.
Comment?
Dad knows and sees all, if you forgot.
Watch out, though.
The old stuck you a restraining order.
Do not tell him that you saw me.
I'm not addicted to "tour page"
so if you are looking a revelation that makes your life...
It's been years that I write.
To explain.
Benjie is Jeb Berg.
I take a nap.
It is there.
I'm with my nieces Connecticut...
We at Universal. Just leave them in the train!
You're so mean!
I kiss later. You want a Cobalt?
Non. Le sucre me rend folle.
Very funny!
So mom and dad sent you in crazy?
The judges, anyway.
You look fit.
I was in major burns and after my transplant, Florida.
The homeland of Scarf ace, Tony Montana. Super.
It was you who brought it?
It is the mother of Havana.
It was you who set the fire?
It's tough.
No shit... Is that you?
I did not want to hurt you.
You know, for them? Who we are? They say?
Pills, vitamins?
Probably sleeping pills.
So you gave me pills and you damn fire to the house?
I have a little hard to believe that you would not hurt me.
I was seeing things.
- Like what?
- Children.
What were you doing when you saw them?
I told them:
"With this ring, you are consecrated to me."
I remember. It was our game.
It worked every time.
I said and they disappeared.
You should go now.
Il ya un scénario.
You are part of a beautiful mythological scenario.
Oh, mon Dieu!
Ma s?ur psychopathe va me pitcher un scénario!
Agatha, va-t'en.
And rebuke this DVD.
Do not worry, I'm not a pyromaniac.
They cut the pilot.
Your program works, Milton.
No fighting in bed
The bed is for sleeping, making love,
but not to compete.
Thank you.
On it you can mardi.
Is she here?
Salut, Agatha.
My books. Thou hast read?
Yes.
Secrets kill.
A classic.
How did you find me?
No examination, please.
- Benjie...
- Told me where you been?
How would he know? You went to see Benjie?
What a bad idea!
It was dangerous.
But the question remains:
What are you doing in Los Angeles?
I am recovering.
I wanted to make amends.
Nobody escapes the 12 steps...
Why did not you come?
It is a matter of victim.
Like: "I never promised you a rose garden."
You know why.
I do not reward a murderous behavior.
I have changed.
I wanted to tell you how...
I'm sorry for what I did.
I wanted to tell you both. I wrote.
Apology accepted.
You need money?
No, I have a job.
I work for Segrand Havana. She told me about you.
Want. Here 10,000 dollars.
I want you to take a plane.
Our lives are rich.
We have built on your ashes.
Resigns in Segrand.
Pope.
It t'en Prie.
Do not even try to see Benjie or Cristina. Do you understand?
You did not think I'd let you ref outre my life away?
Take your skin cream,
your meds and your bags cardboard and put them by the door.
And working your program.
Bon.
It's over, Benjie. At Friday.
D'accord. Merci, Rusty.
What are you doing here?
What are you doing in my pool?
Who are you?
Micah.
It's a little drowned.
I do not want to see.
I will not do anything.
His father thought he could keep him from drowning.
Fathers think like that.
I will do nothing.
Go play with someone else.
I'm alive, asshole.
I'm alive and I'm not crazy.
I know a man
who lives by the sword of Damocles we call AIDS.
"When my time comes," me-he said,
"I'll be ready.
"My bags are packed, the threshold of the door."
I love it. I really like.
Freedom.
Say: "You have to stop."
"You're a woman. I want to help you."
"You do not think I started these fires, is not it?"
Say: "It was not your intention you need help, that's all. ".
Will not you help me?
Do not remove my socks.
I have scars on my legs, stomach and back.
On my school notebooks
On my desk and trees
On the sands of snow I write your name
On any given flesh On the front of my friends
On any outstretched hand I write your name
Your mother, of course, was Clarice Taggart,
the wonderful actress
died in a fire in the 70s.
Christmas 76.
You talked about his addiction
and revealed, with great courage, I must say,
she had abused you physically.
And sexually, yes.
What is rare. Usually, it is the father or stepfather.
And we'll talk about, but first,
I have a burning question:
What's it like
the tourner dans le remake the Stolen Waters,
and play precisely the role of your mother?
It's scary.
It is all that will become his mother said,
but there is a bit extreme.
She was even named...
For an Oscar, yes. But she had only a Golden Globe.
I feel both
as possible.
And we are fortunate to have Damien Javitz.
Agatha, can you come here?
Who did rather strange films. Really strange.
Do not be shy. Vicodin totally constipated me.
I want you to go get me a laxative: Happy Moment.
They should call Unhappy Moment.
I'm going to need you tonight. Maria is taken.
One of his 1000 brats has nabbed cholera...
What should I do?
Stuff in the kitchen.
Fill glasses. Maybe use a little table.
It will amuse you. Lots of interesting people.
Ça served you.
Fuck! It will take me an enema.
Wait a minute.
I wanted to ask you a question.
You see men?
Sometimes.
You see somebody right now?
I see that yes!
Just a little.
What does he do?
He is an actor.
These are the worst! Must play their mirror every morning.
Not mine.
He is also a screenwriter.
You are very attractive. No false modesty.
You kiss?
You can tell me!
How far did you go?
Just about everything.
Tu as des orgasm?
Go for it!
It is server?
He drives a limousine. You saw him.
He's cute.
Drivers are tombeurs.
I need yoghurt and cigarettes.
And called the plumber. The water is cold.
Bordel, ça pue ici!
Hey, pilot fish.
- You go out late for a schoolboy.
- Two days off.
Prends un Shirley Temple.
You're kidding, I hope.
Do not call me Shirley.
Benjie White, Gretchen Voss.
Want to have fun. Do you have something?
- Producers emmerdent you?
- They try.
But one thing at a time.
You surely... Kayla?
Her bum.
It's already done. After the union sold him my shit.
- She has had his song.
- She was where?
- It's a long story.
- Long and hard.
To Sam?
We'll soon find out,
at least I hope so.
She had a crush on you and you've thrown.
Mais non.
I know you have the cam.
I do not want to lose your sobriety you.
You're going to turn the result of Babysitters?
Yes, they made me an offer I could not refuse mother.
It made so much money!
Je t'ai vue dans Thrill Kill. Cool.
A horror comedy. Critics have understood.
If you want, I have some GHB. It smashes.
Je t'aime, toi.
Well, Sam is on the way. Contract fulfilled.
The Terminator.
In yours.
I bought it on eBay.
It seems he has served at Columbine massacre.
It is loaded, man.
Je vais le redirected.
Not kidding.
Benji!
He is sick.
If America knew!
Rhett, the joke ends. The clodhopper.
It does an hour it started.
The clodhopper told the yuppie...
- What's a yuppie?
- Are you serious?
I know what it is. But not what it means.
The clodhopper say yuppie:
"I know a place to go,
"on y danse, on s'y bat, on y boit,
"et on y baise!"
This joke is safe sex?
On s'en branle. On monte à cru.
Come on, give it to me.
I asked if that joke was guaranteed safe sex.
I hope not.
Then I'll kill you.
It starts to do well.
Le yuppie dit:
"Great. Is there going to be other people?"
Then the clodhopper said
"No. Who else? Just you and me."
Fucker!
Tu I'as tué!
- Damn!
- It is crazy.
- Get out!
- Dude, I'm sorry.
I removed all the bullets.
You killed my dog. Fucking stupid.
I enculé of barje,
tu as tué mon chien. Barre-toi!
I come in?
Bad idea.
I did not stay long.
I wanted to make amends.
I saw this house in magazines.
In Architectural Digest. With the profile of dad.
I feel a bit exhibited,
but Stafford likes to personalize everything,
so that we know how and where we live.
You want something?
No, Merci.
Theoretically, I stopped.
I thought you'd come earlier.
It'll be seven years.
That's how long it took me to do my makeup.
Agatha, I did not go to see you...
I would have done the same.
I was scared.
Because of what you did.
Explains nothing.
I dreamed so much of the old house.
This is the first place I visited on my return.
- Nobody does nothing built.
- The land is ours forever.
I redo the same dream for ages.
Benjie and I were married there,
under a white canopy. I realized when I knew for you and Dad.
You were in Europe.
I found the key to the safe. All photos.
We did not know we were brother and sister?
They had been separated since childhood.
It was a monstrous thing.
We met on campus.
We did not know.
What are you doing here?
Stafford, it's nothing.
I told you to leave.
You do not own to.
It was a monstrous thing.
I found your diaries.
Love is stronger than death.
Dirty bitch!
Stop it!
Papa, do not...
You lie mal INFORMATION.
You must go.
Do not hit!
Papa...
Leave me alone!
Ma Bague.
Elle a pris mon alliance.
Ma Bague!
Inspection pee. You are caught in the act!
You know you deserve a scolding sacred.
What does that mean?
You know what I mean...
Will my two zin!
Who's the star here?
You can tell me, Roy?
It's you!
It is not your enemy.
You...
Love is stronger than death.
Tu es un méchant baby-sitter, Benjamin.
Die!
You're a naughty babysitter.
Fuck!
Holy shit!
It must be a bit groggy.
My baby.
I'm sorry, Mom.
But why?
Benjie, why did you do that?
It was only a little boy.
I saw the girl...
That, baby? Agatha?
Agatha came to see you?
The little girl. She tricked me.
What little girl?
The hospital. One who died
and that I keep seeing.
My baby...
He must go home.
He must leave California.
Jonas has to speak to the prosecutor.
He's only 13!
The violence of the attack is going to play against him, Cristina.
He has robbed someone with a gun.
He hurt one boy!
Justice has become very hard for minors.
They'll put him in jail?
They will not put him in jail.
The kid has nothing.
God thank you!
They stopped the series.
Will there be another casting?
But it is a very small role.
Benjie. I speak of the role of Benjie. Everything is over.
Damn it!
Now the whole world will know.
The world will know that we have committed crimes.
You do not want me to have appealed to you?
No, I'm happy.
My God. I feel bad.
I think I have bronchitis.
Your voice is more exciting.
Thank you.
And your love story?
It can go. It works.
That's all you have to say?
I do not understand.
Well, that stuff burns...
This is not a little unhealthy?
The fuck?
No. Not really.
She takes off her gloves?
Your friends do not find it a bit unhealthy?
Do your friends know her?
I started a...
a script on it.
It's research.
While research is at a certain level.
And I, you would be willing to fuck me for "research"?
I do not know.
How would we do?
You get to see me?
Look at what I do.
How we kiss?
From behind?
If you want.
I want it.
It last long?
Yes.
I am more beautiful than she?
And my skin? Is she is more beautiful?
Yes.
And my holes? Are they are better, my holes?
You want to fuck my holes?
Yes.
I must go.
And please, do not go down. Put yourself behind the wheel.
What has happened?
I took the bus.
And the car?
It is broken.
What happened to you yesterday?
I was sick.
I was sick this week.
But I get up at 5:00 and I work 14 hours a day.
Tu Vas mal?
I think I have the flu.
Tu bizarrement Agis. Et tu es sale.
Sorry.
And that's too much to ask of sending a text message?
Stop repeating that!
You liabilities...
Maybe it's time to return to Florida.
Back to Kansas, Dorothy! That's perfect.
But you could move your ass.
Because it gives me the creeps.
Your then. Your then. Your comprends?
Go home take a bath.
I'm sorry.
Oh, mon Dieu!
But you're bleeding!
Tu ne mets pas of Tampax?
You are psychotic?
I'm sorry.
I do not believe it...
My assistant was bleeding on my couch to 12,000 dollars!
Get out of my life
filthy degenerate!
I'll pay you.
Goes to the kitchen
look for Perrier and rubs.
Google goes on to the stain.
I picked you in the street. I did not see you paid for it.
For you to have your period on my couch!
Do you think Carrie Fisher...
Nicole Kidman ou Halle Berry
employ dirty critters?
Wacky and misshapen?
Salut, Agatha!
J'ai was the hosto
and told a carer
I would give him 10,000 dollars.
Asshole fan!
How did you find me?
You told me work for it.
And I've been here.
Où est Havana?
She went to Canyon Ranch.
Damien gave him two days of rest.
I am lost, Agatha.
I can not go anywhere.
Benjie, I want you to hear me.
Everything is over, you know?
It is that of Cristina.
Go get that from Dad. Can you?
You can pick her up?
We'll keep it a secret as much as possible.
Nothing should spoil my class.
At worst, I go to Oprah.
I confess genre Lance Armstrong.
It could generate a lot of money.
Monday on GMA it is launched to try.
Cristina!
Pope?
I've never taken much!
It was so brave of you
back there.
I just slid her finger.
As if he wanted me to take.
We should start...
I spent thirteen summers. It's not so bad.
Invalid if wrong.
With this ring...
You are devoted to me...
I am devoted to you...
As my husband...
As your husband...
With this ring...
You are consecrated to me as my wife...
I am devoted to you as your wife.
Set me as a seal upon your heart? c.
You may kiss the bride.
On absence without desire
On the bare loneliness
On the steps of death I write your name
Health back
Risk missing
On hope without memory I write your name
And by the power of a word...
I renew my life...
I was born to know you, to appoint you...