Weather tracking systems
have put the storms
that are currently about
two hours north of us,
so now's the time to get
your supplies, San Vicente.
For the next 18 to 24 hours,
we're gonna get up to 8 inches
of rain with wind gusts
up to 60 miles per hour.
The storm's coming, people.
Get ready to be blown away.
He ambushed me with a
two carat diamond ring
and a damn minister.
Hey, he didn't say anything
about leavin' Crystal, did he?
Does she even know?
I call that good news.
Lead with that next time.
Well, if it were any other
kind, I'd say the same thing.
But Pernell? The way he's been acting.
Come on, Tessie. This might as
well be from fake documents.com.
It's not legal, it's not real.
Let him play out his little fantasy.
No, I'm not goin' there.
Not even make-believe.
He's leaning on you, Tessie.
And if you step away,
I'm afraid of how hard
he might fall.
But if you stay, somethin' good can
come out of this.
- I mean... for you, I mean.
- Like what?
What, a picket fence? Stroller?
Not a part of my plan.
Nothing like that.
Woman in your line of
work doesn't have much
of a pension plan.
Don't worry about me.
I will not be dippin' in
the penny jar when I retire.
Sure, sure... you're a smart lady,
I know that, but those properties you have
on the Westside...
they could have some real potential.
Once we get the Brooks Project done,
we're gonna need some of that new, um...
What do you call that shit?
Sustainable, low-impact ecosystems.
Yeah, ecosystems.
Hipsters and double-strollers,
living in housing made
of bamboo and whatnot.
Properties in neighborhoods
where that shit goes in,
they are going to triple in value...
maybe more.
You sure they're going on the Westside?
TBD, girl.
TB-fucking-D.
sync and corrected by Caio
www.addic7ed.com
So, Julio was working with the dead cop
and then he killed him.
I sure like the way that ring looks on you.
I like knowing we're married.
Pernell, I'm trying to wrap my head
around what you want me to do.
Can we focus on that for a minute?
Okay, yeah.
Julio says the contact had a place
at the Eastwood Apartments.
So whoever rented the apartment
was the bad guy?
Maybe.
I need for you to go there
and get me a name.
Pernell,
you're talking about rapists and killers.
Being a P.I. is not a part
of my job description.
Job description?
I got down on one knee for you.
If you think of me as anything more
than a fucking John,
you're gonna do this for me.
Talking to me like that
will get you nowhere.
You see? We even fight
like an old married couple.
- Pernell, please.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
Would you please do this for me?
Tess?
I would do it myself, except I'm afraid
it'll come back on me.
I need to send somebody I know
and I trust and I don't trust anybody
more than you, Tess.
What's the address?
Morning, all.
Mr. Harris, Mrs. Harris.
What are you doing here, Josh?
You're about to see.
You know,
almost half the people
in skydiving accidents survive them.
Bullshit.
Seriously,
they might end up vegetables,
but they don't all die.
What's the difference?
Who wants to live like that anyway?
You speak for Stephen Hawking?
I speak for me, man.
Seriously, if I bounce and I don't die,
DNR all the way, man!
Yeah!
I think we can all agree.
There's nothing more to discuss now that
we've heard Pernell Harris
Jr.'s wishes for a DNR...
Fuck that.
You don't tell me when there's
nothing else to discuss.
I tell you.
We'll never let the video in. It's hearsay.
Well, you're welcome to
try to make that argument,
but we are hearing it
right from PJ's mouth.
Hearing what? A joke?
That's not a joke and you know it.
PJ's not here to testify to state-of-mind.
The guy who shot the video can.
That's what Mr. Miller is doing here.
Is that right?
Is that why you're here, Josh?
Why do we have to drag this out?
Your son is talking to you.
He's telling you what he wants.
No, we don't know that
he would say that today.
I do. The last thing PJ would want
is for me to let you pull the plug.
We'll be contesting the video.
You mean you'll be delaying the inevitable.
Chronic care facilities
will not be evacuated,
but ventilator-dependent
patients in these facilities
will be transferred to a hospital.
We're making this determination
based on the nature
of the storm, okay?
Thank you.
That's good notes. Thanks, James.
And can you hold on to them for me?
Okay, ah, kay.
Erwin.
When did you decide it was okay
to ignore calls from the mayor?
I'm not ignoring them. I'm
a little busy at the moment.
I wasn't calling about storm preparations.
We never got to finish our conversation
at the Conclave.
No, I thought it was over
when I told Pernell to go fuck himself.
Come on, Erwin.
You know Pernell wasn't
really trying to convert you.
He just got carried away.
And if I could take it
back for him, I would.
But I need that grid expansion
and you want some things too,
- right?
- Not if it means
swallowing Pernell's shit.
Now, see? There's your mistake.
Now, you're letting personal
get in the way of business.
It's hard not to when someone says,
"Your people killed Christ
and you're going to hell."
You know he crossed a line, Robert.
What line?
He didn't put his hands on you.
He didn't hurt you. Those were words...
Nonsense talking.
You can't get caught up in that.
Oh, so there's no taking it too far?
So, if I called you a
nigger, you wouldn't care?
You sign up on that grid expansion,
you can call me whatever the fuck you want.
Okay, nigger.
You know what it'd take to get me onboard
for the Brook's grid expansion?
Everything I've already asked for,
plus a separate budget allocation
from the discretionary fund.
Let me know if you can make that happen,
nigger.
Brother Harris called.
He says he needs to talk.
- He's on his way.
- Good.
You can give him his check back.
Yes, I still have it.
I do not feel right about how we got it.
Brother Harris wanted to make a donation.
What's the problem?
The problem is that you
married him to his call girl.
That's polygamy. It's against the law.
No one who relies on the law is justified
before God because the righteous
will live by faith.
Paul?
You are compromising
the spiritual principles
of this church to enable this man.
Not "enable," save.
Brother Pernell is helping
us grow this church.
That donation will cover the check
you gave to Bishop Bruce.
We wouldn't have even needed the money
if you hadn't started smoking meth again.
I told you I did not smoke anything
that night.
Yeah, that is what you told me.
- Can you talk?
- Of course.
What can I do for you?
PJ's slipping away from me.
I'm running out of time.
I saw a video of him this morning.
He was so happy.
Happier than I've seen him
for so long.
I don't know if I've ever
seen that side of him.
That wasn't our thing.
Which is why I need him back.
I have to have a chance to...
Jesus...
Don't worry.
It's in the hands of the Lord.
I have to worry.
He said he doesn't want
to be on life-support.
He said that right to the fucking camera.
And when they show that in court,
I'm gonna lose.
PJ dies.
I need your help, Reverend.
I need to get my visions back.
We've talked about Daniel, right?
Yeah, he's the one with the visions, right?
Exactly.
But God didn't just grant him that gift.
He had to work for it.
While others ate, he fasted.
He did it to prove his willingness
to sacrifice for the Lord.
Maybe if you fasted, you'd
get your visions back.
Are you willing to make
that kind of commitment?
I'm willing to try anything.
But I'm scared.
The first thing you need to know is...
You're not alone.
Wait, the church is sending
people to the hospital?
The prayer warriors are gonna stay there
around the clock.
I shit you not.
- Prayer warriors?
- Yep.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
When is Pernell going to realize
these people are bat-shit crazy?
Mm. So I get a call
from Sister Alicia asking
if I can come by tomorrow
and help make food for 'em all.
Good.
Maybe she can tell you what kind of spell
that preacher has on my husband.
I am not going.
Big storm comes in like this, bad as it is?
Everybody want to stock up.
- Hey!
- Uh-uh.
My phone is blowing up.
You're supposed to be finding dirt for me.
This is a perfect opportunity.
I sorry, Mrs. Crystal...
I thought I made myself perfectly clear.
I only spies on the side.
Okay.
All right, fine.
On top of what I'm paying you,
I will buy all of your weed.
See, I thought I told you.
My blends...
are not just for profit.
My shit is community service.
Well, my family is part
of this community
and we need help more than anybody else
right now.
I don't think there's
enough space for the reading.
I'm not talking about the whole group.
I'm talking about, like,
seven or eight people.
It'll be tight in here, but
I think we can make it work.
Doesn't feel premature?
You were there, Josh.
You and Pernell can't pretend that
that video isn't a game-changer.
They can put off the court date,
but the case, it's over.
I just want to give PJ a
proper send-off this time.
They're having a tribute next week.
I know, but PJ won't be there.
So, I want to do it here.
For him.
Okay.
I'm in.
Just as long as I don't
have to read a poem.
♪ ... soldiers marching as to war ♪
♪ With the cross of Jesus ♪
♪ Going on before ♪
♪ Christ, The Royal Master ♪
♪ Leads against the foe ♪
♪ Forward into battle ♪
♪ See his banners go ♪
Uh, what are you doing?
- ♪ Onward, Christian soldiers ♪
- Pernell, what are you doing?
What I've been doing all
along... trying to save my son.
♪ Marching as to war ♪
Can you please take these people and leave?
Please, everybody, just go home, please.
Just go.
We're going to pray until
God gives us a miracle.
Why here, Pernell? You can pray anywhere.
Why you got to do it right in her face?
Shut your fucking mouth, you backstabber.
What, you think you're a hero?
You betrayed me and PJ.
Are you showing off for her?
Are you trying to get
next to my son's wife?
All I did was press "record."
PJ did the talking. And you heard him...
he doesn't want to be a vegetable.
When my son wakes up...
and he will wake up...
he's not gonna be a vegetable.
He's gonna be PJ.
With the help of the Lord, praise God.
Amen.
What's this?
I burnt some DVDs of PJ's videos.
Thought you and Crystal might enjoy seeing
some more of them.
Never seen anything like that before.
It's like a kumbaya convention.
They've kept this bullshit going for hours.
Pernell?
Hey!
Hey.
So...
This is how prayer warriors what, uh...
go to war?
All these people, here for our son.
Oh, that's nice.
Well, I just came to make
sure you got something
better to eat than hospital food.
Oh, I can't, honey. I'm fasting.
Fasting.
The Reverend Paul thought
it might open me up to the spirit.
Oh...
Is that what these people call
low blood-sugar?
It's chicken, pesto sauce... homemade.
I can't.
I need to hear PJ's voice again.
I need to restore my connection with God.
What about our connection?
I've been cooking for us.
And I love our dinners.
But if we're together, it doesn't matter
whether we're eating.
Pernell.
I have made room for
whatever you're going through.
Could you please just
make a little room for me?
I'm sorry, Crys.
Stay with me.
Pray with me.
Brothers, sisters, gather around.
Let us pray together.
Let us read from Isaiah.
"But those who hope in the Lord,
they will renew their strength.
They will soar on wings like eagles.
They will run and not grow weary.
They will walk and not be faint."
Amen.
- Amen.
The hospital said they
have every right to be here,
and they plan on praying until PJ wakes up.
Let me get into that.
In the meantime, try not to get converted.
You sure this is all you want me doing?
I feel like I'm getting off easy.
Everyone has their role.
I just assumed you'd be good at bagging.
That's not what I got my degree in.
But you do bag marijuana, right?
Or are the drug dealer rumors not true?
I have a side business.
I help people who are sick.
Glaucoma, cancer, diabetes.
You're practically a doctor.
- It's perfectly legal.
- That's nice.
Just don't be bringing any of that crap
around Hand of God.
We have a number of recovering addicts
in our congregation.
I don't come here for customers.
Why exactly do you come here?
Because I heard this church
was open and accepting,
not full of judgey assholes
like the church I grew up in.
But maybe I was wrong.
Accepting people and enabling people
are two entirely different
things, all right?
Drugs destroy peoples' lives
and their relation... shit!
Whoa. Let me see.
Oh, yeah.
I think you're gonna need
some stitches for this.
We'll finish lunch. We can continue.
No, you're gonna need
some stitches for this.
Whoa.
Maybe you should insist on it.
So...
What's up, nigger?
- What did you s...
- Hey, I got this.
How you doin', Erwin?
We still playing this game?
I'll stop
as soon as you admit there's a line.
I'm here to talk business.
Right, so, nigger...
will my department be getting
that allocation I requested?
I just need to know what
account you want it in
and what for.
Well, that's a good question, nigger.
We have a non-profit
called the DWP Schoolyard Improvement Fund.
Can you put it in there, nigger?
As soon as you sign off
on that grid expansion.
- Pen.
- Dad!
Fucking pen.
I'm not doing this.
I can't.
You wanna call me nigger a few more times,
put yourself back in the mood?
You think I like calling you that?
I'm trying to make a point.
And it was so eloquently made.
Pernell was wrong. I get that.
Now, let's finish our business.
No. The point is there is a line.
Let's go.
Come on.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Who are you talking to?
You play the game until you win the game.
Oh, Dad, you've been saying
that since I was a kid
and you were running for the school board.
Okay? Now, you're the mayor.
Which means, at the very least,
I know how to get things done.
Yeah, but do you know
how to make a difference?
I am one concrete pour away
from making the biggest fucking difference
in the history of this city.
Are you fucking serious? Look, Dad...
Cops still fuck with me
when I'm jogging in the hood.
White guys at nice restaurants
still throw me their keys at the valet.
Schools are getting
shot-up and left for dead.
Okay, the same schools you went to.
And I'm gonna fix all of that.
When?
You think Brooks is the magic bullet?
Look, you just let that
asshole who ranks below you
call you a nigger...
N-I-G-G-E-R...
in the name of Brooks.
You're reading too many
Huey Newton speeches.
No, I'm not, Dad.
I'm telling kids they can
grow up to be like you one day,
and I'm waiting for you to set the example.
They all think it.
So who gives a fuck if they say it?
As long as they don't stop me
from getting what I came for.
And when you get that, Dad,
what are you gonna have left?
The view alone is worth the price.
It is beautiful, but can you headline
the building's security features for me?
My client and his wife just had a baby
and they have kidnapping concerns.
Well, uh, the lobby, the
parking garage, elevators...
all have video surveillance.
We have a doorman 24 hours a day.
Mm-hmm.
Um, sí... He wants to know the names
of other tenants on the
floor in the past 12 months
so a security team can
run background checks.
Uh, I'm not at liberty to
give out that information.
I'm sure that your client
would appreciate that.
My client likes to decide
what he would appreciate.
If you don't mind my asking,
what kind of business is your client in?
Hmm.
Construction, mainly.
He needs to be here a few
months out of the year.
He hates hotels.
Construction, mainly.
You know, other buildings we toured
had no problem disclosing
names of previous tenants.
The last one had a pool, too.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
Eastwood Apartment's confidentiality policy
is very strict.
Good for you.
That's very commendable.
But my client is ready to pay a year's rent
for all three available
units on this floor by the end
of the week... and in cash,
but not unless he gets this information.
I see.
Let me talk to my boss
and I'll get back to you.
I'll give you 24 hours.
It's gonna be a hell of a storm.
Maybe God will send an ark
to take His faithful
away to somewhere else.
Amen, sister.
So...
you and Josh.
Me and Josh what?
Did you come up here to accuse me
of cheating on your son?
We both know there's no
PJ to cheat on anymore.
In mediation, you made it very clear...
I held the party line.
I have to.
Can't betray my husband in public.
I'm on your side.
You can't get Pernell to understand?
I can't even get Pernell to eat.
Be patient.
He's gonna have to let PJ go eventually...
whether he wants to or not.
None of us want to.
He's already gone.
If there is a "you and Josh"
or a "you and anyone,"
you have my blessing.
There's none.
You have my encouragement.
Why are you telling me this?
Because no one is tying you
to that fiasco down there.
You're free, Jocelyn.
Go find an ark.
Get out of here. Go live your life.
And
with a storm on its way,
many of them are worried
about heavy rainfall,
rising tides, and high winds.
And places like the San Vicente harbor
haven't updated their pilings for decades.
So.
We just passed the two-hour mark,
if you're wondering.
Here you go.
- Thanks.
Welcome.
You don't have to stay.
Well, gonna at least finish my coffee.
I'm sorry I went off on
you like that earlier.
I just, um...
I have a friend who used to have a problem
with drugs that I really care about
and they're clean now,
praise God, but, um...
You're sensitive to it...
- I get it.
- Yeah.
I get it.
Yeah.
Um, Alicia.
Hmm?
I have your blood on my Jordans.
Can't we just cut
the "I have a friend" bullshit?
You talking about Paul, right?
No, no, not Paul.
Please, I've seen the way
the two of you are together.
The Reverend was an addict?
You know what drug dealers are famous for?
Discretion.
He relapsed.
Once, I think.
But he won't even admit it to me.
It's the lying that
really scares me, you know?
Yeah. What's his drug?
Meth.
Meth? Shit.
How do you know when someone's
not an addict anymore?
Well, once you're a pickle,
you can't go back to being a cucumber.
I don't believe that.
God transforms people.
I hope that's true.
Thank you.
Look at this.
Look at everything
you're doing for your boy.
Damn.
I know you're trying to be a good man,
trying to do the right thing,
but you're all fucking up
everything else along the way.
Bobo?
Who cleans it up?
You have no idea what I do,
what I let someone do
to me in front of my son.
My boy.
But it's fine, right, Pernell?
I'm gonna get that concrete pour.
Brooks is gonna move in.
And I'm gonna be the first black man
with a statue in front of the city hall.
Right?
"On the
shores of Gitche Gumee
of the shining Big-Sea-Water,
Stood Nokomis, the old woman,
pointing with her finger westward.
O'er the water pointing westward
to the purple clouds of sunset,
fiercely, the red sun descending,
burned his way along the heavens."
Lord, give strength to Your servant Pernell
in this, his time of need.
We know there is no burden so heavy
we cannot carry it if we
share the weight with You.
We ask these things in Your name.
Amen.
God...
I know You're here somewhere.
I can feel You.
Why won't You talk to me?
Why won't You let PJ talk to me?
I know I haven't been perfect.
But You said You didn't want perfect.
You said all we need to be is willing.
Haven't I been willing?
Eli Eli lama sabachthani.
Come closer.
PJ?
Pernell? What is it?
"As war-parties, when retreating,
Burn the prairies on their war-trail;
And the moon, the Night-sun, eastward,
Suddenly starting from his ambush... "
Close.
PJ?
"Followed
in that fiery war-trail
With its glare upon his features,
And Nokomis, the old woman,
Pointing with her finger westward,
Spake these words to Hiawatha... "
Get outta here.
"Yonder dwells the great Pearl-Feather,
Megissogown, the Magician,
Manito of Wealth and Wampum... "
Close.
"Guarded by his fiery serpents,
Guarded by the black pitch-water."
PJ.
Damn it, Pernell.
Can you please just let
us have this one thing?
Close.
"Coiling, playing in the water... "
I'm close.
Talk to me, son.
The Devil is close.
- Hey!
- Where is he?
- Just tell me where he is?
- Everybody out.
- The Lord is speaking to him!
- Where is the devil?
- Hallelujah.
- Amen!
- Hallelujah!
- Come on, come on!
- The Lord is with him!
No, he's not, he's not...
Everybody, just get out!
Hallelujah, amen!
Please, everybody,
just... just... just leave!
Just get out.
- Hallelujah.
- Praise Jesus.
- What?
- Listen, go home.
You don't need to deal with this.
What are you talking about?
Let me take care of these assholes.
- Okay?
- Yeah, okay, fine.
You heard her. Get the fuck out.
Keep your promise.
- Hallelujah, Amen.
- Praise God!
Find the devil.
Who is he, PJ?
Praise Jesus.
- Who's the devil?
- You guys can't do this.
- Who are you pointing to?
- Back up.
- Come on.
- Who is it?
- Who's the devil?
Thank you, Jesus.
- What's going on here?
- Thank you, Jesus.
Hey, I want everybody out of here.
- I will find the devil...
- You're not part of the family,
- I want you out right now.
- And I will end him.
- Amen, Hallelujah!
Hey, the nurse told me you were ready.
What happened?
Come on. You're scaring me.
Hey, they told me it
was only a few stitches.
You look like you just
found out you have cancer.
Hey.
I think Paul would make a wonderful father.
He's so patient with kids
and fun.
You should see how they gravitate to him.
One smile and they're hooked.
It's a gift, being good with kids.
Hey.
Paul doesn't need this right now,
especially with everything
that he's going through.
You know what? Maybe he does.
Maybe this can remind him of
what his priorities really need to be.
He can't deal with everything at once,
and this baby...
It's too much.
No. No, it's not.
He has you to keep him
focused and together.
And you can do that.
I know you can keep him together,
and you can do it.
- Hey.
You all right?
I'm fine.
- I'm fine.
- Yeah, what happened?
They said you fell.
I cut my finger and,
uh... when I saw the blood,
I passed out.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Let me see your work.
Okay, so, we're not gonna print all three.
Take the one I got.
Yeah, at the moment, no...
- Hi, Robert.
- Oh, I'm Robert now.
I'm sorry, Mr. Mayor.
How about "Daddy"?
I like "Daddy."
I was
gonna come by your office,
but since you're here, I'll do it now.
I want to apologize. I'm not a racist.
I'm not a nigger.
I know, I
never thought it would...
I just wanted you to admit there's a line.
What people say matters.
More than what they do?
Anyway, I'm sorry.
Why now?
I was sorry the second I said it.
No, no, you're telling me now because...
The city auditor called you, right?
I can't open my books
to an audit right now.
Yeah, I thought that might be a problem.
The more I looked into your
Schoolyard Improvement Fund,
the more it smelled like a slush fund.
It's a real account.
You know, I could explain it,
but it's not worth the blowback.
Look, I'll approve the grid expansion
for the Brooks Headquarters.
Please, Robert, call it off.
Please who?
Please... Daddy.
You can go now.
See what I mean?
You call that a win?
♪ Oh, freedom ♪
I'm going to the car.
So...
the preacher is a drug addict.
Recovering addict.
He's just addicted to God now.
Say you take down this preacher.
What makes you think that
Pernell's not gonna just find
somebody else to latch onto?
One problem at a time, please.
Huh?
Hey. What about that chick?
The one that's always with him?
Alicia.
Anything about her I can use on him?
Nothing. She's...
pretty vanilla.
Keep looking.
Ciao, Bella.
Just because we can't stay
here doesn't mean we can't pray.
We'll go back to the church and keep going.
Thank you, Paul, but, uh...
Now that God is talking to
me again, I'm not worried.
I know He'll show me the way.
Amen.
Oh, hey, you can spare
one of these, can't you?
I haven't eaten in two days.
No, you don't want to start with these.
They're for patients who can't take pills.
There's meds mixed in.
Turn to Luke 8:23-25.
"And as they sailed, he fell asleep.
And a windstorm came down on the lake
and they were filling with
water, and were in danger.
And they went and woke him,
saying, 'Master,
master, we are perishing.'
And he awoke and rebuked the wind
and the raging waves and they ceased
and it was calm.
And he turned to them and
said, 'Where is your faith?'"
I know.
Hey, everybody gather around.
- Uh-oh.
- Yeah, "Uh-oh" is right.
- Time for the bubbly.
- The good stuff.
All right.
This is my dad's favorite party trick...
mainly 'cause everyone thinks he's crazy
before they figure out he's a genius.
Oh!
Come on!
You get that?
- Will you pass me a cup.
- Oh, my G...
Hey.
Come.
Sit with me.
We're doing better now.
Better than we've been in a long time.
How would I know?
27 years.
Ups, downs... you should know.
I didn't drug you.
I...
Gave you your medicine.
You tried to take the thing I needed most.
No.
I tried to help you.
I wanted you back.
You did it all for me.
For us.
Because I love you.
Well, I hope so.
Because that's what I'm
going to tell myself.
A storm is coming, a storm is coming.
Trees will fall and block our way.
Cell towers will explode
and cut off contact
from our loved ones.
- That's right.
- Cars will smash
into each other and blood will pour
from the cracks and we'll still get by.
- Yes.
- Yes we will.
But it's not the damage
from the storm that mattered.
It's the clarity that
comes with the cleansing.
It's what clears away
the wreckage of our lives
that's important. Can I get an amen?
Amen!
If you turn your life
to Jesus with open arms,
He is there...
- I'm so glad you could make it.
And He is waiting for you,
and He will make your life better.
Do not give up!
Mm.
Hey.
You doing okay? You look beat.
Mm. Been a long day.
But it just got better.
Thanks for braving the storm.
You said it was important.
You know what I'm gonna do
when this is all over with?
When PJ wakes up.
I'm gonna take you on a trip.
Some place you've never been before.
Uh-huh.
Proper honeymoon.
I do weekend getaways.
Business trips.
I don't do honeymoons.
Didn't that change?
Now that we're married?
I'm not your wife, Pernell.
Look, my last name isn't Harris.
I don't have keys to your house.
I'm not your emergency contact.
I am not your wife.
Okay.
Just so long as you know I love you.
I do know that.
This is the Eastwood Apartment tenant list
for the last 12 months.
I already looked through it.
I only recognized one name.
So what can you see more clearly
now that God has washed
the land clean for us?
And more importantly, what
are you gonna do about it
now that you can see?
God...
And of course I left my umbrella at home.
Oh, God.
On the bright side, the
prayer warriors are...
What's wrong?
Wait. Wait, hold on.
You don't have to feel guilty.
Really?
I want to.
It's not that.
I just want us to be sure.
sync and corrected by Caio
www.addic7ed.com