25.000 English
The Mark of Zorro (1940)
"MADRID - when the Spanish Empire
encompassed the globe, and young blades
were taught the fine
and fashionable art of killing..."
Fair seat, bad hands,
mount not sufficiently schooled.
Disqualified.
Here comes the California cockerel
Ten pesos he clears 'em all.
Cleanly? Taken.
Grow wings, my friend.
Ten pesos, if you please.
Maybe you've forgotten that in California
they use horses for cradles.
- Well done, senor. Excellent.
- And all I did was sit on his back.
Three carrots after his oats tonight.
- You go to an affair of the court?
- No, of the heart.
- Something is wrong.
- The face, man. The face...
Why the fine feathers?
A senorita that would put St Anthony
on the griddle. We're to meet in...
Have you forgotten that you cross swords
with Lieutenant Cortez at three o'clock?
It slipped my mind.
Why do I have to meet
every swordsman in Madrid?
Everybody enjoys a certain amount of
fighting, but why do they all pick on me?
Calm yourself. It's become a distinction
to assail a California cockerel.
You pink them slightly in the arm or shoulder
and they boast of having met you.
Cadet Vega, the commandant wishes
to see you in his office at once.
Good. I can't possibly fight the fellow now.
Explain that to him, will you?
And tell him I'll meet him tomorrow.
Senores, your attention, please.
I'm buying wine for all.
Come on.
It's your last chance to fill up on me.
Last chance?
What do you mean?
My father has ordered me home.
I sail on the first ship from Lisbon.
To California?
But what about your commission here?
I'll have to give that up.
What's it like in California?
Are the Indians troublesome?
- Then who is there to fight?
- No one.
Then what will you do with
this spur of yours, my cockerel?
This...
Leave it there.
And when you see it,
think of me,
in a land of gentle missions, happy peons,
sleepy caballeros, and everlasting boredom.
Wine.
A toast.
To California,
where a man can only marry,
raise fat children,
and watch his vineyards grow.
- Are the vineyards bearing well this season?
- By some miracle the grapes remain sweet.
- Why so gloomy, my friend?
- People can't sing with hatred in their hearts.
- Hatred for whom?
- The alcalde. May his soul burn in hell.
The alcalde?
A kinder, better man never lived.
You don't know him.
I should know him.
He's my father.
I said it, and I won't deny it. I've taken
20 lashes before for a slip of the tongue.
Row, row.
Get me to shore.
- I'm honoured. How can I serve you?
- A glass of your best wine.
- You are a stranger in these parts?
- No, not exactly.
I was born and raised not far from here.
I am the son of the alcalde.
Where can I get a carriage
to drive me to Los Angeles?
Well, wake up.
Didn't you hear me?
This way.
Pedro, here is a caballero who would
employ you. He is the son of the alcalde.
I want to be driven to Los Angeles.
I have some boxes and a portmanteau.
I'll pay you well.
Stop staring at me.
Will you drive me or not?
What's come over this country?
Have you all gone mad?
Listen, you.
Find speech, or I'll cut out your tongue.
Please. You are too late.
Your good father has already attended to that.
My father?
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry, but at a meeting of the peons,
this man spoke against the heavy taxes.
The next day, the soldiers of His Excellency
cut out his tongue. I swear it is true.
Therefore, until we receive
the reinforcements promised us...
So people can still laugh in California.
I'd begun to think they'd lost the habit.
- Your name?
- He claims to be the son of the alcalde.
I claim nothing. I am Diego Vega,
son of His Excellency, Don Alejandro.
And this, although I find it
greatly changed, is my home.
Your pardon, Don Diego. I'd not heard
of your returning. Welcome to California.
I'm Capitán Esteban Pasquale,
military aid to the alcalde.
I'm honoured, but bewildered.
Why has my father turned
his home into a barracks?
Conditions have changed since you left.
Your father resigned. Age, you know.
Since then, the peons have
become more industrious.
As to the caballeros, they're
encouraged to think of their own affairs.
We take care of the government.
I see.
- Tell me, who holds the office now?
- Don Luis Quintero. I'll take you to him.
Thank you, but I should like to see
my family as quickly as possible.
- Where are they living?
- At your old hacienda.
But His Excellency'll never forgive me if I let
you go without a word of welcome from him.
I'm quite sure
that you'll save me a reprimand.
How could I refuse a man anything
with a naked sword in his hand?
So a wit has come to Los Angeles.
Carry out your orders, Sergeant.
Foolish habit of mine.
Some men play with a glove,
or a monocle, or a snuffbox.
Churchmen finger their beads.
I toy with a sword.
Do you fancy the weapon?
I know very little about it, my dear capitán.
Swordplay is such a violent business.
So, this is the bird that killed
the black-breasted red?
Was it a bloody battle?
At the side of the pit,
all the people were covered with blood.
Pity I missed it.
What are you asking for him?
This is a noble bird. Well tested.
I'm asking 40 pesos for him.
40 pesos? Esteban, this cheating dog
should have his taxes raised.
Oh, no, Your Excellency.
The bird is yours, as a gift.
- Not one centimo will he cost you.
- That's a better attitude. Much better.
Turn him over to my handlers.
And what caballero is this?
Or is he some young lord from Spain?
A good guess, Excellency.
He's just from Spain.
This is Don Diego Vega,
son of your respected predecessor.
I thought such fabric came from Madrid.
Must have cost you plenty, eh?
The caballero is here for words of welcome,
not to discuss the price of his clothes.
Of course.
To be sure.
Welcome back, young sir.
Regard this house as still your home.
Luis, a ship has arrived from Spain.
The shops will have something
worth looking at at last. I need...
Money.
It's always money.
I don't know this caballero.
- He's just off your precious ship from Spain.
- How delightful.
Will one of you ill-mannered boors
present him?
Don Diego Vega.
Senora Inez de Quintero.
My wife.
Your Excellency is a very fortunate man.
I'm not so sure.
She thinks pesos grow on mulberry trees.
Your husband was also fascinated
by the caballero's clothes.
Your pardon.
We're overwhelmed by the latest fashions.
And no wonder.
What is there here to interest a woman?
I long for the life you've been leading.
The gaiety and splendour of the court.
- Patience, my love. You'll see it all someday.
- Doubtless, when I'm an old hag.
That catastrophe could never overtake you.
Did you hear? How easily
he makes pretty speeches.
I regret that...
You were saying?
I was saying that I must tear myself away
and make some speeches
to my father and mother.
Don't leave me to these barbarians.
Come to the shops with me
and help me make my selections.
Oh, you tempt me.
I love the shimmer of satin and silk,
the matching of one delicate shade
against the other.
Then there's the choosing
of scents and lotions -
attar of rose, carnation,
crushed lily, and musk.
- As for ornaments and jewels...
- But Don Diego must see his parents.
Too true.
Duty rather than pleasure.
I'll see you to the door.
That's one little peacock
that won't give us any trouble.
You think not?
The capitán is jealous. The fop has
pricked the fencing master. Touché.
I don't like such jests.
Your eye might fail you.
It's possible.
- Who was that?
- No one you know.
- Someone new. Very charming.
- He must be, from the colour in your cheeks.
At last, after all these months
in this dreary place,
someone who knows the newest fashions,
the latest dances, how to flatter a woman.
- When can I meet him?
- Listen to the child.
You're much too young to cope with his sort.
Why do you allow her to wear that mantilla?
It makes her look like a woman grown.
I am a woman grown.
I'll be 18 my next birthday.
Carmen Castellano
is a month younger and already wed.
Her grandmother was a peon.
Such riffraff wed when they like.
You have the blood
of the hidalgos in your veins.
Keep it cool, my girl,
or I'll whisk you into a convent.
I pity your poor mount, Sergeant.
Such a heavy whip.
Do you think I'd strike a good mare with this?
It would ruin her, break her spirit.
See? She didn't flick an ear.
She knows. We are collecting
taxes from the peons today.
And you use that little switch
on the taxpayers?
Only when they are stubborn.
When you come to collect my taxes,
I won't be stubborn, I promise you.
Turn right in here.
Mother.
- My son. My baby.
- Mother.
Hello, María.
Good old Juan, fat as ever.
Hello, Manuel. And José.
Where's Father?
In the study with Fray Felipe.
Come, he's longing to see you.
Take Don Diego's things to his room.
I tell you,
these conditions are beyond bearing.
This whole district, from the hills
of Verdugo to the shores of Del Rey,
is a stench in the nostrils of heaven.
- I know.
- You know, yes.
- But what do you do about it? Nothing.
- What can...
Father.
My boy.
Padre.
Welcome back to your home and my heart.
- I've missed your wise counsel.
- Not too greatly, I suspect.
You remember Don Miguel and Don José?
- Have you returned to steal more melons?
- Melons?
This scamp and my scapegrace son
crept into my garden
and gorged themselves
on my seed melons one year.
But God punished us. We were visited
by the father of all bellyaches.
But he's ripe for more
than boyish pranks now.
- I feel good muscle here.
- Arms, muscle... You men.
Is he without a face? Can't you see he's
even better-looking than when he left?
You should have seen me when I approached
the Spanish throne for the first time.
They said I looked like a frightened gopher.
More like a young angel, I'm sure.
An angel. That's what we need in California
now. An angel with a flaming sword.
Please, don't start that.
He didn't come home to get himself killed.
Hold your tongue. Go to your women.
Leave my son to me. Sit down, Diego.
- What is all this, Father?
- Well, I am no longer alcalde.
- In my place is a man...
- In his place sits a viper so foul and black...
Ah, to be alone with him
for five little minutes.
Long enough to tear
his windpipe out of his throat.
God forgive me.
- Why did you resign in the first place?
- I was forced out of office.
They threatened
to burn the homes of the peons.
- And now he sits here doing nothing, when...
- Enough, Felipe.
The friar urges me
to lead the caballeros in a revolt
which would surely fail
against a garrison of trained soldiers.
Even if I thought it would succeed,
I'd refuse just the same.
- But why?
- Because the law is the law.
I will not rebel against the government
I served for 30 years.
But that government is now vile and corrupt.
I know, but two wrongs
don't make a right, and never will.
- That is my feeling also.
- Sometimes, one must fight fire with fire.
I am a Vega. I will not follow
the lawless footsteps of Luis Quintero.
- Nor will my son.
- No, of course not.
By the way, I went directly
from the ship to our old home.
I met Senor Quintero and his charming wife.
I found them very pleasant and agreeable.
Pleasant scorpions.
Agreeable rattlesnakes.
Oh, Padre. The alcalde spoke
with great respect of you, Father.
I must admit he hasn't
troubled me or my flocks so far.
That being the case,
why get overly excited in this heat?
I know I'm going to miss
the scented breezes of Spain.
Then you believe we should not be moved
by injustice and cruelty until it touches us?
But, my dear Padre, such things
exist in the world and always will.
By the way, I took up sleight of hand
while I was in Madrid.
It's all the rage just now.
Watch closely.
To think that the boy that I helped to raise,
the boy that I taught to hold a firm wrist
behind a true point, has turned into a puppy.
How vexatious. Well, I must go
and remove the dust of travel.
I'll see you later, Father.
Stay where you are.
Put this up.
Put it up. Be quick about it.
Back to the barracks.
Special Notice:
"To all men in the district
of Los Angeles be it known
that Luis Quintero is a thief
and an enemy of the people,
and cannot long escape
my vengeance."
Zorro
I don't understand why you insist on
this stupid drive. And without an escort.
- I have my reasons.
- Suppose you share them with me.
Look... Gold. An agent of the Bank
of Madrid is meeting us in a quiet inn.
This goes to Spain.
For us, my love.
I see.
How stupid of me.
- A military guard would...
- Let Esteban know about this transaction.
- Of course, he would have claimed his share.
- I'm afraid so.
Don't move if you want to live.
- A bandit.
- I have distressing news for you.
I had a small drinking bout
with the agent of the Bank of Madrid.
While in his cups,
the fellow was somewhat indiscreet.
A drunken man is untrustworthy.
I will act for him. Hand it over.
- And that little trinket.
- You would rob a woman?
- I can't afford gallantries.
- I refuse. You dare not take it.
Quickly. I should hate
to mark such a lovely cheek.
This time I take only your money.
Next time...
"5000 pesos reward
for information leading
to the capture of the bandit ZORRO."
Luis B. Quintero / The Mayor
What a nice, quiet study, Your Excellency.
I like a quiet room. Very quiet.
What do you want?
A little talk with you, that's all -
if we come to an understanding.
Do you think the climate in Spain
will agree with you?
Why do you ask?
Because you're either going there or
to some place you might not like so well.
Which will it be?
- Spain.
- It's a very wise choice.
Now to the matter of your successor.
What do you think of Don Alejandro Vega?
He's had experience.
- What does it matter to me?
- Nothing.
But to the people of this district, a great deal.
When you resign, you'll appoint
Don Alejandro as your successor.
As you wish.
This will remind you that
I have been here once, and can return.
- Close your eyes.
- What are you going to do?
- What's that?
- The point of my sword against your throat.
Don't move until I take it away.
- What if I faint?
- You won't.
What's this?
Are you trying to commit suicide?
Speak up.
What's the matter?
- He was here.
- Who was here?
Ridiculous.
- Your fears have addled your brain.
- I tell you, he was here. In this very room.
- Anybody pass by this way?
- No one.
- Has anyone entered this room?
- His Excellency and yourself.
- Anyone else?
- No.
Do you need any more proof?
You must have fallen asleep and dreamed it.
Did I dream that?
Sergeant, turn out the guard. Zorro is
somewhere on the grounds. Find him.
I still can't believe the fellow was here.
If you'd sat here with a sword at your throat,
perhaps you'd believe it.
- How on earth did he get in?
- That's what I'd like to know.
- And it's your business to find out.
- What did he say?
He wants me in Spain
and Vega in my place.
Now we have something.
This Zorro is a caballero.
A ordinary brigand wouldn't
concern himself with Vega.
- It would serve you right if I did go to Spain.
- And give up 50,000 pesos a year?
I can't collect it if I'm dead.
And you get a third for protecting me.
But what protection! You can't keep
even keep one mad dog off my neck.
Can't I?
I'll find him, I promise you.
In the meantime, I'll put a solid wall
of men around this house night and day.
- I can't afford to lose you, my dear Luis.
- No, You can't.
Your pickings end
if anything happens to me.
That's exactly what I meant, Excellency.
Blessed Mother, send someone
to take me from this dreary place.
Someone I can love and respect.
Let him be kind and brave.
And handsome, please, dear Mother.
Fray Ramón, I didn't see you when I came in.
I'm not Fray Ramón.
I'm Fray Pablo, from the mission.
I've just been spending
the evening with Fray Ramón.
Father, I was asking the Holy Mother
to save me from a convent.
- Is that a sin?
- The sin would be in sending you to one.
- I don't understand.
- Well, a young girl with your...
I just think that you would probably be
more useful outside a convent than in.
- You mean in serving God?
- Yes, in a way.
In what way?
Well, the Church must have sons
and daughters, if she is to flourish.
- Do you follow me?
- I think so.
- You mean that I might marry and...
- Yes, exactly.
Strong sons and fine daughters
to the glory of God.
I was praying just now for a husband.
You were? Fine.
I mean, it's quite natural
at your age, my child.
Yes, but it's not natural for a girl of my age
to long for a husband to rescue her.
- From what?
- Father...
Will you sit here and talk to me
for a little while? I'm troubled, deeply.
I want to leave this lonely place.
I want to meet young people.
Girls of my own age.
No one ever comes here.
The caballeros avoid this place
like the pest house.
- Why?
- They hate my Uncle Luis.
You know, I feel that
there's something wrong about him.
Decidedly wrong.
What do you think?
If people hate him as you say,
you have your answer there.
Then I was right. Perhaps I should be glad
my Aunt Inez is sending me to a convent.
No, don't be glad about that.
I mean, probably your aunt feels that
that atmosphere is better for a young girl,
- but I'm convinced...
- Inez? Oh, no.
No. That's not why she's sending me.
María says she's jealous.
She says it's because I'm good-looking.
- María has excellent eyesight.
- Thank you, Father, but are you sure?
No one except María ever says I'm pretty.
Pretty? Why, you are more radiant,
more lovely than a morning in June.
You really think that?
- With all my heart.
- I've never heard such words before.
They make me almost lose my breath.
You should hear such words
every hour of the day.
You're not in the least like Fray Ramón.
You talk so strangely.
You're not a padre. You're an impostor.
You're wearing a sword.
We've been looking everywhere for you.
Zorro broke into the house
and threatened your uncle.
They think he's still hiding
somewhere close by.
Come along. Lock the doors
after we leave, Fray Ramón.
The beast may try to rob the altar.
Good night, Padre.
Padre, you dropped something.
There he is.
There.
"20,000 pesos REWARD
for the capture of the bandit ZORRO.
Dead or alive." Luis B. Quintero / The Mayor
Three pesos.
Four pesos.
- Nine pesos.
- I cannot pay so much.
I swear, it will leave me without a centavo.
- Nine pesos.
- But we will starve.
- How can I feed my family?
- Nine pesos.
Please, I beg of you.
My little girl...
That's all.
I'll relieve you of that, Sergeant.
I'll take that.
Get back.
After him.
Hear our prayer.
And drive far away from it...
all the snares of the enemy.
And let thy holy angels dwell therein...
to keep us at peace.
And may thy blessings...
be upon us always.
Good evening, Padre.
It was so dull at home, and I remembered
that you played a fair game of chess.
So I took the liberty of riding over
and setting up the men.
What's the meaning of this?
How dare you?
We are after Zorro.
We saw him ride toward the mission.
Good evening, Sergeant.
- Zorro, you say? What's he done now?
- Enough to get himself hanged.
- Have you seen him?
- I have only this moment left the chapel.
- How long have you been here?
- Some little time. It seems like hours.
I've been waiting to play chess
with the good padre.
- It's a dull game, but what can one do?
- You have seen or heard nothing?
Of Zorro? Heaven spare me.
My blood chills at the thought.
Out of here.
Search the grounds.
What's disturbing you, Padre?
Thoughts of that bandit?
- Puppy.
- Oh, my dear Padre, really.
When I think of what one man, single-handed,
has accomplished against these devils,
and see you, the last of the Vegas, trembling
at the very mention of his name, I could...
Can't you even listen to me?
Ordinarily, I'd drink in
every word you say, butjust now...
Thank you, Mother.
- Quick. Hide this plunder.
- Plunder?
Don't stand there gaping at me
like a fish. Put it away.
- What is this?
- It's some of the alcalde's gold.
And this I took from his charming wife.
It's pretty, don't you think?
You took it?
Have you seen this one, Padre?
So my old mentor has no more wit
than the rest of them, eh?
Are you trying to make me
the receiver of stolen goods?
No, the dispenser.
This gold was wrung from the peons.
It's up to us to restore it to them.
My boy.
My Diego.
Then you will lead your people
against these scorpions?
No, we'd be no match for their trained
troops. My father was right about that.
You must have had the alcalde at your mercy
when you took the gold from him.
I would have snuffed him out like a candle.
God forgive me.
It would accomplish nothing.
Anotherjust like him would take his place.
I see.
I see everything.
Diego, don't deceive your father any longer.
- It's not fair to him.
- I don't like doing it. Believe me.
But I must.
My father is such a stickler for law and order,
that I'm afraid he might spoil all the fun.
But what do you hope to achieve
all alone, taking his money?
Oh, no.
But I may be able to persuade him
to resign and name my father in his place.
- Amusing, don't you think?
- If you live.
Special Notice:
"Good people of Los Angeles,
do not give up nope. Luis Quintero
will soon resign and leave for Spain
or his blood shall drip
from my sword." Zorro
Dona Inez begs you to make yourself
comfortable. She'll be down shortly.
What's this?
- Don Diego Vega.
- Oh, yes. What can I do for you?
Have you forgotten that you urged me
to regard this house as still my home?
Did I?
It's very good of you to remember the offer,
but didn't you have trouble getting in?
Oh, no. I had a note from Dona Inez
asking me to ride with her this morning,
and I just showed it to the sentries.
Excellent.
Come into my study till my wife appears.
It's been Esteban's privilege
to ride with her each morning.
Why is this house so closely guarded?
I swear I saw a full company around it.
- I wish there were twice as many.
- Their clatter would drive me to distraction.
I find it reassuring.
Let me show you something, young man.
Look.
The mark of Zorro.
He came here one night.
He threatened my life and left that.
I should be petrified.
He's mad, of course.
Quite mad.
- You think so?
- Of course.
There was a case in Madrid, almost identical.
This fellow's mark was a cross.
He was a madman.
Cunning beyond belief.
They always are.
He killed 40 people.
Slit their throats from ear to ear.
Warned them first, you know, and then...
It's a pity your sense of duty keeps you here.
- Frightful risk.
- Sense of duty?
Yes, of course.
I'm so sorry to have kept you.
Esteban was surly about our little ride.
- I'd promised the morning to him, it seems.
- Your invitation was a smile from heaven.
- I was positively suffocating with boredom.
- Then let's fly. I'm dying for a canter.
Goodbye, Luis.
Don't work too hard.
Goodbye, Excellency.
Esteban, Vegajust told me a horrible tale
about a madman in Madrid, like this Zorro.
- He thinks I risk my life by staying here.
- Forget your fears. I have a plan.
Yes?
What is it?
Don Alejandro is the leader of the caballeros.
Zorro wants you to appoint him in your place.
- What do you gather from that?
- Go on.
Doesn't it suggest to you that Zorro
is the tool of Don Alejandro?
- Perhaps, but how can we prove it?
- We can at least help the situation.
- How?
- Form an alliance with Don Alejandro.
That's impossible.
You know Vega's attitude.
Perfectly, but Lolita should have a husband.
What could be stronger
than a matrimonial alliance?
Royal families keep
the peace of Europe in bridal beds.
Diego and Lolita.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
Diego, talking with you is like
a drink of cool water in the desert.
- Oh, it's a pity.
- What?
- I mustn't make you discontented.
- Oh, please. Of what were you thinking?
I was just thinking
how you're being wasted here.
Your beauty, your gift for words,
your perfect poise.
You were born for something higher
and more civilised than this provincial life.
I know.
- May I tell you something?
- Anything.
Yes, of course I may.
I felt from the moment we met that we...
Esteban is urging me to leave
my husband and go to Spain with him.
- Oh, but my dear, no.
- But I'm dying here.
Go to Spain, but not with Esteban.
With whom, then?
- With your husband.
- My husband?
- Go to romantic, beautiful Spain with Luis?
- Let me explain.
As the wife of the one-time alcalde
of Los Angeles, you'd be received at court.
But as the companion of a second-rate
soldier of fortune, you'd be ostracised.
I see.
But Luis at court, imagine.
In Spain the husbands of adorable ladies
are merely background.
- I'd be lost among so many.
- Not you.
You'd need only one "friend"
to introduce you into the proper circles.
But I have no such friend in Madrid.
Who knows? I don't intend
to remain in California for ever.
- What you suggest is utterly impossible.
- I'll give a dowry of 20,000 pesos. 25,000.
Are you buying my son, Senor Quintero?
- There's the practical side to consider.
- It doesn't enter into this.
You come here on a friendly mission
with half a company of troops. Why?
Not to threaten you, Don Alejandro.
It's because of this Zorro.
Zorro is only a symptom. This district
is bleeding under your vile administration.
I would never appear to condone it
by marriage between our families.
In that case, the friendly attitude
I've taken towards you, will cease.
What is all this turmoil about?
His Excellency has offered a marriage
between his niece Lolita and you.
His niece?
How flattering.
But why should that cause
an argument on a hot day like this?
- Do I have to explain?
- Your father resents my efforts
to make the people of the district
more industrious than under his regime.
Grinding them into poverty and despair
to line your own pockets is hardly...
Oh, politics, politics.
What have they to do with my marriage?
- You'd marry into the family of this...?
- How can I tell until I've seen her?
- She may look like her uncle.
- Quite right. I...
Oh, no. She's a sweet little dove. It would
desolate us to have her leave the nest.
If she were Venus,
she'd still be his niece.
But, after all,
I'm not marrying His Excellency.
Don't you think the wishes of your father
in this sort of matter should be considered?
I had no say in my father's marriage.
Why should he try to instruct me in mine?
Exactly.
Will you dine with us tonight?
- Charmed.
- We'll expect you at eight o'clock.
Diego, what have you done?
It will be all right.
No matter what you think now,
please don't worry.
This was your doing, you sly beast.
You gave Luis the idea of this marriage.
Alliances for the good of the state have
been fashionable since the dawn of history.
- María, my knees are shaking.
- Yes, that is natural.
- Shall I bow, or give him my hand to kiss?
- Both. First the hand, then the bow.
It's 20 minutes past the hour.
What can be keeping him?
Well, well, well.
Here you are at last.
I was afraid that you might have been
waylaid by that Zorro fellow.
Oh, heaven spare me.
- I am dazzled.
- And here is our little dove, Lolita.
- I am honoured.
- Charmed, I'm sure.
May I present Senora María de López?
You'll forgive me for being late.
They heated the water for my bath too early.
It was positively tepid. By the time
more was carried and properly scented...
Life can be trying, don't you think?
- Oh, please.
- Courage.
Well, shall we dine?
Come, Diego.
His bath was tepid.
Poor Lolita. I'm afraid
her wedded life will be the same.
- Please do that again.
- As you wish. Observe closely.
- Amazing.
- Quite simple.
- Have you seen this one?
- No.
Now, observe very closely.
- Frightfully amusing.
- Yes, I did this one for His Majesty.
- It must be heavenly at court.
- It's the one bearable spot on earth.
Speaking of that Zorro, Excellency,
could you provide me with an escort home?
On the way here, I fancied that cutthroat
lurking in every shadow. I was unnerved.
How distressing.
- You don't approve of my request.
- You called her hero a cutthroat.
Have you met the fellow?
I've never so much as seen his face.
I happen to admire courage.
Dashing about with a cutlass has been
out of fashion since the Middle Ages.
It seems to be quite effective. He is like
a lion among a lot of frightened sheep.
A madman, that's what he is.
Undoubtedly.
Capitán, you seem to regard
that poor fruit as an enemy.
A rival.
My dear Esteban is for ever
thrusting at this and that.
He used to be
a fencing instructor in Barcelona.
How exhausting.
- I didn't find it so.
- Then why did you give it up?
- Unfortunately, I killed a man of influence.
- A lady was involved, I believe.
The gentleman's wife, no doubt?
Just how did you mean that?
I'd hoped to be amusing.
Have I failed?
Somewhat.
With me.
What are the new dance steps?
You know them all, I suppose.
- I'm afraid so.
- I would so love to have you show me.
Gladly.
- Inez would enjoy it more.
- Nonsense, my child. Dance with him.
Play "El Sombrero Blanco".
I never dreamed dancing
could be so wonderful.
I found it rather fatiguing.
- If you'll excuse me, I wish to retire.
- So sorry.
- What's got into the girl?
- Who knows?
- Our little dove has flown.
- I don't like it.
You can't be serious about this marriage.
But, my dear, it's perfect.
You and I could be seen together anywhere
in Madrid without any danger of gossip.
- Excellency, your niece is charming.
- A sweet child.
May I plead with you
for her hand in marriage?
A refusal would crush me.
She's yours, my dear Diego,
with all my blessings.
Who's there?
- I have a confession to make.
- Please go. You'll be caught.
I must talk to you.
Now, look here, my girl.
What do you mean by running away from the
man to whom I've promised you in marriage?
- You've done that without asking me?
- Of course.
What do you know about such things?
And it's time that you understood that...
- Who's that?
- No one.
Forgive me, my dear.
I've been an old fool.
You seem to know how to handle these
matters much better than your Uncle Luis.
You?
Don't come in here.
I have something important to say to you
and I don't want to be interrupted.
You, pretending to be Zorro.
I don't care to hear anything you have to say.
So unlock that door and go.
I'm glad to see you took the advice
I gave you in the chapel.
About not hiding such beauty in a convent.
What did you say?
You're more lovely,
more radiant than a morning in June.
Surely I must be dreaming.
- You are Zorro.
- Yes, Lolita.
In order to accomplish what I set out to do,
I've had to deceive people, including you.
Yes, I see.
I understand.
You don't have to explain.
You came here to tell me that asking
to marry me was just part of the game.
Oh, no. That's the one real thing
about this whole masquerade.
- Go quickly.
- Ride with me tomorrow.
Yes, but go.
Be careful.
- Open the door.
- Yes, I'm coming.
You seem upset, my dear.
Have you been crying?
- Yes, I have.
- I understand.
This marriage was your uncle's idea.
He's not your type, and far too sophisticated.
- You really think so?
- Beyond a question.
I saw how he affected you tonight.
My heart bled for you, my dear.
When you tell Luis you'll have none of
this marriage, you'll have my full support.
I hardly know what to say.
Uncle Luis has done so much for me.
Nonsense. He has no right
to expect you to spoil your life.
Any marriage is better than none, I suppose.
Perhaps I could learn to tolerate Diego.
I do so want to please Uncle Luis.
There's such a thing
as carrying gratitude too far.
We can't ask you to spend your life
with a man you think repulsive.
We'll talk of this again in the morning.
Good night, my dear.
Past midnight.
He's not home yet.
- How can you read?
- It's the latest European styles.
- Bustles are coming in, it seems.
- Bustles! What is a bustle?
It's something to build you up here.
Our only son
in the clutches of those polecats,
and you sit there
planning to decorate your...
There you are. Why didn't you spend
the entire night with your delightful friends?
What have you done about that girl?
Well, how did you get out of it?
She's perfectly charming.
A lovely, unspoiled child.
- You'll be delighted with her, Father.
- I will be delighted? What have you done?
I've just taken the first steps
toward making you a grandfather.
What?
What a son you bore me.
An alliance with those terrible people.
Why did you do it?
- For the best reason in the world.
- What is that?
- Lolita Quintero.
- She attracts you?
- It's more than that. From the day I first saw...
- I thought you hadn't met her until tonight.
I did catch a glimpse of her
some time ago, and...
You're concealing something from us.
I'm sure of it.
- It's time you went to bed.
- Very well.
But, Diego, tell me as soon as you can.
I will, Mother.
- What's the meaning of that?
- Gonzales was collecting taxes.
A priest resisted.
The fool gave him ten lashes.
- Send Gonzales to me.
- I wish I could.
- What's to prevent it?
- The total disappearance of Gonzales.
- He's gone? Where?
- To Hades, I hope.
I'll collect the taxes
myself from now on.
That should teach them.
What's that?
You...
- What's that?
- Sergeant Gonzales. I think he's dead.
Dead, you say?
- He's alive.
- He's got a Z on his chest.
José.
How is the little one?
She is well again.
I brought this to give thanks to the church.
Give thanks in your heart.
Buy milk for the child with this.
No. This is for the church.
I come at precisely
the right moment, it seems.
- I'll take that.
- These are the funds of the mission.
Not any longer.
Hand them over.
- I refuse.
- In that case, I shall take them.
You should have been a soldier
rather than a churchman.
No wonder you chose the Church.
- Where did you get this?
- I'll tell you nothing.
Run me through and have done with it.
No, my dear Padre.
We shall presently hang you.
For the last time. If you marry that girl,
you leave this house for ever.
It might be rather amusing
to live with the Quinteros.
If I'd only left him in Spain.
Wait till you see her.
She's just like this blossom.
I'll never see her.
I promise you that.
- We are not at home.
- I'm at home to the senorita. Show her in.
- So you defy me, too?
- You're not being sensible.
- Father, this is Lolita.
- I am honoured.
And my mother.
Please forgive me, but would it be
possible to see you alone for a moment?
Senorita, will you answer me one question?
- Certainly.
- Do you want to marry my son?
- Why, yes.
- Why?
Well, I love him.
You are right, my son.
She is like the flower.
Something terrible has happened.
They've arrested Fray Felipe.
They say he is Zorro
and they are going to hang him.
- Where is he now?
- At the barracks. What can you do?
I don't know yet.
So far I've only frightened your uncle.
This may mean I'll have to do more than that.
Do you understand?
If that becomes necessary,
will it make any difference between us?
Sentries!
There's someone in that chair. Seize him.
Diego, what are you doing here?
You frightened me half out of my wits.
This is too much, really.
It's distressing enough to call on
my betrothed and not find her at home.
- Now to be manhandled by these ruffians.
- Leave us.
Where is Lolita?
Oh, riding, driving, walking.
What does a young girl do?
Am I to understand
that my betrothed is allowed to
wander about the countryside
without a duenna?
I protest, Your Excellency.
I protest strongly.
I can't discuss that now.
Do you know Zorro
had a priest for an accomplice?
We arrested him today.
And another horrible thing happened to me.
Sergeant Gonzales
was beaten half to death by Zorro.
He shoved him over the wall
right before my eyes.
How frightful.
But after all, it was harder on Gonzales.
This is no time forjesting.
Perhaps, that madman is lurking
on the grounds right now.
What shall I do?
I offer rewards and nothing happens.
He may change his mind about you.
Those creatures usually do, I believe.
He may decide to
cut the throat of someone else.
- Must you always talk of throat-cutting?
- How thoughtless of me.
- What you need is a drop of brandy.
- Yes, brandy...
It's gone. I'm surrounded by idiots.
Stupid servants, stupid soldiers.
I admire you tremendously.
Your courage, your fortitude.
Why, a weaker man would forget
his civic duty and get away from all this.
- You rang, Your Excellency?
- Yes, brandy.
- On the desk, Your Excellency.
- It's not on the desk. Bring some.
A situation of this sort would wreck
my constitution in a week.
But then I haven't the iron nerve
of Your Excellency.
Your Excellency, come quickly.
Something has happened in the cellar.
Guards.
You, follow me.
Look.
Look, Your Excellency.
Here in the cellar, right below my study.
Here's his trail.
It goes this way.
It ends here.
He couldn't have gone through the wall.
He's not human. He's...
Light my way out of here. Quick!
You were right.
I'll leave this cursed place.
I'll do as he asks.
Pen, paper...
A man should consider his wife.
Inez has gone crazy over the idea of Madrid.
She's been at me
night and day to take her there.
This should do it.
This should suit that maniac.
There, look it over.
That's very direct.
But you forgot to sign.
- Sign what?
- My resignation.
Zorro will kill me if I stay.
You may escape him, but I will surely
kill you if you write any more of these.
But I'm in grave danger.
Diego here will bear me out.
You're in even greater danger than he thinks.
So you tried to get gold out of the country?
If you ever again take one peso of mine,
I'll cut your throat from ear to ear.
I must ask you to change the subject.
He objects to talk of throat-cutting.
Quiet, you popinjay.
I've no reason for letting you live either.
What a pleasant coincidence.
I feel exactly the same way about you.
You wouldn't care to translate
that feeling into action, would you?
I might be tempted, if I had a weapon.
Would you?
Now, please, gentlemen.
- This is going much too far.
- It's only to serve you, Excellency.
You have a champion, Luis.
And what a champion.
I'll make it short, and save you fatigue.
- Sentries!
- No interference, Excellency, please.
We have a hero with us.
- Are you all right, Diego?
- Ask the capitán.
Get out.
The fencing master has met his equal.
Careful.
- Are you tiring, Diego?
- No, Excellency, I'll take you on in a moment.
- It's a good effort, capitán.
- My next will be better, my fancy clown.
- The capitán's blade is not so firm.
- Still firm enough to run you through.
I needed that scratch to awaken me.
He's dead.
Well, he's been troublesome lately.
And you killed him.
A secret stairway from the cellar.
We just discovered it.
A secret stairway?
Leading here?
Good. Very good.
Excellent.
You shall be rewarded.
Sentries!
Keep that man covered.
Take him to the guardhouse
and lock him in the cell.
- The strongest cell you have.
- Why arrest me, Excellency?
For three reasons. First, you have
mud from the cellar on your boots.
Second, that secret stairway
happens to be in your old home.
And third, you handle a sword
like a devil from hell.
And that's exactly
where you're going, Senor Zorro.
That's a pretty way to treat
your future nephew, Uncle Luis.
No more of your wit.
Take him away.
You, Morales...
Send the officer of the day to me. I want
all caballeros and peons summoned here.
All caballeros are requested to report
at the alcalde's residence immediately.
- At this hour? Ridiculous.
- The alcalde's orders.
Sergeant, assemble your men
for firing-squad duty.
- But why did they arrest Diego?
- I don't know.
Luis won't tell me.
He must have lost his mind.
Come in.
His Excellency requests you ladies
to stay in your rooms tonight.
- Why?
- I cannot say. I was ordered to tell you.
Firing squad, forward.
- Good evening.
- Why are we meeting here, Senor Vega?
What do you know, Alejandro?
Nothing. I was forced
to come here like the rest of you.
They must be up to something.
Good evening, senores.
It's a pleasure to see you here.
Get to the point. Why have you
dragged us out of our homes at this hour?
To witness a delightful spectacle.
You will find it particularly interesting.
I'm executing a caballero at midnight.
- What caballero?
- Who is it?
The man you selected from among you
to defy me, to threaten my life.
I brought you here to see him die
as a lesson to the lot of you.
I, for one, don't know
what you're talking about.
You almost convince me.
Too bad you're about to lose
the best actor among you.
But in a few moments,
you'll see your precious Zorro shot.
Observe very closely.
Watch the candle.
Blow.
You should really see something worthwhile,
like changing a copper coin into solid gold.
- Can you do that?
- The good padre here has seen me do it.
- Many times.
- It was a secret discovered by Merlin.
It's been handed down through a long line
of sorcerers to some of us living today.
You can change a centavo into gold?
- Easily.
- Please, do that for me.
I am very weary.
I must seek repose.
I have a wife and seven children,
and the little I earn isn't enough for them.
Please, make gold for them
and I'll pray for you.
If I must, I must.
Now, hold the centavo in your closed fist.
Tightly now.
Put your fist well through the bars.
Cold iron will spoil everything.
I take your fist gently, like this.
Open the door.
Be quick about it.
Get in. Get down under there,
close to the wall.
And not a sound.
Close the door.
Hide this in your robe.
Sit down.
And now, you will behold the result
of your rebellious plans. Come in.
Here is Zorro the fox, safely trapped.
Diego!
What is this?
What idiotic joke is this?
- As if you didn't know.
- Luis Quintero, you are a fool.
Zorro is a man. This is my worthless,
trick-playing offspring.
Have you seen this one, Father?
Help!
Zorro is loose.
- Senores, are you with me?
- I am with you.
God, forgive me.
What a splendid audience you have.
Peons, caballeros, everyone.
- It was thoughtful of you to have them here.
- Luis, what's happened?
Good evening, ladies. You're just in time.
His Excellency is about to make an address.
Address? What shall I say?
You know.
The little matter of your resignation.
Quiet!
Quiet for His Excellency.
We're waiting. Go on.
Good people of Los Angeles,
owing to my ceaseless efforts
to improve conditions in the district...
my health is endangered.
I have therefore decided
to give up my office and go to Spain.
To succeed me as alcalde of this district,
I am naming my illustrious predecessor,
Don Alejandro Vega.
And now, Your Excellency, I personally will
accompany you to the wharf at San Pedro.
I wish to bless your voyage, and ask God
to reward you according to your merits.
Spain...
Spain!
Diego, when may we expect you
and our dear little Lolita in Madrid?
- We'll follow the customs of California.
- What do you mean?
We are going to marry, and raise fat children
and watch our vineyards grow.
Subtitles by Visiontext
ENGLISH