Cain and Abel
Episode 19
Did Sun Woo oppa's tumor get worse?
Lee Sun Woo,
just tell me you're sorry,
that you made a mistake.
Just say that one thing.
Then, we can turn everything back.
Because I wanted to be
Lee Sun Woo's little brother,
Lee Jong Min's child,
and Na Hye Joo's son.
Sun Woo hyung.
"Cho In... "
"my little brother,"
"I'm sorry."
Just say that one thing for me.
Just that one thing.
No.
I can't say it.
Because my little brother Lee Cho In
already died in China.
Episode 19
Since when was it?
When did Lee Sun Woo
develop a tumor?
He said he relapsed.
What?
Seven years ago when he cut off contact in America,
that's when they first discovered it.
I wanted to get acknowledgement from Father.
I wanted to fix the heart of the girl I loved.
I gave up on my previous
specialty of thoracic surgery
and transferred to neurology.
A mother's embrace...
I, not ever having experienced it, I too...
I too lived.
The things I can't have
no matter how hard I tried,
you got them way too easily.
"My little brother,"
"I'm sorry."
Say it for me!
You can send the results of the test
immediately through PACS, right?
Yes.
PACS = Imaging storage and transmission system
that connects all medical images in the hospital.
What are you doing?
Director...
Who told you to do this?
Who told you to take a CT of my brain?
You were brought to the Emergency Room,
so Dr. Lee Cho In ordered it.
[Lee Sun Woo]
Delete the results.
Excuse me?
Delete the results immediately
and don't upload it onto PACS.
Don't you hear me?
Delete it immediately!
Ah, yes.
Dr. Shin Sang Su,
don't tell anyone about
what happened today.
That includes Cho In and everyone else.
Do you understand?
Y... yes, I understand.
Dr. Shin, is it really okay to delete it?
Won't it become a problem then?
He himself wants it deleted.
Cho In, can't you treat Sun Woo oppa?
Kim Seo Yeon,
you know what Lee Sun Woo did to me,
so how can you ask me that?
But what can we do?
He's your hyung, and your family.
He's the hyung you lived
with for over 30 years.
No...
I don't have anything like an older brother.
Then, are you going to let
Sun Woo oppa die like that?
Lee Cho In, can you do that?
Can you?
Why?
You think I can't?
Oppa, are you okay?
Are you okay?
What about the CT?
The results are probably out.
Should we go look together?
Kim Seo Yeon, you can go back now.
Lee Sun Woo,
I told you not to do this to me.
Lee Sun Woo...
Lee Sun Woo!
This can't be.
How can it in that amount of time?
Director Lee Sun Woo said to delete them,
but due to the hospital's regulations,
I left them on the hard drive.
Lee Sun Woo.
Father...
did you know?
Lee Sun Woo is sick.
With a straight face,
he tried to kill me,
and now he says he's sick.
If he tried to kill his brother,
he shouldn't be sick
and live until the end.
Young Ji, why would you be bad?
I'm so grateful for you.
Do you like it?
Doctor.
Young Ji, what are you doing?
With the make up you
gave me in Cheong Ju,
I was giving myself a massage.
Young Ji, do you want
to see this hospital fail?
What do you mean?
I mean,
without massages, there's a rumor
saying how pretty you are,
so all the young doctors are drooling.
If you do massages and get prettier,
what are you going to do then?
Huh?
Don't do that.
What's this?
It's a notebook.
A notebook?
I think Father didn't like that notebook.
He threw it and broke it.
Wow! Did he get better that fast?
Young Ji, sometimes when I look at you,
you really seem stupid.
You're so cute.
Don't do that.
Young Ji, please take it to his room.
It's a request.
Don't worry.
I'll explain to your father
about this computer.
Oh, there's something on your face.
Close your eyes.
I'll get going.
Let's go together.
This is nice.
What about people?
So what if others see?
A lot of younger people link arms now.
Oh, who's this?
Lee Cho In.
Emergency Center founding director,
Director Kim Hyun Joo.
Dr. Lee Cho In.
Okay.
Let's hug.
I heard the detectives that
you were cleared of the charges.
I was worried.
Congratulations.
Thank you for believing in me.
My arms are about to fall off.
Let's hug.
Good work.
Oh, Jin Keun sunbae,
did you drink?
How can I not drink?
Hey, the Emergency Center
was decided upon,
and you were cleared of charges,
so I had to drink.
Do I smell a lot?
There are a lot of troubles ahead, Chief
...no, Director.
Yeah, there's so much to do.
It looks like a thorny path from the start.
Now what is a thorny path?
It's all done. Why are you fussing?
The decision made by the board
hasn't officially been announced yet.
They're going to start the
Neurology Center somehow,
so the Vice President is holding
this decision until the next meeting.
Oh.
I'll take care of that,
So, Director, can you make the decision for
the center's first day and the blueprint?
Well, that's something I've always
talked to the President about,
so that's no problem.
Okay, let's start from there.
Then, please take care of this request.
Okay. See you later.
Work hard.
Father, try moving it.
What do you think?
Don't you think this computer is
more comfortable than the other one?
I'll also tell you the steps for writing.
Then, try using it once.
[Oh Young Ji]
Father...,
you still remembered my name?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Now,  try writing what you want to write.
[Miss Oh Young Ji right now]
[the letter I'm writing...]
Vice President.
What is it that you have to say
about Dr. Lee Sun Woo?
I'm sure you already know,
Dr. Lee Sun Woo's condition
is very bad right now.
Sun Woo...
To tell you the truth,
the linear accelerator we used last time
caused reverse effect only.
linear accelerator = a high tech cancer treatment using
the energy from accelerating an electron
If we just leave him like this,
curing him is definite,
though whether it be a month or a week,
no one can know how long he'll have to live.
Then,
what do you think we should do?
We should perform surgery
right away and extract the tumor
and have him go through chemotherapy.
Then will that save Sun Woo?
No, it'll prevent him
from getting worse.
Even if we do surgery,
he'll live for at most two years.
He should do it, right?
If we can have him live one more day,
he should get surgery, right?
Yes.
Do whatever you have to do
to save Sun Woo.
Do you understand?
Yes, I do.
Why are you here?
You're not even going to ask to me sit?
What do you want?
This is the list of equipment
for the emergency center.
The decision the board made about
the Emergency Center, please announce it today.
What do you mean do it?
Did you just order me to do it?
Did you hear it as an order?
Then, you should follow it.
What?
And...
Lee Sun Woo,
you should discharge him
from the hospital.
What do you mean discharge?
What are you saying right now?!
For someone who has a grade 4
tumor to hold a scalpel,
don't you know what that means?
WHO grade 4 =  Classification for tumors is
from grade 1, benign, to grade 4, most malignant.
Someone who assisted with murder and
the person who murdered are the same!
Wasn't enough to try to kill me?
Who are you trying to kill now?
No, Lee Sun Woo might die first.
Lee Cho In, are you threatening me?
Do you hear this as a threat?
Alright.
Tomorrow, I will contact the office
of the board of trustees.
No, do it right now.
Connect me to the office
of the board of trustees.
Director of the Board,
it's me, the Vice President.
Announce the decision
of the board right now.
I will send you the organization of the
Emergency Center, so announce it together.
Is that all?
No, it's just the start.
So, I'll be going.
There's someone waiting outside to meet you.
General Manager,
what is this?
Director Lee Sun Woo,
no ... he's just Doctor now, isn't he?
It's an ethics committee meeting
for Dr. Lee Sun Woo.
Ethics committee meeting?
It's real!
The expansion of the Emergency Center.
The Center's director is Chief Kim Hyun Joo.
You're going to make Dr. Lee Sun Woo
stand in front of an ethics committee,
and have a witch hunt right now?
Vice President,
I don't think this is a situation
you can cope with emotionally.
What did you say?
Since the case conference,
you know that the number of patients
coming to the Neurology Center
has decreased tremendously, right?
On top of that, the admitted patients
are saying they'll transfer hospitals,
and the number of patients
refusing treatment is increasing.
If it continues like this,
the Neurology Center that President Lee Jung Min
was insistent on making will collapse.
Also,
if Dr. Lee Sun Woo's sickness is found out,
then you will have to take
the responsibility for that.
Did Lee Cho In, that bastard,
tell you to say this?
I'm asking if that bastard Lee Cho In
told you, General Manager, to tell me this!
I'm the Consultation General Manager.
I know this much too, Vice President.
Get out.
Get out of my sight immediately.
Then, have a good day.
How did my Sun Woo come this far.
Do you know how he got here?
Those bastards.
Are you not going to get ready
to treat the patients?
Director,
we want to continue working here
at the Bosung University Hospital,
but we no longer can.
Dr. Nam Yong Tae,
what are you saying right now?
As you know Director, there are
no admitted patients as well as no outpatients.
We, the residents, want to
further our skills by seeing patients,
but we no longer have the chance to do that.
On top of that,
the Neurology Center has been cancelled.
We're sorry,
but Director, make a decision.
Are you telling me to give up the
Director's position and leave right now?
If that's what it takes to save the patients
and our Neurology Center...
Did you just say "save the patients"?
Do you think you have the talent
to tell me to make a decision?
If you're going to disobey me,
do so after you have the talent to do so!
Then, I'll take what you have
to say into consideration.
It's an ethics committee meeting request, Director.
Lee Cho In, are you trying
to take my doctor's license?
Since you suddenly disappeared, Oh Young Ji,
do you know how harsh the complaints
we got from the Chinese tourists were?
I'm sorry, Director.
At least Yang Dong Mi was
able to resolve the situation.
There could have been a big problem.
I'm very sorry.
Since it's the first time,
I'll let it go with this.
Go in and do your work.
Yes.
Young Ji...
Congratulations.
What do you mean?
The board decided on the Emergency Center.
The Emergency Center?
It's the Emergency Center
that Dr. Lee Cho In wanted.
Is that so?
Then, does that mean something
good happened to my doctor?
What kind of person,
who came in with help, doesn't know?
Young Ji.
Doctor.
Let's go eat.
Doctor,
I heard you have good news.
Is that true?
Yes. I can now have
my father's wish come true.
That's great.
That's very great.
You know about father...
Lee Cho In.
Young Ji, just wait a little bit.
I'll be right back.
No. You two should slowly talk.
I'll be done soon.
Wait for me.
Okay.
Lee Cho In,
are you the one who's trying
to take off my doctor's coat?
You have no right to be a doctor.
What?
The tumor on your left lob is 4.7 cm,
but you've continued doing surgery.
That's something I'll take care of on my own.
A patient's life's on the line,
so how can it be your problem?
With a tumor in your head,
if you go into surgery and have a seizure,
what are you going to do then?
To you,
is a patient's life that worthless?
Now that I think about it,
it must be worthless.
That's why you killed your brother, right?
Are you doing this, not knowing
how important the Neurology Center is to me?
I'm doing this because I know.
Don't you get it?
You brat.
There's no strength in your right hand?
Are you already suffering from flaccid paralysis?
flaccid paralysis = Muscles have no response
no matter how much they are stimulated.
You don't have the right to be a doctor.
You take off your gown on your own.
No, I can't even if I die.
I won't give up being a doctor, even if I die.
Then, clarify justly at the
ethics committee meeting.
Young Ji.
Doctor.
I'm hungry.
What should we eat?
Doctor, is the Emergency Center that important?
Isn't it because of the Center that your relationship
with Dr. Lee Sun Woo is so bad?
It's all done, so you don't have
to worry about it, okay?
I'm still worried though.
Isn't he your only hyung in this world?
I'm thankful you're worried,
but when we're together,
let's only talk about us.
Okay.
And, let's touch like this.
Doctor.
What?
You said you love me.
You said that last time.
You don't?
Young Ji, last time we couldn't
see the nightlife, right?
Do you want to go tonight?
Today?
Yes.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Father...
Trying to win you over,
I never wanted that.
I wanted to be like you.
So I ran after you,
looking at your back.
If this is what you want,
then I'll have to follow, right?
But Father,
my gown being taken off
by someone else's hands,
I can never see that.
Instead,
I'd rather die.
Father...
Just a little...
why didn't you hold me
just a little earlier?
Just a little...
earlier...
Father.
Doctor,
in Ahngyeongdo where I used to live,
the lights would all be off
at night, so it'd be black.
But here in Seoul,
even when it's night
the lights are lit,
so it's very pretty.
People probably lit all those lights, right?
Those people who lost family, right?
When we become a family,
do you think we can
become like those lights?
I wonder what kind of people your family is.
Those people are probably
very plain people, right?
They care about each other
and love each other.
I'll find out when I meet them.
What does that mean?
I'm searching for your parents.
We can probably hear good news soon.
Doctor.
Don't be touched yet.
Young Ji,
just because you meet your real family,
you can't push me away, okay?
How could I do that to you?
Even if you told me to,
I'd hold on tight and never let go.
Never.
I throw away but our memories that are still left
Even with my eyes closed I look for you
I call you and call you whose sick
You hold onto me, whose unsteady
Stop
trying to hide those tears
that keep flowing down my cheeks
Stop
the lies that left me hurt
Today I swallow to end them
In the end, I will forget
It will end
Yeah, it's not a big deal
It'll become okay like this
See, even if you're not here
I'll still able to live
I am
Even though the tears have dried
I still don't have the confidence
I don't
Should I try calling him?
Yeah.
Where is Dr. Lee Sun Woo right now?
What?
Alright.
They said Dr. Lee Sun Woo
didn't come today.
Dr. Lee Cho In, it seems like
Dr. Lee Sun Woo didn't come today.
Would you still like to go ahead?
No, let's wait for him
to do this at another time.
That's okay, right?
Thank you.
When you hear the beep, leave a message.
After the message, press the # key.
Lee Sun Woo, where are you right now?
Are you hiding cowardly?
You were so confident,
but why are you hiding now?
Come out.
There's nowhere in the world you can hide.
- Ahjumma.
- Oh, Seo Yeon.
I couldn't get in touch with Sun Woo oppa,
so I thought maybe something was wrong.
He's not contacting you either?
Then..
Vice President.
What happened?
Have you found Sun Woo?
We were just contacted by the police.
They found his car.
Where?
They found it near Gangwondo.
Gangwondo?
Then, perhaps Belly Button Villa?
What do you mean "Belly Button Villa"?
You know Ahjussi's villa.
It's in the center of Korean land,
so Oppa and Cho In call it Belly Button Villa.
I'll go.
I'll go and contact you.
Will you do that?
Dr. Kang Seok Hun.
Dr. Lee Sun Woo's condition,
how bad is it?
He received a treatment of 50 linear acceleration,
but an irregularity is forming by his tumor.
If he doesn't have surgery right away,
no one can know how much longer he has.
You're trying to ruin my doctor's license?
I spent 17 hours of everyday, without fail,
trudging around the OR.
Father did not acknowledge me,
and did not give me a chance.
It may be "no more than" to you,
who monopolized Father's love,
but not to me.
Because you were the brother I loved
more than anyone in the world.
Because you were my idol!
Because you were like a god to me!
Because my little brother Lee Cho In
already died in China.
Lee Sun Woo, then your sins are not forgiven.
Cho In...
Cho In, this is the sound of my heart.
Do you hear it?
Yeah. I hear it.
Lee Cho In, until the day
this heart stops beating,
I will protect you.
Just like today,
if anyone bothers you again,
I'll protect you.
I won't let you suffer by yourself again.
I promise.
Do you remember?
In our childhood, when I went
around smiling all the time?
"What are you so happy about?",
Mother would chide.
Back then,
I really wasn't happy at all.
Lee Sun Woo, you...
I loved you more than anyone in the world.
It's been three years, and you came back.
It's like a dream.
You and I were so happy,
we hugged.
Sun Woo hyung, where are you hiding?
I miss you.
No matter how much I close my eyes
Dear Sun Woo
happy birthday.
No matter how much I hold a grudge
It's been four years since I've seen you.
I miss you.
Hurry come back here.
I just call you
I just look for you
I regret it,
Even though you make me cry
Cho In.
My heart that only knows you
Enough to die. I regret it.
Stopping the deeply impressed memories
I can't forget
I wander looking for you
I hug you and love you
and live in my dreams
Stupid.
At that one word let's separate
My heart just breaks
What are you going to do?
How can I forget you
when I'm not ready yet?
My heart that only looked at you
All those promises
Hurt
I only see you
What do I do?
Is there a love that's not yours?
Even if you leave and forget me,
even if you love again,
my heart that can't have you,
even if a burn mark is left,
the person I am waiting for
is only you.
Your love is the only one
that can make me better
My heart
Sun Woo oppa, where are you?
Can you come get me?
Yeah. Where are you?
Where are you?
Can you take me and go to Seoul?
Just wait a little.
I'll be there.
Just wait.
Oppa!
Oppa.
You're okay....
You're okay, Oppa.
You'll be okay soon.
You're okay.
Sun Woo oppa, can you hear me?
I'm right here.
Seo Yeon isn't going anywhere
and here by your side.
Oppa...
It's been 7 years since
I've received my heart.
Because of you and Lee Cho In,
you brothers,
I've been through so much pain,
so I don't know how much
more I can take.
I don't want to take someone
else's heart to live.
I don't want to wait
for someone I love.
So, Oppa...
whether it be two months or two years,
let's get treatment.
Let's get up soon,
and go to Cho In
and beg for forgiveness,
and live with me, okay?
Now hold my hand
and go for walks
and read me books.
You have to let me wear a dress.
You have to get up
and tell me you love me.
Right?
You're up?
I'm sorry.
I can only do this much.
I'm really sorry to you.
Lee Sun Woo.
Seo Yeon, can you take me to Seoul?
... to Cho In?
Will you take me?
Yeah. Let's go.
Let's go to Cho In.
[Lee Cho In]
[My son]
[I'm leaving this...]
- Hello.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
You came?
Lee Sun Woo still didn't come?
- Isn't that Dr. Lee Sun Woo?
- Right?
I heard he didn't come to the ethics hearing.
Did he finally show up?
Then, does that mean Dr. Lee
is going to lose his license?
Don't you think his body looks a bit weird?
Maybe he really does have a tumor.
Seo Yeon,
from here,
will you let me walk on my own?
Yeah, go safely.
Lee Cho In...
Why?
Are you scared because you're dying?
Is that why you put aside
your pride and came?
Trying to do whatever to live?
Yeah, that's why I came.
Lee Cho In, you perform my surgery.
What?
Whether I live or die,
you decide.
Why do I have to do that?
Someone who's dying on his own,
someone who tried to kill me,
why do I, with my hands, have to save him?
If I die, I want to by your hands.
If I live, I want to by your hands.
Lee Cho In, you do the surgery.
I'm not doing the surgery.
I won't and while
you regret it until you die,
little by little...,
slowly...,
I'm going to watch you die.
- Dr. Kim,
- Yes?
Cho In, do you think he'll perform
Lee Sun Woo's surgery?
What do you mean do you think?
He has to.
He's still his hyung.
That's what's worrying me more.
Looking at Cho In lately,
I don't think he'll blink an eye even
if he heard Lee Sun Woo is dying.
Well, now that you said that,
that's true.
Is that true?
Dr. Lee Cho In refused to perform
Dr. Lee Sun Woo's surgery, is that true?
The news has spread all
throughout the hospital.
I didn't see Dr. Lee Cho In like that,
but I guess he's very harsh.
Should I help you?
No, I'll do it.
Okay.
It was my everything.
Oppa...
Oppa..
Sun Woo oppa...
Is someone there?
Someone help.
Oppa...
Dr. Lee Sun Woo...
When did he get like this?
He got like this five minutes before, Doctor.
His brain pressure is increasing!
Take him to the emergency CT scan
and get an operation room ready.
Yes.
Cho In...
Dr. Lee Sun Woo, stay still.
Lee Cho In.
Oppa...
What are you doing?
Move him to the CT room.
- Yes.
- Oppa
Move him to the CT room now.
Yes.
If he doesn't have surgery right away,
no one can know how much longer he has.
How could a brother kill a brother?!
I thought when I returned from the States,
that my Neurology Center would be established.
But, what was waiting for me
was just your name
on a lousy "Gift Agreement" piece of paper.
And Father,
rather than choosing me,
had chose you, Lee Cho In!
If I die, I want to by your hands.
If I live, I want to by your hands.
Lee Cho In, you do the surgery.
Dr. Lee Cho In.
Dr. Lee Cho In, where are you?
The CT results from the emergency room
are here and there is internal bleeding.
What's more urgent is that the bigger tumor
has internal bleeding and a lot of swelling.
If he doesn't have surgery right now,
I don't know what's going to
happen to Dr. Lee Sun Woo.
Cho In, are you listening?
Dr. Lee Cho In.
Lee Sun Woo...
just...
die...
Then close his head back up
after just reducing the pressure?
We need to stop the internal hemorrhage
and remove the tumor, don't we?!
Unstable.
Let's hurry.
What about Cho In?
Where is Cho In?
Sun Woo said if it isn't Cho In,
he won't get surgery from anyone.
Dr. Kang Seok Hun, call him again.
You just went in,
but why are you out?
He couldn't...
Do you think that too, Young Ji?
For my one and only brother
I won't perform surgery,
so that I'm a bad person?
I know how you feel, Doctor.
I know that compared to doing surgery,
not doing it is much harder.
This...
I will do as I wish.