Marriage, Not Dating
Han Groo
Yeon Woo Jin
Jung Jin Woon
Han Sun Hwa
Heo Jeong Min
Yoon So Hee
Marriage, Not Dating
I heard you have an attachment to this house?
When I was young, there was a time I've lived alone in this house for a few days.
At that time, I had the memories of happiness and warmth.
So even after becoming an adult and I'm in the house alone,
my heart feels at ease here.
Yes, so you are still living in this house alone?
Recently, some woman has started coming here.
After that woman flipped this house upside-down,
she ruined the innate meaning of the house.
After that woman came to this house,
I've come to be uncomfortable and dislike
being in this house alone.
Yes...
I've come to want to be together with that person.
Episode 14  Sorry for not being cool.
Episode 14  Thanks for not being cool.
Let's...
How about a cool relationship?
-What?  -Let's just do the dating.
Not the marriage.
Who are you?
I told you not to laugh.
I really want to be different this time.
Until now, with just the desire to be together,
I thought that was all it took and put everything into it.
Then, in the end, I messed everything up.
I even got a criminal record and was labeled a stalker.
That's because your partner was Lee Hoon Dong.
Yeah.
This time, it is Gong Gi Tae.
This time, I really don't want to mess things up.
Let's just keep our relationship secret for a while.
If our parents know, the house will flip over again.
I'm saying we shouldn't prematurely let our parents find out and hurt them even more.
First, we should fix what we messed up.
We should put the hospital back in place,
and I should find my place, too.
Your mother, because of me staying by your side, thinks it
is because of the money.
We can resolve the misunderstanding.
No.
If I don't change, the misunderstanding will never get resolved.
When people know about the relationship between you and me,
I hate hearing them calling me Cinderella.
After earning money and becoming a dutiful daughter to my mom and dad,
I want to stand by your side proudly.
But you...
You're like kimchi stew. (Eating Kimchee Stew by yourself is an expression that means getting ahead of yourself.)
-Huh?  - Did someone say that they would marry you?
Even when a person's not thinking of that, you're already so hasty.
Here. Just start drinking wine.
Cheers.
I drank it all.
I have said everything I was going to say.
I'll go home.
Hey! Hey!
You're already leaving?
Why are you in such a hurry?
You, for that matter... Why are you in such a hurry?
I am leaving.
Hey! Hey! Wait a minute.
I'll escort you home.
Don't be clingy. I said we should date coolly.
I...
I have to hear that, not from just any person, but from you?
Bye.
♬ Your face flickers before me today ♬
♬ I can’t take it anymore ♬
♬ Starting from tomorrow ♬
♬ we will live happily together ♬
Good morning!
Director. The client who posted badly about you deleted it.
- How did you do it?  - Oh that?
I had another scene maker that was even better than the running scene maker.
-Excuse me?  -Nothing.
Anyway, I told you it was a transient breeze that you should coolly pass over.
How is the surgery schedule for today?
There is still no one yet.
I'm sure we'll recover soon.
Let's not lose confidence, but let's proceed in a cool way.
Fighting!
Drink the juice, Hyeon Hee.
Give me coffee.
You said to give you juice.
You said you read in a book that caffeine is bad for you.
In this book, I read it's worse to have stress from suppressing a desire to eat something.
You should study less. A smart woman has no charm.
There is no other blockhead like you!
-Mom.  -Mother-in-law.
Why did you follow him and then sit here?
You are occupying the best seat.
I'm lonely at home, and there are no customers in the restaurant.
The problem is that there are no customers. That is what I want to say.
I thought you would grow up after getting married, but you found someone just like you...
You two are playing well. Playing well.
In the future, fend for yourselves.
I am going to stop your allowances and start receiving the restaurant's rent, starting this month.
Between mother and son, we should calculate accurately.
Mom.
Hey Lee Hoon Dong, I am hungry.
Hello, Mother.
It's well into lunch time, and your only customers are your family and your friend?
I'm not sure if you're running a business or running a neighborhood love house...
Oppa, I will leave as well.
Okay.
Go home safely.
-Call me when you get home.  -Okay.
Why are you like this?
-What?  -Is there something good?
Not really.
-Are you okay?  -Yeah.
I am okay.
What.
You can't see me.
What?
My wife left!
Come in.
Tada.
Wow, it is nice.
Yeo Reum.
Sit.
I have something to say to you.
I am seeing Gong Gi Tae.
-But...?-If I have to keep seeing you, I thought I should tell you.
Did I ever ask you to date me? I asked to work with you.
Like always, so cool.
I haven't told Gong Gi Tae I am working with you yet.
If I tell him coolly, will he understand coolly?
We decided to coolly date.
- Coolly?  - Yeah.
In a cool way.
What can I do to be cool like that? Teach me.
Then end it.
-What?  -If you like him, how can you be cool about it?
Although you can act cool.
Don't worry. I am not acting cool now. I am really cool.
Because it has ended.
Look at this. You really are cool
if you can say that without feeling anything.
I need to learn. I will attend to you as my teacher.
Do you think anyone can do it if they learn how?
It's almost time for the investor to arrive.
The investor?
Oh, the one that was a secret?
- Unnie!  - Huh?
Hyeon Hee!
The investor hidden behind the veil was you?
I'm sorry I hid it from you. I had to keep it from Hoon Dong.
Why? You already got married.
It's because I'm married to him that I'm keeping this a secret.
He'll be upset if I fill up a different pocket.
Why do you need another pocket?
My husband's family money is my husband's family's money. It isn't my money.
If I want it to become my money, I have to do emotional labor for the next 30 years and act all charming.
Before that happens I have to take care of myself.
That's how I can confidently give my mother an allowance.
Like usual, my Hyeon Hee is diligent.
I spent all the money I saved up before my marriage.
We have to be successful, Unnie.
Can't you two do this without me? And I could bow out?
Why?
-That...-She's a little hesitant because of her boyfriend.
You've got a boyfriend? Who?
The one you're hesitant about...
By chance, is it Gong Gi Tae?
Your so diligent, too.
Really? That's good.
If you two were going to stick together, why go through all that fuss?
Keep this a secret from Gong Gi Tae.
If he knows, it's only a matter of time before Hoon Dong finds out and it becomes difficult for me too.
That doesn't make sense. How can I keep this from him?
Why not? I'm keeping it from my husband...
Even so...
The store sign came!
Lets go out, too.
Here it is.
Thank you.
What's this?
Since we first decided to start this business, we planned to include you in it.
Why are you two insisting on me...
Are you touched?
What kind of old-fashioned restaurant name is this?
So, who told you to have such an old-fashioned name?
I even put your name on the sign.Are you really not going to do it?
Please pass this on to Joo Jang Mi.
Everything on the Internet was deleted.
We should do what that child wants.
Jang Mi didn't have that motive.
Instead, she helped me.
When Jang Mi was convincing that woman,
that's what you saw and misunderstood.
Oh, so Jang Mi was trying to help you?
Are you two still meeting?
The fact that we're meeting each other, lets keep it a secret for a little while.
We're not meeting, but
I, alone, like her and am clinging onto her.
That man... is she still seeing him?
That man also... if you calculate it, she met him because of me.
How badly did I act for her to need someone to lean on?
Oh, our pitiful Gi Tae..
You lost your love and are regretful about your actions...
And the man kept cheerfully putting himself forward, with his smiling eyes, so Jang Mi just accepted it appropriately.
Those two are definitely not in a serious relationship.
That's right. Jang Mi isn't the type to spit on a smiling face.
Anyway, Jang Mi and I are not in a relationship,
so please rid yourselves of any misunderstandings or bad feelings about her.
She's a person that helped me that I'm grateful for,
and she's really a good woman.
I'm like that, too.
I'm sorry. Please wait.
Then, let's talk later.
Should we have a drink?
Your mother let you live by yourself like you wanted.
In the end she called you, and sat you down,
and must have meddled in your life.
When she lived her whole life like that,
would she change so easily?  I understand you.
How you had your heart taken away by a woman like Joo Jang Mi.
How suffocated must you have felt.
We need space in which to breathe.
It may not have been an advisable method,
but I looked for a realistic and reasonable alternative.
Anyway, love and marriage are completely separate issues.
Love requires unending change and trembling,
but marriage requires stability.
So, did you get stability from Mother? And from
that woman did you get change and trembling?
At your age I thought of it as being something that didn't make sense, either.
But having lived it, life originally is something that doesn't make sense.
They may be slightly sad lives,
but they aren't bad lives.
What do you really want to say?
Marry a woman like Kang Se Ah,
and keep Joo Jang Mi as a lover so that your mother doesn't know.
At one point in time, I tried to understand you, Father.
How bad must it have been that he did it?
Even though you said that you had someone else you love,
why did Mother hold onto you and not let you go?
But now I see it.
The one who held on and didn't let go was you.
If I only thought about myself, I would have let her go.
But there is a responsibility associated with our social class and position. And the heaviness of
that kind of burden... you know what it feels like.
So, that's why you made a fuss about living alone.
You're right.
I am your son and am selfish, like you.
It's such an embarrassing thing...
Today is the first time I realized it.
Gi Tae.
But, Jang Mi is different from that woman.
So don't treat them the same way.
Oh? You came?
What's this?
Oh, taste it and I'll request your evaluation.
They are my "Run for it, Joo Jang Mi" toddling (first try sample) products.
You do such preposterous things so well.
When did you prepare this? Wow...
How is it?
It's delicious.
What a relief! I was worried about your reaction.
After this?
If it suits the taste of a picky eater like Gong Gi Tae, whose palate is tuned to the skills of the cooking goddess, Mrs. Shin,
it would fit a normal person's taste.
But you invented all these?
No, the chef did.
The chef? Who is the chef?
Han Yeo Reum.
Han Yeo Reum?
Han Yeo Reum and I
ended all emotions coolly, with certainty.
We decided to coolly date.
No... I didn't know this is what you meant by coolly dating.
In reality, you know all about my past, and I know all about your past.
Now, instead of pretending not to know,
bringing out what happened in the past and acknowledging it...
Isn't that considered coolly dating?
I, too, will acknowledge you and Kang Se Ah being friends.
Please believe me.
If I still had any feeling for Han Yeo Reum
I wouldn't have been able to tell you truthfully.
If you tell me truthfully, do I have to understand everything?
I also thought it over a lot.
Since we became real, I thought about not working with Han Yeo Reum...
But, since my feelings for you have become real,
I need this work even more.
I told you that I don't like to be Cinderella.
I, too, want to be a supportive person.
If you are really uncomfortable, I will cleanly put it out of my mind.
If you tell me not to, I won't do it.
Please pass this on to Joo Jang Mi.
Marry someone like Kang Se Ah and just date Joo Jang Mi.
Do it.
-Do it?-I think I kind of understand what you're trying to say.
Your way of thinking...
I will support it.
As usual, Gong Gi Tae is so cool.
Oh, drink, drink, drink.
Instead, you have to make sure to be successful.
Here.
To our cool dating.
Drink.
We are opening tomorrow, so buy flowers and be sure to come by.
-Okay?-Okay.
Eat this, too.
You came? What do you want to eat today?
-I don't really have an appetite. -You were so excited that you were flying around,
and today you look like you're about to dig yourself a grave and enter it.
What's making your mood swings so abrupt?
Is there a problem with your hospital?
Or... woman?
She isn't cool to anyone else but me. What do you think about this?
So it's a woman. Is she pretty?
You'll be surprised if you see her.
Introduce me. If a woman tries to back out on you awkwardly,
you have to create witnesses for her actions, first and foremost.
Should I? Should I introduce her to you?
Let's see. How beautiful is this woman that she has Gong Gi Tae held by her fingertips?
Welcome.
Congratulations on opening your business.
Ms. Joo Jang Mi and Ms. Nam Hyun Hee made real trouble this time.
Please come this way.
This is the menu. Please look it over.
- What's the best dish here? - Our kimchi quatro pancakes are good, and the makgeolli (rice wine) is really good too.
Welcome.
-Welcome Hyung!  -Oh, hey, Congrats. You're pretty good and proper.
Chef-nim! You have to keep my working here a secret from my oppa, okay?
Yes, I know. Zip!
- Let's go sit.  - Okay, lets go.
This one is good, too.
Oh, hello!
There aren't any seats available. Would you mind sitting together?
-Ah, this is our manager. -This is Chef Uhm Dae Sik.
Hello.
I will bring the food right out.
Gong Gi Tae!
Lee Hoon Dong.
Oh, introduce yourself. Ah,
you guys have already met, right?
Ah, what's this? The woman you said you were meeting was Joo Jang Mi?
Ah, I told you to keep this a secret. Why did you bring Lee Hoon Dong here?
What? Why, why!? What are you hiding, what are you hiding, huh?!
I would have been the first to congratulate you two if you had told me you were dating.
- Let's go in.  - Wait!
We are not ready yet.
-But it's already full of customers inside... -Oh, you're right. So, there aren't any seats available.
Oh, you came?
Oh, hey, Han Yeo Reum. Congratulations.
- Thank you.- Hey Han Yeo Reum. How dare you betray us and grab hold of Joo Jang Mi?!
Unnie! The wine-makgeolli...
Nam Hyun Hee, what are  you doing here?!
Wait. So, one of the friends you said you are opening the business with is...
Oppa...
Yah, seriously, where is the end to your plot twists!?
Oppa!
You guys had to come here and...
You should have told me.
-Come on in.-Here. Congratulations.
Thanks.
Let's go inside.
♬It's I, who can't live without you, not even for a day ♬
♬Where could you be? Where are you? You are nowhere to be seen.♬
Shall we just eat this? ♬ (Can't see you) ♬
♬ Oh baby  ♬
-Let's not sell it. Let's eat this. -Like this...
♬No matter how much I call you, you don't answer.♬
♬Without you, every single day has no meaning for me.♬
♬I'm missing you. Before I forget you, please hold my hand.♬
♬Your voice spins in my head.♬
♬Your face that I can never forget,♬
♬ Should I understand it, so I can find you again ♬
♬Please call out to me, call my name.♬
-Han Yeo Reum. You don't need to be scared, man. -About what?
I don't care at all that you're Jang Mi's business partner,
so you don't need to be worrying about what I would think, or anything like that, at all.
- Yes.  - Instead, my Jang Mi
shouldn't be worked too hard. Alright? Hm?
Yes.
Alright, alright, alright.
Congratulations on the opening.
Se Ah, how did you know?
I called her. Se Ah's hospital is nearby. I'm actually full of connections,
and I will pull in lots of customers for you.
I heard you two are dating. Congratulations on that, too.
Yes.
Ah, sit here with Gong Gi Tae.
Please buy from us a lot, Se Ah!
Oh, I'm just so happy to see her!
Ah, this is  so pretty! Oops, how did I do this?
Oh my gosh, I'm just so thankful. Eat a lot. Have a lot of food, okay?
Han Yeo Reum, let's see how well you cook, then.
I need to know if I can trust my Jang Mi to your cooking skills.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by the Forget Dating, Give Me The Ring! Team
You were really cool today. You were really manly and awesome in front of Han Yeo Reum.
You, too. In front of Se Ah
you were so completely confident.
Was I? Ha ha.
Yeah, well.
As we've begun real dating, we've tried to care for each other sincerely
and become cool,
but sometimes our conversations become shorter and shorter than when we were fake dating.
Let's go to your house.
My house?  Yeah, your house.
Then, I will wash up first.
Oh, okay. Okay, okay, okay. Here.
Gong Gi Tae, don't you have another toothbrush?
Toothbrush?
Here.
- Thank you.  - Is there anything else you need?
Try using this.
What's this?
Oh, it's nice on my skin.
But... until when are you going to stand there?
I'm about to take a shower.
Oh, right, right, right, right, right.
I'm refreshed. My skin feels so soft.
Oh, my legs.
Do your legs hurt?
I'm used to standing up all day, thanks to my job at the department store.
Let me see.
Oh, they're swollen.
It's okay.
No, let me see.
- Hey...  - Just stay still.
♬ Just imagine ♬
♬ I know you want it ♬  ♬ Stay with me ♬
♬ The way you talk always mysteriously stays near my ears ♬
♬ My face grows red (and my heart gets excited) ♬
Joo Jang Mi. Are you asleep?  ♬ Inside the square bus ♬
♬ I faintly hear a well-known song ♬
Jang Mi.  ♬ At some point (falling into you) ♬
You wanted to date coolly, and now you're sleeping? (Cool-cool: Korean idiom for heavy sleep)
♬ Wanna walk together now? (boy) ♬
This woman doesn't seem to know what coolly dating means, yet.
♬ I fall in love ♬ ♬ Wanna take the subway ♬
♬ walking in the rain ♬
♬ Between the clouds, as if it’s slippery and slowly ♬
♬ We are already walking ♬
You bad girl.
I'm only forgiving you because you're pretty.
♬ Walking in that lane ♬
It was the sweetest sleep I'd ever had in my life.
Sleep. Sleep.
Sleep, and sleep again.
Sleep again. Then, sleep again.
Is Run for it, Joo Jang Mi (restaurant name) running well lately?
Oh, of course. The word has slowly started to spread.
Has your hospital recovered?
Of course. Who do you think you're talking to?
Do you think I'd still be so weakly floundering?
I'm Gong Gi Tae.
I'm Gong Gi Tae, I tell ya.
Sleep, and sleep again.
Thanks to the sweet sleep,
I have been able to endure all the time I have to be awake.
Welcome!
♬ When I see you, my heart pounds and my lips dry up ♬
♬ I couldn’t sleep last night because of the butterflies ♬
♬ Why am I like this? My face is getting hot ♬
♬ My head gets dizzy, my body gets electrified ♬
♬ Your face flickers before me today ♬
♬ I can’t take it anymore ♬
♬ Starting from tomorrow, we will live happily together ♬
It looks like there are some customers going in and out.
Look at Joo Jang Mi, laughing because she likes it.
And in front of Han Yeo Reum.
Hey, can Hyeon Hee be like that even when she's pregnant?
#$%^! She pinky promised that she was only going to work at the counter.
Those heavy things like that... Shouldn't Joo Jang Mi, who is very strong, be carrying that stuff?
Hey, how is Joo Jang Mi strong?
You haven't been punched by Joo Jang Mi?
Aigo, aigo, have you been punched?
Have you been pounded on the street!?
I went through it! Is that something you even pay attention to?
Hey, hey, why would I not have doubts?  - What are you talking about?
You don't know what I'm going through!
We don't have any patients today, either?
No, Director.
Yes, please come in.
It's you.
You were waiting for patients, huh?
What do we do?
Should I get some filler injections?
Lets eat.
Joo Jang Mi is doing so amazingly well.
You have strength, too.
Take this opportunity to come over to our hospital.
For a long time, my father
has had his heart set on recruiting you. You know it too, right?
This time, we're introducing skills with a 3D printer.
What do you think? Doesn't it tempt you a bit?
You're always responding with that scaredy-cat face whenever I try to tempt you.
I'm not trying to tempt you as a woman, so please stop being nervous.
As a friend, and as a doctor,
I'm scouting you.
Whatever it's come to,
relying on you isn't good form.
I think it's definitely not the time for you to be acting so cool.
No matter what, you have to get back up.
What? Scout?
That's right. And Kang Se Ah's scouting, at that.
But why, when he's got his perfectly good hospital?
These days, Gi Tae's hospital isn't so good.
-He said that it had recovered.  - No.
It's such a sensitive neighborhood, when it comes to gossip, that it takes a little time once it falters.
Gi Tae will need something to break through that, too.
I didn't know that.
Why didn't he tell me?
Since you look like you're sprouting wings and flying, his pride was probably hurt, and that's why.
Anyway, Jang Mi, what are you going to do?
Are you okay with Gi Tae going to Se Ah's hospital?
Of course! It's for Gong Gi Tae's future, so I have to be cool and understand it.
Aigo, really. Joo Jang Mi is cool.
I'm not the me from before.
But Gong Gi Tae's plastic surgery practice... To have prepared it so well,
and to just give it up, is a bit wasteful.
Not Gong Gi Tae but the hospital, the hospital.
Hospital...
- Yeah?  - Oh...
It's me.
You know, umm.
I'm a bit busy now. Is it urgent?
Oh, no. If you're busy go back to work.
Sorry. I'll call you later.
What is there to be sorry about? It's not like that. It's perfectly okay.
Yeah, okay.
Look, you can't do it.
It's not a cool face but a depressed one.
Gong Gi Tae understood my working with you,
so I have to understand, too.
Even though I am a little disappointed he didn't tell me that he was having trouble at the hospital,
he'll probably have done that, thinking of me. So, I guess I have to understand.
When I was going to school,
the teacher said, if you couldn't understand something, just memorize it.
You look like you're just memorizing it.
This makes you look stupid.
Go see Gi Tae and talk to him, face-to-face.
We have to work. The customers will be crowding us soon.
Daepo Fusion Restaurant,
Run for it Joo Jang Mi?
Mom, Mom!
I found it.  How's she doing?
- She's set up a shop.- What?
Big Gun Fusion. Run for it Joo Jang Mi.
Really?
Hey, Jang Mi's pancake making skills justify that.
She found her way properly.
But we guessed wrong.
Guessed wrong?
Do you know who was next to her?
Who was next to her?
You surprised me.
Welcome!
Mother-in-law...
Have some makgeolli.
It's delicious.
Thank you.
I'm sorry for misunderstanding you.
No, it's okay. It was normal to misunderstand that situation.
My meddlesomeness was the true culprit.
But...
…I can't say thank you for helping, though.
If you really do not have feelings for Gi Tae,
isn't it courtesy to keep a distance?
Yes.
One more makgeolli, over here please.
Yes, I'm coming.
Don't worry too much. I don't have any thoughts of blocking Gong Gi Tae's way.
As you can see, I'm busy living my own life.
It's the first time life is so exciting and happy.
This is all thanks to Gi Tae and you.
Then, enjoy your meal.
- Here you go.  - Thank you.
Eat, eat, eat.
Only Gi Tae is left looking pitiful.
I'm back.
You came?
What are you looking at?
Ah...
It's a very interesting technique for plastic surgery, using this 3D printer.
You see, by printing a frontal view of the patient, we can do a much more precise surgery than before, and...
Ah...
Not interesting, right?
-You know…  -Yeah?
If I ask him about hospital stuff, his pride will be hurt, right?
What?
Let's have some drinks.
Drinks?
Ah…right now… I have to look at this.
Ah…right.
Alright then, we can drink it later.
I'll put them in the fridge.
-Ok, then. -Oh, yeah.
♬ When I see you, my heart pounds and my lips dry up ♬
♬ I couldn’t sleep last night because of the butterflies ♬
♬ Why am I like this? My face is getting hot ♬
♬ My head gets dizzy, my body gets electrified ♬
♬ Your face flickers before me today ♬
♬ I can’t take it anymore ♬
♬ Starting from tomorrow, we will live happily together ♬
Gong Gi Tae, are you not going to sleep?
I'm sleepy.
You're sleepy again? Whenever you see me, you're always sleepy.
Alright, go in first and sleep.
Hmm?
Actually, today your mother came by the restaurant.
I didn't tell her I was meeting you.
No… I couldn't say it.
Being confident, next to you,
is really hard.
The pancakes have come out. The pancakes.
-Ah thank you, I'll enjoy it.- I'll enjoy it, Jang Mi.
Yes.
But..you two..what are you talking about?
Hey Richard.
Hi.
Hello.
He came to our hospital on medical missions, Richard Bernstein.
He's helping us with the 3D printing skills.
My pleasure to meet you Dr. Bernstein.
I've heard a lot about you from Se Ah.
Richard, it seems like Japan has success in creating artificial bones using 3D printers.
Yes, indeed.
Plastic surgeons all over the world are currently taking notice of that case.
All types of artificial bones do not fuse with patients all that well,
and they're also known to be causing inflammation quite frequently.
The newly developed ones do not go under rapid...
A guest came.
-It's nothing, not anything much.  -What are they saying?
More clinical tests are required for applications to the masses.
What is this?
This is Sundae (blood sausage).
Very good.
-It's delicious. -What is this?
Popular?  Oh.
We like each other.
Why do we slowly have less to talk about?
Nothing changed here.
I don't have to give you anything to drink, right?
Your unfriendliness is the same too.
Why did you come?
I'm thankful for the $5000.
You don't have to repay it, already. You are making a fuss because your business is doing well.
Does it look like fussing to you?
You don't see Joo Jang Mi overdoing it?
You don't see her being overly considerate, trying not to let you come to any harm?
I'm also trying to be very considerate of her,
because Jang Mi said that she didn't want to lean on me, but stand up by herself.
It's not that you didn't give her certainty?
-What?  -"I can lean on this man."
"Even if I lean a bit, he's not one who will pull out and run, away like other men."
As a man, you can't even give her that kind of certainty?
This punk, really.
What do you know about Jang Mi?
I know Joo Jang Mi the best.
I know that Joo Jang Mi wants to be with you.
I also know that she's working with me to try to stay next to you longer.
Right now, is it true that you're next to her?
You're overstepping your bounds a bit today.
Why do I need to hear this from you?
Because I like you.
When you like a person there aren't only feelings like between a man and a woman.
Acting cool...
Ah, it hurts.
Joo Gyung Po
Fool… Idiot… Dog poop.
What postcard? Who sent it?
Your dad is this kind of person.
Fool… Idiot… Dog poop.
He's an enemy that doesn't even know his place.
You said that by being pen pals you were fated to be together.
I was fooled by that smooth talk, and I completely messed up my entire life.
Now that it's like this, why don't you also write back, while thinking about the old times?
Forget it.
Exactly when was it?
When was it that you stopped talking to each other?
Why does it matter when it started or who started it?
I don't remember anything.
It's just, once I closed my mouth I couldn't open it again.
Love is like that...
The moment you close your mouth, it's the end.
Let's go inside.
I'll be back. I have to go somewhere.
Jang Mi!
Joo Jang Mi!
"I can depend on this man." It's not because you didn't give her that assurance?
- Yeah?- Where are you?
- I'm home. - I'm heading there right now.
No!
Coming here right now is a bit troubling...
Why can't I?
Ah, something important happened, so see you later.
No! I definitely have to see you, right now.
Gong Gi Tae!
The door has been opened.
I told you not to come!
- Right now...- Why? What is so important that's happening?
It's something I didn't want to show to you.
I told you everything honest about me and Han Yeo Reum.
But why aren't you telling me your story?
Who's inside?
I have a customer, so later...
Stop hiding things from me.
Because whatever you're doing—I know it all.
You... you know?
How did you know?
You really went all out, didn't you?
I really didn't want to go this far.
What are you doing?
You said you already knew. They're conducting an interview.
A magazine?
The employees kept saying we should improve our hospital's image.
But why did you hide that from me?
I was embarrassed!
I should be recognized for my skills. Making a living by selling the image of a handsome, eligible doctor
is all Mother's way of doing things.
So that was it.
But you are a handsome bachelor?
Of course I am. You didn't know?
Is this your girlfriend?
Ah, no, no. I am...
Yes, she's my girlfriend.
A handsome bachelor doctor having a girlfriend is a minus.
What if Mother sees?
Please keep that off the record.
How far were we in the interview?
After that girl started coming to this house,
you said it was uncomfortable, and you didn't like to be alone in this house.
He said that he wanted to be together.
Then, let's keep it off the record.
Now that it's become real, it's harder.
When we were being fake, it was comfortable to be by your side.
I said whatever I wanted to say, too.
Now that we're real,
there are lots of things we can't be found out about.
I guess you wanted to look really good in front of me?
You're too late. Let's just do it comfortably.
I've already seen everything I should and shouldn't see.
You're right. Since we already started over,
we should say everything we wanted to say before now.
You...
Why didn't you tell me working at the hospital was hard?
You think it is only you who wants to act strong in front of me?
I am the same, too.
Why did I even endure doing that magazine interview that sells my face?
Instead of Han Yeo Reum,
I would like it if you depended on me.
I was always depending on you. You didn't know?
During that time, because I slept on your shoulder and dreamed in such sweet sleep,
it gave me the strength to run around all day,  to flip the Korean pancakes,
and be able to serve makgeolli (alcoholic rice beverage).Didn't you know?
Was that so?
What else? Say more of what you want to say.
I understand your friendship with Kang Se Ah.
But,
being scouted by Kang Se Ah's hospital, I don't like it.
How did you know that? Aigo.
If you knew earlier, you should have said so.
I'm going to keep and protect my hospital.
That's why I've been studying more and publicizing more.
All I received from Se Ah was an introduction to Richard.
Was that it?
You wanting to work and earn money I fully understand, also.
However,
I wish you wouldn't smile at Han Yeo Reum, saying how happy you are.
The greatest coldness and prickly attitude,
is what I wish for you to maintain.
I get it.
Let's get rid of this cool relationship.
Since we both can be as petty as we'd like, it's nice.
Ah, and one more thing.
You, I like it when you're sleeping comfortably by my side,
but...
I don't like just sleeping.
Tonight,
stay next to me and don't sleep.
♬ Inside the square bus ♬
♬ I faintly hear a well-known song ♬
♬ At some point (falling into you) ♬
♬ What’s there to think about? ♬
♬ Wanna walk together now? (boy) ♬
♬ You know but pretend you don’t, I fall in love ♬
♬ Wanna take the subway or walking in the rain ♬
Oh... Mother-in-law!
Marriage, Not Dating
Grandma!
This time, it's real...
I really came to like Gong Gi Tae.
The elders think that Jang Mi wants to get married.
Jang Mi does?
You know how much Jang Mi wanted to get married.
Did you get yelled at?
What happened before I came?
Wedding bells rang in my ear.