Based on the true story
of Rocky Dennis
How about a kiss in the sun?
- How about not a kiss in the sun?
Why not? I'm a romantic.
- oh, Mr. Romance! Great.
Hey, Mom. - What? - You forgot
what we got to do this morning.
Jesus. Who's that?
- My son. Did I?
The schooI,
the cIinic, the bIood Iine-up.
oh, shit!
Wait. What's going on? - I've got to
do a miIIion things with my kid.
WeII, what about us?
I was gonna give her a ride home.
Mom.
- Sorry, sorry.
I just gave her a ride home.
OK, aIright.
Hey, Rock.
- Yo, Red.
Are you Iooking for this one?
- No, I aIready got two of these.
I toId you that wasn't the right one.
- Thanks anyway, Red.
You're trying to find Ruby WaIters.
- Rube WaIker, card number 1-0-8.
BrookIyn Dodgers, 1955.
- Good year. Seems Iike yesterday.
You say that about everything, Red.
- Everything does.
I seen you grandstanding for her.
- I protected her. Where were you?
You got the Iease?
I got everything eIse. - Shit!
I toId you it was Rube WaIker ...
Shut up! Let's get going, we're Iate.
What's the matter? Never saw anybody
from the pIanet VuIcan before?
Yes, uh ...
- Never mind. - Wait a minute. Ma'am!
Hi, I'm here to register my son
for the ninth grade.
WeII, Mrs. ... - No Mrs.
I'm Rusty Dennis. Meet my son, Rocky.
PIease sit down.
We're running a IittIe bit Iate,
so couId you move it aIong?
This is a pubIic
junior high schooI, Miss Dennis.
There are speciaI schooIs
with wonderfuI faciIities
more appropriate for his needs.
Do you teach aIgebra,
bioIogy and EngIish here?
Df course.
- Those are his needs.
Perhaps I shouId speak
to the boy's father.
Perhaps you shouId speak to the Pope.
He'd be a Iot easier to find.
Under the circumstances
for the good of my students
as weII as your son,
I'II need additionaI ... - Don't jerk
me around. I'm not in the mood.
I've had a reaI crappy day so far.
First, we're in the wrong district,
I gotta come here and pIay pussyfoot.
This is a copy of our Iease,
a copy of Rocky's birth certificate,
and this is his Iast report card.
He was in the top 5% of his cIass.
I got some additionaI information.
My Iawyer's name is B.D. Higgins.
If you give me any shit at aII,
he's gonna drag your ass into court.
Don't worry, Mr. Simms.
I Iook weird
but otherwise I'm reaI normaI.
Everything wiII be cooI.
Thanks a Iot. See you next week.
Mom?
- What?
We have a Iawyer named B.D. Higgins?
- Yeah, BuII Dozer.
Come on. - So, you're a Iawyer, Doze!
- BuIIshit ruIes!
Cranium circumference: 67 cm.
67 centimetres ...
Last one, kid.
- AIright. ReaIIy?
MandibIe: 32 point 5 cm.
MandibIe: 32.5 - I'II measure you.
- That's good news, Rocky!
Since your Iast check-up, your jaw
onIy increased an eighth of an inch.
I'm cured! I can go home now.
It's the water in Azusa.
Picture time! - He knows the routine
better than we do. - It's true!
You Iook great. - How about my hair?
- You Iook fine, Rocky.
OK. Shoot!
- How's your mom? - Great.
Stand stiII.
- Sorry.
Turn around.
- Why don't you fiII me in, Doctor.
The patient was first diagnosed
with CraniodiaphyseaI dyspIasia
at four years of age
when it was discovered that
caIcium was depositing in his skuII.
My paI, caIcium!
- What have we Iearned about it?
It's extremeIy rare.
Dne in 22 about miIIion births.
How was it first described?
- Lionitis. The Iook of the Iion.
Are you new around here?
- Yes, I am.
Cause?
- It's caused by 2 recessive genes
and happens to normaI parents. His
mother had an uneventfuI pregnancy,
didn't ingest any
chemicaI substance or tetratogens.
That means
it wasn't my mom or dad's fauIt.
HeIIo, Rocky.
Doc Rudinsky!
- Good to see you again.
Dur data on this patient, Doctor,
supports your articIe in ...
How are you feeIing today, Rocky?
- Pretty good. How are you feeIing?
You stiII have those headaches?
- Yeah. They've been bad IateIy.
Is your mother stiII using the
same methods? - What methods?
She taIks to me and they go away.
- No medication? - No.
We're ready now. - You can dress.
- See you Iater, Doc.
Do you have any questions?
- Yeah.
When wiII you invent one of these,
so a guy's rear-end doesn't hang out?
I'd Iike to do the foIIow-up
counseIing with the mother, myseIf.
That's a great idea.
Don't you agree, Doctor? - oh, yes.
Mrs. Dennis?
- What?
I'm Dr. Vinton. I need to taIk to you
about the test resuIts. - AIright.
Hey, Mom. Hey, Babe.
- Why doesn't he wait outside?
What for?
- So we can taIk.
It's about the test resuIts. Dn him.
oh, him. Him has a name.
So if you've got information for him,
you give it to him. - You don't
understand. - You don't understand!
He's got a cheeseburger waiting
out there, so just hurry this aIong.
WeII, as you know,
pIastic surgery is not an option
untiI the skuII stops thickening.
And there's no evidence that it wiII.
The cranium's growing at such a rate,
creating pressure on the spinaI cord,
that the prognosis is not good.
We feeI that ...
Iife expectancy
is ...
- Three to six months.
You're not gonna reaIIy give us
that number again, are you?
You know, for 12 years I've been
Iistening to you guys buIIshit.
First you toId me he was retarded.
Then that he wouId be bIind and deaf.
Then you toId me that he'd never
be abIe to do what reguIar kids do.
If I had dug his grave every time
you geniuses said he wouId die,
I'd be eating
fucking chop suey in China by now.
Anything eIse?
Bye.
It's time to get Dozer to give bIood.
- Never had before.
Dozer's weIcoming committee.
- Come on, Red Cross needs the bIood.
It onIy gonna hurt for a second.
Come on, Dozer!
Hey, Iook who's here.
The prodigaI son returns.
Ben, when did you get back?
- Yesterday. GIad to see you.
He's Iooking good.
- Yeah, better than he acts.
How's your dad? - He was great.
- Great for you, shitty for me.
Here's the usuaI crap starting again.
These are basebaII cards.
- I started coIIecting. - Me too!
You didn't teII me Ben was coming.
- I didn't know. - Happy about it?
Not especiaIIy.
He's acting just Iike his father.
The onIy reason he's back, his father
didn't wanna pay the biIIs anymore.
18 months out of 16 years doesn't
seem Iike a heIIuva Iot to me ...
Who needs it? You take their money,
you gotta take their shit.
What did the doctors say? The usuaI?
- Screw 'em.
Ben's getting a reaI smart mouth.
It's the age.
They think they know everything.
Good sIap upside the head, they don't
know everything. - I never hit Rocky.
I don't beIieve this, Ben.
You don't even have a Steve Garvey!
I must have Ieft it at my dad's.
- You probabIy Iost it.
Garvey batted 325 this year.
You've gotta have a Garvey. - ReaIIy?
WeII, do I have anything you want?
Na, we better forget it.
I feeI reaIIy bad about this, Ben.
I mean, we grew up together.
I shouId just give you my Garvey.
I wiII. For anything you got.
Anything, Iike this one.
Who the heII's Ruby WaIker?
- A Dodger, before they came to L.A.
I'II take it. My grandpa Iikes them.
Take another stick!
Remember I used to taIk about riding
HarIeys across Europe? - Yeah.
I had been pIanning on going
by myseIf, but now you're back ...
That'd be great!
I'd do anything to get out of schooI.
CooI! Look at that one.
Can I pick him up?
- Take your pick!
Hi, puppy.
He was born for you, Rocky.
- I've got to ask my mom.
Come on, Ben. I'II be right back.
- I'II save him for you.
Try this. - What's speciaI about it?
- It's dusted with angeI weed.
Mom? - What?
- I've gotta show you. - Wait.
Am I interrupting something?
- What do you want?
This Iady has reaIIy cooI puppies ...
Did you see them, Doze?
No, no puppy.
- Why?
Because you never taIk to the cat,
or feed the fish, the bird or rabbit.
I'II feed the dog, I promise.
- Read my Iips, Rock: No!
Is the big guy a dummy, or what?
Dozer just doesn't Iike to taIk.
Show her your other stuff.
- Take your pick.
Don't Iet it bother you.
My mom's a pain in the ass aIso.
I don't beIieve this.
- What? - It's Gar!
Come on.
Is that Rocky's dad?
- No, I was married to Rocky's dad.
Who the heII is that?
- Just a guy I used to know.
Damn, it's good to see you.
- Where've you been? - Dn the road.
Gettin' taIIer. Must be pourin' that
heaIth food shit into ya. - She is.
Don't cut yourseIf.
- Thanks.
Been OK? - Yeah.
- StiII pIanning the Europe run?
More than ever. We were just
taIking about it. Weird! - Yeah.
How's everybody eIse doin'?
- Like who?
Grandma and Grandpa.
They're OK. They don't get around
much anymore. We moved, you know.
She taIks about you.
I'II bet she does.
Don't make Benny wait, get going.
I'II see you Iater.
Toss me a beer.
T.J.
- Gar!
You gonna introduce me to your Iady?
- AngeI,
this is Gar. Give him a kiss.
- A shake'II do. - You sure?
Hey, Dozer.
Goodnight, Mom.
- 'Night, babe.
Goodnight, Bone.
- 'Night, bud.
BeautifuI.
MarseiIIe.
oh, my God! Hey, puppy.
Look at you!
Bone?
Dozer?
Scoot over.
I'II make that fat bastard
eat 30 pounds of dog food.
ProbIem is,
he'd probabIy Iove it.
Rock, honey, your Iimo's here!
Can you turn that down, Mom?
- OK.
I don't wanna go, Mom.
- Then don't go.
But I gotta go.
- Then go.
That's easy for you to say. Mom.
You're not the one going to a schooI
where kids wiII run away
when they see you, making fun of you.
When they stop running
and get to know you, they Iike you.
Just Iike at your other schooI.
It takes time to Iike each other.
Why shouId it be different for you?
I am different, Mom.
You're more beautifuI inside than
most peopIe. Whoever can't see that ...
Screw 'em! - Spoken Iike
the true son of a red-headed woman!
Your sister Rose is dead!
- You're weird. - Get outta here!
Thanks, Doze. No, I gotta
do this aIone. Have a good day.
Hey, kid. Take off your mask!
AIright.
WeIcome back, 9th graders.
OK.
We have two new students
with us in homeroom.
First, we have Miss Nancy Lawrence.
Where are you, Nancy?
Wow, thanks a Iot.
Dur other new student
is Mr. Rocky Dennis,
aIso in the back.
Wow, thanks a Iot.
See you Iater.
- Dempsey, Eric.
Locker number 137, combination:
right 46, Ieft past 46 to 16,
right to 4. Got it aII?
Dennis, Rocky. Locker number 138,
combination: Ieft 22,
right past 22 to 12, Ieft to 9.
You're not writing it down.
- Don't need to.
Looks Iike Frankenstein.
What's the matter? Never seen
anyone from the pIanet VuIcan before?
He's weird.
- Cut it out, guys.
4, 5 ...
Damn!
- Get stuck? - No.
Come on, you're taking forever.
- I Iost the goddamn combination.
Try right 46,
Ieft past 46 to 16, right to 4.
Right to 46, Ieft to 16, 4.
CHEMICAL DEPENDENCY CENTER
Drug abuse prevention
for you and your friends
Got enough candy for an orphanage.
- I'm gonna seII mine at schooI.
More money for the trip.
- Maybe I'II seII some of mine.
Thanks. Take this in to your room
and open it up. - OK. Thanks.
I forgot, Red sIipped me a fiver
for the strongbox.
How much have we saved now?
- 31 bucks.
PIus the six for babysitting tonight.
- PIus the five Red just sIipped me.
So we've got 44.
- 42.
Wow, check this out!
Tear that oId sucker off the waII.
I'm reaIIy getting into this!
I wish we couId go tomorrow.
Me too.
Gar said the best run was here
across Europe. He rode by himseIf.
You shouId get some of those ...
- Map tacks. - Right.
I want to go to every pIace
I've ever read about.
Those cities our reIatives came from.
Not mine. We're Americans.
- DnIy Indians were Americans first.
The rest come from somewhere eIse.
Like Paris maybe, or London.
Dr Rome ...
Vienna ...
BarceIona. - oh. Like my grandparents
are from Hungary or Budapest.
Budapest is in Hungary, Ben.
- No kidding, is it?
That jacket's the onIy thing of yours
that's ever gonna be on my bed again.
OK with me, baby. - What the heII'd
you come back for anyway?
Winters are coId back East
and I wanted to see ...
Rocky.
Can someone teII me
how the Trojan War began?
Those Iight buIbs
over your heads are bIinding me.
OK, Rocky, give it a shot.
There was this huge wedding
and aII the goddesses were invited.
AII except for one goddess.
She got reaIIy pissed off.
That's the fact part.
Now, the myth part goes that
she sent this goIden appIe
that said For the most beautifuI.
This dude, Paris, was supposed to
judge who gets the appIe, right?
Like the Miss Goddess Contest.
He's the onIy judge. Lucky guy.
AII the goddesses wanna get picked
so one goes up to Paris and says,
If you pick me, I'm gonna give you
this reaIIy hot wench named HeIen.
But HeIen was aIready married.
Paris saw her and fIipped out
because she was so beautifuI.
She had a perfect body and a face ...
Face
that couId Iaunch 1,000 ships.
Somebody said that. So anyway,
her oId man has this huge
hoIIow wooden horse buiIt
and puts aII his armies into it
and wheeIs it over to Troy and says,
Hey, man, got a present for you.
They open the gates, wheeI in
this horse and say, Wow, big horse.
Night comes, and the horse opens up
and aII the armies come out,
and then ...
And that's how the Trojan War began.
Something Iike that.
Thank you, Rocky, we're impressed.
- Thanks.
Let me read you something ...
Not bad. How about heIping me?
How? - Tutor me.
This guy aImost fIunked me Iast year.
It's gonna cost you.
3 bucks an hour.
- 3 bucks!
3 bucks?
- I don't work for free.
Pay it, cheapskate, you need aII
the heIp you can get. - Thanks a Iot!
Hi, Mom.
- Hi.
I got an A on a poem
I wrote in EngIish cIass.
You've been a busy IittIe boy!
- Want me to read it to you?
Why not?
Are you going out again?
Yeah. Read it, I'm Iistening.
These things are good:
Ice cream and cake ...
A ride on a HarIey ...
Monkeys in the trees ...
The rain on my tongue ...
and the sun shining on my face.
These things ...
These things are a drag:
Dust in my hair ...
HoIes in my shoes ...
No money in my pocket ...
and the sun shining on my face.
That it?
Can I taIk to you? - I'm going out.
- You're aIways going out.
I toId you to take down the tree.
You've been acting Iike you hate me
for a whoIe week. What did I do?
You didn't do the dishes.
- I'II do them Iater. - Do them now!
Don't go out tonight!
I wouIdn't do that again
if I were you.
I hate you aIways coming home wasted!
- It's none of your damned business!
You're my mother!
- But you're not my warden!
You're aIways teIIing me how
to Iive my Iife!
I never teII you how to Iive.
- The fuck you don't! What's this?
What do you caII these? I found them
everywhere but my Christmas stocking!
I don't want you taking drugs.
Don't.
How couId you do that?
I hate you.
You onIy care about are stupid cards.
AII you care about
is getting Ioaded and Iaid!
Shut the door.
What, do you think we're in a barn?
What is it? - Shut up.
It's my kid. Wait for me.
I don't wait for nobody.
- Then get the heII out.
No probIem, baby, no probIem.
Mom,
head hurts.
Where does it hurt? - In the back
mostIy. - AIright, pick something.
Sorry about what I said today.
- Pick something.
I can't think when it hurts.
- Don't think, just pick something.
Trip with Ben.
- How?
Boat.
Now see it and teII me.
Tramp steamer, big, bIack,
with a red bottom,
the paint's chipping off.
Me and Ben on the deck.
We're cIeaning something.
The sky's bIue,
getting cIoudy,
the ocean's dark,
it smeIIs good.
We'II get to Spain in the morning.
I check the bikes.
- TeII me about the bikes.
Mine is a '74 ShoveI Head
with a suicide shift,
bright red ...
What are you gonna do?
Make myseIf weII.
You OK?
- Yeah.
Thanks for Iast night.
Gar caIIed to say
he wants to take you to the carnivaI.
Are you coming?
- Maybe.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I'm sorry about your basebaII card.
That's OK. I have 2 others Iike it.
LittIe shit!
I Iiked your poem though.
I just get scared for you, Mom.
- oh, don't be.
It's bad for you.
- I can handIe it, Rock.
What if somebody gives you bad stuff
or too much ...? - What are you?
The director of the
- InIand VaIIey ChemicaI whatsit?
No, I just get scared something couId
happen to you ... - Just Iay off!
Jesus Christ, OK.
OK, what?
OK,
I'II cut down.
Promise?
I said so, didn't I? Don't push it.
I saw this amazing '74 KnuckIe Head.
- Let's check it out.
Gar, are you going on this? - Sure!
- Mom, you want to ride?
No, baby, go ahead.
Rusty, Iook what Dozer won for you.
Hey, Doze, great!
I couId use it for after-dinner mints.
Let's ride those bumpers!
Better watch out. - Anybody eIse?
- Let the boys pIay.
You can ride, but I can't take the
bIame for what happens to the retard.
I can't take the bIame
for what happens to you.
Take the tickets.
Does it remind you of anything?
- A bunch of guys running in circIes.
Going nowhere.
- Except my Rocky.
A smaII Iemonade, pIease.
Want something nice to go with it?
- No, thanks. - High quaIity stuff.
I promised my kid.
- Promised your kid! I Iike that.
I'II put it with:
I promised my paroIe officer.
Put anywhere you want to.
- You know where to find me.
Did you see where Mom went?
- Yeah.
Don't worry, have a good time.
Are you guys in here?
Shit!
- Got any dope for me, baby?
I didn't get any.
You don't beIieve me?
- ShouId I?
Ben?
- What?
Look. Come and Iook at me.
Get Mom.
What?
You did a terrific job
with the decorating committee.
Are you going to the prom?
- I don't know.
Hi, Rocky.
How are finaIs going?
- Pretty good, Mr. Simms.
I had a great idea for you. How about
a coupIe weeks at summer camp?
No, I'm saving up for something eIse.
- It wouIdn't cost you a cent.
A friend of mine
runs a camp for the junior bIind
and he couId use a C.A. for JuIy.
- What's a C.A.?
CounseIIor's Aide. You heIp
with the kids and get to go free.
LittIe bIind kids?
Most of them.
Hey, Rocky! I got an A in aIgebra!
- You owe me 14 bucks.
I got a Roy CampaneIIa for you.
- It's a deaI.
I tutor him.
- oh. How about the camp, Rocky?
I don't think so.
My mom kind of needs me.
Your mother never gave me
the impression she couIdn't get aIong.
That's not what I mean.
I kind of organize things for her,
just kind of keep things together.
- I guess you probabIy do.
WiII you at Ieast think about it?
- OK, I'II think about it. - Good.
Bye-bye.
Hey, Rock!
Hey, baby!
Mom, what wouId you think of me
if you were a girI?
That's a toughie. Let me see ...
I'd think you're pretty cute.
I Iike guys with red hair.
I want to taIk to
another pIastic surgeon.
We can't do anything
untiI the bones stop growing.
So what's that? 2 years at the most.
We've been doing this for 16 years.
Don't you understand anything?
It's girIs.
Can I get a beer?
Come on.
Wait, I'II wake my ... Shit!
Honey, wake up, you got a guest.
Come on, Screech.
Come on, boy!
Jeez, what happened to your face?
What do you want?
- That Iady brought me here.
oh, my God.
I don't beIieve she did this.
WeII?
- WeII, what?
What do you want?
You don't happen to have
a CarI FuriIIo, do you?
It's just a joke.
Do you want to sit down?
Mind if I smoke?
How oId are you?
- 19.
How much do you get?
- Depends.
oh. Sure.
How much for a basic?
25.
Is that it? You need a manager.
No, thanks. I aIready got one.
Why is your map stuck with pins?
- Those are the pIaces I'm gonna go.
I'm going to SeattIe, Washington.
As soon as I get enough money.
SeattIe.
- I gotta sister that Iives there.
I get postcards.
It's reaI wet, cIean.
What happened to your face?
- I used to do a Iot of drugs.
No shit?
- No, I'm just kidding.
Where the heII have you been?
- Getting something for Rocky. And me.
I hope it was worth that 40 bucks
you took out of my jeans.
I remember when you weren't above
copping a coupIe bucks for some snort.
Grown up since then.
40 bucks.
Want to take it out in trade?
Are you aIright?
My mama used to say some peopIe
are born with no pIace to go.
I don't beIieve that. - How d'you
expIain the rotten things that happen?
I don't know.
Lorrie, I hope you don't mind, but
I think you got a shitty attitude.
It's pretty negative.
- It is?
Yeah. If you think Iike that
things onIy get worse.
When something bad happens
you got to remember a something good.
Like what?
- I got a bunch of them I use.
Like the time
we aII went down to Mexico.
Dr the smeII of my grandma's kitchen.
I don't think I have any.
- Everybody's got at Ieast one.
WeII, maybe the time ...
Na, I don't know.
I hope you don't think
I don't Iike you or anything,
'cause I do.
You're reaIIy pretty and nice.
It's just that I thought
it wouId be with someone I Iove.
I just thought of one.
- Yeah?
Yeah. I was in 5th grade.
You had to paint a pine tree
with snow on it.
Mine was the best one.
Teacher, she put it on the waII
where aII the kids couId see it.
She put a big goId star on it.
And aII the kids saw it.
You want more toast, Lorrie?
I gotta go to work.
- Can you take her to the bus stop?
Sure. Come on, Lorrie.
Bye.
Bye, Rocky.
Mom, do I Iook Iike
a freak to you? - No.
You aIways teII me my face doesn't
matter. But it does, doesn't it?
You think I can't even get a girI
to Iike me unIess you pay for her.
That's not true.
- BuIIshit!
BuIIshit yourseIf! Lots of young guys
got probIems getting girIs.
What if I was your Dad?
- I'd hate that too!
I'm sorry. Maybe I was wrong.
- Goddamn right you were!
But it had nothing to do
with your face. - BuIIshit, Mom!
Where are you going?
Hey, Rock, how's it going?
Your mother sometimes does
the wrong thing for the right reason.
You aIways stick up for her, Gar.
Then she pisses you off and you spIit.
Then you come back.
It's aII so nuts.
First time I met your mother,
she was workin' at a bar.
She had to wear
this cheesy IittIe two-piece thing.
I couId teII she hated it.
Takin' a Iot of shit
from a Iot of asshoIes.
I asked to take her home.
She said she was going to get her kid
and have his picture taken.
At one of those stores.
I said I'd ride her and the kid
on the bike. She Iiked that.
She came out of
your grandma's house with you.
You were 5, maybe 6.
WeII, shit. You didn't
Iook Iike your reguIar kid, right?
We get down to the store
and she's standing in Iine
with the rest of the mothers and kids.
AII the mothers and kids
are staring at you.
When it's your turn, she puts you
on this big red bIock.
The guy taking the picture
nearIy shits.
You're sitting there with your nose
and this big damn smiIe on your face.
I Iooked over at her ...
and I never saw
a woman more beautifuI
than the way she was Iooking at you.
Jesus!
Hey, Screech, come here.
Here comes Rocky.
I'm not going.
- Why?
I don't have anything to wear.
- I got that probIem aII the time.
Hey, it's my goddamn graduation!
You don't care
but it's a big deaI to me.
Remember who you are, boy.
You ain't citizen Iike your friend ...
What's his name?
With Ietters on his shirt? - Eric.
Wear your jeans, for Christ's sake.
- I can't wear jeans to my graduation.
BuIIshit!
Get me another beer and we're going.
What?
Get me another beer. Now!
We aII chipped in
and Gar picked it out.
- But you gotta wear it.
That's a point.
What do you say?
Thank you, everybody.
Go get it on.
Before we send our students
on to senior high, we wouId Iike
to acknowIedge some of our stars.
An academic award in EngIish
is presented to CaroIine MiIes.
For academic exceIIence
in mathematics:
Rocky Dennis.
Thanks.
Stay here. For achievement
in history: Rocky Dennis.
And ...
for academic exceIIence
in science ...
Rocky Dennis!
That's my famiIy.
Have a nice summer.
I'm ...
reaI ...
proud ...
of ...
you ...
Rocky.
Thanks, Doze.
Grandma! Grandpa!
Mom? - Yeah?
- You up? - Yeah.
Mom, they're here!
- Bring them in.
Morning, Gar.
- Mornin', Rock. - Come on.
Why don't you pIay this one straight?
Give your oId man a chance.
What a terrific idea.
Why didn't I think of that?
You go ahead.
I'II put on my wings and haIo.
Gotta get a picture of that.
Honey boy! - What are you
gonna do? Try out for the Nicks?
Look how taII he's getting, EveIyn!
Come on, fake, fake! That's a boy!
Stop that, say heIIo to the boy.
So, show us the new house.
Abe, don't start anything.
You promised, Abe.
Come on in.
HeIIo, Abe. - Hey, sonofabitch!
Look who's back! - Gar!
Let me show you my dog.
- That's aII you need, a damn dog.
Does she have cIeanser?
- That's not your job.
I just want to give her a hand.
I'm not going to do anything.
Quite a mutt.
Hey, that's terribIe. - What?
- HoIe in your infieId.
That's got to go.
- oh God!
oh shit!
I mean, wow! Peewee Reese!
Consider it a beIated
graduation present. - It's wonderfuI.
Why don't you show the dog to
your grandma. - OK. Come on, Screech!
Hi, Pop.
There she is.
Looking Iike a miIIion.
- You Iook great too, Pop.
Hey, Ma, you wanna do the windows
whiIe you're at it? - Gramps?
Where did you get that Peewee?
I've been Iooking for it for 2 years.
I found it a coupIe of months ago
in a store, just waiting for me.
Abe, how does it feeI to be retired?
It's driving me crazy. A man's onIy
as good as his Iast day of work.
How Iong are you staying, Pop?
- Hey, she's trying to get rid of us!
No, I wanted to make some nice Iunch.
- You cooking? No ordering out?
No, I got roast.
You Iike roast.
Yeah, I couIdn't chew it
the Iast time ...
I thought the roast was deIicious.
What are they Iearnin' you at schooI?
- Same oId stuff, math, history ...
Yeah? First you get an education
then a job with some security.
I tried to teII that to your mother.
She never went for the oId 9 to 5.
What was it you said, Rusty?
I'm reaIIy more ...
The freeIance type.
Yeah, the freeIance type!
I got her a job interview once at the
gas company. Luca Pezio's brother,
what the heII was his name?
She shows up in this kooky outfit
with her hair up to here
and these Iines painted under here.
Looked Iike she had spiders
under her eyes.
Remember that, Rusty?
Yeah, I remember, Pop.
The guy's name was Vinny.
He wanted to give me a job.
He aIso wanted to give me a bonus.
So, I took the bonus and
toId him to shove the job up his ass.
FIorence!
Rocky, find out
what time the game's on the tube.
It usuaIIy starts at two thirty
but I'II check.
Wow! Grandpa gave me tickets
to the game! Can I go? Check it out!
Come on, Rocky, Iet's go.
The team needs you.
Bye, Mom. See, you, Gar.
- See you, Rock.
He tried, honey, he reaIIy tried.
- It's OK, Mom.
Anyway, I'm gIad Gar is back.
Don't you want to wave goodbye?
- No, I don't.
Bye!
If you get wasted on that crap
I ain't gonna baby-sit you.
You must be confusing me with someone
who gives a shit. - Must be.
This is not going to work.
I'm doing things to pIease you
and I'II end up hating you for it.
Come on, baby, you and your oId man
been going through this shit forever.
Got to you again, didn't he?
Got you ready for a 2-hour screamer.
Got you to a pIace where I'd
put you through the waII. - Go ahead!
Why shouId you be any different
than any other guy I've been with?
Look what I got.
FIorence?
What did you do today?
Some smack? Ludes?
Some promise you made!
In front of Grandma and Grandpa, too.
Why? Why do you do this, Mom?
I'm not going to hang around
aII summer for this.
I'm going to a camp where
everybody's bIind. It'II be a break.
Who's going to take care of things?
You! You're gonna have to take care
of things incIuding yourseIf.
That'II be something new, won't it?
Come on, Iet's get it together!
- Come on, Dewey!
Kevin, turn off the radio.
Come on. Summer,
can you get them over here, pIease?
Hey, you in the back,
take that mask off so I can see you.
WeII, I'II try
but it ain't gonna be easy.
Gee, I'm sorry.
I reaIIy thought it was a mask.
It's OK.
Happens aII the time. No big deaI.
Hi, Rocky, I'm Norman KapIan.
GIad to have you aboard.
WaIter Simms toId me a Iot about you.
- Jake wants you in the kitchen.
Put your gear over there
and give Dewey a hand over there?
Thanks.
Make myseIf weII.
We're aImost there.
You guys haven't missed too much.
Kevin, how's the caboose doing
back there? - Fine! - AIright.
He's winding up,
trying for the 3rd-base Iine.
He reIeases!
- Swing! - Go!
We got the bases Ioaded, 2 outs.
AIex at bat.
He's winding up ...
Who's that?
My name's Rocky.
- Hi, Rocky, I'm Diana Adams.
Dennis, Rocky Dennis.
Are you a camper?
- Yeah. I'm aIso a counseIor's aide.
That's neat.
You Iook Iike AIice.
You know, in WonderIand.
No, what does she Iook Iike?
You.
That's a big heIp!
Wanna hand me that bridIe?
Great, thank ...
No, this is a haIter.
The bridIe is Ieather
and has a bit. - A bit of what?
No. A bit is a metaI piece
that fits into the horse's mouth.
oh yeah. Right here.
Thank you.
Don't know much
about horses, do you?
WeII, I ride motorcycIes.
I Iove horses. I got one at home.
Where's your home?
- San Marino.
Where do you Iive?
- Azusa.
Are you starving?
I'm starving.
CouId you take me to Iunch?
Sure. Great.
OK, Maria, he's ready.
- Fine, thanks.
No. Here, I'II take your eIbow.
Diana of the woods.
What's that?
A famous goddess.
A huntress, I think.
I couIdn't hit a barn
with an eIephant.
That's funny.
- Thanks.
Rusty? What?
oh, shit!
What's the matter?
- Rusty.
Gar, I can't write
a Ietter to Rocky. I miss him.
You need to sIeep, Rusty.
- No, no!
HeIp me write the Ietter, pIease!
Dear Rocky, I miss you. And ...
you're away at camp.
You're not in your room and ...
I miss you.
And I'm sorry I was bad. And ...
Screech is here and Gar is here
and I Iove you.
Love, Mom. With IittIe kisses.
Have you got that, Gar?
Yeah, I got it aII.
- OK.
You OK back there, Rocky?
- Fine!
Dn your right.
You got some chaparraI.
It's covering a roIIing, green hiII.
It ain't just your forest green,
it's misty, grayish green.
I've been bIind since I was born
and I don't know green.
You don't? - PeopIe have tried to
expIain coIors. I don't understand.
Anyway, go on.
WeII, up above
we got some white cIouds.
White! I'm sorry. - It's OK.
- Some biIIowy cIouds.
I don't know biIIowy either.
This is strange.
We're puIIing over.
WeII, Iet's stop.
I got you.
- Thanks.
I can't wait to teII Eric and Ben
about this. - Who are they?
Eric's my friend from schooI.
Ben's my friend for Iife. Let's sit.
I have a friend Iike that, Anne Marie.
Me and Ben pIan to ride motorcycIes
across Europe. - Yeah? That's neat!
My parents are so protective.
My mom is very modern.
Yeah? Did she name you Rocky?
- Yeah. My reaI name is Roy.
When I was a kid I used to
rock back and forth in my crib.
So she caIIed me Rocky.
- I Iike that. - Hey, you two.
Just one appIe Ieft. You guys
wanna share it? - Thanks, Marie.
I'II cut it in haIf.
I wanna show you something.
What do you Iook Iike?
Describe yourseIf.
Too bad you've never seen
pictures of the Greek god Adonis,
'cause I kind of Iook Iike him.
Wow, he was gorgeous!
He was. We are.
Here.
- Thanks.
See the star? Five-pointed star,
it's supposed to be Iucky.
Diana,
I don't Iook Iike Adonis.
I've got this reaI strange disease.
And it makes my face
Iook reaI unreaI.
Don't be a chicken.
You Iook pretty good to me.
My mom says I Iook Iike a Iion.
She says I was a Iion in a past Iife
and something got Ieft over.
That's funny.
Hey, you two!
Show us your pearIy whites!
Great!
Sorry. Is now a good time?
- Sure, Rock.
Thanks!
I need to show you something.
- What are you doing? - Wait!
Just hoId on a second.
- No! - Right here. Sit down.
HoId out your hands ...
Ready? Wait.
- What is this?
HoId on a second! Damn!
Wait a second. I got it right here.
OK, ready?
- No, what? - This is bIue.
It's freezing!
It's bIue?
This is green.
I think I understand.
- HoId on!
Shit! Sorry, Diana.
- It's OK, I say that aII the time.
You do?
Put those down.
This is red.
Ah! It's red?
- When it cooIs down, it'II be pink.
Rocky, I understand!
- HoId on a second.
This is biIIowy.
And this
is beautifuI.
NEW YEARS EVE IN JULY
Man, do I have
a great one to use now. - You do?
A great thought. My mom taught me,
when things get rotten
I shouId think of a good memory.
Tonight sure is a beauty.
- Does it work?
oh, yes!
Can two peopIe use the same memory?
OK, campers,
ten seconds to New Year's!
Nine, eight,
seven, six,
five, four,
three, two,
Dne! Happy New Year!
Happy New Year, Diana.
Happy New Year, Rocky.
Aren't you going to kiss me?
Bye, you guys!
How are you?
God, I missed you. Mom!
- I missed you so much!
Hi.
- Mom, Dad, this is Rocky Dennis,
the boy I toId you about
on the phone.
Rocky was voted best buddy
and friendIiest camper.
WonderfuI!
We better hit the road, honey.
Wanna beat the traffic ...
Nice meeting you, Rocky.
Come on, honey.
I'm just going to say goodbye.
Bye, Rocky.
Bye.
CaII me, OK?
I wiII.
I wanna kiss you
but my parents are watching.
I understand.
Bye.
Goddamn sonofabitch.
You Iook great!
How are you? - Where's your stuff?
- Dver there.
My buddy!
- Hey, Babe!
Doesn't he Iook great?
- Great.
Mom, I have some great news.
Me too.
You first.
I quit. I'm cIean as a whistIe.
AIright, Mom. - Yeah,
I even caIIed the drug rehab, twice.
What did they say?
- WeII, I hung up.
WeII, it's a start.
What about your news?
It's no big deaI.
I met a girI. We're going out.
Come on, teII us!
- Her name is Diana.
She's beautifuI.
She's got Iong bIonde hair.
She rides horses, she's smart
and she Ioves me.
What's not to Iove about you?
You Iook reaI pretty today, Mom.
I've caIIed Diana every day
since I've been back
and her mom aIways says
she's not there. Isn't that weird?
I don't know ...
- Hey, Ben!
What's happening?
I gotta taIk to you.
- OK. You want some cake?
No. - Sure? Mom made it.
It's actuaIIy pretty good. - Thanks.
Want something to drink?
How about a noose
to hang yourseIf? What's the matter?
I've been wanting to teII this.
What?
I'm going back to Michigan.
My dad got me a job. Great money.
When are you coming back?
I'm not coming back.
What do you mean?
I'II go nuts if I stay here,
with my mom, the schooI.
So I quit.
I can work back there.
I'II be making 7.50 an hour.
What about the trip?
I'm sorry, Rocky.
You can keep the money.
I don't want the money, I want to
go to Europe! What about our trip?
How can you do this? We taIked about
it for a year. - You taIked about it!
BuIIshit, man! You taIked about it too
and you know it!
I know. I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that.
You never know what you mean!
You know why? Because you're stupid!
You are so stupid, Ben!
I'II show you how stupid you are.
I conned you out of Rube WaIker!
Rocky, take it easy.
- No more, Ben! - Stop it!
Get out of here, Ben!
HeIIo, Mrs. Adams? Is Diana there?
Rocky Dennis.
Do you know where she is?
Did you teII her I've caIIed?
Thanks. Goodbye.
Baby, don't cry.
There's that guy I heard about.
If that's a mask he's wearing
I sure wish he'd take it off.
I'II take my mask off if you
take your mask off, you sonofabitch!
Mom?
- We're out here.
I got to go somewhere.
- Where you goin', Rock?
I just got something to do.
I'II be back, don't worry.
No, Screech, stay.
oh, God.
Anne Marie, this is Rocky.
- Hi.
You wanna excuse us and take him?
Come on, Iet's taIk.
Why didn't you caII? - I caIIed you.
You never caIIed me back.
I made tapes and I never
heard from you. - oh, my parents!
I knew it!
- I thought you'd forgotten me.
I thought you'd forgotten me.
They don't want me to get hurt.
I never stop taIking about you.
And I'm going away next semester.
- Where? - I'm Ieaving Monday.
The schooI has good programs
for the bIind. It's in Santa Barbara.
Sit down.
I'II write. I'II send you tapes.
oh, Rocky, I missed you.
I don't wanna go!
Are you Iaughing at me?
- oh, God, no.
It's just that, here it is,
the most rotten time of my whoIe Iife.
You're going away. I hate my schooI.
The trip to Europe is off ...
- No!
But, no, it's OK. That's what's funny,
it doesn't matter.
It's OK now
'cause I know that you stiII Iove me.
I do, I reaIIy do!
I wish we couId run away
and be together aII the time.
We can't run away, Diana.
- I know.
But we can run away in our minds.
We can remember the camp,
the mountains and ocean.
The coIored rocks and biIIowy cotton.
And New Year's Eve.
- EspeciaIIy New Year's Eve.
And right now.
We'II aIways be together, Diana.
Even when we can't be together.
Sing us that oId number, Rocky.
How about it, Rusty? - Good idea!
I'm up for it if he is.
- I'm feeIing tired tonight.
Aw, come on, Rocky!
- Come on, you guys!
Sing a number!
You OK, babe?
My head hurts a Iot tonight.
You don't have to sing.
Go to bed and make yourseIf weII.
How about it, Rusty? You gotta sing.
- What's with the IittIe one?
Yeah, sing that other song! Come on!
How you doin', kid?
Goodnight, Rock.
Come on, Screech.
Why don't we go back to bed?
- That's OK with me.
I got to do this thing with Red.
I'II be back. - I'II wait for you.
See you Iater.
Yeah? No, he's at schooI.
Yeah, I'm sure.
What do you mean, he's not there?
OK, thanks.
You sure as heII aren't getting
a schoIarship if you stay in the sack!
You got a Spanish test,
didn't you? Afraid of a IittIe test?
CoId.
You've got your covers off you.
Don't puII this shit with me, Rock!
Do you hear me? Wake up!
Come on, baby, make yourseIf weII.
Rocky, wake up!
oh, God!
Now you can go
anywhere you want, baby.
These things are good:
Ice cream and cake.
A ride on a HarIey.
Monkeys in the trees.
The rain on my tongue
and the sun shining on my face.
These things are a drag:
Dust in my hair.
HoIes in my shoes.
No money in my pocket
and the sun
shining on my face.
DVD Subtitles:
-klepal-