Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Ja Soo, you
realize the gravity of this matter
but still you utter nonsense?!
The importance of this
I comprehend better than you.
But I saw it clearly with my own eyes.
Something swept over sideways,
and suddenly he disappeared.
He could not have left the palace yet.
I will call the guards,
so you find your own way out.
It would be wise
to place all the blame on him instead.
Otherwise, how would it be possible
to capture him in this huge palace?
This is impossible, Eunuch.
What are you doing?
Hurry and disappear!
I thought he was just a weak scholar.
What magic did he use?
Excuse me.
What's your role?
Which role will you be playing?
Ah.
I'm also one of the actors in this drama.
Queen In Hyun.
I'm the one and only Queen In Hyun.
You haven't heard yet, right?
It was decided just a while ago.
30 minutes ago.
It actually hasn't been publicly announced
yet, so I shouldn't be telling you.
But I'm so happy, I can't stop myself.
You're the only one who knows.
Ah, please have this.
I bought some snacks for the staff.
You don't like donuts?
Excuse me.
Are you not an actor from this drama?
Are you all right?
Wait.
Maiden, do you know...?
What?
...if I am dead or dreaming?
Are you asking
because you sincerely want to know?
I am asking...
because I sincerely want to know.
Then don't get angry.
I'm saying this because
you asked me for an answer.
To me...
you're not dead or dreaming,
but you do seem a little off.
No,
you just look like that.
I'm not saying
that you're actually a little off.
Um... It looks like you don't
understand my joke.
What I mean is that's how
strange your question is.
What I said wasn't serious.
Choi Hee Jin?
Yes?
The director asked you to wait 10 minutes.
Okay, I'll be right here.
Hm?
What's this?
He looked normal.
He's really crazy.
Shi, do, tong, rae,
(Time, path, connect, come,)
gan, pil, gu, in
(space, must, rescue, man)
Who dares
use a sword in the palace?
This is clearly a conspiracy!
You must certainly find who the man is.
I am sure he has yet to leave the palace.
Give me my sword.
Lord of Doctrines,
something unforeseen
has occurred in the palace.
There is an order that no one is
allowed to leave the palace.
I cannot leave?
For now, you must wait here...
I did not wear my official uniform,
yet you let me enter the palace.
If others were to know about this,
then you will be chased out of the palace
without being able to utter a word!
Pardon?
Lord, you said it was an order, so...
We were doing it for your sake...
I do not want to hear any excuses.
Do not tell anyone I was here tonight.
Hand me my sword!
Whoever asks, do not say you saw me tonight.
That is the only way you will live.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Your Highness, congratulations.
Cheers!
Congratulations on your enthronement.
May you continue to do well, Your Highness.
Thank you, Court Lady Jo.
If Your Highness is successful,
don't you think Soo Kyung
will attain success too?
I knew this day would come one day,
so I have invested everything in you.
However, it has been a weary journey.
The fact that you and I would hit the
jackpot is a will by the heavens.
From now on,
we will continue to move forward.
You are correct, Your Highness.
Let us drink to that.
Let's do it in English.
- Cheers!
Wow!
Who knew that this could happen?
You were never casted for supporting roles,
so how did you manage to
become the lead in one try?
Amazing!
You're ridiculous.
You said that if Han Dong Min was Sukjong,
if is best if I don't do it.
Now that I have the lead,
you're that happy?
Hey.
That was only to comfort you.
It's even better if it's Han Dong Min!
Truthfully speaking, he is a bit of an ass,
but we need to go along with him
to make money.
The current trend is Han Dong Min!
It's all right if I don't
make money right away.
I'm just starting out.
Don't think about using him.
I don't want that.
You sure know how to joke, Your Highness.
First of all, it's great you got the role,
but in the future, you need to get
intensive training from me.
All this while, you were half unemployed,
which is why I took care of you.
Now, get ready.
Here, here, eat this also.
Who is it at this time of night?
Who is it?
Is it you, Soo Kyung?
Who are you?
It's Dong Min oppa.
Who?
- Hey, it's Han Dong Min!
- What?!
Oh my!
It really is Dong Min oppa!
Hi.
Long time no see.
What brings you here at this time?
Hee Jin is ignoring my calls.
I have something to talk to her about.
What?
What...?
The director said he wants to give
Queen In Hyun's role to Hee Jin,
but I'm a little worried.
What?
What is it?
What are they talking about?
Why is he here, huh?
He is using an unthinkable method.
What?
He says he doesn't like the fact
that you're Queen In Hyun.
What do we do?
That man is unbelievable till the end!
Wait, the director, chief,
and president all chose me;
so who is he to say
whether he likes me or not?
Hey, that's not exactly the case...
If it's Han Dong Min,
he has a say in who his partner will be.
If he insists that it can't be you,
then the problem becomes serious.
First, start by talking to him.
He said he called, but you ignored him.
- Go out, hurry, hurry!
- What am I supposed to say to him?
Did I go to audition knowing that
Han Dong Min was Sukjong?
Why do I need his permission?
Who is he?
He's the king.
Jeez.
I didn't think you'd still be living here.
Looks like you haven't saved up any money.
Where's the flower pot I bought you?
My signature was on it.
If I still had a present from
a cheating ex-boyfriend,
doesn't that make me a crazy girl?
You, how can you ignore me?
When was our relationship one where
I came out when you told me to?
We had no contact for 2 years,
so isn't this a bit ridiculous?
For me,
Queen In Hyun being a newbie is okay
and being my ex-girlfriend is
not a big deal either.
Then why are you being an obstacle?
In the end, it's your lack of acting
skills that worries me.
What?
Everyone knows you for your bad acting.
Oh my! That was from so long ago!
Didn't you see me earlier?
Everyone was praising me.
That short scene...
By memorizing it endlessly,
anyone can do it well.
Do you think you can deal with a
50-episode historical drama?
In no time,
your bad acting will get the better of you.
I am not the old Choi Hee Jin.
- Will Choi Hee Jin go anywhere-
- So?
Are you saying you're going to fire me?
I'm going to determine
that after seeing you.
Here.
I told the Director that I'd decide
after seeing if we're in tune.
Look at page 78.
Are you telling me to act right now?
If you act alone,
it's awkward, so I'll act with you.
This is too much!
- Even if you are the main actor-
- Hurry.
I'm also a busy person.
People are waiting for me downstairs.
I'm starting.
Why not criticize my hastiness earlier?
Why are you always enduring?
Queen.
Hurry and give me an answer, Queen.
I...
was ignorant,
so I was unable to grasp the opportunity,
please blame my ignorance for everything.
Was it really because you were
unable to find the right timing
or did you pretend to not know?
How could I?
I am a sinner, Your Majesty.
Come here.
[Unable to go over]
Didn't I tell you to come here?
If my Queen will not come,
must I go to you?
What are you doing? Don't come.
Just read the script.
Should we see each other again?
What did you say?
What about meeting again?
That entertainment program you watch,
there are no scandals about me lately,
right?
I have no one right now.
This is all your fault.
Actually, since earlier,
the image of you stripping
has been stuck in my head,
so how could I focus on acting?
Looks like you still see me as a fool.
I think we're in tune.
Okay. I like it.
You pass.
That bastard!
Hey, you ass...!
Hyung, start the car.
What are you doing?
Hurry. Hurry.
You really!
Choi Hee Jin!
Queen In Hyun is yours!
What did you say?
Even if you don't appoint me,
Queen In Hyun was mine!
How irritating!
Hey, what are you doing?
We haven't signed the contract yet,
and you're already entering the actress'
house to create a scandal?
Hyung.
Hyung, it's been a while since
I've felt my heart flutter.
What?
Stop fluttering.
Every time you say your heart flutters,
I break out in a cold sweat.
I remember the past.
Those were the best.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Why did he leave so quickly?
I'm speechless, really.
What did he say?
I was completely fooled.
I really should report him to the police.
He thinks I'm still the old Choi Hee Jin.
He's got another thing coming!
What are you saying?
Did something happen?
They say fortune and misfortune
come together. Seriously.
You don't like donuts?
But, who is he?
He didn't seem like an actor.
Do you happen to know...
if I am dead or dreaming?
Yeah, the way he talked was weird too.
He spoke in a completely historical way.
He must have gone crazy because he really
wanted to be an actor but couldn't.
That's why he comes to the shoot and
wears those clothes and says lines.
That's awful. Awful.
We have searched every
possible hiding place,
but he was not there.
Furthermore,
we have observed the movements
of the Seo-in* (*Western faction)
but it seems as if no one is
aware of this incident.
In other words,
the officer alone contrived such a bold act?
Don't you believe it was His Majesty's wish?
His Majesty is using
this competition as an excuse
to view the friction between the factions.
He is...
acting according to His Majesty's orders...
surely.
But letting go of Kim Boong Do was unwise.
He too lost his family members, did he not?
The criminals shall consume poison.
Oh my!
What is this?
My Lady!
Please awaken, My Lady!
Oh my. Oh my! My Lady!
My Lady!
After that,
it is evident
that he has been plotting revenge.
How can a scholar be so
exceptional in martial arts?
His actions are His Majesty's orders...
His Majesty wants to attack me first...
My Lord,
it is Ja Soo.
Enter.
Do you have any new information?
Yes.
While investigating the people
with relations to Kim Boong Do,
we found an unexpected person.
Unexpected person?
Who is that?
The path of time bridges to the future,
that gap must certainly save man.
How are you feeling?
I am well.
Forgive me for always troubling you.
You never cease to startle me.
When Yoon Wol worried for you,
I thought she was overreacting.
I have something I wanted to ask you.
This talisman that Yoon Wol gave me,
what exactly does it mean?
The path of time bridges to the future,
that gap must certainly save man.
It is a brilliant verse.
A brilliant verse...
I am unsure.
It is Master who wrote this.
He has gone to Bohyunsa Temple.
Yes.
But,
why are you interested in the talisman?
I must confess that I experienced
a very strange event.
A strange event?
At first, I thought I had died,
but I was not dead.
After that, I thought I was dreaming,
but I was not.
...gan pil gu in.
(space, must, save, man)
I had not fallen asleep and I was fine,
so how would I explain this?
It is a strange event.
The things I saw were very strange and new,
so they would not leave my mind.
Even so, I am envious of you.
Perhaps, you saw the immortal world.
Although it was brief,
it seems you saw a fairy there as well.
A fairy?
I am curious as to why you laugh.
I did meet a woman,
but her appearance was...
I could not have met a fairy.
She must not be.
If a fairy really looks like that,
then the immortal world is not immortal.
Even if you do not speak in detail,
I understand.
I will leave once it gets dark.
Please take care of your body.
You must think of your family.
I do this because of my family.
You have already experienced many things.
In any case,
it seems this talisman saved my life,
so I must keep it safe.
As you have said, after experiencing a lot,
it feels as if anything may happen,
and nothing can be trusted.
To Yoon Wol...
I will not tell her you have come.
Please do not worry.
If she knew you were wounded,
she may ask for a hundred talismans
to give to you.
Yoon Wol.
Oh my.
Your Excellency.
Without any notice, what brings you here?
I have been too busy,
thus I have been unable to see you.
I have missed your voice.
My Lord.
Yes, what song were you playing?
Let us hear it.
Do you know Kim Boong Do?
Pardon?
Do you not know Officer Kim Boong Do
of Hongmungwan?
Officer of Hongmungwan?
Oh!
I believe I have seen him a few times.
He came with his superiors a few times.
You are skilled at lying.
Pardon?
I heard,
you were the slave girl of
Kim Boong Do's late wife.
I learned today that you have
a deep relationship with him.
That...
is incorrect.
You were misinformed.
A slave girl?
We were unable to execute a murder
because of you.
It is unimaginable.
You have misunderstood, Your Excellency.
I do not know where you heard such words.
Had I known earlier that I had
a traitor in my household,
I would not have given you any affection.
You are a crafty witch!
Come in!
Yes!
Your Excellency, My Lord!
Tie her up!
Yes!
Why are you doing this?
In order to capture Kim Boong Do,
I must capture you first.
I heard that he placed you here when
you were on the brink of death.
As he cherishes you very much,
he will certainly come to find you,
is that not so?
That is a misunderstanding.
I was just a slave girl.
Who would care for me?
This is an unthinkable
misunderstanding, My Lord!
My Lord!
We have imprisoned her as you have ordered
and told the servants to keep an eye on her.
She did not resist?
Yes.
You can leave.
His Royal Majesty has arrived.
Exactly how many days has this been?
Did those criminals
still not admit to their treacheries?
Your Majesty,
among them, please show Kim Boong Do
special leniency.
What do you mean by that?
There is no doubt
that he was unaware of his father's crime.
As it stands,
his whole household has
received just punishment.
Kim Boong Do is their only son.
Please have compassion on their lineage
and grant him an unconditional pardon.
Do you really...
mean what you say?
I am sincere, Your Majesty.
Why did you let him live?
Such a useless act!
Your Majesty,
Kim Boong Do is one of His Majesty's
most favored officers.
If he were to be exiled as well,
His Majesty will pity him
well after punishing him.
Your Highness,
please understand His Majesty's intentions
and sympathize with him.
Would that not be compassion
most befitting of Your Highness?
It will be of great help in changing
the people's minds.
Will it really be like that?
A fatherless Kim Boong Do is
a bird without wings.
Giving him an official position out of view
will show the fairness
and tolerance of the court.
There is nothing he can
accomplish on his own.
Please do not worry.
This is all...
a result of your kindness.
One day,
I will return your favor.
There is no need to call it grace.
After that,
it is evident
that he has been plotting revenge.
How can a scholar be so
exceptional in martial arts?
What a foolish ignorant man.
Stop.
Does it not please you?
Then, I shall prepare another song.
From the first time I saw you
at the gisaeng house,
I found your face to be oddly familiar.
Where is your hometown?
That is...
for a lowly gisaeng with no true roots,
could I have a hometown?
After hearing your response,
you are quite humorous.
Oddly familiar.
Isn't that a trick
used by youths 19 years of age?
With you in front of me,
I feel as if have become
a student 19 years of age.
Come closer and pour me a drink.
Oh, this girl!
How dare a gisaeng be shy?
Forgive me.
Because I am in front of
a man of such high status,
I was flustered.
Being old is my sin.
I have become slow-witted.
Repulsive brats,
how dare you!
Monk! Monk!
What brings you here?
Miss Yoon Wol,
Miss Yoon Wol has been captured!
What should we do?
What did you say?
Did you just say Yoon Wol has been captured?
Lord of Doctrines!
Who did it?
Everyone is searching for you!
That is why Miss Yoon Wol was captured.
They did not know that you were here.
Who did it?
Is it the Right State Councilor?
What about the letter?
Pardon?
They will be searching for something.
Have they found anything?
I do not know.
They said you had it.
This is your ringtone.
Hello?
Yeah, I'll be taking pictures soon.
Did Yoon Na Jung come yet?
No, not yet.
Jeez.
Why won't they tell us what she's wearing?
Are they competing with us?
No way! Does she have no one else to compete
with that she is competing with me?
If Consort Jang is Queen In Hyun's rival,
then you and Yoon Na Jung are rivals too.
Does becoming a star
depend only on experience?
I don't know. I have to worry about myself.
I don't have time to worry
about other people.
I'm so nervous.
Yoon Na Jung is here.
Hey, hey, hey.
Make sure you properly greet her.
They say her attitude is no joke.
I'm hanging up.
Hello.
I can sit here, right?
What? Oh...
I will go over there.
Um, please accept my greeting.
Hello. I am Choi Hee Jin.
I will be Queen In Hyun.
Miss Hee Jin,
please come over here.
She must be very tired.
Here.
Look a bit into the distance.
Look far into the distance again.
Look farther with your eyes.
Passionately.
All right.
Excuse me, Queen In Hyun, please come in.
Oh, my wife.
Okay, I'll be taking pictures.
Queen In Hyun, smile a bit.
Okay, I'm shooting.
Queen In Hyun,
lean into Sukjong's shoulder.
Yes.
More naturally.
My Queen, why are you being so shy?
Come closer.
I'll start shooting now.
For me, this is the first time
I eagerly waited for a shoot.
You know we'll be filming
together every day.
I just need to endure it
until the 25th episode.
The 25th episode?
The scene where Queen In Hyun
gets stripped of her title.
After that,
there's no need to film together.
Writer, since this is the new Consort Jang,
how about going a bit trendy?
Like this or like this?
Or V?
V, V, V?
Both of you are done.
Consort Jang, please come here.
Ugh.
See you later.
Has Your Highness arrived?
What is this?
Is she trying to mess with me?
Both of you, please stand close.
Since you are rivals,
I think a cut with your backs
facing each other will be good.
Queen In Hyun,
please turn to the other side also.
Hold on a moment. Lights...
You must be happy about becoming
the lead so easily.
What?
After waking up, you're already a lead.
It's fun, right?
What are you talking about?
Do you even think or not?
If someone treats you well,
you should think about why.
I'm taking the shot.
Please don't move.
Excuse me,
please explain so I can understand.
We've only met,
why are you saying such things?
What do you think I'm saying?
You're an idiot, so you're annoying me.
Please don't turn your heads.
Just stare at each other.
Did you greet her well?
What did she say?
It didn't start off well.
What? Why?
I think it's going to be
difficult to work with her.
See. What did I say?
She is competing with you.
It's competing for a lead,
so there's no senior or junior.
This is not just competing.
Then?
Hello, I am Pak Se Il, the host of the
New Consort Jang press conference.
On such a beautiful afternoon,
I am happy to greet the reporters
here at the palace.
I feel very honored.
10 minutes later, we will officially
start the press conference.
Before that,
let's have a look at the trailers.
[New Consort Jang]
Hello.
Hold on a moment.
Whoo, wow.
Don't fall while going on stage.
You're used to falling down.
Did you say anything to anyone?
About what?
By any chance,
did you get involved with the audition?
So I would get selected?
Didn't I tell you Queen In Hyun is yours?
Originally, the percentage was similar,
so I helped them make the decision.
Kid,
I have that much of an influence.
Who told you to help? Who?
Hey!
Like you said, the levels must be similar
so the fans don't complain.
I'll make you more famous than Na Jung,
just wait and see.
Dong Min.
Yes.
Hee Jin, we have to finish up,
so please come here quickly.
Don't tremble.
I'm not trembling.
But you are trembling.
I still have about 10 minutes
before it starts, right?
Hey, where are you going?
For a walk...
I'm too nervous.
Why is she such a wimp?
Get a hold of yourself, Choi Hee Jin.
How did you get this opportunity?
Think about it later.
Now is not the time to think about this.
What's this? Why is it so windy suddenly?
Did you get hurt?
Seeing as I have met you twice,
it is clear this is not a dream.
This...
is fake blood, right?
You're currently filming, right?
Right?
What is this "filming" you are referring to?
Last time, Maiden,
you said I seemed a little off.
I did not understand,
so I thought carefully.
Does it not mean the same as food being
spoiled and that I am not of sane mind?
Is that what it means?
Yes, what other meaning would it have...?
If so, then Maiden, you are incorrect.
I am not crazy.
Death I must rule out, so I am not dead.
I am not dead or dreaming.
I am not crazy as you have said.
Where am I?
We have introduced the director.
Following that,
it is time to introduce the cast.
Han Dong Min, this side please.
This drama's title role...
Our country's famous actor...
Next is Choi Hee Jin.
Yes.
Why isn't she coming?
Did Choi Hee Jin go somewhere?
- Hold on a moment. Hold on a moment.
- Introducing Yoon Na Jung.
Choi Hee Jin. Find Choi Hee Jin!
- Hold on a moment.
- Next is...
- Is that girl crazy?
- the man who is in a love triangle...
with Queen In Hyun and Consort Jang...
Our drama's hero.
Find Choi Hee Jin quickly!
I think we'll have to get ready
just in case she doesn't come.
I think he will make a handsome king.
Sukjong's role...
Han Dong Min!
Look over here!
A little brighter!
Look here!
Here! Here! Here! Here!
Next is the final lead who is involved
In the love triangle with these two.
Giving us a fresh look,
a new face...
Oh, wait.
Just a moment.
What is this?
What's wrong with her now?
Ah, she's really such a troublemaker.
Then...
this person is dead?
He is really dead?
Did I not question you first?
Where exactly is this place?
Did you see that?
I myself cannot comprehend what
I have seen with my own eyes.
Is this by any chance something
that happens often here?
No.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Translator: ahsieee
Spot Translators: lizzyd, purpletiger86
Timer: em_ily<3
Editor/QC: puela
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
I thought he was just a scholar,
but he has extraordinary skills.
There was no body, not even a trace.
The Kim Boong Do I know
has always been like this.
- His nature is despicable-
- You are slanderous!
How many years has passed since
Joseon Sukjong's reign?
From about 300 years ago,
he is a person from Joseon.
He came here through time travel.
That's not possible.
Are you asking me to believe that?
I am quickly losing my mind.
I think she still likes me.
She's not as cool as I thought she was.
A person like you is an actress too!
Do I have to look at you
and say my lines with you?
Why are you doing this?!
Why am I being attacked
when I don't know what I did?
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com