A vacancy just opened up.
Will it be okay
if I fill the empty spot?
Episode 19
Do you know this?
I came into politics with power.
Gil Do, only live today as an animal.
If you continue to do so I'll chew you up.
I asked if I'm capable of filling in?
Come in.
How could I stop this animal?
Your name is...
Hwang Seong Woo.
Which crime committed by the Noodle
Master will you be testifying about?
Soliciting murder and
numerous incidents of
embezzlement and corruption.
Also forgery of documents and...
I'll testify regarding assault,
blackmailing and other crimes.
Let's do it here.
Please spare me.
Go beg the Noodle Master.
It's no use asking me.
You're not able to kill anyone.
But if you send me to the Noodle Master
it's like sending me to my death.
What's the difference
from your killing me?!
Shut him up.
Kim Dae Ha. Kim Dae Ha.
Move it.
Why is Dae Ha's name
coming out of your mouth?
What's going to happen when So Tae Seop finds
out that Dae Ha is the Noodle Master daughter?
Do you think he's going to let her live?
Why does So Tae Seop know that?
The moment that you kill me, all
the information will be sent.
Should I believe your bluff?
That's up to you whether
you believe me or not.
However if I'm telling the
truth, Kim Da Hae will die.
The Noodle Master isn't finished yet.
It's been bothering me.
Forget it.
Nothing will happen, right?
Stop imagining things.
Nothing is going to happen.
Then this is where I step out.
Let's go.
I can testify to everything from the Noodle
Master's murder case to his money laundering.
Of course I have relevant evidence.
Say what your conditions are.
We seem to communicate well.
Doggoo... I mean CEO Lee Jeong Bum... You dropped
his case, right? I saw that and came forward.
Clean everything that is connected to me.
Then I will testify.
I had sent a package to
Madam Go Gang Sook also.
She couldn't quite use it to her benefit. I hope
you don't make the same mistake, Prosecutor.
I need time to think.
Think it over slowly.
However don't take too long.
[Prosecution Service]
[After 3 Days] What's going
on with Assemblyman Choi?
I haven't been able to
make contact for 4 days.
He hasn't attended the assembly
sessions or gone to his office.
As of now, we're not sure whether
he disappeared or is missing.
It seems to be a hush hush situation.
He can't have gone anywhere.
He must be hiding somewhere. As it was a parliamentary
session, we weren't able to conduct the arrest promptly.
You scared me.
Take a look at this.
The police found the trace of briquettes inside the car... [Breaking news,
Choi Seong Do of Hanguk Freedom Party found dead, suicide suspected]
and evidence that shows the deceased's
family was going through recent stress.
It's being treated as a suicide
but is under investigation.
On the other hand, according to a friend
of Assemblyman Choi Seong Do, his aide
was arrested for violation
of the Foreign Exchange Law.
The pressure from the Prosecutor's
Office and the investigation...
Yes, Chief Prosecutor.
Had a great influence over his
decision to commit suicide.
I'll be there shortly.
Opposed to Assemblyman So Tae Seop, who has been Assemblyman longest,
Assemblyman Choi Seong Do won by a landslide in his election,
and won an important Assembly seat.
Due to this incident, the district
of Assemblyman Choi Seong Do
is forced to hold an
election for a replacement.
What oldest presider...
Experience, something that
can't be underestimated.
The first time is awkward. The second
time easier. The third effortless.
I didn't know you'd wrap it up so neatly.
You'll be nominated soon. A
lot of people are watching.
So, stay put and prepare for the election.
If I am to prepare for the election,
shouldn't I have something so I can prepare?
Money, gold nuggets. You took everything.
Except for what you digested, give back
your cud. I'm asking you to regurgitate it.
That way I can get ready
for the election also.
Are you really not afraid of anything?
You and I are now on the same side.
Whether we both live or we both die.
It's one of the two.
If possible I'd like us
to both live together.
For a long time.
Bring me original of the
classified document first.
I'll give it up to you then.
I'll think about it after
I put on my badge.
If I give it to you before
then, you'll chew me up.
Why do I need to fill your stomach?
You're filled up to your
throat for eating so much.
Isn't that so?
You do only what you're told. I'll
be the one to make the decisions.
Think about it just once.
I have a request.
Make sure that the Noodle Master
doesn't do anything else bad.
Where is you head?
I'm sorry.
Secretary Park, do you have
any desire to study more?
Pardon?
Evening college or cyber university.
Places you can study while you work.
After the election, I'll make you an aide.
Prepare in advance.
Do you hear what I'm saying?
I heard you.
Boss.
They're ordering us to forget everything.
I've been issued temporary standby.
As soon as the new prosecutor
is assigned, I'll be let go.
This is how messy things get when a criminal
case gets tangled in political matters.
I'm sorry, it's all because of me.
Yes. It's all because of you.
I worked my butt off to
get to this position.
All because of you, I'm gone in a blow.
So, destroy the Noodle Master.
Pardon?
When you're feeling out the
card is at it's most dangerous.
Do you watch soccer?
To not get ejected from the game, the player
begs before the umpire pulls out the card.
But as soon as he gets a red card, he
leaves the field foaming at the mouth.
Why?!
What's there to fear when
you're ejected from the game?
That's how I'm right now.
Take care of it quickly!
You have until the new Special
Investigative Team lead prosecutor comes.
Thank you.
I'm closer to corruption than justice.
Personal vendetta is more important
to me than public order.
No need to thank me.
Then, why exactly...
Try having your face shoved
into a bowl of mixed noodles.
You'll understand my feelings.
How does working here feel like?
I got fired after being a noodle master
for three years. Why hang it up there?
But still, you've brought the
Goong Rak Won thus far...
I don't want to leave any trace
of myself at Goong Rak Won.
Take it down.
Yes.
- Right now.
- Noodle Master.
Take it down.
I... I'll do it.
I... I'm taller than him.
Your name?
Gil Yong, right?
Yes, dishwasher Go Gil Yong.
Take it down and take it
to my living quarters.
Yes, I understand.
I can't really live.
I thought it would hang for at least 30
years. Why is he taking it down already?
You surprised me!
What is this?
It's nothing, so leave it.
Who did you receive it from?
You don't have to know. Give it to me.
Yeo Gyeong, right?
Yes.
I'll keep it. It can't
be left alone like this.
I didn't just leave it.
I pulled my hair out to find the
safest place in Goong Rak Won.
And I promised Yeo Gyeong
that I'll protect it, no matter what.
I can keep it better.
Why would I believe you?
You're on the side of Noodle Master.
What if you take it to him?
Go Gil Yong.
I don't know what this is and I
don't even want to know about it,
but this is really important to Yeo Gyeong.
I know I must protect it no matter what.
- So you back off. -Listen
carefully, Go Gil Yong.
It's dangerous for the person who has it.
The person who has it may even die.
No! The person will die.
If you have it, then you will die. If
Yeo Gyeong has it, then she will die.
But what if you have it?
Prosecutor Chae.
Of course, I kept it safely.
Right now?
Okay.
Yeo Gyeong wants everyone to get together.
Everything.
Assemblyman Choi committed suicitde?
That can't never happen. A
cockroach never kills itself.
Kim Gil Do is involved in this for sure.
No, perhaps So Tae Seop and Kim Gil Do?
Kim Gil Do is the one who ordered
Tae Ha's father to commit murder.
I can threaten Kim Gil Do with
that classified document.
If it gets to Assemblyman So Tae
Seop, I no longer need Kim Gil Do.
Instead, we lose a way to cut
off Assemblyman So Tae Seop.
If Assemblyman So Tae Seop obtains the classified document,
he'll try to get rid of the evidence first and foremost.
You're included in that, Yeo Gyeong.
I... Thankfully, I'm still a prosecutor.
He can't mess with me rashly.
I'll try to negotiate.
It's dangerous, Yeo Gyeong.
Let's summarize.
We'll finish making a deal with
Assemblyman So before Myeong's program.
Then we arrest him right
away after the program.
And make him die of old
age sitting in jail.
OK, let's do that then.
We all fought the same enemy separately.
Out of care for each other and to
prevent each other from worrying...
We fought on the inside
and outside separately.
Let's not do that anymore.
Do you want to eat noodles?
This is too much.
They're treating you like
an old man in the corner.
What's the matter?
Since you have your nomination,
you should really get started.
My office and campaign staff...
you take care of it all.
That's not even an issue.
Why don't we do a live show?
It's unfortunate to waste the last broadcasting
opportunity right before your election.
Gather a panel of judges and
have viewer participation.
I think we can make a big deal if
we do our first live cooking show.
I quit being the Noodle Master.
It seems too transparent.
Do you want to know how to
become a good politician?
You have to be a good pretender.
Pretend to be just, on
the side of the weak...
Pretend to be genuine...
You're a born poser, so I'll
just provide the forum.
Play a bit and don't miss
out on a good opportunity.
Proceed with it.
He took the bait.
The live show will happen.
Yes. Good work.
Assemblyman So Tae Seop
Prosecutor Chae, what
brings you to call me?
You want to meet me?
Is there a reason for us to meet?
There are misunderstandings we need to hash
out and I also want to show you something.
You still have something to interest me?
K120-17. How about it?
You said you couldn't find it.
Why is it in your hands?
Did you deceive me?
Isn't it important that I have it now?
See me. Come to my office.
Long time no see.
Long time no see indeed, but
I must be the only one
happy to see you all.
Why did you call the meeting?
As you know, I'll be entering an election.
I'll start getting busy and I won't be
able to pay attention to Goong Rak Won.
I thought it would be better if I passed on my shares.
That's why I called for this difficult meeting.
Just keep it. Why are you causing trouble?
He wants to erase everything that's connected to
Goong Rak Won only until the election is over.
Erase? Goong Rak Won is where my roots are.
We'll see about that. We should see what happens to Goong
Rak Won after you let go of your rights in Goong Rak Won.
Don't be afraid. I won't eat you up.
He's exercising his rights.
We can't stop him.
Let's hear who you'll
transfer your shares to.
Madam Seol, please lead Goong
Rak Won in the right direction.
How unexpected.
But why all of a sudden to me...
Who else can I trust besides
you among people present here?
You have 40% shares. So, if the Prime
Noodle Chef wavers, please keep him steady.
Until I come back.
Why wait? I'll tell you my opinion now.
I cannot accept you as the
Noodle Master successor.
There's a rumor that you have a
problem with your sense of taste.
Nonsense! Don't even say what's not true.
If he can't taste, how could he make the palace
pheasant buckwheat noodles exactly the same way?
There's no need to get upset. He just
has to prove that there's no problem.
I heard the upcoming show is a live one?
That's right.
Let's make the palace pheasant
buckwheat noodles on the show.
Without any editing or fooling the eyes, prove
your skills. Then, I'll believe you as well.
Fine.
But if I prove myself, please agree
on my becoming the Noodle Master.
Of course.
And the original?
I'll give you the original as soon
as the nomination is completed.
Look at these guys. They're
trying to play me.
Come in.
Aren't you the Noodle Master's bastard?
I'm Secretary Park Tae Ha.
So, what brings you here?
What is it?
It's the classified document you're
looking for. Is this the one?
It's the original. Why did you bring
it to me instead of the Noodle Master?
What the hell are you doing, you a**hole!
The Noodle Master didn't send me here.
It's in my hands and it will
stay with me from now on.
Don't even try to take it away from me.
If you try, I'll reveal it to the media.
You're asking me to kill you.
You know that?
I don't know about politics.
So, threats and conciliation
won't work on me.
I'll say what I have to say before I go.
You be the judge.
Let me hear you.
Do whatever Prosecutor
Chae wants you to do.
If you do that, this classified
document will be yours.
What's your relationship
with Prosecutor Chae?
I can't answer any of your questions.
Just keep your end of the bargain
about what I've requested of you.
Then, I'll wrap up the deal cleanly.
Such a young kid wants
to make a deal with me?
The deal works... if what I have can
either kill you or keep you alive.
Do you need anything else?
Right, that's right. But...
only death awaits you. This isn't a
deal, but an act of desperation.
Asyou die, you'll remember my words.
There will be someone I'll remember
when I die. But it won't be you.
Never mind.
Would you lie over something if
you'll get caught right away?
What is it you want?
I have a witness I can
nail Kim Gil Do with.
In order for that witness to testify,
I need your help, Assemblyman.
Are you listening to me?
You guys are clueless as to what kind of
world you're living in. Completely clueless.
But do you know what's so funny?
I'm afraid of you guys who are
so clueless about the world.
Did you say, "you guys?"
Catch Kim Gil Do.
This is your last chance.
Go ahead.
Alright then.
What happened? How about Yeo Gyeong?
Did you cause trouble?
I took care of it. Nothing
will happen to Yeo Gyeong.
Are you sure? I can trust you, right?
Trust me. You just have to keep
it a secret from Yeo Gyeong.
Okay.
What are you doing here?
Do you have time right now?
Well? I'm off work and...
I'll wait for you in the parking lot.
Look! I said "Well?" Don't you get that?
It means it's closer to a "No!"
All you will experience is death
As you die you will remember what I said.
Please get in.
Do I pay your salary?
Forget it but
Why are you here?
It's up to the driver.
Are you not eating?
I'll believe that you've
never dated anyone.
What do dumplings have
anything to do with dating?
Let's not even talk about it.
It does taste good.
Recently,
I ate dumplings with the Noodle Master.
That was the day I saw you at the ossuary.
I realized then
that you are his daughter.
Let's not talk about this.
My father is a murderer.
He killed 2 people.
And he was executed.
I wanted to run away from
the dirty blood of a
murderer's son and so I ran.
So, this is where I arrived.
I don't want to run away anymore.
You shouldn't run away either.
Regardless of what kind of person
you father is or his actions.
It's not your fault.
Just endure it from your position.
I wanted to tell you this.
But what if I run away?
You hold on to me.
I've already marked you.
Do you know what you smell like?
Sweat, the scent of automobiles and
the scent of dumplings.
I'm sorry.
But do you know what all the
scents combined result?
Your scent.
You've never dated anyone.
That's true.
I've been kissed twice.
You may not remember since you were drunk.
You were the first.
Goodnight.
There won't be too many people.
- Please edit it.
- Edit?
This is, you know...
Dae Ha.
That outfit looks good on you.
Thank you.
But what brings you here?
How do you feel?
Your senses?
Nothing yet.
But it's getting better slowly.
I can help you during the live show.
Salty, spicy, and sour.
I can give you signals.
I can signal to you with my fingers
like 1 finger equals one spoon.
Something like this.
You don't need to do that.
I can do it by myself.
But
Thank you for your concern.
But today I can't receive
anyone's assistance.
I must endure whatever happens.
The make-up artist didn't show up?
I'm stuck in a corner so
they couldn't find me.
Give it to me. I'll do it for you.
Is it possible that you're feeling nervous?
You've been on the show a dozen times.
This is the first time on a live show.
Just be comfortable.
You can look at your past as a noodle
maker and talk about your future plans.
You can't lose that opportunity.
That's why I'm doing this show.
I won't lose my opportunity.
Do whatever Prosecutor
Chae wants you to do.
If you do that, this classified
document will be yours.
Assemblyman, it's me.
This person. Am I the only busy one?
I have a request that's why I'm calling.
Can you help me out?
I'll consider that I owe you a big debt.
You need to hear me out.
At this point you need to
recognize this person's ability.
When you grill someone you
get something like this.
Warrant for urgent arrest and order to
drop the case against Hwang Seong Rok.
This was decided by the
Secretary General at the least.
So Tae Seop will have to acknowledge this.
This is the last. Both for
myself and the Noodle Master.
Detective Kim, let's go.
Yes, Prosecutor.
Should I go with you?
Did you see the Cue Sheet?
After about 20 minutes of talking,
we'll get into the noodle competition.
During the 20 minutes 3 different noodles.
The dough is done, right?
I've finished the aging process as well.
Good.
Let's do our best.
Have an audience member with
a red shirt ask a question.
There won't be any problems, right?
Promise me.
What?
That you won't run away.
I'll keep the promise.
Alright, we'll start.
Cue!
They must've started, right?
Just now. It'll take about
10 minutes to get there.
Step on it.
Noodle Master's, "Steal, change..."
"and imitate." It's become a trademark.
I had no idea you had such a story.
Now, why don't we take a
question from the audience?
What you'd like to find out from the
masters of traditional noodles...
I'm very curious myself. Now...
Yes, the audience member wearing
the red top on the left side.
- No...
- Can you give him the microphone?
Don't.
Question please.
I have a question for
Noodle Master Ha Jung Tae.
Yes, I'm listening.
How does it feel to kill a human being?
Hey, take away the mic!
You killed people.
You even ordered murder.
I want to hear how you felt at the time.
What's he saying? Kill someone?
I need guys to order a job.
Not thugs. Right.
Find a few people who can take
care of business cleanly.
Genetics Test Center: This is evidence that proves client 1 (Ha
Jung Tae) & client 2 (Kim Da Hae) are biologically related.
Ha Jung Tae...
Yes, there was a small
commotion for a moment there.
You have too many enemies.
How could we work like that?
Why don't we change the mood at this point?
Chef Moo Myeong... why don't we hear about
the time you first learned to make noodles?
I learned how to make
noodles from my father.
He devoted his entire
life to making noodles.
He perfected the palace pheasant buckwheat
noodles with his blood and sweat.
But his trusted friend stole
it from him and killed him.
W... wait...
The person who perfected the palace pheasant buckwheat
noodles for the first time... is Noodle Master Ha Jung Tae.
Is that so?
Why don't you stop? This
won't change anything.
No, it will change.
At the least, the world will know
whether you're a man or animal.
Noodle Master Ha Jung Tae murdered
Noodle Chef Moo Myeong's father and...
stole the recipe to the palace
pheasant buckwheat noodles?
He also killed my mother.
And he even stole my father's name.
The name he's using, Ha Jung
Tae, belongs to my father.
Don't run away.
If you run away now, you'll have to
run away for the rest of your life.
Kim Gil Do... Looking for a robbery
murder suspect in Seongbukdong.
Is that animal's real name.
What's going on here?
Gangnam San 323-37.
The current Noodle Master's office
is where Kim Gil Do was born.
Gangwondo Bongpyeong Yupori 802-2.
It's my birthplace and also the spot
where Kim Gil Do killed my father...
Noodle Master... Noodle Master!
And my mother. As if that wasn't enough...
he stole my father's name and
his life entirely there.
What went wrong?
Where... did it go wrong?
Why is he doing that to me?
All I did was struggle to survive.
Why exactly?
Warrant for exigent arrest
Choi Soon Seok... Choi Soon Seok!
Choi Soon Seok!
You guys...
Stay calm.
If I were you, I'd enjoy the
scenery rather than doing that.
When we arrive, you'll never
see the outside world again.
There's something I'm curious
about, Prosecutor Chae.
I'll accept questions at
the Prosecutors' Office.
You know how you bind people
when you arrest them?
Shut up, Kim Gil Do.
But why...
do you leave the head to move freely?
No...
This after, breaking the Foreign
Exchange Law and tax laws...
murders, ordering murders, and numerous
other charges have been pressed
against Ha Jung Tae of Goong Rak Won. While he was being
transported to the Supreme Prosecutors' Office, he escaped.
At the live show taping of Goong Rak
Won at 4 p.m., he was arrested.
How is Yeo Gyeong?
Her injury isn't bad.
What will do you now?
He'll come to me. I'll have to see the end.
You got what you wanted.
You revealed his true face and he's completely
finished. There's no need for you to fight him again.
Tae Ha... I want to see it.
Kim Gil Do's facial expression
knowing he lost everything.
I'll see his fall clearly.
That's the end of my revenge.
Do what you have to do.
I'll do what I have to do.
And Yeo Gyeong... protect her from now on.
What... do you mean?
I'm putting her on you now. I've
repaid all the debt I owe her.
Da Hae
Blocked Number
Bring me the classified document.
Then I'll let Da Hae live.
You must come alone.
Noodle Master Ha Jung Tae?
No, I should call you Kim Gil Do now.
Where are you hiding?
Let's make a deal. I'll give you the
classified document right away.
Please clean up this situation.
Where is the classified document? How
can you give me what you don't have?
Did you know?
The whole world knows. You're
the only one who doesn't know.
There must be another way.
There has to be a way to
turn everything back.
Listen carefully. I'll let you know
how to resolve this situation.
Your daughter Da Hae...
I have her right now.
Don't lie. I just talked to her.
Really? She's gagged. What a talent.
Let Da Hae go. She has
nothing to do with this.
She's your daughter. How could she
have nothing to do with this?
Let her go!
We're exchanging your daughter
for your life. It's simple.
There's a storage space in Incheon. I'll
give you the address. Hurry up and go there.
You die and let your daughter live.
Isn't that a fair trade?
This is very fun. Whether the father will
come to save her or Secretary Park...
Look at this guy. He's got guts.
Bring me the classified document.
I don't have it with me right now.
I'll check Da Hae's safety and
will let you know where it is.
How can I trust you?
I came here alone.
Must I prove more?
Hello?
Are you okay?
Tae Ha?
Where are you right now?
You're okay, right, Tae Ha?
You're okay, right?
It's nothing. You'll be fine.
Everything will be fine.
- Da Hae.
- Speak. I'm listening.
Next time, let's go somewhere
nice and eat something delicious.
I've been feeling bad about that.
Why do you say such a thing
all of a sudden? I had fun.
So, don't say strange things.
I have a request.
My scent... please remember it.
Listen to me carefully.
I don't know what you're about to do.
But don't do it.
No, never.
If you hang up my phone right now,
I'll hate you for the rest of my life.
Are you listening? I said I'll
hate you for the rest of my life!
Tae Ha, what have you been up to all day?
Go to Da Hae. Right now.
What's going on? Did
something happen to Da Hae?
Go and protect her.
Tae Ha! Tae Ha!
End it here.
Master: God of Noodles
To destroy Kim Gil Do, my friend died.
Don't drag in innocent
people into your revenge.
My friends came into
this hell because of me.
You have two choices.
How about dismissal?
Prosecutor Chae Yeo Gyeong wants
to meet you, Assemblyman.
Kim Gil Do will show up for sure.
Whoever dies, we'll have
to see the end to it then.