(Episode 26)
His Majesty just left
for Mount Dora.
Are you saying
he went hunting again?
Yes.
In that case,
bring me the key to Naebanggo.
Since he is away,
I will take care of it.
Well, it looks like
he took the key with him.
I asked the man who keeps the key,
and he said he never got it back
after he gave it to him yesterday.
I will go to the hunting ground.
I will get that key
no matter what.
Do not go.
I am sure that woman is with him.
You do not need to see that.
The soldiers will be shaken.
Do not worry.
I am looking for another way around.
What is that?
Eun San had it on her.
She must have wished to
use that to bargain for...
her father's release
for hiding her identity.
Is this a list of
her father's assets?
- Crown Prince.
- It seems like...
- we can borrow some supplies.
- Your bride.
She needs my final approval.
Even if you choose whom you want,
you cannot marry her
if I do not approve.
What are you thinking?
Your bride's background
and character are all important,
but more than anything,
we must consider how
she can be of assistance to you.
I will not harm your reputation.
We just need to find...
one very small flaw.
She is here.
Your Highness, I am Eun San.
My master sent me
to help in any way I can.
Master Lin, we meet again.
My master recommends these people.
They are well-learned...
but were ignored because
they lacked connections.
They can help if placed in
relevant offices.
Why are you dressed like that?
Are those your master's clothes?
He also said you should guard...
the warehouses in which
you store your men's wages.
That is too late.
If it is too late for that,
he said to give you this.
- What is it?
- 1,000 sacks of grain and...
200 blocks of silver.
This is what?
Grain we received as rent
from our fields in Gimje...
and stalls in Namdaega...
Forget it.
- My father sent...
- I am the Crown Prince.
- I may be in need, but...
- Your Highness.
What?
You need to accept that.
I have a request.
Okay. I will grant it.
I have not yet told you what it is.
Tell me, and I will grant it.
You said you would find
who killed my mother.
I did.
Take that back.
I should not find him?
Yes.
You are asking me...
not to do something.
Yes.
You will give up?
Why are you interrupting?
You forgot everything else
to chase the tattooed man.
Can you give up?
It is my father's plea.
Very well. I will not find him.
Lin, keep quiet.
I just granted her wish.
- How are you?
- You are so pretty.
You have not visited
in such a long time.
I came to see you.
I missed you so much.
I know, I know.
I am here now.
I knew it.
Why are you here?
I followed you.
Since when?
- Come with me.
- Where to?
There is someone you must meet.
- Who is it?
- Will you just...
Come with me.
Just when...
I am about to forget
about it, you ask me again.
And then again.
Tell this lady...
exactly what you told me.
Why must I...
when I am not at all
proud of what I did?
Exactly.
Immediately.
Yeom Bok, you tell it this time.
No, I do not want to.
Whenever I talk about that,
I have bad dreams for days.
I see the people who died.
Are you a psychic
to see dead people?
- I should just...
- Were you both at Sungjukjae?
That day,
we were there with the bandits.
We were not bandits ourselves.
It is quite interesting.
You are...
the young child who was
there that day, right?
- Did you see me?
- Yes.
There were two young girls.
Right, Yeom Bok?
- I do not know.
- That day,
a man in black flew around...
killing all the bodyguards.
He looked like
a sword-wielding devil.
What else did you see?
One of the girls got hurt.
And then...
Those men came.
My older brother.
This master's brother was shocked...
when he saw the girl was hurt,
and he ran over.
And that girl was you?
- You left something out.
- Left out?
What is that?
My lady.
I know that face.
The Chancellor's second son.
There was...
nothing else.
That is not what you said before.
Before?
What did I say?
The assassin and my brother...
recognized each other.
They made eye contact.
They did not.
- What?
- You must have misheard me.
I never said that.
Tell the truth.
You tried to hit me then too.
You screamed.
That is why I just said
whatever came to my mind first.
Am I not right, Yeom Bok?
I did as you said.
They are great liars.
Master Lin fell for it.
Well done.
The salt merchant.
Jin Gwan went to
tell him what to say.
Will Master Lin go to him as well?
He will.
He is stubborn and
will do all he can.
- Why...
- What?
Why are you doing this?
I do not understand.
Me neither.
I do not understand myself.
His Highness apprehended
someone else.
A salt merchant.
He worked as Song In's messenger.
The Crown Prince...
made him a double agent.
Come with me.
That is him.
He said Song In
and my brother met often.
And...
he saw a man with a snake tattoo.
I will bring him over.
Ask him whatever you want.
What are you doing?
Helping you.
I am looking for the man who...
killed my mother eight years ago.
I know.
Do you know...
why I refused
the Crown Prince's help?
Why did you?
The men I am after...
are connected to your brother.
You could get involved.
Are you concerned for me?
They are cunning.
They even deceived the King.
And you will...
take them on alone?
I have a plan.
What is it?
You need not know.
This is a private matter,
so let me take care of it.
You must know...
why they did it.
You cannot give up.
I must know...
and end it...
to start over.
Only then...
can I stop feeling guilty...
and enjoy good food
and good company.
And get on with my life.
They stayed together all night?
Whom did they meet
and what did they discuss about?
I could not get
close enough to hear.
They are both competent fighters.
The Chancellor's third son...
and Lord Eun's daughter.
And...
Now, I get it.
The Crown Prince's weakness.
I shall see what I can do.
Try to keep this from the soldiers.
Wang Lin was always at his side.
The Crown Prince's
most trustworthy companion.
To separate him
from the Crown Prince...
That should be fun.
Even more so than discussing
Goryeo's future with some fools.
I am glad to meet you.
I will be asking you
for a lot of things.
They were so close that
I never dared to split them apart.
Now, I see a way how.
How dare you hold a blade to her?
I had always known the Crown Prince
had feelings for her, but...
Master Lin too?
What will you do about Master Jeon?
Right.
Wang Jeon.
He gets more anxious each day.
He visits every day
to ask for a plan.
What should I do?
Leave the older
and take the younger?
Which will make...
a king who will serve me better?
Master Lin is very loyal.
Will he side with you?
When he has
no one else to turn to,
he will have to.
You told me to...
find out if the Chancellor's
family had any flaws.
The Crown Prince's bride's family...
can have no flaws
that can become weaknesses.
I heard of a strange rumor.
A rumor is not enough.
What if there is
a witness and evidence?
Will you hear it?
I always knew you were talented.
Thank you, Your Highness.
What about Kim Do Kyung?
He received land every 2 or 3 years.
I saw the tax records somewhere.
Third book on the pile to your left.
Do you remember all this?
Ink.
What?
The ink is dripping.
- My goodness.
- Oh no.
- Wipe it.
Okay.
I am not usually like this.
I did not sleep much last night.
We shall say so.
Where are you going?
When a lady leaves on her own,
do not ask where she is going.
Where are you going?
Just... Outside.
If you are going home,
I shall walk you.
I am not going home.
We are not done yet.
Are you sure?
I want to get some air.
I have a headache.
We shall go. I will walk you out.
No, thanks. I will be fine.
You will not be.
Lin, come here.
Do you know what she did last night?
She went alone...
The lady needs to be alone.
She went to Song In's home.
What if she met
the man with the tattoo?
I fought him once,
and he was a better fighter.
She has a temper.
- If she were to see him...
- I sent a bodyguard after her.
I will protect her.
I overstepped my boundaries.
The Queen sent me.
For what?
To get Master Lin.
You are to come alone.
Is it to Wonseongjeon?
To the interrogation hall.
I am here at your service.
Repeat what you said earlier.
Word for word.
Eight years ago,
I led a group of ruffians.
One day, someone came to us.
They told me to try robbing someone.
Will you come with us?
They said the more, the better.
- Where are you going?
- To rob someone.
Why do you need a whole army
to rob someone?
We are going to rob
Eun Young Baek's merchants.
They wanted to rob
the Minister of Finance's merchants.
So I gathered about 20 men.
I gathered them myself.
They trusted me when they got
into this, but all of them died.
I almost died myself.
I barely made it alive.
I mean, if you can
really call this living.
They blamed the murder on us.
They wanted to make it look like
robbers came to get their things.
They only used us.
Did you say you saw the one
who ordered this to happen?
I did.
Is this his?
He said he would pay us
after the work was done,
so I asked him for a security.
He took that off of his belt
and gave it to me.
Lin.
Yes, Your Highness.
Do you recognize this?
It looks like the butterfly symbol
of your family.
- What do you think?
- They were going to kill us all.
And they killed
every single one of us.
They even killed those who tried
to escape after they were hit.
They cut down our men
over and over again.
Lin.
This is...
our family's symbol.
Master Lin is held down
at the interrogation hall.
- The interrogation hall?
- The Queen ordered men...
to send soldiers
to the Chancellor's house.
- What are you talking about?
- It is because of Sungjukjae...
Yong Je.
Where is So Hwa?
I do not see her around.
She went after Master Lin.
Father, did you want me?
Where is he?
Goodness, I am so tired.
So Hwa.
I found the man
who killed my mother.
He is Lin's brother.
Everything will be over
once I kill him.
No.
That is the only way I can end this.
So Hwa.
No, that will hurt you.
Do not do that.
San.
(The King in Love)
Let us forget about everything...
and pretend like nothing happened.
Can you not do that?
He deceived me.
So I do not think I can do that.
I cannot pretend
like nothing happened.
You do know that...
Lin loves you, right?
Please forgive him.
I saw the way she looked at Lin.
And I saw the way Lin looked at her.
There is no way Lin would like
someone whom I like.
Do not be sick.
Have a safe trip.