[narrator]
previously on dark matter.
[six]
it's a nasty gash.
[wexler]
you know it's really too bad,
We could of had
some real fun together
[three] she got blown
out the air lock.
She held on,
waiting to die and she didn't.
What the hell is she?
Think you could survive
a bullet between the eyes?
[gunshots]
[six]
whatever this thing is,
3 corporations were
willing to kill for it.
What the hell was that?
The field's become unstable.
Shut it down.
[heavy breathing]
[six]
what the hell is this?
[three]
kid's a stowaway.
I was just trying to scare her.
I wasn't gonna
space her, i swear.
[five panting]
[three] at least let's
get something for her.
[six]
shut up, boone.
Look guys, she's an asset.
She's got a head for
mechanics and tech.
[two]
i don't give a shit.
I don't want her on this ship.
[one]
why the hell not?
[two]
she's a child.
[one]
griff's right.
We should keep her.
It's even up.
Your call, ryo.
Welcome aboard, little warrior.
Just don't give me any cause
to regret my decision.
♪
[android]
two, i've completed my analysis
Of all available sensor data
pertaining to the explosion.
Would you like to hear it?
[two]
maybe just the short version.
[android]
it was the temporary manifestatn
Of what's known in layman's
terms as a white hole.
[two]
let me guess.
The opposite of a black hole?
[android]
precisely.
It's an area of space-time
which cannot be entered
From the outside,
but which is capable
Of emitting vast quantities
of matter and energy.
[two] is there any chance it was
a coincidence that it manifested
Five minutes after we
delivered that device?
[android]
it would be highly unlikely.
Research into white hole
technology was banned
By the galactic authority
several years ago
Because of its potential to
de-stabilize the current balance
Of power between
the major corporations.
[two] how many people
were on that planet?
[android] the world was
otherwise uninhabited,
So the death toll was limited
to those on the research facili.
Are you sure you
want the number?
[two]
how many?
[android]
a little over 15,000.
♪
[news anchor] galactic authorits
continue their investigation int
They've classified as
an extinction level event
On a hab-1 world under
the directorship of the mikkei.
Satellite imagery captured
the planet's final moments...
The incident, which claimed
the lives of all on-site person,
Is believed to have been
triggered by illegal research
Into what has been termed
a "doomsday weapon"
Linked to white hole technology.
Representatives of
the mikkei combine offered conds
To all those affected
but have otherwise refused
Comment pending completion
of the official inquiry.
Is that it?
This was the most
relevant of several reports.
No mention anywhere
of our involvement?
None.
Guys, we're in the clear.
[one] just because we're
not in the official news
Doesn't mean we're in the clear.
All i'm saying is
it could be worse.
Mikkei could've
hung us out to dry,
But they didn't, why?
Probably because they
think that we got played
Just like they did.
We're not nearly as screwed
as we thought we were.
[android] i'm receiving a coded
subspace transmission.
It's from calchek.
Patch him through.
What do you want?
Oh, you... you are all so screwed.
[one] and by "screwed" you mean.
[calchek] certain parties
within the mikkei combine
Think you set them up.
[one]
we set them up?
They came to us with that job!
[calchek] which is why
it's always important
To go through proper channels.
[one] yeah, really sorry you dit
earn your commission on that on.
[calchek] it's a small
price to pay for peace of mind.
Okay, let me run
this scenario by you.
Traugott's been doing
r&d on a white hole bomb.
They've got a prototype
but they can't test it
Without getting
the g.A.S onto their backs.
So what do they do?
They float word around about it,
back-channel whispers,
And guess who takes the bait?
Mikkei.
They hired us to steal it.
We do, deliver it, and once
it's safely into their hands,
Traugott triggers the device
And mikkei gets to take the fal.
Does that sound about right?
Huh, sounds about exactly right.
Of course there's the question f
Whether you were
playing both sides.
[three sighs]
come on.
[one] everyone knows
we've been untouchable
Since our fallout with ferrous.
[calchek]
well, things change.
See, ferrous corp reached out te
To reach out to you about a job.
Why us?
[calchek] because they
know you're the best.
And also because you have
burned so many bridges
That you are out of options.
You either take this job and
make nice with ferrous corp,
Which, by the way,
would be a very smart move
While we wait for this
mikkei situation to shake out,
Or you are really on your own.
Look, this time around you
don't have to steal anything.
In fact, you'll be
saving someone,
Its a nice change of pace.
[one]
who?
[calchek] a ferrous corp scientt
was kidnapped about a month ago
By a rival combine.
He's being held in a lab
on some backwater planet.
Very little in
the way of security.
So it's a simple
snatch and grab.
You're in. You're out.
It's a piece of cake.
[three]
i hate cake.
[one]
so we get into ferrous' good bos
By getting in this other
rival corp's bad books?
[calchek] yes, you want
ferrous corp to be your friend.
[two]
we'll do it.
[three]
what?
[one]
shouldn't we talk about this?
[two]
no. We'll do it.
[calchek] excellent. I will
send you the coordinates and,
Uh good to be back
in business with you.
Are you sure?
The only thing i'm sure
about right now is that
We need all
the friends we can get.
We're taking this job.
♪
[the raza powering up]
[four]
what're you doing?
[five bangs head]
ow.
Are you looking for something?
Yeah.
I just uh, dropped
my um... Nebulizer.
All right.
Well, good luck finding that.
Oh, hey.
Thanks.
For what?
Everything?
[four chuckles]
♪
[one] looking to do
some crowd control?
[two sighs]
I'm just going over
inventory from the boxes
That five managed to crack.
Busy night for her.
These uh, these were
a little bit trickier
So we'll probably have to
break into them at some point.
[one]
you okay?
I've had a lot on my mind.
Let's hear about it.
You saw the scans.
Yeah, and they said
you're flesh and blood...
Artificially constructed.
Like one of those
transfer transit clones.
Those only last a few days,
They're not
sustainable organisms.
And they don't have
minds of their own.
Do i?
I mean, i have thoughts, and em-
Anger, sadness, happiness...
But i'm starting to wonder...
How real are they?
Having been on
the receiving end of that anger,
I can confirm it's pretty real.
If every part of me was
designed and manufactured,
Including my brain, then
are my thoughts my own,
Or are they just what
somebody else wants me to think?
And if so,
who is that somebody else?
Who constructed me,
and for what purpose?
I'm sorry, i can't pretend to
understand what you're going th.
But i can tell you this...
It doesn't change
how i feel about you.
I just need to
process all of this.
Sure.
If you uh... Feel like talking..
Come find me.
[door beeps open]
[door beeps closed]
♪
[door opens]
[marauder powering up]
[six] alright raza,
we're on route.
♪
[three] let's go
bag us a scientist.
♪
[door lock beeps]
[one]
all right.
If i was a kidnapped scientist,
where would i be?
[doors opening]
[three]
what the...?
Like i said: I hate cake.
Welcome back, rebecca.
What the hell are...
[high-pitched sound]
[two grimaces]
[one] what the hell
did you do to her?
[man] i merely
rendered her unconscious.
I have no intention
of hurting her.
Now, put your weapons away.
[three]
like hell.
I will not hurt her,
But i have no problem
hurting either of you...
Or your friends
back on the shuttle.
Your progress was monitored
from ship to surface.
We've been expecting you.
[one]
tabor set us up.
[three]
that little prick.
[man] now, if you will kindly
lay down your weapons,
We have much to discuss.
♪
[four]
anger is counter-productive.
It's a natural response,
but after a certain point,
It becomes toxic.
[six] i assume
you're talking about me?
No, i was actually referring
to the passive-aggressive
Empty seat next to you.
You can resent us all you like
For our decision to
deliver the device,
But ultimately you're as much
at fault as the rest of us.
[six]
i tried to stop you.
[four]
did you?
[one]
marauder, do you read?
[six]
go ahead, ground team.
What's your status?
[one]
it's complicated.
[six]
care to elaborate?
[one] well, it looks like
we've been invited to dinner.
[six]
raza, this is the marauder.
Are you there?
[android]
yes.
Is everything alright?
[six]
negative.
It was a set-up.
The ground team has been taken
And we're told the facility
has a lock on our position.
If we attempt to fly out,
they'll take us out.
[android]
what should i do?
[six]
just sit tight for now.
We're gonna go join the others.
If you don't hear from us
inside the next 4 hours,
Get the hell out of here.
♪
[man]
i am so sorry that i'm late.
It's just been
one of those days.
I'm sure you can empathize.
[one]
where is she?
[man]
she is resting comfortably.
I meant what i said earlier.
I will never hurt her.
In fact, this is my small way
of thanking you
For keeping her safe
and returning her to me.
[three]
who the hell are you?
[rook]
my name is alexander rook.
I own a company called
dwarf star technologies
Along with all of its
subsidiaries, patents,
And prototypes,
including rebecca,
Although, i believe in your
company she is going by portia?
[six] i'm pretty sure
you can't lay legal claim
To the results
of banned research.
Last time i checked,
the creation of human facsimiles
Is against the law.
Oh and what would
you have me do?
Put one of those
ridiculous tattoos on her neck
As if she was some
common android?
[rook laughs]
No.
Although rebecca's biological
components are superior,
She must be constantly monitored
and maintained by her nanites.
Slow down the nanites,
slow down rebecca.
Is that what you did to her?
Yes.
I have blanketed this entire
facility in a dampening field.
At its present lowest setting,
it merely renders her harmless.
But at higher settings,
it will shut her down,
And ultimately destroy her.
We can't have her
escaping a second time.
You know, she was created
right here in this facility.
She has no memory of it
because her consciousness
Was inert at that point.
She was moved
to a more appropriate,
Secure facility
for her awakening.
[three] yeah,
how'd that work out?
Not particularly well
for the program,
Or for the 43 scientists
and security personnel
Who lost their lives
when she made her escape.
We believe that there is
a flaw in her neural network
That leaves her prone
to irrational behavior
And outbursts of
extreme violence.
Listen, you are very lucky.
It was only a matter of time
before she turned on you too.
[one]
so you say.
[rook smirks]
[rook] if i actually
considered any of you a threat,
You would already be dead.
Now, come! Eat!
♪
[five]
you left her?
[three]
didn't have a choice, kid.
[six]
prepare to jump.
[five]
you left her?!
[scientist]
they're gone.
[rook]
good.
Let's get to work.
♪
[android] i've dropped
us out in close proximity
To the system's a-type
main sequence star.
As long as we remain
within it's radiation shadow,
We'll be undetectable
by long-range scanners.
[one]
but it's safe, right?
[android]
absolutely not.
If you're going to come up
with a plan of action,
I suggest you do it quickly.
[rook]
hello, rebecca.
[two pants]
Who the hell are you
and what did you do to me?
And why do you keep
calling me rebecca?
Because that's your name.
And you are?
It's alex.
You-you really
don't remember me?
No, i don't.
Where's my crew?
They're gone.
What do you mean they're gone?
I mean they left.
They got in their shuttle,
flew back to their ship,
And they jumped.
No.
They wouldn't just leave me.
They didn't have a choice.
For the moment,
at least, neither do you.
Open this door.
Come, sit down.
Let's talk.
Open this door or
i'm going to come over there
And break you in half.
Your people-breaking days
are over, at least for now.
I'm sorry, but you
are no longer special.
And as long as this
dampening field is active,
You're less than normal.
I am so sorry, but i can't
have you running off again.
What the hell
are you talking about?
What is the last thing you
remember about your past?
Waking up out
of stasis on a ship.
That's it.
Those people you came with,
they did something to you.
No, those people are my friends,
And they'll be coming back for.
I don't think so.
But if they are stupid enough t,
We'll be ready for them.
[three] i say we just do what
we do best: We head down there,
We kill everyone,
and we bring her back.
[one] as much as i admire
your suicidal optimism,
There's no way of knowing
how many men or guns they have.
[three] fine. So we'll lob
a couple of orbital strikes
Their way first to soften 'em u.
[four] a ship to surface
bombardment would be inadvisable
Unless we knew exactly
where she was being held.
[six]
besides, they'd see us coming
And if they have
anti-satellite capabilities,
They'd tag us before we
even got off our first salvo.
[one] okay, how about
taking the marauder in?
It's smaller, easier
to avoid detection.
We can hit them with
a couple of precision strikes.
And then what?
And then land
and storm the place.
But at that point we've
lost the element of surprise.
[three sighs]
They'll cut us to pieces
before we get anywhere near tha,
If we made it that far.
The second we land, our shuttle
becomes a stationary target.
[android]
then don't land.
Come again?
[android] take the marauder,
but don't land.
There's another way
into that facility.
♪
[door ringing]
[five]
uh, hang on.
Come in.
[door opens]
[six]
hey.
Uh, just wanted you to know,
we're gonna go get her.
I knew you weren't serious
about leaving her behind.
The android's coming with us,
Which means someone has
to stay to monitor the ship.
You just don't want me there
Because you don't
think i'd be any use.
I don't want you there because
two wouldn't want you there.
The android is gonna enter
a program into the nav system.
If we're not back
inside of 4 hours,
It'll set an automatic course
for the nearest space station.
You'll be on your own.
This is unwise.
You're abandoning
your obligations to the ship.
I'm fulfilling my duties
to the members of its crew
By helping to
ensure their safety.
My actions will in no way
compromise this vessel.
They will indirectly,
if you don't return.
I have every
intention of doing so.
After careful consideration,
i've come to the conclusion
That the benefits
of retrieval outweigh the risks.
Two is integral to the security
of this ship and its crew.
She is system-proficient,
a capable leader,
And... She is my friend.
Friendship implies
a mutual affection.
You're not programmed to
form emotional attachments.
Furthermore, the assumption
that she would reciprocate...
The crew has demonstrated
a concern for my well-being,
Sometimes at the risk
of their own lives.
They engage me as an equal.
They are... Nice to me.
Humans have an innate tendency
to anthropomorphize.
The fact that you
possess human features
No doubt engenders
a subconscious confusion.
Might i remind you?
You are a machine.
A machine with friends.
♪
[two] back on the ship,
i knew i was different.
I just didn't know how.
Even after i found out,
It was just too
unbelievable to comprehend.
But now, seeing all of this i...
[rook] you should be
proud of what you are.
Your body can overcome any
abnormal biological pathogen.
You can regenerate.
You are faster and stronger.
You are superior in every way.
So my nanites can
cure me and protect me,
But they don't
prevent me from aging?
No.
In the long run,
that would raise suspicion,
And we just couldn't risk it.
Why not?
You are perfection.
You are a living reminder
of all of their failings.
And they will hate you for it.
If the authorities ever
found out about you,
They would use all their power
to hunt you down and kill you.
But you're safe now.
You are safe with me.
And i promise you, i will never
let anything happen to you.
Why was i created?
The answer to that question
Is part of a much
bigger conversation.
And one that we
will have... In due time.
♪
[six]
okay!
♪
[alarm ringing]
[rook]
what's happening?
[scientist] they came back,
they buzzed the facility
To test our perimeter defenses,
but they're gone now.
You think she made it?
Let's hope so, because she's
our only shot at pulling this o.
♪
[two] what are we looking for?
[scientist] a defect that
might explain a few things.
Such as?
Your aberrant behavior.
Have you found anything?
No.
Your results show your
brain functioning normally.
I expected your scans would
reveal psychopathic tendencies
In the cerebral cortex
related to empathy,
But it doesn't seem to be the c.
Well are you sure you're
getting the right readings?
I'm sorry, this,
it's moving all over the place.
Don't touch it!
I told alex you needed to be
restrained but he was insistent.
I can't hurt you anymore.
Of course not.
Then why do you have
a problem with me?
Were you working at
the facility when i escaped?
No, but many of my
former colleagues were.
I was to be involved in
phase three but we never got th.
You saw to that.
I'm sorry.
Are you?
Do you feel remorse?
According to your scan,
it's physiologically possible,
But i can't help
but have my doubts
Given the digital evidence
recorded at the scene.
Your actions were
quite calculated
And devoid of emotion.
I-i can't remember.
How fortunate for you.
I wish i could forget
the images i've seen.
You may have him fooled,
but i don't believe it for a se.
Your time will come,
and when it does,
I look forward to dissecting
your brain for a closer,
More intimate analysis.
♪
Okay, approaching the facility.
Running a scan.
And?
Nothing.
No unusual radiation signatures.
What's taking her so long?
It's not like she's just gonna
stroll in there and get it done.
She has to quietly
enter the facility
Without alerting anyone.
[bang]
♪
[grunting]
[glass shatters]
♪
[six] then, she has to trace
the dampening field to its sour.
Who knows how
it's laid out down there.
Could be a maze.
And there's no telling
where they're holding two.
♪
I told you she couldn't be trus.
Rebecca, you disappoint me agai.
♪
Let go of me!
I swear i'll kill you!
Every last one of you!
[door opens]
I tested you and you failed.
I'm sorry but we're
going to have to start over.
Maybe this is for the best.
We'll be able to do
a complete analysis and gain
A more full understanding
of where we went wrong,
So the next brain we give
you is free of imperfections.
Goodbye, rebecca.
Wait.
Wait! Wait!
I could grant you the mercy
of shutting you down
Before the surgery,
but i think this is a wonderfule
To test your pain receptors.
[buzz]
[six] okay, coming in
for another approach.
Running a scan.
Still nothing.
Come on!
How long does it take
to blow some shit up?!
It's not like it's
rocket science.
Maybe the field emitter was
harder to find then she thought.
[four] could it be possible
that it's affecting her as well?
♪
[saw buzzing]
No.
No!
Something's gone wrong.
We've got to get down there.
Can't.
We set this shuttle down
and we're a sitting target.
So set the shuttle
down out of range.
What?
You think you're going
to cover that distance on foot?
Well we've got to do something.
Come around for another pass.
[sighs]
♪
Your regenerative abilities
have been severely compromised.
[saw buzzing]
♪
[machine failing]
[grunts]
This is a great opportunity
to test your pain receptors.
[grunting]
Help me!
[panicked shrieks]
[buzzing]
[shouting]
♪
Hey!
[grunts]
[gunshots]
[android] the marauder
is awaiting my signal.
Would you like to help me
blow something up?
[rtwo would i!
[six] alright, coming up
on the facility.
Running another scan.
Okay, i've got an explosion...
Multiple explosions!
Whoa!
[five] i knew you'd be back!
[one] worried we
wouldn't make it in time?
Nah. I deleted the nav command
you guys entered, just in case.
And what if we hadn't come back?
Then i would've
programmed a new one.
[six] i didn't know you
knew how to program.
Neither did i.
[water running]
♪
[three]
come on, seriously!
[six laughs]
[three] you just send me
out there man, i am ready.
Once around the ship,
no problem.
[once] yeah, more like once
around and into the side of the.
[three]
hey, hey, hey, hey
[all laughing]
[six] trusting you
to fly that shuttle
Is like betting
on him in a fight.
[six laughs]
no offense!
[all laughing]
[four] he just needs
proper training.
[six]
are you offering?
[four] absolutely not,
i already have a student.
[five] he's gonna teach me
to kick all of your asses.
[three]
ooohhh.
[two]
hey.
Um, i wanted to thank
you guys, all of you.
You risked your lives to save
me and i really appreciate it.
Well, we just figured
that if we didn't,
And you somehow managed
to escape on your own,
You'd come back here,
you'd never let us hear the end.
Never, but you're probably righ.
[all laughing]
[six]
come, sit.
[six] pour that woman a drink.
[six] pour that woman
a drink, someone?
[two]
okay.
[one]
here you go.
[two]
thank you.
[six]
cheers, guys.
Cheers.
♪
[two old recording]
so.
[four old recording]
you were right.
[two old recording]
then we're agreed?
[four old recording]
yes.
[two old recording]
he has to die.
[four old recording]
when?
[two old recording] before
we get to the mining colony,
After we come out of stasis.
♪
[breathing machine beeping]
[mystery man]
where is she?
[rook]
she's gone.
She escaped.
She had help.
How old is this body?
It's 24.
You see what happens.
Would you like to be next?
That won't be necessary.
We've nearly completed
work on the new prototype.
And what are you going
to do about the other one?
We don't need her anymore.
Her continued
existence threatens ours.
You say she has friends
who assisted her?
Yes.
Do they know what she is?
Then they'll need to die too, a.
All of them.
Yes.
♪
[footsteps]
[door opens]
Hello.
[electrical shock]