tell me
whatever you want, I will do it
just say it
really
whatever you say I will do
three steps
step away from me three steps
we better keep a distance, you dont know?
maintain a distance?
if you're worried about the incident this morning ..
sorry, but I'm still afraid of you
so be careful
that's why I changed
after all I do not want to see you anymore
of course because I consider you an enemy
though now I also feel strange with all this
but this is a misunderstanding
so, what happened this morning ..
what happened this morning?
umm, that's not it
hard to tell, I still do not even believe it
so..
I want to tell you something even though I can not say it
hey! oh kyung hwi !!
oh..kyung..hwi ..
hey jang seul gi, what's up with you?
how can you do this to me? hah?!
You have to be strong, why do you even want to kill yourself ?!
What are you doing?
stop! stop it!
no, I dont want
kyung hwi let's go
let's show our relationship to everyone
I'm tired of keeping it hidden
I'm your real friend
oh kyung hwi
lets go together
if we are together, there is nothing to fear
the world is turning !!
What are you talking about? Are you crazy?
you two better go
no!!
never!
han na bi you have been misunderstand
Me and him..
you can be like that but after all this is still school
kyung hwi where are you going?
please stay with me
forgive me
let me go
hey han na bi!
kyung hwi please forgive me
God!
hey han na bi!
kyung hwi where are you going?
Don't touch me!
so the letter fell into your table
that's it
why do you have to write something very deep like this?
You stupid
when do I see this how I do not care?
we are friends
ah, you really make me annoyed
Are you kidding?
you know what happens if someone get panic
you will be fine
hey do you really want to die?
you just kidding, right?
never mind
do you know han na bi's previous school?
I do not know
do not bother her just because her is beautiful
I hear she is older than us
I heard her ex-boyfriend like an exo member
You believe that?
that's why you  like han na bi, right?
I know everything
if han na bi sided with us, we can not be defeated right?
You really have thought it very well
You really have not changed, seul gi
You do not know what's going on
oh yeah, you .. be careful with my sister
Why me? what's wrong with your sister?
cigarette
Sorry
how can there be no bottle of beer at home?
"just do it"
[lifestyle planning]
why is my life like this? hah
tomorrow I have to go see han na bi before go to school ..aigoo ..
hm? What is this?
how can be here?
Monday, 9 July ..
jin wook oppa change school today so I can not see him anymore
if I meet him again, I want to ask if he still has feelings for me
p.s oh kyung hwi is an idiot
I want to say that to the teacher
but I think if I say that to the teacher, still nothing will change so I'm better silent
Monday, 10 July ..
finally i meet again with jin wook oppa
but he's with his girlfriend
shit
if so, then his heart has changed
Wednesday, 11th july ..
I had a fight with my dad
he does not know anything
or rather, he does not know we're fighting
Thursday, 12th july ..
oh kyung hwi decides to commit suicide again
but, actually I envy with oh kyung hwi
at least, he has someone to argue
Friday, 13th july ..
today is a bad day
help me, please help me
[part 2]
today is a bad day
help me, please help me
oh kyung hwi is an idiot
he's really crazy
he is a sly person
I have to get away from him as soon as possible
if you want, I should get away as possible
hah? sly?
well, he's driving me crazy
hah? What is this?
already completed
God
true, time travel is ready to go this
but, now it's changed, then the future may change
then will my future also change?
ahh, it takes a lot of struggle to become a doctor
not right
If han na bi survived, we will go to medical school together
no, no need to do that
what if we open a business?
ah no, no
now han na bi is the most important
~ jin wook ... jin wook ~
Did she kill herself because of this man?
no, this is impossible
oh, i'm so startled
I can not be like this
[the number you are going to can not be reached]
I miss you half dead
until when will you hide?
yes yes thank you
well, see you tomorrow
where have you been lately?
aigoo
I've said do not go anywhere
how many times do i have to say it?
You must listen to Dad! // I know
that's why I like this
han na bi!
[please press password]
please open the door
hey you!
Who are you? what's wrong with your face?
today I went to cubbling and I danced there
it's okay you went to dancing but please go home early
I told you I went to dance
when will you learn?
That is very fun
aigoo
stop jigging
but who are you?
how do I look?
now it's okay right?
I told you to stay away three steps away from me
hey I'm not a bacteria or anything like that
You're worse than bacteria
this is a misunderstanding
do you want to get a hit from me this morning?
han na bi!
Do not you understand?
I told you to stay away three steps from me
wah, he changed
how can he change?
Has he changed because of that person?
do i have to ask her?
ask her about who is jin wook
ah no, no
If I asked without care, it would only cause trouble
but if it is true that person is causing han na bi to kill himself ..
What should I do?
han na bi
have you finished your school entry plan?
aigoo, you really annoyed me
follow me!
What happened to you
hey, hey let me go
aigoo, why can you be like this?
explain to me, quickly
Do not exaggerate
but like what I've said
When someone suddenly changes like this, this may be the end of them
really!
You have to believe me
~ Trust me ~
~ in my dream ~
Hey! jang seul gi!
What's wrong with him?
hey oh kyung hwi what happen with your face?
did you do plastic surgery last night?
How can?
wah, is this a dream?
do not think with you like this I will not tell you to buy more bread!
because I'm still in a good mood so go find some more cream bread for us, we're hungry
now still not too late
that's why you have to run now and back before the bell rings
what the hell? you have to go now
come on!
stop talking nonsense and think about how your life will change
if you continue like this you can all go to jail
What?
hey we told you to buy creamy bread
hey!
if you want to fight to go elsewhere, do not get in the way
han na bi,you still look pretty even when you're angry
how long will you keep going like this?
I've been waiting
You have to make quick decisions
Let's end here
Why?
do you also like han na bi?
oh! That's why you acted cold yesterday?
and you also changed your hairstyle
na bi, it's all because you have not decided yet when you're single
that's why even cats, dogs, and beggars are attracted to you
there are cats, dogs, even pigs
What?
ah, lucky you're beautiful
stop it
do not get this pretty face angry
my memory is still good
you'll be grateful after I told you this
what is this nonsense?
What? you will be sorry
your little friend should be careful
why have not you gone yet?
Go, hurry
How about this?
have not I told you to be careful
han na bi!
na bi!
na bi! na bi!
na bi are you okay?
han na bi! han na bi!
[Thank you for using this subtitle]
[Translated by Sugiyatri Sultan]
[ig @ trysultan98]