Well'?
Nothing.
So you took off, went away
and left him on his own'?
Yes.
It's normal.
Normal'?
He wouldn't have helped me either.
- But how did you feel aftemrards?
- Normal.
Can you explain
what "normal" means to you'?
Normal means normal.
So, nothing.
I know it's hard
to talk about certain things.
But with time
we'll be able to go deeper.
I think we're done for the day.
See you next week.
Bye, Lorenzo.
See, I was right after all'?
Yes.
To open up,
he needed an outsider,
someone who's neither you or me.
Yes, I told you,
he decided all on his own.
It's such a relief.
I phoned you right away!
Lorenzo for a week on the snow!
If you think how it was
just a year ago...
If he feels he wants to be
with the others for a whole week,
that's a wonderful sign.
It's very important.
I could hardly wait to call you.
No! VVait.
I'll tell him myself later.
Alright.
Before we begin our lesson,
who hasn't given me the money yet'?
Tomorrow is the last day. Any hasn't
paid by tomorrow won't be coming.
I'm not joking.
Sign here.
Take this.
- Cuni, coming for ajoint'?
- Don't bother with him.
Lorenzo, what are you doing'?
I was trying to pick up a bean
with the straw.
Cut it out, eat properly.
I heard from your dad. He said
to buy you a snowboard.
- There are new ones out.
- Nitro'?
I don't know, we'll see,
I don't remember.
It has to be Nitro, or Gnu.
But I don't need one, mine's fine.
No, he's counting on it,
he wants to buy you something...
- Is he happy I'm going?
- Of course, he's very happy.
- What did he say'?
- That he was happy.
- What were his exact words'?
- I don't know, he was happy.
No, tell me,
what were his exact words'?
He was happy.
Mom, do you think
people seeing us here now,
could think we were a couple'?
How could they think a kid would be
with a woman of my age'?
Well, you look a lot younger.
No, they'd think I'm your mother.
We need to cut your hair.
Imagine that tomorrow a fatal virus
comes out of a laboratory
and kills the population.
But you and I find the antidote
and are saved.
And we're the only ones
left on Earth.
But humanity is doomed, unless we...
- Stop it.
- Come on, it would save humanity.
Stop this nonsense, eat up.
Why get mad I I mean an extreme
situation I It's to save mankind.
What are you thinking!
- You're worse than a six-year-old!
- Okay, sorry.
Tell me just one thing. If it were
a boy, what would you call him'?
- What did the psychiatrist say about
Lorenzo'? - He has a grandiose self.
- What's that mean'?
- That our son is so narcissistic.
He doesn't need anyone.
That's great news.
- I found them! - Good!
What would I do without you'?
You wouldn't find your shoes.
Where's this chameleon from'?
- What do you mean'?
- Where's it come from'?
- We get them from the dealer,
I don't know. - It's strange.
I think it's African,
Indian ones are bigger.
- Yes, maybe.
- No, I'm sure.
What do you feed it'?
Mealworm larvae.
It's a bit skinny. You should
give it a more varied diet,
- Like crickets or silkworms.
- Will you get me some'?
- Does it ever change color?
- Buy it and find out.
Is this for cats or dogs'?
- It's the same. - It can't be.
- Don't you have anything to do'?
- Are stick insects hard to breed?
- No!
Just a terrarium and some branches,
want some'?
- I'll give you a good price.
- No, thanks, they're not my thing.
And this'? How much is this'?
I was thinking about
that story you told me. I liked it.
- Which one'?
- The one about a pastry maker.
The pasty maker who tamed beetles.
It's a good one.
- Go see if the nurses are around.
- No, no one's around.
- Get my medicine from my purse,
hurry. - Here.
Grandma, I have to go, I'm going with
the school tomorrow to sky.
- How nice.
- See you in a week.
In a week I'll be at the cemetery.
Okay, I'll have my coffin put
on top of yours, like a bunk bed.
Good! That way we can chat.
- Bye, Grandma.
- Bye.
Seven...
Five... six... seven!
That's seven of everything.
- Hi, Lorenzo.
- Hi, Salvatore.
- Did you bring your cell phone'?
- Yes.
- And music?
- Your medicine bag'?
- Yes.
What'll you do once I'm gone'?
I'll go home and sleep a little,
I've got such a headache.
- And then'? - Then at 11:00 I'll
visit Grandma and then I have to work.
- Leave me here. - Eh'?
- Let me get out.
- Put you seatbelt back on.
- Please, Mom.
- Let me get out.
- Why?
Because I want to arrive by myself!
I don't understand.
I said let me get out!
Calm down, don't start
making a crazy scene. It's too early.
I want to go there alone!
Lorenzo! Stop that or I'll get mad!
Okay, I won't go,
that way you'll be happy.
Everyone's going on their own, I'll
be the only one turning up with mommy!
That's enough!
BIO-Hum.
- Good morning, Salvatore.
- Good morning, ma'am.
Hello? I can't hear a thing!
It's the doorman here, speak up!
I can't hear a thing, it's Salvatore.
Hello, Mom'?
Yes, everything's fine. I was having
a snowball fight with the others.
We'll have dinner at the hotel,
then tomorrow's the torchlight party.
The teacher's not here,
I can't put her on.
Why do you want to talk with her'?
No, come on, leave me alone.
They're calling me.
We'll talk tomorrow.
Bye. My God!
Look what I've got for you.
Look, here it is.
Sacrifice to the rubber raft god.
No, that bastard Emiliano
didn't come.
I waited two hours for him!
No, you're a dickhead too,
I'm sick of you all!
Is anyone here'?
VVho the fuck are you'?
Lorenzo! Why are you here'?
- Are you Olivia?
- Of course, why are you here'?
No reason, I was looking
for something and then fell asleep.
- VVho gave you the keys'? - That bitch
housekeeper of yours.
VVho wouldn't let me in because
who knows what your mother told her.
She said my stuffs in a box
here in the basement.
Where is it'? Help me find it.
It's got "Olivia" written on it.
Look where they put me!
Nice family I have!
- Shit, it was here.
- What are you looking for'?
Grandma gave me a gold bracelet.
That bitch, your mother took it.
Don't talk about my mom like that!
What does she care
about your bracelet'?
Your mom's interested
in a lot of stuff.
VVith the excuse that I'm a thief,
she's taken everything.
- Goddammit, it was here!
- Don't shout so loudly, please!
Got any money'?
What an asshole.
- Doesn't your dad give you money'?
- No. And he's your dad too.
Really? I'd almost forgotten.
I never see him.
Give it to me, it's for a taxi.
I don't have any.
Look my in the eyes.
- You've grown.
- So have you.
Yeah, I'm coming. I'll take
the subway, I'll be a while.
ERIN-HEP-
- Listen, sorry.
- What is it'?
Don't tell anyone you saw me here.
Not even the housekeeper.
Nobody must know.
You're even getting a moustache.
- Take this up.
- I can't, no one knows I'm here.
Whatever, do what the fuck you want.
"I'm Lestat, a vampire,
I'm immortal. More or less.
The light of day,
the constant heat of a fire
could destroy me,
or maybe not.
I'm 1,86 meters tall,
a considerable height for the 1780s,
when I was a young mortal.
I'm not bad-looking now.
I have thick
shoulder-length blond hair,
a bit curly, it looks white
in fluorescent light. "
Lorenzo'?
Fuck, you scared me!
What do you want'?
- Turn that damn flashlight off,
let me in. - No. - Let me in.
- Why'?
- I need somewhere to sleep.
- Lower your voice. - Will you let
me in'? - No! - Why'?
This is my place, I don't want you
to make any trouble, it's dangerous!
- Go somewhere else.
- Let me in.
I've got nowhere else to go. There's
no room for you, it's too small.
Let me in or I'll start shouting
and wake up the whole block!
Olly.
Olivia! Come on.
Hurry up!
Come on! They'll see us!
Move it.
Come on.
It's so hot in here.
We're near the boiler.
The heating pipes run through here.
Why are you in here'?
I was supposed to go on a
skiing trip, but didn't feel like it.
Couldn't you stay at home'?
No, if I didn't go
it would have been a total mess.
My mom would've been disappointed
and she'd have stressed me out.
It's best they all think
I'm in the mountains.
- How long will you stay here'?
- Till Saturday.
- Got any beer'? - No, there's fruit
juice over there. - There?
Look how organized you are!
All your snacks are in order, tidy.
You bought all this junk because
they don't let you eat it at home'?
The only thing missing
is a "Royal with cheese".
- Where were you going skiing?
- Borca di Cadore.
- Okay but what is it'?
- Don't move it, you'll upset them!
- What is it'?
- An ant nest.
You'd rather stay in a basement
watching ants
than go skiing'?
Yes, I'm better off by myself.
- You might be right about that.
- Whose stuff is this?
- Countess Nunziante's.
- Who the fuck's she'?
She lived in our apartment before us.
Dad bought the house and
let her stay there till she died.
He did it to help her,
she had no money left.
I see, a bare ownership deal.
- You know what that is'?
- No.
Imagine you're old, poor
and have no one left.
But you have a beautiful house.
You sell your house cheaply
but you still live there
and when you die, the house and
your things go to whoever bought it.
So to get the house,
he had to hope she'd die soon.
- Right.
- That's not nice.
No, it sucks.
Well, I'm going to get some sleep.
I traveled all day yesterday,
I'm dead tired.
- Where were you coming from'?
- From my house, Catania.
Does your mom still have
the shoe shop in Catania'?
Excuse me young man, is there
a restroom down here?
Of course.
Where did you go'?
- Dancing. - Where'?
- Somewhere outside Rome.
Oh, my God!
Water.
Anyway, I knew
about the bare ownership deal.
I couldn't tell you
but Dad and I killed the Countess.
By poisoned chocolate.
I'm cold.
I'm here to make sure
no one finds the body
and to wait for it to turn to dust.
Understand'? Do you understand'?
- What's wrong'?
- My bones hurt.
You're not going to give me the flu,
are you'?
When you go,
there's a pharmacy in the square.
You're going, right'? You promised.
Remember you promised you'd go!
Where are you'? Call me. Mom.
When will I see you'?
Not before, then'?
It's just that I have
nowhere to stay here.
Okay, I'll see what I can do.
What'?
No, I swear, I'm just a little tired.
I wrote to you, I'm clean.
Marco. Marco, listen,
I so want to see you.
Okay my love,
I'll wait for you to call me.
lamb!-
- No, you're leaving now.
- Spying on me, you little shit?
I'll do whatever I like.
This is my place.
Give me a break.
What do you want '? Look at yourself.
Standing there,
pointing your finger at me...
"No, you're leaving now!"
Did you learn that from Dad'?
Ordering people around'? No, there's
something wrong with you inside.
I'm not hurting anyone.
Leave me alone.
If you hide in a hole,
minding your own business
that doesn't mean
you're better than other people.
That's too easy.
It's mommy.
Hi.
I didn't have time to call you.
What do you think we're doing?
We're skiing!
No, I told you the teacher's
not here I You can't talk to her!
- I'm here, is that your mom, Cuni'?
- Yes.
Mrs. Cuni, how are you'?
No, it's Miss Stefanelli,
I teach Science to another class.
Everything is fine, yes.
He's given us a lesson,
your son's a little champion.
Of course, would you like my number'?
Okay. 3- 4-8
55-36-789.
Call me so I can save yours.
Do you want to speak to Lorenzo'?
I'll say goodbye for you.
Good bye.
I'll see you soon.
Wow, you really laid it on her!
Arianna Cuni.
Saved forever.
So you won't bug me again.
Or I'll show you
who Miss Stefanelli is,
she'll tell mom: "Go to the basement
and see your little champion. "
How gross.
I threw up all over myself.
Shit.
Help me.
- What's wrong'?
- Cold turkey.
- What'? - Didn't they tell you'?
- What'?
- That I'm a junkie, a shitty addict.
- No...
Of course, they're protecting you.
They don't tell you the bad stuff.
Please, leave me alone.
Forget about me.
Olivia'?
Go away.
Get out.
Close that fuckin' door!
"He would watch the scene
and learn. That intimacy... "
I know you hate me.
Don't worry, I'm going soon,
you won't see me anymore.
- Back to Catania'? - No, I'm going
to go live in the country.
- When'?
- In a few days.
A friend of mine is taking me
to a farm where there are horses.
I was just dreaming about it.
Have you ever been to see horses?
- No.
- Me neither.
But...
I have to go through cold turkey
and be clean before I see him.
Do you have to do it here'?
I'm not exactly dying
to be in this craphole.
But I don't know where else to go.
- What do you take'? Cocaine?
- No, heroin.
- Is it expensive?
- Less now, but it still is.
- Where do you get the money'?
- Your dad sends it to me every month.
To get over his guilt.
- What guilt'?
- Ask him.
Because he left
your mother for mine'?
You really don't know anything!
Your dad's never given a shit
about me and my mom.
I guess we're
not elegant enough for him,
she sells shoes!
- That's not true, Dad's not like
that. - Isn't he'? How old are you'?
- 14, you know that.
- What planet are you from'?
Can't you see
what shits your parents are,
they don't even realize
they have a psycho son
who reads upside down'?
Psychopath.
"I made that scene
more cruel and playful... "
You'll get a rush of blood
to your head.
"Then the night
lost its normal dimension.
In fact, it remains
one of the longest nights... "
- I don't like this dead zebra.
- Neither do I.
Poor thing.
Can we take it away'?
I know, but the supervisor
had a few problems.
Quiet, please, be quiet!
Quiet, or they' find us!
I have things to do,
I can't wait all morning.
I'll tell the surveyor to call you.
I'm out of sleeping pills.
Did you hear me'?
I'm out of sleeping pills!
Stop! I don't give a shit
if you're sick.
You make me puke.
- I'll kill you if you don't go,
you bitch! - I'm too sick, shit!
Olivia'? Olivia, Olivia...
I didn't mean to hurt you, please.
Please, help me.
I'm too sick.
Want me to call someone'?
No, get me something strong,
that makes me feel well,
I can't do this awake.
Stand by me, please.
Get me some sleeping pills.
I'm that close.
- A little sugar?
- No, thank you.
Get him off,
I don't like the dog on the bed.
- It's time to take him out.
- I already did.
- Lorenzo. Is that you'?
- Yes, Grandma.
Can you do me a favor?
Will you lower the bed'?
There, that's fine.
I have to go now though,
we've got lots of homework.
Won't you tell me
one of your stories'?
- Okay. Do you remember Olivia?
- Yes, Olivia.
Of course, she's my granddaughter.
Her mother was showy, but very nice.
- She was nice? - Yes.
She took me to Mt. Etna once.
It was beautiful.
You must go there.
And Olivia'?
Olivia'? Are you awake'?
- Finally! You were gone so long.
- Mission accomplished.
Awesome!
- Come on. Don't get mad.
- Why'? - Don't get mad.
I'm Ferdinando,
a friend of Olivia's.
- VVho is this guy'?
- A friend, I called him.
- Why'?
- You didn't come back.
She said she wasn't well,
so I came to see
if she needed anything.
- We're old friends.
- I don't want him in here.
He shouldn't have
touched my computer.
Stop making such a big deal.
You've made my brother jealous.
Come here.
- We'd better go, I'll get your stuff.
- Where are you going'?
I don't feel like going all that way.
Please, Olivia,
you sleep, I'll drive
we'll be there in two hours
and you'll wake up by the sea.
- No, I want to stay with my brother.
- I'll take care of everything, c'mon.
- Do you really want one of my pieces?
- Yes, the street lamp with arms.
- But, could you pay for it now'?
- Sure. - Really? - Yes.
- Thank you. - I'll come back for you
if you want. Call me.
You're so sweet.
- Was that your friend with the horse'?
- No, are you crazy'? He's an old man'?
Maybe he was old,
but he was coming on to you.
Really?
Shit, I'm out of cigarettes.
- Want to see a movie?
- No.
I need to get some rest.
Good night, sweetheart.
So why did he give you all that money'?
Maybe he wanted to buy you.
I'll explain later.
I'm sleepy now.
Sicilians can be jealous,
but you... My goodness!
Fantastic.
Impressive.
"They live in colonies that can be
small units or tens of millions.
Often divided into
females, males and workers.
The workers can be
sterile or apterous.
The bigger ones can act like
soldier ants and defend the colony.
After mating, in general,
of the winged males and females,
the first often die
and the females lose their wings. "
No, the snow...
it's weird because
it's all soft and white and clean.
It's like wool,
it's like being in Paradise!
Then you look at the sky
and you realize you're on the ground.
Yesterday we went
to see these frozen waterfalls,
they looked frozen in time.
Next to them was this precipice
that was all brown.
There was some snow
but like it was dirty.
No, that gurgling is a stream
where we've stopped,
it's still flowing, I don't know why
it's not frozen...
it's pretty cold.
Yes, we should be back
around lunchtime.
You don't need to come and get me,
I'll get a lift from Pennacchini,
that tall guy, in my classroom.
Come on, Mom, I have to go.
Talk to you later.
Thirty-eight.
Thirty-eight!
- Are you awake'?
- No.
How much do you sleep'?
You're so tanned,
you look so handsome! Darling!
I missed you so much. Come in.
Lorenzo'?
- Lorenzo. What time is it'?
- I don't know.
It's night time. I'm better,
you know'?
But I have to eat something.
We were invaded by ants.
I saved what I could
but they ate everything.
There's nothing left to eat.
I have to eat something healthy,
not your junk.
- Are those the house keys'?
- Yes, why'? What are you going to do'?
- I'm going upstairs for some food.
- No, you can't!
- You're nuts!
- I won't get caught!
Yes, you will!
You're nuts!
Hey, are you staying or coming'?
C'mon.
I'm begging, it's the end.
Which key is it'?
Come on, I'm hungry! Idiot.
Be quiet.
- Come on.
- Be quiet!
- Come on, I'm hungry.
- Hungry, hungry, hungry!
No, I'll do it.
Olivia!
Go away. Go away.
Get away from there.
Please, go away, please.
Go away, go away!
- Have some more beer.
- No, I don't like it.
It's our last night, we'll get out
of this prison tomorrow.
- C'mon.
- Okay.
Yesterday,
when your friend was here...
- What did you sell him'?
- What kind of work'?
- One of my works.
- Photographs.
- Then I think I saw them.
- Where'? - On the computer.
Shit. I forgot.
- Do you like them'?
- They're nice. - Nice?
- No, I mean, they're great.
- Fantastic.
Let's see this one.
You know until a few years ago
I took photos. I did video art.
I even had some exhibitions.
I won an important award
when I was 18.
- Yeah, right...
- It's true.
- I went to Los Angeles.
- Yeah, right...
- I did.
- Of course.
But then I got messed up with dope
and I stopped.
The photos you saw
are part of a series called...
- "I am a wall".
- What wall?
It's a metaphor,
basically it's me becoming that wall,
entering the wallpaper,
going inside the plaster.
Like a lizard...
Not like a lizard.
Virtually, I wanted to ale-materialize.
Me and you, if we didn't have a point
of view anymore, we'd be the same.
Yes, I mean without a point of view,
we'd stop being against each other
and accept reality for what it is,
without judging it.
- Like... Do you know Buddhism?
- Yes.
- But you're not a Buddhist at all.
- Of course I am.
- No, you're always pissed!
- It's not easy to be a Buddhist.
Besides, it's drugs
that made me mean.
Before, I could pass through walls.
- Yeah, right...
- Really! Sure.
- Do you like this dress?
- It's beautiful.
Want me to put a different one on'?
Countess Nunziante is my size.
- Alright.
Hi, Pablito, look at me.
Do you like my bow'?
Nice, like an Easter egg.
I understand nothing
of retro punk, drunkard.
I prefer serious things.
- VVho are you texting'?
- My friend with the horses.
I'm setting up a place
to meet tomorrow.
Tell me the name of a nice cafe
where he can pick me up.
Bar Afrodite, in Piazza Verdi.
They make good sandwiches.
- Is he your boyfriend? - No.
I just had an affair with him.
But when we met
he was with someone else.
- Did he leave her for you'?
- He cheated on her with me.
After we met,
we couldn't live without each other.
But after a few months
he got back with her.
- Were you upset?
- A little. But I understood him,
You don't break up for a junkie,
that's normal.
But...
two weeks ago he sent me a text.
He said he's made up his mind,
he wants to get back with me.
Only if I kick the habit though.
What's he like'?
Tall, with curly hair,
green eyes.
He's a graphic designer in Rome.
He wants to quit everything
and move to the country with me.
- Where'?
- To Tuscany.
One of his relatives owns a farm.
Maybe we could work there.
For a change of scenery.
I've been on drugs for so long
I can't imagine how it is
being around a normal person.
'WW-Baum...
You don't feel anything.
No one can hurt you.
- Isn't that cool'?
- No, because you're indifferent.
And indifference isn't a nice thing.
You become cold and mean.
Like me!
My mind has taken off,
one thought, just one.
I walk while the city sleeps.
Her eyes in the night,
white headlights in the night,
a voice that talks to me, who is it'?
Say, lonely boy where are you going,
why so much pain'?
You've lost a great love, no doubt,
but the city is full of loves.
No, lonely girl, no, no, no,
you're wrong this time,
I didn't lose just a great love,
last night I lost everything
with her...
Can I ask you something'?
- Why didn't you ever come back to
our house? - You don't know'?
- No. - One summer I almost
killed your mother, remember?
Absolutely not.
I threw a rock at her head,
it bled a lot.
Dad had to take her
to the hospital for stitches.
- Why did you do that'?
- Because I hated her.
- She'd taken my dad away.
- A rock, though...
Where will you go now, lonely boy'?
The night is a big sea,
if you need my hand to swim.
Thanks, but I just
want to die tonight
because you know in my eyes
there's an angel,
an angel who can fly no more,
who can fly no more...
- Are you sleeping? - No.
- Will you promise me something?
- What'? - That you never take drugs
again. Never again.
I promise.
And will you promise me something?
Yin.
Stop hiding.
Shit, you're grown up.
It's time to get a life.
If you get knocked around
once in a while, it doesn't matter.
Look at me, I'm all black and blue.
But you have nine lives like a cat.
- Do you promise?
- Yes.
It's really late now, let's sleep.
Shit.
- Olivia?
- Yes, I'm done.
- You're beautiful.
- Thanks.
Lion'?
urea
Your cigarettes.
Here.
Come here, c'mon.
- I can't do it.
- Sure you can, I'm right here.
- We had fun, right'?
- Yes. It'd be fun to do it again.
Our week on the snow!