Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
[Traffic City]
[Song in English "I do not believe in love"
the group "THE SCHOOL"]
[Off]
"It's like the human body."
"What would the body without
its members?
[Off]
"Yes, they're fragile."
Come on, pulses, only the pulses.
[Off]
"For those companies
that divide and alienate minorities rs "
[Off]
"Societies're mutilated."
They're not united.
Each seems a desert island.
[Off]
"And arms, come Joseph
started, okay?
Okay, Rosario, very well,
open up front and the side.
Do not want this,
rather, we want marriage.
Here there's no women or blacks,
nor homosexuals, nor anything.
Here we are all people.
[Resume song "I Do not Believe in Love"
the group "THE SCHOOL"]
Therefore,
work helps us
us to feel part of society,
because we are,
always were, and we have a voice
this society
a democratic society.
Thank you.
[Applause]
[Almost all the characters
Andalusian speak with an accent]
Daniel? Hello
Consuelo Jiménez.
Okay?
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
Come on, I show you where
work, okay?
We are very pleased
to have him with us.
Another thing that I
tell ...
that there is one on your desk phone,
that my extension is 25,
and so I do not get confused
I put my name, Consuelo.
[Off]
"Good morning. Okay?"
"Okay, good morning.
"Look,
Pepe, our psychologist, who will
explain the entire computer system.
-Whatever you need.
Thank you.
-How you doing, champ?
Very well.
Do not worry so wolf around,
I am your pastor!
[Off]
"She is Rocio, our veteran.
Star. "
[Off]
"And she's Macarena, our little princess."
"Macarena is to help, like you."
You will sit at the table.
And we miss Laura, who is there.
So we have work
accumulated.
What studying, teaching?
[Off]
"And psychology."
Anyway, is proud to have such a phenomenon
you are here among us. Is not everybody?
Sure.
[Phone]
Secretariat for Persons with
Special Needs?
A moment that step.
[Off record]
"Concentrate your intelligence
in front of you. "
"You will feel a slight vibration,"
"A slight sensation of heat
produced by the movement. "
"Soothe tension, relax the ligaments
this part of your body "
"And put yourself in a state of
deep relaxation. "
"More and deeper each time."
"Concentrate your intelligence eyelids
and tissues surrounding them. "
Hello!
You lost?
The public attendance
is not here.
Triana has to go.
Come alone or with your parents?
No, I came alone.
Yeah, that is ...
Oh, I've been here? Documentation
to prepare the folders.
Well I see you already know.
Daniel Sanz.
Daniel Sanz ...
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
Sorry?
Seville, a day of work ...
within an hour meet
technical committees. So you know ...
[Mobile]
I sit there.
[English]
Yeah, right, I do not know
but that's the truth.
It's Sad But it's true.
Oh, my God, hold on.
It was not this.
No ...
It had to be beige, which is young,
this is old.
-This is more beautiful and will love.
Bonito-nothing, Bernabé,
you have no taste whatsoever.
My goodness, that cool! That elegant.
I look like a minister.
Everything comes with time, my son,
will have to point higher.
A Toast by his first
workday.
[Cup beating and giggles]
Just need to get married.
[Gasps erotic video]
[Off]
Saw the video I sent them the new
Metro Sevilla?
[Off]
For me it was the car.
Will have a station in the square.
[Off]
-You will ride the subway?
-Man, of course.
[Off]
In my opinion none of Seville
should ride the subway.
[Off]
"This will fill the mold.
I even fear. "
Laura.
Thanks, Star.
He finished his report to the committee?
I'm still correcting
Councillor's speech, right?
[Off]
Macarena, can you help her?
Is that ... I do not have
no time to compensate.
[Off]
Well, today is Friday
and not finished.
If you want to help you get
and invite you to eat.
I'd rather die of hunger, Pepe.
[Off]
Look at the sympathy of the princess!
Daniel, do not pass me the links
I'll have a coffee.
[Mobile]
[Off]
The copier is damaged,
know where there is another?
Has a left to get out now ...
and your will see a lift.
You go up ... goes into it, huh?
And rises to the top floor.
E. .. leaves the elevator,
and finds a very long corridor,
Too long, too long,
Is picking up?
Very long.
Let's see, leaves the elevator,
long corridor, compridíssimo
until the end that ends in ...
on a ladder ...
[Sound mechanical and repetitive, copier]
And it came to Seville?
Because I was tired of Madrid,
and because I have no family.
It is an orphan?
And I do not have any brothers?
No, I have no brothers.
Therefore this expression on the lips
so ... so sad.
I'm not sad.
I came here to work for 18 years
the stewardess on the "Expo"
Seville because I thought it was the beach.
Turns out the beach we are 100 kms.
A 125 exactly.
Damn!
Well, I think it will be given
well with us.
Because Sonsoles, that you replace
have depression,
it seems that your son ... I do not know,
he was born with a brain injury ...
Ask your mom to buy
shoes without shoelaces, okay?
Okay.
[Off]
Hello Laura, what will it be?
A Parmesan ...
[Off]
A traditional ...
[Off clerk]
You got it ...
[Off]
And that ...
-Fish.
-No, no, this.
-Peach?
-No.
This.
Pineapple.
Something more?
-No.
3.70.
And now you, what will?
[Off] "I'll have
quarter of sausage. "
1 / 4 of sausage.
Leaving 1 / 4 of sausage.
[Blending rock, rumba and flamenco]
Put one dose.
"Blacks are your black eyes,"
"his pen and his black hair,"
"Blacks are the ones I like,"
"blacks that give me poison ..."
[Groans]
Wait a minute.
[Television ads for sale]
[Percussion music with Arab rhythms]
[Off]
Very good, very good class,
okay? Goodbye.
Guys! One moment, they're the times
the academy. Everyone stay.
These are the times of the gym
to do pilates or tai chi.
Swimming is Wednesday,
I said Wednesday.
Let ...
[Off]
Already out?
Here, here Sly.
[Shouts, applause and hoots]
[Whistle intervals]
I gave a discount.
Even think that "The Garden of Earthly Delights"
was a park.
And because they spoke about the
"The Garden of Earthly Delights"?
Because I explained to him about the
framework, the Prado Museum,
it was an allegory
sin,
and she is loose
a park.
I get really crazy.
And well, removing the defects,
what can I do?
Gosh, Dad.
I asked you a Coke Light.
But that's what your mom drinks.
[Off]
It has to be strong,
we will do everything possible
What?
Is blocked.
Well ..
Let's see.
Look, you have to close here, okay?
And after each little window should open,
this and this ... and this.
You see,
this is very easy.
Any LORP does.
If even I'm a LORP.
See?
"Look, just ...
-Laura!
[Off]
Please, I want
answer this.
Encarni, so have the resolution
with the degree of dependence,
Peter give the center a day,
a home or whatever.
Hello
My partner takes the data
and makes you a plug.
Even more, Encarni.
But in a moment.
That was not what I thought.
My brother can not stay on the street,
since my mom died
he only lives down the street.
[Off]
But woman, do not worry
because there will be room
It's like I had told him,
that it should wait a bit.
It's hard to tell how long
or send me somewhere else.
It's nothing ... Do what I say and follow
the procedure and ready.
[Off]
Hey, do not stay down now wife,
it'll help.
[Off]
Listen, and why
not occupy a seat extra?
As an extra seat?
If you are unoccupied 24 hours a day
could occupy an extra seat.
You can not occupy a seat extra
vague because there's extra
[Off]
There is a waiting list and a lot
people need
[Off]
and we will do our best.
Right?
[Off]
Pepe, please answer the Encarni.
A water?
It's not forbidden to come up here?
Yes ..
I climb when I get mad at the rules.
Once the law ... made a trap.
[Laughter]
Is it good?
This ... I'm not going to want more,
if you like ...
Look, it's authentic,
pretty,
works perfectly,
is fun,
is happy with that force,
with that ...
vitality, with that ... uf!
My,
and how ... As it turned out,
shit!
[Answering phone message]
"Hello?"
"Laura ... I am Nuria, his sister,
Quique's wife.
"I'm calling because his father is
15 days in hospital and is very serious, "
"gets in touch with us,"
"if you do not want to talk to his brothers ...
Call me, "
"Look, my number is 675745695,"
"I need to talk to you ...
is important. "
[Voices noisy TV]
[Música disco with plenty of volume]
[Music distorted
and sighs interspersed]
[Gasps imaginary]
HATE ... STANDARDS.
[Alarm beeping]
[Mobile]
[Laughter]
Cute.
How cute.
[Phone]
Daniel ... What?
For eleven times already called me?
[Off]
I was worried,
why not come to work,
feared he was sick or happened
something serious, I dunno.
What was that?
[Off]
Knows "Danza Mobile?
Okay, okay. For further,
not going to be watching TV all day.
[Chora] [Off]
Thanks, I did not know more
what to do,
Look do more shifts at the bar, and paid
what you need, okay?
Peter is invited, no need
pay anything, right?
Pay attention, he is invited
because there's no vacancy, ok?
Thank you.
Staff, came a new companion.
Let's get him?
Is called Peter, loves dancing, and will
stay with us year round.
[Off]
So something is going to dance?
Then come
[Music with Arab rhythms]
[Off]
Let's see who dance with Peter.
Some voluntary, come on.
[Off]
Come, come, dancing.
[Applause]
I'll take you to a nightclub.
I do not like disco, I prefer
dinner in a quiet and talk.
And do not get tired of talking so much?
[English]
Your hair is beautiful.
What was that?
What has the hair very silky.
Silky?
What color is your hair?
You do not like that, or what?
Yes I adore,
is very beautiful.
His is a little creepy, huh?
[Laughter]
[Off Mom]
"The happiness."
The happiness.
[Off]
"Which produced this reply."
Which produced this reply.
[Off]
"Was such."
Was such.
"As He HAD Probably."
Probably he HAD to.
"Never felt before."
Never felt before.
This.
And he the expressed himself ...
Daniel, where you are with your head?
Where is your head?
"The sensibly."
An sensibly.
The sensibly ...
"And the warmly."
And the warmly.
This ... "As a man."
As a man.
"Violently."
Violently ...
"In love ..."
Dani, anybody there?
Daniel please
listen to your mother, please.
This.
"Can Be's suppossed to."
[Car Radio - Music flamenco]
Daniel.
Take an umbrella.
Ah, thanks, Mom.
-Sure.
"Hello.
Thank you.
Well, have fun.
"All right.
Thank you.
And be careful on the road,
okay?
Is.
[Screams]
Do not forget the belt!
[Song in English "If Looks Could Kill"
group "CAMERA OBSCURA"]
Where we go with a melon?
[Laughter]
What a beautiful day!
[Continues "If Looks Could Kill"
to "CAMERA OBSCURA"]
[Laughter]
[Gulls]
They're chubby, no?
Yeah, well, this is a trait
Down's syndrome, a characteristic.
We have over other
characteristics, you know?
For example the palate,
is narrower.
This also affects Condo speech
because it can ...
in his tongue, and is
very difficult to speak.
Why is it ... so?
-Like what?
-So ...
Why is it smart?
In my case it is because
my mom
talked a lot with me,
from small,
we were talking
history, politics,
asked me many things,
and I answered.
And as my mom saw that I understood
what she was saying,
decided that I was
to college.
She did everything I was
to college, my mother.
I think it was traces
or something light.
No, nothing like that.
I have Down syndrome
toes to your head,
No ... whole, entire.
And often say that there
two ages,
chronological and mental.
I do not think.
I am 34 years ...
tie my shoelaces and I know
since 10 years.
And the nose?
His nose is flat, Daniel.
For it is another feature
Down's syndrome.
Want to pass the guard?
"Are you with me.
"Are you?
Is.
What geladinho!
This is you?
What do you want, "fusilli" three cheeses
or Spaghetti "carbonara"?
Ah, but they're the envelope?
Yes of course, are from the envelope.
Drugs, oil!
Ay, ay, ay!
[Laughter]
[Dramatic movie]
[Crying]
[Off]
What was
I pity him who is an orphan.
I'm not an orphan.
I have a father ... and two brothers.
But do not you talk to them
for years, you know?
And why lie?
Because ...
For me, it's like
were dead.
Too bad it gives me.
Daniel please listen ...
Do not cry ...
[Laughter contained]
Ouch ...
[Laughter]
[Song "For You"
interpreted as "Manzanita"]
[Imitating Laura]
Ouch ... my boy!
Ouch ...
Macarena, there's nothing to understand,
she is teasing
and leave you wanting,
it already is.
Like you.
Yeah, like me,
and the entire service.
Must be the only one who did not
knows her home.
By this the boy
stepped forward.
Pepe, each has
what he deserves.
All day with the boy.
Poor, really,
must pass a cut on her hand ...
[Continue "Te Amare"
interpreted as "Manzanita"]
It's a girl distraught
it's not normal, you do not realize!
[Off]
If she works in the Secretariat
is a normal girl.
Well, because the distribution must
being crazy
they should not hire
a girl who gives very bad impression,
as a woman
Hair that.
His son is 34 years.
What will you do?
I am well aware
of age who has, Bernabé,
but you know very well, the amount
interests merged.
That girl, fairly normal,
be interested in a guy like Daniel.
Angeles, his son is
an idiot.
You do not have to be stupid
manipulate it.
I did not want a normal child?
Because you do.
And normal people, climb!
At least once in a while, I say.
Could use a word a little more
elegant as it is the "scholar"?
Have you ever had a girlfriend?
Yes, more or less.
And it was like you?
Formed?
Come on, Daniel ... Syndrome.
Syndrome ... of abstinence?
[Laughter]
We eat together?
I can not ...
You've marked with a friend, you know?
I will ask one dose,
okay?
Is.
Fits me a shot.
Let's see.
I know she feels something
for me, I know.
He treats me like nobody
treated me before.
She sees me as, as one
real normal.
What I have to say.
Say.
I have to say now.
But the truth is in danger, you should know
they may lose. Understand?
Understand?
Kings and I'll have a drink.
Uncle Will.
That thing.
[Off]
Am-grandmother!
"Are you happy?
[Off]
I can not believe. I'm shocked.
Congratulations, son.
[Off]
Thanks, Mom.
What do you think Daniel?
Very cool. Genial.
Very good.
You will be the godfather.
Oh, great!
Yes, the godfather.
Come and grandparents.
[Off]
By the sponsor.
-For the best man!
"And that comes by.
And the parents!
By parents.
[Laughter]
[Off]
I am very happy for both.
The Ursula called me from New York,
and invited us to spend
Christmas there ...
[Slow music for string]
[For the song]
[Hit drums]
Guys, have a fine
private life.
[Off]
Kissing, touching and
do whatever you want.
Even they have secrets
for their parents.
[Off]
But to do this
must be sought privacy.
Privacy ...
Exactly.
You should seek a private place.
And school is not a private place.
Here it comes to dance.
Enjoy ...
Come here ... In the morning can give a
kiss, but no tongue.
[Off]
You guys see me moored Santi
kissing on the floor?
[Off]
No.
No ...
Let's keep things.
And I want to make a toast,
the beautiful people who work with me.
[All]
OLE! OLE!
And do not we freeze the salary!
[Laughter]
[Off]
For the love that will arrive before
menopause. Please.
[Off]
Hope is the last to die!
That hope!
[Music and flamenco clapping]
Having fun?
Very.
I did not have a friend?
What friend?
The poor guy is falling in wordiness
this bitch.
Why do not we go to my house
take the "nightcap"?
Pepe, please!
[Song "La revolución sexual"
Performed by LA CASA AZUL "]
"You who decided that
not worth your life, "
"was down by
always feel bad, "
"which anticipated a future
catastrophic, "
"today bodes
the sexual revolution. "
"You decided that your
love has not served, "
"who preferred to mask
their identity, "
"is preparing for the coup
most fantastic ..."
Have you thought about prostitution
ever?
Think women
I pay?
[Laughter]
[Slightly drunk]
To me you're a kitten ...
A kitten.
You're that beautiful,
in that dress.
Looks like a real princess.
And I a frog.
Ready
[A kiss on the forehead].
I'll convert ...
In Prince!
Hey, that's my prince!
[Continue disco music, slow]
Damn, this is me
troubling.
That's it.
I was tired of
look down.
[Continue ballad in english]
[Drunk]
Hey, this ...
I go to my house.
Want to accompany you?
No.
[Weeping]
[Sighs strong
gasp]
This lad is going where?
Hey, where are you?
"I'd enter.
-None.
Here one can not enter.
Is no place for you. Leaking ...
"But, why is that, Antonio?
"Why not! Trick!
This is for larger
18.
"I am 34 years old.
Problem-yours!
Whatever.
I'm not there either. Trick!
-Let him go!
-No way!
It's too expensive for you.
I have two credit cards, two!
So go buy a present for
your mother. Get out of here!
No kid, please do not be so.
You're not gonna go, right?
[Homepage]
[Screams]
That's not true!
I'm 34!
I'm not a boy!
I'm a man!
I'm a man ...
And I can go in there if I want.
I'm a man!
[Gasps and groans]
[Blows strong in the door]
[Whispers]
See who you are.
[Whispers] Do not open.
[Laughter]
Who is it?
Heck, Daniel, what time are these?
Come here.
[Weeping]
Look at Daniel ...
No woman with 46 chromosomes
will fall for you,
and you do not hand this large,
not going to suffer?
Fall for women to
its power, man.
For thus will not
achieve anything.
[Off]
Can I sleep here?
[Deep sigh]
[Off]
They know I never criticized
the work of you,
but the truth is that yesterday came
with signs in the neck.
And signs in the neck you
know what it is?
What else?
Luisa is "excited"
enthusiast,
and I do not know how to say no,
she does not know.
E. .. the boys know.
Good, but Luisa has already
25 years, huh?
No.
Luisa has just 24.
He told her about his dad?
What about it?
Who died.
But if that was clear, Santi.
If the problem is that we have,
the problem is not that they can distinguish
couples dance and truth.
And I do not know if you two
also help.
Hello
[Harsh]
We eat together?
Today my mother did "paella."
Ah ... And a coffee?
Now I can not,
I have to fix it.
The operator did not come today.
Okay, okay ...
[Failure of the copier]
[Strikes and kicks]
[Screams]
Son of a bitch!
[Off]
52% of Spanish men between
40 and 70 suffer from erectile dysfunction.
[Off Pepe]
Where did that come from?
[Off]
In the paper today.
[Off Pepe]
Fortunately I have good genetics.
My father, my grandfather ...
I never had problems
in bed, never.
[Laughter]
What?
Here I am, to give you fire
fire in his veins.
Ay, ay, ay!
[Laughter]
This is incredible ...
unborn who understands;
the truth is.
Need to make a college
to understand, damn!
Will you say what you have or not?
Oh, Laurinha of my soul,
that is weird!
Out-...
"But how so?
-Out!
"I'm gone.
-Out Now!
"I'm gone!
-Outside of my house!
Go-fight?
[Fighting]
Out, out, out!
What's gotten into you, dammit?
Seems a ...
[Answering machine]
"I am again, his sister."
"I'm calling because ...
Because his father fell into a coma. "
"And doctors need to talk to
guys, the children. "
"And because I need to know what will happen
with the apartment. Well, you know ... "
"I do not know, I would like to know what will.
You coming? "
[Sound of wind in the recording]
[Off]
Right, and the second well,
and once there, drawn.
Okay?
We repeat
Where is Luisa?
I do not know, Peter.
Crouch, Ignacio,
The girls come, come,
go, go.
[Off]
We get around.
And before stopping look
the companion ...
is very important ... Carmen,
for everyone.
"Look at the other.
E-Luisa?
I do not know, Peter.
[Off]
Join Alejandro, Jose enters
Kings ... And Luisa?
It is my dance partner!
I do not know! Right?
We stopped a moment.
[Off]
Until that Peter did not leave here,
this lady says that her daughter's not around.
He called the mother of Luisa?
I offer you Consuelo Jiménez, the
Council for Equality and Social Welfare.
Division of Special Needs.
I'm sorry but they're standards.
It's too crowded?
Yes ..
Could not leave it on the waiting list,
in an emergency?
Luisa loves me.
So thank you.
Even more.
"Let's get married" ...
Together.
You can not decide this,
without the express permission
their parents or guardians.
Why not?
"We are united," you know?
I like Louise.
Can not you see she loves me.
"Happy and I like it."
[Off talk about work]
This ... Love me, my girl.
And I like going out with her.
Pass me the stapler, Pepe?
[Off]
Because we're getting married,
why not?
United States, an apartment,
love us.
Stay with it.
I laugh, let's walk, to the movies.
I'm happy with it, you know? "Capico?
"Hello, good morning.
Good morning.
Daniel need to talk, okay?
After another day?
Well ..
Forget tonight, right?
For what?
To suffer more?
Well, I was drunk.
What can I do?
I'ma pretty big
to understand one out.
Listen, I have not given you an out.
Yes, I walked out because I have
Down's syndrome.
Come, do not use it
to make me feel guilty, right?
He is traveling in mayonnaise.
I thought you liked,
but I guess it is like all
others.
So over.
Okay, tell me that I
looking into the eyes.
Look in my eyes and tell.
[Unintelligible sounds]
Daniel, already given, please.
Stop doing that.
[Screams]
Want to stop playing
the retarded?
Miss not tell that to the boy,
not you see who is disabled?
Look, lady closes its beak!
Okay?
And you ...
[Laughter]
It will not be my
friend anymore, or what?
I do not want to be your friend,
want to be your boyfriend.
Daniel, this is not possible.
In hindsight,
is not even legal, you know.
Right ...
I do not think to denounce it.
Why me?
You do not know anything about me.
Because it makes me feel normal.
That commitment comes with it ...
And who wants to be a
normal person?
[Weeping]
Daniel,
Let's be friends ...
Please, Daniel.
Dammit ...
[Off]
"I love you!"
Caramba!
Do not make noise.
Bobo!
[Off Mom]
Lola, are you? Coming.
[Door bell]
[Off Mom]
Luisa,
if someone comes to say that I am
inside.
[Off Mom]
"You heard me, Luisa?"
Yes, mom.
[Off Mom]
"It will be ready ..."
[Door bell]
Luisa ...
Luisa?
Swapping!
This.
[Screams]
They fled up!
Hey, what happened?
Peter and Louise ... fled!
-Peter and Luisa fled?
-Yes!
Listen a moment,
stay there.
[Cries of joy]
Fled ...
I came and told you!
I said,
and you do not believe
now it has.
Easy.
Take,
this is not the end of the world.
"Just want to be together.
-Daniel
University did not were r,
Daniel.
No need to study
have needs!
Need, you know the
I got into that shit?
If you are horny
masturbation.
But that's not all.
You have company, is
Caring,
is to have something.
Blessed be the hour that gave you attention!
Blessed!
Of course,
is very easy for you
saying all this,
has a wife,
expecting a child, has it all!
Daniel did not make me more guilty
to have what I have.
I do not want to feel bad for
have everything I have.
Daniel ...
Hey!
[They sing very cheerful]
Ouch! Ouch!
Wooh!
Ay, ay, ay!
[Screams] "I love you."
[Car Horn]
God damn it, man, what the
problem, what is?
[Car Horn]
What was that?
You're not seeing the blinkers on?
Not fatter.
[Sings]
"Tirorariro, tirorariro ..."
Do not worry, we will
find, right?
I take responsibility.
[Police siren]
[Phone ringing]
Yes
[People talking]
I love the passion, and you?
Must be nice.
As made jelly beans.
I also have
berries, banana ...
Excuse me.
Daniel, why not call
for your brother?
This is the penis.
And this is the condom.
If you press here to get the air.
Yes, okay?
Wait, so.
It's not ... penis, sorry ...
Daniel, is ba-na-na, is eating.
Sorry I speak.
Let's see, here's a banana then,
but has the shape of the penis.
That is to eat!
This is not ...
[Off]
Sure, look ...
This is a banana,
I know it's a banana.
It's ba-na-na, is eating.
[Laughter]
Luisa ... not have to do anything
they do not want, right?
Yes, I do.
Okay.
He is a "lunch" ...
My soul ...
Please ...
Little heart ... With it ...
Love ... My soul ...
And do not cry, please.
Come here.
Thanks, Daniel ...
Thanks dude.
Okay?
Daniel, I have to go to Madrid ...
I want to tell you something.
Love you, honey.
You're Beautiful "pa" me.
It was not anything.
"Come on!
"Hey, Peter!
Let cool!
Please have dropped his glasses.
Luisa please come,
you leave.
Please, son, okay?
Okay even my daughter?
My poppet,
nothing happened,
daughter is not?
[Off Mom]
But that can not be
can not escape that.
It's a girl.
Resolved.
How are you?
These things run away from home
is childish.
No!
Let me go.
I'm not a child, I am a woman.
And that's it.
Go "pa" and end there.
How is "pa" there?
How so?
Where are you going?
Dad ... is ... dead!
Daughter!
[Off]
"Daddy is in heaven."
[Weeping]
Yes my love, Dad is in heaven,
yes my love.
[Off]
I do not know like anyone.
Forgive me.
[Off]
Not true, not at fault.
[Soft piano music]
Taxi!
[Piano Music]
[Screams and hoots]
[Off]
Laura's work more or less
was to control ...
[Off]
... Correspondence,
both inbound and outbound,
[Off]
Expedients to bring the file
stands there, answering the phone ...
Because we incorporate
these contributions.
And we can draw
the second comprehensive plan of action.
I mean, that in order
I'm saying ...
In order that I
saying,
you put me comm,
architecture, housing ...
[Off nurse]
Also has to stay with her apron
to enter into the room.
Inside there is already a familiar,
but even two people can enter.
The doctor told me that
left to suffer.
When you sign, so ...
The disconnect.
Those are the keys to your house.
Decided to sell my part.
Can I do anything for you?
[Off]
"Ask me for forgiveness."
I like to feel
something more than shit, but I can not.
[Vomiting]
[Off Mom]
"You okay?"
Calm Mom,
I'm not gonna die.
I know it's not gonna die.
Hear me, I'll tell you something.
The first time I saw you
I thought it was a normal baby.
With his face a little different,
but normal.
It was his father who told me we had
had a very special baby.
I cried non-stop one
week.
Until I said:
"But if it happens to everybody
things, why not me? "
And from this moment ever
more pity me.
[Off]
I suppose this broken heart
is the result of such effort,
[Off]
but I want you to know that
not regret.
And why so much effort ...
If not be happy?
I could not do anything,
did not have a choice, you know?
And I could not accept me ...
This was and how?
Forgive me, my love,
forgive me.
[Off TV]
[Christmas Raffle lottery Spanish]
And!
That's my mom!
And that's my mom!
[Giggles]
I dance a little,
come on, come on!
[Laughter]
Who wants a little bit
of nougat?
It's horrible about it.
[Phone ringing]
There's a phone ringing around.
[Off]
Lets play, it's Christmas Eve.
Want a nougat?
Come on, a nougat.
[Off]
"Daniel."
Hello
Merry Christmas.
How are you, kitty?
[Off]
With my family, and you?
Well, well ...
My father died.
[Off]
I miss you.
I can tell you one thing
because it is Christmas?
[Off]
They're so intimate and dates
so special ...
But that enrrolão.
SPIT.
[Honestly]
I love you.
Merry Christmas ...
[Soft piano music]
[Off]
This is from my dad, right?
Let's play.
[Off]
The puppy?
Well, yes ...
Let's save?
So okay.
Let's make a larger room,
in the case of visits.
As it grew, my goodness.
Yes
Say how old
you have.
I have seven years.
And you know who I am?
No.
[Off]
Is Aunt Laura.
Ready? Very good.
Potato, potato.
Potato. Potato.
Ba-ta-ta!
[Music Orchestra of marriage]
[Traffic Noises]
Hello
Wow!
[Laughter]
[Whispers]
What a mess! No?
[Off]
Look, we can go to two places.
One is the Eden
that is wonderful.
But it can also go
Hell.
If we behave
well, go to Eden.
But is led by vice
and excesses,
self-destructs,
if autodegrades.
And the end is going to Hell.
What color is horrible that the
're in Hell ...
Sure, why.
Gets bored and goes to Eden
fun in Hell.
Back then it was normal
this theme,
so moralizing about the good,
evil, sin ...
This is beautiful
hair color.
Sure you want to go?
[Christmas Melody]
[Off]
To move to gain time,
give me your identity documents.
Correct.
[Bell]
[Off]
Hello Login?
Yes
Good morning.
[Whispers]
Hello ..
On one side the part
buyer,
DS. Nuria González and
Enrique Valente. Correct?
And the other part is
saleswoman
DS. Laura Valente and Mr. Michael Valente.
Well, because ... begin by signing
the selling party.
How cold does at Christmas!
[Off]
Dona Laura.
I'm happy to see them.
It looks very good.
I left home because I
not have a choice.
Just wanted to let you know.
If you need a little more time
I'll have a coffee ...
and then continue ...
when ...
Do not sit.
Let us end it as soon as possible.
No, wait a moment.
Laura ...
His father before going into coma,
you confused me.
He asked for forgiveness ...
Believing it to be you.
And told me everything.
[Homepage]
[Deep sigh]
Where do I sign?
[Carol cheerful]
["Kiss You In The Snow"]
[Performed by "THE SCHOOL"]
[Twelve chimes]
[Cries of joy, bombs and rockets]
[Silence]
Has a tattoo?
You like it?
Ever wanted to make one.
The tiger represents strength e. ..
Well ..
If you keep touching me ...
... Gonna pop rockets.
No need to continue.
And if you do not like me?
I. .. I am so happy now.
Being with you is the best thing
happened in my life?
Do not be ...
Making a penalty?
I'm doing ...
Because I love you too.
I never made love.
Neither do I.
Sex with many men
in my life,
but never made love.
With many?
Neither would fit in this hotel.
For me it does.
I like you as well.
Daniel,
if we do, does not mean that
we are lovers.
And you should know that if you suffer ...
... You have to conceal all the time and
be happy whenever you see.
Need to understand
this,
only happen today.
Today, nothing more.
And nothing less.
[Deep sigh]
[Laughter]
What time is your train?
When I want.
[Soft piano music]
[Sigh]
Forgive me but is that ...
I have to say.
It has green eyes
so cute,
that eclipse even the
Pacific Ocean.
Thank you.
Want lunch?
No.
a coffee
-No!
-No?
Sure, a girl as pretty as you,
certainly has a boyfriend.
Worse than not.
[Laughter] Oh, please ...
[Song "Yo también"
Performed by LA CASA AZUL "]
"Whatever will be
seeking in their loneliness, "
"what their whispers have,
not what you can give. "
"At sea, everything is cloudy when
there is time, "
"the waves do not let you see,
that the beach is near. "
"I also
I have dreams in my heart, "
I fall without explanation. "
"I could make
the world stopped, "
"if you leave me one second
without your love, "
"my love is so deep,"
"I could get the best star
I'd give to be the most beautiful love. "
"I could give you the whole universe,"
"the whole universe to me
is small, do you see? "
"If you're not
I can not, "
"nobody else I
could enlighten you, "
"Do you feel
as never before, love. "
"Who will
who arouses your emotions, "
"who deliver all their light,
decide whom to love. "
"I, too, some nights
non-stop crying, "
"I also know you
could fall in love. "
"I could make
the world stopped, "
"if you leave me one second
without your love, "
"my love is so deep,"
"I could get the best star
I'd give to be the most beautiful love. "
"I could give you the whole universe,"
"the whole universe to me
is small, do you see? "
"If you're not
I not, "
"nobody else I
could enlighten you, "
"Do you feel
as never before, love. "
"I could make
the world stopped, "
"if you leave me one second
without your love, "
"my love is so deep,"
"I could get the best star,"
"I'd give to be the
most beautiful love ..."
"I could give you the whole universe,"
"the whole universe to me
is small, do you see? "
"If you're not,"
I not, "
"nobody else I
could enlighten you, "
"Do you feel
as never before, love ..."
Translation:
-== ==- Penguin-SP
END
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org