RESYNC : BSpidey87
RAYNE:
MY MOTHER,
RAPED SEVERAL TIMES
BY MY FATHER,
A MONSTER WHO TRIED
TO RULE THE WORLD
FROM THE SHADOWS.
A MONSTER I TRACKED THROUGH
THE DARKNESS, AND SLAUGHTERED.
A MONSTER WHO UNWILLINGLY
PASSED HIS UNDEAD CURSE
TO HIS DAUGHTER.
I AM THE ONE WHO WALKS
THROUGH THE WORLDS
OF THE HUMANS
AND THE VAMPIRES.
IN THE EARLY HALF
OF MY SECOND CENTURY,
THE WORLD ALLOWED ANOTHER
MONSTER TO RISE TO POWER.
A MAN WHO WALKED
AMONG THE HUMANS,
BUT WHOSE SOUL SNAKED
AMONGST THE DEMONS.
FUELLED BY DESPERATION AND
THE RANTS OF AN IDEOLOGUE,
THE MAN'S POWER GREW QUICKLY
INTO A FORCE
THAT COULD NOT BE CONTAINED.
THE MAN'S DARK SOLDIERS
SPREAD ACROSS THE CONTINENT,
RAPING AND MURDERING,
BUTCHERING MILLIONS,
WHILE HIS EVIL MANDATE
WAS CARRIED OUT
WITH ALARMING PRECISION.
(TRAIN WHEELS SQUEAK
ON TRACK)
(COUGHING)
(TRAIN CHUGS)
SOLDIER:
NO TALKING!
PASS WHEN READY!
QUICKLY!
MOVE ON!
SOLDIERS:
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO!
MOVE IT!
COME ON! MOVE, MAN, MOVE!
LETS GO!
MOVE IT!
RAYNE:
AND THE NAZI SCOURGE
SPREAD ITS BLACK
TENTACLES OUT
TO THE CORNERS
OF THE CONTINENT.
ENSNARING THOSE THAT RESISTED,
AND USING RACE AND RELIGION
AS A CAUSE FOR MURDER.
EVEN HERE,
ON THE EASTERN FRONT,
AT THE EDGE OF THE APOCALYPSE,
THE GERMAN ARMY
ACTS WITH IMPUNITY,
BELIEVING THEIR ACTIONS
ARE WITHOUT CONSEQUENCES,
THEIR DEBAUCHERY
WITHOUT REPROACH.
EVEN HERE THEY BELIEVE
THEY ARE SAFE
TO CARRY OUT THEIR PLANS.
THEY COULDN'T
BE MORE MISTAKEN.
FUCKING NAZIS.
COMMANDANT:
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
WHY ISN'T THIS
TRAIN MOVING?
WHERE'S YOUR SECOND?
(EXPLOSION)
(GUNFIRE)
AGH!
STOP!
(GUNFIRE)
(FIGHTING, PAINED GRUNTS)
(EXPLOSION)
DAMN IT.
AGH!
AND WHO SHALL I SAY HAS THE
HONOR OF BESTING ME TODAY?
HONOR?
THE LAST THING THIS
IS ABOUT IS HONOR.
MY APOLOGIES,
BUT THE LOCALS ARE
FINISHING UP OUTSIDE,
SO LETS JUST MAKE THIS
SHORT AND BLOODY.
(GUNSHOT)
AGH!
(FIGHTING, PAINED GRUNTS)
AHHHHH!
AGHHH...
(FOOTSTEPS THUD)
SWORDS.
NOT LIKELY.
DON'T CAUSE TROUBLE.
NATHANIEL:
VASYL!
I CERTAINLY WOULD HAVE
REMEMBERED YOU
FROM THE MEETINGS.
NATHANIEL.
YOU'VE ALREADY MET
MY PARTNERS, VASYL AND MAGDA.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYONE
MOVE LIKE YOU DO.
I BET YOU SAY THAT
TO ALL THE GIRLS.
CURIOUS THING IS,
I'M NOT SURE YOU
ARE JUST A GIRL.
ONLY THE GOOD HALF.
YOU'RE HER, AREN'T YOU?
YOU'RE THE DHAMPHIR.
THEIR COMMANDANT?
SHISH KE-BOBBED.
YOU DID A PRETTY GOOD JOB
OUT HERE.
THIS ISN'T OUR FIRST TRAIN.
LET'S MOVE!
WE'VE GOT BOXCARS FULL
OF WEAPONS TO UNLOAD.
(DOOR WHIRS OPEN)
VASYL:
WHERE ARE THE WEAPONS?
PEOPLE:
STAY CALM.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
(WHIMPERING)
THERE ARE MANY
EXTERMINATION CAMPS
IF THESE PEOPLE ARE STILL HERE
WHILE THE NEXT TROOPS COME IN,
THEY'RE DEAD.
THEN WE TAKE THEM WITH US.
LETS GET MOVING.
IT'S GONNA TAKE US HOURS.
TO THE FOREST,
THEN OUT THROUGH THE PASS
BEFORE MORNING.
RAYNE:
BORNE OF VIOLENCE,
I HAVE NEVER KNOWN FREEDOM
FROM THE DARKNESS
THAT INFECTS THE WEAK.
PART VAMPIRE, PART HUMAN;
A DHAMPHIR.
MY NATURAL AND MAGICAL
ABILITIES
ALLOW ME TO WITHSTAND
THE ELEMENTS
THAT ERADICATE VAMPIRE KIND.
I'VE WALKED THE SHADOWS
OF OUR WORLD,
MERCILESSLY DESTROYING
THE DESTROYERS,
AS HAS BEEN MY CALLING.
AS HAS BEEN MY DESTINY.
WILL I NEVER BE FREE?
(PAINED GRUNT)
I HAVE NEVER...
WHO ELSE HAS BEEN
ON THIS TRAIN?
NO ONE.
I NEED YOU TO STAY FOCUSED
RIGHT NOW.
CAN YOU STAY FOCUSED,
SOLDIER?
CAN I COUNT ON YOU TO DO
AS I SAY AND STAY CLEARHEADED?
I MEAN,
HE'S SITTING THERE
AND BY ALL RIGHTS UNDER
THE SKY OF GOD
HE SHOULD BE DEAD-
SIR?
FOCUS.
SIR.
CAN I COUNT ON YOU?
SIR!
I NEED TWO MORE MEN, ABLE
BODIED AND TIGHT-LIPPED.
YOU HAVE FIVE MINUTES,
SOLDIER,
AND I SUGGEST
YOU USE THEM.
SIR.
ARE WE EATING?
TONIGHT?
THE HEAT IS FINE.
YOU CAN'T RUSH BEANS
AND AS I SAID,
I REFUSE TO BURN
YOUR SUPPER.
EVEN WHEN
IT'S PIGS BLOOD?
YES-YES-YES-YES-YES.
I MEAN YOU DID GET ME BLOOD,
I DON'T MEAN TO BE
UNGRATEFUL.
WELL, THEN IT CERTAINLY
COMES EFFORTLESSLY TO YOU.
(CHUCKLE)
OH, A CRACK IN THE VENEER.
AND HERE WE WERE,
VASYL,
WORRIED OUR DHAMPHIR
WOULD BE JUST A HUMORLESS
KILLING MACHINE.
HOW MANY TRAINS,
DO YOU FIGURE?
AS MANY AS THEY FEEL
ARE NECESSARY.
I'VE HEARD THEY'VE COMPLETELY
EMPTIED SOME OF THE GHETTOS.
DO YOU KNOW THE ODDS
ARE AGAINST US, NATHANIEL,
THAT THE GERMANS GET STRONGER
WHILE WE DWINDLE AWAY?
WE'RE LOSING.
WHILE WE'RE OUT HERE BEING
PICKED OFF
LIKE RATS IN CAGE.
WELL, THAT'S A PARTICULARLY
CHEERFUL THOUGHT.
I KEEP THINKING ABOUT
THE PEOPLE ON THE TRAIN.
WHO WE SAVED.
AND WHAT ABOUT THE NEXT ONE
AND THE ONE AFTER THAT?
IT NEVER ENDS.
WE DO WHAT WE CAN,
IT'S AS SIMPLE AS THAT.
THE REST YOU
HAVE TO LET IT GO.
I'VE NEVER BEEN THE ONE
TO 'LET THINGS GO'.
NO,
YOU CERTAINLY HAVEN'T.
MY SAUCE IS GETTING HOT.
IS OUR DHAMPHIR
NOT STAYING?
I'VE LOST MY APPETITE.
RIGHT.
APPARENTLY I BURNED
THE BLOOD.
(MACHINE WHIRS)
SHIT.
GET OUT!
(ENGINE WHIRS)
THIS IS AN HONOR.
YOUR CAMP IS TOO DARK.
DIRECTOR:
SLOVAKIAN GENERATORS,
OR SOME SUCH NONSENSE.
I TRUST YOU RECEIVED
MY COMMUNIQUE?
OF COURSE,
SILLY MAN.
JUST A MOMENT.
(GUNSHOT)
THE DOCTOR IS IN HIS LAB.
(PAINED GRUNT)
LIEUTENANT:
DOCTOR?
OH MY GOD!
I CERTAINLY HOPE NOT.
THERE ARE A PLETHORA
OF USELESS DEITIES
TO WORSHIP,
LIEUTENANT,
IF YOU'RE SO INCLINED.
THIS IS CERTAINLY
NOT ONE OF THEM.
(EXHALES)
IS THAT A VAMPIRE?
DOCTOR:
INDEED.
OUR NIGHT PATROL
CAUGHT IT SCROUNGING
NEAR THE WEST FENCE
A COUPLE OF NIGHTS AGO.
UNPRECEDENTED HAPPENSTANCE.
I BELIEVE IT WAS A GYPSY
AT ONE TIME,
BUT WHO'S TO SAY?
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE.
WHICH IS WHY
YOU'RE ALIVE.
THESE CREATURES
NO LONGER HAVE ANY BONDS
TO THE MORAL LAWS OF MAN,
WHICH IS WHY
YOU NEVER TRUST A VAMPIRE.
(PAINED GRUNTING)
MUST YOU SAVAGE HIM
IN MY PRESENCE?
"IT", LIEUTENANT.
"IT".
I AM JUST TESTING
ITS RESILIENCY.
AND LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
I BELIEVE,
THIS CREATURE,
IS ONE RESILIENT SPECIMEN.
(SNARLING)
OUTSIDE! NOW!
I'LL BE BACK.
(EXHALES)
I HAVE NO AUTHORITY
IN THESE MATTERS,
BUT I WON'T STAND IDLY
BY WHILE YOU KILL THAT,
CREATURE, AS PART OF SOME
MANDATED EXPERIMENT OF YOURS,
DOCTOR!
THE FASCINATING CAVEAT,
LIEUTENANT,
IS THAT THEY ARE VERY
DIFFICULT TO KILL.
ONLY BY STAKE, FIRE,
SUNLIGHT, OR HOLY WATER.
THE VAMPIRE WILL STAY
RESPONSIVE FOREVER.
IT'S A MARVEL OF SCIENCE.
I AM ON THE CUSP
OF GREAT DISCOVERIES
IN THE AVENUES OF LONGEVITY.
DISCOVERIES WHOSE APPLICATION
WILL CONTRIBUTE TO THE
BETTERMENT OF THE REICH,
TO THE LEADERS OF THE REICH.
YOU SEE, I BELIEVE I CAN
MAKE HITLER IMMORTAL.
THERE'S BEEN
AN INCIDENT.
PACK A TRAVEL BAG,
WE LEAVE IN TWENTY MINUTES.
I'M SORRY MY WORK HERE
NEEDS ME TO PERSEVERE.
I HAVE TRY-
MY DEAR BOY!
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND?
TWENTY MINUTES.
(LOUD WHOOSH)
(CROWS CROW)
WELL, IT IS DONE.
NOW WE WAIT.
"WE WAIT?"
NEED RESOLVE, DOCTOR!
WHAT CAN I TELL YOU?
IT'S A SCIENCE I DON'T
UNDERSTAND -
THAT'S WHAT I CAN
TELL YOU!
I NEED TO KNOW
HOW THAT MAN -
A MAN I'VE WORKED WITH
FOR THREE YEARS, I'LL ADD,
HOW THAT MAN COULD HAVE BEEN
IMPALED STRAIGHT THROUGH
AND STILL BE ALIVE!
HE'S NOW A VAMPIRE!
I KNOW HE'S A VAMPIRE!
THEN YOU UNDERSTAND THAT
ALTHOUGH IT'S BADLY INJURED,
IT WILL EVENTUALLY HEAL
FROM HAVING THE BAR REMOVED.
I WOULD SUGGEST BEFORE
THAT HAPPENS
YOU HAVE IT IN RESTRAINTS.
OR CUT IT'S HEAD OFF.
OR BOTH.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HE'S VAMPIRE, LIEUTENANT.
NOSFERATU.
I'M RATHER SHOCKED A LIEUTENANT
IN THE FUHRER'S ARMY
IS HAVING A DIFFICULT TIME
UNDERSTANDING THIS BASIC FACT.
HE'S BEEN INFECTED,
AND THE QUICKER YOU SAY GOODBYE
TO YOUR OLD FRIEND
AND DISPOSE OF IT -
THE SAFER YOU
AND YOUR MEN WILL BE.
IT WILL BE UP AND MOVING
SOONER THAN LATER.
NOW I CAME HERE -
I PUT MYSELF OUT TO COME
HERE ON THE PREMISE
THAT YOU HAD FOUND
SOMETHING EXTRAORDINARY.
EXTRAORDINARY, LIEUTENANT!
NOW WHOEVER THAT WAS IN
ITS PREVIOUS LIFE
IS NOW A COMMON VAMPIRE.
AND THAT IN ITSELF
IS NOT EXTRAORDINARY.
NEEDLESS TO SAY,
I EXPECT A CAR, IMMEDIATELY!
LIEUTENANT:
DOCTOR!
THE ASSAULT ON THE TRAIN...
IT HAPPENED IN DAYLIGHT.
(SWARDS CLANK)
DOCTOR:
LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION,
LIEUTENANT.
THIS CREATURE THAT RAVAGED
YOUR MEN AT THE TRAIN,
DID IT MOVE
LIKE A VAMPIRE?
WELL, I DIDN'T SEE HER -
I WASN'T THERE,
BUT YES,
FROM ALL ACCOUNTS.
THEY LEFT TWO MEN ALIVE,
ALIVE LONG ENOUGH TO GIVE US
THE INFORMATION WE HAVE.
THIS CREATURE
PERPLEXES ME.
I SUGGEST WE FOCUS
ON THE MORE PRESSING MATTER.
BUT DON'T YOU SEE?
THEY'RE LINKED.
IF THIS DAYWALKER SIRED
OUR COMMANDANT,
THERE IS A GREATER
LIKELIHOOD HE SHARES
SOME OF ITS CAPABILITIES.
THIS WILL CARRY MY RESEARCH
AHEAD TENFOLD.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT
YOUR RESEARCH, DOCTOR.
I'M GOING IN.
CAUTION, ABOVE ALL.
THE CREATURE HAS HAD
MORE THAN ENOUGH TIME
TO REGAIN ITS STRENGTH
MY STUDIES INDICATE THEY BECOME
INSTINCTUALLY AGGRESSIVE.
YOU EXPECT THAT TO WORK?
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT WILL WORK.
INTO THE BREACH.
I HAVE NO IDEA.
COMMANDER?
COMMANDANT:
(GROWLS)
I CAN HELP YOU
WITH YOUR TRANSITION!
(LAUGHING)
(CHATTER AND LAUGHING)
YOU ARE A MAGICIAN,
NINOSLAVA.
MASSEUSE:
(SCREAMING)
HELP ME!
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
STAY HERE.
MASSEUSE:
(CRYING)
I WAS RELAXED!
GET OUT!
ENJOYING MY MASSAGE.
SOLDIER:
I SAID GET THE HELL
OUT OF MY ROOM!
RAYNE :
YOU MEAN HERS,
DON'T YOU?
YOU'RE JUST A NAZI TOURIST.
YOU FILTHY CUNTS,
YOU NEVER LISTEN!
(PAINED GRUNT)
(FIGHTING, PAINED GRUNTS)
AGH!
I CAN'T PUNISH YOU
FOR THE LEGIONS OF WOMEN
WHO HAVE BEEN BRUTALIZED
BY MEN,
BUT I WILL GIVE IT
MY BEST SHOT.
(PAINED GRUNT)
LET'S GO.
YOU'LL WANT TO LOCK
THAT DOOR.
GO, SHUT THE FRONT DOOR,
WE'RE CLOSING EARLY TODAY.
GO!
BUT THE GERMANS WILL KNOW
SOMETHING HAS HAPPENED.
YOU WILL LISTEN WHEN I ASK
YOU TO DO SOMETHING!
YOUR AGGRESSIVE ENCOUNTER
HAD BETTER NOT BE
PROBLEMATIC FOR ME.
PLEASANT.
CHECKMATE.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
ENOUGH.
YOU TOLD ME,
YOU ASSURED ME,
THAT YOU,
WOULD HELP ME HEAL.
YOU GAVE ME YOUR ASSURANCES!
IT'S UNKNOWN!
I ONLY KNOW
WHAT I'VE LEARNED.
COMMANDANT:
LOOK AT ME.
LOOK AT ME!
WE HAVE TO MAKE
A DECISION.
(DOOR SLAMS)
WE WILL TAKE ACTION,
IF AND WHEN I AUTHORIZE IT.
IF AND WHEN I AUTHORIZE IT!
YES SIR.
NO, NO, NO,
I GOT A PRESENT
FOR YOU.
I ALREADY HAD MY MASSAGE.
THIS IS A THANK YOU
FOR WHAT YOU DID
TO THE SOLDIER.
THIS IS ON THE HOUSE.
THANK YOU.
(BLOWS)
(MOANS)
HAVE FUN.
HOLD ON.
I HAVE INFORMATION HERR
COMMANDANT NEEDS.
REALLY?
ALL RIGHT,
FOLLOW ME
AND KEEP YOUR HANDS
IN VIEW AT ALL TIMES.
WELL, WHAT IS IT?
THE WHORE FROM
THE BORDELLO, SIR.
WELL, SPIT IT OUT, GIRL.
THIS INFORMATION IS
FOR THE COMMANDANT HIMSELF.
I WILL DECIDE WHAT INFORMATION
PASSES TO THE COMMANDANT.
I'M SORRY TO HAVE
BOTHERED YOU.
UNLESS YOU'RE PREPARED
TO BE SHOT
IN THE BACK OF THE HEAD
BY MY FRIEND I'D STOP!
GOOD.
I MAY HAVE UNDER
ESTIMATED YOUR VALUE.
I'M SURE THE COMMANDANT
WILL BE QUITE EAGER
TO HEAR WHAT
YOU HAVE TO SAY.
AND WHAT WOULD YOU WANT
FOR THIS DO DOUBT
HIGHLY CLASSIFIED,
TOP-SECRET INFORMATION?
AT THE BORDELLO,
THERE IS A WOMAN I WORK FOR.
AND I HATE HER.
I WANT TO RUN
THE BUSINESS.
I WANT HER TO GO AWAY.
AH...
A LITTLE COCK
SUCKING ENTREPRENEUR.
(GROANS)
YOU ONLY GET ONE KICK
AT THE CAN IN THIS LIFE.
(MOANING)
OH YEAH, RIGHT THERE.
YEAH, RIGHT THERE.
OH YEAH.
(MOANING)
SVETLANA:
IS THE COMMANDANT
NOT ALL RIGHT?
COMMANDANT:
I AM MORE THAN ALL RIGHT.
YOUR COMMANDANT
IS MERELY GOING THROUGH
A METAMORPHOSIS OF LATE.
A TRANSITIONAL PHASE.
TO WHAT DO I OWE
THE PLEASURE OF YOUR...
THE PLEASURE OF YOUR VISIT,
MY DEAR GIRL?
HERR COMMANDANT, I HAVE
NEWS OF THE WOMAN YOU SEEK.
I SEEK MANY WOMEN,
MY CHILD.
THERE'S TALK OF AN ATTACK
AT THE RAIL DEPOT YESTERDAY,
AND NOW THE GERMAN SOLDIER...
I KNOW SHE'S OF INTEREST.
SOLDIER?
AT THE BORDELLO,
WHERE I WORK.
I SEE.
HE NEARLY RAPED
A MASSEUSE,
AND THIS WOMAN HURT HIM.
DID SHE?
YES.
QUITE BADLY.
THE WORST, REALLY.
I SEE.
AND YOU KNOW WHERE
I CAN FIND THIS WOMAN NOW?
SHE'S STILL AT THE BORDELLO,
MEIN COMMANDANT.
THIS IS VERY GOOD NEWS.
YOU,
LOOK SO YOUNG
AND SMELL SO SWEET.
I CAN FEEL THE BLOOD MOVING
THROUGH YOUR VEIN.
FASTER...
PLEASE.
MY CHILD THERE IS ONE MORE
THING YOU CAN DO TO HELP ME.
I NEED YOU
TO HELP ME HEAL.
AGH...
(EXHALES)
YEAH.
(FIGHTING, PAINED GRUNTS)
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
COMMANDANT
SO, WE MEET AGAIN,
MY DEAR GIRL.
OR WOULD IT BE MORE
ACCURATE TO SAY,
DEAR MOTHER.
AGH!
STOP!
(GUNFIRE)
SHE MUST NOT DIE!
WE NEED HER ALIVE!
I THINK WE GOT HER.
INSIDE!
I'VE GOT IT.
GOOD.
WHAT IS THAT?
THE COMMANDANT DRAINED
YOU AN HOUR AGO.
AN HOUR, GYPSY.
(HISSES)
YES, REMARKABLE HEALING
ABILITY.
I FEEL... DIFFERENT...
STRONGER...
DOCTOR:
OH, IMAGINE HOW POWERFUL
YOU'D FEEL
IF YOU WERE IMPERVIOUS
TO THIS.
A SIMPLE TEST.
YOU'VE INHERITED HIS IMMUNITY,
HOWEVER SLIGHT.
IF YOU WERE A REGULAR VAMPIRE,
THE HOLY WATER WOULD
HAVE CRUSHED YOU HAND
LIKE PAPER-MACHE.
BUT IMAGINE IF HOLY WATER
HAD ABSOLUTELY NO EFFECT,
OR FIRE, OR WOODEN STAKE.
IMAGINE THE POSSIBILITIES.
YOUR BLOOD NOURISHED
THE COMMANDANT,
HELPED HIM WITH HIS HEALING.
A NECESSARY EXCHANGE.
WE MUST ALL MAKE SACRIFICES
TO BENEFIT THE FUHRER.
TIMES THEY ARE A-CHANGING
GYPSY.
WHY JUST YESTERDAY I THOUGHT
THE DAYWALKER WAS A MYTH,
A FIGMENT OF SCIENTIFIC
CONJUNCTURE.
BUT TODAY THE WORLD,
AS THEY SAY,
THE WORLD IN OUR OYSTER.
CHANGE IS INEVITABLE.
EVOLUTION, INEVITABLE.
THE FATHERLAND, INEVITABLE.
ROOK TAKES KNIGHT.
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO,
HERR DOCTOR?
DOCTOR?
I CAN'T HELP MYSELF,
DOCTOR...
IT'S THE DEVIL IN ME.
IT'S CURIOUS TO ME,
THIS CHANGE YOU'VE ENDURED.
I'VE STUDIED IT,
BUT I DON'T COMPREHEND
THE SCIENCE.
WHAT IF IT'S NOT SCIENCE?
WHAT IF IT'S SOMETHING
BIGGER THAN SCIENCE.
SCIENCE IS EVERYTHING!
AM I STILL YOUR FAVOURITE
SUBJECT?
YOU ARE CERTAINLY
THE MOST VERBOSE.
YOU'VE JETTISONED
YOUR HUMAN FOIBLES,
YOUR MORTAL COIL,
AS SHAKESPEARE CALLED IT.
SVETLANA:
HE SOUNDS LIKE A SMART MAN.
YOU'VE MANAGED TO SOMEHOW
BOTH EVOLVE
AND REGRESS AT THE SAME TIME.
SVETLANA:
YOU'RE CONFUSING TO ME,
I LIKE IT.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
YOU'VE BECOME SUBSERVIENT
TO YOUR PRIMORDIAL INSTINCTS.
WHAT ARE THOSE?
DOCTOR:
HUNGER, THIRST,
BLOODLUST,
SEXUAL URGE.
WITH MY NEW LIFE,
YOU'VE OBSERVED THREE
OF THE FOUR.
ARE YOU A GAMBLING MAN,
DOCTOR?
IT APPEARS THAT I AM.
SVETLANA:
TURN IT.
I KNOW,
YOU'RE DYING TO SEE
WHAT I AM CAPABLE OF,
DOCTOR.
(HISSES)
DOCTOR:
DON'T BE A FOOL.
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
(HOLY WATER SIZZLES)
(SVETLANA SCREAMS)
AGH!
AHHHHH!
EVENTS BECAME UNRULY.
YEAH, SO IT SEEMS.
COMPOSE YOURSELF,
JOIN ME UPSTAIRS.
NATHANIEL:
IT'S A FOOL'S ERRAND.
RAYNE:
I NEED GRENADES.
I WAS SURE THAT YOU GUYS
HAD GRENADES.
NATHANIEL:
IT'S A FOOL'S ERRAND AND YOU'LL
ONLY GET YOURSELF KILLED.
RAYNE:
OKAY FORGET THE GRENADES,
I-I CAN USE DYNAMITE.
WHERE IS THE DYNAMITE?
NATHANIEL:
RAYNE, STOP!
YOU'RE NOT GETTING DYNAMITE.
I'M GOING HOME,
TO SHARPEN MY KNIVES!
NATHANIEL:
YOU CAN'T RUSH
INTO A HORNETS' NEST
WHEN YOUR ONLY STRATEGY
IS TO CUT OFF HEADS.
I CREATED HIM,
NATHANIEL!
BELIEVE ME WHEN I'VE
NEVER SIRED ANOTHER
I WILL NOT START
WITH A NAZI!
YOU DON'T KNOW WHETHER
YOU'RE RESPONSIBLE.
WHEN I LEFT HIM,
HE WAS A KRAUT-KEBOB.
THIS MORNING HE WENT
TO THE BORDELLO
TO CAUSE AN ASSAULT
TO FIND ME!
I DRAINED HIM.
MY BLOOD MUST HAVE MIXED
WITH HIS.
THERE IS NO DOUBT
IN MY MIND
THAT I'M RESPONSIBLE
AND NOW I NEED TO DO
WHAT NEEDS TO GET DONE.
HE ENDS TONIGHT!
LISTEN, I'M THE FIRST ONE
TO JUMP INTO A TEMPEST,
BUT THIS IS DIFFERENT.
HE'S NOT JUST A VAMPIRE,
RAYNE, NOW HE'S A VAMPIRE
WITH AN ENTIRE GERMAN
ARMY BEHIND HIM.
NOW DESPITE HOW YOU DID
THINGS IN THE PAST,
WE NEED TO WORK TOGETHER.
WORKING WITH A TEAM USUALLY
MEANS THE TEAM DIES.
THEN THAT'S OUR DECISION
TO MAKE.
NAZI DOGS!
WE HAVE SCOUTS WATCHING
THEIR MOVEMENTS AS WE SPEAK.
WE'LL HAVE SOMETHING SHORTLY.
WE WILL HANDLE THIS.
NATHANIEL I NEED YOU TO
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING,
I NEED YOUR MEN TO UNDERSTAND,
THAT I HAVE SPENT MY WHOLE
LIFE HUNTING DOWN THE UNDEAD,
AND I PROMISE YOU
THAT IT'S ABOUT TO GET
SERIOUSLY FUCKING COMPLICATED.
GOOD.
I WAS SICK OF KILLING
JUST NAZIS.
AN UNDEAD'LL FIRE THINGS UP
AROUND HERE.
BE CAREFUL
WHAT YOU WISH FOR.
VASYL:
MAGDA WILL BE
IN POSITION SOON.
AND WHAT'RE YOU TWO UP TO?
NATHANIEL:
EFFORTS TOWARD
THE GREATER GOOD.
AND WHO'S MAGDA?
MAGDA:
(LAUGHS)
I KNOW YOU MISSED ME.
HAVE YOU BEEN WAITING
A LONG TIME?
(LAUGHS)
ARE YOU AFRAID
I STOLE SOME TISSUES?
DISTRICT LEADER:
COME COME, BE A GOOD GIRL.
DOES HE REALLY HAVE TO FEEL
ME UP EVERY TIME I NEED TO PEE?
THESE ARE TRYING MONTHS,
DEAR.
MY ASSOCIATE WANTS ME
TO ENJOY MY EVENING
WITH YOU AS MUCH I DO,
BUT THERE ARE SOME UNSAVORY
ELEMENTS LURKING ABOUT.
ELEMENTS WHO MIGHT HIDE
A WEAPON IN THAT TOILET,
(LAUGHS)
ELEMENTS WHO WOULD KILL
THE PAIR OF US
BECAUSE OF THE CLOTHES
ON OUR SKIN.
AND CLOTHES,
RARELY MAKE A MAN.
(LAUGHS)
AM I RIGHT? HUH?
BARTENDER! MORE DRINKS.
WE'RE CELEBRATING.
BARTENDER:
ON THE HOUSE.
(GLASSES CLINK)
(LAUGHS)
(GUNSHOT)
DROP IT! NOW!
I SUPPOSE TWO THOUGHTS
ARE VYING
FOR YOUR ATTENTION
RIGHT NOW.
ONE, "HOW IS MY NIGHT
GOING TO END?",
AND TWO,
"WHERE EXACTLY DID
SHE HAVE THAT GUN?"
L'CHAIM.
DURING THE DAY,
WE HAVE A BUSINESS TO RUN.
YOU UNDERSTAND.
NOW, WE WOULD VERY MUCH
LIKE TO TALK TO YOU,
ABOUT THESE CODES.
SO SHE'S A CODE BREAKER?
SHE'S ONE OF THE BEST
I'VE EVER SEEN.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF THE GERMAN'S
ENIGMA MACHINE?
SHOULD I HAVE?
NOT UNLESS YOU'RE IN
THE COMMUNICATIONS BUSINESS.
SHE CRACKED AN ENIGMA CODE,
WHICH MEANS NOTHING UNLESS
YOU FOLLOW THAT SORT OF THING.
BUT AT ANY GIVEN MINUTE,
MAGDA KNOWS THE WHERE,
THE WHEN, AND THE HOW.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE
GOT THINGS TIED UP.
I HAVE TO GO.
LOOKS LIKE WE BOTH
HAVE SOMEWHERE TO BE.
SEE YOU AROUND, RAYNE.
YEAH.
(GROWL)
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
AGH!
(THUNDER)
NATHANIEL!
NATHANIEL?
(FAST BREATHING)
AGH! (CRASH)
AGHHHHH!
AGH!
HELP ME TO CHANGE
THE WORLD.
(HISSES)
(SCREAMING)
(KNOCKING)
DON'T I HAVE TO INVITE
YOU IN?
I DON'T BELIEVE IT WORKS
THAT WAY, LIEUTENANT.
DRINK?
I DON'T HAVE THE THIRST FOR IT
I ONCE HAD, LIEUTENANT.
NOW WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU,
MEIN COMMANDANT?
AS YOU KNOW, RECENT EVENTS
HAVE RE-DIRECTED
MY EFFORTS IN THIS WAR.
WHAT ONCE WAS IS NO LONGER.
WE ARE NOW ABLE TO BRING
A NEW ARSENAL OF SKILLS
TO OUR STRATEGIES.
STRATEGIES THAT WE NEED
TO MOBILIZE
FOR THE DIFFICULT
ROAD AHEAD.
AND HOW AM I ABLE
TO BETTER ASSIST THE CAUSE?
YOUR TRACKING SKILLS,
LIEUTENANT, ARE UNSURPASSED.
I HAVE WITNESSED FANTASTIC
RESULTS
FROM YOU OVER THE YEARS.
NOT TO SOUND ABRUPT, SIR,
BUT WHAT IS IT
ABOUT MY ABILITIES,
TRACKING OR OTHERWISE,
THAT LENDS ITSELF TO A VISIT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT?
LIEUTENANT,
YOU CAN BE SO MUCH MORE.
NEVER!
AGH!
(PANTING)
CHRIST!
DON'T YOU KNOW NOT TO SNEAK
AROUND A DHAMPHIR'S LAIR?
OKAY.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
I WAS HERE?
DON'T HAVE TO BE A BLOOD-HOUND
TO FIND YOU.
I CAN'T GET WARM.
THAT WILL PASS.
IS IT DONE?
IN A FEW MINUTES,
WE WILL BE ONE,
THE LIEUTENANT AND I.
CAN HE BE TRUSTED?
(SNIFFS)
NOW MORE THAN EVER.
THIS IS THE DHAMPHIR'S SCENT,
LIEUTENANT.
FIND HER, TONIGHT.
ALIVE.
FASCINATING TRANSFORMATION.
HEIL HITLER.
THAT WAS QUITE A COLD-HEARTED
EXECUTION BACK THERE.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU
HAD THAT IN YOU.
YES.
HE PUT HIMSELF IN THAT
SITUATION
AS SOON AS HE DONNED JACKBOOTS
AND FELL INTO RANK AND FILE.
"DONNED"?
YES, DONNED.
I AM CONSIDERABLY OLDER
THAN YOU, NATHANIEL.
YES, BUT STILL...
DONNED...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO'S THAT?
IT'S VASYL,
ONE OF OUR MEN.
YOU INVITED VASYL
HERE TO MY HIDEOUT?
HE MISSES YOU.
I'M SURPRISED YOUR KIND
HAS SURVIVED THIS LONG.
AS LONG AS YOU ARE HERE,
I THINK THAT WE HAVE
A MAJOR PROBLEM.
VASYL:
STAY THERE.
RAYNE:
I BELIEVE THE COMMANDANT
IS BRINGING
HIS FREAK SHOW TO BERLIN.
VASYL:
TO CREATE AN ARMY.
RAYNE:
AN UNDEAD ARMY RUN
BY THE MAN HIMSELF.
NATHANIEL:
THEY'LL BE LUCKY TO MAKE IT
TO BERLIN.
RAYNE:
WE CAN'T JUST RELY
ON LUCK ITSELF.
(SIGHS)
WHAT'S YOUR PLAN?
WE'VE GOT COMPANY.
DHAMPHIR!
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE TO US?
TO ME?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?!
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
LIEUTENANT:
WHAT AM I?
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
NATHANIEL,
GET OUT OF HERE!
AGH!
(HISSES)
NATHANIEL:
(SHOUTS)
AGH!
(EFFORT GRUNTS)
NATHANIEL:
HEY VASYL!
RAYNE:
STOP IT!
WE NEED HIM
IN LESS PIECES.
SPEAK IF YOU CAN.
THEY WANTED ME TO FIND YOU,
TO FIND ALL OF YOU.
HE FED ON ME.
THE COMMANDANT?
HE WAS MY FRIEND...
WHY WOULD HE TAKE
YOUR BLOOD
WHEN HE HAS TRAINS
FULL OF VICTIMS
IF HE WANTED THAT?
I'M THE TRACKER.
HOW MANY HAS HE TURNED?
LIEUTENANT: I FOLLOWED HIM...
NATHANIEL: HOW MANY?!
WHERE DID YOU FOLLOW
HIM FROM?
FROM THE WHORE.
HIS SMELL WAS ON
THE WHORE'S CLOTHING.
TO THE CODE-BREAKER,
AND NOW TO YOU DHAMPHIR.
NATHANIEL:
MAGDA! MAGDA!
YOU FUCKING MURDERING
BASTARDS!
HOLD IT! WE WON'T GET
ANYTHING ELSE FROM HIM
IF HE'S DEAD!
"IF" HE DIES?!
IF THEY'VE GOT MAGDA,
THEY'VE THEY'VE GOT
EVERYTHING, RAYNE!
THEY'VE GOT ALLIED
TROOP POSITIONS,
THEY'VE GOT FUCKING
SAFE HOUSE ADDRESSES,
AGENT NAMES!
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING,
HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO MAKE IT TO BERLIN
IF I CUT OFF
YOUR HEAD?!
WHERE DID THEY TAKE HER?
NOWHERE YET,
BUT THEY WILL BE
SENDING HER
WHERE THEY ARE SHIPPING
ALL OF THE REST OF THEM.
GO! THE TAVERN!
SEND THE ALERT!
IS THAT EVERYTHING?
YEAH.
AGH!
THIS IS WHEN THE DAY
GETS UGLY.
AGH!
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(GUNFIRE)
STOP!
NATHANIEL:
MAGDA!
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
HA!
FALL BACK!
NATHANIEL:
MAGDA:
WHO'S THERE?
LET'S GET THIS OVER
WITH NAZI FILTH!
COMMANDANT:
I'VE BEEN RATHER
PHILOSOPHICAL LATELY.
I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT GREAT ARTISTS
LIKE WAGNER, OR BACH,
OR, MAYBE THE MAN WHO DESIGNED
THE CHURCH FOR THIS TOWN.
THESE GREAT ARTISTS,
THEY TRICKED THE GODS INTO
GRANTING THEM IMMORTALITY.
THEY TRICKED THE GODS.
IMMORTALITY, THAT ELUSIVE HARE
THAT OUTWITS US ALL.
BUT IN TWO HUNDRED YEARS,
I MIGHT RETURN TO THIS TOWN
AND TO GAZE UPON THAT CHURCH,
BECAUSE I AM NOW IMMORTAL,
CODE-BREAKER.
I, AM NOW THE TRICK
PERSONIFIED,
THAT HAS BEEN PLAYED
ON THE GODS.
IS THIS SUPPOSED
TO SCARE ME?
AGH!
NATHANIEL:
THIS SHOULDN'T
HAVE HAPPENED!
WE LET OUR GUARD DOWN!
WE SHOULD HAVE FUCKING
HAD HER!
RAYNE:
WE MISSED HER, NATHANIEL!
IT HAPPENS IN WAR!
PEOPLE DIE!
NATHANIEL:
DON'T YOU LECTURE ME
ON THE PRICE OF THIS WAR
AND ON HUMAN LIVES, VAMPIRE!
AND DO NOT YOU LECTURE ME
ON UNDEAD VERMIN
THAT I'VE HUNTED
ALL MY LIFE!
EMOTIONS RUN HIGH,
AND THEY SHOULD.
BUT UNLESS THE LIEUTENANT
WAS PLAYING GAMES,
I SUGGEST WE GET
TO THE RAIL DEPOT
BEFORE THE TRAIN LEAVES
WITH YOUR MAGDA
AND THOSE NAZI FUCKS
GAIN MORE GROUND.
NATHANIEL:
THE THREE OF US AND SIX MEN?
WE HAVE ONE SHOT AT THIS,
YOU KNOW.
THEN LET'S MAKE IT
UNFORGETTABLE.
HOW MANY HAVE I CUT DOWN?
HOW MANY OF THE UNHOLY
HAVE I SLAUGHTERED?
I HAVE STAINED THE CENTURIES
WITH THEIR BLOOD.
NOW THE CREATURES OF THE DARK
HAVE EMERGED
FROM THE SHADOWS,
NOW THEY WALK AMONG US,
AND TAKE THEIR VICTIMS
ON A WHIM - MAGDA.
THE INNOCENT ARE PULLED
INTO THE DARK ABYSS
BY THE WRETCHED,
AND THE CYCLE OF BLOODSHED
CONTINUES THROUGH THE AGES.
WHEN WILL WE FINALLY
COMPREHEND OUR INHUMANITY?
AS WE GAZE ACROSS
OUR BATTLEFIELDS,
FLUSH WITH CORPSES AND HEADY
WITH THE SPOILS OF WAR,
CAN WE EVER HOPE TO REALIZE
THAT WHICH WE HAVE LOST?
THE UNHOLY LURCH THROUGH
THE COUNTRYSIDE
IN SEARCH OF THEIR PREY.
PERHAPS OUR SALVATION,
OUR PEACE,
LIES ONLY IN BLOODSHED.
FOR IT IS ALL THEY
HAVE EVER KNOW.
IT IS ALL THAT I HAVE
EVER KNOWN.
I AM THE HUNTER.
AGH!
STEMPER?
THERE IS NO TRAIN.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING
GOING ON INSIDE.
VASYL:
MAGDA! THANK GOD!
(SNARLS)
RAYNE:
STOP!
COME WITH ME.
I FEEL SO MUCH STRONGER NOW.
IT ISN'T HUMAN.
COME WITH ME.
IT'S ME... MAGDA.
KILL HER.
KILL HER!
(SCREAMS)
RAYNE:
THERE'S NOBODY ELSE.
RESISTANCE FIGHTER:
IS THERE ANYTHING THERE?
NATHANIEL:
END-TO-END AND BACK AGAIN.
RAYNE:
THAT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
WHY POST GUARDS ON AN
EMPTY FACTORY?
UNLESS... MAGDA WASN'T
THE ONLY VAMPIRE CREATED!
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
(FIGHTING, PAINED GRUNTS)
RAYNE:
NATHANIEL!
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
AGHHH!
(SNARLING)
SHOOT THE WINDOW!
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOT)
DOCTOR:
SUCH A PRIZE.
BIND HER LIMBS!
TAKE HER TO MY LABORATORY.
(CRIES OUT)
COMMANDANT:
AND YOU MY DEAR BOY.
WHAT SHALL I DO WITH YOU?
COME ON, HURRY.
GET THAT STUFF UP HERE,
MOVE MOVE!
BE SURE YOU'RE
FOLLOWING THE ROAD.
OKAY. OKAY.
COME ON, FASTER.
HEY, CAREFULLY.
SOLDIER:
OKAY.
I'VE DECIDED TO TAKE YOU
WITH ME TO BERLIN.
MAYBE I'LL GET YOUR
PICTURE IN THE PAPER.
"LEADER OF THE RESISTANCE,
HANGED."
DON'T WORRY,
WE HAVE AN ABUNDANCE
OF INFORMATION
ABOUT WHERE YOUR FORCES
HAVE GATHERED.
WE'LL TRAVEL UNFETTERED.
WE MAY EVEN GET LUCKY,
AND THE FUHRER SHALL
SEE YOU HANGED.
DOCTOR:
YOU, ARE AN AMAZING SPECIMEN.
A TRUE DISCOVERY.
I'VE DRAINED YOU
FOR ALMOST AN HOUR.
YOU PRODUCE BLOOD ALMOST
AS FAST AS I EXTRACT IT.
ALEXANDER FLEMING HAD
HIS PENICILLIUM FUNGI,
I HAVE THIS.
SOON, I WILL INFUSE OUR FUHRER
WITH YOUR BLOOD.
THEN WE WILL SEE
WHAT WE GET.
(LAUGHS)
I DOUBT IT WILL HELP
HIS SMALL DICK COMPLEX.
I WILL NOT LET YOU MOCK
MY EFFORTS!
I HAVE ALL I NEED
FROM YOU.
EVEN A DHAMPHIR CAN
NOT SURVIVE A BEHEADING.
NO NO NO...
I WILL KEEP YOU
FOR EXHIBIT.
RAYNE:
UNTIE ME, IF YOU REALLY
WANT TO DANCE.
AGH!
COMMANDANT:
SOME OTHER TIME DHAMPHIR.
FOR NOW, I'M CONTENT
WITH ONLY DINNER.
(CRIES OUT IN PAIN)
(LAUGHING)
MY GOD.
SUCH POWER...
(PANTING)
STRENGTH...
I'M GOING TO ENJOY
KILLING YOU IMMENSELY.
DOCTOR!
I WANT HER AGREEABLE
FOR TRAVELLING.
IT'S TIME TO MEET HITLER,
DHAMPHIR.
(ENGINES RUMBLE)
THERE'S JUST TEN
OF US NOW.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE'VE GOT ONLY ONE OF THESE.
IF THEY REACH THE PASS,
THEY REACH BERLIN.
BUT THAT MEANS MORE NAZI'S
AND HITLER HIMSELF.
BEYOND THE RIDGE AND DOWN
THE SECOND PEAK.
WE CUT THEM OFF
BEFORE THE PASS.
(ENGINES RUMBLE)
(MOANING, HEAVY BREATHING)
(MOANING)
(ENGINES RUMBLE)
(MOANING, HEAVY BREATHING)
THE DYNAMITE IS PLANTED?
WHERE WILL YOUR BEST SHOT
BE FROM NATALIA?
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
IT IS HIGH GROUND,
WELL CONCEALED,
I'LL GET A PERFECT VIEW.
IT'LL BE A GREAT SHOT.
THEN WE DETONATE
FROM OVER THERE.
LET'S GO, GOOD LUCK.
(ENGINES RUMBLE)
(COCKS THE GUN)
(GUNSHOT)
(EXPLOSION)
AGH!
(SHOUTING)
GO GO GO!
(GUNFIRE)
NATHANIEL:
YOU OKAY?
RAYNE:
YEAH.
(GUNFIRE)
(EXPLOSION)
AGH!
(GUNFIRE)
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
DOCTOR:
WAIT!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
NO!
NO-NO-NO-NO,
THAT IS FOR THE FUHRER!
HEIL HITLER.
OH NO!
SEE YOU IN BERLIN.
(EXHALES)
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
AGH!
HA!
(GUNSHOT)
AGHHHHH!
YOU BOLSHEVIK SWINE.
AGH!
AHGHH!
(FIGHTING GRUNTS)
I AM THE PRODIGAL SON
OF THE THIRD REICH!
I AM POWER INCARNATE!
AGH!
(SCREAMS)
MOTHERFUCKER!
IT-IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT I'M...
I'M FINE...
LET'S GET HIM
IN THE TRUCK!
IT'S DONE.
RAYNE:
WE'VE GOT MORE
WORK TO DO.
(RAPID GUNFIRE, EXPLOSIONS)
(GUNSHOT)
(TRUCK RUMBLES)
WHAT IS IT?!
SIR, IT'S A TRUCK.
I SEE FOR MYSELF.
GO OPEN IT!
RAYNE:
GUTEN TAG, MOTHERFUCKERS!