MEMORIES OF
UNDERDEVELOPMENT
Based on the novel by
Edmundo Desnoes
Leading players
Directed by
Tomas Gutierrez Alea
HAVANA, 1961.
MANY PEOPLE ARE LEAVING THE COUNTRY
She'll have to work over there.
Until she finds someone stupid
enough to marry her, that is.
Frankly, she's still good looking.
She'll forget me as soon as
she finds an easy life.
I'm the one who's really stupid.
I worked to give her a soft life...
... like a New Yorker, a Parisienne,
not an underdeveloped islander.
All those who loved me...
... or nagged me right up to
the last moment...
... have already gone
For years I've wanted to find time
to write, or keep a diary.
Have I anything to say?
Everything's the same.
All the same.
Suddenly it looks like a set,
a cardboard city.
The Bronze Titan.
Cuba, free and independent.
Who'd have believed it?
No imperial eagle, but where's the
dove Picasso was going to send?
Iùs comfortable to be a communist
millionaire in Paris.
"This humanity has spoken 'enough'
and has begun to move."
They won't stop
till they get to Miami.
However, everything looks
so different today.
Have I changed, or has the city?
The moment of parting.
"Oh, abandoned, like the
wharves at dawn.
"Everything about you
was like a shipwreck."
- What are you doing?
- Can't you see?
What are you reading?
Something trite, frivolous and
superficial. "The Best of Everything."
Oh, yes, that film...
Stop looking at me...
...as if I'm some strange insect!
Letùs talk.
Whaùs biting you?
You only talk about insects lately.
Why not?
Aren't we surrounded by insects?
Isn't this country falling behind?
I say so, but what do you think?
Why? You've never been interested
in my opinions.
You're practising your English
lately. I think you want to leave.
Clear off! Leave me alone!
I like you when you become vulgar.
It always excites me...
... when I see you struggle between
elegance and vulgarity.
I've been keeping an eye on you
for some time now.
You've become rather disgusting
lately.
Because I've run out of
Yardley's brilliantine...
...and Colgate toothpaste
and after-shave lotion.
Those things help a lot,
don't they?
Yet you become more attractive
every day.
You're more artificial.
I prefer women like you
to natural beauty.
I prefer good clothes, good food,
make-up, massage.
Thanks to such things you're
no longer a slovenly Cuban girl.
I never know whether you're
serious or joking.
A little of both.
Go joke to your mother!
I can't stand living here
any longer! You stink!
Everything you said was recorded.
Every word. I'ùll be fun when
you hear it played back.
You monster! I'll smash
the recorder!
Women look into your eyes as though
wishing to be touched by your look.
Such a thing only happens here.
Maybe Italian women stare longer,
but no, not like ours.
Havana's like a country town
since "El Encanto" burned down.
To think that Havana was
"The Paris of the Caribbean."
Thaùs what tourists and whores
called her.
A Tegucigalpa of the Caribbean...
... thaùs what it looks like today.
Not only because "El Encanto"
has gone...
...and the stores are half empty...
... but because of the people.
What does life mean for them?
And what does life mean for me?
But I'm not like them.
They're making the first socialist
revolution in America. So what?
They're going back to the jungle,
hungry, like the Haitians.
They beat Napoleon, and so?
The worlds most important sugar
industry, before the revolution.
Now look what they've made of it.
Times change.
Sergio, iùs not our own problem.
Iùs between the Russians and the
Americans, nothing to do with us.
I tell you this whole thing
will blow up, Sergio.
Whichever of them throws the first
punch, we'll catch it.
Why? Because we're a tiny,
little island.
You'll catch the punch,
because I won't be here.
To think we've been friends
for over five years.
Under Batista things got to
breaking point for you.
Not me, I kept out of politics,
I have a clear conscience.
All I've ever done is work,
like an animal.
Just think of Anita. So beautiful,
yet living on a diet of black beans.
Iùs not good enough.
Yet they have the know-how to
develop the country's economy.
Yes, the know-how.
The Americans know how to
make things run properly.
- Check the oil.
- I haven't any, but I can check it.
Why bother?
I've got to hand it in
just as it was.
Iùs been inventoried. If iùs
not as it was, I can't leave.
You'll have to touch it up with
synthetic paint somehow.
You'll have to paint this part,
at least.
He says a Cuban can stand
everything except hunger.
Think how we've starved
since the Spaniards came.
In Latin America...
... four children die of malnutrition
every minute.
In ten years twenty million
children will have died.
Equal to the death roll of
the Second World War.
A symbol of decadence.
If I keep it here I don't have to
get it repaired.
Well, if you prefer walking...
No, but I feel happier.
Iùs a way out of problems.
They say the latest American cars
are incredible.
I was reading a magazine
Julio lent me.
Sealed engines, two spark plugs,
a two year guarantee.
If it breaks down they give you
another one.
Thaùt's the only answer to
our mechanics.
People are becoming more stupid.
- Pablo's right: The French stink.
- They're just naturally dirty.
I don't care if they confiscate
the lot.
Iùs all the same to me.
But I'm not staying safe indoors,
like when they fought Batista.
Truth is, I never thought
they'd topple him.
I must do something now, or I'll be
lost when this thing blows over.
That'ùs what the Bay of Pigs
prisoners said.
THE TRUTH OF THE GROUP
IS IN THE MURDERER
We found, in the invaders' military
organization, a social structure...
... reflecting the social structure
and morality of the bourgeoisie.
The priest.
The free enterprise man.
The dilettante official.
The torturer.
The philosopher.
The politician.
And many sons of good families.
Each of them had specific duties...
... yet it was the whole, the group...
... which gave meaning to
each individual activity.
CalviÒo was a murderer who even
horrified the bourgeoisie.
The housecoat I wore
is still bloodstained.
He kicked my stomach and I bled.
But that wasn't enough for him.
Because I struggled...
...they broke two of my vertebrae.
They hit him with sticks.
You hit him, too. He fell
on his knees...
... you kicked him in the side.
Then he fell down. Do you remember?
You abused him even after
he was dead.
You shot him, then laughed
at the way he died.
On October 6th, at 7 PM...
Do you deny it?
Do you deny...
...nine days after you had
killed Morua...
... you boasted about it?
- Do you deny it?
- I can't answer
In all capitalist societies...
... the same type of man is at
the disposal of the bourgeoisie.
In the moral division of work...
... the murderer enables others
to exist...
... others not in direct contact
with death...
... who, as individuals, wish to
keep their souls clean.
Speaking for myself and
those like me...
... maybe a minority...
... we're not like Ventura, or those
other miserable creatures.
I didn't even know CalviÒo then.
I lived my own life.
They're like disjointed elements of
a whole which no one fully admits.
I can't answer for the others.
Everyone answers for himself.
It seems that you want to accuse me...
... of being the instigator of
the invasion.
I insist my mission was
purely spiritual.
I have never handled a weapon.
Being mixed up in a conspiracy
doesn't make one a conspirator.
As I've told you, I've always
taken a neutral stand.
I'm apolitical; never had anything
to do with a political party.
One's personal behaviour excuses
one from general responsibility.
Everyone concentrates on himself
to escape contamination by others.
Or else, by sinking into the group
to mask his own responsibility...
... he divides his guilt with others.
I wasn't the only one in the group.
Conversely, the group may be
disowned...
... when its members wish to
avoid responsibility.
You're talking about the group's
idea, not mine.
But the idea of group
responsibility...
... is the murderer-torturer's
haven, his claim to moral innocence.
Listen, I've committed no
direct crime, I tell you.
But none of the cases considered...
... shows the dialectic relationship
between individual and group.
None of those who came with
CalviÒo...
... see that they're part of a system
which entangles them in their acts.
In the accounts of landowner
Freyre...
... in the extreme unctions of
Lugo...
... in the reasonings of
philosopher Andreu...
... in the dismissals of
dilettante Rivero...
... in Varona's "representative
democracy"...
... who could divine the death
they'd help spread over Cuba?
Death by starvation, by sickness...
... by torture, by frustration.
She cleans the apartment
three times a week.
She's been coming for a year
and I never noticed her.
She'd be attractive if she troubled.
She's as thin as a Vogue model.
I like her.
She's a Protestant.
A Baptist, I think
Were you baptized in a river?
What happened?
Well...
Is it a secret?
We gathered by the river...
...the pastor and I entered the water
and he told me the meaning of baptism.
For us, baptism symbolizes
the death of sin...
... the resurrection of a new life,
full of faith, hope and dignity.
Then he immersed me in the water.
You've no idea how frightened I was.
But it was all over so quickly.
All that worry and fuss for nothing.
Almost everyone's an exhibitionist.
I see people as weak, almost
hairless animals, on two legs.
Someone said that man's intelligence
and physical imperfection...
...are because he's the premature
foetus of a monkey.
At an exquisite moment...
... between 30 and 35, Cuban women
lose their looks.
They are fruits which rot
at an amazing speed.
The rule of the Yankee empire...
... having been ended by the
triumph of the Revolution...
... their Guantanamo Base
is now a spy centre.
Our cameramen...
... film some of the provocations...
... by military personnel and
counter-revolutionaries hiding there.
You have beautiful knees.
- Will you have dinner with me?
- Are you crazy?
No, I just don't like eating alone.
Are you waiting for someone?
Your boyfriend?
Are you crazy?
Iùs dangerous to wait around alone
at your age.
You are crazy.
No, look... really...
Why not have dinner? I get
indigestion if I eat alone.
I'm waiting for someone from the
film company. I'm having a film test.
I have a friend there. An important
director, I believe.
In the film company?
I'll introduce you to him,
if you like.
- What'ùs the time?
- About six-thirty.
He's late. He won't come now.
Won't you have a drink?
I mustn't. I'm having injections
for my nerves.
Why do you want to act?
I'm tired of always being the same.
I want to be someone different
without people thinking I'm crazy.
I want to develop my personality.
But all those characters
are like scratched records.
An actress just keeps
repeating everything.
The same movements, the same words,
thousands of times.
Where did you get them?
We found them. They're cuts
made by the old censor.
The outfit we had before
the Revolution.
They refused to pass such scenes.
They said they offended morals
and good taste.
So they had their moral
preoccupations, too.
At least they worried about
keeping up a front.
- What will you do with them?
- I might use them.
As a sort of collage,
a bit of everything.
- It will need to have some meaning.
- It will. You'll see.
Will they release it?
Have you acted before? In the
theatre, or on television?
No, I had no luck.
Have you studied drama?
Well, I did intend to
take some classes...
Well, just complete that form.
Aren't you going to audition me?
I can sing, too.
If you say so... Well?
Are you sure iùs no?
What a beautiful house.
Do you like it?
Don't think we'll do anything.
That'ùs where I live. Come on.
- I don't...
- Don't what?
- What about your wife?
- I told you, I'm divorced.
- Even so, what about the neighbours?
- Well, if you don't trust me...
What'ùs wrong then?
Well, you go up first.
Top floor, apartment K-L.
Make yourself at home.
I'll make some coffee.
My parents... and my ex-wife, Laura.
They left on the same day.
And you?
Aren't you leaving?
No, I'm all right here.
Are you a revolutionary?
What do you think?
Neither revolutionary
nor counter-revolutionary.
Well, what am I?
You're nothing.
- They'll send you things.
- What for?
They could send nice shoes...
maybe even a car.
Laura had a figure like yours
You can look at her dresses
You can have them, if you like.
Look at them, anyway.
Perfect!
You must fasten it up.
Come along now, don't cry.
You've ruined me.
We've done nothing wrong.
What shall I tell mama?
Don't tell her anything.
I'll come with you if you like.
No thanks, I'd rather be alone.
Call me.
Thanks to such things you're
no longer a slovenly Cuban girl.
I never know whether you're
serious or joking.
A little of both.
Go joke to your mother!
I can't stand living here
any longer! You stink!
Everything you said was recorded.
Every word. I'ùll be fun when
you hear it played back.
You monster! I'll smash
the recorder!
Let me go! I never want to
see you again!
I'm leaving... alone. I don't
want you to come with me.
Leave me?
Find some other woman,
more to your taste!
I won't be a guinea pig for
your whims and games!
I'm going to live my own life!
I'm getting old!
I don't want to be with you!
I'm leaving!
Before your lips confirmed
you loved me...
... I already knew it, I knew it!
All right now?
I thought you felt bad.
I'm all right now. I'll help you
prepare lunch, if you like.
- What'ùs the matter?
- Nothing's the matter with me.
Go, say it! It couldn't last!
Iùs all over! You don't love me
any more!
Nice?
Why did you cry last night?
- Don't make fun of me.
- I'm not.
You are, you don't have any feelings.
You don't have to criticize
the way I live...
One thing about people
that upsets me...
... is their inability to sustain
something without collapsing.
Take Elena...
... she was totally inconsistent.
Didn't relate things.
Thaùs a symptom of underdevelopment.
The inability to relate things,
to gain experience, develop.
Iùs difficult here...
... because women are conditioned
by sentiments and culture.
A soft environment. People waste
talents on inconsistent adaptations.
They always need someone
to think for them.
I hope to see you soon, Sergio.
No, I'm already familiar with
the States.
What will happen here is the mystery.
Everyone knows what will happen.
Well, I don't. I really don't.
It won't be like the Bay of Pigs.
Maybe not, but it might have
interesting results.
Right, but I'd rather be
on the other side.
You'll be safer.
And you'll be able to see old friends.
I know what you mean, but there are
decent people among them.
So they say.
Whatever they say, I've got
a clear conscience.
You, yes.
Was I like him?
Possibly.
The Revolution is my revenge on
idiots like Pablo, at my own risk.
I know Pablo isn't Pablo,
he's my own life.
Everything I don't want to be.
Good riddance.
Like vomiting them up.
I keep my mind clear.
A disagreeable emptiness.
I can't prevent whaùs happening
to me: Him, Laura, everyone.
Francisco de la Cuesta lived here.
We were eight or ten years old.
Where is Francisco now?
Does he remember our pranks?
I try to and I can't.
At school the priests were
always right.
They had the power.
I'd done nothing...
Then I understood the relationship
of Justice and Power.
Armando's father was a freethinker.
Every week he'd give him a peso
to go to a brothel.
He took me to a woman who charged
50 cents; told her to be nice to me.
But I couldn't do anything with her.
I had to find another.
After that I went every week.
Suddenly I discovered that Elena
didn't think like me.
I expected more of her. I thought
she was complex and interesting.
I'm Europeanized.
Elena forces me to feel
underdeveloped.
I tried to change Elena,
but, like Laura...
... she doesn't understand, she has
a different world in her head.
She doesn't see me.
A TROPICAL ADVENTURE
Hemingway shot this gazelle
on his last trip to Africa.
That was in 1953.
He made that trip with Mary,
his fourth wife.
It is one of the fastest
gazelles in Africa.
He said he killed it to avoid
killing himself.
But finally he couldn't resist
the temptation.
He made several trips to Spain
as war correspondent...
Is this where Mr. Way used to live?
What'ùs special about it?
Books and dead animals.
Just like the American houses
in Preston.
The same furniture, the same
American smell.
- What'ùs an American smell?
- I don't know... you sense it.
Do you like the smell of Russians
best, or Americans?
Leave me alone! I don't know
anything about politics.
The tropics.
Backward countries...
... where you kill animals...
... fish and sunbathe.
And there: "the beautiful
Cuban seÒorita"!
"I'll ever fear anything again",
Macomber said to Wilson.
"Something happened inside me when
I saw the first buffalo.
"Like a dam bursting.
It was pure excitement."
As if chasing a buffalo would
conquer fear.
Anyway, there are no buffaloes
in Cuba.
He conquered fear of death, but
couldn't stand fear of life...
...at a time when the world was
beginning to get too big.
Why did you go away?
You were amusing yourself.
Do you mind?
You don't care.
You don't care about me.
About anything.
This is Hemingway's private study.
He could always be found at
this typewriter.
He never sat down to write.
He'd get up very early and work
till 11 or 11.30.
Few people were allowed into this
room. I was one of them.
I would move about very quietly...
Rene Villarreal.
He was a guttersnipe when
Hemingway found him.
I read that somewhere.
He moulded him to his need:
Faithful servant and great lord.
Colonialist and Gunga Din. Hemingway
must have been insufferable.
This was his refuge, his tower,
his tropical island.
Big game hunting, American
furniture...
... Spanish photos, books in English,
a bullfight poster...
Cuba never really interested him.
It was his refuge, guest house,
base for fishing in the Gulf Stream.
ROUND TABLE: LITERATURE
AND UNDERDEVELOPMENT
Culture in an underdeveloped
country...
...is the sometimes painful
and costly operation...
...by which people become aware of
the possibility...
...of changing social conditions...
...writing their own history...
...and select the most fertile
of their traditions...
...to bear fruit in the conditions
created by national liberation.
We are only a few steps away from
being negro cooks and janitors.
I discovered I was a "spick", a
derogatory term for Latin-Americans...
...negroes and other inferior people.
Although I look like a white,
Anglo-Saxon Protestant...
...I'm really a southern negro.
All Latin-Americans are negroes,
discriminated against, oppressed...
...ignored outsiders in the swindle's
pretensions of universitality...
...the American way of life, the
great white dream of the U.S.A.
Now iùs the turn of
the devil's advocate.
He who piles doubt upon doubt...
...and asks you:
Don't you realize, the words
you are using...
...underdevelopment,
underdevelopment...
...are sick, or at least ailing?
Don't you realize that these
may be language traps...
...accessories of an already
wasted culture...
...a stratagem, a linguistic alibi...
...a linguistic-ideological
arrangement...
...leading to the tranquillity
of formulas?
Iùs useless to flee the linguistic
continent of underdevelopment...
...and forget that the basic
contradiction of our times...
...is not the contradiction...
...between North American imperialism
and underdeveloped continents...
...but the contradiction between
the impetuous development...
...of the productive forces
of the whole world...
...and the forms and relationships
of capitalist production.
Between the socialist revolution...
...and the final imperialist phase
of capitalism.
To take one of your examples...
...the basic contradiction between
the proletariat and capitalism.
I believe that what you have said
is a complete abstraction.
The embodiment of the basic
contradiction...
...takes the form of war.
For me, the basic contradiction
at this moment...
...is not between European
proletariates and capitalists...
...but it is in the areas where
war exists...
...there we see the basic
contradiction, as in Vietnam.
The sole basis of this discussion...
...rests on whether the
basic contradiction...
...is one thing or the other.
On pure Marxist grounds...
...I agree with you, but the
embodiment is something else.
Who are you up there,
with that cigar?
You feel pretty important; you
don't have much competition here.
Outside Cuba, you'd be nobody;
here you're well placed.
Who's seen you, Eddy? Who sees you
now, Edmundo Desnoes?
I'll translate what Jack Gelber
just said.
I don't understand...
The American was right.
None of that helped. Words devour
words and leave you in the clouds.
How does one get rid of
underdevelopment? Iùs difficult.
It taints everything.
What are you doing, mixed up
in all this, Sergio?
You've nothing in common with them.
You're alone.
In underdevelopment things are
forgotten, people are inconsistent.
But you remember too many things,
too much.
Where's your family, your work,
your wife?
You're nothing. You're dead.
Now, Sergio, your final destruction
begins.
Iùs always the same with mother's
letters: Gum and razor blades.
I use an electric razor.
All I asked for was books.
I can't read her writing.
They're crazy. We don't
understand each other.
Hanna was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Escaping Hitler, they landed in Cuba.
Hanna was more of a woman than the
underdeveloped girls here.
How long were we together?
I can't remember; the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Why did I let her go?
When they left for New York
we were engaged.
Not that we believed in convention.
I planned to settle in New York
with her.
I wanted to be a writer.
Hanna was the one person
who believed in me.
She'd help me.
Then father gave me a
furniture store.
I worked like mad for two years.
"Hanna, darling, I can't leave now.
Please understand.
"I don't want to arrive
empty-handed."
Hanna, darling...
One day it was too late...
I'll always look for you.
Where are you now?
What do you think of me?
Stop right here.
- Surname?
- Carmona.
- Middle name?
- Bendoiro.
- First name?
- Sergio.
- Occupation?
- None.
- Don't you work? How do you live?
- From apartment rents.
An ex-landlord.
- Age.
- 38.
- Nett income?
- 600 pesos.
- Income from rest of family?
- I live alone.
- Do you pay Urban Reform?
- No.
- When did you last pay it?
- I never have.
This apartment, are you the owner,
illegal occupier?
I'm the owner.
- Any embargo?
- No.
How many square metres? Roughly.
Iùs pretty big.
Letùs say 100 to 200 square metres.
- Want to measure it?
- No, I'll take your word.
Leùts say 300. We can always
correct it afterwards.
Type of construction: Brick.
Now, concerning these apartments...
- How many rooms each?
- Bedroom and study.
- Servants' quarters?
- Two rooms.
- How many toilets?
- Letùs see now... five.
- Baths?
- Three.
There are two lifts.
State of upkeep: Good.
Sign here.
- What'ùs it all about?
- Iùs just a sort of check.
If anything's out of order
we'll let you know.
You can't turn there,
go straight ahead.
Don't bother, I'll get out here.
In the midst of all this
I'm living off rents.
I've got some 12 or 11 years
to go yet.
Iùs two years since they took over
my apartment block.
Everything's either too early
or late for me.
Once I might have understood
these going on.
But not now.
I'm 38 and I'm an old man.
I don't feel wiser, or more mature.
I'm more stupid, more rotted away.
Like rotten fruit, like refuse.
It may be something to do with
the tropics.
Everything ripens and decomposes
quickly; nothing endures.
I'm old already.
Since 13 I've been to brothels.
At 15 I was a genius.
At 25 I owned a store.
Then Laura.
My life...
... is like a sterile ornamental
plant.
I have a certain dignity.
You Sergio?
I'm Elena's brother.
Is she ill?
She's never ill. Iùs something else.
She says you took advantage of her.
You've ruined her.
Iùs not something to be paid off
with dresses.
She says you promised to marry her,
then took advantage...
I should have known Elena was
capable of anything.
I didn't want trouble.
I was willing to marry her.
I was afraid.
Tell him what you told mother.
You deceived me.
You said you'd give me some dresses...
...then you took advantage of me.
If you say so.
But you know iùs untrue.
You're no virgin...
Show respect! My sister's no whore,
damn it!
How could I get involved in this?
I resigned myself.
I'd let myself be dragged along.
I was afraid.
Girls must go to the altar as virgins!
Iùs their greatest treasure!
Women are liberated now.
Don't talk like a revolutionary,
because you're not!
I won't be forced. If I marry
iùs because I want to.
Why did you want to get rid of me?
Iùs not that, Elena. I'll marry you.
Iùs just that I need to think...
Think about what?
I've got to make arrangements,
haven't I?
I must get my divorce papers.
Yes, madam, I'm divorced.
Why did you have to bring her?
That night when she came home,
her panties were bloodstained...
That'ùs not true!
I'm sure she wasn't a virgin.
What will they get out of this?
Any statement?
Iùs all untrue.
I didn't assault her: She consented.
It wasn't rape.
The accused, Sergio Carmona...
...planned to seduce Elena
Josefa Doredo, aged 16...
...and with that intent took her
to his apartment...
...at Linea, Vadado...
...where he abused her virginity...
...although aware that she was
mentally disturbed...
...therefore incapable of resisting.
Have you anything to say?
Address the attorney.
Do you know Elena Josefa Dorado?
Answer to the bench.
- Where did you meet her?
- On 23rd Street, in Vedado.
Did you take her to your apartment
and have sexual intercourse?
Tell me, before the night
in question...
...did the plaintiff confess to you
any previous experience...
...sexual intercourse with
another man?
No, never.
I was the only one to give coherent
evidence. That finished me.
It was as if I'd duped a
"poor unfortunate."
It was to give me some of
his wife's dresses.
She's left the country.
Now everything's "the people."
Before, they'd have been the guilty
ones and I the respectable one.
The bastard has the nerve...
Did you threaten Sergio's life?
If he didn't marry her.
You threatened him. What did he say?
He said he'd make arrangements, but
in the end he didn't marry her.
When was Elena taken to the doctor?
Well, according to mother...
I don't know exactly...
Mother says it was some months before
all this happened...
Do you know what the doctor said?
And the results of the tests?
Then came the verdict.
The accused, Sergio Carmona...
... invited Elena Josefa Dorado,
aged 17...
... for a walk on the evening of
25th January, 1962...
...and during said walk they went
to the home of the accused...
... located at Linea, where they
had sexual intercourse.
Tests show no evidence of the girl
being mentally disturbed...
...nor that she was insane or
unaware of her conduct.
Secondly, the accusations by
the district attorney...
...are as set out in folios
six and seven.
Thirdly...
... the defence has denied all
the district attorney's charges...
... pleaded for the acquittal
of the accused...
...and dimissal of the case,
with costs.
Finally...
... on the facts as proved...
... there is no evidence to sustain
the charge of rape.
Upon consideration of the above...
...and with regard to Articles
142, 240, 741 and 742...
...of the Social Defence Code and
the Criminal Prosecution Law...
...our verdict is that we hereby
absolve the accused...
...of the crime of rape as charged
by the district attorney.
A happy ending, as they say.
Justice triumphed for once.
But is that so?
I'm left in a bad situation;
I'm too educated to be innocent.
They're too ignorant to be guilty.
I just hope they haven't
locked her away.
MORE PLANES AND WARSHIPS
TO FLORIDA
KENNEDY RETURNS SUDDENLY
TO WASHINGTON
YOUNG MOTHER HAS TRIPLETS
DOG WITH TWO HEARTS
TRADE UNIONS COMPETE FOR
OUTPUT
PUT THIS UP ON THE NOTICE BOARD
WHERE YOU WORK
HOW TO PREVENT TETANUS
MOST CASES ARE FATAL
ANTI-TETANUS INJECTION IS
THE ONLY PROTECTION
THE THOUGHTS OF MAO TSE-TUNG
Attempting to resolve ideological
problems, rights or wrongs...
... by administration or repression,
is not only useless, but harmful.
For the safety of customers who
come to the shop below...
...as well as for the sake of
the tenants...
... why doesn't somebody
repair our balcony?
Seven times I've reported it
to the authorities.
She brought me a stack of photos
taken at her baptism.
It wasn't at all as I imagined.
The robe didn't cling to her body.
There were many people.
I hadn't thought of them, the
witnesses who are everywhere.
People are ready to die, without
considering who's to blame.
What if it all starts?
No good protesting. I'd die, too.
This island is a trap.
We're small, and too poor.
Iùs an expensive dignity.
We definitely reject any intention
of an enquiry...
...any inspection of our country.
Nobody inspects our country.
We know what we're doing.
We know how to defend our integrity
and our independence.
They threaten us with talk of
a nuclear attack.
That doesn't scare us.
We know the age we live in...
...and we must learn how to live
in it, with dignity.
All of us, men and women...
we are all one!
In this hour of danger...
...every one of us, revolutionaries
and patriots...
...share the same peril...
...and victory shall be for all.
Our country or death! We shall win!