TV VOICE: Thirty-six hours ago,
an American B-52 bomber...
... crashed into the Mediterranean Sea.
Moments before impact,
the bomber's crew jettisoned...
... a 50-megaton nuclear warhead.
The bomb capable of leveling
a major city...
... has been lost at sea.
Now underway is the greatest
naval search in human history.
What do you think?
Should be you out there.
PRISONER:
I'm the best diver in the Navy.
Hell, you ain't in the Navy.
You are a damned deserter.
AWOL. AWOL.
Years ago, a man
go on a bender like that...
...they'd pin a medal on him
and take him for a blowjob.
Instead, you got your ass kicked
by a couple of Marines.
Ornery son of a bitch.
Friend of yours.
Looks like chief here
is a nigger-Iover.
Asshole, now you're going
to address me as master chief...
...or I'll snap your goddamn wrist.
You read me?
- You ain't a master chief no more.
- You trifling me, motherfucker?
- Trifling me?
- Sorry, master chief!
Thank you!
Carl.
MOTHER:
Come on, Carl.
Turn off Daddy's radio
and get ready for school.
(RADIO PLAYS IN BACKGROUND)
(HORSE WHINES)
Come on, Jane.
Get ahold, John.
Way to go, John.
Come on. Come on!
Get up there, Jane. Come on.
Come on. Good girl.
Go, John.
Move in, Jane.
You best come in now.
I told Doc Maddox
I'd be done by Friday and I will.
- Daddy, you acting like...
- This was my farm?
No, son. No matter how hard I work,
I ain't never gonna own this land.
I heard you and Mama talking.
You'll lose the farm
if this wheat ain't in on time.
Doc Maddox'll bring in a family
where the kids work too.
My kids go to school.
Now go on before you're late.
I'm not going to school, Daddy.
Not today.
Not till this field is done.
This field ain't ever gonna be done.
Today is Friday.
MAN:
Come on. Good boy. Good girl.
There you go.
Make me a promise.
Sir?
Don't end up like me.
All right.
Best get moving.
Rain coming in.
Ready, Jane, John.
Get up there. Come on now.
Stay the hoe, John.
Get the hoe, John.
CARL:
Get that hoe, Jane.
Get the hoe, Jane!
Get up there!
Come on, Carl. You'll miss the bus.
Let's go, son.
Your father's waiting on us.
NAVY RECRUITER: The U. S. Navy is a
big opportunity for a young man.
We got hot showers.
We got three square meals a day,
unlike the Army...
And I can keep this.
They're just giving it to me.
CARL:
I wish I knew what I was gonna be.
Knowing you,
it's gonna be something big.
He ain't said not one word
since we left the recruiter.
- He's just real scared for you.
- Coloreds now.
- I love you.
Recruiter say first leave's September.
I wouldn't believe everything
that recruiter says.
Put it away for a rainy,
or send it home to Mom and Pop.
I'll come back, help mow the hay.
Don't. Don't ever come back here.
You get in there and fight, Carl.
Don't take promises.
Bust the old rules, if you have to.
And when it gets hard...
...and it will...
...don't quit on me.
Ever.
Now, go on.
Don't come back here.
Not for a long time.
Charge it when you get
where you're going.
"ASNF."
What's that supposed to mean?
Come on, boy.
You got a big future...
...in the U.S. Navy.
A big future.
Tell that recruiter,
to take his crystal ball...
...and shove it directly up his ass.
I just got back from fighting a war,
making the world free for democracy...
...and they still got me slaving
over a hot grill next to you.
There's only three choices
a colored man has in the Navy.
- What, chief?
- A cook...
...officer's valet...
- Listening, Carl?
...or getting the fuck out of the Navy.
Big future.
- Big future, I'll be doggone.
- It'll be all right.
Hot, hot, hot.
JUNIE: Hell ain't got nothing
on the South Pacific.
(SAILORS YELLING AND SPLASHING)
Hold that.
Carl, what the hell are you doing?
Reckon I'm gonna take a swim.
Nigger, you're crazy.
Tuesday is colored swim...
Well, I'm hot on Friday.
Those crackers see
that nappy head...
What are they gonna do?
Make me wash more dishes?
SAILOR:
Someone's confused here.
Better get your ass off this deck.
SAILOR:
Hey, it's not Tuesday, son.
What the hell you doing, boy?
SAILOR:
Wrong day, asshole.
All right, make way.
(SAILORS YELLING)
Captain wants you back
on the boat now.
(SAILORS YELLING)
- He'll beat you!
- Go, Carl!
You got anything to say for yourself?
Your response is noted.
You ever hear
of the Search and Rescue Swimmers?
- Sailor falls overboard, they...
- Dive in and save him. Yes, sir.
You just became one.
I'm transferring you to their unit.
You're the fastest swimmer on this
ship and have the balls to back it.
Thank you, sir. I'll pack up
and report to the deck department...
You're just there to swim,
nothing else.
Stay with the stewards.
Let him out.
The only reason your ass ain't in the
brig is because you're high yellow.
Boy, you're in good
with Captain Pullman now.
Put in a good word for me
so I can drive the boat.
CARL: You won 't believe it, but I made
seaman, which is a glorified deckhand.
I'm not sure what I'll be,
but I'll make you proud of me.
Dad, the mail chopper's here,
so I better get topside.
Give Mom a big hug for me.
Your loving son, Carl.
(BILLIE HOLIDAY SINGS IN BACKGROUND)
Afternoon, chief.
(CRASHING SOUND)
FIRST MATE: The mail chopper clipped
a radiomast. He's down!
CAPTAIN OVER LOUDSPEAKER:
Mail chopper portside.
Diver, now!
Tell him I want him up alive!
SAILOR:
Diver's coming up!
(CHAIN HOISTING DIVER UP)
Faster. Pull him up.
Pull him up.
Faster! Faster!
Brashear, get on that steadying line.
Lay back into it. Keep it steady.
Steady.
(DIVER BREATHING BEHIND MASK)
Bring him in.
Let's get him up! On the hatch.
Facedown.
Goddamn! If I'd been a few minutes
earlier, he'd be breathing now.
You did your best, Chief Sunday.
Lieutenant Hanks.
Complete the diving operation.
HANKS:
The copilot is still in the water.
It's your turn, bring him home.
Take Chief Sunday to the chamber
for decompression.
Lay back. On the side.
Diver coming up and over.
- Chief?
- Cut the weight. Drop the weight!
LOUDSPEAKER: Man overboard.
- Stand by.
- What the hell's going on?
- We lost Caughlin, sir.
- Standby's going in.
- We can't wait. Look at him.
What are you doing?
I've got a man on.
I'll bounce dive,
put him on a rescue line.
- Bounce dive?
- I've done it before.
You can't. He's too deep.
And you will call me "sir"!
Goddamn it, I got a man dying, sir!
Give me a wrench, a spare lifeline
and an air hose!
I've lost two men, another drowning.
I won't let you commit suicide.
- Stand fast.
- He'll be dead before you get him!
- Sir, the air...
- Stand off!
You will lose if you touch that water.
Do you hear me?
Yes, sir!
Goddamn it!
Master Chief Sunday,
you sustained a serious embolism.
Embolism.
Both lobes of the lungs
were severely scarred.
Can't cheat the laws
of nature forever.
I'm afraid the condition
is totally inoperable.
Ain't that a bitch.
So, what happens next time I dive
and take on pressure?
Any increased pressure
at all will kill you instantly.
Kill me? Goddamn. For a minute,
I thought this was serious.
- Keep your voice down.
- Hell, no. I feel like singing.
- Fuck.
- Where are you going?
To celebrate. You had me going.
I thought I couldn't dive no more.
- You're scaring the patients.
- How about me?
Goddamn! Hey, I got an idea.
Maybe you could use me around here.
I'm looking to make a career move.
Maybe you could get someone
to change the bedpans.
Change the bedpans!
DOCTOR:
Chief!
Change a fucking bedpan!
Master Chief Sunday, given
your current physical condition...
...and the far graver issue
of recent acts of misconduct...
(MEN LAUGH)
...you will be medically disqualified
from diving...
...fined 1/2 month's pay
for 3 months...
...and reassigned
to a training position...
...where it is my greatest wish...
...that you will embrace
a newfound respect for authority.
This hearing is concluded.
That's what I want to be, sir.
- A Navy master diver?
- Yes, sir.
Last week, you were a cook.
- The man I just saw...
- The man you saw is a master chief.
That's the highest rank an enlisted
man can achieve in the Navy.
Lot of good men spend
their career trying and fail.
Besides...
...they're not going to take a colored
at diving school. It's that simple.
What if you personally
recommended me, sir?
I just made you a deck seaman
three days ago.
What else do I owe you?
The way I see it...
...I owe you, sir.
I'll endorse your request.
But it ain't gonna work.
Wait outside.
(MUSIC PLAYS ON CAR RADIO)
Well, look at Mr. Navy.
Bell-bottoms bleached.
Shoes all shined up.
Now all we need is an organ grinder.
Welcome to Bayonne, New Jersey.
Pimple on God's ass.
Chief Sunday, we never met,
but I served with you.
U. S. S. Hoist.
I expect I remember you now.
So, what's for chow, Cookie?
I wouldn't know, chief.
I'm reporting for diving school.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
They say you wrote over 100 letters
requesting admission.
You got you some grit, you have.
Yes, sir.
Fucking gonna be a hot one today.
Hope you're better
than the last cook.
Man's food could kill your dog.
Chief.
Had anything to drink today?
No, sir, chief.
Say we go into town
and get us a nice cold one.
I can't do that, chief.
I haven't reported for duty.
I'll tell you what.
I'll buy you a tall one over there.
A bus ticket too.
So you can go on back to whatever
burrow you sprang from.
What do you say?
Sir, I am a Navy man.
Where I come from
there are no oceans...
...only dirt farms and ornery mules.
And no self-respecting Navy man
makes a living driving mules.
Sir.
You know what the Chinese say?
Beware what you wish for.
Let him in.
I stole the pot!
Get in. Hoist away.
Don't stare at him.
- Who is he?
- Commanding officer.
Everyone calls him Mr. Pappy.
He's a war hero.
They were going to make him an admiral
in D. C...
...before they found out he has more
screws loose than a Studebaker.
So they sent him here.
Better salute him, or you'll spend
your first night in the brig.
I'll show you the barracks.
SAILOR:
Attention on deck!
Gentlemen...
...in 1948, President Truman had
the courage and enlightenment...
...to desegregate
the United States military.
I want you to welcome Bayonne Diving
School's first colored trainee...
...Boatswain's Mate Second Class
Carl Brashear.
I don't hear anyone welcoming
Boatswain's Mate Brashear.
Master chief.
No disrespect to the president...
...but I don't bunk with niggers.
- Aren't you going to go too?
- No.
I'm from Wisconsin.
Never been there.
Rise and shine, Cookie.
Time for training.
Are you familiar with the principle
of Boyle's Law?
The what?!
I didn't hear your answer!
Come on, Cookie. Get up.
At a constant temperature...
...the volume of a confined gas
varies conversely with its pressure.
Why is this law important in diving?
I don't know, chief!
That's because you're just
some dumb nigger from Podunk.
I know you. Your smell hung
in every damn shack I ever lived in.
Your face staring
when we had to leave...
...because your daddy
could farm it cheaper than mine.
He drank himself into a $ 7 casket,
but not me!
Because I'm a master diver!
Maybe you'll remember that
next time...
...you imply we got anything
in common. You read me, Cookie?
Get your goddamn Wisconsin ass
back to bed, Snowhill!
SUNDAY:
The men you are watching...
...are going to be Navy divers.
You bottom suckers are not fit
to observe them.
Avert your eyes!
My name is Master Chief Billy Sunday.
There was a preacher by the same name
who rid Chicago...
...of the whoring spics, drunken wops
and motherfucking niggers...
...who were making that place unfit
for decent white folks to live.
The only difference
between me and that preacher...
...is that he worked for God,
and I am God!
Now, the first 10 of you
Girl Scouts step forward.
Come on, drop your dicks!
Let's go!
Three-quarters of you standing here
will fail to become Navy divers.
Three from the first row,
step forward.
Step forward!
Of those unfortunates who pass, only
three of you will live to retirement.
Because diving is
the most dangerous job in the Navy.
So who wants to quit?
Say now, who wants to quit?
You got something to offer?
Who wants to save me the sweat...
...of training your sorry ass?
You?
Cookie?
You gonna look me in the eye?
What are you, some broke-dick Popeye?
Let me guess.
You were captain of the swim team.
You and your girlfriend used
to practice the breaststroke!
Say it like you got a pair!
My wife.
It's in your record.
You knocked her up sophomore year.
Maybe you can bring
the little woman down one night...
...and all the boys can practice
the breaststroke.
I heard you were a hell of a swimmer,
Snowhill. State champ?
Yes, yes, master chief.
Snowhill, please step forward.
March.
About face.
(SNOWHILL YELLS)
You let go before I relieve you,
you fail my course.
Got it, swim champ?
Swimming don't got dick-shit
to do with deep-sea diving.
If Johnny Weissmuller were in the soup
wearing a 200-pound diving rig...
...he couldn't swim to fuck Esther
Williams if she was right there naked.
The only way to survive
is to trust each other.
Underwater, all you got
is the man next to you.
That's why the only men to get through
my course are the very, very best.
Now get out of my sight.
Permission to relieve the man below.
What are you, Cookie?
Some kind of goddamn hero?
I got no room for heroes or stuttering
swim champs with a wife and kids.
Flunk me. But don't punish
him for being decent to me.
You'll flunk all on your own.
Swim champ had half a chance.
He still does.
Permission to relieve him.
Says he can hold his breath
for 4 minutes.
Ain't even been two.
I believe
Gunner's Mate Snowhill's a liar!
We're men of honor, ain't we?
We don't abide liars.
You're out of my program, Snowhill!
Brashear, you have the barracks
to yourself.
Damn!
The Navy diver is not a fighting man
but a salvage expert.
If it's lost, he finds it.
If it's sunk, he brings it up.
If it's in the way, he moves it.
If he's lucky, he'll die 200 feet
beneath the waves.
That's the closest he'll get
to being a hero.
Hell, I don't know why anybody'd want
to be a Navy diver.
Good flange work, Rourke.
- Almost there.
- Thank you, master chief.
CLASS INSTRUCTOR:
Machinist's Mate Rourke, 91.
Boatswain's Mate Brashear, 37.
- You fail the next test, you're out.
- Yes, sir.
There are seats of learning beyond
the walls and control of this camp.
Ladies, this is weekend liberty.
Anyone who ain't back here on time
will have to answer to me personally.
And remember: One-night stands
may be over by morning...
...but syphilis lasts a lifetime.
Dismissed!
(CAR HONKS)
(MEN TALKING)
Hey! Hey! How about some flowers
for your young lady?
What's the hitch?
- You're the one who called.
- Yes, ma'am.
I told you. We're a public library,
not a tutoring service.
Now if you don't mind...
...there is a Mr. Biddle at home.
In fact,
he's probably brought flowers.
Have a wonderful weekend.
And lock up, would you?
And be sure to kick him out.
Hello.
We're closed.
Not for three minutes.
You studying on nursing?
A person doesn't study "on" anything,
boatswain's mate.
You know your rates and ranks.
Did you get that from these books?
Look, I am not here to flirt with you.
I'm in diving school
across the river.
I'm not just good at it.
I was born for it.
But the joke is, I'll wash out
if I fail my next exam.
What's the last grade you completed?
Seventh.
- I can't help you.
- Why not?
It took me four years of work
to get through med school.
Now I have six weeks
to study for my exam.
I pass, I become an intern,
maybe someday a doctor.
You're too far behind.
And I don't have the time.
Okay. Go on.
Go read to yourself.
Don't give me another thought.
Don't you get it?
It doesn't matter if I help you.
- You're gonna fail anyway.
- I won't.
I can't.
Why do you want this so badly?
Because they said I couldn't have it.
I may know a professor at City...
Boyle's Law describes the behavior
of gases under varying pressure.
It states if a diver holds
his breath at 100 feet...
...continues holding while rising
to 10 feet...
...the gases in his lungs
increase four times.
Why is this important? Forget to
exhale going up, your lungs explode.
I can work with you,
but my time is precious.
So the first time you go drinking
and fighting and leave me waiting...
...our arrangement ends.
MRS BIDDLE:
Good morning.
I...
...have to open up.
What's your name? Or is it a secret?
My name is Jo.
My father always wanted a boy.
He was in the Navy too.
Is he still active?
I haven't seen him since I was 9.
Good night.
CLASS INSTRUCTOR:
Fire Controlman Mellegrano, 91.
Mate DuBoyce, 85.
Engineman Crofoot, 69.
Boatswain's Mate Carl Brashear...
...76.
SUNDAY: Boots, Cookie, square away,
ladies. You're next in the water.
Patch the hull of the training vessel
so we can pump her full of air...
...and raise her up.
Then we'll sink her and do it again.
What's going on?
He stays down any longer,
he'll get mail.
ROURKE:
Isert, finish torching that hole.
ISERT: I'm trying,
but this thing's real awkward.
ROURKE: How's it look?
ISERT: Looks like hell.
Green diver, you have three minutes
to get your patch hung...
... before the next team comes.
Move your raggedy ass, Isert.
SUNDAY: Red diver.
ROURKE: Yes, master chief.
SUNDAY: Goddamn, I've had girlfriends
who welded faster. Move him along.
(ROURKE LAUGHS)
- Come on, Isert, hang the patch.
- Yeah, okay, Rourke. I'm trying.
ROURKE:
Do you feel that?
ISERT:
Do I feel what?
What the hell?
ROURKE:
This wreck is rolling!
ROURKE: She's limping, chief.
We're sliding down.
ISERT:
Can somebody tell me what happened?
SAILOR:
Come on! Grab that hose!
- Red diver, what's your situation?
- The whole ship just dropped 50 feet.
We landed on something.
Bring them home
so we can figure this out.
You're coming home.
Negative on the come-home order.
Isert's air hose is tangled.
My air hose is stuck!
Fouled. Now get it unfouled.
Rourke, what's wrong?
Why are we moving?
ROURKE:
We slipped down the channel bank.
This wreck is alive.
- I have to change out his air hose.
- Listen, Rourke...
...he's your buddy.
Unfoul his line and get him out.
ROURKE: I'm trying, it's too tight.
Send down a line.
ISERT:
Help!
ROURKE: Chief, I need help.
- Stay put. Help's on the way.
- I'm ready.
- Undress him.
- You can't go down there.
- I won't have your familiar tone.
You can't dive that deep.
I'm ready. Let me go.
CARL:
Master chief...
...it looks like the ship slid down on
some pipes coming from that factory.
They give out, this whole ship's going
right to the bottom.
SUNDAY: Don 't worry about the boat.
Get that hose to Rourke.
ROURKE: For God's sakes!
- What the hell is that, Cookie?
CARL: The ship's weight is busting
those pipes, chief.
We got to get him on a fresh hose
and out of here.
ROURKE: Topside, blue diver is here.
He's got a fresh line.
Isert, Rourke will change you out,
and you'll walk out of there.
Rourke, he's got five
minutes of air if he don't panic.
- You screw up and he's dead, read me?
- Yes, master chief.
Isert, we can 't talk for a bit,
think of your favorite song...
...and I want you to sing it.
ISERT:
I don't know any songs!
You have to slow your respiration.
Breathe easy.
ISERT:
Please, I wasn't made for this!
I want to go home now!
Would you let me go home now?
I want to quit! I want to quit!
I really want to quit!
I want to quit!
Change him out now!
ROURKE: She's moving!
CARL: Come on, Rourke.
ROURKE:
Oh, fuck!
Topside, Isert's off air.
- What is going on?
ROURKE: She's gonna roll over!
I expect so. Now stay there
and change that boy out, you hear me?
ROURKE:
I'm out of here. I have to get out.
ROURKE: She's going down.
ISERT: Come back here!
ISERT: Rourke, get back here!
ROURKE: I ain't dying. I'm out!
ISERT: Don't leave!
Carl, don't leave me.
I need my air hose.
I can't breathe, Carl.
I'm getting dizzy.
ISERT:
I can't breathe.
- Topside, he's blacking out.
- Goddamn it, hook him up!
CARL: We're coming home, chief.
- Never doubted it.
SUNDAY: Machinist's Mate First
Class Rourke, front and center.
"The President of the United States...
...takes pleasure in presenting
the Navy Medal of Heroism...
...to Machinist's Mate
First Class Dylan Rourke.
Whereby Petty Officer Rourke
on the 22nd of September...
...of the year 1952...
...with disregard for his own life,
did save the life...
...of Petty Officer
Timothy Douglas Isert."
Post.
Class 0252, dismissed.
(PHONE RINIGING)
Hey, I got your telegram.
No, I got the wire. I got the wire.
How's Daddy doing?
Is he up and around again?
JO:
Hello?
- Carl, is that you?
- Hey, Jo. It's me.
Where are you? Are you okay?
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Listen...
...could you meet me?
Miserable son of a bitch,
in there drinking on my anniversary.
You're the one, aren't you?
Well, I'm Gwen...
...Sunday.
Sorry to hear that.
You know he'll kick you out
of the Navy.
He's gonna kick you out of diving.
What're you gonna do about it?
Let him run you over,
like you do everyone else?
You know he's in there right now.
He wanted a party.
Let's give him one.
She told me it was okay
to dance with girls.
I love this song.
Donny...
...be a dear lad
and get us two Scotches.
We're out.
Lucky for us you got a whole bar
full of bourbon.
What the hell you doing with him?
Get out.
Well, I'll be goddamned.
It's prom night at the Moor Bar.
You boys have a drink on me.
Go ahead.
Hell, I don't know who classes up
the joint more:
The fetching young lady
in the fur stole or Cookie here.
So, what did you two kids come here
to do anyway? Dance?
Why not take a turn?
It's a free country. Mostly.
You made a big mistake walking
in here.
- It's my fault.
- It's all your fault.
Spoiled little girl gets her kicks
dragging stray men in here.
Thinks we're a bunch of rednecks
she can shake up for fun.
Hey, Donny...
...be a dear lad and bring the lady
a fresh soldier.
Think you deserve to be here?
Fraternizing among Navy men?
Think you're as good as them?
And me? You better than me?
Damn right I am.
(MUSIC PLAYS IN BACKGROUND)
See this pipe?
General MacArthur himself
smoked this pipe.
I served with him at Leyte Gulf.
Biggest naval battle in history.
Kamikaze ripped into an escort
carrier, the Saint Lo.
Went down on a shallow reef, trapped
me and six boys in the fire room.
- Only one way out.
- Flood the compartment, swim up.
Five decks, Cookie.
Five fucking decks.
Locked bulkheads.
Dead bodies everywhere.
You got to have your balls screwed
on tight for that swim.
We still had intercom. Old MacArthur
came over that squawk box:
"Sunday, you son of a bitch, I bet you
can't hold your breath four minutes...
...and swim out of there."
Know what I said?
"No, Mac, I can't...
...but I'll bet you your cob pipe
I can hold it for five...
...because that's what it'll take."
- This ain't worth it.
- Get your hands off me.
Six men are breathing today
because I let them out of that room.
Now because you pulled...
...Isert's white ass out
of some rowboat...
...you think you're better than me?
Well, let's just see.
What's your bet, Cookie?
Put Snowhill back in.
- What do you owe him?
- Nothing. You do.
Oh, yeah? Fine.
But if I win, you ship out tonight.
Deal?
Deal.
SAILOR:
Show him, master chief.
- Will you be my tender?
- Yeah.
Go, baby.
Come on now.
(CROWD CHEERS)
Go, Sunday!
Go.
Go, Master Chief Sunday!
One minute, fifteen seconds.
ROURKE:
Two minutes, twenty-five seconds.
SAILOR:
Ten bucks right here!
Three minutes, ten seconds!
Four minutes.
- Stop it.
- Chief?
Rourke, stop it.
SNOWHILL:
Carl, are you okay? Carl?
Chief, are you okay?
- Hold it.
- You all right, chief?
SUNDAY:
I'm okay.
Hold him up.
Let's go!
JO:
She tried to drive off the pier.
M. P:
Get her out of the car.
Today's my wedding anniversary.
Come on, move. Move.
No, not you, Billy.
Not you.
Bastard!
Come on, baby. Let's go home.
- Come on, baby. Let's go home.
GWEN: Yeah.
M. P: Go on home now.
Nothing to see here.
Jo.
I can't do this, Carl.
I can't live this life again.
I pulled my father out
of too many Navy bars.
- You don't know what happened tonight.
- Oh, but I do.
I passed my finals.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Jo.
I'm going to be starting
my internship at Bellevue.
It'll be crazy.
I won't have time to see you.
- It won't happen again.
- Yes, it will.
You wanted to fight that man.
You were waiting for the moment.
Don't you see? I'm not like you?
The things I want...
The things I want are smaller.
If I just work hard
and keep my head down...
Your whole life will pass you by.
Most of what's in those diving books
you know better than me.
You don't need me.
You don't need anyone.
I love you.
Jo!
Marry me, Jo!
What?
He wants to know if you'll marry him.
PAPPY:
Come in.
Watch the door.
Try not to touch anything.
Did you know that ordinary
house dust is composed...
...primarily of human skin?
No, sir, I didn't know that.
Makes you think twice
about who you invite into your home.
Two tablespoons of machine oil
can contaminate...
...an entire ship's...
...fresh water supply.
Some things just don't mix.
Do they...
...chief?
He's gonna pass.
Yesterday, he scored a 94
on his final.
He don't have to be fast tomorrow.
All he's got to do
is complete the exercise.
Billy...
...there may come a day when
a colored diver graduates from here...
...but it won't be tomorrow,
or as long as I'm here.
You agree with me, of course.
Don't you, chief?
Yes, sir.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(CARL'S RADIO PLAYS)
Baseball season's over.
I figured Rourke.
I never let myself think...
- Why not?
- Because I saw your last dive.
You want to know what I am?
I'm the sorry son of a bitch
put here to get through your skull...
...that some things do not change.
- I deserve to pass.
- When does deserving mean anything?
They ain't gonna have you.
In their eyes,
you'll never be as good as them.
- So you're failing.
- No, you are.
You think I owe you something?
I don't owe you
a goddamn fucking thing!
You or anybody else.
You got fucked, Cookie.
You were right, chief.
You and I have nothing in common.
I may be some dumb nigger from Podunk
but I'm making something of myself.
You're the same hateful little man
as you started out as.
Without diving you're nothing...
...but a son of a bitch
who used to be something.
What did he say
to make you try so hard?
"Be the best."
Well, you are.
Just don't show up tomorrow.
Pappy ain't going to let you pass.
What about you, chief?
SUNDAY: Today will decide which of
you will become Navy divers.
The object of the test is to correctly
assemble this flange underwater.
The pieces required for assembly
are on the river bottom.
Once you locate
your project flange...
...you will call for your tools.
They will be lowered to you.
You will be timed and accrue
points for a speedy completion.
However, we will pump air to you
for as long as you can stand the cold.
So take your time and get it right.
If you do not complete the flange...
...you have just wasted
six months of your life.
Divers, square yourselves away
and approach the rail.
CARL:
Topside, I have located my work light.
(CARL BREATHING)
Topside, blue diver.
CARL: I have located my project
and request my tool bag.
ROURKE: Topside, this is red diver.
I have located my project...
Tenders, lower your tool bags.
Topside, blue diver.
I'm still waiting on my tool bag.
Blue diver, your tool bag
is on the river bottom.
Chief, start the project time
on all divers.
Machinist's Mate Rourke...
...one hour, 37 minutes.
Perfect assembly.
Surveyor Second Class Yarmouth...
...two hours, 19 minutes.
Perfect assembly.
Never thought I'd live to see it.
Four hours, nine minutes.
Better late than never, Crofoot.
Perfect assembly.
How's the water down there?
Colder than
a well digger's ass, chief.
Take it inside.
(CARL BREATHING)
(PHONE RINGING)
What do you mean, still not up?
(CARL BREATHING)
(TOOLS SHAKING)
Excuse me.
- Dive station.
PAPPY: Chief Sunday...
...we have every cook and shine boy
thinking they'll be next...
... to try a stunt like this,
so you listen up.
Don't bring him up
till he stops moving.
He's near dead now, sir.
Not till he stops moving, chief!
Give up, Cookie.
You go into shock,
you might not wake up.
Come on now.
This ain 't worth dying for.
My name is...
...Boatswain's Mate...
...Second Class...
...Carl Brashear.
CARL: I am a Navy diver.
Bring him up.
- Bring him up!
- I got him.
- We'll bring him home.
- Sailor!
Disregard that order!
Sailor! Sailor!
Chief Sunday, effective immediately...
...I am relieving you of your duties!
Do you hear me, chief?!
Haul in that line.
ROURKE: Come on, Brashear.
You're almost there.
A few more steps.
Come on. We'll help you.
(MEN GRUNTING)
ROURKE:
Open up.
Boatswain's Mate Carl Brashear...
...nine hours, 31 minutes.
Perfect assembly.
Get him inside.
- Carl, did, did...
- Slow down, Snowhill.
They put me back in the program.
I start training next week.
Congratulations.
Thanks, Carl.
I almost forgot.
- You hear about Sunday?
- No.
Mr. Pappy blew a gasket
when the son of a bitch passed you.
He busted him down a stripe
and shipped him out.
I guess that fucker got his
in the end.
I guess he did.
(CARL'S RADIO PLAYS)
From the gentleman.
You hate champagne.
- You got a diving assignment.
- Brooklyn Navy Yard, standby diver.
Brooklyn? Brooklyn.
Baby, we can have dinner
like an old married couple.
Oh, well, baby, I didn't take the job.
We waited three years
for that slot to open up.
I don't move up in rank unless I dive.
I won't make master as a standby.
I'll find something else.
I'm three months late.
Late for what?
You're going to have a...?
A real baby?
We're gonna have a baby!
We're gonna have a real baby!
EMCEE: Ladies, gentlemen,
and the rest of you lowdown cats...
...it's time to ring in the New Year.
Happy New Year.
CROWD:
Five, four, three, two, one.
Happy New Year.
You have to let them know who's boss.
Or they'll never salute you
the rest of your life.
Excuse me.
What'd I tell you, hon?
He don't remember me.
Senior Chief Sunday, U. S. S. Hoist.
You ended my diving career,
lieutenant.
Lieutenant Commander...
...Hanks. Pleased to meet you.
That was a long time ago, chief.
Ancient history.
Well, we just came by to say hey.
- Auld lang syne and all.
- Auld lang syne.
I didn't know you had a daughter.
Right.
She's quite lovely.
We gotta go now,
because Billy's gonna dance with me.
Happy New Year.
- Have fun.
- Come on, Billy.
You're gonna dance
with your lovely wife, right?
See? Now wasn't that easy?
- Has-been.
- Yes.
No. Billy.
He's the biggest drunk
in the Navy is all.
NAVY JUDGE:
Senior Chief Sunday...
...you violated Article 90 of
the Uniform Code of Military Justice:
Assaulting a superior
commission officer.
Your conduct
is completely unacceptable.
You're fined one half
month's pay for six months...
...restricted to the base
for two months...
...and are hereby reduced
in rank to chief petty officer.
TV NEWS ANCHOR: For those just joining
us, our top story continues...
... thousands of miles away
in the Mediterranean Sea.
Hours ago, an American B-52 bomber
flying a routine mission...
... over the coast of Spain
slammed into the Spanish countryside.
Moments before, the bomber's crew
jettisoned their nuclear payload.
Three 50-megaton
warheads parachuted to Earth.
Two were recovered. However, a third
hydrogen bomb remains lost at sea.
You made it.
Becky, get your toys.
Your daddy will be home soon.
TV NEWS ANCHOR: Investigating in deep
water will be the work of AL VIN...
... a two-man submersible on loan from
Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute.
As Navy ships comb the Mediterranean
in search of the warhead...
... so do Russian submarines.
Since the bomb disappeared
in international waters...
... it belongs to whoever finds it.
Charged with locating it
before the Soviets...
... are the elite Navy deep-sea divers
pictured here.
Stationed in Norfolk, Virginia, the
divers were flown here hours ago...
... many still dressed in the uniforms
they had on this morning.
(HELICOPTERS WHIRLING)
Blue diver, this is captain.
HART:
Blue diver, come in.
CARL:
I'm here, Hart. What do you need?
Carl, I'd appreciate it if you could
find my lost nuke for me.
I'd like to make admiral before I die.
I'm doing my best, Hart.
Captain.
I have an unidentified metal object
protruding from the bottom.
He has something.
Proceed with caution.
Roger that.
Topside, we have a Coke can.
Goddamn Coke can.
Bring it up anyway, chief.
I like my ocean clean.
(SONAR BEEPING)
Turn sonar off. A diver's down...
- That's not our sonar.
- What?
Shit.
Alpha Whiskey, this is Charlie Victor.
I've got an unknown object.
Probable submarine.
Blue diver,
we have an unknown contact.
Probable Russian sub.
Bearing at 209...
... at 16 knots
and headed directly for you.
Take immediate evasive action.
Immediate evasive action.
Prepare for emergency surface.
Blue diver, do you hear me?
Do you hear me?
Blue diver?
Talk to me, Carl.
Come in, blue diver.
Tell the dive station
to supply a standby.
Come in, Carl.
Come on, Carl.
Carl, do you read me?
I'm here, captain.
He's there.
HART: Prepare to surface, Carl.
We're bringing you home.
Next time you scare the shit out of me
give me a courtesy warning first.
Captain, the sub kicked up
half the ocean bottom.
It found it for us!
You're kidding.
Oh, yeah!
He thinks he found it.
Yeah, you got it. That's it.
(MEN CLAPPING)
SAILOR:
Steady!
Steady. Let's take it in.
Bring it up.
Let's go now.
Move!
(SILENCE)
Jo.
I was so scared.
I'm sorry.
Oh, shit.
Your leg...
...was nearly severed.
It's gonna take time to heal.
Eventually, you're gonna be able
to walk again, with a cane.
Can I still dive?
I'm so sorry.
Come home, Carl.
NURSE: Your husband was found drunk
on a public beach this morning.
He's an alcoholic and must remain here
in detox for 30 days.
SUNDAY: If he should stagger,
he will not fall!
If he should fall,
he will fall in such a manner...
...as to cover up his rate...
...so that passersby will think
he is an officer!
(GWEN CRIES)
SUNDAY:
A chief petty officer shall not drink.
However, if he should drink,
he shall not get drunk.
If he should get drunk,
he shall not stagger!
If he should stagger,
he shall not fall!
And if he should fall,
he will fall in such a manner...
...as to cover up his rate, so
passersby will think he's an officer!
We're all extremely proud of you,
Chief Brashear.
Now get better so you can go home
and enjoy your retirement.
Give us a smile, chief.
REPORTERS: How will you retire?
- How's it feel to be a hero?
Hey, you.
Sweetheart...
...you'll never dive again.
And what you gotta do now...
...I can't help you with.
But when you're ready to leave...
...and if you can promise me you'll
never take another drink again...
...I'll be waiting for you
in that car over there.
But if you can't...
...then you just walk on by.
NURSE:
Package for you, sir.
CARL:
I want to come back.
- To where, chief?
- Full diving duty.
I want to dive again.
Carl...
...I understand but...
- But...
...it's just not possible.
Good afternoon, admiral.
- Carl, this is...
- Captain Hanks.
Chief Brashear.
Captain Hanks is the senior officer...
...of the Personnel Policy
Control Board at the Pentagon.
He'll be with us a few weeks...
...meeting some of the men from the
front lines, hearing their concerns.
To return to the chief's
primary concern.
Working as a Navy diver
with one good leg and the other...
I'm sorry, it's just not possible.
Cut it off.
"Injured pilots have requested
amputation of injured limbs.
With a prosthesis,
several have returned to duty."
I'm asking this:
Cut off my leg and assemble a medical
review board 12 weeks from today.
Then I will demonstrate that I am fit
to return to full diving duty.
I want to make master chief.
We admire your courage, chief,
however misplaced it may be.
Please excuse us.
(PHONE RINGING)
I am a doctor, Carl.
My opinion might mean something here.
I guess not.
How will you come back with one leg?
I could barely read once.
I found a way.
I could put up with the months
at sea...
...the dangerous assignments
you never refused.
- But this?
- What do you want from me?
That I come home, mow the lawn,
put a wheelchair ramp in?
- How am I gonna look at my son?
- Leave him out of this.
You're not doing this for him or me.
This is about you.
It's always been about you.
Admit it, Carl.
At least give me that much.
Why are you doing this to me?
Answer me, goddamn it!
Or I'm walking out of here
and I am not coming back.
I love you, Jo.
(CARL'S RADIO PLAYS)
(CARL CRIES)
Get away! Get away from me!
Piece of shit!
Cookie.
Goddamn. Looks like I missed
one hell of a party.
I've been all over.
Trouble, mostly.
Navy gave me a second-class diving
school in Little Creek.
Don't amount to shit.
I made some calls.
On Friday, that Captain Hanks...
...is convening a medical review board
and he's gonna retire you.
- He said I had 4 weeks.
- He lied, Cookie.
He don't care how many one-legged
pushups you can do.
He'd trade you and me
and every other sea dog...
...for one glass-eyed
electronics technician.
The man's gonna retire your ass.
My leg's back. I ain't done yet.
You got a stump on a stick
and no chance of beating Hanks, son.
- All I wanted was to be master diver.
- All I wanted was to stay one.
You want to beat Hanks,
you got to go around him...
...right to the top.
Washington.
- Chief of naval personnel.
- That's right.
They don't like cocky pencil pushers
like Hanks any more than we do.
I might be able to pull a few strings.
CARL:
Why are you doing this, Sunday?
Piss people off.
Chief Decker, you are
the chief master at arms...
...of this hospital?
Yes, sir.
Then why is it you don't know
where Chief Brashear is?
He shouldn't be too hard to spot.
He's the only negro diver
in the Navy...
...and he's got one leg.
It seems that the chief
has transferred, sir.
- On whose orders?
- He signed his own, sir.
Call the shore patrol.
Relax, cap. We just want to talk.
Wait, wait, wait.
You know where Chief Brashear is.
Where?
I see. Fine.
Chief Brashear is AWOL.
I want him found and arrested now.
You ain't gonna find him.
What do you want?
Four weeks to train him,
then a reinstatement hearing...
...with the chief of naval personnel.
- The chief of...?
- Yes, sir.
- In Washington?
- That's right.
Forget it.
REPORTERS: Will he be reinstated?
- Will he get a hearing?
Seems Chief Brashear losing his leg
for his country makes him a hero, sir.
Fine.
I will grant you your hearing...
...on one condition.
When he fails, you retire.
He ain't gonna fail.
Minute five faster.
See you in court.
Captain Hanks ordered you
to remain here, chief.
Please be seated,
Senior Chief Brashear.
Only the Army salutes indoors,
senior chief.
The Navy I grew up in
warrants a salute...
...given the gravity
of this occasion.
Well...
...we're in a new Navy now.
Shall we begin?
HANKS:
A diver's life may depend on you.
Do you honestly feel that,
as a man...
You're almost 40.
You have one leg.
Can you really keep up
with healthy divers half your age?
The question is, sir:
Can they keep up with me?
No smoking, chief.
Navy diving studies indicate that
if a subject were to become...
...unconscious or deceased...
...the disparity between the buoyancy
of a prosthetic...
...and a limb would hinder him
in a free dive mode.
You mean if he drowned,
he wouldn't float right, yes?
Sirs, I promise
if I am killed at sea...
...I will make every effort
to die like a Navy man.
(CROWD LAUGHS)
(EQUIPMENT RATTLES)
You should see the future
of Navy deep-sea diving.
This is the latest He/ O2,
mixed gas rig.
It weighs 290 pounds.
Men who want to use it, before
starting diving training, must walk...
...twelve steps unassisted.
Could you do that,
Senior Chief Brashear?
Yes, sir, I could.
Well...
...I see.
Much as I hate to prolong this...
...in the interest of thoroughness,
I'll make arrangements...
...for you to demonstrate.
Here, sir.
Now.
Son, step aside,
or I'll crack you in the jaw.
- This is hardly the appropriate venue.
- I want them all to see, sir.
Captain, I concur
with your assessment.
These slippery floors prohibit
a demonstration.
Haven't you had enough career trouble?
Your advice and presence
are unwelcome.
- Who is this man?
- Chief Leslie W. Sunday, sir.
You swam out of the Saint Lo
at Leyte Gulf.
Held your breath for...
...four minutes.
- Five, sir.
He can stay.
HANKS:
Fine. Irrelevant.
Gentlemen, sirs, returning
to the issue at hand...
...this is not the time or place
for Senior Chief Bra...
Excuse me, senior chief.
Is there a problem?
Captain Hanks...
...I've spent my life in the Navy
trying only to succeed.
But my quest has caused great
personal loss to those who love me.
They too have made sacrifices.
They too have endured
great pains to support me.
If I walk these 12 steps today...
...reinstate me to active duty.
Give me my career back.
Let me finish it,
and go home in peace.
Senior Chief Brashear,
the business of the modern Navy...
Forgive me, sir, but to me
the Navy is not a business.
We have many traditions. In my
career, I've experienced most of them.
Some good, some bad.
However, I wouldn't be here today
if not for our greatest tradition.
And which one is that?
Honor, sir.
Get on with it, senior chief.
Leslie?
What leg you got on?
My walking leg...
...Leslie.
It was my dad's name.
Got a problem?
Oh, no, no problem at all.
That thing's light duty.
It'll snap like a matchstick.
- I'll put my weight on my good leg.
- 290 pounds on one leg?
You'll be passed out by the sixth step.
Tenders, hat the diver.
Navy diver, stand up.
Leave him.
Captain, if I recall Navy regulations,
the diver may be helped to his feet.
It's a lot of brass to sling up
from a seated position.
It's spun copper, chief.
We haven't used brass in a decade.
The new manual states the diver
must rise unassisted.
That's what it says in the new book?
If I may ask, captain,
how would you know?
I wrote it.
Yes, sir.
Navy diver...
...stand up.
Square that rig and approach the rail.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Gentlemen, his leg.
HANKS:
Please.
Gentlemen.
- Navy diver, stand down.
- Diver, you will disregard.
- This is my detail.
- Admiral?
Goddamn it, Cookie, move your ass!
I want my 12.
Nine. The Navy diver
is not a fighting man.
He is a salvage expert.
Ten. If it's lost underwater,
he finds it.
If it's sunk, he brings it up.
If it's in the way, he moves it.
Eleven. If he's lucky, he'll die
young, 200 feet beneath the waves.
For that is the closest
he will ever get to being a hero.
Hell, I don't know why anyone
would want to be a Navy diver.
Now you report to this line, Cookie.
At ease.
Tenders, unhat that diver.
The United States Navy
proudly reinstates...
...senior chief and diver...
...Carl Brashear to full active duty.
Thank you.
I can quit.
The man I married never quit anything
a day in his life.
I love you.
I love you too, baby.
I love you too.