Subtitled by
KBS America
Granny, I will prevail with money.
I will.
She's traumatized by Granny's death.
How else can you explain this strange
behavior? She's been eating non-stop!
I can't even count how
many bowls she has had.
There're five travelers inns in the
market district that sell soup and rice,
but some places do well
and some don't.
Why do you think that is?
Why, because the food is different.
And the place across the street
had good food but bad service...
Have you been dragging us around trying
different restaurants to go into food business?
With you two doing the cooking,
people will be fighting for a table.
Doesn't the thought of starting a business
scare you after what happened?
I am scared.
I'm scare of money and of people.
But what scares me even
more is giving up here like this.
Why this place? This is the
worst place we've tried.
You can't get to the government office
from the harbor without passing this place.
There is no better location.
I guess your heart isn't in this business.
If you don't want the food,
you can just leave.
This is my analysis of this place I gathered
eating here for the past month.
And?
I heard Mu Meng Dal is after this place.
What? Who are you? Why are you
poking around about my business?
If this is how you're going to run
your business,
you might as well hand it over
to Mu now.
You're going to go out of business
before he takes it from you.
What?
Calm down. Calm down!
I know you took a loan
out on this place, too.
What the...!
No, no!
Let me run this place for you.
I'll give you 70% of the profit.
70%?
All you have to do is sit back and watch.
I get a place to sell my product, and you get a
superior product that will bring more business.
It'll be beneficial for both of us.
You think it's easy to run a business?
Don't insult me because I sell soup for a living!
This is the soup we would sell.
Give us a try for a month then decide.
What do we do now that we
have a place to do business?
Our first priority is shedding
the old image.
Yeah.
I think we should separate ourselves from
the other inns by food and other things, too.
Merchants usually travel in groups,
so why don't we make ourselves known
as the place that offer group benefits?
If we only charge for lodging for large groups
and offer food for free, rumor will spread fast.
Ladies, what special menu can we
offer using ingredients unique to Jeju?
How about pork and seaweed soup?
You put seaweed in flavorful pork broth
and thicken it with buckwheat powder.
Why, it'll be like a party every day!
We can serve it with tea
made from tangerine rind.
Tangerines help relieve motion
sickness, so it'll be perfect for travelers.
Let's start experimenting with
pork and seaweed soup recipes.
We have to distinguish ourselves from
the competitors in our food and service.
Jeju Marketplace
The seaweed is not very good today.
I'll give you a discount.
I can fool the customers but
I can't fool my conscience.
We don't mind paying a little more,
so let us be the first to know when
you get in good quality goods.
Sure.
Get in line please.
Here's your pork and seaweed
soup with tangerine tea!
May I ask where you're traveling from?
I'm from Mokpo, Cheolla.
What are you selling?
I came to sell cotton, but Honam is
enjoying a bumper cotton crop due to
the good rain they had.
It drove the price way down, too.
I take it you didn't do too well there.
If I don't make some money here,
I don't know how I'm going to give
my father his 60th birthday party.
Leave a few bolts here with us. We will pay
you enough for the birthday celebration.
Pardon?
We don't charge you for accommodation
here if you give us valuable information.
It's for the interesting story you just
told me, so consider it an even trade.
An outbreak of bandits in Gangwondo
is causing the crop prices to soar.
Lack of snow is affecting
apples crops in Gyeongsangdo.
This month's payment plus interest.
Exactly thirty nyangs.
You're more capable than
most men including me.
I'm sorry, but we're full.
Let me take you to the next inn.
Guys!
Hi!
Good to see you.
I was just taking these men to
the next inn because we're full.
This way.
- You're here!
- Yes, I'm so proud of you!
But are you sending all those
customers to another inn?
If you think about it, it's good for
us, too, to have thriving neighbors.
Chok Sae!
Bravo. You are the best, Man Deok!
Learn from her, will you?
How... did you make all this money?
You are amazing!
You made me more in
the last few months than
I saved the entire time I've been
in business.
I'm glad I can keep my promise.
From now on, I'll stay out of
the management completely.
I'm leaving it in your hands to build it up.
You and I are both businesswomen.
I thought about this for days
before I made the decision.
Thank you for trusting me.
You can be certain I will return the favor.
Six Years Later
Stop that man!
Deok Pal, stop him!
Hey!
You think you can eat and run?
Husband, don't waste your time.
Just strip him!
Strip him? You like stripping too much.
Come here, you little weasel!
Despicable bastard!
What's going on here?
Doctor!
Man Deok, I have to talk to you.
What did you want to discuss?
I wondered if you could help me
find some Joritdae wild bamboo.
Aren't those found at the foot of Mt. Halla?
It's for the King and I need them quick,
but I can't find any high grade goods.
For the King?
Yeah.
I'm told his chest pain has gotten worse.
So if you hear anything,
let me know right away.
Well then.
See you later.
Joritdae... is used to treat cancer.
He couldn't be...
What was the doctor doing here?
If....
Suppose the King was dying.
What would be
the first sign one might see?
You can't say things like that!
You could be arrested for high treason.
If the King died, Jeju would send specialty
products to the palace for the royal funeral.
What would that be?
Stop it, Man Deok.
No, we have to find out.
Dong Ah, go to Slim at the gisaeng house and
borrow the books in the government library.
Here you go.
Enjoy!
Delicious, delicious.
We're just raking in the money!
If only I had made a better
choice six years ago...
You could not have made
better choice, Husband.
Absolutely, Wife.
White hat: Worn during mourning.
"White hats are required
to be worn for six months."
Dong Ah!
Excuse me, sir. Has anyone placed a large
order of white hats in the last few days?
Someone from Hanyang or out of state.
Why would anyone order white
hats when no one has died?
How much money do we have to spare?
We charge less than our competitors,
and after paying rent, food cost and labor,
we don't end up with much.
Mangan and Yoo Bong, please go to the
government office first thing in the morning
and find out if any horses have
been sent up to Hanyang lately.
Yes, ma'am.
Dong Ah, go to Hanyang and
look into what I asked you earlier.
And don't forget to bring back
a white hat on your way back.
Hanyang Marketplace
That despicable fool!
That's all right.
We will just get a new
tenant if he cannot pay rent.
Don't make a fuss.
Have you heard anything?
About what?
About Man Deok.
Do you still think about that wench?
She's probably somewhere living
a worthless life.
I never want to see her face again.
Call Merchant Baek from the fish market.
You look worried.
I fear His Highness is nearing death.
Is that why you requisitioned horses from
Jeju? To prepare for a possible unrest?
Royal Grandson's ascension is definite.
Being of Noron Faction, I fear our family
might become a target of political revenge.
I heard that Royal Grandson is not one
to allow a political war over the past.
I've got nothing else to lose now that I'm
handing over my store, so I'll speak my mind.
You know that it's the Songpa bastards that
ruined my business by dumping their product.
My man, what's the use
of bringing that up now?
I heard a disturbing rumor.
Disturbing rumor?
That it's none other than you,
Madam Oh, that
allowed the Songpa merchants
to run rampant.
Do you have any proof of this?
Leave at once!
You should be grateful that we're paying
you for a business that's practically worthless!
Done. Now we can close up
the fish market in Songpa.
I've heard that fish markets
are cropping up in Newon.
There is a marketplace in Newon?
Merchants are setting up shop
everywhere goods can be delivered.
So it's not easy to knock down
a business like it used to be.
Then something has to be done
about this.
Jeong Dong's Estate, Hanyang
I've heard that a new marketplace
is forming in Newon. What happened?
I'm fighting against it, but it's
Choi Jebum that's the problem.
He insists protecting the licensed shops is not
the answer to all and refutes everything I say.
I need you to stop it.
You know the great loss we are suffering
because of these private merchants.
That does not sound like a request.
Forgive me, Minister.
I will take care of it myself.
Please just hold back the Commerce
Control Bureau while I'm doing it.
Is there any trouble in the royal court?
No, what trouble can there be?
Are you all right?
Yes.
This child does not take after you.
What do you mean?
He is sickly and fragile.
The doctor said he would grow
out of this and not to worry.
I, too, gave him everything
he could ever need...
Neither of us seem to have
raised our sons to our wish.
Kim Eung Ryeol's home, Hanyang
It's already been six years.
How are things in Jeju?
Business is thriving, so we've paid off
much of the debt and all is well, sir.
Man Deok is also healthy and well.
Time heals all wounds.
I'm sure she will be just fine.
You must be tired. Go get some rest.
Thank you, sir.
Sir,
by chance is the King unwell?
How do you know about
the King's health conditions?
Horses were hurriedly requisitioned from
Jeju, and things are rather unsettled.
We figured something is
happening in the palace.
Is this why you came to Hanyang?
Yes. Man Deok wanted me to
confirm our suspicion with you.
Confirm? For what reason?
I'm not certain, but I think she
wants to go into a new business.
I'm sure I don't need to say this,
but you must not mention the
King's condition to anyone.
The situation is very precarious
in the royal court right now.
I understand, sir.
I'd like to buy a white hat.
Huh? A white hat?
You must've lost a loved one.
That'll be twenty nyangs.
Here you go.
The market seems rather empty today.
It's like this every day.
Business is so bad
I can barely make the rent.
Do you need anything else?
No.
Did you find out?
Yes. One bundle of bamboo
is plenty to make one hat.
But weaving the brim is very difficult,
so labor cost is quite high.
They sell the hat part for 5 nyangs each,
and the brim part varies depending
on the material.
So I figure with material and labor, it'll cost
about 20 nyangs to produce a white hat.
Twenty nyangs...
Twenty nyangs each,
so one thousand hats would...
Twenty thousand nyangs.
Yes.
It's a considerable amount...
Why are we researching
white hats anyway?
I heard that business was dead at
other inns because of this place.
It must be true.
I'll take a bowl of soup and rice here!
Yes, sir!
Who do you think you are
coming in here demanding food?
Get out of here this instant!
Is this how you treat
all of your customers?
Customer? What customer?
That table is reserved.
Reserved? In this hole in the wall?
That table is reserved as well.
If you want to taste our food,
you have to wait for a table.
What would you like to do?
Would you like to wait?
You're that busy, huh?
Well, past is past, so call
me if you ever need a loan.
I'll take this business as collateral
any time.
Good. We don't need that man's business.
Dong Ah.
You were right.
Did you confirm it?
And how about the white hat?
Ask me one question at a time.
Here.
How about the hat shops in Hanyang?
Did they seem busy?
No, not at all. The whole city
seemed to be in the dark about it.
Good.
No one knows about it.
We're ahead of everyone!
So what's your plan?
A business?
When you say business...
What other kind of business
do you want to go into?
White hat business.
But it's not as if the King is dying. Why...?
I'm just going to pretend
I didn't hear this.
The King... is dying.
We've confirmed it with Lord
Jung Hong Soo in Hanyang.
The King is dying?
Is this true?
Yes.
And I don't want to lose this opportunity.
But we don't have the capital
to start a new business.
I know. But we've been
preparing for the past six years.
It's a once in a lifetime opportunity.
I support anything Man Deok does.
Here, here! Go for it!
Man Deok can never do wrong with you.
- Chok Sae,
- Yeah?
Are you drunk?
Have you ever seen me not drunk?
Well, we'll support you if you think this
is a good idea, but with what money?
Like Eun said, we don't
have a money growing tree.
How can we start a new business?
I'll take care of that, so don't worry.
But I do have one important request.
Do not tell anyone that we
are starting this business.
If word gets out that we're anticipating
the King's death and producing white hats,
we will face serious consequences.
Don't worry.
My lips are sealed!
Seek out talented hat makers in neighboring
villages and bring them to meet me.
Sure, I'll do that.
Don't worry.
Thank you all for trusting me on this.
You want to borrow my money?
Yes.
You do know that I'm Mu Meng Dal who
had lent money to East Gate. Don't you?
How could I forget?
But past is past. If you dwell
on the past, you can't go forward.
So how much do you need?
Twenty thousand nyangs.
Would it be possible?
Why not?
Money is all I've got.
But...
Collateral?
Ownership of our traveler's inn.
How about it?
I don't know.
You think this is enough?
It's just a tiny inn.
Then I guess I will go elsewhere.
I didn't say no. Did I?
Twenty thousand?
Draw up a contract.
I'll pay you back in three months.
Did you hit something big?
Let's just say it's a new business.
Sure. I'm all for it if you
want to borrow my money.
Well then.
I don't have to remind you, do I?
That if you fail this time,
you're finished for good.
Of course.
I've asked you all to come here because
you are the best hat makers in Jeju.
Do you know how much
your talent is worth?
Well, I get one and a half nyangs
for a brim at the five day market.
Tongyoung Hat Shop pays you two.
I will pay you three times that.
No, you won't make any profit.
West Gate is always trying
to reduce our wage.
I will make a profit. Jeju is the
best in the country at hat making.
The hats you make sell for double in
Tongyoung and four times its cost in Hanyang.
I'm just paying what
your talent is really worth.
What our talent is really worth?
But there is one condition.
You must use your talent only for me.
For the next six months, put all of
your effort into making hats for me.
And until we are done, you must
tell no one about our project.
If you don't think you can do this,
please leave the room now.
You're paying us a fair price.
How difficult could it be
to keep it a secret?
Until now, the brim and the hat
have been sold separately in Jeju.
Now we are going to change that.
If we succeed, every nobleman in
Joseon will wear a hat made in Jeju.
Doesn't that excite you?
Use the best material and make
the best hats you can possibly make.
I will double the pay for the
person who produces the finest hat.
Divide them into high, mid, and low grade
by color and refinement of workmanship.
Enjoy.
Goodness gracious!
What are you doing here?
Yong Cheon! Girls, get out here!
Why you...!
Wait, I can't waste salt on this crook.
What are you doing back here?
I came to see how my collateral is doing.
Didn't you know? I'm holding
this inn as collateral for a loan.
No way. Man Deok borrowed
money from this guy?
I can see that it wasn't for remodeling...
What kind of business are you folks doing
with my money? Can you give me a hint?
It's a hat business.
That's all we know.
Oh dear... West Gate has all of the
horsehair in Jeju. That's a bad idea.
I wonder how much this
place brings in daily.
That's it! Bad luck, go away!
Move! Move!
She borrowed money to start a new
business and she's making hats.
How can she make hats when
we own all the horsehair?
Who cares?
Even so, how could you lend her money?
Whose side are you on?
I don't care who it is as long as they make
good on the loan. The only side I'm on is mine.
You are a greedy old man.
Be that as it may, I cannot have
you helping that wench Man Deok.
Don't worry, Assistant Magistrate.
How successful can she be?
Has Man Deok lost her mind?
She still hasn't learned her lesson after
seeing what happened to Foreman Go.
You took something
as collateral I presume.
That traveler's inn is a hot little business.
Foolish girl will end up losing
the inn indulging her greed.
You are incredible, my lord!
Money just sticks to you wherever you go!
It sounds like you are ready
to stick to him for his money.
Tell me about it.
She is my sister, but...
Have you heard anything back from
Yoha from the Royal Music Institute?
Why do you bring up
that wench all of a sudden?
You're really giving us all this?
Your skills exceeded my expectations,
so I added a little more.
Please keep this confidential as promised.
If all goes well, I will also compensate
you for keeping your word.
Okay.
Let's go.
Man Deok!
I'm glad you're here.
Let's get these boxes on the ship.
Where are you sending them?
To Hanyang.
We're selling all this in Hanyang?
Once you get there, rent the closest warehouse
to the marketplace regardless of the price.
And?
And when you hear news of King's death,
go to the hat shop and supply them the
highest grade white hats wrapped in silk.
I guess if we're the first to offer the goods
when they don't have any white hats in stock,
we'll be able to get great price.
The best time is right after the
owner has met with a courtier.
They will care more about the quality
than the price,
so emphasize that they are Jeju's finest.
Our products in the royal palace?
We're going to seize the opportunity
let our name be known not just in
Hanyang but in the royal palace as well.
Make way!
Look at them. All of these people
are bowing their heads to you.
This is the power of money.
Remember that.
Father,
just as you dreamed, your company in
Hanyang has become the biggest in Joseon.
Are you content?
The woman who did this to us
cannot be allowed to live free.
I will get our revenge,
so you just watch, Father.
Boss!
Boss! What are you still doing here?
Let's go.
We must get back within two months.
Two months later
Thanks. I'll see you again tomorrow.
This is the second month.
We're here to make money, but we're
just making the warehouse owner rich!
Two months! Think about how many orders of
soup and rice you can buy with that money.
Do you think Man Deok
could be wrong about this?
Let's give it a few more days.
My man, what is this commotion about?
His Highness... His Highness is...
Your Highness!
Close your shops!
Why are they closing the shops?
Do you see those people?
They're from the palace.
What? Really?
The King must have passed away.
I'm sure of it.
It's time. Let's move.
Okay.
Man Deok's Inn, Jeju
This is the best quality hat I've ever seen.
I'll pay you double the normal price!
The palace will normally pay double the
wholesale price, but when there is a national
mourning, the seller names the price.
I will sell them for twelve
times the wholesale price.
Now you're being unreasonable.
You won't find white hats
of this quality anywhere else.
Ten times the wholesale price and you
have a deal. How do you want to be paid?
A promissory note will do.
We will cash it in Haenam.
Done.
East Gate Market Brokers of Jeju, right?
Let's do business again.
It would be our pleasure.
I can't even reckon how many sacks of rice
we can buy with this one piece of paper!
Good work, guys. Now let's sell
the rest of the goods and go home.
White hats from Tongyoung as promised.
We've got the best quality goods.
I've already acquired all the
white hats I need for the palace.
What? But we agreed to supply the white
hats in the event of a national mourning!
Words come cheap, fellows.
I need the hats by tomorrow.
How could I wait when I'm the one who'll get
flogged if the hats are not delivered on time?
Do you know how long
we've traveled for this?
Stop.
Which merchant did you buy from?
They were from Jeju.
Have a look yourself.
It's the finest quality and they had the goods
right in front of me. How could I pass up?
What did you pay them with?
We have a problem.
The licensed shops are closed for the
mourning, so the peddlers got together
and set up a market.
Round up the men.
But we are in national mourning.
Jung Hong Soo was assigned to the
Royal Coffin Hall Supervisory Council.
This is our chance while he is
preoccupied preparing for the funeral.
All right. I'll get to work.
Get your high quality white hats from East Gate
Market Brokers of Jeju with a huge discount!
Step right up, folks!
Discount?
Yes, sir! Why, you might even
convince me to give you one for free!
We are East Gate Market Brokers of Jeju!
Get in line, folks! Get in line!
I can buy new clothes, new shoes...
I'm going to have my wife
make me some japche.
I'm going to have myself some chicken!
This is great!
Who are you?
Even animals respect each other's territory.
How dare you do business on ours?
Men!
Get them!
Don't do this!
Don't hit me, you bastard!
Give it back.
Let's go!
Your time is up so pay up.
We still have 15 days left.
Please be patient.
Dong Ah! Dong Ah!
Dong Ah!
They... they took the note.
Subtitled by
KBS America
This bastard threatened the vice
boss when the market was raided.
Threatened him? How?
Give me back the note!
Search his house at once!
What do you mean you lost it?
When are you going to return my money?
It doesn't look like Man Deok is
going to make good on the loan.
What happened to the
peddlers market in Songpa?
We cannot allow the unlicensed peddlers
to cause us any more damage.
Arrest them all!
Yes, sir!
Lord Jeong is protecting the peddlers.
How can I do business like this?
Peddlers markets in Songpa and Newon
are threatening the licensed merchants.
We must put a stop to this.
Round up the peddlers.
Let's take them on once and for all.
Destroy everything!
I am reporting these men for physical
assault and property damage.
But the licensed merchants have
assaulted the peddlers as well.
Do you call it assault when the state guards
hurt the wrongdoers while restraining them?
Are you trying to play word games with me?