What about this weather today?
You're telling me.
The weather is great.
This weather!
Shall we get something to eat or not?
Hey, in Betty, no matter what, you can't eat.
But it's Yoon Pal's car.
♫ On a dark desert highway, ♫
♫ Cool wind in my hair...♫
What the hell?
Have we just had an accident?
It was one episode in a boring life.
The car is a Joondaehyung sedan.
The driver is a male in his early 20's.
For sure, the car belongs to his dad.
When we get out, what will we say?
All together, "my neck!"
Get out!
Ouch.  Oooh.
Aigoo, it's my bones.
My Number #3  vertebra!
My spine.
Oh, my knee!
Do you know who we are?
We collectively have the most valuable bodies
in the Republic of Korea.
Jeez, how, under Korean law,
is someone your age driving?
One moment, make a telephone call.
Hello, it's Attorney Choi Yoon.
Supreme Court Justice, Sir, I'm a bit concerned right now about a car accident.
This is the police, right?
If he's there, could I talk to the chief?
He knows Im Tae San.
Oh, honey.  It's me.  I've had an accident.
Right now we are taking turns making phone calls.
Hello, is this National Forensic Service?
Could I speak with Yoon Ji Hyung?
Yes, Supreme Court Justice.
I'm not terribly injured.
The current condition of the back of my neck is unknown,
but then in a car accident,
one never knows immediately.
Yes. Has Doctor Yoon Ji Hyun passed away?
What's this?  Look at this.
Yes, Is this the insurance company?
I just had an accident.
It happened because I rear-ended a car.
Yes , it was my fault.
Yes, I will wait.
I'm really sorry.
Someone will come in ten minutes.
Are you badly injured?
--It's fine. The weather is really nice.
--It's warm.
The police chief?
Why hasn't the police chief shown his face immediately?
Speak for yourself.  Right there, he was looking for his wife.
The highest authority for me is my wife.
What?  National Forensic Service??
Well, trying to make the genre a bit different
went that far.
Why's the time creeping?
Calling the insurance company after you have an accident was not something we didn't know.
However, when we were in our 20's, we scorned the way the older generation treated people in their 20's.
If you applied common sense,
it was the hard way to go, and
if a bluff felt like it was of substance,
unfortunately for you
you, who despised the older generation like that, didn't know  you would eventually become "misters"
or old men.
A Gentleman`s Dignity
Episode 18
Why was your phone turned off?
Meari is leaving now.  She's at the airport.
Just now, even for me, her cell phone has been deactivated.
Are you going to let her go like that?
Hey, Meahri's leaving.  She's going.
Today, she's going.
It seems you already heard that?
You may still be able to see her.
If you really step on it.
It's not yet the ticketed time.
She's not that driven.
There's duty free shopping or she might miss the plane.
She might get arrested for firearms or drugs in her bags or something.
Some guy might be carrying the same bag
Some guy might be carrying the same bag.
After switching bags, their eyes meet.
She's waiting for you now.
Can you leave?
I have a trial tomorrow.
Dumbass.
The trial is tomorrow, but
Meahri is leaving right now.
If my brother finds out...
♫ Even more freely on my own, ♫
♫ I am fine caring more for you like this. ♫
♫ You more than I ♫
♫ loving me...♫
I love you, Im Meahri.
I'm sorry because you suffered alone.
For admitting it so late, I am sorry.
You aren't going anywhere now.
I am not letting you go anywhere.
Oppa.
Now that I'm holding you, what I said doesn't
just mean not going to the U.S.
It means you are coming to me.
And it means my heart is not hiding.
It means, from now on, I am the Oppa you follow.
Because I will take care of everything.
Although it's going to be difficult,
--it's definitely not going to be easy-- but
I will never let go of your hand.
I will never let you cry alone again.
Where are you?
I'm here in the cafe parking lot.
Okay.  I'll wait.
He should wash his car...
Oh, you came.
Have you had dinner?
I haven't eaten.
I caught her.
I'll come in for a while.
Let's sit and talk
You...
How could you...
Choi Yoon Pal...How could you?
I'm sorry
If I let her go now, I thought I'd lose her forever
Then you should have just let her go
I . . .
What am I supposed to do?
If you say you're sorry to me.
what am I supposed to do?
Im Meahri, aren't you going to stop?
Say it to me.
Whatever you're going to say, say it to me.
I'll take the blame.
Choi Yoon Pal.
I've thought about it more than a thousand times.
It was a thousand times worse.  So I  suppressed it.
I suppressed it to death.
The moment that I heard that Meahri was leaving,
I thought the world was ending.
Because at that moment,  I was full of regret.
I was avoiding, not thinking, and pretending it wasn't
what my heart was hoping for earlier.
I'm sorry
because I've made Meahri cry so many times.
I'll do well.
I'll take care of her forever.
Tae San...This is my first and last request of you.
Just this once, forgive me.
So, are you ready...
to lose me?
Im Meahri...
In the end,
this is what you have to do to be happy?
Oppa!
Just forgive me this once.
I've forgiven you too many times.
Now, I regret it. I didn't know
how you two would end up like this.
I said I'd watch over you.
I  alone will be crazed as a raving lunatic.
Oppa!
From now on, I...
have lost both of you.
Im Meahri...Leave this house.
This isn't your home anymore
and I'm not your brother.
That rude little girl.
She always fought back against what you said, but this time she's leaving because her brother told her to?
If she was going to listen so well,
why didn't she listen to me?
She's quite smart on that side.
Do you think those two people met?
Did he even go to find her?
I give one point to he went, and two to they met.
Why?
Because I'm a guy that lost someone and found her again.
I know the feeling of having lost your everything.
If you fall in love, you can't even put on hand cream by yourself. You can't.
What time is it?
Why isn't he calling?
Didn't you do that when you were dating your wife?
You want to do everything for them, and when they said they'd do it by themselves, you wouldn't believe them.
It bothers me so much this woman eats alone.
I mean, if I don't feed her, how does she eat?
Oh sorry, my stomach...
Ah, seriously!
At this rate, you're going to be kissing the window.
A perfectly normal person kissing through the window!
How did you know that?
Huh?
Oh! It's Attorney Choi.
Hello?
Right now?
It would've been a hard choice to make for you...
This is embarrassing, the state that I'm in...
No, out of everything I've seen of you,
you seem the coolest right now.
A person that made a hard choice to a friend...
Shouldn't look cool
If I were to give you advice as someone who has gone through this hardship,
that weight was too hard for me to carry so that I couldn't even move a step.
But at one point, I overcame it.
Thinking, "oh this weight, is the weight of my heart...
As much as you loved and as much as you were happy,
it was that much heavier."
I was really... in love.
It'd be nice if Tae San made
the same conclusion as you did.
He will.
Don't worry about it too much.
And, what I wanted to say
although it's a bit late, I'd like to say thank you.
For....
I found out. At the cafe, you four came to help me.
You're the oppa that helped
me with the stuff with the law.
Ahh
But I was thinking, the other
people could contact you too...
If they do, then please let me know.
I don't want the four of you to worry about it.
If they call, I'll tell you.
Since you're taking care of Meahri,
I would have to do at least that much.
Then I'd be so grateful.
But...How'd you know we went to the cafe?
Because you guys didn't pay or anything,
then left after breaking things there.
Ohhh
Your helping is helping.  But since money is money,
I'm planning to get it from you all evenly.
If Tae San doesn't approve of Meahri,
then should I charge a lot more to Tae San?
What?
Yoon stopped you?
Does your brother know?
I met him with Yoon Oppa...
But my brother told me to leave, so I did.
He said he doesn't have a sister like me anymore.
So you just left because he told you to?
What was I supposed to do? He was totally pissed.
Even if he was, how could you leave him alone like that?
You can stay here alone, right? Lock the door.
Thank you.
There's nothing to be thankful for. You take care of your man, I'll take care of mine.
I'm going to tell Tae San you're here.
He's probably going to be worried.
I've come.
Where are you?
You didn't even turn on the lights.
Are you okay?
Meahri...is at my house.
It's okay.
It's going to be okay.
That little brat, to her brother....
Im Meahri...I'm totally going to yell at her.
How dare she make my man cry?
Does she want to die?
Honey! I came back home~
I haven't been able to contact you the whole day today!
You told me you were in the parking
lot and you didn't even come in!
Hey, did you know?
Yoon and Meahri, they
(You) went to the motel?
Motel?!
Huh...
They even went to a motel?!
When?
You think I'm in the mood to joke around?
(You) went to the motel. Lee Jeong Rok did.
Me? Myself?
Oh you, why would I?
Ah, I did go!
Tae San suddenly left for a business trip,
so I went to bring him his clothes.
Now your facial expression doesn't even change. And now you have an alibi.
Figures. It's about time your acting improved.
You're getting at an innocent person again... You did this at the party too! Ask Tae San!
Did you guys agree on saying something too?
But if you come out so confident,
then it gets me even more angry!
What do you mean agree on saying something?!
I'm going to go crazy.
I understand.  This isn't the first time I've done this kind of things.
But I swear, this really isn't it.
Oh Meahri! Ask Meahri, because she's the one that asked me to do that.
So now you're trying to buy some time?
How am I supposed to call a girl going on a plane to America!
Meahri didn't go to America!
Yoon, stopped her.
Anyway, call her right now!
You think I won't do it?
You're really going to do it?
Don't embarrass yourself in front of Meahri.
Let go. I said I don't care
Yeah, It's Min Sook unni.
I want to ask you something.
Your manager said he went to Choon Chun, because you asked him a favor. Is it true?
Yeah. I got into a fight with my brother, so I asked Rok oppa for a favor.
Why? Did Rok oppa still not come home?
It's nothing.
I understand.
What'd she say?
She said I'm right, right?
Why are you like this?
She said it's not true?
Why that little, there's some things not to joke about!
She said you're right.
She said that...
She did ask that of you.
Then, why are you crying?
Because you're embarrassed?
I don't think I can do this.
I really can't do this.
Let's get divorced.
Again?
You always say that. Aigoo.
If you're embarrassed, just say you are.
Why mention divorce?
If you say that again, you're in trouble!
I'm going to wash up.
Subtitles brought to you by The Gentlemen's Club @ viki.com
What about school? Is it okay? Is it fun?
The amusement park is more fun than school.
Did you make a lot of friends?
One, who looks like a lot of friends.
You made a friend?
What's his name?
Kim Dong Hyub.
Manly, tough...
That kind of person is in mind.
But he's bad at studying.
Did you think about making other friends?
Did Jung Rok do well in school?
What time is good for you?
Of course, minus lunch and break time.
1 minute before lunch time.
1 minute before break time.
I like those times.
By any chance... Does 1 minute
before meeting your real dad...
Count?
I'm tired. I want to sleep.
You left your girl with my girl.
Yeah.
She got kicked out by Tae San.
Really?
Looking at your face, at least you didn't get hit by him.
At least for now.
Do you remember?
When Meahri was in elementary school, a boy in her class hurt her forehead.
And Tae San was in a rage.
He went to that boy's house and said, "Do you know who my Meahri is?"
She's going to be Miss Korea, what're you going to do about this?
I remember,
I was with him.
Of course, we didn't know at that time that she couldn't try out for Miss Korea due to her height, not that wound.
But why that?
He went crazy over a scratch on her forehead.
But I'm the one that wounded her life.
And in Tae San's view, this is a betrayal.
Will he ever forgive me?
Why is every man's love like a war?
How can I help you?
I'm okay, so you just take Tae San's side.
I should suffer.  Meahri is everything to Tae San.
Today was a long day for you.
Rest.
♫ My heart aches ♫
♫ Only looking at you ♫
♫ Not having you with me ♫
♫ I became used to it like a habit ♫
♫ So I don't even know that it hurts ♫
♫ Though tears form ♫
♫ I can't say anything ♫
♫ And I need to smile ♫
♫ But like a habit ♫
♫ In front of you I love you like a fool. ♫
♫ So tears come ♫
Tell Team Leader Choi to get ready
for the presentation rehearsal.
Be ready in 10 minutes.
Yes!
Subtitles brought to you by The Gentleman's Club Team @Viki.com
Sorry for being late.
You couldn't sleep a wink.
Are you okay?
Didn't you say
if you act like you're okay, you will eventually be okay.
How do I look?
Do I look okay?
Nope.
Really...?
Did Yoon come to work?
Did Tae San come to work?
Is what Yoon just texted me.
Do you want to respond to him?
Aishh.
Oh!
If you come out like that, it's going to be hard.
For Meahri's problem, I'm on your side.
Why?
Yoon told me to be on your side.
He said he's fine.
Pisses you off, right?
You, really...
Wow, you can't trust me.
You want me to kick Yoon out of the house?
You want me to tell my girlfriend to kick Meahri out??
Alright.
I guess I'll have to do that.
These kids, would they understand
after they start hanging out in the streets--?!
Why?
Why don't you just live with both of
them and set up a house for them?
I'm going to the presentation rehearsal.
Forget it.
I'll go.
Then you do that.
The houses of 44 families full of individual personalities
will share the same big front yards
in this Dong Tan Loft  Village.
Reflecting each owner's life style,
A house of light, a house of a pin wheel,
a house which will be the background for life,
a house with bigger space, and so on.
Each will have a theme and...
The revival of front yard and the loft will become
the family's revival as well as the neighbor's revival..
Should I start over?
Huh?
Don't worry about him.
He's suffering from a family issue.
I heard what he said.
A house with a love affair (sounds a bit similar to "pin wheel),  a house with really big space..
It's good.
Go ahead.
Why are you laughing?
It's been quiet for a while, right?
Are you performing an exorcism of the statement of accounts for the first half of the year?
Generally it's good.   It's just that it doesn't have a lot of humor.
No humor.
What's humor?
It's a way to gently deliver
the result of deep observation!
Right!!
A house with a love affair,
a house with really big space..such things!
This stuff isn't humor, but...
It's Mom.  Mom!
Let's add one more thing.
The functional aspects like A/C, heating system
or security system,
the common prejudice that people, who have lived in apartments for a long time, often have.
For your reference, the A/C and heating of this project would use the cooling system.
That's all.
Yes!
This person~
It doesn't seem like it, but he does his job very well~
First let's go eat, I'll buy it.
You go eat.
I have to see someone.
With whom?
You...
Yeah. I took off the ring.
Let me say it so you can understand it. Let's say you brought a 24 year old girl and said it was your girlfriend.
Then I, probably would've said this,
"Hey you cradle robber!"
But that 24 year old is my younger sister.
How do I understand this?
Jung Ah... is your deeplyy hurting wound
for me to discuss with you as your friend,
But as her brother, it's your past
which is hard for me to accept.
Put youself in my shoes.
If you were me, would you accept it?
I understand your reaction.
It's an obvious reaction.
If you understand,
then why would you make a situation like this
and let me say that? Why?
I can't give up.
I know it's stupid and that I'm a bad guy.
I also know you must feel
like you are suddenly robbed.
Does a guy that knows that do this? A guy that knows?!
Even though I didn't trust Meahri, I at least trusted you!
I'm sorry.
But I . . .
I hate that Meahri's crying over a guy like me.
So, now, I'm going to try to not let Meahri cry.
What about her dreams, her future?
The fact that Meahri wants to design and make bags,
Actually I don't like it.
But, it's her dream.
I want her to learn more, and master more
and achieve her dream.
I don't want Meahri to toss away her dreams either.
Tae San...Meahri....is also my dream.
Whether she's a designer, or anything else,
I'm going to try my best
to care for my dream.
I'm going to look at some houses.
Do you want to come with me?
I heard Do Jin oppa was going.
Go with him in a lovey-dovey mood.
Although I have more problems than you now,
I'm Meahri who cheers for your love, Teacher.
You think you'll be okay?
Se Ra will give you a real hard time.
It's really unexpected.
I didn't know she loved my brother that much.
In Se Ra's life, there are only two groups,
enemy and ally.
You're now in big trouble.
I'll be back later.
See you later.
Please come in.
This place was used by a single woman,
so it's cleanly maintained well.
Will you two live here?
It would look good in your opinion, right?
Two women will live here.
With my friend.
Se Ra and I have decided to live together.
This time, I'm the owner.
So, do you like that?
That's unhappy news to me.
The price for rental is very good,
so there are many people coming here to look at it.
So, if you like this place, you'd better sign
the contract before other people take it.
Then, look around more.
Thank you.
We must look like newlyweds.
How could you dream such an ambitious dream
in the daytime?
Well, we might look like a couple
whose marriage is the second one.
Are you embarrassing me
because I have a son?
I meant that we're both already passed
the usual age of marriage.
Are you embarrassing me
because I have a son?
I meant that we're both already passed
the usual age of marriage.
You must have an inferiority complex.
I should have that kind of humble charm a bit.
If I'm too bling-bling,
I would look like a hero of a TV drama.
Choose this one.   As an expert, I think this is
the best among all the places we've seen so far.
Which parts do you like as an expert?
The part that this place is the closest one
to my place?
How did you suppress your
desire to do this all that time?
Since I barely suppressed it,
I will do this whenever I have a chance!
The condition of wall paper is still okay, so....
if we change just one side wall
with some color paint as a point color...
It will be done soon.
Then it will make the space look lively, not dull.
You will do the painting, won't you,
Kim Do Jin ssi?
Do you have to use this high-quality
human resource in that......?
Oh, oh, it's a bug!!
Yi Soo Oppa, you're number one!
What did you say?
Didn't you know that?
Usually, if someone catches a bug for others,
that person becomes Oppa.
I will sign the contract.
Within this week, can we come back for disinfection and painting which will give a lively look to a dull place?
Of course.
♪ I love you High High ♪
♪ Thank you High High ♪
♪ Painful memories  are now Bye Bye ♪
♪ I'm smiling High High ♪
♪ Looking at your eyes High High ♪
♪ I am praying that from now on
we will be happy together ♪
♪ I am praying ♪
♪ for the two of us ♪
♪ I will never make you feel so lonely ♪
♪ My heart which is  looking at you High High ♪
♪ I'm feeling High High ♪
♪ I pray that from now on
we will be happy with each other ♪
Subtitles brought to you by The Gentleman's Club Team @Viki.com
It's not an easy task...
You couldn't have done this without me.
If you weren't here,
I could've done it much earlier.
Why did you give me a piggyback ride
while the ladder is sitting there?
I didn't think you would really climb on my back,
even though I told you to do so.
I helped you by betting my life as a man.
My back could have been broken.
It would have been very unfortunate
for Seo Yi Soo  eventually.
Aish, seriously...
That's sexual harrassment.
You know it's a sexual harrassment
if the victim feels uncomfortable about it?
Is that now a uncomfortable look on your face?
It's the face that wants more.
Aish, seriously, you're so good at talking.
I said I'll do it directly.
Do you think I'm the type to hold myself back?
She brings in dangerous things, this woman.
Lay down again.
I'm letting you win.
How's Tae San?
Meahri is... doing alright...
He's not letting me know what he feels.
Since he doesn't show emotion about what he feels about Meahri.
I think she's really... brave, Meahri.
Seo Yi Soo is the same way.
I guess so.
I'll build a cool house for you later.
Big, with lots of room, and sunshine coming through. And where the wind flows nicely.
A house where no one leaves.
Where in Canada are your parents?
Toronto.
It's a place that feels cool when you
go in the shade in the summer time.
How long did you guys live together?
As soon as I went to college, they left like the wind.
Actually, I wanted to study another year before college.
My mom said that with my skills that was enough and that they had to go to Canada.
And she told me to just register for class.
My personality is like my mom's.
A harmonious family.
Although we weren't rich, I grew up in decent comfort.
Because their relationship was excellent,
I was always the disrupter.
At that time I was sad, but I knew later.
That's what happiness is.
It seems as though your confidence and composure flows from that.
I'm also confident and composed, but you're different from me.
Because I am working hard to make real what you were born with.
People can recognize at a glance a person who is naturally like that.
Because it makes someone a little more frustrated.
I didn't have a really happy childhood.
My family was nothing to be proud of.
Look at me.
Do you know this?
Seo Yi Soo's happiness at the sweet age of 36 has been driving me since the third quarter.
Let's start now from this moment.
You will be happy.
Will it satisfy you if I say again
I will keep a promise I made before?
Tomorrow you will be happier than today,
the day after tomorrow
you will be happier than tomorrow.
I promise you.
I am going to believe it again.
This time, I'm going to keep it until I die.
Is this call taxi service?
I'll call you back.
Were you going to take a taxi carrying that?
Sometimes I use Yi Soo's car. I was going to do that.
The car is also equipped with a spare tire.
It's also full of high quality gasoline.
Thanks.
Here.
I'll have the rest of the money the day after tomorrow because of  moving-in day.
You drive.
Take me back.
When did you say you're moving?
You don't have to worry since I called a packing company.
How can a stranger's work be the same thing as the  work of a family member?
On that day, a man should help out.
This isn't like moving out of a rented room when you're in college.
Meahri will be there, and you probably
don't want to see her.
Where is Meahri sleeping now?
Sometimes she sleeps in the living room on the couch while watching the TV,
and sometimes she sleeps on the floor of Yi Soo's room.
You don't cook often.
You worry about the unncessary things!
The take-out booklet has over thirty choices,
from Korean to Mexican.
Did you talk to Yoon yet?
I only say what I have to say,
and he only says what he has to say.
If we just look at Meahri's life,
this might be her happiest moment.
I met the man of my life when I was 36,
and she met hers when she was 24.
She'll be happy twelve more years than me.
Don't take sides. I would still be disappointed even if she were 34. But she is just 24 years old..
Do you know how mean I am to her?
Should I go see Yoon and be a complete jerk to him?
What should I do?
Tell me anything.
I graduated from sports university.
Everyone's dead meat.
Do Jin will come, and I will send Jung Rok.
Have a good moving day.
Don't worry.
We're here.
You came?
You, come here.
You were going to run off to America without saying good-bye?
In the end, I didn't leave.
Teacher, Do Jin oppa is here.
Why did you change your clothes? Isn't the dress uncomfortable?
No, not at all. I just spilled something on my clothes.
Teacher, this is awesome.  If this weren't moving day, at this rate, you would be wearing a bikini right now.
What's this? Who are you to join in the conversation?
This is because Kim Do Jin is here, right?
Because of somebody, Tae San can't even come here.
I'll go organize the clothes.
No, it's not.
This is my normal attire.
Why didn't you just wear clothes you wear when you head outside?
How's the unpacking going?
I have to start now. Follow me.
What should I do?
I used to do this a lot long ago.
Work at a comfortable pace.
We will.
You guys look great in your uniforms.
Switch places with me!
Who said to wear tthat kind of clothing?
You even catch bugs. Do you think that flower-print suits you?
Look! A bug!
None of your beeswax.
Go to work.
What number is it?
What?
What number is it out of 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5?
Was it three, the number I liked?
Three my butt!
Number two?
Oh. Number two.
What about yesterday?
Kitty.
Your face is really funny.
What's up?
I was thinking of something else for a second.
I didn't move that much stuff, but yet my nails are all broken.
Me too.
When are we going to eat today?
You're hungry?
We worked all day. Of course I'm hungry.
Tae San isn't hungry. He has no appetite.
I am walking on eggshells too.
It's just that I am not making it apparent.
Make it apparent! You look too fine.
Honestly. After what happened, have you met Lawyer Choi?
We talk on the phone everyday. He dropped by for a short time a few days ago too.
My brother needs to calm down a bit for us to do something.
Please don't move.
Will it take long? She said she's hungry.
No. It's a fast-drying nail polish, so it won't take long.
A few days ago, you met Tae San. How was he?
Manager Im, nice hitting.
What do you want?
Why did you come here?
The move went well.
The two women are happy in the little house.
It's a gem of a house.
Meahri has already made herself at home.
Meahri worried about you a lot.
When?
We bought you some medicated strips!
Do you want the sticky kind or the spray-on kind?
Do you want to go to the sauna?
Do you want me to scrub your back for you?
We are always on your side. You know that?
Honestly..
You guys leave.
I have a foul temper!
Go. Go. go. Go.
Lawyer Choi! Nice pitching!
Nice pitching!
What? What is it?
We moved in successfully, and Meahri has already made herself at home.
Meahri worried about you a lot.
Did you go see Tae San?
Rok: Yes
Do Jin: No
Both: Really?
If you planned it out, at least match your words.
Rok: We were going to go now.
Do Jin: We just came back.
Both: Seriously?
How is Tae San?
You're throwing and he's hitting.
We bought medicated strips.
Do you want the sticky kind or the spray-on kind?
Do you want to go to the sauna?
Do you want me to scrub your back for you?
We're always on your side. You know that?
You did that to Tae San too, right?
But... aren't we cute?
Let's go
Go!
Why did you come so early? I said I'd wait.
Because... It just happened this way.
But why aren't you looking at me?
I can't seem to look at you.
I want to look at you. Raise your head.
Is this really your concept?
It's not a concept. I'm doing it because I'm really nervous.
I don't even know why I'm nervous.
Huh?
You didn't throw the bag away?
How can I throw it away? You personally made it.
Let's go eat.
So we
went to Tae San and told him we were on his side.
And then we went to Yoon and told him we were on his side.
So?
So that is why I couldn't receive your call.
I couldn't be like "Hi honey!" when Tae San and Yoon are both about to die.
They're my friends.
What?
By chance...
Do you not believe me?!
Fine.
Do you want to call Do Jin?
No...you won't believe Do Jin either.
How about Yoon?
Are they not that much different?
Yeah! The pharmacist!
We bought a whole bunch of medicated strips to give to them. The pharmacist would remember me.
Wow honey...
Do you really not believe me?
Yeah.
I can't believe you anymore.
Even if you carry a surveillance camera with you, I can't believe you.
Why are you suddenly acting like this?
Other people
tell me that I have everything.
That's right.
I do have everything.
But, I...
To me, you were all I had.
Why are you crying again?
A wedding ring, since a husband and wife cannot always be together,
it's how a husband keeps his wife
at the side closest to his heart.
and how a wife keeps
her husband at her closest.
On the ring finger, which is connected to the heart.
But now, this ring...
I'm the one who wants to take it off.
I really mean it.
Now, I can't believe you even if you tell me that 1+1 is 2.
"What did he talk about with that woman?"
"Is that phone call with a man or a woman?"
"Is he just smiling or smiling for her?"
I go to heaven and hell back and forth everyday.
I'm sorry...
I know I've done wrong up until now.
But, honey...
I'm never going to take off my ring now.
I'm being serious.
I really won't do it.
Okay?
I'm going to do it from now.
Even if you won't, I will.
Please do this for me.
Let's get a divorce.
This is because I feel so bad for myself.
This is because I look like a crazy woman for doubting you nonstop!
Honey.
I will ask you sincerely.
Just let me go.
Please divorce me.
While I am at least still intact,
please let me go, huh?
Science Department Park Hyun Joo
010-6985
Hello. This is Teacher Park Hyun Joo from Joo Won High School, right?
I don't know if you're enjoying tonight's meal.
I come here very often with my husband,
I like this kind of place.
But can we accept dinner from a parent?
I have invited all of you here, not as a parent,
but as Seo Yi Soo's boyfriend.
If by any chance you enjoy wine . . .
Oh my!  How did you know that I only drink wine?
Did you tell him, Teacher Seo?
Oh...
About that...
It's written on your face.
Elegant and refined.
I wish that wasn't so blatantly obvious.
It's a bit pricey.
Really?
Then look at just the most pricey one.
I am honored to treat you.
Teacher Seo, you are so lucky.
You have this actor-like boyfriend.
What?  Then are you saying my husband
is lacking qualities?
Everyone says he looks like Jang Dong Gun (actor's real name).
Is that so?
You are so beautiful.
Good-looking men must have something in common!
Teacher Seo, you've met the perfect man.
Yes.
You're drinking a lot today.
I am in a very good mood.
Cheers, then chug it.
Cheers!
One shot!
Please take good care of her, who is careless very often.
Our Teacher Seo is like a younger sister to us.
I think you know already because you've heard, but I'm really sorry that
I am the sole flaw in her life.
What do you mean by flaw? No one thinks of it like that here.
Then that's good.
But I wish for her to be happy while doing
the work she wants to for a long time.
In order to make that happen, I hope that you guys will help out.
All of us here are on Teacher Seo's side!
Teacher Seo...
Cheers!
Are you alright?
Yes.
I didn't drink a lot.
Thank you. You did a lot of work today.
If it is this kind of work, then I'm not opposed.
Let's stay seated a little bit longer before we leave.
Okay.
Should we turn on the radio?
Alright.
My hot lips want to
touch your soft lips.
So that my love will be delivered to your heart
What are other stations playing?
Touch me. Hold me. Don't stop.
I feel like I am about to fly.
To my two eyes
Start now. Little by little, hotly.
Don't be afraid.
The sun shines a path before your eyes.
Don't ever stop.
Don't go home, baby.
I have a present here for you.
Don't go home tonight, baby
So funny.
What kind of a radio turns on music according to the person listening to it?
It's so weird that all the songs are sexy.
I know.
I think when I hear this song later, I will remember today.
I can make it more memorable.
What are you going to do
if I don't let you go home tonight?
I don't want to let Seo Yi Soo go.
My love, my love.
My love that I long for.
Who I call out as loud as I can
but can't hear me.
My love, my love.
My love that I miss.
A melody of destiny that cannot be forgotten.
Five Fingers