- Come on, Perla! Here!
- Come to me.
Come on, Perla! Here, Perla.
- When will be our turn?
- In a little while.
- I must go home. It's almost dinnertime.
- I'll stay a little longer.
How am I supposed to get home?
I came with you.
Okay, let's go.
- It's dinnertime.
- Follow your brother.
- See you tomorrow!
- Goodbye!
Dinner is ready, Baldur!
Are you going far?
Yes.
I see that you are armed.
Nothing to keep you
here anymore?
Good morning.
Are you going with me this time?
I'm going to town.
I know.
I have written a new song,
but it is not quite finished...
I will play it for you later.
So...
I thought you were going to town.
I missed the bus.
Mom?
Is it cod?
Don't we have
any haddock?
Here it is.
- Are you going to stay home tonight?
- No.
- What should you do?
- Anything, I don't know.
Why don't you stay home?
There's a good movie on tv.
Why don't you find a boyfriend?
I am lesbian.
There's more on the shelf.
Hello, Lukka.
They should have distilled it better.
Fucking moonshine...
This was funny maybe once,
about five years ago.
But she's an adult now.
When she is sober you may ask her
where the hell she parked the tractor, Karl.
I will need it this afternoon.
Thank you, Einar.
- I was going to introduce myself.
- Welcome.
It's not a large congregation, so
it is important my personal contact.
I heard that both of you
use to sing in the church choir.
Do you enjoy being here?
Or they sent you...
No, I have no children and I'm not married.
- Want some coffee, something to eat?
- I don't know if I can take more...
I have eaten a lot at Staöur's home.
But I would love to.
- What do you do here on the farm?
- We produce milk.
- And how is it going?
- We can't complain.
- I'll see you on Tuesday.
- Sure.
Where is the tractor?
Where is Einar's tractor?!
- Behind Iadan in Hrauntunga.
- You need to stop that.
There is not a scratch on it.
I can pay the fuel.
- With whose money?
- Nevermind.
- I'll go to town soon.
- You must find something to do!
The winter will start soon, ask
Halldora for a job at the slaughterhouse.
I won't be like her.
I have my own plans!
You cannot live in a dream forever,
Hera Karlsdottir!
Hera, hairnets.
You must wear a hairnet.
Hairnet!
- I haven't found anyone.
- Those are the rules.
- How's Satan doing?
- Go fuck yourself.
And tell your girlfriend
to do the same.
Excuse me, there's a line here!
We missed you.
I'm still with flu, but I'm better now...
He seems to be very nice.
But why he's not married, do you know?
Well, who knows?
Maybe he likes men.
He is certainly more liberal
than the last priest.
- What about Charles?
- What do you mean?
- Is it better with his arthritis?
- Yes...
I mean... he does not complain.
He's not known for doing that.
The strong, silent man...
No. The dryer is in the socket.
I must do something about
our damn electricity.
Do you have to play so loud?!
You are going to make your mother deaf!
Can you play something...
Happier?
Out. Get out!
- Where are you going?
- We have to be involved with our community.
What about mom?
I'm going with you.
Mercyful Lord...
Sorry.
What are you doing?
It is not allowed to smoke here.
Can you go outside and put it out?
Then you can come back.
Hey. We were not introduced.
Your brother?
I feel so much.
He's in good hands now.
- Is this new?
- Really old.
Teaze, "One Night Stands."
Yeah... I know Teaze.
I will never solve it.
How is school?
It's okay...
Just a semester left.
- And then, what?
- I have not decided yet.
- Haven't you decided it previously?
- I'll look into different possibilities.
- Don't you have a girlfriend?
- It's mostly guys here.
A married girl works in the cafeteria.
There's another one in the store. But it is
nothing like that, she just work there.
And what do you listen to? Eurovision-shit?
I really don't care that much about it.
Haven't you listened my mixtape?
Well, I have it in the car.
Let's go dancing tonight?
It's been a long time since I was at the disco.
Not long enough, I think.
- Hey, hello there.
- Hello.
Don't you remember me?
Ena, Sigurdur's wife, from Haugur.
No.
Oh, it's been a long time since I moved.
I remember when you were a baby. I
have even changed your diapers.
That's wonderful.
- Oh look, here's Miss Perfect.
- Hello! Can't believe you're here...
It is funny to see you!
It's like a reunion.
Remember that we were only three kids in our class.
I have twenty-six children in mine.
What are you doing here?
Not starving to save children somewhere?
You haven't changed at all, Hera!
I came home to visit my family,
and then decided to dance!
I have not seen you.
Aren't you living in your town anymore?
Last time we met you were going there.
Shall we dance?
For who?
Will you dance with me?
Not now.
Karl?
Where are you going?
Home.
Watch out!
Wait!
- Why are you following me?
- We're best friends.
And I was getting bored there.
Crappy music. No Rock at all.
I wouldn't mind that.
Ask my dad first.
It's his cow.
Don't go.
- Oh no.
- Why not?
Stop it!
Hey, stop touching my breast!
It was not my intention.
It's just breasts.
They did not explode.
Do you have a condom?
- Have you?
- I was not expecting this.
I can try to...
Does your dad have one?
Fuck it ...
Are you sleeping?
I want to tell you something.
It is not confirmed yet.
He does not want people to know it
until everything is done. But...
Elli on Holtsmüli
asked me to tame his foal, Fluga.
I was there earlier today.
The foal has a very good temperament.
Elli dreams to ride it,
but it can also be used for breeding.
The first steps are important.
You must know what you're doing.
Mistakes cannot be undone.
A horse will always remember the errors.
Next summer is the last chance to
tame the foal. And then it will be four years.
Hey, honey.
What keeps you here?
It's time for we to get rid of these
things. They are not going to be used.
- I can make it it a living room.
- A living room?
- Life is not over.
- You have no right to do something.
This room will remain here!
Young musicians caused a wave
of attacks on churches in Norway...
A movement called "Black Metal".
This 500-year-old wooden church
in Bergen burned down last week.
Another thirteen got the same fate last year.
I would like to see this music banned
and vanish from the face of the Earth...
and all those who are
behind it must be arrested.
Pagan symbols
adorning album covers...
from bands like Mayhem,
Hades and Darkthrone...
their lyrics are difficult to discern,
but contain negative messages.
The priest Sven-Ole Christiansen
speaks about the dangers of this music...
...and leads an organization
that wants to ban it.
- When I first listened that music, it gave
me a cold shiver, and I thought, "What...
Oatmeal is done!
We have to get out and ...
- Not now, Knütur.
- I need to talk with you.
I bought it last summer before school
began. I've saved it.
- Is this a joke?
- No.
Don't you want to have a look?
I can take care of us...
Can't you see anything?
What?
Damn! Get out!
What's the matter with you?
Get out, you idiots!
Go away!
You are free!
- I don't understand you anymore.
- What's wrong with your mind?
- You don't have to talk to me like this.
- Yes we do!
You let the cows flee in the middle of winter!
- Can't you just be normal?
- Normal? Like you?
- You don't know what I've been through.
- I don't? Explain then!
It would be easier if she gave a
chance. Things can't be like this forever.
Has she been difficult
like this for a long time?
There was never a moment of peace.
I can't sleep when she's not at home.
What are you afraid might happen?
And what about your life as a couple?
Is everything alright?
That's not the problem.
It can be difficult to manage
a loss. Did you get any help?
I mean, based on what happened.
We have some good friends here...
It's just something we've got to live with.
And what about her?
I'm sorry to hear that...
How old was she?
She was twelve.
Hey.
"Shout at the Devil", "Screaming
For Vengeance ". Classics.
You don't understand.
Don't? What's that
I do not understand?
Church is always saying that these bands
are related to Satan worshipping and all that stuff.
But if you read their lyrics...
They deal with death and war -
about reality.
They say things about it,
and not to harp on it.
You could never understand.
What are you doing?
Never judge a person by appearance.
I'm proving that I can be your best friend.
Which bands do you like?
Bands that I like?
Where should I start?
Iron Maiden, early Leppard,
Diamond Head, Celtic Frost...
I love Venom,
especially as a live band.
Cronos is probably
my favorite frontman.
Now you think that with
the new priest it can be different?
God can also be found in the dark.
Jesus did not mind walking with the outsiders.
He himself was an outsider.
That was why he was crucified.
Most people can't do what Jesus told:
"Accept people as they are".
He is in debt with me.
About your brother?
Wanna talk about it?
What?
I was just wondering
why you did that.
They say that time heals all wounds.
This is fucking bullshit.
Don't do this, Karl.
It's up to you.
- We've never talked about what happened...
- Of course we have.
Not sincerely.
I know you think...
I...
I should have... put protection
of the drive shaft.
I never blamed you.
But I know what you think.
- People have to do a lot of things.
- Yes, too much.
There was so much that summer...
We had purchased the land, and the
tractor used to break down all the time.
Sometimes I was under
the engine hood all day long.
I can't go on like this.
Hey. I've made a mixtape.
Just a few songs you might like.
See you around.
Did you want
to come here?
A good song.
Damn, what a long time since I heard it.
The first song from
"Sad Wings of Destiny".
They helped me get through school.
I listened a lot of bands at that time.
There was not a day that
I didn't listen to Priest.
Downing and Tipton are my favorite
guitar duo. And Halford is a god.
A metal god!
Wait... listen to it.
What a song.
Black Sabbath, Purple
and Zeppelin announced it, they made it.
You know your stuff.
It was Baldur's favorite song.
He always listened to it.
You make some of your own music too.
Where have you heard that?
Has my father told you about me?
I'm curious.
Yes.
- Can I hear it?
- It's not finished yet.
- What are you afraid of?
- Afraid? I'm not.
I'm not afraid of anything.
POST SERVICE
What is it that keeps me here?
It does not suit me that well...
Because I'm not one of them
with a spoon shoved up my ass...
Now I'm looking to get my ass out of bed...
They secretly look forward...
peaceful images of the country life...
They want to live a happy life
With no issues to deal with...
They're children of nature,
Armed with their optimism...
Do we want our children to fall asleep?
Farewell, my little Reykjavik!
My city...
With the boots on...
Hey.
Wouldn't you ask the lady to come in?
- Am I disturbing you?
- I was going to bed.
It's only eleven o' clock.
Age is taking its toll?
Can I help you with something?
I just wanted to meet you.
You're different.
I can talk to you.
- Hold me.
- I can't.
Why not? Because you're a priest?
- You're not Catholic.
- Hera, you have misunderstood...
- I thought...
- I'm terribly sorry if I've...
This time she has gone too far.
Now she went away from town...
It's time for us to move on.
I have to let go of him.
Yes.
It will be good...
Baldur...
It's the community meeting.
We have decided not to publicly
reveal how the fire started.
The congregation will say
that it was an accident.
We're doing this as a sign
of respect for your parents.
I will help with the funding.
Since we live together now,
it is the right thing to do.
It's not necessary. I'll do this myself.
You cannot do it alone.
Well, if it takes the rest of their lives.
Everyone knows what you and your family
have been through -
...so we've decided to help
and build a new church together.
Take it, dad.
That's for you. It is a
housewarming gift, you might say.
What is it?
I know you don't wanna change anything,
but we use one of those back in school.
It's good to be able to make sandwiches
or heat up leftovers.
It is a microwave.
Thank you.
I'll put it to use.
Are you sure that is it fresh?
Sure, we got it yesterday.
Hello, dear.
Hello? Yes...
- Hera, a phone call for you.
- For me?
Hello?
- Some foreigners are here asking for you.
- Foreigners?
- Hera Karlsdottir?
- Yes.
Hi, I'm Øystein.
This is Yngve and Pål Ole.
We heard your music. We got ahold of
a copy of your tape in Oslo.
- We want to release it at our label.
- It's a small one but...
- Your sound is unique.
- But that was just a demo.
It is the most evil and brutal music
I have heard. Your band is incredible!
Band? There... I did it
on my own. It's just me.
- How did you get here?
- We arrived by boat Norröna.
- The day before yesterday.
- It took us four days.
Take it for you.
Was it bad weather?
I was damn seasick the whole way.
I'm not used to it.
We took the express bus
from Eskifjördur to Reykjavik.
It was a misunderstanding, and we
did not know it took so long.
- How much milk do you produce per year?
- A cow yields about 6,000 liters per year.
What is it that hangs
around the udders?
A bra.
How many animals do you have?
Your hair looks beautiful that way.
Now I can see more of your face.
Thank you.
You have changed.
But you probably know what you're doing.
Yes.
- That's what's important.
- I thought you'd be happy.
It's not about what I want.
Hey, come on and please help us.
There's no reason to be shy.
How is it going?
What? Did you forget something?
I am so incredibly sorry.
Knütur, can I talk to you?
I need to say a couple of things.
- What is it?
- I just want to explain.
Explain then. Is that so hard?
Should we really listen to that?
I never wanted to play in a band, but
I sold my horse to buy a drum kit.
I always liked you and supported
all of your weird ideas.
- You kissed me on the hill at school!
- Knütur, we were eleven years old.
You have never for one second
thought about how I feel.
It must be awesome to be so tough
and always know exactly what to do.
- It must be amazing.
- I'm not that tough.
- I changed me for your sake!
- I haven't asked you to do that.
I hate Dio. I can't support him...
"Holy Diver"? What the hell does that mean?
You must also have known that.
We have not been honest with each other.
I was just expecting...
You are my best friend and I love you.
But not the way I do
I'm sorry...
Get out!
- You got a pick?
- Yes, it's in my pocket.
- Wait in the car, I'll be right back.
- Bye. And thanks again for the dinner.
Are you tense? Of course you are.
Your first big concert!
There is no concert.
We'll play only two songs.
- Want a ride, crazy one?
- No, thank you.
It must be nerve-wracking.
What do you say?
I'm getting really nervous.
It's too loud!
Flesh and blood
To earth you shall return
- We can't hear you singing!
- Play something Icelandic!
Flesh and Blood
To earth you shall return
Courage of a warrior
Anything shall burn
The scorched earth
Devouring our best
Always killing everything
My pain
It drains my soul
Plagued defeat
Black sands of Iden
As far as the my can see
Lacerated all land
There shall be no end...
Every detail is reminiscent of him,
about how it could have been.
But life must go on.
You can't wallow in grief
forever, it will eat it up.
I can't.
Certainly we can.
English translation: Alex Witchfinder