This is a city near the sea
Tidal carrying people
Departure homing
It also brings many stories
The corner dock
A seat prominent red lighthouse
It is time to shine the light
Always remind people to come and go
That final
Road to home
welcome
Oh, the first time
Only those menu
But if you want to eat special
I want to do you can do to eat
Wait
You are this place were it
Hello there
My name is Kelly
I'm Mark
I can not hear
Mark is a crew
Childhood deafness
But it looks very nice
Female guests are often unaware of the strike
He is pretty surprising
Hello there
My name is Angel
I'm Mark
sorry
I am Ai Lin
Ai Lin
Eileen
Nice to meet you
Good
This man handsome ah
How can Oh
I hate you
Such a good stuff
You did not introduce me
You're out of it
His ears hear
He ah
Dedicated lines running ocean
Would rather stay at sea
He do not want to exchange with others
Ling-Ling ah good man out
I see you ah
forget it
I must be picking
I'm Vicki
Vicki
I'm
Most of the time Mark
The girls would quickly leave the store Mark
mark
Other times
He will have a windfall
In fact, he
It is a completely lonely man
Rove between the crowd and the sea
until one day
Welcome light
Hello friends after class
Uncle good
Hi Lele
Lollipops for you to eat
Thank you, Uncle rude
These two pieces of cargo
Just like those two
This afternoon have to let it go
Aaron then tomorrow
Be careful
Ah Yin
Catch you coming
Lele
Run Run Run
Fifty-eight yuan keep the change
Well, the boss did not
I'll miss
He has a straw boss
Have
Miss your straw
I want to boss Mark
Accompany me to see the movie
But he can not
Read so many words
And he has been to me
Translation to him
Many of his questions
Oh
That it was not
Well a lot of fun
I will not be
Good to see a film friends ah
That next time
I go to see a movie is good
Do not want it
So I can not tell you to listen
Oh, that is
Ok
I have to remind Mark
You have grown up
He had to keep up with you Yeah
You think the boss Mark
With the other dad does not like it
It is not the same
but
Because he is an alien
So his language
With us it is not the same
But I like his language
I would also like
Your boss did not give me
Put it to steal vegetables
Please check
Dad's favorite vegetables
And children do not eat vegetables
This Xiangshui
Welcome back
Take a look inside what
Delicious
mark
Our school today
We have learned a dance Yo
You jump with me, OK
what
Well jump together
Well a little faster
jump
Mark a little faster
Since coming Lele
Mark posting on the application
From crew
Into a shipyard maintenance workers
The real from the sea
Back to the land
Hear it
Lele do not eat vegetables
Not a bit to eat
Mark was very nerve-racking
So every Friday
Lele is
Vegetables daily supplement
Well, the boss did not
Coming
Wait
and also
Long live Friday
Please That movie really touching
good or not
(Where touching)
Where not touching
(Not just a bunch of monsters scare children)
That big eyes
Really hard in scary
It nearly made it
You can not read the subtitles and friends
You do not know it
(do you want it)
Do not
(Next month I buy it for you)
Really I do not have a
The terms of the contract
Please read the detailed
(and many more)
(Not stamped on it)
You can say it
We do not understand
what
Your father can not read ah
That your mother do
My mother in Xia Weiyi
We save money
And so we saved enough money
We went to her
You speak slowly
I can understand the
Coming
Today boss Mark to our school
When the story Oh Dad
Really really ah ah
Lele picked up a text book
The Lion and the Mouse
Talking about what the story ah
Lions put a little mouse
Mouse and saved lion
Then they became good friends
Good fun
Sure enough, look at children's books are for children
In real life ah
Lion with mouse
You will not know when friends
You are too real friends
How does it
I told Aaron
Well that is a good friend
Mark and I also was ah
Best best friend
Me too
(Lele have a best friend at school do)
a lot of
A small pull-yu Qibei children
But there are a bully my little boy
I sat behind Chen Yikai
Always kept pulling my hair
(What about you)
I told him
You like me
Send me candy bar
You pull my hair
Hair do not give me that ah
You're great
Put great
Lele
You have not told me
Mark is how
To tell you the story ah
With a ratio of ah
Ratio of ah
How more than ah
For example, this is the owl
This one
Wow so hard ah
The lion than how
That it was
Mouse do the little mouse
What if
long, long ago
A lion
He met a
tiger
How to say
What did he say ah
He said
I'm going to tell you what to do ah
Standing at attention looking here
Too nervous to ease
Heroes appear soon
It too loud
Come on Come a pep talk
I'll give you artificial respiration
You have to be my prize winner
Oh, my baby you and me
red beans
Red beans
taro
Shaved shaved shaved shaved shaved shaved
You want to add
What material
red beans
Red beans
taro
Mung bean powder round Mi Taimu
Peanut and jelly immortality
Taro dumplings small round cake flour
Ching Bing Tangshui milk ice
Spicy sweet and salty
The smell of incense best
How to match whatever you
Guarantee mood change for the better
Standing at attention looking here
Too nervous to ease
Heroes appear soon
The best man was the first
Come on Come a pep talk
I'll give you artificial respiration
You have to be my prize winner
Oh, my baby you and me
mark
Mark Mark
Clean the wound is
(What's up with her)
How child injury
(I do not know)
(I found out she hit the floor)
(Head had been bleeding)
Ok I do not understand sign language
Your wife does
(I hear) come yet
When he sent
Do not leave your name and information
Give him a pen and paper ah
You write down write down
(She bumped his head)
(Why she would not wake up)
Contact Director Liu is
boss
(I'm a bad father)
What happens now
They took Lele
That is to understand
Their living conditions
They were also temporarily not to meet
They like doing
These people are sick do
Hello I am a hospital social worker
Now we want to know
Children's rehabilitation situation
Some of life assessment
She does just need to be hospitalized for observation
So let's take care of it by the
In order to avoid her wounds were infected
She will temporarily isolate
It is the best way
We are also in the protection of children
Good for her
Etc. We have evaluated
She can be discharged home
of course
The reason we will of her injured
To understand
thank you
what are you doing
All right all right all right
You are so excited about Lele recovery
It did not help
We are all for the sake of her health
Sorry sorry
You go you go first
You're scaring her friends Well, well
Mark Mark Gee
You calm down first before you calm down
calm down
Why not come pick me up Mark
Because you have not hurt good
Aunt to ask you some questions, oh
How you learn to speak it
They just speak my learned friends
But your father
You can not teach it to speak
This is what you see Aunt
Yes
Penguins do
You see how I learned to speak
That action is not done talking
Lele aunt asked you ah
You do housework because it falls right
You only five
So you every day
We have to do a lot of housework
help with housework
What is wrong with you
boss
They also understand the situation
And then wait for a while
I went over there, Dr Chan
You stay with him for
Why can not I go home to die
You can spend the night here today
Aunt to buy a lot of good
Hamburg fried chicken to you
why
This is the inspection report for you
Thank you
Lele is type AB
like me
Grow up must be very clever
That type O it
It is also very clever
Who is type O
mark
Your father is type O
Ah My father is type O
How you coming
Lele's mother
What is your name
I do not know
Then you explain to me
Why is your blood type
And does not match Lele
I do not know why
why
Because Lele
Is simply not your real daughter
Lele is my daughter
Your blood type does not match and Lele
But you she has her birth certificate
why
Lele is my daughter
The child in the end is where's the
mark
Only you tell me the truth
I can help to you
The child in the end is where's the
what
I'm looking for a lawyer to
Blood does this matter
In fact, very simple
I explain to you
You know
Blood what constitutes it
Three genes
ABO
It is a dominant gene AB
O is recessive gene
So these three genes twenty-two group phase
What is obtained after permutations
Get our biology.
Six kinds of blood
Which six kinds
And O
Then just said
O because it is a recessive gene
So when it encounters
A and B that two major
When the dominant gene
It does not play any decisive factor
That is to say
AB blood type of a child
His parents must have the same time
A and B are two major dominant gene which
To be able to give birth to a
AB blood type of child
Blood type O
Of course, no AB blood born children
In the end what you say ah
If not natural
That come from Lele
Ok
Mark economic conditions
It is impossible to adopt a child
it is good
Not adopted
But Mark
There is a hospital birth certificate
The fact is certainly not
Mark said that the way
boss
at the begining of
Mark took the children
You appear in
right
it is good
So tell us
That evening
In the end is what happens
For ah boss
Lele in the end is where the ah
As we all know that
Lele's mother threw her
Then Mark
A shoulder to take up the responsibility of raising Lele
Trying to be a good father
This is what happened that night
Yep
there is only one truth
Those abducted the child's parents
Genes have left information
We just find
Children of unknown origin
We will put the child's genes
And database to do than to
The truth soon surfaced
I've asked the head office of legal affairs
To deal with the case of
That will happen next
Lele now
Come back yet
Mark insist on keeping the hospital to visit Lele
Can you win back
difficult
Just because he can not hear the ear
illiterate
still is
Yes
Not entirely
I do not worry too much about it first
Now there is no evidence of adverse Mark
Unless it is proved
Lele is really abducted
But if it is the case
That might come back Lele
Hello there
I am a lawyer Yan
Come
Your friend
Please let me be your lawyer
Do you accept
Ok
If accepted
You can immediately go
When will I
You can see Lele
Oh Lele
I have been proposed to apply
You can see her
But she can not take away
why
Because blood typing
Lele completely unrelated to you
She has not your child
My dad is Lele
She was abandoned by her mother
You do not so impulsive okay
Ok
The other side waiting for such an opportunity
You want to fight for custody of Lele
Chances are very low
Why do you
You no blood
You can not hear
illiterate
Your income is low
I will try to fight
But you have to prepare mentally
If you found
Lele's biological father and mother
You're no chance at all of
You know.
This Friday night
Mark and Lele
Ultimately did not come to the cafeteria
Sister sister school
look
Ah good to determine compliance
I have to report that good
what happened
(I can not take you home)
What does it mean
why
I can not go home and you
Because I fell off it
(Not)
(Not your problem)
(is my problem)
(They say I can not take care of you)
You can not take care of themselves ah
So I have to take care of you
You have to take care of me
(Okay I will soon be back to pick you up)
Come pick me up
(do not worry)
(I'll take you home)
I do not like it here
I can not sleep
We do not go home
You stay here
Hey ah I
Mmm
Investigation centers notified yet
Ok
Lele's mother found
Someone coming soon
Forget the rest come quick
impossible
My boss can not wait three hours
We are about to take off
Whether helicopter or airplane
We are now going to start
Yes, I understand
You are a professional lawyer
She hoped that the aircraft can meet with you
Correct
Ai overall hotel already booked
Is this your passport
Data in line with
This is the information currently found
Ok
Ok, I know
Mmm
it is good
(No mother in Xia Weiyi)
You have something
He did not tell me ah
I was lost mother
You took me to retrieve it
Like Tarzan
(Like Tarzan)
(we)
(To be separated)
(forever and always)
Why I Do not
(Your mom to come pick you up)
I do not I do not I do not
We escape it
Hello there
Owner Mark it in your place
Lee police officer he did in
Oops
He put away Lele
what
mark
Mark hurry hurry
The boss came
Hurry hurry hurry
mark
Mark back
You put yourself into a
Intractable dilemma inside
Daughter also want
Away from me
You're Lele biological mother
She will leave no stone unturned
Jean-Marc forever
Not able to close Lele
You must not give up
She is now the only way to rely on
It is for you
You this shop
Are these people
I really hard to imagine
Her five years
Over what kind of day
may
For Lele speaking
If you can
Back to her real mother there
maybe
better