Episode 35
Guan Lang Village
This child.., doesn't he know how to clean up a little bit.
Excuse me. Is this Yow Tsyr's house?
You... are looking for Yow Tsyr? Anything I can help you with?
Is she here?
She went out.
Of course.
You are...
You must be Zhong Tien Yiu. Do you want t know
what your wife is doing right now?
If I didn't guess wrong,
You must be Tang Bai Bou's wife.
So you know your wife is with Tang Bai Bou.
It has been years. What is so surprising for old friends to meet up?
What about this. Why don't you come in and sit with me.
I think Yow Tsyr will be back soon.
I really don't understand.
Are you useless or are you pretend to be dumn?
You really don't care that they are together?
Ms. Tang,
we are old enough.
What haven't we seen the past 30 years?
Why would you still unsettle about things happened in the past?
Unsettle?
Zhong Tien Yiu, are you so useless and not able to restrain your wife?
Do you want me to be like you not able to restrain my husband?
Okay, I'll go find them myself.
Ok, ok, off you go. I am busy so excuse me for not keeping you company.
Wait
You still didn't tell me where they went.
H-How should I know where they went.
I can't believe you are so useless.
Okay, I'll go find them myself.
Be careful!
Dad! Dad!
Dad, are you okay?!
Mom!
Dad! Dad!
Ke Ke
Mom
Mom, are you okay?
Your dad...
Sorry, we have done our best.
Yow Tsyr. Ke Ke.
Dad, why is your hand so cold?
Yi Fan
You are all good kids.
Yow Tsyr, the person I worry the most
is you.
Ok, Tien Yiu, don't talke any more.
Don't talk. Rest.
Yi Fan, Ke Ke.
Help me take care of your mom, okay?
Old man, why are you talking so much?
There is still me in the family. Don't worry.
It's fine, Dad, you talk less.
You should take a good rest here today.
Tomorrow, let's tell the doctor that we want to go home, ok?
Yes.
Silly child. Everyone has to leave one day.
My Ke Ke and Yi Fan are all grown up.
Dad believe in you tow.
I know you will be able to take good care of yourselves.
Yi Fan, Ke Ke.
Promise me that you will take good care of your Mom.
Tien Yiu, stop talking now.
Don't talk any more.
Promise Dad.
Don't disappoint your Dad, ok?
Being with you all make me really happy.
Don't talk, Dad.
Don't talk.
Yow Tsyr.
Tien Yiu.
Subtitles brought to you by  The Love Band-Aid @ Viki
August 21st,
Yow Tsyr came to me and was crying today.
Even though she didn't say anything
but I know who she was crying for.
Bai Buo is getting married today, she must feel really sad.
What can I do for her so her smile will come back?
January 2nd, I finally gather my curage to ask Yow Tsyr to marry me.
She said yes. She finally said yes.
This is the happiest moment of my life.
No matter what, I promise
I will make sure she live happily ever after.
July 10th,
it is the day our son come to this world.
Zhong Yi Fan, welcome to the world.
Welcome to our family.
The responsibility on my shoulder seems to be heavier now.
March 1st, passing in a flash, we are married for 22 years now.
Ke Ke wrote to us and said she is doing very well at school in Shanghai.
Finally, I can rest my dangling heart.
Your happiness is my happiness.
Yow Tsyr, I really didn't do it on purpose.
This is all my fault.
For 30 years now, I have always want to bring it to an end.
I didn't imagine it will end like this.
As a matter of fact, since we all have our own family,
we already let go of the past.
But Bai Buo has always kept the painting of you.
Bai Buo is only feeling sorry for me.
You and your kids are the most precious thing to him.
Over 30 years,
Tien Yiu and I lived very happily.
You need to let it go entirely,
so you can enjoy your own happiness.
Thank you.
Subtitles brought to you by  The Love Band-Aid @ Viki
Sorry.
Cry if you want to.
Don't touch me. You, go.
I am talking to you. Are you not hearing me?
You. Go!
Don't be like that.
I am not going.
Don't you think that we can be together now they are okay with each other.
Let me tell you, there is a gap in my mind and I can't bet pass it.
We want our own lives, don't we?
That is my DAD!
Don't you show up in front of me. You. Go! Go! Go! Didn't you hear me?
I have told you... I am not letting you go any more.
What do you want from me?
Do you know how much I hate you and your family?
You can hate me and my family.
But please give me one more chance.
I only want to stay by your side,
to pay you back or to take care of you. I only want to stay by your side. I beg you.
I beg you, ok?
Please let me go.
I am not going to be with you in this life. Don't you understand?
Are you sure this is your decision?
♫ Perhaps I am still thinking of you ♫
♫ Perhaps I can still bear to lose ♫
♫ Every memory of you ♫
♫ is why I exist ♫
♫ Where will be a person ♫
♫ who would long for you to sing for her. The voice! ♫
Only one day. Let's be together for one day.
Let's don't worry about anything or think about anything. Let's spend the day together. Ok?
♫ Take my heart and go ♫
♫ Wherever you belong ♫
♫ To holding on what I believe is you ♫
♫ All the memory ♫
Where are you taking me?
My childhood.
- Your childhood? - Mmm.
I like to share with you everything happened in my life.
If I can,
I wish we can both return to our childhood.
Because the smile then is the most innocent and pure.
When we were young and in the class The teacher will said,"Hello, students." What would the students said?
"Hello, teacher."
You are pretty smart!
Do you know how to do eye exercise?
Eye exercise? No, I don't.
I will teach you.
♫ You holding me so tight, there is no disguise ♫
♫ I am longing to feel ♫
Now you know how to play hopscotch, right?
Yes.
- Let's go play. - Ok.
I was little, after school,
my parents didn't come pick me up.
I sat on the swing just like now, swing back and forth.
I saw a lot of kids playing games on the playground.
Gradually, there were less kids.
But I was never afraid.
At that time,
there doesn't seem to be any trouble at all.
It is truly beautiful here.
Yes, it is beautiful.
It is as beautiful as our encounter.
Leave me more beautiful memories.
So when I think of you,
my heart will be warm.
I like to cook for you.
I like you to remember the taste.
Did you remember the restaurant we ate when we first met?
How could I forget?
Back then, you were so arrogant. It mortified you to ask you to eat that meal.
It was all your fault what happened that day.
Why?
My stomach has been very sensitive since I was little. I would suffer from diarrhea if I eat anything unclean.
So that day...
I throw up and had diarrhea for 3 days.
Why did you eat then?
Don't mention little food stand. Even if you ask me to eat poison, I would.
I will eat everything you cook today. Everything will go into my belly.
I like to ask you a question.
What question?
When did you start liking me?
You guess.
I can't.
Then I won't tell you.
Are you going to tell me?
The moment when I saw you.
Really?
What about you?
When did you start loving me?
Me, too.
Ke Ke, which is the pole star?
Don't know.
Fine, I admit I don't know any of the stars in the sky.
Zhong Ke Ke. I have always want to tell you.
Could you be more un-romantic?
What?
You are the least romantic girl I ever met.
Every time.
What about this. Is it romantic?
Not bad.
Remember you have promised me.
You will be happy.
Thank you. I am satisfied now that I had this day.
Sorry, I got here so late.
Mom, you are looking for us?
Yi Fan, I have been thinking. You two should return to the city.
Shao Yin love to dance, You can't let her give up her dream.
Mom, we are here to talk about this with you.
Shao Yin decide to stay here to help us with the business here.
Once Dong Dong is healed, we will bring him back here to stay with you.
But Shao Yin... you are not going to dance any more?
Auntie, I have think about it.
All these years, I have been out on my own going after something so called, the dream.
I have not taken good care of Dong Dong and didn't get him a good father.
Finally I found my happiness.
I am not going to let it go.
I just want to take good care of you and live a good life together as a family, alright?
Thank you! Thanks!
Thank you, my son.
You found a good wife for the family.
Thank you, Yi Fan.
Yang Ming, why are you doing eating? Eat what you like.
Auntie, you are too formal.
Mom, you don't need to treat him like a outsider.
Here, eat the carb.
Yang Ming,
even if my cooking is not good, I am sure it will taste pretty good to you.
Because you know Auntie is very good to you and treat you with my heart.
Auntie, please don't say that. I know you are an excellent cook.
In fact, falling in love is the same theory.
Ke Ke, after experience so much,
Mom like to tell you one thing.
No matter what decision you made,
Mom will be on your side.
But, you can't
avoid seeing how nice the other people have been to you, understand?
Mom, eat.
Mom, Yang Ming and I are getting married.
What are you talking about?
Why? You don't believe me?
Is it so unbelievable? It's making me really unwilling now.
You.. Are you serious?
Is there fake marriage?
Mom, you should think of a good date next month.
This... We still have to get the invitation ready as well as the guest list.
There are so many thing to work out. My head is going to explode just thinking of it. So many things.
Freeze? Eat!
You should eat some crab.
You eat too. Yang Ming, eat some.
Yang Ming, eat more. Eat more.
Just.. Sorry.
Do you have nothing else to say to me?
Auntie said that under that circumstances, I can understand.
But, if she believe you and force you into marriage...
What are you going to do?
Are you welling to marry me?
I... I say sorry earlier was not because
I use you to putting my Mom off.
It is because I told my Mom before asking you.
I didn't know if you are (willing to marry me.)
S-So what you mean is
You're willing to marry me?
You know about my past.
You understand me better than anyone else. You know me better than anyone else.
If you are welling to accept a wounded person,
Then let's get married.
I am willing.
I've always waited for this day to come.
Even though...
I didn't think I have much hope.
But I like to tell you that I am willing and I truly am willing.
I will work very hard to be a good wife.
I will use the rest of my live to repay the good you place upon me.
Do you know?
In fact, right now I
really feel like I am dreaming.
But no matter what. at this moment, you are making me really happy.
We will all be happy in the future.
Auntie, don't see us to the door. We will leave directly from here.
You are still calling me Auntie.
Mom, don't walk us to the door.
Yang Ming, make sure you book the restaurant right away for the date we have agreed upon.
Sure, we know that, Mom.
I wonder if it is too late. Everyone said the engagement party is quite important.
No worries. Success all depends on human effort anyway.
Actually, we only want to share our happiness with our relatives and friends so no need to go all out and waste money.
Yang Ming, I am marrying my precious daughter to you.
Mom, don't worry. I'll take good care of Ke Ke from now on.
Yang Ming, as a buddy, I like to give you a warning.
Don't treat her too nice or you are in trouble.
What kind of brother saying this kind of stuff?
I am just telling the truth.
Fine. We are leaving.
Okay, be careful on the road.
We're leaving. - Okay, take care of mom.
Don't worry.
Okay, okay, okay. Congratulations, congratulations, congratulations.
Good date! Good date!
Ke Ke, you are not a good friend.
True, Director. So sudden. You are getting married!
Yes, so sudden.
I also feel it is very sudden myself.
You guys just have to come.
Of course. This is a very surprising news.
Wrong, this is a heavy weight red bomb. (Wedding invite refer as red bomb in Chinese culture because of the cash gift.)
Our wallets!
In fact, it is only a chance to gather up everyone. Please don't mention about red envelope. (Red envelope = cash gift)
Ke Ke and reporter Yang are a fine couple and a best match.
Congratulations. Congratulations.
I going to borrow her for 5 minutes, is that okay? - Of course.