Perhaps some day
you will understand
how much I cried,
I begged on my knees
to those poor bastards.
That night I screamed,
the hills echoed
and people laughed.
I fought with my pain saying...
"A bitch with rabies must"
have given birth to you.
And that is why you have
eaten her breasts.
Now you can swallow me,
now you can devour me,
"as you did your mother."
This woman who sings
was grabbed,
was raped that night.
They didn't care about
my unborn daughter.
They raped me with their
penis and hands,
with no pity for my daughter
watching them from inside.
And not satisfied with that,
they made me swallow the dead penis
of my husband Josefo.
His poor dead penis seasoned
with gunpowder.
With that pain I screamed:
"You better kill me"
and bury me with my Josefo.
"I feel lost here."
Every time you remember...
when you cry, Mother...
you stain your bed with
sweat and tears of sorrow.
You haven't eaten anything.
If you don't want any,
just tell me.
I won't prepare anything.
Na, komm.
I'll eat
if you sing to me,
and freshen
my drying memory.
I don't see my memories,
it's as if I no longer lived.
Come on...
Sit up.
You're worn out
like a dead bird.
I am going to make up
your bed a little.
Mama.
Mama?
THE MILK OF SORROW
Hurry or you'll be late.
Jonatan, come help your sister.
Jonatan!
- Coming!
Can't you hear me?
Jonatan, Mama is calling you.
What do you want?
Help me with my veil.
Take the tip, but carefully!
Look, Dad. My train is short.
I want more material.
More material? Who'll pay for it?
You, Dad. Aren't you my father?
Okay, but I think it's too long.
Dad, it's short.
Can't you see it's short?
Out!
I think it looks fine.
Jonatan, grab the tip.
Look, you're getting it all dirty!
It's not that dirty.
- Shake it!
It's not that dirty!
- Shake it off, son.
Dad, I want
two or three more meters.
It's huge!
How can it be huge?
Máxima, I have no material left.
Get out of here, Chicho!
You won't be happy until
you finish staining my dress.
But, baby, it's just fine!
You're exaggerating.
Dad, I'm your only daughter...
- Okay, but...
Besides, I'm only getting
married once...
Immer auf den letzten Drücker.
I have no money,
I've given it all to your mother!
Fausta, it's short, isn't it?
It needs more material!
Try some ornaments.
My veil! Shit, Mom!
Baby it's long and pretty.
Faustita, tell her it's okay.
Just talk, say something. Faustita.
Use more ornaments, that's all.
- Shut up!
Faustita, are you okay?
Mom, Fausta is bleeding again!
You're bleeding! Fausta!
Your full name?
Where is my uncle?
Your name, please.
Fausta Isidora Huamán Chauca.
Single?
Yes.
Virgin?
I don't know.
This has nothing to do with
her bleeding or fainting.
It's a rather strange,
unusual case.
I've seen similar cases,
but in women older than Fausta,
with a placenta previa.
Which isn't Fausta's case.
Fausta has a tuber in her vagina.
A potato, to be exact.
She hasn't let us treat her.
She's rather upset.
Are you her husband?
I'm her uncle.
You weren't aware, were you?
She's bled since she was a child,
when she's scared.
Her mother,
she just passed away,
and that's why she fainted.
She lived through very hard
times in the village.
Fausta was born during terrorism.
And her mother transmitted her
fear through her breast milk.
The "milk of sorrow",
as we call anyone born that way...
without a soul
because it hid underground out of fear.
There is no illness like this
in Lima, is there, doctor?
I mean, did you know your niece
had a potato in her vagina?
Oh, no, I didn't know about that.
It must have gotten in there by itself.
There's lots of food at home.
Fausta's uterus is inflamed.
That is dangerous because she
could have more infections.
Evidently, as the potato grows,
the bacteria will increase.
What do you mean by growing, doctor?
Have you seen a potato
saved for a long time?
It's the same, the roots protrude
from the vaginal area.
The bleeding isn't related.
Her capillary vessels
are very superficial.
With a simple operation they are
cauterized and that's the end of it.
She bleeds because of the illness,
because of the milk of sorrow.
She was born that way, no potatoes.
How can we harvest potatoes
from a vagina?
The illness of the milk of sorrow,
or whatever, doesn't exist,
and much less transmitted
by a mother's milk.
Here is a document so
as to have her admitted.
Later we can talk about
a real contraceptive.
Thank you, doctor.
Uncle, that doctor knows nothing.
It's not a birth control method,
I know that!
I am not ignorant.
I'd prefer that...
Don't tell my aunt,
she won't understand it.
And you must respect me.
Mom told me that during the
terrorism, a neighbour did it
so as not to be raped.
They said it was disgusting.
I thought she was the smartest.
Then she got married, had 4 kids,
and didn't have to live with a rapist.
These are other times.
In Lima it's different.
Things have changed.
No one will hurt you.
You came to Lima very young.
Mom told me everything!
Your mother is dead, dead!
My uncle doesn't understand me, Mom.
This is my protection.
I saw it all from your belly.
I felt the slashing of your body.
That is why I now wear this
in me like a shield,
like a stopper.
Because only revulsion
stops revolting people.
Uncle,
I have to take her to the village.
With what money?
Don't you worry, Uncle.
I must wash your clothes well
so you won't go
back to the village with me
smelling of sadness.
The contract includes all services.
Coffin, chapel,
and carriage for 600 soles.
That's the best I can do.
The coffin comes with the ornaments.
We want the coffin
and carriage, but in the province.
To the province? That will cost you.
The coffin, carriage and paperwork,
800 soles complete.
Not even if it were a limousine.
Brother, this is a first-rate
service I am offering you.
Look at the coffin, and the ornaments.
You can see the finish on it...
This is the Imperial model.
Besides, I'm the owner here.
Here's my card.
Well, but you cannot have it.
It's the last one I have.
Now it's up to you.
Come this way, we have more coffins.
This one is for fanatics.
For sportsmen. For patriots.
"For God and the country."
This one's for those
who miss the land. Look, pure oak.
Some bring a picture of their
loved one
so as to be together.
And that one is for peace.
It's the Pacific ocean that
lightens their loads
and washes their sorrow.
That's hot, Papi!
That's great for when I die. How much?
500 soles each. It's all handmade.
But figure about 700
for any special iob.
I remember once my sister-in-law
took her father on the state bus.
She put the boxwith the luggage.
Maybe you can too.
Or I can rent you a grave
for one night.
We can remove her the next day
and you find a cheaper place.
Ask Jonatan to do you
a chignon for the wedding.
They're in style.
That puts years on you.
I want my hair loose, like Thalia.
In the TV novel she wears a chignon.
Like in "The Wild Rose".
Did it make her look older?
But I don't like it, Mom!
I was just telling you...
Zonia is written
with an "S".
What will the client say?
She can't read.
It's getting away, Mom!
It's getting away!
Be careful! Get that pigeon, please.
They got away!
Severina, pass me the oil,
and don't burn yourself.
This is making me sick.
Sick or not sick, we've helped so many
preserve their dead.
How could we prove their existence?
We didn't even have a picture,
or an ID card.
We had no proof of being born,
and much less of being killed.
Here go over her breasts,
I don't want to be infected,
it might be contagious.
They're looking for someone
for the Big House,
nights only.
You could go, make money
and take your Mom to the village.
You might ask for an advance.
But you will have to go alone.
What do you say?
Are you sure?
She never goes anywhere alone.
I accept, Auntie.
Okay, honey,
you needed that, didn't you?
Where are you going?
I am going to heaven
to water flowers,
to water flowers.
Where are you going?
I am going to heaven
to water flowers,
to water flowers.
Where are you going?
I am going to heaven
to water flowers,
to water flowers.
Don't worry,
Fina is my friend and she will help you.
I'm going to prepare
Carvaial's wedding.
Hi, I'm glad you're here.
I was waiting.
You're a bit late.
Come in, Fausta, come in.
I'm sorry about your Mom.
I'm having bad luck too.
But, that's life, dear!
I forgot. Good heavens!
Mrs. Aida says there is no advance.
She doesn't do these things.
There's no way.
And as I was saying,
my son is in jail.
Can you imagine?
I hope he doesn't
get raped in prison.
But he must have done something
to have these problems. What a shame!
He says no, but he must
have done something.
He can't tell me he didn't!
What do they think?
Now I have to take care of
my grandchildren at night.
Why must I be in this situation?
You can leave at seven o'clock.
The gardener comes before
you leave,
he is Noé.
Before opening the door,
ask if it's him.
If it isn't,
please don't open
the door for anyone else.
I recommend staying inside
because, as you know,
delinquency is terrible right now
and if you open the door,
they could empty the house.
Hurry up, dear, hurry up.
Hurry!
Let's see those ears.
That's okay. Now your mouth.
Show me your teeth, please.
Let's see those teeth.
And that neck.
You're pretty sweaty.
You'll have to have a bath anyway.
Show me your hands.
Spread your fingers, please.
Oh, well, they're clean.
Your other hand.
Here you have a long fingernail.
Why, what happened?
Why didn't you cut it?
You should know that for these things,
Mrs. Aída could lose interest.
Here is your uniform.
You've got soap,
scissors for you fingernails, shampoo,
and deodorant, which is obligatory daily,
after your bath, your deodorant.
She gives you mimosas
because she's very good.
After your bath, you'll wait
in the kitchen.
If she needs you, she'll call.
If she doesn't,
just stay in your kitchen.
Fina.
Fina!
Finita!
Take this.
My name is Fausta.
What?
Fausta Isidora.
Mrs. Fina told me...
Oh, yes, now I remember.
Hand me that picture.
Let us sing, let us sing.
Let us sing pretty things.
To hide our fear,
pretend it doesn't exist.
Let us sing, let us sing.
Let us sing pretty things.
To hide our fear,
conceal our wound,
pretend it doesn't exist...
Who is it?
Me.
- Me, who?
Noé, the gardener.
Let me see your hands.
Long life to the bride and groom!
Viva!
Smile,
you're not going to the slaughterhouse.
They think they're commiting suicide.
Bravo, bravo!
The kiss, the kiss!
Bravo! Bravo! Applause!
The kiss. Is there no kiss?
The kiss!
Everyone applaud, this isn't a cemetery!
Let them dance. Music, please!
Very close together.
Smile Héctor and Hermelinda.
Have the bride's family come in.
Cheese! One, two, three,
the picture!
Here we go.
Have the bride's family come in.
Smile, everyone.
Stay close together.
Ready? Cheese!
One, two, three... picture!
Now the groom's family.
Get close together...
The groom's family, please.
Everyone smiling. That's it...
Are you all ready?
Cheese. One, two, three... picture!
Hello, hello. Testing, one, two three.
Be careful,
don't trip.
Where is the buffet going?
It's only a mobile buffet.
They have left only chips.
This is the highlight
of "Bodas Chic".
We do wonderful, quality weddings,
within your budgets!
The groom should be more cheerful!
Nowwith your cousins!
Nowwith the old folk!
Did you get the advance
at the Big House?
At the end of the month, she said.
I want no dead people
or sad memories at Máxima's wedding.
You must take Perpetua away
before the wedding.
If not, I'll bury her myself.
Understand?
Round trip? What dates?
Give me the price for a package
and my return trip.
How many people?
- One, sir.
And a coffin.
- What, a coffin?
You had to tell him.
- Are you pulling my leg?
It's a piece of baggage.
There's a donkey for that.
Just move on.
Next! Name?
Wait, can't you see I'm pregnant?
I've had to buy a new piano.
And the other one?
Did it fall out the window by itself?
Yes.
Mom, you left me four messages saying
the premiere is in a week
and you have nothing.
Now I'm here and you act like
everything is fine.
You worry me.
Don't worry, there's nothing
you can do.
That's normal. What do you think?
Isidra, leave it right there.
They're cold.
I'll do it. Sit down.
You were singing a song yesterday.
Sing it again.
I heard you, don't be shy.
I can't, Madam.
Right.
Bring it to my room.
Isidra, come help me.
My necklace has broken.
If you sing, I'll give you a pearl.
If you complete the necklace,
it's yours.
Who is it?
The piano fell.
It's broken, but it still sings.
Can't you hear it?
And these look like coloured sweets.
It's whole and very thin.
It will be a long life
full of love and hope.
Bravo!
- Bravo!
Well, today I will speak
in the name and heart of
my cousin Marcos, Don Lúcido.
With this act
we've confirmed that Máxima
is worthy of marriage,
and that was a gnarled and
very difficult potato, sir.
We wanted to ask
for your permission.
We have a date for the church.
Perhaps you could lend us something,
a little economic help
to carry it out
and to build a roof for our house.
You will no longer have to
take care of Máxima.
My maximum love.
Well, those are the sincere wishes
of my beloved cousin Marcos,
Don Lúcido.
Bravo!
Hey, listen, your cousin is hot.
Didn't I tell you she's ill?
She suffers from the tit illness.
She looks fine to me.
You're crazy.
Can I sit down?
- Sure, sit down.
I'm going for milk.
I bet many guys flirt with you.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Maybe something like
"You're a nice piece..."
if red is the color of passion,
bathe me in your menstruation...
Just call me and I'll kick their asses.
Just let me know.
I'm watering the garden again.
That calms me down.
No.
I've done that concert for 20 years
and I won't miss it.
Not even stark raving mad. I'll show up,
even just to play the funeral march!
Yes.
Wednesday.
Nowwhat?
900 soles, Madam.
You must be out of your mind!
How can you charge that?
I'll never call you again,
you're too expensive.
The job is worth that.
Too expensive. Impossible, I can't.
I'll stay several days
until the job is done.
An optimum iob,
first-rate materials.
At a special price for you.
I only have 700.
Since you always hire me,
Madam, 750 soles.
I'll be right back.
Isidra, is that your name?
- Don't bother the girl.
Let's get to work.
Hi, Faustita.
Máxima sent me to pick you up.
She didn't tell me.
Máxima is "busy" with Marcos.
And since you don't like to
walk alone,
I volunteered.
That's what friends are for.
- I'll wait here.
Faustita, did you make me
come on a whim?
I'll wait.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You'll have to go back all alone.
Could I have a glass of water?
I'll take you home.
Take me where?
- Home.
No, I'm fine.
In my village you have to
walk very close to the wall.
If not, you get caught by
the lost souls and could die.
My brother died of that.
He was as thin as a skeleton
for not paying attention
to the lost souls.
He had terrible stomach aches.
Mom was on the farm.
And Grandfather in town,
selling animals.
Nowwe only have
a picture of his stomach.
That's all we have left.
An X-ray?
Yes, that's it.
We're almost at my place.
It's there, on the corner.
I'll stay here.
But I'll be watching
until you get there.
Auntie! Auntie! A swimming pool!
Let's see
if they recognize you
when we reach the village.
I will carry you on my back
like you did when I was a baby.
My papa will no longer
be alone with the maggots...
In my village they say
that musicians have a
secret contract with a mermaid.
For their music to be heard
more than always,
more than ever.
If theywant to know
how long the agreement lasts,
they must pick from a dark field
a handfull of quinoa,
and give it to the mermaid.
And so
she starts counting.
They say each grain
means a year.
So when the mermaid
finishes counting
she takes the musician
and throws him
into the sea.
But my mother says,
says, says
quinoa grains are
too difficult to count
and the mermaid gets worn out,
so the musician can keep
his talent forever.
You need comforting.
- Why?
There's geraniums, hydrangea, iasmin...
You choose daisies. For comfort.
Plants tell the truth.
They're not like people.
In the stems and blossoms
are the plant's life and memories.
The earth must be stirred
from top to bottom,
so the sun doesn't always
burn the same layer.
If not you get a crust and
the plant dries quickly.
I know that.
I had a small
vegetable garden
in my village.
My little
lost dove,
you ran away out of fear
and you lost your soul,
little dove.
I'm sure your mother brought you
into the world during the war,
and perhaps your mother
gave birth to you with fear.
Even if they
hurt you there,
you shouldn't walk crying,
there's no reason
to walk suffering.
Search for, look for
your lost soul
look for it in the darkness,
look for it in the earth...
Little birds, little birds...
Not this one, sing the mermaid one.
I can't remember. I make them up.
Okay, make it up again,
but exactly the same.
...a mermaid.
From a dark field you must pick
a handful of quinoa
for the mermaid.
And so
the mermaid counts it all.
The mermaid says
that each grain...
What is this?
This was my doll.
They said if I buried it,
the earth would take it away
and I'd never find it again.
Liars!
I brought you a present.
There are geraniums,
camellias, daisies, cactus,
sweet potatoes, everything
but potatoes. Why?
Why are you afraid
to walk alone on the street?
Because...
Me too, because I want to.
I'm not afraid because I want to.
Only death is obligatory,
the rest
is because we want to...
And when they kill you or rape you, what?
That's not obligatory!
Potatoes are cheap
and bloom very little.
All brides stand up, please.
Do you all accept your husbands?
Yes, we do.
Now, all grooms stand up, please.
Do you all accept your brides?
Yes, we do.
Everyone stand up, please.
Grooms,
you may now kiss your brides.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the highlight of the celebration.
The families of the grooms
have saved up all year
to give them a great gift.
Let's receive, with a round of applause,
those guinea pigs
so that the couples may eat.
And here come the rest
of the gifts! Let's see!
There is also a beautiful painting
of the Sacred Heart.
What beautiful gifts
for the happiness of the home!
What great gifts!
Wonderful beer
to cheer up the attendants.
This beautiful sofa
for the bride to sit down on
while happily watching their TV.
Welcome to that bed!
The bed of love!
For the enjoyment of the bride and groom.
And there are the chickens,
for them to have eggs at home.
And those great gifts as well.
That beautiful mirror for
the bride to look at herself.
And that ironing board.
This is wonderful!
And the cradle ready for the baby.
And this bird
to cheer their home up.
Thank you, family.
Thanks for so many gifts!
Let's have them kiss once again.
Congratulations and thank you, family!
What a wonderful family, thank you!
Feeling better?
- Yes, Uncle.
Melvin's taking you to the doctor.
How much did your earrings cost?
What?
- How much did your earrings cost?
My grandma gave them to me before dying.
They're pretty.
- I like them too.
And where did you buy your pants?
In the market.
For how much?
- 12 soles.
Did you buy your sandals there?
What?
At the market too?
- No, at a store.
And for how much?
- 23 soles.
They look comfortable.
- They are.
I'd like to buy a pair, but...
Your report number?
Where is your report?
Didn't you get a paper for admittance?
Or a number for your firstvisit?
Have you come before?
Yes, doctor, but I didn't bring...
What have you got so I can find
your case history?
I don't want to be rude,
but we attend over 80 cases a day.
We're tired and short-staffed.
Look at the line.
Go get the report, come back
tomorrow and we won't waste time.
Next.
You are ill as well.
So you won't follow me.
Look here.
Take them.
Thanks a lot, Barbarita, thanks a lot.
Yes, I'm happy, very happy.
Okay, whenever you want.
All my love. Ciao. Ciao.
Won't you say anything?
Congratulations, it was great.
All of Lima was there.
They really liked it, didn't they?
Isidra gets off here. She's walking.
At the corner?
- Yes, drop her off.
What can I do here?
My pearls, my pearls!
We made a deal!
Stop, Mrs. Aida!
I went to volleyball the other day
and I played with Katty.
I tell you,
she hit so hard
she almost broke my wrist.
Speaking about volleyball,
I've been invited
to a championship.
Will you go?
- Why, sure.
Grandma, say hello to the camera,
a few words.
You'll all look beautiful!
Marcos, I love you.
You better love me
as much as I love you.
They're going to brush the cat.
He'll look great for the wedding.
Uncle, I tried to take her
to the village but I couldn't.
Forgive me, Uncle. Please.
Mom, my train doesn't fly.
Relax, Máxima. Give me a hand.
It does fly!
How could you put balloons there?
Máxima, please relax.
It should fly like the angels!
Marcos is waiting for you.
Come on.
You're so whimsical.
I won't go up until it flies.
- Come on.
No, not till it flies!
Máxima, people are waiting.
Be careful, please.
Slowly, slowly.
Come. Give me your hand.
I don't want to.
- Give me your hand.
- I'll help you.
Máxima, don't be so whimsical.
Máxima, slowly, slowly.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the first picture. Say cheese!
That's it!
Now for the second picture, friends.
Love is so beautiful! Say cheese!
That's it!
The third picture just like Romeo
and Juliet.
Say cheese. Look at the camera.
That's it!
And now all relatives.
A beautiful family.
Mom, on this side.
- Hurry, cousin!
A family united by the love
between Máxima and Marcos!
Hold still a moment,
just a moment.
Just a bit more.
Now look at the camera
and say cheese.
That's it! How nice.
Now we're done.
Now let's get to the banquet,
ladies and gentlemen.
To the banquet!
Today is a very special day.
Love has blessed us.
And now they are also surrounded by
the love of our beloved family.
Thank you for coming.
These were hard times for the family,
but life goes on
and is renewed with new happiness.
Todaywe celebrate life that,
despite everything, always has
beautiful surprises
full of happiness.
We will dance and eat till dawn,
because this banquet today
is going nowhere. It is my gift.
See how you breathe?
See how you want to live?
You want to live but you don't dare.
- Let go!
Breathe!
Fausta, don't leave!
Fausta, don't go! Fausta!
Have it removed. Please.
Get it removed from inside me.
Emergencies, please.
- The 2nd door.
Relatives of Meza Ala.
The doctor said you didn't
open your hand during the operation.
Uncle, stop! Uncle, stop!
Uncle!
Look at the sea, Mama.
Look at the sea.
No, not like that!
You have to stomp your feet hard.
That's it.
Fausta, someone is calling you!
Translation: Edward Ledden
Subtitles: Laserfilm