This is a free fansub
Translation & corrected timings:
themagician@KG
MILKA - A movie based on
Timo K. Mukka's novel TABU
Directed by: Rauni Mollberg
God, grant me love
Grant me what my heart
yearns for
Grant me fruits
to fill my soul's chalice
Grant me flowers
for the pleasure of my eyes
Grant me what I want
But not that which might be
a burden for my small hands;
Anguish for my heart;
Trouble for my mother.
Ojanen will return to our place
with Milka.
Stay further back.
You'll lose your legs
if you get in the way.
- You're too big to frolic.
- I'm not a big girl.
Don't be sad, 'Christ'.
Take this...
Little Milka.
Milka...
What are you holding?
Keep it.
Keep it, if it's so dear to you.
Dear God,
Suffering has penetrated my heart.
Come, God, and take it from me.
Lead me not into temptation,
But deliver me from evil.
Protect your child,
So she might not prove herself
guilty of sin and shame.
And so she might not bring
sadness to her mother's chest.
Grant me light;
Grant me purity.
MilkaÉ
Come here.
How miserable if it rains
every day in the summerÉ
It feels melancholy to have to wait
for winter after a summer like this.
And yet, it is a good thing
that it rains.
It flushes the earth,
It cleanses the earth.
If we had no rain...
We'd have no sun either.
One must have everything,
little Milka.
Milka, the rain isn't stopping
and the hay is going to go bad.
You'd better run to Ojanen and ask
What we should do with the hay.
What would be... for the best.
Put father's hat on Ð
otherwise your hair will get wet.
It's still a good hat.
It hasn't been spoiled by mould.
I came to dry my clothes.
Why won't you fix the roof,
'Christ'?
No need to when it's not raining.
- And when it's raining I can't.
- Yes you can.
What shall we do with the hay?
It'll get spoiled by the rain.
Nothing you can do about it.
Can't move it inside
when it's raining.
You just have to
wait for it to stop.
Mother sent me.
Did you have time to tell her...?
I'm not a kid.
Well I'm not a little girl,
but many boys' prick-tease.
Tilulilu lilulilu tilulilu littuun.
Tilulilu lilulilu tilulilu lei.
Can't I stay here until the rain stops
so I can go home without getting wet?
No.
I miss father.
Father has been granted peace.
He's in comfort.
- We have no reason to be sad.
- I just miss him.
Everyone must walk
the path of death once.
Deliver some butter to Laanila.
I don't want to go there.
Fine, little Milka.
I'll go by myself.
Oh Jesus, the bliss of my life.
With eternal mercy
for your children.
You died for me so that
I could live.
When I get sinful thoughts,
And they darken my spirit,
Then let me be at the base
of your cross
To remember your death.
Here's something for Milka.
- Thanks.
- Though she'll soon be a big girl.
How they grow up! Our Auno, too.
He's a big man now.
He just stays there and plays.
You have that Ojanen
as your field hand.
What's he like?
Everyone knows him,
that 'Christ-Devil'.
A damned good labourer.
Yes, he is.
Come with me, Milka.
There's a frog in the drying barn.
Where is this frog?
Auno, kissing is sinful.
You must think hard before
doing such a thing.
Come have a cup of coffee.
I don't care for coffee.
It's not healthy.
But you've had it before.
Isn't it good
if I don't drink it so much?
It's expensive.
Fine, Milka.
Milka, what if
Ojanen were to repair
the cold bedroom?
You could have it for yourself
at some point.
My husband
would have finished it.
He was a fine carpenter.
But not as good as you.
I'll have to think about it.
Take your time.
Milka,
Would you sleep in the
cubby house tonight?
It will surely be a warm night.
'Christ', wait up.
I'll be your wife.
You're the only one I care about.
Little Milka, you're so young.
I want you, please.
You can't get married
for many years.
By the time you can,
you'll have changed your mind.
You'll find some other fine man.
You'll understand
once you become a woman.
Don't you care for me
even a little bit?
And even if you didn't change your
mind, I still wouldn't want you.
I'll keep on living
the same old way.
It's what's best for me.
Dear God,
There's a fire in my chest
that won't go out,
And I won't ask you to put it out.
I want you to let it keep on burning.
You'd grant me a heart
full of goodness and luck.
And you would grant him to me.
I'd thank you for that, God Ð
Forever and ever.
Take your clothes off, Milka.
Little Milka, you've been quiet.
You're a woman now.
Mother, you've never told me
how to become a woman.
Now you know, little Milka.
You're one beautiful girl.
Not even a princess
can match you.
There's no match for you here...
Though one shouldn't
say it out loud.
People can be so jealous.
- You could stay here.
- I should go warm up the house.
I wish you were my girl, Milka.
I'd make a cradle for you and
rock you in it.
I'm a big girl already.
The bed is still too big for you,
Milka.
You'll grow still.
It's the right of the bedmaker to sleep
in the new bed for the first night, right?
That's right.
Don't I still have...
beautiful legs?
I wish you knew, little Milka.
I wish you knew
what a great day it is today Ð
How well I feel.
Milka, deliver some butter
to Laanila today.
Ojanen may change his shirt.
It needs to be washed.
I'll give you another one.
You could bring all your dirty
clothes here to be washed.
They could be washed with
the small amount we have.
May God bring peace to this house.
Good day, Cantor Malmstršm.
Do you know Ojanen?
He's made all kinds
of things for us...
A new room, a new bed,
A rocking chair...
Oh, so he's a
capable carpenter then?
A good shepherd says
'Tuku, tuku... tukuÉ'
Oh dearest Jesus, come swiftly Ð
come into my heart.
From me the sorrow and suffering take,
And bring me comfort.
You know best
What I need here.
Forgive me my sins,
And give peace to the tormented.
Go ahead and borrow a horse
whenever you need one.
Merry Christmas.
How brightly shines
the morning star.
He brought the light, grace
and truth to the skies.
You holy son of David Ð
My king supreme Ð
You won me over.
Jesus, Jesus,
My only one, my beloved,
The bringer of hope.
I only yearn for you,
the shelter of solace.
On this earth, sins are given
the most beautiful names:
Pride is called honour;
Adultery is called love;
Greed is called frugality;
And beauty is called the
protection of the body.
But the curtains of Satan
are elegant and soft.
The worst enemy lives
within a Christian's own flesh.
Only Lord Jesus can
but with a single word
heal our hearts,
cleanse our feelings
and put an end to all bodily
and spiritual troubles.
But God's love
is like that of a mother's.
It's like an inexhaustible
ocean of love,
bringing with it
bliss and suffering.
We're all on our way to eternity.
Be with us, Lord Jesus,
As evening has come
and the sun is going down.
This is for you.
'Christ', do you want to get dry?
You're not a woman yet.
I'm different from last summer.
I know you're unlike
all the other men.
I can give you everything you want.
Why didn't he come?
He'll come, but not today.
Has he been... offended?
Did he give you a reason?
I don't know. Go and ask him.
That's what I should do.
Keep in mind that he's a good man.
- There's no-one like him.
- I know.
There isn't.
This is for you, little Milka.
May God bring peace to you,
virgin Milka.
Perhaps Ojanen ought to go home.
I have something important
to discuss with this widow.
I'm asking you,
widow Anna Siekkiniemi:
Would you become my spouse?
Little Milka, what would you think
if I became your new father?
Guess what he said...
He wants to marry me.
Where did he get the idea
that I'd accept him Ð
An old man?
He doesn't need a wife,
even for bodily needs.
Would you want me to have him?
No.
I promised to answer
in a month's time.
I hope Ojanen didn't get mad
at us because of the cantor.
Can anyone work better
than Ojanen?
That's the thing.
- There's no-one like him.
- I can go and get him back.
Very well, Milka. Do that.
Run after him.
I'll talk to him.
Mother asked you to come.
You can do to me
what you did on Christmas.
I know you like it.
I can take it.
God,
From heaven you explore my paths.
You live within my heart, God.
Grant joy to my mother's chest.
Grant joy to my mother's eyes.
Wipe away her tears.
Grant her what she wants.
Don't deny it from her.
And grant me what I want.
Let me sleep next to him;
He whom my heart loves.
Thank you for all the good days.
Protect me from evil
When you can.
Everything happens
according to your will.
I love you
from the bottom of my heart.
In spring when women
desire men the most.
The men pursue
a particular matter.
Well...
It's been over a month.
I'm waiting for your answer, widow.
My heart lacks
that feeling for you
That is required in marriage.
Have you given it
serious consideration?
Yes.
Well then.
Perhaps this is how
I'll be rejected
Just as I rejected
that cantor.
Well...
Rejected the cantor...
can't have the priestÉ
I'll have someone far better,
if I can.
Perhaps you'll have a new
father soon, little Milka.
'Christ', don't you
care about me after all?
Why are you rejecting me?
I won't reject you, little Milka.
What's happened?
You'll take mother
as your wife anyway.
Take me.
Milka.
Tell me, is blood still
coming out from within you?
Not any more.
Aren't you happy about that?
Yes... I am.
'Christ'.
Come.
- Do you still have that coin
I gave you in the summer? - Yes.
Put it inside this ball.
Seal it tight;
It won't open any more.
Did he promise to
come and visit?
He didn't say.
I hope nothing's...
happened to him.
What's inside?
I don't know.
It won't open.
Perhaps he'll tell me.
Probably.
Anna Siekkinen doesn't
come here very often.
- Where's she going now?
- There's so much to do.
We'll go visit Ojanen.
It's probably a waste of time.
He borrowed a horse and cart
from us yesterday.
Must've gone to village
to sell his works.
He's a capable man.
He's been an essential help
for us for many years.
It would be great if you could ask
him to come by when you see him.
We won't do anything
if he's late.
Do you want anything to eat,
mother?
- How's everyone doing here?
- Well, thanks.
I've been having a headache.
I don't know why.
Right.
We haven't heard anything
about the former field hand.
We lost a horse and a cart.
It doesn't matter much.
Go, Milka.
Make her a cup of coffee.
Thanks.
You don't have to.
Auno ought to help you
With the hayfield.
And with other things...
if you need anything.
- I came to help.
- We don't need help.
Have you heard anything
About 'Christ-Devil'?
What about yourself? Have you?
Perhaps your mother would
like to hear about him.
Didn't she sleep with him
at your place?
Soon we'll catch 'Christ-Devil'.
He'll end up in prison.
Who told you about Christ-Devil
and mother? Tell me.
It's the talk of the town.
I will bring to justice
anyone who shames my mother.
But it's true.
Anyway,
You know it.
We don't need Laanila's help.
We'll get by on our own.
But I won't...
Why didn't you want Auno inside?
You can see he's
in love with you.
I don't care for him.
Good night, Milka.
Milka...
With whom have you been?
What, mother?
You've spread your legs!
You've given yourself!
You'll have a child.
I didn't know.
With whom?
Tell me, with whom?
Say with Auno.
Have you been with Auno?
With nobody. I swear.
Goddamnit... you're lying!
With whom, then?
- For the love of God, with whom?
- I didn't know.
- With whom?
I didn't know.
Is that why 'Christ'
left and abandoned us?
Abandoned us in shame?
Left me alone.
I didn't know.
Mother...
I haven't sinned.
I've committed no sin at all.
Do you believe me, mother?
I swear.
I believe you,
My child.
God.
You've concealed
your secrets from me,
You haven't given me
your knowledge.
Suffering has penetrated
our chests.
Sorrow has settled in our house.
Laughter has vanished
from our house.
God...
Why won't you let the sun
shine into our souls?
Why do you abandon us?
Why do you forget your children?
Milka,
You'll give birth to
a child of Christ-Devil,
But I'll marry you.
I don't care about you.
You can make love to me.
You can have me here.
Virgin Milka,
can I walk with you for a bit?
The birth of a child is
God's grace.
A great gift.
It was not granted to me.
I wish you were my girl...
You'd bring flowers to my grave.
You can make love to me.
You can have me here.
I wouldn't dare!
A pious manÉ
But Milka hasn't been
With anyone.
But something has happened.
But we can probably right it.
The cantor is a good person, mother.
He is a good person.
Am I not good,
Little Milka?
You built this for me and Milka.
There's none other like it.
Sometimes I miss him.
Still...
There's no hope.
I wonder what's inside?
He's hidden a secret in there.
He was a beautiful man.
Curiosity leads to punishment.
...his guidance...
Look, my boy.
Don't cry.
This is a table.
Look, a table.
Well, naturally
he's ignorant of it.
A table. That's right.
He'll learn once he grows up.
This here. It's a book.
A book, indeed.
He doesn't understand yet.
Of course not.
A beautiful child.
Into pieces, God...
Into pieces,
they tore my heart...
And sucked the blood
out of my veins.
But I passed by you
with joy in my heart...
Once the suffering had passed.
And once again my heart was full,
as if it were full of milk.
I took my heart in my own hand,
I explored my paths
with my own eyes,
With my own lips
I kissed my wounds,
And healed my suffering.