Hello. I'm Johnny Cash.
Good evening.
Feels good tonight.
Jacks, go and get ready.
Your dad's coming.
I fell into a burnin'
ring of fire
Went down, down, down
And the flames went higher
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
Why do I have to go
with my father?
Because Sam came first...
you came second...
so...
I might as well keep the first.
Bound
All right, ready?
One, two, three.
Paper beats rock.
I fell into a ring of fire
I fell into
a burnin' ring of fire
Went down, down, down
One, two, three.
Scissors beats paper.
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
The Memphis Horns
and the Tennessee 3.
The taste
Of love is sweet
I don't want to go
with my father.
Get out.
When hearts like ours meet
I fell for you like a child
All right, again.
One, two... Yes!
Rock beats scissors.
But the fire went wild
I fell into a burnin'
ring of fire
Chicken.
Went down, down, down
And the flames went higher
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
Got you! You're dead!
I'll show you whether I'm dead.
I fell into a burnin'
ring of fire
Went down, down, down
Get off of me!
And the flames went higher
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
Aw, shit!
And it burns, burns, burns
The ring of fire
See you.
Come on!
Fuck you, Red!
Fuck you, too, baby!
World's going to think your head
blowing apart is a backfire.
Don't miss.
Forget about it, Red.
I'm not marrying him.
That's the deal you made.
Fuck the deal.
Fuck you!
I would hit you in the face,
but it's your wedding day.
You get the fuck up...
before you ruin
that nice dress even more.
Think you can make
a fool out of me...
steal from me
and just walk away?
You lucky you got
a nice piece of ass.
Otherwise...
I don't even want
to think about it.
You going to marry
that little fucker Sam...
and you going
to cook and clean...
and you going to suck his cock
every once in a while.
Do you want to know why?
'Cause that's the worst thing
I can think to do to you.
Now fix yourself up pretty
because people are waiting.
You want to fight me?
Go fuck...
I changed my mind.
Bill...
Stay right here.
Be right back.
Yo, Red. Red, how you doing?
Yeah, what?
Shake hands.
Go get a job, man.
Got one?
Come on.
That was good. I like that.
- Hey, guys.
- Hi, Ruby.
My favorite cop.
Yeah, what?
I took care of that
little problem for you.
You might want to go away
for a couple of days...
go fishing or something.
All right.
- How'd we do this week?
- Good, boss.
I don't know. It looks like
it could've been better.
Good... Business is good.
Every day is payday.
That's a nice tux, Sam.
What's this?
The American dream, huh?
Yeah. Why not?
Hey, why not?
Get going, buddy.
Well...
There she is...
Your Christmas bonus...
a few months early.
You're a beautiful girl,
Freddie.
I feel bad the way you turned up
in this bad crowd situation.
It's a shame.
If ever you want a way out,
just...
give me a call.
You know? Maybe I can help.
Fuck you.
God. She's beautiful.
She was beautiful yesterday.
Yeah, but today, she's mine.
What are you fucking looking at?
Let me ask you something, Lloyd.
Why are you
such a fucking wick, huh?
All passengers
should be on board.
I wonder if your brother
is going to show up.
Jacks.
Who invited him?
I told him it wasn't right...
if he didn't come
to his brother's wedding.
But, please, if he comes,
try and get along with him.
Sam, I'm talking to you.
What if she doesn't come, Mom?
Will you stop eating?
I didn't take your money.
I told you that!
You embarrass me, little girl.
Sir, sit down right here.
Come on, Freddie,
make it easy on yourself.
Come on, get in the spirit.
Straighten up.
Hope you two kids
will be very happy.
Dearly beloved...
we are gathered here
in the sight of God...
to witness and bless...
Hi, Mom.
the joining together
of Sam and Freddie...
Jacks, you came.
How nice.
What's the story?
They make a nice couple,
don't they?
No, they don't.
Behave yourself, Jacks.
But that is the portion
in this life...
What did you get them?
Whisper it to me.
When it is God's will...
Come on.
Nothing, Mom.
I didn't get them nothing.
Knowledge
and love of the Lord...
Therefore, marriage
is not to be entered into...
unadvisedly or lightly.
You showed up empty-handed.
And in accordance...
What is the matter with you,
Jacks?
Into the holy union...
Sam and Freddie
now come to be joined.
Here we go. I love this.
When somebody loves you
It's no good
unless he loves you
All the way
Happy to be near you
When you need someone
to cheer you
All the way
Can I get a beer?
I just want to get
the fuck out of here.
Thanks.
Who are you?
Jacks.
Jack?
No, Jacks.
Jacks?
- Jacks what?
- Clayton.
You're not related to him,
are you?
Sam's my brother.
I don't know who's worse off,
you or me.
Me.
Are you shy?
No.
He ain't heavy.
He's my shithead brother.
You didn't have to get
all dressed up, you know?
What were you in for
this time, huh?
My brother likes to spend
his free time in prison...
isn't that right, Jacks?
Whenever I can get away.
This is my new wife Freddie.
Come on.
Chicken.
Scissors beats paper.
Come on.
Paper beats rock.
OK?
Come on.
Shit!
Rock beats scissors.
God!
Fuck!
She's a knockout, isn't she?
So you won the game,
I won the girl.
I can't believe
you even showed up.
Especially without a present.
Nice tux, Sam.
I'm going to go pee.
They
Asked me how I knew
My true love was true
A little to the left.
A little to the right.
Bull's-eye!
Did you come for me?
I don't even know you.
No! Did you come for me?
Did you?
You got to shave, baby.
You're ruining my skin.
Jesus.
I look like shit.
Don't I look like shit?
Yeah, I do.
I'm getting old.
You're not even, what,
twenty-five?
I'm closer to thirty
than to twenty.
I used to be seven years old.
I used to be unborn.
I used to be fourteen.
And tomorrow
I'll be forty or fifty.
So?
I'm dying.
I'm dying. You're dying.
Right now, we're both dying.
Listen to the ticking.
It gets louder
with every second.
I don't want to die here.
You should just split.
Really?
You think those guys are just
gonna let me walk away?
They haven't yet.
See? They did this to me.
- Jesus.
- Yeah, Jesus.
Red says that
I owe him ten grand.
He says that I stole it
from him.
It's bullshit.
He found it on the books.
Your damn brother did.
So, there it is.
I'm his reward.
He's my punishment.
Fuck them anyways.
See you out back?
You see a pair
of laughing eyes
And suddenly
you're sighing sighs
You're thinking nothing's wrong
You string along, boy, then snap
Those eyes, those sighs
They're part of the tender trap
It'll always turn to shit.
Not only don't you bring
a gift...
you don't even say good-bye.
Those dreams that dream
They're part of the tender trap
Some starry night
When her kisses make you tingle
She'll hold you tight
And you'll hate yourself
for bein'...
Empty the cash.
Come on, come on!
Move it, move it, move it!
Jacks? Jacks, is that you?
Damn it.
Just give me the money.
You wouldn't shoot me,
would you?
I'm not gonna shoot you.
Sorry, Bob.
In my life
There's been heartache and pain
I don't know
if I can face it again
Can't stop now
I've traveled so far
It's a candy dish.
Congratulations
on your marriage.
Good-bye.
Don't leave me.
I'm sorry.
Mommy!
- Oh, my God.
- Is she all right?
You...
You killed her.
You show up to my wedding
after no one invites you.
Mom invited me.
Get her all upset...
so she faints and dies
just like that.
Maybe it was you who upset her.
Me? Not me.
I was her favorite!
She didn't send me off packing
when I was eight!
Stupid.
Hey, Freddie.
Sorry.
So how is married life
treating you?
That good, huh?
Hey, can I bum one of those?
Thanks.
Sorry about your mother, boys.
Mine died about six years ago.
Worst fuckin' day of my life.
I need a word with you, Jacks.
Why? Huh?
What did he do this time?
Christ!
What did you do that for?
Tell me about the gas station
you knocked off.
I got a captain crawling
up my ass for an answer...
so I'm gonna take
a little refuge up yours.
Now that old guy, Bob...
he didn't see you,
but he heard you, right?
It's always something
when you show up.
It's not finished
between me and you, Jacks.
Just want you to know that.
I can't sleep.
It's cold in here.
Want another blanket?
Did you stay for me?
I stayed to bury my mother.
Tomorrow?
I'm taking off.
I know you've been
thinking about me.
'Cause I've been
thinking about you.
And when I do...
I can feel you inside me.
You want to be
inside me again, Jacks?
We shouldn't.
Again.
I thought I told you to shave.
Sorry.
Have you ever
been to Vegas, Jacks?
It's the best.
I went there when I was little
with my mom.
We met Ann-Margret.
Man, she was the coolest.
I mean, she was like...
Like a kitten with balls,
you know what I mean?
She gave me this.
She signed her picture
and gave me this.
It's supposed to bring me luck.
Let's just go.
Let's just start this thing up
and get out of here.
I can't.
Why? Why can't you see?
Maybe all this shit happened
with me, with you...
with your mom dying...
Maybe it happened
so we'd end up together.
I can't.
If you leave me here
with these bastards...
I swear you're a bigger fucker
than they are.
Don't you see?
It feels too good.
It's gonna turn to shit!
I just can't!
Come on. I can make you happy.
- Don't touch me.
- I can't sleep.
I'm not in the mood.
Get off of me.
For Christ sakes, Freddie.
You're my wife.
- I want to make love.
- I don't want it!
- Let me...
- No, it hurts.
Don't push me away. Please.
Sam, stop.
It hurts like that.
Come on. Get off me!
But it feels good like that.
It's great out here.
Wait for me. Come on.
Right over there.
What are you doing back here?
I got a car waiting outside.
For me?
You came back for me?
Where are we going?
What are you doing?
I'll be back in a minute.
Do you believe
in love at first sight?
Me neither.
It came with the car.
They're gonna be looking for me,
you know.
I know.
How young are you?
How old am I?
Let's count the rings
Around my eyes
How smart are you?
How dumb am I?
Don't count any
Of my advice
Meet me
- Anyplace
- Anywhere
Or anytime
Now, I don't care
Meet me tonight
Let me speak to Red orJoseph.
Look, I don't care
what time it is.
OK, I'm sorry.
Just give me the...
I gotta turn my life around.
I gotta do things different.
So is this doing things
differently...
running off
with someone else's wife?
You can't look at it like that.
I mean,
look at it like this...
Time is like...
an orange.
It's round.
It means that everything
repeats itself.
And everything that happens
happens for a reason.
Lieutenant Ben Something.
Some...
Costikyan! Yes!
Yes, just leave a message.
No, I don't need
to speak to anybody!
Just leave a message, OK?
Thanks.
The big promise I made myself...
was that I'd never spend
another day in prison.
Not one.
You want to know the truth?
You want to avoid prison?
Quit sticking up gas stations.
What I'm talking about
is different.
I'm just saying go home
one last time and get the money.
We have a little cash.
I got fifty bucks
stuffed in my underwear...
and you've got enough
to spring for this swell place?
We left in a hurry, Jacks.
We forgot.
- I know, but...
- Come on.
We're almost there.
Almost.
It's like, if I close my eyes...
I can see us in Vegas...
lying by a pool...
with water in it.
It's always sunny and warm.
And guys in white jackets
bring us daiquiris...
and all the food we can eat
for four bucks.
And all the towels smell
like Downy fabric softener.
There's no clocks, no bedtime...
and when I get going there...
you can come see me
perform at night.
I'd be wearing
big red feathers...
one of those things
on my head...
like crown things,
with diamonds in it.
When I come offstage
I'd be too wired to sleep...
so we'll make love
until morning...
sleep until 2:00.
It's half my money, Jacks,
right?
I'm his wife, right?
It's the law.
He kept saying that he
was gonna make me happy...
that he had all this
money stashed away.
So after everything...
let him make me happy,
Jacks.
I just don't know
where he hides it.
What?
You know where, don't you?
Do you?
Look at me.
You told me to call, Ben.
Nothing.
He's back.
Alone.
I spend my whole life trying
not to come back here.
I always end up
coming back here.
Where's Freddie?
Why don't I just
put the money back...
and really never come back?
So you and my wife
can live happily ever after?
That sounds like
a really good deal for me.
We're gonna go at it,
aren't we, Sam?
Big time.
Shit!
Bastard.
Shit.
You bastard! You piece of shit!
Take a little refuge up yours.
Jeez. You need a doctor?
I need a tank of gas.
Just fill it up.
Where's your can?
Hello.
I just saw a cop get beat up.
Ben... Ben Costi-hoo!
Costikyan.
Yes, I did. Jacks Clayton.
I don't know. He just
beat the hell out of him.
He might be dead. Yes.
One-eighty-two Goodrich.
That's right. I don't...
Stop! That's my horse!
Clementine!
Hi, honey. I'm home.
What happened?
- I got him good.
- You need a doctor.
No. I hate doctors.
I always throw up
around doctors.
Shit. I can't believe this.
Look. This is what he did.
Christ.
I hung on to the sucker, though.
My God, that is disgusting.
I don’t feel good.
Let me help you, OK?
I need to lie down.
Yeah, you should lie down.
You sure you know
what you're doing?
Be quiet.
You know how to operate this?
Look at that.
Isn't that your horse?
I didn't mean for this
to happen, Jacks.
I'm so sorry.
I'm afraid to ask.
What?
Did you get the money?
You think this is the best time
to discuss finances?
It's my last chance, Jacks.
Yeah.
I got it.
That's what I found.
He's got more than this.
He said so.
- I don't understand.
- It's enough.
We can check out of here
and go...
in the morning.
What are we gonna do?
This was our last chance!
They're gonna find us
and fucking kill us!
How could you
let him get to you?
I didn't let him get to me.
Let go of me!
I counted on you, Jacks!
- Hey, shut up in there!
- You shut up!
You shut the fuck up!
Is everything
all right in there?
What's going on?
Where are the car keys?
I'm gonna call the cops!
I'll get you some help.
Show's over, so crawl
back into your fucking hole.
All right.
Hi, Freddie.
- Where's Red and Joseph?
- It's just me.
Let's go for a drive.
Come on.
Come on, I want to talk.
Come on, drive.
You don't need that gun.
You gotta be reasonable
about this.
This wasn't meant to be.
You know?
I'm sure
there's lots of girls...
I guess, who...
would be just right for you.
Let's talk about it.
It was supposed
to be a surprise...
but I can tell you now.
I sent half the money already.
Not a down payment,
but half of it.
You would...
You'd laugh if you knew how hard
it was to get this money.
Red’s shit his pants.
Look.
This is the model right here.
It's nice.
It's 2,700 square feet.
Central air and heat.
It's got cable
with fifty-seven channels...
a two-car garage...
and look, a swimming pool
with tennis courts...
and a park, you know,
that they're building.
I can't breathe.
Don't open the fucking door!
Look, I know that your dream
is to live in Vegas...
but this is close to Vegas,
but better.
It's like a real neighborhood.
We have a choice.
Look what it says here.
"Eggplant or ecru"
for the carpeting.
Is that a color?
I don't know. I guess.
Eggplant.
And how many children
should we have?
Two.
You're a liar.
Can I get a Coke...
and a Hostess cupcake?
Sure.
One of those sweatshirts, too.
Here.
What are you famous for?
I don't know.
That was a nice horse you had.
What?
You know.
Yeah, thanks.
So, did you call the cops?
No. Why? Did you?
No. It wasn't my horse.
Shoot.
Could I use your phone?
I'm sorry. We can't tie it up.
Tie it up?
- Who's gonna call?
- Sorry.
There's trouble in there.
A murder!
I saw the guy.
My name?
Shit.
Jesus.
Oh, shit.
This is
the manager of the motel.
The police are here.
They want to have a look
around your room.
Whatever you got going in there,
get rid of it.
I ain't in the mood
to have the place busted.
So, what's going on?
Well, let's find out.
I just spoke to him.
I'm sorry.
I was in the bathroom...
and my wife is sleeping.
Please, let's whisper.
She's come down
with some sort of flu.
Poor thing was throwing up
all night.
She just fell asleep
maybe ten minutes ago.
What happened to you?
My stupid brother and me.
We got drunk.
It was stupid.
- What's this?
- What?
There's blood here on the sink.
From my head.
He got me pretty good.
But I got him better.
Where is your brother?
Kicked his ass back home.
I came to visit, right?
He gets drunk
and all bent out of shape.
Who needs that, right?
Where is home?
About half an hour
outside of St. Paul.
Let's go.
Why don't you come on outside?
Come on out here for a second.
Just need to talk to you.
You ever been in any trouble?
Not really.
Maybe a little.
You got a record?
Figured as much.
You staying out of trouble?
Yes, sir.
I've got my life and my wife.
That's all a man needs
to turn things around.
Yeah, well...
I'm sorry, Freddie.
And?
What...
I got an emergency call,
come on!
Life is one big emergency,
man, so fuck off.
Some asshole. I don't know.
Am I given to understand
you killed Freddie Clayton?
Is that true?
Is that a yes or a no?
It doesn't matter because
your brother here...
says he knows where
you stashed the body.
And if that's true,
that's a very sad thing...
because that was
a beautiful girl...
with her whole life
ahead of her!
Son of a bitch.
I liked that girl.
Kind of a stupid fucking name
is that, anyway?
What?
It was supposed to be Jack...
but they fucked up
his birth certificate.
No, yeah!
A stupid fucking typo.
That's all your life
amounts to, huh?
It's here somewhere.
Where?
He must've did something
with it.
Sure you got the right spot?
Well, there's nothing here.
Don't point out the obvious.
It's fucking annoying.
No, he moved her.
You did something.
Where is she?
Come on!
Hey, hey! Jesus!
You think I've got the time
to fool around?
You remember I'm a cop!
People depend on me.
I'm here to serve and protect.
I don't have the time
to fuck around...
with a couple of fucking losers
like you!
But I saw it!
How do you know she's here?
Maybe it's up the road
or something.
This is it. This is the spot.
I'm telling you what I saw!
I don't think so.
You find your own way back.
You can't just leave me
out here.
I can't, huh?
Gimme a light, asshole.
So what went wrong?
She make you mad?
Come on, you can tell me.
What did you do with her body?
You know I know.
People know she didn't
want to be with you.
And people know
you let those motherfuckers...
write that on her arm,
you bastard!
- I didn't tell 'em to do it!
- Who did?
She was my wife!
For four fucking days!
So?
Wasn't conventional.
We didn't meet at the prom.
So what?
So why couldn't
she love me anyway?
You know I didn't have
any reason to kill her...
but you did!
I can't remember anything,
but you were there, right?
Maybe.
Where's the body?
Kiss my ass.
Hey, you set me up.
Only if you're setting me up.
So, was it love or just...
with Freddie?
Fuck off.
A good blow job feels like love
every time, right?
Shit!
I'm not letting you
out of my sight.
Not for a minute.
That's fine with me.
Where you going?
Don't answer it.
Who is it?
Tell my brother
what you just told me.
Who is it?
Just take the phone.
That's right, Mr. Clayton.
What my wife saw the other night
made me sick.
One of you carrying
that woman...
her body... into the room...
and then the other one
carrying her out.
I think you know what I mean.
Fifty thousand dollars
ought to do it.
I don't want to be hard,
'cause you got problems...
but I'd really like
the money by morning...
or I'll have to go
to the police.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Did you hear what he said?
He said...
one of us carried her body
into the room...
and one of us carried her out.
I only carried her out.
I mean, I couldn't remember.
You bastard!
You let me think it was me!
Look, it doesn't matter
who killed her, right?
I mean, he saw me
and he saw you...
It matters!
I loved her!
Well, don't worry now.
You did the right thing
calling me.
I'll take care
of everything, OK?
But you gotta
take care of me, too.
Listen to me, asshole,
this is what's gonna happen.
You buried me in this shit,
and you're gonna dig me out.
You're gonna give me the money.
- What money?
- To pay that motel guy off.
There is no money.
You lying sack of shit!
I don't have it anymore!
It's gone!
I bought a house!
Half a house.
Near Vegas for Freddie and me.
We're supposed to have a house.
A house?
You bought a house?
Get up!
What are we going to do
with a fucking house?
You're gonna get that money!
Wait! Wait!
I got it. I got it.
This is what we do.
We go to where
you hid her body...
and we dispose of it
once and for all...
where nobody can find it
in a thousand years.
Then we don't have
to pay nobody nothing. See?
You idiot!
What?
I never moved her body.
How could you lie to me
about that?
You ate my ear...
you killed your wife,
you framed me...
and you're mad at me for lying?
Jesus, what kind of sicko
would take a dead body?
My head...
You really hurt my head.
Shut up.
Better pray I calm
this motel guy down while...
I go to Red's
and ask him for the money.
Ask him?
Beg him.
Bear his fucking children
if you have to.
You better take this.
I don't need it.
I don't want any more problems.
We're talking
about serious stuff here.
You might need it just
to reason with the guy.
You don't have to shoot him
unless you absolutely have to.
Good luck.
Fuck off.
Always burning the midnight oil,
as they say.
Jesus Christ.
This is unbelievable.
I was just about
to come to see you.
Here you are.
I should come back later.
You're busy.
No, I'm finished.
This adding and subtracting
shit you do is hard.
It's very hard.
I don't pay you enough.
Yeah, well...
What did you want
to see me about?
It can wait.
Naw, it can't.
Well...
I'm in kind of a fix, you know?
I was gonna see
about borrowing...
some money, maybe.
You want more money?
You think you can fuck
with my books...
and I won’t find out?
Who the fuck are you?
I didn't take nothin', I swear!
OK, I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I want it all back.
I'm gonna break
your fucking legs anyway...
but you are going
to give me back every dime...
and every seed of every joint
you ever smoked of mine...
that didn't belong to you!
I don't have it anymore.
He took the money.
My brother...
I don't give a shit!
You took it first!
He stole it from you,
you steal it back.
I got no beef with your brother.
Thirty-eight grand you owe me.
That's what I figure’s
gone over the past year...
give or take a penny or a pill.
I mean it.
If I had it, I'd give it to you.
No! That prick...
Are you listening to me?
I don't care about
your fucking problems!
I look like a fucking shrink?
You tell it to that cunt
Ann Landers.
You do what you gotta do.
Sell your mama's blood
for nickels.
I don't give a fuck.
My mama's dead.
Right. Well, I guess
you shit outta luck.
Just let me go.
OK? I'm sorry.
Hey, don't move!
Red, don't move.
You fucking shit!
All right... Damn, Red!
Drop the gun.
You drop yours.
I pulled mine out first.
Then, Sam, you're fired.
Aw, shit!
Shit. Shit.
It's forty-six thousand,
you fucking idiot.
You can't count, you bastard.
You got here fast.
You said by morning.
That's right. I guess I did.
Would you like a cup of tea?
A sandwich?
So, where's your brother,
parking the car?
Relax. He's getting the money.
He'll be along.
He'll be along?
- Yeah.
- When?
Look, I just...
I don't want no trouble.
Just relax, OK?
OK, I'll relax.
You relax, too.
What's the matter?
Where you going?
Look, maybe this wasn't
such a good idea.
What the fuck is going on here?
Stop it! Stop it!
You took her body, you sick
son of a bitch, didn't you?
You sick fucker, you!
Where is she?
She put us up to it! That girl...
Shut up!
I'm really tired
of the motel business.
There's no future in it,
you know?
Inside.
We had our eye
on this really nice RV.
It's OK, baby.
Don't worry.
I know it was Sam who killed me.
Fuck!
Oh, shit.
It's OK.
I don't...
I don't get it.
Someone found me
at the side of the road.
Jesus.
Saved my life.
But I saw... I mean, I saw.
Oh, my God, you're bleeding.
She's bleeding! Help!
I'm OK. I'm OK.
Sam's a lousy shot.
Even that close.
The bullet went in there
and out there.
Doctor says I was lucky.
I told him
there's no such thing as luck.
It's real, right?
It must be.
I mean, I've never felt like...
Whatever that word is.
Happy.
I need you to tell me
exactly what happened.
I don't know exactly.
I blacked out.
I couldn't remember
anything and...
there you were.
I thought I'd killed you.
- Why would you want to kill me?
- I wouldn't.
- What did I ever do to you?
- Nothing.
Just thinking about you
in that ravine...
bleeding to death...
You broke my heart, Jacks.
I was scared.
I was stupid. I was fucked up.
Please forgive me.
Baby...
I've already forgiven you.
- Where are you going?
- I'm hungry.
I've got a fucking hole
in my stomach.
You want something to eat?
I'll bring us back something.
You wait here.
Oh, shit.
Damn.
Here you go.
Can I ask you something?
You want me to throw
that out for you?
What? No.
Are you OK?
Can I ask you something?
Go ahead. Shoot.
If you had, you know,
killed two people...
murdered them...
and in the process had gotten
almost a hundred grand...
That's close to
ninety-eight thousand dollars...
which nobody was going
to miss, you hope...
and a stranger
was blackmailing you...
would you give him
a big chunk of that money...
you worked so hard to get?
You are weird.
No, I wouldn't give
the bastard a red cent.
Yeah? That's what I think, too.
Could you...
bring me...
one of those doughnuts, too?
Yeah, hold on.
Since I'm a regular,
think I could use your phone?
Yeah, but...
don't make a habit of it, OK?
The Suburban motel.
Twenty-one ninety-five.
That includes a color TV.
How can I help you?
Put him on.
- Yeah?
- It's me.
It's about time.
Did you get the money?
I got the money.
Good.
OK, so come on.
You should have seen me.
I was great.
So we'll see you soon, right?
He had no choice
when I put it the way I put it.
I made him see it my way.
And, Sam, bring the key.
What key?
On top of everything,
he says I owe him 30 bucks...
for the motel key I took.
It's in the fish dish.
The fish dish.
Look on top of the TV.
But I'm not at home.
Where are you?
I'll get you another cup.
See ya.
- Shit.
- What?
Stupid machine forgot
to put sugar in my coffee.
This is weird.
You scream
like you just saw a ghost.
I'm the one
who just saw a ghost.
You are a ghost, aren't you?
I know 'cause I killed you.
I was there.
You fucker, you.
What are you gonna do,
kill us all?
Come on, what's in the bag?
Is that money?
We can all get out of here.
Oh, boy.
You know...
how does something like this
happen to me?
All along
it never occurred to me...
that the only reason
that your body was missing...
is because you weren't dead.
I gotta keep my head here.
I gotta do something right!
You know, Jacks...
why can't it be nice
when you come home to visit?
Normal, like other families?
Leave him alone!
Stop!
No! No more, please!
It's all right.
I'm a police officer.
Drop the gun, Jacks.
Come here, Freddie.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
You drop that gun, Jacks.
Folks, you mind
stepping outside, please?
This is officially
a crime scene.
Oh, my God.
I don't think
I can go through with this.
You called me, remember?
There's no turning back now.
It's done.
Don't worry. It'll be nice.
You tried to bury me, Jacks.
Fuckin'- A. And, Jacks...
if you're gonna kill someone...
you gotta kill 'em.
I could really get
in a lot of trouble for this.
I'm not supposed to let you in
without Mr. Cos... Custodian.
Well...
I won't tell if you don't tell.
Thanks.
What is your name again?
Listen, Lloyd,
I am trying to help you.
I was there. I saw everything.
Jacks did not kill his brother.
Listen, I gotta go.
He's gonna be OK, right?
Leave me alone!
I don't know where...
You promise?
What are you gonna do?
I'll look into it.
How?
All my money is fucking gone!
Oh, oh, jeez.
There's nothing wrong
with my wife, is there?
Your wife's fine, Ben.
She's a little pissed at you.
We got a call from Freddie.
Freddie who?
And she had some very
interesting things to say.
She stole all my fucking money.
Ask this guy.
Hey, tell him.
Tell this fucker,
who works for me...
that she stole
every last fucking cent.
Tell him, for Christ's sake!
Come on, hey!
Look, hey, Lloyd, OK,
we're cops.
We gotta stick together.
That's what we do.
If we don't look out
for each other, who will, man?
Let me ask you something, Ben.
Why you such
a fucking wick, huh?
Hey, I got pants up there!
Hey, listen!
I suppose
it's none of my business...
but after all that...
you sure
this is the right woman for you?
I don't know.
Maybe.
How do you know for sure
she's even here?
She's here.
Thanks for the ride.
Appreciate it.
Take one of these with you.
I don't have twenty-five bucks
for a Bible.
- It's a gift.
- Keep it.
You got a family to feed.
Don't look so worried.
Look at this.
I got a letter from her
not too long ago.
"Dear Jacks,
maybe it's all bullshit.
"Maybe nothing does happen
for a reason after all...
"but I'm doing great.
"I'm living my dream.
"So fuck you anyways.
Freddie. "
I hate to say this, son...
but that don't sound
exactly like a love letter.
You gotta read
between the lines.
Good luck.
Good night, Freddie.
What took you so fucking long?