...we the members
of the People's Council,
representing the Jews of Israel
and the Zionist movement,
are here assembled on the day
of the end of the British mandate.
By virtue
of our natural and historic right,
and based
on the United Nations resolution,
we do hereby declare
the establishment of a Jewish state
in the land of Israel
to be known as the state of Israel.
Who are you? Why are you here?
We were attacked last night.
Bombs, fire.
My mother pushed us
out the back door.
We couldn't see.
Too much smoke.
We called to each other.
Houses on fire.
We heard shooting, bombs.
Mohammed said
he saw tanks and soldiers.
We ran and ran.
And that's when Abdullah fell.
Hamid said soldiers
came into his house.
Killed his grandfather,
father and mother.
His sisters, too.
We're all from Deir Yassin.
Soldiers shoved us in a truck.
Lots of smoke.
People died.
I don't know where my brothers are.
Everybody died.
What is your name?
Zeina.
Mama! Hello!
Hello, Hind.
Mama, don't worry.
They'll only stay a few days.
Why don't you take them
to your grandfather's?
One times one?
Girls!
All together and very politely,
nice and loud:
"Hello, Colonel Smith!"
- Hi, Jamal.
- Hello, Miss Hind.
Hey, beautiful.
Can I buy you a drink?
I don't drink.
Your Hebrew's great.
Where you from?
What are you, stupid?
I don't want to talk to you.
Get lost.
Go sit down or get out.
She your woman?
Out!
Why do you let her dance?
What are you staring at?
A whore. An Arab whore.
We can't wait for outside help.
No one will help us.
We must do this ourselves.
This war is not over yet.
I'm fine.
Take care of each other.
Take care of yourself.
Congratulations
to the husband and wife!
Mama.
Can I eat your kunafeh?
Look at me.
Daddy!
Listen.
Miral, your father will be back Friday.
I want my daddy!
I want to go home.
You have 10 minutes to clear this area!
This house will be destroyed.
You have 10 minutes to clear the area!
This house will be destroyed!
It's a threat to national security!
Get out!
Where are you going?
It all looks the same.
I can't read Arabic.
Can you?
Just take one.
Police! Open up!
I am Miral Shahin.
You translate for her!
Where are you going, girls?
Jerusalem.
OK, go.
Allah be with his soul.
He was a good man.
He lent this to me.
I return it to you.