"Everyone who practices sin
is also practicing lawlessness."
Alas, the first humans
rebelled against God's authority.
By this betrayal
they became sinners.
For thousands of years,
Jehovah has let humans
make their own choices.
History
shows they are unable to do so.
Every human government...
Every human government
causes suffering.
None has ever succeeded
in eradicating war,
criminality, injustice or disease.
God is here, and will soon
put an end to all our suffering.
Some might think
that death is unjust.
But Jehovah tells us
it is not unjust.
It is normal.
Mrs. Simard? Your keys.
Mrs. Simard?
Heard from Etienne?
He fell again.
No.
What's going on?
Don't worry.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Hello?
I'm fine. It's nothing.
Is everything OK?
Sure. I drove his car here.
His vision's blurry.
He fell from the ladder, right?
Yes. I'm fine.
I grabbed the drainpipe.
- You're not hurt?
- No!
Hi.
My nurse will treat my scratch.
- What scratch?
- It's nothing.
Leave it to me.
Michel, some tea?
No, thanks. I should head home.
- You OK?
- Yeah. My back hurts.
She keeps suggesting I see a doctor.
I don't want to.
You should tell them.
No way.
No, I...
I don't want her to worry.
But tomorrow...
we'll pretend to go.
I need you.
Help me.
I made your bed downstairs.
You know I love you, right?
Etienne?
- Etienne?
- Yes.
The hospital called.
There was a big plane crash.
I'll take your car, OK?
A plane crashed?
Yes.
Were many people killed?
No one?
One.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
- You've been in Venezuela for...?
- Three years.
- Why three years?
- What?
What did you do in that time?
Escaped the snow.
Do you come back often?
Never.
And you're here for...?
My niece's birthday.
Are you bringing her a gift?
Have a good day.
Welcome home.
- Good morning, guys!
- Morning.
So, Henri, have a good night?
I'm down to my last 5 thou.
Today's the day
I begin a new life.
I can't go home.
Don't sweat it. You're not dead
till your last cent's gone.
I'm Kim.
Christ, it's early.
I haven't had a coffee yet.
First time?
So, are you digesting OK?
Who's that? You're supposed to
keep a low profile.
He's my brother.
Shit!
C'mon, let's go.
The night wasn't too long?
The usual. What about you?
I slept in the hotel.
Tonight I fly south.
Yeah? Where to?
Cuba. With my wife.
Same hotel, same beach umbrella
for 14 years.
Wow, you're lucky.
It'll do her good.
Each time we're in a hotel bed,
I dunno...
It's like the first time.
For a few days, we're honeymooners.
Ever been to Cuba?
Nope.
Want to go with my wife?
She's still pretty.
Sorry. I'm already taken.
Hi, it's Evelyne.
I just wanted to say hi
before leaving.
We're flying out tonight.
I wanted to know how you are,
how your belly's coming along.
By the way, we meant it
when we offered to be godparents.
I know we don't have any experience.
But still,
I'm pretty sure we'd be good at it.
I know we would.
Anyway, that's not why I...
Why I called.
I just wanted to say hi and that...
I'll be thinking of you,
my feet in the sand.
And...
That's all.
I just wanted to say hi
and that I'll call
when I get back, OK?
Already?
I'm going back soon.
You can do what you want.
Got the money?
After you crap.
I'll come and meet you.
They said I'd get it on arrival.
Who said that?
- Ramon.
- He's full of it.
You'll stay on the crapper
till it's out.
I got stuff to do.
We good?
I'm hungry-
Shit first.
It'd be nice if you washed 'em
before I come back.
I'm on my break. You?
Everyone can see us.
You get more beautiful every day.
There are cameras all over.
So what?
I'll be waiting.
The hotel reception
told me you'd left.
Where?
What time's your meeting over?
We have to be at the airport
by 8:45, max.
Not much. I had a coffee,
hung out on Facebook.
The beach will be nice, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, I imagine.
What you did to me
with your fingers...
Took me two months of research
to find it.
Tell me about it.
Even I couldn't find it anymore.
Never thought it would happen to me.
What?
Well, this... This here.
Want to go south with me
on vacation?
What?
My treat. We leave tonight.
Be serious.
Head south, just like that?
Yeah. You...
You go home and pack.
Tell him you're leaving.
I'll be waiting outside.
No, Raymond.
I want you, just for me.
Just us two.
Think about it.
The two of us,
our feet in the sand.
So, what did the doctor say?
That I have two cracked ribs.
That's all.
It'll heal by itself.
What about your dizzy spells?
He said I work too hard.
That I don't drink
enough water and...
But... Don't worry about it.
I'll be fine.
I don't want you to worry.
I'm fine.
Under Karine Tessier.
It's an old cell number.
How can I get her new one?
There's no way?
Yeah. Thanks.
- Marc-André?
- Yes.
I'm going to be sick.
For a week.
Get real.
I've never asked
for anything. Please.
Raymond...
Please.
You're not sick.
No, but I'm going to be.
If you're not here,
you're fired.
I'm sorry.
Then I'm fired.
How's Etienne?
Don't try, it's pointless.
What are you waiting for?
A miracle?
We told you.
We can't give or receive blood.
Julie, forget your religion
for two seconds.
You don't understand.
Using blood makes you impure.
I understand.
He has no white blood cells.
The leukemia has destroyed
his immune system.
You're back to transfusions.
We can't.
He has to come in. Right away.
Without chemo, he has no chance.
We are going to a better world.
Death is only a transition.
We return to Paradise on Earth.
All I want is to save him.
I guarantee that with transfusions,
he'll make it.
What'll happen to him afterward?
After what?
After. You can't guarantee him
a place in heaven.
I'm talking about
his life here, now.
For him, it's about eternity.
His chances are slim.
You don't understand.
What don't I understand?
It's not about chance.
Fucking hell!
I hear you.
Only Bed 6 is left.
Ten of morphine, burns on 60%...
thoracic bleeding...
I prayed for him all night.
Are you alright?
He's the only one we saved.
- They were headed on vacation.
- Don't go there.
Why them?
Because man is impure.
Yes, but... Why did he make it?
He was at the right place
at the right time.
We have to work, sweetie.
My mom told me.
He fell at work?
But he's OK.
I'm almost done.
It'll pull a bit, but I'm done.
There.
This will soothe you.
It'll feel cold.
There.
We'll leave it half an hour.
Someone else will remove it.
I'm off.
See you tomorrow.
THE HOLY SCRIPTURES
What's wrong?
I have a niece.
Karine... Find her.
- Give her the money.
- What?
Say it's for her.
You swallowed 60.
That's not 60!
Listen to me, you fuck!
I don't know you, you're nobody.
But you're gonna shit 'em out!
Did one burst in you?
Christ! You're not gonna die on me?
Nathalie, get the cart!
Prepare the defibrillator.
He's coding! Call the doctor!
- One of adrenaline.
- Let me do it.
Keep I'! UP-
Keep going.
He's back!
He's back.
Tonight, I also have
Jamaica, 8:05 p.m.
Cuba, 10145...
Cuba?
Holguin, on the northeast tip.
But it's a two-week minimum.
Do it.
Two weeks... We'll live it up.
You won't regret it.
The hotel's so romantic.
The other passenger's name?
Why do you need it?
To book her ticket.
Louise...
Louise Carpentier. She's gorgeous.
- I've never been on a plane.
- No?
I was always scared.
Don't worry. Seriously,
it's safer than driving.
I know, but I'm still scared.
Nothing's wrong.
No, he's fine.
Yeah. Room 509.
Bye.
And?
- Won't come out.
- Christ!
And your cramps?
Great.
Listen. The exchange
is in another room.
Do as I say.
Wait here with the stock.
I'll go see him so he doesn't freak.
He'll want his 60 packets.
Come down when I call you. Room 509.
You hand me the bag,
come back here and wait.
What about the money?
Who says you'll show?
Me. I say so.
You know I'll pay you back.
What's the problem?
It's a whack of cash.
Look, when your luck's down,
you lose.
You have to hit bottom
to bounce back.
It's always like that.
I'm a winner, a winner.
Did I ever not bounce back?
Parking B, 15 minutes.
There!
Why a new bikini?
I must've gained weight. I dunno.
- Where's the garage remote?
- I loved the old one.
I told you, I'm here till 6.
Samuel and I are
reviewing our strategy.
I'll check out
and meet you at the airport.
You bet. OK, bye.
Gotta go, Samuel's waiting.
100,200, 300, 400, 500.
OK, keep going.
- Bonus.
- Thanks!
Some blow?
Why not?
What was that?
A loser. Every year,
a few decide not to go home.
- I'll put it on your bill?
- What do we do?
Crazy day. Late for daycare...
How are you?
- The man from the plane?
- Good. The bleeding's controlled.
Did you know he's O neg like you?
The doctors hate that.
You're so pretty!
- I love you.
- Me too.
Find your dad.
I think he's in the kitchen.
He had no passport.
- They don't know who he is.
- Sister!
I was there.
She wore a beige dress.
Yellow!
That's what I said.
Beige, yellow...
- Brother?
- No, I think Michel's right.
You weren't there. Wait,
weren't you in Seattle to build...
Are you OK?
- Isn't Etienne here?
- No, he's not.
No, no. You were in Seattle.
Shut it!
So, Sister, when's the big day?
Second week of May.
You know what I told
your father and mother
at least 10 years ago?
- You're not going to start?
- Sure.
I said, "Those two will get hitched
and have a slew of kids."
- Brother, you can't contradict me.
- No, it's true.
Etienne, not eating?
No, I'm not hungry. Sorry.
It's her fault, of course.
I stuffed my face
with your muffins.
Again.
I bought the color for the hall.
The paint.
- It's a nice color, I think.
- Good.
Forgive me.
With the crash, I have to go.
- You're not working.
- No, I'll just drop by.
No more bets.
Eight.
Twelve. Over.
Ten.
Sir? You have ten.
Yes?
No, your daddy's...
Your daddy's busy.
He went for a walk.
Yes.
OK, yes, I'll tell him to call.
Hi.
Yes?
Where do you think I was?
Sure. Don't freak out, I'm coming.
I know, 509.
Who's that man?
I don't know.
This is us.
Your bags!
I nearly forgot. Thanks.
- Let me help.
- Thank you.
Thanks. There we go.
Hop, hop, hop!
That's OK, I'll...
I'll put them here.
- Police, open up!
- Thanks.
Can I use the toilet?
I forgot my key. Sorry.
We know you're in there!
Police! Open the door!
We have a warrant! Open up!
We have the key. Open up!
- Look, you...
- Sorry. The pool?
Please, go now.
Leave.Leave.
- Yeah, sure.
- Please.
Thank you.
I didn't do anything! Let go!
Let go! I didn't do anything!
It's not me!
I didn't do anything!
Christ, I swear I didn't!
Get off me!
- Who are you?
- Room 504.
This way, sir.
- What floor's the pool?
- No idea.
Good bye.
Can I help you?
Yes, please. I'd...
- I'm not sure.
- Is it for a bikini?
I can show you our one-piece suits.
Like to try one?
You have the body for it.
What's on?
A dumb quiz show.
- I have something to tell you.
- Look at the guy.
He's gonna lose everything he won.
Madame?
What do you think?
It's no good.
What's the problem?
I have a great one-piece in black.
It's slimming.
Do you want to try it on?
Shall I get it?
Yes, I'll try it on.
What are you doing?
I'm taking a plane.
You're taking a plane?
Yeah.
I'm taking a plane.
Madame, do you need any help?
What are you doing in there?
I'll need the booth.
I don't understand.
Are you alright?
Madame?
Just leave me alone, OK?
Madame, you have to come out.
How are you?
This is my son,
8 months, 2 weeks.
Jonathan, this is Julie,
my best friend.
I found a job at Dony's,
the restaurant.
I want you to know...
I had to leave.
You know I love Alexandre.
This is my stop.
Tell my dad I miss him.
Mr. Thibault?
I saw Mélanie on the bus.
She's doing well.
Good for her.
Your grandson's name is Jonathan.
Yes?
Why did you bring that up?
Etienne can't work
with you tomorrow.
What Will he do?
Nothing.
He'll do nothing.
He should go to the hospital.
He'll be disfellowshipped.
Even if he changes cities,
countries...
The whole congregation will know.
You love him very much.
But tell yourself that
Jehovah loves us just as much.
He watches over us.
He left us His Word.
It can go fast.
- He'll catch a virus.
- We must abstain from blood.
- Dad!
- He has no choice.
He has no choice.
Etienne knows that.
We have to keep the faith.
All we can do is
believe in His Word.
Get some sleep.
You need your strength.
Hello?
Sorry to bother you, but...
I'm at the pharmacy.
I wanted to know what to buy.
Should I get some 30 or 45?
What do you prefer?
Some 15.
The 15 is shit. It's useless.
You've been drinking, huh?
You've been drinking.
I'm not well.
Now I have to start all over.
We're on vacation.
You'll stop after.
I can't talk.
I have to wrap up my meeting.
Fuck, Why'd you come back?
I can't sleep.
- How is she?
- None of your business.
Can you lend me some cash?
I'll pay you back.
No. Just go and don't come back.
- Is she a black belt now?
- Leave her alone.
- I have something for her.
- No!
I'm going crazy there.
She has her second dan.
She's aiming for the Olympics.
She's doing well.
She is?
Yes?
Is Louise home?
She's out.
- You are...?
- Raymond.
Raymond. Sure.
You work at the casino, right?
Do you know where she is?
Doing errands.
She shouldn't be long.
- Come in and wait.
- No, that's not...
I have 223 days left
till I retire.
I counted.
I work in debt collection.
A sort of bailiff.
A shitty job.
Hitting people
when they're already down.
What do you do?
- Barman.
- Oh yeah?
Louise can't stand the smell.
So I indulge while she's gone.
- Care for one?
- No, thank you.
Go on, these are good ones.
Enjoy life while we can.
Like it?
Yeah.
Cuban, the best in the world.
Blow toward the purifier.
I shouted, "Don't pull it out!"
The swordfish was still
in the water.
- But he wanted his trophy...
- Who's here?
You were gone a while,
so I offered him a cigar.
He likes Cuban cigars
even more than me.
I looked after your guest...
Raymond.
Well then...
I'll go to the park.
See you later.
Why'd you do this?
What else could I do?
It's your decision.
I'll be at the park.
Nothing will stop me.
Holguin, Cuba.
I don't know.
Look, I'm not interested in just
screwing you in the sun.
I want to be with you.
Not just for two weeks.
Every week.
All of them!
I know who the guy
in the parking lot is.
Aren't you in enough shit?
Not in shit.
Today, I bounce back.
I told you,
you're talking to a winner.
Forget the parking lot.
Meet me in the toilet in five.
- But what...?
- You need to piss!
' 3° YOU just...?
- Go piss!
It'll be better.
For now, we're calling him Jean-Guy.
OK, that's close enough!
You're Simon?
Yeah. You, what's your name?
Are you fuckin' with me?
That girl has a big mouth.
She'll spill all she knows.
You're screwed.
- The money.
- Gimme the stuff.
The cash first.
It's freezing. Hand it over.
I got nothing to lose.
C'mon, there are eyes everywhere.
Where's the rest?
That's it.
Now hand over the stuff.
- It's double or nothing.
- Don't fuck with me!
Calm down. Not here, jerk.
I told you, I've nothing to lose.
Dickwad!
So where's the stuff?
The table.
Fuck you.
Grab it, Raphael.
- Shit.
- Go on!
How many?
56. Sorry.
Come on! We said 60!
Yeah, but...
Soon as it comes out, I'll call.
Been there myself.
Hello.
The guy from the plane...
They've had problems with his BP.
I heard about his leukemia.
Why didn't you tell me
he was tested?
- Yes?
- Hello, sir.
Jehovah's Witnesses.
Sorry to disturb you.'
How are you today?
We're visiting the area
to answer your questions.
When you look around,
do you find things are going well?
We don't, which is why we're here.
To talk about it.
Let's not waste time.
If planes crash...
it's because your omnipotent god
doesn't exist.
Think about it.
Let's go.
My mom wept all day.
Why'd you tell your dad?
- I couldn't take it.
- Yeah.
OK.
People will talk, gossip.
Everyone will know.
Think it's easy for me?
I'm scared too.
But...
I can't.
We can't.
Understand?
Do we advance the wedding?
- Why?
- It's in 32 days.
In 32 days
we'll get married.
Trust me.
"And wherever he entered...
into villages or cities
or countryside...
they placed the sick ones
in the marketplaces,
and pled with him
that they might touch
just the fringe
of his outer garment.
And as many as did touch it
were made well."
Exodus“.
Chapter 15, verse 26.
"And he went on to say,
'If you strictly listen
to the voice of Jehovah your God...
and do what is right in His eyes
and indeed give ear
to His commandments
and keep all His regulations
I shall put none of
the maladies upon you
that I put upon the Egyptians;
because I am Jehovah
who is healing you.'
After..."
Sorry.
You were right to tell him.
It's another test.
We love him.
We have to stand by him.
He needs us, understand?
Completely with him.
Yes.
There's a reason.
All we can do
is support him and pray.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Will you?
- You'll do that?
Yes.
Go away. lsabelle's in the shower.
Is she home?
No, she's at judo.
- I said I'd pay you back.
- Don't!
- It's for her.
- No.
- Let me make amends.
- Christ, no!
The cops are after me.
I have to fly south.
Holy Christ!
Help me leave. Anywhere.
I'll never come back.
OK.
I'll try to get you out.
Be at the airport tonight.
Call me. I'll try something.
But go away.
- For her studies.
- What were you thinking? What?
She tells us nothing.
What did you do?
I told you.
We don't understand.
She won't tell us.
All she says is no.
No.
Don't forget to call me.
Can I help you?
I'd like to talk to...
to Karine.
Karine!
What?
Are you OK?
Sure. Top shape.
Hello?
Samuel?
No, Martin's not here.
Yeah, we're flying out later.
Isn't Martin with you?
Yeah.
OK.
When we're finished
moving the chairs over here...
Mom, the wallpaper.
Can you look after it?
Diane?
Could you do the wallpaper
with my mother?
- Michel and I will do the wiring.
- Etienne?
And then,
after, Mr. Thibault...
Etienne?
Sorry...
- You OK?
- Mr. Thibault, here...
The airline called. They think
they've identified Jean-Guy.
He's the only unaccounted passenger.
His wife will identify him.
It won't be easy.
What's his name?
I don't know.
Dr. Sauvé, quick!
He's 70/40, pulse 40.
You just got your second dan?
You could've written.
This is for you.
Maybe it can help
toward your studies.
Why?
Well, for your training...
the Olympics.
- It's a tidy sum.
- Why?
You won't have to worry.
I have to change.
Will you wait?
I'm going back.
When?
Later tonight.
You're leaving?
Why?
You know why.
I've something for you too.
Letters.
What kind of letters?
I missed you.
- I worry about you.
- You shouldn't.
At the cottage...
What I did...
What did you do?
What we did.
I told them nothing happened.
- Karine, I...
- Why give me money?
You know.
What?
I'll get changed.
I'll be right back.
Wait for me!
Now where?
The airport.
Yes.
She'll identify him
when he comes out of the OR.
Yes. Complications.
Hemorrhaging.
- Yes.
- Madame?
- What?
- Your cell, please.
Excuse me, is everything alright?
Are you the wife of Patient 6?
Yes.
Don't worry.
Yes. OK, I have to go.
You have to turn off your phone.
Etienne?
- I brought you a coffee.
- Thanks.
- I want you to take a break.
- Put it on the table.
- Take a break now, please.
- Hand me...
- Etienne?
- What?
Now.
We have an emergency in the OR.
You're type O negative?
It's in the hospital files.
I know your religious principles.
The crash survivor?
O negative like him.
No, I can't do it.
He needs your blood.
He's still in surgery.
We'll lose him in the next hour.
But I can't.
You're his last chance.
He's going to die.
You can save him.
- For Cuba?
- Yes, right here.
- Where's Mr. Lemay?
- He's coming. It may be tight.
Is he in the airport?
Can I check him in anyway?
He's at a meeting.
It'll be tight.
Alright, but don't tell anyone.
Thanks, it's kind of you.
The suitcase, under your name?
Madame? ls the suitcase yours?
No, it's his.
Why are you doing it?
Go ahead.
Stop.
Julie.
You'll be shunned.
Did the operation go alright?
Yes. It went fine.
It has to be him.
He's the only one not identified.
He's burned, right?
I should've been with him.
I was sure he was dead.
He'll make it.
He Will?
He's saved.
Would you mind?
Once you pass security,
go to Gate 34,
the flight to Holguin, Cuba.
Someone else's place?
Yeah, a passenger's late.
Won't you get in trouble?
No, when they realize the mistake,
you'll be in the air.
- Look, I...
- No, I don't have time.
Wait.
I won't come back.
I just wanted to say...
Twice in one day...
That's a first.
We can't miss the flight.
But your body's irresistible!
Today was hell.
Hell.
Did you take my sunglasses?
I hope so.
- What gate is it?
- 34.
Oh yeah?
You're right.
What's that look all about?
I'm not going with you.
I don't love you.
It's all gone.
I feel nothing for you.
I don't care where you were.
I'll move out of the house.
Have a good flight.
Two minutes?
I don't know how to tell you this...
It's not my husband, right?
Have a good flight.
Etienne?
- Etienne?
- Yes.
The hospital called.
There was a big plane crash.
I'll take your car, OK?
A plane crashed?
Yes.
A big pl...
Were many people killed?
Attention, the following passengers
on flight S6622 for Holguin, Cuba...
Martin and Evelyne Lemay,
Raymond Samson
and Louise Carpentier...
Final call, Gate 34 please.
Martin Lemay, Evelyne Lemay,
Raymond Samson
and Louise Carpentier...
Can't do it?
We don't have to leave.
We can just go to a hotel.
I'll tell them.
Afraid to fly?
I'm just terrified.
It's just for her...
Yeah.
Damn, I love her.
Have a nice day?
- Where's Etienne?
- He's resting.
Did something happen?
He's fine. He works like crazy,
that's all.
He's sleeping downstairs.
Sit down.
Madeleine's warming up some supper.
Julie.
Let him rest.
It'll be fine.
- Don't touch me.
- You're burning.
No, I'm cold. Stop it.
- You know you're not OK.
- I said I'm fine.
You're getting pneumonia.
Go to the hospital.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
You just have to decide to.
- Stop it. Stop.
- They can save you.
No.
We must follow His Word.
- Follow His Word.
- Etienne...
We'll go to the hospital.
Or I'll leave.
You won't see me again.
What do you mean?
Come with me.
"Only...
flesh with its soul-
its blood-
you must not eat..."
"And...
And...
besides that,
your blood of your souls...
shall I ask back."
I'll resurrect with the others.
'H..-
For sure, there'll be
a place for me...
I gave blood.
I'm leaving.
You know I love you.
What'll you do? Where'll you go?
If you want him to die...
I can't go on doing nothing.
Hello, sir.
You OK?
Great. You?
You're still here?
You made your decision.
I'm starving.
- There's lasagna.
- OK.
Seat D26. Have a good flight.
He died yesterday.
If planes crash...
it's because your omnipotent god
doesn't exist.