REPORTER: In other news tonight,
a constitutional amendment
which would allow 18-year-olds
to vote in all elections
cleared the congress
and headed for the White House
this afternoon.
President Nixon
has given every indication
that he will soon sign
the amendment into law.
This is not an invasion
of cambodia.
[ Protestors chanting ]
REPORTER #2: As the increasingly
powerful Soviet military
displayed its arsenal
at this year's May Day parade,
the State Department reaffirmed
that the cold War
is as cold as ever.
ANNOUNcER:
The Soviets take the ball in.
It's a crosscourt pass to Belov!.
He's got it! He's up!
He scores!
And the Soviets win the gold
over the United States!
Because people have got to know
whether or not their president's
a crook. Well, I'm not a crook.
I shall resign the presidency
effective at noon tomorrow.
REPORTER: The secret behind
today's modern computer
is the silicon chip.
Some experts predict
this modern marvel
might one day impact
our daily lives.
REPORTER #2: This is
homecoming day for Apollo 1 7.
The last round trip to the moon
Americans may take
in this century.
MAN: That's right! Now anyone
can turn their ordinary TV
into a magic box of video games.
I, Gerald R. Ford, do solemnly
swear that I will faithfully...
We must whip inflation
right now.
REPORTER: What was called
"peace with honor"
only a few short months ago
has disintegrated into utter
chaos as the U.S. evacuated...
MAN:
Okay, let's light this place up.
Let's get on the dance floor.
come on, everybody, now.
REPORTER: Streaking continues
to take the nation by storm
as college students
across the country
are shedding their clothes.
[ Screaming ]
[ cheers and applause ]
MAN: Happy 200th birthday,
America, and many, many more!
That I will faithfully
execute...
MAN: The office of the President
of the United States.
The office of President
REPORTER: Billy Beer
hit the shelves this week.
The White House
declined to comment
on the business venture
of President carter's brother.
REPORTER #2: As President carter
issued the order
prohibiting the purchase
of lranian oil,
Americans again find themselves
dealing with another oil crisis.
REPORTER #3:
Governor Brown,
implementing emergency
regulations,
reviewed his plan
for gas rationing.
REPORTER #4: Funeral
arrangements for Elvis Presley
have not yet been announced.
The entertainer died Tuesday
in Memphis
from what doctors called
cardiac arrhythmia.
MAN: Breaker 1 -8 Northbound.
Over.
REPORTER: Mr. carter approved
emergency financial aid
for the Love canal area
of Niagara Falls, New York.
That area is
in a state of crisis
because of chemical leakage
in the landfill
on which it's built.
REPORTER #2:
Authorities say there's been
an uncontrolled release
of radiation
from the Three Mile lsland
nuclear facility,
but details are still unclear.
It is a crisis of confidence.
It is a crisis that strikes
at the very heart and soul
and spirit of our national will.
The symptoms of this crisis
of the American spirit
are all around us.
WOMAN:
USA Hockey.
Please hold.
He's just stepping
into a meeting.
When's the best time
to reach you?
He's got your number?
Okay.
Herb.
Hey, Walter.
How we doing?
Good to see you.
How was the flight?
Oh, not bad.
Well, that's great.
Everybody's waiting to see us.
Who all's here?
Just money who's got a say
in this thing.
Bob Fleming, the lnternational
council, USA Hockey.
Lou Nanne, I think you know,
from the NHL.
The only way we can compete
with the Eastern Bloc teams
is if we're willing to change.
change what?
The way we train, the way we
prepare, even our schedule.
What kind of scheduling changes
are we talking about?
I think we need to
make it longer.
Much more competitive.
Longer?
You gonna pay for that?
We also need to change the way
we play the game.
What exactly does that mean?
My plan is to adopt a new style.
A hybrid of the Soviet school
and the canadian school.
A combination that requires the
highest level of conditioning,
speed, creativity,
and most of all, team chemistry.
Is this what you've been using
at the University of Minnesota?
We've been phasing it in over
the last couple of years.
He has won
three NcAA titles, fellas.
Walter, we don't have years.
We have months.
You think you can take kids
who've never played together
and teach them a new style
of play in the time we have?
Here's the North American style.
What if these kids can't
pick it up fast enough?
We all know we're
a long shot for a medal,
but we don't want to
get embarrassed.
-That's right.
Bob, four years ago,
our Olympic team
Iost to the czech "B" team.
I think it was 15-1.
In all due respect, I don't
think we can embarrass ourselves
any more than that.
That's assuming
they don't go pro.
I don't know about you, but l'd
have a hard time giving up money
to finish sixth at Lake Placid.
It's a tough draw, Herb.
Tough draw.
It's a tough draw even if
we don't play the Soviets.
What the hell happens if we do?
We put our best on the ice
with them last year.
Professional all-stars.
They still beat us.
It wasn't because
you weren't good enough.
All-star teams fail
because they rely solely
on the individual's talent.
The Soviets win because
they take that talent
and use it inside a system
that's designed for
the betterment of the team.
My goal is to beat them
at their own game.
Beat the best team in the world?
Gold medalists in
'64, '68, '72, '76?
That's a pretty lofty goal,
Herb.
Lou, that's why I want to
pursue it.
Well, fellas,
any more questions?
-I'm good.
-No?
That's it for me.
Thanks.
It's good seeing you.
-Herb, thanks.
-Thanks a lot.
-Appreciate it.
Hey.
It's coming down out there.
Hey, where are the kids?
Oh, I gave them away.
How'd it go?
Ah, I'm not their guy.
The only reason
they had me come out there
was because two other coaches
already said no.
I think they're still
looking East coast.
What's that?
-It's a costume party, Herb.
-No, Patti.
come on. Nick and Nora charles.
"The Thin Man."
You're gonna make me wear this?
They're sophisticated, they're
dashing, they're debonair.
I've got a mustache for you.
-No, Patti.
-A little dog for me.
[ Yipping ]
You can leave
& You can go &
& 'Cause you know
I love you so &
Excuse me.
& But you can suit, suit,
ooh-ooh-ooh &
& Baby, you can suit yourself &
[ T elephone rings ]
Oh, Linda, can you get
that for me?
Oh, sure.
Hello?
Yes, just a moment, please.
Patti, it's for Herb.
Someone from the U.S.O.c.
It's 8-0!
All right, it's gonna be
a dramatic comeback.
Go.
-Herb.
-Yeah?
Herb.
You've got a call from colorado.
We're not done here.
Yes, well, so then he what?
He just went along with that?
Well, I appreciate that, Walter.
Thank you.
What'd they say?
I got the job.
How about that, huh?
Oh, great! Oh!
-When do you start?
-Two weeks.
Two weeks? They want you
to start that soon?
The games are in February.
Yeah, but it's June.
Is there even ice?
Mommy!
Mommy, Mommy.
We're supposed to take the kids
to the Black Hills.
I know, I know.
cleopatra's leaving,
and she wants to say goodbye.
Okay. Okay.
I gotta call craig Patrick
right now.
-Hey, Buzz.
-Hey.
What's going on?
-How are you doing?
-Good.
-Phil Verchota.
-Verchota?
Name?
Ralph cox. U.N.H.
Name, please.
-Mike Ramsey.
-Hi, Mike.
Number, towel.
Jack O'callahan, right?
-Last time I checked.
-Good luck.
-Thanks, buddy.
-Who's next?
Jimmy craig.
Hey, Jack.
What's up, you sieve?
-How's it going?
-Good.
Is there a reason why
Joey Mullen's not here?
Yeah, about 30,000 of them,
all sitting in
his New York bank account.
He got a $30,000 signing bonus?
-crazy, isn't it?
-Yeah.
How's it looking?
A lot of guys
from Minnesota and Boston.
Yeah, that's gonna work.
You're Robbie Mcclanahan, right?
Yeah.
Mike Eruzione.
Boston University.
'76.
Try to play for Brooks
a little more, huh?
I played for him for four years.
A few more months wouldn't hurt.
How about you?
Just trying to play a little
more hockey, that's all.
Rest of your boys all here?
Of course.
Think they'd miss out on this?
Might want to wait a day or so
before you go over and say hi.
[ Whistle blows ]
check!
come on, hit those lines!
Head for the net!
The net!
come on, come on!
Skate, boys! Skate!
Skate!
Drop your shoulder!
On the wing!
Hey, go to the blue line!
Man, look at that move.
Whoo, Rizzo!
Eruzione?
cross him off the list.
Kid doesn't have a shot
of making this team.
-You think so?
-No way.
One more!
Do it again!
Pucks in, pucks in!
Forward! Blue line!
So, Doc cleared him.
Says it's just a sprain.
Good.
I wanted to let you know
how much I'm looking forward to
being able to coach with you.
You were a hell of
a player, craig.
And you're gonna make
a hell of a coach.
Thanks.
I'm gonna need you to
stick tight with these kids.
If there's any big problems,
you'll let me know.
Otherwise, you take
care of it, okay?
Okay.
Take a look at that.
What's this?
26 names.
The tough part
will be getting it to 20
before the opening ceremonies.
What, this is the final roster?
You're kidding me, right?
This is our first day, Herb.
I mean, we got a week of this.
What about the advisory staff?
Aren't they supposed to
have a say in this?
Technically, I guess.
I don't know.
Well, you're missing
some of the best players.
I'm not looking
for the best players.
I'm looking for the right ones.
You have Jim craig
to back up Janaszak?
Other way around.
Other way around?
I'm sorry, didn't Janaszak just
win you a National championship?
Jannie is a solid goaltender,
but we're not playing
for the National championship
here, craig.
People I speak to
say craig's game has been off
since his mom died.
Did they ever see him
when his game's on?
Hughes. Ross.
Auge. Delich.
Horsch. Strobel.
christoff. Morrow.
Suter. Ramsey.
Janaszak. christian.
Pavelich. Verchota.
Baker. Harrington.
Schneider. O'callahan.
Mcclanahan. Silk.
Johnson. craig.
cox. Eruzione.
And that's the roster for now.
Rest of you,
thanks for coming out.
-congratulations.
-congratulations, Robbie.
Way to go, Rizzo.
Take a good look, gentlemen.
'cause they're the ones
getting off easy.
We're putting
a few of you on reserve
in case somebody gets injured
or their game goes to hell.
The final roster will have
20 names on it in 7 months,
so more of you are going home.
You give 99%, you'll make
my job very, very easy.
I'll be your coach.
I won't be your friend.
If you need one of those, take
it up with Doc or coach Patrick.
God.
PATRlcK:
All right, gentlemen.
congratulations to all of you.
That's it for today.
On the way out,
pick up one of these.
You've got a little homework
to do before you celebrate.
Thank you.
Whoo!
Herb!
Herb.
Hold on a minute.
Hey, Walter.
How we doing?
I think we got
a problem here, Herb.
What's that?
I got a roomful
of people up there
who want to have a say
in this process,
and you've already
picked the team.
-Look, Walter.
-No, no.
There's a right way to do
this kind of thing,
and this is not it.
I know you got a job to do.
If I was in your shoes,
I'd be saying the same thing.
All right, then.
Let's go upstairs.
We'll help piece together
a hockey team.
All of us.
Together.
Walter, that's just
not gonna happen.
Do you realize
what the A.H.A. went through
to put this thing together?
The best amateur players in the
country on the ice for a week?
-Yeah.
-Not just a day.
I didn't ask for that,
because I already know my team.
How do you know your team?
Those kids haven't been on the
ice for maybe a couple of hours.
Every one of those boys was
chosen for a specific reason.
I've studied film
on each one of those boys.
I've watched them,
and I've coached a lot of them.
The ones I haven't,
I've spoken with their coaches
and scouts in the area.
Now, I know best
what I need to compete.
And the team I've chosen is it.
What am I supposed to say
to the advisory board?
Tell them the truth.
This puts me
in a hell of a spot, Herb.
A hell of a spot!
Well, they hired me to do a job.
I'm trying to do it.
All right.
I'm gonna back you on this.
But I sure as hell hope
you know what you're doing.
Hey, Phillie, what are you on?
My test is done.
Jesus!
Me and Jannie are done.
Verchota, you're done?
I'm on page four.
"71.
You get stopped by a policeman,
but you're not at fault.
Do you state
your disagreement right away?"
He's got 300 of these things.
It's just a test, Silky.
You've taken one or two before.
Not to play hockey, I haven't.
can you even read, Silky?
I try.
Hey, Rizzo!
-What's going on?
-Mac.
Easy, big guy.
I don't know how you can sit in
the same room with that clown.
Let it go. It's over.
Let it go.
What's going on here?
O.c.'s got a little
unfinished business over there.
Not for long I don't.
What did I tell you, man?
Mcclanahan?
You're not still going on about
the '76 playoffs, are you?
come on, O.c., that was,
like, three years ago.
You know what, coxie,
let me ask you a question.
Why did you want to
play college hockey?
Isn't it obvious?
For the girls.
I'm serious, coxie.
Why did you want to
play college hockey?
'cause I love to play hockey.
I want to go to the NHL
just like everybody does.
I wanted to win
a National championship.
That pansy over there
cheap-shots me.
I get tossed out of the game.
He steals the ring
right off my finger?
How would you feel?
Everyone was throwing
cheap shots that night.
Rizzo, it's funny you say that.
I was just wondering
what side you're on.
I'm on your side.
You know,
it really seems that way.
All right, just relax, okay?
Jeez.
I'm not doing this right now.
I'm outta here.
Where you going?
To my room. Is that
all right with you, Mother?
cOX:
Just let him go.
Well, no wonder the guy
gets so many penalty minutes.
SlLK: He gets a little
carried away sometimes.
HERB: That's it.
Pick it up.
-That's it.
-Kick it out!
Look for the pass.
come on, hit him with a pass.
-Go, Johnson!
-Outside!
All right, Johnson,
hit him on the other side.
-Get them up!
-Look for him!
Move and hit him, Johnson.
He's open.
-center, center!
-come on, Johnson!
[ Whistle blows ]
Johnson!
That stuff may work here,
but it won't against
the teams we'll be playing.
Next line up.
Let's go. Let's run it again.
Morrow.
Let me take this one.
Don't worry about it.
Keep your head up.
HERB: This is
a breakout play, gentlemen.
So, please, let's get rid
of the puck early.
All right, let's go!
Hey, hey!
-Oh!
-Oh, my God.
-What's O.c. doing?
-That was cheap.
He didn't have the puck.
What are you hitting
like that for?
That's bush league, O.c.
Nice hit, O.c.
Tell your boy to keep his head
up, and he won't have to worry.
You all right, man?
Let's go!
craig, let them go.
You got him?
-Hey, stay on him!
-Stay out of it, Buzzy!
Get him.
come on, give it to him.
-What are you doing?
-Stay out of it, Baker!
come on, give it to him!
All right, Mac.
come on, Mac.
Take him down!
come on, O.c.!
Let him have it!
-Put him on the ice!
-come on, O.c.
There you go.
Beat him, O.c.
-Oh!
-Oh, man!
Whoa!
That's it.
HERB:
Well, how about it, boys?
Look like hockey to you?
Looks like a couple of monkeys
trying to hump a football to me.
What do you think, craig?
Yeah.
You want to settle old scores,
you're on the wrong team.
We move forward
starting right now.
We start becoming a team
right now!
Skating.
Passing.
Flow.
creativity.
That is what this team
is all about, gentlemen.
Not old rivalries.
Why don't we start
with some introductions?
You know, get to know
each other a little bit.
Where you're from, who you are.
Go ahead.
Rob Mcclanahan.
St. Paul, Minnesota.
Who you play for?
For you, here at the U.
Jack?
Jack O'callahan.
charlestown, Mass.
Boston University.
Over here.
I'm Ralph cox.
I'm from wherever's
not gonna get me hit.
Very good.
Everybody on the line.
Let's go.
& Must of got lost &
-Hey, Jim.
-Hey, coach.
Been wondering why
you wouldn't take this test.
Yeah. Well...
It's nothing against you
or anything.
I just don't see what it has to
do with stopping a puck.
Well, that's all right.
You just took it anyway.
& Honey, I don't know &
Hey, coach.
So, if I took it...
You know, I meant to ask you.
How's your family doing?
Doing all right.
And you?
I'm okay.
You know, I got 26 guys
trying to make this team, Jim.
Only 20 are gonna go
to Lake Placid.
So I gotta know how committed
you are to being here.
Because if you're not,
you're just wasting our time.
Look, coach.
My dad's going through
a rough time right now.
He's got nothing.
He lost his job, and with
Atlanta trying to sign me...
Bottom line is,
my mom wanted this.
Me playing on this team.
Hard to say no to someone who
drove you to practice every day.
You didn't answer
my question, Jim.
I'm here, aren't l?
I'll see you in the morning.
Don't forget to bring your game.
MAN ON RADlO: The Soviets
performed a nuclear test,
setting off a 75-kiloton bomb
in eastern Kazakhstan.
So much hate and fear.
-What's that?
-The Soviets and the West.
They have nuclear weapons
pointed at each other.
It's bound to end in disaster.
Oh, come on. They'll figure
something out, Doc.
Don't got any other choice,
right?
Well, yeah, hope so.
But it seems to me there are
some people who never get along.
Yeah.
Like hockey players
from Boston and Minnesota.
Our own private cold War.
Hey, Doc, let me ask you
a question, all right?
You've worked with Herb
for a long time, right?
I've known Herb
for quite some time.
So tell me something.
Does he always treat
his players like this?
No. No, no.
This I have never seen.
But, craig, believe me.
Herb has a reason
for everything he does.
Well, he's ending up with
20 players who hate his guts.
Maybe if they hate him,
they won't have time
to hate each other.
& Out on Thunder Island &
& Doo doo doo &
& Doo doo doo doo-doo &
Hey, honey.
How much longer you gonna be?
I still got a few more.
Well, I'm going to bed, okay?
-Okay.
Oh, you know, Kelly has ballet
at 4:00 tomorrow
and Danny's done with hockey
camp at about the same time.
Which one do you want to get?
-Herb?
-Yeah.
can you pick up Danny at 4:00?
We got team meetings
after practice tomorrow.
I can't be in two places
at one time.
-What about Margie?
-They're on vacation.
Well, I don't know, honey.
You'll figure it out.
can you turn that off, please?
Please.
Herb, this is what happens
over the summer.
The kids are off
doing a zillion things,
and once in a while,
your meetings have to wait.
come on, Patti.
I'm coaching a hockey team here.
I mean, we already
talked about this.
Oh, really?
When exactly
did we have this talk?
Because I don't recall being
a part of the conversation.
What did I say?
Was it interesting?
We never had this talk.
Never.
Okay, what's on your mind?
Nothing.
No, you're obviously mad
about something.
First you're upset
because we didn't talk.
And then when I try to talk
about whatever it is,
you don't want to.
Patti,
if you're not willing to...
It's not because we didn't talk.
It's because
you never even asked.
I know what this is about.
I know it, and you know it.
What? Know what?
This.
What you're doing.
chasing after something
you didn't get,
that you may never get.
What if it doesn't
work out, Herb?
Are we gonna do this
every four years?
It's okay.
Go finish your work.
Go, go.
Hey.
You know...
Ever since I stopped playing,
I wanted to coach this team.
And this is the only way
I know how to do it.
It's not the easiest way,
I know, for you.
Or the kids.
But...
Patti, I have to do this.
I know you do.
I'm sorry we didn't talk.
And I was wrong not to ask.
So I'm asking now if you
can be with me on this,
because it won't mean anything
if you're not.
Blue line, back.
Red line, back.
Far blue line, back.
Far red line, back.
And you have 45 seconds
to do it.
Get used to this drill.
We'll be doing it a lot.
Why?
Because the legs feed
the wolf, gentlemen.
I can't promise you
we'll be the best team
at Lake Placid next February.
But we will be
the best-conditioned.
That I can promise you.
[ Whistle blows ]
Be prepared to grow
through pain, gentlemen.
You're gonna skate harder
than you've skated in your lives
every minute of every day
you're on the ice with me.
Stretch things out
north and south,
you open things up
east and west.
center's gonna fill in here.
This far-side winger is gonna
come in, take the center spot.
-What's your name?
-Mark Johnson.
Where you from, Mark?
Madison, Wisconsin.
-Who you play for?
-University of Wisconsin.
[ Whistle blows ]
come on, go, boys.
Go, boys!
The fastest way to make
this team is by being fast!
No, no!
Stop.
Look at you.
Three men being covered
by one guy.
This isn't weaving
for weaving's sake.
Spread out!
Use the ice!
-Right there.
-There? Okay.
come on, Jimmy.
challenge them!
You're getting beat
on the side here.
challenge them.
Yeah, I don't blame you.
How you holding up?
-Oh, no.
-Not good, not good.
-How about you?
-Name's christian.
-Who do you play for?
-University of North Dakota.
Pass it! come on!
No!
No, no, no!
Get him to a point!
You're quarterbacking this play!
come on, Rizzo,
I got you running this play!
You're gonna run the bench.
Mac, get out here!
Boom, he can hit him.
Boom. Boom. Boom.
We're opening up options, see?
We've got four options
off one play, guys.
You guys got that?
Anybody have any questions?
Okay, let's go.
-What is he talking about?
-No clue.
20 of you are going
to Lake Placid.
6 are going home.
Who that is, believe it or not,
is up to you.
-How about you?
-Mark Pavelich.
-Who do you play for?
-U.M.D. Bulldogs.
Let's go!
Next line up!
All right, turn it up, boys.
Let's move it, Bah.
Get it up, get it up!
Eric, it's open!
Here you go, here you go!
They can't stop us yet.
Attaway, Buzzy.
Nice pass.
That was a good shot.
You three.
-Run that again.
-Again?
-All right.
-Let's go.
christ, we don't have a chance
in hell of winning.
So I understand how you feel.
Don't let them know that.
Yeah.
-All right.
-Thanks, coach.
The coneheads are coming in.
Who?
That's what the guys
have been calling them
'cause, well, they're
a little...[ whistles ]
You know, like the coneheads.
What's that?
Dan Akroyd, Jane curtin.
I guess it's off your radar.
come on in, boys.
Wanted to see us, coach?
Yeah, I'm thinking about
keeping the three of you
together on the same line.
Everybody okay with that?
-Yeah. Sure.
-Yeah.
How about you, Buzzy? You think
this works with Bah and Pav?
Yeah, it's going good.
Moving the puck well.
It's different
playing with them.
We just seem to always
find each other
at the other end of the ice
and make things happen.
Pass, shoot, score.
-Pass, shoot, and...
-Score.
Well, all right.
We'll see how she goes.
-All right.
-Thanks, coach.
Take it easy.
Rest up.
Well, looks like we're taking
a line of coneheads to Europe.
Yeah, if they can keep
their legs under them.
All right, Herb,
I'll see you next week.
Something on your mind, craig?
Or is that just
too far off my radar?
I don't think
you can push them this hard.
Not for six months.
It's too long.
-They're doing all right.
-Well, whole team's tired.
I know how hard
to push them, craig.
You sure about that?
You know why I had them
take that test?
Make sure I could
push them this hard.
I'll see you Monday.
All right.
Oh, wow. Dynamite.
Look over here, Phillie.
Section two, about four rows up.
Two girls. Blond.
Man, they're gorgeous.
What row?
About the seventh row up.
To the right.
Lovely blond girls.
Maybe we can take a few home.
Must be something in the water.
Get a whistle.
Good game.
-Good game.
Hold up, there.
Hold up, hold up.
Gotta get back on the ice.
Let's go.
-What for?
-You'll find out soon enough.
Let's go.
Back on the ice.
What for?
We'll find out in a minute,
won't we?
come on,
let's see what he wants.
Get a picture or something?
What's going on?
You guys don't want to
work during the game?
No problem.
We'll work now.
Goal line.
That one!
[ Whistle blows ]
Hustle!
Think you can win
on talent alone?
Gentlemen, you don't have enough
talent to win on talent alone.
Again.
[ Whistle blows ]
If you think you can come here
and play the Norwegian
National team and tie them
and then go to the Olympics
and win...
You got another thing coming.
You better think about
something else,
each and every one of you.
When you pull on that jersey,
you represent yourself
and your teammates.
And the name on the front is
a hell of a lot more important
than the one on the back!
Get that through your head!
Again!
[ Whistle blows ]
Win, lose, or tie, you're
gonna play like champions!
Again!
Kick it in the ass, Verchota!
You want to go home early?
Keep it going, Suter.
All the way to the line
and all the way back.
It's not that difficult.
Again!
Again.
Herb.
What?
The rink manager wants to clean
the ice and then go home.
Tell him to leave me the keys.
I'll lock up.
Again.
You keep playing this way,
you won't beat anybody who's
even good, let alone great.
You want to make this team,
then you better start playing
at a level
that's gonna force me
to keep you here.
Again!
Thank God.
Think we're getting out of here?
Hey.
Where you going?
Back on the line.
Again.
Send them.
How about it, Silky? You gonna
be the first one to quit on me?
How about you, O.c.?
You ready to go down?
Oh, I think I got
my money on you, Verchota.
You got a hot date
in about an hour,
but you're not looking too good
for that right about now.
Send them.
Again.
Doc, I mean,
this is madness, right?
[ Gagging ]
This cannot be a team
of common men
because common men go nowhere.
You have to be uncommon.
Again.
Herb!
This has gone on long enough!
Everybody on that line.
Somebody's going to get hurt!
[ Players coughing, wheezing ]
Everybody get on that line.
Hey.
Again.
Herb.
come on, craig.
Blow the whistle.
Again.
Mike Eruzione!
Winthrop, Massachusetts!
Who do you play for?
I play for
the United States of America.
That's all, gentlemen.
come on, you Minnesotans!
My back's starting to hurt
from carrying you all.
Pretend you're pushing
some cows!
Why don't you stop talking,
Boston boy, and start pushing?
-What do you got there, Pav?
-Three 9's.
Not bad, Pav.
Not bad.
I got two 7's.
Well, we were taxiing out
to the runway, right,
and we, you know,
we kind of hit a moose.
No, the moose is fine.
But we gotta make sure
the airplane's all right,
so some of the boys
are pushing it back
so these guys can take
a look at it.
Patti, the moose is okay.
He ran off. I saw it.
So, what's going on at home?
REPORTER:
Big matchup tonight in New York
between the NHL All-Stars
and the Soviet Union.
-Yeah, she did, huh?
-And this one was no contest,
as the Soviets dominated
the NHL's best
from start to finish,
winning by a score of 6-0.
The Soviets, led by the
superb play of their captain,
Boris Mikhailov,
were superior to the NHL stars
in every way tonight.
Their passing was crisper,
their offense was relentless,
and their conditioning, superb.
-No, I'm here. I'm listening.
-The Soviets coasting to a win
in New York tonight.
An embarrassing evening
for the NHL All-Stars.
Russian style of play, boys.
Fluid.
creative.
Forwards are
constantly circling.
They don't so much look for the
man as they do a patch of ice.
They get the mismatch,
two-on-one, easy goal.
Looks a lot like me
out there, huh, Buzz?
Boris Mikhailov.
captain for the last six years.
He is the best player
at his position.
And that includes, as we've
just found out, the NHL.
Do these guys ever smile?
They're Russians.
They get shot if they smile.
HERB:
Vladislav Tretiak.
You score on Tretiak,
keep the puck.
'cause it doesn't happen often.
42 games in the last 3 months.
42 wins.
Their main weapon
is intimidation.
They know they're gonna win,
and so do their opponents.
Look, I can give you all
a load of crap
about how you're a better team
than they are,
but that's exactly what it'd be.
Everyone in this room knows what
people say about our chances.
I know it.
You know it.
But I also know there is a way
to stay with this team.
You don't defend them.
You attack them.
You take their game
and you shove it
right back in their face.
The team that is finally
willing to do this
is the team that has a chance
to put them down.
NHL won't change their game.
We will.
Rest of the world
is afraid of them.
Boys, we won't be.
No one has ever worked
hard enough
to skate with the Soviet team
for an entire game.
Gentlemen, we are
gonna work hard enough.
[ Whistle blows ]
come on, quick feet, boys!
Quick feet! Work it!
Work hard now, boys!
come on, Strobel,
pick up your knees!
Keep your shoulders square.
Push it!
come on, boys.
Go!
The legs feed the wolf, boys.
The legs feed the wolf.
Go! Stay with him, Jimmy!
Stay with him!
Damn it!
How's your legs?
I'll let you know
when I can feel them.
come on, boys.
Go get him, go get him!
Attaboy, Jimmy.
Better.
Not good, but better.
You gotta have
the mental intensity, boys.
Move, boys!
There you go, there you go!
That's it.
Work it, boys. Work it.
Quick feet!
Push it!
Hit the tape, boys.
Passes come from the heart.
Want to stretch things out
north and south.
We got the coneheads
on the line.
Take me through it here.
Bah.
I'm gonna stretch the "D."
Gonna open up some space.
What are we gonna do?
I fill the open lane.
I fill in for Pav's lane.
That's it, that's it!
Attaway, boys.
come on.
Attaway, Jimmy!
Don't let them have it!
Attaboy! Yeah!
come on, build your legs up,
boys. Build your legs.
You're not gonna have anything
left for the third period
if you don't
build your legs now.
Here.
What's that give us, boys?
-PLAYERS: Options.
-All right, let's run it.
-How's it going?
-What's going on?
We're playing the Soviets
three days before Lake Placid?
Yeah, how about that?
How about that?
Ah, that won't work with Wells.
Oh, Rizzo, you're killing me.
Why can't you find the net?
You've been staring at the same
piece of paper since dinner.
Take a break.
How do I cut this kid?
He's done everything I've asked.
Well, so keep him.
I didn't think it was
gonna be this hard.
MAN ON TV:
This is "NBc Nightly News."
Yeah, you did.
With Jessica Savitch,
and Dick Schaap with Sports.
This isn't gonna work.
I'd have to stick christian
on defense.
The embassy in Tehran is in
the hands of Moslem students.
Wait. That works.
Spurred on
by an anti-American speech
-Or Baker.
-by the Ayatollah Khomeini,
they stormed the embassy,
fought the Marine guard
for three hours,
overpowered them, and took
dozens of American hostages.
-Oh, my God.
-Maybe that'll work.
Herb.
We have two reports,
beginning with Steve Mallory.
MALLORY: United States Marine
corps guards used tear gas
to try to disperse the mob
of lslamic students,
but that wasn't enough.
Hundreds of lranians finally
overran the embassy compound,
seizing about 90 people,
mostly Americans.
The hostages, men and women,
were blindfolded
and herded into
the embassy's basement.
Earlier today, the
Ayatollah Khomeini publicly...
We gave those guys at Harvard
a good schooling.
Hey!
How about Johnson
and Mcclanahan now?
come on, that works.
Doesn't it?
They're starting to
come together.
Thanks for coming out.
I wouldn't have missed it.
-Hey, you beat Harvard.
-Yeah.
Well, I should
probably get going.
Yeah. Yeah.
I love you, Pop.
You too, son.
-Jimmy.
-Yeah?
You keep that glove up.
You got it.
Switch.
Rizzo's making dinner, boys.
You know there's gonna
be meatballs.
You boys keep eating them,
I'll keep making them.
I think you guys
are insane to eat that stuff.
No offense, Rizzo.
I wonder how it's gonna affect
the chemistry of the boys.
I don't know.
We'll see.
Timmy.
Who the hell is that?
What's he doing here?
How you doing, Tim?
Good to see you.
Thanks, coach.
Hey, Bah.
-Yeah?
-Who's that guy?
Timmy Harrer.
Plays for the Gophers.
Having a big year.
-What the hell's he doing here?
-No idea.
Why is he here?
Hey, you guys know
he was coming?
So, listen, why don't you
warm up, stretch out,
jump on Johnson's line
for the day, okay?
Good to have you here.
-See you, boys.
-See you.
This is ridiculous.
Don't worry about it, Rammer.
It'll be all right.
Right, O.c.?
Herb's not gonna do
a damn thing, boys.
He's just messing
with our minds.
Oh, you think so, Jack?
Yeah, I do.
Well, we all know Herb made
the Olympic team back in '60.
So?
So, a week before the games,
coach Riley calls him into
his office and sends him home.
What's your point?
My point, Jack,
is that one week later,
Herb's on his couch
with his old man,
watching his team win
the gold medal.
come that close and get nothing?
He'll do whatever it takes.
That's my point.
Yeah, I'm aware of that, Walter.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, you've talked to
everybody else then, all right.
Nothing else we can do, then.
Thank you, Walter.
Is everything okay?
Walter says that there's talk
carter may boycott
the Moscow games next summer.
So if we don't go there,
they might not come here, right?
Right.
Don't do this to yourself, Herb.
There are things you can control
and things you can't.
No milk.
Herb.
Yeah, I heard you, honey.
You'll still have everything
you won here.
Don't tell me
what I'll have, Patti.
You don't know this enough
to tell me that.
You know, I understand
you being upset with me
when I say you work too hard
teaching a simple game.
But don't ever criticize me
for caring about you.
[ Whistle blows ]
HERB: That's it.
come on, boys, push it.
Here we go! Push it!
Go now! Move!
Damn it!
come on, Rizzo.
I know, coach.
-I know.
-You know?
If you knew,
then why did you do it again?
You start putting
the puck in the net,
or you're not going anywhere.
And don't think I won't do it.
Johnson, line up!
Let's go!
come on!
Shoot it!
Up and around!
Keep it moving!
Attaboy!
center, center, center!
-Now move it up!
-Go, Mike, go!
Drop it back.
Go to the net, Timmy!
Go to the net!
Go, go, go!
-[ Buzzer ]
-Whoo!
Yeah!
Nice play, boys.
Nice play.
ANNOUNcER: Goal scored
by number 18, Tim Harrer.
change them up, boys.
Let's go.
come on, boys.
Let's go, boys!
Timmy.
You keep driving the net.
That's all I care about, okay?
That puck goes across the
blue line, you drive to the net.
Okay.
All right.
Herb.
Some of the boys
want to have a word.
What about?
I think you ought to
hear them out.
This had better take
about two minutes.
This is crazy, Herb.
Bringing him in this late.
Hey, we got parents buying
tickets, getting rooms.
What are we
supposed to tell them?
And with one of us
going home as it is?
I don't have to ask where
you stand on this, huh, Rizzo?
This wasn't Rizzo's idea.
You want me to say
I'm scared of getting cut?
I'm scared of getting cut.
Everybody is.
We just want it to be fair.
Don't even try telling me that.
He was in colorado.
That was 6 months ago.
You don't think he's been
playing for the last 6 months?
-Not with us, he hasn't.
-So?
-So there's a difference.
-Like hell there is!
All I know is that kid
can flat-out play.
We can't?
He moves the puck, he's got
great vision on the ice.
That's not the point!
I'll tell you
something else he's got.
He's got the attitude I want
on and off the ice,
so somebody better explain to me
why I shouldn't be
giving him a look.
Because we're a family.
What?
We're a family.
A family?
Yeah.
And this is the family you want
to go to Lake Placid with?
Definitely.
-Yeah, without a doubt.
-Absolutely.
Wouldn't have it any other way.
Timmy Harrer can help us, boys.
And I'm gonna send him home.
We got one more
to get down to 20.
You understand.
Yep.
Looks like you got
yourself a team.
Almost.
-Let's talk about it.
-The rules.
Well, your girl left these
at my place.
With some milk and cookies.
Give her a hug for me.
You guys are unbelievable.
Real funny, guys.
Hey, boys.
We still got
two more presents to open up.
Yeah.
Pardon me, coach.
Yeah?
coach Patrick, from the boys.
Oh.
Here we go.
I thought you forgot.
"To craig."
That's beautiful, boys.
-You're gonna like this one.
-What?
That's very good.
-Perfect.
-Again!
-[ Whistle blows ]
All right.
That's enough of that.
It's going back in the box.
And, Herb.
Merry christmas from the boys.
Drumroll, please.
coach.
Ah, yes.
The gift that keeps on giving.
No.
Speech.
-"Ayatollah."
-Speech.
Speech.
Well, this may come as a shock
to some of you guys,
but I'm not really very good
at giving sentimental speeches.
-No?
-You're kidding?
come on.
I don't think
I should start tonight.
Hey, thanks
for having me over, Velta.
Good night, Herb.
-Doc, Merry christmas.
-Merry christmas, Herb.
You guys have a great holiday.
TOGETHER:
Merry christmas, coach.
Play some football!
WOMAN: By many
as the most important speech
of President carter's term.
A look back now as 830 WccO's
year-end special continues.
PRESlDENT cARTER: The erosion
of our confidence in the future
is threatening to destroy
the social and the political
fabric of America.
The confidence that we have
always had as a people
is not simply
some romantic dream
or a proverb in a dusty book
that we read
just on the Fourth of July.
It is the idea
which founded our nation
and has guided
our development as a people.
confidence in the future
has supported everything else.
We've always believed in
something called "progress."
We've always had a faith
that the days of our children
will be better than our own.
Our people are losing
that faith.
For the first time
in the history of our country,
a majority of our people believe
that the next five years
will be worse than
the past five years.
We were taught that our armies
were always invincible,
and our causes were always just,
only to suffer
the agony of Vietnam.
We respected the presidency
as a place of honor
until the shock of Watergate.
We've got to stop crying
and start sweating.
Stop talking and start walking.
Working together
with our common faith.
We cannot fail.
-Yeah.
-Hard workout.
Silk, you guys want to
grab something to eat?
Yeah, I'm starving.
Where you guys gonna go?
Maybe that Mario's place.
Mario's?
Hey, coach.
coxie.
Herb wants to see you.
[ Knock on door ]
come in.
coach Patrick
said you wanted to see me.
Why don't you have
a seat there, Ralph?
Well, there's just
no easy way of doing this.
The rules say that we gotta
be down to 20 men,
and right now we're at 21.
I wish like hell
I could keep you, Ralph.
I do.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
You're a hell of
a hockey player.
This doesn't change that.
Thanks.
Well...
Thanks for giving me
a shot, coach.
your very best.
[ Paper tears ]
[ Telephone rings ]
-Yeah?
-Herb, Walter.
Well, you've got your wish.
Brezhnev's telling carter
to screw himself.
Yeah, Walter, how's that?
The Kremlin just released
a statement today
saying they're gonna prove
how good they are
by beating us over here
on our own ice.
They're all gonna play.
The Soviets, the czechs,
the whole bunch of them.
Have you got your roster
finalized yet?
Yeah, I got my team.
Well, I still don't know
why you scheduled this, Herb,
but get your guys to New York.
They've got a game to play.
& Oh, say does that
star-spangled banner yet wave &
& O'er the land of the free &
& And the home of the brave? &
ANNOUNcER: Ladies and gentlemen,
your 1 980 U.S. Olympic Team.
-[ Air horn blares ]
-[ cheering ]
MAN: And so, as we await
the opening face-off
in this game between
the Soviet Union and Team USA
at Madison Square Garden,
the teams line up
on their respective blue lines.
And Soviet Union team captain
Boris Mikhailov
skating over to his bench
to pick up
that NHL challenge trophy.
The trophy that his team won
here at Madison Square Garden
last October,
and won in decisive fashion,
beating the NHL All-Stars.
Getting a mixed reaction from
the capacity audience here.
Some cheers, but a few boos
going through the crowd as well.
And now the two teams
clear the ice
and repair
to their respective goals
as we get set
for the opening face-off
in this final tune-up
for these two teams
before the Olympic Games
in Lake Placid.
[ Speaking Russian ]
1, 2, 3.
TOGETHER:
USA!
MAN: And as we get set to drop
the puck for this contest,
the Soviets starting
their big line
of Mikhailov between
Kharlamov and Petrov.
Team USA countering
with Mark Johnson at center
between Mcclanahan
and Dave Silk.
And we're ready to go
with this warm-up contest.
Want to go hard, boys?
PETROV:
Here!
It's the Soviet Union
in control,
making a charge
into the Team USA zone.
corner!
Move it out!
And in behind the Team USA net.
Puck bounced back
to the blue line.
Moving in with a shot,
stopped by Jimmy craig,
and it goes into the corner.
Finally Team USA
gets its stick on the puck
as Ramsey brings it up
to the blue line.
He's absolutely flattened there
by Kasatonov.
HERB:
Two-on-one!
Team Soviet Union turning it
into a two-on-one.
Back door, O.c., look out!
Get the puck!
Moving in to the boards,
shoots and scores.
come on!
Hey, break it up!
Break it up!
That's it.
Let's go.
That's a nice expression
on your face.
Let's get it back, boys.
Get it back!
HERB:
Jack, you gotta listen to me!
You gotta listen to me!
The Soviets breaking out
of their own zone now,
up the ice to center.
Krutov goes in
over the U.S. blue line.
Shoots and scores.
He's in front and scores.
Shoots. He scores.
He shoots.
He scores!
The Soviet Union
drubbing Team USA 10-3.
There's always things
you can work on.
This club's
no exception to that.
You know, I think
we're gonna be all right.
This Soviet team has been
together for 10 years.
We got college kids still
getting to know each other.
They could have
won this thing 30-0.
Herb, Herb!
Herb Brooks!
Sorry.
How is he?
Well, I'm not sure
if he needs surgery yet.
I'm hoping it's just a ligament
pull, but it could be a tear.
Look, Herb, we got
three days until Sweden.
You give him a roster spot,
it's a waste of money.
Give me a "best case."
He'll miss three
or four games minimum.
That's the whole
qualifying round.
Kid's made the team,
he's busted his ass for me,
and now I gotta send
him home, that the deal?
What'd Doc say?
Oh, he doesn't know yet, O.c.
He's gonna go
with you to the hospital
and get a picture
of your knee taken.
Then we'll see.
Thinking about
sitting you down, Jim.
-What are you talking about?
-Nah, it's not your fault.
I played you way too much,
and you're too tired.
Oh, I think it's time
I gave Jannie a look.
-He's been waiting.
-You're kidding me.
-Now?
-Yeah, of course I mean now.
-That's my net, man.
-They just scored 10 goals.
Right now it's everybody's net.
Whoa, wait a second.
I've given you
everything I've got.
Have you?
Given me your very best?
'cause I know
there's a lot more in you.
A whole other level that
you just don't want to go to.
Oh, what the hell.
You don't even understand.
Oh, no, I'll tell you
what I don't understand, Herb.
I don't understand you.
Nobody on this team
understands you
and your ridiculous sayings
and your drills
and those stupid psychology
tests you had everybody take.
Everybody?
What?
So that's what this is about?
Because I didn't take your test?
Fine!
I'll take your test.
Is that what you want?
No.
I want to see that kid in the
net who wouldn't take the test.
You gotta be kidding me.
What did he do?
PATTl:
Well, he did something amazing.
He started to laugh.
And then everybody in the whole
audience started to laugh.
It sounds funny,
but I was so proud of him.
I was starting to think
that our son takes after you.
Well, that's
all part of my plan.
My, you're a very smart woman.
I miss you.
Oh, the Games are only
a couple of days away now.
You got your airplane tickets?
Oh, yeah.
Walter had them sent over.
Yeah.
-I guess I'll see you then.
-You sound tired.
You should try
and get some sleep.
Yeah, well...
All right.
-I'll talk to you.
-Hey, Patti.
Yeah?
I miss you, too.
Good night.
Okay, I'll check on O.c.
Take care of these guys here.
come on, guys.
Stick with me.
MAN:
Next.
MAN #2:
This is your room key.
And this is your l.D. badge
that you'll need
for just about everything.
Don't lose it.
Herb.
Herb, it'll be fine.
I can fight through it.
Okay, why don't you join
the boys over there, O.c.?
It's good to see you, kid.
Attaboy.
-Well?
-It's not a tear.
It's a stretched ligament,
so he won't need surgery.
But there is no way he can play
before the medal round.
Forget about the medal round.
You keep O'callahan,
and you lose one more skater,
you're gonna have a tough time
putting a decent hockey team
on the ice.
It's that simple, Herb.
I asked Herb.
He's keeping me in the dark.
Oh, boy.
So if he gets shaky, it's you.
Stay loose, Jannie.
All right.
You're in there tomorrow, Jimmy.
Let's bring it up, now.
Okay.
Thanks a lot, man.
Attaboy, Jimmy.
Go get them.
I'll see you on the bus.
All right.
Doc said no, right?
He said you might
be able to go in a week.
Maybe two.
What if it's two?
That puts me in a tight spot,
doesn't it?
Jack, I got 20 guys
to think about here,
and they're all looking at me
to do what's best.
I understand, coach.
Which is why
I'm hanging on to you.
I swear to God, Herb, if you're
not being serious right now.
I'm only saying this
if you promise
you won't even think
about asking me to play.
I won't.
I mean, I will,
I promise you, coach.
'cause if you do, Jack, I'll
stick your ass on an airplane
and you're headed
back to Boston.
All right,
Doc's waiting for you.
Thank you, Herb.
Whoo!
O.c. is playing, baby!
Boys, move your feet!
MlcHAELS: Ramsey with the puck,
passes to Eruzione.
Eruzione carrying the puck
up the boards.
Drops the pass for Broten.
He shoots.
Kicked away by Lindbergh.
Boys, hit that one-timer now.
come on!
Al Michaels with Ken Dryden.
With 4:10 to go
in the first period,
it's Sweden leading
the United States 1-0.
Ahlberg to Eriksson.
And a big hit by Dave christian.
Eriksson picks up
the loose puck,
passes to Lundqvist,
Lundqvist to Ahlberg.
Mike, where is it?
-Up. This way.
-Okay. Okay.
-Yeah, yeah, that.
-That's it.
MlcHAELS: Ahlberg shoots.
Save by craig.
Eruzione fighting for it.
Mike Eruzione
recently named team captain
by coach Herb Brooks
for his firm footing,
his leadership qualities
on and off the ice.
Hey, I'm taking him out.
DRYDEN: The U.S. team is playing
tentative hockey tonight, Al.
Tough draw having to
face Sweden,
third-best team in the world.
-You know what I mean?
-No, I got you.
Look, I think it's worth a try.
Okay.
What's the deal with Mac?
Upper-leg contusion.
I think he's done for the night.
-What if he plays?
-I don't understand, Herb.
If he plays on it,
can he hurt it any worse?
Well, no, but it will be
very painful for him,
and he won't be able to
do very much.
This is unbelievable!
You guys are playing
like this is some throwaway game
up in Rochester.
-Who we playing, Rammer?
-Sweden.
Yeah, you're damn right!
Sweden!
In the Olympics!
What the hell's wrong with you?
Put your gear on.
I said, "Put your gear on."
-Doc told me I can't play.
-Yeah, I know.
You got a bad bruise.
You know what?
Put your street clothes on.
'cause I got no time
for quitters.
come on, Herb.
Nobody's quitting here.
You worry about your own game.
Plenty there to keep you busy.
A bruise on the leg
is a hell of a long way
from the heart, you candy-ass.
-What'd you call me?
-You heard me.
You want me to play?
Is that what you want?
I want you to be
a hockey player!
I am a hockey player!
You want me to play
on one leg, huh?
I'll play on one leg!
-That'll get them going.
-Oh, yeah.
-Will that make you happy?
-I'll clean up.
I am a hockey player!
MlcHAELS:
2:49 remaining in the game.
Sweden leading 2-1.
DRYDEN:
The U.S. team has fought hard,
but they've still got
nothing to show for it.
MlcHAELS:
This is a crucial game.
If they don't beat
or tie the Swedes,
it'll be very difficult to
advance to the medal round.
Mcclanahan after the loose puck.
He's hit hard by Soderstrom.
-Go, go, go, Mac!
-come on, Mac!
Mcclanahan gutting it out
despite being injured.
Silky!
Silk to Johnson.
Back to Silk.
-Through the neutral zone.
-Attaboy, Mac!
Dumped into the Swedish zone
and stopped behind the net
by Lindbergh.
Johnson fighting Eriksson
for it now.
It goes out to Waltin.
Ooh, he's hit hard
by Mcclanahan.
-All right, Mac!
-Baker, you're up next.
-What?
-Take the right side.
The Swedes regain control.
1 :40 remaining in the game.
coneheads, you're up next.
Mats Waltin moving it out
to Jan Eriksson.
Jan Eriksson
out to Hakan Eriksson.
-Across the U.S. blue line.
-Take it back, boys!
Into the corner.
Stay with him, Ramsey.
-Watch the slot!
-Passes across to Ahlberg.
Wrist shot. Knocked out
of the air by craig.
Puck picked up by Suter,
moved ahead to Johnson.
Switch them up!
Go, go!
Johnson gets rid of it
and heads to the bench
with just over a minute
and a half left to play.
Precious seconds ticking away
for this U.S. team.
What are you doing
with Baker out there?
1 :20, Herb.
Herb Brooks has molded
this unit.
Seven months of training.
Points to the net, just
a little over a minute left
to avoid a very damaging loss.
Ahlberg up the wing
to Hakan Eriksson in the slot.
Stopped by craig.
Rebound picked up by Schneider.
Schneider flying up the wing,
over the blue line,
and into the corner.
Jimmy, come on now!
And Brooks is pulling goalie
Jim craig for an extra skater.
Go, go, go!
45 seconds left to play.
Sweden leading
the U.S. team 2-1.
Across to Silk.
He moves in.
His backhander is
stopped by Lindbergh.
39 seconds remaining.
Let's go, Baker!
Schneider to Ramsey,
across to Baker.
He wraps it around the boards.
Baker fighting for the puck
with Naslund.
Back to Ramsey at the point.
To Johnson in front.
Broken up by Holmgren.
Kept in by Baker
and fired behind the net.
Get a shot, get a shot!
Loose puck. Schneider
and Waltin fighting for it.
Schneider holds him off.
Kicks it loose.
Pavelich has it.
He makes a move
around Hakan Eriksson.
Hits across to Baker.
He scores!
The United States has tied it.
Bill Baker scores in
the final minute of the game!
And the U.S. team
is still very much alive
in the opening round.
It was a hell of a move.
I didn't see him out there.
I'm Jim McKay,
and we're back again live
in Lake Placid, New York.
What an amazing start for these
13th Olympic Winter Games.
After a remarkable
last-minute tie
against Sweden two nights ago,
the U.S. hockey team,
huge underdogs,
pulled off a tremendous upset
last night,
defeating czechoslovakia,
considered the second-best team
behind the Soviet Union.
The final score, 7-3.
"Why so many reporters?"
Are you serious?
Well, we won two games.
We got a ways to go here.
Think of what
they've had to write about.
Hostages, Afghanistan.
Transportation chaos.
Patti probably has
talked to you about that.
Listen, Herb, the bottom line
is that your young guys
just kicked the crap
out of czechoslovakia,
and this is something that
this country is ready for.
Now, you want to see reporters?
Win a couple of more games.
They are just kids, Walter,
so let's not turn this
into something more, okay?
I'm not sure we got
any control over it.
[ Speaking Russian ]
Victor.
Somebody's gonna beat
those guys.
MlcHAELS: Buzz Schneider
flying up the right wing.
Takes a long pass from Ramsey.
Now he's all alone
on the breakaway.
He shoots!
He scores!
Buzz Schneider on a breakaway
puts the U.S. up
5-1 in the third period.
coach Brooks!
Monsieur!
Herb!
Herb, now that Norway
is behind you,
what do you look for
out of Romania?
It should be a tough test.
We're sure not
gonna overlook them.
-Herb!
-coach!
Mike.
All right, Jimmy craig's
been great between the pipes.
Is there any chance
we could talk to him?
Well, as I said the other night,
Mike, you know,
this isn't an individual
effort going on here.
It's about a team.
We're a team on the ice,
and we're gonna be one off it.
MlcHAELS: Palavka breaking up
the left side,
chased by christian.
Behind the U.S. net.
Drops the pass.
Slams it.
Shot.
Glove save by Jim craig.
The U.S. up 7-2
here late in the third.
Well, making it
to the medal round
was always our goal
from day one,
so we feel real good about
what we've accomplished so far.
Herb!
Still no chance we can talk
with any of your players?
-Still no chance.
-Okay.
How do you respond to those
who feel you're doing this
to keep the spotlight
on yourself?
MlcHAELS: Luzbach.
Esom across to Krutzman.
Ooh! He's hit hard
into the boards by Strobel.
Huge hit.
Ramsey has it,
moves it up to Verchota.
Verchota across the blue line.
Lines up.
He scores!
Verchota puts it past Sutner
to put the U.S. up 4-2
with 15:43 remaining to play
here in the third period.
And we'll be staying
with this one right to the end.
BUSH: The pairings for
the medal round are as follows.
The United States
will play the Soviet Union
in the first game tomorrow.
Sweden and Finland
in the second game.
The face-off for the U.S.-Soviet
game is 1 700 hours.
Now, if you have any questions,
we have the U.S.
assistant coach, craig Patrick.
[ Reporters murmuring ]
-Patrick.
-coach Patrick.
-craig.
Right here.
Where's Herb Brooks?
How come he's not here today?
Herb is out preparing
for tomorrow's game.
craig!
Yeah?
Hi, Daddy.
There we go.
There was no whipped cream.
That's all right.
-What?
I got a telegram
from a lady in Texas today.
You know what it said?
"Beat those commie bastards."
Wow.
We're playing against
the greatest team in the world,
maybe the best
that's ever played this game.
Why can't we just
leave it at that?
Because this is more than a
hockey game to a lot of people.
Yeah, I keep running
through them all.
Johnson on Mikhailov.
Broten on Petrov.
Pav against whoever-ov.
We just...
We don't match up, Patti.
You might want to skip that when
you talk to the boys tomorrow.
Herb.
There's no disgrace
in losing to this team.
I know.
The important thing is
you got this far.
The important thing is those
20 boys knowing in 20 years,
they didn't leave anything
on the table.
That they played
their hearts out.
That's the important thing.
Hey, craig.
Walter.
Great, great job.
-Great.
-Thanks. Sure is.
-Sure is.
-Hey, craig.
Any chance we can
wish the boys luck?
Oh, I'm sorry, Bob.
You know Herb.
Not a good time right now.
After the game, all right?
All right?
-Hey, craig, whoa, hold up.
-I can't.
Herb doesn't want
any distractions.
It's understandable.
We just wanted
to wish them luck.
Okay, that's...
You ready to go?
You serious?
Am I playing?
Suit up.
Great moments
are born from great opportunity.
And that's what you have here
tonight, boys.
That's what you've earned
here tonight.
One game.
If we played them ten times,
they might win nine.
But not this game.
Not tonight.
Tonight we skate with them.
Tonight we stay with them.
And we shut them down
because we can.
Tonight we are the greatest
hockey team in the world.
You were born to be
hockey players.
Every one of you.
And you were meant
to be here tonight.
This is your time.
Their time is done.
It's over.
I'm sick and tired of hearing
about what a great hockey team
the Soviets have.
Screw them.
This is your time.
Now, go out there and take it.
Hold up here a second, guys.
We're just gonna wait
for the okay.
Yeah.
We're all set.
All right.
Go ahead and send them in.
-It's time.
-Let's go.
come on, Jimmy, Buzzy.
Let's hustle.
[ crowd shouting ]
Here we go.
come on, Bakes.
come on, Brots, Dave.
Let's go, Strobel.
cROWD:
[ chanting ] USA!
-Rizzo!
-Let's go.
MlcHAELS: The excitement,
the tension building.
The Olympic center
filling to capacity.
The face value of a top ticket
for tonight's game, $67.20.
Outside they were
exchanging hands
at three times the face value.
USA!
Hello again, everybody.
I'm Al Michaels
along with Ken Dryden.
It should be a great night.
I'm sure there are
a lot of people
who do not know the difference
between a blue line
and a clothesline.
It's irrelevant.
It doesn't matter.
Because what we have at hand,
the rarest of sporting events.
An event that needs no buildup,
no superfluous adjectives.
In a political
or nationalistic sense,
this game is being viewed
with varying perspectives.
But manifestly
it is a hockey game.
The United States
and the Soviet Union
on a sheet of ice
in Lake Placid, New York.
Ken, some of your thoughts
before the game.
Well, for the U.S. team,
it's really discovery time.
It's one thing
to be young and promising.
And it's quite another
to be good.
And in the next 2 1/2 hours,
the U.S. players will go through
perhaps the most difficult
and demanding
yet exhilarating time
of their lives.
They will be playing against
the best team in the world,
a team that's far better
than they are,
a team that's dominated
world hockey
for the last 15 years.
In the crowd, Jim craig's
father, Donald craig.
It's been a difficult time
for the craig family
with the passing of Jimmy's mom.
One of her dreams was to have
her son play on this team.
So this has to be an emotional
night for the two of them.
They don't look too nervous
down there.
The U.S. team very young.
Average age, 21 years old.
The Soviets much more seasoned.
Some of them have been playing
together for the last 15 years.
Let's go, here, boys.
And this game is about to
get underway.
All right.
On three, boys.
One, two, three!
TOGETHER:
USA!
MlcHAELS: Jim craig in goal
for the United States.
Vladislav Tretiak, considered
the best goalie in the world,
in the nets
for the Soviet Union.
The U.S. team in white,
skating up to center ice.
The Soviet Union in red,
all business.
And here we go.
Face-off is won by Mikhailov.
Back to Kasatonov.
Move on him!
carried up ice by Kasatonov.
The pass is to Petrov.
Puck picked up by Morrow.
Pressured by Mikhailov.
The pass in front
of the U.S. net.
-And a shot deflected by craig.
-Watch the middle!
come on, Jimmy.
Keep it out of the middle, boys!
Jim craig tested
for the first time.
Dave Silk with the puck
along the boards.
Taken away by Kasatonov.
Up ahead to Petrov.
Petrov streaking up the boards.
Powering past Ramsey.
A centering pass to Kharlamov.
He shoots.
Saved by Jim craig!
Puck cleared
out of the U.S. zone.
Big hit on Mcclanahan
by the Soviet captain,
Boris Mikhailov.
Krutov with a hard shot
from the high slot.
craig with the save!
Golikov across to Petrov.
Again craig is equal
to the task.
come on, boys.
Use those boards!
Screen! Screen! Screen!
Pass is across to Kharlamov.
Shot. Stopped!
-Petrov tries to lead now.
-Watch point!
To Makarov at the point.
He fires it along the boards.
Picked up behind the net
by Buzz Schneider.
-come on!
-That's a slash!
Schneider losing it.
Out to the point.
Slap shot!
Deflected in!
That was a slash!
The Soviet Union takes
a 1-0 lead.
Kasatonov's slap shot
was deflected in past craig.
So the Soviet Union leads, 1-0,
early in the first period.
Forget about it now.
come on. Let's go.
Let's go.
Mikhailov and christoff
facing off at center ice.
Here we go, boys.
Move it!
-Kharlamov to Mikhailov.
-Pick it up!
Mikhailov up the boards
and into the corner.
To Kharlamov for a quick shot.
Big save by Jim craig.
Makarov with the puck now.
craig gets his stick on it.
Hey, Jimmy!
The U.S. in possession now.
Ramsey moving it up to Johnson.
Johnson is hung up
by Bilyaletdinov,
who feeds it around the boards,
where it's picked up by Krutov.
Golikov crossing the blue line.
He's hit hard by Ken Morrow!
The puck is picked up
by Eruzione.
And he's sent hard
into the boards by Krutov.
Johnson with it now.
Flying up the boards.
You got time.
-O.c., go!
-Avoids the hit from Golikov.
O.c., get in there!
The Soviets control it.
Kasatonov.
Let's see the "D"!
Krutov with the puck now.
A big hit by Jack O'callahan.
Pavelich up ahead to Schneider.
Slap shot.
Whoo!
Yeah!
That's the type of goal
you don't expect someone
like Tretiak to give up.
The United States ties
the game at one.
Jack O'callahan returning
after a serious knee injury
at Madison Square Garden,
making a big contribution
with that hit on Krutov.
WOMAN ON P.A.:
Number 16, Pavelich.
Time, 14:03.
MlcHAELS:
Petrov to Kharlamov.
Skating into the U.S. zone.
Tying up O'callahan.
Golikov.
cross-ice pass to Petrov.
He shoots.
And craig is right there!
Picked up by O'callahan.
Moves up to Pavelich.
Through the middle.
crossing the Soviet blue line.
centering pass.
cleared by Fetisov.
Talk to each other out there.
Play your position!
Krutov with the puck.
Through the neutral zone.
Knifes through the defense.
Right in front.
Picked up by Mark Johnson.
Nice move to get around
Bilyaletdinov
as he moves up the ice.
Another great move around
Makarov, charging for the net.
Hit by Golikov
and sent flying into the boards.
The Soviets now working
out of their own zone.
come on, now.
Pick him up.
Don't let him
through the middle.
Golikov crossing center ice.
Leaves it for Makarov.
Makarov around Morrow.
And he scores.
-[ crowd booing ]
-Oh!
Makarov put the puck
right between Morrow's legs,
skated in, and scored.
DRYDEN: That was a textbook
Soviet passing play.
Beautifully done.
Once this team gets rolling,
it's almost impossible
to stop them.
24 gets the goal.
Give 25 the assist, boys.
MlcHAELS: And with
the Soviets leading, 2-1, Ken,
the U.S. teams knows that
all too well
after what happened
with these two teams
at Madison Square Garden
13 days ago.
cROWD:
[ chanting ] USA!
Now tonight's referee,
carl Keisler,
calling the players over
for the face-off.
And you can hear the crowd
trying to reinvigorate
this U.S. team.
Face-off won by the Soviets.
Fetisov across to Kasatonov.
He circles behind his own net.
Leaves it for Fetisov.
Get the pressure on them
in there! come on!
-Pick him up!
-Watch the pass!
To Maltsev.
Over to Makarov.
Shot stopped by craig.
Don't let them have
that middle so easy.
Less than a half minute
remaining in the first period.
And the U.S. can't clear it.
Petrov with the puck.
Quick pass to Kharlamov.
Stopped by craig!
Petrov tries for the rebound.
craig knocks it away.
Kasatonov with a shot.
-craig with another save!
-Keep going hard!
Play it out!
And the U.S. team
finally clears it.
DRYDEN: It looks like the U.S.
will be able to end the period
only a goal down,
a tremendous achievement.
Johnson, go!
MlcHAELS:
The puck is picked up
by christian
in the neutral zone.
Long shot.
Easy save by Tretiak.
But Johnson is there.
And scores!
With one second to play
in the period!
Right now the clock
shows nothing.
It was stopped at one
when we looked up
and the goal was scored.
Right now it shows nothing
as the period, apparently,
has come to an end.
But the United States
has tied the game.
DRYDEN: A big, big goal
for the U.S. team.
Dave christian took a shot from
the other side of center ice,
knowing there was
almost no time on the clock.
But the rebound comes right out
to Mark Johnson,
who goes wide of Tretiak
to tie it up.
[ Shouting in Russian ]
MlcHAELS: Tikhonov very upset.
Questioning the goal.
The time on the clock
shows zero.
Keisler, the referee,
indicating that the goal stands
and the period is over.
And this crowd is electrified.
-Whoo!
Tikhonov, like his team,
not normally prone
to showing much emotion.
[ Shouting in Russian ]
As the teams skate off to their
respective dressing rooms,
this game is tied at 2 on
an incredible last-second goal
by Mark Johnson.
& Coke adds life &
Wow!
Thanks, Mean Joe.
& Smile &
[ Man speaking Russian ]
MlcHAELS: And we're back for
the start of the second period
for what is turning out to be
a very exciting game.
If you're just joining us,
there were four goals scored
in the first period.
Two by the Soviets.
Two by the Americans.
There'll be a change
for the Soviet Union,
as Vladimir Myshkin becomes
the new goalie
after Tretiak had given up
two goals in the first period.
DRYDEN:
Al, this is a big move.
Tretiak's been Tikhonov's
bread and butter for a decade.
Still, Myshkin is
a very capable backup.
Well, boys, you just put
the best goaltender in the world
on the bench.
MlcHAELS: It is very uncommon to
see Vladislav Tretiak taken out
and something we have not seen
in these Olympics.
Let's go, now, boys.
come on!
And here we go.
The second period is underway.
The conehead line
out for the United States.
Jim craig in goal.
Krutov with the puck.
Down the right side.
centering pass.
Shot.
Swatted away by craig.
Attaboy, Jimmy!
Harrington breaks out.
He gets behind the defense!
-He has a breakaway!
-come on. Block!
He can give the U.S. the lead.
He shoots.
Stopped by Myshkin.
Fetisov up to Maltsev.
Maltsev gets past christian.
Shoots.
The rebound!
Maltsev scores!
And the Soviets take the lead,
3-2.
[ crowd booing ]
DRYDEN: Jim craig knocked down
on the play by Kharlamov,
allowing Maltsev an easy goal
on an open net.
MlcHAELS: And Jim craig's
not getting up, Ken.
DRYDEN: This could be
devastating to the U.S., Al.
Jim craig's been the anchor
of this team,
playing every minute of
every game here in Lake Placid.
MlcHAELS: Herb Brooks may now
be faced with replacing craig
with his backup goalie,
Steve Janaszak.
Janaszak played on Brooks'
championship team
Iast year at the University
of Minnesota.
But he's played very little
over the last six months
and not at all
during these Olympics.
Jimmy, you need Doc?
No. I'm good.
Just give me a second.
[ crowd cheering ]
Take your time.
MlcHAELS:
Jim craig back on his feet now.
Shaking it off, and it appears
he'll remain in this game.
Attaboy, Jimmy!
Getting a huge hand from
this very appreciative crowd.
come on, boys.
Let's get them, now!
The Soviet Union, 3,
the United States, 2.
We're back for the start
of the third period.
20 minutes left in a game
that's closer
than most anyone anticipated.
The teams were tied, 2-2,
after the first.
And the Soviets are now
leading, 3-2.
Al Michaels here
at the Olympic center
with former Montreal canadiens
goalie Ken Dryden.
The American team comes into
this medal round unbeaten.
The Soviets are also unbeaten,
winning all five of their games,
scoring 51 goals in the process.
The U.S., four wins
and a tie against Sweden
and a huge upset win over
czechoslovakia eight days ago.
Herb Brooks' young team
is trying to overcome
enormous odds to beat the
best team in the world tonight.
cROWD: [ chanting ]
USA! USA! USA!
Boys!
come here!
Bring it in.
Listen to them.
USA! USA! USA!
That's what you've done.
We've come from behind
in every game
in this tournament so far,
and we can do it again.
We can beat these guys!
come on, Herb.
Get your guys to the face-off.
Everybody in.
-Let's go.
-come on, boys.
Let's do this.
Who do you play for?
TOGETHER:
USA!
come on, boys!
MlcHAELS: As the third period
begins, the crowd is chanting.
Everyone on their feet.
The Americans are winless
against the Soviets since 1960.
And since that day
at Squaw Valley,
it's been 20 years since a U.S.
team has defeated the Soviets.
The Soviets, of course,
have been gold-medal winners
in every Olympic Games
since 1960.
The top Soviet line
is out there right now.
Mikhailov at center.
He's flanked by Petrov
and Kharlamov.
On defense,
Kasatonov and Fetisov.
And in net, Vladimir Myshkin...
Face-off won by Johnson.
Ramsey with the puck.
Up to Johnson.
Johnson.
Wrist shot.
-Pick him up!
-Stopped by Myshkin.
Puck is picked up by Kasatonov.
To Mikhailov.
Over to Kharlamov, who carries
it into the U.S. zone.
Shot.
Stick save by Jim craig.
Picked up in the corner
by Krutov.
centering pass. Shot.
Saved by craig.
Back to the point man
for Kasatonov.
Slap shot.
Stopped.
-And again.
-Thataboy, Jimmy!
We're on, baby!
We're on!
christian with the puck now.
And he goes down!
And we've got a penalty
coming up on the Soviets.
Petrov going off for slashing.
coneheads! Let's go!
coneheads!
DRYDEN: This is
a big opportunity for the U.S.
They haven't been able to go
on the offense
for quite some time now,
and this is the chance.
WOMAN ON P.A.: Soviet Union
penalty to number 16.
come on, boys. Let's take
advantage of this now!
MlcHAELS:
O'callahan moving it up.
Slips by Kharlamov.
Set it up, boys!
Set it up!
A long pass from Harrington.
Harrington inside
the Soviet blue line.
Back to O'callahan.
Back to Harrington now.
To Ramsey at the point.
Over to Schneider.
Shot.
Stopped by Myshkin!
Bilyaletdinov clears the zone.
Keep it going, now, boys.
Keep up the intensity!
-Silk! Silk!
-Across to Mcclanahan.
Back across to Silk.
Shot deflected by Myshkin.
The Soviets clear the puck
around the boards.
Let's go, boys!
come on, now!
16 seconds!
16 seconds left!
The U.S. team with one more
chance on this power play.
Last rush!
come on, Silky!
Dave Silk crossing.
Silky! Silky!
I'm with you!
He's checked.
Loose puck.
Picked up by Johnson.
He scores!
Mark Johnson, with only four
seconds left on the power play,
ties the game at 3.
Only a goal!
WOMAN ON P.A.: USA goal
scored by number 10, Johnson.
Assist, number 8, Silk.
Time, 4:43.
MlcHAELS:
Ken, a couple months ago,
did you think this was
remotely possible?
DRYDEN:
No. Absolutely not.
But the thing with the U.S. team
is they're very young,
very talented.
And now they're beginning
to believe.
There's my boy!
Way to work!
Score to tie the game.
3-3, the United States
and the Soviet Union.
Face-off controlled
by the Soviets.
Kharlamov on the attack.
Down into the corner.
Drop pass.
Kasatonov with a shot!
Wide.
And the Americans with the puck.
clear it.
Maltsev streaks across
the U.S. blue line.
Over to Makarov.
craig with the save!
Kasatonov from the point.
-Thataway, Jimmy!
-craig again!
Thataway, Jimmy!
Keep them wide!
come on, Buzzy!
-Harrington up to Schneider.
-Rizzo, go!
Schneider gets rid of it
and heads to the bench.
All right, Buzzy.
Bilyaletdinov picks up the puck
in the corner.
checked by Harrington.
Pav!
-Rizzo! Rizzo!
-Pavelich has it now.
Over to Eruzione.
He shoots.
He scores!
Mike Eruzione!
Whoo! Whoo!
Right now we've got bedlam!
DRYDEN: Anyone who was at
Madison Square Garden
two weeks ago who's
watching this game tonight
has got to be shocked.
MlcHAELS:
Oh, I love Brooks' reaction.
Thataway, Rizzo!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
cROWD: [ chanting ]
USA! USA! USA!
MlcHAELS:
And the chant resumes.
Mike Eruzione
out of Boston University,
the captain of this U.S. team,
has just put the U.S. ahead
for the first time
exactly halfway through
the third period.
WOMAN ON P.A.: USA goal scored
by number 21, Eruzione.
DRYDEN: This U.S. team was
demoralized by the Soviets.
Very tentative.
Very nervous.
Very much in awe
of the Soviet team.
And this is a U.S. team
that is not in awe of anyone.
Keep it going, now, boys!
Whoo!
come on, boys.
Here we go.
MlcHAELS:
10 minutes left to play.
The face-off to Petrov.
To Kharlamov.
Krutov crossing
the U.S. blue line now.
Quick pass back to Maltsev.
Shot. Save.
-Now ice it!
-Get it out of there!
Kasatonov at the point.
A drive.
Just wide of the net.
Krutov with the puck.
Right in front.
And another huge save
by Jim craig!
-Play your game!
-Johnson looking to Mcclanahan.
-It's intercepted by Kharlamov.
Take him wide!
Kharlamov leading the charge
up the ice.
He fires a shot.
Glove save! Jim craig!
Keep it moving.
Wristed from Petrov.
craig again with the stop.
Kharlamov back to Kasatonov
at the point.
He shoots.
Stick save.
Attaboy, Jimmy!
Rebound out to Mcclanahan.
can't clear it.
Great play!
Mcclanahan dives
to clear the zone.
7:10 remaining
in the third period.
We're gonna go with
short shifts, boys.
30 to 40 seconds.
Short shifts.
Keep an eye on it, Doc.
Kharlamov with a long pass
to Mikhailov.
Over the blue line.
To Petrov right in front.
Shot.
Sliding save by craig.
Switch them up! Let's go!
Go! Go!
Petrov over to Maltsev.
Off to Kasatonov at the point.
He sends it around the boards.
Picked up by Fetisov.
Hit hard by Silk.
Get it out!
Picked up and cleared by Morrow.
And the Soviets retreat back.
Keep it going, now!
Five minutes to play
in the third period.
Kasatonov leaves it
for Mikhailov.
Mikhailov moves it over
to Kharlamov.
Slap shot!
Knocked away by craig!
Get men out!
Ramsey moves it ahead
to Pavelich.
Get ready!
And he's run into
the boards by Bilyaletdinov.
change them up!
Let's go!
-Go off! Get off the ice!
-lntercepted by Kharlamov.
He moves it up to Krutov.
Krutov with the puck.
Through the neutral zone.
Moving in on the net.
That's stopped by craig.
Thataboy, Jimmy!
Play your game, boys!
Loose puck in the corner.
Krutov chasing it.
Schneider right behind him.
Fighting for it.
Off the board!
Bring it off the board!
chip it out!
Thataboy!
3:19 left to play.
O'callahan moving out.
-How are we doing, Doc?
-32!
change them up!
-Let's go!
-Golikov moving it up.
Leaves it for Makarov.
Get him off!
Saved by craig.
[ Speaking Russian ]
Poise and control.
Mcclanahan scrapping for it.
And Mikhailov in there.
Hard hit by Mike Ramsey!
2:1 7 remaining.
Okay, no more changes
until the next whistle.
No more changes
come on, Jimmy!
Loose puck in the corner.
When they pull Myshkin,
I want fresh legs. O.c.
Yeah, yeah.
Kharlamov to Mikhailov.
Ramsey diving.
Stand him up!
Mikhailov over the blue line.
Across to Petrov.
Shot.
-come on, Jimmy!
-Save!
DRYDEN:
I'm really amazed
how well-conditioned
this U.S. team is.
I've never seen the Soviets
outskated this late in the game.
And that's exactly what the
U.S. team is doing right now.
MlcHAELS:
Golikov across to Petrov.
Shot.
Kicked away by craig!
-Way to go, Jimmy!
-Over to Maltsev.
Moving in on the net.
Hand stop by craig!
chip it out!
come on! chip it out!
That's it!
[ Shouting in Russian ]
They're not pulling Myshkin!
Kharlamov at center ice.
To Krutov.
He doesn't know what to do.
36 seconds left to play.
Makarov over the blue line.
To Maltsev.
Fires.
Another save.
Fighting for possession.
Morrow trying to get it away
from Kharlamov along the boards.
come on.
Whoo!
Again, coming to you
from the Olympic ice arena.
come on, baby!
The U.S., huge underdogs,
leading the Soviet Union.
Johnson over to Ramsey.
Bilyaletdinov gets checked
by Ramsey.
Mcclanahan is there.
The puck is still loose.
1 1 seconds.
You got 10 seconds.
The countdown going on
right now.
Morrow up to Silk.
Five seconds left in the game.
Do you believe in miracles?
Yes!
Whoo!
Yeah!
USA!
Beautiful! Beautiful!
Yes!
cROWD: [ chanting ]
USA! USA! USA!
Way to go, coach!
Yes!
Whoo!
HERB: Two days later,
the miracle was made complete,
My boys defeated Finland
to win the gold medal,
coming from behind once again,
As I watched them out there,
celebrating on the ice,
I realized
that Patti had been right,
It was a lot more
than a hockey game,
Not only for those
who watched it,
but for those who played in it,
I've often been asked
in the years since Lake Placid
what was the best moment
for me,
Well, it was here,
The sight of 20 young men
of such differing backgrounds
now standing as one,
Young men willing to sacrifice
so much of themselves
all for an unknown,
A few years later,
the U,S, began using
professional athletes
at the games,
Dream teams,
I always found that term ironic
because now that we have
dream teams,
we seldom ever get to dream,
But on one weekend, as America
and the world watched,
a group of remarkable young men
gave the nation
what it needed most,
A chance, for one night,
not only to dream,
But a chance, once again,
to believe,
& Every time that I look
in the mirror &
& All these lines on my face
getting clearer &
& The past is gone &
& It went by
like dusk to dawn &
& Isn't that the way? &
& Everybody's got their dues
in life to pay &
& Yeah &
& I know nobody knows &
& Where it comes
and where it goes &
& I know it's everybody's sin &
& You got to lose
to know how to win &
& Half my life's in books'
written pages &
& Live and learn from fools
and from sages &
& You know it's true &
& All the things come back
to you &
& Sing with me &
& Sing for the year &
& Sing for the laughter
and sing for the tear &
& Sing with me
if it's just for today &
& Maybe tomorrow the good Lord
will take you away &
& Yeah, sing with me &
& Sing for the year &
& Sing for the laughter
and sing for the tear &
& Sing with me
if it's just for today &
& Maybe tomorrow the good Lord
will take you away &
& Dream on &
& Dream yourself
a dream come true &
& Dream on &
& Dream until your dream
come true &
& Dream on &
& On &
& Sing with me &
& Sing for the year &
& Sing for the laughter
and sing for the tear &
& Sing with me
if it's just for today &
& Maybe tomorrow the good Lord
will take you away &
& Sing with me &
& Sing for the year &
& Sing for the laughter
and sing for the tear &
& Sing with me
if it's just for today &
& Maybe tomorrow the good Lord
will take you away &
And I know you'll do a good job.
And see you guys later, okay?
[ Applause ]