(Episode 17, Destiny Changes)
We almost got wet.
It's coming. The wave's coming.
It is?
- Go in. - Wait.
- Go in. - Wait. Don't push.
Are you okay?
Forget this.
- What? - Come.
- No. - Come here.
No. No!
Let's just stay here.
I'll be right back.
No. Don't go.
Stay right here. Okay?
Black Korando, license plate number 56T3275.
He just went on road 125.
Make a U-turn.
The mistake made by the deity...
changed the destinies...
of all humans.
If the banker Song Hyun Chul...
had died as predestined,
and the other Song Hyun Chul...
didn't enter his body and bring him back to life,
the crime wouldn't have been discovered,
but it has now.
And that was...
just the beginning.
That jerk.
Get closer. Closer!
Song Hyun Chul!
Hye Jin.
She was pretty.
How could he fire her on her first day here?
What are you talking about?
Ms. Yang. The branch vice manager.
Mr. Song kicked her out just because...
she was sent here through nepotism.
That's up to HR.
He's out of control. He doesn't care.
He's so self-centered.
You're only sad because Ms. Yang was pretty.
Naturally.
Why else would I be sad?
We don't need the help. You can do all the work.
You and your wife get along well.
You talk on the phone every day.
Do you still get happy when you see pretty women?
How is one related to the other?
They aren't related at all.
- This is delicious. - This is why...
I can't get married.
- I can't trust men. - That's right.
Like women can be trusted? They're the same.
I noticed from before,
but you have an odd complex toward women.
You were dumped badly, weren't you?
What do you mean?
You're not my type. That's why I'm not nice to you.
I have a very positive attitude toward women.
He may be a bit dumb, but he has a sharp tongue.
I get hurt sometimes too.
I am nice only to people that I really like.
What are you doing?
Thank you for lunch.
Why are you being so gross?
Sleep in your room.
No. I'm going to sleep with you tonight.
- Mom. - Yes?
I'm going to be your daughter...
in my next life too.
I guess I am a pretty good mom.
That's not it.
Go to sleep.
- Mom. - Yes?
Is there anything you regret...
when you think about Dad?
That day.
That day?
The day he ran out of the kitchen...
to go to FSS to find out...
what happened with that loan.
For not stopping him.
If I had stopped him then,
he wouldn't have gotten into that accident,
and this never would've happened either.
I regret that day the most.
Smile.
1, 2, 3.
Would you take one more please?
- One more? - Yes.
1, 2, 3.
- Enjoy. - Thank you.
You don't use ketchup on sushi?
Are you teasing me?
You got me.
Let's go on trips often from now on.
Think about where you want to go next.
- I know already. - Where?
- Chuncheon. - Chuncheon?
Yes.
I went to there alone on our 10-year anniversary.
I forgot Nami Island, so I wanted to go back.
Let's go then.
We can go for our anniversary this year...
I'm fine.
You told me not to think about it rationally.
Let's just...
accept what's in front of us.
Okay?
Eat up.
You really don't need ketchup?
I'm off to school.
Okay.
Have a nice day at school.
Don't fall asleep, and study hard.
Okay.
Father. Aren't you going to dance school anymore?
- Yun Hwa. - Yes?
Well,
I don't know how to face you.
After I sent my son off like that, I wonder...
if it's okay for me to live here with you...
shamelessly like this.
So what?
You want to live there?
Father.
You may be Hyun Chul's father,
but you're also Ji Soo's grandpa.
It's just that Ji Soo's dad is gone...
from the relationship that he, Ji Soo,
you, and I created.
Don't think that way.
You and I...
have our own past that we've shared too.
Let's cling onto that.
Happily and for a long time.
Hearing you say that...
makes me feel sorrier and more grateful.
He has to call someone "Mother"...
although she didn't give birth to him.
That's how...
our fates are right now.
Let's be cool about this.
They were happy.
No one knew what fate awaited them.
Neither the deities...
nor they knew...
what would happen.
He's here.
- Woo Jang Choon. - Woo Jang Choon.
With the death of the banker Song Hyun Chul,
the truth that would've been buried...
came to light.
The deity's mistake...
ended up being fortuitous.
However...
Hey. Are you dating that phone?
You've been staring at it like crazy.
Whose call are you waiting for?
- Nobody. - That's right.
The forum members are meeting this weekend.
You'll all go, right?
- I can't. - To study again?
You traitor.
I have plans with my dad.
We're going to a bath house.
Someone...
had to be the sacrifice and face...
the sadness resulting from that mistake.
You'll be so pretty once the swelling goes down.
This is a new royal class combination insurance.
It covers not only illnesses and injuries,
but if you want a nose job...
I already got one.
If you want to fix your entire face...
I did.
Anyway, whatever you get done,
we guarantee 50 percent of hospital costs.
You should get some work done.
Look.
You're super ugly, okay?
Seriously. There will be no end with you!
You're hopeless.
I'm speechless.
What's her problem?
Get a refund! It's a major fail!
You can get insurance for your child's salary.
You obviously don't worry about your future,
but you never know about your children.
This policy looks nice.
How old are your children?
My son...
is 50.
- Pardon? - And my husband is 83.
In a few years...
That's right. My son will get pension soon.
I... I see...
That's how it is.
I thought I had to return her husband to her.
The banker Song Hyun Chul...
died as he was destined,
and the one who came back to life...
only borrowed his body.
Since the soul inside was her husband.
So I thought it was only natural...
for him to return to her.
I told you to come only if I called.
You seriously don't listen.
Hey.
Will you be okay without me?
Why? Are you going somewhere?
I think I'll have to.
Where to?
Somewhere far away.
Do you have a passport? You don't even have an ID.
Hey.
What's your wish?
Why are you asking? It's not like you'll grant it.
I'll grant you your wish before I go.
Tell me anything you want.
What are you, really?
Are you a magician?
Tell me your wish. I'll grant it.
Insurance Queen. Okay?
Take care of yourself, okay?
You take care of yourself.
Sorry.
However, her husband...
was no longer the same Song Hyun Chul.
Of course,
he wasn't the banker Song Hyun Chul either.
He...
was a brand new person entirely...
ever since the memories...
within the banker's brain started to surface.
Because memories...
aren't simple records of time,
but accompany the emotions of each moment.
That...
was a shocking result...
that we couldn't predict.
It's so dramatic.
One Song Hyun Chul helped solve the case...
for another Song Hyun Chul.
If Manhojang's Song Hyun Chul...
hadn't gone to your bank...
to request a loan,
this crime would never have been uncovered.
You're probably right.
(CCTV footage of reporter planting a bug.)
You must be relieved.
Your case is closed.
Then let's control the traffic properly now.
But you know,
something still nags at me.
What nags at you now?
The banker Song Hyun Chul...
and Manhojang's Song Hyun Chul.
The relationship between them.
I really don't get it.
They got into accidents at the same time...
Hey, hey, hey. Where are you going?
It's true.
He woke up during his funeral.
The entire hospital was in panic mode.
How could that...
It's incredible enough...
that he woke up during the funeral,
but his state...
He was totally fine.
You would never guess that he had died.
I'll cooperate.
I will uncover the truth.
Why did you give someone with bad credit a loan?
He's a veteran,
so I lowered his interest rate too.
The savings bank...
is flipping out about the law on loans.
The restrictions are too burdensome for us.
Then we should adjust our rates...
to counter the effect. Prepare a proposal.
Okay, I'll get to it right away.
Mr. Ha. Did you send the performance report?
I'm about to.
Send it right away. It should be processed.
Hello.
Hi. What brings you here?
The case is going well thanks to you.
I wanted to stop by to thank you.
I heard you went in to testify.
I did.
I remember...
the first time I met you in this office.
You were upset about the late Song Hyun Chul...
as if it happened to you.
And you eventually resolved it for me.
You did a great job as well.
But...
there's something I still haven't figured out.
What is your relationship...
with the late Song Hyun Chul?
Why did you say you were friends...
when you weren't?
You have the same name,
and the same date of birth.
When he first came here to get a loan,
he found out he had a loan that he never took out.
That's why...
you began investigating.
Yes, that's correct.
Mr. Song Hyun Chul.
What is your relationship...
with Manhojang's Song Hyun Chul?
Ji Soo?
Don't you know me?
You're a detective.
That's right.
But why are you here?
I came to see my dad.
Your dad?
Yes.
Dad?
Yes?
Ji Soo. What brings you here?
Come in.
Can't you use this?
It was your phone.
I just wish there was at least one thing...
that would stay the same about you.
Ji Soo.
I can't...
go back to how things were.
Now, I...
am not a cook who uses a wok.
I'm a banker.
Yes, I'm definitely Song Ji Soo's dad.
But...
I can't go back...
to how things were as you want.
I shouldn't either.
You're so mean.
Ji Soo.
Stop denying it.
Kwak Hyo Joo told us everything.
The 1.3 million dollars you deposited...
into Park Min Joo's account was for her.
I never did such thing.
He's lying.
The depositor, Henry Smith,
is Woo Jang Choon.
He has 9 million dollars in his account.
Woo Jang Choon.
We have a certified bank statement too.
You're hurting yourself by denying it.
Well,
do you have proof that Henry Smith...
is me?
Kwak Hyo Joo is lying.
Look. What are you trying to pull?
Are you kidding me?
Hello, Jaeil Insurance. Jo Yun Hwa speaking.
I'd like to discuss getting a policy.
Yes.
Okay. I'll go see you there.
Okay, thank you.
Hello, Jaeil Insurance. Jo Yun Hwa speaking.
Yes.
Yun Hwa. I'm sorry.
Take care, okay?
I gave Yun Hwa and Hyun Chul...
small miracles before I left.
That was the only thing...
I could do for them.
Thank you.
- What's her secret? - She's impressive.
How did she do it?
(Jo Yun Hwa)
(This month's performance)
Thank you.
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
- Thanks. - Congratulations.
- Thank you. - Applause.
Who's telling the truth?
Woo Jang Choon claims he never sent her the money.
And Hyo Joo says he's lying.
Neither of them will budge.
Then where is the 9 million dollars?
Where did you move the 9 million dollars...
from Henry Smith's account?
The balance is zero. Zero.
What's going on? What's wrong with this?
Where's my money?
My money!
- Why? What is it? - What's wrong?
- What is it? - What's going on?
Why is this in here?
Yes, of course. I will manage your assets.
You can trust me.
You should take care of your health too.
I'll see you on the course this weekend.
Okay.
Yes?
- Of course, - Mr. Lee.
not all miracles came from me.
Mr. Song. We did it.
We received an investment of 8 million dollars.
Congratulations.
I'm so happy for you.
It's all thanks to you.
If you hadn't given us the loan back then,
we would've gone bankrupt for sure.
I just paid off the loan,
and stopped by to thank you.
I'm so glad.
I wish you success with your business.
And please keep working with Shinhwa Bank.
Thank you from the bottom of my heart.
Not at all. Congratulations.
There were also beautiful miracles...
that the humans created.
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
(Little Brother)
The number you have dialed...
is not in service.
What's going on?
Why don't you move?
There are too many steps here.
Your joints aren't good either.
It must be difficult to get around.
You should move into an apartment.
If it's because of me, don't worry about it.
There's Ji Soo's high school matter too.
So I've looked into a place for you.
Hyun Chul, it's okay.
- Do as I say. - No.
We'll take care of ourselves.
I may be in the situation that I am,
but Father, you, and Ji Soo are all my family.
If it gets top difficult, I'll tell you.
Help us then.
Let's move into an apartment.
You're trying to move into Kang Ho's, aren't you?
Ji Soo.
He wants to do his part.
He's trying to do it at least with money.
Let's ease his guilt.
That's why you let him go. Why are you doing this?
If we don't accept it,
he'll feel guilty.
Let's move.
There's no one to water the yard anymore anyway.
All of Jungin Grade School's teachers...
will have their paychecks deposited into our bank.
Get Jungin Junior High and High School too.
Yes, sir.
The company that you mentioned before, Youngho,
did in fact lie about the number of employees,
so we denied their loan.
An owner like that...
probably got his patents dishonestly too.
Cut all business with them.
Yes, sir.
Thanks to your efforts, our branch...
became the top branch nationwide.
Are you happy?
It's too soon to be happy.
Now, we are our own competition,
not other branches.
Aim to increase your numbers by 20 percent,
and hit the ground running.
If not, you will fall and die.
That will be all.
But still, go out for a celebration first.
Thank you.
We still get to go out though.
Okay.
Where should we go?
Is my dad...
living with you guys now?
No. Isn't he living with your family?
You're not lying, are you?
Why would I lie about that?
Ji Soo.
To be honest, my dad...
He's my dad.
The body is my dad and the soul is your dad.
Strictly put, he's more of my dad.
That's not right.
What if I'm in your body?
That would be me, not you.
It would be me.
- The body matters. - The mind matters.
The body is just a shell.
Where would you keep your mind without a shell?
- What? - Without my dad's body,
where could your dad have gone in?
He could've gone into another body.
Then he'd be that person, not your dad.
Just because his soul is your dad,
you can't insist that he's your dad.
Hey. Say you asked for a bowl of rice.
Are you asking for the rice or the bowl?
What matters? The rice or the bowl?
People aren't rice.
Answer the question, you idiot.
You're impossible to talk to.
You're so ignorant.
Let's go.
What? Ignorant?
Why you...
- That doesn't scare me. - You...
- Hey! Hey! - Hey, stop.
I'll kill you today!
So...
you got into a fight while arguing...
about your dads?
Call your parents.
You're minors,
so we can't just let you go.
You kids can go home.
- Okay. - Okay.
Excuse me...
It's all done. You may take the kids.
Thank you.
Kang Ho. Go home first.
I'll go after I talk to Ji Soo.
Is that okay, Ji Soo?
- Enjoy. - Thank you.
Here. Eat.
- Ji Soo. - I'm sorry.
I'll make sure it never happens again.
Okay.
Whatever the reason, violence isn't the answer.
Of course,
Kang Ho probably started it.
If you end up hitting someone,
you lose your chance to explain yourself...
even if the other person was wrong.
It's hard for me to sit here...
with you.
I know.
I told...
Kang Ho...
that he isn't his dad.
I knew how it felt to lose my dead...
and how much it hurts,
but I was nasty to him.
It was hard, wasn't it?
He has a different face...
and a different voice.
My dad didn't dress that way.
I didn't believe it at first either.
But...
he made me believe it.
He came to Mom and me...
and made us all believe that he was Dad.
If he was going to do this, why did he do that?
I hate...
my dad.
It's not something I can understand,
but the adults want me to understand.
There's nothing I can do...
other than to hate him.
But Ji Soo...
I'm going home.
Sorry about today.
Where are you?
Why aren't you answering your phone?
What's going on?
Why were you at the police station?
It's nothing.
Nothing? How is it nothing?
What's the big deal?
What do you mean?
That's nothing.
And why do you keep waiting for people here?
Don't wait for me or Dad.
Don't wait for anyone here anymore.
It's annoying.
What's gotten into you lately? It's upsetting.
You weren't like this even when Dad passed away.
Why are you doing this now?
Sorry, Ji Soo.
I'm sorry about everything.
Why are you sorry? What did you do wrong?
That's how it is for moms.
Even if we didn't do anything wrong,
we feel sorry toward our kids.
The photos are crisp.
The angles and ambiance are great.
You can be the main photographer.
Do you mean it?
Then am I qualified to be an assistant?
Above and beyond.
Gosh, excuse me.
Hello? Where are you?
I'll pick up Mother and go.
Okay.
I'll head home too.
She said she wanted to eat at home.
You'll get tired.
It's okay. You can help.
You're a cook.
Anyway,
how long will you stay at the residence?
Sorry for bringing it up.
See you tonight.
Okay.
Really?
Really.
He said he saved Grandpa at the constructions site,
and you at the stairs.
I don't know what he meant,
but he said he fixed Dad's phone and helped him.
Mom. Draw his face for me.
I can't draw.
Then I'll draw. Tell me if it's him.
Yes, that's right. This is the face.
You should've told me sooner.
Call him again.
He left. I can't reach him.
Why do you think he helped us?
He asked me for a wish.
I should've told him a better wish.
Like introducing me to a hot guy.
Just eat.
I should've asked him out.
Hey. It's your father's memorial soon.
How should we do the memorial?
I'll prepare it.
I'll help.
There's so much food to prepare.
She can't do it alone.
Every now and then,
you really seem like a different person.
That's exactly my point.
Regardless, this time,
let's prepare a proper table...
and let your father feast.
I think it's thanks to your father...
that you came back to life the way you did.
Anyway, my little puppy.
I hear you're studying hard lately.
Yes. He's turned a new leaf.
That's good.
You take after your dad, so you'll come in first.
I can't come in first because of math.
That's absurd.
Your dad was a math genius.
Ask him to teach you. Okay?
I had Hyun Chul teach me math in high school,
and he was so mean.
He yelled at me and was a total pain.
Seriously.
I'll teach you. Ask me anytime.
It would've been so nice if your father were here.
Don't you miss your father?
Your father did everything for you.
Kids. Eat up.
Let's enjoy our meal. Mi Ho, eat up.
Okay.
You're so cute.
So it was a bit strange.
- I'm sorry. - Hey.
- Wait for me, kids! - Father.
Hello?
Father, where are you?
Me? I'm in Sokcho right now.
I had to come for a friend's funeral.
I see.
I'm sorry, Father.
For what? Just live a good life.
I'll be good to you.
Live a long life.
Just hang up if you called to say stupid things.
Bye.
Yes?
What brings you by?
I came to have lunch with you. Do you have time?
I'd make time if I had to. Let's go.
Mr. Song and his wife seem so happy together.
I know, right?
He's like someone else when he's with her.
They don't look like a married couple.
It's more like they're having an affair...
or a second marriage. Like it's been only one month.
Why are they so happy together all of a sudden?
You should find a religion.
The world may appear beautiful then.
That's why I don't.
What if Kang Ho was in Ji Soo's shoes?
It would've been worse.
They're going through puberty.
It's hard enough for adults like us.
Imagine how much harder it is for Ji Soo...
to accept and understand as a child.
Tomorrow,
the kids are going on a field trip.
I thought you should know.
Ji Soo.
- Hello. - Hi,
Young Joo.
You go first.
Bye.
What are you doing here?
I came to see my daughter.
You're going on a field trip tomorrow, right?
How did you know?
Kang Ho must have told you.
I'll make you gimbap tomorrow.
I always made you gimbap for your field trips.
You always said...
my gimbap is the best in the world.
I'll ask Mom.
Okay.
I'll do it if Mom says so.
Thanks.
Ji Soo.
Wear this on your trip tomorrow.
(Hyun Chul)
Hello?
Should I pick up anything?
Hold on.
My goodness.
We're out of eggs.
We have everything else, but I couldn't get eggs.
Can you pick some up?
Will do.
He hasn't changed. How annoying.
I can't wear this for a field trip.
Okay. Let's go for dinner!
Mr. Song won't be able to attend.
His child has a field trip tomorrow.
Mr. Song cares about...
children's field trips?
He is so inconsistent.
Mr. Yook.
Why don't you move into Ms. Kwak's office?
There's bad energy in there. I don't want to.
Then should I move in there?
There's a hierarchy. That's not right.
Hierarchy and order.
You must value things like that a lot.
Of course. I'm more conservative than I look.
I heard you were in another line of work.
I was a firefighter.
So that's why you're so hot inside.
Fire.
- We know your secret - We know your secret
Excuse me...
Did you shop to make Ji Soo's lunch tomorrow?
Yes.
What are you doing here?
For Ji Soo's lunch. I've always packed her lunch.
You did.
She loved...
Dad's fried shrimp in her lunchbox.
I was going to make it for her this year.
That's what I came to get too.
They have fresh seafood here.
I see. That's why I came here too.
I'll pack her lunch.
It's okay. I'm going to do it.
- Pack Kang Ho's for him. - I promised Ji Soo.
Don't do that anymore.
It's okay. It's uncomfortable for me.
- I'll drive you home. - That's okay too.
I'll drive you. The grocery's heavy.
Stay here. I'll get the car.
Okay. Then I'll wait here.
Okay.
Hey. I'll be home soon.
I heard.
I ran into him.
Take the lunch Daddy packs for you tomorrow.
That tastes better.
Okay.
Sorry.
- Call an ambulance. - Hurry up.
Hello? There's been an accident.
Please come quickly.
Don't move her.
You can't move her.
- Hello? Can you hear us? - Give her some room.
- What happened? - Do you think she's dead?
Are you okay?
- Hurry up. - Okay.
- Ji Soo. - Mom!
No. Ji Soo.
What were you doing?
I thought you were with her. What were you doing?
Why did you let her get hit by a car?
Get out. I don't need you.
Don't ever come here again.
Get out! Go!
Mom!
Ji Soo...
Is Jo Yun Hwa's family here?
- Mom. Mom! - You can't go in.
Mom!
She passed away.
Mom.
May 28, 2018. At 08:08pm,
Jo Yun Hwa passed away.
Mom. Mom!
No! Mom!
Mom!