Episode 3
"Die Fahne hoch" by Horst Wessel
[Hymn of the Nazi Party from 1930~1945]
"Marschieren im Geist in unseren Reihen mit"
March in spirit within our ranks
"Die Stra©¬e frei den braunen Bataillonen"
free the way for the brown battalions
"Die Stra©¬e frei dem Sturmabteilungsmann"
free the way for the stormtroopers
- Suam! Suam!
- Suam.
- Suam!
What have you done?
I just shot your cat,
because he killed our hen!
This is Suam.
He carried my cousin's name,
and was like family to me.
It's nothing but a damn cat!
And what are you?
You damn Asians...
Doctor Li.
I'll apologize on his behalf.
People have changed too much.
But don't let it put you down,
not everyone is taking this lying down.
This was in the mailbox.
"There is nothing as shameful as silently
enduring a regime's undignified..."
and despicable delusion
without any resistance."
""The world is like a mysterious vessel,
impossible for man to control."
"Anyone trying to control
it will destroy it all,"
"those trying to grab it
with their hands will lose it." Lao-Tse*
[*a.k.a. Laozi]
You're not involved in this, are you?
[*Confucian philosopher from
the Warring States Period]
Xun Zi* once said, knowing
is better than seeing,
and that acting is
better than knowing.
But he also said this,
that if you erect a straight tree,
you're only hoping for its shadow to bend.
Trying to act despite
knowing you will fail is foolish.
Your lives could be in danger.
Yes, it's dangerous.
But someone must do it.
Didn't you come
to Germany for the same?
- Because you were one of those people?
- But you have a family...
and responsibilities towards them.
Know what I was thinking,
when I crossed the Yalu?
Seeing my mother's
face as I was leaving,
I wished I never took part in
the resistance in the first place.
If you could go back in time,
would you have done otherwise?
See?
[*Fellow students!*]
[*Fellow students! German people
were shaken by our defeat in Stalingrad*...]
[*Battle of Stalingrad, 1.7mil dead,
and one of Germany's worst defeats]
Doctor Li.
You have a guest.
How do you do?
My name is Eva,
I'm majoring in Asian studies.
I've read all your
work, Seonsaengnim*.
[*deferential for esteemed elder/professor]
Seonsaengnim,
take me as your pupil.
You already speak my language,
what else would I teach you?
I want to learn all of Korea's
culture and customs.
I want to go and see for
myself, whether Korea is...
as beautiful as you depicted it.
Then, did you?
Are you part of the White Rose, too?
No.
I just wanted to tell people how
many men lost their lives in this war.
What you did was too dangerous.
Then, why did you help me out?
Wasn't it because you
think what we're doing is right?
Reading your works,
I felt a sense of peace about you,
so much I wanted to meet you in person.
Seonsaengnim, please
take me as your pupil.
Your calligraphy is a mess.
You will have to
learn it a little more.
This chocolate was sent from
abroad by one of Eva's friends.
Ahh... precious chocolate.
Remember how long ago
we had something like this?
Just eating something so
precious would be a waste.
Don't you think, Mirok?
Quick, quick!
Six, six!
Yes, yes... okay.
Six! Six!
Ahh... no.
Six!
Good.. good.
Ahhh... five.
Quick, quick.
Six!
Quick, do it quickly!
Six, six!
Six! Six.
One six.
That's cheating!
And why?
Hurry up and give me the chocolate.
How do you know it was really a six?
I saw it, it was a six.
It fell off, so it doesn't count.
Don't you think this is too much?
I haven't touched that chocolate once!
- Anyway, do it once again.
- This is really unfair!
This is how.... just...
the game works!
It was a nice wake up call for them.
That simple game
made them lose their smile.
But hunger, like war,
makes your forget reason and dignity.
Doctor Li....
I will soon be arrested.
The reason I ignored you last time
was not to involve you in this.
If they arrest you now,
it will mean death!
When I started this, I
knew I would have nowhere to run.
But if they arrest me, people
will learn what we're doing.
I believe many more people
will sympathize with our cause.
- Professor...
- This is how I'll show my love for this country.
But I hope you will help
Germany in other ways.
But...
But how can I...
You have the power to surprise
people, like you did earlier.
Our people have lost their sense of human
dignity because of this war.
Help Germany regain that dignity,
for itself and everyone else.
Are you bringing that
to Huber's family again?
Haven't you heard they're arresting
everyone who tries to help them?
You don't need to worry about me, Lina.
Don't worry?
How can I not?
We can survive
with just a little food,
but those good people will not
last a single day, if they lose their hope.
I know how hard it must be for you.
I feel sorry for not helping you more.
Look, Doctor Li!
Just by coming here, a place abandoned
by everyone after he was arrested,
I'm already thankful.
You must be strong.
Unless a miracle happens by next week,
my poor kids will lose their father.
Hey, you there!
What is inside this bag?
Tao Te Ching*
[Laozi's essential Taoist text,
6th Century BC]
What is this?
It's a book about
classic oriental philosophy.
And you need this why, exactly?
Aren't you trying to
diffuse disturbing ideology?
Doctor Li.
What are you doing here?
- Do you know this man?
- Yes.
He's my teacher, here to
teach me Chinese characters.
Ahh, here it is. I've been
looking for this for a while,
I didn't know you had it.
If you pardon me.
- Is this yours?
- Yes.
Read it for me, then.
"Taesang, Hajiyuji"
"The best form of authority is one
where people acknowledge their ruler"
"Gicha, Chiniyeji"
"one where the ruler loves
and is close to his people"
"Gicha Wiji, Gicha Moji"
"one where a ruler fears his people,
but also makes them despise him"
And what does this all mean?
That the best form of authority
is akin to that of our Fuhrer Adolf Hitler,
and his strong autocracy leading us all.
We're gathering texts like this
to boost loyalty for the Fuhrer and the party.
Heil Hitler.
I think this might be useful to you.
After the execution of Professor Huber,
anyone connected to him,
or even those who tried to
help him are all being arrested.
It's best just to avoid
all this while we can.
While you're here with me
in Switzerland at this congress,
this White Rose scandal will quiet down.
They disgraced the LMU,
we must get them all and kill them.
They'll learn that anyone trying
to oppose our great leader...
is nothing but a
traitor to the German Empire.
And who is this Hitler?
You don't even know
the name of our great Fuhrer?
No.
Where do you come from?
Germany.
Are you making fun
of our great Fuhrer?
Gentlemen, please.
Don't misunderstand.
This man came here from Asia
for an holiday, so he doesn't know.
Let's go.
Milady.
Don't take all this personal.
I'm just doing this for our country.
Don't you agree?
Move!
Let's go!
That morning, I received news from
my faraway hometown.
My older sister wrote that my mother
passed away, after suffering for a few days.
End
(Thomas) Mann
Buddenbrooks
Let's write that letter now, Seonsaengnim.
Piper only publishes novels
from the most illustrious writers.
Would they possibly publish something
from a nameless writer like me,
not to mention having interest
in any story from the Far East?
I'm sure they will publish it.
Come on, Seonsaengnim.
My first novel is a simple
account of the experiences...
I went through in my childhood.
It purely depicts what happened,
and attempts to represent the
human psyche of East Asian men.
It neither tries to put the
spotlight on their ideal tendencies,
nor attempts to spread
any pretentious ethical musings.
I merely wrote about
my nostalgia for things lost,
and the transience of life.
By reading this book, I wish my German friends
will be able to reminisce about...
the happy memories they made,
however brief they might be.
Japan will soon capitulate.
Your homeland will
soon be free, Doctor Li.
Milady!
It's all over!
We're finally done with it!
Done with what?
We were liberated!
Down at the village, people
gathered in the streets to celebrate,
and those Japanese fools are running
away like there was no tomorrow.
Now your husband can come back.
Is this a dream, or what?
I brought this fool to you, Milady!
You fool, how much longer
do you think you could last...
playing a pawn to those Japanese?
Milady, what should we do with him?
Let him go.
What?
Mister Li.
A letter for you.
Seonsaengnim,
hurry up and open it!
Is something wrong?
My novel is going to be published.
Ahh... my God!
I knew it!
Congratulations.
If it weren't for you...
none of this would have been possible.
Then, I have a favor.
Give me a name in Hangeul.
I want you to give
me a name, Seonsaengnim.
"Ae*"
[*Ae = Love]
Ae...
Pa*...
[*Aepa = Wave of Love]
Does this really mean
what I'm thinking?
Doctor Li.
I have wonderful news for you.
Your novel will be featured in
our German school textbooks.
From now on, all German
children will learn about your hometown.
Seonsaengnim!
[Li Bai's "Homesick on a Silent Night"]
Sang Jeon Myeong Wol Gwang
"Before my bed you shed,
O lustrous moonlight"
"Eui Shi Ji Sang Sang"
"Like frost caressing
the ground, I doubt "
"Geo Du Mang Myeong Wol"
"You capture my eyes,
moon of many feelings bright"
"Jeo Du Sa Go Hyang"
"And down I look,
my yearning gushing out"
The liberation our
country found itself in...
doesn't feel like liberation at all.
Only the South is having elections,
and, if this keeps up, I worry our
country might be divided in two.
Doctor Lee.
Before it's too late,
shouldn't you return home,
and do whatever you
can for your country?
Seonsaengnim.
Your novel is becoming
more and more popular.
And more students are
majoring in Asian studies.
Is anything wrong?
I received a letter
from Doctor Kim Ji Won.
He wonders why I don't
try to help my homeland.
He's asking me to return to Korea.
If you leave that door open,
will he return home?
Leave that open for a thousand years,
and you still will see nothing.
For a few decades every morning,
how could you not miss a single day?
Only seeing that
open door drives me crazy.
You heartless man.
Will she be able to see
you again before it's too late?
Are you still thinking about home?
Hoffman Miniatures
I tried to build it in
accordance with your design.
It's just as I remembered it,
exactly the same.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for
showing me your house.
In this part of the house
live the men of the family,
and this is where the women stay.
Ahhh... so this is
how home looked like.
I'd like to see this place myself.
This way is the room where
Suam and I stole all that honey.
You don't look good.
It just my stomach,
nothing to worry about.
No wonder, you're skipping
meals all the time these days.
Calm down, please.
You'll only receive 40 mark per person,
and even after the currency reform*,
[*June 1948, after the division.
Ostmark were used in the DDR]
you will be able to exchange all your
Reichsmark into Deutsche Mark.
They're making beggars out of all
of us with this exchange rate!
This is no money,
it's just a piece of paper!
The Soviet Union blocked Berlin,
so if a war breaks out,
what will all these pieces of paper count?
Let's just burn them all!
The Reichsmarks I gave you
aren't worth a penny anymore.
So you came here to pay
me again with the new currency?
You recreated my precious hometown,
it's not something money can buy.
I'd really like to visit
this hometown of yours,
if it produces
honest people such as you.
I knew you'd come here.
When I crossed the Amnok,
going from east to west,
I dreamed of finding a new world.
But, when I escaped Japanese
tyranny and came here,
what I found wasn't
the ideal place I dreamed of,
but just another dictatorship.
Are you going to return home?
Return?
I don't know.
If I cross the Amnok once again,
will my hometown be there?
The place I was born in, that
land populating my dreams.
That is now just a chimera
existing inside my novel,
a place I will no longer
find wherever I go.
You wrote about the
hometown you were born in,
so now you must write about
your newfound hometown.
I'm talking about Germany.
Your first book
was a tremendous success.
Doctor Li,
let's publish a sequel as soon as possible.
I'd like to talk about that later.
No problem.
But don't make us wait too long.
Is everything all right?
Why have you waited so long to come?
You must have realized yourself
something was not right.
How serious is it?
It's cancer,
in a critical stage.
You must go through
surgery immediately.
Immediately?
Please, give me some time,
so I can prepare myself for this.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Seyler.
I brought you the corrected manuscript.
Doctor Li has left.
You didn't know?
Insaengdocheojihasa
What could life resemble?
Eungsabihongdabseolli
Like a wild geese's
footprints in the snow.
Isanguyeonyujijo
Although only a caress
of fate leaves them behind,
Hongbinabugyedongseo
As the wild geese
flies away, unknowing.
Seonsaengnim!
Where there is life,
there is death.
Where would you find someone
as happy as me?
Someone with two hometowns.
Who could receive
as much love as I did?
Seonsaengnim...
He says he's coming back, right?
When will he be back?
Munhwegeumjikchicheosa
Your soul drenched my
heart in that sightly silk.
DanjeolEunjeongbulhakchi
Love's extinction, never did I
learn such foolish words.
Unusaetanjongyubyeol
I grieve my loss,
despite choosing to part.
Bunshinomunimsieui
I had the doltish suspicion,
wondering whether you would be angry.
Ehh... always making me wait.
What is he saying?
Is he coming back or not?
Uh?
He probably...
will not come back.
What?
He talked of the past,
trying to comfort me.
There must be
something wrong with him.
Now...
that river...
What's wrong?
I feel so anxious.
Mirok.
Why are you outside?
The wind is cold.
It feels refreshing outside.
Mirok.
I am all right.
Don't cry, please.
Mother...
I want to go home.
I want to spend my last days at home.
Why do you say that, Mirok?
You must be strong.
Is there anything you wish to eat?
I'd love to eat
Korean rice one last time.
This clock didn't stop,
but looks like my time is finally up.
Just like your book Der Yalu Fliesst
will always populate our memories,
you will always have a
place inside our hearts.
Germany has become your new hometown,
and Korea has become
the home of peace for us.
My father gave me this clock.
Mirok.
Your rice is coming.
Mother...
Seonsaengnim.
Until the East Sea's waters and Mt. Baekdu...
"Donghaemul-gwa Baekdusan-I"
[Korean Hymn, Aegukga]
"Mareugo Daltorok"
"are dry and worn away"
"Haneunim-I bouhasa"
"May God protect and preserve us"
"UriNara Manse"
"and bless our nation"
"Mugunghwa samcheolli"
"3,000 Li of beautiful
rivers and valleys..."
"Hwaryeogangsan"
"filled with
Roses of Sharon"
"Daehansaram Daehan-Euro"
"May our great Korean people
live the Korean way"
"Gir-I Bojeonhase"
"and protect our path"
We are all here today to celebrate
his academic achievements,
his cultured ways, and his
endless love for teaching;
his genius as a writer,
and his wisdom as a philosopher.
But before all those
qualities which marked him,
to celebrate the man, Mirok Li.
The people who had the pleasure
to meet this slim and subtle man,
with his quiet and reserved demeanor,
must have felt the warm embrace...
of his ways surrounding them.
Mirok Li gave everyone
the confidence to believe in one's means,
and had the gift of giving us the courage
to act according to our ideals.
By meeting this man and the way
he interacted with people,
we discovered that the joy
of life can only prosper,
when your life is based on honesty
and generosity for your fellow men.
Mirok Li, as a writer, a scholar
and a human being,
played a bridge of understanding
between East and West.
Through his life and works,
we discovered a hometown of peace...
which transcended race or continents.
That spirit connects and reconciles
every single thing on this earth,
and it's the spirit involving
and leading all of our lives.
He found this hometown not
for himself, but for all of us,
and left us this wonderful gift.
Let us stop shedding
any more tears today,
for Mirok Li was
able to find his hometown.
Let's all partake in all the
peace joining and surrounding him.
Our crying would mean belittling
the immortal legacy he created...
while living among us.
So, just like his Der Yalu Fliesst
remains in our memories,
his life will not end here, and will
continue flowing inside our hearts.
Why two letters at once?
What is he writing, this time?
It's a letter from the people
who gave him hospitality.
She asks me to send her some rice.
Says he wants to eat Korean rice.
Ahh... really.
If he came here himself,
he would be already tired of eating rice.
This...
Does this mean he's dead?
How can he?
How can you die?
You heartless man.
How could he die there, so
far away from his hometown?
You left like in a dream...
and you go without a last word?
Where are you, my dear?
Are you crossing the river?
Are you coming back to your hometown,
your home, by my side?
Where are you?
Did you go to that place?
That place you dreamed of?
The place which only
existed in your works?
Did you go back there?
Main Translator & Timer: MisterX
Timing QC: selvaspeedy
Editor/QC: szhoang
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Produced by
Bayerisches Fernsehen and SBS
Directed by Lee Jong Han
Written by Lee Hye Seon
Based Upon
Der Yalu Fliesst by Mirok Li