Final list of those who passed the judicial exam
Kim Eun Chul
I passed!
Son! Son! What happened? Did you pass?
Here. My name.
Final list of people who failed the judicial exam.
How did this happen? This can't be. I'm Kim Eun Chul.
I'm Kim Eun Chul with an IQ of 157. No way.
This is nonsense!
Oppa, come and eat!
Do you think I can eat right now? This is a nightmare!
No!
I told you to come and eat. B-o-p! (Rice/Meal) Bop! Bop!
Are you not quiet these days? You ruined my condition in the morning.
So annoying. Why is he yelling at me?
Episode 8
Laundry for the worried youth.
Day before the exam 8:15 AM
-Tomorrow is the first part of the judicial exam, so be careful not to catch a cold. And eat slowly so you don't get indigestion.
-Okay.
Here, princess.
Should I remove the fish bones for you judge Kim?
Yes.
Our Madame Yang, you're number one in jumping the gun.
The judicial exam hasn't even started yet. Why is he a judge?
-Hey!
-What?
This damned girl. Have you ever seen your brother fail an exam?
Why are you acting like an amateur?
What's the point in passing? He already dropped out twice during the training period.
Won't he leave this time too?
This time he promised me that he would finish his training and the judicial research institute.
Isn't that right, judge Kim?
Yes, don't worry.
Hey, Kim Bom. Eat quietly! I can't read in the middle of all this ruckus.
What can I do? I have a fish bone stuck in my throat!
Why do you keep yelling at me since earlier?
Hey! Stop eating and go. Let go of those chopsticks!
Okay, Okay.
I bet that noona will come looking for a snack again after eating breakfast.
Where else would there be a good boyfriend like this?
Boyfriend...You crazy man.
What boyfriend?
Maybe her future boyfriend.
You're here?
Is that a red bean bun? Can I eat it?
Yes.
Eat slowly. Slowly.
Thank you. You eat one too.
Cute.
Why are you smiling?
Huh?
You're going to choke. Eat slowly. Who is going to take your food?
Wait.. Is this an indirect kiss?
You should drink too.
Hey, you're so careless. Take it off.
What?
I'll wash it for you so take it off.
Why are you doing this? It's okay.
It's hard to remove fruit stains. Hurry up and take it off.
Please!
You shouldn't be taking off a man's clothes so openly in the middle of the day.
A man? Bull Sh*t. Aren't you still in your diapers?
He's a young man.
Welcome!
Please dry clean this for me.
Ok. I'll take good care of it.
This is for your academy fee. You have to get a good job this year.
I'm sorry, mom.
If you're late on the interest again,
I won't go easy on you.
So scary! What is that? What is so nightmarish?
Wait. Where did I see that girl before?
That will be 7,900 Won.
Ah. She's a student that works part-time at a convenience store.
But what's going on?
Is there's something she's being blackmailed for?
So scary! And what was that ghost?
It's time. Why isn't he coming out?
Day before the exam 4:25 PM
It's oppa!
Oppa!
Since I don't have the time to talk to you, can you move?
Okay. Since it's your exam day tomorrow,
I just came to give you this.
I paid 300,000 won for that talisman to give to you so you can pass the exam.
If you have this talisman, you can get 100% on your exam!
I'm not a person who believes in superstitions like this so take it back.
It's not a superstition? That guy is so good.
He knew that I almost drowned while playing in the ocean when I was young.
And he knew that I didn't study well in school.
Who has no experience of almost drowning in their childhood?
And after just talking with you for a few minutes, who can't tell that you didn't study well in school?
He even knew that there is a man in my life.
He said he's younger, the same age or older than me.
Younger, the same age or older. Is there anything else?
There's nothing else?
Anyway, I don't need this talisman so whether you return it or not
Do whatever you want to do. I'm going.
Oppa!
What are you doing?
This...
You're telling me to sew this on oppa's underwear behind his back?
If that's too hard can't you put it in his backpack?
This is such a waste of money. You paid 300,000 won just for a piece of paper?
You said it's just a piece of paper? Bad luck.
You better put it in there.
Because if you don't and Eun Chul oppa fails the exam, I'm going to blame you.
Fine.
She spent 300,000 won on a talisman?
I clearly told her not to spend more than 30,000 won on a guy.
What happened with looking up his background?
Chauffeur Park.
Why is the font Times New Roman?
Don't you know I don't like that font?
I told you to use Arial!
I'm sorry, madam. I'll redo it.
But that'll take forever.
Can't you do anything right? Why don't you know this simple thing?
Go.
Kim Bom. 27 year old younger sister.
She owns a laundry. Kim Eun Chul was Kim Bom's brother?
It sucks that he doesn't have a job. And even his family has no roots.
I'm upset.
I'm home!
Oh, baby! You have taken your business management lessons.
I have something to say, come sit down for a bit.
What is it?
My baby... You're already 27. You're quiet and lady-like but you never even get to date anyone.
Mommy is very upset about that.
You know I can't look into a man's eyes
because I'm so shy.
Of course I have no interest in dating.
So I'm going to set you up with a man.
Set up? I don't like being set up.
You're like an orchard in a greenhouse, baby.
A bee has to come and find you. Cause a flower can't go looking around for a bee.
Mommy is only looking at men who came from good schools and good families.
I'm only looking for high class men so you just wait. Ok?
I don't know.
I just want to focus diligently on my business management classes for now.
Mommy, please keep that in mind.
Baby...
What should I do? I can't even tell my husband about this.
I think the convenience store the girl is working at is somewhere in this vicinity.
Give me back my money.
Let go. Let go of this.
Give me back my money!
Let go of this. I told you I can't return the money that was spent on appeasing the spirits.
You said if I gave money to the spirits I would be able to get a job.
You couldn't get a job because you weren't devout enough. Ugh, seriously.
Appease the spirits again. I'll do it for 5 million won.
Did you think I would get fooled again?
Just give me back my money!
If you feel wronged then you can sue me.
My money...
Are you okay?
Thank you.
You should drink it when it's warm. My grandmother once said
When you're cold in the inside and out,
you should give warmth to your inside.
Yes.
I seem like a pathetic fool, don't I?
No. When you live there are times when misfortunes happen.
I failed and failed again at getting a job.
When I felt like I was dangling off the edge off a cliff,
That's when someone held out his hand.
I thought that hand,
was going to grab me.
My father passed away when I was young.
My mom raised me and my younger sister all by herself.
I wanted to get a job quickly and take care of my mother, but
I'm sorry but you couldn't get the job.
I tried so hard for several years, but I still couldn't get a job.
There's nothing wrong with you, but are you trying to find a job?
What?
Come and find me.
That is the time
that person approached me.
Let's see... the God of rice cakes.
Look. You saw how it fell?
If you pay to appease the spirits, it'll stick on.
If I pay to appease the spirits, I'll be able to get a job right?
For the past year, I've been here helping numerous people get jobs.
-How many?
-1387 people.
You heard, right? Including you it's 1388.
I gave him 10 million won. I even borrowed money from a loan shark.
Please take care of me. Definitely take care of me.
In the end, I failed.
That time he pretended to hold my hand at the edge of the cliff,
but then he just pushed me off.
Did you try reporting this to the police? This is fraud.
I tried but they said they can't be prosecuted.
Who can I blame?
I'm the idiot for believing in their lives.
I wish I could just end my life here.
Don't say stuff like that. I'll get your money back for you.
Then you can comfortably start looking for a job.
Bom, why would you do that?
Huh? Uh, about that...
Look. I was also tricked by that guy.
I'll get your money back for you, no matter what.
Thank you for your kind words.
It's time for me to go to work, so I'll leave first.
You're here?
Day before the exam 8:40 PM
I want our Eun Chul to get married as soon as he becomes a judge.
Please look for a good match for him.
Of course.
-At least that much.
-For those who committed crimes listed in sections 329 to 322,
Up to half those crimes can be punished by...
It's section 330. For those who committed crimes listen in sections 329 to 330,
Where do I put it?
Is Young Mi making you do that?
Yeah. Young Mi told me when you weren't looking-
You do whatever she tells you to do?
Oppa, are you okay?
That talisman. Go and throw it out right now.
But still, Young Mi was thinking about you when she bought this. And she spent a fortune.
Get out.
Okay.
It's not that he got cut from the training institution.
My son just quit and left because it didn't fit him well.
Job training professor Min Chul Soo
Kim Eun Chul.
National Diplomat Academy 2 years ago
Do you not know the meaning of a group project?
I have you a warning the last time too.
But again you handed in a report by yourself.
I couldn't agree with the group. I had no choice.
Did you even try to come to an agreement?
What I heard,
Was that you said you can't work with people
who are on a lower level than you.
I was only saying the truth that they were on a lower level.
Kim Eun Chul. I hope you're aware that your evaluations are one of the worst.
Your rash and uncooperative attitude
is unfit for diplomatic work.
That idiotic dictator...
I heard he didn't participate in the group project again.
He thinks he's better than everyone else.
Even if he goes through the training,  he won't get any job offers.
Of course not.
What's the use of being smart?
He's got no social skills.
He'll just continue to act like a loser, and get cut.
You quit and left?
They may have passed the foreign service
officer exam, but they are at such a low level.
I could never work in that environment.
You said even the Minister of Foreign Affairs called and asked you to stay.
He did.
My colleagues wanted me to stay, too.
Then maybe you should have just stuck around.
Even when you took the public officer qualification exam,
you left during the training period.
Mother.
I want to take the bar exam.
I think that's a worthwhile place where I can prove my skills.
I need to respect your decision.
But what am I going to do about the academy fees?
Whatever...
I can take out a loan, or tell Bom to take money out of her account.
But...
You are going to finish your training there, right?
Yes, Mother.
This will be the last time.
Don't worry.
Okay.
I have faith in you.
You must become a judge or a prosecutor, okay?
Okay, no matter what.
- I must...
- You must...
He'll definitely finish the training period this time.
Please find a good match for him.
Of course, we care about her education. Her husband will be a judge after all.
Of course.
I heard it's on the 10th floor of this studio building.
It must be there.
He's done for today. Goodbye.
I'm not here to get my fortunes told.
I have something to say to that quack, so move!
What's with this girl? What the heck?
Let's see...
I won't get the job this time, either?
Don't be disappointed.
If you call upon the spirits, you'll have no problem getting a job.
What's wrong with you?
Can I get a job too, if I call upon the spirits?
- This girl just keeps...
- Let go!
Your problem is not getting a job.
What's the use of making money?
Because of all the men crowding around you...
You won't be able to save any money.
You need to appease the spirits.
Men are crowding around me?
I've never had a single boyfriend in all my life.
I mean after you find a job.
Not now.
I'm the CEO of a laundromat right now!
- CEO?
- What's this?
- He got everything wrong.
- I thought he was good.
This person is a total fraud.
He lies and says that you'll get a job if you just pay to call upon the spirits.
He's a total crook.
So go before he takes all your money. Hurry, and get up!
- Hurry, and leave.
- Listen, girls...
Go...Get out!
Go, go...
What's wrong with you?
How dare you walk into my workplace and ruin everything?
Me?
I'm Park Ji Young's friend.
You cheated my friend.
Give me the 10 million won you took from her right now!
Why are you taking it out on me?
It didn't work because she wasn't being devout enough.
Jerk!
You are nothing but a crook that takes money from those trying to find jobs.
What did you say?
You should experience how it feels to get strangled, too.
Min Soo!
This psychopath is going to kill me!
- Die!
- Min Soo!
Let go of this, and talk.
- What's wrong with this woman?
- Mind your business!
Jerk!
What are you looking at?
Just give me the money!
I wanted to live a quiet life.
That jerk!
I should have beaten him up until he gave me the money.
Still, violence is wrong.
If it's hard to resolve this alone,why don't you ask for help?
Help? From who?
Young Mi?
No, that artist guy.
Grandma, he's a total baby.
Baby.
He can't help with anything.
They say everything has a use. He's better than nothing.
I'll think about it.
Anyway, can you give me the power to look into the future?
Why?
You want to open up a fortune telling business on the side?
It's not that.
I want to let Ji Young know when she'll find a job.
And I'm a little worried about Eun Chul, too.
Right...
Tomorrow is the bar exam.
Yeah.
Mom is already calling him 'Judge Kim' and totally jumping the gun.
I think he's feeling pressured.
I usually can't tell you but I'll tell you just this once.
Got it?
What?
What did you say?
I didn't hear anything.
I said I would tell you just once.
I'll see you again, granddaughter.
How can you do this? Tell me again before you go...
Grandma...
She left again.
[Day of the exam, 7:30 AM]
He studied so hard for the past year.
Eun Chul, get yourself something good to eat.
What's this?
He's still holding onto the talisman that Young Mi bought?
He acts all cocky...
But I guess he's got no other choice when it comes to getting a job.
What were you doing?
Nothing.
You're not going to eat?
I don't feel like eating.
Still, you can't go on an empty stomach to take a test.
I'll make some warm citron tea.
You should drink it before you go.
My hopes and dreams, you've always done well on even the hardest exams.
I'm not worried at all.
Don't make any mistakes, and get home when you are done.
Eun Chul, I had a really good dream last night.
I think you'll pass with flying colors.
Okay.
Eun Chul!
Eun Chul...
Drink this before you go.
I made it with honey.
Yeah, you should drink something to warm yourself up.
Wretched girl...
Why the heck did you break the cup on his exam day?
Why did you do that?
Nice job...
Ki Joon.
Ki Joon, what brings you here so early in the morning?
I came to wish Eun Chul good luck on the test.
I guess you are busy.
I'm not busy.
Come on in.
Okay.
He saw me getting beat up by Mom so early in the morning.
How embarrassing.
Bom, wait up!
You're going to work early.
How is the laundry business?
Not bad.
That hospital gown you washed for me...
it became like new.
You've got an expert's touch.
Since I was young, laundry was a hobby for me.
I'm really good attaking the stains out.
Laundry was your hobby?
That's very unique.
What's your hobby?
I like playing instruments...and watching movies.
- I like watching movies, too.
- Yeah?
We should go watch a movie together sometime then.
Have a good day!
Wait.
When?
Let's decide the exact date and time to the second right now.
Now.
Right now.
Mrs. Kim.
From a family of doctors or professors...
Is it so hard to find a doctor, prosecutor, judge, lawyer...
or high ranking civil servant who graduated from a top school?
Madame, if the man has all those qualifications
he would be very picky about the girl's family and education.
What's wrong with our family?
And Young Mi may not have gone to college, but...
Mrs. Kim.
Mrs. Kim, why is it so hard to get in contact with you?
Did you have a chance to find a good match for Eun Chul?
Excuse me, Mrs. Kim is talking to me right now.
Why are you being so mannerless?
Is that so?
I'm sorry.
I'll mind my manners, and just talk to her for one minute.
Did you find a good match?
I'll make sure to reward you.
Yes! This works out.
This is exactly what you've been wanting.
Her son graduated from Seoul University and he will soon pass the bar exam.
That's great.
This must be fate.
Not all law school students become prosecutors and judges.
How can you try to match my daughter to that bum?
He's so low class.
How dare you call my precious son a bum?
Oh my...
Your temper hasn't changed at all since then.
Not changed since then?
I know I've seen this woman before.
We saw each other nine years ago inside
the conference room at Culture Girl's High School.
Your daughter was such a bad influence on my daughter.
She got suspended because of her.
So upsetting...
Yeah. Now that I look at you, you are that nasty woman.
Let's only speak the truth.
Everyone knows that Young Mi was the school thug.
- Who was the bad influence on whom?
- What did you say?
- That's such nonsense...
- And...
I would never marry my son off to a low class
loan shark family even if it means he'll never get married.
Stop dreaming.
Why are you doing this?
Loan shark family?
Low class?
Our family financially backed the Korean army during the Japanese occupation.
We are a respected family.
...
Is that why your daughter walks around, collecting
money wearing a skirt the size of my hand?
What the heck...
How disrespectful...
Are you insulting my baby's style?
Honey...
Something really bad happened to me.
Yeah, come pick me up.
Okay.
What the heck.
Mrs. Kim...
I will never become an in-law with that family, please find another girl.
I can't believe her...
Honey, where are you?
Why is my stomach hurting all of a sudden?
No.
Get a hold of yourself, Kim Eun Chul.
Get a hold of yourself.
I'll have to take out a loan, or tell Bom to take money out of her account.
This is the last time.
Don't worry.
I have faith in you.
You must become a judge or a prosecutor, okay?
Hey!
Are you okay?
Get a hold of yourself! Look here!
Hello?
Hey!
Her phone is turned off.
Did Park Ji Young come out to work today?
Yes.
Do you know where she is?
She was sitting alone on top of the building steps a while ago.
I don't know about now.
It's almost time for her shift. I wonder where she went...
Okay, thank you.
[Will]
Ji Young!
No!
Don't come near me.
Ji Young, why are you doing this? Don't do this.
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
It's not like I don't understand how you feel.
But this isn't right.
Think about your mom and sister.
No.
If I want to help my mom and sister,I need to disappear.
Ji Young.
The loan sharks went to look for my mom at her work this morning.
She was so shocked, she fainted.
If I die, at least she won't have to pay back the loan.
I have a way to get that money back.
So, don't do this scary thing.
Please just trust me.
I'll make sure you get all your money back.
So, please come down.
It's too dangerous.
Are you okay?
Let's go.
Let go of me! I need to go.
Calm down. You can't go.
Let go!
- I need to go in to take the exam.
- Calm down.
You can't go in during the exam.
That's the rule.
This exam means everything to me...
I can't give up like this.
I can't give up!
I need to take that exam.
I bet he won't even give me back a penny.
How am I going to get him to give me 10 million won?
This mouth is the problem.
So why did you make such a bold claim?
What else could I do? I had to save her life first.
She even wrote out her will, and she was about to jump from the rooftop.
What do I do?
It's no use suing that quack.
Of course, you don't have 10 million won, right?
Should I borrow it from Young Mi?
But why are you so fervently trying to help this customer?
You know her?
Huh?
Yeah, I know her.
You see...
She's my friend's in-law's cousin's sister.
If it's that close...
you should definitely help her out.
The best thing would be to make that quack cough up the money himself.
I know.
I have a good idea.
Hey!
Let's do that right now.
Let's go.
Let's go...
I'm almost finished with taking care of my son.
I made him into a judge.
It would be perfect if I can get a doctor daughter-in-law.
I'm getting so annoyed thinking about it.
How dare she try to match him up with a daughter of a loan shark.
Wait until Eun Chul becomes a judge...
I'll get him to investigate that family, and punish them!
The rice is ready.
Let's see...What time is it?
Oh my God.
It's almost time for my hope and dreams to come home.
Rib eye roll...Rib eye roll...
Rib eye roll!
Yeah, I'm on my way to deposit the money we got today.
Okay, I'll see you there.
Nice.
You can't go in during the exam.
That's the rule.
Son!
You shouldn't have come out, it's so cold.
Son, of course I should come out when you just took that exam.
You went through so much in this cold.
Right...
Did you do well on the exam?
Of course.
I don't even need to wait for the results from the first round.
I'm going to start preparing for the second round right away.
Of course, Judge Kim.
Right...
I wanted to nourish your body...
So I went and bought some rib eye rolls.
Let's go.
I didn't know it would be this easy to fool people when we started.
It's best to target those who are in despair.
Yeah! But don't you think we've stayed too long in one location?
I think we might get caught for fraud, we should move to a different region.
- We should.
- Yeah.
I don't feel good about that girl, Park Ji Young, catching onto us.
- I don't have a good feeling about it.
- Let's go.
It's you again?
I can't return her money.
And tell that girl, Park Ji Young, or whatever...
She should sue us if she feels wronged.
Sue?
She can't do that even if she wants to.
My friend...
She died.
Because of the loans she took out to pay you...
she threw herself into the river in her hometown.
When was that?
Last night!
How could this happen?
- That was her will.
- Will?
Mother, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, my sister, Ji Hee.
I won't let that fortune teller get off easy for doing this to me.
I'm going to get my revenge on him in my death.
What do we do?
Hey, are you trying to threaten us with this?
You killed an innocent person.
I can't let you sleep in comfort.
I didn't kill anyone!
Return that money to Ji Young's mom right now.
Otherwise...
my friend's restless spirit will put a curse on you.
Hey, something's weird here.
What?
I mean...
She said the girl died last night, but she called early this morning.
She was crying and asking back for the money.
I'm sure you are mistaken.
Did you fall asleep drunk last night?
No, this is weird.
Let's give back all that money, and go back to our hometown.
Shut up.
There are no such things as ghosts.
Stop talking nonsense.
Look for a new house for us to move into tomorrow.
Feels so crummy...
I should be careful who I cheat in the future.
Is the lightbulb out?
I told him to change the bulb.
Cold!
Seriously, why is there water here?
I told Min Soo to clean up before leaving.
Let's see...
Where's that towel?
What's this?
They're footsteps.
She left a will last night, and threw herself into the river.
No way...
No way.
Min Soo probably just left in the middle of cleaning up.
I should change.
Let's go.
[I'll get my revenge.]
Cellphone!
Cellphone...
Why isn't this turning on?
Why isn't the power turning on?
What's this?
Please turn off...
Turn off.
Please turn off.
What's this?
Why isn't the door opening?
Min Soo?
Is it Min Soo?
Even if it's in my death,I'm going to get
revenge on the one who did this to me.
My friend's restless spirit will put a curse on you.
He won't be able to do anything bad ever again.
What a tragic end to a crook...
He's getting what he deserves.
Thanks to you, I was able to get all my money back.
It's not easy to help out someone you hardly know.
I don't know how to thank you.
No...
That bastard...
Those crooks need to be taught a lesson.
That way, there won't be any more victims like you, Ji Young.
Yeah.
You were probably freaked out to pretend that you were dead...
And I'm sure it felt strange giving me your will...
I'm sorry for asking you to do those things.
Don't worry about that.
If it weren't for you, I would never have been able to get back on my feet.
Right...
I finished dry cleaning your clothes.
You said you have an interview today.
You should wear this.
Thank you.
I'll get going.
Good luck on your interview.
Ji Young, fighting!
Bye.
Pretty...
I'm sure if I wear black stockings, it'll cover up the burn scars.
This is a perfect outfit to wear on a movie date with the man of your dreams.
This would be perfect for Bom.
Should I get it for her?
No...
You are not her boyfriend, Yong Soo Chul.
Stop overdoing it.
Ki Joon.
Who's she?
Bom!
You came early.
Yeah.
I'm sorry for not letting you know earlier.
My girlfriend really wanted to see this movie.
I brought her out so I can introduce her to you, too.
I heard a lot about you from Ki Joon.
I'm Yoo Min Young.
Bom?
Bom.
Huh?
It's nice to meet you.
Yes.
Let's go in. It's time.
Wait.
I just remembered.
I... left the stove on at home.
I should hurry back.
Nobody's home?
No, nobody's home.
I should hurry back.
I'm sorry.
Bom...
Bom, we should watch a movie next time.
Watch where you are going.
Bom!
Bom, are you okay?
Subtitles by DramaFever