"She had received
a most beautiful doll
as a present.
Oh, what a glorious doll,
so fair and delicate.
She did not seem
created
for the sorrows
of this world."
Mommy.
Diana.
Took the baron
to the train.
Funny, Miss Julie
isn't going with him.
I mean, all their friends
are celebrating Midsummer together,
big event.
Left me his boots
to polish.
Changed into something
more fancy,
His Fanciness,
His Most Divine
Fanciness,
His Vainglorious,
Most Elegant Highness.
Sir Boots, I think.
So the baron
went into the station and told me to wait,
said he'd have
something for me.
When I see him
come out of the station,
he was putting something
in a folder.
Guess what was
in the folder.
A packet
of travel brochures.
Like that's how
someone like me travels.
But no money, no.
They don't
think that way, not those people.
No, they don't think
that way.
And then I leave
and I'm carrying his boots
and I pass the barn and ask the stable boy
to take the horses home
and I go in.
And there
I see Miss Julie leading the dance
with the gamekeeper--
the gamekeeper.
And what do you know?
She sees me and she rushes over to me, Kathleen,
and commands me, Kathleen--
commands me to dance with her.
She thinks she can
control everyone.
Who am I?
I can't control anything.
Oh, Kathleen, come and look
at these pictures.
Look, Paris.
Rome.
This is Lake Como.
Oh, I know
about that place.
Lord, it's lovely.
I'm hungry.
It's kidney,
your favorite.
Delightful.
Yes, you are right.
This is my big délice.
You should have
warmed my plate.
You're harder to please
than the baron himself.
Get me a glass.
A proper one,
a fancy one.
When one is drinking
bon vin...
Oh.
It's good.
It's pretty good.
It's a tiny bit
too cold.
-What are you cooking
with that infernal smell?
Oh, just some devil the young lady has me
making up for the dog.
Miss Julie thinks
it's pregnant again,
because she's been,
ah, you know,
close to
the gamekeeper's dog.
Miss Julie told me
she watched them
and it made her sick.
And now she'd rather
risk the dog die from the remedy
than have a mixed breed.
God save her.
You should have seen her
coming to the dance.
Looked like she'd been lying
on the ground having a nap.
We wouldn't act
in that way.
But still,
she's elegant--
Miss Julie--
magnificent.
Oh, her waist,
her neck.
Stop it.
I've heard Clara
talking.
She's seen her naked
lots of times
when she gives her
a bath--
Oh, Clara--
too cross-eyed
to get anything right.
You women, you're always
jealous of each other.
Listen, I, who have been
out riding with her--
I know her
well enough--
the way
she sits a horse, her legs,
and then
the way she dances.
Well,
is it done--
my abortive poison?
Is it some kind of
witches' broth
you ladies are cooking
on Midsummer Eve, huh?
Listen.
Come, dance
with me again.
I don't want
to be impolite,
but I have promised
to dance with Kathleen.
Let me borrow him,
Kathleen.
You go and rest.
If Miss Julie
is so gracious,
it isn't for him
to say no.
Go along, John.
Be thankful for the honor.
Frankly speaking,
but not wishing
to offend in any way,
I cannot help wondering
if it's wise
for Miss Julie
to dance twice with the same partner.
What are you
talking about?
I, the mistress of the house,
honor the workers' dance,
in the barn,
with my presence.
Since I really want
to dance,
I have to dance
with someone who knows the steps,
so I don't look
ridiculous.
As you command,
Miss Julie.
I am at your service.
I have chosen
to forget all rank,
and so must you.
Come, give me your arm.
Thank you, John.
I really don't
want to treat you as an inferior.
Let us go through
the entrance hall.
You would like that,
wouldn't you?
Don't be afraid,
Kathleen.
I won't run away
with your fiancé.
That's what he is,
isn't he?
You're a man of the future,
aren't you?
-Diana, come here.
Come on.
My love, come here.
Come here.
Poor you.
I know.
I did not put very much
in your food.
It's mostly
good meat.
You'll be fine.
Shh.
Listen.
You like it?
You stay here.
I left her.
She's strange,
Kathleen.
She's always strange.
Are you upset with me?
Why?
For small things
like the two of you walking off?
You are a sensible girl,
Kathleen.
You'll make
a good wife.
Can you imagine
what the baron would say
if he saw
her behavior?
Huh?
Did you see her?
See her?
Is it possible?
Are you flattered?
Don't be another dog,
will you?
You are such a charming
cavalier,
running away
from a lady.
As you can see,
I hurried back
to be with the lady
I had deserted.
Why are you
wearing your livery on Midsummer Night?
Remove it at once.
Then I must ask
if I can go to my room.
My black coat
is hanging there.
Go to your room then.
And I will go too,
and make sure
you don't run away
from me again.
Miss Julie,
with your permission,
may I go and get it?
Kathleen,
are you and John
engaged?
Engaged?
You seem so familiar.
In a way.
We call it that.
You call it that?
Were you not engaged
yourself, Miss Julie?
Miss Julie,
I am tired.
Would you mind if I go
to my room and--?
Where did you learn
to speak French?
In Switzerland.
I was the wine waiter
at the one of the biggest hotels in Lucerne.
You look like
a perfect gentleman.
Charmant.
-You flatter me.
-Why would I flatter you?
Oh, well,
my natural modesty forbids me to believe
that you would give
someone like me
such genuine
compliments,
and so I dare to assume
that you were flattering me,
or worse,
patronizing me.
Where did you learn
to talk like that?
You'd be surprised
to know the places
I have visited.
But you were born
in this area, weren't you?
Aye.
My father worked the land
right across the way.
And I visited
your garden
long before I came
to work for the baron.
I saw you
when you were
a little girl.
But you, Miss Julie,
did not notice me.
Who gave you permission
to walk in our garden?
I remember one time--
No.
I'm not
going to tell you.
Is it bad?
It isn't.
But Kathleen
might hear me.
From her room?
I think she's snoring.
She doesn't.
But she talks
in her sleep.
How would you know?
Why don't you
sit down?
It wouldn't be
proper
in front of
Miss Julie.
And if I order you
to do it?
I'll obey.
Get me something
to drink.
I'm not sure
what we have in the icebox.
-I believe it's only beer.
-My taste is simple.
I want beer.
Miss Julie.
Thank you.
Are you not
going to drink?
I don't like beer,
but of course
if you order me...
I thought a polite gentleman
should keep his lady company.
A point well taken.
Toast me.
Are you bashful?
To your health,
Miss Julie.
Bravo.
Now kiss my shoe,
to get it
just right.
Excellent.
You should have been
an actor.
This won't do.
Miss Julie,
somebody might see us.
What would that matter?
They would start
talking.
Miss Julie
should have heard
how their tongues were wagging
when we danced.
What were they saying?
Sit down.
Tell me.
Ah, you know.
You're not a child.
When one sees a lady drinking alone
with a man--
a servant in the night--
then--
We're not alone.
We have Kathleen.
Let's go and get her.
Leave her!
What?
You shouldn't bother
those who are resting.
She's been working all day,
standing over the stove,
even cooking
for your dog.
She's earned a rest.
How nice you are.
Shall we go
and pick some lilacs?
I can't do that.
Absolutely not.
I order you.
Go.
I'm sorry,
Miss Julie.
She was sick with
the broth you asked me to give her.
And I hardly
gave her any.
I mean, it could have
killed her.
I like to take her out
in the sunshine.
She loves
to run around
in circles
in the grass.
And then she drops down
on the warm stone steps
and spreads out
with the sun on her back.
I see.
You may keep her.
It's John's.
Take the rest.
I sent him out
to pick flowers for me--
lilacs.
Miss Julie,
I am tired.
And if you don't
need me anymore,
may I go
to sleep?
Why wouldn't you go out
to the garden with me?
I don't understand
what you're scared of.
My father
isn't even home.
And the other people--
they are hired
to work here like you.
Do you think
they would believe
that I'm in love
with a valet?
Such things happen.
It may be.
What an imagination.
I could step down.
Don't step down,
Miss Julie.
They will say
you fell.
You are strange.
So are you.
Life is strange,
people--
everything.
We're just foam
floating on water
until we sink.
Sometimes I dream
that I'm on top of a column
and I can't
get down.
I'm almost fainting
when I look down,
but I must
get down.
I'm so scared
to fall.
I can no longer hold on
and I long to fall.
But I don't fall.
Yet there's
no peace,
no rest
till I come down.
I would be descending.
I would fall.
And if I reach the ground,
I want to go further down.
Deep into the earth
itself.
Did you ever
feel this?
No, no, I--
I dream that I am lying
under a tall tree
in a dark forest and...
I want to go up,
up to the top,
and look around
at the bright landscape
where the sun is shining
and so I can rob
the nest
in which lies
the golden eggs.
And I climb
and climb.
But the trunk is so thick
and so slippery,
and it is so far
to the first branch.
But I know
that if I can only reach
that first branch,
then I would easily
reach the top.
I haven't
reached it yet--
that first branch--
but I will,
if it only be
in my dreams.
Are you ever
afraid to hear
that you're
no longer wanted?
That you
don't belong?
I shared a bed
with my
little brother,
and one morning
when I was eight
I woke up and found him
dead beside me.
I saw death for the first time
and, yes, I was afraid,
but not in the way
you're talking about.
I mean,
my wee brother,
his open coffin--
frost was creeping
into my backbone then.
It's always there.
It's in me.
I will never go back
to what I was born into,
where I used
to belong.
Come, come, let us pick
nine Midsummer flowers
and put them
under our pillows, Miss Julie,
and all our dreams
will come true.
-Let me see what you've got in your eye.
-Oh, it's nothing.
It's just a bit of dirt.
It'll be gone in a minute.
Sit down.
Sit still.
My,
I think
you're shaking.
Careful.
Sit still.
Yes.
Now it's gone.
Kiss my hand
and say thank you.
Miss Julie, listen to me. Kathleen is close by.
Will you listen to me?
-Kiss my hand first.
-Listen to me.
-Blame yourself then.
-For what?
Are you a child?
You're playing with fire.
-I'm not. I'm dreaming.
-No, you're not.
Shame.
I said shame on you,
John.
-You meant that?
-Yes, I meant it.
I am tired
of this game.
And I ask to be excused
in order to resume my work.
The baron will return in the morning,
and he'll want his boots polished.
Stop!
I forbid you.
Put away the boots.
It is my duty,
which I am bound to do.
He is a good master.
And I'm not expected
to serve as your playmate.
Then shine
my shoes first.
Why, you're proud.
In some ways,
not in others.
Pour us a drink,
a strong one,
a Midsummer Night one.
I will empty the glass
in one swallow.
Thank you, John.
How nice of you.
Have you ever been
in love?
We don't use
that word.
But I have liked
a lot of girls.
And once when I could not
have one girl I wanted,
I became sick,
horribly sick,
sick like a prince
in a fairy tale,
a prince who cannot
eat or drink
because of love.
Who was it?
It was you.
Do you know what the world
looks like from my place?
No, you don't.
Your lot are like hawks.
You're like falcons,
always floating about high in the sky.
And their backs
are rarely seen,
'cause they just
glide along,
right up there.
Come.
Come with me.
See?
It's as if you have
your own secret world.
Tell me
about your home.
It must be a boundless
misfortune to be poor.
Oh, Miss Julie,
a dog can lie
on a countess's sofa.
A horse may have
its muzzle stroked
by a young lady's hand.
But a servant boy--
Ah, well.
My home--
it is a shack
far out there
in the gray wasteland
where there isn't even
a single tree.
And you can't see it
from here even if you climb to the top.
It's hidden.
Sometimes, as a boy,
I was drawn to see
your castle,
your gardens.
And when I came
close enough, I could see
the wall
around your park.
In the evenings I would
creep to the wall
and climb up
to see your home--
oh, far more magnificent
than the church.
I had never been
inside of it, never,
but no matter
where my thoughts went later in life,
they would return always
to that place--
me sitting
on the wall,
shaded by trees
and covered
by honeysuckle,
watching the people
coming and going,
like they were kings
and emperors,
and I knew
that world
would never be mine.
And then
one day
I caught sight
of a pink dress
and a pair
of white stockings.
I saw you
walking among the roses.
Yes.
I fell in love.
Oh, I wanted
to talk to you.
I-- I wanted to...
touch you.
And I thought,
if it is true
that a robber can enter the Kingdom
of Heaven and be with the angels,
then why can't
a peasant like me
be in the baron's
garden
and just play
with his daughter?
The next Sunday,
I washed myself with soap and hot water
and put on
my best clothes
and went to church,
where I could see you again.
I did see you.
Yes, Miss Julie,
I did see you
and went home
determined to die.
But I wanted to die
beautifully
and peacefully,
without any pain.
And then I recalled
that it was deadly
to sleep
under an elder bush.
And I knew
of a big one,
in full bloom.
I picked
all of its flowers
and made a bed
in the big box where we keep the oats.
I laid down
and pulled the lid down
over myself,
closed my eyes.
I fell asleep
on the poisonous elders
and I woke up
a very sick boy.
But I didn't die,
as you can see.
And I knew that I could
never have you.
You're everything
I can never have.
You speak like--
like what I find
in my books.
Did you ever go
to school?
Not much, no,
but I have read a lot
and gone
to the theatre
and have listened
to the conversation
of better-class people.
I even try to speak
like them.
You stand around and listen
to what we're saying?
Oh, yes.
And I have heard
a lot
when I was driving
the carriage for you, Miss Julie,
or rowing the boat for you--
you and your girlfriend.
What?
Tell me.
It wouldn't be easy
to repeat.
I was surprised.
I couldn't understand
where you, Miss Julie,
had learned such words.
I--
Perhaps there isn't
quite as much difference as they think
between human beings
and human beings.
May I ask permission
to go to bed?
Go to bed?
On Midsummer's Night?
You said--
Dancing with the mob
out there
has no attraction
for me.
Good night, Miss Julie.
Sleep well.
Get the boat
and take me out
on the lake.
I want to watch
the sun.
Would that be wise?
Are you afraid
of your reputation?
I don't want
to be made ridiculous.
And I don't want
to be discharged with no recommendation.
Maybe I even owe
Kathleen something.
Oh, you're afraid
of Kathleen?
-Take my advice and go to bed.
-Are you ordering me now?
Yes, for once,
and for your own sake.
The night is far gone.
You've been drinking.
You don't know what you're doing.
I hear the crowd
coming this way to look for me.
I can't be found
here with you.
I love the people,
and they like me.
Let them come,
and you'll see.
No, Miss Julie, they don't like you.
They--
they take your food and your money
and spit at your back.
Why?
I never hurt them.
The mob is always
cowardly.
They are
false-hearted.
In such a situation
there's nothing to do but run away.
-Let us run away.
-Run away where? To my room?
No, no, Miss Julie,
to mine.
We'll be safe there.
I'll look after you. Trust me, I will.
-If they will look for you in there?
-I'll bolt the door.
And if they try
to break it down?
I'll shoot.
Come.
-Do you promise me that--? Promise--
-I promise.
Man: Kathleen!
Open the door, Kathleen!
-Woman: Kathleen?
-Man: Will you open it?
I don't know
who I am.
who you are.
I don't either.
You don't know
who I am?
Did you say that?
No.
No what?
Come over here.
Your hand in mine.
I did not tell you,
that time I saw you
in the garden,
I sat for hours
on the wall,
just looking at the house
until the sun set.
And then I--
you may
despise me now,
but I did what I never
had dared to do before.
I jumped down
on the other side,
hoping you'd come out again
so that I could speak to you.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
I knew that
I didn't belong.
I was very scared,
Miss Julie.
I knew who I was--
a boy who found his brother
starved to death in the bed beside him,
and my father
telling me
to never upset
His Lordship,
how good the baron
had been to us.
I knew I had to get out
of your garden.
It was forbidden to me
and I would upset my father.
And then I saw
someone coming.
It was the baron.
My heart
was hammering.
I ran like mad
afterwards,
plunging through
the raspberry bushes,
thorns tearing at me.
You can't imagine what it was like,
with the thistles
that stung my feet.
A week later
I saw you again...
walking among
the roses
in such
deep thought
and looking
so lonely,
even unhappy.
You did not see me.
Oh, I wish you had.
John:
Please.
I beg you.
I am sorry.
You don't understand.
Forgive me.
I cannot stay here
any longer.
Please stay in the room
until I make sure
Kathleen won't see you.
Kathleen, please.
Please, Kathleen.
Please stay here
just for a little while.
Please stay in here.
There are things I--
I can't control now.
I can't control her--
Miss Julie.
Don't.
Don't talk, shh.
Wait.
I will talk.
I'll come back.
I will.
Stay in here now,
Kathleen,
for me, for us.
Try to sleep.
Please, you--
you need sleep.
Kathleen may have
heard us.
I think she knows.
What shall we do?
John, what are we
to do?
We?
We.
We've been doing
what everyone is doing.
It is Midsummer Night,
Miss Julie.
Between midnight and dawn
lovers are allowed
to open their hearts
and their loins.
Listen, we--
we could run away,
travel far away
from here.
Leave?
Far away.
To Switzerland,
the Italian lakes,
Lake Como.
I've been there.
I even told you earlier.
Life has given us an answer.
It's a miracle.
I even have a picture
over here.
Look.
That's the life--
always new faces,
never a moment to spare
for worry and nerves,
no need to wonder
what to do with yourself,
people dancing
night and day,
trains whistling,
and all the time
the jingle of gold coins.
That's the life, Julie.
Oh, eternal summer,
orange trees,
laurels.
I'll start a hotel,
everything first-class.
- I'll have first-class customers.
- A hotel?
Yes!
That'll be our life.
You will be
the pride of the place,
what with your looks
and your style,
why, it's a sure thing.
I'm telling you,
you will never be
lonely again.
I'll take care of you.
I promise.
Freedom, no more walls
and no gardens.
And you'll sit there
like a queen.
You'll keep the slaves going
by the touch of the bell.
And the guests will file
past your throne,
timidly leaving
their offerings.
And you cannot imagine
how the people will tremble
when they're
holding out a bill,
and you just sweeten them
with your pretty smile.
And one day
I will be as rich
as your father.
I may even
buy him out.
Tell me you love me.
Otherwise I am nothing.
Not now, not here.
And above all, it's important--
no feelings.
Then everything will be lost.
Cold blood, clear heads,
grown-up people.
Let us sit at the table,
you there.
And I'll sit here.
And we'll just talk amongst ourselves
as if nothing's happened between us,
making our plans.
Have you no feelings
at all?
I?  No one is more full of feeling
than I am.
A while ago you held me.
I-- I was in your bed.
Yes, that was then.
Now we have other things to think about.
Don't speak harshly
to me!
We have made
one mistake,
a big one.
There's no sense
in making another.
Now the baron may be back
at any moment,
but before he comes,
I need to know--
do you believe
in me?
How can we do
all this?
We have no money.
True enough.
I want you to be
my partner.
I'll need
your money.
I have no money,
not of my own.
I have nothing myself.
That's it then.
You think I'm going to
stay in this house
as your woman?
Do you think
I'll let people
point their fingers at me,
laughing at me?
Do you think I can ever
look my father in the face after this?
- Oh, what have I done?
- Don't try that one.
Turn off
that fountain!
Do you even know
what love is?
Me?
I should say so!
Do you think this is
my first time?
Oh, now you
despise me.
Don't pretend
you're nervous
and don't pretend
you're special.
We are the same now.
Look here,
my little one.
Let me treat you
to a glass
of something
super fine.
Where did you
get this?
In the cellar.
My father's wine.
Well, isn't it good enough
for his son-in-law?
Thief.
You going to tell
on me?
Yes, to the fools.
I'm so unhappy.
Why?
Think of Kathleen.
I even had to forbid her
to come to the kitchen now.
-Don't you think she has feelings?
-A servant is a servant.
And a whore
is a whore!
Oh my God,
I'm so scared.
I'm in a dark hole
and it's like I'm sinking.
I'm sinking.
You are sick,
young lady.
I do feel sorry
for you.
When I was
a little boy,
lying there in secret,
looking at you in the garden
and saw you walking
among the roses
and saw your
slim white ankles,
well, I tell you now,
I had the same nasty thoughts
like all young boys.
You said you wanted
to die for me.
It was a lie.
I had to think
of something.
It's the fancy talk
that makes women open their legs.
-Bastard!
-Make sure you don't carry one.
-So now you've seen the hawk's back.
-Not exactly its back.
-Oh, how can a human soul be so filthy?
-Wash it off then.
You minion!
Stand up when I speak to you!
Stand up
when I speak to you!
Minion?
Shut your mouth, lady whore!
Shut up and get out of here!
Telling me I am a minion!
You have no right to be in here!
You're not needed!
Kathleen doesn't like
your kind
visiting her kitchen,
especially you.
Do you think she would be
so vulgar as you were this evening,
-throwing yourself on a man the way you did?
-No more.
Where do you think you are?
In a zoo?  In a whorehouse?
No more.
Yes, I'm dirt.
I'm nothing.
I don't belong.
I know.
But please,
please help me, John.
I need to find
a way out of this.
Please help me.
Help me find a way
out of this.
I may be
partly to blame,
but do you think
someone in my position
would dare even to look
at someone like you
if you hadn't asked for it,
begged for it?
Please.
I'm still amazed.
Though I must say
the victory
was far too easy
to be really exciting.
Oh, no more.
I'm sorry
I said that.
I don't want to strike
one who is unarmed.
Oh, I cannot deny
that it has given me
pleasure
to discover that what has
dazzled us below you
was only gaudiness,
that there is powder
under tender cheek,
that there is grime
under your dirty nails,
that your perfumed handkerchief
is dirty, Julie.
Oh, it hurts me
to realize
that what I yearned to reach
is so far from genuine.
It's nothing.
It's worthless.
I'm sorry you've sunk
so low, Julie,
far lower than
your own cook.
It hurts like
watching the last flowers
of autumn
hanging their heads,
already faded
or torn to shreds
by the rain
and turned
into muck.
You talk as if you are
already above me.
I am bred
by a baron.
You can never
achieve that.
Aye, that's true.
But I can provide a baron,
with your help.
You're a thief.
I'm not.
There are worse things
than being a thief, much worse.
Anyway, think about it:
I am serving
in a household
and I look upon myself
as one of the family,
as a child
of the house.
And it isn't regarded as stealing
if a child picks a berry
from a large bunch.
Shh, shh, Miss Julie.
Miss Julie.
Shh.
Miss Julie, you are
a wonderful woman,
and you're far too good
for one like me.
You've been drinking.
You lost your head.
And now you're trying
to cover up your mistake
by telling yourself that you love me.
Well, you don't.
Unless my looks
may have tempted you.
And maybe there was
a physical attraction.
But that makes your love
no better than mine.
I could be your pet,
like your dog
that you give affection when it suits you,
but that's not enough for me.
I can never make you
love me.
Are you so sure?
Are you meaning to say
that it might be possible?
Oh.
And that I could
fall in love with you?
Oh.
Oh, aye.
Well...
Aye.
Yes, I could.
You are beautiful.
You are refined.
Oh, I love that
in a woman.
You are educated.
We could read together,
all the great writers.
We could discuss them.
Oh, you--
the fire you ignite in a man
isn't likely to go out.
You are like hot spices
with one of your kisses.
Leave me alone.
You're disgusting,
like a rat.
I hate you.
Run away
with me then.
Yes, we'll run away.
Are you my friend?
I am at times.
But don't rely on me.
I need you
to understand me,
to see me.
Don't give me the secrets
of your life.
You'll regret it.
You sound
like my mother.
Oh, she was
so beautiful.
Look at this picture
of her.
She didn't want
to be a mother.
She would smile at me
but didn't mean it.
Sometimes when I think
of her,
my mouth smiles.
But I do not smile
within me.
Don't drink more.
It's as if
I am cut off from everything
that's life.
Inside me,
within me--
nothing.
A black hole.
She taught me
to mistrust
and to hate
all men.
And I promised her--
this little girl of 10--
that I would never,
never be a slave
to any man.
I didn't even understand
what it meant.
Then you hate me too.
Yes.
I'd like to shoot you
like a dog.
No qualms?
No qualms.
But you have nothing
to shoot me with.
And I'm no dog.
I'll take you up
to my room...
and then I'll put you
in my birdcage.
Most of all,
I'd like to die.
Die?
How silly.
On the shores
of Lake Como,
you said,
the sun always shines.
Look at the wall
out there.
It's all you can see
from down here.
You can only feel
the light of the sun.
And you can only hear
the wind.
On the other side
of that wall,
I have a place,
a secret garden.
There's no wind there.
I go there
when I'm anxious.
I'm anxious
all the time.
I'm always longing
for some other place.
You cannot imagine
how different
I wanted
my life to be.
When I was little,
just after Mama died,
I was hoping that
all of my garden
would be
full of animals.
They'd come from--
I don't know where
they'd come from.
They'd be there
to keep watch
over me.
I have a pit
in my stomach.
I do not know where
my sorrow comes from.
And now you.
You and me--
yes, we must leave.
To make life hell
for each other?
No.
To be happy,
smile on the inside.
Enjoy ourselves
a few years,
as long as we can.
And then...
to die.
Would you die
with me?
I won't die at all.
I enjoy life.
You refuse
to die with me?
I'm sorry,
Miss Julie.
I'll talk no more.
I'm going to bed.
You-- you dishonored me.
You owe me something.
There.
Thank you.
This is what I get
for opening my heart to you,
for giving away
my family honor?
I told you
not to.
You-- you forced me.
You were
the seducer.
We can get--
we can get married.
And then
we can divorce.
I won't demean
myself.
-Demean?
-Yes, demean.
Oh, how I wish it undone.
How I wish it--
-I told you.
-Oh, if only you loved me.
I told you
you should not drink,
because then you talk.
You shouldn't talk.
A butterfly dies
in the act of love.
I wish I did too.
What do you want?
Am I to cry with you again?
What--?
Do you want me to kiss
your feet again?
What?
I've had enough,
Miss Julie.
I--
this is painful.
Miss Julie,
I see that
you're unhappy.
Yes, you are suffering,
but...
I don't understand
what you're saying.
I mean, my people--
we don't carry on
like you do.
We don't hate
and destroy each other.
We make love for fun.
Yes, it is a game,
and we play it
when we get time off from work.
But we don't have
all day and all night
like you people do.
You know what?
I think you're ill.
Yes, I'm sure
you're ill.
Be kind to me, John.
Talk to me
like a human being.
Well, then be
a human being yourself.
You think you can
spit on me,
but won't let me
wipe it off on you?
Help me then.
Tell me
what I should do.
Lord, if only
I knew that myself.
I-- I know
I-- I've been
acting wild,
as-- as if I'm mad.
I know.
But now
what do I do?
Stay here
and keep quiet.
Nobody knows.
I-- I can't stay here.
Everyone knows.
They don't know,
and they would never
believe it.
But suppose
there are consequences.
Consequences?
Then there's only
one thing to do--
you must disappear.
You must leave at once.
I can't go with you.
Then they would know. You must go alone.
Alone?
Where?
I can't do that.
You must, and before
the baron gets back.
If you stay, you know
what will happen.
Later you will write
to your father,
tell him how unhappy you are.
He loves you.
He will take care of it.
He'll never guess it was me.
I don't think he'd be
anxious to find out.
-I'll go if you come with me.
-Are you stark mad?
Miss Julie is
running away with a--
a servant?
It would be
in the papers.
And, Miss Julie, the baron
will never survive.
I'm so tired.
I'm so tremendously tired.
Order me.
I must be told.
I can no longer
think.
I can't move.
Do you see now
what helpless creatures
you people are?
Why are your kind
strutting about
with your noses
in the air,
like you were
the lords of creation?
Well, I'll tell you
what to do.
I'll order you.
Go to your
father's library.
In his drawer
there is money.
Get the money.
Come up with me.
Go.
Get up there.
Speak kindly to me.
Orders always sound
unkind.
Now you know
what it feels like.
Go.
Am I allowed
to leave my room now?
You look a mess.
May God forgive you.
What have you
been doing?
You are my woman.
But the night is long,
Kathleen.
All the wine--
my head
wasn't with me.
It was swimming.
I asked what you
have been doing.
I have such pain,
Kathleen.
Let us hold
around each other.
No.
I have this
ready for you.
For church.
Oh, you-- you always
have my things.
Yes.
Thank you.
You promised me
you'd come with me this morning.
Oh, yes.
I remember now.
And here you are
with my finery.
Yes.
Come on with it then.
What's the text today?
The beheading
of John the Baptist.
Ah.
Oh, you're--
you're choking me.
Oh God,
I'm so tired.
So tired.
I'm exhausted.
So why did you stay up
all night then?
Hmm?
Have you seen
your face?
Miss Julie.
She would never
leave me.
Stop it.
And she--
she who doesn't know
what's decent, she doesn't.
She talked.
She needed to talk.
You know
the way I am.
I'm always placing
a veil over people,
idealizing them.
So I never see
who they really are.
I did that with her--
Miss Julie--
and I was bound
to be disappointed.
We are all forced
to face ourselves
as less than
we'd hoped to be.
Isn't it funny
anyhow,
when you come
to think of it, her?
What is funny?
Everything.
Look at me
straight in the eye.
Yes.
Is it possible?
It is.
It's awful.
I could scratch
your eyes out.
Yes, that's the way
I feel about it.
It's nasty.
It's simply disgusting.
You're angry
with her then?
No, I'm angry
with you!
It was a rotten thing
to do, really rotten.
Poor young woman.
I won't stay in a house where you can't
have respect for your employers.
Are you jealous
of her?
No, not of her.
If it had been
Clara or Sophie,
then yes,
I would have been.
No, I will not work
in a house
where people can't
behave decently.
Would you?
You just dragged yourself
down in the dirt by doing it.
Get out of here!
-Get out!
-Why should you respect them?
-You don't know?
You, who think you are such a smart fellow?
You don't know?
All it shows is that
they are not a bit better than we are.
If they are not any better than us,
then there is nothing
to inspire us to become
better ourselves.
And did you ever think
of the baron?
Just think of all the sorrows
he's had in his time.
Listen, Jesus,
I won't stay here any longer
and have to
face him.
And then with someone
like you.
I can't imagine why she did it with
someone like you.
If it had at least been
with a man of her own people--
-if it had been with a better man.
-What are you saying?
She, who wanted
to give her dog poison
because it ran after
the gamekeeper's mongrel.
-What?
-Listen.
You're fine
for what you are,
but there is
a difference.
Class is class.
Well, let me
tell you,
I won't stay here
any longer.
On the 14th of October
we are leaving.
Yes, that's right.
You're coming too.
You can get a job
as a janitor,
or maybe a messenger
in some government office.
It may not pay you as well as the baron,
but it will be secure.
And then your widow and children
will get a pension.
I'm going to plan my death
so you will get a pension?
I'm sorry, I have better prospects
than that in mind.
Who's that walking around
up there?
Can it be the baron?
Already?
Listen.
If I leave,
I'll never get
another job like this.
And you--
why should you go?
You've never seen
much of the world anyway.
I-- I don't know
why you would go.
When the baron leaves
on the 14th of October,
then we are
leaving too.
It's been some years now,
you and me.
Don't you forget
your obligations.
Let's hope
that the baron
will never find out
what happened here,
in his servant's room,
this Midsummer Night.
Go and shave yourself.
You don't want him to come home
and see you looking like this.
I'll take the dog out
and I'll come back.
And you and I
will go to church
and you will ask God
to forgive you.
And I will ask Him
to help us,
all of us.
My God.
What a sight
you look.
Why?
How do I look?
You're white
as a corpse.
The sun's rising.
And the trolls
are dancing.
Yes, they've been
dancing all night.
I've got the money.
How much?
I took all of it.
Please come with me.
I can't go alone,
not today.
On Midsummer Day,
the trains
will be packed.
I can't--
I can't go alone
in the midst
of the black and gray
on the train,
people looking at me
as if they know.
Oh, it's so beautiful
out there.
The garden.
I never showed you
my little brook, did I?
I know you'd love it,
all my flowers.
Miss Julie,
I am going with you,
but it has to be
right now, right away.
What's that?
Oh.
What is it?
-It's my canary.
-Are you taking a cage along with us?
I'm not
leaving her behind.
Drop the cage.
It's the only thing
I'm taking with me from home.
Drop the cage,
I'm telling you.
Kathleen will be here
at any minute.
All right, listen.
You-- you will go
out the main entry.
I will use
the servants' entrance.
And we'll meet outside
the front gate.
L-l-let go
of that bird.
Now. Kathleen will
take care of it.
-No, my little bird.
He's not
taking you.
No.
The bird.
Give it to me.
My little bird,
he's not
taking you.
For God's sake.
Shut up.
Kill me too.
Kill me.
Killing an innocent
creature
without blinking
an eye.
Oh, I hate
and despise you.
There's blood between us.
I curse the moment
I saw you.
I curse
the day I was born.
Kill me too.
You think I can't stand
the sight of blood.
You think I'm weak.
Oh, I should like
to see your blood,
your brains lying there
on the table,
see your whole sex
swimming in blood
like my little bird.
You think
I am weak!
You think I love
you because my womb
cried out
for your sperm.
You think I want to carry
your brat under my heart,
feed it with my blood
and give it your name!
You, what are you
called anyhow?
John, John and then?
What is your family name?
Maybe you don't
have one.
I would be Mrs. Lackey,
Mrs. Shit-pile,
you dog there
wearing my collar,
you minion
wearing my crest.
Share you
with Kathleen,
share you with my
own servant,
parcel you out to all
the other needy women working here.
You think I'm a coward
and want to run away.
Oh, no!
No, I'll stay,
and let
the lightning strike.
My father
is coming home.
He'll find his desk
broken into,
his money gone.
Then he'll ring
that bell there
twice for his lackey.
And he'll send
for the police.
And I'll tell them
everything-- everything.
Oh, it will be good
to get an end to it.
And then my father
will have a stroke
and die.
And that will be
the end of all of us.
And all will be quiet,
peace,
eternal rest.
The baron's line
will be wiped out
and the lackey's line
will continue
in an orphanage.
There spoke
the royal blood.
Dragged up in the gutter,
and dead in the jail.
Bravo, Miss Julie.
Make sure the lackey
doesn't lose his place.
What is going on?
What a mess
you've made.
You're a woman,
Kathleen.
You're my friend.
You must
understand me.
You must listen
to me.
I don't want to know
anything from you, Miss Julie.
What's going on?
Kathleen:
What? What?
Kathleen, you have to
understand me.
I don't want
to understand.
You must listen to me.
If you're planning
on getting John
to go away with you,
Miss Julie,
I will have to stop you,
both of you.
Quiet, Kathleen,
and listen to me.
I-- I can't
stay here.
And John-- he can't
So we have to--
to get away.
What?
Wait, I have an idea.
All three of us can
go-- go together
abroad to start
a hotel.
I have--
I have money, see?
And John and I
will run
the whole thing.
And-- and you can--
I think,
can run the kitchen.
Oh, wouldn't that
be fine?
Oh, please say yes,
Kathleen.
Come along with us.
You have to get out
and see the world.
You can't imagine
how fun it is
to travel by train.
We just talked
about it.
You'll love it.
Trains whistling,
carriages stopping,
bells ringing
upstairs, downstairs.
You'll stand--
no, you'll--
you'll sit in the kitchen
like a queen.
Of course.
You're not going to stand
at the stove yourself,
naturally not,
with all the fine
clothes
you'll be wearing
to greet the guests.
You're so beautiful,
Kathleen.
Yes. I'm not
flattering you.
You'll find a husband,
a rich Englishman.
They're so easy
to catch.
And we'll be rich.
We'll build a villa
on Lake Como.
It rains there
a little,
a little bit
sometimes.
But the sun will be
shining sometimes.
Though it looks dark.
And...
Then--
Or...
we can
go home again,
come back here
or...
somewhere else.
Do you believe in this
yourself, Miss Julie?
Do I believe it
myself?
Yes.
I don't know.
I don't know anything
anymore.
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
So you were
going to elope?
Elope?
That's a big word.
You heard
the young lady.
And maybe
she's tired now
from being up
all night,
but it's a plan
that could work.
Are you telling me
I'd be the kitchen girl
for her?
Her?
Will you please
speak more refined
when you're talking
in front of your mistress?
Do you understand?
My God.
Listen to you.
It would be better
for you
to listen
a little more
and talk
a little less.
She is
your mistress.
If you despise her
for what she has done,
you should
despise yourself.
I have always
respected myself.
And looked down
on others.
And I have never done
anything that is beneath me.
You could never say
that the baron's cook
had lowered herself to be with
the stable groom or the swineherd.
Quite so.
You had me.
And very lucky
for you too.
Lucky?
A man who steals
from the baron?
You shouldn't be
talking.
You, who can't even respect your own
mistress anymore.
John,
are you coming with me
to church?
You could use
a good sermon.
No.
I am not going
to church today.
You go alone
and confess your sins.
Yes.
I'll do that.
And I'll bring back
enough forgiveness for you too.
Jesus suffered
and died on the cross
for us.
And if we go to him
with an open heart
and all our sorrows,
he will take our sins
on himself.
You really believe that,
Kathleen?
I've believed it
all my life, Miss Julie.
And that is why
I stand here now
with the faith
of my childhood.
Where sin overflows,
there grace
overflows more.
Oh, if--
if only I had
your faith.
It is not given
to everyone,
without God's
special favor.
Not everyone
deserves it.
To whom
does He give it?
Only God
knows that.
It is a work of grace,
Miss Julie.
And God is no respecter
of status,
except the last
shall be first.
So He helps
the last then?
And it is easier
for a camel to pass
through the eye of a needle
than for a rich man
to enter
the Kingdom of Heaven.
So you see, Miss Julie,
it's just the way it is.
Well...
I am going
alone.
And as I pass
by the stableman,
I shall tell him
not to let out the horses
if someone should like
to get away
before the baron
comes home.
Goodbye.
What would you do
in my place?
In your place?
Let me see.
Well, as a lady,
as a woman,
after that kind
of mistake,
as one
who has fallen...
I don't know.
Yes.
I do know.
With this?
Yes.
But I wouldn't do it.
I wouldn't.
Do you understand?
There is
a difference
between us.
It's the same difference
as between a man and a woman.
This about
a rich person
not getting
to heaven--
it's a lie,
isn't it?
The baron is back.
Kathleen.
What if Kathleen--?
He's seen his desk.
Yes, it is John,
Your Lordship.
Yes, Your Lordship.
Right away.
In half an hour,
your lordship.
Yes, yes.
In half an hour.
He called
for his boots.
Wants his coffee
in half an hour.
Julie:
Half an hour.
I'm exhausted.
I don't know
what to do.
To run, to stay,
live or die.
You know
what I want to do,
but I don't know
how to do it.
Make me.
Order me.
I'll obey you
like a dog.
I can't.
I don't know why.
I-- I--
it's as if
just wearing this jacket,
I cannot order you.
I-- I-- I heard
the baron's voice.
Now,
I can't explain it,
but--
Oh, God, it's that--
it's that damn servant boy
sitting on my back.
I-- I-- I do
what I'm told.
I-- if he-- the baron
came down here now
and told me
to cut my throat,
I'd do it
on the spot.
Then pretend
that you are him.
And pretend
that I am you.
Did you ever
see a magician at the theatre?
The magician says,
"You do everything
I tell you,"
and she does
what she is told.
He says,
"Take the broom,"
and she takes it.
He says, "Sweep,"
and she sweeps.
I see silver
and gold...
and all the stars.
Just like when I went
to sleep as a child.
I'm floating
out of the window and up to the sky.
Such freedom,
surrounded by
sparkling crystal.
And the dark
is no longer dark.
The whole room
is warm and safe
like an open fire.
It's you.
And I am close
to the fire.
How nice and warm
it is.
And it is so quiet
and so light.
Here is the broom.
Go to the barn.
Use it.
Go now,
while it's light.
Use the tunnel,
so you don't meet
your father.
Thank you.
Tell me
that the first
can also receive
the gift of grace.
Say it even if you don't
believe it.
The first?
No, I can't do that.
But wait.
Miss Julie, I know.
You no longer belong
among the first.
Oh, you're among
the last.
I am
one of the last.
Oh.
And the first
shall be the last.
Don't speak.
Don't think.
Go, Miss Julie.
No other way.
Go.
Wait.
I'm sending you out
into the world.
Look.
You're like
bright-colored stars.
The water
is your heaven.
Do you know that,
my flowers?
Yes.
Everything is
so much bigger
than the little
pieces.
Do you know that?