Did you feel that?
Kiss-kiss!
It's OK, it's OK. It was great.
Is there anything you're keeping from me?
No...
What day is today?
How did you know?
God told me.
You have party tonight?
Yes, I'm going out
with some friends later.
What are you thinking now?
I wish you were here.
I want to show you something...
Close your eyes first.
You can look now!
Oh, my God, it's so beautiful!
That is Taipei.
I really hope that you will be here.
Do you mean that?
Do I look like a liar?
I might show up one day.
Welcome.
Tell me when you're ready.
Yes. I will.
Kiss, kiss!
Bye.
Happy birthday...
- Hi!
- Hi. No Viktor?
He'll be here soon.
Happy belated birthday.
Thank you.
Take your coat off.
Can I have some water?
Thanks.
How's he doing in school.
Fine. You can ask him when he comes.
How long have you lived here for?
Why?
I was just wondering
if you're happy here.
Well, yes...
It could be nice here... if you
just sorted yourself out a bit more.
Listen, Mum.
If you're going to start
we might as well forget it.
Hello!
Hi! Come in!
- Is it cold out?
- A bit.
My, how you've grown!
Happy birthday!
- Thanks.
- Did you find your way OK?
Yeah...
We've bought you a little cake.
How lovely...!
We didn't want to
have to carry it on the train.
Kicki, come and sit yourself down.
Viktor can take care of that.
Can you make the coffee?
What is it?
Can't you find something for you
to do together?
He'd be so happy.
But Mum, I can't come up with
something just like that.
That's usually
not a problem for you.
Thanks.
Look, I'll pay.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you...
Thanks. Thanks very much.
Four cheers for Kicki!
Thanks. Thanks.
For you.
Oh, thanks!
You shouldn't have...
It's from Grandma too.
So sweet.
It must be ages since you
heard Happy Birthday in Swedish!
Yes, ages!
Oh, look!
It's lovely!
Thanks.
Pardon?
Nice cake.
Viktor...
...would... would you like
to come on holiday with me for a week?
I mean... only if you want to, that is.
We haven't really spent time together
since I came home.
Sure.
Take a week off school.
I can go whenever.
It'll be fun!
- Here it is.
- Are you sure?
Yes. Number 16.
Hello.
You want room?
How much is it?
Restorsleep?
Sorry?
"Restorsleep"?
- He's asking if it's for rest or sleep.
- Sleep. Two days. How much is it?
Very cheap.
Cash is OK. Cash OK.
It's OK with credit card also?
Cash better. Credit card OK.
The big window for the lady.
Thank you.
How do you say thank you in Chinese?
Well, here it is.
Exciting, eh?
Have you got the right room?
I'll see you in a bit, then.
OK.
Viktor?
Yes?
Can you hear me?
Yes...
Damn.
What?
Nothing.
Do you fancy going to do something?
Or do you want to go to bed?
I don't know. Want to see my room?
Look.
Cool.
It's not that bad here, after all.
It's OK.
Maybe we should be getting to bed.
Sure.
Good night.
You too.
And don't forget I can hear everything!
I'll close the door.
Good night!
Sorry. Can I buy something to drink?
Of course.
Beer?
Perfect. Thank you.
I join you.
Is it always so noisy?
Daytime, bang, bang, bang...
Night-time,
king, king, kong, kong...
Better.
How I say your name?
My name? K-Kicki.
Kikiki?
No, Kicki.
Kicki.
Kicki, yes.
You sitting OK?
No problem.
Do you know this address?
Neihu. The Neihu district.
Neihu? Is it far away?
No.
No? OK, thank you.
What is this?
It's a secret.
On my roof,
Taipei is more beautiful than anything.
Here's your coffee.
Thank you.
Excuse me, can we sit here?
Will they come out with the food?
What do you usually eat for breakfast?
Different things. Bread and cheese.
Grandma makes you breakfast in bed, right?
I usually make breakfast
for her, actually.
I called Grandma yesterday
and said we'd arrived safely.
Oh, really? So how was she, then?
She was alright.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Are you going out with anyone?
Have you got a girlfriend?
How do you say it?
How do we say it?
I don't know, I don't do it...
Have you got anyone?
God, no. It's just me.
May I?
Sure.
You don't smoke, do you?
No.
We made a bet once.
So I've had one cigarette.
That's so daft!
I was going to ask about school.
It's what all adults ask when they
don't know what to talk about!
Can we go and see that building later,
I've got a few things to do. Buy stuff.
OK.
So I'll see you at the hotel at?
Sure...
Thank you.
May I help you?
Yes, please. May I use your bathroom?
Yes. This way, please.
Thank you.
Excuse me...
Excuse me, do you know the way to the...
Hello...
Hello!
Where are you going?
I'm just going.
Where?
Into town.
I can help you.
No, thanks.
That way, nothing.
So is it far?
No, here.
What's your name? I'm Didi.
Viktor.
Viktor, OK...
Where are you from?
I'm from Sweden.
Come!
You take.
- It's not...
- If you show me I can walk.
No, I drive you.
It's OK.
No, it's OK.
Hi! Hello. Sorry I'm late.
That's OK.
I got a bit lost.
Is that... a new... little...
Pretty sexy, eh?
Do you like it?
Yes, it's nice.
Why, hello!
Hello!
How are you? What you do today?
I'm fine, how are you?
I been busy...
Oh, that's beautiful.
Like you.
What you do today?
Stop asking.
- They haven't spent the day together.
- I'm just asking.
- Well don't.
- She's been drinking, OK?
Ladies and Gentlemen we have arrived
at the 89th floor, thank you.
Shall I take your picture?
Please do!
Stand looking out of the window.
It worked out well with us doing
our own thing today, didn't it?
You didn't have to drag
your old mum around with you.
We can do it again tomorrow,
and then have dinner together.
Well?
OK...
So are you doing
anything special tomorrow?
No...
...not really.
You?
There's loads to do.
I'll see.
I'll just go
and have a look over there.
Viktor!
Hello.
So, what you do today?
I don't know.
Just going into town.
So I can drive you.
Do you have a new motorcycle today?
Yes, every day.
But I will give back, always.
I'm looking for Mr. Chang.
No people.
No people?
No people!
You want drive?
OK, sure.
So...
Hurry! Hurry, hurry, hurry!
What do you mean, hurry?
Go fast!
OK are you all right?
What are you?
Any question?
You want noodles?
OK, thanks.
Come here.
OK!
It's very hot.
Yeah.
Thanks.
It's good.
It's OK.
Yeah.
It's good.
OK.
Good? Good?
Yeah!
Really good.
You are like me.
Well how do you mean?
You are sad, but happy, outside.
OK!
So where's your father?
I don't have a father.
You don't have?
No, I never had one.
Actually, I don't think
my mum knows who he is.
She had a lot of boyfriends.
How many?
I don't know.
I don't live with her,
I live with my grandmother.
But she live with you now?
Yeah, here in Taipei.
She wants to get to know me.
And you?
My mum is dead.
- Dead?
-Yes.
And my father,
he just play cards
and drink beers...
He gamble.
He's a gambler.
So he loses money?
Of course he lose money!
He's a fucking loser! Really.
Sju Sjosjuka Sjostjarnor!
Sju Sjosjuka Sjonairna...!
It's too difficult.
You know
you are a very nice person.
You're a very nice man.
Yeah, I like you.
My son is also very nice.
You're nice.
Me?
No.
No!
What?
I don't know.
Shit!
Shit! I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
You come Taiwan for man?
Yes. Jesus Christ.
And you know what?
I didn't speak to him.
No.
I was supposed to be a surprise.
And then I... Whatever.
I'm so stupid.
No.
No? Yes.
I am stupid.
I'm a coconut.
What?
Bang on the floor!
Like fountain!
I don't understand.
I happy, you happy.
Yeah?
So put on the music again.
Put on the good music.
So we can dance.
Yeah?
No. No, don't take that.
Don't take it.
He's a foreigner
and you're Taiwanese.
If you didn't take him there,
who did?
He want to drink.
Don't you know how dangerous
that place is?
How old are you?
I've told his mum to come.
Translate.
He says your mother is coming.
But I can go by myself.
What did he say?
He said he's fine.
Fine?
I'm warning you, do you understand?
Hello. Hello, I am Kicki.
I am his mother.
How are you!
Hello.
Hi.
I'm just saying
it's a dangerous place to drink.
It's a restricted area.
Other than that, there's no problem.
Tell her to take a seat.
He want you to sit.
Sit?
Ask them if they like Taiwan.
He says you can go later.
OK.
Tell him that
I'm very sorry about this.
I will take care of my son better.
What did she say?
That she loves Taiwan.
Do you think he works here?
No.
But who is he?
Tea
You have very beautiful eyes.
Yes, you have!
So why you come here, Taiwan?
To Taiwan?
Yes.
Well, because I thought it was
good for us to travel together.
To make a trip together...
We haven't been travelling
for a long time.
But do you know what?
He's always been
so afraid of flying.
What?
I have an address to a friend,
but it's written in Chinese.
So I don't know what it says.
Do you know... where this is?
Which area?
Are you coming?
Yes.
Here.
OK!
Is it far away?
No.
Excuse me, Mr. Driver,
where are we going?
We go to your friend.
Now?
Where are we going now?
Well, let's go to my friend.
Who is she?
Your friend misunderstood.
I just asked where on the island the
address was and now we're on our way.
How are you?
Looking for anyone?
Hello?
Hello.
Good evening.
May I help you?
Yes...
I'm looking for Mr. Chang.
Oh, OK. Follow me, please.
I'll be right back.
So he's home?
Yes.
Shall I take them off?
Shall I put these on?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hi!
Hi, I'm Gwen.
Hello, I'm Kicki.
Kicki. Are you here for Mr. Cheng?
Yes.
I drove by
and I just want to say hi.
A little surprise.
OK. No problem. He's inside.
Please follow me. Watch out.
OK!
I guess you live
in this neighborhood?
No!
Do you work with him
at his office?
No, I'm on vacation
and I just want to say hi.
OK good
Let me introduce you to our kids.
Come on.
Say your names.
In English, of course.
Hi, I'm Nicholas.
Nice to meet you.
Hi. I'm Kicki.
Hi, I'm Ellen.
Kicki.
Why don't you join us for dinner?
No, I must go.
People are waiting for me.
But I think they're coming in.
Hi, my name's Gwen.
Hello I'm Viktor.
Viktor nice to meet you.
You too.
And this is my friend, Didi.
Hi
He's my son.
Oh, good. Please join us.
Please sit down here.
Have something to eat.
Why are you standing there?
Come and say hi.
Hi, Kicki. What a surprise.
Hi.
I just want to say hi.
Maybe it's a bad time?
No, not at all.
So, are you on a business trip
in Taiwan?
Yes...
You are?
Viktor, her son.
So you're her friend?
They are business partners.
Business.
Please sit down.
Is it your first time
to visit Taiwan?
Yes.
How do you like it here?
I think it's beautiful.
So you are their Taiwanese friend?
Yes.
You met here in Taiwan?
Good.
Then you can show them around.
Have you been Sun Moon Lake?
Sun Moon Lake? No.
No?
No. We've just been to Taipei.
I think we should call Mr. Hong
and make a reservation.
It would be a shame
if they only saw Taipei.
It's not necessary.
It is our pleasure.
It is.
Viktor right?
Are you still in school?
Yes.
So what do you study?
Just normal school.
I see.
My daughter studies music.
Play something for us.
Now?
Yes.
What shall I play?
It doesn't matter.
But we haven't eaten yet.
Just play now.
She will play some music for us.
Well, I guess we should go.
Shit! Money!
I guess we all have a reservation
at Sun Moon Lake.
Please stop at the corner.
Bye bye.
Bye.
Was that why we came here?
I don't want to talk about it.
Viktor, wait. Viktor!
I don't want your fucking money.
Pack your things. We're leaving.
Leaving?
Didi, you're welcome too.
We're going to that Sun Moon Lake.
Are you serious?
Does it look like I'm joking?
Please help him.
Are you sure she really
want me to go?
Yeah, I think so.
Is OK I come?
I don't want to be alone with her.
Are you hungry or anything?
No.
Didi? Didi!
Do you want some snacks?
Something to eat?
Viktor, do you want...
Here, you take it.
So, Mr. Viktor. Your key.
Shall we have dinner later?
We'll have a look around on our own.
OK
See you later then.
Comfortable trip?
It was fine. Long, but fine...
We should just float away.
Where?
You know, out...
You know this is a lake.
Yes, so?
We could find an island
and never come back.
Start our own country.
You can be the president.
And you?
I don't want to be anything.
Do you have a girlfriend?
No.
Do you?
I don't know. She's nice.
What?
Why should I come home?
I don't have the money.
They're not going to harm you.
So do you have
any brothers or sisters?
No, but I wish.
What are your parents doing?
My mother is dead, and my father...
His father gambles away their money.
When Viktor was four,
why you move to America?
Because I was working
so much there...
So we thought it was better
for Viktor to stay
with his grandmother.
But you live in Sweden now?
Yes, I moved back a year ago.
Why are you talking to her?
Do you think it's funny?
No.
Why are you laughing?
I have to go back to Taipei.
No. Why?
Do you mean you have to go now?
Yes.
Hi! Where have you been?
I've been looking for you.
Where's Didi?
Hasn't he spoken to you?
Where is he?
Viktor, come and sit down.
Let's have something to eat.
Hey...
Viktor...
Can't we talk about it?
You planned all this.
Why are you so angry all the time?
Angry? Don't you know
why I'm angry with you?
Where do you want me to start?
I just don't get you.
That's enough.
Why did you bring me along?
If I'm such a pain, why invite me?
Because I thought
we'd have a good time together.
Grandma made you, I know she did.
No she didn't!
You're just jealous.
Jealous?
Because I went to meet Mr. Chang.
Do you know what they call people
who fuck for money?
Well?
You're just a piss head cunt.
What the hell...?
Oh, Jesus...
Viktor?
Hey, Viktor...
I was thinking about
what happened last night.
Hey, open up...
Hello.
Hello?
I'm looking for my son.
Check out.
Check out?
Hello... Is Viktor here?
Viktor? No.
I need to speak to...
A Huang?
Miss Kicki! Is something wrong?
Yes.
I need you to call the police.
Police? Why?
The policeman who called here
the other night.
Because Viktor is gone.
Is gone?
I think the policeman
might know where he is.
OK OK
Hello?
I'm looking for the policeman
who called here the other night.
Her son seems to be missing.
Five minutes, OK?
Five minutes? OK.
Thank you. Thank you.
It's OK.
OK?
Here it is.
OK think you.
OK. Bye bye. Thank you.
Bye bye.
Hello?
Hello, Didi?
Hi.
Do you know where Viktor is?
Is he here?
I don't know. Please go away.
I need to speak to you.
Please go away.
What's going on?
Do you know where he is?
What the...?
Viktor, what's going on?
Don't worry.
My father went to get more money.
What's going on, Didi?
He should've come two hours ago.
They want more.
OK...
I'll try to help you.
Tell him I'll try to help.
She can get the money.
Is she going to call the police?
I'm warning you.
If you call the police...
Don't call the police.
No. No.
Did you find your son?
Can you drive me to Neihu?
Are you OK?
Yes.
I think we have a problem.
I'm going to need backup.
Close to Chung Hua and Shin Jiang.
Hello, may I help you?
I just want to speak to Mr. Chang.
Mr. Chang is in a meeting.
I just need him for two seconds.
I can't let you but if important...
It's very important.
You can talk to him later.
Let go of me!
I just want to speak to him
for two minutes.
Can I speak to you for two minutes?
It's very important.
Give me two minutes.
Please, please...
What the...?
I don't know what to do.
I don't think my father's coming back.
I am so sorry about all this.
But I really need your help.
I want her gone. Call the police.
You don't know
My son's in trouble. I need money.
You come to me
because I have money?
You never told me you had a family.
Leave us.
Please...
You never told me you had a son.
Please, I need to know
if you can help me or not.
Give each other a kiss.
What's he saying?
He say to kiss.
Go on, then.
Go on.
Nice one. Now a French kiss.
Stop that!
It's disgusting!
Can't you stop pacing?
How long are we going to wait?
Don’t move
Go!
Hello!
Hi. Is everything OK?
Yes.
Thank you very much for helping me.
OK. You want room, Miss Kicki?
Same room, please.
OK.
Same room.
So, what you do tonight?
I don't know.
Maybe we should go out
eating or something.
Are you hungry?
I know something special.
Yes?
Special.
Want to borrow some clothes?
I'm OK.
You are not angry with me?
Are you angry?
No.
You should take these.
He'll be right out.
Good.
Come on.
I don't know where to start...
There's so much... I want to say...
It's OK.
Grandma didn't make me.
I really wanted you to come with me.
I didn't mean it.
I just wanted you to know that.
I don't know if you're aware
that Grandma... that Grandma's...
That she's sick?
In some strange way,
I'm still glad we came here!
Me too.
It's nice, isn't it.
Lovely.