Beautiful day.
Yes, it certainly is.
- That's a pretty dress.
- Thank you.
What you reading?
- Poetry.
- I know a poem. Want to hear it?
- No, thanks.
- I love Little Pussy.
Her fur is so warm. And if I don't
hurt her, she'll do me no harm.
What's the matter, don't you like it?
Hey, why don't you and I get some lunch
and you could read some
of those poems to me?
No, thank you.
I prefer to read silently.
Oh, 'cause I'm real hungry
and I hate to eat alone.
Then perhaps a cafeteria-style
diner would suit your needs.
Think you're pretty cute, don't you?
My mother says I have a
certain kind of loveliness
though I believe in the Anasazi Indians
that the face is for others to look at.
Get in.
I'm going to walk away now.
I suggest you let me.
Get in!
- Are you threatening me?
- Get in!
Toodle-oo.
Who saw him die? "I,"
said the fly, "With my little eye."
Mother dear, how do we
get blood out again?
I told you, dear. Lemon juice
with equal parts ice water.
If you let it soak long enough,
no one'll know the difference.
- It'll be our little secret.
- We have so many, Mother dear.
Now, tell Mother.
Don't fib. Did you accidentally
cut yourself with a knife again?
No, but don't worry
about me, Mother dear.
- Oh, Mother never stops her worry, Mary.
- You always say that.
- 'Cause it's always true.
- I can take care of myself.
So... what does my little big girl
plan on doing today?
I am substitute-teaching
in a low-income,
racially mixed bottom-scoring,
first-grade classroom.
Oh, you poor darling.
You could have run a charm school
in a soon-to-be bankrupt department
store or been president.
But that wasn't my destiny, Mother.
Well, I hardly think your destiny
is being a temporary teacher.
Well, no one knows their
destiny except... God
or... a best-selling author.
Well, I just don't understand why
you don't something more permanent.
Permanence is temporary, Mother dear.
Well, I suppose there's
some truth in that, Mary.
The truth is relative.
- I guess I should let you go.
- You'll never let me go.
- Toodle-oo. I love you.
- Toodle-oo. I love you too.
Life is mostly froth and bubble.
Two things stand like stone...
kindness in another's trouble
and courage in your own.
What the author in this
book is trying to tell us,
that no matter what the most important
things in life are kindness and courage.
Who can tell me an example
of courage in their own lives?
- Miss Meadows, Miss Meadows!
- Gordon?
- Mrs. Meadows?
- It's Miss Meadows. Let's continue.
If you're a "miss," does that
mean you miss having a husband?
Well, that's one interpretation.
Although the other is that I prefer it
that way because I have all of you.
So who has an example for me?
Wow!
You thought of one, Heather?
Can I take a snack break now?
No, not yet. Can I help you
find an example of courage?
Well, Mrs. Dodd left us.
Well, Mrs. Dodd isn't here right now.
Miss Meadows is.
She's never coming back.
- Of course she is.
- No, she's not!
My grandma had the same
thing she does and she died.
I saw her in her coffin.
She looked like string cheese.
Well, it sounds like Mrs. Dodd
is an example of courage.
How about we make "get well soon"
cards for Mrs. Dodd
and I will personally see that she gets
them? Are we doing colored or plain?
- Plain. Colored!
- Plain... oh, my goodness!
Mrs. Dodd's got the Big C. Don't fill
those children's minds with false hope.
There are over 13 million cancer
survivors throughout the world.
The only thing false is
not having any hope.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes, for verification,
you can contact the
American Cancer Society.
Alright, Miss Meadows.
I've had it up to here with you.
Perhaps you're confusing me with the
scarf around your neck that's in danger
of becoming a tourniquet.
I shall return to Mrs. Dodd's class.
The children don't need any
more changes right now.
I shall give them as much
consistency as I can
which might serve to reassure
them in these troubled times.
- Go home. Your check's in the mail.
- I seriously doubt that.
I rarely receive any checks
through the mail. Toodle-oo.
- Good morning, Mrs. Davenport.
- Good morning, Miss Meadows.
Oh! Your garden looks especially
perky today. What's your secret?
Honestly, coffee grinds
and meticulous weeding.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Alright, I'm gonna have to try that.
I just have to say, Miss Meadows,
it is such a pleasure having
you in the neighbourhood.
Ever since you've moved here,
things just feel different.
For the better, I hope.
Oh, yes! I mean, it's a
pleasure to live here again.
I do hope you'll renew your
lease and stay for good.
Stay for good? Good to stay.
What doth the bluebird say?
Miss Meadows, a new
dentist joined Doug's practice
and he's available and we thought
we might fix you two up.
Thank you. But I
don't need a dentist.
Oh no, I just meant... well, I don't
want you to end up an old maid.
That's impossible.
I don't clean houses for a living.
And I have no intentions to
start domestication training.
- Okay.
- But thank you. Ooh...
Careful on the thorns. Toodle-oo.
Oh, it's okay.
Okay. No broken legs.
Good job. Yeah.
Excuse me, miss.
Hello, Sheriff.
Do you have any idea
why I pulled over?
Yes. I parked my vehicle illegally
in the middle of the road
which causes the same safety hazard
as leaving a vehicle unoccupied.
But I was concerned for
the safety of this toad.
And there was no on-street parking.
Do you think if I kissed it,
it would turn into a prince?
Maybe.
Or it'll just be one lucky toad.
This is a '56 Metropolitan Nash?
Yeah, it reminds me of an old
pair of saddle shoes I once had.
Reminds me of my
grandmother's kitchen floor.
- So clean you could eat dinner off it.
- I prefer a table setting.
Right.
Can you... one... don't move.
Do you think that's really true? That you
can make a difference in this world?
I think it's impossible not to try.
I feel the exact same way.
- What is it you do for a living?
- I teach kids.
- Oh, that's nice.
- My pleasure.
Alright, so I think
I'm gonna let you off
- with a warning this time, Miss...
- Meadows.
- Meadows. That's a beautiful name.
- Thank you.
Can I ask where you're from?
"Can ask" is if you're physically
able; "may ask" is permission.
Toodle-oo, Sheriff.
Ca...carry on.
I know it's hard but although
Mrs. Dodd has left this world
and is teaching in another,
we're never going to forget her, right?
And she's never going to
forget any one of you.
I can feel her spirit in this classroom
right now, especially if I close my eyes.
I see her.
She's wearing that blue dress.
She looks so pretty.
And she's smiling at all of you.
Do you see it?
- Yeah.
- Do you see her pretty smile?
Yeah.
See, we're starting to remember her.
If we do this every single day,
she'll always be with us.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
You're probably wondering why I
passed your cards back out?
I was thinking that we
should paste them, each one
to its own balloon,
and then one day,
we're going to release them.
Yeah.
- You said she'd come back.
- I know, sweetheart.
I was wrong. Sometimes
Miss Meadows...
Lie! You lied!
Heather. Excuse me, children.
Why don't you get started?
Heather, sweetheart.
Heather, sweetheart. Heather.
Come here, come here. Heather.
It's okay, sweetie. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
All the bad people stay
and all the good ones die.
I hate the world.
It's a terrible place.
I know. Sometimes it
is but not all the time.
And it's our responsibility...
to make it a better place.
Hey, Miss Meadows, do you
want to come to Happy Hour?
Hey, Katharine.
I don't see how Happy Hour will
make much of a difference...
- Bye, Miss Meadows. I like your outfit.
- Well, thank you. Have a good afternoon.
Toodle-oo.
Miss Meadows.
- May I?
- Sheriff.
An absolutely splendid edition
that is essential to all.
If this doesn't make
you proper, nothing will.
Thank you.
I've always wanted my own copy.
A sentence contains
no unnecessary words,
a paragraph no unnecessary sentences.
Make every word tell.
I would like to take you
for an afternoon spin
in my 1970 classic
Chevrolet pickup truck.
I would like that very much.
How, may I ask,
do you know where I work?
I ran your plate.
Your work address came up. I...
- That's illegal.
- Yes, it is. I feel really bad.
I just... I couldn't stop thinking
about this girl
in the middle of the
road holding a toad.
Dead right, I'm sorry. I apologize
to you. I broke the rules.
I think it's okay to break
the rules sometimes.
Good.
You tell your kids that?
What?
That it's okay to break
the rules sometimes?
Well, I remind them
of their goodness.
How to...
protect themselves if they're around
someone that they don't think is good.
I like that.
Listen, if kids aren't safe, if they
don't feel safe, we're all lost.
- I like the rain.
- Why?
Makes me feel clean.
I bought this property
a few years ago.
And right here, this is where I figured
I would build a house one day.
- Do you have a contractor's license?
- No, I don't have a contractor's license
but I will hire someone
to help me, so thank you.
Butterscotch or liquorice?
Sheriff, what may I ask made you
choose law enforcement as your career?
- Fear.
- Of what?
It's a career choice motivated by the
soul-numbing fear that I might end up
- like the rest of my family.
- What does that mean?
Are you familiar with
the term convicts?
So you have bad blood.
I don't know if I'd call it that.
Why did you start teaching?
- I'm asking you the questions.
- Oh, really? Okay.
So what's your second...
career choice?
- You have to promise not to laugh.
- No.
No?
- You want me to take a risk?
- Yes, please.
Professional accordion player.
Why?
Why not? I think it has
this obscure beauty.
It's misunderstood.
Did you know that the accordion is
the second least-appreciated musical
instrument
right ahead of the bagpipe and right
behind the dead-kitten flute?
No, I did not know that
until right this very moment.
- What may I ask are you doing?
- I'm dancing to your accordion.
I'm not that good.
It's a work in progress.
Isn't everything?
Thank you for the... the spin
and the snack.
You're very welcome.
Miss Meadows.
Yes?
- May I...
- Yes.
Right.
That's gonna cover that
top window pane, right?
- Yep.
- The top and the bottom.
Mrs. Davenport, what are you doing?
Oh, better safe than sorry.
I'm sorry you don't feel safe. I thought
you said the neighbourhood had improved.
Haven't you been reading
the newspapers?
The Department of Corrections
released nearly 2000 prisoners
over the last six months
because of "overcrowding."
Now they can only account
for 800 of them.
Some say that they've moved
right into this very neighbourhood.
My Doug says that
it's unconstitutional
to try and stop them.
He says it's the law.
Well... you can't live in fear.
Oh, Miss Meadows.
You're so young and naive.
I dare say I'm neither.
I just appear that way.
I hate to say this but I would not
walk around the neighbourhood
in such lovely outfits.
You make yourself a target.
Mrs. Davenport, I don't
change my style for anyone.
Toodle-oo.
Yes, Toodle-oo to you, too.
Oh, dear.
So, I leave you, my friends,
with a question from Luke.
Who are our neighbours?
Let's then ask ourselves,
how can we serve them better?
Isn't that the example we
want to give our children?
Go in peace to love
and serve the Lord.
- Hello, Sheriff.
- Miss Meadows.
Much as I was looking forward
to seeing you, I never imagined
I'd see you here.
- Are you Catholic?
- No.
No, thank you.
I like singing in choirs.
You?
Recovering. My grandmother used
to take me here when I was a kid.
I used to get kicked out all the time.
And she sat me down
and reminded me that she's the only
one in the family not going to hell.
And that if I played my cards right,
she'd take me along with her
which I think is quite
morbid, actually. Anyway,
I promised her I'd just show up.
You kept your promise.
I don't make them if
I can't keep them.
I can still taste your kiss.
Make a wish.
- Is it okay?
- Yeah.
Is that good?
- Look at me.
- I'm sorry.
- It feels good.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Look at me.
- Okay.
Do you think repeat criminal
offenders can be rehabilitated?
Is this your idea of pillow talk?
Pillows don't talk.
Just... just...
- Sorry.
- Okay.
Come here. Come here.
So do you?
Do I?
I believe in second chances.
I believe in trying but rehabilitation
didn't work for my father.
So why do you do what you do?
Okay, why don't we keep
business out of the bedroom?
Because the law is
everybody's business.
Is it? Is it?
Is the law everybody's
responsibility?
- I don't know.
- Yeah.
Look at this vigilante case I'm working on.
Part of me admires the guy.
But you're never gonna get me to say it out
loud because it's not politically correct.
You know, "politically
correct" is for politicians.
And there are bad
people in the world.
And they shouldn't be
around the good people.
Especially the little ones.
You're amazing.
You look amazing. You are amazing.
That was amazing.
Can I ask a question, Miss Meadows?
- Sure.
- Was that amazing for you?
Sheriff,
there are certain things that a lady
doesn't... tell a gentleman.
You do have manners.
Don't you, Miss Meadows?
What would the world be without them?
We'll never forget you, Mrs. Dodd!
She's an angel up
there now. Isn't she?
Yes, she certainly is.
Would you be our teacher for the
rest of the year, Miss Meadows?
- Oh, no, I'm just your substitute.
- Why don't you stay?
Can we have our snack now?
Yes.
I think that we all have earned a treat.
I'm gonna go get us some hot dogs.
You guys stay with Miss Katherine.
Play nicely. I expect good manners.
Hi, I'd like to order
16 Top Dogs, please.
Hello.
I want to die.
- I think you should.
- What?
You're of no use to society. You'll
waste innocent taxpayers' dollars,
abuse the weak legal system and
enter a cowardly plea of insanity
to a morally bankrupt
defense attorney. For what?
Oh, and once incarcerated, you're gonna cost
taxpayers approximately $47,000 per year.
So you know what? Make sure you point the
barrel of the gun to the back of the throat.
- I think I've changed my mind.
- That is so not an option.
- Never fear, Miss Meadows is here.
- Where's our hot dogs?
Oh, well, Top Dog is experiencing
some unforeseen problems
and when it does, it's important to
have another plan to fall back on.
You know, when one path is blocked,
we simply walk down another path. Right?
- Yes.
- And that's what hope is.
Hope is usually...
right around the corner. Just like that
ice cream truck. Ice cream for everyone!
- Hey, you.
- Hi.
What kind of flavour
are you gonna get?
Same kind as you, Miss Meadows.
Miss Meadows, when I grow up,
I want to be just like you.
- Please don't say that, sweetheart.
- Why not?
Well, because you should aspire
to be your own individual.
You know, grow up and
have your own unique traits.
And secret ways, too?
- Pardon me?
- I can keep a secret, Miss Meadows.
But children shouldn't have secrets.
And they shouldn't keep them.
But you spilled something
on your dress.
What?
But you spilled something on
your dress, Miss Meadows.
I guess I did.
I dislike that very much.
How about we get some ice cream?
Miss Meadows needs some
ice cream right now.
- Yay!
- Yeah, let's do it.
- What's his name?
- Frank.
- Hi, Frankie.
- I said his name is Frank.
Children, we mustn't approach
animals that we don't know. Come on.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Always let them come to you.
Always let them come to you.
- Mike.
- Yo.
- Heads up.
- What?
Nice catch.
Hey listen, we've been compiling the case
information from the other jurisdictions
and we've got a composite
on the vigilante.
And it looks like some kind of a...
Pulp Fiction Mary Poppins.
Now, personally I'm not buying
that a woman is pulling all this off.
I mean, not that they're not capable
of it. Clearly Michelle is batshit
before her period comes.
- Danny, thank you.
- You got it.
And can I get the ball back?
Thought I taught
you better than that.
Good afternoon, Sheriff.
Miss Meadows.
How you doing?
You look beautiful.
I got you something.
Wow. I love yellow.
I hope so. I stole it
from your front yard.
So I thought maybe we could talk?
- Yeah, it's a lovely day.
- It is a lovely day.
And this is a lovely door.
You always wear those on your shoes?
Yeah.
Oh, this needs some work.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. You?
Good, yes. I'm fine. I'm just asking...
there was a shooting near the school
today.
And civilians were massacred.
The alleged shooter was killed also.
- Excellent.
- Excellent? That's a good thing?
Yeah.
Wait, I'm... I'm confused, Sheriff.
You just said that
civilians were killed.
What's the concern over
how the shooter died?
Oh, no. My concern is about you.
There was an ice cream vendor
who said there was
children from your school there right
around the time of the shooting.
- Vanilla chocolate chip.
- Excuse me?
That's my favourite flavour and
they said that they will have it
restocked by tomorrow.
- What's your favourite?
- Vanilla chocolate chip.
Then maybe we could
go together sometime.
- I'd like that. Do you like cones?
- Yeah.
Good. I like the cones.
I feel a little goofy
when I'm walking down the street
holding one but the uniform helps.
Where did you live
before you moved here?
- Somewhere else.
- Like Dayton?
No. I didn't like Dayton.
So you did live there.
Why do you want to know?
Well, there was just other
vigilante-style killings there
and I thought maybe
- you'd heard of them.
- Nope.
No.
I moved here five and
a half months ago.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
There are a lot of things
I'm not telling you, Sheriff.
Elements of Style's 17th instruction
recommends to omit...
needless words.
Okay.
Sheriff, can you do me a
favour please? I want to know
if any of the newly released convicts
have moved into this neighbourhood.
- Why?
- For the school, for the kids.
And I've seen someone lurking
about and he makes me...
- uncomfortable.
- Okay, who?
- Someone said anything to you?
- No.
- Nothing's happened?
I'll look into it.
I should go back to...
work, so...
You're killing me.
I can't sleep at night.
Toodle-oo.
You're a vital young woman.
Don't worry.
A mother never stops her worry.
- Is it fair?
- What's that, Miss Meadows?
To bring a child into this world?
I tell all my patients, if you make your
home a loving, stable environment,
that's all a child needs to thrive.
- How big is it?
- About the size of your thumbnail.
Wait.
Toodle-oo.
Frank, shut up.
Frank, I said shut up!
Sit down!
That's him. I've seen him
walking with his dog.
He was convicted of
felony child abuse.
That's a nice purse
you have, by the way.
Thank you.
My mother says a lady never leaves home
without her accessories. I agree with her.
You don't talk about your
mother much. What's she like?
Peanut brittle. Maybe artichokes.
In that rare exception, a clean
public restroom, which I agree with.
- Miss Meadows?
- Yes.
- May I ask you a question?
- Sure.
What do you do when
you're not working?
My hobbies. You know, my gardening.
Takes a lot of time.
And knitting, and sometimes I paint.
And then there's my volunteer work.
Can you be a little more
vague, maybe? Today.
What did you do when
you got off work today?
Sheriff,
I went to the fabric store, and I
got some yarn and knitting needles.
And I started making a blanket.
A baby blanket... for our baby.
Why didn't you tell me?
I just did.
Do you know what this means?
Yeah. I don't... I don't know.
Look at me.
Miss Meadows...
I want you to marry me.
Me?
Yes, you.
- You don't know me.
- I know everything I need to know.
I'll take care of you.
It would be the highest honor of
my life to protect you and this child.
Really?
Please.
Yes.
Yes!
Sheriff...
Miss Meadows?
You know marriage has
a certain... ring to it.
You know, a wedding ring,
engagement ring...
suffer-ring.
Oh, you have a very
strange sense of humor.
- You think I have a sense of humor?
- I do think you have a sense of humor.
- You think I'm funny?
- I think you're strangely funny.
Mother?
I met someone.
And he has... kind eyes.
- Just like Grandpa did, remember?
- What are little boys made of?
Frogs and snails and puppy dog tails.
Well, he's not a boy.
He says he's a man.
- That's what they all say.
- Was I a good baby, mother?
Mary... you were a perfect baby.
Mother...
When did I become...
- less perfect?
- You were always perfect to me.
When did I start to realize
that the world was...
A rotting cesspool of
decay and mediocrity?
I'd have to say that was when that awful
Mr. Redding tried to bomb the mall.
- I thought it was when Uncle Clybert...
- Oh, no. It was years later, honey.
And it was before I found Mrs. Hartford
hanging from the theater rafters.
Oh, I still think that was a shame.
She has such a beautiful singing voice.
Or maybe it was...
All... through... the town...
The wipers on the bus go
swish, swish, swish...
Swish, swish, swish...
The wipers on the bus go
swish, swish, swish...
All... through... the town...
- I did it.
- Of course you did.
- You can do anything.
- I can?
Hey, come here.
Mary? Mary?
Are you still there?
Mother, I have to go.
- Where are you off to now, my love?
- I'm going to have tea with a neighbour.
Oh, very good, dear.
Remember, mind your manners.
Our time we must not idly waste,
since all our hours fly off in haste.
With each new minute I strive to
fill my seven new acts of duty still.
- Toodle-oo, I love you.
- Toodle-oo, I love you too.
You.
- Hello.
I brought some tea and crumpets.
Really? That's nice.
You have no idea how
much that means, Miss?
- Meadows.
- Won't you come in, Miss Meadows.
Please.
You'll have to, excuse the house.
I'm still settling in.
- Did you just move to town?
- Yes, just like you, right?
No, I've lived here for months.
Me too.
This is so thoughtful. To be honest,
I haven't made a lot of friends yet.
First of all, I wanted to say...
that I try to approach...
every situation...
- hoping for the best.
- What a lovely way to think.
And I certainly do hope
that you respect the...
peaceful and safe ways that this
community works so hard at,
and they've come to cherish it.
I'm looking forward to it.
And I also want you to know that I
know exactly who and what you are,
and should you harm anyone,
or any child, you will be killed.
What did you just say?
I said you will be killed.
And just... who's going to kill me?
- I am.
- You?
Miss Meadows, have no fear. Your message
was received loud and clear.
Good.
That was my intention.
I have to say... we're two peas
in a pod,
- and we have a lot in common.
- We have nothing in common.
- Actually...
- So now that you've come to visit me,
I think I should pay you a
visit at the school sometime.
That is not a good idea.
It won't end well for you.
- Gosh, that sounds like a threat.
- I do not make threats.
I make promises. And only
promises that I intend to keep.
Where are my manners?
Here you are in my house,
and I've not even properly introduced
myself. My name is Skylar.
I don't care to know your name.
Well, now, who's
forgotten their manners?
What gives you the right to come into my
house, threatening, making accusations,
when I haven't done anything wrong?
That's illegal, Miss Meadows.
The truth is not illegal.
Hey.
You have no idea what it's like
to have to start over again.
- I most certainly do.
- Are you forgetting something?
My therapist says I have to take
care of myself and my needs
before I can be good for
anyone else. Do you have one?
Because... and please don't
take this personally...
I think you could really use one. And I
would be happy to make a recommendation,
because... you shouldn't wait.
Toodle-oo.
Hey, you.
Even though this is Sunday,
what we discuss in here applies
to every day, Louie.
- Miss Meadows?
- Yes?
How come Jesus looks like a
fashion model in that picture,
but, like, any better in
my Aunt Bea's bedroom.
Well, since Jesus was a
Jew and came from Israel,
my guess is that he looked like
neither one of those paintings.
Those paintings were most probably
done by... an idealistic painter.
- Oh, look at him!
- He's so cute!
He looks like he's
about two years old.
That's 16 in a dog life.
Too old for this class.
We were discussing how every day is
Sunday, in terms of how we live, right?
Hey, William, what are
you drawing a picture of?
I don't know.
- You don't want to join the other kids?
- I don't know.
Are you feeling okay?
Why does Jesus say to turn the
other cheek when someone hits you?
Because he's saying that
that's preferable to fighting.
But what if you do turn it, and then he,
like, punches that one too?
Miss Meadows has an idea.
How about an early cookie break?
Special one for you.
Amber? I think it's your turn.
You're doing a very nice job.
You're so quiet. One cookie
each, alright? Ooh.
Beautiful.
You know you can tell
me anything, right?
Are you sure you ran into that wall?
- I have to prepare at church for mass.
- What are you talking about? It's over.
Papa Peter says I have to be there.
He doesn't like it if I'm late.
He says it's a sin!
Stop it! Stop!
- Father!
- The Lord ask that we not judge.
I think he asks more of us than that.
How dare you? How dare you?
- I do God's work!
- Don't you touch him!
- Get out of my bed.
- Boo!
Is that a toy gun?
Guns are not toys, sweetie.
That was a... secret toy?
Heather, I'm so sorry.
I hope I didn't frighten you.
Never fear... Miss Meadows is here.
- How did you get here?
- I walked.
It was only a couple of blocks.
I wanted to surprise you.
And how did you get in my bed?
It was easy. I just crawled
through the window.
You don't have ugly
bars like everyone else.
Miss Meadows?
Can I...
May I... be your flower girl?
- Flower girl?
- Please? Oh, please!
Okay, okay.
I want you to be happy.
If you want to be my flower girl,
- you can be my flower girl.
- It'll be so much fun!
We'll be like best friends.
I could tell you my secrets,
because I already know yours.
Secrets?
- Miss Meadows has a secret.
- What are you talking about?
If I told you, it wouldn't
be a secret anymore.
You have to tell me. It'll be
a secret between you and me.
If I tell you, can I still
be your flower girl?
Yes!
Only if you tell me.
I saw you kill that man.
What?
- What man?
- In the Top Dog.
I forgot to tell you I
wanted relish on my hotdog,
and I went to the window, and I saw.
You're just a little girl.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so, so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry. I'm very, very sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I still saw. It's okay.
I have to go home now, for dinner.
Why do you lock that
one twice, Miss Meadows?
Sometimes Miss Meadows
can be so... silly.
It's not silly to be scared,
Miss Meadows.
I'm not scared of anything.
Can I wear gloves like you do?
Yes. Come on.
- Hello, Mary.
- Hey, Mommy.
I had a feeling you might call.
Mom... Mom, I'm scared.
I think I might...
I might call the police.
- The police?
- Yeah.
Mary, how many times must I tell you?
We must never rely on others to
do what we know must be done.
We have to take it upon ourselves
to right the wrongs of this world.
If a woman's tongue is her sword,
just think what her body can do.
But...
our bodies can bring new life, right?
I mean, that too, right?
- Right?
- Sometimes.
It can also take it away.
- Isn't that up to God?
- Oh, Mary, here you go again.
We don't want to rely on
the overburdened heavens
to give everyone their
retribution, now, do we?
Mom...
Mom, I almost...
I'm gonna have a...
I'm gonna have a baby.
Me. I'm gonna... I'm gonna
have a baby.
I'm gonna have a...
I'm gonna have a wedding!
Are we supposed to forgive everyone?
Mommy...
Not everyone, my love.
Some things are unforgivable.
Today, we bid our dear
Mother Meadows goodbye.
Lost to another act
of senseless, random violence.
She leaves behind her pride and joy.
Little Mary. Let us all pray
for good to triumph over evil,
and let us pray that some thing
or someone will guide us on.
So am I... am I always gonna be
the black sheep?
- Yes, dear.
- Okay. But I don't want to be.
Oh, now, now... there, there...
Just remember... black sheep
are still lambs.
Mommy? Mother?
I miss you.
But I'm gonna let you go now.
I'm gonna let you go now.
- Hey, Mike?
- Yeah.
- Got your ballistics report.
- Great.
- Looks like we got a match.
- Right on.
The truck driver and the Top
Dog kid, and now the priest,
all with a .25 caliber short-barreled
pistol. Same gun.
- Okay.
- Oh, and there's this.
It appears Father Peter
was a serial child molester.
And now a bunch of kids are coming
forward claiming sexual abuse.
Nobody misses a pervert. If you
ask me, this guy's lucky he's dead.
Anyway. Oh, hey, we got
the wedding invitations too.
- That didn't take long, did it?
- I guess when you know, you know.
- Danny.
- Yeah.
Was there anything about Michelle
that would've been a deal breaker?
Maybe if she was a Steelers fan.
That probably would've done it.
The baby has grown since
I started making this.
I had to let out the seam.
Can you tell?
I think you look beautiful.
Thanks.
Is your mother coming to the wedding?
My mother doesn't like weddings.
You don't think she'll make
an exception this time?
No.
What mother doesn't want to see
her daughter walk down the aisle?
Mine.
What happened to your shoe?
Oh, it lost a tap.
I found this one.
Oh! I've been looking all over
for this. Where did you find it?
It was at the church.
I am gonna just put
that on right now.
Thank you.
Dammit, it's not fitting.
Yeah. That's right.
Because it's not real.
What are you talking about?
It's not real.
None of it is.
Let's stop pretending, okay?
Okay, now, let's stop pretending,
and let's tell the truth, you and I.
Because I know.
I know.
I've been covering.
I've been denying the obvious,
because I would do anything
for you. Anything.
So I need you to do something for me.
I need you to promise me you're
going to stop this. Okay?
I can't promise you that.
- Do you want cream or sugar?
- What happened to you?
You can tell me. You can tell me anything.
If you don't want to tell me,
that's fine too. I'm here. But I
don't know what made you this way.
And I just need you
to stop all this insanity.
It's not insane!
What I do is not insane.
You gotta be kidding me. You're walking
around with a gun in your purse.
I don't know what you're
talking about anymore.
I don't understand
anything you're saying.
You can't talk to me like
a normal human being.
You think I want to do this?
No one else is doing it!
I see that. I'm aware of that.
I mean, it's like the wolf
says to the lion...
Okay, no. No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop.
You can't talk to me like this anymore.
Just talk to me like a normal person.
- I'm trying, okay?
- If you keep doing this...
we're gonna get married
in federal prison.
I don't want to, but I'll do it.
I'll come visit you.
But if you stop...
If you can stop, I can bury this.
Okay? But I need you to say that you
promise me you will never do this again.
I need to know that
you're here with me also.
Can you promise me?
- Yes.
- Yes?
- Yeah.
- You can?
- I promise you.
- Okay.
- Okay, good. Good, good, good.
- I'll...
- Sheriff?
- Yes.
I'll try.
I will try.
Here you go.
She's got quite a...
following.
Oh, Miss Meadows, you look so pretty.
Thank you. You look beautiful.
Can I see you twirl in that dress?
Wow!
What about your hair?
You should have a flower in it?
- You don't think the veil is enough.
- You need a flower too, for the baby.
What a sweet thought. You know, there is
one single white rose in the back garden.
I'll get it, and then we'll
leave for the church, okay?
Not in your dress. I'll do it.
Oh, no, sweetie, there's thorns.
I'll get it in a second.
I'm a big girl, Miss Meadows.
Besides, I have gloves on. See?
Okay. Go ahead, but be careful.
- Thank you for your help.
- You're welcome.
Heather, it's okay.
I think the veil is enough.
You know, I just remembered that my mom
said it's bad luck to pick the last flower,
and I have this whole bouquet
right here. I'll save it for the baby.
I just don't want to be late.
Heather?
Heather? Heather?!
Heather!
- Miss Meadows!
- I got you, sweetie.
Late on your first day. And a
tad overdressed, but oh, well.
- Stop, stop, stop. Give me that.
- No! No!
I will cut your throat. Now,
no offense, Miss Meadows,
but you do tend to
over-accessorize.
Sheriff? She's never late.
Never ever.
You wouldn't let me
come to your school.
So I thought I'd bring you to mine.
- I thought you said you changed.
- I did, and then I changed back.
And that's what the system gets
for kicking a kid out of school.
You can't teach an
empty seat, can you?
You know what they say, you spare
the rod, you spoil the child.
- I don't agree with...
- Nobody cares! You're in my classroom!
So you can shut up, okay?
He says he's a teacher,
but I don't believe him.
That's 'cause he's pretending.
He likes pretend, just like you.
Just like Miss Meadows.
Now, Heather, shall we
continue where we left off?
Well, come on. Be excited!
I honestly do not know how
you do this all day long.
Go, go! Go come on, let's go!
We're gonna go come on.
Run, Heather, run!
- Get off me.
- Stop it! Sit down!
- Get off me!
- Sit down. Sit down...
That's it. There we go. There we go.
You really think you could just go
off and live happily ever after,
while the rest of us struggle to
carve out any version of a life?
I'm assuming that's
rhetorical question?
You think you're so
much better than me.
You think you're perfect.
You wanna know something?
We're exactly the same.
Exactly.
Help! Help!
He's got Miss Meadows!
No! No! No! No!
- Give it here!
- No! No, give it to me! Give it to me!
Give me my purse! Give it to me!
What's got you in such a fuss?
What have we got here?
- That's why you're so excited.
- No.
- Is this thing real?
- It's not real. It's not real.
- Really? Really? Is it? Is it?
- No, it's not.
Oh, yes, it is real!
- Don't do this.
- Crazy, arrogant...
I am not crazy! You are crazy,
and I'm nothing like you!
You really think you
can save the world?
How about you try
saving yourself first?
No! No!
- Is that your gun?
- Yes.
That's great. That's his prints now.
You can have some.
Dinner's gonna be late.
It won't take long.
Mommy has to go,
but she always comes back.
If others need what I can spare,
I must with them my treasures share.
Bye.
- Be careful.
- I always am.
Toodle-oo.
SubText: NoRMITA.326