JOE NAVARRO ON CD PLAYER:
Number 11.
Some players increase
their chatter when nervous or anxious-
This usually happens with extroverts,
who End great comfort
in babbling to reduce tension-
Number 12.
Furrowing of the forehead.
Furrowing of the forehead
is a good indicator
that something is amiss
or the person is insecure.
It is also seen when
people are concentrating
or trying to make sense of something.
It is usually associated with
doubt, weakness, or concern.
Number 13. Sneaking a nose touch.
Sneaking a pacifying touch
by ever so slightly
rubbing the nose with the index Hngen..
(CD sTol=>s)
Hey, Gerry. Good luck tonight.
-Hey, Louise.
-Hey, Gerry.
How's the knee?
Ugh_.. it's getting there.
Good luck.
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
-MAN: Hey, Gerry.
-Hey.
Hey, Chuck.
How'd you do on Saturday?
(PLAYERS CHATTERING)
KATE: Anyone know the spread
on the Hawkeyes game?
Six points.
CLIFFORD: Getting warm out there.
LARRY: Yeah, it's just weather.
CLIFFORD: What does that mean,
"It's just weather"?
LARRY: Warm, cold. "It'sjustweather, baby."
KATE: (LAUGHS) l like that.
"It's just weather, baby."
CLIFFORD: Yeah, well, it's just poker, baby.
-How's that? You like that one?
-(KATE CHUCKLES)
Anyone see that rainbow yesterday?
Table seven looks like heaven.
How is everybody feeling tonight?
That's okay by me.
Let's play some cards, huh?
Iowa.
CURTIS: Hit me with some Iowa trivia.
Tell me something I don't know.
-Like what?
-Aces are good, right?
You're out. I'm in.
DEALER: Raise. 600 total.
-Call.
-DEALER: Call.
Heads up.
CLIFFORD: Aces, huh?
Fold.
CURTIS: Thank you very much.
Anybody over here need any drinks?
-Bloody Mary.
-Bourbon.
-What is the bourbon?
-It's just the cheap stuff.
Make mine a Woodford.
-Um, I'm not sure we have...
-Hey, friend, you want a Woodford?
-Oh, no, no, no...
-Bring him a Woodford, too.
-No, no, no, cheap stuff's fine with me.
-Thank you.
It's fine. I got it, I got it.
My old buddy, Tony Roundtree__.
Does anybody know Tony?
Hosts a high rollers game
every other month in New Orleans.
Anyway, I knew him up in Detroit.
-You from Detroit?
-IVle? No.
I'm from all over,
but I knew Tony Roundtree up at Detroit.
This guy, he loved to play poker,
but he kept dodging
my invitations to play in the casinos.
Apparently Tony, he had a little bit of
a gambling problem before I met him.
You guys know about
the disassociated persons list?
You have that in Iowa?
Okay, well, in some states,
you can put yourself on this list
if you're trying to quit gambling. Right?
Which means that you are legally banned
from all casinos in the state.
-For life.
-CURTIS: For life.
Right, so, you know what I'm talking about,
right? Makes sense, right?
Well... (CHUCKLES) Not to Tony.
He puts himself on this list
to show his girlfriend
that he was serious
about changing his ways.
Well, couple of months go by
and, of course,
she dumps him. For a guitar player.
-It's always a guitar player.
-It is always a guitar player, isn't it?
-Why is that?
-Nice hands.
So, he's... He's lonely,
he's depressed and he starts getting the itch
to play poker again.
Walks into MGM... "Sorry, buddy."
Goes over to Greektownu.
"No can do, amigo- ”
Motor City... "No dice, pal."
What does he do?
-Disguise.
-CURTIS: Yes! He puts on a disguise.
-Yeah.
-(GERRY LAuGHING)
Sunglasses, a fake mustache, a wig.
-(MEN LAUGHING)
-KATE: Come on, a wig?
CURTIS: He walks right through the doors,
blows past Security,
sits down at the poker table,
and he is in heaven.
-He is...
-We didn't have Woodford.
So sorry about that, that is our top shelf.
-it's Bulleit bourbon.
-All right.
-I'm not paying for his, though.
-Excuse me?
I said his Woodford is on me
and that's not a Woodford.
I'm just kidding, I'm kidding, lady.
-l'm_.. I'm joking. Here, come on.
-(ALL LAUGHING)
-Here you go. Thank you, keep the change.
-Very cute.
All right, here, good luck to you, my friend.
Thank you, thank you.
Better than the cheap shit, right?
GERRY: Hey, Dale.
DALE: Hey, Gerry, how'd it go tonight?
Yeah, not bad. Placed third.
DALE: Congrats! What's the payout on that?
$900.
-What's the score?
-Not sure.
Have a seat.
The usual for you?
Uh, actually, do you have Woodford?
-We have that.
-(LAUGHS)
-Yeah.
-Come on, let's get one of those.
Let's get a Woodford.
Okay, Oregon is up by six.
That's not bad. That's okay.
-How much you got on this?
-Uh... $900.
-It's a Woodford kind of night.
-What's that mean?
That guy right there shooting darts,
he likes it, too.
GERRY: Hey! Woodford man!
Next one, on me.
Poker man! I'm Curtis.
Curtis? Nice, like, uh, Tony?
-No, like Mayfield. Curtis Mayfield. Yeah.
-Oh!
-Okay, I'm Gerry.
-Like Lewis?
-No.
-Jerry Lewis.
No, Gerry.
Gerald. Like Ford, I guess.
-How did it go for you tonight?
-Uh, not bad.
-What's not bad?
-Second.
Get outta here, that's great.
Could have been first.
Could have been first if you didn't bully me
out of that mountain before you left.
I can never last through
those tournaments. I...
-Why'd you buy in?
-I like people.
Yeah? (LAUGHING)
You should have stuck around,
you're a good player.
For a few hours, maybe,
but I don't have the stamina for poker.
-Oh, yeah?
-I get restless.
So, what's your game? What do you like?
-Darts.
-Darts? Any good?
-I can hit the board, sure.
-IVlmm-hmm.
I gotta ask.
-What... Yeah.
-What was I holding? Yeah.
Pair of deuces_
-Really? That's all?
-That's it. That's all.
Shit!
'Cause I'm usually good at reading people.
But you're all over the map.
-I can't spot your tell. Yeah.
-You want to know why?
-I don't care about winning.
-Oh, that's bullshit.
-No...
-No, that's...
I just like to play, I really do.
Did you see...
Hey, did you see that rainbow yesterday?
-GERRY: Oh, yeah. That was beautiful.
-Gorgeous.
Wasn't that the most fucking...
-I mean, that rainbow was beautiful.
-CURTIS: Best rainbow ever.
How come I've never seen you before?
-Just passing through.
-Where you headed?
-New Orleans.
-Oh, man, I love New Orleans!
-IVle too.
-Oh...
You're going to your
friend's home gig, right?
Tony Roundtree?
No, I don't have that kind of money.
-Then why?
-What do you mean?
What, you're just heading down
to New Orleans for the hell of it?
-Yeah, pretty much.
-(SCOFFS)
-That sounds all right.
-it's all right with me.
-Dale!
GERRY: He just sits there staring at me,
staring at me.
"Okay, buddy. Pick a card."
Oh, I see, either of these cards...
(STAMMERS)
BOTH: 'Cause whichever card he turns over,
he's gonna think it's a full boat!
-(LAuGHING)
-Yeah!
-Oh, that's beautiful.
-(KNOCKING ON TABLE)
Yeah, it really was. (CHUCKLES)
Okay, um, heads or tails?
CURTIS: Tails.
Yeah, again. All right, hold on.
(lvluTTERING)
-And... Call it.
-Tails.
(Com CLATTERS)
Where did you come from?
(LAuGHING)
GERRYZ NO! NO!
(CHAIR scRAl=>lNG)
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY ON T\/)
CURTIS: Hey, Denise,
do you have any coconut oil?
I have lotion.
Uh... Never mind.
So, um, you're his, uh...
DENISE: Just friends.
-Thanks for the couch.
-You want breakfast?
CURTIS: Dog races start at 1:00.
-GERRYI What time is it?
-9230.
Oh, Shit. Shit.
-CURTIS: What's wrong?
-I have work.
-You have a job?
-Yeah.
-Where'd I park the car?
-Hey, look at this.
You see that?
Look who's running
in the sixth race, Dynamic Rainbow.
Is that not our dog?
Look me in the eye
and tell me that's not our dog.
-That's a good name.
-It's a great name!
(GROANS)
HSFS.
Go on. Count it.
-GERRY: Oh, no, that's okay.
-Come on, it's all right.
Trusting a stranger, Gerry.
It's just one of those things.
I think that I'm finally starting to
understand what you guys are after.
And I think you're gonna
find this is a real winner.
Real winner.
Sorry about this, folks.
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Well, even still, there's not
much counter space.
(MAN RESPONDING INDISTINCTLY)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I am on my way.
CURTIS: Ah, that's beautiful. Beautiful.
Do you want me to place a bet for you?
They're saying that Dynamic Rainbow
has got 48-to-1 odds.
That's terrible.
That is what makes it fun, Gerry.
I'm laying 50 to win.
What do you want to do?
48-to-1? Geez, I don't know.
Don't stress, baby, it's just dogs.
NAVARRO ON CD PLAYER:
Number 9. Nodding and...
You know what?
Put me down for 200 to place.
All right, got it.
(SINGING) Dynamic Rainbow
Dynamic Rainbow
-(BELL RINGING)
-ANNOUNCER: Here comes Casey.
GERRY: Which one is it?
CURTIS: Number four.
Dynamic Rainbow, number four,
in the green, here we go!
Come on, Rainbow! Come on, Rainbow!
(BOTH SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Go, Dynamic Rainbow!
-Beautiful...
-Look, look, look, look, look!
-Let's go, Rainbow! Come on.
-GERRY: Oh, yeah!
-Yeah! He's bringing it up!
-Come on, Rainbow.
Pick it up! Come on, Rainbow!
Go, Rainbow!
ANNOUNCER: Around the turn,
coming down the home stretch to the wire.
GERRY: Who do we got? Who do we got?
Who do we got?
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
ANNOUNCER: Dynamic Rainbow at the wire!
-We won!
-(BELL RINGING)
CURTIS: Of course we won.
You're damn right, we won!
Oh, fuck, I'm an idiot.
-I'm an idiot. I bet to place!
-Oh, easy, you know what you had?
-I should have listened to you.
-You still won big, buddy...
Come on, we just won a whole bunch of
money. Let's go... Let's go celebrate.
We'll have, uh, some drinks,
we'll meet some ladies...
Oh, no, I love this place.
We can get drinks here.
-We can meet ladies here, I'm sure.
-(LAUGHING)
Gerry, come on,
it don't get any better than this. Right?
-Let's go, let's go have some fun...
-We just got here.
Okay, hold on. Tell you what, tell you what...
Next guy that comes out of the bathroom...
-If he's wearing glasses...
-No, no, no!
-We stay, if he's wearing glasses.
-No.
-It's just... It's just...
-You're on.
Yes!
I'll tell you what, Gerry, never bet on a dog
named after a disabled president.
-I thought it was Teddy.
-Rollin' Roosevelt?
-It's a good name.
-No, no, it was not a good name.
-(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-Next time you quit when I tell you it's time.
So, there was this guy back
in Kansas City, Archie Hannahan.
-Never knew when to quit.
-Oh, yeah, yeah.
I think I know where this story's going.
-You don't have to tell me.
-Hey, listen. Listen, Gerry.
-Okay.
-Archie, he owed
every poker player in town at least a
three... At least 300 bucks minimum.
And it got to a point where
he was asking his little nephews
for change out of their piggy banks.
I see him in Harrah's poker room
one day and I walk over to say hello.
I see that he's got a handsome
pile of chips in front of him, over 5 grand.
Archie starts bragging
that he started the night with just 60 bucks,
60 bucks that he borrowed
from some new chump, by the way.
So, I pull him aside,
and I say, "Hey, listen, cash out now."
He's got enough there
to pay back everybody he owes
and still get a slab at
Oklahoma Joe's. Right?
(IN SHRILL VOICE)
"You're right, you're right," he says.
"I'll stop as soon as
the blind comes around."
-(CHUCKLING) Did he talk like that?
-Like a ball of helium, yeah.
So, I feel good about myself, right?
I'm smiling, I go back to my table.
I'm thinking I've done a good deed here.
The next thing I hear
is Archie's high-pitched
screaming voice saying,
"I'm all in!"
And he lost everything, right?
-Of course he lost everything.
-Yeah.
But you know what he says to me?
He says, "Don't worry, it was just 60 bucks."
Some guys are born to lose.
-You play? Pool. You play?
-Hmm?
Oh, yeah. Not in a long time.
CURTIS: Hey, hey, hey!
20 bucks on my buddy here.
-GERRY: What are you... What are you doing?
-All right?
I'm gonna watch you play
this big winner right here.
-You said you played.
-Yeah, but not in a long time.
-So, you'll lose.
-No, you'll lose.
No, I'm not gonna lose. I'm spending 20
bucks to watch you make a fool of yourself.
(STUTTERING)
That's not losing, that's entertainment.
MAN: We're gonna play or what?
CURTIS: We're gonna play.
And We're gonna... We're gonna play, huh?
You want to be entertained?
-50 bucks. Let's play for 50 bucks.
-CURTIS: Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Gerry! Play nice now.
Okay, 50 bucks. You like that?
500.
1,000_ Let's play for $1,000.
(CHUCKLES)
That's enough.
You fellows don't belong here, do you?
-I'm... I'm really... I'm not very good.
-CURTIS: Okay...
-I'm really...
-Hey, hey, hey, no...
Easy, easy, We're good.
We're good. We're good.
We don't want to upset your
beautiful highness, thank you very much.
(LAuGHING)
-And what're you doing tomorrow?
-(LAUGHS)
What are you doing tomorrow?
Well, I think it's Machu Picchu time for me.
Time for me to hit the road.
-Oh, okay.
-Yeah.
Okay, well, it was great to meet you.
You too, Gerry.
-Hey, do you want a ride someplace?
-No.
No, I'm just gonna... I'm gonna steal a bike.
Hey. Hey.
Man, you, uh, you got a light?
Uh, no.
-What's that for?
-Give me the money.
-I don't have any money.
-Bullshit.
$1,000 bets? Yeah, I heard you back there.
-No, no, no, fuck...
-Just give it to me.
Hey, I told you, I don't have any money.
Okay, I lost it on Rollin' Roosevelt.
-Don't make me cut you.
-Take it easy, buddy.
Okay? Take it easy. I'm gonna show you.
-Hurry up!
-Here, here, here.
See, I don't have any money.
-Do I look stupid?
-(DOOR OPENS)
Ahh!
Damn it! (GROANS)
-Damn...
-MAN: You all right, man?
-Shit.
-Hey, man, you want us to call somebody?
Hey, you forgot your knife, asshole!
Hey-hey!
Gerry, hey! (LAUGHS)
It's so great to see you, man.
So, how long's it been?
Oh, I don't know. A couple of months.
Too long. It's been too long.
Yeah, I know.
-Have you been avoiding me, Gerry?
-No, no, I...
Can I bring you something to drink?
GERRY: Um, yeah, I'll take a coffee.
Oh, forgive me, but I got here early.
I ordered a salad, order whatever you want.
-It's on me.
-No, it's fine.
I know it's fine, but I insist.
Okay. Sure.
I'll take a burger, medium-rare. And fries.
WAITERZ All right.
-Hey, and how are you?
-You know, same old grind.
I would like to retire soon,
but it doesn't seem to be
heading that direction.
Uh...
-How's the real estate?
-Oh. Slow and low.
-I'm sure it'll pick up soon.
-Yeah. Eventually.
Don't make me ask, Gerry.
Um, so,
last night I had $800.
I go out into the parking lot,
fucking guy robs me. Meth head.
With a knife, he stabs me.
-In the gut. See.
-Oh!
Oh, God, Gerry, put that down.
You need to have somebody look at that.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
-I can't imagine.
-It was pretty scary.
-At least you're okay.
-Yeah, it's just a scratch.
It could have been a lot worse, you know?
-Hmm.
-(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(lNDlsTINCT)
I got to take it.
Hey! Oh, Jesus, Lord. No.
I'm not bringing it to the school.
I'm in a meeting, ask your dad.
I don't know where he is.
You know, it's not my fault that you forgot it.
Teenagers! God.
Hey... srm!
Okay, I'm... I will, I'm gonna bring it.
This is the last time though.
I'll be there in half an hour.
Do not keep me waiting out front.
You're so lucky
you don't have to deal with that shit.
-Gerry, I tell you.
-Oh, fuck...
So, what do you have for me today?
This is about $80. I had the rest, but...
-Meth head.
-Fucking meth head.
-Bad beat.
-The worst.
-Things will look up.
-They always do.
Well, not always.
Couple of weeks.
Couple of weeks, don't worry about it.
-Tomorrow.
-IVlmm, no.
Tomorrow, Gerry.
I'll send Tim to drop you a visit.
Oh, no, no. There's no need
to bring him into all of this.
Couple of days
I'll have a commission, and, uh...
-Get it together.
-I had the money.
-Yeah.
-This time it wasn't my fault.
SAM: I understand.
-Take care.
-Yeah.
-Gerry.
-Hey!
Curtis, I know you're probably
halfway to New Orleans...
Crazy day. Gerry I ended up in Chicago.
I won a ticket to the Bulls game shooting
dice this morning. So, I went.
But now I'm back
in your neck of the woods.
You are? Where?
I'm at the same, uh, same place.
Same place we met the other night.
What place? No.
-(LAUGHS)
-Gerry.
Gerry would you be so kind
as to order me a Woodford?
(LAuGHING)
A Woodford! Two Woodfords!
Have you seen a NBA game up close?
-Those guys are tall!
-Hey, man.
-it's a sign.
-What is?
It's a sign!
You walking in the door
while I'm calling you on the telephone
-is a sign, I'm telling you, it's a sign.
-All right.
Okay, look what happened to me
after you left last night.
-What is that?
-In the parking lot.
-Some guy cut me.
-Are you okay?
(STUTTERS) It's not serious.
What I'm getting at...
Did you know the guy?
Yeah, yeah, I know him,
we play some softball on the weekends.
-That's a fair question.
-No! It's not a...
-He was mugging me.
-That's gonna hurt like hell.
It stings a little bit,
but what I'm getting at is...
CURTIS: Shit.
Hey, hey, Curtis,
what I'm trying to get at here,
is that good things happen
when you're around,
and when you're not, when you leave...
-(LAUGHS) You get stabbed.
-Yeah!
(BOTH LAuGHING)
I've been thinking, you know?
That home game, uh, New Orleans,
-disassociated guy...
-Tony Roundtree?
Boom! I want in.
That game has a $25,000 buy-in, Gerry.
-Which is a lot. That's a lot.
-Yeah.
-But I got a plan.
-I'm listening.
-We go down the Mississippi.
-Okay.
Yeah. We go down
the Mississippi like Huck-fucking-Finn
-and Jim...
-On a raft.
-No, we take my car. Okay.
-Okay.
But we hit up all the action,
everything along the way.
-I know some weekly home games.
-Yeah.
-Casinos.
-Sure.
Then we got the gambling towns.
We got, uh...
(SINGING) Memphis, Tennessee
(SINGING) We gotta win that race
Vicksburg
-Tunica.
-Absolutely, Tunica!
Now, I'm gonna be straight with you.
I'm in a little bit of a hole right now.
I'm working my way back out,
so all I need you to do
is stake me 500 out the gate...
Hey, look, it's not... it's not...
it's an investment. Okay?
Because I'll play, you'll be my lucky charm.
-We split the winnings even-steven.
-What about your job?
-They won't miss me.
-Can I ask you a personal question?
(SIGHS) Yeah.
How much do you owe?
-A lot.
-To who?
Everyone.
I'll stake you $2,000. Your car, my cash.
-Hot damn. That's what I'm talking about.
-(LAUGHS)
-That's what I'm talking about.
-Come here!
Easy, easy with that.
Wish me luck.
(GERRY LAuGHING)
-Let's go.
-Go, go, go, go.
Is everything okay?
CURTIS: Tony Roundtree,
he once had a pet tiger.
He won it playing baccarat
with an Arab prince.
Cleans the guy out,
the prince wants to keep playing,
so he puts his tiger on the table,
-not literally, but... Yeah.
-Yeah.
You know, joke's on Tony, though.
Didn't know he'd be
hemorrhaging money on this thing.
He's got to register it with
the federal government,
get a special permit.
First time I met him was on a bar car
of an Amtrak train from
Denver to Albuquerque.
I remember he was wearing
this blue velvet smoking jacket
and drank from a copper flask.
(NAVARRO CD PLAYS)
And the tiger?
He's tranquilized
and checked with the other cargo.
He checked a tiger on an Amtrak train?
Apparently they have a policy.
-(LAUGHING)
-Hey, hey, hey.
You want to know what it costs
to check a 600-pound animal?
Yeah! Yeah! (LAUGHS)
Hold on a second,
what're we listening to here?
Oh, this? 200 Poker Tells by Joe Navarro.
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
How often do you listen to this, Gerry?
Whenever I drive.
Are you gonna make me
listen to this the whole way to New Orleans?
We don't have to listen to it.
WOMAN: Hey there, Gerry.
Substituted you at the ofHce today.
Hope everything's okay. Um...
Anyway, it's all a bit awkward,
but I feell need to mention that some of
the petty cash seems to have gone missing.
Not that I'm accusing you of taking it,
but Janice said when she left last night
there was over 200 in the box.
Also, a friend of yours named
Tim stopped by.
Said he's looking for you.
NAVARRO ON CD PLAYER:
Fean These soft areas will quiver or twitch,
-revealing the person 's...
-(CELL PHONE RINGS)
...negative emotional state.
(CD CoNTINuEs PLAYING)
(GROANS)
Who's that?
Nobody.
You bring any snacks?
Yeah, I have some jerky back there.
Can you grab some for me, too?
Yeah.
Nice.
-You brought cigars.
-Oh, no, it's not...
CURTIS: Oh, What'S all this?
An emergency fund. Just in case.
-In case of what?
-Emergency.
You got watches, Gerry.
You collect baseball cards?
Is that a wedding ring?
-Yeah.
-Get outta here. You were married?
Hard to believe, huh?
I didn't mean it like that.
I just... What happened?
She left.
Would you want
any of that jerky back there?
Yeah. Yeah. Here it is.
Jackpot
Yes, sir. Hot chocolate.
That's what I'm talking about.
(WOMEN LAuGHING)
-Well, hello.
-Hi.
-Can I help you with something?
-I'm Curtis.
-Simone.
-That's a nice name.
-Thanks.
-I'm, uh, I'm looking for...
-For a woman.
-Sure, what sort of woman you looking for?
Oh, she's about that tall.
She's got cinnamon hair,
soft pale skin, devastating blue eyes...
Funny, but I think
I've seen just the woman you're looking for.
-CURTIS: You have?
-Yeah.
CURTIS: I've been tracking her scent
for miles around here.
They say that working-class
hound dogs have the best sense of smell.
Woof, woof.
Woof, woof, woof, Woof...
Well, don't just stand there
barking, little doggy.
Come inside and get yourself a treat.
(SIMONE LAUGHS)
-This is Gerry. Gerry, Simone.
-Hey.
All right, these were the best that I could do.
-Did I ever tell you now amazing you are?
-Too often to feel sincere.
-Here, Gerry.
-Thank you.
Hey, don't be shy, Gerry, we're all friends.
So, you guys play poker?
No, we just work here, honey.
What is it you do?
We get paid for our companionship.
Oh, yeah, yeah. (CLEARS THROAT)
Hi.
What happened there?
-It's nothing serious.
-Doesn't look like nothing.
Gerry saved my life in a knife fight.
-I'm Gerry. That's not true.
-Vanessa.
Hey, Curtis, how was Peru?
-Uh, not yet, sweetie. But soon, I promise.
-IVlmm-hmm.
You can change in there if you want to.
Yeah, okay. Fine.
Looking good, Mr. Vonn.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
I'll tell you something, Gerry. First thing
we do when we get to New Orleans,
we buy new suits.
Oh, I don't really wear suits.
Yeah, you're gonna have to.
We are going to Tony Roundtree's_
We can't go dressed like this.
Well, in that case,
I've always wanted a white suit,
you know, like Glen Campbell.
Mental note, next trip, open sea.
Hey, what's up with Peru?
I heard you talking to Vanessa.
What's that about?
It's kind of a joke, you know?
Like when I'm done with a person or a place
and it's time to move on, I'll say,
"It's Machu Picchu time."
-Machu Picchu?
-Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
You might say it's kind of like
the end of my rainbow, you know?
Mysterious and exotic,
it's like a place you just get lost,
you never come back from.
Plus it's fun to say...
Lot of fun to say. Machu Picchu. Try it.
-Machu Picchu.
-(ENUNCIATES) Machu Picchu.
(ENUNCIATES LOUDLY)
Machu Picchu.
(l=>lANo PLAYING)
I'll be at the bar if you need me.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
CURTIS: Excuse me.
Excuse me. Hey!
Tell me something that
I don't know about St. Louis.
I've only been here a few months.
That's no excuse.
I was only in Iowa for a few days.
I can tell you that Marion Robert Morrison
was born in Winterset, Iowa, 1907.
Am I supposed to know who that is?
You might know him
by his stage name, John Wayne.
John Wayne.
I can also tell you
that Iowa is the only state in the country
that begins with two vowels.
And that the National Balloon Museum
in lndianola
chronicles over 200 years
of guess what?
Right, ballooning history.
Okay. Okay, fine.
So, I don't know if this is true...
I don't care. Lay it on me.
You know when you're in a hotel room
and they put the little
chocolate on the pillows?
-IVlmm-hmm.
-That was started in St. Louis by...
You have nice legs.
-You're supposed to guess who.
-Okay, Ben Franklin.
Close. Cary Grant.
Really?
He was staying at the Mayfair
and wooing a certain lady friend
by putting chocolate on her pillow.
Who told you that?
-A friend.
-Who?
I don't remember.
-Take a guess.
-What are you getting at?
Were you in a hotel room
when this friend told you
-about Cary Grant's chocolate...
-I don't remember.
-...seduction technique?
-So what if I was?
Six months is a long time, Curtis.
Six months? It hasn't been six months.
Six months. September,
October, November, December,
January, February, March. Seven months.
Seven months.
Tell me something else about St. Louis.
DEALER: Heads up.
500 is the bet.
Raise to 1,000_
Call.
Heads up.
Check.
DEALERS 1,000 is the bet.
Call.
Heads up.
Check.
DEALERS He'S all in.
How do you get a sweet
little old lady to yell, "Go fuck yourself!"
(PLAYERS CHUCKLE)
You get another sweet little
old lady to yell, "Bingo!"
(LAUGHTER)
Bingo. (CHUCKLES)
-Yeah, I'll call.
-DEALER: Call.
-Take it. You got me.
-(GERRY THUMPING HAND ON TABLE)
-It's trust. Trust her.
-(BOTH LAUGH)
Is that a problem? I love that story.
Back in England there was, you know, earls_
-Yeah.
-Okay? There was an Earl of Sandwich.
He was a gambler.
He was standing at the tables all day long.
Oh, I'm a bit hungry. What am I gonna do?
Uh, I know. Hey, you know, buddy,
go put some meat
between a couple of pieces of bread.
(LAUGHS) The Earl of Sandwich is...
-There it is.
-...the best name I've ever heard.
-(LAUGHS)
-What are you talking about?
-He came up with...
-You boys just gonna sit there all night?
GERRY: He was a great gambler.
VANESSA: Come dance.
C-A, C-A. ._
I didn"t know that...
(CURTIS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
VANESSA: First word.
CURTIS: First word.
Hey, I want to smoke a cigarette.
CURTIS: He just won $7,000.
Give the man something.
(CHUCKLING) Where did you find him?
Poker table, tournament with a $60 buy-in.
He had a collared shirt
and a missing button.
And you ordered him a Woodford.
(LAUGHS)
What's he need the money for?
He believes that it will set him free.
He's a good guy.
That's what you said about George.
You mean Jorge?
What do you have against Jorge?
His name was George.
And he was a liar and a thief.
He was not.
Okay.
What's in this for you?
The journey is the destination, sweetheart.
It's not an answer. It's a bumper sticker.
There's nothing in it for me.
There's nothing.
-Do you know any magic tricks?
-GERRY: No.
Do you?
Yeah? (LAUGHS)
-Do you want to see?
-Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay, but I'm just learning.
So, you can't make fun of me.
I won't make fun of you.
Wait.
So, what next?
-What?
-After New Orleans. What then?
-You should come with us.
-Shut up.
It would be so much fun.
-I have school.
-Play hooky.
Curtis, I can't just, you know,
-like you, hit the road on a whim.
-Didn't your mama
ever tell you that you can do
anything you want?
-No, she did not.
-Well, then I'm saying it for her.
Okay, I'll come with you.
Tell me what I need
to pack for this little mystery tour.
-Whatever you want.
-Should I bring a jacket? Will it be cold?
No.
What about a bikini?
You know I love the beach.
-Definitely bring a bikini.
-Should I bring my running shoes?
Will there be a gym where we're going?
-I'll find one.
-Um, dresses...
Should I bring a dress for you?
Will you help me pick some
to go with my high-heeled shoes?
And what about condoms?
Am I going to have to work on this journey?
Are you gonna cover my expenses?
-GERRY: Okay.
-IVlmm-hmm.
(l3Lo\/vs AND LAUGHS)
(LAUGHS) That's good. That's good.
(LAUGHS)
What!
Wow!
So little. That's amazing.
Where did it come from?
I hid him earlier so that
I could show you guys my trick tonight.
Magicians are not supposed to reveal their
secrets. I'm just sayin', you know.
I'm still learning, I guess.
GERRY: Hey.
Hey, little buddy.
Oh, look at you. You're so small.
-(MEWS)
-Hello, hello, you're okay.
You're okay. Yeah?
You're okay.
Look at this little thing.
-Your turn.
-I don't know any tricks.
Come on, I showed you mine,
you have to show me yours.
-(CHUCKLES)
-No, it can be anything.
Anything?
Okay. You got it? Okay.
(GERRY l=>LAYING CHORUS)
GERRY: Okay.
(PLAYING SOFT MELODY)
Is that Vanessa?
No, it must be your friend.
I didn't know Gerry played.
He's pretty good.
I liked that.
You married?
Girlfriend?
I have a little girl.
That's cute. Do you have a picture?
She lives with her mom in Little Rock.
I have problems with money.
Did I say anything about money?
I didn't mean it like that.
No, it was...
It was something
I wanted to tell you so I don't.._
I'm gonna do something with my life.
I may not have that figured out yet,
but I'm gonna do something.
It's something I wanted to tell you.
-SO I did.
-(BOTH LAUGH)
(LAUGHS)
Hey. Hey, JP? Can you put me down
for a five tonight on Hawaii over Gonzaga?
That's bullshit. No, bullshit.
I have it. I have the money.
I literally have the money
right here in my hand.
I'm looking at it.
Eh, JP?
JP? Fuckin' asshole.
JOE NAVARRO ON CD:
Number 118. Sitting lower and /owen
Players who slip
lower and lower in their chairs
during a hand
are progressively revealing their weakness.
-Most players are not aware how low...
-That's yours, you know.
-...or how high they're sitting.
-H uh?
You're a sloucher. It's your tell.
-You slouch when you're worried.
-Get outta here.
Hey, you're doing it right now.
Seemed like Vanessa was really into you.
Yeah, we had a good time.
-Did you sleep with her?
-No.
-What?
-Why not?
I don't know. It just didn't___
Didn't feel like there was that, you know...
I thought you knew how to read people.
She was sending you signals all night.
Well, maybe I didn't feel like it.
-You like women?
-Yeah.
-It's okay if you don't_
-Oh...
What about you and Simone?
Whats going on there?
-We had sex last night.
-No, that's not what I'm asking.
Why are you changing the subject?
Do you know your voice goes up an octave
when you talk to her?
You get all soft, dreamy.
You must really love that girl.
You're avoiding the subject, Gerry...
What are you doing?
-What are you afraid of?
-I'm not afraid of anything.
What, what are you talking about
"afraid of"?
-Your ex-wife.
-IVlmm-hmm.
Yeah, that's what this is about.
She left you. You want her back.
I should have known it was about a woman.
-it's not about a woman.
-Yeah, it is.
You know how I know?
-(WHISPERS) You're slouching_
-You don't know anything.
I've been on the road a long time.
I know what makes people tick.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You're a regular Oprah,
-Dr. Phil, right?
-I'm saying that,
look, my experience has given me
certain insights into the human condition.
Your experience? How old are you?
-Forget it.
-No, come on.
No, forget it.
-How old are you?
-All right, bullshit.
I know what you're doing, all right?
Age is not the only indication
of life experience.
See, I'm 44.
-I'm 39.
-Bullshit!
But I bet you for 100 bucks
-I can guess your age.
-(LAUGHS) You are on.
Okay, take your glasses off,
just for a second.
Let me have a look. Let me have a look.
Oh, that's 35.
You're 35.
I am 35.
-How'd you know that?
-I told you, I'm good with ages.
My ass, you're good with ages.
How did you know that?
I read your driver's license.
-When?
-This morning.
-You were in the bathroom.
-Why?
-I wanted to know if you are...
-Why did you do that?
-...who you say you are.
-And what did you learn?
You're Curtis Vonn, 35, with an expired
North Dakota driver's license.
Holy shit. Is that it?
Is there anything else you want to share?
No.
(CD CoNTINuEs PLAYING)
Muddy Waters, Howlin' Wolf,
B.B. King, Otis Redding,
Isaac Hayes...
There's even some famous white folk
from Memphis you might have heard of.
Elvis Presley, Jerry Lee Lewis, Carl Perkins,
-Johnny Cash...
-All those people from Memphis?
And don't forget about Justin Timberlake.
CURTIS: Very impressive, my friend.
MAN: Yeah.
Hey, how we doing?
I'm gonna get a burger. You want one?
No, no, no. I gotta get ready.
I gotta go to this game.
Au right.
WOMAN: Why you didn't bet
on Midnight Runner?
Why?
-What happened?
-CURTIS: How long were you married?
-Eight years.
-That's a long time.
-It's supposed to be longer.
-I like women too much to marry one.
-(LAUGHS)
-Are you married, pops?
Been married six times, but not at present.
-Well, nere's to lucky number seven.
-Thank you.
-CURTIS: If you want it.
-(LAUGHING)
Miss the married life?
Do I miss it? Well, let me put it like this,
I just know it's better to not be alone.
Amen.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(slNGING UPBEAT SONG)
Oh, Shit.
-Well, Hawaii beat Gonzaga.
-WOMAN: Big-time upset.
-Well, I heard...
-Rainbow Warriors.
I raise 600.
DEALERS Raise 600.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Heads up.
DEALERS 1,500.
Call.
I'll check.
All in.
DEALER: She's all in at 10,600_
I'll Call.
DEALER: She's got you covered.
(ALL EXCLAIM IN SURPRISE)
DEALER: Heads up.
(ALL ExCLAllvl)
DENNIS: Wow. That's a night.
WOMAN: IVlan!
MAN: Wow.
WOMAN: I did not deserve that.
Sorry, Gerry.
DENNIS: Oh, that's a tough break, Gerry.
I'm gonna get a smoke.
Let's go again.
MANI Shit.
GERRY: Let's go again.
WOMAN: Gerry, call it a night.
Oh, come on. Just give me $1,000.
Tell her I'm good for $1,000.
MAN: It's a bad beat, Gerry.
DENNIS: Throw in the towel, man.
(slGHs DEEPLY)
(CROWD cHEERING)
(SINGER l-lovvl_s)
(LAuGHING)
(sol3l3lNG)
(CELL PHONE RINGs)
-$100,ooo, right?
-(MAN vvHlsTLEs)
The deal was that Slim had to get
C-cup breast implants
and leave them in for exactly one year.
Not only did he win the bet,
and he was paid, I can vouch for that.
-MAN: Woman titties for a whole year?
-But he meta woman,
a straight woman
that loved his fake tits so much,
-that she married him.
-MAN: Get the fuck out of here.
-He's still got 'em, perky as ever.
-(MAN LAUGHS)
Right? Gerry?
-Hey, how did it go?
-Good.
That's a... Son of a bitch, that's great.
Come sit down with us, here,
have a... Have a drink.
Let's celebrate. Meet some people.
Actually...
Just take a moment of your time?
I'd like just to have a word.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll be right back, you beautiful losers.
I don't know what it means.
What, what means?
Okay.
(CHUCKLING) This is gonna sound crazy.
I was all in on this monster pot.
Okay? I was down to the river, I was gone,
I mean, I was wiped out.
And all I needed was a queen and...
A queen, the only thing that could save me,
and I made myself a promise
and I know this sounds so stupid,
but I made myself a promise
that if I got a queen,
I'd go and... I'd go to Little Rock.
I'd make things right,
you know, with my queen.
You know what I mean?
Your ex-wife.
-You were right.
-Of course...
A woman. What did I tell you, huh?
it's always a woman.
(SOFTLY) I don't know what to do.
I know what to do.
We go to Little Rock. That's what we do.
It's not on our way. It just seems crazy.
Am I crazy?
-Oh, you're a fucking lunatic.
-(CHUCKLES)
-But I love it.
-You don't mind?
Gerry, I don't...
A beautiful woman right in there,
asked me to go home with her tonight.
-And?
-And I turned her down.
-You did?
-Yep.
Why?
When you come to a fork in a road,
you take it.
Let's go to Little Rock.
-Gerry.
-Hey, Dorothy.
What are you doing here?
I was just driving through Little Rock.
I thought I'd stop by.
Oh, you were just stopping
through Little Rook.
Look, I don't have to stay. I just...
Thought it did be nice to see you.
Even if it is just for a minute.
Come on in, I guess.
I was just making some tea.
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
-Do you want some?
-Yeah, yeah. Sure. Absolutely.
Hey, darling. Did I wake you? I'm sorry.
SIMONE: No, it's okay. Where are you?
We're... We're on a little
detour in Little Rock.
-Little Rock?
-Yeah .
What happened to New Orleans?
No, I'm sitting in a car right now,
outside Gerry's ex-wife's house,
and he just went in there to win her back.
And he got me thinking about you.
Me and St. Louis,
Kansas City, all kinds of places, really.
-Where is she?
-School.
That's good.
Hmm. How are things with Gary?
We got married.
Oh, oh...
Congratulations.
Did you ever think it was funny
that you traded me in for a Gary?
You know, Gerry, Gary...
Well, where is he?
-Working.
-What does he do?
He's an electrician.
That's a good job.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
(slGHs)
I... That... That...
I used to be in this photograph.
That's my hand.
You cut me out of this picture.
I didn't want you on my wall, Gerry.
Well, okay, but you have to cut me
out of my daughter's life
-so that she can't see me?
-Is that a joke?
You cut yourself out years ago.
-No, no.
-Yeah, yeah.
When is the last time you visited?
Or sent a present on her birthday?
Well, I had been having some
-money difficulties...
-it's not about money.
How about checking her homework,
or making dinner
or, uh, calling? (CHUCKLES)
To say hi.
You...
Thank you for the tea.
May I use the bathroom
on my way out, please?
You know where it is.
Teach me something.
I'm tired, Curtis.
Come on. I just want to hear your voice.
Sing me a song.
-I'm not gonna sing you a song right now.
-Please.
Please. Pretty please?
All right. How about this?
(SINGING) A, B, C, D, E, F, G
H, I, J, K
L, M, N, O, P
Q, R, S, 72 U, \L I/MX YandZ
Now you know your ABCs
Next time won't you sing with me?
-Hello?
-What if I came back?
Get out.
You know, I was gonna pay you back.
(GLASS SHATTE RS)
DOROTHY: Leave it.
You want to talk about it?
No. it's fine.
I love this place, Gerry.
IVIoe Greene of Tunica, Mississippi.
We're gonna get comped for days.
I'm not gonna let anyone stab you.
Welcome back to Player's Town.
Thank you, Dora.
I'm sorry, this expired in 2009.
IVlmm-mmm.
I'm afraid so.
I don't see how that's possible.
Can you try that again?
Go easy now.
I'm sorry, sir.
Well, I have to say that
I am very disappointed in you, Dora.
Well, we do have some suites
available for $395 a night.
Can't you just, you know, push
the right buttons down there
and comp us a suite
for old times' sake, what do you say?
Um, sorry, sir.
What time you get off?
I'll be here till 11:00.
I want to meet you
in the Player's Lounge at 11:15.
-I got a man.
-What's your man have to do with me?
That's a pretty ring.
Okay, look.
I can get you the AARP discount.
That'S 10% Off.
Gerry, hey.
What do you say? How about one night?
We can afford one night.
-Forget it. Let's go someplace else.
-Why?
Okay. How much is the regular room?
-$99.
-That's a little steep, don't you think?
-Come on, just give me the money.
-Oh, hold on.
Just one moment.
Do you realize that this guy
is the Mel Greene of Tunica, Mississippi?
He has a VIP card. So, please, can you just
comp us for one night, that's all?
I'm sorry, sir.
I don't have the authority to do that.
Okay, that's not... Okay, no.
No, I'm gonna need
to speak to a manager right now!
-A manager!
-Hey, Gerry.
Excuse us. I'm sorry. One second.
Can I talk to you for a second?
-Where's the money?
-What money?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
We're gonna be fine.
Gerry, your lips are
telling me that we're gonna be fine,
but you're slouching like a...
Like a kid who just pissed
his pants in the sandbox.
Where are we at, huh?
Ger?
Ground zero.
I tried to tell you before.
-You tried to tell me?
-Fucking cunt! Shit!
I was nailing her all night
and she fucking turned queen on the...
You lost in Memphis.
(slGHs)
What were we doing in Little Rock?
I can win it back. I can get it back.
I can get us all the way to 25.
It isn't about the money, Gerry.
Yeah, of course it's about the money.
Come on, man.
What do you think, this is a vacation for me?
(slGHs)
(CHUCKLES)
You're a piece of work, you know that?
Hey, I did everything right.
I played it right.
I just...
I just can't catch a break! I just can't win.
This story doesn't have
a happy ending, Gerry.
I think you should go back home to Iowa.
No, no.
No, can't do that.
I can't go back empty-handed.
I can't do that.
-You keep trying to lose.
-Oh... Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm trying... Yeah, I'm trying to fucking...
-(Tl-IUD)
4Ah!FucK!
(GROANS) It was closed.
I'm not trying to lose.
Rm... (GROANS)
(CHATTERING)
What's up, faggots?
What's up with these guys?
(sNlcKERING)
FRAT BOY: Hey, got to go find some girls.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Dude, what the fuck! Get off me, bro.
What the hell's your problem, asshole?
FRAT BOY: Where're you going, pussy?
Oh, you want some?
You want to go?
(GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(LOUD SCREAMING)
IVlove, move, move, move.
(YELUNG)
(CURTIS TALKING ON THE PHONE)
CURTIS: Where is she?
Her cell went straight to voice-mail.
Just tell me.
Is she with someone?
Don't say that you don't know.
I know that you know.
VANESSA: I'll tell her that you called.
No, and you know what?
Forget that... Forget that I called, okay?
-Curtis---
-I'm... I'm serious.
Vanessa, listen to me,
don't tell her that I called, okay? Don't.
-Okay.
-Can you do that for me?
Don't tell her, okay?
Okay?
-Okay.
-Are you gonna tell her?
-No.
-(SLOWLY) All right.
I'll talk to you later.
GERRY: Hey, buddy.
(BED CRE/\KING)
(slGHs)
You know, you're missing a pinky.
How'd you do that?
Some crazy bastard bit it off
in a bathroom brawl.
Okay.
(FAUCET RUNNING)
When I was eight years old,
me and my sister,
we went to go live with
our grandparents for a couple of years.
It was this old house on a hill
and, uh, my job was to mow the lawn.
It was one of these old, um...
You know, these rotary blade thing...
You push it.
And my little sister,
she jumps out and she's, uh...
Well, she's screwing around.
Making fun of me or whatever.
You know, like little kids do and...
And she won't move,
so I give her till the count of three.
-Fair warning.
-I thought so.
But one, two, three goes by
and she doesn't move.
So, I ran over her foot.
She lost three toes.
But what about your toe?
My grandfather's brilliant idea of justice.
(SWITCH CLICKS)
This morning my ex-wife
caught me stealing from her sock drawer.
Not the first time.
Purple sock.
Same sock she had when we were married.
I'm not a good person.
I'm not.
I don't deserve you.
But you appeared. You... (CHUCKLES)
Like a leprechaun.
Like a big, handsome leprechaun,
right there in Iowa.
There you were. Boom!
And I had to follow you.
I mean, boom. Magic!
Right there.
And can't do without you.
We're in it together.
I will tell you one thing though,
I didn't follow you
down this damn river to lose.
Long way down, ain't it, Gerry?
(lNAuDIBLE)
(HORSES GALLol=>lNG)
GERRY: This is our horse.
Toto's Revenge.
CURTIS: 7-to-1. I don't know.
Hey, look! It's Toto's-fucking-Revenge.
Yeah, well, look. I say that
we go with the favorite here, number one.
-Mississippi Grind?
-That just feels right.
-No, uh, look. It's Toto.
-(SIGHS)
Curtis, Toto.
Dorothy, rainbows...
I mean, this feels right.
-This, right here, feels more than right.
-You want to blow it all?
On a long shot?
I want to win it all on a long shot.
-All right, good, Toto's Revenge.
-No, no, no.
No,no,no,no.
I need you to be with me on this.
-Yep. I'm with you.
-No.
No, I... I... But I need you to mean...
I'm going to ask you again.
Is this our horse?
-This is our horse.
-Oh, Curtis!
-Is this our horse, Curtis?
-This is our horse, Gerry.
-Say it one more time.
-Toto's Revenge.
-That's our horse.
-Yes!
Yeah, and... And, it is!
(ANNOUNCEMENT OVER PA SYSTEM)
Here we go.
(BELL RINGING)
(COMMENTARY OVER PA SYSTEM)
I see that. I see it, baby!
(lvlouTHING)
Go. Go, Toto!
Yeah, hot damn!
Now, go!
(SMACKING PAPER IN HAND)
Go!
Go! That's it, girl, that's it!
Go, Toto! That's what l'm___
(SMACKS PAPER)
(COMMENTARY CONTINUES)
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
Come on! That's what I'm talking about.
That's it. That's it. Come on, number three.
Go, Toto!
Fuck. Fuck that...
Run, baby!
Run!
Run, you fucking horse!
AN N O U N C E R:
Mississippi Grind and Toto's Revenge.
Mississippi Grind, won going away.
It had to end this way, Gerry.
Here's 100 bucks.
Get yourself a bus ticket and go home.
You didn't bet it all?
I saved 100 each. Just in case.
-So, we got 200?
-No.
-We got 200.
-You have 100.
And I have 100.
(PAPER RUSTLING)
-Stop it, Gerry.
-You're not gonna believe this.
This is fucking amazing.
Thunder Clap is running in the next race.
-She is 40-to-1.
-We're done.
40-to-1. We bet that, we are...
-We're back. We're right back.
-Is that where we'll be?
I'm serious... We are right back.
What about Tony Roundtree, huh?
(STAMMERS) Hey!
What about my white suit?
Thank you for the ride.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry it didn't work out.
-Hey, there.
-Hi.
Cash out.
-(REGISTER BUZZES)
-Race number three, horse number one.
$5,000.
One, two, three, four, five, six, twenty, one.
Congratulations.
Everything okay, sir?
Guys, you on a meth break?
MAN: Yo, you lost?
GERRY: New Orleans, Louisiana.
Last name, Roundtree. First name, Tony.
You have an address?
(BASKETBALL PLAYERS SHOUTING)
(LAuGHING)
Hey, any of you fellows know where a guy
can play some darts around here?
MAN: Darts?
I'll play your best guy for 100 bucks.
MAN: Oh, that's funny.
Ah.
(CHEERING)
Come on, man. Come on, man.
Come on, man.
Ball up.
Come one, bring it. Let's go. Come on.
Right into my trap!
GERRY; Tony?
Tony Roundtree?
I'm Gerry.
You don't know me, I'm a friend of Curtis'.
Curtis Vonn?
Are you hosting
a poker game in here tonight?
Game! (LAUGHING)
-Stealing from a baby.
-(GRUNTS)
100 bucks.
MAN: Now we know why he play darts.
Something funny?
I don't have it.
MAN: Nah, nah, man.
You don't have the money?
Uh-uh.
(l=>ANTING)
What're you gonna do about it?
Oh!
You're the Tony Roundtree
that I'm looking for?
You met Curtis on an Amtrak train,
you were headed to Albuquerque.
You had on a blue velvet smoking jacket
and you were traveling with a tiger
that you won from an Arab prince?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
-You know Curtis?
-Yeah.
Yes, yes. Yes, I know Curtis.
He's a close personal friend of mine.
-He's a great friend...
-Curtis with you?
No, couldn't make it.
But he wanted me to let you know
you really should let me in.
Letyouin?
Yeah. Okay, full disclosure.
-Yeah?
-I'm a little short on the buy-in.
-(CHUCKLES)
-A little short.
You seem like a good guy,
I'm sure we can come to some arrangement.
You know, financial arrangement, say,
60/40...
(LAuGHING) 70/so.
(BOTH LAuGHING)
-What did you say your name was?
-I'm Gerry, I'm Gerry.
Fuck!
Fuck! (YELLS) What the fuck was that for?
(GROANS) Had it coming.
(slGHs)
Bingo. Bingo, jackpot!
What's wrong with you, man?
I have intimacy issues.
Couple stacks in here.
CURTIS: Yeah. (G RU NTS)
Man, you're a crazy, son-of-a-bitch,
you know that?
(GRO/\NING)
MAN: Wayne,
why you ain't taking the rest of it?
Good game, guys.
Best two out of three?
(l=>lANo PLAYING)
Hey, long time. How've you been?
Living the dream.
-What happened to your face?
-You should see the other guy's hand.
Give me a bourbon.
-What kind?
-Uh, just cheap stuff.
(WOMAN SINGING MELLOW SONG)
(MACHINES CLATTERING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(SLOT MACHINE MUSIC PLAYS)
(RHYTHMIC BEEPS)
(Al=>l=>LAuDING)
Oh, thanks, Pete.
-Cheers.
You got my smokes?
Great.
(UGHTER cLINKs)
Thanks, darling.
Happy birthday, IVIom_
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You're a little late, aren't you?
Just a day or two.
(CLATTERING)
DEALER: How're you doing, sir?
Change for 100.
Good luck, sir.
Sir, are you sure you want to
put that on a double zero?
Well, good luck to you.
CHERRY: Where you been hiding, darling?
Not hiding.
Just traveling.
Travelers have a destination.
Well, the journey...
The journey is the destination.
CURTIS: Destination.
I think I know where you heard that.
Anyway,
it's good to see you.
You bring me anything?
Oh, I didn't have time to stop.
CHERRY: I know the feeling.
You came alone?
All by my lonesome.
CHERRY: You should find somebody, baby.
A man alone's half a man.
I think I'm doing all right.
(CHUCKLES)
Sure you are.
Listen.
This year's been unkind to your mama.
(LAuGHING)
That's a good tune.
I got to get back to work.
Why don't you stick around for the next set
and I'll buy you a drink.
All right?
Pete... (SNIFFLES) Take this for me.
Life's a long grind, ain't it?
All right, this one's for
my little boy over there.
(STRUMMING GUITAR)
(SINGING) I was born
A poor; poor man
All my life I 'Ve had
Hard-working hands
But I sang my song
As I carried my load
'Cause I had a dream about Rain
Rainbow Road
(HulvllvllNG)
Then one day
My chance came along
A man heard me singing
And playing my song
He bought me Hne clothes
And paid the money I owed
Sent me on my way
Pete?
To Rain
Make sure she gets this.
Rainbow Road
Then one night
A man with a knife
Pushed me until
I had to take his life
Though I pleaded with him
DEALER: Double zero.
(CHEERING)
Oh, so desperately
The judge showed no mercy
on me
And passed his sentence
Now I'm pulling
This ball and chain
Wearing a number
For my name...
DEALER: Change, 100.
DEALERS Bust.
DEALER: Dealer bust.
(KNOCKS TABLE TWICE)
(CHll=>s CLANKING)
DEALER: Dealer bust.
Two Woodfords!
(GLASSES CLINKING)
(CHEERING)
(YELUNG)
(ExcLAllvllNG)
(CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRovvLING)
Ooh! Okay. Here we go.
Here we go. Here we go. Here we go.
Okay, it's Simone!
It's Simone! I'm gonna take this.
Oh, make it quick!
Okay, baby. Listen to this.
Hey, listen to this.
(CHEERING)
Perfect!
Oh!
All right, you hear...
Hear, baby, you hear that?
What's going on?
Did you hear that? That right there
is the sweet sound of success.
We... We made it. We made it, okay?
Just pack your bags.
We're getting out of here. We're gonna go.
I don't care where we're gonna go.
(STUTTERING)
We're going somewhere.
You pack your bikini,
you pack your boots, your dress,
whatever you want.
And we're out of here.
I'm... It's... It's loud, it's loud, okay?
We can go to Salt Lake City,
we can go to fucking Las Vegas,
we can go to fucking Monte Carlo,
I don't give a shit!
We'll go wherever you want to go.
Okay?
I want to tell you something, I love you.
I love you.
You hear me, huh?
I love you!
Sure, Curtis. We 'll talk tomorrow.
All right. Okay, call...
You call... Call me tomorrow.
We can't lose.
No, we can't lose.
(\/vHlsTLING)
Let's bet it all. Double or nothing.
Yeah.
Bet it all.
Wait, Wait. (STUTTERING)
-No, no, no, no, it's okay.
-Hang on a second, Gerry.
It's okay. It's okay.
We can't lose.
-We can't lose.
BOTH: We can't lose. (LAUGHING)
We made it.
Hey! We made it.
I'm not afraid.
We're gonna bet it all.
(CHEERING)
GERRY: Hard, hard 10!
-Everything.
-Floor.
-CROUPIER: On the field, everything!
-(INDISTINCT)
CROUPIER: On the field. Everything.
'lO0,000...
'l50,000.
(MAN LAuGHING)
285,000.
(CHATTER ON RADlo)
-Okay.
-Your roll.
(CHEERING)
(DICE ROLUNG)
(DISTORTED CHEERING)
(CLATTERING)
I love this country.
I just bet $285,000
on a roll of a dice.
A hero is nothing more
than the guy who pulls off
what the rest of us are scared to do.
I was wrong about you, Gerry,
I thought you were a sick pony.
I thought I was gonna have to put down.
But, uh...
No, you're a hero.
A new American legend.
What's wrong?
Something's not right with this.
-Your steak?
-Yeah.
-Can you try that?
-Hmm.
-Oh, my God.
-Right?
No, that's delicious.
IVlmm.
Oh, there's nothing off
about that steak, Gerry.
Excuse me.
Gerry.
Can I get a cheeseburger?
I'm sorry,
is something wrong with your steak?
No, no, no. Don't worry about it. It's perfect.
I'm gonna eat it. Thank you very much.
Okay. Cheeseburger?
-Yes, please.
-WAITRESS: I'll be right back.
-Thank you.
-CURTIS: Thank you.
Why? It didn't__. It didn't taste right.
CURTIS: Whats the matter with you?
You just won half a million dollars.
Cheer the fuck up.
You know what I'm gonna do tomorrow?
First thing tomorrow, I'm gonna wake up
and I'm gonna go see the Cadillac man
and I'm gonna buy me
a shiny, new, white Caddy.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-What do you want, huh?
You want a Cadillac?
After you pay off your debts, your ex-wife...
Tell me what you want?
First thing that pops in your head, go.
What do you want, Gerry? Tell me.
Hit me! One, two, three...
Lay it on me. Boom!
-What do you want?
-Do something nice for Wendy.
CURTIS: Good.
Great. Who's Wendy?
-Daughter. My daughter.
-You have a...
Shit! You never told me that you had a kid.
-I didn't?
-No. That's great!
(MUMBLING)
What... How old is she?
Ah, she's seven... Six.
I think.
She's six.
Well, there you have it.
Tomorrow's a new day.
So is the next.
(l3EEl=>lNG)
(slGHs)
(PHONE vll3RATEs)
(TAKES DEEP BREATH)
(PHONE THUDS)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(slGHs)
(sNIFFLEs)
Gerry.
I had a dream that we were on a steamboat.
And river bandits took all our money.
(SWITCH CLICKS)
Ger?
(l3EEl=>lNG)
(SOFTLY) Machu Picchu.
-Hello.
-WOMAN: Hi.
I'd like to check out of my
VIP penthouse suite,
Alice.
Oh, looks like everything's
been comped, IVIr_ Vonn_
How was your trip?
Spectacular. Thank you very much.
You heading home today?
-Peru.
-Peru!
-I'm off to Peru.
-Wow!
-That sounds nice.
-Yeah. Yeah.
-You want to go with me?
-(CHUCKLES)
I got lucky.
Hmm.
(ENGINE STARTS)
NAVARRO ON CD2 Number 199.
Relaxed and squared.
Shoulders that are
suddenly relaxed and squared are saying,
"I am com7dent. "
If someone goes from slumped shoulders
to squared relaxed shoulders,
I would be concerned
as they are likely to be strong.
Number 200. ._
Number 1. Hat lift to ventilate.
Men will suddenly lift up their hat
to ventilate their head
when they are struggling with something
or stressed or have concerns.
Look for other conHrming tells
such as the tense face,
high shoulders, etcetera,
to help you.
Number 2.
Ear lobe pulling or massaging.
Pulling on or massaging the ear lobe
tends to have a subtle, soothing effect on us
when we are stressed or merely
contemplating alternatives.
I would associate ear lobe rubbing
with doubt or hesitation.
Number three. Head scratching.
Head scratching paciHes us
when we have doubts or stress or concern.
When pondering a situation
or when perplexed
is usually when you see this behavior:
Number 4. Botox.
Because the forehead
gives away so much information
about stress and anxiety
some players, and I highly recommend it,
have been Botoxing their foreheads-
It is very effective at
hiding tells of the forehead
even though it may leave them
totally void of forehead expression.
One way to detect
if players have been using Botox,
is to look to see if there is
a quarter-inch area
just short of the hairline
that reacts to the emotions
in the normal way.
This is a fairly good indicator
not to look for cues of the forehead
because they have been
literally Botoxed out.
Fixed & Synced by MoUsTaFa ZaKi