MISUNDERSTOOD
Where are the children, Duncombe?
They're not here.
I sent them away.
To the Gill's house...
as soon as I understood there was no hope.
They don't know anything yet.
To Andrea...?
I'll tell him...
he's already big.
I don't yet know how
but I'll find the courage.
Milo?
We'll try to distract him.
He believes...
that she left.
The nanny should already have arrived.
She will be very helpful,
She's a serious woman, an expert.
Milo...
he's so delicate...
so fragile...
just like...
like his mother.
Keep him close.
He needs her and you need him.
Well...
Thank for me the whole of
the English community please
Of course
-Thanks-
Accompany the Pastor to his home.
Go Andrea, closer!
Children!
Look who's here!
When did you arrive?
You came back to us?
To work?
How could I?
Don't you know I now have
a husband and laundry?
Who takes care of them?
No, I just came to give you a little visit
Blow, come on, blow.
I've got a cold!
That's not new!
Come on let's go,
I'll take you back home.
Has mum returned?
No, not yet.
Come on, say bye to Ms. Gill
and thank her again.
Good-bye Ms.Gill and
thank you very much
thank you very much!
Come on, who gets there first!
I'll give you five metres of advantage.
No, ten!
Seven!
4... 6...
9... 8... 10...
Go!
Milo don't run! Then you'll sweat
and you have a cold!
That's not fair, you left before me!
Dad!
How are you...
sweet-heart.
Well...
Did you leave mum in London?
Yes.
Why?
She still had some things to do.
-When will she get back?
-Soon.
Soon.
In how many days?
Oh...
Two...three...
How were you at Gill's?
Really well.
What are you saying?!
"Stop that baby,
be quiet baby...
don't speak baby
don't touch baby..."
And you would stop wouldn't you?
Look at him, Mr. Consul,
poor baby.
If only you were there daddy...
He chased lions...
then he fell from the north pole
and ripped his shirt
Good morning children!
No. No injection!
No Milo!
No, no, no!
-I'll take it orally
-No Milo
It's only your nanny.
Look at her
Treasure!
She's dressed for injection
-Oh no.
-Come on, come on.
Here.
I present you my two children...
This is Emilo...
this is Andrea.
This is Luisa
What's she for?
Wel...
She has to clothe you,
feed you...
she'll keep you company...
and...
she will play with you.
I'm going to play with Andrea.
Come on.
If she does everything,
then what will mother do when she returns.
I know we will immediately get on
and that Milo will now give me a kiss.
Here it is!
But why?
She's good you know...
and she knows so many nice games.
So many!
-Just like Mary Poppins?
-Of course!
Do you have a magic bag?
I have a bag,
even if it isn't magical.
I'll be with you a little.
Will you give her your hand?
Of course he'll give me it.
Well done!
What a treasure!
You also come Andrea!
No Andrea.
You wait.
I have to speak with him a moment.
Milo, go over there, be good.
I have to tell you something.
It's not easy for me...
To tell you what I have to say.
You saw...
I had to hire a nanny.
From now on it won't be the same,
here at home
When I sent you to Gill's house...
I told had them tell you...
that mother had to suddenly leave.
And it wasn't true.
Instead she was here at home.
Sick...
and...
and during your absence...
she got worse.
And now...
you see Andrea...
I know.
The Gills said it quietly...
but I heard them anyway.
Stop that!
Better that way Andrea.
It gives me pleasure
this courage of yours.
I knew you were strong in fact...
I had decided to tell you that...
mother is no more.
But until now I didn't imagine.
Better that way...
everything will be easier in your life.
There is only one thing
you have to promise me...
Yes father.
That you won't tell Milo anything.
No father.
Promise?
Promise.
Now go.
You can go.
I think you need a nice bath no?
Yes father.
I know Will...
that if you had been able
you would have come.
Don't worry about it.
She smiled until the last you know...
I still can't believe it.
The children?
No Will.
They're children.
What do you think they'll hear
Mummy! The tow...
Daddy isn't here?
No. He had to stay in the office.
He was waiting for a call from London.
Bye English!
Go!
Quick get on!
Franzini! Get down
if you have the courage!
No! You get down instead!
I'll get you off with punches!
Always you!
But even you Franzini!
Give me my hat you idiot!
Here's your hat!
Sir. Don't bother. Just forget it.
Done!
Please stop by the stationary shop
on Via Maggio.
Of course.
By the way, would you have
180 lire to lend me?
Yes Sir!
Come on my love...
this is for the love of Jesus...
come on!
But they don't make Jesus eat
this disgusting stuff!
Careful! It will spill!
Here he is! Here he is!
Hi Milo!
Close it. There's a draft.
-You have it?
-Yes
Come on love, eat up.
Andrea, go away. Let him eat in peace.
Come on, eat up,
it will make you feel better.
No. I don't like it, I'm not hungry
and I don't feel like it.
Do what you like then.
I will show your father
how much food you left.
Andrea, don't close the door...
don't put yourself out.
You see how good I was.
I ate it all.
-You ate it.
-No!
Funny.
What do you think you've done?
Milo has to nourish himself.
It had supplements.
It was disgusting.
He's right! What do you feed him?
Good. Show him your example.
I will also tell your father about you.
Milo!
But it's two days I have no fever.
now let's check eh?
Andrea has a neck wound!
Yes. This morning I fought someone.
He caled me "English".
Why aren't you English?
Yes. But when they tell you
it's an insult.
Very impressive.
Go and disinfect it at least.
-Look how cool!
-Is it stratospheric?
Of course. It cost 180 lire.
Come on!
Quick! Get the counter-weight!
-Hey. Careful about the thermometre!
-I'm holding it.
Well done!
Here...
-Do you have matches?
-Of course.
Against the wind!
Ready for take-off. Go!
10 - 9 - 8 - 7...
What are you doing idiot! Look!
- 3 - 2 - 1...
Perfect take-off.
It went at least 1000 metres
It hit a cloud.
What are you doing with the window open?
You've gone crazy Andrea!
You want him to get pneumonia!
Come my little star...
You close the window!
Oh! The thermometre!
Here it is!
Did it break?
No because I took it out.
But if I hadn't been fast...
Why you laughing?
It was your fault you know?
-My fault?
-Yes yours. Only yours.
There you see...
You made his temperature come back.
37.4.
Let me see!
Andrea give me the thermometre!
Exactly 37.
You're a liar!
I'm better! I'm better! Hurray!
Go back to bed! You still have a fever!
You have to be in bed, sleeping!
Andrea. Don't touch!
Mum.
Dad is not even coming today?
He phoned just a moment ago.
He'll dine out with some guests.
Sir. You're not hungry?
Absolutely!
Where you going with that?
To eat it.
Where?
With Milo.
No way!
Milo has to rest now.
Yes Andrea! Come eat here!
Shut up! Sleep!
I'm not tired!
And you go away immediately.
Go back to the dining hall.
-I don't feel like eating alone
-Come Andrea!
Listen Andrea.
I have to do my job here.
Your father wants Milo to rest
in the afternoon...
and I have to respect his orders.
Understood?
And even you.
-OK
-Good.
-Now stop Milo! Sleep!
-Come Andrea!
Your brother was wise, you saw?
You go away! Andrea!
Sleep Milo. We'll be together later.
-Calm down!
-No. Go away!
Don't touch me! I won't sleep anyway!
I want Andrea!
You can shout until
tomorrow evening if you want!
You can shout
until tomorrow morning...
I won't get you up until you've slept.
I want Andrea!
Stop it!
That's enough Milo!
A black crow...
was perched on the highest branch...
of a large tree...
with a nice piece of cheese
in it's beak.
A small hungry elephant came along...
"Throw me your cheese crow",
said the little elephant...
or I will make you have a nice shower.
But the crow didn't let himself
be intimidated...
and so...
the elephant's trunk launched...
A large... jet... of water...
But I'm still not sleeping.
The elephant had a good laugh...
and left.
Then a starving tiger came along...
"Fly down to me",
said the tiger sweetly.
Place your cheese on my nose...
and I will show you a wonderful game.
But the crow didn't move.
Because...
he didn't trust the tiger.
Don't turn it off.
I'm still not sleepy.
And how come Andrea?
It's late.
I don't know.
Can you stay here a little more?
You want to know how the tale ends eh?
No. I can't believe it Andrea.
You're big now no?
Yes father.
You want to know why you can't sleep?
Because you're upset about
what you did today.
What did I do?
You didn't do anything to Milo?
He was anxious all day long.
He didn't want to sleep
until I'd come back.
You saw how long it took him to fall asleep.
Why do you do these things Andrea?
You know it's bad for him.
It's the fault of that...Witch, daddy.
-Come on Andrea
-Yes daddy!
I'll tell you a good one now.
Milo didn't have a fever today.
I saw the thermometre.
But that woman invented that,
to keep him in bed.
If I took care of Milo
he wouldn't get ill again.
Don't be silly Andrea.
Now go to sleep.
What you don't believe me?!
About the fever yes, of course.
But maybe you saw badly. Good night.
Good night.
Daddy...
tomorrow, there's the judo tournament.
Can you come and see me?
Tomorrow?
-I don't think I'll be able to Andrea
-Dad!
But all the parents are there dad...
OK
As soon it will be possible Andrea.
But I can't tell the Irish Consul that...
the consul isn't here,
he went to his son's judo contest.
Don't you think?
Yes daddy.
Good night
Maybe tomorrow I would have won daddy.
Good night!
Fight!
Bussi wins.
Fanzini. Duncombe.
Salute.
Fight.
Well done Franzini!
Go English!
Franzini wins!
Salute.
Ah, it's you.
What do you want?
Why aren't you in bed?
Listen dad...
I have to explain something to you
Today I lost but...
but I was winning.
Even you saw that when you came no?
Came where?
To the Judo!
Oh yes...
but don't shout. Stay calm.
How can I be calm!?
I had already almost got his back
on the carpet...
there was nothing left,
nothing, but then...
then you came and then...
You mean it was better
if I hadn't come?
But no! You don't understand!
You told me you wouldn't come...
so I wasn't waiting for you any more...
but you came and I suddenly saw you...
so Franzini took the opportunity...
to slip from under and come on top...
but I gave it everything Dad.
Everything...
just that my arms wouldn't hold me,
they shook...
they weren't shaking,
just that they couldn't hold me.
You're really upset about losing?
No no it's not that, yes also...
just that it makes me angry...
Anyway it's not serious.
In fact. You have to also learn to lose.
You'll win next time...
when I won't be there.
Yes Dad.
Now go back to sleep.
Good night.
-I disturbed you didn't I?
-No. Not at all.
You were working with the recorder?
Well. Good night.
Good night.
John...
why you inside with this nice sun?
Come into the garden.
You come here.
What did you do?
Your hair's a mess.
I was on the swing with Andrea.
What is it, a tape recorder?
Yes.
But it's on!
It's recording everything we say?
Yes.
Come on say something. Speak.
What should I say?
Recite a poem.
Mine?
But I can't recite.
That doesn't matter...
Then...wait...read.
Try to read this, with feeling though.
What is it?
No. Not Eliot. How can I?
-Come on. You're embarrased with me?
-OK, I'll try.
That's good.
What do you want? Be quiet. Sleep.
I can't. I'm scared.
Of what? There's the lightening
conductor no?
Yes I know...
but I'm scared anyway.
Put your head under the pillow then.
Help I'm drowing! I'm drowing.
OK. OK. Come into my bed.
I'm scared even with you.
I want mum.
Stop it.
I want mum...
why doesn't she come back?
you always say she'll be back...
and she never does.
I want her.
Stop it.
Mum has things to do.
Things to do, to do,
always things to do.
Where is she?
Where do you think?
In a place.
Damn how tiresome you are.
What place?
A villa.
A marvelous villa.
With a big green lawn.
And there's also a lake...
with swans.
And then the stables...
with so many horses.
And sunday...
they go hunting foxes...
in the middle of the woods.
Like the paintings in the corridor?
Yes.
Well done.
And what's mum doing there?
Mum?
Mum...
does what she did here with us.
She prepares breakfast
with buttered bread...
she puts lipstick on.
and everyone obeys her because...
she's beautiful.
But then why doesn't she do that here.
Does she not think of us?
Of course...
of course she thinks of us.
only that...
only she can't...
Dad!
Milo.
I want to go to your bed
No darling, you can't,
don't be a nuisance...
you have to sleep in your bed.
I want to be in your bed,
not in mine!
Come on, be good little fish...
I'm scared of thunder...
Yes I'm scared of thunder.
-There is no more thunder. It's over
-Yes. It's still here.
No it went away, listen.
Now you lie here and
you'll fall asleep immediately...
I want mum.
Mum is dead.
What did you tell him?
Nothing Dad. I promise, nothing!
Come sweetheart, come with me.
Dad!
He doesn't believe me. Why?
Why doesn't Dad want to believe me?
Why?
Come on, count!
1... 2... 3... 4...
5...
7...
9...
8... 10...
12... 13...
15... 17...
Lady, what comes after 17?
What did you say?
Milo!
Please stay there!
Wait, I'm coming!
Mind out!
Stop it!
What comes after 17?
Milo, for the love of baby Jesus,
get down!
You get angry with baby Jesus!
Come on! Tell me what comes after 17!
I don't know. Who put you up there?
Andrea. I'm the stopwatch.
Andrea.
Andrea. Get down...
Milo! It doesn't count.
I met a wounded horse on the course!
Go. Start again!
1... 2...
Watch out for the wounded horse Andrea!
Andrea, I order you to stop!
-That's an order, understood?
-What's after 22?
Stop immediately! Andrea!
Now I want to see if you're
brave enough to run me over!
Get out the way!
Get out the way idiot! Get out!
Don't fall!
I could have killed you.
Yes idiot, it would have been
better if he had!
Yes, idiot, idiot and idiot!
Just look at this indiot!
She made me even break my bike.
Lady, help me down, I want to go!
I've had enough! I'm going.
Your Dad will have to find another.
I can't stand it any more!
Stay there Milo. I'm coming.
Come on, put your feet here...
Andrea, you did well. Very well.
She's really an idiot.
Mum was always happy
when I went fast on my bike.
Really!?
She would urge me on...
Quicker Andrea, come on... pedal!
Come on, you have to beat the record!
And she looked at her watch.
And...
she would give me a prize...
Now this idiot.
What right does she have?
-Andrea, shall we make a promise?
-Yes.
-Then promise
-I promise.
Well, what did you make me promise?
-I can't remember any more
-Well done!
Ah yes, even if she says sorry,
we'll send her away anyway.
I promise!
Andrea, did the slap hurt you?
No.
Then can you take me to the lake?
Of course, immediately.
Now we're free anyway.
And if another comes,
we'll send her away too.
We'll send them all away
kicking them bums...
Milo! Who teaches you
these rude words?
You.
Mum would sit here,
when she brought us to the lake.
Sat on the floor?
No. She would bring a folding chair.
Andrea, what was mum like?
You don't remember her?
Before yes, but now not so much.
Well, didn't you see
the portrait in the hall?
Yes.
In summer she was like that.
In winter a little paler.
When she ran...
she was all red, and would laugh...
I remember that she laughed.
She was always happy.
When she played cards, she would cheat!
What did she do?
She would cheat,
take two cards instead of one.
Why?
Because she wanted to win.
Dad found her out many times...
but she would say if she didn't cheat,
she didn't have fun.
You look like her.
Who? Mum?
Yes, eyes and mouth, and
when you laugh it's the same.
Andrea. What does it mean to be dead?
-It's difficult to explain
-Why?
Try to close your eyes,
not breath and block your ears.
You see. It should be
like that more or less.
No. I can't see anything.
What did you want to see?
Mum.
To see her you'd have to really die.
You know what that branch is?
It's a branch that has fallen
No, it's an audacity-meter.
What is an a-a-audacity-meter?
It's this, look!
If I hang here, nothing happens.
It doesn't creak
because there is no danger...
but if I go a little further
it goes "crack".
I've already reached two "cracks"
I want to see if I can do three.
if I do three, I beat my own record.
Careful Andrea, it went "crack"!
Yes! One!
Two!
Stop Andrea!
Shut up or I can't hear it!
Come on.
Harder, come on!
-I'll do it
-No it's mine
Come on then!
You don't have stength?
I have more!
Yes, but I spend it!
100... 200...
Wait!
600... 700...
800... 900...
1000...
The idiot forgot them.
The idiot? Good!
Anyway...
who's going to see her anymore?
3000.
3100... 3200...
5200... 5300...
5400... 5500...
5800!
-Is that enough?
-Yes.
I think so.
The important thing is
to have a nice idea.
A great one.
The price doesn't matter.
Well, wish me good luck!
Well? What happened?
What you doing on the floor?
Why you crying?
The money is half mine.
Actually more than half.
Milo, let's not start please...
I can't take you to Florence...
on the rack? Are you crazy?
Tomorrow the other one comes,
the new one.
Tomorrow?
Yes. And because of you
Dad chose a really strict one.
Andrea, today is
the last day that we two...
that us two can do what we like.
Milo, please stop it. Don't insist.
-Be good. Don't cry.
-No, I'll insist.
Or cry, but later,
wait for me to leave! Bye!
Get out Milo!
Milo, get out the way!
Anyway it's useless...
I found it!
-A pipe, a lovely pipe.
-He doesn't smoke!
Who are they?
Two sheriffs...
Milo, don't get distracted...
Think hard, we have to find
something to give Dad.
An umbrella!
He has four.
All of them bought in London.
Mum would always bring them
when she came back
Maybe they're broken.
A raincoat!
A vest!
Yes, a shirt...
what a waste to have a rich Dad.
Damn.
We just give him the money and
he buys what he likes!
Ready?
Now it's your turn Milo.
Be still and smile.
Stay still.
It's the photographers fault...
he said half an hour, then he took two.
God, let us arrive a minute...
even just one minute...before Dad.
You're going like a snail.
It went up...you're heavy!
Look at those two Mr. Consul.
How Irresponsible...
But...
It's Andrea...and Milo is also there!
Andrea, let go of the bus,
let go immediately!
You want to kill youself?
Let go I told you!
We'll settle this at home!
I don't know what to say Andrea.
I give up.
It's not worth shouting at you!
You don't have the slightest
sense of responsibility.
Are you listening?
Yes Dad.
Ok then.
From now on, for me,
you can do whatever you like.
All the crazy things you want.
Anyway it's useless
fighting against you.
But only you...
and not with Milo!
Did you understand me?
I didn't want to take him Dad...
he wanted to come,
he always follows me.
And why does he follow?
Because he cares for you no?
-Yes Dad.
-Whereas you obviously do not.
You think you do, but
for you he's a toy, some fun...
What do you want?
Happy birthday, Dad.
Ah, it's my birthday.
True, thanks so much.
Open it.
[Be Prudent. Don't go Fast]
Do you like it Dad?
It's really a magnificent thought...
I am very happy, thank you.
We bought it with both our money.
-Oh yes?
-But I had more...
Now go though eh? Go over there...
So it's I who should be prudent eh?
Send me to college Dad...
I'm too naughty.
You're not naughty.
You're just made that way.
Things don't affect you, they slide off...
I didn't even see you suffer when...
then I had said it was lucky
for you to be like that
but be careful
not to exaggerate though.
Because at some point,
without meaning to...
you could really harm your brother...
Now go, go...enough.
Thanks for the present.
But there is only one present
I want from you.
Only one.
Try to be better...
at least try.
You promise?
Yes Dad.
Kids! Where did you hide
my right slipper?
Hello? Nazi spy has passed...
she didn't see me.
OK. Received. Stay alert.
Only shoot if necessary.
Operation Martian Base in Space
continues...
Seen: mysterious black figure...
seems like a mummy...
probably in a state of hibernation.
threatened by a remote-controlled robot!
With... metal fingers...
Arriving Lawrence of Arabia and
the White Sheriff...
Friends or foes?
Attention attention!
Dinosaur sighting...
Threatening...
my right foot.
Base. Sighted new mysterious object
in distance...
I'll go an explore...
Over and out.
agent ZK here...
Spy X2 here, can I go and pee?
You disturb me for this?
I'm in the middle of action. Go!
Thank you!
John!
Why you inside with this nice sun?
You come here.
What did yo do?
Your hair is a mess
I was on the swing with Andrea.
What is it, a tape recorder?
Yes.
Oh God! It's on.
And it's recording everything we say?
Yes.
Come on say something. Speak.
What should I say?
Recite a poem.
But I can't recite.
That doesn't matter...
Then...wait...read.
Try to read this, with feeling though.
What is it?
No. Not Eliot. How can I?
-Come on. You're embarrased with me?
-OK, I'll try.
That's good.
Hello!
Here spy X2, uncle Will has arrived.
For me it's enough
if I can't hear chickens...
or children.
I can get them to pull off
the chicken's neck
But not the children?
Ah, here they are. Come, come in...
Thank you Miss. Judy.
This is...
Milo.
Milo, what you doing,
who told you you can...?
Eat!
Eat. At least your mouth will be busy...
-And this is Andrea.
-Good morning
Hi Andrea.
Last time I saw you,
you were this small...
You grew.
Well done.
Well done, both of you.
You go to school?
I go to school. He's still small.
He's really good.
He has all 9 and 10.
Oh my God!
I don't want to believe it!
Why?
Because studying is absolutely...
unnatural.
A slow suicide.
I study very little. Almost never.
How do you manage?
Don't tell me you're intelligent
by any chance?
Not particularly.
Oh good.
Why?
Becuase intelligence, remember child...
is even more dangerous than study.
Don't worry Andrea.
Uncle Will is joking.
Not at all.
I'm always convinced by what I say.
-Enough now!
-It's for Uncle.
Thanks my dear.
In any case I realise that as educator
I am of little value.
The truth is I don't like children.
And I don't like old people.
Andrea, you lack humour.
On the contrary! Nice reply...
well done Andrea!
Yes, yes, but now go and play.
-Yes Father.
-And don't make noise.
Break all you like...
but do it in silence.
Let's go Milo.
Uncle Will. What do you have
in all those suitcases?
Nothing important.
Just some heads.
-Heads?
-Yes, little children's heads.
I collect them.
My recorder!
Who touched it Mr. Casilino?
-I didn't Mr. Consul
-Someone touched it! A tape disappeared.
I don't know Mr. Consul.
-You know what there is in the suitcases?
-Leave me!
Have you gone mad?
Milo did you hurt yourself?
-To my head
-You are crazy Milo.
-I didn't touch it Dad!
-You threw him on the ground!
No Dad, I didn't touch
your tape recorder.
I hope you aren't lying Andrea.
No Dad.
I promise.
-Cancelled.
-Cancelled, you know what that means?
It's not there anymore. It's gone.
Can't you make it return?
How can you if it's not there any more?
You must have pressed the wrong button,
but the tape is still good.
Try again. Do something.
I'll pay all you like.
Nothing to do with paying,
don't you understand?
If it's not there, it's not there.
And yet you seem like an intelligent boy.
Come here, boy!
You forgot the tape.
You're crying?
What was on that tape?
My mother's voice.
Your mother's voice?
-Yes.
-And you cry?
Why?
-Is she dead?
-Yes.
Yes?
So sorry little one,
but what can I do?
If I was a magician...
Come, come poor boy.
Calm down, come on.
I'll give you a drop of stuff
and it'll lift you up.
It's strong eh? It burns.
But it's great.
In a minute you'll feel like new man.
Come, sit here.
You'll feel immediately better,
you'll see.
Hello?
Yes it's me. What do you want?
OK.
Not today.
Tomorrow. Of course.
He's drunk!
Not in your room.
In mine, it's safer.
Grit your teeth son,
let's not leave traces.
No no, not on the carpet.
One last effort.
Here we are.
If I were you,
I would try to vomit quietly...
otherwise everyone will arrive.
And I promise
you are not a pleasant site.
-Finished?
-Yes.
First you filled up...
then you emptied.
And now a little on the bed.
And now, if your use of reason has
returned, remove for me one curiosity...
you get drunk every Thursday,
or today was special?
It's the first time Uncle.
Ah well, you started a little quickly.
I know that sometimes
these steps are necessary...
I think you had good motives...
don't ask me Uncle, I won't tell you.
No no, don't worry...
There's a tacit agreement
between us drinkers...
to respect the others right to get drunk.
Now rest, and try to look presentable
for dinner at least.
You know Uncle, it's not true
I don't like old people.
And I continue to not like children.
There in that tomb is a preacher,
with a huge beard...
with the face of a bandit.
There is a poetess...
with her husband, but she's not famous...
a certain Parker,
who isn't in the encyclopedia.
This one's son died 100 years ago...
-There is Mum
-You're right at home here.
You come often?
Sometimes.
Oh Dad, they're here even this time.
Yes.
Cornflowers, she liked so much,
they're always here.
I wonder who brings them.
-Dad shall I go change the water?
-Go.
You know what I often think Will?
I should have forced her
to take care of herself.
-Maybe...
-Why do you continue to torment yourself?
You couldn't have made her live
under a glass bowl...
she would never have been happy
She was like that, John.
Look Will.
Look at Andrea.
The world could collapse and
he continues to play.
I think you're wrong John.
Andrea is like a dog without an owner.
Try to caress him...
Andrea is not a dog.
He's a child...
and I expect from him human reactions.
I don't want to offend children or dogs...
but they both share the need for an owner.
I tried to be a friend to Andrea.
Not friend John, owner.
Make him carry a paper in his mouth
and you'll see how happy he'll be.
Oh Will.
Can't you speak seriously even once?
No but I'll shut up.
Anyway you've understood me.
Well Dad? Aren't we going?
Listen Will...
leave me at the Consulate.
You keep the car and go where you like.
I don't know... Florence...
Maybe Andrea wants to go on the go-cart.
Yes. The go-cart, and I'll watch.
I have a group of Nigerian students
for breakfast.
You also come, and then at 3
we'll take you to the station?
So we'll see you at the restaurant.
Don't pick me up.
I'll come directly with the Nigerians.
OK.
Andrea.
Wouldn't you like to stay with me instead?
Why?
Well, you could help me...
you could open my letters,
if you want to of course.
Yes, I want to, I want to.
Even me, Even I want to come!
I want to open the letters.
It's boring, it's a job!
Go, go...
we're going to have fun.
Let me get off,
I want to go with Dad.
Come.
Listen...
wouldn't you have prefered to go
with Milo to the go-cart?
No Dad. I prefer to be with you
2 million times!
-Let's go?
-Of course.
Where you going?
My office is on the ground floor.
What, you'd never come here?
Never Dad.
Really?
Upstairs are the rooms
for receptions and parties.
Here works your father.
Make yourself comfortable.
Do you like it?
Yes father.
Sit down. Sit.
Did you see the portrait of the queen?
The big one.
There's a dedicated autograph on it.
To Sir John Edward Duncan.
How much post eh!?
But the portrait we have of mum
at home is nicer.
Here she's a bit sad.
Yes. You're right.
She wasn't like that.
-Good morning Mr. Consul.
-Good morning Charles, come in.
Did you see the post?
Yes, thank you Charles.
Let me introduce my son Andrea.
My eldest.
Good morning Andrea, how are you?
This morning he came here
to give me a hand.
Well done.
I had to open his envelopes.
I got distracted Andrea, how stupid of me!
That doesn't matter.
Take this pad and ped and go to that table.
Take the stool.
Give him a hand please Charles.
I'll dictate a letter.
A very important letter...
to our ambassador in Rome.
Come, sit.
-Are you ready?
-Yes Dad.
Good.
So good luck.
Excuse me.
Thank you Charles
"My dear ambassador...
I reply to you about...
the projected transfer...
to another site...
of the offices of our consulate...
here in Florence.
There are many problems...
and I would prefer to tell you in person...
during my next visit to Rome.
Slower Dad.
You're right, sorry.
-Tell me.
-Yes Dad.
Saturday, in school,
what important lessons do you have?
Saturday...
class work in Maths, why?
Because...
...I thought to bring you to Rome with me.
-But if you have class work...
-Yes Dad. Please!
We could leave by car
after you get back from school.
We eat on the way,
and in 3 hours we're in Rome...
-and we come back sunday evening
-Really Dad. You mean it?
Of course. Nothing wrong with that.
But you'll have to be
a perfect secretary...
otherwise why should I bring you?
Yes Dad.
In the meantime lets finish this letter.
So. Re-read it.
Where did you get to?
"Dear Ambassador...
A friend of mine died exactly that way...
they boiled him...
then they covered him in mayonnaise,
capers and olives...
a nice portion of salad...
luckily it wasn't a great loss
because he was unfriendly.
-But we have to tell Dad.
-Better not to.
Here they are.
Come on Will...
-it's an hour we're looking for you.
-What you doing there?
Come on, quick, we're hungry!
We worked!
Come on Milo, come!
What you doing? Go back to your table.
Come on!
What is this novelty.
You don't get up from the table, you know.
And you don't whisper.
If you have something to say...
say it out loud.
So. What did you want to tell Andrea?
Come on.
Well?
I can't hear.
I told you not to speak in a low voice...
bring it out!
Come on.
What you scared of?
Don't worry. No one will eat you.
That's not true!
Carnivorous men eat human flesh!
Milo. What are you saying?
Have you gone mad?
Uncle Will told me.
They are cannibals, they eat human flesh,
especially...
if it's tender...h
and white.
I'm certain that your Uncle couldn't
have said such a shocking thing.
Do you realise what you've done?
You've offended my guests.
Why did you get him angry today.
He had promised me something.
You will see...
Wait...
Bye!
They'll roast you, Uncle Will.
On the grill!
-Andrea, where you going?
-Shh. Sleep!
Andrea, where you going!?
Milo, what you doing here?
Go back to sleep!
Why you running away from home?
Me? Are you crazy?
Go back to bed or you'll get a cold.
Go! Come on.
If you're not running away
why did you take the car?
To wash it. I want to surprise Dad.
Even I want to surprise him.
But Dad has been good to me, not to you.
What have you got to do with it?
Why has he been good?
He's taking me to Rome.
I don't believe you.
Yes. We're going today, after lunch.
Me and him.
I also want to come to Rome.
But Milo we're going for work.
He needs a secretary so he's taking me.
I help him. Please Milo. Go to sleep.
Even I'll help him!
Shut up! Shut up!
You can't! You're too young!
Even you are young.
-I'm the eldest son.
-Even I'm the eldest.
Shut up! Shut up!
Listen Milo. If I let you wash the car
with me will you stop?
Will you stop?
Yes.
-And then you'll go to sleep?
-What?
And then you'll go to sleep?
Yes.
What?
OK.
-Is the water arriving?
-Yes.
Don't come down here, you'll get wet,
and then get a cold.
Stay there.
Now turn it off.
What are you doing? Have you gone mad?
Why did you wet yourself?
Come here, I'll dry you.
Milo, stop!
Why do you run, why did you wet yourself?
I didn't do it on purpose.
-Yes, you did it on purpose.
-I didn't do it on purpose.
Don't talk nonsense Andrea.
Who do you think will believe you?
Why would he have wet himself?
-I don't know but he did!
-Not true.
Yes it's true. I saw you perfectly.
And now I'll go and tell Dad.
It's enough that he believes me.
You can't wake him up now.
Dad got in late.
He said he shouldn't be called before 9.
Before 9?
Doesn't matter.
You tell him when he wakes up.
Just tell him everything I told you.
You'll see. He'll believe me.
Now everything has changed.
Yes, and be late for school too.
Well done.
You are even sneezing on purpose now.
Won't you take my temperature.
Miss Judy. Did Dad leave?
Yes.
-Left for Rome?
-Yes.
Didn't you explain to him?
Dad didn't take you to Rome.
-Why?
-Dad is really angry.
You're dead when he comes back!
Now I even have a fever.
38.2
Didn't you tell him it was you?
No.
You see, even I'm the first-born.
Andrea, can you help me glue?
Hello is that the Hotel Excelsior of Rome?
Is...
His Excellence...
John Edward Duncombe?
What did you say?
Yes, tell him his son, he knows me.
Don't get disturbed.
Where are you?
At home Dad.
Good evening Dad.
First of all,
who gave you permission to call Rome?
I'll pay Dad. For one week,
don't give me pocket money.
Listen Dad. I don't mind that
you didn't take me to Rome.
I mind that you believe me.
This time it's not my fault
if Milo has fever.
He has a fever?
Yes he does, but only a little.
Miss Judy has called the doctor.
Yes, I'll call her later.
Listen Dad, this morning I wanted...
Yes Dad.
Immediately Dad.
Miss Judy. Come immediately. Dad is here.
WHat is it Andrea?
Andrea, where are you?
Where did you end up?
What you doing there?
Dad on the phone from Rome
wants to speak with you.
Oh. Good evening Mr. Duncombe.
Actually I thought I wouldn't disturb you.
To not worry you.
-Pass him to me.
-A normal cold like other times.
Yes. He ordered the usual things...
and said it's time to take the tonsils out.
Yes, he's sleeping.
More than an hour ago...
His fever's going.
no, there's no need to change your plans.
Come when you've decided.
OK. Don't worry Mr.Duncombe.
Good night Mr...
Oh sorry. Andrea wanted to speak with you.
Very well...
Good night Mr. Duncombe.
He was in a rush.
He says he'll speak with you
when he returns.
No. Anyway he's not interested.
But if he thinks I'll pay the phone call,
he's crazy!
-Santina. The thermos!
-Here it is.
Bye Milo. You'll see
how lovely the clinic is...
when you come back
I'll make you a ricotta pudding.
-Mr. Consul. The post.
-Ah. Thanks.
-Get in the back please.
-Please open the door.
I'll give you my tonsils
so you can put them in alcohol.
Come back quickly.
Quick, let's go.
No, the operation went well...
but now he has to go 15 days to the sea
for the convalescence.
He's not even coming back for one day.
After tomorrow
he comes out of the clinic...
and Dad will accompany him by car...
to Castilloncello. Him and Miss Judy.
And you're not going?
I have school.
Give here.
Did I burn them?
No, but it's ironed enough.
So give me something else.
Don't you have anything else to do?
Anyway it's late.
It's 7 and I have to close.
Another 5 minutes...
If the guard passes and sees the
shutter open, it's a 10,000 lire fine.
Go quickly. It's late for you too.
They'll shout at you.
Give me. I'll do it.
No one shouts at me anymore.
Why, have you become good?
I don't know. For them it's enough
that I'm not in the way.
You regret the scoldings?
-There you are.
-Thanks.
Come back when you like.
You keep me company.
I don't need company.
I said you would keep it for me.
OK.
If I find 2 hours I'll come. Bye.
Orange juice, beer...
Can I have a beer?
100 lire thanks.
A popcorn please.
-How much is it?
-The coke?
-No everything. I'll pay for everything.
-200
There you are.
-Thank you.
-Your welcome.
I'm one of those
who if I have my 5 minutes...
I always kick Maria, the waitress...
and Miss. Judy I send to hell
just as she starts to speak.
And I sent my brother to hospital
by beating him...
What does your Dad say?
I never see my Dad. Not even for lunch.
Why, he has a whole day?
No, he's a politician.
But I have other ideas.
You know they operated my appendix?
If only you knew!
They put me to sleep.
But first they tied me.
With straps. There was gauze,
alcohol, scissors, everything...
What a hospital. My mother has insurance...
-And your mother?
-Well my mother...
-Why you don't have one?
-Of course I do.
But she's always in her room.
She never leaves.
Why, is she old?
What old? She's 20.
So she had you when she was 10...
What's that got to do with it?
I don't know...
But she... she's the only one
I get on with...
She talks, sings,
and I record her on tape.
The tape for hair?
What hair-tape! On the...
recorder.
I have to go. Bye.
Wait a little more. We talk, we chat...
I have to go, bye.
-Hey, but what's your name?
-Dracula.
Andrea! I've come back!
Milo, you got better!
Yes, how many "cracks" did you get to?
Four. But who did you come with?
By myself. I escaped...
Come on Andrea. Do it!
Now I'll come too!
No Milo. I'm on the limit of safety! No!
Just until the first "crack".
Stop! It can't hold both of us!
I'm light.
They even took my tonsils out.
Stop! No!...
Mr. Consul, I'm so glad you arrived...
Miss Judy just called from the villa.
She was very agitated.
Why?
I don't know. She didn't tell me.
She didn't even know herself...
but it seems that
both children fell in the lake.
Milo. If something happened to Milo...
No. It's useless to telephone,
no one will reply...
not even Miss Judy is there.
She went to find the children.
This time he'll pay!
Run!
-Milo!
-Dad!
Milo where are you?
How are you darling?
Are you okay?
God, what a fright!
-Mr. Consul
-Yes?
They climbed up a branch, the branch broke,
and they fell into the water.
Andrea we took to the little room.
-What do you mean "you took him"?
-The audacity-metre broke.
I don't know what that means.
But come over there, come to Andrea.
Why did you put him here?
He asked for it.
The syringe please.
You see... everything went well.
Milo...
didn't hurt himself.
Don't think about it.
You're in a lot of pain...
What's wrong with him, what did you do?
Be calm Andrea...
you'll see that in a minute
you won't feel the pain.
Tighten your fist.
Well done. Like that.
Excuse me?
Milo, stay over there.
Andrea has hurt himself.
Yes son. I'm here.
You're...
angry with me?
No, no Andrea. Why should I be?
Yes because I knew it was dangerous.
but only because of that I did it.
It would help me settle my nerves.
Nerves? Why?
No it's not a worsening...
it's only the effect of the injection.
He's falling asleep.
What does he have? Tell me!
Unfortunately I fear there might be...
-a lesion to the spinal column.
-What!?
How is it possible?
The branch fell on him and
he hit some stones below.
I don't want to move him.
We have to x-ray him immediately...
and call a specialist.
Where is the telephone?
Take the Doctor to my office.
Come.
No, wait!
I'll go.
I'll telephone...
I want the best, from Rome, Milan...
from abroad if necessary.
They can fly here.
He's still agitated.
He asks for you.
Here Andrea. I'm here.
Send all those Doctors away.
Don't call them again.
Why?
Because I don't want them.
I don't want them.
But they're here to cure you.
To heal you.
They can't.
-They're not capable.
-Yes, yes Andrea.
They're the best.
The best in the world.
No Dad, I know what a paralysis
of the lower limbs means.
I heard them...
while they were saying it.
I will not...be able to walk again.
No, no, no. I assure you.
You misunderstood.
Let's hope.
Why did you put him in a cage?
Come up, quiet, quiet...
what you doing here?
Go back to bed.
-Let's go.
-What's he doing under there?
-To make him breath...
-Go with Miss Judy.
Let's go Milo.
Be good.
I have to say good night to Andrea.
Quiet. I'll give it for you.
-No me!
-You'll give it when he's better.
And if he gets better in the daytime?
Promise me one thing...
What? Anything you want.
Swear it.
I swear.
If I won't be able to walk again,
don't cure me.
I told you you will walk.
You're already getting better.
I'm not scared of dying you know?
Even Mum died.
Remove the tent, I don't want it!
You have to be under here love.
It's good for you.
I don't want it.
I don't want to live without Mum.
But I am here dear,
I will always be close by...
always next to you.
No. You only love Milo.
No. I don't want to live without Mum.
You never embrace me.
Mr. Teacher...
I didn't finish the essay...
It doesn't come...
I don't know what to write anymore...
I'm sorry.
Who cares!
It's too strong.
Too strong.
It burns.
It's breaking my ear-drums.
It's dark.
Like the tape recorder,
I erased your voice.
Only Dad wanted to listen to it.
It's the fever.
I'll give him an injection.
Only a miracle they said.
If he survives,
he will never move again.
Paralysed Will, from the waist down.
He's as if dead.
We can't move him, not even from the sofa.
Not even touch him.
He still has the shirt he had yesterday,
when he was running and jumping.
I messed everything up.
I thought he was invulnerable, instead...
Instead... he was weaker.
And...
now it is he who judges me.
He thinks I never loved him.
He can't go like this.
Without having me spoken to him.
But he has so few moments of clarity.
Hello. ZK here...
I see a very mean animal.
Here mean animal...
see good boy to eat.
-Did he wake up?
-No he's still sleeping, but he seems calm.
Thank you.
Mr. Consul.
Maria told me that since yesterday
you haven't eaten.
Would you like me to prepare something?
No, I don't want anything. Thanks.
Milo. Be quiet.
No. Let him play.
Go and sleep for an hour.
I don't want to sleep.
I only want to speak with Andrea.
Every minute could be the last.
Please go upstairs and
get my electric razor.
Do you mind?
Of course no Mr. Consul.
The notebook...
I want to finish the exam...
I'm not able to...
Mr. Teacher, I'm not able to...
It's too hard.
He always says that in his delirium.
He always talks of this notebook.
About this exercise.
I can't finish it at home.
Dad... can't help me.
Why?
Hi Dad.
Hi son.
You slept you know?
How do you feel?
Well.
So so
What is that?
This?
You didn't read it?
I wanted to read it with you.
I heard you speak about it in your dream.
You spoke of a homework you couldn't do...
Maybe I can help you?
No Dad. Don't read it.
I didn't finish it.
I know. Because of that...
I want to try to help you.
At least once.
If you want.
"Describe your best friend, and explain...
on what your friendship is based."
"Without any doubt...
my best friend is my father.
"Naturally he is much older than me...
but this makes no difference"
"He's very tall, he's very strong...
"He can easily pick me up with one arm,
and he speaks many languages"
"Beyond Father-Son,
we are very good friends and...
our friendship is based on many things"
"For example we often play together...
and there is never a secret between us"
"If sometimes I feel sad,
he immediately understands me..."
"So he picks me up,
and says to me..."
Why didn't you finish it?
You never say anything to me.
Do you want us to finish it together?
I beg you. Let's try.
-If you want.
-Of course. Immediately.
Let's see how we can continue it...
"He picks me up in his arms...
and he says "Son...
"forgive me...
"because it's not true that your father
has always understood you...
He was so blinded by his pain,
that he didn't realise...
that...
maybe you suffered even more than him...
true?
"Dad took a long time to understand this.
Too long.
"And this is sad... unforgiveable...
"But from now on we will
really be friends because...
"because now it's he who asks you...
"and he's proud to ask you...
"you are exactly the son
that every father...
"would want to have...
Is... is that all true Dad?
You'll see... that I'll get better...
and I don't care if I can't walk anymore...
But I feel so weak.
So... even if I don't live...
don't be sad.
When mum... left...
I stayed with you.
But if Mum wants me now.
Dad.
Andrea, I was able to go round the house
with the ball without making a mistake.
Dad. Has he gone to sleep?
Yes.
Will he wake if I give him a kiss?
No.
Go. Go back to play.