School finally ended
and summer came...
and so did Dill.
- Good mornin'.
- Good mornin'. My, you're up...
mighty bright and early.
Ooh, I been up since 4:00.
- 4:00 ?
- Oh, yes, I always get up at 4:00.
It's in my blood.
My daddy was a railroad man
'til he got rich.
Now he flies airplanes.
One of these days,
he's just gonna swoop
down here at Maycomb,
pick me up and take me
for a ride.
Who's that in the car
with Sheriff Tate ?
Tom Robinson, son.
Where's he been ?
In the Abbottsville jail.
- Why ?
- The sheriff thought
he'd be safer there.
They're bringin' him
back here tonight...
because his trial
is tomorrow.
- Well, good evenin', Heck.
- Good evenin', Mr. Finch.
Come in.
The news has gotten around
the county about my bringin'
Tom Robinson back to the jail.
I, uh, heard there might be trouble
from that bunch out at Old Sarum.
Cal, if I need you to stay here tonight,
can you do it ?
- Yes, sir, I can.
- Thank you.
I think you better
count on stayin'.
Yes, sir.
- What's goin' on ?
- Shh. Go back to sleep.
- Shh.
Hey, there's his car.
There he is over there.
No, Scout, don't go to him.
He might not like it.
I just wanted to see where he was
and what he was up to.
He's all right.
Let's go back home.
Come on.
- He in there, Mr. Finch ?
- He is.
He's asleep.
Don't wake him.
You know what we want.
Get aside from that door,
Mr. Finch.
Walter...
I think you oughta turn
right around and go back home.
- Heck Tate's around here somewhere.
- No, he ain't !
Heck and his bunch is out in Old Sarum,
lookin' for us.
We knowed he was,
so we come in this other way.
- You ain't thought
about that, had you, Mr. Finch ?
- I thought about it.
- I can't see Atticus.
Well, that changes things some.
Atticus.
- Hey, Atticus.
- Jem, go home.
Take Scout and Dill
home with you.
- Son, I said go home.
- No, sir.
- I'll send him home.
- Don't you touch him !
Let him go !
That'll do, Scout.
Ain't nobody gonna
do Jem that way !
You get 'em out of here,
Mr. Finch.
Jem, I want you to please leave.
- No, sir. - Jem !
I tell you, I ain't goin'.
Hey, Mr. Cunningham.
I said, "Hey, Mr. Cunningham."
How's your entailment gettin' along ?
Don't you remember me,
Mr. Cunningham ?
I'm Jean Louise Finch.
You brought us some hickory nuts
one morning. Remember ?
We had a talk.
I went and got my daddy
to come out and thank you.
I go to school with your boy.
I go to school with Walter.
He's a nice boy.
Tell him "hey" for me,
won't you ?
You know somethin',
Mr. Cunningham ?
Entailments are bad.
- Entailments
Atticus, I was just sayin'
to Mr. Cunningham
that entailments were bad,
but not to worry.
It takes a long time sometimes.
What's the matter ?
I sure meant no harm,
Mr. Cunningham.
No harm taken, young lady.
I'll tell Walter
you said, "Hey."
Let's clear outta here.
Let's go, boys.
- Now you can go home.
All of you.
I'll be there later.
Come on.
Mr. Finch, are they gone ?
They've gone.
They won't bother you anymore.
'Morning, Mr. Strikes.
- How do you do ?
- Ever seen so many people ?
Just like on Saturday.
Where you goin' ?
I can't stand it any longer.
I'm goin' to the courthouse and watch.
- You better not.
You know what Atticus said.
- I don't care if he did.
I'm not gonna miss
the most exciting thing that
ever happened in this town.
It's packed solid.
They're standin' all along the back.
- Reverend. - Yes ?
- Reverend Sykes,
are you going upstairs ?
- Yes, I am.
- Thank you, Brother John,
for holding my seat.
- That's okay, Reverend.
Come on, children.
Come on, come on.
This court's now in session.
Everybody rise.
On the night of August 21,
I was just leaving my office
to go home when Bob-
Mr. Ewell came in.
Very excited he was,
and he said to get to his house
as quick as I could,
that his girl
had been raped.
I got in my car and went out
there as fast as I could.
She was pretty well beat up.
I asked her if Tom Robinson
beat her like that.
She said, yes, he had.
I asked if he'd
taken advantage of her.
She said, "Yes, he did."
That's all there was to it.
Thank you.
Did anybody call a doctor, Sheriff ?
- No, sir.
- Why not ?
Well, I didn't think
it was necessary.
She was pretty well beat up.
Somethin' sure happened.
It was obvious.
Now, Sheriff, you say that she was
mighty beat up. In what way ?
Well, she was beaten
around the head.
There were bruises
already comin' on her arms.
She had a black eye startin'.
- Which eye ?
- Let's see.
It was her left.
Well, now, was that, uh-
That was her left,
facing you...
or looking the way
that you were ?
Oh, yes, that would make it
her right eye.
It was her right eye, Mr. Finch.
Now I remember.
She was beaten up
on that side of her face.
Which side again, Heck ?
The right side.
She had bruises
on her arms and...
she showed me her neck.
There were definite finger marks
on her gullet.
Well...
all around her neck,
at the back of her throat ?
I'd say they were all around.
The witness may be seated.
Robert E. Lee Ewell.
Place your hand
on the Bible, please.
Do you solemnly swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth, and nothing but
the truth, so help you God ?
- I do.
- Sit down, please.
Now, Mr. Ewell,
you tell us,
just in your own words,
what happened on August 21.
Well, that night...
I was comin' from the woods
with a load of kindlin'...
and I heard Mayella screamin'
as I got to the fence.
So I dropped my kindlin',
and I run as fast as I could,
but I run into the fence.
But when I got loose,
I run up to the window,
and I seen him
with my Mayella !
What did you do
after you saw the defendant ?
I run around the house
tryin' to get in,
but he done run through the front door
just ahead of me !
But I seen who it was, all right !
- I seen him. -
And I run in the house and...
poor Mayella was layin'
on the floor squallin'.
Then I run for Mr. Tate
just as quick as I could.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, Mr. Ewell.
Would you mind if I just,
uh, ask you a few questions, Mr. Ewell ?
No, sir, Mr. Finch,
I sure wouldn't.
Folks were doin' a lot
of running that night.
You say that you ran to the house,
you ran to the window,
you ran inside, you ran to Mayella,
you ran to Sheriff Tate.
Did you, during all this running,
run for a doctor ?
There wasn't no need to.
I seen who done it.
Now, Mr. Ewell, you've heard
the sheriff's testimony.
Do you agree with his description
of Mayella's injuries ?
I agree with everything
Mr. Tate said.
Her eye was blacked.
She was mighty beat up,
mighty beat up.
Now, Mr. Ewell, can you, uh...
can you read and write ?
Yes, sir, Mr. Finch,
I can read and I can write.
Good.
- Then will you write your name, please.
-
Write there.
Show us.
So what's so interesting ?
You're left-handed, Mr. Ewell.
What's that got to do with it, Judge ?
I'm a God-fearin' man.
That Atticus Finch,
he's tryin' to take advantage of me !
You got to watch tricky lawyers
like Atticus Finch !
Quiet. Quiet, sir.
Now the witness
may take his seat.
Mayella Violet Ewell.
Put your hand
on the Bible, please.
Do you solemnly swear
to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God ?
Sit down, please.
Now, Mayella...
suppose you tell us
just what happened, huh ?
Well, sir-
Sir... I was s-sittin'
on the porch...
and he come along.
There's this old chifforobe
in the yard,
and l-l said,
"You come in here, boy,
and bust up this chifforobe,
and I'll give you a nickel."
So he come on in the yard,
and I go in the house
to get him the nickel...
and I turn around
and before I know it, he's on me.
I fought and hollered...
but he had me
around the neck...
and he hit me,
again and again.
And the next thing I knew,
Papa was in the room...
a-standin' over me, hollerin',
"Who done it ? Who done it ?"
Thank you, Mayella.
Your witness, Atticus.
Miss Mayella,
is your father good to you ?
I mean, is he easy
to get along with ?
Does tolerable.
Except when he's drinking.
When he's riled...
has he ever beaten you ?
My pa's never touched
a hair on my head in my life.
You say that you asked Tom to come in
and chop up a- What was it ?
A chifforobe.
Was that the first time that you ever
asked him to come inside the fence ?
Yes.
Didn't you ever ask him to come
inside the fence before ?
I might have.
Can you remember any other occasion ?
No.
You say, "He caught me, he choked me,
and he took advantage of me."
Is that right ?
Do you remember him
beating you about the face ?
No.
I don't...
recollect if he hit me.
I mean, y-yes !
H-He hit me !
- He hit me ! -
Thank you.
Now will you identify
the man who beat you.
I most certainly will.
Sittin' right yonder.
Tom, will you stand up, please ?
Let Miss Mayella
have a good long look at you.
Tom, will you
catch this, please ?
Thank you.
Now, then, this time, will you please
catch it with your left hand.
I can't, sir.
Why can't you ?
I can't use
my left hand at all.
I got it caught in a cotton gin
when I was 12 years old.
All my muscles were tore loose.
Is this the man
who raped you ?
It most certainly is.
How ?
I don't know how.
He done it.
He just done it.
You have testified...
that he choked you
and he beat you.
You didn't say that he sneaked up
behind you and knocked you out cold,
but that you turned around...
and there he was.
Do you want to tell us
what really happened ?
I got something to say...
and then I ain't
gonna say no more !
He took advantage of me !
And if you fine,
fancy gentlemen...
ain't gonna do
nothing about it,
then you're just a bunch of lousy,
yellow, stinkin' cowards !
The whole bunch of ya !
And your fancy airs
don't come to nothin' !
Your "ma'am"-ing
and your "Miss Mayella"-ing,
it don't come to nothin',
Mr. Finch !
N-N-
You sit down now.
Atticus.
Mr. Gilmer.
The State rests, Judge.
Tom Robinson, take the stand.
Put your hand on the Bible.
Do you solemnly swear
to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God ?
- I do. - Sit down.
Now, Tom...
were you acquainted
with Mayella Violet Ewell ?
Yes, sir. I had to pass her place
going to and from the field every day.
- Is there any other way to go ?
- No, sir.
None's I know of.
- And did she ever speak to you ?
- Why, yes, sir.
I'd tip my hat when I'd go by.
One day she asked me
to come inside the fence...
and bust up
a chifforobe for her.
She give me the hatchet,
and I broke it up.
And then she said, "I reckon I'll
have to give you a nickel, won't I ?"
And I said, "No, ma'am.
There ain't no charge."
And I went home.
Mr. Finch, that was way last spring.
Way over a year ago.
Did you ever go
on the place again ?
Yes, sir.
When ?
Well, I went lots of times.
Seemed like every time
I passed by yonder,
she would have
some little something for me to do:
chopping kindlin'
and totin' water for her.
Tom...
what happened to you...
on the evening of August 21
of last year ?
Mr. Finch, I was going home
as usual that evening.
When I passed the Ewell place,
Miss Mayella were on the porch,
like she said she were.
She said for me to come there
and help her a minute.
Well, I went inside the fence,
and I looked around
for some kindlin' to work on,
but I didn't see none.
Then she said to come in the house,
she has a door needs fixin'.
So I follows her inside,
and I looked at the door...
and it looked all right.
Then she shut the door.
All the time I was wondering
why it was so quiet.
Then it come to me.
There was not a child
on the place.
And I said, "Miss Mayella,
where are the children ?"
She said,
"They all gone to get ice cream."
She said it took her a year to save
seven nickels, but she'd done it.
And they'd all gone to town.
What did you say then ?
Well, I said something like...
"Why, Miss Mayella,
that's right nice of you to treat 'em."
She said, "You think so ?"
Well, I said, "I best be goin'."
I couldn't do nothin' for her.
And she said I could.
I asked her what.
And she said to just step
on the chair yonder...
and get that box down
from on top of the chifforobe.
So I done like she told me,
and I was reachin'...
when the next thing I knows,
she grabbed me around the legs.
She scared me so bad,
I hopped down and turned the chair over.
That was the only thing-
only furniture-
disturbed in the room, Mr. Finch,
I swear, when I left it.
And what happened after you
turned the chair over ?
Tom ?
You've sworn to tell the whole truth.
Will you do it ?
What happened after that ?
Mr. Finch,
I got down off the chair,
and I turned around...
and she sorta jumped on me.
She hugged me
around the waist.
She reached up and kissed me
on the face.
She said she'd never kissed
a grown man before...
and she might as well kiss me.
She says for me
to kiss her back,
and I said,
"Miss Mayella, let me outta here,"
and I tried to run.
Mr. Ewell cussed at her
from the window.
He said he's gonna kill her.
And what happened after that ?
I was runnin' so fast,
I don't know what happened.
Tom, did you rape
Mayella Ewell ?
I did not, sir.
Did you harm her in any way ?
Robinson,
you're pretty good at bustin' up
chifforobes and kindlin'
with one hand, aren't ya ?
Strong enough to choke the breath out
of a woman and sling her to the floor ?
- I never done that, sir.
- But you're strong enough to.
- I reckon so, sir.
- Mm-hmm.
How come you so all fired anxious
to do that woman's chores ?
Looks like she, she didn't
have nobody to help her.
Like I said, she-
With Mr. Ewell and seven children
on the place ?
You did all this choppin' and work
out of sheer goodness, boy ?
You're a mighty good fella, it seems.
Did all that
for not one penny ?
Yes, sir.
I felt right sorry for her.
- She seemed- -
You felt sorry for her ?
A white woman ?
To begin with,
this case should never
have come to trial.
The State has not produced
one iota...
of medical evidence...
that the crime Tom Robinson
is charged with...
ever took place.
It has relied, instead,
upon the testimony
of two witnesses...
whose evidence has not only been
called into serious question...
on cross-examination,
but has been flatly contradicted
by the defendant.
There is circumstantial evidence
to indicate that...
Mayella Ewell
was beaten savagely...
by someone who led,
almost exclusively, with his left.
Tom Robinson now sits before you
having taken the oath...
with the only good hand
he possesses,
his right.
I have nothing but pity
in my heart...
for the chief witness
for the State.
She is the victim
of cruel poverty and ignorance.
But my pity...
does not extend so far...
as to her putting
a man's life at stake,
which she has done in an effort
to get rid of her own guilt.
Now I say "guilt," gentlemen,
because it was guilt
that motivated her.
She's committed no crime.
She has merely broken
a rigid and time-honored...
code of our society-
a code so severe that whoever breaks it
is hounded from our midst...
as unfit to live with.
She must destroy the evidence...
of her offense.
But what was the evidence
of her offense ?
Tom Robinson, a human being.
She must put Tom Robinson
away from her.
Tom Robinson was to her
a daily reminder...
of what she did.
Now, what did she do ?
She tempted a Negro.
She was white,
and she tempted a Negro.
She did something that,
in our society, is unspeakable.
She kissed a black man.
Not an old uncle,
but a strong, young Negro man.
No code mattered to her
before she broke it,
but it came crashing down
on her afterwards.
The witnesses for the State,
with the exception of the
sheriff of Maycomb County.
have presented themselves
to you gentlemen, to this court...
in the cynical confidence...
that their testimony
would not be doubted.
Confident that you gentlemen
would go along with them...
on the assumption-
the evil assumption-
that all Negroes lie,
all Negroes are basically
immoral beings,
all Negro men are not
to be trusted around our women.
An assumption that one associates
with minds of their caliber,
and which is, in itself,
gentlemen, a lie,
which I do not need
to point out to you.
And so,
a quiet, humble,
respectable Negro,
who has had the unmitigated
temerity...
to feel sorry
for a white woman,
has had to put his word
against two white people's.
The defendant is not guilty,
but somebody
in this courtroom is.
Now, gentlemen,
in this country,
our courts are the great levelers.
In our courts,
all men are created equal.
I'm no idealist
to believe firmly...
in the integrity of our courts
and of our jury system.
That's no ideal to me.
That is a living, working reality !
Now I am confident that you
gentlemen will review...
without passion...
the evidence
that you have heard,
come to a decision...
and restore this man
to his family.
In the name of God,
do your duty.
believe...
Tom Robinson.
How long has the jury
been out now, Reverend ?
Well, let's see.
Almost two hours now.
I think that's
an awful good sign, don't you ?
Court's now in session.
Everybody rise.
Gentlemen of the jury,
- have you reached a verdict?
- We have, Your Honor.
Will the defendant please rise
and face the jury ?
What is your verdict ?
We find the defendant
guilty as charged.
Gentlemen, this jury is dismissed.
Court is adjourned.
I'll go to see Helen
first thing tomorrow morning.
I told her not to be disappointed,
we'd probably lose this one.
Tom.
Yes, Mr. Finch.
Miss Jean Louise.
Miss Jean Louise,
stand up.
Your father's passin'.
Atticus ?
I-l'm sorry, Atticus.
- Well, thank you, Maudie.
-
Atticus, can I see you
for a minute ?
Will you excuse me ?
Jem ?
Yes'm.
I don't know if it'll help,
but I want to say this to you.
There's some men
in this world...
who are born to do
our unpleasant jobs for us.
Your father's one of them.
- Oh, well. -
What's the matter, Atticus ?
Tom Robinson's dead.
They were taking him
to Abbottsville...
for safekeeping.
Tom broke loose and ran.
The deputy called out
to him to stop,
and Tom didn't stop.
He shot at him to wound him
and missed his aim.
Killed him.
The deputy says...
Tom just ran like a crazy man.
The last thing I told him was not to
lose heart, that we'd ask for an appeal.
We had such a good chance.
We had more than a good chance.
I have to go out
and tell his family.
You look after
the children, Maudie.
Atticus, you want me
to go with you ?
No, son, I think I'd better
go out there alone.
Atticus.
I'm goin' with you.
All right, son.
Hello, Mr. Finch.
I'm Spence, Tom's father.
Hello, Spence.
- Is Helen here ?
- Yes, sir, she's inside lyin' down,
tryin' to get
a little sleep.
We been talkin'
about the appeal, Mr. Finch.
How long do you think it'll take ?
Spence, there isn't
going to be any appeal.
Not now.
Tom is dead.
Dead ?
Helen.
Boy.
Go inside and tell Atticus Finch
I said to come out here.
Go on, boy.
By October,
things had settled down again.
I still looked for Boo
every time I went by the Radley place.
This night my mind was filled
with Halloween.
There was to be a pageant representing
our county's agricultural products.
I was to be a ham.
Jem said he would escort me
to the school auditorium.
Thus began
our longest journey together.
- Scout ! - Yeah ?
Will you come on ?
Everybody's gone.
I can't go home like this.
Well, I'm goin'.
It's almost 10:00...
and Atticus will be
waiting for us.
All right, I'm comin'.
But I feel like a fool
walkin' home like this.
It's not my fault
you lost your dress.
I didn't lose it.
Just can't find it.
- Where are your shoes ?
- I can't find them either.
- You can get 'em tomorrow.
- But tomorrow's Sunday.
You can get the janitor
to let you in. Come on.
Here, Scout. Let me hold onto you
before you break your neck.
- Jem, you don't have to hold me.
- Shh.
- What's the matter ?
- Hush a minute, Scout.
I thought I heard somethin'.
Ah... come on.
Wait.
- Jem, are you trying to scare me ?
- Shh.
- You know I'm too old.
- Be quiet.
- I heard an old dog bayin'.
It's not that. I hear it
when we're walking along.
When we stop,
I don't hear it anymore.
Oh, yeah, my costume rustlin'.
Halloween's got ya.
I hear it now.
I'll bet it's just old Cecil Jacobs
tryin' to scare me.
Cecil Jacobs
is a big, wet hen !
Come on.
Run, Scout !
Run, Scout ! Run ! Run !
Scout ! Scout !
What happened ?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
- Cal, tell Dr. Reynolds to come over.
- Yes, sir.
- You all right ?
- Are you sure ?
- Yes, sir.
Sheriff Tate, please.
Atticus, is Jem dead ?
No. He's unconscious.
We won't know how badly he's hurt
until the doctor gets here.
Heck ? Atticus Finch.
Someone's been after my children.
He's got a bad break.
Like somebody tried
to wring his arm off.
I'll be right back, Atticus.
How's the boy, Doc ?
He'll be all right.
Sheriff Tate.
What is it, Heck ?
Bob Ewell's lyin' on the ground
under that tree down yonder...
with a kitchen knife
stuck up under his ribs.
He's dead, Mr. Finch.
- Are you sure ?
- Yes, sir.
He's not gonna bother
these children anymore.
Miss Scout, you think you could
tell us what happened ?
I don't know.
All of a sudden
somebody grabbed me,
knocked me down
on the ground.
Jem found me then.
Then Mr. Ewell, I reckon,
grabbed him again, and Jem hollered.
Then somebody grabbed me.
Mr. Ewell, I guess.
Somebody grabbed him...
and then I heard someone
pantin' and coughin'.
Then I saw someone
carrying Jem.
Well, who was it ?
Why, there he is, Mr. Tate.
He can tell you his name.
Hey, Boo.
Miss Jean Louise,
Mr. Arthur Radley.
I believe he already knows you.
Heck, let's go out
on the front porch.
Would you like to say good night
to Jem, Mr. Arthur ?
You can pet him, Mr. Arthur.
He's asleep.
You couldn't if he was awake, though.
He wouldn't let you.
Go ahead.
Let's go set in the swing, Mr. Arthur.
Heck, l-l-
I guess that
the thing to do is, uh-
Good Lord...
I must be losin' my memory.
I can't remember
whether Jem is 12 or 13.
Anyway, it'll have to come
before the county court.
Of course, it's a clear-cut case
of self-defense.
I'll, uh- Well, I'll run down
to the office-
Mr. Finch...
do you think Jem
killed Bob Ewell ?
Is that what you think ?
Your boy never stabbed him.
Bob Ewell fell on his knife.
He killed himself.
There's a black man
dead for no reason.
Now the man
responsible for it is dead.
Let the dead bury the dead
this time, Mr. Finch.
I never heard tell it was
against the law for any citizen...
to do his utmost to prevent a crime
from being committed,
which is exactly what he did.
But maybe you'll tell me
it's my duty to tell the town
all about it, not to hush it up.
You know what'll happen then.
All the ladies in Maycomb,
includin' my wife,
will be knockin' on his door
bringin' angel food cakes.
To my way of thinkin',
takin' one man,
who done you and this town
a big service,
and draggin' him with his shy ways
into the limelight-
To me, that's a sin.
It's a sin.
And I'm not about
to have it on my head.
I may not be much,
Mr. Finch,
but I'm still Sheriff
of Maycomb County,
and Bob Ewell fell on his knife.
Good night, sir.
Mr. Tate was right.
What do you mean ?
Well...
it would be...
sort of like shooting
a mockingbird, wouldn't it ?
Thank you, Arthur.
Thank you for my children.
Neighbors bring food with death...
and flowers with sickness...
and little things in between.
Boo was our neighbor.
He gave us two soap dolls,
a broken watch and chain,
a knife...
and our lives.
One time Atticus said...
you never really knew a man
until you stood in his shoes
and walked around in them.
Just standing
on the Radley porch was enough.
The summer that had begun
so long ago had ended,
and another summer
had taken its place.
And a fall.
And Boo Radley had come out.
I was to think
of these days many times,
of Jem and Dill...
and Boo Radley
and Tom Robinson.
And Atticus.
He would be
in Jem's room all night,
and he would be there when Jem
waked up in the morning.