Would you people excuse Hart and I
a few minutes?
We have an urgent matter to discuss.
Very modern.
No, Armand can stay.
Armand speaks no English.
Indeed, le petit coquin rarely speaks at all.
The other night with you was wonderful.
But there's a complication.
My husband died unexpectedly
over the weekend.
As you can imagine,
it was a terrible shock.
- We were very close.
- Right.
A perfect couple.
I'm sorry.
You won't have to copy
those paintings now.
I see.
I knew you'd understand.
There is one hitch, Nathalie.
You and I had an arrangement.
I expect you to fulfill it.
But I intend to.
I intend to.
What would you like most?
A suit, or a watch?
A weekend together by the sea?
Because that was
part of the arrangement, too.
Remember?
Enjoying opportunities
as they present themselves...
...and not losing
what's most important to us.
Exactly.
Which is why you're going to pay, Nathalie.
In full. In cash.
Or you'll never see your pictures again.
Don't you threaten me, Hart.
I will never be threatened again by anyone!
You're behaving like a cheap whore from
the rue Saint-Denis, and not like an artist.
I'm ashamed of you.
Brute.
So who is this Libby Valentin?
I mean, is she French or what?
She's "or what."
Is she really a nun?
Defrocked.
You know, I think it was Gustave Flaubert
who said there are only four reasons...
...for getting involved with women.
- Sex!
- One.
- Money!
- Two.
- Publicity!
- Three.
Goddamn it, what was the fourth one?
- Drunkenness.
Buddy, Rachel's not for you.
She's not gonna make you happy.
Yeah.
I mean, in Hollywood...
...the women are gonna be tall.
- There's a reason.
- They're blonde.
- There's another reason.
Promiscuity is just a religion with them.
Oiseau, you know, you are absolutely right.
- No permanent attachments.
- That's right, buddy.
Do you realize...
...that drink...
...and permanent attachments
have been the undoing of virtually...
...all of our friends?
- That's right.
- Hit it.
"She's got a Sunday school face
"She's got..."
She's got a what?
"She's got a...
"She's got a Sunday school face"
- Wonderful song.
- I know that car.
Get some sleep.
Monsieur Hart.
Shit!
Nathalie.
Libby!
I disclaim all responsibility.
Come here.
I want to show you something.
- Lf I didn't know they were copies...
- What makes you think they're copies?
Because I've seen the originals.
Nathalie asked me to ship them
to New York.
I suppose you put my fee in your pocket.
Jamais.
Sur mon honneur, as a woman of God.
These are the originals.
Nathalie took my copies by mistake.
She did?
A little bit like stabbing yourself
in the back, isn't it?
So what are we supposed to do
with these?
I'll cut you in for 30 percent.
It's a crackerjack scheme, dear boy.
But now leave everything to me.
When it comes to artifice...
...moi, Valentin, am a master.
Stone will pay through his nose
to get these in his salon.
Should have heard him on the telephone.
Beside himself.
I'll get the money he owes me,
you'll get the money I owe you...
...and when Nathalie de Ville sees
these new beauties...
...at Stone's exhibition,
the Pope himself would blush with shame.
Perhaps this one, then,
which again is in keeping...
...with the whole anticipation
concept we discussed.
I particularly like this one with, as you see,
the focus on the lady...
No, I don't like any of these.
I need an ad that, when you look at it,
would jump at you.
Something simple but dramatic.
Jump. Yes.
Oui?
- Oui.
- Et madame?
Entrez, entrez.
Valentin.
- Libby, I changed my mind.
- About what?
- I don't want to show anything of mine.
- Okay.
I'll just pick it up when we go.
I don't want you...
...to participate in this.
Merci.
- May I call you on Friday?
- Yes.
- Thank you again.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
What is he doing here?
It was Hart who put me in touch...
...with the owner de ces ouvres.
He wanted to come along.
Did you bring me
some samples of your work?
I've decided I prefer not to be collected.
Makes me feel like a manufacturer.
You're in the wrong business, then.
- Got anything to drink?
- No.
My wife is an alcoholic.
- How is your wife?
- What do you mean by that?
Not much.
- Do you want to see them?
- Yes! Let's see it!
Look at the skin tone.
The shape.
So sensual.
Did you know that Modigliani's
models were tarts?
All women are tarts.
That's why I love them.
I think...
...you could easily say...
...that these three works capture...
...capture...
...the true spirit, I'essence de modernit.
- I'm prepared to give you a bargain price.
- Yes.
I'm informed that
you specialize in bargains.
I have a certain talent in that area, yes.
But am I to assume
that money is an object?
Don't be daft.
Money is always an object.
For myself, I'm only interested in price.
See that Picabia?
I could burn it tomorrow,
and it wouldn't mean a thing to me.
But I did pay 7,000 francs for it...
...so I am not as impulsive
as I ordinarily might be.
In fact, if I'd paid less...
...it would be less beautiful.
Stone, I've changed my mind.
I think it would be an honor
for you to own some of my work.
I'll just run over to the gallery
and pick something up.
"It rained today.
"Even the rain seems like a lie here.
"I detest the verisimilitude of Parisian life."
- Bertie's downstairs.
- Rachel.
I decided to go to Hollywood with Oiseau.
- Yes?
- Yes. You're coming with me.
Am I?
You are.
Not in the tub.
- Why not?
- Trust me.
I don't know.
I think I need
more of a commitment from you.
Yeah? How long?
Are these genuine?
Est-ce que le ciel est bleu?
Ordinarily, I wouldn't care.
If a picture sells for a big price...
...and it's praised to the teeth
by the experts...
...is it really worthless, then...
...when it's discovered
the signature is forged?
Depends on whether
you're the buyer or the seller.
All the critics and art snobs will be
at my salon.
- I want to make an impression.
- Yes.
- Not a reputation.
- No.
I already have that.
Now.
The interesting part.
How much?
Une chanson...
... 5,000...
... amricains.
I'll take them.
- You will?
- But not at that price.
I've already given you
the dealer's discount.
I'll give you $3,000.
You insult me, Mr. Stone.
Not you.
- Take it or leave it.
- I'll take it.
I thought you might.
- Good.
Perfect timing.
What have we here?
Distinguished.
- I'm sorry, Bertie. I didn't know...
- Rachel, come here.
- Allô, Rachel.
- Hello, Libby.
What do you think of Hart's painting?
Yeah. I'd like to know.
- Hello.
- Afternoon.
It's nice.
Should I buy it?
If you like it, Bertie.
Yes, I think I have just the right spot for it.
- I'll give you $100.
- Done.
I did it.
Did it, dear boy.
We started at $2,500,
and I suckered him up to $3,000.
- Let's go to the bank.
- No, let's go to the bar.
We have to talk about something.
I'm not interested.
What are you interested in,
besides yourself?
Not much.
But I'm looking.
Writing about yourself can be very lonely.
- What are you writing?
- It's my obituary.
It's too important a job to leave
to those hacks in the obituary department.
Why don't you just quit
the goddamn paper?
This'll interest you. I've decided on poison.
Drowning was my second choice.
I mean, it's better than asphyxiation.
I saw a man once who'd been hung.
He looked a bit disappointed.
You can't kill yourself, Oiseau.
We're going to Hollywood.
I'm gonna tell you why Carlos beat you
in the ring a couple days ago.
- Who?
- Carlos. Stone.
I'm working on something.
It doesn't matter.
- Right, let's have it.
- Scruples.
- Scruples?
- You can't win Andrea with scruples.
- Who?
- Andrea.
Rachel. Forget it.
I'm sitting there, watching him
waltz around you like he owns you.
He doesn't own me. He does not own me.
He thinks because he buys something,
he owns it.
It's the same to him.
A piece of ass, property.
It's about ownership.
He doesn't own me, he doesn't own Rachel,
and he never will.
Guys like that are bad for all of us, Clark.
- Nick.
Who?
You know,
writing about yourself can be very lonely.
- What are you writing?
- It's my obituary.
It's too important a job to leave
to those hacks in the obituary department.
Why don't you quit that goddamn paper
like I did?
This'll interest you. I've decided on pills.
He doesn't own me.
- Who?
- Stone.
- Carlos.
- Who?
Sex is all about power.
Champagne, monsieur?
You can't help but make a mess.
- What do you mean?
- Take Nathalie de Ville, for instance.
She's as cool as
somebody else's cucumber.
Armand.
Merci.
Les critiques.
You look stunning tonight, my dear.
I look stunning every night, Bertie.
Have you had a chance
to look over my collection?
Come, I'll give you a tour.
My latest acquisition...
...should impress even someone
as formidable as you.
Bertie. You really did it.
Outside of a museum, I've never seen
such a fascinating collection of pictures.
A museum?
- Oh, l...
- It doesn't matter.
What do you think?
Get a hold of yourself. It's only a painting.
These are forgeries, Bertie.
They simply have to be.
Nonsense. I bought them from the estate
of the late Comte de Polignac.
Then you bought forgeries.
I own the originals
of these three paintings.
In fact, I shipped them to America
only the other day.
And Bertie,
my papers have been authenticated.
You've been had.
That painting is no more of a fake
than you are.
Look at the nipples in the Matisse.
Henri would have never painted nipples
in that manner.
They look like cones...
...or warts.
Perhaps I should have framed
the money I spent on them instead.
- Bertie, I'm afraid you've been had.
- Shut up!
Monsieur Stone, I think we've had enough.
No! I've had enough.
I don't give a tuppenny damn for
your silly opinions on the value of art.
There is no value,
except what I choose to put on it.
This is art...
...because I paid hard cash for it.
Don't you understand?
Your precious painters
mean nothing to me.
I could have Nathalie's mutt
shit on a canvas.
And if I paid $5,000 for it...
...you critics would call it a masterpiece.
I'm afraid not, monsieur Stone.
I'm afraid you have missed the entire point.
- Have I?
- Yes.
Fakes is what we have called them...
...and fakes is what they are,
fit only for the fire.
The fire?
I see what you mean about the nipple.
Au revoir.
- Laloux?
- Oui, monsieur.
- Take that picture down.
- Bien, monsieur.
- Look at this nipple.
- This one is not so bad.
It's worse.
- The shape, the form...
- The shape is...
- It's all wrong.
- But the color...
The masterpiece.
I should throw all of you in as well.
- Looking for the toilet, Hem?
- Art is never the whole story.
It's upstairs.
There's more to you than meets the eye.
Piss off, or I'll barbecue your dog.
What happened, Bertie?
Didn't anybody like your paintings?
You're drunk.
Did you really think
you could buy your way in?
I feel so sorry for you, Bertie.
Clean up the mess.
All of it.
I'm going out.
- Bonjour.
- Merci.
What?
No!
The son of a bitch actually did it.
You know,
he kept telling me he was gonna do it.
I thought he was just...
I didn't believe him.
I believed him.
It makes me feel like a coward, you know?
But we're not the cowards, are we, Hart?
The dead are the real cowards, right?
I don't know.
The dead are not the cowards.
Rachel?
Rachel, is that you?
It's me.
- You son of a bitch!
- It was the only thing I could do.
I'm dead, and I'll soon be gone.
And now I can be anybody I want to be.
Jesus! I need a drink.
Did you see my obituaries?
They're all raves.
And I'm gonna be buried tomorrow
afternoon at Pere-Lachaise.
Racine has made me
the most charming coffin.
- I think we ought to look in.
- Naturally.
We've got plenty of time.
The train doesn't leave till 4:00.
Aprs vous, madame.
Could I lean on you?
These heels are just killing me.
Yeah, sure.
We'll have a beautiful boat ride
to New York.
And then Hollywood!
- I'm just dying to get there.
- I ought to kill you myself.
No.
Really, we can't go in there.
I'll be recognized.
Why don't we go
and have a tasse de verveine?
- No, I need a drink.
- All right. I'll come by at 1:00 tomorrow.
- I'll pick you up in a taxi.
- All right. Don't talk to strangers.
Since we're living in Paris,
does that make us Parisian?
Pal. How you doing?
I think I miss the little bastard.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
You know what time it is?
Time? Too late. That's the time.
He loved you.
I didn't even like him, but he loved you.
"I love you, I swear I do
"Even if I can't find the right words
"Believe me, it is true
"I love you
"I love you"
Rachel. Where the hell have you...
Don't worry, Nicky.
At least, when they find us,
our skeletons will be embracing.
I forgot to tell you. Oiseau is still alive.
I didn't know he was dead.
He's gonna meet us at the boat train
tomorrow at 4:00, right after his funeral.
- I thought you said he was alive.
- Ain't it great?
Hart.
- Libby, what are you doing here?
- I shadowed you here.
Stone's men came into the gallery,
slashed all the paintings.
Not just your paintings,
but valuable ones as well.
What?
I never expected violence.
I'm leaving town.
Taxi!
He's gonna kill me.
Can't they take a joke?
This place, completely uncivilized.
Cannes. Rapidement.
- Told you he was crazy.
- I don't want to talk about him.
- Let's go upstairs.
- We can't stay here.
- Why not?
- It's the first place he'll look.
- I don't give a damn.
- Come on, we'll get a hotel.
Get in the car, Rachel.
She's staying with me.
You had your fun.
Now let's go home.
- It's not that simple, Bertie.
- Come on.
I need you, Rachel.
You don't need anybody, Bertie.
I'm going back to America with Nicky.
- Don't be stupid.
- I'm not stupid.
She's my wife.
Nicky and I were married a long time ago,
before you and me.
We were never divorced.
Sorry, Bertie.
I knew that!
I know everything about you.
You don't know anything about me.
What are you laughing at? Get in the car!
What are you gonna do? Kill me?
Then kill her.
- Go ahead, kill me.
- You slut.
- Go ahead. I want you to.
- Maybe I should.
- You want me to kill you?
- Come on, do it.
- Do it!
You get in the car!
You coward.
I don't want you, Bertie.
I don't want your jewelry.
I don't want your chocolates.
I don't want your money.
I don't want your rubbers. I don't want...
- Fucking bitch! Get in the car!
- I'm sick of it! I hate you!
I can make up my own mind,
what's left of it.
Between the two of you,
I don't have one thought left in my head.
Could you stop it, please?
This has nothing to do with you. Stop it!
I'll decide what happens to me.
What's the matter?
Can't you live without me?
Cowards.
Rachel. Wait a minute. Wait!
Where are you gonna go?
I don't know.
He can't swim.
He can't swim?
That figures.
Rachel!
Non, non, non...
Vive Dada!
Jesus, I didn't know it would be so sad.
Vive Oiseau!
Look at them.
If it weren't for me, people would've
thought "surreal" was a breakfast food.
The dead are the most brave.
They take their love with them.
Can you imagine the courage
to love someone...
...who loves you...
...when there's nothing
you can do about it?
Let's go.
Jesus,
I just didn't know it would be so sad.
We did appreciate him,
but did we tell him so...
...so he was secure in his mind,
knowing that we did?
We did not, and he was not.
And so,
with his sweet smile and gentle concerns...
...Oiseau is not still with us.
He is not.
Oiseau!
Driver, Gare Saint-Lazare, s'il vous plaît.
Jesus, I just ran into Maurice Ravel
in the men's room.
He didn't recognize me.
You know, Paris has been taken over
by people who are just imitators...
...of people who were
imitators themselves.
It's become a parody.
It's finished. It's over.
Believe me, Hollywood is gonna be
like a breath of fresh air.
Hart, let's face it.
Rachel, she's not coming.
- Yeah, I know.
- So let's go.
Paris is...
...a traveling picnic.
Paris is a portable banquet.
You should work on that.
This whole experience gives me
a great idea for a movie I could write.
And it would be perfect for von Stroheim.
You can get a very good meal on this train.
And they actually have
an excellent wine list.
This is gonna be the best thing
that ever happened to you.
Yeah, the hell with it.
Au revoir, Paris.
"Au revoir, Paris"
Touché.
- We're just gonna be a few minutes.
- Yes, sir, I'll be here.
The train to Hollywood leaves in an hour.
We'll make the train.
I just want to see what they have in here.
- It's gonna rain.
- You're so morose, it's monotonous.
Babe Ruth hit three home runs today,
and we're going to Hollywood...
...where the sky's always blue,
the sun always shines...
...and we're gonna be rich!
This, of course, is Modigliani.
A short, but fruitful life.
His work is evidenced
by the plasticity he employed...
...in his nudes and portraiture as well.
Always the oval face,
the elongated trunk, arms.
Yes, Henri Matisse.
Odalisque.
Study, if you will, the face.
It's the most realized of all of his works.
In my mind, the best.
No. Look at this. Can you imagine this?
Boy, Nathalie certainly gets around.
Aren't you Irving Fegelman?
I'm Ada Fuoco.
We grew up together on Flatbush Avenue.
Je ne connais pas I'anglais.
But you look just like Irving.
Jesse, he looks exactly like Irving.
Let's proceed to Paul Cézanne,
considered to be the father of modern art.
This is a work of rare emotional delicacy.
This revelation cannot be taught...
...nor can it be duplicated.
Only the greatest artists can achieve
what has happened here...
...and only then,
in that rare moment in time.
So let's silently observe this.
Come on, I'm bored with these pictures.
I want to go where the pictures move.
I like your stuff better anyway.
Just a minute.
This might help me appreciate my work.
Gentlemen. Did it touch you?
Did you sense the mystery?
Do you know now
why this is a masterpiece?
Why we praise it?
Why we genuflect before it?
Why it will live through the ages
for all humanity?
My God, I hope you understand that.
Why is it, you are never
where you're supposed to be?
I am now.
Looks like rain.
No, not now.
Maybe tomorrow?
I was thinking, Nicky,
maybe we should move to Hollywood.
- Ever thought about it?
- You been talking to Oiseau?
John, if you were lucky enough
to have lived in Paris...
...lucky enough to have been young,
it didn't matter who you were...
...because it was always worth it,
and it was good.