( roars )
¶
HMM.
IF THIS THING
WERE ANY MORE POWERFUL
YOU COULD SEE THE LORD HIMSELF
IN HIS HEAVEN.
WELL, AS I SAY,
IF YOU WANT A JOB DONE WELL,
DON'T LEAVE IT TO A LESSER MAN.
( all grunting )
COME! COME!
BUGGER OFF!
NO!!!
COME ON!
BEHAVE, WILL YOU?
( screaming )
GIRL YOU HAVE THE DEVIL
IN YOU!
YOU'RE RUNNING
MY FEET OFF!
AAAH!
STOP WIGGLING!
HOLD STILL, CHILD!
LET ME GO!!!
( shouting )
STOP IT, CHILD!
BEHAVE YOURSELF!
I COULD FIND YOU
A QUIETER ONE IF YOU LIKE.
CHILD!
( coughing )
BE STILL, CHILD!
SHOW HIM THE PENDANT.
OH, YES.
YOU'RE NO HELP, CHILD!
Man:
THAT IS AS DESCRIBED.
LET ME GO!
HOW DARE YOU!
Man:
I HAVE A MORE TERRIBLE
LESSON FOR THIS CHILD.
IT'S BEEN AN OVERLY LONG
ADVENTURE LOCATING YOU.
AS WE MAY BE TOGETHER
FOR SOME CONSIDERABLE TIME,
YOUNG LADY,
ALLOW ME TO INTRODUCE
MYSELF.
Nun:
THAT LITTLE VIXEN
WILL BITE IT.
MISS FLORA,
MY NAME IS HIBBLE.
YOUR MOTHER, MOLL FLANDERS,
WAS A MURDERESS,
WAS A MOTHER,
AND A THIEF
BY HER OWN ACCOUNT.
THE LOSS OF HER SOUL,
TO SOME,
WAS OF AS LITTLE CONSEQUENCE
AS AN EMBER
DRAFTING UP A CHIMNEY.
I AM INSTRUCTED
BY A WEALTHY BENEFACTOR
TO OFFER YOU THE CHANCE
TO ACCOMPANY ME.
IN RETURN FOR YOUR
BOARD AND KEEP,
I AM TO READ YOU THIS--
THE FIRSTHAND MEMOIRS
OF YOUR MOTHER.
YOUR BENEFACTOR HOPES THAT
YOU MIGHT...
NOTE ANY SEEDS OF HER CHARACTER
THAT MIGHT TRY TO...
ROOT IN YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND MY WORDS?
SHE DOESN'T RESPOND
TO WORDS.
I'LL RESPOND TO ANYBODY
THAT TREATS ME
LIKE I'VE GOT A SOUL
AS GOOD AS THEM.
INDEED, THERE IS
MUCH OF HER IN YOU.
WHAT IS IT?
I WAS SEPARATED FROM
A CONSIDERABLE AMOUNT OF COIN
ON THE GROUNDS THAT ONLY SILK
WOULD SUFFICE.
ARE YOU TAKING ME
INTO SIN?
I'LL SPEND TEN ETERNITIES--
YOU MAY REST EASY.
CIRCUMSTANCES HAVE TAUGHT ME
THAT A MAN'S ETHICS
ARE THE ONLY POSSESSIONS
HE'LL TAKE BEYOND THE GRAVE.
PRAY DRESS YOURSELF.
NOW TO BUSINESS.
"MY NAME IS MOLL FLANDERS.
"I WAS BORN
SOME THIRTY YEARS AGO
IN A PRISON IN LONDON.
"BUT MY BODY, A FEMALE,
AND MY STATION...
Moll Flanders:
"...IS A PRISON OF THE FLESH
"THAT I HAVE WORN FOR
THE LENGTH OF MY LIFE.
"CONVICTED FOR SOME THEFT
SO SMALL
"THAT ITS SIGNIFICANCE
WAS LOST TO ALL MEMORY,
"MY MOTHER GAVE UP HER VIRTUE
TO A PRISON GUARD...
( woman screaming )
Woman: PUSH! PUSH!
"IN THE AGE OF REASON,EVEN
THE ENGLISH WERE TOO GENTEEL
"TO EXECUTE A PREGNANT WOMAN,
"SO MY MOTHER RECEIVED NINE
PRECIOUS EXTRA MONTHS OF LIFE
"AND THEN WAS HANGED
AS A THIEF THAT NIGHT.
"DEPRIVED OF MY MOTHER
BY THE AUTHORITIES,
"I WAS DELIVERED
TO THEIR MACHINE
OF CIVIC LOVE,
A HOME FOR ORPHANS
AND FOUNDLINGS."
( bell rings )
( baby crying )
Man: MILLGATE PRISON.
ANOTHER OF THE LORD'S LOST.
NEVER STOPS THEM, DOES IT?
BOY OR GIRL?
BOY OR GIRL?!
GIRL.
FLANDERS.
MOLL FLANDERS.
GOD HELP HER.
Moll: "MY MOTHER
HAD SOLD THE ONLY THING
OF VALUE SHE HAD--
"HER HAIR.
"I TRIED TO NAVIGATE
MY EARLY LIFE
"BY WHAT SHE'D PURCHASED
FOR ME--
"A TUPPENY BRASS CROSS.
"THERE ARE SOME WHO'D SAY
"I'D GROWN UP
AN UNGRATEFUL WRETCH.
"EVEN AS A YOUNG WOMAN
I'D BETRAYED THOSE
WHO FED ME AND GAVE ME
SPIRITUAL SANCTUARY."
( whispering )
MOLL. YOU--DON'T!
YOU'RE MAD.
QUIET!
WHAT IS THAT?!
IT'S FOR THE POOR,
MOTHER.
BLESS ME, FATHER,
FOR I HAVE SINNED.
I HAD A JEALOUSY
OF MARY BARNES
AND I WISHED SISTER ORIAN
WOULD DIE.
HAVE YOU HAD
IMPURE THOUGHTS,
MY CHILD?
I'VE BEEN
THINKING OF YOU.
OH.
AND WHAT ARE THOSE THOUGHTS,
MY CHILD?
HMM?
IF I DID SOMETHING...
WHAT WOULD THAT BE,
MY CHILD?
THIS!
AAAH!
KEEP YOUR HANDS
TO YOURSELF, SATAN.
Nun: CONFESS!
HE'S THE SINNER!
STOP YOUR LYING,
MOLL FLANDERS!
I AM NOT A LIAR!
HE'S TOUCHED
EVERY ONE OF US!
HOLD THE EVIL TONGUE!
Priest: LIAR!
DAMNED FROM BIRTH,
JUST LIKE YOUR MOTHER!
YOU'VE NO RIGHT TO WEAR
THE CROSS OF CHRIST!
YOU TAKE THAT AND I'LL CALL
THE DEVIL HIMSELF AFTER YOU!
YEAH?!
SURE AS HELL ROASTS SOULS
HE KNOWS WHAT
YOU'VE BEEN DOING!
NO! LEAVE HER THE LORD'S SYMBOL,
FATHER. I'LL GET HER TO CONFESS.
THEN DO IT!
DO IT! DO IT!
IT'S A MAN'S WORLD, MOLLY.
HE'D BEAT YOU TO DEATH
TO HOLD HIS POSITION.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
IF YOU BELIEVE ME,
WHY WON'T YOU GO
TO THE BISHOP?
YOU ARE SO YOUNG.
LET THE LORD
TAKE CARE OF THEM.
BUT I THOUGHT YOU
WERE A SISTER TO DO GOOD.
I DO...THE BEST I CAN.
YOU'RE SCARED OF HIM,
TOO, AREN'T YOU?
WELL, I'M NOT GOING TO FEAR
ANY MAN OF FLESH AND BLOOD.
NO MATTER WHAT COSTUME HE WEARS.
Moll: IF GOD MADE ME
IN HIS IMAGE,
SHOULDN'T MY THOUGHTS
AND MY IDEAS BE LIKE HIS?
( flapping of wings,
bird chirping )
IF YOU HAVE ANY USE
FOR MY MISERABLE LIFE...
I PRAY HELP ME.
WHISPER IN MY HEART...
A SIGN...
DON'T BE LOSING
YOUR MENTAL PARTS, MOLL.
( bell tolls )
( bells continue )
Nun:
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?!
( birds chirping and singing )
I AM A SPARROW.
"DESPITE THE DEPRAVITY
OF MY PAST
"AND THE UNCERTAINTY
OF MY FUTURE,
"I SHARED A STRANGE JOY
AMONGST THE LEAST OF
THE LORD'S FEATHERED FLOCKS.
"I HAD DISCOVERED
A TRUTH OF NATURE:
"HOPE COMES TO THE YOUNG
AS NATURALLY AS SPRING RAINS--"
MY MOTHER--
DID YOU KNOW HER?
CAN A MAN TRULY KNOW
ANY WOMAN?
YOU'VE GOT A SNAKE
FOR A TONGUE, HAVEN'T YOU?
YOU SAY HER BOOK TELLS HER
AS A FOUL MURDERER,
AND WORSE.
WELL, SOME OF HER STORIES
WERE QUITE UNPARALLELED.
WHY WOULD ANYONE
HELP THE DAUGHTER OF ONE
SUCH AS THAT?
PERHAPS TO DISCHARGE A DEBT.
JUST WHO IS MY BENEFACTOR?
THE ANSWERS WILL COME,
BUT NOT IF YOUR MOUTH
IS WORKING HARDER
THAN YOUR EARS.
JUST WHO IS MY BENEFACTOR?!
EITHER YOU HAVE NO PATIENCE
OR NO MANNERS.
A WOMAN OF WEALTH
HAS TAKEN UP YOUR INTEREST.
ONE MRS. ALLWORTHY.
DESPITE HER HIGH POSITION,
SHE HAS EARNED
A TERRIBLE REPUTATION
FOR BEING INCITED TO CRUELTY.
IT IS SUGGESTED
SHE HAD TO LEAVE ENGLAND
BECAUSE HER VEXATIOUS DEEDS
MIGHT HAVE GOT HER GULLET SLIT.
I WARN YOU--
CURB YOUR ANTICS.
AND YOU WOULD DELIVER ME
TO SUCH A PERSON? BLOODY HELL.
IT IS MY FONDEST HOPE
THAT YOUR SWEETNESS
AND PURITY
WILL TRANSFORM HER.
WHAT IS ME MOTHER'S PART
IN THIS MADNESS?
YOUR MOTHER,
GOD REST HER SOUL,
WAS MRS. ALLWORTHY'S MAID.
I'M JUST THE DAUGHTER
OF SOME NINNY SERVANT GIRL?
SHE WAS A REMARKABLE
WOMAN.
HOW'D THIS REMARKABLE
MOTHER OF MINE DIE?
PUSH. PUSH.
I HAVE PLANNED THIS TRIP
TO THE LAST DETAIL,
AND MY SCHEDULE
WILL BE PLAYED OUT.
WELL, I HAVE THE NEED TO PEE
IN MY SCHEDULE.
AS I SAID,
I PLANNED FOR EVERY DETAIL.
UGH.
LORD. CHILD, HOW LONG
CAN IT TAKE TO PEE?
I SAY, AREN'T YOU DONE YET?
AH, DAMN!
Man: WATCH YOURSELF!
SEE, DAD'S RIGHT.
IT'S JUST LIKE YOU SAID.
LET GO OF ME!
CUNNING LITTLE WHIPPET,
AIN'T SHE?
YOU SON OF A WHORE
AND A HORSE'S ASS!
AS I SAID,
I PLANNED FOR EVERY DETAIL.
UGH!
AHH!
NOW, WHERE WAS I?
AH.
"LIFE WAS MAKING ME...
"...A STUDENT OF HER MYSTERIES.
"SHE SOMETIMES PROVIDES
A FORTUNE,
AND SOMETIMES A DISASTER."
I'M NOT GOING BACK!
Man: SHE'S A MADWOMAN!
( shouting )
"BUT ONE CLEAR MESSAGE
I STARTED TO GLEAN:
NO MATTER WHAT YOUR STATION,
NEVER SURRENDER HOPE."
GET IN THERE!
"MY PELL-MELL FLIGHT
HAD BROUGHT ME TO A SUBURB
"WHOSE TAX ROLLS
WERE OVERWHELMED
"SUPPORTING THE SPAWNS
OF LOST YOUNG WOMEN.
"THEY WOULD GIVE ME SANCTUARY.
SATISFIED?
"PRESUMING, OF COURSE,
CERTAIN CONDITIONS
COULD BE MET."
AHEM.
SHE IS INTACT, SIR.
AH.
WELL, YOUNG LADY,
I HAVE ARRANGED
WITH THESE GENTLEFOLK
OF GOOD CONSCIENCE
TO TAKE IN SUCH STRAYS
AS YOURSELF.
DO NOT LET YOUR CONSCIENCE
FAIL THEM,
OR YOU WILL KNOW MY WRATH.
UNDERSTAND ME?
I MAY BE BORN FROM NOTHING,
BUT...
I'VE ALL THE SENSE I NEED
TO VALUE MY FORTUNE.
WELCOME TO THE FAMILY.
"SO, UNBELIEVABLY,
LIKE SOME CINDERELLA,
"I WAS TO COMPLETE
MY JOURNEY TO WOMANHOOD
"WITH THE DAUGHTERS OF ONE
MRS. MAZZAWATTI,
"LEARNING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS
OF A WELL-BROUGHT-UP YOUNG LADY
SUCH AS DANCING, FRENCH,
MUSIC, AND CHARITY."
HAVE SOME BREAD.
WHAT ARE YOU IN HERE FOR?
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
GO TAKE YOUR PLEASURE
AT SOMEONE ELSE'S EXPENSE.
( baby crying )
PLEASURE?
IF NOT FOR YOU,
FOR YOUR BABY.
IT'S CHRISTMAS.
GO ON.
THANK YOU.
HAVE SOME BREAD.
BREAD?
Old woman:
I'M VERY SICK.
A DRINK?
YOU FOOL!
THAT'S JAIL FEVER!
THEM SPOT'S AS GOOD
AS THE HANGMAN.
Woman:
MOLL, IT'S SMALLPOX!
SAVE YOUR MERCY FOR THOSE
WITH A BETTER CHANCE!
WHO BETTER DESERVES MY MERCY?
( clears throat )
PUT ONE AT EVERY POINT.
MOLLY'S GOT THE POX.
( singing )
¶ MOLLY'S GOT THE POX
Both:
¶ A TISSUE, A TISSUE
¶ WE ALL FALL DOWN
IT'S NOT FUNNY.
I SEE A SPOT
ON HER CHEEK.
OOH, AND ANOTHER.
GOING TO SAVE A HANGING,
MOLL?
( chuckling )
YOU WANT ME DEAD?
DO FOR ME YOURSELF, THEN,
GO ON.
WE HAVE OUR BUTCHER
SLAUGHTER THE PIGS.
YOU'VE SHAMED ME.
IF YOU WANT TO SEE
THE SORT OF CHARITY
I EXPECT FROM A DAUGHTER,
TONIGHT MOLL WAS
A LIVING LESSON.
GO AND GET READY
FOR OUR GUESTS.
THAT'S IF I'M NOT
TOO EMBARRASSED TO BE
SEEN WITH YOU.
I'M SURE IT'S JUST
THE EXCITEMENT OF
THE SEASON, MA'AM.
I WISH IT WAS, MOLL.
"BY UNCONSCIOUS DESIGN,
"I WAS BECOMING A STONE
IN THE COMFORTABLE SHOE
"OF THIS HOUSEHOLD.
"I REALIZED I MIGHT BE
STEALING SOMETHING I NEVER HAD:
A MOTHER'S LOVE
FOR HER CHILDREN."
HOW SOMETHING SO UGLY
CAN BE SO QUICKLY FASHIONABLE,
AY?
QUITE SO.
( grunting )
THANK YOU, SIR.
IF I WERE YOUNG,
I'D MARRY MY DAUGHTERS
AND I'D GET ME TO
THE SUGAR ISLANDS.
THERE'S FORTUNES TO BE PLUCKED
FROM THE GROUND THERE.
THAT'S THE LIFE!
SUN AND MONEY.
AND NO DAMN GOUT!
( all laugh )
WHAT PLANS HAVE YOU
FOR THE FUTURE,
YOUNG LADY?
WELL, I ALWAYS THOUGHT
I'D BECOME A SISTER OF MERCY.
BUT I RECKON
THAT'S TOO HARD A ROAD
FOR ANYONE WITH
THEIR OWN IDEAS.
AND WHAT ARE
THOSE IDEAS?
WELL, ONE DAY
I WANT MY OWN COACH.
WITH A GLASS ROOF,
SO I CAN SEE THE STARS
AT NIGHT.
HOW CHARMING.
INDEED.
( both giggling )
AHEM.
MOLL, ISN'T IT?
YES.
THANK YOU.
LET ME HELP YOU SERVE, MOLL.
MANY HANDS MAKE LIGHT WORK.
BUT I WANT TO REPAY
THE MAZZAWATTI'S HOSPITALITY.
HE'S RIGHT.
THIS IS YOUR FIRST CHRISTMAS
AT YOUR FRIENDS' TABLE.
LET US SHOW YOU
OUR HOSPITALITY.
SERVE ME, JEREMY.
MOLL'S FIRST.
SHE'S THE GUEST.
"THE MAZZAWATTI SISTERS PLANNED
ACTS OF WAR AGAINST ME.
THEIR WEAPONS WERE TO BE
THEIR SUPERIOR CULTURE."
( playing chamber music )
"I RETURNED THEIR ASSAULTS.
"MY ARSENAL WAS SOMETHING FERAL
THAT NATURE HAD PROVIDED ME...
"A SENSE OF SELF
THAT THESE WOMEN
WOULD NEVER UNDERSTAND,
LET ALONE POSSESS."
( music continues )
BRAVO, MOLL!
"ON BOXING DAY,
"I WAS TAKEN ILL WITH
GREAT DISFAVORS OF THE STOMACH.
"I FEARED AT FIRST
THAT THE MAZZAWATTI GIRLS
"HAD PLOTTED TO POISON ME.
"BUT AS FATE WAS TO TWIST ME,
I WAS WRONG.
"THEY WERE CAPABLE OF
A CRIME AGAINST ME...
( screaming in distance )
"I HAD JUST NOT FORESEEN
ITS NATURE."
( screaming, sobbing )
WELL, YOUNG LADY.
IT SEEMS YOUR CONSCIENCE
HAS PROVED QUITE AN INSPIRATION
TO THIS FAMILY.
THEY SOLD SOME OF
THEIR CHRISTMAS JEWELRY
TO RAISE FUNDS
FOR THE POOR.
SPARKED BY YOUR
ACTS OF KINDNESS,
THEY ENTERED AN AREA SO ROUGH
EVEN MY MEN GO IN SQUADS.
THE PRICE OF THEIR COMPASSION
WAS THEIR VIRTUE.
"WRACKED BY MY OWN GUILT,
"I COULD NOT STAY.
"ADAM, THE BUTLER, TOLD ME OF
ANOTHER HOME FOR YOUNG LADIES
"RUN BY A GENTLEWOMAN
WHO WAS PRIVY TO THOSE
"OF THE HIGHEST RANKS
OF SOCIETY.
"WITH MY HEAD DOWN AGAINST
THE RAWNESS OF THE DARK AIR,
"ALL I REMEMBER IS
THE FLICKERING YELLOW SHEEN
"OF THE NIGHT LANTERNS
ON THE ROAD BENEATH MY FEET.
"AT THE END OF OUR JOURNEY,
AMIDST THE YELLOW LANTERNS
WAS ONE ADDITIONAL REFLECTION:
I FOUND IT RICH,
AND SO PRETTY."
"I FOUND IT RICH,
I'M JUST RESTING MY EYES.
YOU ARE LEARNING
FROM HER STORY?
NO! I WANT YOUR DUMB SERMON
OVER WITH.
( hits roof )
WHOA!
FOR NINE YEARS,
I'VE SENT AGENTS
TO SCOUR THE COUNTRYSIDE.
AND NOW I MYSELF
HAVE SEARCHED EVERY PARSONAGE,
CHARITY, AND WORKHOUSE
TO FIND THE SWEET
LITTLE LOST DAUGHTER
OF MY MISTRESS' MAID.
I AIN'T DELIVERING
SOME SCULLERY HELLCAT
WHOSE TONGUE IS BIGGER
THAN HER BRITCHES,
THAT'S FOR BLOODY SURE!
NOW YOU LISTEN OR SO HELP ME,
I'LL RETURN YOU
TO THAT PALACE OF GOD
I JUST SPRUNG YOU FROM.
IS THAT PERFECTLY CLEAR TO YOU?
DRIVE ON!
( hits roof )
BEGGING YOUR PARDON,
SIR.
YES?
I HAVE A YOUNG LADY.
THANK YOU, SIR.
GO INSIDE.
GO ON.
COME IN, GIRL...
BEFORE THE COLD
STOPS MY BLOOD.
"I SUPPOSE I SHOULD HAVE BEEN
MORE AWARE,
"BUT SOMETHING IN ME CRIED OUT:
"HERE WAS THE HOME
OF MY DREAMS.
"HERE WAS NOT JUST WEALTH...
BUT ESCAPE."
( chamber orchestra
playing )
STAND HERE.
"AND THAT'S WHEN I ENCOUNTERED
"THE AWESOME PRESENCE
OF MRS. ALLWORTHY.
"TO ENLARGE MY UNDERSTANDING,
"THE LORD HAD DELIVERED ME
TO A SOUL
"WITH THE ALLURING AIRS
OF SOME GREAT DUCHESS
AND THE SURVIVAL INSTINCTS
OF A COUNTRY CAT."
WHAT A STRANGE WORLD.
LOOK WHAT A CURIOUS YOUNG THING
THE WIND HAS BLOWN IN.
SO, WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A HOME?
I'M WILLING TO WORK
FOR MY KEEP.
JUST SO,
BUT IN THESE TIMES
THERE ARE SO MANY
WHO WILL LABOR
FOR A ROOF.
WHAT MAKES YOU
SO SPECIAL, MISS--?
FLANDERS, MA'AM.
IT'S MOLL FLANDERS.
MISS FLANDERS.
WHAT'S YOUR NATURE?
I'M LEARNING TO HAVE
A VERY FAIR MANNER.
LEARNING?
IT SEEMS TO BE A NECESSITY
IF ONE IS TO SUCCEED.
SO...YOU'VE BEEN
A TROUBLE MAKER.
I'VE JUST STOOD
FOR MY RIGHTS.
I CAN'T COUNTENANCE
POOR BEHAVIOR.
IT DISPLEASES MY GUESTS.
( laughter )
YOUR LAST JOB?
I'M STRONG FOR MY AGE.
I HAVE AN HONEST UPBRINGING,
MA'AM, AND I WON'T EAT TOO MUCH.
MEANING YOU HAVE
NO SKILLS AT ALL.
I HAVE THE MEMORY
NEVER TO BE TOLD
A TASK TWICE.
HIBBLE, MY HOUSE
IS NOT A SCHOOL.
CAN YOU FIND IN YOUR HEART
TO TRY ME, PLEASE?
IF YOU THINK ME LAZY
OR I DISPLEASE YOU,
THROW ME OUT,
AND YOU'VE LOST NOTHING.
MISS FLANDERS.
WE HAVE A CONTRACT, THEN.
HUBBLE, FIND HER
SOME VICTUALS.
SHE'S SKINNY.
( laughter )
YOU'VE GOT BRASS, GIRL.
THERE'S NOT MANY
STANDS UP TO HER.
THAT WAS YOU?
I COULD NEVER TURN THEM AWAY.
Man: STEADY! EASY THERE, EASY.
( moos )
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
THE AMERICAS.
THAT'S THE END OF THE EARTH!
YOU HAVE A REASON TO STAY?
DO I HAVE A CHOICE?
THEN I SHALL HAVE TO
TAKE MY CHANCES WITH
YOUR MISTRESS, SHAN'T I?
I'LL DO THE BEST I CAN FOR YOU.
LIKE YOU DID FOR MY MOTHER?
( indistinct chatter )
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
I LOATHE SHIPS.
I WOULDN'T MIND MEETING
SOME PIRATES.
OF COURSE YOU WOULDN'T.
AND THEY'D KILL YOU ALL
AND MAKE ME THEIR QUEEN.
OH, REALLY.
THEY SAY THIS
IS JUST A CHANNEL,
AND IT GETS WORSE
IN THE ATLANTIC.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
MY MOTHER WAS EVIL. AWFUL.
I SHALL NEVER FOLLOW
IN HER FOOTSTEPS.
DOES THAT SATISFY YOU?
SO THROW AWAY THE CROSS.
WHAT?
IF YOU REJECT HER,
THEN THROW AWAY THE CRUCIFIX.
IT'S THE ONLY THING
I HAVE OF HERS.
THEN I MUST ON
WITH HER JOURNAL.
DAMN, MY EYES.
YOUR MISTRESS MUST INDEED
BE AN EVIL BANSHEE
IF YOU'RE MORE SCARED OF HER
THAN YOU ARE OF THESE WATERS.
THERE ARE MORE
COMPELLING MOTIVES
THAN FEAR.
( wave hits boat )
( gagging )
"MRS. ALLWORTHY'S CONSTANT--"
ARE YOU LISTENING?
WELL, I'M NOT DEAF, AM I?
"MRS. ALLWORTHY'S CONSTANT
CONTENTION WAS...
"THAT ALL MEN
ARE FORTUNE HUNTERS,
"AND, THEREFORE, ARE FAIR GAME
TO BE HUNTED IN RETURN.
"AND THAT WOMEN, LOGICALLY,
MIGHT AS WELL BE
"TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF
BY ONE OF THEIR OWN SEX
THAN JUST GIVE THEMSELVES TO
MEN AND SEE NO PROFIT IN IT."
AH, FOR YOUR UNDERSTANDING,
FLORA,
THIS IS RATHER...
DELICATE.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
THE MALE AND FEMALE
WERE INTENDING?
SURE. I'VE SEEN DOGS
IN THE STREET DOING IT.
YES, WELL,
IT'S NOT QUITE
THE SAME THING.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
YOU'RE NOT A DOG.
HUH.
"MRS. ALLWORTHY NEVER
FORCED A WOMAN...
"INTO HER SERVICE.
"BUT, LIKE A GOOD
HORSE TRAINER,
"SHE MADE SURE THAT THE PROCESS
BECAME SO FAMILIAR
"THAT IT WAS QUITE NATURAL
THAT ONE MIGHT EVENTUALLY
"BE BROKEN AND SADDLED.
"I VIEWED MY NEW SHELTER
WITH THE WISDOM OF THE YOUNG,
SO UNAWARE AS TO HOW MUCH
I WAS YET TO LEARN."
( woman moaning
in distance )
( moaning continues )
( horse nickers )
( gasps )
Mrs. Allworthy ( in distance ):
HIBBLE!
MR. HIBBLE!
WHERE THE DEVIL ARE YOU?
Hibble:
OH, GOD.
SHE'LL TEAR THE HIDE
OFF ME.
Woman: YOU WON'T
PRATTLE ON US?
MR. HIBBLE!
I SAW HIM.
YOU, GIRL?
WHERE?
IN-IN THE KITCHEN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
ARE YOU BEING WITH HIM?
NO, UH, I WAS LOOKING
FOR A PLACE TO REST.
I CAN SEE INTO
YOUR LYING SOUL.
ARE YOU HIDING SOMETHING
ON ME?
NOTHING. GOD'S TRUTH--
YOU BETTER NOT HAVE BEEN
WITH HIM!
YOU LAZY TROLLOP.
YOU WORK, OR YOU LEAVE.
MOLL.
I'M A MAN OF GRATITUDE,
I'LL REMEMBER.
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT, YOU ARE.
FOR A LIAR.
WAS HE HURTING YOU?
HURTING ME?
( laughs )
YOU'LL LEARN.
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
GOD MUST HAVE
A DARK SENSE OF HUMOR...
GIVING MEN
THEM STUPID WHACKERS
AND US THE DESIRE
TO TAKE THEM IN.
BUT IT PASSES NEAR TO
THE BEGINNING OF CREATION
FOR A FEELING IN YOUR BODY
IF IT'S DONE RIGHT.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT SOW CAN'T TAKE AWAY.
( knock at door )
COME.
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU?
WENT TO A GENTLEMAN'S HOUSE.
COME ON, GET WARM.
SOME GENTLEMAN IF HE
DIDN'T PAY FOR A CARRIAGE.
MRS. A WOULDN'T
LET US GET A CAB.
SHE'D RATHER KEEP THE MONEY.
UH-UH. DON'T WASTE MY WOOD.
BUT POLLY'S COLD.
YOU KNOW BETTER.
IF SHE STAYED AT
THE FEVER HOME,
HOW MUCH WOULD SHE EARN YOU?
( laughs )
SET FIRE TO HER IF YOU WANT.
NOW, YOU,
COME DRESS ME.
Mrs. Allworthy:
EXTREMELY PROFITABLE
EVENING LAST NIGHT.
MONEY'S A FAITHFUL DOG.
NEVER ASKS NOTHING,
GUARDS AND COMFORTS
LIKE A FRIEND.
BUT YOU GOTTA KEEP IT CLOSE.
STRAP ME UP, GIRL.
TAKEN MY FINGERS TO THE BONE,
I HAVE,
TRYING TO BREED THIS DOG.
DAY OR NIGHT,
GONNA BE ONE DEAD ROBBER
TRIES TO SEPARATE ME
FROM MY HOUND.
I CAN'T MAKE UP MY MIND
ABOUT YOU.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'RE
GRATEFUL OR NOT.
I'M WORKING MY BEST
TO SHOW IT, MA'AM.
NO, YOU AIN'T SHOWED
YOUR BEST.
THAT'S FOR YOU TO
CATCH THE MEN WITH,
MAKE US BOTH HAPPY.
FETCH MY GOWN.
NO, THE BLUE ONE.
IT'S SUNDAY.
CAN'T WEAR RED ON SUNDAY.
MOTHER OF GOD,
YOU'LL HAVE THE BLUE-NOSES
DOWN ON US.
FOR WEARING RED?
FOR EVERYTHING
THEM AND THEIR WOMEN ARE NOT.
I'VE GOTTA TAKE YOU IN HAND.
HMM.
A MAN'S NOTHING BUT A BULL...
BEAST OF LUST.
SAY ANYTHING, DO ANYTHING
TO EASE HIS URGES.
GOD'S NOT MADE A MAN
FIT TO BE WOVEN UP WITH YET.
BUT THERE'S PRECIOUS FEW WOMEN
WHO LEARN TO LEAD THEM
BY THE NOSE.
THESE ARE THE MOST AWESOME
WEAPONS YOU HAVE, GIRL.
PROP THEM UP,
AND A MAN WON'T BE ABLE
TO RAISE HIS EYES TO YOUR FACE.
SIT DOWN.
SOME OF THE FINEST GENTLEMEN
IN LONDON COME THROUGH MY DOORS.
WOULDN'T YOU WANT TO
HAVE POWER OVER SUCH MEN?
SO ALL THEY COULD THINK OF
WAS WORSHIPPING YOUR YOUNG BODY?
I WAS RAISED CATHOLIC.
SO WAS THE VIRGIN MARY,
AND DON'T TELL ME
SHE DIDN'T DO IT.
THAT'S BLASPHEMY.
NO, THAT'S COMMON SENSE,
GIRL.
WHAT ARE YOU
SAVING YOURSELF FOR?
GIVE YOURSELF SOME PLEASURE.
LIFE'S TERRIBLE SHORT FOR SOME.
YOU NEVER BEEN KISSED, I'LL BET.
AND WHY?
TWO FLAT PIECES OF FISH
WHERE THERE OUGHT TO BE
A RED RING OF ALLURE.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE
THE INNOCENCE OF A DOLL.
THEY WANTS THE CHILD IN YOU.
AND THE EYES.
TEASE THEM DOWN THERE
WITH YOUR EYES.
WHEN A MAN'S PART GOES HARD,
HIS BRAIN GOES SOFT.
THAT'S WHEN THEY'LL SAY
OR DO ANYTHING TO POSSESS YOU.
THAT'S WHEN YOU FEEL THE POWER.
DID YOU HAVE THIS POWER
OVER SOMEONE?
EVERY MAN WHO COMES
THROUGH MY DOOR.
MOLL.
WAS SHE BULLING YOU
ABOUT LAST NIGHT?
NO. NO, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THANKS.
EDNA AND ME...
WELL, IT'S NOT LOVE.
WE HAVE AN EAR FOR
EACH OTHER'S TROUBLES,
YOU KNOW?
SHE'S NOT SO YOUNG ANYMORE.
I DON'T WANT THE MISTRESS
AFTER HER.
WHAT WOULD SHE DO?
SHE'S CAPABLE OF ANYTHING.
( door opens )
THERE'S NO HEART
IN THE WOMAN.
( sighs )
ESCAPED FROM CARDIFF
PRISON HULKS, I DID.
WITH A HIGHWAY ALCHEMIST
NAMED GAY.
OH. HE COULD TURN THE LEAD
IN HIS PISTOLS TO GOLD.
MRS. ALLWORTHY
WAS HIS ACQUAINTANCE.
SHE HID HIM AND ME.
BUT HE DIED FROM A SHOT
HE TOOK WHILE ESCAPING.
FOR A WHILE, SHE AND I...
LORD, MAKES ME STRANGE
TO SAY THE WORDS.
WE SHARED THE SAME BED.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I DONE WRONG,
BUT SHE TURNED ON ME.
SUDDEN.
SHE WON'T TOUCH ME,
BUT SHE WON'T SET ME FREE.
HERE.
THIEF.
ONE WORD FROM HER
AND MY OWN SKIN WILL HANG ME.
I'VE GOT THIS THING
IN MY HEAD.
WHAT THING?
IF THE LIKES OF MRS. ALLWORTHY
CAN HAVE THE GENTRY
DANCE TO HER TUNE,
I COULD HAVE EVERYTHING--
NO, MOLL, NO.
A WORD FROM AN OLD PILGRIM:
GET YOURSELF OUT OF HERE.
FIND A FARMER.
BE A MILLINER'S WIFE.
HAVE A COMMON MAN
COME HOME TO YOU, LASS.
DON'T TRAVEL HER ROAD.
NO GOOD CAN COME OF IT.
WITH HER MONEY,
I'D KNOW HOW TO BE HAPPY.
( footsteps )
MR. HIBBLE!
OH, LORD, COME QUICK!
COME ON, LADIES, COME ON.
STAND ASIDE, STAND ASIDE.
( crying )
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
POLLY KILLED THE PIE MAN.
SHE MURDERED HIM?
NAH, THE OLD GEEZER
WOULD GIVE US A PIE OR TWO
FOR A TWIST IN THE LARDER.
CAN'T TOUCH HIM
CAN'T TOUCH--
DAMN, POLLY, NOW WE
AIN'T NEVER GONNA GET
ANY DECENT FOOD.
AW, BUT YOU SHOULD LOOK
AT THE SMILE ON HIS FACE.
( laughter )
Mrs. Allworthy: FIVE GUINEAS?
NOW, SURELY, GENTLEMEN...
"I DECIDED
THIS WASN'T PROSTITUTION.
"THAT HAPPENED ON STREET
CORNERS AND BACK ALLEYS.
"THIS WAS MAKING FRIENDS
WITH ELIGIBLE GENTLEMEN--
NOBLE, RICH
PROSPECTIVE HUSBANDS."
THIS IS NOT
ONE OF THOSE YOUNG GIRLS
WHO SWEAR TO THEIR VIRGINITY
AND THEN GET YOU DRUNK
SO THAT YOU DON'T NOTICE
THE DIFFERENCE.
( laughter )
NO, THIS IS THE REAL THING.
ALL THE MYSTERIES OF EVE
WAITING TO BE UNRAVELED.
NOW, WHICH OF YOU
NOBLE GENTLEMEN
IS GOING TO TAKE
THIS GENTLE FLOWER
TO THE FULL BLOSSOM
OF HER WOMANHOOD?
( men murmuring )
FIFTEEN GUINEAS.
FIFTEEN GUINEAS IT IS.
DO I HEAR TWENTY?
I'LL GIVE YOU THIRTY!
CHRIST, MOLL,
DON'T SELL YOURSELF
FOR THE BITCH.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
FORTY GUINEAS!
FORTY GUINEAS FOR SIR WILLIAM
AND HIS LOVELY LITTLE DOG.
LOVELY!
ANYONE FOR FORTY-FIVE?
NOW, GENTLEMEN, GENTLEMEN,
THERE WILL BE ONLY ONE NIGHT
IN THIS YOUNG LADY'S LIFE
IN WHICH, LIKE A FINE WINE,
YOU WILL BE ABLE TO TASTE
HER INNOCENCE.
( men chortling )
Man: FIFTY GUINEAS.
FIFTY GUINEAS!
WELL DONE!
DO I HEAR FIFTY-FIVE?
I BID FIFTY-FIVE GUINEAS!
FIFTY-FIVE IT IS,
YOUR LORDSHIP.
SIXTY? SIXTY GUINEAS!
DO I HEAR SIXTY-FIVE?
SIXTY-FIVE!
I HAVE SIXTY-FIVE.
DO I HEAR SEVENTY?
ONE HUNDRED
GUINEAS.
ONE HUNDRED GUINEAS!
THAT'S PUT A PRICE ON HER!
ANYONE ELSE?
ONE HUNDRED GUINEAS
IS A DONE THING.
BRAVO! BRAVO!
PREPARE YOURSELF
FOR THE PLEASURES
OF A LIFETIME.
THANK YOU.
I CAN'T.
NOT HIM. PLEASE.
FOR GOD'S SAKE,
SHE'S NOT READY.
SHUT UP.
FOR 100 GUINEAS
I'D PUT HER IN BED
WITH THE DEVIL.
NOW, I HOPE I HAVEN'T
WASTED MY TIME WITH YOU.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD
SOME BONE IN YOUR BACK.
HERE. FIND YOURSELF.
GO ON. GO ON.
BUT DO HIM GOOD,
OR YOU'LL HEAR FROM ME.
ALL RIGHT.
( coughs )
COME ON. COME ON.
HE IS FAIRLY DISGUSTING,
ISN'T HE?
"I TRIED TO PREPARE MYSELF
FOR THE MYSTERY OF LIFE--
"TO BE WORSHIPPED.
THAT NIGHT, I WAS NOT
MY MOST POWERFUL."
DID YOU GIVE HIM
HIS 100 GUINEAS' WORTH?
WORKED MYSELF UP AN APPETITE
TONIGHT, I DID.
HERE, LASS.
SIT YOU DOWN.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
OH, COME ON.
GET THE GIRL A GIN.
I'LL GET YOU
SOMETHING TO EAT.
I'VE GOT IT WORKED OUT.
IF HALF THE MEN THAT COME
HAVE GOT WIVES,
IT'S THE OTHER HALF
I'LL INVEST IN.
DON'T BUILD ON IT.
ONCE YOU'VE EARNT YOUR LIVING
ON YOUR BACK,
THERE'S PRECIOUS FEW MEN
WILL LOVE YOU.
HERE YOU GO.
THIS'LL STEADY YOUR NERVES.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
"I WAS THE SPARROW OF HOPE
LOOKING FOR A NEST.
"CLERGYMEN, SCIENTISTS,
PARLIAMENTARIANS,
INSURANCE SALESMEN,
AND EVEN AN ETON SCHOOLBOY."
I'M NOT READY YET.
"MY LIFE BECAME A WHIRLIGIG
OF SWEATING MEN'S BODIES
AND FAIRY TALE HOPES.
"I KEPT KISSING FROGS
LOOKING FOR A PRINCE.
"AND FINDING ONLY COLD,
GREEN FLESH.
"THE SCIENCE OF LIFE
DEVELOPED THE OTHER HALF
OF MY FEMALE INTUITION.
"MEN FEEL LEAST OBLIGATED
TO THOSE THEY CAN BUY.
"FINALLY, I THOUGHT
I WAS FINDING SOME LIGHT.
A GENTLEMAN FROM EAST CHIZACK."
HE'S MINE, YOU BITCH!
HE PAYS ME!
I'VE BEEN DOING HIM
FOR WEEKS!
( screams )
( yelling and screaming )
STOP THIS. STOP IT!
YOU'RE BOTH BLOODY STUPID.
THE MAN'S A SERVANT.
HE STEALS MONEY TO HAVE YOU.
UGH!
"AND MRS. ALLWORTHY ABOUNDED,
"HAUNTING THE STREETS
IN HER NEW CARRIAGE,
"ALLOWING NOT A HINT OF SUN
"TO DEFILE HER PRECIOUS
WHITE SKIN.
SHE FOUND NEW
AND DEVIOUS METHODS
TO FATTEN HER DOG."
( knocking )
WHAT IN HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
GOOD MORNING.
NOW, YOU SEE THIS ENTRY?
IT WAS A MEASURE OF NINE MONTHS.
WHO'S HERE, DADDY?
HELLO!
GOD, WOMAN,
LEAVE BEFORE MY WIFE--
IT IS JUST A MATTER OF YOU
GIVING A LITTLE SUPPORT
TO THE POOR DEAR ONE
OVER MY SHOULDER.
OH, HE'S A PICTURE OF YOU,
ISN'T HE, SIR?
"WE TRAVELED, PLAYING
THE SAME SCENE AGAIN AND AGAIN.
"IT DIDN'T MATTER THAT IT WAS
THE PIE MAN'S CHILD--
"THE POWER OF NINE MONTHS AND
THE IMAGINATION OF THE GUILTY
"SERVED THE PURPOSE.
( baby crying )
Allworthy ( to baby ):
HAVE SOME MONEY.
POLLY SAYS
YOU'RE HURTING.
SHE MUST HAVE CAUGHT ON.
SHE SOLD EDNA.
WHAT?
SHE CAN'T JUST
SELL SOMEONE.
SHE'S GONE.
GONE TO IRELAND
WITH A SQUIRE...
A WIDOWER WHO
TOOK A CHARM TO HER.
LORD HELP US, HIBBLE.
EDNA WILL HAVE A ROOF.
AND A COMPANION.
SHE WAS LOSING HER BLOOM.
SHE MIGHT HAVE PUT HER
IN THE STREET.
GOD HELP ME.
YOU SEE BEFORE YOU
A PRINCE OF PITY, MOLL.
THE COWARD'S COWARD.
"I DIDN'T KNOW WHY
I COULD STAND MY OWN PAINS
"BUT HIBBLE'S LOSS BROKE ME.
"I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD
HOW CAGED WE ALL WERE.
CHILDREN, COME AWAY.
YOU'RE ALL SINNERS!
AWAY. COME ON.
THAT'S THE DEVIL'S PLACE.
COME ALONG! COME ON!
"FOR WEEKS I PUSHED MYSELF
INTO A GIN BOTTLE
"LIKE ONE OF THOSE SHIPS
A SAILOR MAKES.
NO, NOT THIS ONE.
"AND WHILE I SOLACED,
LIFE PREPARED
TO PLAY ME AGAIN."
Mrs. Allworthy:
NOW, SHE'S FIVE GUINEAS
FOR WHAT YOU'LL WANT.
RIGHT.
SHE'S NEW.
VERY GOOD.
SHE'S VERY SKILLED
AND EXTREMELY INVENTIVE.
SEVEN GUINEAS.
OH, NO, SIR,
SHE'S THE SHAME
OF MY ESTABLISHMENT.
STUPID GIRL WON'T BE HERE LONG.
MEN COMPLAINED.
I JUST KEEP HER TO DO THE ONES
THE OTHERS WON'T.
WANT TO WORSHIP ME?
DO YOU WANT TO SEE
MY WEAPONS OF LOVE?
MOLLY--
HOW MUCH?
HALF A CROWN.
AND YOU'LL BE LUCKY
TO GET YOUR MONEY'S WORTH.
( indistinct chatter )
HELLO, DARLING.
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING AT?
WHERE THE BLOODY HELL
DO YOU LIVE?
TAKING ME TO HEAVEN, ARE YOU?
GOD!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
THE STEPS ARE CROOKED!
IT'S AN OLD HOUSE.
DON'T BELIEVE IN
KEEPING ORDER?
IT'S NOT PRETENTIOUS,
BUT IT SERVES MY NEEDS.
IT'S MORE THAN I'VE GOT.
WOULD YOU
SIT OVER THERE, PLEASE?
HAVE YOU GOT A DRINK?
I DON'T DRINK VERY OFTEN.
YOU WILL AFTER TONIGHT.
IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL.
I OFFEND EVERYBODY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHY'D YOU PICK ME,
ANYWAY?
'CAUSE YOU WERE
THE CHEAPEST.
NOW, THERE'S A BLOW.
I WANTED TO...
PAINT A WOMAN.
YOU PAID JUST
TO LOOK AT ME?
WHAT'S WRONG?
IT'S THE STRANGE ONES
THAT HURT PEOPLE LIKE ME.
GIN...
OR WHISKEY?
I BELIEVE I COULD GET
A BOTTLE OF SOMETHING NEARBY.
MAKES NO DIFFERENCE.
COME ON, MISTER.
( Moll sighs )
( door opens
and closes )
HELLO.
ALL I COULD FIND WAS WHISKEY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
DON'T TOUCH THAT.
WHY NOT?
OH, GOD!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA KILL ME!
NO. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
PLEASE DON'T!
YOU'RE NOT GONNA HURT ME?
NO.
NOT UNLESS I FALL ON YOU.
TRUE?
YES.
YOU BASTARD!
YOU SCARED ME TO DEATH!
I MAY BE AN IGNORANT TROLLOP,
BUT I STILL GOT FEELINGS,
YOU KNOW.
I APOLOGIZE.
SPEECH IS NOT
MY FIRST LANGUAGE.
I ATTEMPT TO MAKE A LIVING
DOING THESE STUDIES.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER
I'M AN ARTIST OR A SCIENTIST.
LIFE FASCINATES ME.
EVERYTHING HAS A PURPOSE.
THE WAY OUR HEARTS WORK,
THE WAY OUR VERY BLOOD FLOWS
AROUND OUR BODY
ALL FITS TOGETHER
IN A BRILLIANT SYSTEM.
BUT PART OF ME REALLY YEARNS
TO CATCH WHAT TRULY ANIMATES
OUR HUMAN CLAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I WANT TO SEE WHO
I REALLY BOUGHT.
WHY?
BECAUSE YOU LOOK LIKE
A DROWNED CLOWN.
SO DO YOU.
THERE USED TO BE MORE OF ME.
BUT THE BOOZE
IS THINNING ME DOWN.
MUST HAVE DRANK HIMSELF
TO DEATH.
( chuckles )
COULD YOU PLEASE
KEEP A LITTLE MORE STILL?
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU SLEEP.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
WITH ALL THESE
DEAD FOLKS' PARTS
LYING AROUND.
WHAT KIND OF PERSON
WOULD LET YOU CUT THEM UP
LIKE SUNDAY JOINTS?
PEOPLE WILL THEM TO SCIENCE.
WELL, THIS BODY
AIN'T WILLING.
NO MATTER HOW CHEAP IT GOES
WHEN IT'S ALIVE.
YOU'RE NOT VERY GOOD,
ARE YOU?
I DON'T HAVE AN EGG
FOR A HEAD.
I'M ONLY STARTING.
IT'S REMBRANDT'S
LINES OF FORM.
I WOULDN'T COPY HIM,
NOT IF HE PAINTED PEOPLE
WITH EGGS FOR HEADS.
DO YOU REALLY NOT KNOW
WHO REMBRANDT IS?
NOT EVEN IF
I'D SLEPT WITH HIM.
MAYBE THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
YOU CAN'T LIVE
SOMEONE ELSE'S LIFE.
YOU'VE GOT TO DO THINGS
YOUR OWN WAY.
PLEASE, SIT DOWN
AND LET ME SEE
WHAT I'VE PAID FOR.
A CARRIAGE?
HAVE YOU LEFT YOUR SENSES?
FOUND 'EM, MORE LIKE.
DIDN'T I WARN YOU?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOUR FEET?
NOTHING!
HE WANTS ME EVERY NIGHT
FOR THE NEXT FORTNIGHT.
A CARRIAGE EACH WAY.
YOU?
( coins jingle )
ME.
WHATEVER YOU DID TO HIM,
TEACH IT TO THE OTHERS.
I NEVER TOUCHED HIM.
I'M SHIVERING.
I'VE GOT BLOODY GOOSEBUMPS.
( chuckles )
MISSED.
I WASN'T AIMING AT YOU.
YES, YOU WERE.
WEREN'T.
DID I MISS THAT TIME?
WOULD YOU PLEASE
SIT STILL?
I TOLD YOU,
I'M FREEZING.
IT'S FREEZING.
JUST SIT THERE...
AND HOLD THIS.
IT LOOKS JUST LIKE
A MIRROR OF ME.
IT'S GOOD?
( dejected )
BRILLIANT.
IT'S NOT GOOD?
IT'S JUST...
IT'S JUST SO DAMN
MECHANICAL!
I'M THERE.
YES, THIS MUSCLE
IS CONNECTED TO THIS TISSUE...
DA VINCI COULD HAVE MADE
YOUR EYE DANCE WITH
A TOUCH OF LIGHT FROM HIS BRUSH,
BUT HE WASN'T PAINTING
THE THING, THE BODY,
HE WAS CAPTURING ITS...
ITS SPIRIT.
WELL, THE SPIRITS IN ME
COST TUPPENCE A QUART,
LOVE.
( chuckles )
YOU'VE THE DEVIL'S SPIRIT
IN YOU, ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S NOTHING IN ME.
HARD LIKE A ROCK.
THAT WAY THERE'S
NOTHING INSIDE
TO GET CONFUSED.
AND THE MOON IS MADE
OF GREEN CHEESE.
COME.
YOU SEE THE RESTRICTIONS
OF YOUR MORTAL BODY?
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
INSIDE YOU...
THERE'S SO MUCH SPACE.
THE COSMOS.
YOU SEE?
INSIDE, YOU GO ON FOREVER.
I'M STONE.
YOU WANT TO PAINT
ANOTHER ONE?
NO.
I'M JUST THE WRONG WOMAN.
IT'S NOT YOU.
I DON'T THINK THESE HANDS
WILL EVER CAPTURE YOU.
YOU'RE A KIND MAN.
( thunder crashing )
Driver: WHOA.
GIDDYUP.
HELLO?
HELLO.
AAAH!
THAT'S THE LAST
OF THEM.
TEACH HER THE LESSON.
Moll:
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHERE ELSE TO GO.
WHO DID THIS TO YOU?
IT HAPPENS.
CAREFUL, JONATHAN,
THIS IS NO STRAY KITTEN.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
KIND OF PERSON YOU'RE
LETTING IN YOUR HOUSE.
STRANGELY, I FIND
THE MYSTERY INTRIGUING.
SEND FOR ME IF SHE
HAS ANY SIGN OF TREMORS.
OTHERWISE,
IT'LL BE A BAD FEW DAYS
BEFORE SHE'S COMFORTABLE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I NEED A DRINK.
THAT'S THE LAST THING
YOU NEED.
DAMN YOU, DO YOU
KNOW HOW I FEEL?
ANGRY, FRIGHTENED, LOST--
THAT'S HOW I'D FEEL.
I'M NOT YOUR FRIEND.
HE'S RIGHT, YOU DON'T NEED
MY KIND IN YOUR HOUSE.
GENTLY.
IS IT ME YOU DON'T TRUST?
YOU'RE HURT. STAY.
I WON'T HAVE A MAN
TELL ME WHAT TO DO!
ALL RIGHT THEN,
PLEASE STAY.
NO.
LEAVE THEN.
BANISH YOURSELF.
I'M TELLING YOU WHAT TO DO.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
MY LIFE'S NOT SOME GAME.
MINE NEITHER.
WELL...GOOD-BYE.
DAMN YOU. I HAVEN'T GOT
ANYWHERE ELSE TO GO!
I'LL SLEEP ON THE FLOOR.
NO, I'LL SLEEP ON THE FLOOR.
YOU ARE THE MOST
CONTENTIOUS PERSON
I'VE EVER MET!
YOU HAVEN'T LIVED MUCH
THEN, HAVE YOU?
"DAYS PASSED QUICKLY
IN MY NEW CAREER.
"IN EXCHANGE FOR PARTICIPATING
"IN THE QUEST TO CAPTURE
MY SOUL IN PIGMENTS AND OILS,
"I WAS GIVEN FOOD AND LODGING
BY A MAN
WHO SUBJECTED HIMSELF
TO INTERNAL TORTURES."
DAMN!
LET'S NOT STAY IN TODAY.
LET'S GO DO SOMETHING FUN.
JUST A SECOND.
THIS THEN. JUST LIKE THAT.
I CAN'T SEE YOU.
GOT IT?
AAH!
IS THIS ANYONE YOU KNOW?
A RICH WIDOW
FROM WIMBLEDON.
( chuckles )
HOW COME YOU HAVEN'T
CUT ANYONE UP
SINCE I GOT HERE?
I DIDN'T WANT TO
DISCONCERT YOU.
WELL,
THAT'S YOUR INCOME.
FROM THE LOOKS OF
YOUR SCRAWNY BODY
AND THIS PLACE,
YOU HAVEN'T GOT TWO PENCE
TO RUB TOGETHER.
YOU'RE A DESPERATE MAN
TO PAY TO PAINT ME,
I'LL TELL YA THAT.
BUT EVERYTHING'S ON
THE SURFACE, MOLL.
THERE ARE DIFFERENT KINDS
OF DESPERATION.
LIKE WHAT?
Artist:
THE MAD HERMIT THAT I AM
LIVED A WILD LIFE AS A CHILD.
I MADE WINGS FROM CANVAS
AND BAMBOO.
I WISHED TO NAVIGATE
THE ATMOSPHERE LIKE A BIRD.
INSTEAD, I STUDIED GRAVITY
AND PLUNGED 40 FEET FROM
THE MILL ROOF.
MY BODY LAY STATIC FOR WEEKS,
BUT MY MIND TRAVELED
TO PLACES IN FEVERS
THAT ARE STILL VIVID IN ME.
ONE MAN CAME
AND WAS BY MY SIDE
DAY AND NIGHT,
A VERY OLD DOCTOR,
TOUCHED, I AM TOLD,
BY MY INVENTIVENESS.
HE EXHAUSTED HIMSELF.
I'M STILL HERE, OLD MAN.
STILL TESTING THE WINDS,
THANKS TO YOU.
MY PARENTS TREATED ME
AS AN INVALID.
FREQUENTLY I WOULD
GET SICKLY
JUST TO REINFORCE
THEIR SMOTHERINGS.
I CAME TO LONDON
TO BECOME A KNIGHT OF MEDICINE.
BUT MY STAMINA IS INSUFFICIENT
FOR THE WORK OF A PHYSICIAN,
SO I DEDICATED MY DRAWING
TO HELPING THOSE WHO ARE
BETTER SPECIMENS.
( bird calls in distance )
THAT CHILD IN ME
YEARNED TO CREATE
THE EXTRAORDINARY--
A PARTHENON,
A SISTINE CHAPEL.
AND NOW...
I THINK I'D SETTLE
FOR CREATING ANYTHING
THAT WOULD GIVE ME
A SENSE OF COMPLETION.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FROM LIFE, MOLL?
NOTHIN' ANYMORE.
COME ON, MOLL.
I BARE MY SOUL--
AND I BARE MY BOSOMS.
WE MAKE A GOOD PAIR.
( loud chatter
and laughter )
MOLL.
NOW, THERE'S A SIGHT.
CAN I SPEAK WITH YOU
PRIVATE-LIKE?
YEAH.
HIBBLE, WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU?
MOLL, THINGS AIN'T GONE RIGHT.
WHAT'S WRONG?
HELLO, MOLLY.
DRIVEN OFF BY
THE GUARDIANS OF MORALS,
WE WERE.
LOST MY HOUSE, MY GIRLS...
GETTING OUT OF NEWGATE
COST ME MY COMFORT, GIRL,
MY FAITHFUL DOG.
SHE'S LOOKING SO GOOD.
ISN'T SHE, HIBBLE?
SO NICELY ATTIRED.
I THINK SHE'S BEEN FINDING
WHILE WE'VE BEEN LOSING.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I TOOK YOU IN.
PUT A ROOF OVER YOUR HEAD.
KEPT YOU WHILE YOU WAS
ON THE BOOZE.
NOW YOU'RE COMING BACK,
AND YOU'RE GONNA WORK FOR ME.
I'M BEYOND YOU NOW.
COME WITH ME OR I'LL PUT YOU
BEYOND EVERYTHING.
MOLL,
SHE DIDN'T TELL ME THIS.
I MEAN IT.
WHAT'S GOING ON,
MOLL?
IS THAT YOUR BUSINESS?
MORE THAN YOU THINK.
OH, YOU GOT YOURSELF
A LOVER BOY, MOLLY.
HAVEN'T YOU LEARNED
ABOUT MEN YET?
HE'LL BURN YOU.
YOU'RE BETTER OFF WITH ME.
DON'T DOUBT I WILL USE THIS.
ONE SMALL SHOT LIKE THAT,
SO FEW GRAINS OF POWDER,
MIGHT KILL ME,
MOST LIKELY NOT.
BUT I SWEAR
I'LL LIVE LONG ENOUGH
TO RUN THIS BLADE
THROUGH YOUR BODY SIX TIMES
AND DANCE UPON YOUR GRAVE
BEFORE I DROP.
Woman:
SOMEONE GET A MAGISTRATE!
NOT HERE...
NOT TODAY.
YOU AIN'T WORTH MY SPIT.
LET ALONE MY NECK.
I'LL HAVE MEMORY OF THIS.
YOU'LL PAY ME.
I ALREADY DID.
MOLL, I'M SORRY.
HERE, HAVE SOME BREAD.
I'M SORRY.
WAS THAT GUN
THAT USELESS?
I LIED.
AND...
RATHER WELL, I THOUGHT.
WELL?
TAKE YOUR BOOTS OFF.
YOU HAVE YOURS ON.
I HAVEN'T BEEN OUTDOORS.
THIS IS VERY UNIMPORTANT.
ANGRY 'CAUSE I
CLEANED FOR YOU?
DON'T DO THIS AGAIN.
I'LL NEVER FIND ANYTHING.
THERE. BACK WHERE IT WAS.
GOD, THAT FELT GOOD!
( both laugh )
"FOR A WHILE,
OUR LIVES WENT ON...
TWO STRANGE COMPANIONS
IN THE CIRCLES OF LIFE."
MADAM.
I WASN'T LONG, WAS I?
"NO, MOLL.
NOT LONG AT ALL."
THAT'S A FINE PERFUME.
SHE WAS VERY PRETTY.
IT'S NOT WHAT YOU THINK.
I DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS COMING.
AGAIN.
IF SHE'S WHAT YOU NEED--
THERE ARE THINGS
I HAVEN'T TOLD YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL
THE LIKES OF ME ANYTHING.
LET'S JUST
GET THIS OVER WITH.
CIVILIZED. I'M LEAVING.
SLOW DOWN, DAMN YOU.
THAT WOMAN WAS MY SISTER.
SHE BRINGS ME MEDICINES.
A LITTLE MONEY FROM MY FAMILY.
HOW DOES HER KIND LIKE
YOU HAVING ME FOR A LODGER?
IT'S NOT FOR HER TO KNOW.
SO YOU DON'T WANT HER
TO KNOW.
IT'S HER I DON'T TRUST.
IT'S ALL A MISTAKE.
EITHER I WANT YOU COMMITTED,
OR I WANT YOU
TO FREE YOURSELF NOW.
COMMITTED?
TO ME.
WHAT?!
EVERY NIGHT
WHEN YOU'RE ASLEEP,
I LOOK AT YOU
AND I FEAR ONE THING--
THAT YOU MIGHT NOT BE HERE.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
I'M GOING TO FAIL YOU.
I CAN ACCEPT THAT.
NO, FEEL THAT!
THAT'S NOTHING
COMPARED TO THE PAIN
THAT COMES WITH ME!
LET ME LOVE YOU.
DO I HIDE WHEN YOUR FAMILY
COME TO VISIT?
I'LL TELL THEM EVERYTHING
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
"THEY HUNG HER MOTHER."
FEEL THAT!
"SHE SLEPT WITH
HUNDREDS OF MEN!"
FEEL THAT!
"SHE'S A BITCH
AND A TROLLOP!"
AND I HATE YOU!
THIS IS MADNESS!
FORGOT ME BLEEDIN'
STUPID SHOES.
PUT THEM UNDER THE BED,
MOLL.
"I'D HAD SEX
WITH MANY A MAN,
"BUT THIS WAS THE FIRST TIME
I'D MADE LOVE.
"HE WILLED HIS SOUL
INTO ME.
"WE WERE ONE,
"A FUSION OF PASSION
AND UNSPOKEN KNOWLEDGES.
"WE WERE A UNITED FORCE
PUSHING BACK THE DARKNESS
IN EACH OTHER'S LIVES."
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
I HAD TO BE RICH
TO OWN THE STARS.
MOLL...
I WANT YOU TO BE MY WIFE.
WAKE ME UP IN THE MORNING
AND SAY THAT.
I MEAN IT.
WE'LL SEE
IF THERE'S SOME CHANCE
WITH YOUR FAMILY FIRST.
THEN I'LL ANSWER.
IF YOU SAY SO.
FEELING COLD?
NO, THAT'S NOT
WHAT I'M FEELING.
( sheep bleating )
WELCOME!
WELCOME HOME!
IS THAT YOUR FATHER?
IS THAT HIM?
NO, IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
THAT EASY, MOLL.
WELCOME HOME!
THE MASTER'S HOME!
STEADY, BOY, STEADY.
WHOA, WHOA.
NO.
YES.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME?
WELL, THIS WAS YOUR IDEA.
OH, GOD.
NO, THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THIS IS MOLL FLANDERS.
HELLO.
NO, MOLL.
THIS IS MY MOTHER,
AND THIS IS MY SISTER
CHARLOTTE.
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO MEET YOU FORMALLY.
THE PAINTINGS--
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE ALREADY MET.
YEAH, WELL, I'M SURE YOU'VE
NEARLY SEEN ALL OF ME.
YOUR FATHER WILL BE
JOINING US. PLEASE.
WELL, AT LEAST HIS BODY
IS WORKING WELL.
Servant:
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WOULD WISH FOR, MA'AM?
Moll: NO.
WE'LL HAVE SOME WINE.
YOU KNOW HOW YOUR FATHER
FEELS ABOUT ALCOHOL.
SOME RED WINE, GARETH.
I BROUGHT IT WITH ME
IN THE CARRIAGE.
MOLL, LET ME EXPLAIN
THE LITTLE HYPOCRISIES
OF MY FAMILY.
ALL THIS COMES FROM THE SUCCESS
OF THE FAMILY'S BREWERIES.
IT IS
AN HONEST BUSINESS.
PROFITING FROM THE SINS
OF THE LITTLE MAN.
WHAT SCHOOL DID YOU GO TO,
MISS FLANDERS?
UM, CONVENT OF
THE SACRED HEART.
NICE PLACE, SORT OF.
IT PROVIDES WORK
FOR THE INDOLENT.
IT IS AN HONEST BUSINESS.
BUT PLEASE, LET US NOT
SPOIL WHAT IS TRUTHFULLY
A WONDROUS OCCASION.
MY SON HAS RETURNED HOME.
SO MUCH HAS HAPPENED
SINCE YOU'VE BEEN AWAY.
BUT WE CAN SHARE
ALL THAT LATER.
BUT GOD SO HELP ME,
IF YOU...
WANTED A WOMAN AT LAST,
SURELY YOU COULD HAVE
PAID FOR ONE.
OH, I DID.
MOLL IS MY MODEL.
AND MY FIANCEE.
FOR A FEW PENNIES,
SHE'S HELPED ME FIND MYSELF--
AN EXPERIENCE
YOU'VE DENIED ME
FOR THE DURATION
OF MY EXISTENCE.
PATIENCE.
Mother: MY DEAR...
IT'S OBVIOUS MY SON
FINDS YOU VERY ATTRACTIVE.
WHATEVER YOU WISH--
NAME IT.
A THOUSAND GUINEAS?
FIVE THOUSAND?
TEN THOUSAND?
HERE.
THIS IS WORTH MORE THAN
YOU COULD EARN IN A LIFETIME.
YOU CAN BUY YOURSELF
A FUTURE
WITHOUT TAKING MY SON'S AWAY.
ALL MY LIFE I'VE DREAMT
OF OWNING SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
FUNNY, I THOUGHT I'D FEEL MORE.
I KNOW WHO I AM...
AND WHAT I'VE BEEN.
AND SO DOES YOUR SON.
I JUST THOUGHT MAYBE
THERE'D BE SOME CHANCE
I'D FIT INTO YOUR FAMILY.
THAT WOULD HAVE MADE ME
THE PROUDEST LIVING THING.
BUT NO ONE CAN SEPARATE ME
FROM THIS MAN.
UNLESS HE TELLS ME
HE WANTS ME TO LEAVE HIM.
I LOVE HIM ENOUGH
TO DO THAT.
BUT YOU CAN'T BUY ME AWAY.
Father: THIS IS
ALL MY FAULT, YOU KNOW.
I SWEAR, IT IS MY MISTAKE.
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER SENT THE BOY
TO SCHOOL IN LONDON.
OBSERVE, MOLL.
GREAT MONEY DOES NOT
A GREAT HUMAN MAKE.
MY SON TELLS ME
THAT I HAVE NEVER
DEMONSTRATED LOVE FOR HIM.
WELL, LET ME SEE
HOW I CAN DO THAT.
WELL, I CAN AT LEAST
PROTECT HIM.
IF YOU MARRY HER,
I SHALL NOT ONLY
DISINHERIT YOU,
I SHALL EXCOMMUNICATE YOU.
AS GOD IS MY JUDGE.
ENOUGH!!!
YOU KEEP SENDING MY SISTER
TO LONDON WITH MONEY
TO SEDUCE ME,
BUT YOU NEVER ONCE
CAME YOURSELF!
OH, I DIDN'T ALWAYS
TAKE THE MONEY.
AND SOMETIMES
I THOUGHT I MIGHT FOLD
AND RUN BACK LIKE
SOME SCARED RABBIT.
BUT I HAVEN'T.
AND I NEVER WILL..
AS LONG AS MOLL IS AT MY SIDE.
IF PAIN....
IS THE PROOF
OF OUR DEVOTION...
NOTHING HURTS ME MORE TODAY
THAN THE ANGUISH
WHICH YOU HAVE CAUSED
MY WIFE-TO-BE.
WITH THIS RING...
I THEE WED.
WHERE'S THAT WINE BOTTLE?
WHERE'S THE WINE BOTTLE?!
( both laugh )
"HE FOUND ME IN THE MIRROR.
"HE BECAME AS FERTILE
IN HIS IMAGINATION
AS I WAS IN MY BELLY."
"WE EXPERIENCED
A DELIRIOUS, TIMELESS PEACE.
IT'S MOVING.
KEEP STILL.
BOTH OF YOU.
( bell rings )
IT'S A GIRL, MOLL.
I KNOW IT'S A GIRL.
I'LL BE JEALOUS
IF YOU LOVE HER TOO MUCH.
IF I CLOSE MY EYES, I HAVE
ENOUGH LOVE FOR THE WORLD
AND YOU AT THE CENTER OF IT.
( chuckles )
YOU HAVEN'T A CANNY THOUGHT
IN YOUR HEAD, DO YOU?
FLORA.
I HAD A NANNY
BY THAT NAME.
SHE OFTEN STOOD BETWEEN
ME AND MY MOTHER.
FLORA.
I THINK IT'S
A BEAUTIFUL NAME.
"IF IN THE ACT
OF CREATING HUMANKIND
"GOD MIRRORED IN US HIS IMAGE,
"WE AND HE ARE THEREFORE
EQUAL IN THE STRUGGLE
FOR RATIONAL KNOWLEDGE--"
WILL YOU SIT STILL?
I AM SITTING STILL.
YOU'RE NOT SITTING STILL.
"WE AND HE SHOULD NOT BE
CONDEMNED FOR OUR FAILURES
NOR LOSE OUR WONDER
AT OUR SUCCESSES."
SO, STUDENT...
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK YOU REALLY DO
HAVE AN EGG FOR A HEAD.
LET ME SEE THIS INSULT.
PLEASE.
NO.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
Moll: I'M NOT CLIMBING
THOSE STAIRS AGAIN.
IT'S YOUR TURN NEXT.
HOW'S IT GOING?
FINE.
THAT'S PRETTY.
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S NOTHING.
YEAH.
Doctor:
I'LL SEND ONE OF
MY PEOPLE OVER.
WITH A CHILD IN YOU,
YOU SHOULD LEAVE.
NOTHING WILL MAKE ME LEAVE.
I ALREADY
THREW HER OUT TWICE.
I'LL FIND A WAY,
NO MATTER WHAT THE COST.
I'M SERVING HIM
AS IF HE WERE MY BROTHER.
IT'S NOT A MATTER OF COST.
IT'S SMALLPOX.
IF YOU'RE A DOCTOR,
THEN CURE HIM!
HE'S TRYING HIS BEST, MOLL.
HE'S DOING HIS BEST.
"AND IF SHE CHANCE TO NOD,
I'LL RAIL AND BRAWL
"AND WITH THE CLAMOR
KEEP HER STILL AWAKE.
THIS IS A WAY TO KILL A WIFE
WITH KINDNESS."
YOU SEE? I COULD TEACH YOU
A THING OR TWO.
YOU ALWAYS COULD.
KEEP READING TO ME, MOLL.
I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
( shivering and muttering )
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOU NEED TO GET YOUR REST.
( coughing )
YOU'RE GONNA GET BETTER.
I WILL IF ONLY TO STOP YOU
GETTING MAD AT ME.
IF I COULD PUT MY BLOOD
IN YOUR BODY, I WOULD.
I KNOW.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
( shivering )
M-MOLL.
WHAT?
MY-MY BOOTS.
YOUR BOOTS?
I WANT YOU TO
PUT MY BOOTS ON.
YOUR BOOTS ON?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I WANT YOU TO
WEAR MY BOOTS.
( shivering
and gasping )
ARE THEY DANCING BOOTS?
THESE YOUR DANCING BOOTS?
YOU'RE SO SILLY.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE. YOU HAPPY?
YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO WEAR THEM
FOR BOTH OF US.
OH, DON'T.
AND FOR FLORA.
STOP.
I-I-
I K-KNOW YOU CAN DO IT.
I FOUND MY CREATION IN YOU.
IT'S LIFE.
GOD IS LOVE, MOLL.
LOVE IS GOD.
( crying )
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
SO-SO BRIGHT.
( crying )
WHY NOT ME?
WHY CAN'T YOU TAKE ME?
Hibble:
"WHY NOT ME?
WHY DIDN'T YOU TAKE ME?"
I BET HE WOULDN'T HAVE
LET HER ABANDON ME,
IF HE'D LIVED.
WELL...
TIME TO SLEEP.
NO, DON'T STOP.
NO, IT'S TIME.
COME ON.
FIVE POUNDS.
A DESECRATION.
YOU COULD USE THE MONEY.
IT COULD HELP OTHERS.
HE ALREADY DID.
I HAVE HIS LETTER OF BEQUEST.
NO MAN WHO TOUCHES HIM
WILL LIVE TO GET OUT THAT DOOR.
I'LL GIVE YOU TIME
TO THINK THIS OVER.
"I STAYED BESIDE HIM
FOR TWO DAYS.
"I FEARED IF I LEFT
FOR A SINGLE MOMENT,
" THEY WOULD TAKE HIM.
I USED OUR SAVINGS
TO MAKE HIM SAFE."
"I BURIED HIM
BESIDE THE OLD DOCTOR.
"I WANTED HIM TO HAVE
A COMPANION
IN HIS LAST GREAT ADVENTURE."
( bell tolls )
"I HAD HEARD THAT
LETTING ONE'S BLOOD FLOW
"WAS AS NEAR A PAINLESS DEATH
AS COULD BE ACHIEVED.
"BUT LIFE WAS NOT
FINISHED WITH ME YET.
"I DON'T KNOW WHAT MANIAS
OVERCAME ME...
"BUT IF IT WAS MADNESS,
IT WAS ALSO A STRANGE LUCIDITY.
"WE HAD NOT FUSED OUR SOULS
IN MY BELLY
"TO MAKE A MOCKERY
OF ALL OUR EFFORTS.
"I FELT THAT THERE WAS
NO LIVING SOUL I COULD TRUST.
"I FEARED HIS FAMILY
WOULD TAKE THE BABY
"IN AN INSTANT.
"SO I DETERMINED
TO BRING OUR CHILD FORTH
ALONE INTO THIS WORLD
SURROUNDED WITH
HER FATHER'S SPIRIT."
"I WAS DETERMINED THAT
THE FIRST THING
"TO BRUSH THE CHILD'S EYES
WOULD BE THE BEAUTY
THAT HER FATHER HAD CREATED."
( groaning )
( grunting, screaming )
( baby crying )
OKAY, FLORA, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S YOUR CROSS.
"IN ORDER TO PUT FOOD
IN OUR MOUTHS,
"I WAS EXPENDING MY MEMORIES.
EVEN THE BEST."
I'LL GIVE YOU
ONE SHILLING.
THAT'S VERY SPECIAL TO ME.
FIVE SHILLINGS.
I'LL GIVE YOU TWO SHILLINGS,
AND THAT'S ALL.
ALL RIGHT.
THREE PENCE, SIX PENCE,
NINE PENCE, ONE SHILLING.
"BUT IN MY DARKNESS,
I FOUND A GREAT JOY
IN MY NEW MEMORIES."
( baby crying)
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
"I LEFT MY CHILD
WITH A NEIGHBOR, A WIDOW.
I TRUSTED HER."
SHE'LL BE FINE,
MISSY.
"WE WERE UNITED
IN OUR UNDERSTANDING OF GRIEF.
"I HAD USED UP MY LOCAL AREA
"AND HAD TO FORAGE
FURTHER AFIELD.
"I WAS FAILING,
AND FAILURE MEANT
I COULD NOT FEED MY CHILD."
WATCH OUT!
"MY MIND WAS RACING.
"PART DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
"ANOTHER PART HEARD
THE DEVIL IN ME...SCREAMING.
"ALL I COULD SEE WAS MY CHILD.
THE HORROR AND THE RISK
NEARLY OVERWHELMED ME."
Man:
IT'S HER!
THIEF! THIEF!
THIEF!
( all shouting )
Moll:
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING!
I DIDN'T DO IT!
Woman: HOLD!
HOLD!!!
WHY...THAT'S MY SERVANT GIRL.
OUT OF MY WAY.
I PAID FOR THEM CLOTHES.
HOW DARE YOU GET THEM FILTHY?!
I WAS JUST DRIVING BY.
I DIDN'T HAVE YOU
ON MY MIND.
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
LOOK AT HER SHAKING.
EYES LIKE A ROOSTER
SEEING THE AXE.
WHERE'S YOUR LITTLE
LOVER BOY?
DEAD.
HE'S LEFT YOU
TO THE GALLOWS, GIRL.
YOU WANT MY HELP NOW?
ARE YOU SURE?
EH?
I SAID YOU'D PAY.
YOUR LIFE IS MINE.
GIVE ME ONE SOUL...
WHO SAW MY GIRL IN YOUR SHOP.
MY GIRL MAY BE STUPID,
BUT SHE'S INNOCENT.
AND WHEN YOU ACCUSE HER,
YOU ACCUSE ME.
I HAVE A LAWYER
WHO'LL SUE YOU
OUT OF HOUSE AND HOME!
BUT I HAVE
A GENEROUS NATURE.
FIFTY POUNDS
WILL REPAIR THIS SLANDER.
OR WE CAN GO TO
THE BARRISTERS RIGHT NOW.
"MY LIFE CLOSED IN AGAIN.
"BUT AT LEAST I COULD
TRADE MY HUMILIATION
FOR FOOD FOR MY CHILD."
FOUND A FRIEND IN LIFE,
OUR MRS. ALLWORTHY.
THAT PIPE HAS DONE WONDERS
FOR HER DISPOSITION.
SHE USED TO BE MISERABLE.
NOW SHE'S BLEEDING INTOLERABLE.
( coughs and chuckles )
OH, WE MADE A PRETTY
LITTLE CONTRACT.
HAVEN'T WE, MOLL?
NOW THIS TIME,
YOU BETTER LIVE UP TO IT.
OH, RUB MY FEET.
THEIR TIRED.
NOW, BITCH.
OR YOU'LL END UP
JUST LIKE YOUR MOTHER.
"THEN I BELIEVED IN A CRUELER
SPECIES ABOVE MERE HUMANS.
"THEIR POWER COMES FROM
SO MUCH STRENGTH OF SELF
THAT IT FREEZES US LIKE RABBITS
TO BE TORN TO SHREDS."
"THE JOURNEY TOOK US
THROUGH PART OF THE CITY
I HAD NEVER SEEN."
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
MY LUCK'S BEEN CHANGING, MOLL.
YOU'RE THE LIVING PROOF.
CAN'T SEEM TO PUT A FOOT WRONG.
'TIS A GRANT OF
HER MAJESTY'S LANDS
SIGNED BY THE PRIME MINISTER
OF ENGLAND HIMSELF.
( chuckling )
AN OLD CUSTOMER OF MINE.
I PLOTTED THE MOST SIMPLE
OF COUPS,
FILLED MY FAITHFUL DOG
WITH COMFORT,
BOUGHT A HOME
IN THE NEW WORLD.
FIT FOR A MERCHANT PRINCE.
WANTED ME ABOUT AS FAR AWAY
FROM LONDON AS ONE CAN GET.
SO...WE'RE ALL GOING TOGETHER.
LIKE A FAMILY.
ARE WE LEAVING?
MRS. ALLWORTHY.
THE NEXT TIDE.
MRS. ALLWORTHY!
I HAVE TO GET MY GIRL.
I'VE GOT TO GET MY BABY!
YOU AIN'T GOIN' NOWHERE!
I CAN'T LEAVE
WITHOUT MY BABY!
I'LL FETCH HER, MOLL.
THERE'S TIME.
I'LL FETCH HER.
ALL RIGHT?
WHAT HAVE YOU.
ON STEPNEY LANE,
WHERE YOU FOUND ME.
SECOND FLOOR.
SEE MRS. O'MALLEY.
MRS. O'MALLEY.
I'LL FIND HER.
OY, BLACKIE,
GOT ANY NEWS FROM THE DEVIL?
OW! UGH.
SENT YOU THAT.
HOW'D YOU LIKE IT?
UGH.
THERE WAS A--
THERE WAS A FIRE
ON STEPNEY LANE.
I'VE GOT TO GO!
NO. NO. NO!
THEY SAID THEY GOT
AS MANY OUT AS THEY COULD.
BUT GOD HELP ME,
I LOOKED.
I COULDN'T FIND THEM.
NO! NO!!!
I'VE FAILED YOU, MOLL.
Allworthy:
HOLD HER.
HOLD HER, HIBBLE.
IT'S HER BABY, MA'AM!
ONE LESS MOUTH.
FOR GOD'S SAKE!
I SAID HOLD HER,
HIBBLE.
( screaming )
LET ME GO!!!
NOW GET HER ON THAT SHIP...
OR I'LL SEE YOU HANGED
ALONGSIDE HER.
NO! NO!!!!
( sobbing )
"A TORMENT.
"A PAIN SO DEEP
IT CUT THROUGH MY SOUL.
"I HAD SWORN
IF I EVER HAD A CHILD,
"THE DEVIL HIMSELF COULDN'T
PULL IT FROM MY BREAST.
THEN I KNEW DEEP IN ME
THAT MY CHILD HAD LIVED."
DAMN THAT WOMAN!
THERE'S NO BALANCE TO LIFE.
WE'RE THE MEEK.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO
INHERIT THE EARTH.
IT'S A TERRIBLE THING, MOLL...
BUT I STILL CARE FOR
THE WRETCHED WOMAN.
Woman:
MRS. ALLWORTHY!
THE SHIP!
IT'S THE SHIP!
THERE!
WELCOME HOME,
MR. HIBBLE.
THANK YOU.
MY MISTRESS
WELCOMES YOU.
SHE WANTS TO SEE YOU ALONE,
MR. HIBBLE.
I SHAN'T BE LONG.
THIS WAY, MA'AM.
MADE A GOOD IMPRESSION
ON THE MISSUS, YOU DID.
SHE COULD HARDLY TELL.
I SPOKE WELL OF YOU.
SHE BIDS YOU
COMPLETE YOUR TASK.
THERE'S ONLY
A FEW MORE PAGES.
WHAT DOES THIS WOMAN
WANT OF ME?
NOTHING.
EVERYTHING.
"EVERY NIGHT
WE CROSSED THE ATLANTIC,
"I DREAMED OF MY CHILD.
"I HAD TO BELIEVE
I HAD SOMETHING TO LIVE FOR.
EXCUSE ME, LOVE.
"WITH HIBBLE'S HELP, I OBTAINED
A SPARE PURSER'S LOG
"AND I WORKED ON THIS MEMOIR
TO TALK TO MY CHILD.
( thunder crashing )
Sailor:
THE MIZZENMAST!
TIE EVERYTHING DOWN!
QUICK, BEFORE WE LOSE HER!
GIVE ME A HAND HERE, WILL YA?
Captain: JACK TO THE ACE.
DIAMONDS ARE TRUMPS.
ACE TO BET.
ACE BETS.
OH, GOD ALMIGHTY.
THAT'S ROUGH.
HERE.
WHAT?
THERE! ROCKS!
CAPTAIN JARVIS,
ARE ALL MEN ON DECK?
Allworthy: WHAT'S GOING ON?
Sailor: COME ON! COME ON!
( shouting )
OH, GOD!
AAAH!
WE'RE GOING DOWN.
WE'RE DOING DOWN!
WE'RE TAKING HEAVY WATER!
I'M GONNA DROWN!
I CAN'T SWIM!
PUT IT ON ME!
TOO HEAVY!
YOU'LL DROWN!
YOU'RE YOUNG,
YOU'RE STRONG!
MA'AM, COME ON!
PUT IT ON!
COME ON!
HIBBLE, MY BOOK!
I'LL GET IT!
WHERE IS IT?
BY THE TRUNK!
GO! HURRY!
( shouting )
I CAN'T SWIM!
AAAAH!
WATER'S COMING IN!
AAAH!
( coughing )
MOLL! COME HERE, GIRL!
TOO HEAVY!
HELP ME!
HELP ME, MOLL!
I CAN'T SWIM!
HELP ME, PLEASE!
NOT THIS HAND
NOR THIS BODY!
CALL THIS MURDER,
BUT NEVER AGAIN!
DAMN YOU TO HELL!
NEVER AGAIN!!!
Hibble: MOLL!
HIBBLE!
MOLL!
MOLL! WHERE ARE YOU?!
Hibble:
THE NAME OF MOLL FLANDERS
WAS LOST FOREVER BENEATH
THE WATERS OF THAT STORM.
I LEARNED ABOUT
THE COURAGE OF LIVING
FROM YOUR MOTHER.
BUT IT NEVER SET WELL
IN MY BODY.
IT WAS ON A BEACH
VERY MUCH LIKE THAT ONE
THAT I LEARNED
THE TRUTH OF MYSELF,
BECAUSE THE LORD SPARED
ONLY ONE OTHER FROM THAT SHIP.
I THINK IT WAS TO TEST ME.
NO MORE STORIES.
NO MORE BLEEDIN' LESSONS!
FLORA, YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND!
FLORA!
FLORA, PLEASE!
( gasps )
I HATE YOU!
I HATE ALL OF YOU!
SHE'S STILL IN HERE!
MINE UNTIL I DIE!
FLORA?
FOR NINE YEARS, FLORA,
I KINDLED A SPARK OF HOPE,
THE TINIEST CANDLE FLAME
KEEPING YOUR MOTHER
FROM THE DARK.
AS MRS. ALLWORTHY,
SHE HAS EVERYTHING
A PHYSICAL BODY COULD NEED.
EXCEPT HER SOUL.
NOW IT'S A MATTER OF TRUST.
NOW YOU KNOW ENOUGH
OF OUR DECEPTIONS
TO HANG US BOTH.
I WANTED YOU
TO HEAR MY STORY.
I WANTED NOTHING
BUT THE TRUTH
BETWEEN US.
I NEVER KNEW
MY OWN MOTHER.
NEVER FELT HER,
OR SMELLED HER HAIR.
I SWORE THAT TERRIBLE FATE
WOULD NOT BEFALL MY BABY.
BUT I FAILED YOU.
AND DESPITE MY...
...DEEPEST FEAR
THAT MY OWN FLESH AND BLOOD
MIGHT REJECT ME...
WE HAVE ENOUGH TO SEND YOU
ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
THE CHOICE IS YOURS,
FLORA.
DO WITH THE TRUTH
AS YOU WILL.
OH, MOTHER.
FINDING THIS WAS
EASIER THAN FINDING YOU.
THAT SEEMED LIKE
A LIFETIME.
IT'S YOUR FATHER,
FLORA.
I LOVE HIS SPIRIT
YOU CARRY IN YOU.
"WE DANCED LIKE SPARROWS
AROUND THE FLAME OF EACH OTHER,
"FLUTTERING AND GLIDING ON
THE CURRENTS OF OUR EMOTIONS.
"WE CELEBRATED
IN THE GREAT TRUTH
"THAT I HAD LEARNED
FROM HER FATHER:
"ALL MEN AND WOMEN
ARE CREATED EQUAL.
"WE ARE ONE BEING...
HUMANKIND."
¶
¶ THE WINTER WAS COLD
AND BITTER ¶
¶ IT CHILLED ME TO THE BONE
¶ I HADN'T SEEN THE SUN
FOR WEEKS ¶
¶ TOO LONG,
TOO FAR FROM HOME ¶
¶ I FELT LIKE I WAS SINKING
¶ AND I CLAWED
FOR SOLID GROUND ¶
¶ I WAS PULLED DOWN
BY THE UNDERTOW ¶
¶ I NEVER THOUGHT I
COULD FEEL SO ALONE ¶
¶ OH, DARKNESS,
I FELT LIKE LETTING GO ¶
¶ ALL OUT OF STRENGTH,
ALL OUT OF COURAGE ¶
¶ COME AND LIFT ME
FROM THIS PLACE ¶
¶ I KNOW I CAN LOVE YOU
MUCH BETTER THAN THIS ¶
¶ FULL OF GRACE,
FULL OF GRACE ¶
¶ MY LOVE
¶ IT'S BETTER THIS WAY
¶ I SAID
¶ HAVEN'T SEEN
THIS PLACE BEFORE ¶
¶ WHERE EVERYTHING
WE SAID AND DID ¶
¶ HURT US ALL THE MORE
¶ IT'S JUST THAT WE
STAYED TOO LONG ¶
¶ IN THE SAME OLD SICKLY SKIN
¶ I WAS PULLED DOWN
BY THE UNDERTOW ¶
¶ I NEVER THOUGHT I
COULD FEEL SO ALONE ¶
¶ OH, DARKNESS,
I FELT LIKE LETTING GO ¶
¶ ALL OUT OF THE STRENGTH,
ALL OUT OF THE COURAGE ¶
¶ COME AND LIFT ME
FROM THIS PLACE ¶
¶ I KNOW I CAN LOVE YOU
MUCH BETTER THAN THIS ¶
¶ FULL OF GRACE
¶ I KNOW I CAN LOVE YOU
MUCH BETTER THAN THIS ¶
¶ IT'S BETTER THIS WAY
( music fades out )