Previously on "Damien"...
Help!
I blame you for those deaths,
the evil you felt that night.
It comes from inside of you.
You showed him the shrine?
How did he take it?
He'll be back.
That's three dead by freak accident.
It's a holy trinity.
It's Kelly's notebook.
She must've been working on
some kind of religious story.
We've been thinking
it's time for a change.
Troy will take over.
There are very
mysterious forces at work.
They can't be manipulated.
They operate according to design.
Jesus.
Ugh.
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
This will certainly make me think twice
about wearing my necktie again.
How did you get this?
Ann Rutledge left it in my bathroom.
I thought I warned you about her.
I made a mistake. I dropped my guard.
She used me.
Used you? How?
To kill Troy Hendrie.
Are you saying you're somehow
responsible for his death?
It's complicated.
Son, I know we've lost
touch through the years,
but even I can see you're a mess.
Why? What's troubling you?
You'll think that it's crazy, that...
that I'm crazy.
Nothing surprises me anymore.
What exactly did Ann tell you?
I'm the Antichrist prophesied
in the Book of Revelation.
I'm not making this up.
I know Ann is... challenging,
to say the least,
but this takes batshit crazy
to a whole other level.
Forget about her. I'm worried about you.
You need some help. Please see someone.
Lean on me all you want.
And whatever you do, stay
far away from that woman.
Yo.
Perfect timing.
You went shopping without me?
Got you some fresh batteries.
You know you don't have to
keep checking up on me.
I'm not. I got some news.
Collodion Collective
wants to meet with you.
The photography co-op?
Yeah. I sent them your portfolio.
You know I'm not much of a joiner.
I know, but hear me out.
With editors, right, even Ceci,
we've always been on a leash,
beholden to their corporate interests.
Comes with the territory.
Well, the Collective
is photographer-owned.
It's completely autonomous.
They want your point of view.
If they let you in, you
broaden your reach by a mile.
If they let me in?
Yeah, well, they have to
approve of you in person.
I can't do a dog and pony
show right now, Amani.
Come on, man.
You can use the win right about now.
Detective Shay. From the other night?
I remember. What can I help you with?
I just wanted to come by, check on you,
make sure you're all right.
I'm fine.
Good.
I heard about the thing
in the subway last night.
It's a good thing you weren't killed.
It looks like I should
be asking about you.
Yeah, do you know, there was someone
killed in the subway, though.
Yeah, and he heard about that
after he pulled the kid
off the train tracks.
Saved his life.
Who are you?
A friend.
Do you have a name?
What can I do for you, Detective?
Well, I got a whole bunch of questions
about the, uh, taxicab incident
that you were involved with.
And I have some information
about your assailant.
I thought maybe you could
come down to the station,
we could talk about it.
Shouldn't take too long.
Whatever I can do to help.
I'll catch up with you later.
Sure thing.
You got some big balls,
pulling that kid off
the tracks like that.
I just did what anyone else would've.
Yeah, well...
...most people, they'd like
to think they'd be the hero.
But in that moment of truth,
they're more concerned about
saving their own skin.
It's a shame about that
other guy, though.
What happened?
Well, some guy got his tie
stuck in the escalator.
Couldn't yank it free.
Pulled his face right
into the machinery.
Ripped it wide open.
You want anything? Corn chips?
Twizzlers?
Mm.
Yeah, broke his teeth...
...chewed off his nose...
...severed his carotid artery.
Blood everywhere. It was a mess.
You know...
it was right about that
time you saved that kid.
I saw some of the commotion.
Mm.
How'd you know him?
Who?
Escalator guy.
I didn't know him.
Troy Hendrie. Wall Street player.
Armitage Global. Mm?
I pulled the security tapes
in the subway station.
It was pretty clear
you were chasing him.
I was just running to catch the train.
Oh, yeah? What train?
Where were you going?
I'd really like to help you, but
I just don't know anything.
See, here's what I'm struggling with.
In the last few days, you've
been in very close proximity
to a few, uh... oh, I don't
know, what do I call 'em?
Unexplained deaths?
Four, to be exact.
And that's a shitload of
wrong place, wrong time.
So... why don't you sit down?
We have a lot to talk about.
I'm not going to mince words.
There's a void here today.
We all feel it.
We're all stunned and confused.
In all that confusion,
let's not forget about
what's really important...
Troy, and all that he gave.
Ann? Would you like to say a few words?
Um...
John and I have, um, been
around the block a few times.
We're at that age
where we're losing some
of our dearest friends,
people we've known all our lives.
But so many of you are so young.
I can tell by looking around this room
that this is the first
tragic death you've faced.
I remember when I was told
that my husband and
daughter were killed.
I was... I was 20.
My whole world fell down.
The only thing that got
me through that...
was people reaching out.
That's the only way we get
through times like these.
Compassion heals...
all suffering.
You never fail to surprise me.
We've seen a lot of people
come and go over the years.
Nature of the beast.
Pardon the pun.
But you and I are still here.
Perhaps we'll be the last ones standing.
Damien said you left
this in his apartment.
I had nothing to do with that.
Things are reaching a critical point.
We can't afford to fall
into separate camps.
Perhaps we should get used
to sharing the stage.
What are you proposing?
You've got Damien.
I have everything else in place.
We need to work together,
not against each other.
We need to trust each other.
I couldn't agree more.
Igor Reneus.
You and Kelly Baptiste
paid him a visit. Why?
She was doing research for an article.
Around the same time that she died
in her "accident"...
right outside of your
apartment, I might add...
he was mauled to death
by a pack of wild dogs.
The cab driver who hit Hermon Saroyan?
He swerved to avoid a wild dog.
I don't know what you're
up to or how you do it,
but you're puling some
really freaky shit.
I may to be able to prove it,
but I know you're responsible
for those deaths.
Get up.
Wanna show you somethin'.
So last night, I'm walking
down the hall just like this,
when out of nowhere, a Rottweiler...
must've weighed 90 pounds...
jumps on me, tries to take my arm off.
Ooh. Careful. You don't
wanna walk into that,
get it on your shoes.
Can you believe it?
I was in the E.R. till 3:00 a.m.
22 stitches.
They did say there was no, uh,
permanent nerve damage, though.
The dog was not so lucky.
Well... what the hell?
He was trying to kill me, so...
I blew his head off.
Good thing he didn't go for
my shooter hand, though.
I would've been gone.
Scary thing
about this hallway...
there are no cameras.
Uhh!
Oh, yeah. Come on, try something.
Give me the chance.
Leave me alone.
That professor, your dog
attack, the taxi...
nothing to do with me.
Let me tell you how this plays
out with guys like you,
how we handle it.
Now, I know you're a piece of
shit, but I can't prove it.
So I keep my eyes on you.
Person of interest.
And I keep you here all
night for questioning,
kick you free when you're exhausted,
and then bring you back tomorrow...
and the next night, and all next week.
After a while, you've got a shadow.
Always right over your shoulder.
One night, you're driving.
There's sirens in the mirror. Pull over.
Busted tail light, expired tags. Mm.
I'll find somethin'.
And you're pissed 'cause
I'm crawling up your ass.
Agitated.
And I ask to see your license,
and you reach over to get your wallet.
Boom!
Just... I thought I saw a gun.
I feared for my own life.
But you, no one will miss
an asshole like you.
Trust me...
you don't want to do that.
Are you threatening me?
People who come after me,
they don't fare so well.
You've seen enough to know.
Very weird stuff happens around me.
Not to me. Never to me. To others.
Can't explain it.
You think my wallet's a gun?
Your pistol's likely to
blow up in your face.
So you're the roadrunner,
and I'm the coyote?
Is that what this is?
I'm just a guy living his life,
and you're just a weak-ass cop
with nothing but a handful of piss.
I'm a war photographer, remember?
Mm-hmm.
I've been in the shit.
More than you ever will.
You wanna play the cowboy?
Go ahead, pull your gun.
Yeah.
I didn't think so.
Hey, Sherlock Holmes,
you know who seems to
have all the answers?
Ann Rutledge.
She has a room full of
my childhood possessions
in her house,
behind a secret doorway in a bookcase.
Oh, so she's creating all these
deaths to make you look guilty?
You're the police. You figure it out.
What's he doing here?
The Destroyer!
You let him in?!
He is the one who
follows me in darkness.
He is the serpent!
He needs to stop running.
It's time to confront this head on.
What did you say?
He urges me and tempts me.
He is the lie!
Hey!
Uhh!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
- That's enough!
- Hey! Don't!
Get off!
Get down! Hands behind your back!
Hey! Don't! Don't! Don't! Hey, watch...
Uhh!
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
Get him up here!
The Beast.
Mr. Thorn's work is brilliant.
There's no question about that.
But we do have some concerns
about him professionally.
Is this because he didn't
show up to the interview?
Among other things.
The woman he loves
dies a horrible death,
is literally ripped from his hands,
and you think he should've
made this his priority?
Two days after Kelly dies,
he risks his own life
to save a stranger's kid
from the train tracks,
and you're saying he's
not a reliable guy?
Mr. Golkar...
Damien Thorn is the best
photographer out there,
hands down.
But he's also the most selfless,
courageous guy I've ever met.
And if these aren't the
qualities you want
in your collective,
then good luck to you.
Mr. Golkar, please, wait.
Detective Shay.
Good afternoon, Ms. Rutledge.
Is something wrong? Is Damien...
No, he's fine. Do you,
uh, mind if I come in?
Of course.
Just had a few questions to ask you.
May I offer you some coffee?
No, thank you.
I'm gonna get right to the point.
Mr. Thorn's down at the
police station right now.
We brought him in for questioning
about his possible involvement
in the death of Troy Hendrie.
Mr. Thorn suggested that
you might've known him.
Yes. He worked with me at Armitage.
Hmm.
Ms. Rutledge, are you Mr.
Thorn's attorney?
Yes.
He says you're not.
He says he only met you a week ago,
and he suggested that you
might be stalking him.
He said that?
Well, to be specific, I'm
not his personal attorney.
I represent the Thorn Family Estate.
Hmm.
He said there was a special
room in your house,
with, uh, his personal belongings
from when he was a child?
Now that's ridiculous.
Well, he said this room has access
through a secret doorway in a bookshelf.
It's a panic room.
I never use it.
I never panic.
I suppose I should warn you.
Damien's given to very erratic behavior.
Are you saying that he's a liar?
I'm saying he has trouble distinguishing
between reality and fantasy.
Good meeting?
You have that look.
I think I got their attention.
Who were you pitching? Bob? Carol?
That fat bastard Luigi?
No, it was, uh, Fumika.
Ooh. Fumika... she's tough.
I heard she once knocked out
an intern with a staple gun.
Don't tell her I told you.
I hope you're headed out to celebrate.
Yeah, you know what? I am
heading out to celebrate.
Know any good bars around here?
I've known him his entire life.
Besides handling the legal
affairs of the Thorn Estate,
I'm also executor of his father's will.
Then why would Damien claim to
only have met you last week?
He spent years overseas
in extremely high pressure situations.
That's certainly taken a psychic toll.
Could you be more specific?
The specifics of his mental health...
...are attorney-client privilege.
But you have to understand,
if there's a hell on earth,
Damien's been dead center,
photographing it.
Mm.
Does he own dogs?
I don't think so.
'Cause I was attacked by one last night.
Another man was mauled to
death by a pack of them.
Damien training
dogs to attack people?
You give him too much credit.
I will say he used to, uh,
be prone to fits of rage.
He supposedly knocked his
mother over a balcony
when he was young.
I assumed it was an accident.
But then I was on the board of
one of the school he attended,
and there was an altercation
with another student.
I can't remember his name.
Thorn hurt him?
The poor boy spent
his life in a facility.
So he rang his bell pretty bad?
Charles Powell. That's the name.
I will look into that.
Damien was treated after that.
And I thought he'd
pulled himself together.
But I guess we can only outrun
our demons for so long.
Wouldn't you agree, Detective?
What the hell is this?
He's a very powerful babalawo.
A witch doctor?
The bird in the tub was Kelly.
The bird that broke the
stained glass window
at the funeral, it was Kelly.
She's trying to come back
or she's lost her way.
Either way, she's trying
to tell us something.
He can help her.
Mom, this is not real.
This is an old world superstition.
You can't possibly believe this.
You found a... bird in your bath?
Yes.
Then you are threatened, too.
The spirits will come for you.
What are you gonna do?
This house need to be purified.
Mom.
Oh, my God. Please stop.
No. No! Those are Kelly's things!
Please! No! Oh, no! No!
May the road be open to you.
May nothing evil meet you on the way.
I hate photography.
Taking pictures is for people
who can't remember things
with their own brain.
Kidding.
These are great, really.
I'm not surprised you crushed it today.
So you and this photographer
been working together long?
Uh, two years.
You know, I think we make a-a good team.
You guys have obviously
been through a lot.
You don't even know.
So tell me.
All right. Uh, well, uh,
I was working as a
translator in, uh, Libya
for the Americans, and, um,
Gadaffi loyalists, they just
blitzed through Tripoli,
and they were rounding people up.
And, you know, they put me in a ditch
with a hood over my head.
And the soldiers, they
moved down the line.
Started, uh, shooting
guys I knew one by one.
And, uh, all I could think about w...
was my mother, my sisters.
They'd, uh, never know
what happened to me.
And Damien, he just steps
up out of nowhere.
And I have no idea what he said, but...
...they let me go.
Never really told anyone
that story before.
Why are you telling it now?
I don't know.
Taxi!
Ooh, hoo!
All right, no, I got it. I got this.
- Yo! Wait!
- Oh, he sped up!
Oh, come on! Taxi!
Seriously! Wow. Don't worry, I got it.
This is it for sure.
Oh.
Wow.
You wanna give it a go?
You gotta teach me that trick sometime.
Right.
Bye.
We can't hold you.
You're free to go.
What is this?
Did you see the room?
I'll take it from here.
Everything's going to be all right.
What the hell did she tell you?
You can't let her do this.
You take care.
And don't let me see you again.
Let's get you home.
What did you say to him?
That you've witnessed more than
your fair share of suffering.
Did you tell him the part you've played?
Not exactly the most eloquent
"thank you" I've ever received.
Why would I say thank you?
You say you've been there my whole life,
- watching out for me.
- I have.
You've done a shitty job!
Look at this mess! You want gratitude?
I can't leave my apartment
without shit going down.
Enough death.
You're just looking
for someone to blame.
Oh, you're not the puppet master?
Oh, you sure do play the part well.
The part I play is insignificant.
This stops now. These
killings will stop now.
Even if I have to slit
your throat to make them.
Do it.
Slit my throat.
You know that's what you want.
Desperate men have nothing to lose.
The day will come.
Did you go to Ann Rutledge's home today?
I hear you accused her
of being involved in
that escalator death.
N-Not exactly...
I don't give a rat's ass
what you were doing. Stop it.
Captain, listen, I went
there for a reason.
Damien Thorn, he accused her of...
What's your obsession with this guy?
Is he your type?
Just drop it.
Let's not make this
another Baltimore, okay?
Took you years to climb
out of that pile of shit.
You wanna go right back there?
I don't think so.
Be smart. Leave Thorn alone.
Hey.
Can I come in?
Of course.
Everything all right?
No.
Where did you get this?
Ever since Kelly died,
I've been seeing things.
The church where we held the funeral...
you remember the bird that
flew into the window?
I found another one in my drain.
My mom's Nigerian.
I told her, and she brought
in a Yoruba priest.
He thinks Kelly's trying to talk to us.
That was a scam.
What else could it be?
There's a rational
explanation for all of this.
You know, a bird flew into your window,
and another got caught in your drain.
I don't know how, but it did.
And your fortune-teller
pulled a magic trick.
He might as well have
sawed a lady in half.
I wish things were different.
But trust me, I do.
The things I... and Kelly...
have seen...
brutality, natural
disasters, massacres...
there's always the ones left behind.
Human wreckage.
People suffering so badly,
they can't possibly go on.
They need answers. They're...
Well, their... their pain is... is so...
great, th-there must
be a higher purpose.
There must be a reason.
But, uh...
There is none.
Kelly died.
And a bird is just a bird.
I'm sorry.
I'm...
No...
I am.
You know, I wish you two
had gotten to be together.
She really loved you.
I probably shouldn't be saying that.
No, it's okay.
I know.
You don't think McGarry's
gonna make trouble?
He hates you, you know.
He hates everybody.
That's why he's a cop.
Well, he's right. You should
leave well enough alone.
I got it.
If that suspect has a history
of mental illness...
That only confuses his alibi.
That doesn't explain anything
about all the deaths around him.
It's a statistical cluster...
Don't talk down to me, okay?
You know I can't handle
the Stephen Hawking shit.
Well, I try not to talk down to you.
It's just so hard not to.
Are we getting all healthy now?
Yeah, we're
gonna go with olive oil.
Olive oil. So domestic.
I love this.
- That's it. See that?
- Parsley, yeah.
How many eggs do you want?
Two.
This Thorn guy is a dick.
He walks into my station,
and there's some guy in
there for parking tickets
who suddenly decides he
wants to castrate himself.
And then there's all these
deaths and the dog attack.
I-I just don't get it.
You're not gonna leave
well enough alone, are ya?
I try, but it's just so hard not to.
Jacob! Breakfast!
Babe, come on. It'll get cold.
Jacob!
Jacob! Jacob!
Oh, God, Jacob.
Patrick! Patrick!
Jacob?
I'm here. I got him. I got him.
All right, Jacob. Jacob.
- Oh, Jacob.
- Honey, come on. Jacob, wake up.
He's not breathing. He's not breathing.
Move out of the way. Move
out of the way. 1, 2...
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Jacob. Come on.
Ah! There he goes! It's okay. It's okay.
- Okay.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Okay, get him in there.
I got him. We need an ambulance.
- You got him?
- Yeah.
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -