In 1942, most of Western Europe ...
had fallen under the onslaught of the German army.
But in the east, the Soviet Union
resists the invasion of Nazi forces.
Throughout the Eastern Front is a desperate
struggle for every inch of land.
Both sides suffer heavy losses.
And neither party will be satisfied
for anything less than victory.
Victory at any cost!
FIRST SQUADRON:
MOMENT OF TRUTH
Attack!
That girl is obviously mentally ill.
Don't exaggerate.
She is an orphan, a victim of war.
Smile!
It is for the party newspaper.
And now, our next attraction ...
I'm not afraid to say ...
an amazing girl wonder.  Let's
give her a round of applause!
She can answer any question.
Ask her anything, even your
innermost secrets.
Come on, just ask.  Don't be shy.
What's my name?
Dimitry Sonin.
It's true, folks!  Well done.
And you are private Panteleyev, from Tula.
Your nickname in school was "Mozart".
That's true, he told me so.
Okay, everyone, let's find out when
the offensive is starting.
What's my name?
When will I receive a letter from home?
Who stole my knife?
Will Lyuba marry me?
I just wanted to ask ...
How long do I have to live?
Nadya, time to wrap up ...
We're ...
Airstrike!
Happy birthday, little Nadya.
Stealing apples is not okay.
Yes, sorry ...
I'm Leo, what's your name?
Nadya.
This is the Friendship of Nations
fountain.
Nadya, this ...
is for you.
How cute!
Thanks!
Marat, let's race!
I cannot go any faster with this thing.
Lieutenant Valya destroyed
another enemy bomber!
Don't worry, you'll learn it too.
Everyone at the boarding
school can do this.
Explosive substances can
also be mixed using ...
It is your duty to be fearless ...
determined, calm
in any situation ...
maintain a common bond,
and, most importantly ...
abide by the principles
of the 6th Division.
Quick, hide there and don't come
out until I return!
I'll get the guys and come back.
Don't worry, and do not move from here.
No matter what happens.
We have them, let's go.
Run for the exit!  It's
too soon for you to die!
Leo, I don't understand ...
You are trapped between life
and death, but you must survive.
Run!
At last, we meet again ...
Gentlemen ...
leaders of the Reich are concerned about
the state of affairs on the Eastern Front.
All offensives on the Eastern Front
during the winter campaign have failed.
The army proved unable to
break the Russian lines.
To win this war, we must
take drastic measures!
What do you suggest?
It is time to start
Operation Sword of Vengeance.
Astrologers have confirmed that
the Moment of Truth is approaching.
But Director, for such a ritual we
would would need an artifact ...
with a great energy potential.
And finally, we have one!
Gentlemen, behold the legendary sword
of Grandmaster Baron von Wolff.
With it, we shall summon the
baron's ghost to join our cause!
That is my sword!
Give it back to me!
Grand Master, we Elders
of the Ahnenerbe ...
call upon you and your fallen brothers.
Rise from the dead,
and with this sword ...
take revenge on your sworn
enemies -- the Russians.
I've waited 700 years,
dreaming of revenge!
At last, my sword returns to my hands.
I accept your offer!
Come, Nadya.
That knight ... I have dreamt about him.
I had this nightmare, over and over.
This dream is the last thing I remember.
He was a legendary warrior and sorcerer,
known as Baron von Wolff.
Baron and the knights of his Order were
excommunicated for practicing black magic.
In 1242, he set out to conquer Russia.
Von Wolff's crusaders burned villages ...
and slaughtered their inhabitants.
Many believed he was served
by demons of the underworld.
But finally, people of many villages
united to resist the Order ...
and managed to defeat Von Wolff in a conflict
referred to as the "Battle on the Ice".
The knights of the Order perished
at the bottom of the lake.
A prophecy says that 700 years
after his death ...
the Baron's ghost will return to life.
And this is the year, 1942, which will mark ...
when those 700 years will have elapsed.
But why have I been dreaming about this?
Nadya, those aren't just dreams.
They are visions.
You must use your gift to avert disaster.
You have the gift of premonition.
But I don't even know who I am,
or where I am ...
Now eat.
You have a long journey ahead of you.
I have nowhere to go.
I don't remember where I live.
We will go to Moscow together,
to the Kremlin ...
I'll take you where ...
your help is needed most.
Nadya, go to Moscow ...
find General Belov in the Kremlin,
he will explain everything.
And you?
Don't worry about me, just go!
Go away!
Please, allow me to enter.
I really need to get in.
Where is the General Belov?
Please, I must see
General Belov immediately.
You know, little girl, if you
behave violently again ...
we'll be forced to sedate you.
I cannot let you see General Belov ...
because no such person exists.
He is a figment of your imagination,
a side effect of the contusion.
Oh, contusion?  I see, but ...
Lies!  You don't know anything!
Let me out, now!
We do they accept these lunatics?  We
are full with the wounded as we are.
Who are you?
You don't know who I am?
I am your commander, General Belov.
We have been searching all over for you.
What happened?
Sorry, but I do not remember anything.
I spoke with the doctors.
A blow to your head has
damaged your memory.
Do you remember anything at all?
A circus ...
friends, summer ...
boarding school ... then the war began ...
my friends were killed ...
That was over six months ago, many
things have happened since.
We don't have much time.
I'll tell you everything you need to know.
World War II is under way.
Nazi Germany attacked our country.
Parallel to regular military operations ...
two occult secret service agencies are
engaged in a covert struggle.
The German "Ahnenerbe" within the SS ...
against the 6th Division of the Soviet
Military Intelligence -- that's us.
We are not a regular intelligence
division though.
We use the tools of occult and magic:
astrology, clairvoyance, and hypnosis.
I am the director of the 6th Division.
And you, you are my best agent.
Since the beginning of the war, you have
completed numerous important missions.
A week ago, we sent you to the frontline on
an assignment, as a member of a propaganda team.
That's where you vanished.
Your parents both had extrasensory abilities.
Ever since they died ...
the 6th Division has been your family.
They died?  How, when?
Before the war, while performing their duty.
We have an tremendous workload now ...
we need you more than ever!
Much depends on the counter-operation
we are currently planning.
The Astro-radar shows enormous
activity in the Beyond.
We have intelligence that the
Ahnenerbe have found a powerful ally.
If it's Baron von Wolff and his knights,
we have a real problem on our hands.
Does that look familiar?
I saw him in my dreams.  He will come soon.
Yes, very soon.
The old prophecy is being fulfilled.
And that means that within hours ...
The spirits of Von Wolff and his warriors ...
will fall upon our positions.
Obviously, the ghosts and demons
are not afraid of our weapons.
The living cannot even see them.
But how can I help?
You're the only one who can.  I'll explain.
For years, the 6th Division has been developing
a special task force of teen agents ...
The First Squadron.
It was terminated at the beginning
of the war by the Ahnenerbe.
Leo
Zena
Marat
Valya
They were all killed ...
You're the only survivor
of the First Squadron.
Training at our school was designed to create
a spiritual bond between the Squadron members.
That's why you can just call upon the
spirits of your fallen comrades ...
and with them, stop Von Wolff's assault.
The time has come for you
to meet them again!
But how?
You said the Pioneers were killed, weren't they?
Exactly.
I want you to go to the other side.
The 6th Division has created a
special machine ...
called Sputnik Alpha.
This is our only chance.
Will you do it?
I'll try ...
Your locker is marked with the letter "N".
There you will find everything
you need for the assignment.
The machine travels to the Beyond
through the pilot's subconscious ...
so you will land in a familiar place.
Your sword is a rare and powerful
weapon against the supernatural.
Don't hesitate to use it.  You're an expert
with it.  You have very little time, so hurry.
Most importantly ...
do not miss the red return signal.
If you miss it, you'll be stuck there forever.
Come back alive.
Let's go!
Hello?  Is there anybody there?
Seventy-seventh, Seventy-seventh,
cease fire, over.
Brothers!
When the enemy stole our
victory by deceit ...
and lake ice broke under our feet ...
they thought we had been vanquished forever.
They were wrong!
We haven't spent 700 years
in limbo in vain!
A new Moment of Truth is coming ...
and this time, we will be victorious!
We will destroy the destinies of the living!
What?
She's alive!
There's no place for the living here.
Okay, take her to the butcher!
Time waits for no man.
We're moving out!
The evil spirits left the man ...
and entered the pigs ...
and the herd ran down a sharp
slope, into the water ...
and found their destruction.
The Gospel of Luke ...
What is this?
Ready to roll?
On cue, as always ...
Listen, how did you get here?
Are you dead?
Didn't I warn you ...
No, I'm alive.
General Belov sent me.
They have a machine that can
send people over here.
Are they crazy there,
at the 6th Division?!
No one returns alive from this place.
Now they do.
How did you find me?
We all sensed you.
Remember the mental frequency
synchronization exercises at school?
We may be dead, but we still know
everything we learned while alive.
Below.
So frightening, so gloomy ...
And yet, so beautiful.
What a strange place.
Yeah, not the best place for an school reunion.
That is the Valley of the Shadows ...
where the spirits of fallen
warriors go after death.
They say there are other lands beyond those
mountains, but no one knows for sure.
There is no way out of the
Valley of the Shadows.
So, why are you here?
After waiting 700 years, Von Wolff is about ...
to break the threshold between the worlds.
He reached an agreement with the Ahnenerbe ...
and will fight on their side.
Unbelievable.
The threshold has not been broken for centuries!
The dead versus the living ...
The living have no chance ...
Von Wolff has become an extremely
powerful demon over the years.
His hatred has great destructive power.
Once the Nazis can control that power,
they'll rule the world of the living.
I've come for you.
We must stop Von Wolff.
I can't do it on my own!
Nadya, don't you get it?
We were killed, we are out of the game.
We can not return.
It's forbidden ...
If you don't intervene, millions
of people will die!
The world of the living and the world of
the dead will become one!
That will be ...
the apocalypse.
Listen, you were killed
and I kept living.
But I come asking you to help us,
the living, win this ruthless war.
Let everyone decide for themselves ...
I, for one, am ready.
It is my war, too.
I can't just sit and watch
as things get worse there.
So, guys, hark back to the
old days of yore.
We weren't killed in vain.
Well, Nadya, how typical ...
don't you just love being the
center of attention.
Okay, I'm in.  I don't want to miss
an opportunity to kick some Nazi ass.
And what about me?
I'm with you guys!
I knew you'd agree.
First Squadron is back together,
just like old times.
Comrade General, Sputnik is overheating.
Let's bring her back!
What is this?
What's going on, Nadya?
The signal!
We must hurry to the Ferris wheel!
What's taking her so long?
We're going to lose her.
Nadya ...
Come on, girl!
Come back here when the
amusement park runs again.
That will be the signal to cross.
We'll be there.
See you on the other side!
You had me worried sick.
Congratulations -- you're the first human ever
to return alive from the world of the dead.
Now, tell me what happened.
Did you see them?
Von Wolff is ready to cross.
But the First Squadron will fight!
I have a surprise for you.
Oh, hello.
You see, like I said, I'm safe and sound.
It was a close call, but ...
actually, those two were after you.
Back to business ...
700 years after his death ...
Von Wolff will cross into our
world at the Moment of Truth ...
but we don't know precisely
when and where it will happen.
The Moment of Truth!
That's what Von Wolff told his knights.
What does it mean?
Moments of Truth are the most critical ...
decisive moments, when
actions of one man ...
determine the outcome of a
battle or an entire war.
Moments of Truth are instants ...
imperceptible to mortals, when
creatures from the other world ...
may enter our world and interfere
with the natural course of time.
Moments of Truth always have and
always will exist in history ...
but only those with a rare gift
can foresee and endure them.
And you, Nadya, have that gift.
Herr Obergruppenfuhrer.
Here come our beauties!
Any good news?
The girl was spotted on the Eastern Front ...
a clairvoyant, working for Soviet intelligence.
Despite our efforts,
we failed to eliminate her.
Could you, please, get rid of this
6th Division clairvoyant?
It must be done before the Moment of Truth.
Tomorrow morning you should be in Moscow.
You are dismissed.
Yes, sir!
Retire.
This is what we know ...
a large number of troops are concentrated
on both sides of the lake shore.
Each side has tried to attack
but every attempt has failed.
It is around here that the
Moment of Truth will occur.
The commander in your dream is the only one
who will dare to rise from the trenches ...
and lead the soldiers in in the attack.
At the Moment of Truth, Von Wolff
will try to behead him.
Should our attack not take place ...
the Germans will launch a counter-
offensive and break our frontline.
Try again, maybe you will see his
face, or perhaps his platoon ...
I'm trying ...
I can not see.
You're too tired.
You just need to rest.
A driver will take you to the barracks.
Get some sleep, recuperate, and it will work ...
I know you.
You were a circus performer.
I drove you once, before the war.
I also remember your parents.
They were wonderful people ...
May they rest in peace ...
Please, tell me about my parents.
I hardly remember them.
You don't remember?
But only a year has passed since  ...
" CAPTAIN ALEXANDER NEMOV, THE
SOLE SURVIVOR OF HIS SUBDIVISION ...
HAS BEEN TREATED AT A NEARBY HOSPITAL
FOLLOWING A MASSIVE ENEMY AIR RAID ...
NOW HOPES TO RETURN TO THE FRONT
LINES OF COMBAT TO FIGHT THE ENEMY "
The sole survivor!
This is the subject of the Moment of Truth!
I found him.
It's me, I found him.
Captain Alexander Nemov.
Yes.
I need the exact location of his regiment.
No, I'm fine, but the driver was killed.
Someone is following me.
I understand.  I will call
you from the station.
Can I get over there before the fork?
Soldiers retreating from their positions
without an order are traitors.
Cowards and deserters will
be executed on the spot.
The enemy will be defeated!  We shall prevail!
Here we go.
I hope he's there ...
Go away, we're closed!
What do you want?
Can't you read ...
What are you doing?
Everybody wants something from the Hunchback ...
I've told you I have nothing to sell!
Listen, Hunchback, we have no time.
How about a trade?
6th Division of the Russian Military Intelligence.
A rarity.
Okay.
Damn!
Wow!
That's more like it!
The latest models on the market.
Russia, Germany, Japan.
All calibrated and in perfect working condition.
Let me check.
Was that necessary?
I hope this works.
Really?   Here?
This is the only pavilion with lights on.
This will be the gateway to Nadya's subconscious.
Come on.
Get in, she's calling uss.
This tunnel should lead us
to the world of the living.
Stealing apples is not okay.
It's accelerating!
Hurry up, faster.
They didn't come.
Knights ...
you are all part of the
most glorious of battles.
Your names will remain anonymous ...
but your deads will live for eternity!
Here goes ...
It's starting ...
Some like it hot, huh!
Not a moment too soon.
Leo!
Nadya!!
Welcome to the Valley of the Shadows.
Nadya!
What just happened?
Did Nadya just whack Von Wolff?
Bon voyage, weirdos!
Attack!
Fire!
Speaking!
Prepare an airplane now.
I will pick Nadya up in person.
That's not him!
He escaped ...