Episode 15
Da Mi's heart seems to have been hurt.
What happened?
She thinks that I abandoned her.
Isn't that the truth?
I thought that you abandoned me.
No matter how angry I was or
how much I wanted to break up,
even if I had made it seem as though
I never wanted to see you again,
if you really had the intention to come back to me,
you would have been able to break it off over there.
Was that what you had hoped for?
I thought I had done what you wanted.
When a woman who views her husband as her everything,
finds out that he has another wife,
what else is there to say?
Then, I was thirty.
You were thirty-two.
It seems like it was very hard for you
and I to understand one another.
What thoughts do you have about Da Mi?
I want to do everything I can for her.
As long as you allow it.
It'd be good if you took her to Japan too.
If she wants to make up her mind to study,
it might be hard for her because there
are so many people here that she knows.
Although she says she'll no longer be an actress,
but for now the things mentioned on
the Internet will not settle down.
I think that the best choice is to
put her in a different setting.
Her Japanese is already pretty good.
What do you think?
Would you be okay without Da Mi?
I'll be fine. It won't be a problem.
I have to work.
And I'm going to get married.
Da Mi.
What's going on with my daughter? Let Mom see.
Did Dad make you sad?
Then why are you sad?
Why are you crying?
Like a silly fool.
Mom.
What's wrong?
It's about Dad's home in Japan.
Yes.
It's like the home we used to have.
Mom, Dad, and me.
The home with the three of us together.
Dad looks very happy in that home.
I had thought that Dad would be missing Mom and me.
Living very depressed everyday.
I thought that he'd be living with
an ahjumma that he didn't like.
Imagining Dad like this, I was able to forget my own
feelings of loneliness from those twelve years.
Dad loves that ahjumma.
Mom knows that, right?
Da Mi.
Hmm?
Even though your dad and I separated in that way,
I never wanted your father to have an unhappy marriage.
Dad was definitely a good husband and will be a great father.
No matter where he is at, he will sincerely do his best in everything.
That's the type of person he is.
Mom, be honest.
You really don't care?
I feel really awful.
I understand how you feel.
At your age, of course it will be hard.
But...
Because your father is that type of person,
that's why I loved him.
Dad…
Don't say anymore, Mom. Forget about it.
Da Mi.
No matter where he is at, he will sincerely do his best in everything.
In these past twelve years, I never even got to see his face.
That was because Mom didn't let him come.
If he really wanted to see me,
he would have come no matter what, right?
Mom, are you inside?
Oh, Mom's washing her face.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
You didn't have much to eat, so then why would it hurt?
They say if you eat knowing you're going to get
indigestion, it'll be worse. Don't worry about it.
Is it because you feel uneasy having seen Dad?
No.
Da Mi.
Hmm?
You think Mom hates Dad, don't you?
It's Dad's fault, isn't it?
It is.
Mom doesn't want to understand him either.
What does that mean?
Because I was hurt too deeply,
I don't want to understand your dad, or forgive your dad.
Dad isn't a bad man.
He's just not a person who is able to guard himself.
Gentleness and weakness does not matter.
Let's go, Mom.
I want to go home and rest.
You've gotten skinnier, my child.
Are you living in a dark corner?
How my heart aches for you.
What?
In all of South Korea, only Mom feels sorry for me.
Mom... Mom...
Mom...
I want to live, Ji Sup.
I don't want to die.
A month is okay. A week is fine.
Let me live a bit longer.
Okay. You've got the right idea.
Right now, the treatment at the hospital is also effective.
If you stay at the hospital and accept
treatment it will be easier for you.
So first, stay at the hospital.
I understand.
There are a lot of people in this hospital who recognize you.
Nearby there is a newly-constructed hospital.
My friend is the director. His medical skills are very good.
Please.
Kang Ae.
I've seen patients who have gotten better on their own.
A person's health is uncertain.
It's impossible to explain too clearly our modern-day technology.
Don't lose your courage.
Also, although I've already told you this, but you need
to remember not to allow yourself too much stress.
Stress is the worst thing to have right now.
- Where's Da Mi?
- She just got a phone call and left.
It's an interesting skill.
I have something I'd like to discuss with you.
Go ahead.
Because my child's mother is getting remarried,
I want to bring my child over here to study.
Have you already agreed on it with the child's mother?
Yes.
After you broke up, didn't you still pay child support?
But a child that has already been raised
up is now going to be handed over to you?
It might be in consideration of the child's future.
Even if I allowed it, would she come with you?
Because of this issue, I want to go back one more time.
Give me some time to think about it.
Seeing each other after twelve years,
I like her.
Sakae.
Can you forgive me one more time?
Is it something concerning the other place?
About Miss Da Mi?
I'd like to bring Da Mi over here to study.
If it's something like that, please don't talk to me about it.
Don't make Yuka and Aki upset.
Don't let anyone know.
Just take care of it quietly on your own.
If you have confidence, then do as you please.
Sakae...
Ahjumma, Da Mi is back.
Where did you go?
To the company. I have to go back again at noon.
The company? Why?
I'm going to start working soon,
haven't I been on break for too long?
Didn't you say it was over?
Didn't you say you weren't going
to be an actress any longer?
How did Mom know?
I saw Chairman Ha's mother.
Mother?
She came looking for me.
But why are you all of the sudden
saying you're going to work again?
The company is running into some hard times.
Da Mi.
This is the last time.
Afterwards I'll go to school.
Once you start, it'll be another few months.
Mom can't wait that long.
Why not?
Just this once.
I'll promise you, okay?
Whatever you've gotten from that company,
you've already returned more than enough.
There's no need to continue, Da Mi.
Mom.
Go to Japan.
You can't just stay here. You can't.
Go to Japan with your father.
Go study.
Dad will take care of you.
Why are you suddenly like this?
I won't easily let you end up like this.
I'll make you go to school.
Do you really want to send me away?
Yes.
Don't waste any more time.
Come and pick up the child.
What does Da Mi think?
She won't be that obedient.
But in the end, she will understand.
Don't let her think that she's being
kicked out because I'm getting married.
I trust that you'll take good care of Da Mi.
Please.
Are you listening?
I'm listening.
Hearing the word "Please" from you,
My heart aches.
Thank you for entrusting her to me.
Are you ready?
I've gotten the results of our hospital check-up.
I didn't check up on anything useless.
The liver, white blood cells, and bone marrow have all checked out fine.
So tomorrow we will begin treatment.
I can be better, can't I?
Think about when you and Da Mi's father broke up.
At that time, Jeong Seon called me long distance.
She told me to pick you up when you came back to the country.
She said she was very worried about you.
When I saw you in the airport, my heart ached.
Didn't you make it through all of that?
The Lee Kang Ae that I know isn't a weak person.
That's true. You're right. I'll get through it.
In the next five days, everyday you'll have to get three types of shots.
When you get them, it might hurt a lot.
A week after they're done, it'll be a lot better.
Because the medicinal properties are too strong,
every day the shot will be in the same place.
Even so, you have to endure it.
Oppa.
That's right.
Don't you believe me?
Hear me out!
Why do you only think of yourself?
It's really hard to understand!
She's still not back?
Go warm up the house.
Good, you've done well.
Oh, at the airport.
Da Mi, you've worked hard!
- Yes, you've worked hard!
- You've worked hard, see you tomorrow!
Yoo Da Mi ssi.
Yes?
Appearing now is good.
Our company raised you.
Don't think of having a change of heart.
In the future, you should concentrate...
And hand over the position...
as Chairman, right, Mother?
That's the way it should be!
Let's talk about it when we get home.
Please just don't interfere anymore.
Up until now, hasn't Hyung done a great job?
You stubborn rascal, what do you know?
Just because of your brother, the company almost collapsed!
Can you promise that in the future something like this won't happen?
Mom.
My being like this is all for you!
Don't you know?
Throw aside all of that useless greed!
I'm really ashamed of Mom.
What is there to be ashamed about?
Have I gambled or have I stolen someone else's money?
Don't say anymore. Hurry on home.
Hurry and go.
This child…
Hyung.
I'll take him home.
You go ahead.
Don't let him drink, have him home early.
Aigoo, you stubborn rascal.
Let's go. Let's go eat.
I understand your feelings.
I understand your feelings toward me.
It's okay.
The first time I saw you, it was when you were seven, right?
Then, I was in my first year of middle school.
Before you appeared I always felt so tired.
My father was busy all of the time,
My mother was sick all the time.
Because I always ate alone,
I felt very lonely.
Hyung.
When Mom ridicules me, do you think
I always just endure it patiently?
It's hard to always be patient.
But when I remember that I have only one
younger brother, I wouldn't feel bad anymore.
I can endure it.
Mom, aunt, uncle and the others, they always tell me,
that I'm a guy who wouldn't bleed a
drop even when pierced by a needle.
That might actually be true.
But when I saw my brother hurting, I would hurt too.
Oppa.
Come inside.
If you're like this, then the Chairman will feel even worse.
Oppa.
Traveling?
Hey Da Mi, did you know that Mom went traveling?
Earlier this morning, she didn't say anything.
She must've wanted to go all of a sudden.
Well anyway, artists are always like that.
Then I won't say anything, Da Mi.
Sin Ae has set a date.
Omo, really?
Yeah, she said she's going to marry him
no matter what. What else could be done?
Congratulations, ahjumma.
I don't know if I was right or wrong.
After that stubborn girl heard it, she ran out of the
house so happy like a little dog. She's still not back either.
Then when is my mother getting married?
Yeah.
- I heard that they've already started building the house.
- The house?
Ajussi says that he's going to build a
beautiful house and bring your mom over there.
- You go too!
- What?
Get married!
- You get so happy just at the mention of marriage.
- Oh, that's not it, Ahjumma.
What? You're even blushing!
What are you talking about, Ahjumma?
Look, look!
Aigoo, aigoo!
My beloved Da Mi,
Mom has begun to accept treatment.
Yes?
Are you sleeping well?
Yes.
Are you going to work?
Yes. I'll stay ten minutes here and then go.
Don't worry about it.
I'm not worrying.
Is your mood a bit better?
Mmhmm.
Think about it, Ji Sup.
I don't think that my life isn't good.
Aren't there many people who, though
they have the ability and the strength,
have never experienced success even once?
Whenever one of my pieces is a success,
I'll feel both guilty and thankful.
I'll be fine.
Yes, that's the way to think.
Coming from Ma Pu to here isn't a complete waste.
It was all because of your hard work and luck.
You aren't a weak person either.
Try with all your effort.
A medical professor in New York wrote a book..
Your sickness can be healed based on your personal mood and feelings.
The patient's attitude and mood is very important.
You have to keep believing that you'll get better, believe that you'll be healed.
I will.
I've seen Keon Hee Hyung.
He seems to be working very hard.
I was thinking about whether or not to tell him the truth.
If we tell him the truth...
It'll be even harder for him.
I know too...
That he is a compassionate kind-hearted man.
He won't just let me alone.
But there's no way to keep on until the end.
I don't want to let him know that I might be dying from sickness.
I don't want to get his comfort before I die either.
I only want to let him remember when I was good.
Kang Ae.
I don't know what my Da Mi is doing.
Since there's also a branch of the company here, I'll come often.
Did you come here because Mom asked you to?
You already know?
If that's the reason then your trip was a waste.
Although Mom brought it up first,
I don't think that Mom asked as a favor.
I think that this is Mom's consent.
I know you resent me.
I need time to be with you.
How about Yuka?
Is she doing well?
It's a letter from Yuka.
Dear Da Mi Unni,
Right now Yuka is very studiously learning Korean,
Next time when I see Unni, I will loudly shout
"Da Mi Unni!"
At that time, please embrace Yuka in your heart.
During this time I didn't know the truth, I'm sorry.
See you next time!
Yuka.
Did Dad tell her?
No.
Yuka found out on her own.
Is Dad always a person to be carried away by circumstances?
Because of Grandpa, because of Mom, because of Yuka.
What type of person is Dad, really?
I love you, Da Mi.
I will resolve my own problems.
Are you going back to the film set?
I have an appointment to meet someone.
Let's go, Dad will take you.
It's close by.
It's really cold, hurry back.
It's okay, it's okay.
It'll be okay. It'll be okay.
I heard that you threw up, didn't you?
Yes.
Try taking it again after you have calmed down.
If that still doesn't work, we'll change the medication.
Do you have any other symptoms?
My mouth is dry, and it's a bit hard to breathe.
When will radiation begin?
It has to follow a sequence.
Did the results of the blood tests come out yet?
Not yet.
We will decide after the results come out.
Well then…
Lee Kang Ae ssi, here is your medicine.
Hello?
Mom?
Yes, it's Mom.
Where are you, Mom?
Oh, by the ocean.
How wonderful!
What did you do today?
I watched the sea, and ate yummy stuff.
I slept a long time.
And also walked around a lot.
Can you see the ocean from your room?
Oh, yeah, I can see it.
Mom, rest comfortably there for a while. You don't have to worry about me.
And also, I had lunch with Dad today.
Really?
What did Dad say?
Mom, Yeo Jin is at our house right now.
Let's talk about it next time.
Okay, I got it.
Be happy.
You too, Mom.
Did you hang up so quickly because of me?
Talk some more.
Hmm, what is Sin Beom Oppa doing?
If you're curious then go see.
Where are you going?
To wash up.
Yeo Jin.
I'm going to do that commercial that I mentioned last time.
Didn't you say you weren't doing that?
I want to earn money.
Why'd you take away even the IV tube?
Just now they even took off the IV tube.
Kang Ae.
What? I'm fine.
I can take it.
The results of the blood test indicate
that the level of the white blood cells have greatly decreased.
You can't continue to accept treatment.
Having less white blood cells means a weak immune system.
The immunity towards terminal illnesses is also weaker.
So we have to stop.
Then, if it goes back to normal, will I continue accepting treatment?
We'll see.
Give me some hot water.
Okay.
Besides hospital treatment, there are still many other ways.
Don't give up here.
Then tell everyone, okay?
Tell Jeong Seon, tell Da Mi, tell everyone.
Then accept help.
Eat whatever is said to help.
If there are any good methods then look for them.
That's why...
That's why I said there were people who got better.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Taking it by yourself, not letting anyone else know.
What type of arrogance is this?
It was hell when I first found out about it.
Even like that, will my sickness get better?
Why should I let everyone be upset in advance?
Sickness also gets better.
Say it.
Who knows what type of method will come out from where?
Ji Sup, please.
Weren't you the same way with Ji Na's mother?
Everything that could've been tried was tried.
So, aren't you regretful?
There's obviously nothing left that we can do.
But is it good to still waste all the time that's left?
So?
Does Ji Na like you?
How is Ji Na's mother now?
Did she want to leave by that method?
No.
She only told me afterwards,
to let her go.
What could I have done?
I still don't know.
Because I'm a doctor,
compared to other people, I didn't give up on Ji Na's mother that early.
That woman was in pain longer than others.
Let me decide how to leave.
- Kang Ae.
- I want to live like a normal person in the time I have left.
Knowing I don't have long to live... Seeing the people
I love worry and not able to breathe because of me...
I don't want it to be like that, Ji Sup.
This precious time,
I will use it well.
Da Mi ssi.
- Da Mi ssi.
- Yes.
This is from the Chairman.
I was the one who said that your cell phone was broken.
I'll just buy it myself.
He says that if his younger brother calls, then get in touch with him.
What?
They say he's disappeared.
Why'd you come back without contacting us?
Oh, I just got back.
What? If you'd told me I would've gone to pick you up.
You don't look well.
Are you sick?
Yes, it must've been something I ate.
What did you eat?
In a matter of days, your complexion has completely changed.
Why act so carelessly? It's affecting even your stomach.
Are you alone?
Yes. Having not been able to get in
touch with you, I've almost gone crazy.
Sin Ae has set a date.
Really?
That's good.
Hey, he wanted the mother-in-law to be healthy,
so he bought a dumbbell. What do you think?
Really?
After he brought it here, he said... Mom, do this. Mom, do that.
After a while, he drilled a hole and hung it up.
Don't laugh, my heart's rather miserable.
Did you go traveling together?
Stubborn girl, I knew it.
Were you happy?
Was he good to you?
Jeong Seon,
I want to eat that Sesame Porridge of yours.
Now I've seen everything!
You've even asked me to make something for you!
Aren't you really good at making porridge?
When my stomach's not feeling well, you have no idea how good it feels to eat that.
Silly girl.
I am rather good at making porridge.
Just porridge?
Your meat and ginger soup is also
really good. Your kimchi is also good.
It's really nice when you're by my side.
If it weren't for you, it'd be really hard for me.
You're about to get married and you really say the strangest things.
Don't say anything, you've gotten my heart all warm and tickled.
Thank you, friend.
Aigoo, really.
Wait a sec, I'll soak the rice.
I'm back!
You're back?
Mom!
Come on in. I made kimchi fried rice.
When did you get back?
Earlier in the morning.
Was it fun?
Yes. But since I was so anxious to get back I didn't buy anything.
It's okay.
Did Mom make the kimchi fried rice?
I only helped out a bit.
She ate something on her trip and it got her sick.
So that's why you don't look well.
Eat well.
It must be very good!
Eat slower.
Mom must really like taking walks.
Did Dad say that?
Mm-hmm.
Dad said that as soon as you finished dinner you'd drag him out for a walk.
I seem to still remember taking a walk before with Mom and Dad.
On the walk, didn't we always have to go into the stationery store?
To go look at the erasers and the pencils.
Really?
Every time a new eraser came out we'd have to buy it.
Aigoo, back then we really bought a lot.
We liked to look at flowers.
We'd stand in front of the flower store and stare a long time.
How many more times will I be able to take walks with Mom like this?
Didn't you say you were getting married?
I still don't know when we'll get married.
But why are you so eager to send me over to Dad's?
It's not because of this.
Mom.
Because of that, it's been very hard for me.
I'm like a burden.
Da Mi.
I know, I'm not doing it to make you feel bad.
But it's still rather strange.
Mom is Mom, Dad is Dad.
Both say that they love me.
And I know that neither is lying.
But why isn't there anything that can enter my heart?
Why do I always feel like I'm alone?
It looks like I really haven't matured after all.
It's not like that.
I'm sorry, for making you feel this way.
It's okay.
I want to tell you something, Mom.
I rented a house.
Hmm?
It's near the company.
I found a small apartment.
I'll be moving in the day after next.
Da Mi.
Well, after Mom gets married,
it'll be me living in that house by myself anyway.
So if I went along to the new house it'd be hard for me to get used to.
Don't worry about me.
Mom, just do as you please.
I can live on my own now.
You're not going with Dad?
I'll give myself some time to consider it.
Even if I went to Japan,
Then will I not have a house here anymore?
If you live by yourself there, will you think it is too big?
Mmhmm.
Then Mom will buy a house for you.
Just move in directly.
But not now.
Go later.
Huh?
Let me take Grandma's stuff.
Don't take Grandma's stuff away.
Why not?
Da Mi, isn't there a phrase like this?
"You must also learn to let the ones you love go."
No matter who it is, there will be a time for him or her to leave.
Let her go, forget her.
This is also love.
Mom hasn't done it.
It's really very hard.
In the eight years that I knew your father,
I was very happy, Da Mi.
But, when I should've let him go, I didn't.
I lived with Dad forever in my heart.
Because of this, I missed out on many precious things.
Don't be like this.
You've loved Dad, haven't you?
Yes.
I loved him more than anyone else in the world.
He's a good man.
Let me see how beautiful my daughter is.
When you make something, do it directly.
When you watch, watch it directly.
My thoughts are right, aren't they?
Yeah.
Their parents will want to see how we live, won't they?
You've done well.
You're doing well too. It should've been this way a lot earlier.
Cut, okay!
Good work!
- Good work!
Is there a reason why you're here for me?
I want to go back together.
Mom invited me to eat dinner together.
Mom?
Yes.
You came.
Thank you for your invitation.
Bring him in.
Wow! Mom is really a great chef!
When it's a special occasion, she'll like to invite others.
Mom also really likes to use candles.
Sit.
I'm going to wash my hands.
Dad.
Mmm.
You seem to be a lot thinner.
I'm not feeling too well.
Where?
It was something I ate.
You have to be careful of your health. Don't get sick.
You have gout...
I'm fine. It hasn't started up for a long time now.
Don't get sick anymore.
When the time comes for Da Mi to get married, you have
to be healthy and well in order to walk her down the aisle.
Will you allow me to?
Is she called Yuka?
Da Mi told me.
And also...
Aki.
Does he look like you?
Aki does.
I want to meet them.
The way you were before, that
image still appears in front of me.
Often with smiling people.
People smiling often.
Oh, yes.
I left the red wine in the car.
Don't you like red wine a lot?
Didn't I get it from you?
I learned a lot about red wine.
Kang Ae.
Bring the red wine in.
We'll make a toast to Da Mi.
Teach Da Mi about red wine too. Start from the basics.
Slowly.
Dad is going out to get something from the car.
Mom will just take some medicine and come back.
Did Mom make this bouquet?
Wife!
Kang Ae!
Pull yourself together!
Kang Ae, what's wrong?
Mom!
- Mom!
- Kang Ae!
- Mom, what's wrong? Mom!
- Pull yourself together!
Mom, Mom!
Can you hear me?
- What's wrong? Kang Ae!
- Mom!
Even if you can't see Mom with your eyes,
you have to remember that Mom is always by your side.
No matter where you go.
Hey, Kang Ae?
Isn't there anything that can be done?
My beloved Da Mi,
Because of you, Mom has been very happy.
Watching you smile, watching you persevere.
That's why I can stand up again.
If Mom forces you to do anything,
it's also because Mom is loving you deeply.
I'm sorry, Kang Ae.
I'm sorry!