MONSIEUR VINCENT
Châtillon's that way;
we're not going there.
Hello there.
What are you looking for?
I am the new Priest.
There is no Priest here.
Hasn't been one in a while,
-and that's not about to change!
-What is happening here? Everything's shut down.
They're all cursed!
Where does Monsieur Bénier live?
Monsieur Bénier!
They're all cursed!
What is it?
- Is this Monsieur Bénier's house?
- What do you want?
Tell your master
Monsieur de Paul is here.
I don't know any Monsieur de Paul.
I told you not to open the door for anyone!
You idiot!
No one, I said!
These idiots could let
the plague into my house!
Be on your way.
We don't know any Monsieur de Paul.
I am the new Priest.
Monsieur Bénier is expecting me.
I told you
I won't open the door.
I am Monsieur de Paul.
Go tell your master.
He says he's a Priest!
Open the spy hole.
Pray forgive me, Monsieur de Paul.
I forgot your name.
I was expecting you.
- Did you just arrive?
- I took the afternoon coach.
You came straight away, didn't you?
You didn't talk to anyone in the village, did you?
-No. Why?
-Good. Open the door.
Go on!
Welcome, Monsieur de Paul.
- Did you have a good trip?
- Not too bad.
Except for a few pirates.
Do I scare them?
Be more discreet.
We are all going to die, dear Anne.
I hope we still have some time.
-And my husband is right here!
-He'll probably be the first to go, my dear!
The plague isn't
such a plague after all.
The plague?
Who's been contaminated?
A lady from the old part of town.
We walled her into her house.
When she dies,
we'll just set it on fire.
God willing, we'll still be able
to enjoy a few joyous days.
Have some chicken!
- How long has she been locked in?
- Three days.
Patience is the key here.
Some people take up to 10 days to die!
You should try the cup-and-ball.
It's a great pastime.
We have to do something.
We have to drink, eat and dance
and be merry. That's the only cure.
- Where does that woman live?
- What woman?
- The plague victim.
- Why?
I wish to visit her.
This is nonsense.
Why expose yourself to contamination?
Your quarters are ready for you.
You must be tired. Have some rest.
Thank you, but I am the Priest of Châtillon
and thus I will stay at the presbytery.
Dear Monsieur de Paul...
You have obviously not seen that building.
Our Priests gave up on it 10 years ago.
I shall stay there anyway.
Please have my things brought to me.
- And direct me to that woman's house.
- Enough joking around.
We shall be glad to have you here...
but if you leave tonight,
I will not be able to have you back.
Excuse me,
but that is my desire.-
Go get my things.
Tell me where
that sick woman lives.
I am your Priest and
I am asking you a question!
-It's the small house with the fires.
-Thank you.
My bag.
My hat.
Open up.
Excuse me, Sir,
but I must see that woman.
Thank you for your warm welcome.
What a boor!
I do apologize. He was recommended
by a friend of mine.
Looks like he forgot something.
Listen to this!
It is rather amusing.
"Resolutions towards
my masters the poor."
Look! He is really going!
He's going to get stoned to death!
That crazy man is so funny!
If he's still round on Sunday,
I'll go to Mass!
He'll be gone by Sunday.
Or he'll be dead.
Don't be afraid, child.
Carpenter, I need a coffin.
Do you hear me?
I need you to make a coffin.
Open up!
I am your Priest!
You'll open up
if you're not a coward!
Do not fear.
Get back!
Forward!
Seventh!
I hear you insisted on seeing me.
Who are you?
I am the Priest of Châtillon, Sir.
- Touché!
- My guard was down!
There is no Priest in Châtillon.
-There's been one for an hour.
-What do you want?
You are lord of this village,
so I've come to pay my respects...
and to ask you to order
the burial of this child's mother.
I appreciate your visit and
I welcome you to Châtillon,
but I have better things to do.
On guard!
The carpenter refuses
to make her coffin,
and that woman needs
a proper burial place.
- As lord of this village, your duty...
- My duty?! What duty?
Who do you think you are,
teaching me lessons?
And what is this?
The plague victim's daughter.
She had been locked in with her.
Aren't you crazy?!
Get out!
Get out at once...
or I'll have you thrown out!
Are you trying to kill us all?
What do you want?
- We need shelter.
- This is my house!
It is mine too.
- What did you say?
- This is my house.
Isn't this the presbytery?
I am the Priest of Châtillon.
There is no Priest in Châtillon!
There is no Priest and no God!
Get out!
You'll find out about God some day;
as for the Priest, I am right here.
Priest or not,
I won't be taken for a fool.
Nobody likes that.
- Is the soup ready?
- Don't touch it!
We don't want her
to choke on that bread.
Wait up. What do you
eat it with?
Do you want me to gut you?!
Get out!
- You would kill over soup?
- I would!
You wouldn't be the first!
The girl is hungry.
She hasn't eaten in three days.
Put your blade away...
and get me a spoon.
God damn it!
Quit insulting the Lord's name in my presence.
He created you out of love.
The same way He created that girl.
You both are equally unhappy,
that's why you'll share your soup with her.
Give her your spoon.
Thank you.
Take it easy.
There'll be more.
You know what?
You're the first Christian
I've met in Châtillon!
Did you lose your leg
during the war?
- I spent 10 years on Bassompierre's side.
-Then you are a brave man. We will get along.
- Are you courageous?
- Courageous?
Look at this!
I wouldn't look
like this if I had run off!
Do you really believe
it's the plague?
What plague?
The girl is the plague victim's daughter.
I'll make her mother a coffin...
-and I might need you tomorrow.
-No, I won't fall for that!
-But you've risked your life many times.
-Not like this. With weapons...
...but not like that.
-What is your name?
-La Fouille.
If I ever run into the Maréchal de Bassompierre,
I'll tell him about...
how you could fight 10 Spaniards but
that you feared illness like an old woman!
I can do this
better than you.
What is that?
- Legenda não traduzida -
Yes.
I am still alive.
That woman did not have the plague,
yet you left her to die
in the most awful way.
If I hadn't broken
into her house last night,
this little girl would be dead too...
maybe eaten by the dogs.
While praying for the deceased,
I asked God...
to forgive you too.
Wherever she is now...
I am sure she is praying for you too.
What will you do
with this child of God's?
She will need a home, a mother.
Who will take her in?
I am not talking to those
who have everything
but to the woman who barely
has enough for her own children.
May that one only move forward...
to take the child in.
The Lord will bless her,
He who was poor and alone.
I already have five at home.
Good. She is yours.
Go.
Tomorrow is Sunday. The church will
be ready for Mass at 8am.
Hurry, you idiots!
Do you need a week to take me back?!
Hurry!
Where's the doctor?
What is he doing?
Be patient, father. He might have
been called somewhere else.
My grandfather had his own live-in doctor
and got the attention he needed.
Nowadays they want to be paid!
Everybody wants to be paid!
In my day, being honest and serving
one's lord was more important.
- What is he doing?!
- Relax, dear uncle. He'll be right over.
Poor Louise. You're not about to forget
your stay in Châtillon!
Between my injury and the plague...
It was not the plague. The new Priest
buried that woman and he'll say Mass tomorrow.
Don't you mention that Priest!
I'm injured because of him!
-How can you say such a thing?
-I know what I'm talking about.
Everything's been going wrong
since he arrived.
I usually get people injured!
What took you so long, you stupid idiot?
You left me here to die!
-But Sir...
-You left for three hours!
I've been bleeding
like a pig at the butcher's!
- I've searched the whole village, Sir.
- Quiet!
-But Sir...
-Quiet, I said!
So you're leaving again...
what are you doing here?
They can't find the doctor,
so I'll take care of you.
Get the hell out of here!
I want my sword! Bring me my sword!
Well...
you won't use your sword
for a while, I'm afraid.
Do you think a few words
in Latin will fix that?
Miss, I need some water and linens.
I might also need a scalpel.
-Or a sharp dagger.
-Don't you think I've waited long enough?
You're quite some Priest.
You bury people, you heal wounds...
Where did you learn all that?
I was held as a slave for two years in Barbary.
I lived with a doctor.
I had got hurt in a fight on the boat,
so he treated my wounds...
and he taught me to do the same.
During a fight, you said?
Were you in combat?
-What was your weapon, a rosary?
-I took the sword of a wounded man.
Did God say it was okay
to kill people?
He never said to submit
to unfair punishment.
I like you! If all Priest were
like you, I'd attend Mass.
Sunday might be a little early,
but I want to see you...
there in two weeks.
-Bring us something to drink.
-Yes.
I could use some wine, indeed.
I'm tired.
I haven't eaten since yesterday.
-No wine for you, though.
-No wine for me?
Nobody's ever used
that tone with me!
Duty to the lord... it used to be true,
when lords still had their rights.
Nowadays, peasants are nothing
but a bunch of lazy idiots!
All they do is not pay
the taxes they owe me!
- They are dirt poor.
- Me too!
- No.
- Just a drop.
- A tiny drop.
- No.
Thank you.
You are not as poor as they are,
so you owe them everything.
If you made the law,
the world would be something else.
Yes, it would be
quite something else.
That girl you kicked out yesterday,
do you know who took her in,
- Who is sharing her bread with her?
- I don't.
The poorest woman in the village.
She already has five children to feed.
The rich of Châtillon
are feeling cozy at home,
and to them,
the world is in perfect order.
But that poor woman
took that extra burden.
She'll stay up later at night and she'll
wake up just a bit earlier in the morning.
But she is richer than you.
Of course, it all makes sense coming from
your mouth! The world is as it is.
It is as we created it, Sir.
We'd never seen a lady at our house!
And I'm just standing here...
I'm sure you've had your share
all day! Let me do it.
-Mom!
-Yes, I'm coming.
You don't want to get
that beautiful dress dirty. Here.
What's been going on in Châtillon?
Hello, good woman!
Have the children emptied
the cupboards yet?
I've come to bring more food.
-So?
-Sir, Madame la Comtesse sends her apologies.
Madame la Comtesse
does not wish to see anyone.
Fine.
I apologize.
I am afraid Madame de Gondi isn't feeling
well and won't be seeing you.
- Nothing serious, I hope?
- No.
No, she has heard some
upsetting news, that's all.
I don't wish to remind you
about the reputation of our name,
but the Gondi should
have enough influence
to find their own runaway!
An official complaint might...
-...have accelerated the search.
-A complaint?
Against Monsieur de Paul?
A complaint against my own confessor?
Against my children's tutor?
Of course I'm complaining,
but not to the police!
He's a Priest,
and we cannot find him!
We've been with the archbishop
for half a century!
A Priest says Mass, and Monsieur de Paul
must be saying Mass somewhere!
His Grace has sent emissaries
to all bishoprics in France.
Has he left any clues
when he left?
He wrote a note of apology.
The tone was firm yet tender.
He said he felt his duty was
to renounce his position with us.
We also found
some scrap paper in his room.
This is a list of resolutions
he must have accidentally left behind.
- Admirable resolutions!
- Of course,
but where have they led him? In what
kind of hole, with what kind of savages?
Give me a minute.
Madame,
God allowed this fortunate encounter
so I could apologize properly.
This is no fortunate encounter.
God has nothing to do with it.
so I came on my own. I found out where
you were and I've come to take you home.
Why did you abandon me?
I was appointed Priest of this town
and I have a duty towards these souls.
What about my soul? You know how much
I needed your guidance.
Who will soothe my pain?
God will provide.
What about my children's souls?
There are plenty of excellent
men of faith in Paris, Madame.
You shall find another,
more worthy confessor.
Excuse me.
These poor people
are waiting on the soup
I give them every day.
They are hungry.
Hungry.
Monsieur de Paul!
Father...
I am as hungry as they are.
I am waiting, just like them.
The Gospel tells us the good shepherd
left his flock to save one soul.
One soul is not enough,
and these people
are more miserable than you are.
I am aware that one single woman...
is too little for you.
12.000 souls live on my land.
They are yours.
Since you have time in the morning,
you'll help me with the soup.
Why? Is Monsieur de Paul
not staying with us?
I believe so.
"Sir Philippe-Emmanuel de Gondi,
Count of Joigny, Marquis of the Hyeres Islands,
lieutenant of the Eastern Seas,
general of the French galleys,
and the grand Françoise
Marguerite de Silly,
Baroness of Montmirail
and our lord's wife,
hereby agree to pay Monsieur de Paul,
Priest at the Diocese
and holding a Degree in Canon Law,
45.000 Livres
which shall be used
as income fund constituted
and which profits will serve
to clothe, feed
and other needs of
six Priests who shall travel
through villages
to preach and instruct
poor countrymen."
Poor and abandoned
countrymen.
"Poor and abandoned
countrymen."
This is what was read to you, Sir.
I know.
I am verifying the number.
This money belongs to the poor
and I'm responsible for it.
-They're covering him in gold,
and he's verifying the number.
-What a strange fellow.
-Are you happy now?
I will be happy
when I have done something.
- You have all powers now.
- God has all powers.
I will try and accomplish a little
if He lets me.
Will you have supper with us?
The Duchesse of Chevreuse
is interested in your project.
-She shall have dinner with us.
- I am not used to the world.
You'll have to get used to it. You asked
the world to help you, so you can't just
-ignore it anymore.
-I will see you later. I'm counting on it.
Are you waiting for someone?
Yes, I am waiting
for Monsieur de Paul.
I am the curate of Montmirail.
You have an accent.
Where are you from?
- From the Landes.
- What part
Dax.
I knew a little boy from Dax.
He was a little shy
and awkward like you.
That boy was not looking
to impose himself in the world.
What did you do there?
My parents are really poor.
- I was tending the sheep.
- Why be ashamed?
The boy I was telling you about
used to tend the pigs.
Listen, go back to Montmirail.
Don't pay your respects to Madame.
I will tell her you came by.
Once you're there,
go visit the poor. go visit the poor.
Go visit him personally.
Don't let anyone come between you two.
Believe me, you need your poor.
-At least as much as he needs you.
-Monsieur de Paul.
-What is it?
-The duchesse of Chevreuse has just arrived
-and she wishes to see you.
-I'll be right there.
Farewell, my boy.
We shall see each other again.
I shall show my face to the duchesse of
Chevreuse. One of the great ladies in France
You go see your poor.
At least we won't both
be wasting our time.
Come closer, Monsieur de Paul.
I asked to see you because
I've heard a lot about you.
From women, mind you.
Madame de Gondi started a new trend.
All the great ladies at court
only swear by you. That's a good thing.
In the meantime, they're not
plotting to have me assassinated.
I thought maybe you could
be even more helpful.
I am afraid his Grace might overestimate
my talents. I am nothing but a local Priest.
Not everybody can be well born.
What's important is
what we do next.
Will you serve us, Sir?
Those missions you organized
are a very smart thing.
Being a guide to humankind
makes us blind to charity
sometimes.
You little brutes!
These beautiful little creatures
give me respite from men,
yet they're the cruelest!
They make me bleed every day.
-What were we talking about?
-Charity.
It is your friend.
I would probably like it too
if those plotting against France
didn't steal all my time.
I don't have the luxury
of thinking about charity.
But I can help you.
What you are doing
on a small scale,
can you do it bigger?
You belong to the Gondi. Monsieur
de Gondi is general of the galleys.
I am thinking of creating
a new position for you:
chaplain to the King's galleys.
Your Grace...
Good news has a strange
effect on you. You seem confused.
I'm scared, your Grace.
- I cannot accept.
- Scared of what?
You are remarkably organized
and you never fail.
Are you afraid you might not be
good enough for the job?
No, your Grace.
With God's help, I feel like I can
accomplish any task at hand,
-with patience and humility.
-Then what are you scared of?
Speak!
Of what you may call my success.
I am nothing
but the son of peasants.
I wanted to become a Priest
to help save people poorer than me,
and ever since the important people
of this world started noticing me...
ever since they allowed me
to do big things, as they say...
-the essential things seem to escape me.
-The essential things?
- Yes, your Grace.
Since I've returned to Paris, you've
been telling me I've done a lot.
I've seen a lot of important people,
I've talked to them a lot
to convince them to give some
of their time and money for the poor...
but I haven't called a poor
person by their name.
I don't know the face
or the name of a single
poor person.
That is what scares me.
I think I might be
making a mistake.
Everyone of us has a part
to play on this earth,
according to what's
been given to us.
Do you think I know any names?
Do you think I have the luxury
of looking at people's faces?
All I do is call an unknown officer
I don't even look at
There, an army
of faceless unknowns
get on their way
to face their destiny,
or, in some prison,
to cut an unknown head off.
Only my king and France
have faces and names I recognize!
I am not asking what your feelings
or preferences are, Monsieur de Paul.
I hereby appoint you chaplain
to the King's galleys
because his majesty
and France need you.
We're headed to a good start.
We have many good galleys,
but with the general on board,
the Real is bound to win today!
Good man!
I am sure
Monsieur de Paul is praying for us.
Your grace.
-What is it?
-A great invention.
The top opens like so,
and releases a nice sent.
-Sent?
-I advise you to keep it.
After a half hour of hard work,
if the wind don't help...
-the smell gets intolerable.
-You are a man of faith, Monsieur de Paul.
Here you are, chaplain to the galleys,
and your galley slaves stink so much,
you will appreciate the sweet smell.
-Here is how you use it.
-Strong winds!
Strong winds!
Forward!
One would think that, after such an effort,
these men would get weaker. Not at all!
After a certain point,
men go past the exhaustion.
They're catching up to us!
Isn't this fascinating?
It is indeed, Sir.
It's fascinating.
Whip!
-Why?
-You'll see.
Whip!
This might hurt your Christian
sensitivity, dear chaplain,
but the whip is absolutely necessary.
At the height of their effort,
it is a stimulant the men request,
sometimes.
Muzzle!
The muzzle is a leather device we insert into
their mouths to prevent them from screaming.
Sir! Look!
I think the Real will honor
your presence!
Wonderful!
I could increase the rhythm, but that won't
be necessary. We don't want to lose any men.
Heart problems.
Shall I stop him?
-Leave him. It is his good will.
-He'll die from exhaustion.
It is a terrible effort.
Maybe it is God's will.
And we have no right to interfere.
I shall give...
from this day forward...
my belongings...
in other words...
consisting in 900 Livres...
as well as...
40 acres of land...
inherited from my father...
to my brothers and
my sister Marie's older son.
I renounce the profits made
by the abbeys and priories
of Saint-Leonard-de-Chaume...
and the Equilles...
of Saint-Leonard-de-Chaume
as well as my responsibilities
of Priest in Clichy...
and to all related
advantages and privileges.
I wish to keep...
no sign of power or fortune...
so as to better love
and serve the poor...
my brothers...
and masters.
That will be four soles a week.
That includes housekeeping.
You'll like it here.
A Priest used to live here.
He left the crucifix.
It is nothing luxurious,
but the bed is clean.
And this is a reputable house.
Don't you like it?
Is it too expensive?
Maybe it is not
good enough for your taste.
No, it is actually too good.
Thank you.
Yes?
- Do you know if there are any rooms for rent?
- Try upstairs.
My milk ran out,
so he's hungry.
Would you like...
some bread?
I have too much.
It is not a palace,
but it's good enough to sleep.
The person before you
never paid.
So you need to pay upfront.
It's three soles a week.
You're splurging, for a week.
My daughter takes care
of the housekeeping.
Did you hear? He's got money!
Go bring him some water.
Go now!
Do what I say!
The water.
Thank you.
What is it?
Lambert doesn't
live here anymore?
No. I do.
Well...
What do you want?
I used to sleep on his floor
when I didn't know where else to go.
Stay.
Where did you sleep?
He would let me borrow a cover.
Here.
You must have caught a cold.
Do you think?
I've been coughing up blood
since I was born.
Don't you have anywhere
else to go?
No.
How do you make a living?
I am no beggar.
I am a worker.
I paint fans.
But my coughing has
turned off all my bosses.
I spit on their fans...
and the ladies don't like that.
No!
You tramp!
- You tramp!
- No!
- It's true!
- Don't worry.
The guy on the first floor
just got home.
He's been beating his wife
ever since he got laid off.
What are we to do?
Just sleep.
Just try to sleep.
The neighbors know...
the children will fall asleep
in the hallway...
husband and wife will
end up making up.
They both drink a lot.
See?
It's going to be quiet again.
Well, almost.
That'll be one more child to share
the joys of this world with them.
That's the crazy lady
from the third floor.
She does that
every 15 minutes.
But you get used to it.
You'll see.
What's that?
The weaver.
He's got 10 kids
and his parents with him.
He gets one sole an hour,
so he works at night too.
Men of faith don't suspect
such things, do they?
I'm sure God Himself doesn't.
The poor don't sleep at night.
They work.
They insult each other.
They cough.
They make more poor people.
You can't let that get to you.
You have to do like everybody else
and not care.
The rich can afford to care.
The poor have had enough.
Every man for himself.
Forgive me, God.
I didn't know.
I told her it's a mortal sin.
She said it was only a venial sin.
But I'm sure it's a mortal sin!
She didn't come to Mass yesterday.
The flowers for the Virgin Mary
were all wilted!
She picked them the night before
so she wouldn't have to get up early.
She wants to serve the Lord,
but she also wants to sleep in late.
So you noticed?
I told the Priest the flowers were wilted.
God will do justice.
Portail.
Portail!
Monsieur Vincent.
- Come with me.
- But, Sir...
Come quick.
- I need you.
- What do I do about confession?
Leave it.
Portail.
I learned something awful last night.
I realized that,
before saving their souls,
we need to allow the poor
to live a life of awareness.
To have a conscience.
Let's go!
Herminie Labotte.
Herminie Labotte!
So what have you been doing?
Begging?
I used to live with the children,
but my son got married
and his wife claims I eat too much.
- That's not true. I don't eat too much.
- You told me already.
- You don't have any teeth, but eat well.
- Yes. A good soup...
Well, you'll get soup today.
And tomorrow too.
But...
you know, soup is expensive, and we
need a lot every day. We, too, are poor.
But you keep coming back,
and I don't know what to do with you.
I don't know what to do
with myself either.
Okay, you can stay.
But you'll cause our ruin!
With you, it's different!
- It's fate!
- You've been pushing your fate!
And fate is not everything!
There is the Providence.
The little birds get food every day,
but they still have to look for it!
You're a strong guy!
You could hold a shovel!
- I can't find a job!
- I'll find you one!
Come back tomorrow,
I'll get you hired.
Get some bread
with Mr. Portail...
But this is the last time
you swindle God!
Tomorrow's bread will be earned!
They're hungry.
I'm not asking for anything for myself.
Four.
Okay, you can come every day.
Give me a minute.
Monsieur Vincent, we're out of bread.
- Cut up some more.
- But...
- Then buy some more.
There are no more...
Really? Already?
Monsieur Vincent, we have
some people for you.
- Who sends them?
- The hospital can't do anything.
They are not sick.
- But they are sick.
- From what?
- Misery.
- Mother Superior said...
that if you didn't want
them, we'd have to throw them out.
Tell her I'll keep them.
- What will we give them?
- Soup and bread.
Bread?
Okay, soup.
And a little prayer,
after they've eaten.
- Father...
- What do you want?
- We ran out of wood.
- What do you do, eat it?
I was careful and followed
your instructions.
Let's start with prayer. That, we have.
I'll see about the rest.
Come in!
Monsieur Vincent is here for you.
Bring him in.
- I apologize, Sir.
- What else do you want?
- I ran out of wood.
- That doesn't make sense.
- Are you cooking those poor?!
- I've been cautious!
Some important people have helped me
get you a room here
and I was made
to provide for your wood.
I don't even want to know
who visits you in that room.
You are so weak and credulous!
Those people would spend the whole day
there if they could!
They are weak, old and sick!
I am the regional hospital accountant.
That is an important office!
I have set resources...
that I can't possibly increase!
I cannot afford your generosity
and frivolity!
I don't have any more wood either.
Monsieur Vincent...
you are a pleasant man. If you
are cold, come warm up at my place.
I am always happy
to chat with you.
Thank you, Sir.
Money...
I need money.
Without money,
nothing can happen.
Madame!
You came right away!
- I am not one to make you wait.
- You are right.
This is the money
you asked for.
Thank you.
That will buy a lot of bread. We
couldn't give them anything this morning.
Hurry up! Get some bread!
And wood?
And wood.
Is money the only thing
I can give you?
You are such a lady,
what else could you possibly give me?
You are carrying the weight
of your fortune and your name...
just as they are carrying
the weight of their misery.
Excuse me.
I need these linens...
to cover their wounds, later.
A maid would cost money I could use for
bread, and I don't want to deprive them.
You may leave now.
Madame...
you can't possibly do this every day.
I can. And others will, too.
This is our first meeting,
and we wish to thank you
first and foremost, Monsieur Vincent.
I should thank you, ladies.
Without you, I was lost.
You have come down from the heavens,
to help my poor...
like angels carrying jam, soup,
warm clothing and good words.
I was dreadfully
scared the first time!
I had always given them
a coin or two after church,
- But I had never talked to them.
- I thought they'd insult me!
But not at all.
They are very polite.
- They always thank me.
- Not all of them.
I demand a "thank you."
Just like with my dog:
you want sugar, show your paw.
Poor people are quite sensitive.
You have to be rather creative at times
to give...
without upsetting them.
That, you can teach us.
We'll be proud to learn.
Today, though, we should
talk about practical issues.
First of all, it's only the 12 of us
and there are lots of poor people
- Should we take in more ladies?
- This is what I think:
I don't know why, but everybody
want to be like us.
Everybody's trying to copy.
No, I think we should stay
amongst ourselves.
I think we should take in
a few people.
- I spoke with Madame de Guemene yesterday...
- Madame de Guemene?
With the luxury she lives in?
If we accept her...
all she'll want to do is give
more than us, just to snub us!
The poor might actually like that.
It's not just about the poor.
It's about us too!
She's a friend of mine
but Madame
de Guemene is not a pleasant person.
So yesterday, this woman
comes up to me in a shop.
She said she's heard I created a charity
and so forth...
She is filthy rich and she was ready
to contribute 10,000 Ecus to be a member.
So I told her, "Madame,
there is still a world in France
where money alone
does not open doors."
What do you think, Monsieur Vincent?
I'm thinking...
about the 10,000 Ecus.
I have a question. I don't know what
you wear when you go to the poor.
I personally wear
a simple grey dress.
I borrow one of my daughter's dresses.
It's so much fun to dress up!
You know what I was thinking?
We could have a special dress made.
Some kind of uniform
we would all design.
I saw my draper. He showed me some exquisite
linen. It is grey, with some blue undertones.
- Come take a look!
- Excellent idea.
We'll have
to make it simple, in black.
- Grey is softer and not as prone to stains.
- It's so dirty there.
Excuse me, Father.
- Is anybody home?
- Who are you looking for?
- Monsieur de Paul.
- What do you want with him?
I'm a maid from Suresnes.
I've come...
because I heard some ladies
did charity work in hospitals.
- Is that true?
- It is.
For the most part.
So I'm here because...
excuse my audacity, but I wanted to tell
Monsieur Vincent something.
Tell him what?
The ladies are used to being served
and they might not know
how to serve others.
I'm a milk maid, so I'm used to doing
things they might not want to do.
I...
I could offer my help.
I'm not asking for money.
Food only.
I could do the bleedings, enemas, clean the
wounds, make the beds, empty the chamber pots.
All the things they don't want to do.
If I'm going to be a maid,
I'd rather serve God's poor
than my masters.
Am I being arrogant?
No, dear child.
Did you walk here?
- Did you eat this morning?
- I left before dawn.
Go to the kitchen. Tell them Monsieur
Vincent is sending you.
I'll see you later.
Do you think they'll take me in?
I have no doubt about it.
Thank you, Lord,
for sending this simple girl.
She is simple, but
she understood what I didn't.
The poor...
will help me save the poor.
That poor milk maid from Suresnes
was Marguerite Nazeau.
She was the first servant to our poor.
The charity work those ladies had
somewhat sugar-coated...
she did it, in her simplicity.
She worked hard,
like a poor person.
Soon enough, others joined her:
Barbe Engibouste
and Madeleine Drugeon.
Their lives were difficult.
They were exposed to bad jokes,
and sometimes ill-treatment.
Everybody was against us!
People couldn't tolerate to see nuns on
the street. They thought their place...
was at the convent.
For our girls...
the street was their...
convent.
Their cell...
was
a simple room for rent.
They felt extremely lonely.
That is why I got the idea
of bringing them together.
We needed a house
where they could feel at home,
after a hard day of work.
His Grace Lebon, in his generosity, has given
us the priory and the Saint Lazare domain.
But the buildings are in ruins...
the hospital, the pharmacy,
the room where we host
the poor during the day.
And we need to take care
of the demented, too.
So I need someone
who will supervise my girls.
Why me?
Because it is not enough
to do a little good.
You have to take on more,
You have...
to take on a little more every day.
What you're asking of me
is rather heavy.
I'm doing as much as I can.
These people are frightening.
I'm scared of the poor
Yes...
they're terrifying, aren't they?
As terrifying as God's justice
they know is without pity.
We can afford to hide behind our decent
clothes and our well-fed bodies.
But look at these awful rags,
the illness...
the misery, the bones,
the crazy look in their eyes.
They are mine, though.
They can be tough and unfair...
but we have to serve them
and love them...
like we would our masters.
I am scared.
I am weak, hesitant and gauche. I have
none of the qualities a supervisor needs.
You are my first soul.
The first person who understood me.
Mademoiselle de Marillac, you will be
strong, firm and efficient. I need you to.
Father! Father!
We can't do it anymore!
There's only the four of us!
There're a dying man and there's no more place.
- I'm coming.
Come with me.
Come see how much I need you.
- Why him? Why not us?
- My legs are wounded too!
- I only got up to come here!
- But I was on bed rest!
- The old should go first!
- Let the young go first!
- What about me?
Will you let me go?
Monsieur Vincent.
- So?
- We have no bed for him.
Who's feeling better here?
Who can give their bed
to a sicker man?
You?
There's a spot.
Have the body taken out.
What about me?
I've been waiting here
for three days, waiting for him to croak.
This is my spot.
He told me before he died!-
I want to die in bed.
- I want to die in a bed.
- They're here?
I'll be back.
My dear, I have to go.
Make sure things go smoothly.
I want to die in a bed.
- I want to die in a bed.
- What about me?!
I've been waiting longer than you!
Stop it!
There is no fighting in here!
I'll call for Monsieur Vincent.
Madame, please make them stop.
We can't do it.
They demand things,
they insult us, they spit on us!
- How could I possibly love them?!
- Go back to bed!
- I'll call for Monsieur Vincent!
- There's not enough beds!
- Get some more!
- You can't treat the poor like this!
The poor are not animals.
- We're not animals!
- No!
We're not animals!
I can't do it!
I can't! I can't do it!
- Very well, I'll do what I have to do.
- This is a copy of the eviction form.
I have 12.000 sick in Saint Lazare, serve
2.000 soups a day. Where will these people go?
I am only the messenger. My job
was to give you the eviction form.
Sir!
Sir, they've turned against us!
They fought over the dead man!
They insulted your name.
I can't do it. I can't, Sir.
You should go, Monsieur Portail.
I'll be right there.
Well, I'll manage alone, my dear.
You are trembling.
I'll walk you to your carriage.
Who were those men?
I thought Saint Lazare was too small, and they're
evicting me from Saint Lazare. Must be fate.
Where will you go
with these poor people?
I am responsible for them. I'll find them
shelter somewhere else. I am used to this.
We'll find an even less
suitable shelter...
These are the refugees
from Lorraine.
I hear that region has been
reduced to ashes.
There are 2,000 of them
coming to Paris.
What misery...
2,000 more for me.
For us.
I apologize for being so weak.
I'm staying.
Monsieur Vincent,
what you accomplished is admirable.
The help you gave those refugees
was a blessing.
Where do you get the bread
and the clothing?
The finance ministry would like to know
what kind of magic tricks you do.
They are given to us,
Monsieur Chancellor.
How lucky you are!
The ministry is not
given anything!
There is no tax money,
the people are crying for mercy.
We've supposedly taken everything
from them, but we're still broke!
The poor are multiplying
and they've become a real threat.
Beggars everywhere!
And nowadays,
if you don't give them anything...
they threaten you.
They're hungry.
They're hungry...
With my job, I have other kinds of hunger
to appease! France is hungry...
for safety... for order.
Well.
I've requested your presence here
because I have some good news.
After your life-long
dedication to them,
you'll be happy to hear that, in two days,
there will be no more poor people!
- How?
- It's very simple. They're under arrest.
But, Sir...
- poverty is not a crime.
- I am afraid it very surely leads to it.
My job is to anticipate, and that's what
I'm doing. I have several premises...
La Pitie, le Refuge, la Savonnerie, Bicetre,
la Salpetriere... I'll just store them there.
The problem is
that they'll have to be fed.
We'll manage.
Public health comes first!
Would you like to be in charge
of the general hospital I am founding?
The poor are people.
They deserve to be free.
Free to bother people on the street?
To starve?
I'm feeding them, I'm giving them shelter.
What more would they want?
Charity means helping them
keep their humanity.
Charity?
You invented charity!
It used to be a quality.
It was good enough
for old church ladies.
We chatted about it,
we cried a little, we pulled out a coin,
and everybody was happy.
You, however,
blew things out of proportion!
You've put in some much effort
that the government is now
responsible for your charity!
We were busy enough
with finances, the Protestants,
the navy, international
issues and war...
that don't work well...
Do you think we need your charity
business on top of everything else?!
Before your time,
there were poor people,
but they didn't bother honest people.
Now they're everywhere!
It almost seems like
you're pulling them out of your hat!
Do we have the right to hold
those things against him?
This is not against him.
We just want to express our opinion.
What if we gave more time,
- more time and more money...
- We give whatever we can.
Nothing would be enough.
It used to be the elderly,
and that's sad. So he founded an association.
Prostitutes, the galley slaves,
the prisoners... fine.
We're already struggling with the hospitals.
We do as much as we can.
And now he's come up
with the refugees.
They had to come to Paris, since
their region has been turned to ashes.
Well...
I'm sure there are charitable people where
they live. Why not invite negroes over, too?
- He did mention it, Madame.
- What?
He told me once that he felt for those
barbaric people in our colonies
and that he wished
to send missionaries there.
To negroes?
See, he has to be stopped
before he takes us too far.
- It's cold tonight!
- Can't wait to be home.
- Look, there's another one.
- Happens every day now.
They come to Paris to have a good time.
- Don't be afraid.
- The fruits of their sins end up here.
- This one's dead.
- At least he won't be unhappy.
It's so cold out, it's no surprise.
- See you tomorrow!
- Tomorrow!
What were you going to do?
I am alone, I don't work.
I don't know who his father is.
God created him.
He is your son. One day, he'll be a man
who won't abandon you.
Show him to me.
You have a beautiful child.
Be brave.
I can't. I can't.
I'd rather not see him die.
Come back!
I'm telling you to come back!
So you found one?
He's still alive?
They usually survive longer
in the summer. The other one's dead.
He's been there for two hours.
He cried for a little while,
then he stopped.
- And you didn't move?
- I don't have any legs.
I walk on my hands,
so holding babies is hard.
Then what would I do with them?
People don't care.
They're cold, so they just
walk by to get their soup.
Do many babies get
dropped in that box?
Three, four a day.
Half of them die.
The other half is no luckier.
They get sold to beggars like me
who maim them. A baby is worth nothing,
but an infirm can
bring in lots of money.
- Those women who abandon them know that?
- They're not the worst.
They hope the baby can survive.
As for the others,
they just drop them in the river.
Such is life.
Life as God made it.
All that's not supposed to survive has to die.
Monsieur Vincent,
we have spoken our minds
with our deepest feeling of charity.
And with common sense.
Women know what is
and what is not possible.
Among the weakness and misery, God has given them
a kingdom to run, but also that humble knowledge.
And men wouldn't make so many mistakes
if they listened to them.
Madame...
I didn't mean what I said, Sir.
- Please forgive me.
- No, I agree, Madame Groussault.
I am glad I sometimes
lack some common sense.
Common sense and folly lead us
to as many sins.
They're just different sins.
We are waiting for your answer.
What is this?
My answer.
You think I do too much?
I think I'm not doing enough.
I just saved this child, but three
or four innocent children die
every night on church steps.
Maybe God wants them to die.
They are children of sin.
When God wants someone
to die to pay for sin...
He sends His son.
God never wanted a single
innocent child to die to pay for sin.
It is the cowardly, the selfish and
the vicious...
- who accept that idea.
- Monsieur Vincent, I respect you,
but I won't follow you blindly.
I hate sin and vice,
and as much as you love charity,
I won't love these children.
I hate this child
born from sin and vice.
God is listening to you, Madame.
- God cannot possibly love him.
I won't allow you to be the judge of that!
I know
that God is asking me
to save this innocent child
before anyone else.
I will go out tomorrow
and every night.
I will put more on this table!
You will watch them fight
and ask you to let them live.
- We'll see if you let them die.
- Monsieur Vincent...
we told you we have
too much on our hands.
I know you won't listen to us
because we lead a rich and idle life.
But these girls
work day and night
and they'll tell you
they can't do any more.
If God asks them to,
they will do more.
- We are trying to talk reasonably.
- I am the one who started that trend!
I've told you not to go too fast,
but tonight, I won't be saying that.
I'm afraid
I've gone too slow.
Monsieur Vincent, there are institutions
that collect these children.
They pay nurses to feed them.
Don't you know that?
I don't know what they do for children, but
I know that if I hadn't been there tonight.
this child would be lying
in a box in front of the church.
He would be dead by now.
We have enough enemies,
Monsieur Vincent.
Priests and judges are
in charge of that work,
and if we start doing their work,
they will hate us too.
No, madam.
When I appear in front
of my only judge,
do you think I'll tell Him,
"I witnessed crimes
but I didn't want to interfere and get
in trouble with the local institutions
- and the judges who allow those crimes"?
- You'll do as you wish.
But I know
that none of these women will stain their
hands taking care of these miserable children
and touch their own children later.
Don't ask for more, Monsieur Vincent.
Don't ask for too much.
What you want to do here... -
is too repugnant.
-So are you.
No one will look at me.
Mademoiselle de Marillac.
I am ashamed.
I am ashamed,
but they do disgust me.
- Madeleine...
- Sin is ugly. It's too ugly.
You too?
I'll never make it.
I was a fool to believe
I could move your souls,
that I could let you out
of your repulsive solitude.
I'm begging you...
at least look at me.
Grant me at least...
one look.
Don't leave me to my loneliness.
I will never make it.
Monsieur Vincent will be sorry
he couldn't be here to welcome you.
His position
at the moral council
where he was appointed by his Majesty
kept him busy today.
His Holiness the Pope very much
admires the works of your superior.
He said to me, "go visit Saint Lazare
and tell me how it is,
since I will never have
the chance to go."
These are the elderly
we support...
after they are too weak to work...
and earn a living.
Monsieur Nacquart died in Madagascar.
We named our foreign
missions office after him.
- Marguerite Nazeau? I've never heard of her.
- She was our first daughter of charity.
- She died while caring for plague victims.
- And Louise de Marillac was the first...
- supervisor to the daughters of charity?
- Absolutely, Sir.
We don't have enough room.
We had to host a few of our abandoned
children over here.
I think you've had to face many uneasy
feelings. It must have been hard.
You are right.
But with time and Monsieur Vincent's will,
we managed to do everything.
Everything.
Similar institutions now exist
in Italy, in Europe and around the world.
What will people say in the future
when they learn that a single man
had the desire to create what seems
so normal and so just today?
Your Grace, Monsieur Vincent
should be here soon.
I will wait.
He's the Reverend Father
Philippe-Emmanuel de Gondi.
When the countess passed away,
he joined the order.
Our congregation
owes him so much.
Are you feeling better,
Monsieur Vincent?
Your Majesty is too good.
- Please forgive my poor state.
- Rest with me just a little bit longer.
You can leave us now.
You're doing too much.
We are old now.
One is old when one wants to be old.
When there is time to be old.
You have to take the time.
It's good to be done.
I have done so little.
Sometimes I wonder
if you're not giving in to false modesty
when talking about yourself.
I have many horrible flaws...
monstrous flaws for which
I am begging God to forgive me...
but false modesty...
- But since you're mentioning it...
- You know you've done a lot.
Very few will be able to show
for as much work as you did
on Judgment Day.
I did sleep.
I slept so much.
I had to be old to realize one could live
on four hours of sleep a night.
I was a coward quite often.
I gave in...
and I closed my eyes
so I could forget about misery.
What about us?
We thought of our own pleasure,
of our lust for good things.
Without you, our eyes
would still be closed.
I wanted everything.
And I got everything...
gold, power...
and love.
Everything a little princess
could dream of...
the most beautiful kingdom
in the world,
the most beautiful love,
for whom she could have
lost her kingdom,
the most beautiful diamonds.
she had everything.
But it seems that
between the greedy little girl
and the old powerful queen
dreaming aloud with you...
there has only been
some long, empty dream.
I haven't done anything.
Tell me.
You've given your whole life...
you're given up happiness
and power forever...
you've built more
than useless palaces...
more than vain glory.
Do you also feel,
now that death is near,
that you're leaving nothing
but an empty hole behind?
Yes, Madame.
I haven't accomplished anything.
What is one supposed to do in life, then,
to accomplish something?
More.
We are so neglecting.
They're expecting me at Saint Lazare.
The poor are waiting.
Does Your Majesty allow me to go?
Go, Monsieur Vincent.
Tell them the Queen of France is asking for
forgiveness for stealing you from them.
Stop. Stop.
Is he sick?
Hunger...
will always exist.
- Help me.
- Let me do it. You can't possibly
Of course I can.
One always can
See, I told you.
It's nothing.
Let's go home.
You are too careless!
- It's okay.
- Careless.
Stay around, Portail,
- and help that poor fellow to bed.
- You, too, should go to bed.
I haven't finished my day.
Sir?
Sir.
I am not feeling well.
I can't see anyone.
His Grace Graziani is here to see you.
That is such an honor.
Throw yourself at his feet
and beg for his forgiveness.
But...
I think that...
I have to wait...
for another visitor tonight.
A more important visitor.
Tell him I can't.
Leave me now.
- Can I ask the doctor...
- No.
No one.
Yes.
Yes, I will see someone.
Jeanne.
You know, the new girl
who's helping the poor for
the first time. Send her in.
Sir, that is not important.
Anyone could train her.
At the point I'm at now,
one knows what is important
and what is not.
Send her in
and thank everybody else.
My God...
will You finally
allow me to see You?
Will You finally...
call me to my rest?
Do You think I've earned my rest?
I've done so little.
I am tired, it's true.
Who is it?
- It's Jeanne, Sir.
- Come over here.
Jeanne...
I asked to see you.
I know you are good and brave. You'll tend...
- to the poor for the first time tomorrow.
- Yes, Sir.
I wasn't always able
to talk to all the girls
who were tending
to the poor for the first time.
We can't always do what we want.
But with you,
the youngest, the latest girl,
I had to do it.
It is important.
Always remember...
- remember everything.
- Yes, Sir.
You will soon realize
charity is a heavy load to carry.
It is heavier than a bucket of soup
and a basket of bread.
But you will always
keep your tenderness and your smile.
It is not hard
to serve soup and bread.
Even the rich can do that.
But you are a servant to the poor...
a daughter of charity...
always smiling,
always in a good mood.
They are your masters.
Touchy and demanding masters,
as you'll see.
The uglier and
the dirtier they are,
the more unfair
and vulgar they are,
the more love you'll have to give.
Only because of your love,
and your love only,
will the poor forgive you
for the bread you're giving them.