All passengers of LOT flight
from Warsaw to London
are requested immediately
for to go to passport control
and custom clearance.
Before we left, customs
checked all our luggage.
That bag contained hammers
drills and an axe.
Today is the fifth
of December, 1981.
Warsaw black market exchanges
one pound sterling
for well over 1,000 zloty,
the average weekly wage.
I landed in London with 1,200
pounds in my pocket.
A sum that would have taken
me 25 years to earn.
The purpose of our visit
to London is to buy
a second-hand car with
our joint savings.
The purpose of our visit
to London is to buy
a second-hand car with
our joint savings.
It was very difficult
to disguise the weight
of our hand luggage.
As my men didn't know
a single word of English,
I would have to speak
for them all.
Number four.
The purpose of our visit
to London is to buy
a second-hand car with
our joint savings.
How many are there
of you?
We are...
We are four...people.
I have the passports.
How much money have
you brought with you?
Twelve hundred pounds.
And where will you
be staying?
We are staying in a flat
in Onslow Gardens, number 5.
It is a friend
of my wife.
You must make absolutely sure
that your friends understand
exactly what this
is about.
"Leave to remain in
the United Kingdom
on condition that the holder
does not engage in employment
paid or unpaid, and does
not engage in any
business or profession is
hereby given for one month."
Now do you understand
that, Mr. Nowak?
Nov-ak.
Yes, I understand.
Thank you.
Mr. Wolski.
Mr. Bana-zak?
Banaszak.
Mr. Kudaj?
Ku-day.
Are you a member
of Solidarity?
No.
That was the only true
answer I gave him.
Where did you get
those trolleys, please?
the trolley?
Take this.
Oh!
This is for you.
Thank you, bless you.
Idiot Banaszak!
Your attention please,
will Mr. David Ellis
please contact
airport information.
Mr. David Ellis, please
contact airport information.
Today's Times page five:
"At her concert in Warsaw's
ice hockey stadium last night
American pop star Tina Turner
was determined that politics
be left alone despite
the current climate of freedom
so that Poles could concentrate
on her athletic charms
and gold lamay
nickel skirt.
However, the audience began
to warm up when they realized
that her song titles could
conceal political meaning.
'What do you want?'
she asked suggestively.
'Food!' shouted
the audience.
'What do you need?' she
repeated equally provocatively.
'Dollars!'"
We were there only
last night.
The boss took us
and our wives as a treat.
Anna was sitting between
the boss and me.
And that's another two
quid for the baggage!
Good morning,
can I help you?
Yes, I have...
Oh, yeah.
Yes, well that's fine,
I'll just get the keys.
There you are.
Two keys.
Two keys for
the one door?
Yeah, I'm sure
you'll manage.
Thank you.
It's nice to see you.
It's my very pleasure
to meet you.
I made it clear,
no smoking.
I hate the smell
of cigarette smoke.
Oh, f---!
Ladies, don't settle for
anything but the real thing.
Spaghetti Rigatoni in the
traditional blue paper pack
at our delicatessen.
Don't hesitate,
only 38p.
Ladies, does your husband
come home tired and irritable?
A can of Party Four will keep
him sweet at home all evening!
Party Four 2 pounds 40
in our office.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Ooh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Coca Cola!
Nowak, here mini Cola!
Rita, how much is the
Kitty Cat turkey flavor?
Twenty-six pence,
I think.
You are intending to pay
for the goods concealed
in your handbag, madam?
Oh, I didn't really
mean to take...
It's our policy
to prosecute shop lifters.
I think we should go
to the manager's office.
Please, just put it
back on the shelf.
I really didn't mean
to take it.
It happens
all the time.
This way, this way
officer!
Nowak, come get!
Banaszak...
You just wait!
Thank you.
Hello?
Moment.
It was as simple
as the boss said.
The line for Warsaw
was better than in Warsaw.
If our conversation was taped,
it must be a good recording.
I confirmed that everything
was okay,
still the boss insisted
that every detail
should go into his
black notebook.
'Just for the record,'
he said.
Stop, stop.
Okay.
As instructed by the boss,
knocking the walls down
until 8pm selecting
usable materials until 11pm.
To bed at midnight.
The men are not to know
what I know,
but by sending work men
over from Poland
and paying our wages
in zlotys,
our boss can have
his London house down
for a quarter of what
he would have to pay
a British builder.
Don't they ever wonder why
the bosses prepare to pay
for one months hard labor
what it would take us
a year to earn
in Warsaw?
And the bonus are 20 pounds
each when the job is done.
The magic of hard currency,
our boss is one of the few
in Poland who has dollars.
Sleep well Anna.
Sunday mass at
the Polish church.
Bus fare 20 pence each...
to come out of
the entertainment money.
A television.
Twenty pounds
for entertainment,
nearly one pound
gone already.
An evening out when
the rest were easily got.
I had a better idea.
We took a vote on it,
Kudaj was against.
Can I help you?
Nice set, sir,
only 50 pounds, very cheap.
Forty pounds is all
I have, no more.
Forty pounds fully
guaranteed 26 inch
color television set?
Sir, I can see you have
a nice sense of humor
but please, let us
be serious.
Forty pounds without
the guarantee.
Cash?
Forty pounds,
no guarantee, no aerial.
without the guarantee,
and with the aerial.
Forty pounds without
guarantee with aerial.
And no plug!
To buy it I added
my 20 pound bonus
to the entertainment fund.
Anna has been asking
me for a color TV.
Liverpool's still got the upper
hand in this half.
Oh, and my god what
a terrible mistake!
Out to Robertson.
Inside Hugh McDonald
and...
Anderson brings it down
takes it down to Wing.
Beaten down by Walden!
I repair the TV
in Warsaw.
All the better, no time
will be wasted.
I can see you believe
in working hard
Sunday or no Sunday.
Oh it's perfectly
all right with me,
Just carry on,
if you must.
I only hope the other
residents won't complain.
You don't mind?
Oh no, no I don't mind.
It was very like
my boss in Warsaw
even dresses like that.
Ah yes,
him over there.
He always comes
around on Sunday.
When the cat's away,
you know?
People like a bit
of peace and quiet!
There...that's better.
Almost acceptable.
I can speak their language,
this is why the boss
choose me for the job.
But I don't know
what they really mean.
Sign that.
Damn you!
Come on, boy,
come on.
So, this isn't the only
house full of rubbish
'round here.
Good morning.
Oh, good morning.
I see some English
work harder at night
then Poles onto Sunday.
Yes, quite.
Couple parts will
be in tomorrow.
When?
Tomorrow.
Trade?
Master electrician.
Trade or private?
I almost forgot
the business card
the boss had printed
in order to obtain
professional discount.
Eagle Builders.
Anna's face could look at me
from every shop window.
wherever they sell
those clothes.
Maybe I could involve
that girl.
I have to go that way
for copper pipe anyway.
The girl seemed
to be nice,
girls are always attracted
to men who have pretty women.
Oh, damnit.
The photograph.
Can I help you, sir?
I'm just looking
around.
Okay.
Thank you very
much, good bye.
Excuse me.
I was--I was looking
at you through
the window yesterday.
Can I help you?
I have a great
publicity idea
for Wrangler.
Look, you see this
poster here, it's good.
It's too small.
It's a good poster,
but what about sweatshirts?
Well, I've got lots
of sweatshirts here.
Would you like--
Huh?
Whenever I show this photo
to my friends in Poland
they say, "Where did
you get the sweatshirt?"
Well, wouldn't it
make a great
Wrangler poster?
Hmm, it's very nice.
You want a sweatshirt
for her?
So much for daydreams.
You're wasting time.
Aw, come on.
Look, just come on!
I was sure it was
only five to three,
but Kudaj's watch
says ten past.
Did somebody telephone?
Yes indeed,
I just did.
It is working.
No, whatever,
I mean from Warsaw.
It's ringing.
Excuse me.
Banaszak.
Barbara!
"I'm well," he says.
"It's going well here.
I hope you and the kids
are keeping well.
I think about you
all the time."
I wish I could
be like him.
By the way I do think
about Anna all the time.
I never stop!
Nowak.
Anna?
Three glasses of vodka she's
had with the boss already.
How many more
will they have?
Why did he really
choose me?
They have agreed
to miss church today.
We'll fall behind
otherwise.
I must talk to Anna,
I can't wait until Saturday.
Which country?
Warsaw, Poland.
All the lines
have been suspended.
Suspended, why?
There was a military coup.
A coup?
That's right, didn't
you hear the news?
Yes, I know.
I want to make an
airline reservation
for tomorrow's flight
to Warsaw.
I'm afraid, sir,
all air traffic to Poland
has been stopped.
Till when?
I have no idea, sir,
I'm afraid we're
just as much in the dark
about what's happening there
as everybody else.
Sorry, sir.
Well...
How will you take
the news, Banaszak?
No more phone calls
from Barbara.
No flights home until
God knows when.
No boss, only me.
I'm not afraid,
I'm quite calm.
Thing is, I've not had
a clear thought in my head
since yesterday.
A government proclamation
banned a wide-range
of civil liberties.
A 10pm to 6am curfew
was introduced.
Polish soldiers patrol
the streets of Warsaw
in battle gear,
telephone and telex lines
for outside world
were all cut yesterday.
They sleep soundly,
they don't know.
Let them sleep.
Oh, two for Banaszak,
he likes his coffee strong.
Wake up!
Hey, I say...
Have you seen the news
in the paper?
Must be extremely
upsetting to you
what's happening
in Poland.
Yes, it is ver--
it is very upsetting.
Why are you doing that?
Why?
There's too much
on there, pal,
get some of it off.
It's not--it's not
my rubbish.
You pay 40 pound
for one load,
not for six loads.
Get some of it off!
But it was the people,
it was the neighbors here.
I'm the geezer driving
the wagon,
I'll go up the road,
I'll get nicked!
Get it off!
We've had enough
of you people.
Because the people,
it was--I was shaving
I looked out of the window
and it was here!
It's not my rubbish!
Oi!
Get your own skiff!
You lazy scruffy
rat-faced, rat-eared,
cobble-eyed maggot!
Just because you
come over here
Raffie knows
you're a Commie,
it don't mean you wipe
your ass on our flag.
Those are told by
the authorities
that the west is reacting
calmly to the weekend crackdown.
"Those who diluted themselves
of the introduction
of Marshall Law in Poland
would bring about
a political earthquake
all over the globe
have been disappointed," said
a Warsaw television reporter.
The broadcast said that
on the whole, western statesmen
and influential propaganda
centers have adopted
at least a restrainer
during two events in Poland.
I'm sure the boss
would take care of Anna.
Unless he's been
locked up.
'Scuse me, sir,
that's not your paper.
This is yours, sorry.
The first initial bloodshed
by the Polish authorities
since the military takeover
was reported last night
that seven workers
had been killed
and 39 injured in a clash
south of the country.
Polish television news
reporter wearing an army uniform
said that the soldiers
had no choice.
They were under attack
and forced to shoot.
I must concentrate
on work.
I must drive them harder.
Stabilizers should've
been sprayed on yesterday.
We must start
the plumbing tomorrow.
Three days without water,
it won't be easy.
I must allow them
time for a bath.
I'll tell them now.
--Concrete cells,
no furniture,
food, water,
toilets or heat.
All I could say
was, "Who smoked?"
Top, top,
on top!
Top, top, top,
top, top, top!
Banaszak.
Kudaj.
Nowak!
Nowak, Nowak!
It should have been
a great day for us.
All the new joints leaked.
And neither
I nor Banaszak
have any idea what
has gone wrong.
It has set us
days behind,
and I don't know
how many pounds short.
That made them forget
the weekend phone call.
I'll have to wait
until Monday
to find out what went
wrong with the joints.
I said that everything
at home was alright,
their wives send
their love,
Banaszak's lady wants
some Beyer aspirin.
They'll all ring again
next Saturday.
I think they
believe me.
It's not true I never
finish a job!
That I always fail!
Not this time!
I'll show them.
Anna, the boss.
Seventy-two pound
for new joints.
He said we must've
overheated them.
There's no way I can
find 72 pounds.
No more beer but I can't
cut down on food.
Pack those too.
Have you paid
for them madam?
That's the second time
I've been asked that.
I certainly have.
See your receipt then
please, madam.
Go on,
it's okay.
So that's it.
With a receipt
you're okay.
Sir, 1.56 please.
One pound fifty-six.
May I have a carrier bag?
This is Radio Moscow,
broadcasting
for Great Britain
and Ireland.
Okay,
Banaszak.
We'll have to work
18 hours a day now
to finish the job.
I'll pay them with food
they can take home.
They've slept
three hours
after working
all night.
To make them
feel better
I'll tell them
it was five.
The only watch that
works now is mine.
Wake up!
It is Christmas Eve,
and I have not slept
for three nights.
I can't make
a mistake now.
Or Christmas
will be ruined.
That's 52 pence change.
Excuse me, I bought
this turkey here
this morning, my friends
also have a turkey.
Is it possible you could
take it back for me.
I'll have to ask
a manager,
if you can wait
a minute.
Kid over there's free
if you want to go over.
Yes, Rita,
what's the problem?
It's this gentleman, sir.
Can I help you, sir?
I'm sorry.
I bought this here
some time ago,
it's a turkey.
My friends also
bought one,
we have two,
I wonder,
may I return this?
May I have a word
with you, Mr. Rogers?
Not for a moment,
Mrs. Rostrom.
Did your friends buy
the other turkey here?
No.
Well why don't they
return theirs?
Theirs is fresh,
this is frozen.
Well actually, sir,
it isn't our policy
to make refunds.
I, I--
Oh, let me see
the receipt, sir.
Well...they tell me
that it's Christmas.
Rita, would you give
this gentlemen
seven pound,
fifty back please?
Actually you'd have been
having a late lunch, sir.
These things take
24 hours to defrost.
Well, merry Christmas
to you.
Sir?
Yes?
Merry Christmas.
The Quiet Life.
Or Sleep Complete.
Which is the cheaper?
Quiet Life.
Did I leave
the door open?
Kudaj?
Banaszak?
Wolski?
We all worked right
through Christmas.
And Saturday the 26th
we took turns waiting
for the telephone call
from Warsaw,
which I knew
would never come.
Nowak!
Banaszak?
That damn Kudaj
still waiting
to talk to
his wife.
Enough time has
been wasted.
Poland, no!
Warsaw no telephone!
B-b-b-b-b-b-boom!
Thank you.
Poland no exist.
Solidarity caput!
Oh.
It is quite clear
to me.
From now on,
this is the only
safe place
for them.
Excuse me, sir.
Did you just get
those goods here?
Yes.
Have you paid
for them?
Of course.
May I see
the receipt?
I left my gloves
on the refrigerator,
I had to come back
for them.
I see.
I'll just check
the goods anyway.
Only two loads
this time.
One I paid for.
And I better not
come back
for a couple
of days.
Hey!
From Poland,
Kudaj.
From his wife.
Censored.
Spaghetti, thermal underwear,
sweatshirts.
Save on carpet
delivery.
Start on thermal
underwear.
Time for your spaghetti,
Mrs. Kudaj.
Excuse me, sir!
Excuse me!
Your glove!
The manager would
like to see you.
This way please.
Well you are
a regular customer, sir.
My supervisor's noted
you quite often.
You don't spend
a great deal,
but you do come
in a lot.
Live nearby don't you?
Yes.
Yet you always
use your bike
when you come in.
What did you want
to ask me?
Just how you enjoyed
your friend's turkey, sir.
It was okay.
It's Mrs. Rostrom.
He's in conference.
Good, good.
When my supervisor told me
about you the other day,
I put two
and two together.
The man who always
leaves his gloves.
Do you mind if I see you
to your bicycle, sir?
Is this your bike, sir?
Yes.
Very nice.
It's very nice.
So this is it,
Mrs. Rostrom.
Mr. Nowak?
Yes.
Took your bloody
time didn't ya?
Three hundred and fifty
yards pine flooring.
Cash on delivery.
Two hundred
and two pounds.
I'm left with
70 pound now.
Remember me?
Yes.
Yes, you were the--
I brought these sweatshirts
some time ago.
Yes, and is there
anything wrong with them?
The size.
I need bigger.
Happy New Year.
Same to you.
I don't want
to confess.
I no longer
believe in God.
I'm here to find
my...self-respect.
I chose those men
because they were stupid,
I thought I could
control them.
But I can't.
I'm weaker than
they are.
Banaszak!
I forgot it's
new year.
They should go to
the Polish church.
But the risk's
too great.
Huh?
I should have seen
this coming.
They've had
about enough.
I have to get
them back to work!
Whatever the priest says.
They've accepted
the deal,
but they want
their bonus
to go shopping
tomorrow.
Twenty pounds each.
I still need that
money for a deposit
to hire the sander.
There are flights
to Warsaw now.
We are booked
on Tuesday morning.
It's our last
Saturday.
What if the telephone
rings now?
We can't wait about
much longer.
They want to buy
their bloody watches
this afternoon.
But what if the phone
rings now?
Airline tickets
to Poland?
You must be joking.
No deposit,
no sander.
Yeah, I'm just gettin'
through it now.
We could deposit
our passports.
Look, we can't go anywhere
without them.
We have to go home
on Tuesday.
You want to go back Tuesday
that's your lookout.
No deposit,
no sander.
How much was it
exactly?
Sixty quid deposit,
8.60 a day, plus VAT.
That's 69 pounds 89.
Call me thief.
They'll have to let me
in sooner or later.
When they realize that
unless the sander's returned,
they'll never get
their money back.
They can't manage
without me.
They need me.
Anna.
They told me I'm free
to do as I like.
They don't want to be told
what to do anymore.
Let them try.
Hey you lot!
Switch that damn
thing off!
Banaszak,!
Switch it off!
You can do what you like
in your own country!
But if you don't stop
that noise this minute,
I'll...I'll call
the police!
Go back to Poland!
You, you, you Commies!
Morning.
We have the machine.
Ah, yeah, I'm not
the man you want.
Who's the bloody army?
Didn't think you were
going back till tomorrow.
Can I take my bleeding
coat off?
Sixty quid deposit, right.
There you are.
Bye!
They've just
discovered
their new toys
make no sound.
They have no more
use for me.
They want to finish
the job on their own.
The boss will have
his London refuge
if he ever
gets out.
What am I
doing here
with five pence
in my pocket...
and no present
for Anna?
Forty-eight pounds.
She'd like that.
Cashmere, silk scarves,
shirts, gloves, ties,
belts and other
gentlemen's accessories.
He's probably worked
here for years.
He must know
all the tricks.
I don't stand
a chance.
Ground floor.
Cashmere, silk scarves,
shirts, gloves, ties,
belts and other
gentlemen's accessories.
Well done.
You didn't even take
the price tag off.
What am I so
worried about?
Ground floor.
Cashmere, silk scarves,
shirts, gloves, ties,
belts and other
gentlemen's accessories.
Excuse me, sir.
The scarf.
Yes?
The scarf you took
from there.
Yes, my scarf I took
from there,
I left it on
the counter.
Two AM, Tuesday,
5th of January, 1982.
All we have left now
is my five pence
and a six hour walk
to Heathrow Airport.
Now I cannot delay it
any longer.
I must tell them
the truth.
What has happened
in our country.
God help me.