What will become of them without me?
It's like a stone, right here
in my chest
Him again
Go away, Arsène; don't stay here
Please go
But come back
The heat helps
I can breathe now
Have faith in hope; three days,
Columbus told them...
...pointing to the vast heavens
on the horizon
Three days, and I shall give you
a world...
...you who have no hope
His eyes opened to see it...
...in the empty vastness
Sing!
You promised, Louisa
Did I misunderstand?
Maybe I promised yesterday...
...but today...
You love another?
Answer me, Louisa
Arsène is making a fool of you, Mathieu
- Of me?
- Yes, Mathieu
I'll fix him
Arsène loves you, doesn't he?
And you love him?
Is it any of your business?
It is, and I'm going to smash him
You won't; you're too afraid of him
We'll see
He's going on the the prowl tonight
Arsène had better behave himself
You want it?
Take it
We haven't finished
You'd better leave Louisa alone, too
Are you her keeper?
I don't like people getting in my way
Nobody pushes me around
Try something and see
What are you doing there?
I got lost
Why don't you use the road,
like the others?
Hadn't you better find that shoe?
We're not staying here...
...but get dry first
When did you leave school?
At six; I left before the others
Alone?
Anyone see you?
I don't think so
You went by the woods?
Listen to me: You didn't come
this way at all
You went by the road to buy some marbles
Marbles?
Some barley-sugar, then
Buy it? What with?
Say you found the money
Say you saw me coming out of the bar
I told you I'd been setting snares
at Bassompierre
Do I mention snares?
Even to the police?
I'll find your shoe
If anyone asks, we haven't been here
Nobody will be any the wiser
No ashes here
Listen to the cyclone
Come on, we'll manage without him
There's dry wood and candles
We'll keep a blaze going
There'll be a mountain of ash
in the morning
I'll say I was here all day as well
Do you understand?
Listen, kid...
I've got to go on and tell you
everything
Try to look at me
I may be drunk, but I know what
I'm doing
I think I've killed a man
Mathieu the gamekeeper
How did you know?
He was on the prowl tonight,
to get you, as he says
Well, I got him
We fell in the water, and the stopper
came out of my canteen
I gave him a drink and we were
mates again
But I don't know what came over Mathieu;
we were both drunk
Don't worry, that happens to me
sometimes; an aberration
I can still see myself holding the trap
He fell forward, his legs thrashing
Then he stopped moving, face down
in the reddening water
When I went for your shoe
and heard the shots...
I thought: He's not dead,
he's trying to summon help
It was him
I recognized the sound of his gun
If he really isn't dead, he'll talk
You must think up another story
I'll deny what he says;
newspapers like that
Perhaps I can help, Monsieur Arsène
Try to remember what happened
Remember...
He was face down in the water...
...legs thrashing
I'll say I saw it all,
that he attacked you
Please listen to me
Do I say he was drunk?
You can trust me. I hate them.
I'll defy them all
I can't think clearly; my neck hurts
I'm going to have an attack
Were you singing?
I'll take you home
Where are we really going?
To your house
What about the gamekeeper?
Did you kill him?
What with? My gun?
With the trap, Monsieur Arsène;
you were holding the trap
Let me past
Where are you off to?
Straight home, I swear it
I won't forget
If you breathe a word of this,
I'll break your neck
I'd rather die than harm you
Harm me?
Where have you been?
Your father and brother are out
Warm up the baby's milk
There's a nappy on the line
He'll cry if you leave him wet
What are you standing there for?
I'll need you to put out the lamp
What time is it? I can't hear
the church clock now
The wind changed with the cyclone
What cyclone are you talking about?
It was a cyclone... wasn't it?
Listen, mum...
Make him stop; I can't bear it
I can't breathe
There's some gin hidden under the sacks
by the cellar door
At least I can die painlessly
What a mess
Steer clear...
...of drunks and good-for-nothings
Mum, I've got to tell you...
Where are you off to?
I'm going to get milk for the baby
She was a brave woman
Stop looking at me like that
Shit!
Have some coffee
So your poor mother's dead,
and so suddenly, too
Don't take it to heart
It comes to all of us
At least she didn't know
she was dying
What's got into you?
Little slut
Rat face!
What are you up to?
I wanted to have a word with you
Arsène and I had words yesterday;
he was drunk
Our fight was just between
the two of us
But the police arrested him today
for dynamiting the river
Arsène says he met you in the woods
last night. If so...
Yes, he did
He really came to your house,
didn't he...
...to fix an alibi with you?
I saw Monsieur Arsène in his hut
last night
What were you doing there?
I was sheltering from the cyclone...
From the rain
So you're afraid of a little rain now?
Monsieur Arsène took me there
Where were you coming from? Don't lie
- From school
- At night?
It wasn't night yet.
Monsieur Arsène said...
He wasn't capable of talking
He could walk straight
Stupid child
He always does when he's drunk
He said you'd fought and that
you were drunk, too
So you took shelter
When the rain stopped I suppose
you went home?
At daybreak. I stayed there
nearly all night
You spent the night there?
I might have known
The poor child still stinks of gin
Arsène got her drunk
I could tell you hadn't been home
Look at your hair
Her eyes are still unsteady
from the drink
I think you've told the truth,
but not the whole truth
Leave us, Mathieu
Don't go, Monsieur Mathieu
Let her be, or you'll upset her
You wouldn't let that brute get away
with as much as a hare...
...but you don't care whether
he got this child drunk
That's a matter for the police...
if the father lodges a complaint
Call that a father?
I can't question you the day
your mother died
But tomorrow I'll have ten francs
for you
You needn't tell me unless you want
Monsieur Arsène is my lover.
Ask him your questions
Is something wrong?
I must get back
Your poor mother
I'm sure you haven't a sheet
to bury her in
Once upon a time the dead
used to be embalmed
Now they're not even washed
I know the departed go to heaven,
as the curé says, but even so...
The dead were worshipped once
They were gods; real religion, that was
In here...
...you'll find some dresses
I've known you a long time, you know
They should fit you
I'll take this lovely sheet
and watch over your mother
I like the dead; I understand them
At your age, I used to be afraid,
but now I talk to them...
...and they reply... softly, quietly
Have you ever thought of death,
Mouchette?
Are you asleep?
Your little heart sleeps
Try not to awaken it too quickly
You're disgusting, you old bitch
I only wish you well,
but you're too wicked
It's in your eyes... because you
don't understand