Subtitles by DramaFever
[This is a fictional story based on
actual historical figures and events]
Did you see the guest's face?
I did open the door for him.
Our goal is the State Palace.
This was an unexpected event.
Use this opportunity to get a
clear look at his face.
This is a heaven-sent opportunity.
Should we make the call?
It is not yet time.
What's going on?
You're supposed to
be in the bridal room.
Tell me everything that you know.
What exactly have you
done to In Yub's family?
I came running over here to
ask to you that question.
You told me not to say a word in prison.
You knew the
State Councilor was innocent.
Yet, you stayed silent.
Why?
For what reason?
Do you suspect your father now?
Let go!
I have to go. Let me go!
What do you think you're doing?
I have to see the King.
I have something to tell him.
Are you insane?
That's no place for you to butt into.
Give it back.
What will you do with that?
Those are my father's last words,
written in his blood.
In his last moments, he did whatever
he could to relay that message.
Here is the evidence
of my father's innocence.
If you show that to the King,
do you think he'll right this wrong?
It's the King's job to listen
to the plea of his citizens.
Citizen?
- You are a slave.
- Isn't a slave a citizen of this land?
If I feel something is unjust,
I have the right to make an appeal.
Get your act together.
It was the King that decreed the
death sentence upon the State Councilor.
In the end, it was the King who ordered
him to be killed, not anyone else.
Do you think an appeal from you
will make him even bat an eye?
I'm going to find out.
I'll find evidence so irrefutable,
they won't be able to dismiss it.
I'll find the real traitors and
bring them to the King.
I will avenge the unjust and
bloody death of my father!
Lift your head.
Your daughter was pregnant with
my child when she disappeared?
Yes, Sire.
Why has she kept this from me?
The Queen had sent her
away to another household
and kept her under close watch.
She wasn't been able to find a way.
She wasn't afraid to
lose her lowly life, but...
She was in fear of losing your child,
so she has been on the run.
Can you prove that what
you are saying is true?
This is what you put in your hair
before you became King.
I was told that you gave it to my
daughter as a token of affection.
When she received this...
I recall that she cried tears of joy.
The other half is in the
child's possession.
When the child was born,
he had a birthmark on his shoulder.
You will be able to verify
the child with the birthmark
and the other half of the hairpin.
Then...
where have the mother and son gone?
They were taken in by
a group of merchants, but...
they are people who never
stay in one place.
I lost contact long ago.
You must find them and bring them to me.
If I can find that child...
Then the ones who tried
to tamper with my bloodline...
The Queen and the in-laws will have to
answer for the crime they committed.
I will do my best to follow your order.
Eun Ki.
Father... are you okay with
sacrificing an innocent man?
The State Councilor's crime's are
determined by the nation.
Your father just...
wanted to keep you alive.
That is what a parent is.
She was about to be my bride.
We were going to
spend our lives together.
A noble man wanted to
run away with a servant girl.
What parent in their right
mind would allow that?
Son!
How can you be here on the
first night of your marriage?
Do your duty as a newlywed husband.
If our two families' relationship sours
because of your rash behavior
how will you take responsibility for it?
I will never... let this go.
Please tell the truth.
Tell the truth directly to In Yub.
Please head back carefully.
Wait just a little bit longer.
He must have had a lot to drink,
so he's getting some air.
Ba Woo is looking for him.
It's alright, Mother.
It's not so bad,
getting some last moments with you.
Master! Where have you been?
Master! Master!
What do you think you're doing?
How could you disappear
on your first night?
It's none of your business.
Kim Eun Ki.
I cannot let you off the hook anymore.
Didn't you already know?
Didn't you marry her off
knowing full well how I felt?
So... you think you can behave in
this irresponsible manner?
- Is that what you're saying?
- This is me doing my best.
Be satisfied that I've accepted
this marriage at all.
Don't expect anything more from me.
Where have you been all this time?
Master?
My hairpiece is getting heavy.
Isn't it hard?
Waiting for someone who isn't coming?
Isn't it difficult for you?
Because I feel like it's killing me.
What's the reason for
movement from the King?
The Defense Minister had been ordered
to find the whereabouts of a woman.
There was no way to find her,
but her mother was alive.
Today, that old woman and
the King had a meeting.
So, it's a woman that's
connected to the King?
I suppose.
Once I can verify, I will let you know.
Have you secured the item
that In Yub is holding?
I've confirmed it.
Get it and take care of it quietly.
The timing is just right, isn't it?
Her former betrothed one has just
married another woman.
She will be full of grief.
She will be miserable
enough to commit suicide.
I've seen the note,
but I could not decipher it.
In order to understand its meaning,
we need to keep her alive.
It wouldn't be wise to wait too long.
If Moo Myung cannot take care of her,
you will do it.
Keep a close eye on them.
Are you saying you
don't trust Moo Myung?
Even if it wasn't for real...
he considered marrying In Yub.
Moo Myung is not acting like himself.
Moo Myung has never shunned his duties.
That's why he's dangerous right now.
He's a person who has never
behaved this way before.
You girls are eating by yourselves?
You should share the food with everyone.
We brought some food over a while ago.
Let's see...
No one's sharing their food with me.
- I wonder why.
- Huh?
Why won't anyone eat with you?
Well, because... well...
I haven't been here long...
It's not because you
don't know your place?
We got ourselves a
fighting rooster here.
Didn't you two work in the same house?
It's not enough that you spoke so rudely
to the master that you formerly served.
You have the nerve to beat her,
and then even try to marry her?
You've got to be crazy!
You must be insane!
Is she still my master?
She and I are now at the same level.
So why do I have to crawl at her feet?
This is why you shouldn't bring
beasts into your home.
Didn't you think of Lord Gook at all?
- He was so good to us!
- That's right.
I didn't.
I didn't think about him at all!
Nobleman or not, when you fall...
you can't do anything.
What did I do wrong?
Just because you have a mouth,
don't speak so freely!
- You bastard!
- Get your act together.
You and Miss In Yub are both just maids.
Jerk! You deserve a death sentence!
Poong Yi isn't technically wrong.
I'm going to hit you again!
Just eat this.
Yes.
Did you sleep well?
Did you have good dreams?
Last night we had a very
special guest come to our home.
Yes, the King came by.
Is that true?
He left the palace in order to
congratulate you on your wedding.
Who else in Joseon can say they've
received such a guest?
How unfortunate.
I missed an opportunity
to meet the King.
Isn't that right, Husband?
Out of all the academics,
the King has high expectations for you.
He's had interest in you since he heard
about your trip to Ham Heung.
If that's the case...
I better focus on my studies.
I may not be able to perform my duties
as a newlywed husband due to my studies.
- I hope you understand.
- Still...
It wouldn't do to keep a
new bride in solitude.
That is not how a man should behave.
Wife, I'm sure he would not do that.
I'm sure you don't feel
comfortable living here.
Think of it as your own home,
and live comfortably.
Thank you for your kindness.
Wait.
My son-in-law is eager to
get back to his studies.
But what is my son up to?
I wonder if he's awake.
Is this even possible? Really?
I need to spread this around.
Yoon Seo, are you still sleeping?
What were you doing?
Were you reading a book?
Yes, well...
I'm curious,
what kind of book is my son reading?
Have you eaten?
- Father, I...
- Here, let's see.
You were looking at a picture book?
Do you intend to take the National Exam
or some sort of a courtesan exam?
- What is this, so early in the morning?
- Father, the thing is...
It's too early in the morning for this!
Don't you look at your
brother-in-law and feel anything?
You're family now, and people
will start comparing you two!
Father, I am working very hard.
But, you need a lot of good luck
to pass the National Exam.
So maybe you can recommend
me for a government post...
A son of a Defense Minister?
Getting a job through
connections is a shame!
Not a glory!
I'm going to confiscate this dirty thing
so please, get your act together!
Focus on your studies.
That crazy bastard!
Oh, wow!
Oh my...
What was the reason my husband was
so late to enter the bridal room?
Was it because of In Yub?
The thing is...
Before he was supposed to enter,
he was briefly with In Yub.
He disappeared after that.
What were you thinking,
not even informing me?
If something like that happened,
you should have come and found me.
I sat alone in the bridal room
like a dummy.
And I waited.
I'm sorry, Miss.
What did the two of them do?
What did they talk about?
From now on, watch them like a hawk.
Do not leave anything out, and tell me
everything going on between them.
Do not worry, Miss.
I'll keep my eyes on her and make sure
she doesn't go near Master Eun Ki.
No, don't.
The heart yearns for
what it cannot have.
It will be easier to
manage what I can see.
It would serve me better to
lay out the straw mat for them.
Excuse me?
When my husband returns,
get In Yub to attend on him.
Do you really mean it?
I want to observe what they do when
they're confronted with one another.
Which one is my husband's?
The one I'm making.
Do you want to make it yourself?
No.
- What did you put in?
- It's just a little something.
- Hello.
- Good day.
These are food preferences for Eun Ki,
sent by the in-laws.
He doesn't like overly seasoned food.
- And he prefers fish over beef.
- I'll take that into account.
Someone else should be
preparing the medicine.
Sincerity is half of the
process behind the preparation.
What is that, Mother?
It's brain medicine for my
son and my son-in-law.
How nice would it be if
your brother and your husband
both pass the National Exam?
Just let In Yub prepare the medicine.
The have their long history,
she has more sincerity than anyone here.
That makes sense.
In Yub.
I trust you'll prepare my
husband's medicine well.
Your Majesty.
Is it true that you could not
sleep last night, as well?
I've developed insomnia ever since
my father left for Ham Heung.
Day or night, I cannot fall asleep.
Could there be anything
more miserable than this?
With that in mind,
I'd like to prescribe a solution.
A prescription for insomnia?
I've brought a master musician.
Would you like to hear?
No, thank you.
I assume it will be
a female entertainer.
This palace is already
overflowing with women.
Then, I shall rescind the offer.
I apologize for interrupting...
Your Majesty.
Though I am a female entertainer...
I am not here as a woman.
You are out of line.
How dare you speak without permission?
That's alright.
Tell her to enter.
I will not come in and see the King.
Instead, allow me to play
my music from out here.
That sounds good.
Just play your music and leave.
Those are my father's last words,
written in his blood.
In his last moments, he did whatever
he could to relay that message.
Here is evidence
of my father's innocence.
You all better wipe
the plates thoroughly.
You better not leave water spots.
- Here, drink this.
- Hey, I want some water too.
Get it yourself.
What's with the favoritism?
- What is this? It's bitter.
- Just drink it.
- It's good for you.
- What is it?
It's herbal medicine!
Why would a slave get herbal medicine?
We prepared some in the kitchen.
It's a special medicine that's supposed
to make you really smart.
It's not like I'm taking an exam,
what would be the point?
You can drink it and get smart yourself.
So, you're giving this to me?
Wow! I'm getting more clever!
Hey!
I'm getting so smart!
Hey! Don't laugh!
Why you little...
Ji Bu...
Lim Jae Woo...
Jung...
Betrothed one...
Father... innocent...
Knowledge...
Father of betrothed?
I have a favor to ask.
You know the dagger that you gave me?
Teach me how to use it.
The main purpose of a dagger is...
to stab your target.
You can use it to make
wounds in specific places.
Being a woman,
if you can't win on your first blow...
you won't get a second chance.
So, make your first blow a fatal one.
Right here... the heart.
When you're stabbing,
hold the dagger with both hands.
Use one palm to cover the
top of the dagger's handle.
Next, hold it close to
your body and stab.
Like this... in one motion.
Here. You try.
What did your father's last words say?
He said that he is innocent.
Will that amount to anything
without a witness or a corroborator?
There is someone who
holds the key to everything.
Yoon Ok.
Did you really complete your
first night together?
Of course, Mother.
Do not keep secrets from your mother.
There can't be anything
I don't know about.
Lady, Master Eun Ki has arrived.
- Alright. Has he had his dinner?
- Yes.
He had his dinner at Sung Kyun Kwan.
I'll send a maid to bring him
water to wash his hands.
- A maid will attend on him.
- Yes, Miss.
Give him his herbal medicine
before he sleeps.
The medicine we prepared is
in the kitchen, isn't it?
Tell them to bring that out.
Why don't you come too, Mother?
Me?
You went out of your
way to prepare it.
With your encouragement,
he'll be able to study harder.
Where have you been this time?
Master Eun Ki is home.
Go and give him this.
- Me?
- It was Miss Yoon Ok's orders.
Master... I have brought
water for you to wash yourself.
They said you just arrived.
Come in.
Why does my father compare me to Eun Ki?
Why won't he just use
his power to get me in?
Why is he making me
take this National Exam?
Dan Ji!
Dan Ji, Dan Ji!
Dan Ji, Dan Ji, Dan Ji!
Come here. Sit down.
What brings you by?
Are we playing a surprise-visit game?
I'm totally open to it.
Give this back to Lady Kang.
I'm so scared, I can't do this anymore.
Okay.
No matter what the origin, I was going
to accept it since it was from you.
But I'm so scared of Lady Kang,
I can't even wear it.
I have no use for this thing.
That's right! If you get caught,
you'd be in big trouble.
Wow! Good thing we avoided that.
Dan Ji, Dan Ji, Dan Ji...
Dan Ji.
I will get a new ring, just for you.
Forget it!
How could you be so clueless
about a man's pure heart?
A thief with a pure heart?
Thief... thief?
I temporarily borrowed that
from my wife just for you.
Heaven is my witness that I
have nothing to be ashamed of.
Dan Ji... Dan Ji?
Husband... it's me.
Your mother has prepared
some herbal medicine for you.
Oh, Wife!
Please just wait a moment, Wife.
- I'm coming in.
- Wait one moment.
What are you waiting for?
- Excuse me?
- Aren't you here to wash me?
I made you a promise.
After the wedding,
you would wear two rings.
We'll run away together.
There's no other way.
If we're to be together,
this is the only way.
It ends here.
Your fate, and mine...
ends here.
Remember all our days past...
and please forget about me.
I hope that you will be happy someday.
Should I prepare your bedding?
Why are you learning how to use a knife?
Because I must fight.
I'm going to exonerate my father
of the false charges.
If you don't need anything,
I'll get going.
Eun Ki!
It seems there is someone inside.
I sent in a maid to serve him.
- Why are you doing this?
- Take out your knife!
Stab me.
You can stop me.
- I said stab me.
- Eun Ki...
Kill me now...
And get your revenge against my father.
Mother, I think we should
come back another time.
It's not the right time to...
What in the world is this?
Let's go, Mother.
I'm sure there is an explanation.
It could just be
a misunderstanding.
In Yub!
I was the one who instigated it.
Punish me instead.
You dare to lay your hands
on my daughter's husband?
Even as a lowly servant,
you still do not know your place.
You've made this mess,
and now you will pay the price.
Follow me out, right this instant.
I'm sorry about this, son-in-law.
These are the actions of a
tactless maid, please understand.
In Yub!
If you continue to interfere,
In Yub will not be safe.
Oh my! Didn't I mention that it's hot?
Mother made this medicine so that you
can focus on your National Exam studies.
I added a little something
else in there.
- What did you add?
- Dodder grass seed.
What's that, exactly?
It's a libido booster.
Wife, I can't eat things like this!
Even without this, I'm about to
break my chamber pot every night.
I might not be highly
ranked in studies, but...
This down here... no joke!
What! That's nonsense.
Since we've been married, we've slept
together twice, maybe three times.
They were annual events.
A noble lady like you shouldn't
be saying things like that.
Well, honestly...
I have something I need
to talk to you about.
I'm in the middle of studying right now.
- Later, we'll talk later.
- I've waited a really long time!
When are we going to have a child?
Once I pass the National Exam,
we'll really get down to it.
Come on now.
You've had your medicine.
Come on!
I'm really getting into my studies now.
I think I can pass the exam.
Forget about that!
Wife! Wife! Stop!
Oh my!
What is this... ouch.
What am I going to do?
My ring...
You!
Bring the Head Maid and Moo Myung.
Don't do this!
- Don't do this.
- Miss, please let go!
What's this all about?
Mother! Please punish Dan Ji!
This wench has taken everything from me.
She stole my ring, and my husband!
No Lady! I did not steal the ring.
Oh no! Dan Ji!
What are you going to do?
The moral fiber of the servants' hall
has reached an all-time low.
You two lowly slaves dare to covet the
men in this household?
Your master's husband's at that!
Dan Ji even committed robbery.
Lady, why are you doing this?
I told you,
Master Yoon Seo gave it to me.
Shut your mouth!
You hid it, knowing who it belonged to.
You are no different than a thief!
Lady, this is all my fault.
I did not raise my daughter properly.
For the crime of robbery and misconduct,
Dan Ji will be branded and flogged.
For the crime of lewd conduct,
In Yub will be flogged.
- Lady, please!
- Let me go at once!
Lady, for my sake...
please forgive her this once.
Do not do to Dan Ji
what you did to Ok Yi.
I've treated you too well.
You don't know when you've gone too far.
Do not speak so rashly.
Is Moo Myung out there?
A servant guilty of committing the crime
of robbery will be branded in the face.
I assume you know this.
Lady!
Forgive her! Lady!
Do not forget this
moment of hot suffering.
And do not touch another person's
belongings ever again.
Brand her forehead!
Head Maid! Save our Dan Ji. Please!
Lady!
No, you can't! Mom!
You should not be interfering!
Forgive Dan Ji, Mother.
- Husband!
- Dan Ji is not a thief.
- I gave it to her.
- Do not get involved.
- Get out of here!
- I was the one who was wrong!
I stole my wife's ring.
Lady... Dan Ji's mother needs
medical attention.
We can postpone the punishment
of the two for tomorrow.
We must move Dan Ji's mother.
In Yub and Dan Ji will be
locked up down here.
The punishment will continue tomorrow.
Yoon Seo and your wife... follow me!
Get me some cold water.
Bring soju and tofu too.
Disrobe her and check on the wound.
Use cold water to cool it down.
Put the cold tofu on it.
Check the inner house kitchen.
We have some badger oil left.
Bring it. It will help with the wound.
Yes.
You can't do it.
You can't take my Dan Ji.
You can't do it to my Dan Ji.
You're not going to kill her, right?
You're not going to kill her
like you killed Ok Yi, right?
Is she for real?
Be careful what you say.
Your mother was quite amazing.
Throwing her body in
the way to save you.
She was scared I'd end up like Ok Yi.
Who is that?
The Head Maid brought her up too.
She was one of us maids,
before you came.
This Ok Yi, she was like us?
When something like this happens,
is it always Moo Myung who punishes?
A noble would never get
blood on their hands.
How does he do it, even with orders?
We are all family now, after all.
You're a bit strange.
You seem like a real maid now.
I am a real maid.
I wonder if my mother is alright.
This is unfair. This is so unfair!
It was Master Yoon Seo
who came after me first.
And I'm the villain in all of this?
We were in this all together,
but only the maids' life gets ruined.
And what wrong has my mother done?
How hot it must have been...
How much pain she must have felt...
Eun...
Wait. Where are we going?
Let's go inside.
My father has agreed to save you.
You know very well that he isn't
someone who would do that.
He will keep his promise.
I threw my whole life away for it.
I'm sure you have a
lot to ask him as well.
The father of your betrothed
knows that I am innocent.
Okay.
Let's go inside.
Subtitles by DramaFever
You're like a dog that fetches even
his own family members to his master.
What kind of person is
Lord Kim Chi Kwon?
She will come to realize her
fate as a maid is set in stone.
Fine. Once I create the perfect time,
I will return.
Everything in this house is mine...
forever.
Where do you plan on selling us off to?
Look forward to it. It's a place
you'll get a lot of admiration.
I have determined where
one of you will go.
You two can decide
which one of you will go.
It must be a son...
They are looking for a surrogate woman.
What is this nonsense you're saying!