Muriel,
or The Time of Return
What I'd really like
is a chest of drawers.
Not much more than a meter wide,
to put between the windows.
If I can't find one,
I'll buy a Swedish table in teak.
I don't want to go too antique.
You're dealing with two different
tastes, mine and my husband's.
You know what I have in mind.
I'm depending on you.
I want it to be in good condition.
Good- bye.
You're so careless.
How can I sell that if it's damaged?
Didn't you hear what I said?
- When does he arrive?
- In less than an hour.
Staying long?
Please don't ask him.
He's old enough to be your father.
That's not the point.
Don't hold his age against him.
He has a hard life.
- I'm going to see Muriel.
- You'll be back for dinner, I hope.
For the first night.
Where did you meet this Muriel?
Such a strange name.
She's ill now.
No, she isn't ill.
- Damn this stupid thing!
- I've sold it. It's going soon.
You never know which period
you'll wake up to in this flat.
- Was that the Paris train?
- Yes, it was late.
When does the next arrive?
Ten o'clock tomorrow morning.
Was there a man
who seemed rather lost?
I just look at the tickets.
Thank you.
Maybe he was delayed.
I don't know.
It's so easy to miss a train.
You should have known.
Don't forget your gloves.
I'll look around.
She may be late.
Ask if there's a room here.
I don't know what to say.
Haven't you got any luggage?
It's at the cafe.
My niece is with me.
I didn't know you had a niece.
She needed a break.
I told her to come.
Quite right.
Will she stay long?
Just so that I know.
As long as you wish.
I meant to have my hair done,
but life is so hectic.
- Let me look at you.
- Later.
This is Francoise.
Meet Helene, our gracious hostess.
- Are you a student?
- I'm an actress.
- A lovely profession.
- But rather wearing.
Shall we go?
Do you have any change, Francoise?
Let me pay.
We'll walk.
I sold my car to a friend.
The weather's been ghastly.
The same in Paris.
We're nearly there.
The sea is quite close.
- Can you hear it?
- When there's a gale.
- You look cold.
- No, it's just the fresh air.
I'm glad to see
it's more than a small town.
You have no idea
how dead it is at night.
- I must get cigarettes.
- Where can we buy some?
I've got some at home.
- I only smoke Bensons.
- You must make do with Pall Mall.
- I'd prefer Gauloises.
- I've got those, too.
It's raining.
I felt a raindrop.
It's not such a great journey
from Paris after all.
We often misjudge distances.
See, it wasn't so far to walk.
- All rebuilt after the war?
- It's a martyr town.
Yes, lots of people were killed, shot.
I forget how many.
200, 3,000. I'm not sure now.
Like me, you're lucky to be alive.
I'm so moved.
I wanted to tell you...
I'll lead the way.
Excuse me, Francoise.
Here, give it to me.
- I'll walk up.
- It's on the 5th floor.
HELENE AUGHAIN
Antique Furniture
I'll lead the way.
I'm sorry the place is such a mess.
I'm still moving in, after two years.
Everything is just like you.
- Make yourself at home.
- It takes me a while to warm up.
Please excuse me
if I keep my overcoat.
Since I returned to France,
I feel cold all the time.
We could go to a hotel tonight.
Tomorrow, we'll see.
It's no trouble.
There's room for everyone here.
We will figure it out.
You cut your hair.
You used to have long hair.
- What will you drink?
- Whatever you've got.
- Any Schweppes?
- No.
- Muscat, Alphonse?
- Don't open it just for us.
You know it's no trouble.
Shall I show you where
the bathroom is?
How can we least
inconvenience you?
I could share a room with Francoise.
Let it be.
What should I call you?
Helene, as everyone else does.
Can I help?
Oh, no. I'm fine.
Oh, it's you.
Two of them?
Did he pick her up in the train?
It's Bernard.
Go on.
You don't seem to be pleased.
Go on, please.
Bernard Aughain, Monsieur Noyard
and his niece Francoise.
- You must be tired.
- We're feeling better already.
Bernard's finished service in Algeria.
- I was still there a year ago.
- We must have met.
Fifteen years I was there,
the best years of my life.
I , only twenty-two months.
A wonderful country.
The sun, the eternally blue sky.
- He looks like you, Helene.
- Funny, everyone says so.
We always resemble those we love.
To your health.
To your return.
When I think that Bernard
fought in Algeria...
Where did you live?
I ran a cafe
in the northern part of Algiers.
You know how it is. Things are
uncertain, there's a curfew...
I hear that
it's a draper's shop these days.
What was it called?
You wouldn't know it.
It was more like an exclusive club.
I was rather influential.
What is that?
Remember these?
None of your jokes now.
It's not dangerous. It's sleeping.
It will only wake up when it's warm.
Put it away.
- You're scaring them.
- I pick up spiders by their feet.
- It's his age.
- This isn't the right time.
- It's the only monster left.
- Monster?
I can't even touch a bird.
- I'm a Scorpio. Are you?
- I don't know. Lobster, probably.
It's very late.
You must be starved.
Sit where you like.
Don't stand on ceremony.
Damn! I've lost my keys again.
This is your style, Helene.
I'm very fond of crystal, too.
Mind the plates.
They're very delicate,
and I've sold them.
Bernard, get the wine, will you?
There's a chicken saute
in a light sauce with mushrooms.
You're not on a diet, I hope?
He's crazy about Italian salami.
Just like you, Helene.
Although you preferred Prosciutto.
Those were the days.
There's still some fennel
and red cabbage left.
Please, have some.
- Are the shops good here?
- I stick to the same people.
You're miles away, Bernard.
I'm going to New Caledonia.
Good idea.
Who gave you that idea?
- Who gave you that idea?
- No one.
Where were we going, Helene?
Near Estampes,
because of the mirror in the house.
It made our faces look green.
What a funny family.
We never went anywhere.
Where are you going?
I don't like chicken.
I'll cook an egg.
It wouldn't hurt you for once.
Bernard has a passion for eggs.
- Bernard, get the spoons.
- I'll get them.
Big or little spoons?
Nothing's ever simple.
It would have been easier to eat out.
Your poor mother.
- She's not my mother.
- Then who is she?
She's my father's second wife.
I was already there.
Oh, I see.
- Where's your father?
- He's dead.
I said it would have been easier
to eat out.
I'll look after you better tomorrow.
I had so many customers today.
English amateurs, connoisseurs.
They took forever to decide.
I'll help you.
- Do you like crossword puzzles?
- Not at all.
They make me dizzy.
Alphonse can't live without them.
He even had to buy a new dictionary.
His was all worn out.
They always use the same tricks
for two- letter words.
- His favorite cake.
- With lots of rum.
He can't sit still.
This is paradise.
No, thank you.
It's silly, but it makes me nervous.
It ruins my acting
when I do radio plays.
I end up saying more than my lines,
and I act poorly.
Besides, I have a very bad memory.
People with good memories
have a much easier life.
- The cake must be finished up.
- I hear honey is very healthy.
We're eating
as if we were in a hurry.
One always overeats
in the provinces.
My trade, feeding people,
takes all the pleasure out of eating.
Congratulations, Helene!
We'll come again.
I've never seen my uncle
so relaxed before.
You've transformed him.
He's usually so nervous.
- Me, nervous?
- What's the time?
Bernard!
I'll come with you.
May I?
Do people still swim in the sea here?
You don't seem to be
enjoying yourself.
- What do you do?
- You know, I'm back from Algeria.
- What did you do there?
- The same as everyone else.
Is that all?
What about now?
I'm back.
Is all this stuff for sale?
That's not for sale.
Pity, it would make
a nice paper knife.
What's your job?
- What is it?
- I'm looking for one.
- What do you hope to find?
- I'm just looking.
What?
- Do you read?
- A little.
I only read short things.
I'm too busy.
Why are you so busy?
If I was in antiques,
I'd deal in Louis XV.
You're not easy to talk to.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Go ahead.
What are you doing here?
I'm with my uncle.
Yes, why not?
Did you enlist?
Yes.
Were you unhappy?
Did Boulogne get on your nerves?
Shall we go?
Coming?
This place is an auction room.
I was an extra in a war film once.
It was set in 1830.
It was exhausting.
- I'd like to see you eat lemons.
- I've got the right mouth!
To the sea?
It's on the way.
I'm not used to walking.
- How is your sister?
- My sister?
- Francoise's mother?
- Oh, yes!
Francoise is my sister's daughter.
You couldn't have known her. She's
dead, like everyone else I've known.
I'm sorry.
I was so afraid you'd be disfigured
in the war, an injury...
I don't know.
In my dreams I always saw
your head in the shadows,
as if you wanted to hide your face.
You can sleep late tomorrow.
We all do here.
That's good. I'm so lazy.
- We'll upset your routine.
- Not at all.
Well, how are things?
Very good.
People in the north
are supposed to be aloof,
but that's not my experience.
- Is it hard to find a place?
- Like everywhere else.
There's a small core of rich people.
A friend gave me the idea
of selling from my flat.
Antiques can't be well displayed
in modern shops.
Concrete walls, large windows...
Selling at home seems the best.
People seem to think they're
getting family treasures for cheap.
I've gotten to know a lot
of households very quickly.
We should kiss, Helene.
Are you afraid of me?
It's all so much. Tomorrow...
- I'm always misinterpreted.
- That's not what I meant.
But we've become...
We've become...
We were stupid not to meet again.
- You work too much.
- I don't like to sit around.
Where the devil are my keys?
This table doesn't roll very well.
Let's not sit at the table.
It's nice here.
- Did you marry?
- Did you?
Well, I married Gerard Aughain.
He had a son, Bernard.
Actually, I think he loved me.
I was looking for security, really.
You're afraid to be the odd one out,
and you pay for it.
I've had no time to think of myself
these past few years.
I've been really busy.
I'm working 24 hours a day.
Not a moment to myself,
but I never get downhearted.
So you've been happy.
Often, you don't have a choice.
Let's not sit here.
I never thought you'd settle
in the provinces.
A seaport isn't exactly provincial.
Do you live in the same place?
I've always lived the same way,
in Paris or Algiers.
Still, an extra room
would be welcome.
- Lovely palm trees!
- You would have liked them.
I always forget to take photos.
I can't believe
I'll never see it again.
I'm so conservative.
You were impossible.
Those phone calls at all hours.
I didn't dare go out
until you phoned.
I was always late
getting to my appointments.
I cooked you lobsters
and had to eat them myself.
Then you'd turn up
just as I was going to bed.
You were furious
because I looked you in the eye.
I loved you as only
a 20-year- old girl could.
I'm curious to know
what happened after...
During the Liberation,
I loved a girl.
Do you mind if I tell you?
We have nothing to hide.
And I owe it to myself
to tell you of my life.
She'd had a terrible time in the war.
In September 1939, she was
abandoned by a good- for- nothing,
a braggart, unable to live or love.
He treated her badly.
It was her first love.
- I felt pity for her.
- That's our story!
- Not at all.
- Wasn't I abandoned, too?
- Let's not rake up the past.
- But that's why you're here.
To think that you didn't even
mention Boulogne...
It's unforgivable of me.
Our three days
at the Folkestone Hotel.
We ate sole, fish at every meal.
Yes, we got lost
by the cold storage depot.
I must go out.
Why are you looking at me like that?
- Are you disappointed?
- I can't help it.
I can't help it.
I must go out.
I was so happy to come.
Why did you invite me?
I remembered some words of yours:
"If you need me, let me know,
and I'll come at once. "
- Did I write that?
- No, you said it.
You see how I loved you.
Alphonse, this is
Roland de Smoke.
- He demolished the town in 1945.
- As a contractor.
Monsieur Noyard, back from Algeria.
Algeria?
I'd like to talk to you about that.
We are very badly informed
on this issue.
It will be a long time before
I can speak openly about that.
We need time to heal.
Roland de Smoke
once lived right here.
And then, there was a bombing.
He says my flat is where
his attic once was.
I'm ready.
- Where are the children?
- Francoise has run off, as usual.
Don't worry.
She's gone out with Bernard.
She doesn't consider me...
How old is she?
I don't deserve
such offhand treatment.
If we see them,
we'll say how worried you are.
- We're late.
- Don't be so worried.
I really shouldn't have come.
I was better off in Italy.
Well...
His hair is quite white.
Quite white?
Yes.
It's quite natural for him
to have white hair.
He is just as I expected him to be.
Although his eyes...
Roland, what's the matter?
I lifted the cover.
Muriel's eyes weren't closed.
It's war. Only civilians
can think as they please!
Then I noticed he no longer
washed his hands.
He claims the soap
is harmful to skin.
They have their revolution.
What have we got, back in France?
People thought we were engaged.
I began to see the truth with Muriel.
Since Muriel, I can't really live.
I'm lost. I think I want to die.
Anyway, I'm not afraid.
Poor Helene.
Anyway, he didn't come alone.
He brought his niece.
- Lf I received such a letter...
- What would you do?
You know me.
Disappointed?
Where is the sea?
It's disappeared?
It's high tide, though.
Is England straight ahead?
I was going to stay near Paris.
Without your uncle?
You've known since the beginning.
He is not my uncle.
I met Alphonse a year ago.
A boring story, after all.
- In Algiers?
- No. In Paris.
I met him at the radio studio.
I don't know what he was doing there.
Nothing, probably.
He laughed, so did I.
- Love at first sight.
- Could be.
He used to get tickets
for dress rehearsals.
He got me the part in that war film.
I could have kissed him.
He took no advantage of it.
I was the one to thank him
as he deserved.
It was only fair.
- Why tell me all this?
- Because you asked.
I used to spend
a lot of my time in cafes.
I was only getting
bit parts of two lines.
I'd had enough of auditions,
"We'll let you know."
I'd had enough.
Do I shock you?
No. I know how it is.
You're not listening.
It's none of my business.
I don't want to be unhappy.
I'm afraid that if I'm miserable,
I'll never get over it.
I wanted to be a stage actress.
You sound as if
you were applying for a job.
As a kid, I acted the role
of a woeful child.
With Alphonse,
I can relax and breathe again.
He's clever.
He's clever and elusive.
I'm well aware of it.
"Very timely," he said
when he got Helene's letter,
all boyish.
I must leave you now.
I'm more or less engaged to a girl
who lives near here.
I won't be long. About an hour.
I'll meet you at the Amyot cafe,
over there.
You're not spending the night
shuttling between her and me.
There's no point in talking.
You're very much like a boy I know.
Tell me later.
I mustn't keep her waiting, you know?
I understand.
Isn't this your scarf?
I found it in the roulette room.
Thank you.
- I took the liberty to run after you.
- Thank you.
Alfred told me
you were unlucky tonight.
A bad day.
My mind wasn't on it, that's bad.
I'm sorry, I have nothing left.
Are you married?
My wife is the blonde cloakroom girl.
So you spend the winter together,
when the casinos are closed.
We work on the Riviera then.
That must be nice.
I don't know. It's very overrated.
Can't you both retire soon?
We'll get divorced first.
We haven't had time until now.
- Is it all over?
- It never began.
When I'm older, I will do as I please.
- Good night.
Will you come tomorrow?
Maybe.
I've got relatives staying with me.
Well...
Where is Francoise?
She was going to see a film.
- What do you think of her?
- Nothing.
I forgot to tell people
where to sleep.
You could sleep
at the Borges' upstairs.
Alphonse can sleep
in the living room.
Francoise can have your room,
and then we'll see.
I'll sleep in my studio.
Be careful.
The ceiling isn't too safe.
- Do you want a drink?
- No.
I just saw you as I went by.
Don't go to bed too late.
- Did you lose?
- My luck will change.
- Good night.
You're back late.
You shouldn't have waited for me.
Where do I sleep?
That's right, I forgot to tell you.
In the living room.
I'll make the bed.
Something to drink?
Still doping yourself?
Not at all.
Just sleeping pills, that's all.
When is the train for Paris
tomorrow?
Pardon?
When is the train for Paris
tomorrow?
Forgive me.
You have few nights alone.
Must I make an appointment
to see you?
What about that evening in June '39,
your birthday?
Where were you?
We even looked for you
at your mother's.
And that Sunday when I waited
with the picnic basket?
Everything is so difficult.
I used to disappear
so as to make you want me.
It was silly.
I would wait for you to call,
to look for me.
I could see it all,
me in tears and you laughing.
It never happened like that.
And tonight?
It's nearly one in the morning.
We must rest.
Do you keep
the demolition man waiting as well?
What am I to you?
You don't mean what you say.
Am I supposed to be a reminder,
nothing more?
Isn't this the "come and see me
before I die" act?
I don't know
what possessed me to do it.
We are never really
in control of our feelings.
I could have chosen
not to write to you.
I could have played dead.
But suddenly,
I remembered your hands
and in the street,
someone spoke with your voice.
I turned, it wasn't you.
Is Simone dead?
- No. Who told you that?
- Who told me she had disappeared?
She's alive.
Stop her coming here!
- Why?
- I don't know.
Do you want a pillow?
I wonder where Bernard took her.
Did you notice
how he looked at me?
You're imagining things.
He only occupied Algeria.
What does he know about real war?
Well, you should understand.
Leave Bernard and Francoise
to live their own lives.
That morning, I went to
the one cupboard that hadn't burned
and found nothing
but white ashes inside.
Rain dripped onto Bernard's bed.
He was still terrified.
Aughain looked at me.
I took them both to my place.
The silverware had melted in pools.
Bernard wouldn't let me
out of his sight.
That's why he looks at you
as if he must justify himself.
It hasn't been easy, loving him.
Could I have a front door key?
I'll leave one outside
for Francoise tonight.
All these memories, Helene...
I resent you for them.
One o'clock already.
Is there a photo shop
open tomorrow?
I'd like to have a photo of you.
You know I always look
as though I'm blind in photos.
Must we be so formal?
Where is Francoise?
Are you all right?
I am so worried.
Any plum brandy left?
Francoise will sleep in your room.
I must ask the Borges
if you can sleep there.
You could have cleaned your room.
I already told you,
I'd rather sleep at the studio.
- I'm taking the newspaper.
- But it's not in good shape.
I don't know why you like going there.
It's dirty and dangerous.
Don't be so careless.
Just for tonight.
Tomorrow I'll go riding very early.
- Alone?
- Ciao!
- Is Muriel better?
- Who said she was ill?
Why snap at me?
Have you got a clock?
If anyone asks for me tomorrow,
don't say where I am.
Don't over wind it.
Alphonse?
Come in.
I can hear voices in the dining room.
It's the neighbors.
They talk all night long.
The plumbing carries their voices.
- I can't understand them.
- They're southerners.
Why didn't you come
to the Globe d'Or?.
I wrote in September,
just after war was declared.
I asked you to come
to the Globe d'Or.
I never got any letter.
Of course you did.
Was that to be the end?
I wanted to marry you.
I asked if you would be my wife.
I waited at the Globe d'Or
until midnight.
I didn't know what to order next.
You're lying.
- I swear...
- Don't swear anything!
I mailed it at the main post office.
There was a Sunday pickup.
What's the time?
Quite early, about 9:00.
I had a horse once,
when I was in Australia.
Are you new here?
Yes. I like this place.
The police doesn't bother you?
No. I've got a license
to gather mussels.
Listen, you can probably help me.
Where could I find a mate
for my goat?
- You must know lots of people.
- Of course.
For my goat!
- Did Marie-Do stop by?
- I haven't seen her.
No, the Casino will close
for the winter soon.
Claudie, I can't explain
everything all the time.
Believe me.
Thank you.
I swear.
I don't know, Claudie.
Can you manage 10,000 francs?
I didn't realize what was happening.
I screamed.
Everyone's jumpy sometimes.
He looked nice.
He was more surprised than I.
Extraordinary things
always happen to you.
You're cold. We'll go back.
I know your throat.
It's always easier to talk
outdoors, isn't it?
- What's this?
- That's a piloconte, sir.
Ah, a piloconte.
I used to have a trout pool
for my customers.
I reckon you could do
with less staff here.
I'd like to open
an exclusive snack bar here,
a buffet for rich people.
Just what I keep saying.
Good- bye.
- It's a small town.
- You must know everyone.
You think you know someone well
because you are on first-name terms?
- Darn.
- What's wrong?
Does it show?
Not even a window latch
for me to salvage.
- Not even a window latch for me.
- No kidding!
Is this a documentary?
Even worse.
You scare me.
Mind you, I'm no mover.
Isn't this one cheaper?
What are we waiting for to be happy?
What are we waiting for to party?
You're not sleeping?
Did I wake you?
- I dozed off. What's the time?
- About 2:00 or 3:00.
- I dreamt about you.
- You shouldn't.
Don't do that while I'm here.
Don't close your eyes, Marie-Do.
I'll take a bicycle instead.
I have another one.
Excuse me. Do you have
a Monsieur Noyard staying here?
Noyard.
Disappointed?
I got a letter from Transat.
I'm going to Montevideo.
- Is it certain?
- For three years.
It will go by quickly.
We'll talk it over later.
But I couldn't have.
We were
the victims of circumstances.
- But you believed her? Why?
- You were capable of anything.
- But you believed her?
- I did and I didn't.
Me? I'd want to see you die?
Nobody knew this woman.
I would cross the office I was
working at, pass the typewriter.
I would cross the courtyard.
I can still see it.
The shed was in the back,
with the ammunition.
I didn't see her at first.
I stumbled over her
as I went up to the table.
She looked asleep,
but she was trembling.
They said her name was Muriel.
It probably wasn't her real name.
There were five of us around her
discussing it.
She had to talk before nightfall.
Robert bent down
and turned her over.
She moaned.
She had her arm over her eyes.
He let go,
and she collapsed like a sack.
Then it began again.
She was dragged by her ankles
to the middle of the shed.
Robert kicked her.
He pointed a flashlight towards her.
Her lips were swollen
and flecked with foam.
Her clothes were ripped off.
She was propped on a chair,
but she fell.
One arm was sort of twisted.
Finish it!
She was beyond talking, anyway.
I hit her, too.
Muriel groaned under the blows.
My hands hurt.
Muriel's hair was all wet.
Robert lit a cigarette
and went up to her.
She screamed.
She stared at me.
Why me?
Then she closed her eyes
and began to vomit.
Robert sprang back in disgust.
I left them then.
I went back later.
I lifted the cover.
As if she'd been a long time
in water,
like a sack of potatoes split open,
blood all over her body,
in her hair,
burns on her breast.
Muriel's eyes were open.
I almost didn't care.
Maybe I didn't care at all.
I went to bed.
I went to sleep.
Early next morning,
Robert disposed of her.
Where is that boy now?
Walking around Boulogne,
like everybody else.
Like you?
Well, there are always things
you can't anticipate.
When you start to dig...
Me, I stay in my corner.
We would have had to hide.
You wouldn't have let me go to war.
We would have tried
to cross the border to go to Spain.
We would have lived
in Madrid like poor refugees.
I could have introduced you
to my family.
You always imagined me
to be an orphan.
My sister, my finishing school
friends, my dog Lucky.
Then, we could have gone
to Africa together
on one of those sailing boats
that carry oranges.
It isn't worth worrying about.
The main thing is for you
to feel at home here.
Look at me through it.
Hurry. The van is waiting.
Come in for a minute.
I'm not going to buy that table.
It's too expensive.
- Are you alone?
- Here, yes.
- You look pale.
- I'm frightened.
- Why?
- I don't know what will happen.
What more did you expect?
I wonder what I am doing
with my life.
Later I'll be my age.
Do I look my age?
You are in such a state.
He's cold all the time.
I know he can't help it.
His overcoat and cigarettes
are always lying about.
I'm just as bad, I know.
But still, I am mad at him.
Bernard sneers,
and you think I'm ridiculous.
No.
I should have sorted things out
by myself, not involve everyone.
I should have gone in hiding
with Alphonse as soon as he arrived,
just us two, far from here.
It's my concern,
but everyone pokes their nose in.
You're very unkind.
Love affairs are like dinners.
Some guests behave. Others don't.
I should have worked it out alone.
I should have... I ruined it.
And this flat...
I wanted it to be
extraordinary and wild.
You need sleep.
That's just it,
I've slept like a log.
Hello.
- Is it 220 volts here?
- Yes. Roland was saying...
What were you saying?
- Shall we go back?
- Where?
We must go.
Can you see me with Helene
in ten years?
I don't see you with her now,
but she loves you.
That will pass, now she's seen me.
Do you know what you're doing?
I'm thinking of you.
That's easily said.
And I'm thinking of her.
But memories of you
come more easily to mind.
It's just as though...
- And especially those...
- Finish your sentences.
I know I'm not making sense.
Give me your hand.
We'll leave tonight.
I'll leave you in Paris.
We can't go on after this.
- What about me?
- I mean it. It's inevitable.
I'm late!
You know I don't like to run.
That's him, indeed.
- Do you know where I can find him?
- No, but Marcel will know.
There's plenty of time,
that's what's so marvelous.
It was here.
Poor Folkestone Hotel,
it's a crossroads now.
Madame Aughain,
don't forget that round table for me.
- No, I...
- Remember that buffet?
You promised,
but someone else got it.
- There you are.
- Shall we have a drink?
- I never go to cafes.
- Today is a special treat.
- I don't know this place.
- It's nice.
Him again!
- I don't want anything.
- You must drink something.
Two beers with lemonade.
Help yourself.
Thank you.
Do you see who's here?
- Then you escaped?
- I didn't escape.
What nonsense.
- I wouldn't risk my life.
- That's what you wrote me.
- You'd escape to join me.
- But where were you?
- The war separated us.
- I can see that letter now.
We can't rehash every detail.
Well, did we love each other or not?
Poor Helene.
You deserved better.
You did.
I followed you for an hour,
then I came up to you in a restaurant.
Then a young man
came to the table.
Hello, Madame.
Hello, Robert.
Has Bernard gone to Paris?
I haven't seen him about.
No, he's in Boulogne.
- Are you on leave?
- No. Discharged.
I was hospitalized in Paris.
I was ill.
I haven't seen Bernard for a week.
- Were you badly injured?
- Just a small hole in my thigh.
Do you still live with your parents?
No. How could I?
Forgive me. I have a bad memory.
I forget everything.
Never mind.
Try to tell Bernard to go back
to his old job, will you?
You must come to see us.
Oh, I didn't introduce you.
- Is Bernard there?
- You never know when he's there.
He's discreet.
Pardon me.
I'm going up.
- What are you doing here?
- It is my place, isn't it?
It's strange to see you here.
- Will you show me a film?
- I don't want to be a filmmaker.
- I'm gathering proofs, that's all.
- Proofs? Against whom?
You wouldn't understand.
Please go.
I'm leaving.
You've been back for eight months,
don't forget.
Muriel isn't here, you know.
Can you lend me 3,000 francs?
I'm only interested in Muriel
because of you.
- Bernard.
- What?
Well, was he there?
There was the Polish shop,
then the seed merchant.
No, the Spanish grocer.
First, the florist, surely.
Haven't you forgotten
the fishing tackle-shop?
Then the hosiery.
I don't remember that one.
No, they sold cigarettes.
What are you talking about?
I haven't forgotten my street
just because it was bombed.
I've had sugar.
You're very quiet.
I never go brown.
I go red.
Helene tans well.
3 - 7 - 9, a foolproof system.
Many systems don't work in practice.
What would you have done?
Are you all right down there?
Were you better off behind your till?
I don't know if I told you,
but I was the manager.
I paid dearly
for the right to live in peace.
To our cost.
We had no transistors
to lull us in the Second World War.
Why did you leave Algiers?
You didn't want to serve Arabs?
I respect all races,
even if I can't stand Arabs.
Finish without me.
Don't forget this.
You could be
a little more considerate.
You're right, it's better if you go.
You've changed,
and I know who's changed you.
Whereas you don't change.
The things they invent in the news.
I read today
of a prisoner in Indochina
who was released
five years after the war.
Alphonse loves the bizarre.
What can be done with him?
It's like my story of the subsiding
house, which you all surely know.
It's that tall building
which looks like a tool chest.
They went through all the planning,
a 300-page quantity surveyor's report,
they began construction
with a 1,000-page specification
and full insurance cover.
The building went up.
Every doorknob,
every timber in place.
The block was finished,
windows glazed, but...
It is slipping on a subsiding cliff.
So we wait for it to collapse.
It's new, empty,
and we wait for it to collapse.
It will be an ugly ruin,
concrete and twisted iron.
And not even a window latch
for me to salvage.
Not even a window latch for me.
They never serve us scallops
at the Casino.
Sometimes we have tuna or flounder.
It's a revelation.
- They're wonderfully light.
- Southerners don't eat them.
There's a wonderful restaurant,
Chez Adrien, king of the lobster,
next to the St Lazare
train station in Paris.
You see him boil lobsters alive.
You get used to it.
Like with eels.
If this cook hadn't survived
deportation, the recipe would be lost.
I'll try to make some like it.
Give me a fresh grilled herring.
With mustard sauce.
With a cigarette in his beak?
A man's not a bird.
- He's got an eagle eye.
- That's a strange bird.
I can sell you 200 windows,
95 assorted doors,
30 fireplaces and 150 used cars
in perfect order.
Also the marble staircase
of the old Folkestone Hotel.
- And the submarine?
- The navy wouldn't sell it.
And a convoy of trailers
and six plane engines.
Would you have a fur coat
by any chance?
Where are we going?
I'm taking Francoise
to see the trawlers.
I'll bring her back.
Good night.
- She doesn't mean to be rude.
- Never mind. She's young.
- But I do mind, Helene.
- Stop worrying.
I must repay you tomorrow.
I've lost the keys to my desk.
It's better not to be young
like Francoise, but like you.
Good night.
- Aren't you going home?
- I'll be back soon.
Are you going to the Casino?
Shall I come, too?
You wouldn't enjoy it.
I won't be long.
Watch out.
He's spoken to me about you.
Who?
This Alphonse, who has
invited himself in your flat.
- I have no illusions.
- You'll find him gone one day.
I've heard his story,
seen his hands, and I know.
Lend me some money.
I must have some.
Stop gambling.
He doesn't trust you.
We suspect each other,
that's the problem.
Give me 20,000 francs.
I'm holding a bond on your flat,
don't forget.
I know, my sweet.
It's good business for you.
- Your Alphonse is afraid.
- We're all afraid.
Yes, but fear makes you forget.
You know how much I loved him.
Good night, Claudie.
Thank you.
Hello.
It is you, Alphonse.
Is it you, Alphonse?
This is Ernest.
Hello?
- Did you lose?
- Why?
What's wrong?
I don't want to blame you,
but you must admit...
Did I hurt you?
We must leave.
Why didn't you go to bed?
I never know what's on your mind.
It is as if you forget I'm here.
The forest,
trees without birds, rain.
You're gathering twigs,
making a pile of them, lighting it.
You tend the smoldering wood.
An hour later, the wood is blazing
in the rain, you get lost in a frenzy.
You run to tend to the fire, you dance
around it, carrying me along.
Darling, you're soaked to the skin.
You're so reckless.
That day I knew I loved you.
It's hard to follow you.
Helene?
I tried to kill myself.
Today?
Of course not.
You know when it was.
I still bear the scar.
You went to a meeting.
You never asked me any questions.
You don't care.
How often did you pretend to die,
bringing Simone running?
I can't help it if I have a hard life.
Don't answer it.
Why did you invite me?
We'll have lunch at home tomorrow.
We'll invite Claudie. It will be fun.
Helene.
We're back.
I'll get it.
Yes?
Yes.
Yes, one moment.
For you, Alphonse.
Yes, this is.
No, certainly not.
Where are you?
Certainly not. I'll come.
A liner has run aground,
all lights blazing!
It's fantastic!
It looks like a carnival float!
What a sight!
It's so close, you could swim to it!
Is it for television?
A beer.
What are you doing?
Hiding away?
No.
You don't come around anymore.
Not in bed yet?
I go to bed late now.
For a change.
Two Saint-Jacques.
- Alphonse.
- Shut up.
I know that boy.
- Helene said you should...
- Go back to my old job, I know.
You were supposed to be here
two days looking for a job.
You disappeared.
Simone's frantic.
- What about our plans?
- All off.
- But we agreed...
- That's all past.
I look around all day.
I've got an interview tomorrow.
What is courage?
You wouldn't know.
Who is this Aughain woman
you're staying with?
I'm taking you home tomorrow.
You and your camera!
What do you expect to film at night?
Give me two more days.
I'm expecting an answer.
I know what I'm doing.
Call Simone.
She just wants to hear from you.
You want to tell Muriel's story?
- It's impossible.
- Shut up about Muriel!
Two more days.
Call Simone. Don't let me down.
Have you got money?
It's a trap, really.
You dramatize everything.
You're right.
You must go.
Roland? It's me, Helene.
No. I'm frightened.
What shall I do?
You had blocked your door.
You lived in a dressing gown
and ate yogurt.
Marie-Do, don't close your eyes.
Bernard!
You should film that stranded boat.
It's like a monster.
Muriel, come here at once!
Some people attract stains
more than others. I'm one of them.
Good- bye.
Robert followed me.
I'm sure he's after me.
I'm afraid.
- Are you sure?
- You don't know him!
You're right. I'll talk to him.
Marie-Do, it's so easy
to be happy with you.
Listen, Claudie, I'll give you half
tomorrow, I promise.
I think it would be best if you left.
Wouldn't it be more convenient
if I stayed?
Where's the town centre?
This is it.
I'll stay in a hotel
until you're ready to leave.
Why?
I'm sorry I've met Helene.
Mireille's trying to find
a complete edition for him.
Algeria is all over for us.
The loudspeaker cars, the public
speeches, the leaflets, all gone.
We're in France.
The main thing is for every
Frenchman to feel alone, scared.
He'll erect barbed wire
around his little ego.
He doesn't want trouble,
so let's keep him guessing.
- Do you enjoy the situation?
- You bet.
Are you still on about Muriel?
Is that your trouble?
What about the amnesty?
The others should hide, not us.
- Worried about me?
- No, but you're still in a mess.
Do you want to die?
Why say that?
- Don't trust that little Marie-Do.
- You're a bastard.
Good evening.
You know everyone!
Don't wait for tomorrow!
Enter today!
Enter our great contest
"The Future is Ours"!
That's where I used to live.
I miss you, Helene.
We'll bring you oranges!
I couldn't come yesterday.
Never mind. I managed.
- A woman was asking for you.
- Young?
She looked like a Parisian.
- Any message?
- She seemed in a hurry.
Hello. Monsieur Noyard, please.
He's out. Who's calling?
Parting is so final.
No, it isn't,
or people would never part.
If you leave,
I'll never see you again.
I wouldn't leave if I thought that.
- Lf you leave, you won't see me again.
- You don't mean that.
It's a country house.
We want to keep its style.
- It hasn't got any style, really.
- Well, it's old.
I've got just the right wardrobe.
I'm sorry, my husband's asleep.
He has a weak heart.
Anyway, I don't have it all here.
Can I take you to see
some furniture tomorrow?
- Can one mix styles?
- Certainly.
Have you got a painting
of some charming ruins?
Or, rather,
a cliff with little temples?
With jolly fisher folk
and lots of sky?
We'll call again.
I'll show you out.
Thank you.
It's nice to soak up the past,
especially in this town.
- They saw you on my bed.
- I was doing nothing wrong.
Somehow, I've been able
to sleep again in your house.
I've fixed up a bedside lamp,
so you won't strain your eyes.
- No one's watching.
- Let me finish.
Finish what?
You asked me to come here.
I hurried without a thought.
With you , one never knows
the right moment.
Alphonse, can't we be done
with the past?
We are.
It's nice to think it's a
common enough story, really.
It's amazing, you think you know
someone you love.
But you're wrong.
Every person is a private world.
I hope you'll need me
for years to come.
- Will you need me for a long time?
- Always, I hope.
I bet you've been through my things.
- Looking for what?
- Just looking.
- I wanted to marry you.
- Don't be idiotic.
It's difficult enough living with you.
- With me?
- Near you.
You've touched my tape recorder.
I only moved it to make room.
What's on the tape?
Secrets? Confessions?
I've had enough of this dump
that feeds on memories.
What a family!
And now you slap me!
A pair of ancient lovebirds.
- And you, you're crazy!
- That's possible.
I let everyone know when I'm fed up.
Don't worry about me.
I'm going.
You can stay.
A bar of Chocoreve.
I could have sworn
you were Mrs. Clore's daughter.
I'm often mistaken for someone else.
Bring me the napkins, over there.
Hold them flat.
Linen creases very easily.
Thank you.
When are we leaving?
You said we were leaving.
I can't do that to Helene.
She's so considerate.
We could wait a day or two.
Time to let her know.
Did you really love Helene?
Did she love you?
How do you expect me
to answer that?
Yet she invited you back.
She needs to have
her world around her.
Alphonse, how you've aged
in a few days.
If we met now,
I'd help you cross the street.
I'm going to leave.
Are you mad?
I'm changing the reel.
Too late now.
Are you making yourself useful?
We must help Helene.
Why stare at me?
I'm trying to picture you in Algeria.
I'll talk to you when I'm dressed.
I'm not afraid.
Good. The children
will dance at the wedding.
I'll buy you
a ticket for Paris tomorrow.
Why not tonight? I'm packed.
I wouldn't like to be you.
I put an end to things very quickly.
Easily said.
- Eavesdropping?
- I'm waiting outside my door.
Don't take it out on the azalea.
Visitors don't seem to please you.
Is it normal to stroll around all day?
Is it normal for Alphonse
to meet so many people?
Is it normal to go through our things?
He doesn't even have the guts
to defend his opinions.
I know what I'm talking about.
I've watched him in cafes,
buying drinks for ready listeners.
He goes into all the cake shops,
as if half-starved.
- Don't you know?
- Are you finished?
Are you beyond reproach?
Haven't I been indulgent enough?
My brooch, it disappeared ages ago.
I didn't sell it.
Here it is.
Bernard, what does this mean?
I'm moving to the studio.
We'll get on better apart.
It's too bad, you're always late.
Watch out!
- Hello, Claudie!
- Hello! Do you know Marc?
- No. Hello.
- I'll lead the way.
Hello.
I've brought Marc, do you mind?
Another cactus?
- Where can I put this?
- In the kitchen.
I found a hairdryer,
did I tell you?
Excuse me.
Poor Marc, he was like a lost soul.
Here is what I brought.
There's mayonnaise.
Lobster, cold meats,
cheese and pickles.
Helene, Champagne!
Remember that day?
The restaurant where
I ordered people to stop eating?
One woman offered me a ring.
She took us for thieves.
We were so drunk!
The car ended up in a pond.
We had missed the road.
The wheels were covered in grass.
Where's Bernard?
I thought everyone had forgotten
how to laugh.
Let's make punch!
Remember that punch at the Casino?
You never told me where
you wandered off to, afterwards.
Phone for you.
- I'm not here.
- Tell him yourself.
I'll say that you're out.
Hello. Mr. Noyard isn't here.
It must be hard for an actress
in the provinces to be discovered,
even in Paris.
I gave Patachou a manicure.
She looks younger in person.
She's not bad.
She's very good!
No, she's not bad.
He hung up.
But I can't believe it.
It was Ernest's voice.
I stopped, I looked at him, and I told
Francoise, "That's him, indeed."
He was dressed
in a ski outfit, in June.
I asked him what he was up to.
You'll never guess his reply.
"I'm going skiing on pine needles.
It's better than snow."
Record us on your tape recorder.
It's very funny.
I never recognize my voice.
It's broken.
Tape recorders
are too personal, too fragile.
I had a big one in Algiers.
I recorded music on the radio.
It must have been lively
at your place.
Yes, very lively.
Well, as lively as one could be
down there.
I won my trip to London.
You lost the bet, pay up!
I can't find the nutcrackers.
Won't sugar tongs do?
Don't worry,
the glasses aren't valuable.
- I think the doorbell rang.
- I'll get it.
No peace, even on Sunday.
- Madame Aughain.
- It's you, Ernest!
You know me?
- I'm Helene. I'd been told...
- Me too.
How nice to see you.
I recognize you now.
You used to be so thin.
- Come in. We're finishing lunch.
- No, I'll wait.
Alphonse is here.
No doubt it's him you're after.
So he came to Boulogne for you?
For me?
A ghost, Ernest Choisy.
Bernard Aughain, my friends,
we'll make room.
Take my place. I'm done.
Well, I work long hours, yet I read.
I read until the book
drops from my hands.
He's a fishy guy from the suburbs.
He's still hungry,
so he says he didn't eat well.
I only like books
that I have seen as films.
He's like a cat.
He can smell the lobster.
- How long will you stay?
- As long as you.
- Here on business?
- No.
When I tracked him down...
He's the man skiing
on pine needles!
- How long since we last met?
- Exactly seven days.
I'll get it.
It's the way a dish looks,
that makes me hungry.
For you.
Thanks, Claudie.
It was a nice thought.
I'm sorry I came empty-handed.
Cars aren't the only things
that go fast.
That go fast
It's infuriating
Time flies
In such a crazy hurry too
Take it easy, Mr. Time
Slow down, there is a turn
My hair is grey, but only yesterday
I was a child
It's true
I'm going grey already
When you turn 30
You start saying "already"
When talking about your age
Then at the age of 40
You start saying it more often
But at the age of 50
You tend to say "already" less often
And when you're really old
You don't say it anymore
But you often look
At your old photos
You see yourself as a child
In your mother's loving arms
And she was surely saying
"He's six months old already"
If only women could be 20 forever
And men could be 30
What a dream
But we must grow old
We must die
There's happiness around
But we can't see it
We like to fear the future
Regret the past and say:
"Already, already, already"
Gallant Lindbergh flew here
Not so long ago
Yet how long ago that is already
And further back we count
The heads of presidents
And going back further
We find Cecile Sorel
Despite our cunning and tears
Fate toys with us
All things pass
Let me speak, Alphonse!
I'm not here for fun!
I do not want to meddle
in Helene's affairs!
She's a big girl.
Let's talk about Algiers.
He whines about it,
but he never set foot there.
Never, I tell you.
Did he tell you he was
a secret agent in 1945?
Four identities,
hobnobbing with royalty,
high life in Cairo,
his film productions.
Yet he's more discreet
about his bankrupt restaurant.
I've come for you, that's all.
You see, he's married
to my sister Simone.
I'll speak as I please, Alphonse.
You're bankrupt.
Simone is alone,
stuck with the restaurant.
I can't help out anymore.
Why are you back with Helene
after all these years?
Why, I don't know.
No one ever knew
what you two wanted.
That's what killed Simone.
Yes, that's what
almost killed Simone.
We were buddies during the war.
Those were your best years.
Alphonse, you're coming with me.
When his Algeria story will get old,
he'll tell other stories!
Yours, Helene!
Why not tell Helene about
the appointment I made with her,
one Sunday in September 1940,
at the Globe d'Or?.
Yes, to tell you...
It's not worth the effort.
You wouldn't understand.
And I never sent my letter.
You and your "love"!
That's not love!
I'll take you back, Alphonse!
- I'll take you back!
- Get my tape recorder.
I'll take you back!
I didn't start it on purpose.
All I heard was laughter.
Don't look at me like that.
Was it you?
Was it friends?
Someone who's dead?
Excuse me.
Helene!
Helene, where are you?
Is that you, de Smoke?
Helene's disappeared.
It's serious.
We must find her.
I don't know.
Yes, perhaps.
- Do you live here?
- Yes.
Robert!
- Robert!
- What's wrong?
Come down.
- Come down!
- Why?
Come down, I say!
No, don't!
Monsieur!
Have you found a mate
for my goat?
For my goat.
Helene!
I was going to write to you and say,
"Let's bury the past."
And here you are.
You've taken the initiative.
Thank you.
Antoine will be pleased.
He's so fond of you.
Come in.
Antoine, guess who's here.
We've got a rush job for a wedding.
The bridegroom's suit.
You know the man.
The son of Maurice, the little chap
who had a crush on you.
- How about some coffee?
- Nothing, thanks, Angele.
We saw your sister.
She's changed a lot.
She'd be delighted to see you again.
How's Bernard?
We haven't seen him for ages.
- He's well.
- Is he thinking of marrying?
At his age, one settles down.
He's just out of the army.
All you think of is marriage.
One of our neighbors is
a different man after army service.
The little girl's asleep.
She looks like you.
She's so good.
Thanks for the money order.
There was no hurry.
Luckily, she didn't get sick
last winter.
- Did you hear that?
- It was a plane.
No!
I hope it wasn't Bernard.
I'm going.
Remember the holes in the roof?
The charred linen,
the melted silver?
The snow fell on my bed.
It wasn't snow. It was rain.
Your hair was white with plaster.
I'm going away.
I'm saying good- bye.
I don't think I'll be able
to come back.
You haven't got any money.
It doesn't matter.
Stay here with us.
You look awful.
Give Helene some brandy.
Where do you want to go?
- We must let Muriel know.
- Who is Muriel?
Bernard's fiancee.
But I've never seen her.
Bernard told me
about a Muriel he knew.
Better not disturb her.
If only I had done
what I should have done!
Bernard can't be far away.
He'll realize we're worried.
He will surely come back.
How nice if it ended like that.
I need some cigarettes.
- Where's the train for Paris?
- It doesn't stop here anymore.
You must go to the new station.
Things change.
- Will we convince them?
- I hope so.
That would solve everything.
Alphonse.