DIJON - SPRING 1954
For the wounded in Indochina.
I have no change.
Red Cross for the wounded
in Indochina.
Tightwads!
Let's try somewhere else.
MURMUR OF THE HEART
Did you hear Jelly Roll
on the radio yesterday?
There was a fantastic piano solo.
For the wounded in Indochina.
Are you crazy?
I'm tired of the old jazz.
Always the same thing.
The music store has
the new Charlie Parker.
Let's go.
- You got money?
Ouch! You've got nerve
coming here for that.
I have no money.
Besides, I'm against the war.
It's for the wounded.
Same thing.
Go see the boss. He's a sucker.
- Come with me. I'm shy.
Listen, I'm all for charity,
but TB, nuns, old folks,
cancer, blue babies - there's a limit.
But this is for France, sir.
It's a great record. Charlie Parker
solos with a rhythm section.
The loony bin made him even better.
- What's the loony bin?
The madhouse, stupid.
Is he crazy?
Nervous breakdown.
Lots of jazzmen have them.
And no wonder -
alcohol, drugs, women.
You count it.
And don't steal it all.
Where's my book on Corneille?
I'm not done yet.
I need it for homework.
Get your father to help.
My father's no intellectual.
He makes washbasins.
Relax. You'll have it tomorrow.
What are you doing, Joseph?
I've got a record
that'll knock your socks off.
Written and Directed by
LOUIS MALLE
I ought to fire you!
All you do is mess up!
It's not that hard!
Stop crying! I hate that!
Medical secretary
is a serious profession!
Now, now, Solange, don't cry.
Take my handkerchief.
Come, I'll drive you home.
Hello, Augusta.
Is Mama home?
Of course.
You know what time it is?
Where's your cap?
Thomas, I'm no fool.
With your grades,
you'll fail your exams.
As sure as two and two make four.
You sure they make four?
Five, if you like.
My Renzino, how are you?
Why are you so late?
- We collected for the Red Cross.
Good. You got some fresh air.
Thomas, you're going to fail your exams,
and your father'll be furious.
It'll ruin everyone's vacation.
Marc, you filthy pig!
Don't do that in my sink!
First, Dad couldn't care less anyway.
That's not true.
Second, you said you yourself
never passed a single exam.
But I'm a girl.
And look what happened.
I'm completely ignorant.
Thomas, that's too much!
Give that back! You've stolen
enough from me already!
This time I'll tell your father.
Stop it, both of you!
What an example for Laurent!
I'm an old lady!
You have no respect!
Bastard!
I need that money.
The Cintra bar
won't serve me anymore.
It's bad for my reputation.
You shouldn't be going
there anyway.
Take it.
I'm too easy on you.
But stop helping yourself.
It's getting out of hand.
I never know how much I have.
You'd never do that to me, Renzino.
You're no thief.
No need to be.
He collects in the street.
Solange is impossible.
Two appointments
for the same time again.
She's crazy,
and she never stops eating.
But otherwise she's charming,
isn't she?
Yes, she's charming.
What did you do today?
I had lunch with the Desages.
Their son is at Dien Bien Phu.
They're very worried about him.
Why did the French
get into that hellhole anyway?
'Cause our generals are incompetent.
Everyone knows it.
War is too serious
to leave to the military.
That's original.
There're plenty of civilians
in Indochina.
Rotten politicians
lining their pockets.
You voted for them, Daddy.
So now I pick the ministers?
Did your deputy
vote for the government?
Yes or no?
Is that my fault?
Leave me alone.
We'll see if you do any better.
I don't vote, so I shouldn't talk,
but colonial expeditions
are a bit passé in 1954, no?
Renzino, if you don't eat,
you won't grow big and strong.
What's the matter?
It's your favorite dish.
I'm not hungry.
Leave me alone.
Stop treating me like a six-year-old.
Don't speak to your mother like that!
Augusta, serve him.
I won't eat.
I said I wasn't hungry.
You're getting on my nerves.
You won't eat?
Then leave the table!
Get out!
Is that how you raise your sons?
Don't be so hard on him.
He's very sensitive.
Sensitive!
He's a pain in the neck.
He's been unbearable lately.
Go kiss him.
You know you're dying to.
After all, he's your son.
And yours too.
If you took more interest -
I've given up.
Two idiots and a little genius -
it's too much!
Your father's right.
I should be angry with you.
Come listen to my new record.
You know I hate jazz.
And your aunt and uncle are coming.
I can't avoid them again,
though they're no fun at all.
Will you come say good night?
- Do you deserve it?
- I don't care that much.
Liar.
Are you going to study?
Promise you'll wear your glasses?
I've come to put
my darling Renzino to bed.
He's the most darling,
the most sensitive of all.
Mama's favorite,
always first in his class.
What?
Not wearing your glasses?
You'll never be a gynecologist
like your daddy.
We have an account to settle.
Don't act innocent.
Your gallant act with the money.
Know what you are?
A collaborator!
I ought to cut off all your hair.
Listen to this.
"But as Camus wrote,
the only serious philosophical
problem is suicide."
Perhaps action is a way
of avoiding suicide."
You really get something
out of what you read.
Send it to Camus
with an autographed picture.
"To Albert, from his young disciple."
How soft and sweet and pink!
Good enough to eat!
- He's got a hard-on!
The choirboy has a hard-on!
Shame on you!
I didn't even notice. You're gonna
have a tiny dick, like Marc.
You're both off to a bad start.
Some sex life you'll have!
Oh, yeah? Look here.
Bigger than yours already,
and I'm still growing.
Midget!
Wanna see a man's dick?
I might scare you.
Great!
You need a magnifying glass.
Want to measure?
Go get a ruler.
Size isn't everything, you know.
It can even be bad for your health.
- Seven.
- No, 6 1/2.
What are they doing?
I'm not hard.
That's my normal size.
Filthy pigs! Shame on you!
Look! Isn't it gorgeous?
I liked it better
when you were children.
If only you'd stayed that way!
Not bad what you wrote last night.
But drop Camus.
He's not worth it.
If you're into suicide, read Crevel.
- Who's that?
A surrealist who gassed himself.
You ever felt like committing suicide?
You?
Once or twice.
Take General Lasalle.
Called "the finest sword in the empire."
You know what he said?
"A cavalryman still alive at 30
isn't worth his salt."
How old was he when he died?
Shot in the head at 32,
at the Battle of Wagram. Not bad.
Oh, no, I'm late!
Morning, Father.
Chevalier, this is too much.
This is the last time
you serve mass.
I helped a blind man
across the road.
Don't give me that nonsense!
He's cranky this morning.
You know it's Friday.
Compulsory communion. Did you fast?
No. What's it to you?
A rebel now, eh?
Children, there'll be no sermon today.
The news from Dien Bien Phu
is very troubling.
The last survivors face
hand-to-hand combat,
outnumbered ten to one.
Let us pray for these heroes
who've gained the world's admiration
in recent weeks,
and particularly for two
of our former students who enlisted,
François Barsac
and Pierre de Chambiges.
We've had no news of them.
I hope that one day, if called upon,
you'll be worthy of their example.
And don't dawdle.
Yes, Father.
Want one?
No, sacrilege doesn't interest me.
It's like blasphemy:
It means you still believe.
I'd like to see a black mass
I read about.
The real thing,
said by a defrocked priest
and celebrated
on a naked girl's belly,
a whore hired for the occasion.
To think someone might
do that in Dijon.
I knew you'd be early.
I skipped a class.
Some schoolboy.
Where do you live?
- Rue de la Barre.
- Not far from me.
- You ever smoked?
- Yes, once.
Then this'll make it twice.
Like it?
You got the latest Tintin?
But the one before it
was funnier.
- What's wrong?
- Leave me alone.
Why aren't you at school?
Your mother just went out.
Did you study hard?
Want some cream puffs?
Leftovers from lunch.
Everyone complimented me
on them.
Go to hell!
What language!
I'll tell your mother.
That'll keep you busy.
One really has to be a saint
in this profession.
What is it?
- I want to talk to you.
- Get out of here!
- Know what I just saw?
Tell me later. Come on, out!
Solange, get rid of him, will you?
The boy's crazy.
I don't know where he gets it.
Hi, Joseph.
Need any help, little bugger?
Go to hell, Thomas!
You know what'll happen?
You'll Iose your mind
and turn impotent!
Your teeth will fall out!
You 'Il be the shame
of the whole family!
At least put on your glasses!
Know what I heard today?
Baguemouille, the ear man,
the one who interned with me -
he got a professorship.
He can't tell an earache
from pneumonia.
Don't exaggerate.
He's a little overrated, maybe.
His wife's connections helped.
She knows the right people in Paris.
She's a snob.
She's a pretty woman.
And she spreads it around!
Good evening, Claudine.
Forgive me, Léonce.
I really must pick up my watch.
It's been at the jeweler's six months.
No kiss?
- No, no kiss.
Don't worry, Mama.
He's a bit tired tonight.
You know Pleven seized L "Express?
You think the government will fall?
I hope so.
They're all puppets anyway.
Great for our standing abroad.
We look like fools once again.
Mendès should be elected.
He's clever.
Being clever isn't enough.
Does he have character?
What we need is a Clemenceau.
Or de Gaulle.
Why not Pétain?
What do you young people think?
We young people don't give a damn.
Chevalier, confession.
Father Henri's waiting.
I'll go after gym.
Don't push!
Be sure to watch your butt!
Hello, Father.
Oh, it's you, Laurent.
If confessions weren't compulsory,
I'd never have the pleasure.
You exaggerate, Father.
How are your two brothers?
Very well, thank you.
Glad to hear it.
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
I confess to Almighty God,
the Blessed Virgin,
St. Michael, St. John,
and the apostles Peter and Paul,
that I have sinned
in thought, word and deed
through my most grievous fault.
What were your sins?
I lied to my parents.
I swore.
I smoked in the bathroom.
Is that all?
- I stole a book the other day.
- What book?
The Girls by Montherlant.
Nothing else?
No wicked thoughts?
Sometimes.
Did you abuse yourself again?
Yes, Father.
How many times?
Quite a few.
Alone?
Yes, except twice
with my brother Marc.
Sit down.
I want to talk to you as a friend,
not a confessor.
Do you realize how serious this is?
If you don't stop these bad habits,
God will turn away from you forever.
We're all such weak...
pitiful creatures,
prey to the vilest temptations
of the flesh.
For those who vow chastity,
it's a struggle, believe me.
Such temptations come with your age,
and you give in to them.
But watch out.
You'll form habits
that you'll later find
impossible to break.
Think of your future wife.
She'll expect the same purity of you
that you'll expect of her.
I'm confident you'll master this.
We have high expectations
for you.
My, what muscles.
Do you do much swimming?
You've developed a lot in a year.
I bet both my hands
won't even go around your thighs.
See? They don't.
Congratulations.
Mens sana in corpore sano.
May I go back to gym, Father?
I have to absolve you first.
For penance, say 30 Our Fathers
and 30 Hail Marys.
- Thirty?
- The penance must equal the sin.
They punished
my whole class Saturday.
What for?
We put a bra on the statue
of St. Thérèse.
You're such babies.
You know what my brothers did?
You know that big statue
of St. Ignatius?
They hoisted it
onto the chapel roof.
My parents were furious.
- Were they caught?
Someone squealed.
They tried claiming it was a miracle.
They got expelled anyway.
- Your brothers were great.
- They still are.
I just read The Little Prince.
Great book, don't you think?
Not bad. A bit overrated.
Stop the dirty war!
Peace in I ndochina!
Michel, if your father
saw you here!
Madam, this child is entitled
to his political opinions.
Just getting home now, Laurent?
Out running around again!
You'll start with the course we're on.
Renzino, darling, give me a kiss!
Did you put your glasses on?
Clara, stop treating him like a baby.
Charles, you know
how sensitive he is.
He's a pain in the neck, you mean!
But do as you like.
He's your son.
Augusta, another bottle, please.
I'm thirsty.
What? You drank
all that already?
It's always the same
with your parents away!
Why are they in Paris?
Your father's
attending a conference on VD.
What a filthy job!
I'm warning you,
that's the last time!
That's good.
What pigs!
What are you doing, you pig?
I'm not changing the tablecloth!
You may go.
I'll ring when I need you.
You can bet I'll go!
You ever play "spinach tennis"?
No. What's that?
You'll see.
It takes real skill.
Watch out.
Afraid to have a cigar?
Not at all.
- Here they are.
- We brought you something.
Careful, it's still wet.
I just finished it.
This is amazing!
You've got talent!
They really do look alike.
Let's put it up right away.
You can't tell them apart.
- What'll we do with the real one?
We could sell it, buy a boat
and go to Tahiti.
Don't be a fool,
or I'll do time for forgery.
We'll see. Hide the real one.
If they notice,
we'll say it was a joke.
I'm thirsty.
All gone.
I'll go down to the cellar.
Not dancing?
Don't you know how?
Come on.
You're plastered!
But you're the cutest in the family.
You're worse than Thomas,
and you stink of cigars!
You have to choose:
cigars or women.
Cigars.
You bit me, you bastard!
You can't even kiss!
Shall I teach you?
Open your mouth.
Not that wide.
That's disgusting with your tongue!
No, it's not. You try it.
We're out of whiskey, kids.
I've got white wine and brandy.
You swine should be ashamed!
I swear I'll tell your parents!
Give me that!
What's this?
Leave that child alone,
you shameless slut!
Come on, get to bed!
Let them do their dirty work alone!
Dupertuis, an 11.
Pagès, average as usual,
but not average enough: 9 1/2.
Renaudin...
yours was particularly poor.
You always seem
to be translating from the Hindi.
You write,
"The human condition is thus
that it scents of divine presence."
God's not in the perfume business,
as far as I know.
You're talented, Grandsire.
Go show that to Father Superior.
I'm sure he'll appreciate your artwork.
Chevalier, you got
the best grade again,
but "in the land of the blind,"
as they say...
You've been slipping lately.
Your ideas on suicide
are straight out of the five-and-dime
of modern literature.
And from the bargain table, too.
- How was Paris?
- Just fine.
Did you see The Barefoot Contessa?
Of course.
Ava Gardner was fabulous.
Charles, you're tired.
Come lie down.
We stopped at the Dumaines'.
What a lunch!
To begin with we had shirred eggs,
then chicken à la Lucien Tendret.
washed down with a Chablis '45
and a magnum of Corton-Grancey.
And champagne with dessert,
like traveling salesmen.
We did drink a lot!
You drank a lot.
- Isn't this a wonderful painting?
- Wonderful.
Is it true your grandfather hated it?
So it seems.
I salvaged it from the attic.
It's worth millions.
- Do you like it, Mama?
- Of course. It's a Corot, isn't it?
Don't you?
- Not much.
Of course not.
Too dated for you.
You prefer Dubuffet.
My father, the smiling hero!
Laurent, my boy,
we've decided to introduce you
to the joys and sorrows of sex.
We're going to Madeleine's tonight.
No, I'm going to a jazz concert.
Who's Madeleine?
Never heard of
"L'Orée du Bois"?
I'm not in the mood.
Courage.
We're counting on you.
You'll make the grade.
How are we going?
On bikes?
Dad's lending us his car.
He just doesn't know it.
You haven't got a license.
Can't have everything.
Dinner's served.
Isn't Madame here?
No, Madame is putting
Monsieur to bed.
No, I won't go to my room!
Leave your bags alone.
What is it?
What do you want?
A kiss.
Please, sweetheart, just a kiss.
Like we used to.
You're tired.
Go and sleep!
Go to your room now and rest.
Won't you sleep with me?
Tell me why.
You won't sleep
with the big bad wolf anymore.
I'll eat you up.
You're hurting me.
You're no fun.
Where are you going?
Your father's had a bit to drink.
You look so handsome.
Sure you're going to a concert?
Don't be out too late, all right?
Watch it, idiot!
- There's not much gas.
- We're not going far.
You got any cash?
I don't.
You're my guests.
I get special rates.
Drink up.
It'll give you courage.
Who'll we give him for his first?
Dolorès?
She's got beautiful breasts,
but she rushes things.
Francine, the Belgian girl?
No, she's cross-eyed.
He'd be traumatized for life.
Don't worry. We'll ask Madeleine.
That's her job.
I'll wait in the car.
You'll save money.
Come on, move it.
And be nice to the ladies.
I'll go talk to Madeleine.
You sit down.
That boy's the same age as my son!
Can you imagine!
That's her.
She tells fantastic stories
about the days of real brothels.
She should write a book.
She's been in the business 35 years.
That's your little brother?
Not bad.
You know what she told me?
"One look at a new client
and I know what his vice is."
Do I have a vice?
Sure. You just don't know
what it is yet.
- Wanna dance?
- I can't. I hurt my foot.
Come on.
- My name's Freda. And yours?
- Laurent Del Dongo.
Not your last name.
Are they your brothers?
No, just friends.
Let's have some fun together.
They should put in an elevator here.
These shoes are killing me.
They're too small.
You like them?
- They're very smart.
Oh, I've got a run.
Come sit by me.
So this is your first time?
Don't worry. I'm used to it.
I always get the virgins.
Everything'll be all right.
Just relax, sweetie.
I never kiss customers.
That's only for my fiancé.
Come here and I'll wash you.
I washed before I came.
Come on.
You're cute, you know that?
You're big for your age.
You're raring to go, I see.
Dry off, sweetie.
Since it's your first time,
I'll take off my bra.
But you'll have to help me
put it back on.
You think I have a nice figure?
Do you like me?
I've put on some weight lately.
The food's so good around here.
I hear your friends are paying for this.
Nice of them.
Is it your birthday?
What soft skin!
Softer than mine.
You okay?
Frightened?
Don't you worry.
I'm very gentle.
Everything will be just fine.
Just do as I say.
I excite you a little, don't I?
Let me lie down,
and you get on top.
What's the rush?
There's no meter running.
Ouch, that hurts!
Gently.
I'll give you the rhythm.
You like that?
Nice, isn't it?
Not bad for a beginner.
You're gifted.
You'll be a lady-killer
when you're older.
You bastards!
You little jerks!
That's no way to act,
especially his first time!
How long is scout camp?
You going to Lake Settons?
We were real jerks last night.
We were really drunk.
When you get back from camp,
I'll introduce you to a great girl.
She'll spend the whole night with you.
Go to hell!
And leave my cat alone!
What's this?
Teasing him again?
No one asked you, Augusta.
And you - hurry up.
You have enough sweaters?
Hands out of your pockets, Michel.
- Scouts forever!
- Ready!
Long live France!
The evening spreads its velvet cloak
over the earth
This Ionely camp
wraps itself in your Iove
O Virgin of light
Star shining in our hearts
Hear our prayer
Our Lady of the Scouts
The Eag le Patrol will present
Goethe's The 'Erlking.
Who rides so late
through dark and wind?
It is the father with his child.
He holds the boy fast in his arms.
He keeps him safe and warm.
Son, why are you frightened
and hiding your face?
Father, can't you see
the Erlking with his -
Crown and robe.
My son, it is a wisp of cloud.
Darling child, come with me.
I will play lovely games with you.
So many flowers grow on the shore.
My mother has many golden robes.
Father, Father, can't you hear
the Erlking's whispered promises?
Hush. Be calm, my child.
It's only the wind in the dead leaves.
Darling boy, will you come with me?
My daughters already await you
to lead you in their nightly dance
and rock and sing you to sleep.
Father, Father, can't you see
his daughters in the dark?
My son, I see them well.
They are but old grey willow trees.
I love you and am charmed
by your beauty.
And if you're not willing,
I'll take you by force.
Father, Father, he's taking me.
The Erlking is hurting me.
The father, terrified, gallops on,
holding the moaning child in his arms.
Worn and tired, he reaches home.
In his arms the child lies dead.
Hurry up. Lights out.
Can I sleep next to you?
If you hurry.
You're always last.
- You're sweating. What's wrong?
- I must have caught cold.
The sound is quite clear.
I can only confirm your diagnosis:
rheumatic aortic insufficiency
due to scarlet fever,
and dilation of the left ventricle.
Excuse our jargon.
It merely means a heart murmur.
I really don't think it's serious.
He must have
an electrocardiogram right away.
You know the routine:
complete rest,
ice packs over the heart,
and a good dose of salicylate.
You must be careful
for a month, young man.
Then we'll see.
He ought to go
to Bourbon-les-Eaux.
There's no better place.
- And school?
- What does that matter, darling?
You just changed it an hour ago.
It's hot, so the ice melts quickly.
Keep still! It'll slip off.
- You're getting on my nerves.
- I don't care, as long as you get well.
Did you take your "sicilate"?
- Salicylate. Yes, I did.
I had a strange childhood.
Until 15, I lived like a savage
near Florence,
in a villa designed by Michelangelo
but with no bath or central heating.
I lived there with Augusta
and never went to school.
- And your mother?
- You know she died when I was three.
My father was a madman.
He got involved in politics,
so his family cut off his money.
He'd come see us,
with a different woman every time.
He'd rant and rave
about Mussolini and the Vatican,
and then off he'd go.
One day he came to get us.
The fascists were after him.
We managed to cross the border
and ended up in Paris
without a penny.
5:20!
You always make me forget the time.
This is awful!
Be a good boy
and take your temperature.
- When will you be back?
- What?
After dinner.
I hope you'll be asleep.
You're crazy!
You're out of bed, and barefoot!
Proust to amuse you
and Tintin to instruct you.
Here.
- Dizzie Gillespie? Great!
- We're loaded.
Did you win at the races?
Thomas sold a carpet
to an antique dealer.
We found it in the attic.
Five hundred francs!
We got a rotten deal,
but who cares?
I'm dead!
I screwed too much last night.
Don't make me laugh.
He claims he had Martine,
Dr. Picot's daughter,
with the huge -
All I'm saying is
I screwed too much.
Martine doesn't screw around.
Frank tried all winter.
I won't argue.
You're just children.
Now she's leaving for Italy.
I always get yelled at
because of you.
It's great to be sick.
I'm gonna stay in bed all my life.
With the entire household
at your beck and call, right?
No, just you and me.
And Gusta.
Beautiful, isn't it?
But don't let it drone.
Give it rhythm.
You understand the meaning?
- Very well. Why?
Congratulations.
It took Heidegger 200 pages
to translate two lines of Heraclitus.
Please sit down.
How are the studies?
His illness has matured him.
He won't have any trouble passing.
I knew it.
My son's a prodigy.
You'll be a genius
like your grandfather.
It always skips a generation.
Since your son is a genius,
may I suggest you treat him
like an adult?
Of course you may, Father.
It's none of his business!
That guy never stops!
How old is he now?
You're a rotten player.
I can't concentrate
with that damn TV.
Hello, sweetie.
We came to see the little wonder.
Evening, Claudine.
Does it work well?
Léonce refuses to buy one.
It's expensive,
and the programs are lousy.
How do you know,
if you don't have one?
Everyone says so.
We bought it for the children.
Hear that?
Brush your teeth!
You could kill a fly at 50 feet.
What a gorgeous dame!
Where'd you come from?
Marc, come on!
What's wrong with you?
I have a surprise for you.
A big surprise!
I'm going to college.
I passed the entrance exam.
Are you sure?
You saw your name on the list?
That's good news.
What about you, Thomas?
I don't have my grades yet,
but my horoscope isn't too good.
If you fail,
you're going to summer school.
I think the moment has come.
Uncle Léonce, what do you think
of this picture?
It's magnificent.
I love Corot.
No one can compare.
It's a little dirty.
It needs a cleaning.
Marc, leave it alone!
Are you sure it's genuine?
I think it's a forgery.
What's wrong with you?
It's beautiful.
Corots are worth a lot of money.
A painting's worth the price
of the canvas and paint.
The rest is capitalist speculation.
I don't like this picture.
In fact, I hate this picture!
Are you out of your mind?
I know, I know!
I came here a lot when I was young.
You never told me that.
Aunt Juliette had an estate nearby.
I remember I had bicycle races
with my cousins.
- You rode a bike?
- Yes, and quite well.
This is the bedroom.
The bathroom.
The sitting room.
Just one bedroom?
The letter said "Madame Chevalier
and child," so we thought -
Your secretary's crazy, Charles!
Are you full up?
We are, sir, unfortunately.
For you, that is.
Never mind. Put another bed
in the sitting room.
That way I can keep
an eye on you.
I must get going.
- You in such a hurry?
- Actually I am.
I'll try to come see you.
Bring the boys along.
If those idiots want to come.
Best time to call
is early afternoon.
All right, dear.
Two or three aren't bad,
but that's all.
You're hard to please.
An after-dinner drink, madame?
They're talking about you.
You should be flattered.
It's you they're looking at.
Then you should be
even more flattered.
Do you enjoy hotels?
- I haven't stayed in them enough.
I adore hotels.
I feel free, as if I were
starting a new life.
Even if it's only a feeling,
it's very nice.
Daddy hates hotels.
It runs in his family.
Remember your great-aunt?
The one who always said,
"Education will be the end of France."
The first thing she did in a hotel
was to take a big bottle of methyl
alcohol and disinfect everything:
sink, tub, chamber pot.
She was so clumsy with it
that she often set the place on fire!
Put your shoes outside the door.
Why are there never any hangers
in French hotels?
Good night.
Sleep well.
You have to buy me
new shoes tomorrow.
All right.
Did you brush your teeth?
I didn't want to disturb you.
It won't disturb me at all.
What time's your treatment tomorrow?
9:30.
Can you help me?
My zipper's stuck again.
I'll order breakfast
for 8:45, okay?
They'll bring the tray to your room,
and you can tiptoe in
to wake me up.
There.
What do you want?
Coffee and rolls?
Tea and what?
Orange juice and toast.
I'm sure their orange juice is canned.
What's the matter?
Don't look at me like that.
I have no sense of modesty.
Your father never could
get used to it.
How much? Ten grams?
Hold it in your mouth a while.
Your mother's very pretty.
I saw you at the hotel last night.
Next.
It's your turn.
Hello, Fernande!
Mr. Bizot, you'll never change.
Go stand at the bar.
Facing me.
Afraid I'll cripple you?
I know what I'm doing.
What's your name?
Nice name.
I had a cousin named Laurent.
Turn to the side.
Which side?
Either. We'll do both.
Lift your arm.
You're already a little man.
How old are you?
Fifteen.
This cure will do you good.
Me, I've never been ill.
Where are you from?
Paris, I bet.
You look like a Parisian.
Turn your back, sweetie.
The weather's changing.
The new moon
and the west wind will bring rain.
You Parisians don't understand
these things.
When you look up,
all you see is the Eiffel Tower.
All done.
Come here and I'll rub you down.
You mustn't catch cold.
It's bad for the treatment.
Is Malavelle your doctor?
You're lucky.
He's the best here,
but he's temperamental.
He laid into my husband
the other day.
You know Hubert, that tall fellow
you were talking to outside?
He makes me laugh, that devil.
Renzino, you know
you shouldn't run.
Introduce me to your mother?
I'm so hot.
Hubert Bizot.
Pleased to meet you.
- How about a game with me?
- I'm a very bad player.
That doesn't matter.
How about tomorrow at 11 :00?
All right, but I warned you.
He's got a lot of nerve.
Don't play with him.
You'll make a fool of yourself. Look.
What's the matter?
Are you jealous?
Not at all.
People will laugh, that's all.
You should take some lessons.
- You're right.
That charming young man
will teach me.
Laurent, wait for me.
St. Tropez isn't everything
people say it is.
- You know St. Tropez?
- St. what?
My parents have a villa in La Baule.
I came here
out of fear for Hubert.
My grandmother died of rheumatism,
my father has attacks,
and now it's starting on me.
I think it must be hereditary.
Really? You're a doctor's wife.
What do you think?
We never discuss medicine.
Isn't it always like that?
You're mother's great.
I hope to be like her at her age.
How old is she?
She's 85,
and she still has all her teeth.
The countryside here is lovely.
Very restful, in any case.
Your mother says you know Italy.
Is that true?
We lived in Naples.
My father was the French consul.
Your friend Hubert's nice.
He speaks Italian very well.
What do you mean, my friend?
He's a real idiot!
You know what he is?
A royalist, of all things!
You're flirting with a royalist!
You're behaving like a husband!
Worse! Your father never
carried on like this.
You're my prying little
French husband.
My bourgeois,
malicious,
jealous and bad-tempered
little husband!
Next.
Oh, it's you, Laurent.
You're in quite a hurry.
Oh, it's you.
You can call me Hélène.
What are you doing now?
Nothing special.
Wait for me?
If you like.
Were you afraid of dying
when you got sick?
A little. You?
Yes. I think a lot
about death in general.
You don't look the type.
- I'll show you.
- I'll never get it.
Shall we sit down?
There's a bench there.
No, let's walk.
Have you slept with him?
Me? Are you crazy?
- Have you kissed him?
- No.
He's handsome but conceited.
Does your mother like him?
- Not at all.
Do you like jazz?
Wanna hear my records?
- In your room?
- Yes. Does that scare you?
Me? You think you're dangerous?
I can't stay long.
You've got a nicer view.
Shall we trade?
All very serious.
You're really an intellectual.
Will you study medicine
like your father?
Not on your life.
I hate the Tour de France.
Where are your records?
Stop it!
Laurent, you're tickling me.
Besides, I'm older than you.
I'm 16 1/2.
Liar! You'll be 15 in October.
I asked to see the hotel register.
Daphnée and I made a bet.
I like you.
I want to too,
but I've decided to wait.
I don't want to sleep around.
Keeping yourself pure
for your wedding night?
Don't be silly.
I'm waiting to fall in love.
And I'm a little scared.
Aren't you?
It's normal the first time.
You've already slept with someone?
- Yes and no.
- What do you mean?
I can't explain.
- Your mother will be coming back.
- I locked the door.
She'll know I'm here.
She intimidates me.
What about my jazz records?
Bring them downstairs tonight.
We'll dance.
It's not dance music.
Pardon me!
See you.
"...and so ends the broadcast
of today's race."
Oh, I'm bushed!
Your friend's nice, but you're right:
He's not very smart.
That's not a book for you.
I've already read it.
Thomas lent it to me when I was sick.
- You're kidding.
- I'll tell you the story.
Don't! I haven't read it yet.
And I thought I hid it so carefully.
In any case, Thomas was wrong.
Your father's right.
I'll never be a real mother.
You've already read
The Story of O at your age!
There's no childhood anymore.
I was surprised to find it there.
- Did that shock you?
- Absolutely.
That's the last straw!
What did you think of it?
- It's interesting.
Well written.
Why not take things as they come?
Meaning?
I don't know.
Begin at the beginning.
Wait to experience things yourself.
And there's plenty of time.
I'm not rushing you.
Everyone has to discover
love for himself.
Lots of things can happen
between a man and a woman.
Better to find out for yourself,
not from a book.
Don't you agree?
It's funny.
My three sons are already men.
I can't get used to it.
Especially you.
I guess I'm getting old.
Do you think you're a man?
Come in.
Put it over there, please.
It's a nice morning,
but with the wind coming up,
we may get a storm.
Some more tea?
Laurent, don't mope like that.
I'd rather you slapped me back.
I should ask the manager
for another room.
The hotel's completely full.
Another thing:
I'm expecting someone today.
It's nothing, but -
Okay, I get it.
You want me to leave you alone.
Shall I go outside and play?
I think you're great.
I only meant
I wouldn't be here for lunch.
Do as you like.
I'll go sightseeing in Autun
with Hélène and the others.
Don't forget:
Whatever you do, I'm on your side.
Hurry up!
Hélène, what are you doing?
There's no room.
Go ahead without me.
Come on, squeeze in!
I don't feel like it.
See you tonight.
Don't be silly.
- What a pain in the neck.
- Anything to get attention.
Have you ever had cirrhosis?
A cure at Vichy would help.
I've had five of them.
Being a woman, I love fine wines.
A nice Beaujolais is very good.
Look how well-behaved the boy is.
Your mother said you'd be out today.
That's possible.
I'll have shirred eggs to start,
then foie gras and toast.
- That's not on the menu.
- So what?
The toast nice and crisp this time.
And some Chateau Laffite '47.
We don't have it in half bottles.
Who said a half bottle?
Bobet is in the lead.
It now seems certain he 'Il win
today's leg of the Tour de France.
No cigarettes, no matches,
no nothing -
what a lover!
Did you find some?
Call the concierge.
Jacques, get dressed quietly.
Are you crazy?
Come here.
Let me go!
Laurent's asleep in there.
You said he was out.
That boy is unpredictable.
Now hurry up. Let's go!
- This time it's too much!
- You 'Il wake him up!
All right, I'll go,
but you're coming with me.
Are you crazy?
I can't leave Laurent.
Don't ask me to.
- I am asking.
Just once, show me that I count.
Be quiet!
Come on now.
"I have to leave.
I'll be back in two days.
Don't be sad.
I'll explain everything.
I Iove you."
Jacq ues, stop it! Let me go!
You ' re crazy!
Jacques, stop it! Let me go!
You're crazy!
I can't leave Laurent.
Don't ask me to.
I am asking.
Please.
Who won the leg?
I don't give a damn
about the Tour de France.
I thought you were sick.
- Do I look sick?
I didn't see you this morning.
I overslept.
Is it true your mother's gone?
Seems she drove off in a hurry
with some guy last night.
My older brother broke his leg.
Did you see the news
from the Geneva Conference?
Mendès is trading off Indochina.
All those guys killed for nothing!
We've lost anyway,
so it's better to stop.
Lost for you maybe.
We'd win with more troops
and the US Air Force.
You're too dumb, even for a fascist.
I'm not a fascist, I'm a patriot.
A country's lost without colonies.
Look at the English.
I'm leaving.
The music's lousy.
You can't come in here
without a jacket.
Really? Just watch.
All lesbians.
What a waste.
And the mothers approve.
What an age we live in!
It's nothing new.
Just read Proust.
But you don't read Jewish writers.
Hubert, come sit here
and bring your friend.
Would you like a cup of tea?
Aren't you going to dance?
It would distract you.
You must be lonely.
My poor little boy.
I'm neither poor nor particularly little,
and I'm certainly not yours.
Stop it! Everyone's watching!
So it's true what they say -
you're a lesbian.
I should have known.
I've always wondered:
How do you do it?
That's enough or I'll slap you!
All right, don't get upset.
I'll tell you a secret no one knows,
not even my parents.
I'm really a woman.
We could have fun together.
You don't believe me?
Come to my room and I'll show you.
Very poor manners.
But then, what can you expect?
Is it true your daughter's a lesbian?
That's what Hubert said.
- Could you turn off that awful music?
- It's Gillespie.
I have a headache.
You don't look so good.
I've seen you looking better.
Don't cry.
It'll make your eyes red.
What happened?
It'll feel better to talk about it.
Is it that bad?
He asked me to get a divorce
and leave with him
for Paris right away.
And you refused?
I tried to explain.
He said I was a coward,
afraid of leaving everything behind.
What a dope.
He doesn't understand you.
Maybe I am a coward.
But I don't want to be forced.
I want to be free.
That's my way of loving.
Couldn't he see that?
He sees things differently.
He wanted to organize
my life around his.
What about us?
He's got some nerve.
You're not his problem.
He's very jealous.
I'm afraid of being hemmed in.
But you loved him.
Of course I did.
There are different ways of loving.
Another misunderstanding.
Did he leave?
- Yes. He's moving to Paris.
- You won't see him again?
I don't think so.
You'll find someone
who'll love you just as you are.
Renzino, you're wonderful.
What a conversation
for a mother and son to have!
Why not?
I'm your friend too.
And then?
I was alone with Gusta.
I spoke with everybody
to learn French.
That's how I met your father.
He came up to me
at Place St. Michel.
I didn't understand him very well,
but I thought he was very handsome.
He had a long beard then.
He looked like a young Garibaldi.
Who can say no to Garibaldi?
That's how I get pregnant.
- With Thomas?
Of course.
You got married right away?
It created quite a stir.
Your grandma was furious.
For the Dijon bourgeoisie,
a 16-year-old foreign refugee
without a penny -
I was some catch!
They all came to get a closer look.
"The fortune hunter,"
your aunts called me.
My French made them shudder.
What about Daddy?
He was crazy about me.
We were like lovebirds.
- Hard to imagine.
- You don't know your father.
He was very jealous then.
He almost resented me
for giving in so easily.
- Was he the first?
- Of course.
I wonder if he realizes that.
He should. It's his profession!
- May I?
- Please.
Are you playing gin rummy?
Yes, American style.
It's a special style.
It's a bit different.
I'll take one card.
I'm putting up my two.
- But that's the ace of spades.
- Yes, it has a curse on it.
That's right. I forgot.
I take nine, six, four.
I put a jack on your two,
turn and pass.
This is quite impossible.
Look, a crossed card.
Crossed?
- You never seen that?
- Never.
I'm positive.
Watch this.
Watch out for my feet!
My father adored the waltz.
What a shame you didn't know him.
He lived only for women and politics.
You know how he died?
He went back to Italy during the war
at a very dangerous time.
He was going
to join the resistance.
But he fell in love
with a girl in Milan.
He lived at her house.
That's how they caught him.
Aren't you being unfaithful
to Hélène these days?
I've never been after her.
Liar.
She's nice, and pretty too.
She gets on my nerves.
She's a tease.
What about Daphnée?
Isn't she a tease?
Sure, but at least
she's not a virgin.
How would you know?
I can tell.
Just like that, at first sight?
Pretty good!
And you? Are you a virgin?
That's my business.
Anyway, Hélène's a lesbian.
- What a thing to say!
Hubert says almost all girls are.
Not so cold!
They start in school
and continue afterwards.
Hubert certainly knows a lot.
With your stories about Father Henri,
you're opening my eyes.
Men are queers, women are lesbians -
everyone's happy.
Cold water's good for your hair.
You're hurting me.
Don't blame me.
Your nails are hard as rocks.
It's a sign of virility.
Of old age, you mean.
Must be funny being married
to a gynecologist.
You get used to it.
I've been meaning to ask you:
Is Daddy really my father?
- Are you kidding me?
- No, I'm serious.
I swear you're your father's son
and your brothers' brother.
Why did you ask?
I don't love him.
I just can't.
And the feeling's mutual too.
Laurent, stay with us.
You see how these soldiers dance?
Incredible!
A bunch of hicks!
Poor France.
What a republic we have!
Want to dance?
Can I have a drink?
You won't dance with me?
That's not very nice.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
the fireworks!
I brought you a classy lady.
Now, on with the dance!
Lovebirds, out on the floor!
May I have this dance?
I'm spoken for.
He can step on your toes
the next dance.
Want me to kick your teeth in?
Don't get familiar with me!
You're not good enough
to fight with me.
That's what you say, punk!
Take it easy!
Calm down!
That's enough now.
Go sit down!
Great timing!
Insulting the working classes
for Bastille Day!
I'll knock him flat!
Let's dance.
Here he is.
Who does he think he is, anyway?
- He's dumb but harmless.
- He's a damn snob.
I like dancing with you.
Hubert's an idiot,
but I think your mother's overdoing it.
Really?
You should keep an eye on her.
Have a drink.
Dancing works up a thirst.
This'll cool you down.
I've had too many.
- Where do you live?
- The Hotel des Bains.
Could I see you tomorrow afternoon?
I'm not working tomorrow.
Say, you're Italian, aren't you?
I knew it!
Me, I'm from Brittany.
And where are you from?
I'm from Paris.
A city slicker.
Let's take a walk in the park.
I've got something important
to show you.
Something very pretty.
It's my bedtime.
- I'll go with you.
- Don't bother. I have an escort.
She got me all wet.
Rich women are all bitches!
They're all bitches, those rich dames.
Let's go, Laurent.
No, please! Turn that off!
My head's spinning!
What a great invention,
Bastille Day!
We should celebrate it more often.
We can start again tomorrow.
No, not every night.
Oh, I'm dead!
I can't even get undressed.
I'll help you.
I don't want you to be unhappy...
or ashamed, or sorry.
We'll remember it
as a very beautiful...
and solemn moment...
that will never happen again.
What's going to happen now?
Nothing.
We'll never mention it again.
It'll be our secret.
I'll remember it without remorse,
tenderly.
Promise you'll do the same.
Laurent, what is it?
You know what time it is?
Are you crazy?
Get out or I'll scream!
You've lost your mind!
All right, all right.
I'm leaving.
Which is Daphnée's room?
- 27.
Are you going to her room?
Daphnée, open up!
It's almost 10:00!
- I'll meet you downstairs.
- We're leaving in five minutes.
Hurry up!
Wake up!
Get dressed!
You mustn't let anyone see you.
The coast is clear.
Hurry up.
Hurry, Françoise.
The Bollingers are waiting.
Isn't that the Chevalier boy?
Sneaking out at night now?
What's all this about?
The explanation had better be good.
And walking around barefoot!