Subtitles by DramaFever
[Episode 8]
Don't you think about the person that
makes food and waits for you at home?
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
Okay.
You don't even think about the
people waiting at home for you.
You're just busy minding
your own business.
Where did my cellphone go?
Look at that forgetfulness.
Hello?
- Yes.
- Oh my. President.
Looks like I left my
cellphone in your car.
Yes, you did.
Choon Hee, the mister said to eat.
Hey! What are you doing?
You came back late, and now
you're making calls again?
President, are you far away?
If you haven't gone
too far, I'll come get it.
I'm sorry, but I'm already
pretty far from your house.
I'll give you your phone tomorrow.
Okay. Please take care
on your way home.
Hurry up and eat.
I ate already.
What?
You made people wait, and
then you eat on your own?
I'm sorry.
What did you make?
Can I taste some of it?
Do whatever you want.
Jang Joon Hyun.
I can't bear it.
I must eat some.
Give me some rice.
Is that so?
How can you hit so hard?
- You smiled right?
- No, but...
This time...
it hurts a bit.
It grew so much!
Our teacher said she would
give rewards to students
who wrote a good plant
observation diary.
I can taste it, right?
It really tastes like lettuce.
Wow! It's amazing.
You're really coming down.
Does it hurt a lot?
Stop. Stop!
Hello, President.
This.
Thank you.
I can't just give it back to you.
I want to eat dinner
at your place today.
It's been a long time since
I've had homemade food.
Then I'll assume you invited me and go.
See you later.
That... That...
What's up with that bastard?
He thinks everything is about him.
Why does that bastard have
your cellphone though?
Well, it just happened like that.
Were you with that bastard yesterday?
You're not really going to
let him into the house, right?
Hey, you could have just
told him to not come.
Why are you in a hurry now?
How could I say no to him?
Oh my. When am I going
to clean all of this?
You don't have to clean carefully.
Nobody important is coming.
Hey, I'll give you this so please
go buy some groceries.
What?
By the way, there's lettuce
in front of the house, right?
Pick the lettuce and bring it as well.
Are you crazy?
I don't know about other things,
but you can't touch that lettuce.
Go and hurry back.
- Oh my.
- It's hot.
- You're back?
- I'm so tired.
Good job.
- What are you doing?
- What?
- Stay outside.
- Where should I go?
The President is coming. He'll get
the wrong idea if he sees you.
What wrong ideas?
Come back two hours later.
Two hours?
There. Come back later.
Where is the mister going?
There's going to be a guest today.
Oh, right. Byul, help me clean up.
I'm going crazy because
of that President.
Where should I spend
two hours for though?
I told you the cabinet above
the sink is dangerous.
Be careful.
No!
What's dangerous is not the
cabinet but you, you bastard!
Looks like you're really
good at cooking as well.
- Normally the mister...
- Byul, enjoy your food.
It's a relief that you
think it tastes good.
There's not a lot of
dishes, but please enjoy.
I always eat alone. It tastes
good when eating with others.
Of course! Come every day.
- I would love that of course.
- Hey. Hey.
But your sister says I can't.
Actually I asked your
sister to date me yesterday
and I got rejected.
Could you help me perhaps?
Okay! How should I help you?
Byul, don't say useless things.
Let's eat the beans. Beans...
Sister, do you not like the President?
I like him.
Byul.
Who is it?
What? What?
Something smells yummy.
Hey, what brought you here?
How can I not come when
there's yummy food?
How did you know about that?
- Joon Hyun!
- Hello.
- The President is here as well.
- Yes, Mr. Jang Joon Hyun.
Wow! It's meat!
I love meat.
Excuse me, President.
Drink with this cup please.
Yes.
Why do I like lettuce so much recently?
Have some stew please.
Just eating plain rice is delicious.
Yes. Thank you.
Yummy.
I ate meat and then fruit.
I'm so full today.
Are you not leaving immediately?
Why should I?
Are you really going to act like this?
It's really been a long time since
I had a meal as tasty as today's.
Yes.
Isn't it too much for
just returning a cellphone?
At least he knows.
No. We're really grateful that
you enjoyed your meal.
I should have treated you earlier.
Then I'll be leaving.
Yes.
Oh my.
Are you not leaving,
Mr. Jang Joon Hyun?
Me?
Please take care on your way home.
- I enjoyed dinner.
- Yes.
- Little miss, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Excuse me.
I'm saying this because I'm worried.
Don't come here often.
It doesn't look good
for the company's
President to be visiting
a singer's home.
What should I do?
I plan on coming here
often in the future.
What?
I like eating food that
Miss Choi Choon Hee made.
Sorry?
Also, I didn't come as President
of the entertainment company today.
What does that mean?
You know.
- Then...
- Yes.
I like Miss Choi Choon Hee.
Exactly what's happening between them?
Then it's a love triangle?
Hey. How can you show up
suddenly like that?
I was completely surprised.
Hey! Are you going into your room?
Hey!
Why is he the one upset?
Hey.
Are you mad because of the lettuce?
- Hey.
- What?
He likes Choi Choon Hee?
You.
That's right. You.
Here. My Byul's and mine.
Now, let's eat.
Let's eat.
It's not her eyes.
It's not her nose.
Byul.
Her mouth isn't pretty either.
Well, her smile is...
not bad.
What are you doing?
You've been weird since yesterday.
What?
You...
got mad because of the
lettuce patch, right?
What?
I'm sorry. Gosh.
Choon Hee, it says you're in third place.
What?
What third place?
Choi Choon Hee.
[Third place: "Hot Pepper"
by Choi Choon Hee]
[Third place]
[First place]
He's really not thinking straight.
You've become popular with
your trot remake album recently.
How is it? Don't you need experience
dating to sing love songs?
I've always been busy training,
so I haven't ever dated.
Training?
Yes. I used to be a marathon runner.
Wow! Your experience is really unique.
Then what are your strong points?
Strong points...
Since I did a lot of sports,
my body is pretty strong.
It's over. It's over.
Why would you mention
your body is strong?
This is the car Miss Choi Choon Hee
is going to use from now on.
I don't need such a nice car.
What do you mean you
don't need it?
Of course the company
should give you a car.
They want you to move fast
and earn more money.
- You... Seriously...
- Well, that's true.
Then work hard.
Thank you.
I have a car.
The car is really nice.
Nowadays this is just a basic car.
Why aren't you wearing the scarf?
I told you to protect your
throat so many times.
Come here.
It's stuffy.
When you're in the car, you'll turn on
the AC on a hot day like this.
Then wear the scarf like
this immediately. Okay?
Okay.
Don't drink coffee.
It's not good for your throat.
- Drink water.
- I'll get sleepy while I'm driving.
Wow. It's an honor
to be riding a car you're driving.
Relax. Now you just need
to turn right ahead.
- Turn right.
- Yes, right, right.
No, no. Turn right. Turn right!
No, no. Not that.
That one. That one.
J-Joon Hyun, go s-slowly.
- Be quiet!
- Slowly... Slowly...
Slow down. Slow down.
J-Joon Hyun, slowly please. Go slowly.
I'm really going crazy.
Smile more. Smile brighter.
Okay.
This time lean your
face this way.
Good.
Now touch the waist gently.
Like that.
Good. Great. Okay. Great.
That bastard. How far
down is that hand going?
Be a bit more closer.
Okay.
- Miss Choi Choon Hee.
- Yes?
- Have you ever dated?
- No.
This is a couple concept.
You need to feel more like
you're looking at your loved one.
Your eyes need to look
tender and teary.
Try it.
Here, here. Look at me.
Seriously...
Like this.
You need to feel like you're in love.
You need to feel nervous.
What kind of hiking clothes has
anything to do with tender and teary?
It's weird.
Where is he going now?
It turned out great.
Was my advice correct?
Yes.
It was all teary and...
The managers can just go to the hall.
Enjoy your meal.
Soo In.
Manager.
They want Choi Choon Hee to throw the
opening pitch instead of you as well.
What?
[Trot Singer Choi Choon Hee
throw opening pitch at Jamsil]
What are you going to do now?
She took over your song's ranking
and your advertisements.
And even your opening pitch?
What else is she going to take?
Park Soo In.
Listen carefully.
This world is a cold place.
Even though it took you eight years
to get to where you are now
it takes less than one
day for you to fall.
If you're going to lose to someone
who sings trot like Choi Choon Hee
then just give up everything right now.
Got it?
You've been having a hard
time recently, right?
Sir.
I'm scared every time I go on stage.
I'm stressed because
I have to take all
responsibility for the
three minutes on stage.
But when I get off the stage
the stress is even more exhausting.
Yes, it's me.
Find out everything
about Choi Choon Hee.
If you look around,
you'll find something.
Why are you like that? Are you sick?
Your schedule is so busy.
I'm just out of strength.
Should I help you find
your strength back?
What?
Ta-da.
What is that?
Take a look.
You got mad last time because
I didn't buy you a present.
When did I do that?
"When did I do that?"
This is the clothes the model guy wore.
He didn't wear it. I bought it.
Really?
Wow! If you're not going to
wear it, I will. Awesome!
What are you touching?
I should just...
Keep working.
I should have been the male model.
Thank you, Choi Choon Hee.
I'll wear it a lot.
This clothes really lets heat out well.
It's not even hot.
Maybe I should go hiking
while wearing this.
What kind of guy steals
other people's lettuce?
This person. Right now...
President?
The lettuce really grew well.
Why did you come to other
people's neighborhood?
What do you mean other
I live here.
What?
Things just turned out that way.
That's that.
Is everything going well?
Her song ranked third on
The Music Trend a while ago.
You haven't forgotten, right?
If Choi Choon Hee ranks first, you're
releasing a comeback album for me.
It's around here.
Let's meet at the Korean
sausage restaurant at four.
From God of Trot.
Welcome, dear customer.
Excuse me.
Yes, dear customer.
Do you not recognize me?
I-I'm not sure, dear customer.
Are you here to eat Korean sausage?
Yes, yes.
- Wait one moment.
- Yes.
Awesome. Awesome!
Why did that woman come here?
Hello?
Hello.
Mr. God of Trot?
Miss Ballad, Miss Ballad.
How far are you?
It's not about that.
I just met my destined companion.
I think we'll need to push back our
meeting to another time. Is that okay?
Well, that can't be helped.
You met your destined companion.
I have to give way to him.
In return, you must do well today.
Fighting!
Fighting.
No way...
Mr. God of Trot?
Then... Miss Goddess of Ballad?
What an unbelievable situation.
It's okay to rest when
you're feeling down.
What is this?
Go with the new President.
Those tickets are hard to get.
What is it?
I'm hot.
What about the fan?
We're doing well recently.
Let's buy another fan.
We don't have money for that.
- Hand it over.
- I can't sleep. It's too hot.
Why can't you sleep?
- Why?
- Then what about my Byul?
Why are you cheating and
talking about Byul?
Give it to me.
- Give it to me.
Did you come to see me?
Yes.
Do you want to go watch
an opera with me tonight?
I got two tickets.
I heard these tickets are hard to get.
I'm sorry
but can we go next time?
I need to go somewhere right now.
Yes.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Did you ask for me, President?
Get in.
- Why? Did something happen?
- You'll know after you get there.
Why?
Get in.
Get in?
Where are we going right now?
My friend asked me to bring you
so he can treat you.
Huh?
I told him about you, and
he's super curious about you.
Is it okay?
I-I... That...
[Jang Joon Hyun]
Are you not going to pick up?
Hello?
Where are you right now?
You're still in the
practice room, right?
Yes.
Well... Of course.
- Why?
- I'm going to pick you up.
You?
I practiced driving.
Therefore I can go pick you up.
N-No. You don't need to come.
Why?
I'm on the road in
front of the company.
- I'll arrive soon.
- Don't come!
I have an appointment.
Appointment?
You didn't say anything about that.
It suddenly came up.
I'll call you later.
H-Hello?
What appointment suddenly came up?
Today is the first time
I've driven alone.
Don't come if you don't want to.
Your friend lives here?
Probably.
Dal Bong, have you been well?
I told you about my friend Dal Bong.
He's my best friend.
Then the friend you
were talking about...
That was you.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
He's so pretty.
How old is he?
He's 20 this year so that's like
50 years old for humans.
50?
Now, don't stare at the horse's ears.
Look far ahead.
Do you want to try riding him?
- Me? He's moving! He's moving!
- That's right.
You're good at riding horses.
Now try riding him on your own.
On my own?
I'm scared.
Well, isn't life something you
have to live on your own?
Well, I'll be next...
I'll be next to you.
Dal Bong seems to be really gentle.
It was so hard to train
him to be this gentle.
We went between heaven and
hell at least 10 times.
Really?
He doesn't look like that.
Do you know what's the most effective
way to make a hurt heart open up?
It's to wait.
At first it felt novel.
After spending some time
together, it was fun
and I wanted to get closer with him.
At first I stayed by
his side because it was interesting.
Later on, I just wanted
to be there for him.
Then this guy...
That's when I realized that
if I keep waiting
then one day I'll win that heart.
This is why I like you.
You're always so lively.
- Let's go.
- Oh my.
Did Dal Bong hear my belly
make noise as well?
Thank you.
Does it taste good?
Yes, it tastes good.
Horse meat always tastes good.
Dal Bong.
Thank you.
You're so innocent Miss Choi Choon Hee.
Would I do that to Dal Bong?
I almost couldn't eat.
Enjoy.
Yes.
I asked them to pack up
some for the little miss as well
so take it when you leave.
Thank you.
Can you pack me one more order please?
I want to go home and
eat together with her.
Yes.
Thank you.
Twenty. There.
There.
Play better.
Yours aren't easy to hit either.
- Byul.
- It's Choon Hee!
- Oh my. Have you been well?
- Yes.
Why is it steak though?
My friend gave it to me.
You have friends that can
give you something like this?
Let's eat first.
Eat.
I was wondering when I
saw your car outside.
You didn't go the opera?
No.
I'm a bit tired.
Why? Did the new
President say he's busy?
It's not like that.
Okay.
Rest then.
Soo In is pretty and she sings well.
It won't be hard for
her to get married.
Please recommend her if there
are good guys out there.
Last time at your party I saw
this guy from Shine Star I think.
They looked good together.
But I think President Jo's
son has a girl already.
Is that so?
My son went to school
with him in New York.
Soo In, you know that too, right?
Yes.
I think yesterday he took
some girl to go riding.
Director Wang.
Find out if the new President
has a girlfriend please.
- Here is your order.
- Thank you.
Miss Choi Choon Hee.
Talk to me for a moment please.
Yes.
Where did you go yesterday?
Sorry?
Did you perhaps go horse riding?
Yes.
What's the reason you
entered Shine Star?
- I came to sing...
- Then sing. Why are you dating?
What?
You've got the President in one hand
and Joon Hyun in the other.
You're keeping both guys in your hands.
I didn't think of you like that.
Miss Choi Choon Hee, you're
really above average.
Senior, I think you've
misunderstood something.
Misunderstood?
Then why did you go ride horses
with the President yesterday?
Here's some advice.
If you're going to succeed
through seducing guys
try it somewhere else.
Shine Star is not a place where
someone like you should be.
- Senior.
- Stop calling me Senior.
I've never had a junior like you.
What are you doing right now?
It's none of your business.
How is it not my business?
Choi Choon Hee is my singer.
Choi Choon Hee, Choi Choon
Hee, Choi Choon Hee!
Why do you all only care
about Choi Choon Hee?
Soo In.
You wake up too. You
said she's your singer.
Then manage her well.
It's not good for there to be
rumors about her and the President.
What do you mean?
Don't you know that word has spread
how she's seducing the President?
What do you know about Choi Choon Hee?
She's not that kind of person.
I think you're the one that
doesn't know anything about her.
Do you know the two of them
went horse riding yesterday?
What?
Have you found out about the
President's girlfriend?
Instead of that, there's something
else that's interesting.
Something interesting?
President Jo Geun Woo.
I have something to discuss with you.
Who are you?
Let's talk after you look at these.
Go that way. I'll drive.
You?
Turn at that pharmacy there.
I know.
Hey, hey! People are
crossing over there!
Stop it!
I almost got into an
accident because of you!
I was worried that you didn't see it.
Mr. Jang Joon Hyun.
Let's talk for a moment.
Hurry up and talk.
Get out of Miss Choi Choon
Hee's house immediately.
What?
I know that you live in that house.
It doesn't matter.
I understand that a manager
needs to live with his singer.
But I'm not the problem.
A reporter came to me.
He said he'll give me the pictures if
I pay twice as much as Director Yang.
Although I blocked it this time
this won't be the last time.
Thanks for telling me
but I can't leave this house.
Why?
Because like you said, I'm
Choi Choon Hee's manager.
Let people talk.
They'll stop if you ignore them.
A scandal is the end of a singer.
Don't you know that better than me?
You're going to leave
that house, right?
Mr. Jang Joon Hyun.
You like Miss Choi Choon Hee.
I'll take care of my own business.
Is it you, Joon Hyun?
Yes.
Did you just come after parking?
Anyway, this is pretty
fast for you already.
Here.
- Wow!
- You should have said something.
You adorable guy.
Are you not eating though?
Eat.
Then we're going to eat all of it.
Here. Eat.
I'm not sure if you should do this
to people in the same company.
What about you, President?
Should you this?
You let her take away the
advertisements and even
the opening pitch of a singer
from the same company.
Why do you only help
Miss Choi Choon Hee?
Did I do that?
Well, that's true. I might
have helped her a lot.
Actually, I like Miss Choi Choon Hee.
Sorry?
Therefore you shouldn't bother
Miss Choi Choon Hee anymore.
Stop minding her business.
What? Does your throat hurt?
I'll go get warm water.
Excuse me.
I'm Miss Choi Choon Hee's fan.
Could you please give this
to Miss Choi Choon Hee?
Yes.
Even if I pass them all,
it's an endless mountain pass.
Passing by hills...
Wow! This must taste good.
Byul, do you want to try one?
Did you wash that?
Do you want to try one too?
There.
Now...
- Chicken.
- Yes. There's cherries too.
I'm listening to your song every day.
When I listen to your
song while working
I feel like I'm with you.
This is balloon flower tea that I
made for your mom whenever she sang.
I sent one bag.
What?
What is it?
Dad?
It's Dad!
- Dad?
- See?
Since you sang on TV,
Dad sent a letter again.
That's true, Byul.
I'm Miss Choi Choon Hee's fan.
Could you please give this
to Miss Choi Choon Hee?
I'll work harder. Okay?
I should have recognized him instantly.
What are you doing?
Are you crying?
You know... I'm really
going to work hard.
I want to work hard and
live with Byul and Dad soon.
You're going to help me too, right?
A scandal is the end for a singer.
Don't you know that better than me?
[Jang Joon Hyun's complete fall.
Jang Joon Hyun in his underwear.]
[Jang Joon Hyun jump.
Jang Joon Hyun crash.]
What do you mean you're
going to quit now?
Her song is already at third place.
I'll make you an album
if she gets first place.
I said I don't want it.
Did you eat something wrong?
Your comeback is right in front of you.
What are you talking about?
There's a saying that
you can quit being
governor of the capital
if you want to.
I don't want to do it.
Therefore the contract between
us is automatically terminated.
I'm sorry.
Hey, you. You! Hey!
She needs to take care of her throat
so make sure she doesn't
drink cold things.
Make sure to make ball
flower tea for her.
She needs to wear a
scarf around her neck.
And the most important thing is
she's crazy so she can't stop
practicing once she starts.
You need to stop her from time to time.
Did you get some incurable disease?
Are you going somewhere?
I know, right? Why are you
letting us be her manager?
That's because
she has sold quite a few albums.
Choi Choon Hee has grown enough.
I need to focus on my own music.
She took up so much of my time.
Can we do it?
Where are we going right now?
We're going to study music.
Is it a nice place?
Yes.
It would be nice if Byul came too.
What is this place?
Let's go in.
This "pang" noise is really loud.
The sound of the ocean.
Choi Choon Hee.
Yes?
How long has it been since
you played outside?
This is the first time since
senior year of high school.
Are you happy?
Yes. It's fun.
I'm happy too.
- Choi Choon Hee.
- Yes?
Thank you.
For what?
Just... thank you.
Then thank you too for
driving me yesterday.
I'm sorry.
For what?
Just know that I'm sorry.
That's true. There's more than
one thing you should be sorry about.
This girl...
Excuse me.
- Huh?
- What are you doing?
Studying sound.
Hey, you get this. Thank
you for your hard work.
Welcome.
It's pretty.
You like it?
Your taste...
What? It's pretty.
- Thank for your hard work.
- Yes. Goodbye.
- Yes.
- Hurry up!
It's so nice.
This is a special place
that only I know about.
You're the first person
I've brought here.
Really?
I feel honored.
You know, there are times in life
when you're hurt, annoyed
or depressed for no reason.
That's true.
There are times you want to
be comforted by someone.
Close your eyes
and try feeling it.
If you stay here alone, you calm down.
It's really nice.
Choi.
You're going to be a shining
singer no matter where you are.
Why are you giving me goose bumps?
Stop it.
My sixth sense is crazy accurate.
I know this song.
- You?
- Yes.
You know something besides trot?
Don't underestimate me. I
listen to a lot of songs.
I like you so much.
I want to tell you that
but I can't find the courage.
I like you so much too.
I want to tell you that
but I can't find the courage.
I want to say I love you.
While I'm burning like
this on the inside
I'm worried that you'll leave.
We keep worrying like fools.
One, two, three. When I see your eyes,
I'm surprised, so I turn my eyes.
My face becomes red in
front of you like a fool.
I practiced saying "I love
you" more than I can count.
But I can't say it.
Is there nothing you want to eat?
Triangle kimbap!
One that hasn't expired yet.
Why did you ask?
I'm going to make it for you.
Why?
Because I want to.
Are you not done yet?
I'm going to starve to death first.
Joon Hyun, hurry up. I'm hungry.
It's all done.
I'm hungry.
It's done.
Hurry up and bring it.
- Here.
- It looks like it tastes good.
There's a lot of meat.
Chew slowly and eat it.
This is good.
You eat too.
It's okay.
What do you mean it's okay? Here.
It's yummy, right?
Just say it inside. Why do we
have to come all the way outside?
I'm going to move out of your house.
What?
I'm going to quit being
your manager as well.
What are you talking about suddenly?
What do you mean "suddenly"?
Did you think I would follow
you your whole life?
Your life is good enough now.
More people recognize you too.
You might have forgotten
since I'm here like this
but I'm a singer.
I need to prepare for my album too.
Isn't that right?
That's true but...
you didn't say anything until now.
It feels sudden.
You asked me before
why I wanted to make you a singer.
Actually, I made a deal.
President Jo Hee Moon
said he would make a
comeback album for me
if I made you a singer.
What?
That's why the artist Jang
Joon Hyun made a trot singer.
I wasn't next to you
because I liked you.
Do you understand now?
Then what should I do now?
We need to go our separate ways now.
I'm going in first.
Here.
- I'll go to school now.
- Byul.
Do you have your observation diary?
- Oh, right.
- Oh my.
Come here.
You can't forget next time. Okay?
You can just remember it for me.
Come here.
Done.
I'll be back.
Byul.
If you get full credit
on your observation
diary, it's all thanks to me.
Okay?
Buy me food.
Goodbye, Choon Hee.
Come back soon.
The first thing on the schedule
today is the radio program, right?
Let's go.
Wait a moment.
Why?
Let's do well on today's broadcast.
Yes.
Hello, Miss Choi Choon Hee is here.
- Hello.
- I'm Choi Choon Hee.
- Please go in.
Yes.
Do well.
You're going to be here, right?
Of course.
You have to be right here.
The moment you stood next to me
I loved how you looked.
Although I cried yesterday.
Today I know
tomorrow will be happy
because of you.
I didn't need someone
handsome or cool. No, no.
I only needed a tender person.
I'll forget all the past.
Now I can't do anything without you.
I can't do anything but love.
Subtitles by DramaFever