♪ A special smile ♪
♪ A certain touch ♪
♪ I never had a love ♪
♪ That I loved so much ♪
♪ When I look back ♪
♪ You're everywhere ♪
♪ Turn the page ♪
♪ You were there ♪
♪ My one sure thing ♪
♪ My solid ground ♪
♪ All I ever wanted ♪
♪ Was the love we found ♪
♪ You came and answered ♪
♪ My every prayer♪
♪ Turn the page ♪
♪ You were there ♪
♪ You were ♪
♪ There ♪♪
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Hey, watch it, you idiots!
Be careful with those!
They're violins, not bowling balls!
- Why so many?
- [Groans]
- Boing, boing, boing,
boing, boing, boing...
- Mom?
- What?
- Which box has our toys?
What the hell is Lexi doing?
I can't hear the phone!
Yes, I'm still holding.
Okay, well, um...
Listen, you don't have
to lie to me...
because I know
that he's there.
Well, just check under Lana Holden,
Mrs. Lana Holden.
Well... okay, okay, fine.
Just tell Lieutenant Demetras that his
wife called again, will you? Please?
- And tell him that... Ma! Jeez!
- No!
- [Sighs]
- I want you to listen to me now.
You can't keep doing this to yourself
or to the boys.
They need their mother now.
- You're a beautiful, talented woman.
- [Laughing]
- You have your whole life ahead of you.
- Ma, if I'm so beautiful...
and talented, tell me
why did Charles leave me?
Because Charles
is a big jerk.
Now get dressed.
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Sighs]
What am I gonna do?
Well...
first you eat breakfast.
A little black coffee.
And then you get a job.
Any job.
The boys,
God bless them...
They're big eaters.
I can't afford it.
Well, he's gonna get
sick of her, Ma.
We'll see.
[Sighs]
Well...
in the meantime...
get a job.
Just wrap,
you're not Picasso.
Picasso would have
put the bows on the back of the box.
Brian Turner.
Roberta Guaspari.
[Laughing]
Oh, my gosh. I thought you moved away.
I did. I'm just here
for my mom's birthday.
Oh, that's nice.
That's really...
- Uh, that's for my mom.
- Oh, man... Yeah, Turner.
Very pretty though.
Oh, go ahead. Go ahead.
- Yes, I knew... I heard
you wrote a book, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- I didn't read it, though. [Laughs]
- That's okay.
Neither did my mom. Looks good
on her coffee table, though.
[Laughing]
Thank you very much,
and please come again.
[Brian]
So what are you doing here?
I thought you'd be
in Carnegie Hall by now.
It's a long story.
So my college professor said
it was too late.
You know? I hadn't had enough training
to be a concert violinist.
So I took a degree
in teaching.
I bet you're
a great teacher.
Well, I think I am.
Or I could...
But every time I would
get started on something,
Charles would be transferred.
And then I had my kids,
and I took time out to raise them.
Then by the time I wanted
to start teaching again,
nobody would hire me
because...
You know, Navy wife.
You can't count on her to stick around.
So l-l-I decided what I would do
is start my own program.
And Charles gave me
the money... to do that.
- We were in Greece. I bought
50 violins at this little Greek shop.
- "Fifty"?
And I started the program
at this little private school and, uh...
- And then...
- And then your husband ran off
with your best friend.
That's right. No, she was not
my best friend. She was a friend.
So what are you gonna do? Just wrap
presents and wait till he comes back?
You sound like my mother.
[Laughs]
Oh, God. Heaven forbid.
- [Laughing]
- I've met your mother.
- You don't look like her, though.
- [Sighs]
You know something?
I've been thinking.
I know this cool lady.
I wrote a piece about her.
She runs
this elementary school.
- It's public, but it's alternative.
- Mm-hmm. Hmm.
I don't know. I think...
I think you should meet her.
I would love to,
if you don't mind.
If it works out, you'd have
to be willing to relocate, though.
Hmm. Where is it?
- [Siren Blaring]
- [Shouting]
- [Car Honking]
- [People Speaking Spanish]
- [Car Alarm Blaring]
- [Kid] Come here!
- [Cabbie Honking Horn]
- [Pedestrian] Damn, man!
- [Gasps]
- Hey! Do what you're doing, man!
- You trying to kill me?
- Watch it, fool!
Welcome to East Harlem.
[Train Horn Blaring]
[Woman Sighs] Aside from half
a term in a private school...
in Greece...
and a year teaching chorus
in Hawaii ten years ago...
That's... the Navy.
They move you around.
Um... it doesn't look as if you've
had any other teaching experience.
Well, not traditional
teaching experience, but I have, um...
- Uh, I've given private lessons.
- Oh.
That's not on there. I...
I taught my sons.
I'd like to help you,
Mrs. Demetras.
Brian spoke highly of you,
and I told him I would consider
starting a violin class.
But without
the proper qualifications...
and without any experience
in inner-city schools...
I'm very sorry.
Okay.
Thank you for seeing me.
You're quite welcome.
[Bell Ringing]
[Children Chattering]
[Man]
What I did is change the 8... 45 to 9... 45...
- to 8:45 to 9:30...
- [Knocking]
- Come in.
- Excuse me.
- Oh, I didn't mean to interrupt.
I wanted you to meet my boys.
- [Woman] I'm sorry, Janet.
- This is Nick.
- [Nick] Hi.
- Hi.
- And Lexi.
I'm sorry. Hi. Oh, I'm Roberta
Guaspari-Demetras.
Dennis Rouche, our music
teacher and program coordinator.
Mrs. Demetras, did I not
make myself clear yesterday?
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
I just wanted to show you something.
Just take a second.
Ready, boys?
Are we having a talent show?
I should have brought my tap shoes.
Five, six,
ready, and...
Beautiful. Beautiful.
Oh...
- Will you hire her now?
- Oh!
Uh... how long
have you boys been playing?
- Since I was three.
- And you?
Maybe since I was
three and a half.
Your mom must be
a pretty good teacher, huh?
- She's okay.
- [Janet Laughing]
Nick... That's right.
You guys wait out there.
- Okay, so...
- Mrs. Demetras, if you could...
teach our students to play as well
as they do, l-I'd be thrilled, but...
I could. Any child can learn
to play the violin.
Assuming they have
the discipline.
I would teach them
to have discipline.
Mrs. Demetras, a lot of our parents
are struggling...
to feed their kids,
to pay the rent.
They don't have time
to help them learn violin.
Well, they wouldn't have to.
They wouldn't have to.
It would be great if they
wanted to help, but these kids
are going to be committed.
They would practice on their own, and
they'd help each other in the classroom.
I think I know these students,
Miss Demetras.
- Mrs.
- Mrs. Demetras.
And I can tell you right now,
their attention span
doesn't go past do, re, mi.
Maybe on a good day,
I can get them to fa.
I think you're
underestimating them.
They can learn to play
as well as any other kids.
- That I'd like to see.
- Well, you will.
Or you would... if...
I'll tell you what...
I'll put you down as a sub.
- [Sighs]
- For now.
- Thank you very much.
- But even if it works out,
the board may not let me create
a permanent position for you.
That's okay. Anything is okay.
That's great.
- I have already planned out
the whole term.
- Oh, thank you very much.
- [Laughing]
- Yes!
- There is no room for this.
Besides, where are you gonna
find money for violins?
Oh, you need violins?
- [Scoffs]
- I have violins. I have 50 violins.
Thank you very much.
Nice to meet you, Mr...
- Rouche.
- Rouche. Th-Thank you.
- Okay. Lucy?
- [Children Chattering]
[Boy] Hey, let's go get one!
Come on! Come on!
I want one!
Give it to me, now!
- Come on, I want one! Come on!
- Please, don't open...
Don't open the cases, okay, everybody?
Don't open the cases.
- [Imitating Gunfire]
- [Roberta] No guns.
Okay, now...
listen to me, please!
- [Girl] I don't like this one.
- No, no! Please, keep them closed!
Stop it, you two.
You two, what did I just say?
Stop! No, no, please, don't. Don't.
No, no, no. No, no, no, please.
just put them back
in the case, all right?
Who's plucking?
Who's plucking my violin? Hey!
Please, will you put it back
in the case right now?
Good. Okay. So today I'm going
to be dividing you all up...
- ♪♪ [Drumming, Humming]
- into five different classes.
♪♪ [Continues Drumming,
Humming]
Hello.
Come with me.
You're gonna be the first student
who is not in my violin class, okay?
I want you to go
to the office right now.
Right now.
Out, out, out.
Go on, go on, go on.
Out, out.
- [Door Opening]
- Who wants to be next?
Who wants to be kicked out
of my class?
Are you raising
your hand...
- because you want to be kicked out?
- [Boy] Yeah.
- Wh-Why?
- I don't want to learn
about no stupid violins.
- Man, violin's for wimps.
- [Class Laughing]
- Who told you that?
- [Boy] Nobody.
- I just know.
- [Roberta] What's your name?
- DeSean.
- Well, DeSean...
you didn't give me
a good enough reason, so you're staying.
Anybody else?
Very nice.
Everybody be quiet.
I'm gonna hand out
the violins.
Hey, I play pretty good.
Yeah, see how easy it is?
- ♪♪ ["Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star"]
- [Chuckles]
That's great.
You know what?
In the spring, maybe,
we can have a big concert...
- and invite all your families
and the whole school.
- [Children Chattering]
Huh?
That would be great.
- What's your name, honey?
- Naeem.
Naeem. Okay, you can
sit down, Naeem.
You're gonna be
a quarter size.
Yeah, and if you guys do exactly
what I tell you, if you listen to me,
you're gonna sound beautiful
in the concert,
and you're gonna feel so proud
of yourselves, you know?
But if you don'
listen to me,
you're gonna sound so bad
your own parents will get sick
when they hear you.
- They might even throw up.
- [Laughing]
I'm serious.
[Knocking]
- You decent?
- Yeah.
- What's this?
- A toast.
- A toast?
- To Roberta...
- for making it through the first week.
- Ah.
[Sighs]
I'm proud of you.
I really appreciate everything
you've done for us. I really do.
I swear to you...
I promise, this weekend,
I will start looking
for a place.
There's no rush, really.
No rush. It's...
No, you've done enough.
You should be writing
and not baby-sitting us.
I've been reading your book.
- I think it's really great. Yeah.
- Oh?
It's really good.
It's such powerful stuff.
Wow.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Well, thank you. [Laughs]
Um, so the next one
is on migrant workers?
Yeah.
How do you know how you...
What... [Stammering]
What you're gonna
write about next?
- I mean, how do you...
- I just follow my gut.
Pay attention to...
what I'm being drawn to.
[Laughs]
What...
What are you doing?
[Sighs]
I've been wanting to do that
since Mr. Duvane's orchestra class.
[Both Laughing]
You never noticed me
in that class.
Oh, you... You completely ignored me.
You used to drive me wild.
You had like
five different girlfriends.
I never had
the one I wanted.
That Roberta
isn't around anymore.
[Sighs]
I don't believe you.
- No, I can't... l-I shouldn't.
- Why?
- Because the boys are...
- They're sleeping.
Yeah.
Oh, man, I'm still married.
And what's your husband
doing right now?
[Sighs]
[Distant Siren Blaring]
Oh, my God.
The boys.
It's okay.
[Chuckles]
They're still sleeping.
Where are you going?
Uh... Texas.
What?
What's in Texas?
Farm workers.
My research grant?
I just got the call. It came through.
- [Laughing]
- Wow.
I've got some families lined up there,
and then I go on to California.
How long
are you gonna be gone?
I don't know.
Two, three months.
I thought
you would be around.
I... Um...
And last night...
Roberta...
last night was great,
but what did you think?
We were gonna get married
in the morning?
No, I didn't think that.
I just... We just got here,
and I barely even...
I don't even know
where to buy groceries.
You're gonna be fine.
You have a job,
a place to stay,
your kids have
a school to go to,
and there's a D'Agastino's
right around the corner.
What am I doing
right now?
- Rosining the bow.
- Rosining the bow. That's right.
And what am I doing when I tighten
this little screw,
when I turn it like this?
- Tightening the horsehair.
- [Students Chattering]
Everybody, be quiet.
Naeem?
- Tightening the horsehair.
- The horsehair. That's right.
Okay, what do we call this?
- [Snapping Fingers]
- What is this called?
Bird was shooting
them threes, man. Bird was...
- [Roberta] DeSean? DeSean?
- Yeah.
- What is this called?
- I don't know.
- Yes, you do. Why not?
- I wasn't here.
You were here, but you weren't
paying attention. You want
people to think you're stupid?
Okay, you can tell him, Naeem.
- It's called the frog.
- It's called the frog. That's right.
Okay, anybody remember
what this is?
Lucy, do you like it when people snap
their fingers when you talk?
- Yeah.
- [Laughing]
- "D," "D," "D," "D."
- ♪♪ [Recorders]
- "E," "E," "E," "E."
- ♪♪ [Continue]
"D," "D," "D," "D."
"C," "C," "C," "C,"
"E," "E," "E," "E."
"D," "D," "D," "D."
- ♪♪ [Continues]
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry.
- [Chattering]
- [Dennis] No talking!
- [Ticking]
- I was supposed to collect kids
from Miss Cooper's classroom...
for my 10:00 class,
and there's nobody there.
Miss Cooper's students
have Phys Ed on Tuesdays.
- [Talking]
- [Roberta]
But you scheduled them for violin.
You must have read
the schedule wrong.
[Inhales]
I don't think so.
Well, I can't solve this problem
for you right now.
I'm trying to teach.
[Metronome Continues Ticking]
So am I.
[Students Murmuring]
May we continue, please?
- "C," "C," "C"...
- ♪♪ [Recorders]
- But I thought all the teachers
agreed to this.
- In theory.
Adam, I want to see you
in my office after lunch.
- What did I do?
- Think about it.
Look, whenever you pull
the students out, it's a disruption.
Plus, it's extra work
on the teachers...
because they have to fill
the kids in on what they missed.
- Some of the teachers resent it.
- But can't you talk to them?
Look, I pulled this
off a second-grader this morning.
I'll help you, Roberta,
but I cannot hold your hand.
I want everybody to put
your right foot on a tile,
and then you put
your left foot on a line.
See? Because we're trying
to make a box with our feet.
- ♪♪ [Humming]
- Lucy, do you want to leave
the class right now?
Yeah, because I'm trying
to make you stand strong. See?
So strong and balanced that if I tried
to push you over, I couldn't do it.
- See?
- Michael Jordan's pretty good, though.
If you were standing strong,
I couldn't push you...
Hey, DeSean. Hey, James.
Now, cut it out.
Anybody seen Naeem?
- I saw him this morning,
but he's not here.
- I know he's not here.
That's why I asked you. See?
Okay, good.
[Roberta Chuckles]
You're not standing strong.
See? See how I could push you?
That's because your feet are not...
centered.
Somebody bring me
a chair, okay?
Guadalupe, I think it would be
a good idea for you to sit, okay?
Thank you, DeSean.
Now, who can I yell at?
Hey, Naeem!
Where were you today?
I can't be involved
in class anymore.
- Why not?
- My mother won't let me.
Why?
My son's got more important things
to do than learn dead white men's music.
[Chuckling] They're gonna learn
"Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star."
How many black classical
composers can you name?
violinists do you know?
That doesn't mean
that's the way it should be.
I mean, Naeem's learning
how to play music.
Maybe it makes him
feel good about himself.
- What does it matter who wrote it?
- Please, Ma.
Can I be in the class?
Look, I've seen this before.
You white women come up here
and think you can rescue
our poor inner-city children...
who never asked to be rescued
in the first place.
No thank you.
Come on.
Don't look back at her.
Turn your head around.
[Phone Ringing]
Shit.
Hello?
[Talking, Softly]
Where are you?
[Sighs]
Are you still with her?
Oh, God.
We've all
missed you so much.
The boys and me... We're gonna be
so happy when you come back.
I promise it will be better.
I... I...
What?
Well... What? I thought you said
that you and Lana...
You were...
That was all over.
- [Line Disconnects, Dial Tone]
- Charles? Charles?
[Dog Barking]
Mm-hmm.
[Roberta]
Yeah, that was it, you know?
No explanation.
No discussion.
No... anything.
He just...
He basically didn't even want
to talk about it.
- Just "I want a divorce. Good-bye."
- I know it's hard.
You're gonna
get through this.
You will.
You'll survive this. You will.
I'm gonna take the boys
and move back to my mom's.
What?
You're gonna quit teaching
in the middle of the term?
Well, I just...
I don't fit in there.
I'm not making any progress
with those kids.
What are you gonna tell Janet?
Huh? Your husband left you,
nothing else matters?
I don't know.
[Boy]
My mother gave it to me.
- Why would she give you $50?
- To buy breakfast.
Do you know how hard
your mother works?
- Yeah.
- Do you think it's right
to steal from her?
- I didn't.
- Why don't we go to my office
and call her and ask her?
- Come on.
- I need to talk to you.
It will have to wait.
- It's important.
- Take a number.
Guadalupe,
what are you doing here?
I can't keep
my bow straight.
Well, honey, your teacher
must be looking for you.
Here.
I can't come anymore.
It's too hard.
The violin is hard
for everybody.
But everyone
is better than me.
I'll always be...
weaker.
Did you ever hear
of Itzhak Perlman?
- No.
- He's one of the greatest violinists
in the whole world.
He has problems
with his legs too.
He has to use
two canes to walk,
but he still makes
the most beautiful music.
- And he sits down when he plays?
- Yeah, he has to.
He was your student?
No, but if he were, I would tell him
the same thing I'm telling you.
You shouldn't quit something
just 'cause it's hard.
But I can't stand strong.
Standing strong doesn't mean
just using your legs.
You can stand strong
on the inside.
You know what I mean?
[Children Playing,
Chattering]
- Hi. Want to sit?
- Mm-mm.
- That's the sub I was talking about.
- Mm-hmm.
What's the matter, you got
cooties or something?
Oh, apparently.
[Laughs]
Well, I'll take my chances.
Isabel Vasquez, second grade.
- Hi, I'm Roberta Guaspari.
- The violin teacher. I know.
Is it my imagination
or does everybody here hate me?
Look, it's hard to fit in when
you're doing a special program.
People figure you're not gonna be here
long, so they don't make the effort.
It may take a while for folks
to warm up, but they don't hate you.
What about Alice Cooper?
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
- [Isabel] A... She thinks
the violin is a waste of time.
- B: She's a bitch.
- [Laughing]
So why are you
being so nice to me?
Ulterior motives.
I want my daughter
in your class next year.
[Laughs]
If I'm here next year.
You will be.
[Woman]
Is just for you and your boys?
[Sighs]
Yes.
No husband?
No boyfriends?
No. No.
[Siren Blaring]
- I'll-I'll take it.
- [Siren Blares Louder]
♪♪ ["Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star"]
Slow bows. Slow bows.
Don't squeeze.
Oh, man. Stop.
Everybody, stop, stop, stop.
DeSean, how much have you
practiced this week?
My asthma... It was very bad.
I had to go to the hospital.
Again? You told me you had
to go to the hospital last week.
Oh, yeah.
Maybe it was last week.
- [Chuckles]
- Uh-huh.
What about you, Lucy? You sounded
the worst of all. Have you practiced?
- No.
- [Roberta] Why not?
You can't be in this class
if you do not practice.
My grandma got mugged.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Is she okay?
She died.
Oh... Lucy, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Just do the best you can,
okay?
- [Kids] Good night, Roberta.
- Hey... good night.
- See you tomorrow.
- You ready? All right, we'll see you.
Let's go.
- Hey, Naeem.
- Hi, Roberta.
Hey, can I talk
to your mama for a second?
I just wanted to tell you that I didn't
come up here to rescue anybody.
I'm a single mother,
and I needed the job.
And I know you think you're protecting
your son, but you're not.
I mean, what if Arthur Ashe's
mother said he couldn't play tennis...
because it's
a white man's game?
You know, the important
thing is Naeem.
When he plays music,
his whole face lights up.
You should see that.
[People Chattering Outside]
[Laughing,
Chattering Continue]
- What's up?
- [Scoffs]
You are.
- I was thirsty.
- [Chuckles]
[Nick] Remember in Greece
we could see the ocean?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
- And the fishing boats and...
- And the octopuses.
[Sighs]
Yeah.
Um, is Daddy
coming here soon?
[Sighs]
Well... that's something...
I was wanting
to talk to you about.
Daddy isn't gonna live
with us anymore.
Um... you and Lexi
are gonna see him;
special times like Christmas and,
you know, summers.
Um... can you tell
a birthday story?
Don't you want to talk
about what I just said?
I want to hear
the birthday story.
Okay.
[Sighs]
Um...
You know, it was
your grandpa's birthday,
and I was a little
bit sad because...
because he had died
a couple months back.
- But you knew I'd be born that day.
- Yeah.
So I packed,
and I got ready.
- Then Daddy left.
- [Laughing] Daddy left, yeah.
He didn't believe me because I said,
"This is my dad's birthday.
This baby
is gonna be born today."
But he didn't believe you,
but I was born...
- You sure were.
- on the same day as Grandpa.
That's right.
[Chuckling]
It was a happy day.
Was Daddy happy too?
Of course he was.
Then why is he leaving me?
Well, he's not
leaving you, Nick.
I mean, he loves you,
and he loves Lexi very, very much.
Then why
can't he live with us?
[Sighs]
It's just sometimes things
h-happen between...
- [Sniffles]
- grown-ups: : :
that are very hard
to understand.
They can't...
They just can't be together.
- I need to buy some...
- Mommy, come look!
What?
[Laughing]
What are you...
Oh, my God, you're killing me.
- What's this?
- A dog.
- What is this?
- Mom, look, look at her. She's so cute.
- Right? Can we get her?
- No. We're not getting a dog, no.
- [Lexi] She could stay with us.
No, you don't have to...
- No, but... Yeah, but...
Okay.
Now we're all gonna take turns
cleaning up after this puppy, right?
- Uh, absolutely.
- [Growling]
Yeah, right.
You're on the wrong string,
Becky.
I've only told you
this 14 times.
Look at your nails.
You're supposed to cut them
for violin... I've told you th...
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
That sounds so bad.
That sounds terrible!
You're gonna make
your parents sick.
[Sighs] Is this
an important question, Tanisha?
- What?
- Do you have two of those skirts?
- Huh?
- You wore one just like that on Monday.
- [Students Laughing]
- All right, I don't think that's
such an important question.
- [Door Opening]
- Let's try it again.
Okay, just practice
on the fingerboards silently.
Naeem and I were wondering
if he could still be in the class?
Well, I would love that.
You've got a lot
of catching up to do.
- You think you can work that hard?
- Yeah, I can.
Okay. But I can also arrange for
some private lessons at my apartment.
I wouldn't be able
to afford that.
That's okay.
Why don't you go get a spare violin
and see if you can remember...
how to set it up.
[Giggling]
Okay, let's try it again, shall we?
- [Students] Yes.
- Come on out, Naeem.
See if you can remember
how to do that. All right.
- You're shouting at them all the time!
- I'm not shouting all the time!
Just when
they don't listen.
- They have to listen to me.
- Didn't you tell them they were
making their parents sick?
[Roberta Stammering, Laughing]
I did say... But I didn't say it
exactly that way.
I'm raising Becky
in a supportive atmosphere.
- I don't send her to school
to be abused.
- I'm trying to teach discipline.
That's all. If you want to take
a very difficult instrument,
you have to take it seriously, you have
to focus, you have to pay attention...
[Janet] I think what Mrs. Lamb
is trying to say, Roberta,
is that you are
a little too harsh,
but I'm sure you might be able
to soften your comments to the children.
I don't believe we have an impossible
situation here, now do you?
Mm-mm. No, that's...
I can do that.
Good.
♪♪ [Playing Off-Key]
[Sighs]
Okay, that's enough.
Thank you.
[Inhales, Clears Throat]
Well, that was...
pretty good.
That was...
not so bad.
It wasn't?
I thought we stunk.
Well...
I wouldn'
put it that way.
I would just say
that some people...
could maybe practice
a little bit more.
James, did you practice
at all this week?
Okay, well, perhaps you could try
a little harder for next week, okay?
Good. Because all you got
to do is your best.
Roberta, why are you
acting like that?
- Like what?
- Like nice.
- Well, don't you want a nice teacher?
- I already got nice teachers.
- You added some variety.
- Yeah, we like you better
the way you used to be.
[Students Agreeing]
I agree. This is even worse.
You're acting weird now.
Okay, I take it all back.
You stunk!
You all stunk!
- [Students Laughing]
- Don't tell your parents
that I said that, okay?
- [Girl] Okay.
- Let's do it again.
Right this time.
Stand up straight.
Make the box with your feet.
Come on, tabletops up.
Stop sign. Beautiful.
Let's go.
Five, six, seven, and...
Tempo, tempo, tempo!
[Roberta] Don't open the presents,
all right, on the airplane.
It's time to board.
Time to go.
Okay, gotta go.
Hugs, hugs, hugs.
I'll take good care of them.
- Can't you come with us, please?
- Oh, baby, I told you.
This is Daddy's
special time with you.
Bye.
Bye, Nick!
[Man Talking Over TV]
Oh, Tom Sawyer
is drying out too.
You should read the new book
Mark Twain's writing now.
How did you happen
to fall in?
- I didn't fall in.
I jumped in to save George.
- [Knocking]
What? To save me?
- Who is it?
- You didn't go through with it,
did you?
- Through with what?
- Suicide.
- [Knocking Continues]
- It's against the law
to commit suicide around here.
[Santa]
Ho, ho, ho! Merry Christmas!
- [Gasps, Screams]
- [Laughing]
- Oh!
- [Santa] Merry Christmas!
- I'm back.
- You're back. Oh, God.
- Hut, hut, hike!
- I gotcha, I gotcha!
- I'm open!
Touchdown!
[Cheering]
- First down and ten now!
- Okay.
That's it.
Enough goofing off.
- Back to work, everybody.
- Hey, no fair.
- Everybody.
- What are you trying to do, kill me?
You're wearing me out.
- I'll wear you out. [Laughs]
- You already did that last night.
The only one in the entire coffee shop
not speaking Spanish. Boys, lunch.
- [Loud Bang]
- Oh, my... Gunshots. You hear that?
How you gonna live here
by yourself?
That's a truck backfire, Ma.
I work in this neighborhood,
and I want to live here too.
[Brian] Say hello
to the next-door neighbor, Assunta.
He won't bite.
- What's your name?
- Lawrence.
- Are you hungry, Lawrence?
- Yes.
[Lexi] Do you want half of mine,
and I'll have half of yours?
- Okay?
- [Brian] Lawrence?
- Come sit with us.
- Hey, get in here.
- Why did you let her buy this house?
- [Brian] "Let her"?
Your daughter does what she wants,
in case you haven't noticed.
[Laughs]
I noticed.
- I just don't understand the rush.
- I want my own home.
I've been living on Navy bases
since the day I got married.
The boys don't have a dad.
They can have a home.
But if you invested
your divorce settlement,
you could buy
a nice house someday.
Bad enough you're living
in this neighborhood.
- You lock yourself into a mortgage...
- Ma!
Please stop, okay?
[Sighs]
I'm sorry. I am.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
[Chuckling]
Forgive me. I love you.
Don't worry.
It's gonna be okay.
[Clears Throat] Things keep
going as well as they have been,
- eventually, I'm sure,
Brian will move in with me.
- [Sighs]
And how much do you know
about that man?
He's a good person,
you know?
He's...
He's been a big help to me.
He's great
with the boys.
Just don't want you to make
the same mistake twice, Roberta.
You barely knew Charles,
and you married him.
I don't believe this!
I don't believe it!
You're ragging on me for buying
the house in this neighborhood.
I would think you would want
Brian to move in with me!
Not if he's
the wrong person!
- [Door Slams]
- [Sighs]
Okay, everybody look alive.
We're coming up to the fermata.
Here it comes.
Nobody move.
Hold, hold,
hold, hold, hold.
Now at the spring concert,
the audience is going to be
dying for this next note,
but we're gonna make 'em wait.
And wait and wait
and wait and wait.
You wait here. I'm gonna
go get a cup of coffee.
- [Students] Roberta!
- Good-bye.
- [Students Yelling]
- Roberta!
All right, all right, all right,
all right, all right!
But you gotta remember, you gotta
all come in together. Promise me.
♪♪ [Students Playing
Out Of Synch]
- Man, we'll never get that right.
- That's not a very nice thing
to say about your classmates.
How many people think we can
get it right by the concert?
[Chuckles] See?
I think we can. Have faith, DeSean.
- It'll be all right.
- [Laughs]
All right.
Practice makes perfect.
Can I go upstairs?
Yeah, go see if you
can find your room.
- Careful, there's no railing... yet.
- All right.
- Hey, Ernie.
- Hey. [Chuckles]
- How's it going?
- If I could just remember
what I did here yesterday,
- I could be moving a whole lot faster.
- [Laughing]
- You look real pretty today, honey.
- [Laughs] Thanks.
Roberta, honey...
have you lost your mind?
- [Saw Buzzing, Workers Chattering]
- Wait, what is that?
- That's Sheetrock.
- Why does it have wallpaper
all over it?
- That's how it comes.
- Wait a minute. What do they call that?
Sheetrock.
- And why...
- That's the way it comes now.
[Laughing]
Roberta,
you've got to be kidding me.
These ex-cons you've hired
ripped this off,
just like
they're ripping you off.
I have spent every single
penny of my settlement on this house.
I don't have the bucks, okay,
to hire fancy union workers.
Okay, fine.
Do it your way.
As usual.
- Fight, fight!
- Oh, my God!
[Children Shouting]
- Okay, boys...
- Come on, kids. Break it up.
- Calm down. What's wrong with you?
- Nick, come on!
- [Children Continue Shouting]
- Hey.
I'm putting him
on two-day suspension,
- but next time he will be expelled.
- There will not be a "next time."
I promise you that.
Have you noticed
your son lately?
He's tied up in knots,
and he's asking for help.
Kids fight.
You're making too much of this.
He was choking
the kid, Roberta.
Nick is in trouble,
and you need
to deal with it.
Hey, Lexi, catch!
[Roberta]
Oh, no, no!
- Oh, no!
- I'm sorry.
- Come here.
- I didn't mean it. The wind took it.
- No, I don't have enough power!
- [Nick Screaming] No! Help me!
- You're gonna get it.
- Are you a duck or a chicken?
- I'm a chicken!
- You're a chicken?
- [Continues Screaming]
- Careful!
- You got yourself a chicken.
- [Laughing]
- I'm a chicken!
[Boys Chattering]
[Ducks Squawking,
Boys Shouting]
[Roberta] You're the only one
that can make Nick laugh nowadays.
He just misses his dad.
I'm just a fill-in.
No, I don't think so.
I think he really, really likes you.
- Huh.
- We're all hopin'...
you'll move into the new house
with us, you know.
Whoa.
Slow down here a minute.
- [Laughing]
- That's a little too much
like getting married.
- He's sweating. [Laughing]
- [Laughing]
What's so bad
about that?
How do you know that in five years
we'll even like each other?
- Oh, well, you know, maybe we won't.
- Yeah.
But if two people care
about each other,
you know,
they take a chance.
Yeah, like you and Charles
took a chance.
I'm not talking about Charles,
I'm talking about us.
Roberta, look, marriage...
[Groans]
It's based on a belief that one person
can completely meet another's needs.
Now, I just...
I don't buy that.
- Whoa, wait, wait a minute.
- I never have.
What are you saying?
Are you saying that...
if you have some needs
that I don't meet,
you would go and have them
met by somebody else?
[Laughing]
I'm saying it's a fantasy to think
about marriage lasting these days.
One out of two marriages
ends in misery and divorce.
No, no, no, you're not
answering my question.
[Laughs]
What is your question?
If I don't meet
all of your needs,
you know, and we're
in a committed relationship...
I'm not talking about marriage.
I'm just talking about a relationship.
You would go
to somebody else?
In theory... yes.
"In theory"?
Wait a second.
Wait, wait.
Wh-What happened here?
Weren't we having
a nice time?
Yeah, okay. Have we been having
a great time together?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
So let's just keep it
that way, all right?
Or not.
[Lexi Hooting]
Let's go!
Come on!
Let's go home!
We're all going home.
- [Nick] Why can't he?
- Because he just can't.
Brian is at his house
tonight.
[Latching Locks]
We are at ours.
- Then I want to go to his house.
- That's enough, Nick.
Come on.
Will you please just set up
your violin and start practicing
while I make supper.
Why don't you see if the puppy left
us a little present in the bathroom?
I don't feel like practicing!
I don't care.
Just go do it, now. Go. Go.
I want to go to Brian's!
[Roberta]
Stop whining...
and go practice
the violin.
Get your violin.
Man.
[Water Running,
Roberta Sighs]
- ♪♪ [Scratching On Strings]
- What the hell do you
think you're doing?
The problem with you is
you're mean to everybody,
and then they don't want
to be with you!
[Turns Off Water] I've had just
about enough of you, young man.
You just set up that violin properly
and start practicing right...
I hate the violin!
Pick up that bow right now.
Don't you ever, ever
throw down your bo...
It's all your fault!
You made Daddy leave us!
Now you're gonna make
Brian leave us!
You're gonna be all alone,
and I'll have to take care of you!
You don't have to...
take care of me.
- Then who's going to?
- I can take care of myself.
And I can take care of you
and Lexi. I promise.
You didn't try hard enough.
You made Daddy leave us.
That isn't true.
And that is not fair.
I begged him not to leave us,
but he wouldn't listen to me.
- Why not?
- Because he found somebody else...
that he likes more...
than me.
Who?
[Sighs]
Lana.
Remember Lana and Tom,
our friends in Greece?
That's her.
[Sighs]
Is he gonna marry her now?
No, honey.
But he's not...
He's not ever coming back...
to me.
Come here, Lex.
Come here, baby.
I'm... I'm gonna
take care of you, Nick.
And I'm gonna take care
of your brother.
And we're still a family.
Come here, baby.
I'm never gonna go anywhere.
Okay?
You don't have to worry.
♪♪ [Radio Blaring]
Hey. Hey!
♪♪ [Continues]
- [Turns Off Radio]
- ♪♪ [Radio #2 Blaring Rap]
♪♪ [Rap Continues]
- [Turns Off Radio]
- ♪♪ [Radio #3 Blaring Salsa]
♪♪ [Salsa Continues]
[Radio Deejay
Speaking Spanish]
[Spanish Continues]
[Turns Off Radio]
[Snoring]
- Hey.
- What?
- What color is that?
- White.
- No, I told you eggshell.
- Eggshells are white.
[Painter Scoffs]
Women.
- [Snoring Continues]
- Roberta...
how many times
I tell you...
you can't be
your own contractor?
You're an idiot.
Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
I am an idiot.
- Hey! Ernie! [Snapping Fingers]
- [Continues Snoring]
Ernie, wake up. Come on, come on.
[Claps Hands]
I'm sorry,
but you are fired.
You're fired.
Yeah. Go.
You two...
You're fired.
- Out. Get out.
- Is she kidding?
- You're kidding, right?
- I want you out of my house! Go!
- You're fired too.
- [Sighs]
Take it! Go!
Yeah.
- Yeah, that's more like it.
- You're fired too.
What?
I mean it.
I mean... I mean it.
I need to be with a man,
you know,
who can make
a commitment to me.
I need that,
and my boys need that.
Can you do that?
Roberta...
Get out!
All right.
[Panting]
[Footsteps Departing]
[Exhales]
♪♪ ["Shave And A Haircut"]
[Audience Laughs, Applauds]
- Whew! That was great.
- [Audience Cheering]
[Applause, Cheering
Continue]
[Cheering, Whistling]
♪♪ [Stops, Shutters Click]
[Audience Murmuring, Softly]
[Audience Chuckling]
- [Exhales]
- [Man] All right!
Bravo!
[Audience Cheering]
- All right!
- [Applause, Cheers Continue]
- Yeah!
- [Shutter Clicks]
- [Laughs]
- [Audience Cheering]
♪♪ [Salsa]
[Janet] Children, today
is a very special day...
because we're starting the tenth year
of the East Harlem Violin Program.
Now, some of you might know that I used
to teach just 50 kids at this school.
But now I teach
150 kids...
at three different
East Harlem schools.
So many children want
to take this violin class
that we have to have a lottery.
[Janet]
Now this is a wonderful opportunity,
so I want you to talk to your
parents about whether or not
you would like to try this.
My daughter took violin with Roberta
when she was your age.
Now she's in high school, and she
still talks about how much she loved it.
Janet and I
started this program...
because we knew how much you kids
could benefit from it.
You should know, however,
the violin...
is a difficult instrument.
So I...
What is it, Justin?
- Who's that lady in the back?
- [Janet] Oh, excuse me.
Yes, this is
Dorothea Von Hauften, and she...
- What kind of name is that?
- [Isabel] Justin, shh.
[Janet] She's taking pictures
of Roberta's classes...
for a magazine article
on music education.
- I want to be in a magazine.
- [Isabel] First things first, Justin.
Roberta's going to explain to us
about the lottery.
What we're gonna do is, you're going
to bring in your permission slips.
Have your parents sign them.
You bring them in.
I'm gonna take a hat.
I'm gonna close my eyes...
and I'm gonna pick just 50 names
from each school...
'cause there isn't enough room
for everybody else.
So, on Friday,
bring in the slips,
and we will tell you
who gets to be...
- in the violin class.
- [Roberta]
Yeah, but everybody gets a chance.
- Yes?
- I really, really hope
that I get in the class.
- [Adults Chuckle, Students Agree]
- I really hope you do too.
♪♪ [Cello]
- ♪♪ [Stops]
Wait, Lex, what time is it?
- 2:20.
- I got to go.
- Nick, Lexi, how come you guys
don't play the violin?
We used to, but you know
how my mom is as a teacher?
[Laughs]
Picture her being your teacher
and your mother.
- Oh, I'm sorry I'm so late.
- [Lexi] Hi, Mom.
- [Roberta] Hi, Rachel.
- Hi.
- Hey, Allegra, come here.
Nick, are you
finished practicing?
- Yeah, I'm done.
- [Roberta] Already?
- You hardly even practiced.
- [Nick] What, are you
timing me with a stopwatch?
- Why don't you pick on Lexi
for a change?
- 'Cause I'm perfect.
- 'Cause he's perfect.
- [Hitting Lexi]
Yeah, but your head hurts, right?
- Have a good lesson, Rachel.
- Thanks.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to meet Lawrence,
play some basketball.
- I'll be back in a couple of hours.
- Okay.
♪♪ [Violins]
Don't forget the vibrato.
Dang,
I just can't get that right.
Well, that's almost it.
You almost got it.
Almost isn't good enough.
Ooh, did I turn you
into such a perfectionist?
No, I came that way.
[Laughs]
That's what I thought.
Well, just as long as you get it...
for your Juilliard audition.
- [Turning Page]
- What?
I've recommended you
for a gifted kids scholarship.
Really?
I think you can do it.
And the next is...
Shandra Wilson.
- [Squealing]
- Yes!
- [Roberta] Congratulations.
- All right, Shandra! Good for you.
- Congratulations, sweetie.
- All right. Next is Justin Brady.
- Yes!
- [Women Laughing]
- Yeah.
- Yes!
- Here you go.
- Next one is... Could be you.
- Look at this, Ramon.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Vanessa Klein.
Vanessa, good for you, honey.
Wow, such a good class.
[Roberta]
And the very last one, okay?
- And that is Ramon Olivas.
- [Screaming]
All right, Ramon.
Good for you. Oh, my gosh.
[Children Squealing,
Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
- Thank you!
- [Woman] Yea!
[Child]
I got it!
[Cheers]
[Chattering Continues]
Does that really work,
the ticket thing?
- Oh. Oh, hello.
- Hello.
[Laughs] No, that doesn't work,
but I keep trying.
You know, maybe one day, the school
will give me a parking space.
- Oh.
- That would be nice.
- Here. Photographs.
- Oh!
Oh, no!
They're fantastic!
- [Dorothea]
Those copies are for you.
- Oh, thank you so much!
Oh, they're great!
Oh, can I pay you for them?
Oh, don't be silly. You'll need
your money for parking tickets.
Oh, thank you so much!
That's fantastic!
I think what you're doing
for these children... It's wonderful.
My husband's a violinist. He was very
impressed when I told him about you.
- Oh, really? What's his name?
- Arnold Steinhardt.
- Of the Guarneri String Quartet?
- Yeah. Oh, here.
Stay in touch. Let us know
when the kids have a concert.
I will, I will.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you so much.
That's really...
- Here.
- That's... Oh, gosh.
- Keys. Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Very good! Okay, now when you
take your violins home,
I'm gonna ask you to put your
music... Tape it up on the wall
directly in front of your nose.
'Cause you don't want to be bending over
like this, trying to read your music.
- Your parents are gonna be
so excited to see you... play.
- [Softly] Stop!
Yeah, okay.
Let's try it again.
Ready?
And...
♪♪ [Violin, Off-Key]
Ramon, how many cats
you killing back there?
Ready and...
Myesha, your stop sign
should be touching, honey.
Don't let it wiggle around
like that.
- Justin, you're on the wrong string.
- [Door Opens, Closes]
Look at your feet.
All right, hold it, hold it, hold it.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. What time...
- Vanessa, where is your violin?
- I forgot it.
Again?
This is...
Good-bye.
Go on. Good-bye.
I'm sorry, but, you know,
you may be dropped.
Go!
[Clears Throat]
Hey, Ramon, that's very much better.
I have to tell you, I'm very impressed.
- [Door Opens, Closes]
- That practicing is paying off.
Let me see your nails, Rosario.
See? You gotta keep these clipped.
And I'm looking at you too, Myesha.
- Everybody, I've told you...
- Drop dead, Justin!
- It was an accident.
- It was not!
Hey, Ramon, I don't like
that kind of talk in here!
You pick that stand up now.
You get the music.
Come on.
Listen to me, buddy.
We have a big concert coming up.
You're not gonna be in it maybe.
- Is that what you want?
- No.
- [Girl Laughs] Ooh.
- Nothing funny here.
- [Roberta Sighs]
- [Man] Here you go, sweetheart.
Come on, I got it.
- Good night.
- Bye-bye. Work hard.
- Get inside.
That a girl. We just got...
We're in a hurry, that's all.
- Mr. Klein?
- Yeah?
You know, I'm gonna have to drop
Vanessa from class if she keeps
forgetting her violin.
Hey, look...
she's going back and forth
between houses.
My wife and I split up.
Oh. I'm sorry.
Vanessa, why don't you write down
for your mom and dad...
which days are violin days,
okay?
[Pats Mr. Klein's Shoulder]
Relax your two, Simon.
Good.
Kenny, your stop sign should be up.
Up, up, up, up. That's better.
Stephanie, you look like
you never had a violin lesson
with me in your entire life!
Oh, Carlos.
Where's your violin?
- Um... it's coming.
- What's it, walking here by itself?
- [Girl] I'm coming!
- Thank you.
- Your buddies giving you a hard time?
- Look, it's just not cool.
- You wouldn't understand.
- You want your sister to carry
your violin, that's fine.
But is she practicing
for you too? Because that's
the way it sounds to me lately.
- I've been busy.
- I don't want to hear it.
Get here on time and commit to
this class or I don't want you in here.
You understand me?
Go.
You're a good violinist,
Carlos,
but it is definitely not cool
to waste your talent.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
So, let's do it again.
Perfect this time.
[Sighs]
Hi.
Hey...
What happened?
[Sighs]
- I guess you've all heard
the bad news about Justin.
- I didn't hear.
There was a drive-by
shooting by his house,
and he got shot by accident
and he died.
[Sighs]
Would anybody like
to talk about this now?
Ramon?
I think we should
just play violin.
♪♪ [Violin]
[Knocking]
[Knocking Continues]
- Roberta, come in.
- I just wanted to stop
by and check on Ramon.
- Why?
- Didn't he tell you what happened
at school today?
♪♪ [Violin]
- Hey, Roberta wants
to talk to you, okay?
- Okay.
- Did that sound okay?
- That sounded very good.
[Moves Chair Closer]
Very good.
I've been thinking
about Justin.
[Sighs]
Remember how mad I was
at him the last time I saw him?
Yeah. You got
really strict with him.
Yeah, but, you know, it wasn't
always easy to be nice to him.
You think Justin's
in heaven or hell?
Heaven.
I told him to drop dead.
Well, Justin didn't die
because you said that.
- I promise.
- How would you know?
Well, I don't think
you're that powerful. You know?
If you had such powers,
just imagine what kind of
a violinist you'd be by now.
- Yeah, I'd be better than you.
- [Laughing]
[Sighing]
It's okay to cry.
Not for a man.
My boys still cry,
and they're big, strong
young men now:
And I'll bet Justin's
daddy cried.
[Sniffs]
[Crying]
[Softly]
It's okay.
[Muttering]
[Continues Muttering]
What's this?
[Clears Throat]
Oh. What is all this?
What is this?
[Reading, Softly]
I...
Nick! Lexi!
You come down here right now!
[Nick]
Mom, we were just trying to help.
[Softly]
This is so humiliating.
No one even knows
it's you.
I mean, you don't even have to
read them, if you don't want to.
- [Sighs]
- Although, look, obviously,
a lot of guys are interested
in dating you.
No, a lot of guys are interested
in dating you and Lexi.
What did you say
about me anyway?
[Laughs]
Beautiful musician,
late thirties,
tired of playing solo...
Seeks a healthy, stable, attractive man
who's not afraid of a duet...
- with a strong, independent woman.
- [Laughing]
My violin playing
will feed your soul.
And my lasagna will be music
to your palette.
Oh, my God!
Did you catch
all the music metaphors?
Oh, no. Listen, don't you think
it's a little weird...
that you're trying
to get your mother a date?
And don't hit him again
or I'll smack you.
Don't you think it's a little weird that
you're not even interested in dating?
Look, even if I were
interested in dating,
which... which I'm not,
I don't have time to do that,
and, besides, you know,
I have my teaching...
which I love.
I have you...
and you.
That's all I need.
- [Footsteps Departing]
- I really thought she'd
like the music metaphors.
She said don't hit me.
[Groans]
God.
"Dan Paxton."
[Chuckles]
[Laughing]
That's good.
♪♪ [Both Playing]
- ♪♪ [Piano, Cello Continue]
- You're flat, Nick.
- I'm not flat, Mom.
- Sounds flat to me.
Play the violin.
I'll take care of the cello, okay?
♪♪ [Playing]
So, you nervous, Mom?
No.
- [Doorbell Rings]
- [Barks]
I'm... I'm just...
I'll be right back. I just...
Let him in.
Hi. I'm Dan Paxton.
- Is this the right place?
- Yeah.
- Roberta, right?
- Yeah. I'm her son, Lexi.
- Oh, hi, Lexi. Nice to meet you.
- You can go in the living room.
[Exhaling]
- Hi.
- Nick.
- Uh, Dan.
- Dan, nice to meet you.
- This is Allegra and...
- Hi. Oh, hey.
She should be...
She should be out in a minute.
[Roberta Closes Door]
Hi.
- Dan?
- Yeah.
- Hi, I'm Roberta.
- Wow. An honest woman.
- "Honest"?
- Your ad.
You said you were a beautiful woman,
and you were telling the truth.
Oh.
[Giggles]
- We should probably take off... soon.
- Okay, all right.
I'll get my bag.
Make sure you're home
by midnight, young lady.
- [Laughing] He's like six four.
- I know.
[Lexi]
To the right. To the right.
[Video Game Continues]
- [Brakes Squeaking]
- That's the car. They're here.
- All right.
- Oh, Mommy's late.
- What time is it anyway?
- 12:30.
- That's promising.
- Ten bucks says he tries to kiss her.
That's a no-brainer. Of course,
he'll try. The real question
is whether she lets him.
- Okay, ten bucks she lets him.
- You're on.
Well, I had a good time
tonight.
Yeah, I did too.
I, uh...
I have a confession
to make though.
Uh...
[Clears Throat, Laughs]
Uh, I've...
I've never answered
an ad before.
Uh, I lost a poker bet.
- [Laughing]
- [Laughing] No.
But I'm glad I did.
But I... [Laughs]
I have a little confession
myself.
[Laughing]
My boys placed the ad behind my back.
- You're kidding.
- [Laughing] No.
- [Laughing] I had a great time.
- No. Really?
Yeah, they did this.
They're so worried I have no...
social life.
- Ten dollars.
- No way, man. She ain't gonna kiss him.
- Just watch.
- Shut up.
Dan, I just...
I want to tell...
I went along with this because
it's been a while for me.
It's been quite a while.
But, um, I'm not sure...
I really want to get involved
with anybody just yet.
Does this mean
I don't get any lasagna?
- [Laughing] Oh, yeah.
- [Laughing]
Bye.
[Gasps, Laughing]
Oh, my God!
- Jesus, what are you guys doing up?
- Sorry.
- Why, is it late?
- [Laughing]
- How was it, Mom?
- It was nice, you know.
- "Nice"?
- Yeah.
[Nick] What, as in like
"Let's just be friends" nice?
Well, you know,
I don't know.
But we'll see.
- You know, there's a lot more letters.
- Good night, Nick.
- Good night, Mom.
- Good night, baby. [Kisses Lexi]
Good night, Mom.
That's right.
Pay up.
Mom, could you
loan me ten dollars?
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Panting]
Hi. Kids, I'm sorry I'm late.
I got stuck over at C.P.E. 2.
[Panting]
Where are your violins?
- What's the matter?
- We heard you got fired.
[Scoffs]
You what?
[Ramon]
They don't want music anymore.
Is it true?
- Come into the office, Roberta.
- It's true? You're firing me?
It wasn't me, Roberta.
The Board of Ed cut the budget.
The district had to comply.
As of the end of this term,
the violin program has been excessed.
"Excessed"?
They specifically said
that my violin program has to go?
They slashed the budget! Music and
art programs got hit the worst.
- Yeah, what about Dennis's classes?
- Uh, I'm tenured, Roberta.
Yeah. When was this
decided anyway?
Things happened very quickly.
I wanted to tell you myself.
- I can't believe this is happening!
- Why not? You are a sub.
- Your position has never been permanent.
- Hey, Dennis, just smile!
- This is the happiest day
of your life, isn't it?
- Come into the office.
You are not helping.
- [Sighs]
- Come on.
- There must be some way
that we can fight this.
- Fight it with what?
I don't have any other extra programs
I can give them instead.
[Scoffing]
I see. I see.
After ten years, after 1,400 kids
have learned the violin,
this is just
an "extra program."
You know I don't
feel that way,
and you know damn well I've been
standing by you all these years!
You think I haven't noticed
what you've done for these kids?
- Then do something!
- I have been on this phone
for the past three days...
trying to do something!
They're sick of hearing my voice!
Believe me...
there are other people around here
I would much rather get rid of,
but as far as the board is concerned,
violin classes are not a priority!
I don't have
the power here, Roberta.
I am so sorry.
[Door Closes]
♪♪ [Playing]
[Applause, Cheering]
[Applause, Cheering
Continue]
[Continues Cheering]
- [Roberta] Please sit.
- [Applause Dies Down]
This beautiful concert
that you just heard...
could be
the very last concert...
- of the East Harlem Violin Program.
- [Audience Murmuring]
The Board of Ed and the district
superintendent think that music...
isn't important
for our kids.
- [Murmuring]
- [Roberta] But they are wrong,
- and they're gonna get a big fight.
- [Applause, Cheering]
[Continues Cheering]
[Applause, Cheering
Continue]
[Cheering]
[Cheering Continues]
[Continues Cheering]
[Assunta]
Why do the parents have to meet here?
- You should be using the vacuum
cleaner, by the way. I got it.
- [Doorbell Rings]
- [Allegra Barking]
- Oh, God, somebody's early.
- Hello, Assunta. How are you?
- Well, I'd be a lot better...
- if my daughter had a job next year.
- Well, so would I.
- Ma.
- [Groans]
Sorry I'm early, but, um...
I figured we'd need
a little extra time to set up.
Beware of Greeks
bearing you-know-what.
Mommy, will you mind taking Allegra
for a walk right now please?
- You are having a meeting here tonight,
right? Parents and teachers?
- Yes.
- Get down, get down.
- [Assunta]
Come on, Allegra. Let's go.
- [Janet] Take it from me,
- Good-bye.
if you want to get parents to help you
with something, you got to feed them.
- Do you have a cutting board for these?
- [Door Closes]
[Unpacking Bags] And if you think
parents are bad, teachers are worse.
Believe me, I know.
I was a teacher.
That's why I brought snacks.
- Wow.
- Gets them every time. [Chuckles]
[Continues Unpacking Bags]
Uh, you didn't expect me
to bring homemade, did you?
- No, I didn't...
- Good, because my husband begs me
to stay out of the kitchen.
- I didn't expect you to be here at all.
- Why not?
We got to figure out a way
to fight this.
And after ten years,
I don't know,
I just can't imagine walking down
those hallways and not hearing that...
off-key, nails-on-blackboard
violin music.
[Laughing]
Thank you.
- Ma. Ma, get some...
- I'll tell you this.
If this was
a downtown problem,
- they would take care of it tomorrow.
- [Guests Agreeing]
Absolutely right.
They don't realize how much
this program helps our kids.
Simon is our third child
to study with Roberta.
james is premed.
April is valedictorian.
- Now that says something.
- [Woman] Nobody knows that.
We should inundate
the board and the district
with letters. I mean, flood them.
It doesn't matter how many letters you
send them. It's just not in the budget.
- What if we raise the money ourselves?
- Oh, they wouldn't object.
[Dorothea]
What if you did a benefit concert?
We could raise a batch of money
from the ticket sales,
and the concert itself could
be great publicity for the program.
It can't just be me
and the kids, I don't think,
not if you're gonna charge money.
Perhaps I could persuade Arnold
to play with you and the kids.
- [Guests Gasp]
- And, well, maybe he can get
another violinist too.
Itzhak Perlman, perhaps.
Itzhak Perlman?
Arnold and... Arnold would do this?
[Giggling]
And Arnold... Would they
do this, though?
Yes, Arnold and Itzhak
are very good friends.
- [Roberta]
Seriously, you think they would?
- Yes, yes.
And we could rent a place like the
92nd Street "Y." It's perfect for this.
- It seats about 900 people.
- Nine hundred would be more than enough.
And if we charge between
$50 and $100 a ticket, then...
That could raise you enough
to reinstate your program for a year.
- [Guests Chattering]
- That's a very... That's a great idea.
- That's a lot of money, Roberta.
- It'll be fun.
- [Doorbell Rings, Guests Chattering]
- If you can get us the fellows.
Beg him. Do whatever
you need to do.
- Hi.
- Well, I have some good news
and some great news.
- [Gasps]
- We're in five different papers.
[Guests Chattering]
Oh, my... Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
[Screams]
- [Whooping]
- [Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
Itzhak, it's Arnold.
You know,
the other fiddler.
I have something
to propose to you.
[Chattering]
♪ Let's break all the rules ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Me and you ♪
- Thank you.
- [Merchant] Okay, good luck.
♪ Let's break all the rules ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Me and you ♪
♪♪ [Spanish]
[Talking, Laughing]
Hey!
[Yells]
Everybody, listen to me.
Pay attention. Fall in.
You people
are my very best...
beginning and advanced
violin students,
and that's why you have been chosen
to be in the Fiddlefest.
Because I trust that
you can handle this pressure.
This is gonna be a lot of work,
a lot, a lot of work!
People have already
bought tickets to this thing,
and we are not gonna be here
in the fall if, you know,
they all run screaming
to the box office...
and want their money back,
okay?
So you gotta be good!
- "Bach's Minuet 1"?
- [Roberta] Yes, that's right.
Because people are gonna be
paying good money for this concert.
They don't want
to hear "Twinkle."
Okay. [Clears Throat]
Now, on the second page of your music,
you will see a contract.
I need you and I need your parents
to sign that...
because that promises me you are gonna
be there at each and every rehearsal.
- Every Saturday and Sunday?
- Every Saturday and Sunday...
- and nighttime rehearsals
during the week.
- [Students Protesting]
Oh, yes!
We have six weeks, people!
Six weeks to this concert.
All right?
That's not enough time.
We can't do it all in school.
I'm thinking, maybe, we're gonna come
in early before school in the mornings.
- Come in early...
- [Students Groaning, Protesting]
No, that's what it's gonna take. Have
you ever heard of Navy SEAL training?
- [Students] No.
- Well, this is gonna be
Roberta's String Training.
- It's gonna be tough.
It's gonna be rough.
- Hi, Roberta.
Oh, Naeem! Oh!
Great!
I'm so glad you came.
- Roberta!
- Guadalupe, is that you? Oh.
[Sighing]
Oh, I'm good, I'm good.
Now, I'm grea...
That's not Lucy.
- [Snaps Fingers]
- Oh! Oh, guys, this is so great.
- And DeSean?
You're a monster. You're huge!
- How you doing?
[Laughing]
You grew a little.
You guys,
you grew a little bit.
Okay, these are four of my... not my
best students, but my first students.
- [Scoffing]
- They've agreed to come and play
in the concert with you guys.
I'm trying to tell them how hard
they're gonna have to work. All right?
Take it from me,
you gotta work your butts off.
[Roberta]
Six weeks to this concert.
- [Chuckling]
- [Exhales]
[Chattering]
Hey, Carlos, where you going?
We got a game, remember?
- Yeah, but I can't make it.
- What are you talking about?
Look, I just can't make it.
What? Do you have a date
with the violin teacher?
Yeah, I do.
Give me that.
More bow!
Stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop!
My God, you sound...
Is anybody practicing at all?
How can we practice?
We're rehearsing all the time.
- [Students Laughing]
- Oh, that's funny. You think
that's funny, Stephanie?
You think the 400 people that have
bought tickets so far are gonna think...
You think Itzhak Perlman is gonna
think it's funny? [Clears Throat]
I'm not trying
to beat you kids up.
I'm really not.
But I know two things.
One: If this program
disappears next year,
you're gonna look around, and you're
gonna really, really miss it.
Two: If you have
a hand in saving it,
each one of you,
you're gonna feel
real good.
Real good.
Boy, that will be better than any lesson
I can teach you in class.
It's gonna be worth it,
so please hang in there with me.
Oh, you know, I cannot believe
I ever agreed to do this!
These kids are never
gonna be ready.
You should hear the Bach double.
It's a complete disaster.
- Good morning.
The good news is the tickets
are selling like hotcakes.
The bad news is the kids
sound like sh...
- There's more bad news.
- What?
- We've lost the "Y."
They had a flood.
A water heater burst.
The concert hall was damaged,
and they've canceled all events.
Until when?
- Until further notice.
- Oh, no, no, no.
This can't happen. We've sold tickets.
We've done publicity.
We have a concert
in three weeks.
I've been on the phone
all morning calling other theaters.
Nothing's available.
[Kids Chattering, Playing]
- [Boy] Come on.
- The teacher's late.
You know, I think she should
be dropped, don't you?
- Yeah, I don't know if we should
let her play in Fiddlefest.
- Yeah.
[Clapping]
Check it out.
Here you go, youngster.
- Yeah.
- Hey, somebody gave us money!
Stop. No, hold it.
Are you guys kidding me?
You have
to have more bow.
And you gotta go
to the frog.
You guys sound terrible.
I can't believe how terrible you sound.
- [Laughing]
- You're gonna make everybody
sick to their stomachs.
They're gonna pay $ 1,000 a ticket,
and you're gonna make them throw up.
Carlos...
you imitating me?
If you're imitating me, you should
do it right. Stand up straight.
Put that violin up.
Higher, higher.
Look at your feet.
All crooked.
Come on, continue.
That's okay.
You can take it from here.
Yeah. He's right, you know?
You do sound terrible,
and you are gonna make everybody sick
to their stomachs.
Rachel! I can't believe
you're late. Hurry up.
- I need to talk to you.
- All right, go on in, everybody.
Start on the Minuet 1, okay?
I'll be there in a minute.
Hurry up, hurry up. Go, go, go, go, go.
What's up?
We're moving away.
You're moving?
Where?
It's a secret.
My father...
has been hurting my mom.
So we have to get away.
Has he been hurting you too?
I'm sorry
about Juilliard...
and about the concert.
What? No. I'm not gonna take your
violin. That's yours. You keep that.
- No, I don't want it.
- You can't give this up.
It's a very
important part of you.
[Nick]
Do the kids know we lost the "Y"?
- [Roberta] No.
- We gotta find a place.
- What about the Bronx?
- What about... What about Cleveland?
We can have it
in Cleveland.
Mom, no one's gonna go
to the Bronx.
You gotta have it at one
of the schools. It'll be smaller...
I can't have it
at a school because...
- there will not be enough money raised.
- "Enough money."
No, because it's too small.
- Then just postpone it.
- I can't postpone it.
- Why not?
- Because Steinhardt is booked.
Perlman's booked
all summer long.
- [Allegra Barking]
- It's not gonna work.
[Doorbell Rings,
Knocking]
[Dorothea Knocking]
Roberta! It's me! Are you there?
What is she doing here?
Hello, hello. I have good news!
Really good news!
Arnold got a call from
his friend Wally Schurer...
who heard about us
losing the "Y,"
and he wanted to see
how he could help.
Then Wally had this brilliant idea
and called his friend Isaac Stern,
and it's all arranged.
We have a new place
for Fiddlefest.
- Where?
- Carnegie Hall.
Oh, my God!
[Laughing]
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh! Oh, my...
Isn't this terrific?
[Laughing]
- It's fantastic!
- It's huge!
- You're a genius.
- Thank you.
Whoa!
That's fantastic!
- Oh, jeez.
- What?
- We can't play at Carnegie Hall.
- [Nick] Mom!
- No, I mean, you know...
- [Lexi] Yeah, you can.
- [Nick] Mom.
- It's fantastic.
Amazing sound, isn't it?
You must be Roberta.
- Mr. Stern.
- I was working upstairs...
and I thought I'd come down
and just welcome you.
- [Stammering]
- It's so nice to have you here
in this house.
Thank you very much
for your help bringing us here.
Let me show you something.
If you're very,
very quiet...
listen and you can hear
Tchaikovsky...
conducting
the opening concert in 1891.
And if you listen over there,
you'll hear Jascha Heifetz.
If you listen over there,
you'll hear Sergey Rachmaninoff.
And right over here is where
Vladimir Horowitz played on his piano.
And they're all here
in the walls...
to welcome all
who come here.
- This is what Carnegie is for,
- Yeah.
and we are so happy that you
and the children are coming.
I'm very, very grateful
that you're giving us a chance.
- I want to ask you a favor.
- Mm-hmm.
Could I, with a couple of friends,
come and join with you and the kids?
- We'd love to help.
- [Laughs] Really?
That would be...
That would be fantastic.
Well, we'd love
to be part of it.
Oh, my God, yes.
I mean, yeah, that would be...
You do such special work.
It's just a way of saying thank you.
And don't worry.
It will work out. I promise you.
[Laughs]
From your mouth to God's ear.
[Both Chuckling]
[Assunta]
Which earrings?
- Here.
- I'm not gonna wear earrings, Ma.
I'm gonna play the violin.
- At Carnegie Hall.
- Get me two more violins.
- You can't go to Carnegie Hall...
Ma, you got two already.
- How many emergencies can there be?
- Get... three.
And make sure that, um,
two of them are half size.
Five, six, seven, eight, nine...
Lexi, will you call
the car company?
Mom, they're not gonna
forget to send the car. It will be here.
- Make sure that, that they're gonna...
- Mom.
- Yeah?
- What are you doing? Mom...
- I'm trying to straighten up.
- Mom, you're insane, you know that?
- It's okay, though.
Come on, just get dressed.
- Hang up your nightgown.
Okay. I'll put
this last one in.
- I think I'm gonna forget it.
- No, you are not.
You're gonna be just fine.
Look here.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
Ah, Maria.
[Spanish]
- [Honking]
- I'll be down in a minute!
[Sighs]
Yes!
[Roberta]
Mommy! Ma!
My God, I caught
the hem on my heel,
and I can't thread the needle
because my hand is shaking.
- Here.
- [Honking]
- It's not time. It can't be time.
- It's time.
I'll sew it in the car.
Oh, my gosh!
[Lexi]
I told you they'd send a car.
- [Woman] Hi, Roberta!
- Hi!
[Lexi]
Hi, Mrs. Johnson.
Thank you.
Give me that skirt.
- There it is.
- Oh, that's not so bad.
- [Sighs]
- [Sighs] Thank you, Ma.
Don't worry about it.
You rip, I sew.
Not just for that.
For getting me out of bed.
Oh, don't thank me.
Thank Charles.
What? Why Charles?
If he hadn't left you,
none of this would have happened.
[Sighs, Laughs]
Well, thank you, Charles.
- [Door Opens]
- Okay, okay, okay, okay!
- Vanessa's missing in action.
- Oh, my God. Did you call
her mother and her father?
- You know, it's two separate places...
- No answer at either!
- They stole the car.
- [Roberta] What?
- And the violin was in the car.
- Oh, no. You okay? Nick! Lexi!
- I need an extra violin!
- Done. It's done.
- [Gasps]
- Oh, congratulations.
- It is so beautiful.
- Carnegie Hall.
- I know. [Laughs]
- Hi.
- Thanks for coming on time, buddy.
- [Laughs]
[Sighs]
It is you.
Oh, my gosh.
Congratulations.
- I knew you'd get here, sooner or later.
- [Laughs]
- [Both Laughing]
- Well, thanks.
I'm just glad
I'm here to see it.
I'm really glad you are too.
- Break a leg.
- Thanks.
Can I have your attention,
please?
This is the five-minute call.
We now have five minutes.
- [Excited Chattering]
- Oh.
Galahad.
Thank you so much.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- You're glowing.
- Oh... well, it's terror.
[Laughs]
Thank you.
[Groans]
If I get through this night...
Okay, everybody!
Everybody, hey! Come here!
[Roberta Clearing Throat]
I just need your attention
for a second.
Can't see you all.
Okay?
All right, I just want you all to take
a second... and just breathe, okay?
- [Students Inhale]
- Deep breath.
- [Students Exhale]
- [Roberta Sighs] That's good.
Ten years ago,
Roberta Guaspari-Demetras...
walked into my office
because she needed a job.
And, because
she had a vision...
that any child...
could learn
to play the violin,
together we created
the East Harlem Violin Program,
through which more than
a thousand students...
have expanded
their vision...
of what is possible
in their lives.
When a program like this is cut,
our children's future is compromised.
I want to thank each of you
for your generous support,
and I sincerely hope
that you enjoy the concert.
Thank you.
[Roberta]
Listen to me.
I would like you all to play...
from your heart.
Do you understand me?
Play like I know you can play.
Don't look at the audience.
Watch me.
You do not have to be afraid.
You are going to be really,
really wonderful tonight.
Just play from here.
I'm so proud of you.
[Cheering]
[Applause]
[Announcer]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the children of the East Harlem
Violin Program,
led by their teacher
Roberta Guaspari.
[Audience Quiets]
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome
a man who has long been considered...
the most sought-after and accomplished
fiddler in Nashville, Mark O'Connor.
♪♪ [Piano]
♪♪ [Students Join In]
♪♪ ["Orange Blossom Special"]
Yeah!
[Audience Cheering]
Ladies and gentlemen,
as a conclusion to this evening's
wonderful concert,
we present to you a group
of international artists...
who have united in support
of the East Harlem Violin Program.
It is our great pleasure
to introduce to you... Michael Tree,
Charles Veal, Jr.,
Arnold Steinhardt,
Karen Briggs,
Itzhak Perlman,
Isaac Stern,
Sandra Park,
Diane Monroe,
joshua Bell,
and Mark O'Connor.
At the piano,
jonathan Feldman.
Performing their unique
ensemble version...
of Bach's Concerto in D Minor
for Two Violins.
[Audience Cheering]
Bravo!
[Cheering Continues]
Come, come,
come, come, come!
That's my daughter.
And bow.
[Laughing, Sighs]
When we play the violin, we play
right across those holes because...
that's where it resonates,
that's where the sound is nice.
Okay, we're gonna talk
about the bow again.
- Who remembers what this is?
- Ooh, I know!
- Yes?
- Frog hair.
It's... [Laughs] "Frog hair"?
Did you ever see a frog with hair?
- No.
- [Students Giggling]
- No. So what is it?
- Horsehair?
H-Horse's hair.
That's right, that's right.
But he's right.
There is a frog here somewhere.
- [Straining]
- [Roberta] Let him answer.
That's right.
That's a frog.
[Imitating Frog]
See him? His little eye?
Okay, now why do they use horsehair?
Does anybody know?
- Yes?
- [Girl] It's strong and soft.
Because it's strong.
A horse's tail...
The hair is very strong,
and it's very soft.
That's nice because
when we put the bow on the string,
it makes a lovely sound.
♪ You'll never know ♪
♪ What you've done for me ♪
♪ What your faith in me ♪
♪ Has done for my soul ♪
♪ And you'll never know ♪
♪ The gift you've given me ♪
♪ I'll carry it with me ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Through the days ahead ♪
♪ I think of days before ♪
♪ You made me hope
for something better♪
- ♪ Yes, you did ♪
- ♪ And made me reach
for something more ♪
♪ You taught me to run ♪
♪ You taught me to fly ♪
♪ Helped me
to free the me inside ♪
♪ Helped me hear
the music of my heart ♪
- ♪ Helped me hear
- ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ You opened my eyes
You opened the door♪
- ♪ To something
I'd never known before ♪
- ♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
- ♪ And your love ♪
- ♪ Your love ♪
♪ Is the music
of my heart ♪
♪ The music of my heart ♪
♪ You were the one ♪
- ♪ Always on my side ♪
- ♪ Always standing by ♪
♪ Seeing me through ♪
[Together]
♪ You were the song
that always made me sing ♪
♪ I'm singing this for you ♪
♪ I'm singing this
for you, baby ♪
♪ Everywhere I go ♪
♪ I'll think
of where I've been ♪
- ♪ Think of where I've been ♪
- ♪ And of the one who knew me better♪
♪ Than anyone
ever will again ♪
♪ You taught me to run ♪
♪ You taught me to fly ♪
♪ Helped me
to free the me inside ♪
♪ Helped me hear
the music of my heart ♪
♪ You opened my eyes ♪
- ♪ You opened the door♪
♪ To something
I'd never known before ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- ♪ And your love ♪
♪ Your love
is the music of my heart ♪
♪ Music of my heart ♪
♪ Your love ♪
♪ Helped me hear
the music of my heart ♪
♪ Hey, yeah ♪
♪ What you taught me ♪
♪ Only your love
could ever teach me ♪
♪ You got through where
no one could reach me ♪
♪ Before ♪
♪ Because you always
saw in me ♪
♪ All the best
that I could be ♪
♪ It was you
who set me free ♪
♪ You taught me to run ♪
♪ You taught me to fly ♪
- ♪ Helped me to free the me inside ♪
- ♪ Me inside ♪
♪ Helped me hear
the music of my heart ♪
♪ You taught me to run ♪
♪ You taught me to fly ♪
- ♪ Helped me to free the me inside ♪
- ♪ Me inside ♪
- ♪ Helped me hear
the music of my heart ♪
- ♪ Music of my heart ♪
♪ Helped me hear
the music of my heart ♪
- ♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
- ♪ You opened my eyes ♪
- ♪ You opened the door♪
- ♪ Opened the door♪
- ♪ To something
I'd never known before ♪
- ♪ Never, never found before ♪
♪ And your love ♪
♪ Is the music of my heart ♪
- ♪ Music of my heart ♪
♪ Is the music of ♪
- ♪ My heart ♪
- ♪ My heart ♪♪