Finish with it!
Do you realise you've made me late for work?
- Well?
I don't want any of your ruddy cheek!
I want to see my gran!
I'm not going!
Run for it, Jamie.
I'm not going! I'm not going!
I'm not going! I'm not going! I'm not going!
I'm not going!
Da!
They're gonna take us away!
He was brought up
by his granny on his mother's side.
Would you know where his mother is?
She's in an asylum.
By law, the father will have to accept
full responsibility for the child's welfare.
Well, he's always welcome here.
The boy is obviously in need of care.
Don't you try to tell me my business.
My son's character's spotless.
There's not a black mark on his conscience.
Your mother's ruined my son's life.
He had the makings of a great man.
He could have had the whole world at his feet.
All gone.
She wanted to destroy him!
What made you think you could come here?
Tommy!
Come on and wash yourself.
Come on, give that to me.
What a state!
It's freezing.
It's cold, Jamie. It's cold.
There we are.
Look up. Look up.
Are you all right?
Hm?
How old are you now, son?
Would you like to come home and live with me?
You whore! You whore! You bloody whore!
I'll swing for you! Bitch! Bitch! Bitch!
Bitch of hell!
~ Summer suns are glowing
~ Over land and sea
~ Happy light is flowing
~ Bountiful and free
~ Everything rejoices
~ In the mellow rays
~ All earth's thousand voices
~ Swell the psalm of praise
~ We will never doubt Thee
~ Though Thou veil Thy light
~ Life is dark without Thee
~ Death with Thee is bright
~ Light of light, shine o'er us
~ On our pilgrim way
~ Go Thou still before us
~ To the endless day
Come away from there.
You're not allowed in there.
Open the door!
This'll never be a blaze.
Ach!
Come on, pet.
Oh...
you must have peed your bed.
Ach, never mind, it was my fault, dear.
Your mother should have taken you out
much earlier than she did.
I'll sit and wash that.
And I'll get you a clean blanket, so I will.
My bottle's safe.
Come on, pet.
It's not your fault. Dinnae worry.
Ach, she's just my wee dearie, so she is.
You're my wee darling, are you?
Ach, you're just a wee bit...
Ach, you're wanting to go down, are you?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute till I get this done.
There you are. Away you go.
Who's the best boy...
.. in all the wide world?
Who is it, my darling?
Have a drink.
Ah.
Ah!
My young prince!
Please, Jesus,
make my granny drunk every night.
I got word from the asylum.
Your mother's dead.
Whatever misfortune she had in her life,
she didnae deserve that.
There is more beauty than horror
in our countryside.
More hope than despair.
If you get stung by a bee,
you can cure it with...
a docken leaf,
because it has healing properties.
There is a legend that says it is safe
to take home anything from nature,
except for one thing -
this is called dead man's flourish.
If you take home this flower,
it means somebody will die.
Your electric treatment
must have done you good.
I would have came and seen you quicker,
only you know what like she is.
He's wondering who I am.
Is he all right?
Hello, darling.
How are you getting on, darling?
Any chance of coming up
and seeing you some time?
Oh, you havnae changed a bit.
Well, I'm away.
- Is that you when you were young?
- Mm-hm.
Let me see your muscles now.
I've got bigger muscles than you.
Hm?
Thanks.
Your mother was a very nice girl.
I was very fond of her.
Always remember that.
Grandad,
Granny isn't very good to you, is she?
No, son.
Why are you laughing?
Dear Jamie, just a few lines
to let you know how I am keeping.
Well, I am keeping well.
My da came to see me,
then he never came back.
If he comes again,
I am going to ask him to bring you.
A man came to talk to me
about a career in the Army.
But I don't care about anything.
The home is not bad,
so long as you learn to look out for yourself.
From what I can see,
it's every man for himself.
They would take your head
if it wasn't fixed onto your shoulders.
I am wearing long trousers now.
That is all I have to say.
Love, Tommy.
How are you getting on, son?
Are you getting along all right, son, are you?
Well, son,
you're growing up to be a fine, big lad.
I had a word with the wife
as regards giving you a home.
It's not that we don't want you, son, but er...
I think you'll understand.
Because you're growing up to be a man now.
Well, son, I've been a bit worried about you.
But I don't suppose it will be very long
before you start work.
Who knows?
You might get a girl.
Everything might go all right for you.
As long as you mind and look after yourself.
You'll do that, son, won't you?
Want a fag?
Oh, thanks, son.
You see, son, it's the kids.
They're set in their ways, and it'd
probably be difficult for you to fit in.
But don't let it worry you.
I'll be back to see you again.
Can I come up here very often to see him?
- Certain dates, is it?
- Any day of the week.
Is it? That's not so bad, then.
'Cos I do miss him really, you know.
Help yourself to an apple, son.
I don't like apples.
Whisht.
There's a mouse listening.
Do you know what pearls look like?
Do you know where your mother kept them?
Well, go and bring them to Granny,
and she'll look after them.
Come on now, son. Where's the pearls?
I don't know.
You're lying.
I couldnae find them.
You know what happens to laddies
who tell lies, don't you?
They go to hell.
- Where's the bloody pearls?
- I don't know where they are!
I'll kill you, you wee bastard!
JAMIE: I don't know where they are!
- Where are they?
You're a bloody liar!
Tell me where they are!
Where are they?
You're a bloody liar.
You know where they are!
I'll kill you now!
- I'll bloody kill you!
- I don't know!
There, now. There, now.
Your granny loves you.
Breathe a word, son, and I'll kill you.
The world.
Now, who lives in the world?
- We do.
Are we a big part
of the world or a small part?
Small part.
- A very small part, indeed.
But if you take us compared with this,
which is a picture of
the whole of the solar system in the sky,
we are so tiny that we wouldn't be seen.
Now, this circle here represents the sun.
Now, can you touch the sun?
- No, miss.
- Why?
It's too hot.
Hands up when you want to answer.
Put away those rubber bands, please.
It's a sphere. Say it.
A sphere.
Now, you can't touch the sun.
It's too hot.
And you couldn't get near
it because it is too...?
- What?
- Hot.
Apart from being too hot.
- Too far away.
- Too far away. Very good.
Now, if you wanted to travel to the sun,
it would take you years and years and years
and lifetimes of people.
If we take this as being the sun,
around it go a lot of things which are called...?
What?
- Planets.
Now, we live on a planet. This is a planet.
This is the Earth, the planet that we live on.
Now, we're not the nearest one to the sun.
The nearest one is Mercury.
Mercury's a very hot planet.
It's so hot that you could fry an egg
on the ground with no bother.
Off to see your old flame, are you?
Off to get her sympathy?
You can't wait to get on top of her.
Hm?
It's a long, long time.
It's imagination.
He never thought I knew about his whore,
all these long years.
But I never let him touch me.
No.
Not once.
He never cared for me!
You're wearing my shirt.
Grandad!
Would you not be better off in a home?
Grandad hasn't got the strength
to fight for you any more.
Forget the whore, son.
Forget her.
She disnae exist.
You're a king.
The whole world is yours.
Go and find a woman that's worthy of you.
But you must never give up.
Never.
I believe in you, my darling.
I believe in you.
There, there.
Now, now, my darling.
And don't come back!
Oh, for God's sake, what's going on?
Threw me out.
And you mind your own bloody business!
You never cared for my son,
and you broke his heart.
You sympathised with him, with him, that!
You were a whore right from the beginning.
You were nae wife to him.
I warned him. I told him it would come to this.
But he wouldn't have believed it
because you wanted your clutches on him.
Away you go, take him.
There's his silks, go on, wash them!
Your bloody son... A bloody whore?
I'm a whore? You're a...
You get bloody in.
- Stop pushing!
- Away, woman, and shut your door!
You tell me to stop...
- Ma!
- Let go of me!
You get in! Get bloody in!
You'd break my son's heart and then...
Your son's heart...
You broke his fucking heart, not me!
- You bloody old bag!
- You whore!
- You're just a whore!
- Don't call me a whore, you bloody old bag!
Break, break!