My Brother's Wife
What would you do without me?
Ready.
I had my 20 grapes for breakfast.
Can't it be 21?
No, it has to be 20...
not one more.
You're nuts!
Maybe.
At least I don't talk to insects.
Zoe...
you're not going to mass
dressed like that, are you?
Better wear what I got you.
I don't like it, Ignacio.
Baby, this dress is too
flashy for mass...
There'll be a lot of people,
I don't like it.
Listen to me.
Did you find my mother's
prayer book?
Yes.
I hope it helps.
The Lord be with you.
And with your spirit.
The blessing of Almighty God...
...Father, Son,
and the Holy Ghost...
...descend upon you.
Amen.
- You may go in peace.
- Thanks Be to God.
Alright?
Let's go.
- Hi, Santiago!
- Ignacio!
- Congratulations.
- Thanks a lot.
Parish priest, who'd say?
Monsignor Moretti has been very
generous with his decision.
I'm so glad you could come.
Zoe knows we cannot
lose faith, Santiago.
Faith is the main thing, Ignacio.
Zoe, you must be strong in spirit...
...to support your husband.
By the way...
...I'd like to recommend this book.
"Path", by Balaguer.
It will help a lot
with your problems.
We could talk about
it if you come visit.
I promise I'll read it.
Well, we're off...
My mother's expecting us
for lunch at her house.
God bless you.
Give my love to Christina.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Excuse us.
Oh, Santiago!
Keep up the good behavior
and you'll become the Pope.
God willing, Ignacio.
You can't imagine
how sorry I am!
I really hoped the doctors had finally found
a way to give me a grandchild.
- Yes, it's a pity, Mother,
- Thank you, Mercedes.
There'll only be three of us again.
Why's that?
Isn't Gonzalo coming?
Oh, Gonzalo must be painting.
He forgets time when he works.
Son...
...why don't you call him for me?
If you ask him,
maybe he'll come.
A mother, Zoe,
is never wrong...
...my children aren't
the same anymore.
They were...
...more than brothers.
They were friends and...
...suddenly...
...something happened.
Boys' things.
I left him a message,
but I don't think he'll hear it.
Let's begin without him.
Hello.
- Hey, Raulito.
- Hi!
It can't be.
Impossible!
Gee, it must be a miracle.
Take that painting downstairs, please.
- How're you?
- What's up, sister-in-law?
- Fine. You?
Fine! Alright, man,
it's good to see you!
Same here. We waited for you
at your mother's house.
Yeah, I know, but I've been
really busy with the show and...
How's it going?
Better to ask how it went.
I'm already...
...taking down the paintings.
But come in and see
what's left of it.
This one is really nice.
Like it?
And why the unexpected pleasure?
Well, I came because...
...I want one of your
paintings in my room.
What do you think?
Really?
Well, choose one.
Which one do you like?
I like this one.
Then it's yours.
- Do I just take it.
- Sure.
This painting's worth
3 thousand dollars.
It's good, right?
Do I have to pay for that?
Yeah, well, I wouldn't take
your money, but...
...I know my brother's
going to enjoy it...
...so I'll have him pay for it.
- Hey.
What's that?
One of Gonzalo's paintings.
Not bad.
- You don't like it?
- I like it.
- If you don't, I won't hang it.
- No, I told you I did.
Did he give it to you?
Did he charge you?
Not much.
The son-of-a-bitch!
Isn't it enough with what
I send him every month?
Did he have to sell
you the damn painting?
Don't overreact, Ignacio,
it's just 3 thousand dollars.
It's not the money.
It's what he does.
I work my ass off in the factory
Dad left us.
And Gonzalo doesn't lift a finger.
He just stays home painting
or screwing around.
I send him a lot of cash
every month, Zoe,
so it's not money he needs.
It was in very poor taste
to charge you for the painting.
We can adopt if you want.
No.
Why not, Zoe?
It's not such a bad idea.
Look, if I can't conceive,
there must be a reason.
- It was God's will.
- No.
Maybe He wants us to adopt.
Leave God out of this.
So?
So nothing. We're not adopting.
I don't want to.
Honey...
...if I ever have a child,
I want him to look like me...
...smell like me...
my flesh and blood.
But we can't, darling.
You mean, you can't.
So what?
Would you have a kid
with another man?
No.
Love...
...I'm calling to tell you...
...I'm having lunch with Boris
so don't wait for me.
No.
Tell you later.
So do I, baby. Bye.
I had to lie to him.
I couldn't tell him I was with you.
Why?
What's wrong with you
being with me?
Nothing, but...
...Ignacio wouldn't approve
of me posing for you.
He wouldn't like you
painting me at all.
He'd go ballistic.
He's such an asshole.
Very good.
Don't smile so much.
There!
You still haven't told me
what the snapshots are for.
I'll tell you.
Move to the edge of the bed.
I take the pictures...
...turn them into slides,
I project them...
...and then I start painting on them.
- Is this alright?
- It's perfect.
You look tense. Why don't you
relax and lie down?
Go on!
Like that, right,
very good.
Ignacio... He's a lucky son-of-a-bitch.
He doesn't deserve
a goddess like you, man.
- I can't take it anymore.
- Hello?
We only make love on Saturdays.
- Zoe?
- Only on Saturdays?
He says he enjoys it more that way.
That he has better climaxes.
He has always been an asshole.
You should've seen him
when he saw your painting.
I can imagine,
He's jealous of me.
I don't know why he did it.
I swear I don't get it.
Jealousy.
He's jealous of me,
because he knows I'm happy.
He knows I love what I do,
and that bothers him.
He's so damn bitter about
working in a factory...
...because he never had
the guts to do what he likes.
Don't say that,
he's your brother.
- And he's my husband.
- I don't give a damn...
...that he's my brother, man.
He didn't have to treat
my painting like that.
You know how long it takes
to paint one of those?
I know, Gonza.
Maybe it was my fault.
I shouldn't have told him
you sold it to me.
That's not the problem, man.
He's got money to burn.
The thing is I painted it.
You know what?
I think... I'd better go.
Why?
I need to sleep.
I'm exhausted.
You can rest here.
I mean...
...you can have some wine and...
...if you're tired you can sleep.
Come on.
I'll be painting...
...and there won't be any fighting.
Hi.
Where were you?
Out.
Out where?
Why did you do it?
I don't know.
I lost it.
Forgive me, okay?
You're going crazy.
It just bugged me that he
sold you the painting.
It made me angry.
Why?
- It shows he earns a living.
- No, it's not.
Gonzalo doesn't work.
He's a lazy bum...
...who lives off what
I give him each month.
It was my painting.
I liked it.
Yeah, sure, anything Gonzalo
paints is cute.
Is that why you called me?
How many times must
we go over this, honey?
We've been together
for three years, baby.
- So what?
- What do you mean?
Any couple that has been
together that long...
...should want to live together.
What part of it don't you get?
We aren't girlfriend
and boyfriend, babe.
I won't get married.
I don't want kids.
You and I are lovers, baby,
and we're good.
No strings attached,
no conflicts, man.
Save the bullshit
for someone else.
- Not for me.
- Don't you like my bullshit?
Then why don't you
get yourself another guy...
...to give you head
while I paint, huh?
I'm fed up with you.
Grow up, asshole!
I'll call you tomorrow when
the storm has blown over, doll.
Hi. I just wanted to tell
you I made a deposit.
I threw in a little extra because...
...it was a good quarter.
I'm sorry about the painting, dude.
I don't know what happened, man.
I think I lost it.
I lost it.
Fucking fag.
See you.
What's up, Zoe?
What're you up to?
I want to see you.
I called so you'd see
the photo before I paint it.
Did I tell you Ignacio called?
He wanted to meet,
but I told him to go to hell.
What did he say?
Just bullshit.
That if I sell you another painting...
...he's going to piss all over it.
He's a fool.
He's hopeless.
Truth is I don't know how
you can stand him.
I get to see you once in a while.
I haven't been able to get
you out of my head.
- Gonza...
- Jesus, I like you so much!
Me too, but...
this is wrong.
Promise me you'll keep it a secret.
Obviously, babe.
I'm a classy dame.
Discretion is one
of my greater virtues.
Don't you think
I've acted like a slut?
Not at all!
Besides, ladies have a right to act
like sluts now and then.
- But it's his brother!
- So?
Gonzalo's so hot.
He's such a stud.
I'm crazy about him!
I envy you, girl.
Don't feel bad.
Guilt...
...was invented by priests.
If your husband doesn't realize
he's neglecting you...
...that you're a lady, that you need
maintenance as well...
...it's only fair, it's only right that you look
for other ways to make up for it.
And there's nothing wrong
with kissing Gonzalo, what a stud...
...if he calls you again...
...don't miss your chance.
I don't know.
I feel like... a whore.
Well, if you're a whore,
where does that leave me?
How can you wear
two pairs of socks?
My feet are frozen.
Why? Does it bother you?
No, it just always surprises me.
I'm happier this way.
And do we have to listen
to this music night after night?
Turn it off if you want.
I'm going to bed.
I'm tired and I have a
business trip tomorrow.
- Again?
- Yes, again.
I don't have any help at the factory.
And I have to do all
the important things myself.
Don't be long.
I'll be waiting for you.
Darling?
I'm off to the airport.
Sure you won't come with me?
Well, I'll be back in two days.
Call you tonight, okay?
Come in, Maria.
You look very nice today.
- Thanks, Maria.
- Ma'am...
... I've got to tell you something.
- Yes?
I found this in the microwave.
It's kind of burned. I think it's one
of those CDs with the funeral music...
... Mr. Ignacio likes.
- Well, then...
...I'm glad. Throw it away.
It's like there are...
...ghosts in the house.
- I agree, ma'am.
Fortunately, those ghosts go away
every now and then.
Looks like it.
Excuse me.
Call me if you need anything.
Thank you, Maria.
Okay!
I put it on low.
Yes, ma'am, the egg's
almost done. What else?
The rice is in the pot, right?
Half an hour before,
you just press this.
Perfect!
You know what to do
with the salmon?
Yes, Maria, I remember
my cooking lessons.
Of course, ma'am. Are you sure
you won't need me tonight?
Yes. Don't worry.
In fact, you can take...
...the day off, tomorrow.
- If you want...
...I can stay and help you serve.
I like Mrs. Christina a lot.
No thanks, Maria.
- Who is it?
- Forgot my keys. Open up, babe.
Ignacio?
Come on, it's Gonzalo.
Open up, man!
- Hello.
- What's up?
- Did I scare you?
- Yes, you got me.
I would've loved
to see your face.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
It's been a long time
since you've visited.
Yes, a very long time.
That dress is great.
Thanks.
You look very nice.
I brought wine.
Thanks, I spent all afternoon
in the kitchen.
Oh, yeah?
I spent all afternoon...
...thinking about you.
- Gonza, don't!
Don't what?
Just a little kiss.
No, this is Ignacio's house.
- So what?
- Gonza...
...I invited you for dinner
because I like hanging out...
...with you, but...
promise me you'll behave.
I promise.
Hello?
Hi, darling.
How are you?
Fine, very well.
What were you up to?
Nothing. I was about to have dinner.
Zoe, you sound stressed.
You alright?
Yes, everything's fine.
You?
Fine, fine.
Heavy day, lots of work, but...
...I'm finally back at the hotel.
Zoe... do you love me?
Of course.
Why? Do you doubt it?
No, I don't.
I'd just like to hear you say it.
Well, then, I love you,
I love you, I love you.
Alright.
Three times is enough.
See you on Wednesday.
Sleep well.
Recently I've been thinking
about your wedding day.
Truth is,
what a boring wedding.
Average age: 84
I danced with all my aunts,
and my Mom's friends...
Gee, how boring!
Really, guys.
I recall...
...when I chased you
to the bathroom, remember?
Yeah.
What an ordeal that was.
First... I had to keep
an eye on Ignacio.
Then, get away from
all the old broads.
You don't know how much
I wanted to kiss you then.
But you didn't want to.
Why don't you leave him?
I mean, it must be a bummer to be with
someone who doesn't make love to you, huh?
I can't.
I don't like being alone.
I don't want to live alone.
I don't...
I don't... like sleeping alone.
You've got me.
You're my brother-in-law.
I can't be with you.
You've got me as a friend, man.
Well...
... I'll be going now.
- No, don't go. Stay.
You want me to sleep here?
Yes.
I don't want to sleep alone.
Not today.
Well, can I borrow a pillow and a blanket,
I'll stay here. No problem.
Why don't you sleep over there?
Over where?
Upstairs, with me.
Nothing will happen.
I just want you to keep me company.
Yeah?
Well.
Want some PJs?
To tell you the truth,
if you don't mind...
I wear my shorts to bed.
No, I don't mind.
Gonza?
I need a hug.
I've dreamed about
you many times.
Have you touched yourself
thinking of me?
Yes.
And you?
Have you touched yourself
thinking of me?
No.
I don't believe you.
Then don't.
I don't believe you, you liar.
I don't believe you.
Wait!
No, no, no!
Oh, I can't believe this.
No, don't go.
Boris!
This is delicious.
For the love of God!
Wipe that guilty look off your face.
I wish I woke up with something
to feel guilty about.
Look at how he left,
that is...
Who cares how he left?
What matters is how you came.
How was it?
It was divine.
Well... nothing, excellent.
It's alright.
It's just that...
...now you have...
...to go back...
...to your husband's
bed like a good girl...
...and forget Gonzalo.
Well, if you want a lover,
well... I won't criticize you.
I'm a philanthropist with my ass.
I give it to the neediest.
But not you.
You can't do it with
Gonzalito anymore.
Oh, this is so good, baby!
So good!
- Tell me.
- What, baby?
Have you been with other women?
Just answer me.
Don't stop baby.
Don't stop.
Answer me.
But come on,
how can you ask that?
Swear it.
- Don't stop baby.
- Swear it.
- I swear.
I swear on my brother.
Come on!
Who's the love of my life?
I am.
So?
Talk dirty to me, baby.
Zoe...
...sweetheart,
is something wrong?
No.
I'm just very sensitive.
Do you want us...
...to adopt a child?
No.
It's not that.
Then what is it?
Are you sure
you love me, honey?
Of course, silly, of course.
Do you have any doubts?
Hold me.
Come, come!
Kiss me, okay?
Remember today's not
Saturday, honey.
Sorry.
A bit more, Zoe.
Bend back a little, not too much.
Sorry, it's my phone.
Hello?
Hi, Ignacio.
What's up? I'm in yoga class.
No, no, no.
Go ahead, tell me.
Lunch? Well...
Hold on.
I have another call.
Gonza?
Hi.
Why did you leave
without saying goodbye?
No, I'm not angry.
I can't right now.
What hotel?
Alright, yes.
See you soon.
Kiss.
So... who was it?
Gonzalo.
You little slut!
Oh, yeah?
Look who's talking!
Shouldn't we be
taking precautions?
Are you on the pill or what?
What for?
I can't have children.
I thought it was Ignacio
who couldn't.
Ignacio can't...
and neither can I.
Good.
Because I hate wearing condoms.
What are you doing here?
Enjoying the night.
And those flowers?
They're...
...for you.
Where shall I put them?
Throw them on me.
Go on, throw them on me.
Are you telling me to throw
the flowers in the pool?
Yes, what's the problem?
You're like a goddess.
Now, jump in.
No, you're nuts.
It's cold.
Come on, honey,
the water's delicious.
Are you crazy?
I'm not wearing...
...my trunks, Zoe.
- Oh, how awful!
The master of the house
can't go skinny-dipping...
...with his wife in his own house.
Don't be silly. Jump in.
Alright...
...fine.
- I'll catch a cold!
- You're such an old lady.
No, baby.
What is it?
Don't know.
I'm cold, sweetheart.
I'm sorry, but I'm getting out.
I'm too cold.
How's Boris?
Devastated.
Just imagine. He found
his boyfriend with a woman.
- You don't say.
- Poor thing.
Aren't you going to get dressed?
No.
You'll catch a cold
if you don't cover up.
Not...
...if you keep me warm.
Honey, what is it with you?
What are you on?
Why do you analyze
me all the time, Ignacio?
Better make love to me.
Today?
Yes, today.
And don't say
it's not Saturday.
Cut the crap.
Honey, that's the way I am.
I don't feel like it
if it's not Saturday.
But tomorrow's Saturday, darling.
Yes?
What are you doing?
You'd rather masturbate
than make love to me?
No, silly,
of course not.
I just couldn't sleep.
And I thought...
...maybe I could relax
a bit more like this.
Who were you thinking about?
You.
Promise?
Promise.
If you were thinking about me...
...why didn't you wake me up?
I don't know. It's...
I didn't want to.
You looked so sweet
sleeping that...
...I didn't want to wake you up.
But waking up like this...
...is better than sleeping.
Much better.
I went to see your dad this morning.
I took him lilies. So pretty.
Excuse me...
This was made just for you.
It's fish.
I'm allergic.
Zoe didn't tell you?
About 10 years ago...
...I had a fish stew
that almost killed me.
There's chicken in the fridge, Maria.
I'll prepare it for you.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Anyway, we'll wait for Gonzalo.
He's not coming, Mom.
Gonzalo doesn't like this house.
Look, your brother
may always be late...
...and lazy, but you two?
He loves you very much.
Besides, he promised me he'd come.
Don't worry, love, it must
be Gonzalo. I'll get it.
Maria, get the door, please.
What's up?
- Am I very late?
- No, come in.
We're used to it.
How's the man with the money?
Fine, fine.
I'm glad you came, Gonzalo.
- Come on!
- No, seriously...
...Gonzalo, we're brothers.
It's wrong to be so far apart, man.
You know that in this house,
we love you very much.
As much as you love
my paintings, asshole?
Look...
...Gonzalo, I wanted to
apologize personally...
...for what I did.
I don't know what came over me.
It was stupid and rash.
Will you forgive me?
Come on, man, I don't want
any jealousy between us.
We're brothers, Gonzalo.
Quite the contrary. I'm glad you're here
in your house, having lunch with the family.
Come on.
Mom's waiting for us.
In fact...
...we should have lunch together
once a week, man.
- What do you say?
- As long as you're buying...
...I'm okay with that.
Thanks.
How's the most beautiful
woman on the planet?
- At last.
- Hey.
- How are you, mother?
- Very well.
It's good to see you.
Hey, sis.
Hi, Gonza!
- How're you doing?
- Fine.
- Brought a bottle of wine.
- Thanks. You shouldn't have.
Yes, I should, sis.
How are you?
Everything alright?
- Besides you being late.
- Yeah, sorry.
Oh, well...
we already know it's not...
...one of your strong points.
- Sorry.
Why didn't you bring
your girlfriend?
Which one?
The latest. The South American
actress, was it?
Laura.
Yes, she's from Venezuela, ma'.
Right, Laura.
Are you still seeing her?
Like all the others.
Good. I'm glad, son.
She's a charming girl.
Yes, charming, ma'.
You should start looking
for a woman to marry.
- Marry? Me?
- Of course.
Ma', you know I don't
have any plans.
...to marry anybody.
- Oh, dear!
You should think
about being a father.
And making me a grandmother.
Alright, give him time.
He just hasn't found
the right woman.
So what?
And if I can't have children
like Ignacio, then what?
Don't be silly, man!
So the future of this family
depends on me?
Jesus!
I feel so proud!
Excuse me. I'll go open
Gonzalo's bottle.
Excuse me.
And wash those filthy hands.
Yes, ma'.
Maria, take that to the dining room
and serve it.
Gonza, not here!
Want me to come
and fuck you good?
Tell me.
Want that?
Maria, begin preparing the dessert.
Yes, ma'am.
Maria, may I have a glass
of water, please.
Was it good for you?
Just good or very, very good?
Very good.
How's Ignacio in the sack?
Let's say he's...
...so-so.
- That means he sucks.
When we met,
he wasn't like that.
He was a good lover.
Or maybe I didn't know what
a good lover was like.
That's more like it.
But now it's a disaster.
I have the feeling...
...he only does it
because he has to.
And when he does,
his head's somewhere else.
You know why?
Because I think he doesn't like women.
Why do you say that?
Don't know.
I think he's a repressed fag.
Are you serious?
Yes...
...although I know he'll never accept it.
Why do you say that?
Intuition.
Sheer intuition.
Tell me the truth.
Your 'gay-dar' never fails.
Thanks, but... Let's see...
The truth, the truth, the truth...
The truth is I don't
think your husband...
...is a closet gay.
No.
To me...
...he's a crazed fag locked up in his
granny's dusty trunk with seven locks.
Poor thing!
I feel sorry for him, because I can't
imagine when he'll come out of that closet...
...of that trunk, in there
where he's locked up.
But how?
Why do you say that?
Because sleeping with you and not wanting
to screw you every day, to me, seems...
...it's a crime.
A crime, my dear.
An unmentionable crime.
He doesn't like to make love to me.
No, no, no.
I'm talking about fucking.
Real, honest-to-God-fucking.
Riding, humping, shagging,
as they say.
And if your husband doesn't
want to fuck you...
...either he's really a fag
or he's impotent.
No, not impotent. That he isn't.
I know that for a fact.
Well, you're right about that.
I know it too.
What?
No, not the way you think.
Don't be silly.
I'm just kidding.
How can you even think?
Ready, sir.
That was the last one.
I don't know why the last one
always hurts the most.
- Aurorita, give me a massage.
- Of course, sir.
Shit!
What do you say we leave
the massage for another day?
- Alright.
- I'll call you.
- Fine.
- Thanks.
Mariana, didn't I tell you
no interruptions?
You stood me up, man.
Weren't we going to have
dinner once a week?
Oh, you forgot!
No, don't worry.
It's okay, man.
I told you not to sweat it, man.
But I will send you the bill, okay?
Bye.
May I have the menu, please?
And a bottle of whisky,
blue label.
- Right away, sir.
- Thanks.
What did you do?
What's that?
You said you wouldn't
wax your back anymore.
I don't like it, Zoe.
It makes me feel older.
Besides, I want to be
attractive for you, babe.
You didn't think there was
another woman, did you?
Ignacio, I need to ask you something.
Yes, sweetheart?
Have you ever been with a man?
Yes.
I was with one today.
An engineer from the factory.
We were together, checking out
the machinery we want to buy.
Don't get cute.
You know what I mean.
No, I don't know what you mean.
Have you ever...
...had sex with another man?
No. Never.
Why do you ask me that, honey?
So you've never had sex with a man?
I already told you.
I don't like men, Zoe.
I like you.
And I thought you'd ask me
something serious.
- Promise you're not gay.
- God! Zoe...
...don't be silly. I don't have
to promise anything.
- Promise.
- Alright, I promise.
Zoe...
...you are the love of my life.
No one else.
Now go to bed.
You're in a bad mood.
Gonza? Hey.
Fine.
I made a decision.
I wrote him a letter.
Maria...
...will you carry my bags
to the car, please?
Yes, ma'am.
Fuck!
Who is it?
What do you want?
You're an asshole, Gonzalo.
I love you too, motherfucker.
You're a son-of-a-bitch!
Hope Ma' doesn't hear you.
How could you tell
Zoe I was a fag?
Don't touch me, man!
Is that your problem?
You and your fucking paintings!
Don't touch my painting,
or I'll kick your ass.
Don't! Don't you dare
call me a fag again, asshole.
Don't you dare.
I forbid you to see Zoe again.
You hear me?
What is it you want?
To destroy my marriage?
Is that it?
Who the fuck d'you think you are
to tell my wife I'm a fag?
Who do you think you are?
I only told her the truth, man.
You think I don't remember,
asshole?
- What are you talking about?
- You know perfectly well...
...what I'm talking about,
you fag.
Tell me what you see here.
Nothing.
What do you see here, huh?
What you see there
is that little boy's world, man.
A boy who's full of fear.
He's totally manipulated...
...because his older brother
wanted it that way, man.
I remember perfectly when you said
"Close your eyes, dude...
...and think about the girl
you like the most".
And when I finally
got to be with a woman...
you know what's the first
thing I thought of?
You, man.
You, you fucking faggot.
You molested me!
And I looked up to you, man.
You were my idol.
I did everything...
And now you come here
whining about stuff.
Fuck you, asshole!
Get out of here!
You're sick, Gonzalo.
Stay away from my wife.
Zoe!
Fuck!
Gonzalo, you son-of-a-bitch.
Son-of-a-bitch!
I told Gonzalo I couldn't
get pregnant.
- You lied to him!
- No, I didn't.
I thought I couldn't.
You must believe me Boris.
Alright.
I believe you, sweetie.
And now what?
I'm sure you want to have
your baby anyway.
I think I do.
But...
...what if Gonzalo doesn't?
If you want, you can have
it on your own.
I wouldn't like my child
to be fatherless.
Right.
If you want your child
to have a father...
...no problem.
I can be the father of your child.
Just like that.
Me too, me too.
I mean, I adore myself.
Would you really be willing?
Of course, sweetie,
of course.
We admire the way
he's developed...
...his market.
- Mainly because...
...he did it when so many...
...factories were closing.
- That's why we want...
...you to participate...
...in our companies.
Participate.
Yes.
What is it exactly you want?
You want my..?
My advice or my capital?
It's obvious that someone
as well informed as you
knows we've had capital problems...
Excuse me for a moment.
Excuse me.
Could you tell me
if Ms. Zoe Edwards...
...is staying in this hotel?
- May I have her name again?
Edwards.
But you said you
couldn't get pregnant.
So I thought.
Gonza, It's a miracle
that I'm pregnant.
A miracle?
Are you out of your mind?
What if it's in your head?
How can you be so certain that
you are pregnant? Come on.
I did three tests,
they were all positive.
Jesus! For the love of God, man!
Those tests are shit, man,
they're just shit.
What will you do?
Damnit!
And you haven't slept
with anybody else?
No.
How do you know
Ignacio' s not the father?
- Ignacio shoots blanks.
- Says who?
The same doctors who said
you can't have kids?
Don't fuck with me.
If you're pregnant, which I doubt because
those tests you took are useless...
...you have two choices.
Either you tell Ignacio he's the father...
...or you get rid of it.
An abortion?
Is that your advice?
Either that or you tell
Ignacio he's the father.
Those are your two choices.
You don't care
it's yours, do you?
How can that be?
How the fuck do I
know it's mine, huh?
You lied to me.
You said you couldn't get pregnant and
now you want to have a child with me.
Well, go screw yourself!
Don't call me.
Don't look me up, I don't want this
ever mentioned again.
Once I leave this room
you don't know me, got it?
Yes?
Good morning, Ms. Berkley,
this just came for you.
- Thanks.
- Excuse me.
Congratulations, Ignacio.
Don't be afraid, Zoe.
I'll be discreet.
No one can forgive me.
Don't say that.
We're all sinners and God always
forgives those who repent.
I'm pregnant.
Shouldn't that make you happy?
Haven't you and Ignacio
tried for years?
Yes, but...
...Ignacio' s not the father.
Who is it?
I can't tell you.
Tell me everything, Zoe.
Or God won't forgive you.
I can't.
My guess is you haven't
considered an abortion.
God wouldn't forgive that.
Human life is sacred.
You must have that child.
Ignacio will kill it.
Tell him it's his.
Tell him God works miracles.
Ignacio and I go a long way back...
...he's a very kind, noble soul.
He'll believe you.
In fact, Zoe...
...this goes against my ethics...
...but I empathize with you.
You can solve your problem here.
Call them but don't mention me.
Here lies Juan Ignacio Edwards
A memory of his beloved wife Christina
And his sons Ignacio and Gonzalo
Mexico City 1942-1992
Dear Zoe: No hard feelings.
I found your phone in the pool.
I'm sending you a new one
so you can call Gonzalo.
If you press number 1
you'll get his phone.
If you press 2, you'll get me,
if you need me.
I still love you,
Ignacio.
I want to explain what happened.
You don't have to explain anything.
Gonzalo wants me to get rid of it.
Forget Gonzalo.
He's not worth it.
Only you and the baby matter.
Zoe, I'm with you.
I'll be your unconditional ally
for anything you need.
If you want, I'll be the father
of your child.
But I must...
...tell you something
before you say yes.
What?
Tell me.
It's embarrassing.
I've never told anyone.
- Is there another woman?
- No.
I like men.
Zoe, I love you.
I love you more than anything.
But I like men.
I can't help it.
Well, I want to be a mother.
I've dreamed about it for years.
And if you want
to be the father.
I'll never leave you.
I wouldn't leave you
for any one else.
But if we're going to be together...
...I need to now that if I feel like
being with a man, you won't say no.
It's only fair.
Inbox
Subject
Zoe and I are parents.
Dear Gonzalo, a few days ago
Juan Ignacio was born.
We named him after Dad.
Damn!
We wanted to share our joy with you.
That asshole fell for it!
What's that?
I have a nephew, babe.
Ignacio and Zoe had a kid.
Can you believe it?
That's great, sweetie. Why didn't you
tell me Zoe was pregnant, baby?
I didn't know.
We wish you the best,
Ignacio and Zoe.
Well... I see you are bringing
my grandson to me.
Hi Cristina.
Hello.
Hello, Jose Ignacio.
Hi Mom.
The kid is looking more
and more like you,
isn't that right?
This is a miracle, he even has that little
dimple just like your Dad, Ignacio.
Definitely,
he is an Edwards.
I don't see he looks that much like me.
Come on, Ignacio, for God's sake...
...this kid is your son,
wherever he might go.
Also, a Mother is never wrong,
you cannot deny it.
No Mom,
I do not deny anything anymore.
MovieFull-HD.com
~ PertamaX ~