~ All things bright and beautiful
~ All creatures great and small
~ All things wise and wonderful
~ The Lord God made them all
~ Each little flower that opens
~ Each little bird that sings
~ He made their glowing colours
~ He made their tiny wings
~ All things bright and beautiful
~ All creatures great and small
~ All things wise and wonderful
~ The Lord God made them all
~ The purple-headed mountain
~ The river running by
~ The sunset and the morning
~ That brightens up the sky
~ All things bright and beautiful
~ All creatures great and small
~ All things wise and wonderful
~ The Lord God made them all
~ The cold wind in the winter
~ The pleasant summer sun
~ The ripe fruits in the garden
~ He made them every one
~ All things bright and beautiful
~ All creatures great and small...
We're going now!
Eine Minute, bitte.
There's no time.
Come on, you lot, get moving!
I'm hungry.
You're selfish!
Will you stop it, boys? Stop it!
Tommy, you're the eldest. Get up.
Stop it! Oh, stop it, boys!
Stop it! Stop!
Stop it, son.
Don't do that to the wee chap.
Get up, Tommy! Get up, Tommy!
Oh, son. Get up.
Jamie, off the floor.
Stop it, Tommy!
Granny, where's my da and ma?
Ma's dead.
What does 'dead' mean?
You go up to heaven.
What's heaven?
My teacher says
it's a beautiful house up in the sky.
Go to sleep.
Oh, my poor girls.
What have they done to you?
God curse them!
Bitte, Junge.
Apfel.
- Apple.
B is for Boy.
- B is for B... Bo...
- Boy.
C is for Cat.
Dog.
Dog?
- Dog.
- Good.
Das ist dein Buch, Jamie.
No, it's for you, Helmuth.
Gehst du jetzt nach deine Mutter?
Auf Wiedersehen, Jamie.
There's a good girl. Come on.
Hello, old one. How are you getting on?
It's a long time since I've seen you, mind,
but I'll tell you, you're looking well, mind.
How are you feeling?
Hm?
Come on,
you must have something to say to me.
Oh, well.
See what I've got for your birthday?
How are you doing, son?
Is it really my birthday?
Do you no ken that, a big laddie like you?
What are you going to do when you grow up,
son?
I hope to God he'll not be anything like you!
- Well, I think I've been no bad in the past.
- Just get out. Go on, get out.
Go back to wherever you came from,
and take your birthday present with you!
I brought him a bird because
I've been thinking about him.
He's no needing anything from the likes of you!
Go on, get out!
Right!
What did you do that for?
Because he's no earthly good to man or beast!
Da!
Da, come back!
Just you leave my birthday cage alone!
I'll take it away if you want,
but just leave it alone!
Right?
OK?
You'll be all right with me, Joey, eh?
You'll be all right with me, eh?
What's wrong?
Tommy, Granny's lost.
I'm not bothered!
Das... Das ist in Deutsch
- Apfel.
Und das ist in Deutsch
Junge. Kleiner Junge.
I want something easy.
Kleiner Junge, ich muss nach Hause gehen.
Get away.
If you don't let me play,
I'll tell Granny you've still got the canary.
You're just jealous
because my dad gave it to me.
- It's my dad, too.
- No, it's not.
Yes, he is.
I know a secret.
What?
Well?
OK.
A whippet?
Jamie, your da lives over there.
Where?
There.
- How do you know?
- 'Cos I do.
Get lost, you.
I got do'd through you.
Aye, it makes a difference...
I love you, Helmuth.
Guter Junge.
~ Thou'it aye be dear to me
~ Entwined thou art
~ Wi'many ties
~ O' hame and infancy
~ Thy leaves were aye the first of spring
~ Thy flowers the summer's pride
~ There was nae sic a bonny tree
~ In a'the countryside
~ Oh, rowan tree
Give me that cat!
It's my cat.
I'm going to kill it!
- It's my cat.
- I'm going to kill it.
Sixpence!
You're mine.
I took you in and loved you
when nobody in the world cared.
God in heaven, the dreams I had for you.
She was a whore, son.
All women are whores.
You're a king!
How can they know?
Where to, hen?
That will be one and three.
Oh, it's all right. We can afford it.
Granny, who's Mary?
Granny, I don't want to go to the hospital.
Oh, come on, come on. What a naughty girl!
This is no way to behave
when you've got visitors, is it, now?
No, it isn't.
Come on, now.
That's a girl.
There we are.
That's better now, isn't it?
I'll make you look pretty.
There we go. That's it now.
That's better, isn't it?
That's lovely.
That's it.
There we are, now.
That's fine.
Now, are you feeling more like yourself, eh?
Going to give us a wee smile?
That's a girl!
That's it, now. Comfy?
And what's your name?
Jamie. You stole my apple.
That's an awfully nice name.
Would you like to say hello to your mother,
Jamie?
That's a boy.
~ It's a long way to Tipperary
~ To the sweetest girl I know
~ Goodbye, Piccadilly
~ Farewell, Leicester Square
~ It's a long, long way to Tipperary
~ But my heart's right there
There, you... you hold it.
It's red... red and yellow.
Nice start.
Can you hold it all right?
All the different colours of the flags.
Ja, nice.
- Nice kite. Watch, don't let it go too far.
We're going now!
Jamie...
I have got to go home now.
Auf Wiedersehen, Jamie.
Helmuth!
What's the matter, Jamie?
Don't you feel well?
Is it because of your dad?
It'll be all right, Jamie.
Me and Granny'll look after you.
We'd better go and get your da.