[Call Me Mother]
[This program is suitable
for viewers ages 15 and up.]
Subtitles by DramaFever
Um...
is this your daughter's bag?
Is she Kim Hye Na from Class 1-3?
[Cafe Latte]
[One month before Hye Na's disappearance]
[The lab will close as of January 2018,
so please take note of the following...]
How can you manage to be
looking at this right now?
This is the critical time
in which all of the data from
the past year can be collected.
Everyone else is packing their things.
When do we have until?
The end of this month, at most.
I'm planning to wrap things up here
by the time the kids have vacation
and move over to
the Pacific Seasonal Migration Project.
Have you seen this?
A GPS tracker?
It sends the GPS coordinates
once every four hours
and you can check it on an app.
And it's accurate within
a 40 meter radius.
That's crazy.
By the way,
what are you going to do?
I recovered 9 of the 120 rings.
I'm planning to pack my things
when I collect 20.
How will you manage
when we stop getting paid?
I'll have to do anything I can
by using what I've studied.
[How do birds fly?]
How do birds fly?
I'm going to draw
the shape of a bird's wing.
If you were to cut a bird's wing
the cross-section
would look like this.
Teacher!
What's a cross-section?
- Cross-section?
- What's a cross-section?
A cross-section is...
I thought you were going to use me
as only a science teacher.
Yes, that was originally our plan.
But the teacher of Class 3 said
that she's quitting immediately.
She got pregnant with twins,
and I think her babies will be born soon.
And the kids will have
their vacation soon
so it'll be hard to hire
a new teacher.
So please be that class's homeroom
teacher for just three weeks, Ms. Kang.
And please help her out
a little, Ms. Song.
Don't worry about planning lessons.
I've written all of them
so all you need to do is go to
the classroom and follow them.
Oh Cheol died yesterday morning.
Who died?
Oh Cheol. It was a duck that
the kids in Class 3 were raising.
I'm sure that the kids
will be quite sad.
Ah, have the kids write a letter to
Oh Cheol during fifth period.
[Lesson Plan]
Write a letter to a dead duck?
As you know,
children also feel pain from loss.
So we have to give them
a chance to express that.
[A Letter to Oh Cheol in Heaven]
Hye Na.
Are you not going to write one?
Dead things can't read letters, Teacher.
To be honest, there's no such
thing as Heaven, either.
I feel so sorry for Oh Cheol!
Teacher.
Ducks can't read, anyway.
- Yeah, you're right!
Hi, Duck. You can't poop anymore
since you're dead, huh?
Be quiet, kids!
When you're dead,
you can't breathe
and you can't eat.
That's right.
And you don't poop, either.
So I'm sure he can't
read a letter, either.
But Oh Cheol is a duck that you guys
were raising since he was young.
So to have a duck
like that die...
would probably make you all sad.
And I'm sure you miss him, too.
Write stuff like that in your letters.
So if you write a letter like that
you will feel a bit less sadness
and pain than before.
You don't have to write
a letter if you don't want to.
Since Oh Cheol can't
read your letter anyway.
Goodbye!
- Ah!
- Oh, oh!
Goodbye, Teacher!
You're so pretty, Teacher!
I love you!
- We love you!
What is this?
The secret behind Oh Cheol's death.
Joo Hyuk Tan and
Jang Min Sung heard that
ducks die if they eat chocolate
and cooking flour
so they fed the duck chocolate
and flour every day.
It's only three weeks, so do your best.
Looks like you'll end up learning
a lot about young primates.
I applied to programs in
China, Iceland, and Canada.
The Skomer Center in Iceland is quite
interested in researching murres.
How many rings did you retrieve?
12.
So you have eight left, then.
Leaving quickly,
and coming back quickly.
You're just like a migratory bird.
I'm thinking about
not coming back this time.
Don't you have any interest
in participating in society,
like other people?
Don't you want to stay in one place,
find a mate, and maybe have kids?
10 percent of all groups of animals
are loners, you know.
What did they say?
Look for Soo Jin.
Is it... cancer?
Go find Soo Jin.
It's been over 10 years since we
were last in touch with her
so how could I suddenly
go and find her now?
First, tell me what they said...
I want my daughter, Soo Jin,
to be the first person I tell.
"The elephant and crocodile tried to
stop them, but they wouldn't listen."
"Then, the lion said,
'Let's all share a little.'"
"'I think the giraffe is acting that
way because it's hungry'"
"'and I think the monkey got mad
because it was woken up from its sleep.'"
"The elephant saw the giraffe and monkey
make amends, and said"
"'Wow, Lion! You really are amazing!'"
[Normal Garbage]
Who did this?
Teacher.
I don't want to eat next to Hye Na.
Why?
Her nails are so dirty.
Do you know what my job is?
A... bird researcher?
I know a ton about birds.
But you know, the way that Oh Cheol
died this time was quite suspicious.
Ducks really don't die
that easily, you see.
But when I started observing Oh Cheol
I noticed that he suddenly started eating
a lot less, and vomited strange things.
Maybe...
someone fed him something
that he shouldn't have been fed?
For example, chocolate...
or cooking flour.
It wasn't cooking flour.
It was candy sugar.
There is a way for me to check.
I can go get
Oh Cheol's carcass
and open up his stomach with a knife
and check what's inside.
And I can use the CCTV camera footage
to find out who fed Oh Cheol
what kinds of things, too.
Should I do it, or not?
Don't!
Don't, Ms. Kang.
Can you promise me one thing?
Don't ever...
harass animals, girls, or anyone
weaker than you ever again.
- Yes, Ms. Kang.
"Napoli."
"Pizza."
"It is..."
"comparable to a pizza"
"made by..."
"a pizza-making master from Italy."
There are two consonants
at the end of this syllable cluster.
It's difficult, isn't it?
There aren't a lot of kids in my class
who know how to read all the words
with two consonants at
the end of a syllable cluster.
Were you surprised, Ms. Kang?
Why are you walking around alone
at this time of night?
I've always walked around alone,
ever since I was five years old.
What about your mom?
She's not home yet.
Would you like a bite?
I don't eat red bean buns.
It tastes good, though.
Want me to give you a bite?
It really does taste like an
Italian pizza-making master made it!
You know what I'm talking about,
right? Napoli pizza!
You smiled.
It's the first time I've ever
seen you smile, Ms. Kang.
What's that?
A notebook filled with
my favorite things.
If I write down the things
that I like, like this
I won't forget them, and I can take
it out to read them when I need to.
Um... kind of like a refrigerator.
And what do you have written in there?
A curving, sloped road.
Big bags with wheels on them.
When balloons get bigger and bigger.
A key, and a lock.
[Cafe Latte]
Cafe lattes.
What?
I really like them.
Young children shouldn't drink coffee.
I'm fine, though.
If young kids drink coffee
they won't be able to sleep well.
And it's not good for their brains.
You won't get taller, either.
Really?
What kinds of things
do you like, Ms. Kang?
Eating a meal...
quietly, by myself.
Kim Hye Na.
Listen carefully to what
I'm about to tell you.
Cut your nails once a week.
And wash your hair at least
once every three days.
Be sure to wipe your mouth
after you eat anything.
Change your socks and
underwear once a day.
And if you don't have
a lot of clothes, alternate outfits.
A dirty child will be attacked.
Because it's a sign that there's
nobody taking care of them.
So you might as well have a sign on you
that says you're easy prey.
What do you think you need to do
if nobody is looking after you?
You have to take care of yourself.
Many children do this.
So I'm sure that you will be
able to do this, too.
Did you know how to cut your nails
when you were eight years old, too?
You evil wench!
You were so wicked to your mother
so how dare you covet
someone else's child? Huh?
You deserve to live alone forever
without ever having your own kids.
She's my teacher, Granny.
And I really like her.
- Hey!
- Stop it, that hurts!
Where's Hye Na?
She's sleeping in the bathroom!
Hey, it's not like
the bathroom is the classroom!
[Nurse's Office]
The nurse says that
she thinks she's malnourished.
And...
she has scars all over her body.
I worry a lot for children who
are raised by single parents as is...
but she's such a strange child.
She doesn't cry
no matter what happens to her.
Didn't you notice anything off about her?
Hye Na.
Did Ms. Ye Eun leave?
Yeah.
That teacher is weird.
Why?
I told her that I tripped down the stairs
and she took a photo of me.
Where? Which part of you
did she take a photo of...
Do you...
enjoy seeing other people's scars, too?
I tripped down the stairs, too.
Did it hurt?
Did you cry?
A little.
I didn't cry.
At times like that, you should
think of something you like.
Then you might stop crying
even when you're crying.
I see.
But you know,
Ms. Ye Eun really is weird.
She keeps asking me if I like my mom.
So, what did you say?
I told her that I like her
quite a lot, of course.
I see.
Are you relieved?
What did I tell you last time
about what I do to noisy kids?
But, Uncle.
We... live on the first floor.
Is anyone home?
Are you home, Hye Na?
Oh, Hye Na!
Hello.
I'm Song Ye Eun, a teacher
from Hye Na's school.
Hye Na didn't come to
school today, so...
I called the school
and told them that she has a cold.
Um, but...
Hye Na, what happened to your ear?
Oh, I'm sorry. Did it hurt?
Um, let me see, Hye Na.
Show her, Hye Na.
And tell her how you got hurt.
I got hit by a baseball.
On the street, right here.
Oh, you poor thing!
They said that she almost
burst her eardrum.
I don't know why they were
playing baseball on the street
instead of at a field.
Um...
Hye Na has other injuries
all over her body, too.
I know.
Did you...
come here to ask if I was the
one who did it, by any chance?
Ms. Song.
I just keep tripping a lot.
The doctor said some kids trip a lot
because they have bad hearing.
Right, Mom?
I heard that there is a man
who is living with you two...
Ms. Song.
I make a living on my own,
and raise my kid alone.
I leave for work at 10 a.m.
and come home at 8 p.m.
so what am I supposed
to do with my child?
Should I put a lock on the door
and lock her inside?
Also, do I need to tell you two
if I'm seeing a man or not...
just because you two are
my child's teachers?
- Ow!
- Oh!
Hye Na!
Are you all right?
Oh no, you're bleeding!
Oh gosh, oh no!
Are you okay?
Huh?
You saw that, right?
She was acting.
They say that a child
who is being abused
protects their parent,
no matter what.
Goodness.
And what did the child say?
She said that she tripped on the stairs.
That makes no sense. You can't get
injuries like these from tripping!
I believe that she's lying.
100 percent.
And her mother is saying
the same thing, as well.
I'm sure that she told her to say that.
First, we'll have to put in
a request for some assistance
and pay them a visit at home.
We'll get an idea of
the situation then, and...
What about after that?
To be honest, even if
a child has injuries like these
if both the parent and child insist that
she tripped or bumped into something
we can't do anything.
So, our job is to visit them at home
to see if the child is safe there.
And when necessary,
we'll work alongside the police
and give them a stern warning.
We'll keep an eye on them
for three to six months or so
by paying them a visit at home
once a month, or something like that.
Shouldn't we get that child
out of that home immediately?
She doesn't only live with her mom!
There's a man who lives with them, too!
Do you think her eardrum almost burst
because she was beaten by her mother?
In Korea, parental authority is
considered to be quite important.
According to the law, we can't
just ignore the parent's authority
and forcibly investigate the home.
And it's even more impossible to just
forcibly remove a child from her home.
Hello?
Is anyone home?
This is the police!
What brings you here?
Is this the home of
Student Kim Hye Na?
Yes, so?
We received a report
so we will be confirming
if your child is faring well here.
May we come in?
Wait.
Um, sure.
Kim Hye Na!
Are you Hye Na?
How did you injure your ear?
I got hit by a ball.
A baseball.
Why? Were you playing baseball?
I got hit by one on the street.
While I was walking by.
You're a good girl, aren't you?
You can't lie to a police officer.
We'll check all of the CCTV cameras.
What are you doing right now?
Are you threatening my child?
Well, we're here because
we received a report.
So we need to check
everything thoroughly.
Hey, Jjing.
Let's eat, Jjing.
You were hungry, weren't you?
I'll feed you, so let's eat.
I'm really sorry, Honey.
I'm sorry that I'm a
woman who has a daughter.
And I'm so thankful that
you're so understanding, but...
But please, let me ask you one favor.
Leave her alone. Please?
Things will be really difficult for me
if people keep showing up like this.
If you really can't stand the kid
should I send her off to an
orphanage or something, instead?
I'll give birth to your kid instead.
- Okay?
- Damn it!
Don't go, Honey.
What am I supposed to do
if you just leave like this?
[DramaFever Ver] tvN E01 Mother
-♥ Ruo Xi ♥-
Mom.
I'm sorry.
Go away.
I said, go away!
Go somewhere I can't see you!
Sweet potatoes...
are delicious.
Delicious things...
are...
I heard that the child is
quite obedient to her mother.
It's because her mother is
the only person she can trust
so the child has no choice
but to cling on to her.
I've heard back from the police
and I've requested help from
Child Protective Services as well
but we have to treat this matter
with the utmost seriousness.
A child, her family, and our school's
honor are all on the line here.
Outsiders can't really get involved
too much in other families' matters.
At any rate, I've already
visited the principal, too.
I don't like this school or the cops.
If they all sit and do nothing, aren't
they all just enabling domestic violence?
Right?
In my opinion...
I think we should listen a bit more
to what Hye Na has to say.
Hye Na is being manipulated
by her mother right now!
She said she tripped on the stairs
and got hit by a baseball!
And you want us to keep listening
to this sort of nonsense?
I think that Hye Na is saying that
she's afraid to betray her mother,
who is her only blood relative.
She's scared to say that
she got hit and was abused.
She's embarrassed
to tell other people about it.
And she's scared to be sent
to a facility full of strangers.
I think those are the kinds of
things that she's saying to us.
How long do you want us to just
sit and watch her get hit, then?
Rather than referring to is as
"sitting and watching..."
You're talking about this
as if it's someone else's problem.
You don't want to become
a teacher, do you?
Becoming a teacher means that
you have to take on responsibilities
that may be difficult or troublesome!
Do you honestly think that
I want to be doing this?
My wedding is next week!
I don't have time to be
going all over the place.
I'll be going now.
She keeps asking me
if I like my mom.
So, what did you say?
I told her that I like her a lot.
- Of course.
- Are you okay?
Huh?
Are you relieved?
She finished her master's at
the University of Wisconsin in 2008.
And in 2014, she was
working on her Ph.D
at the University of Canterbury
in New Zealand
and moved elsewhere three years ago.
Her advisor from the university
in New Zealand changed
so they said that they don't know
for sure where she went.
They did say that they'd
look into it for us, but...
Jae Beom.
Yes, Ma'am?
I want you to go.
Where?
Do you really think they'll
try that hard for us
when they couldn't truly know
just how much of a rush we're in?
So, I want you to go to New Zealand.
But, Ma'am!
You have events on your schedule here
and you're not in the best of health.
So how could I leave you?
And I can't speak English, either.
Give us a moment.
Jae Beom.
Yes, Ma'am?
I'm not just asking you to
search for Soo Jin on a whim.
For the past 10 years
it was so hard for me to let her
roam free, doing as she wished.
But I can't allow her to do that
anymore in my current state.
Find her for me.
I'm begging you.
Mom!
Ah, you're here, Yi Jin?
What's going on that
you're looking for Big Sis?
I'll tell you later.
She hasn't contacted us once
in the past 10 years.
And yet, there's something
you can't tell me about
but want to talk to her about?
She's still your big sister,
whether she kept in touch or not.
Just wait until we find her.
Found you.
Eat this.
Eat it quickly.
How disgusting.
So, when do they want you to come?
As soon as possible.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I used to buy you tons of food because
I thought you were from a poor family.
I am.
But your mom came looking for you
in your first year.
Mom!
There are a lot of cases in which the
mom is rich, but the daughter is poor.
Feed yourself well there,
and don't be lonely.
All right.
I don't get lonely, though.
Are you really not lonely at all,
even in the slightest?
Haven't you ever liked someone
and wanted to be with them
or gotten mad because
you cared for someone?
You've never felt like that?
I'm home.
What's this?
We were playing hide and seek.
But I couldn't get out of here.
Honey!
I really find these sorts of
pranks to be quite scary!
What if someone came here and saw this?
Go outside and play.
[Yoon Bok's Restaurant]
"We do delivery."
"Yoon Bok's Restaurant."
"Curry and rice."
"Omurice."
"Donkatsu."
I love donkatsu more than
anything in this world.
"Spicy rice cakes."
"Spicy rice cakes with ramen noodles."
I'm memorizing how to pronounce
the names of foods well, at least.
Kim Hye Na!
Ms. Kang!
Young children shouldn't
be out at this hour!
This caller cannot be reached.
You will be transferred to voicemail.
Your mom keeps on
not picking up her phone.
Is it okay if I feed this
to Jjing, Ms. Kang?
Jjing is hungry.
Yeah, sure.
There's some left over...
so should I eat this?
Do, re, mi, fa, so, la, ti, do!
I'm not really good at reading books.
Why not?
Because I can't read quickly.
Really?
I had no idea.
[Yoon Bok's Restaurant]
So I practice every day.
My mom is really good at cooking, too.
Really?
What's she good at making?
Um, curry and rice?
Omurice.
Donkatsu.
Sounds yummy, right?
And...
spicy rice cakes...
and spicy rice cakes with ramen noodles.
You must be so happy...
that your mom is good at cooking, Hye Na.
Yes! And my mom is really pretty, too!
Really?
She's really good at putting on makeup
and she works at a cosmetics store.
So she smells nice.
But...
why don't you ever put on
any makeup, Ms. Kang?
My mom is really pretty, too.
And she's really good at
putting on makeup, too.
When I was young and watched my mom
put on makeup, I thought to myself...
that there was no way
that I could do it.
And that I should just
give up altogether.
You didn't want to become
like your mom, Ms. Kang?
Yeah.
Did you...
not like your mom, Ms. Kang?
Then, who do you like, Ms. Kang?
I like birds.
"The birds... started..."
"flying toward Egypt..."
"and they are now already in Egypt."
Migratory birds fly across oceans...
on journeys that are sometimes
tens of thousands of kilometers long.
And yet, they never lose their way.
Rain or snow, day or night...
they fly over chilly oceans...
without any maps or landmarks
to follow as reference.
But they always reach their
destination, no matter what.
Wow!
Because they have maps
and directions, all in their heads.
What do you think it feels like
to fly such long distances?
Want to go see them?
The migratory birds, I mean.
When?
It's too cold right now.
So if we get some sleep and
bring a blanket and some warm food...
But then, my mom...
My mom might worry,
don't you think?
Yes?
Yes.
Your mom said that she's home now.
Let's get you dressed.
All right.
Thank you.
- Get home safely.
- Ms. Kang.
I really want to go later.
To see the migratory birds, I mean.
Let's go.
Did it hurt?
Did you cry?
I've never asked you for
a favor before, right, Senior?
Did something happen?
[Baek Island
Elementary School, Class 1-3]
I'll give you a call later, so can you
check to see if she's safe for me?
What do I need to check on, exactly?
If she's attending school
and is getting home safely.
I don't know. I feel like
something will happen.
Is she a student in your class?
- Yes.
- So, why?
I'm worried.
I'm so worried that
I feel like I'll get angry!
I saw the man who lives
with her and her mother.
It was the first time
that I'd ever seen him, but...
he had a look in his eyes
that I am familiar with.
The look of a beast who
breaks women and children.
Well, at any rate,
congratulations.
A person needs to chase her dreams.
I'm sure I'll find
another teacher somehow.
Don't worry too much.
Thank you for everything up until now.
Sure. Go on, now.
I knew this would happen.
You've been given an opportunity
to pursue your passion, right?
I'm sure things were quite tough on you
because of me, Ms. Ye Eun.
So... you research birds?
- Yes.
- It suits you.
And your cold, callous image.
Hye Na!
Kim Hye Na!
I thought that I would be going to see
the migratory birds with you, Ms. Kang.
Jjing!
Mom.
Where's Jjing?
Jjing went to Heaven.
That's better for her than
living locked up in there.
But, Mom.
Heaven...
doesn't exist.
I'm not the one who did it!
A curving, sloped road.
Big bags with wheels on them.
Were you crying?
You didn't cry, right?
If you cry, you die.
The sound of Jjing
eating sunflower seeds.
If that tear falls, you're dead.
If you make even
the smallest sound...
you're dead. Got that?
The sound of waves crashing.
The smell of the wind before it rains.
What did I tell you last time
about what I do to noisy kids?
When my eyes meet a cat's gaze.
But, Uncle.
We live on the first floor.
Falling from the first floor...
won't kill me.
When balloons get bigger and bigger.
Want me to tell you
what I did to Jjing?
I pressed down on her
really hard, like this.
Really, really hard.
The road that leads to the ocean.
And then, do you know
what happened to her?
Her eyes swelled up
like a shrimp's eyes...
and they popped right out of her head.
There was this liquid,
the color of blood.
And there was also this sticky thing
mixed in there, like saliva.
All right?
The sun reflecting on the ocean.
You're disgusting, all right?
You're disgusting.
Mom!
Mom.
When my mom hugs me tight.
How disgusting!
[Cafe Latte]
Cafe Latte.
What time is the movie?
I want to have a nice,
sweet cup of coffee.
I need to get myself together, too.
Cafe latte.
The first day that
Ms. Kang Soo Jin smiled.
I'm sorry.
Would you like some water, Hye Na?
Is there anything you want to eat?
Would you like...
a cafe latte?
I want to go see...
the migratory birds, Ms. Kang.
I'll tell you a secret.
His name was...
Lee Hwan.
When Uncle was living with him and Mom...
he was being too noisy...
so Uncle threw him off the balcony.
But that apartment
was on the fourth floor.
You don't have to tell me.
Don't tell me if it's scary
for you to remember.
At the time, he was five years old...
and died, so he can't become
an elementary schooler anymore.
He attended Long Legs Kindergarten,
and was in the Ongdalsaem Class...
so I wrote his name
in my notebook.
Even if all of his classmates
and teachers forget his name...
I will never forget it.
Because the only person
who knows how he really died...
is me.
Uncle told me that he'd kill me...
if I told someone else.
Hey, you guys!
Where are you all going?
Can't you take me with you?
Take me away with you!
Far away!
Far, far away!
To Heaven!
Hye Na.
Listen to me carefully.
I will take you away.
To a place several
thousand kilometers away
where nobody will find you.
Won't you go to jail
if you do that, Ms. Kang?
I could.
No, Ms. Kang!
You don't have to leave with me.
If you leave, you'll never
be able to come back.
And you'll never be able
to see your mom again, either.
But if you go back home...
you may end up like Lee Hwan
from Ongdalsaem Class one day, too.
Why is it that a child
can't survive without a mother?
They can.
And I'll help you so that you can.
My mom threw me away
in the trash bin!
And now...
you will be the one
throwing your mom away.
Will you be able to do it?
[Call Me Mother]
Subtitles by DramaFever
Ripped by RuoXi @ Subscene
Let's walk on bravely,
as if we're completely fine.
I'm not scared, Mom.
I feel like my head will explode
because I feel like
she died because of me!
This wasn't an accident.
It was murder.
You would've left already
if it hadn't been for me.
Hye Na!
Hye Na's face... is on television?
- Her mother must consent...
- No.
- I can't live like that.
- The child may have died already!
What if she's not dead?
I'm sure it'll be fine.
- Quite a lot.
- We'll take it slow.
Because I'll find a way,
no matter what.
Resynced for RUMORS by
gabbyu @ Subscene