Do your prayer my brother.
Said that Allah is the only god that
exists.
And is the largest.
Expensive present!
Since April 2003, the Kurdistan is
free.
Saddam Hussein has left a country in
ruins.
We must rebuild this country.
Establish strong institutions.
Police and army.
To protect our people.
There is no justice without
security.
And there is neither justice nor
security without punishment.
Sir.
Mr. Doctor.
Mr. Estimated mullah.
Today I feel honored.
For the first time in Kurdish
history.
In our democracy.
We will apply the death penalty.
The culprit.
Anwar ahmed gefur.
Committed murder and rape.
He will be hanged.
- Sir we do how?
- You have not prepared anything?
- Prepared what?
- The rope of the gallows!
Oh yes the string.
Idiot!
Do not kill me I am innocent.
That's illegal.
We must stop it.
He is not dead.
The law says?
The law is formally.
He must be hanged.
Not twice.
Condemn the imprisonment.
Has not yet been in prison he has to
die.
Then pull a bullet in the neck.
Not hanging is the only way.
I have a solution: the condemned is
small.
If I cling to him he will die soon.
So what do we do?
Blessing fell.
Hanging did not tell you like it?
I understand you.
But it should be out of this
situation.
I am a fighter not a cop.
The war is over Saddam fell.
Kurds are free.
I resign.
We need you now.
I did my work.
I leave you the honors.
Now I go home.
This country needs laws to security
and stability.
Otherwise we will lose everything we
have undertaken.
Does not become resistant cop.
You're too idealistic baran.
Our situation has improved.
It has all.
We sleep on oil.
No misses your luck.
Was not the concept of luck I think.
Well give me your gun.
The weapon it is mine.
Mom!
- My son missed you.
- You too.
Will shelter us.
My daughter I said no.
You do not go back to this village.
I work with children.
I sleep in the school.
You do not have to worry.
Enough Govend!
The father said no.
You will not go back.
Working one does not need your
salary.
If I had married taqiyeddine.
We would not be here.
I'm not made for taqiyeddine.
But you're a girl my daughter.
Well you trust my brothers?
Yes.
And your daughter?
I trust you too.
How you doin?
How you find my son?
It has the serious air.
It looks good.
It is beautiful.
Baran you came back to marry you and
we caches!
Kader what's this marriage thing
where you leave it?
Just in the garden my son I need
you.
Leave me alone mom.
Come see my son.
I decided to take the service.
This time.
You will work with me.
No.
Send me where you need me.
Very well.
Then I will send you there.
Qamarian.
A brand new police station waiting
for you.
I can not go farther.
The Turkish army destroyed the
bridge.
How I'm going to qamarian?
2 hours walk.
The bridge is destroyed continue
riding.
You're baran?
- And reber you?
- Yes it's me your assistant.
You were punished?
Nobody wants to come here.
It's my choice.
In town there's oil business money.
Why come here?
I fly my mother.
I can not leave the country rotten.
What were you doing before?
Fighter.
Since the age of fifteen years.
In our village there is nothing
going.
There is already something.
One makes smuggling here?
Here is the Bermuda Triangle.
Our Kurdish Iraq make alcohol
traffic.
With iran.
Our turkey Kurds are supplied with
weapons by.
Is Turkish planes?
They seek resistant.
It is the teacher.
I can not let you walk.
I'm used to walk.
Ride with me.
My name Govend.
Baran.
What do you qamarian?
I'm the new commander.
Thank you.
I prefer staying here.
A woman with two men people will
talk.
Thank you.
It is still in the works but you
have a nice place.
Between I beg.
There are only two telephones in the
village.
A in here the other restaurant.
The villagers come here to call.
You're forced to listen to their
stories of love.
Hens and roosters.
Is boring.
But sometimes it can be used.
All these people are your photo
predecessors.
It is always the same photographer?
Yes.
What for?
Good evening.
- M.
Zirek!
- How you doin?
Good evening.
We changed the lock.
I know they did when I was not
there.
- You do not have the new key?
- I'll see.
If you come stay with us.
Home?
Or at the inn.
It often cuts?
Electricity?
God only knows.
There are also two rooms with a
small prison.
This is the last commander of the
rifle.
That was the previous.
Cursed be your electricity!
Good evening.
You are welcome!
Thank you.
Alcohol?
I have very good alcohol.
For the night two or three bottles?
Since the death of simko.
It was not heated in you.
Good evening.
M. Saman.
I do not have the keys you do not
have a room?
There is a room?
No.
No I have no room.
I see.
They do not want a teacher.
It's school or the only woman they
do not want?
Since when you work here?
Three months.
Your family thinks what?
They are not all in agreement.
I respect what my father.
And he agreed?
Yes.
It is surely a good person.
Thank you.
Hello.
It's you again?
The new commander.
Aziz aga send me.
You are his guest tonight.
I do not know.
Is the lord of the region.
It invites every newcomer in the
evening of his arrival.
An invitation that does not refuse
reber is not it?
Then agree.
But for lunch.
You know what you're doing?
I'm going too fast?
Baran it would be a shame.
We do not have time to take at least
your photo.
Aziz has many ways.
It is very powerful.
Govend!
I have not had time to look for the
key.
When I got home the little had
fever.
He is better now?
He is better thank you.
Which changed the school's lock?
What?
It is you who have changed the lock
or is aziz aga?
I do not know Govend.
Do not you know?
We did not know you'd come back.
I came back.
In a few months you will be
transferred.
But I still.
And I have to feed my family.
You can accommodate children?
Sit!
Hello.
Where is my heater?
Not breathing.
That was very well.
Super.
It was very well.
Welcome baran.
Aziz thank you aga.
Welcome.
Enter.
Baran.
You're in front of bradost.
This mountain has always protected
us.
Turkish Persians and Arabs failed to
come here.
Aziz aga I am delighted to hear
that.
If there is corruption in the region
and.
Unworthy or compromise.
Or influence of foreign forces.
You can be proud of.
Baran I know who you are.
The liberation war is one thing.
Maintain peace and security is
something else.
You're aware of the fate of your
predecessor?
Poor simko.
He has been brutally murdered.
Stubborn he lost everything.
But do not worry.
I offer you my protection.
Times change.
Today authority is Kurdish.
Laws should apply everywhere.
It is I who must enforce.
And it is to me to protect you aziz
aga.
Baran.
My family rules over these mountains
for years.
I know everyone.
Old young children.
Rather repair the bridge of the
village.
It is not the mission entrusted to
me that.
But I'm glad you hope modernize the
country.
Time will make you understand.
I'm the new commander of the region.
From now.
I will ensure law enforcement.
There are laws written.
And there are ancestral laws.
The fact.
I heard noises.
Your first night seems to have been
nice.
And though.
It does not concern you.
During the war that was aga?
He sometimes help our resistant.
By contacting the Turkish and
Iranian.
It was collabo?
Quite often found where you least
expect.
Here the war is not over.
We are not at peace here?
I go go.
Good evening!
What's going on?
One of our comrades was wounded.
He needs medication.
You can go and see if there is such
drugs at the inn?
And some food also.
What are you doing in these
mountains?
Rice.
Rice lenses.
And drugs?
- Penicillin?
- Antibiotics?
Hello!
Welcome Tajdin.
What do you want?
We will have fun.
Not touch me!
Bastard!
You hurt me.
Let me go!
Loose it!
Pull over!
Enough!
Shame on you!
Sluts!
Kind of whores.
I'll kill you.
These trails have nothing to do
here.
They must go.
I'll take care Tajdin.
It's me who'll take care.
We must rid the area of these
parasites.
You understand?
I'll tell you one thing.
I'll take them to the police.
Name commander!
I take them to aziz aga.
He will know how to take care.
Tajdin!
The law that's me!
You understand?
It will not always be there to
protect you.
What are you doing here?
We need medicine.
Turkish destroyed the bridge because
of you.
Now.
We can move on foot or on horseback.
You are fighting against the Turks
go to Turkey.
It has helped you against Saddam.
Enough!
One is that either Kurdish Turkey
and Iraq.
You're on their side?
Politically non.
Yes but morally.
I do not agree with the armed
struggle.
But I understand.
When you are in Turkey and Kurdish
woman.
The bush is freedom.
We can leave?
What medications you need?
Hello mistress.
You've seen before?
Six times nine?
Six times three?
Do not you know?
And one plus one?
One plus one does it make?
Say something.
Even if you do not know.
Ten.
- How much?
- Ten.
Ten?
Mizgin him and how much is it?
I know mistress.
But my mother more than my father
ten children are.
Was that fake drugs here.
Look.
Is flour.
Mr. Approach.
For $ 40 I give you the good.
Your university.
Should teach you morality too.
Medications!
You missed the opportunity to get
down!
You do not have things to say to my
lord?
I can not be a teacher and caretaker
manager.
I need it.
But thou hast hid me which housed
the turkey Kurdish home.
And its relationship with the
commander.
All that you knew zirek.
Nevertheless it is a good teacher.
Children learn best with it.
That's the most important.
Zirek rids us of her.
It is the administration that
decides not me.
Your son is still sick?
I could send abroad.
He will be treated in the best
hospitals.
Hear?
Yes.
She prostitute well with the
commander?
I want the address of his family.
Hello.
Silence.
I'll do the class.
What?
You can leave you free.
There is a problem?
No.
You can go.
I do the class.
Govend.
I do not understand.
I go and you make the class?
Yes.
- I'm leaving and you make the
class?
- Yes.
C'mon do the class.
C'mon begins.
I want to talk to aziz aga.
It is not.
You mean him?
I will never leave this school.
Say it to him.
I'll stay.
Hello.
Agreed.
Back in a few minutes.
Thank you.
Govend!
Hello.
Phone for you.
Dad what happens?
What you mean daddy?
Who told you that?
Reber come see.
You think they are smugglers?
It is men aziz aga.
Will know what they traffic.
There are too many.
We go.
It's our job.
Pull over!
Advance!
Stand still!
What are you a merchant?
Nothing.
It's a little soap and sugar.
Medications or drugs?
We need these drugs.
They are out of date?
I do not touch that.
I did not check the dates of
medications.
Handcuff him.
What do you want?
A cigarette please.
I dream of a cigarette.
Shut up and be quiet.
Opens the door.
I want to smoke and going to the
toilet.
Cigarette or toilet?
Cigarette.
This is not finished?
Stand still!
Baran why you stopped?
His file is empty.
He sold expired drugs.
You have evidence?
They have them removed.
Robert and I are witnesses.
Sir they sell expired medicines.
To poor people who die.
You tortured.
And have him extract confessions.
He could not defend himself.
Jaffar mohamed emin is that you?
Yes sir.
Do you recognize these accusations?
No.
We have families on the other side
of the border.
Sometimes we exchange.
Food.
You also have a witness?
My lord the respected aziz aga.
Attests to the honesty of his friend
Mohammed Emin jaffar.
His uprightness of his good faith.
And loyalty to our country.
Jaffar mohamed emin.
You are free.
Release it!
It's a shame.
Not now jafar.
Commander.
I talk to you?
You should not attack you aziz aga.
About your morals dating is sacred
here.
Morality?
It's good you can go reber.
They are dangerous, you know.
You want me to stay?
No thank you.
If your tribe asks you to kill me.
You kill me?
Fuck off!
Here is the police.
Govend?
And who are you?
Taqiyeddine.
Zirek?
Zirek is that you?
Who's there?
Zirek?
I heard the noise.
Who's there?
It's a school here or?
You finish your sentence and you're
dead.
What do you want?
We saw the light when we entered.
And here.
It was expected that.
Shame on you.
Go home Tajdin.
You do not scare me commander.
You do not scare anyone here.
My brother I do not want to kill
Kurdish.
You must respect the school and the
teacher.
It is there for your kids.
Rather it is there for you.
Stop!
Make us our weapons.
The mountain is dangerous.
We want our weapons.
If you cross a jackal negotiate.
Our weapons is our honor Commander.
Make us weapons.
You have no honor.
Get thee Tajdin.
Get the fuck camp.
You will regret commander.
Thank you.
Is brave for taking on this post.
Nobody wanted this village.
While children here need education.
I like it here.
I also love your children.
You do not have you?
No.
I have made up my studying
twenty-six.
For the people here I am very old
now.
How old are you?
Twenty-eight years.
Here if you're not married at my
age.
People think you have a problem.
Is that taqiyeddine?
What?
What for?
He called.
It's nothing.
He's an idiot.
You like music?
What for?
Like that.
Why you ask?
For nothing like that.
Yes.
Really?
What do you listen to?
Elvis Presley.
Jean Sebastian Bach.
Mozart.
There are many other.
Will not you sing?
Right now?
When you go away from me.
The moon darkens.
Your beautiful face your neck thy
mouth.
Become for me the veil of night.
Your beautiful face your neck thy
mouth.
Become for me the veil of night.
You're my end hoofed my end.
Here.
- Great picture!
- It shows.
It's not much but it's good.
Thank you!
Was the visit.
Welcome aziz aga.
I want to see the commander.
Without your men.
Last night it is a serious mistake.
I understand you do not know all of
us.
Guns do not count as.
But disarm a man.
It is an insult.
Weapons in schools is prohibited.
I love you very baran.
I like the stubborn men.
Then content yourself touching your
salary.
And do not meddle with the rest.
There is a problem?
It is said that you and the teacher.
You became friends.
A rather special friendship.
It does not concern you aziz aga.
You still do not understand baran.
Home the honor.
Matters.
I do not know which side you were
during the war aziz aga.
But I'm not sure we have the same
sense of honor.
Thus please.
You lack.
Cold blood.
Yes that's right.
I hope you know what you're doing.
If it is to prove your might aziz
aga not wrong.
You must be crazy!
Tajdin.
The real problem is baran.
Must neutralize.
Abdullah how are you?
It's okay?
It will be a particular course.
Abdullah!
Are you okay?
You were not going to school.
You should go.
People do not like me here.
Go away!
Let's go!
You listen to me ever!
Baran.
Govend here is your tea.
Thank you.
You do not like my tea?
If so.
It is a little bitter for me.
I like it like that.
I too infused or I put too.
It will not?
Excuse me.
It is because of the children?
- They do not come?
- No.
What are you going to do?
I do not know.
I have no solution.
You're going to apply for a
transfer?
I could.
Excuse me I have to go.
If ever a child arrives.
It is better that I be there.
What are you doing here?
Welcome my brothers.
Where u from?
I am not accountable to you brother.
I am your brother.
I was in the police station.
You're reassured sadu?
Not meddle with it.
That's what I want to talk to you.
Returned.
Hence.
This is the first school to be
opened in this village.
There are problems.
What problems?
Some do not want a teacher.
This is not the problem.
We heard of a man!
We trust you my sister.
But we heard gossip.
Is to reassure the father sends us.
Leave me alone.
Taqiyeddine and his family returned
to ask your hand.
I have the right to have an opinion?
- Yes.
- I dont no!
I never marry with taqiyeddine.
Clear?
Why are you doing this to him?
Down a tone.
Not forget to whom you speak.
You exhaust me.
You make me mad.
On the hill!
Whore burst!
I regret that it happens like that.
I give up.
I'm leaving.
Collabo!
It's good we go!
Uncle you okay?
It's up to you my lord.
Goes!
As will be alive aga.
You and your bitch will never have
peace.
Baran.
We can find a compromise.
I do not compromise.
Govend quickly do your suitcase!
Father is waiting for you.
It was you who decided or father?
Shut your mouth!
You are our honor.
We have to protect you.
Have you your honor I take care of
mine!
Get up!
You totally tried.
We must wash our honor.
Our father decides.
I do not give him that bitch!
You totally tried.
Shame on you!
He hath kissed?
You are no different occupant.
You are like the soldiers of Saddam.
Dare you say that?
We love you my sister.
Out!
Kill me!
C'mon kill me!
You will be relieved.
Go ahead make yourself happy!
And then cry for me.
C'mon!
Let her!
J'te released or killed.
Let her go.
Let her.
It gives off!