MY WAY HOME
Khleb means "bread".
Say it.
- Khleb
- No, say it softer.
- Woda means "water".
What does pashlee mean?
Pashlee? It means, "Go to hell!"
Let's go on. Kushaty
- Kushaty Know what that means?
- It means "to eat".
Dai mne kushaty
means "give me food".
Good, very good.
Why hide?
They stopped attacking.
Get changed!
Just put the shirt on.
- Give me food.
- Kushaty
Dai mne kushaty
Is that right?
Yes.
How do you like it?
Will it be OK?
Put on the cap too.
- They're stationed at the road.
- We have to pass them.
The region's full of them.
- Let's take a chance.
- Let's go.
- And you?
- l'm not going.
Idiot! Stay then.
The Cossacks!
Hold them.
Come here.
Over there.
Traitors! Bandits!
We got the last ones.
You go with them too!
Hands up!
Dirty fascists!
Take your clothes off!
Hungarian?
I'm Hungarian too, sir.
They forced me to wear this.
Come here.
Are you Hungarian?
Do you have any documents?
Schoolboy? Student?
Joseph.
How old are you?
Your age! How old are you?
17 years old?
- Done?
- Done.
Come on! Quicker!
Just a little more!
Girls!
The Cossacks are coming!
What's the hurry, gorgeous?
- l'll get you!
- Try!
Get me, Cossack!
Line up in fives!
You go too! Over there!
You all right, old man?
Open your mouth.
Nothing.
Healthy.
He's OK.
That chap will escape.
Come on,
splash about in the water.
Come on, splash!
Come on, jump, splash about!
There's barbed wire
all the way down.
I'll try once again.
Come! That was enough.
Come out!
All of you. Enough!
How many times do I have to say?
Take your things and come on!
Move, move! Come on!
Fourth company, line up!
Line up, you at the back too!
Hell! What are you waiting for?
Line up!
Are you in the fourth company, too?
Stop gawping! Come on!
You too! Get in the line.
Get in the line!
What are you waiting for? Move!
One, two... You too.
Four, five...
I'll take four men to fetch water.
Thirsty, all of you?
One...
Can you lead a horse?
Step out!
- For water?
- Go up to the guard!
Five men to fetch water.
- O§ä§Üp§îi§Óa§Û! - Ec§ä§î!
Go ahead!
Come on!
Stop!
How did you get here?
Did I select you?
I live quite near.
On our way back, l'll get lost.
- You'll stay!
- Shut one eye, that's all.
- Are you a soldier?
- I used to be. Does it matter?
Shut up! I am the boss here.
Go and draw water!
- Do you have a cigarette?
- No.
Halt!
Carefully.
Stop.
Why are there six of you?
Get in line. Quickly!
Where's the sixth one from?
One, two, three, four, five, six.
From here, go.
What shall I do with you?
Well, go home. Go.
Go home.
Get out!
You are free!
Go to hell!
He means you. Go home! Go!
Get up!
- Are you German?
- Hungarian.
What are you looking at, kraut?
One, two, three.
Go to the truck.
One... two... three. Go!
Wait!
- How old are you?
- 17.
Do you speak Russian? German?
- Do you speak German?
- A little.
What's your profession?
What work do you do?
Can you drive?
I don't understand.
Car? Chauffeur?
- l'm a schoolboy.
- Schoolboy? Get in, schoolboy.
Let's go.
Praise be to our Lord.
- Where is he?
- Go.
Kolya!
Where have you been?
The milk will get sour.
- Where's the milk?
- lt's coming!
Hurry up!
Load them up! Work!
- Here's your parcel!
- Thanks.
- How are the troops doing?
- It won't take long.
Let's go.
You stay.
I left him for you. He'll help you!
Here, eat!
Why are you coming here?
Who called you?
Go away! I told you to go away!
Where are you going?
There are mines there.
Stop! I told you to stop!
Stop or l'll shoot!
B§ïop§Óe§ê§îc§ñ, §Ú§Õ§Úo§ä!
You'll die there!
Do you want to die?
You fool!
There are mines all round.
Mines, understand?
Read the sign. Mines!
Read the sign.
It says here!
See? There are mines here.
Look.
I'm taking you back.
You're my prisoner of war.
If you run away,
l"ll get into trouble.
If you try to escape, l'll kill you.
Do you understand?
No, you don't.
Let's get down to work.
We're short of churns.
Pour it out...
...onto the ground.
Stop a bit, driver!
Can I take a ride?
Come, get on.
Comrade Commander,
what a lovely dog.
Ta§ß§è§å§Û!
Well, student, do you
understand Russian now?
Come here, doggy.
Hey, who's going to work
instead of you?
Come on. Run!
Stop it! Come on!
I've even got a name
for him - Burka.
Come, come!
Leave the dog here, Comrade.
I could use him.
You already have a helper.
Burka!
Come here. Stop!
Come over here!
Give me the dog.
Stop it!
Let's go.
There you go.
Come! Come here!
- What's up?
- There are potatoes here.
Where?
Give me the bucket!
Spit it out!
You want to die now that you're free?
Spit it out! Don't you understand?
Spit it out!
Idiot!
More people tried to escape
from our camp?
Three Poles were kneeling
at the steps of the chapel.
- Poles?
- Yes, but there were others too.
They kneeled down
and tried to escape.
Four of them dug a hole
under the altar.
They got three of them.
One escaped.
- What is it?
- This bucket is ours.
- You're Hungarian?
- Yes.
- Really?
- You rotten NaZi!
- l'm not a NaZi.
- Not any more, of course!
- He is a NaZi. You can see it.
- Leave him alone!
- I will kill you, you bastard!
Let go or l'll fire!
That's not right.
- What's not right?
- lt's not right.
All of you against one, is that fair?
Let's go, don't be scared.
All against one.
- Are you Hungarian?
- Yes.
- A prisoner of war?
- Could you escape?
- Yes.
Follow us.
We'll get a striped coat for you.
Nothing, nothing.
This boy would get into trouble,
if I escaped.
Look, frogs!
Quiet.
There... a hit!
Xo§ée§ê§î §áoc§äpe§Ý§ñ§ä§î?
Got it!
Come on.
Come on, move.
Go to hell!
Go.
Follow me! Come.
Come here.
One... Hold this.
Two, three.
Look, statues.
Statues.
A whole museum.
What's that? A broken head.
Look at the style. Greek.
Pretty, isn't it?
I'll put it back.
It lay here.
Give me your coat.
She's freeZing.
There.
This will be the wreath.
How beautiful!
Let's throw stones through
the window. Will you?
One...
More. Got it?
One more.
One more, come on.
Throw some more.
I was lucky!
Hold it up.
Hold it for me.
I'm going to climb up.
Be careful.
- Hold it!
- Jump!
It breaks easily.
This one's finished.
She gave her soul to God.
Let's go.
Go. Go. Move!
Watch out!
Don't let her back out.
- Come on, go!
- Damn you!
Come on, move!
Go.
What was that?
Stop. I'll go alone.
Be careful. On the right.
Follow my tracks.
To hell with it!
Look here.
Here are their tracks.
- Go carefully over there.
- I can see it.
Come.
Yeah, l'm coming.
We won't be hungry
until the end of the war.
- lt'll be a rich meal.
- Grab it.
Yeah. Come on.
Heavy, isn't it?
Give me a piece.
Delicious, isn't it?
It's cooked in the Georgian way.
I love it.
Just a little bit.
Give me a drink.
What's the matter?
Are you in pain?
My stomach.
It's my wound here.
I got wounded.
The bullet is still in there.
The doctor told me to exercise.
To do this... and l'll be OK.
Can you hear?
Look at them!
Can you see it?
Give it to me.
You're so far away.
Run!
Let's catch up with her!
Come on! Run!
- Look out, he's coming for us!
- Take to the ground!
- He's coming back.
- Look how it turns.
He wants to play.
I told you so.
He's coming back.
- Run!
- Take to the ground.
Where is she?
Over there. Look!
She's too far away.
Come on.
Don't you know your duty?
Where have you been?
- Everything's been OK.
- That's what you think.
Disinfectant.
Do you have a samovar?
What do you want it for?
You'll get clean anyway.
Two handkerchiefs?
- Is that all?
- Stop asking questions.
- Why only two handkerchiefs?
- I don't know.
It's order number 248.
Obey, or do it yourself.
What manners! I work all day long.
You can't do that to us.
- Keep quiet.
- Brother, l'm wounded.
A soldier must obey orders.
- But since l'm wounded...
- Undress. I'm also wounded.
Shall I cover myself with this?
Do that, the rest doesn't matter.
Where are you going?
Go over there.
You can only go there dressed.
Come on.
Get undressed.
Nothing else works...
...only disinfectant.
Are you a girl or a soldier?
What are you doing? Close it.
They're not ready,
and the machine needs to cool down.
Hurry up, boys!
Look at those soldiers!
They make you strip!
Look! Napoleon! Is it ready?
Patience, soldier! Hold on!
Open it!
You've ruined my uniform.
Don't be fussy.
Here...
Let's go.
Nice work.
- Enough, soldier.
- Yes, indeed.
- Stop squealing!
- You've ruined my uniform...
- What's the matter?
- It hurts.
Something's hurting me... inside.
Look... my tongue.
Good.
The Germans got me.
The devil knows how,
but I survived.
And l'm OK,
do you understand?
The doctor said I need
a good diet and exercise.
Don't worry, l'll survive.
Water, hot water.
Come on, quickly.
They are waiting for the milk.
Kolya is ill.
What are you saying?
Hurry up!
We've got a lot of wounded.
Don't you understand?
Kolya is ill.
He didn't understand a word.
- l've got documents.
- I see.
Go home.
- l've got documents.
- l'm Hungarian.
Is there a doctor amongst you?
No.
Do you want some meat?
Thank you.
- Do you live here?
- I do.
- Is he ill?
- He is.
He got wounded,
and now he's ill.
- Is he Russian?
- He is.
What are you waiting for?
Why don't you get lost?
Some more meat?
No, thanks.
Let's go!
Stop!
Don't drink this. You're ill.
- We have documents.
- Go. Go.
Hello, Comrade.
Where are you heading?
I've been near VoroneZh
for two years.
I worked there in a factory,
you know.
- I worked...
- Go.
Halt.
Move on.
Halt!
We have documents.
Step back.
Turn away.
He's alone. That's unusual.
Don't show you're afraid.
A doctor?
Is there a doctor here?
Doctor, yes?
Come on.
He's alone.
Take his weapon.
Be careful. He's loaded it.
Let's go!
- Let's go.
- Don't let him do it!
Stay calm.
Probably someone is ill here.
Move!
Move, move!
Move it!
Wait here.
Go back.
Go!
Be careful by the tracks!
I baked cakes for them,
and meat, too.
They were so nice,
they didn't hurt us.
I made strudel for them.
They said, "Mama, let it be good!"
I said, "You'll gobble it up!"
Tovarish!
There is room here!
Come and sit down!
Sit down.
- Thank you.
- You're Hungarian?
- Yes.
- In this uniform?
I thought you were Russian.
Here.
Eat.
So you are Hungarian?
Well, well...
We've already met, haven't we?
I want to tell you something.
Come! Take his gun.
Look!
Look! The scoundrels!
Don't let them get you!