Isn't the air nice, Tatsuo?
You'll get used to it here soon
I'm sure you'll make good friends here
It's Jun-shik!
I'm faster than a car!
Grandpa!
You show the signs of
a great imperial soldier already
Welcome, my boy
How've you been, Father?
Greet them
He's the new, young master
Jun-shik Kim, sir
I'm Eun-soo Kim, sir
Great, Tatsuo
You have a new friend your age
Tatsuo runs well. Like you
My brother's the best runner
in Kyung-sung, sir
I'm the best in Tokyo
No match for a country boy
Wanna race me?
Ready
Go!
Hasegawa beat Korea's Jun-shik Kim
in the 4th high school marathons!
Korea's son, Jun-shik Kim,
beat Hasegawa Tatsuo and won!
"HASEGAWA TATSUO
WINS NATIONAL MARATHONS AGAIN!"
"KIM JUN-SHIK WINS!"
Congratulations
Jun-shik Kim,
the light of Korean marathon
Hasegawa Tatsuo,
the star of Japanese marathon wins again
Good job chasing behind me
Must be your damn lucky day
Let's applaud Hasegawa Tatsuo
who won the national
high school marathon
and brought great honor
to Imperial Japan
Long live our Emperor!
Long live Imperial Japan!
Long live...
This is my grandson, Tatsuo
You must be very proud
I expect a lot from you
Thank you
It's a gift
from the Japanese Minister of Defense
Open it
Yes, sir
Give me that!
Get away!
Grandfather! Grandfather!
- Father!
- Grandfather! Grandfather!
Do something! Father, please!
Do something!
You're a doctor who saves lives!
Why aren't you doing anything?
- You killed him!
- No
You killed him!
No
Bring my grandfather back!
Let go!
He didn't kill anyone!
You bastards killed him!
Jun-shik!
Bring my grandfather back!
No!
- Daddy!
- No! I didn't do it!
Daddy!
- Jun-shik!
- Daddy!
Father!
Bring my grandfather back!
Jun-shik
Let Go!
- Father! Father!
- Daddy... Daddy
Don't show your face around here again
Or I might kill you
Korea's hero, Ki-jung Sohn
won an Olympic gold medal! Rejoice!
MAY, 1938, KYUNG-SUNG, KOREA
Why do you have sandbags strapped on?
Are you a marathon runner?
Korea's luck in the marathon
stops with Ki-jung Sohn
A Korean man will never be
an Olympic victor again
Koreans are banned from Olympics
'cause Sohn covered the Japanese flag?
If you were a bomb,
I'd run straight
into the Athletics Association
Marathon running is a science demanding
concentration and fighting spirit
I'll prove it once and for all
at the Olympic tryouts
Can you go any faster?
You might regret it
I'll pay double
if you get there in 30 minutes
Triple for 20 minutes
Hold on tight
Your victory in the tryouts is a given
What is your goal in the Olympics?
I'll win the gold and set a new record
- What a laugh?
- In honor of our great empire!
Look out!
Let's go! Coming through!
Move! Out of the way!
To a marathon gold medal
at the Tokyo Olympics!
- Cheers!
You're quite the runner
Here you are
Double would've been fine
Opportunities come to those
who don't give up
Jun-shik Kim
Jun-shik!
Are you okay?
Isn't that...
Are you all so happy
over half of a race?
I'm Ki-jung Sohn
Ki-jung Sohn's in Japan
Wanna bet?
If I win, I get to marry your sister
Hurry
You say Japan and Korea are one
yet you ban Koreans from tryouts?
Are you claiming
the Athletics Association is unjust?
Your comment, Mr. Chairman?
The board has decided
If a Japanese runner will win anyways,
what's the problem?
It'll be boring for Hasegawa
without Jun-shik Kim
I think Jun-shik Kim
shouldn't be in the discussion
See!
Jun-shik Kim?
Jun-shik
Jun-shik Kim, what have you been up to?
What are your thoughts on the ban
on Korean runners?
Are you still training?
How much do you train each day?
Your comments, please
Mr. Hasegawa?
Are you confident you'll win
even if Jun-shik Kim enters?
You think he stands a chance against me?
But aren't Jun-shik Kim's records better
than yours?
That was in the past
You think a mere rickshaw driver
can beat a well-trained marathoner?
If you could enter,
are you confident you can beat Hasegawa?
How good can a mere rickshaw driver be?
I'd be grateful just to enter the race
Here is your acceptance letter
from Berlin Medical University
Sign it
The marathon is more important to me
than my studies
This is the most important period
in your life
Focus on your studies
Our men are sacrificing their lives
to build a Greater East Asia
I don't want to be a coward
who runs away from war
War is futile
You are insulting Grandfather
Tatsuo, watch what you say
Think of the people before your country
That's the way of a doctor
Then I must treat the Korean people
who killed my grandfather?
Even if it kills me, I'll never do that
The picture is missing from the frame
in my room
Jong-dae! Why you
Why would someone steal
a picture of all things?
It should be around somewhere
Anyway, I hope you can enter the tryouts
Father will be so happy
Don't get your hopes up
Can't trust the Japs
Get more firewood. The fire's dying
Please?
It's so pretty
How do I look?
Eun-soo
I think you're the prettiest girl
in all of Asia
"OLYMPIC TRYOUTS ENTRY FORM"
Please win and bring hope to Korea again
I can really enter the race?
Show them how scary
a mere rickshaw driver can be!
Jun-shik
Listen carefully
The man in front of Jun-shik
is Ki-jung Sohn
Then, you must be holding
the Olympic tryouts entry form
If I'm right, hold it up high!
Yes!
Let me see!
Sir! Sir!
Jun-shik!
Min-woo! Everyone!
Korea's best marathoner, Jun-shik Kim,
will run the marathon again!
Hurray for Jun-shik Kim! Hurray!
Jun-shik Kim! Jun-shik Kim!
Get the rice cake kings ate!
Rice cakes here!
Here you are
Father picked it out himself
The best pair there is
Promise you'll win the race today?
Tatsuo
Your father will be here soon!
Look
Let's relieve
all our Korean folks' heartaches today!
Jun-shik Kim! Jun-shik Kim!
Act according to the plans.
Runners to the starting line!
You can do it!
And they're off!
Tatsuo!
Go, Jun-shik
Tatsuo, go get 'em!
Hasegawa! Faster! Faster!
Jun-shik, you're halfway there!
Don't mind Jun-shik Kim
Hasegawa! Spurt ahead!
Spurt ahead!
Hasegawa!
The runners will come
into the stadium any minute!
Why are you so late?
A surgery took long
What a tense moment!
There! The runners can be finally seen!
Who is the first runner coming in?
Who will it be?
As expected,
it's Hasegawa with Kimura behind him!
What? There's another runner!
It's Jun-shik Kim!
You can do it
Jun-shik
Jun-shik Kim!
Go, Jun-shik!
Kimura! Kimura!
Hey! What's that bastard doing!
Jun-shik!
Tatsuo!
Jun-shik! The rickshaw won!
Jun-shik Kim! Hurray!
Jun-shik Kim!
The last runner is coming in!
It's a dream come true!
The medals will be awarded soon
I knew you could do it!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the results will now be announced
The winner of All Japan Olympic
Marathon Tryouts is
Hasegawa Tatsuo!
Second is number 13, Ando!
Third is number 18, Kimura!
Will the three runners
come up to the victory stand?
Hasegawa, Ando, and Kimura
Please come to the victory stand
- Jun-shik Kim was first!
- What's he saying?
Jun-shik Kim!
Spectators,
please calm down and be seated
Jun-shik Kim has been disqualified
for blocking Kimura's way
Disqualified? How!
Jun-shik
Is this why you let me enter?
Go back. Didn't you hear
you've been disqualified?
You should've run fair and square
Fair and square?
Crazy bastards
Try Saying it again!
Jun-shik!
Damn bastards!
Jong-dae!
Hasegawa!
Please come up to the victory stand,
immediately!
The winner of the Olympic tryouts
is Jun-shik Kim!
Hasegawa, Ando, and Kimura!
Please come up, immediately!
You bastards cheated first!
Tatsuo!
This court has decided
on the following sentence
Based on section 4 of the legal code,
all accomplices of the riot
will become Imperial soldiers
and swear allegiance to the Emperor
Mother!
I didn't do anything!
Jun-shik!
Eun-soo!
Father!
Jun-shik!
Soldiers must behave with decorum
Stop mumbling!
Soldiers must
always improve their battle skills
I don't believe this
Soldiers must
always improve their battle skills
Soldiers must serve with utmost loyalty
Soldiers must always be frugal
Frugal...
"JULY, 1939,
NOMONHAN, MONGOLIAN BORDERLAND"
Retreat!
Everyone retreat!
That Way!
Concentrate!
Get up there!
Retreat!
Min-woo!
You okay? It's me, Jun-shik
Wake up!
Shit. I should've fought
for independence instead
Who would've guessed we'd end up
fighting for the Japs here?
Our damn fortunes
I'm starving to death
You're hungry 24 hours a day
Grow up will you?
Hey! Hurry up!
Lazy Korean fools!
Yes, sir
Let's hurry
Hope you get shot down dead
He's really dead?
- Choon-bok! Your butt!
- What?
Where's it coming from?
I almost got my head blown off
The broken wall at 1 o'clock
I heard the 1st regiment
got attacked, too. It's him
Just our damn luck
Jong-dae! Cover me
No! Stay back, Jun-shik!
Cover him!
Choon-bok! Cover him!
Are you okay Jun-shik?
It's great you shot down just Japs,
but Noda's gonna kill us
She killed so many
Hey! Don't hog all the food!
Give me some
Don't slobber over it!
Give me some!
This is you?
You keep eating. I'll look at this
Fine, I'll show you. Let me see first
Not that sexy
She's crying
Coz you took her picture
No, it's coz you ate all her beef jerky
Fools. Why'd you make her cry?
The bullets happened to swerve
and hit only Japanese soldiers?
Did the bitch smell
your Kimchi breath? Talk, you fools!
Speak, you bastards!
Who sent you here! Say it!
I'm Shirai from Hailaer
You raped my mother before my father,
and raped me, too
Listen!
There are many like me in China
China will never lose to you!
I will never forgive! Never!
Tell me! Why did the bullets
fly past you Korean rubbish!
Speak, you bastards!
Damn it! Stop it!
I said no speaking Korean!
Enough
That won't bring back the dead!
Go back to your work places
What's all this? Who's coming?
Colonel
I'm Colonel Takakura
Company, halt!
Attention!
What? Why's that bastard here?
Colonel Hasegawa, what brings you here?
Private Takakura ever drive past
honorable Imperial soldiers' corpses?
Mukai!
Yes, sir
First!
For shamefully ordering a retreat,
you're demoted to private as of today
Second
Private Takakura will prove loyalty
to our Emperor and commit hara-kiri!
Be thankful our Emperor
granted you an honorable death!
Long live our Emperor!
Handle the deceased with due respect
Yes, sir
Remember, after feeding off corpses,
crows can come and gouge out your eyes
I'm Hasegawa Tatsuo
I came here to demolish
Soviet tanks!
I'll show them true power
of the Imperial army!
When out of bullets, Imperial soldiers
must charge with bayonets!
If bayonets are broken,
we must fight with bare hands!
Imperial soldiers do not leave
the battlefield till death!
Understood!
Yes, sir
We either win or die
First!
We'll build a pontoon bridge
over Khalkhin River within 48 hours
Second!
We'll form a special suicide unit
of 50 men to demolish tanks
All officers will stand with me
at the vanguard of the special unit!
Mukai!
Yes, sir!
Write up the list and have it
on my desk by tomorrow
Dismissed!
I'm sorry about your picture
I glued it together
Take it
I have a sister like you back home
My name is Jun-shik Kim
Thank you
"Shei-shei ni"?
The sun's going down!
Hurry up, you bastards!
Stop dawdling!
Hurry up! Work harder!
When the sun goes down, it's over!
Squad 9!
Damn slow Korean dogs!
Build this in 2 days? He's insane!
They worked us from dawn!
Where's the food!
Stop talking about food!
You're making me hungry
Choon-bok? What's "Shei-shei ni"?
Learning Chinese?
Why do you keep asking?
Just tell me
It means thank you
Stop working!
Attention!
At ease
I heard Tatsuo was your marathon rival
He didn't stand a chance
Jun-shik's way better!
Come out!
Keep that in your mouth and come out!
Choon-bok Hwang!
Come out faster than a bullet,
or you'll drink all the water here!
Repeat after me
I'm a barbarian
I'm a Korean
Repeat that, keep the fish in,
and do squats till sundown!
Begin!
Catching fish on duty
or running during bedtime!
You think this is a playground?
Make sure everything gets incinerated
Yes, sir!
No!
How dare you!
Not my running shoes!
Oh, is that so?
If you wanna run, do it barefoot
Where are you going, fool!
Damn bastards!
How many more beatings you need!
Korean dog!
No!
Gwang-choon? This side's sinking
What? There's a screw lose
Who unscrewed this?
It was there before
Squad 9! Step forward
If we went on like this tomorrow,
what would've happened?
From now on, the engineering unit
will fix up Squad 9's area
Squad 9 will hold the faulty
plank on their heads
And return to the base before sundown
The best marathoner will be leading you
The plank must be leveled!
Keep it leveled!
Noda, the bastard!
Save your breath
Just walk, Jun-shik
We'll hold up the plank
Don't worry
If you hurt your knee,
it's over! Listen!
Keep it leveled!
One! Two!
How is it? Cool enough for you
Squad 9 Sluggards!
John Yushe.
Yes sir.
Yueh Sanchin.
Jong-dae Lee!
Yes, sir
Jun-shik Kim!
Why're they calling us this time?
Attention!
The 50 soldiers called will fight
in tomorrow's attack
On a special suicide mission with me
What did he say? Suicide? Us?
We will carry bombs
and demolish enemy tanks at dawn
Fight like Imperial soldiers
and die with honor
I'll kill anyone. Who dares retreat
Koreans should be honored to be
included in this heroic mission
I'm not taking part in this operation
Oh, really?
For what reason?
The Korean soldiers
and I didn't volunteer
we cannot consent to
a mission that demands death
Your permission to shoot, sir!
Dare disobey me?
All Koreans here, including our squad,
think the same
I'll ask again
Are you disobeying me?
This is insane
Execute him with the other POWs!
Before we march out tomorrow
Have fun on your last night
Stupid bastards!
Are you okay?
I'll be executed at dawn
Like this
The Japanese are evil
Korea and China are foolish
I'm not afraid to die
I'm just mad
I couldn't kill more Japanese fools
If I could, I'd get more revenge
I'd kill them all!
What are you doing?
If we're gonna die like dogs,
might as well save Jun-shik!
Hurry UP
Hurry!
Shirai
Why her?
Pull her out!
Why? At a time like this
It's coming!
Run!
Get down!
Jun-shik!
Let's head to the bridge and go south
on Khalkin River to cross the border
Where's Min-woo?
We're the only ones going?
He's out on a job with Noda
We can't take all 100 Koreans with us
Let's hurry
We don't have time. Come on.
Jun-shik!
Get on
Jun-shik! Jun-shik!
Jun-shik!
What's that?
It's an attack!
We could've gotten killed, too
Damn Japs! Good for them!
Let's go! Come on,
Jun-shik! Hurry up!
What's going on?
Soviet tanks are coming! Grab the oar!
Tanks?
Get on!
Jun-shik!
The tanks are coming!
Get on!
Go ahead without me
What did you say?
What the hell are you doing!
Crazy?
Get on, Jun-shik! Come on!
What the hell are you doing!
Come with us!
Let's all survive and meet again!
Jun-shik! Are you crazy?
Are you crazy?
Just get on!
If you go back, you're dead, too!
Come back! Jun-shik!
Jun-shik!
Jun-shik Kim!
Shirai!
Watch out!
Shirai is an ace shooter
Shirai!
Hurry.
Go save your friends
Thank you.
Stop!
Don't come!
It's an attack!
It's an attack, sir!
Get ready for battle!
Block off the front with trucks!
Move the trucks up front!
The rest to the first line of defense!
To the first line of defense!
Defend the first line of defense!
Charge!
Scatter!
Long live our Emperor!
Die bravely like
a special suicide unit member!
You son of a bitch!
Min-woo! It's okay
You go and die bravely!
Min-woo!
Help me
Min-woo
Fools!
Imperial soldier don't retreat!
How dare you run away!
Charge!
Don't show your back to the enemy!
Don't back away!
Charge!
Don't back down!
Don't run! Fight! Charge!
Want to get everyone killed?
If you want to die, do it alone!
We're not dying like dogs!
Order the retreat!
Imperial soldiers must charge ahead
even as ghosts!
Enough with the Imperial soldiers!
Order the retreat!
Colonel!
Here's your chance to die honorably
as an Imperial soldier!
Long live our Emperor!
Long live Imperial Japan!
Where are we going?
Can we make it back home?
Hurry UP!
Move it! You bastards!
"CHITA"
"OMSK"
"PERM"
"FEBRUARY, 1940, KUNGURSK,
SOVIET UNION PRISONER OF WAR CAMP"
We are not prisoners of war,
but criminals who started war
We'll repay our debts to Soviet Union
with dedicated labor and reform
As proof you'll carry out the oath
The leader of you Japanese dogs,
Hasegawa Tatsuo,
must step on your national flag
We're not labors or criminals,
but proud Imperial soldiers!
You have no right to force us to reform!
Imperial Japan will not abandon you!
Keep your dignity till the day
you return and fight with honor!
Long live our Emperor!
Long live Imperial Japan!
Hurry up! Move it!
Walk in a line!
Colonel! Don't fall asleep, sir!
Shut up, fool! Keep moving!
Hurry up! You yellow bastards!
You slow sluggards!
Newcomers to the left!
Old maggots to the right!
Hurry!
Line up, you bastards!
Newcomers to the left!
Old maggots to the right!
Choon-bok!
Gwang-choon!
- Jun-shik!
I thought you were dead!
What a relief you're all alive
Where's Jong-dae?
Jong-dae's here, but
Attention!
This is Anton, your supervisor
I'm Anton
If Area 3 doesn't shape up,
it'll be hard to stay alive here
Officers or soldiers,
I won't tolerate anyone
slacking on the job!
Each group leader, take 20 new POWs
and go to your work areas!
Go!
Jong-dae!
Jun-shik!
You're alive!
I was so worried
I'd never see you again
Are you okay?
I'm fine. When did you get here?
About two months ago
I rule here
Nothing for you to worry about now
Korean dog! Jong-dae Lee!
I didn't like the way you were talking
I'm sorry...
Thought I'd say that?
You damn Jap!
Dare call me a Korean dog?
Give me that
Still think I'm a damn soldier
under you?
You stupid son of a bitch!
This isn't Kyung-sung or Nomonhan!
This is the great
Union of Soviet Socialist Republics!
I'm the colonel here!
And I'm the king!
You got that, fool?
Got that, you damn Japs!
Colonel
Wake up, sir!
Noda
If you wanna stay alive,
stay out of my sight
Hey!
So damn cold
If we don't warm him up, He'll die
Please move
Who cares?
That bastard's not even worth
stomping on
I beg you
Make room for him, please
Try saving him, then
It probably won't work
What are you doing!
We have to save the Colonel!
Mukai! If he's a goner,
bring him to the incinerator
No use watching him die
Let's go
Jun-shik, have a drink
Look at that
If you get frostbitten here,
you end up being firewood like him
This is the warmest place
in the whole camp
Your legs are your life
Take good care of 'em
I like it here
No Japs calling me a Korean dog
We should go back when the war's over
I'm not
There's nothing
but pulling a rickshaw there
Having a drink reminds me of home
Eun-soo's probably fine, right?
I miss her
All stand!
Starting the day without bowing
towards our Emperor is contemptible
There is no exception here!
Get up!
No need. Keep eating
It's an order!
Crazy bastard
Everyone stand! Now!
Private Jun-shik Kim! Get up!
Private Kim!
We're no longer your subordinates
We were unjustly dragged
and forced to become Imperial soldiers
As the Soviets can't demand reform,
you have no right to force us to bow
Remember
From now on,
I'm not Private Jun-shik Kim
but the Korean marathoner Jun-shik Kim!
Crazy fool!
You want to die!
You're the crazy one
who killed hundreds of soldiers!
Commit hara-kiri like Colonel Takakura!
Bastard!
Since you have the energy to fight,
guess you're not hungry enough
Grudges between
a Korean and a Japanese, huh?
You got your wish
Fight till one of you dies!
Kill him, Jun-shik! Hurry!
Jun-shik!
Jun-shik! Hurry!
One of us should've died
Today's the day
Colonel! The knife, sir!
Colonel! Colonel!
Jun-shik! The knife!
Kill me, Korean dog!
Kill him!
Hold it up right!
Hurry up and do it!
Stop slacking off!
When did this happen?
It's okay, Jun-shik
Don't
It's okay
Hold still
Germany invaded the Soviet Union
The Soviets may speed up exchanging
POWs to reinforce their army
Number 1277!
He's one of your men
Anton! Go catch him!
Yes, sir!
It's time for frostbite examination
Where's Choon-bok?
Take him away
Gwang-choon!
No! No!
Drag him out!
Let's go!
I'm fine! I can still work, sir!
Tell 'em Jun-shik!
I want to live, Jun-shik!
Gwang-choon!
- I want to live, Jun-shik!
- Gwang-choon!
I want to live, Jun-shik!
Lets Go!
Help!
Gwang-choon!
Choon-bok? Choon-bok?
You're not hiding in here, are you?
Choon-bok?
- You son of a bitch!
- Shut up!
Come out, pal!
Come out!
You wanna die?
I was starving
Put the bread down and come out now
What do we do?
Who's there?
How dare you steal, you bastard!
He's the one
- He's the thief!
- What are you doing?
Tell 'em I didn't eat it!
Please Jong-dae!
Jong-dae! Jong-dae!
A rat sneaked
into our food storage today
Luckily we caught him,
thanks to comrade Anton
As you know,
stealing is punishable by death
Jong-dae! Tell 'em I didn't eat it!
I'm scared!
Tell 'em I didn't eat the bread!
Execute him!
Jun-shik! Gwang-choon!
Make it back home alive!
Is it because of this?
This is more important
than a friend's life?
This is who you really are?
Call yourself human?
Yeah, I'm not human
I'm not the Jong-dae you know!
I'm Anton!
I'm Anton, you bastard!
Call me Anton from now on! Got that!
How long do you think this
armband will protect you?
How could you do that to Choon-bok?
What do you know?
You don't know anything!
Shut up and stay out of my life
Do you know that Gwang-choon died?
He's probably nothing, but ashes by now
If you pull that again in front of them,
I'll kill you
Your emperor abandoned you
How dare you speak of our Emperor!
POW repatriation has been denied
We showed mercy on you,
but the Japanese refused
They're battling Americans
in the Pacific
and have no interest in you
You expect me to believe that?
Imperial soldiers
are sons of the Emperor
A father does not abandon his son
That's what you want to believe
You naive, poor, abandoned son
You will also face death
in the incinerator here
It's a Kokeshi
Is your hometown Yamagata?
You're good
You know, sir? Have you been there?
My grandfather took me there
when I was young
It's a beautiful place
I grew up there my whole life
My family ran a carpentry shop
for generations
When I go back,
I want to be a great carpenter
like my father
Do you know why I chose to be
your adjutant for Nomonhan, sir?
Because I saw your firm conviction
for our country in your eyes
Conviction
Look out!
Son of a bitch!
Tsukamoto!
You okay? Wake up!
I go easy on you, you cripple,
and for what!
Jong-dae!
We're doing our best, too!
Your best?
I'll show you my best in beating!
You son of a bitch!
You call that your best! You bastards!
This is the best!
Jong-dae Lee!
It's Anton, fool!
He's dead
Lieutenant!
What?
Never seen a man die before?
Get back to work, you bastards!
Work, you fools! Get back to work now!
You fools never listen!
Damn Jap! How dare you!
Stop it!
I told you to stay out of my way!
Damn Jap!
I gotta beat it into your head?
You bastards!
Damn Jap!
You son of bitch!
Kill 'em!
Bastards! Back to your posts!
Stop! You bastards!
There is no mercy for those
who started the riot!
Begin the executions!
It's an urgent telegram, sir
Grab a uniform!
Change into now!
Germany has declared war against us
Comrade Stalin has given you too,
your final calling
The choice is yours
Those who want to convert
may wear Soviet army uniforms
- Go get the uniforms! Hurry!
- Yes, sir
Hurry up and put it on!
Anton
This is a great opportunity for you
I hope you come back victorious
Long live the Soviet Union!
Good luck!
Comrade!
Please give them a chance, too
Let them go!
Thank you, sir!
Long live the Soviet Union!
Hurry up and put it on!
Hasegawa Tatsuo
This is your last chance
I'll say it one more time. Put it on.
Let's give it a good shot
It's better than freezing to death
Right, Jun-shik?
Long live the Soviet Union! Hurrah!
Bastards
The Soviet army uniform suits
our colonel so well, doesn't it?
"DECEMBER, 1941 ZHEDOVSK, SOVIET UNION"
Get off! Get off, now!
Get off!
Long live the Soviet Union!
Hurrah!
Get off! Move it!
This will be a grave
for the Germans' today!
Thank you, sir!
Show the cowardly Germans
the valor of the Soviet army!
It's mine!
You are proud Soviet soldiers!
Charge! Attack!
Charge!
Fire!
Charge! Charge!
Let go, you bastard!
What? You wanna live, too?
I do, too!
I'm not dying here! You die!
You die!
Tatsuo!
Move it! Move it!
Charge! Charge!
Charge!
Jong-dae!
Damn bastards!
No bullets!
Jong-dae! Let's run!
This is dying like dogs!
It may be for you, but not me!
Charge!
You don't have any more bullets!
Charge! Charge!
Charge!
Jong-dae! Stop!
Come back!
There is no retreat! Charge!
Charge! Attack!
There is no retreat!
Attack!
Charge!
Jong-dae!
What's with my goddamned life
Shit, I wanted to live it up
I'm so sorry, Jun-shik
Jong-dae
I want to see Eun-soo
I miss Eun-soo
Jun-shik
No, Jun-shik
Stay right here
Don't go out there
Charge! There is no retreat!
I'll kill anyone who tries to run!
Charge ahead! Attack!
Fools!
Attack!
Imperial soldier don't retreat!
Charge!
Attack!
You'll need it to make it
over the mountains
Where do you plan to go?
To German territory
I hope we're going the right way
I hope the snow stops
Even if we make it to German territory
it won't be easy to make it back home
You don't have to come,
if you don't want to
Back then
Why didn't you kill me?
Tatsuo!
Wake up!
I'll go find some medicine
Kim...
Jun-shik Kim
I'll be right back
Help! Help me!
Help me! I'm a Japanese soldier
My friend's in danger
What's he saying?
I'm a Japanese soldier
We're on the same side!
Take him away!
I'm a Japanese soldier, not a POW!
Lets Go!
You bastard!
Help me!
A man is dying! Please!
Take him away, now!
Let go! Let go!
Tatsuo!
Lets Go!
Search every corner
You go up that way
"3 YEARS LATER"
There's word that the Allied Forces
will invade Nord-Pas-de-Calais
Then we hit the jackpot
getting stationed in Normandy
If Germany loses,
aren't we all dead anyways?
Think they'll take us back?
We'd be lucky if they don't
call us traitors and shoot us
That's why we should run away
You said you'll run for 2 years now
I'm going for sure this time
I heard from a man in another unit
There's a secret merchant ship
to Jamaica at Cherbourg Harbor
How'll you get there? Swim?
If you get caught trying to run,
you'll be shot!
Wanna make a bet?
I bet 50 marks you can't run away
Bet 100 marks, stupid
Bet even your boots, you pig
"May, 1944, NORMANDY, FRANCE"
Our battalion
will build additional defense walls
and defense lines in the Atlantic
From tomorrow,
you will build defense walls
on the shore with unit 795
Our job is to build
the defense encampment on Normandy hill
March forward! Hurry up!
Squad 3! Unit 2! Go to barracks 14!
Hey
Shouldn't you give up
looking for your Korean friend?
You're the only Asian here
That guy's so lucky
He gets to go in and out of base at will
Tatsuo! Aren't you coming in?
Let's go
Go ahead, I'll rest here for a sec
See ya later, then
I thought you might be dead
But you're here in the Eastern battalion
When did you come to Normandy?
Jun-shik?
Did you say something?
Can you repeat it?
Tatsuo!
It's more comfortable this way
I can't hear gunshots or screams
It's over
Let's play soccer
Tatsuo!
We're going to play against Squad 8!
Man, they're fast
I sometimes think of
when we first ran together
The day you moved in
I lost coz my rubber shoes fell off,
But I was happy to have
a new running mate
We came much too far
How long will it take
to run home from here?
More than a year, right?
We know the Allied forces
will attack Nord-Pas-de-Calais
The Eastern battalion will all be
sent to Nord-Pas-de-Calais!
You will all be reborn
as true German soldiers!
Pack up your gear
We move out at 09:00 hours tomorrow!
Dismissed!
We're all dead
I thought we'd be safe in Normandy
What's going on?
We're being transferred
It's nothing
Sending us to battle but
feeding us this rubbish
I thought we'd get wine and steak
when we came to France
Damn
Karim
I'm going to Cherbourg at dawn
Are you crazy?
I got the contact info from Roman
Is Roman going?
That liar
How will you get there?
The food truck always leaves at dawn
We gotta go when you're on watch
Think it over
If you get caught, you're dead
Is it coz of your friend?
Fine
I'll see you at dawn
We're not going to Nord-Pas-de-Calais
We're going to Cherbourg
Cherbourg?
A ship there will take us home
Jun-shik
Let's go home
where your sister and father are
Can we really make it home?
We could get killed on the way
Still, we can't die here
Karim!
Tatsuo!
Those aren't planes, are they?
Jun-shik!
Tatsuo!
Tatsuo! Tatsuo!
Jun-shik!
Stay there!
I'll come to you! Wait for me!
Hurry! It's an attack!
Prepare for battle!
All units to battle positions!
The Allied Forces have attacked!
To your battle positions!
Hurry and grab the machine gun!
Grab it!
Everyone to your battle positions!
Move it! Move it!
Fire!
Jun-shik!
Tatsuo!
Are you okay?
Let's get out of here, now!
Grab the machine gun! Now!
Hurry up, you fools!
Can't you see the enemy!
Reload and fire, now!
Allied forces attacked!
Send reinforcements!
Damn it
Let's run for it
Don't lag behind
You'll be watching my back as you run
Are you okay?
This won't kill me
Let's go!
Jun-shik
Come on! We have to get home!
Tatsuo
Are you okay?
Jun-shik
You're Jun-shik Kim from now on
If you say you're Japanese,
they might kill you
Say you were dragged here
and forced into the Eastern battalion
Jun-shik! Wake up!
I have no regrets
Though I couldn't achieve my dream
You can't go like this!
Let's go home and run together!
Jun-shik
I wanted to run again
when I go back home
Promise you'll make it back alive...
Jun-shik!
I sometimes think of
when we first ran together
The day you moved in
I was happy to have a new running mate
Ready, go!
SubText: NoRMITA.326