Hachi! Don't just stand there!
This is your fight!
He's your boyfriend. Win him back!
I don't want to.
I never want to see him again.
I want to do it in a bigger place.
Yeah, the bathtub's too small.
No, I'm talking about our gigs.
Oh.
We attract huge crowds.
We should book a bigger venue.
Do it then.
Don't you care?
What was Yasu talking about earlier?
It sounded serious.
Ah, my pills.
You're such a junkie.
No, the pill, you idiot!
You don't use protection.
What if I get pregnant?
Then we'd raise kids.
I worked all through high school,
I'm loaded.
I could support a kid or two.
Maybe you could, but not me.
I want to play gigs...
NANA...
Live your life the way you want.
What?
I'm going to Tokyo.
I agree, Shoji's to blame.
But so are you, in part.
Junko, whose side are you on?
He cheated on me.
He's been unfaithful all this time!
Not all this time...
I did everything he wanted.
Found a job, was independent...
That's got nothing to do with it.
You know, all you ever really
think about is yourself.
Did you ever think how
Shoji really felt?
It takes two people
to make a relationship work.
You've got to think about your partner!
We're the Black Stones.
The wide-open window,
The deep sky dances above
Ah, look up
What's the meaning
of each passing day?
Ah, you scream
Run away from home, go
Put on your worn rocking shoes
Hop over the puddle
Flashback
You're clever
Ah, remember
Over that rainbow
I wanna return to that morning
Gathering our dreams
When we walked together,
glamorous days
Is there any value to an empty love?
Ah, you scream
Let it all out, go
Drink up, rock'n roll
A breathless battle
Flashback
Your flavor
Ah, remember
Let's go collect those stars
I wanna wear them like a necklace
We strung the dreams together
As we danced, glamorous days
I can't sleep
Does Nana Komatsu live here?
Yes.
Sign here, please.
Hachi. It's a registered
letter from your folks.
I'll sign for it.
Please.
Thank you.
Wow! I won!
I won tickets to a Trapnest concert.
2 front row tickets!
I'll be able to see Takumi
right in front of me.
You'd never get tickets like this
in Tokyo. You're coming, right?
Right? NANA.
Right?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Everybody, listen up!
Trapnest are playing a gig
back home next week.
Who wants to come?
I asked NANA,
but she wasn't interested.
It's a long way to travel,
but they're front row seats.
What a waste not to go.
No, NANA wouldn't want to go.
She hasn't told you anything?
Ren and NANA?
Yeah.
Ren from Trapnest and NANA?
Ren wasn't always in Trapnest.
He played in our band back home
until Trapnest recruited him.
I see...
Why aren't you surprised?
You told me everything the other night,
when you were drunk.
Did I? Really?
Yeah.
Oops!
But why didn't NANA follow Ren
to Tokyo?
They still could have stayed together.
NANA didn't want to center
her life around Ren's career.
She wanted to make it on her own.
So she made a tough decision.
How come you're telling the story?
Because I heard it from you.
Oh, really?
Is that really what NANA wants?
She's an independent woman.
With Ren's career on a roll,
she knew she couldn't play housewife...
So she worked on her singing,
and built up her confidence.
And vowed she'd come to Tokyo
someday when the time was right.
She chose pride over love.
Simply put, yeah.
But who knows how she really feels?
She keeps her feelings
about Ren to herself.
Be better than Ren.
What are you doing?
Need any help?
No... NANA...
I still want you
to come with me to see Trapnest.
You don't have to go to the concert.
But I'd like you to see my hometown.
Not that there's much to see.
I could introduce you to my folks.
I'll go to the concert.
Really?
Sure.
Why the change of mind?
No reason.
I'd like to check them out.
Trapnest?
Your parents.
What a nice house! You must be rich.
Hardly. Property is cheap around here.
Welcome!
Make yourself at home.
Hello!
Pleased to meet you.
Welcome back.
I thought you were bringing a man home.
Don't say that, Nami!
You left in such a hurry,
we thought you'd eloped.
Yeah.
Don't be silly. I live with NANA.
No boyfriend.
What?
Right?
That's too bad.
I was looking forward to meeting
someone... who could put up with you,
to take you off my hands.
Sorry. We're a noisy bunch.
Not at all.
Please come in.
Your mother's awesome. I love her.
Just your average,
middle-aged housewife.
My father should be home soon.
He's average too.
Don't get your hopes up.
What's wrong with being average?
I don't have parents.
I used to dream of living in a house
No parents?
With a large family.
Yeah, my mom left home
when I was 4.
I never had a father,
so I lived with my grandma.
She was my mom's mother.
But she died when I was 15.
Don't look so depressed.
I'm so happy.
What?
You never told me this before.
You never talk about yourself.
It made me feel lonely.
I see...
I never thought about it.
You only had to ask.
No need to feel lonely.
Something funny?
You're so cool!
You're more like a boyfriend than
a girlfriend. I think I'm falling in love.
You're hopeless.
Will you really tell me anything if I ask?
Yeah.
You'll answer me straight?
What is it?
Do you still love Ren?
You knew?
Sorry. I pretended not to. But...
You brought me here knowing that?
Thanks.
Trapnest concert this way!
I'm going to have a smoke.
OK.
NANA didn't give me a straight answer.
But she didn't need to.
He's 2 years older than me.
I'll introduce you to him later.
You'll love him.
Who cares? I came to watch the gigs.
Ren was abandoned in the warehouse
district soon after he was born.
Made the news. He still lives there.
He says that's where he belongs.
Wants to be a professional musician.
A good background story can help.
That's pathetic.
Cashing in on one's misfortune.
I don't buy it.
Uh oh, we'll be late!
The orange sky
that shines down upon the city
But I won't look back, I've let go of
yesterday and started on my journey
My heart is driven by passion,
not delusion
It's strange, but I'm not frightened
Searching for myself
Overcoming unhappiness
- so far away
My dreams are packed up in a suitcase
Always chasing that
distant shining light
I ran through the snowstorm
The red dress hidden beneath my coat.
I don't know how to describe the
feeling that was born that night.
My life had been dark for so long that
Ren's light was dazzling.
Ren and I first made love the
Christmas one year after we met.
"For NANA"
A homemade cake?
My fans love me.
It could be poisoned.
It's actually from one of my fans.
Poison for the girl who's seeing Ren.
Taste it. I don't want to die for
something I haven't done.
Neither do I.
Fans should know band members never
touch the girl vocalist.
Now I don't care if they poison me.
I would have been happy to die.
Because I wanted him.
I wanted him so much.
Lotus flower?
Called a "Ren."
"Ren Honjo
NANA Ozaki"
Ren taught me the joy of singing.
He taught me how to play the guitar.
He gave me hope.
I was pulled towards him like
the tide to the moon.
But Ren wasn't the reason I sang.
I always sang for myself. And I still do.
I watched Ren's every move,
trying to get him to look this way...
hoping that he'd notice
NANA standing there.
Could I reach him?
If you haven't changed your mind
Stay by my side, tonight
Don't want to pretend to be strong
I should be less childish
Every time I think about you baby
I can say it now - I miss you
It is so hard to say I'm sorry
No luggage?
Just a guitar and cigarettes
are all I need.
He's bullshitting. He's already
sent his stuff on ahead.
Guess I won't be your porter anymore.
Train's here.
I lived with Ren for 15 months.
Winter was coming to an end.
And so were we.
Sometimes, I sensed Ren
glancing our way.
But his eyes always
seemed elsewhere... far away.
It is more for you
and not anyone else.
That I sing this song
A never ending story
continuously shining.
Always to tell you eternally
Ren, you missed a few notes
out there.
You covered them up well.
But I noticed.
I gotta pee.
Wow, even Ren makes mistakes...
"Even Homer sometimes nods."
It's a saying.
Encore! Encore!
I wonder if Ren noticed you?
Not under those bright lights.
Really?
Don't know. Never played
on a stage like this.
You never know...
Must feel really good playing
an arena like this.
Yes, Yamazaki Law Office.
Hey, Yasu. NANA's here!
If you knew, why didn't you tell me?
It was a surprise.
It threw me off completely!
I recovered somehow, though.
I'll give you her friend's number.
Call her if you'd like.
I wouldn't know what to say.
If you're no longer interested...
I'll take her.
Trapnest played 2 more songs,
but Ren never looked this way.
Come in.
We're back.
Welcome home.
You must be starving. Dinner's ready.
Hello?
Hold on. I'll pass you over.
Yasu.
What is it?
Ren might call you.
What's that mean?
Stay out of my business!
I've got nothing to say to him!
Say that to his face.
You've still got the key, right?
Give it back.
If you're through with him,
then set him free.
Alright. Where's he staying?
NANA...
It's about time I did this.
I'm returning the key.
Key?
The key to the lock on his necklace.
But if you return the key,
that would mean...
Get me a cab.
Excuse me.
Are you on the guest list?
Yes.
Can I see some ID?
She's with me. Let her through.
I came to return... the key...
Is that all?
And to say that it's over.
I don't like clinging to the past.
Good luck!
Wait!
Don't get the wrong idea.
I've got nothing to say to you.
Oh, there is one thing.
We'll be bigger than Trapnest someday.
NANA. You haven't changed a bit.
You're looking well.
Ren...
Let go!
I don't want you back!
I missed you.
I wish I'd never come.
I wonder how NANA felt
that night going to see Ren.
I really wonder...
"Shoji"
"Delete"
"Delete entry"
"Delete Shoji?"
"Yes"
If her feelings for Ren
she would have gone to him ages ago.
Those roses are expensive.
Don't be cheap, Mr. "Rock Star".
Yeah. They'd only wither anyway.
But you won't. Never.
Feels like old times, huh?
Sitting in the bathtub, chatting...
I still rent that room.
With no one living there? That's a waste.
That's where I belong.
One day I'll buy it and retire there,
with you.
Says who?
It was an empty warehouse
when I was a kid.
I used to escape from the orphanage
and hide there.
I'd play guitar all night.
I wasn't born talented.
It's all from practice.
You never told me that before.
Never told anyone.
I want people to think I'm gifted.
Hey, Ren?
It's no good.
We can't live together like before.
Can't get over my pride.
But maybe we could meet sometimes.
Make love... talk about our lives.
And when we're older...
when pride and fame mean nothing...
when I'm tired of singing...
I'll return to that warehouse with you.
Back then, I didn't want to
fall in love again.
But I knew that no matter
how hurt I was,
I would keep on dreaming.
And someday I would find love again.
That's how I felt as I prayed for
NANA's happiness.
How did it go with Ren?
You promised you'd tell me anything.
I owe you one this time.
Anything I can get for you in return?
Takumi's autograph?
That's easy. I'll ask Ren.
Ren?
It's only an autograph.
No. Did you get back with him?
Something like that...
That's great, NANA.
No it isn't. I don't know what happened.
It wasn't supposed to be this way.
Why not?
I wanted to end it.
Make a clean break.
How could I be so weak? I'm pathetic.
NANA blushed and she seemed
smaller than usual.
I'd never seen her so tame... so sweet.
Ms. Komatsu!
Can't you do something as
simple as this?
You had enough time.
When I was your age I took
my job more seriously.
This isn't a game, you know.
No matter how I try, I don't fit in here.
I need to find a better job.
Set your cell phone to silent mode!
Is there nowhere in the world
that I belong?
I envy NANA.
Li-zhi!
What? That was quick!
What?
Ron!
No way!
Li-zhi! Double East.
You're too good at this. Go easy on us.
I am.
Hang on...
Hachi?
Could be.
You're on!
Welcome home...
Nana.
I made her cry.
The reason I started to cry...
was because I knew this was
NANA's way of saying thank you.
Her gift to me.
Here.
I felt an overwhelming sense of love.
I'd never felt happier.
I know I can't go through life
expecting the world to come to me.
But NANA let me dream
a wonderful dream.
It was like falling in love
for the very first time.
The wide-open window
The deep sky dances above
Ah, look up"
What's the meaning
of each passing day?
Ah, you scream
Run away from home, go
Put on your worn rocking shoes
Hop over the puddle
Flashback
You're clever
Ah, remember
Over that rainbow
I wanna return to that morning
Gathering our dreams
When we walked together
glamorous days