NANAYO
Is something wrong?
Will you come with me?
Will you?
You don't speak French?
I'll take you somewhere, OK?
What happened?
Hi, Amari.
Ah, Greg...
Hello.
No, someone attacked her
in the woods.
Mommy!
Poop!
Oh, dear! Come on, then.
You OK?
Would you like
some more tea?
Could we have some more tea?
Mother, give them some tea.
I just did.
Hello, Marwin!
What is it?
What happened?
Did he attack her?
She's scared of him.
Stay and eat.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I was just
passing by in my taxi.
Well, anyway...
Mother, bring Marwin some water.
Would you like to eat?
Would you like a massage?
I'll give you one.
A massage.
Go on...
Lie down.
First, spread the towel.
Then cross the feet,
and place your hands on them.
Press down lightly.
Hey, Saiko...
Come here.
Come on.
Sit down.
Over here.
Have a massage. Go on.
Let Greg practice massage on you.
There.
Good.
No.
Come back to the feet.
Three times, I told you.
Here again.
Press three times on the feet.
OK? Back here.
I'll show you. Watch.
Like this.
Sit up.
Greg, you lie down.
Behave yourself!
I'll show you how to do it.
OK?
Stretch out your legs.
Come here.
Come on, try it.
Me?
First you pray to the spirits...
...of the masters of massage.
OK? Like this.
Good.
Like this.
That's right.
Good.
Now we start.
From the feet.
Feet together, like this.
That's right. Now press.
Like that. Do what I do.
This hand above.
Hold them like this.
Now press down lightly.
Hey, watch the nails!
Are you OK?
What are you doing?!
She dug her nails in me!
What was that for?!
What?
She dug her nails in me!
Show me your nails.
They're pretty long...
That's not good for massage.
Are you OK? Are you hurt?
You got a bump?
Where? There's no bump here.
There's no bump.
No bumps.
But look here,
you scratched me.
Not a mark on you!
To do it right,
you need to concentrate.
They respect massage here.
Do you understand?
It's in the breathing,
and listening.
You don't understand, do you.
I don't understand.
Do you want to learn?
Do you want to?
I don't understand.
Are you going to hurt me again?
You're not angry any more?
When I talk to you,
you're always angry.
When I threw you off me,
you were angry.
Whatever.
The wind's come up.
Yes, you're right.
It's clouded over.
'Water'.
'La pluie'.
'Rain'. 'La pluie'.
Not 'puryui'.
'Pluie'.
'Water'. 'Eau'.
'Mizu'.
'Kanpai'.
You know 'cheers' in Japanese?
What?
'Santé'.
In Thai?
'Chai yo'.
You too, Toi.
In French?
She's still here.
When you're all playing like that
you look like a family.
You're right.
That was with one.
Now do it with two.
Nope. What if I do one twice?
No. Two at once.
Let it go.
Really?
Let it go?
Toi...
'Morning.
My nails are too long
to play with you.
I have to cut them.
It's sparkling.
You do it, too.
Stop it! That hurts!
OK?
Go on. You try it.
I know how.
Do it.
Can you?
Sure I can!
He's good.
He sees me every day.
Stretch your legs out.
Let go with your hands.
Down!
Like it?
You know, I always hid
my homosexuality from myself.
And perhaps...
...as I let things take their course...
...I'm starting to find
a link with the world.
In my work,
it's always me. Just me.
I got sick of it.
That's why I came here.
I want to disappear behind an action,
melt into an action.
Concentrate myself.
Feel pain where it is, in others...
...and soothe it.
That's all that interests me now.
That's why I'm here.
See this?
Did your girlfriend give you this?
Who's it from?
What?
I can't take it off.
I always wear it.
Otherwise I'd give it to you.
It's going to rain.
La pluie.
'Lovely'?
Someone dear?
Oh, 'rain '?
I was a soldier.
It was scary.
You're in a house,
talking like this...
Suddenly a bomb
smashes the roof...
'Die'.
'Dangerous'.
'Abunai'.
There's danger everywhere.
Toi might drown.
'Splash'!
Amari might accidentally
cut her wrist cooking...
...and die.
Me...
...I've seen it.
Lots of dead bodies.
People... me, you, him...
...shouldn't kill each other.
We should never do that.
Understand?
Do you?
'Understand?'
More or less.
Thai...
...Japanese, French.
All different.
But we shouldn't kill each other.
We should love.
She doesn't understand.
Understand?
Do you understand?
You speak Japanese?
He wants to meet his father.
I want Toi...
...to meet his father.
What's Japan like?
Beautiful?
Beautiful? What's it like?
What's Japan like?
Japan is...
.... Very peaceful.
We're blessed.
But....
.... We don't have...
.... The warmth...
.... That you all have.
Give me some advice.
I want to put Toi into the temple.
What do you think?
Put him in the temple?
Have you asked him?
Not yet. I'm still thinking.
You'd better ask him first.
Even a loser like me...
I wish I could see my daughter.
Did something happen?
What?
Nothing. I'd just like to see her.
Drink?
There.
I'd like some water.
I wonder where they sell it...
This is good.
Beer?
Can I have this?
All right, Marwin?
Singha Beer?
One can.
Singha?
'Dtao huu'.
Water.
Tofu.
'Tofu water'?
Like milk.
It's sweet?
What should I say?
Rice crackers.
Do you have any fresh ones?
No?
Too bad.
Let's get four bags.
One's enough.
Let's get something for Toi.
No thanks, girls.
No thanks, I said!
Go away.
Stop it.
Why did you hit her?!
Run!
Hold it, you!
I'm running!
Marwin!
Asshole!
Were you watching?
Come pray with us tomorrow.
Together, tomorrow.
Let's go have breakfast.
Your daddy's Japanese.
You know that, don't you.
But we're in Thailand.
Here you can be a monk.
OK?
Would you like to be a monk?
A monk?
Why?
I want you to.
Could you do that?
You'll live in a temple.
And be a monk.
Always?
Forever?
You can if you want.
Not forever.
Maybe for a while.
Could you live there alone?
I'm a woman,
so I can't go with you.
But the other monks
would be there with you.
In the morning
I'll come with an offering.
In a bowl, just like that one.
You'll accept
your mother's offering.
'Please accept this,' I'll say.
Can I go?
I want down.
OK?
Why?
I'm thirsty.
Can I go?
Did Daddy love you?
Is Japan that way?
That way?
Where I can meet my daddy?
What do you want?!
What kind of father
have you ever been to me?!
You never paid for anything!
Sure I did! I work hard!
It's not enough!
That's no excuse
for selling yourself.
I need to work!
Who was that yesterday?
My boyfriend!
A foreign boyfriend?
You're a whore.
That's not true!
You were all over him!
In my taxi!
That doesn't concern you!
Come on!
No!
We're going.
Come on!
No!
Mother?
Where's Toi?
I haven't seen him.
He's not here.
Marwin, did you take Toi anywhere?
Nope.
Where did you take him?
Me? Don't be stupid!
I can't find him anywhere.
That's my fault?
You talked to him.
A little bit, last night.
Think about how he feels.
What did he say?
That you want him
to be a monk.
He doesn't want to.
I'm against it, too.
So you put ideas in his head!
You're as bad as my daughter!
Are all whores like that?
You bitch!
It's my fault?
How would I know?!
You're dumping the kid?
I can see him at the temple.
He should be with his mother.
He hasn't got a dad.
Why did you even have him?
I wouldn't have...
...if I'd only known!
You're crazy!
What did you just say?!
Don't say that!
You mustn't say that!
You have no right!
Get out!
You can't say things like that!
Now look what you've done!
Amari, what's going on?!
Stop, stop.
Stop!
What did you hit me for?!
He's your son!
You're nuts!
What happened?!
I didn't take him!
What happened?
Stop it!
What's wrong?
Amari?
Where's Toi?!
Toi? What about Toi?
Was it you?
Toi's gone? He's gone?
He's gone!
Give him back!
Bring Toi back!
I didn't take him!
Where is he?!
Don't blame it on her!
Her country's beautiful and rich.
She wouldn't understand.
Saiko!
Have you seen my son?
Have you?
He's been gone all day.
Did you hide him?
Where's Toi?
I don't know!
Why won't anyone tell me?!
Where's Toi?
I don't know! Why is everyone
shouting at me?!
You have to understand.
I want him to be a monk!
Your country
is beautiful and modern.
But I want him to be
rich in spirit!
Not materialistic.
I don't understand!
Thai, French, I don't understand!
Tell me why
everyone's hitting me!
She doesn't understand people.
She's only rich in things.
What's wrong with you?
Have you gone crazy?!
I'm not afraid of you!
Enough!
Ow!
That hurt!
That's enough.
Move.
So Toi's missing?
Why aren't we looking for him.?
Why are we wasting our time
with this?
Shouldn't we be looking for him?
Toi!
Go away!
Let's go look for Toi.
Where did you take him?!
We'll split up and look.
You go that way, I'll go this way.
Yo! Have you seen Toi?
A kid with long hair.
Has he been here?
Thanks, anyway.
He wouldn't come this way.
Come back to Mommy!
Toi!
I understand.
You're here!
I think Daddy loves Mommy.
You want to go to Japan?
You do?
So do I.
To Japan.
We'll go.
Look.
Saiko's shoes are all dirty.
Rinse them.
A little bit louder.
1, 2, 3...
'Sleep, sleep, fast asleep...'
'Fast asleep... '
Again.
1, 2, 3...
'Sleep, sleep, fast asleep...'
'Fast asleep... '
'You're a good boy...'
'Go to sleep....'
'Where did Nurse go?'
'She went from the village,
over the mountain...
'What did she bring
as a souvenir?
'A rattle-drum,
and a set of pipes... '
Kiss me.
By your leave...
'Water'?
'La pluie'.
Not 'puryui'.
'Pluie'.
'Eau'.
'Water'.
'Nam'.
'Eau'.
'Mizu'.
'Kanpai'.
You know
'cheers' in Japanese?
What?
'Santé'.
In Thai?
'Chai yo'.
All these words!
Yeah.
What's 'tasty'?
'Aloi'.
'Aloi' means 'oishii'?
In French?
'C'est bon! '
What's 'thank you'
in Japanese?
In French?
'Merci'.
'Arigato', 'khoop khun kha',
'Thank you'.
'Love' in Thai is 'rak'.
'Rak', 'amour', 'ai'.