[Episode 15]
Shall we begin?
I guess everything ends today.
We go until the first one dies.
No way. No one dies.
Today is the day that
I bring you into the station.
My friend JJ...
Is this because you want to kill him?
If I get you...
I'm sure I can get JJ too.
I'm sure that everything is okay,
right Detective Im?
We should trust Shi Yoon.
Wait, what's this?
This watch...
I gave this to my daughter as a gift.
Who sent me this?
Hello?
Yes... That's my Soo Bin's watch.
What?
That's... my Soo Bin's hand?
Who are you? Who the hell are you?
Where's my Soo Bin?
We have Im Soo Bin.
Kid, let your father hear your voice.
Loud and clear.
Soo Bin... Soo Bin!
Come on! Say something!
You must...
So that your father doesn't worry...
Dad...
- Louder!
- Dad!
Yes, Soo Bin!
Soo Bin, are you okay?
You... who are you?
What are you doing with my Soo Bin?
Quiet down and listen to me.
We need the original memoir that
Baek Shi Yoon has.
If you give us that memoir...
We'll let Im Soo Bin go.
That is our only request.
Get that memoir, as soon as possible,
and wait at the Neighborhood Bar.
We'll call you back.
Hello? Hello... Hey!
Those bastards...
Detective Im!
What?
I understand! Okay!
Tae Ho, try to calm down! Okay!
Hey, Tae Ho's daughter was kidnapped.
It's an emergency!
Get the details from Tae Ho.
Then check all local security cameras!
- Move!
- Yes, sir.
If you didn't interfere
with our business...
Nothing would have happened...
The culture district
would have stayed quiet.
And your friend wouldn't have
died in Macau, three years ago.
I should have caught you then.
Your friends, who took a trillions of won
from Korean Commerce Bank...
Do you know how many people worked
themselves to the bone for that money?
These same bastards...
They show up in the culture district...
And they dare to step over the lives
of powerless, laboring citizens?
Shi Yoon! Shi Yoon!
Shi Yoon... Shi Yoon...
- The memoir! Where is that memoir?
- What's going on, Detective Im?
What's wrong?
My daughter, Soo Bin has been kidnapped.
They told me to bring the memoir!
Negotiation, cancelled.
And...
Since you refused my act of kindness,
things will get harder for you...
As well as for the people around you.
Who will be targeted first?
Out of the people around you?
- Yoon Sang Min! You son of a...
- No!
This isn't the time, okay?
Please...
You and your friends...
You're all going down together.
I can't wait.
Hello.
Did you have to come
when there were kids here?
A classified document
that could pose a real security threat.
- We had no choice, Mother.
- Don't call me Mother.
My son never had a friend like you.
Hey... Shi Yoon.
What is there to think about?
We give them the memoir,
get Soo Bin back, and then catch them!
We need to be cautious, Detective Im.
Even if they get their ransom, kidnappers
don't return subjects, just like that.
But saving the person should be
the first priority, should it not?
For Soo Bin's sake, let's make a plan,
rather than just succumbing to them.
Stop bullshitting me.
What plan do we need for this?
We need to get Soo Bin back,
first and foremost!
Shi Yoon... I'm begging you...
I know... that this item
is very important to you...
But the priority is saving
my daughter... please?
I'm begging you... Please!
I'll bring the memoir.
Please wait.
What's going on?
Honey, what happened to Soo Bin?
The kidnappers must've gotten
in touch with Sun Young too.
Why did this happen to Soo Bin?
Because of something he has?
Who does he think he is?
Why did you get involved
with that man? Why?
Try to calm down.
Chief, it's not here.
It's not here.
Shi Yoon!
Did you have to go this far?
When I looked at the footage
on the security cameras
the box holding the memoir
was delivered here, from your bar.
This is a justifiable,
legal action on our part.
If you gave it to me from the start,
this wouldn't have happened!
The memoir...
Will be given to Yoon Sang Min.
What are you talking about?
Don't you know that it's safer
to give it to the agency?
A child was kidnapped
because of that memoir!
Kidnapped?
Thank you.
I'll tell you if I need any more help.
Of course!
I would do anything for you.
You're running a free pre-school for us!
You're our neighborhood hero.
- I'm sorry, Mom, but I have to go.
- Okay.
The memoir... is at the Neighborhood Bar.
Bring Soo Bin here, now.
The plan has changed.
We will accept the memoir
at Central Park, in one hour.
Baek Shi Yoon and the police
may not be in the area.
What about Soo Bin?
Once we get the memoir, we'll let her go.
Where will you release her?
Then bring Soo Bin...
to Central Park, okay?
Please let me hear Soo Bin's voice.
Soo Bin, Soo Bin!
We'll see you in one hour.
We'll say this again. Baek Shi Yoon
and the police, better not be with you.
It's a tracking chip.
Then... I'll go with Detective Im.
If Shi Yoon or the police can't be there,
I should go instead.
Me too.
Us too.
Please help us get Soo Bin back.
After that, the police and I
will find whoever took her.
Don't make any mistakes.
You'll get the rest
when you bring me the memoir.
I will take care of it flawlessly.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Yes, I can hear you.
In a space this big, they'll have to
be in a car when they pick it up.
Okay, don't worry.
I'll keep a lookout.
The police detective has arrived,
with one man and one woman.
Yes, Shi Yoon?
One second.
Have they contacted you yet?
No, not yet.
What if they take the memoir
and don't release Soo Bin?
They just want the memoir,.
They won't do anything crazy.
Put on your headsets.
When I said that
the police are not to come
that included you, Detective Im.
What?
Send the girl.
She can wait in front
of the whale statue.
I'll go.
- I'm coming with you.
- Wait a second.
I think they're watching us.
I think Writer Bae
should go alone for now.
- But still...
- Let her go alone, for now.
Writer Bae, be careful.
But still...
How can we...
Let's go.
Chan Gyu, can you go by yourself?
What? Right now?
I'll try.
Sorry about that!
Shi Yoon, I'm going in now. Okay.
I'm sorry.
One of us will keep watching you.
So don't worry, Writer Bae.
Ri Soo, please make your way to area B.
Okay.
They're starting to communicate,
so keep your guard up.
Get on the boat,
with the ticket inside your pocket.
Yes.
I've got my eyes on Writer Bae right now.
Bae Jung Yeon. You can do this.
We'll win, no matter what.
Soo Bin, I'm coming for you.
They're out of my view now.
Okay, I'm watching.
I got a report about a strange item.
- Can I take a look at your bag?
- It's nothing.
I'll let Soo Bin go...
after I check your bag.
It has begun.
Wait until we see Soo Bin.
Okay.
That man...
- I think I found him.
- Okay!
What are you doing? Hurry up!
Where's Soo Bin?
Do you want to die too?
I want to see Soo Bin, first.
Wow... Seriously...
- Let go.
- I can't just let you have it.
- Where's Soo Bin?
- Oh, my... Seriously?
Where is Soo Bin?
Where's Soo Bin? Where is she?
Soo Bin?
Okay, Soo Bin. It's okay now.
Wait a little longer,
I'll open it for you.
I found Soo Bin.
Writer Bae, we found Soo Bin.
It's okay, just let it go.
We can catch him later.
- Give it to me!
- What are you doing?
We've secured the memoir.
Okay...
Who are you?
You bastard! This little...
Okay, okay.
You son of a bitch.
- Are you okay?
- Soo Bin!
- Yes.
Are you really okay?
I'm sorry...
Your dad is so sorry....
It's all your dad's fault.
It's all your dad's fault...
It's a little late...
But I have something to tell you.
I insisted on doing everything alone,
and solving everything on my own...
But I think I was wrong.
The truth is, these are things
we were meant to do together.
I wouldn't have been able
to do any of these things by myself.
Thank you, all of you...
for being by my side.
We're all friends.
With a little difference in age.
Thank you, Chan Gyu,
for catching the bad guys.
Isn't that what the shadow does?
Wait... Isn't he from
the intelligence agency?
Um, yeah...
I think you're right.
What's the meaning of this?
Are you on your way
to get the memoir?
Don't you know what will happen
if you act so carelessly?
You want to be arrested for kidnapping,
as soon as you pick up the memoir?
There are Gangjoong police officers,
right behind us.
Tell me where it is.
It'll be safer... for my team to go.
I'll give it to you the next time
we meet with our friends.
Since when are you
concerned about my well-being?
I got word that one of your men
was arrested for kidnapping.
I can't stand to watch you
fall into a bottomless pit.
So I thought I'd help you out.
Yes, after he met with the man
from the agency, he turned around.
The location could have been changed.
Please keep following him.
I'll keep following the kidnapper.
Did they see us?
Yoon Sang Min
is going back to his office.
Jung Soo Hyuk must
have put this together.
At the very least,
we have to catch the kidnapper.
The patient keeps
leaving the hospital.
He needs to retain his stability.
But if he keeps straining his body...
His muscles and nerves
could become paralyzed, as a result.
If you were in the hospital...
You should have told your mother
that you were...
Who did this to my son...
Who is doing this to you?
Who...
is putting my kind son
through all of this?
Shi Yoon...
Yoon Sang Min asked you
to do this, didn't he?
Then... did you need
the memoir, personally?
What were you going to do with it?
And, how did you know it existed?
I would like to exercise
my right to remain silent.
The right to remain silent...
The right to remain silent?
After you kidnapped my daughter...
After you put her through that...
What? The right to remain silent?
Hey, hey, hey, calm down, Tae Ho.
Hey, sit down, sit down.
Okay. You should say hello,
since you know each other.
Last time, you were here together,
claiming that Shi Yoon beat you up.
Since you're two guys in the same boat,
let's get everything off of your chests.
You have no relation to Baek Shi Yoon,
so why did you try to kill him?
I resented him for hitting me,
so I went to get my revenge!
So, what you mean is,
you had to go kill him?
It's for the money. The money!
What other reason could there be?
And, the only person who can give you
that much money, is Yoon Sang Min!
Admit that Yoon Sang Min
is behind all of this!
I'll exercise my right to remain silent!
Geez...
How could these former
subcontracting labor union workers...
Fall into committing crimes
of this nature, one by one?
Huh?
"Yoon Sang Min gave me the orders."
That's all they need to say.
Is it that difficult?
I'm sure that he promised to give them
a staggering amount of money!
It's obvious who gave the orders...
But the fact that no one
is willing to bring him down...
You've worked with them before.
Can't you try to convince them?
No way, no way.
They don't treat us well.
They wouldn't listen to us either.
If anyone could do it, it's Bong Chul.
Bong Chul?
Yeah, our president.
We've arrived.
Oh, yes...
- How much is it?
- It's 16,000 won.
- Here.
- Thank you, and your change...
- Oh, I don't need the change.
- Oh, thank you! Thank you.
Oh, yeah... I made an extra 4,000 won.
Let's see here...
Who will be my next caller...
Huh? Why is he calling me?
Yes... It's me.
Huh?
- Hey! You guys!
- Oh, sir!
- How have you been?
- You're here.
Wow... It's nice to see you.
So...
I heard that you have
a strong sense of responsibility.
That you're very good to your family...
And that outside of your home,
you take care of your younger friends.
That's because I'm generous.
But while you were away,
look what happened to your juniors!
What did they do wrong?
Attempted murder and kidnapping.
A murder and kidnapping...
Oh, geez...
They're being sold off
to Yoon Sang Min, one by one!
Your juniors!
We're sold off for money...
And then thrown away.
And then we're sold off again...
And thrown away.
Geez... It's not like we're slaves
from the ancient times...
Thank you.
Aren't you guys eating?
- I already ate.
- I ate before coming here.
You must have gathered up
a lot of courage to come here.
Ma'am.
From now on,
I'll only come when I'm hungry.
I'll pay for my food, and will honorably
order one dish for any person I'm with.
I won't do anything bad...
When I'm here,
I will only eat. I promise.
I'll take that as an apology
for things you've done in the past, okay?
Oh! And please give me some of that
spicy pork! That delicious spicy pork...
Okay.
When you're not causing problems,
you're quite the cool guy.
I guess I'm pretty cool.
For Min Sik...
His mother is only 65...
But she already has dementia.
And Jang Jin...
With his newborn baby,
and that baby's mother...
He lives in a dark half-basement.
So I know... why they turned into this.
Wow, this kimchi stew...
This is really good.
- Chan Gyu.
- Yes?
- Our president's mother.
- Shi Yoon's mother?
Yes, this is her specialty.
Yes, it's this man. Please go ahead.
Hello.
How old is your baby?
I'm sure... that this is what
Yoon Sang Min told you.
He told you, don't rat him out,
even if you get caught.
And that if you don't, he'll give
your family a huge reward. Right?
But... do you really think that
Yoon Sang Min will keep his promise?
This is a guy who uses people, and then
throws them away when he's done.
Hey, you're a witness to that right now!
So your baby has asthma now,
because you live in a half-basement.
Has she been discharged
from the hospital?
Yes.
Tell her to bring the baby.
What?
Bring the baby to my pre-school.
We have a spare bedroom upstairs.
The room gets a lot of sunlight. Okay?
But still... The most important thing is
that you leave here as soon as possible.
If I leave this place,
what's going to change?
Don't speak to me informally...
My mother is 65 years old right now.
So if I need one million won every month,
for the next 20 to 30 years...
Do you know how much that is?
If a long-term nursing home charges
one million won every month...
That means you're a level four.
Your Long-Term Care Insurance level.
You're not getting government
assistance because of your level.
Hey, do you know that woman?
And, tell your wife
to come with your baby.
It's called "The Shared Study Room"
and everybody knows about it.
So it's a safe place.
About what you just said to me...
Do you really mean it?
Of course!
And... Does your mother
take any medicine?
Who do you think you are?
Well, senior care hospitals are better
than nursing homes, if she's sick.
After she gets treated, she can save
90 percent on her medical fees!
Wow! Did you say 90 percent?
Hey, it's 90 percent!
Medical benefits! You don't know
about these, do you? Look it up.
And you two...
Let's testify, and leave this place soon.
Even if it means you'll get less money!
If we put our heads together and work
them out, we can solve our money issues!
But, the little time we have left...
There's nothing we can do about that.
- Um, Ma'am.
- Yes?
I'll testify.
He says he'll testify.
Finally, after all of this time...
It looks like we'll catch Yoon Sang Min.
Jung Yeon.
Yes?
I've been thinking...
I don't think there is any one person
who doesn't have some shadow in them.
You're right.
People just forget about
the shadow inside of them...
Why does it hurt so bad?
Maybe I ran too much today...
Hey, hold my hand for a second.
Hurry! I'm telling the truth!
Hold my hand.
- Hey, get up.
- I'm telling the truth... Hurry.
Before it's too late.
Just once.
Hold tight.
It doesn't hurt anymore...
all of a sudden.
Hey.
Don't do that.
Hey, you didn't wash your feet...
- I'm home.
- Dad!
Hello!
We're doing that again? We did that
when Soo Bin was in elementary school.
Honey...
Yes?
Am I a good father to our family?
I put Soo Bin in danger...
And I make you worry about money...
Am I... doing a good job?
There's no such thing as good or bad.
You're doing your best for your family.
If I just continue to live like this...
Things will get better, right?
I'm sure they will get better...
We have to believe in that.
In my life...
I've made many wrong choices.
But I did... one thing right.
What?
Having this family.
Us. The five of us.
I heard that you got the memoir!
Wow... Is this how Representative Yoon
lives his life? Huh?
Let's see it.
I have one thing I want to say.
Chief Jung Soo Hyuk.
Don't trust him, from here on out.
Explain this, Chief Jung.
The kid that Representative Yoon hired,
had a tracking chip on him...
So we could have had
the memoir taken from us...
And Baek Shi Yoon and the police
could have come here.
I read some of it already.
It includes me...
And it includes... your fathers...
There are quite a few dangerous
things written here about us.
But... As long as
we have the original copy...
Everything that this memoir contains...
becomes a fictional story
that someone made up.
Then... does that mean you can secure
your post for prime minister?
Yes, that seems likely.
Okay, then...
What about our Representative Yoon?
You made three promises to us.
But you're a cruel human being,
who killed his own best friend.
So the fact that this person
left Baek Shi Yoon alive...
No one understands that anymore.
How much time will you give me?
Did we ever... tell you to kill anyone?
You are the one who came out
and said that you would do it.
And you couldn't follow
through with your promise.
We are handing over all rights to the
Hallyu Core Mall to The Channington Fund.
You worked very hard until now.
For us... and for our fathers.
Hallyu Core Mall...
I'm sure that I've told you already.
I put my life on the line for this.
I guess you didn't take it seriously.
Chief Jung. Enough.
The man you hired to kill
Baek Shi Yoon in the hospital
and the man who kidnapped the detective's
daughter, were both arrested.
Now... It's all over for you.
Before they restrict your passport,
it will be best if you leave the country.
20 years ago...
Since I first met you,
and entertained you, and protected you...
I've always thought the same thing.
You guys can't win over me.
There's only one thing you can win with.
Fathers.
But as time passed, that's all it was.
Powerful fathers...
I didn't lose to you.
Except for that one thing.
I'm sorry, JJ.
The tallest and brightest building...
I don't think I can build it yet.
I'm sorry.
But...
I can't end it like this.
Right, JJ?
Yoon Sang Min!
I was waiting for you.
Joon Hee.
The two men confessed.
You're under arrest for
attempted murder and kidnapping.
You have the right to remain silent,
and the right to speak with an attorney.
And, there are economic crimes and
other murders in which I was involved.
If there were accomplices,
to whom are you referring?
You know who they are...
The strong men behind me.
First, take these handcuffs off of me.
I'd like to be interrogated
somewhere else, in a private room.
Then I will cooperate.
This isn't a hotel!
And you're a suspect
for murder and kidnapping!
Pass on this message to the president.
He won't be able to refuse.
Since we fought a lot, back in the day.
I'll go meet him right now.
I don't think
he's planning on leaving the country.
I think he's about to...
start a counterattack.
There will be many people here to see me.
But...
There is someone I want to meet first.
Baek Shi Yoon.
Bring me Baek Shi Yoon.
Hey, Shi Yoon...
Will you really be okay, like this?
I'm all better now.
Now we have to begin...
The last fight.
You... Who told you to come in here?
Yes?
I'm here,
at the Gangjoong Police Station.
Why don't we have a talk,
Representative Yoon?
Chief Jung... I don't have
any intentions to talk, just yet.
But do you know what I figured out?
I realized that while I'm in here,
I'm the stronger one.
If I start to talk...
You'll be dragged in here,
one by one...
Chief Jung.
I'm understanding
the situation correctly, aren't I?
Huh?
You were right.
I ended up at the police station,
after living the way I did.
Voluntarily.
Since you called me here, I assume you're
willing to answer any of my questions.
If you help me.
Why do I have to help you?
Isn't the shadow...
someone who protects others?
You... want to be protected?
You're strong.
And you're not afraid of my connections.
And you fight for the weak citizens
of the culture district.
Do you want to be protected...
Or do you want to take revenge
on the ones who abandoned you?
I'm fighting to stay alive.
That's my natural instinct.
From the dark alleys
of New York, to here...
That's how I made it here.
If you want my help...
You have to tell me everything you know.
Everything you say will be recorded.
And it will be used as evidence in court.
But that's okay, isn't it?
But I still can't tell you
everything so easily.
I'll decide after seeing how you respond.
I'll have to see how much
you can help me...
And how you'll help me survive.
How about it?
Is he expecting to get out of this?
After he committed these crimes...
There's no way that will happen...
Not while I'm here.
Oh... While we're here.
Let's talk about three years ago.
JJ killed my junior colleague,
Jang Jin Woo.
- Did you give the orders?
- Yes I did.
Why?
Do want to come and choke me?
Should we stop?
I'm sure there's someone...
Who gives you orders from above.
The strong Koreans,
hiding behind Bay Star Hong Kong.
The New York Study Group.
Okay, let's get things sorted,
one by one.
Where is JJ?
Shouldn't you catch
the guys above me first?
Answer me...
Where is JJ?
There's something you should know,
Baek Shi Yoon.
The New York Study Group...
They are dirtier, and much crueler,
than you can imagine.
I asked you where JJ is!
Do you want to know their phone numbers?
Or which method the New York Study Group
members use to contact each other.
The password.
Since the murderer hasn't been caught...
If the instigator denies it,
there's nothing we can do.
He wants to provoke New York Study Group,
and he wants to bring those guys in here.
He wants to find a way
to stay alive after that.
I'd like a cup of coffee.
We need to check
if he's telling the truth.
Hello.
We thought the dog would
run away when we let it go...
But he came back to bite his owner.
If Yoon Sang Min says something
to the police, it won't be just us.
But it will affect our fathers, you know?
Do you... have a safety net prepared?
- Was I supposed to have one prepared?
- What?
Oh, oh...
You said that you wanted
to talk about that...
- I did?
- Yes.
You sent us a message...
That today's meeting was about that.
It's nice to see you, gentlemen.
[Neighborhood Hero]
Protect me, from now on.
I'm not protecting a criminal like you.
Help us establish a closer bond,
using a guaranteed method.
- I'll make sure that I save your life.
- Under what condition?
You must testify in court.
Remember the order,
I told Jung Soo Hyuk to call.
Overthrowing a giant could be a very
difficult fight, so please be prepared.
If something happens to me, Chan Gyu,
can you take my place as the shadow?