I was the hero of Hughes Creek.
I can still see the glint in me
da's eye as he looked down at me..
his hand on me shoulder.
What did he call me that day?
Ah, what did Da call me?
That's right. He
called me Sunshine.
You're a pretty girl.
You're Wild Wright's
horse, aren't ya?
I know whose ya are.
It's all right.
I'll look after ya.
Handsome-looking horse you got there, Ned.
You're cuttin'a flash, all right.
Ah, great.
You're Ned Kelly, aren't ya?
Red Kelly's boy?
Get down, Jane.
Fine animal you got there.
- Distinctive, wouldn't you say?
- She's Wild Wright's.
- That's the postmaster's mare.
- No, it isn't. It's Wild Wright's.
He lost her when she
bolted into the bushes.
You're a liar, Kelly.
No, I'm not. I found her
this morning, grazing.
She's been reported stolen.
- Stolen, me arse!
- A horse thief!
- Get your hands off me!
- You're under arrest.
Stand, Kelly, or I swear to
God, I'll shoot you down.
- I was only going after the horse.
- You were trying to escape.
You're just as thick
as your bloody father.
Jesus Christ! Now, what
are you trying to do?
I could've tanned
your hide for that.
Strike an officer, and
you'll bloody swing for it!
Strike you down to the ground!
- No blows struck yet, Constable Hall!
- Help me, someone!
Help him! Help Constable Hall!
Poor Constable Hall!
He's such a fuckin' rat!
He's trying to kill me,
the rascally blackguard!
- Help me, someone!
- Stand put! Go on! Put me down!
He tried to shoot me, for Christ's sake!
All right! All right!
Is that the best you can
do, you bloody coward?
Go on. I can take it.
That's enough!
Hello there! Please,
can you help me?
Hello! Hello there! Please!
Slow it down, please!
Come on! Come on! Please!
Please, now! Oh, come on!
Give us a ride, you bastards!
Christ, it's muddy
enough to bog a dog.
- So, where'd you go after Beechworth?
- May Day Hills on a road gang.
Ah, you see Sean Gallagher?
I heard he was up there.
Yeah. I saw him for a while.
Hey. I think that's old man Wicks and..
What's his daughter called?
- Sarah.
- Sarah. That's right. She's a picture.
Oh, we could be in love, boys.
Mr Wicks, good mornin'.
Mr Wicks, I don't know if you remember me.
I'm Aaron Sherritt, Mr Wicks.
If you could just hold
up for one moment..
If anyone can persuade..
an old man to share his daughter with
three larrikins like us, it'll be hard.
So how's me ma?
What?
Ah, the coppers have been
giving her a hard time, Ned.
Something goes missin',
a bullock or anything..
they come round the
middle of the night, tear
the place apart, scarin'
the kiddies and all.
- She's had it hard.
- Come on, lads!
- Jump up!
- Well, will you look at that.
What did I tell ya?
- Thank you very much, sir.
- Thanks a lot, Mr Wicks.
Thank you, Mr Wicks.
Dan!
Ma, there's someone coming.
Oh, God. It's Ned.
Neddy!
Mommy, I named
Hobson's kookaburra.
- What did you name him, darlin'?
- Beefy, 'cause he likes beef.
Well, that's a fine name
for a kookaburra, Grace.
Who's the proud father, Ma?
Don't even ask. He's a long time gone.
That's all there is to it.
- The stinkin' Proddy.
- He was a Yank.
George the baker. We were
married, Ned, right and proper.
Well, that's grand, Ma.
Christ! Will you stop messin'?
I'm sick of the pair of ya.
Give your mother some respect, or I'll give
ya a hidin', both of youse, ya hear me?
- And who are you, anyways?
- Steve Hart.
Well, seein' as how the two
of you are so full of beans..
you can both get off your asses
and help me fix up this place.
You haven't done a minute's
work to help your ma, have you?
Come on, everyone.
- Sit down, now.
- What kind of stew is it?
Wombat. A wombat's a marsupial,
and it lives in a hole.
I know, darlin; I put
one in the stew.
Shh. Da-da-da. La-la-la.
Ned, would you like
to say the grace?
All right.
Dear Lord, thank you for
looking after me mother..
me sister Grace, me sister
Kate and me brother Dan.
Thank you, Lord, for our
beautiful baby Ellen..
Shh, shh, shh.
And for this wonderful
stew made out of wombat.
- Amen.
Amen.
It's not easy for an Irishman
in Queen Victoria's colony..
to walk the straight
and narrow..
but I toed the line..
despite all temptations.
- With me fighting with
my fists for money.
And after all, I did three
years for that stolen horse.
Wild Wright only got 18 months. You
think I was gonna let that one slide?
I declare Ned the winner!
Bets are in.
So, are we square?
Course we are, you mad bugger.
Come here!
Thank Christ for that!
Could it be possible that the
Kellys were finally getting ahead?
That I could actually
better meself?
Steady.
Excuse me. You there.
Would you mind coming and
holding my horse's thing?
All right.
Steady.
Now, what thing are you
talkin' about, ma'am?
Are you gonna help me or not?
I've been riding him pretty
hard the last two days.
Poor thing's been holding
on since Saturday.
His bladder's paralyzed
with the colic.
- Good God.
- Have you got that?
- Right there. Good. Good.
- Just hold it there.
Keep still.
I'm glad that's not me. Christ.
- Steady.
- Whoa, boy. Whoa, boy.
Okay. All right.
Watch your boots, boys! Whoo!
It looks like you've done
this kind of thing before.
Only on horses.
Thank God for that.
My name's Ned Kelly.
Pleased to meet ya.
- Hello, Ned.
- Right.
Watch out, lads! Here he goes again!
Clear the way!
The horse is too wild.
It can't be broken.
A waste of damn money.
Fetch my rifle, please.
What? You can't just shoot
a horse 'cause it's wild.
What else can we do?
We can't keep it here.
Why don't you set it free?
I could break that horse
for you if you like.
I've broken horses before.
You can ask around.
I'd like to give it
a try, at least.
We know there's not much point.
The horse is bad.
You know, the Chinese say you should have
only one true love in your entire life..
otherwise you are no better than
a mangy dog or a loose woman.
What did he say? Good
thing I'm not Chinese.
What did he say?
He said what a lucky fellow I am
to be with such a beauty as you.
Too lucky, if you ask me.
Oh, hello, Kate. I
didn't see you there.
- Fancy seeing you here.
- I'm just having a swift pint after work.
It's not like I'm a regular or anything. A
man needs to relax after a hard day's work.
What would you know about
a hard day's work?
Sleeping and drinking and beatin' up
yellow fellows is all you ever seem to do.
That's not fair, now.
I'm only doing me job.
I get along with everybody.
Everybody gets along with me.
- Can I buy you a drink?
- No, thank you. I have money.
- I just wanna buy you a drink.
- I said I don't want one.
You're startin' to get
on me nerves now.
Think you're too good for me?
Is that it?
Who do you think you are?
Let go of me bloody arm.
You're hurtin' me.
- Let go of her arm, you.
- I'm just bein' friendly, Ned.
Just offering the
young lady a drink.
She doesn't want one
from the likes of you.
A problem there, Fitzpatrick?
No. There's no problem
here, Constable.
I'm sorry if I upset you.. Kate.
Right. This one's a
request from Ned Kelly.
Right. Follow me, lads.
One, two.
The nerve of the bloody knacker.
Look at him.
Acts as if he owns the place.
Come here and dance with your sister!
Come on!
That fella needs taking down a
peg or two, that's for sure.
- Ned, the horses are gone.
- What?
The biggest thieves and liars
the sun ever shone on.
The Victorian police.
Well, I'm telling you
something now, boys.
I'm not gonna let these bloody
maggots put one over on me.
To change a horse's brand is
easy, easier than you'd think.
You just pluck the little hairs
and prick the skin with iodine.
A "C"or an "O" can become a "Q."
"Q"for "Quinn".. me
mother's maiden name.
Who's that at this
hour of the night?
- Dan, is Kate in?
- Yeah, she is.
Well, would you mind telling her I'd
like a word, please? In private, like.
No, I won't. She wants
nothing to do with you.
You know that full well.
Well, I'd like to hear that
from her, if you don't mind.
Fitzpatrick, you've already heard
that from her many's the time.
Will you do yourself a favour.
Take a ride home.
- You think you're so smart.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- I've a warrant for you.
- You've no warrant, you fool.
A Kelly stole them horses. I know it
was, and I have a warrant for you.
Ned and all. I've
warrants for both of ya.
I don't suppose I could see
them warrants, could I?
There's your warrants. Hmm?
There's your warrants.
Oh, hello.
I just came down to
find my riding jacket.
I thought I left
it here somewhere.
I haven't seen it.
I was sure it was here.
If I find it, I'll be sure to
bring it up to the house for ya.
- All right then.
- Right.
- You're from England?
- Yes.
Surrey, actually. You're Irish?
Yeah. Me da was from Tipperary,
but I was born here.
I've never been to Ireland.
I came over when I was 17.
Richard acquired the land
through his family, and..
My da had to go to all the trouble of
stealing a sheep to get the trip over here.
He got a free fare then.
He was lucky.
Yeah.
- How are you tonight?
- Fine. Till you showed up.
Drink, boys?
- Steve?
- I don't drink with coppers.
Aye. There's no need for that.
So I'm leaving here tomorrow. The
work here for me is finished now.
Yes. I know.
So I won't be seeing
you any more.
You sure you don't want to have a
better look for that riding jacket?
No. I.. I must have left
it in the house somewhere.
Well, it was nice
to have met you.
I really should go.
I think you're the most
beautiful woman I've ever seen.
You don't have any
warrants at all, do you?
Oh, I do, Mrs Kelly. I do.
I don't believe this. You
just plain thick or what?
Come on, Kate. I'm just having
a bit of fun, you know.
Now, let's see those
bloody warrants.
I've split me head open!
You bastards!
- It's your hand, you bloody idiot.
- Hey, Fitzpatrick.
- Bottom rung on top now, huh?
- Shoot him.
- Don't, Dan.
- Give him back his bloody gun.
Go on! Get!
I'll be back for
ya, ya bastards.
Can you believe the brass
neck on that idiot?
Trying to be all
friendly with the grog.
Yeah. He seemed sobered up when
you pointed the gun at him.
See his face?
I'm glad you think
this is all very funny.
- Where have you been?
- Never mind where I've been.
What's happened?
Fitzpatrick couldn't hold
his brandy and lemonade.
- What are you talking about?
- We had a fight with Fitzpatrick.
- A fight? Why?
- He said he had warrants for me and you.
What warrants?
Horse stealing, but there
was a load of shite in it.
Whether it was or wasn't,
there's trouble now either way.
You can't take that seriously.
How can you stand there and act like this
is one big joke, after all the trouble..
we've had with coppers
in this family?
What are you thinking, Joe?
You and Dan oughta clear
out for a day or two..
just to be safe.
God willing, it'll
all blow over.
What the hell happened to you?
- Ned Kelly shot me.
- He what?
Take your rotten hands
off me, you bastard!
Get off her!
You're under arrest! I'm
taking you to the cells!
You filthy bastards!
Ned! Ned!
- Ned. Jesus, Ned, they've arrested Ma.
- They what?
Yeah. They've taken her to the cells,
charged her with attempted murder.
Attempted murder?
And Fitzpatrick's saying
you took a shot at him.
I wasn't even there.
We know that, but it's
your word against his.
Take the word of a drunken liar
and arrest an innocent woman?
Is that right?
I won't take this injustice!
I'm gonna kill him!
I swear I'll scatter his
blood and brains like rain!
- Ned! Ned! No!
- Stand aside!
- No, Ned! Don't make this worse for Ma!
- Stop it, Ned!
Take the children
inside, please.
- What are you doing here?
- They arrested me ma.
- What for?
- The copper says I tried to kill him.
Why?
'Cause he's a bastard liar,
like all coppers. That's why.
The thing is, I
wasn't even there.
I was here with you.
You could tell the truth, show the
swine up for the drunken liar he is.
- And then they'd have to release me ma.
- That's impossible.
I couldn't. Do you realize
what that would mean?
Yes.
I can't. I'd be disgraced.
He'd take away my
children, and..
It's all right. I understand.
- Ned.
- Go ahead. Go ahead.
Right.
I made them an offer
at the outset:
Charge me and let me mother go.
The answer came back: "We
don't bargain with outlaws.
We'll catch you anyway."
You see those stretchers?
You know what they're for?
The bastards ain't plannin' on
takin' prisoners, that's for sure.
There's another party down past
the neck of Bullock Creek.
Four of'em. They've hemmed us in on
either side, whether they know it or not.
We'll come back at dawn, hold up these
two, take their guns and horses.
At least then we'll have a
chance of making a run for it.
Right.
Drop your arms!
Christ, it's Lonigan, Ned.
You've killed Lonigan.
Do you want marmalade, Ned?
Are you gonna kill me or what?
I'll leave the force first
thing tomorrow morning.
I swear it on me mother's life.
Ned.
- Jesus Christ.
- Do as I said, and no one will get shot.
Sergeant, you'd better surrender.
You're surrounded.
You been into the whisky
again, you old sod?
- Get some toast on, Lonigan.
- Lonigan's gone, and you two'll be next..
If you don't get off
them damn horses.
Oh, Christ!
Give it up, man! It's over!
Will you stop running? I
won't shoot you. I swear.
Why didn't you surrender?
I wouldn't have shot ya.
I can't breathe!
- No! I can't breathe!
- Right, right, right.
Listen. It's okay.
I can't breathe.
One minute. One minute.
One minute.
- It's all right. It's all right.
- Oh!
Why did you have to run?
I wouldn't have shot ya.
God damn. Look. No.
- I don't wanna die like this.
- No. No. I'm sorry I shot you.
I don't wanna.. I got a
wife and two children.
What are they gonna do without me?
What are they gonna do without..
- No!
- Look at me. Look at me.
God forgive me!
God forgive me.
I don't know why I
took his watch.
It was something to do
with him not needing it.
Later, I thought about
sending it to his family.
But by then, the papers had me
down as some sort of monster..
so I thought, "No point now.
I'm damned anyway."
Is it true what they've been
saying about the three coppers?
Yeah, it's true.
Oh, God.
It was a fair fight, Ma.
Better them than Ned.
They'll kill him now.
They'll kill him for sure.
Don't shoot, lad. I'm unarmed.
Come on. Put that away.
There aren't any troops.
Aw.
You're bloody chirpy for
this hour of the morning.
Gotta keep your voice down.
- I've a visitor.
- Who?
- Mary Hegarty.
- Mary Hegarty!
- Mm.
- Jesus. She can be only 13.
I'm not superstitious. Well,
well, well, well, well.
I've never met a man whose lies are worth
€2,000 before, especially not Irishmen.
- It's €6,000.
- Is that what it's up to?
My cock alone's worth
more than that.
I could do with
the money meself.
I'd build a shed out the
back, buy a few horses.
In fact, I could buy half of
Beechworth with all that.
- That's very funny, Aaron.
- Clause two.
They've recalled parliament.
Passed something called "The
Felons Apprehension Act."
It means we're
listed as outlaws.
We can be shot on sight
by anyone who chooses.
They said I'd lost what
it meant to be human.
Maybe I never had it
in the first place.
But wasn't this about
protecting the ones I loved..
the ones who gave me food and
shelter, even the clothes on me back.
And therefore,
wasn't it now a war?
Dan, you see that wooden gate?
Around the back there is
their living quarters.
If anyone's there,
you keep 'em there.
- Can I help you?
- Yes, you can. Me name's Edward Kelly.
- His mates call him Ned.
- Ned Kelly?
I'm sure I've heard
that name somewhere bef..
I'm sure you have, sir.
Stay where you are.
What do you think you're doing?
Who are you?
Going to a funeral, eh? Better do
as I say, or it'll be your own.
- Ma.
- Shh.
- Fanny Shaw, what are you doing here?
- I work here.
- I can't believe it.
- What are you doing here, Steve?
We're robbing the bank. Me and Fanny
used to go to school together.
Steve. Hello, kiddies.
- You're Ned Kelly.
- That's right.
What are you going
to do with us?
You're coming with us to Faithfulls Creek.
We can't leave anyone behind..
to raise the alarm, now, can we?
Mr Kelly, we are supposed to
be attending a funeral today.
As you can see, I'm
dressed in mourning wear.
Obviously unsuitable for a woman travelling
in the countryside, hostage or not.
- Even a blackguard like yourself..
- Susan!
I do apologize for
my wife's behaviour.
There is no need to apologize
on my account, Charles.
The man is wearing a magenta
cravat, for God's sake.
I have an outfit just
arrived from Melbourne.
L'eau du Nil silk.
Well, you'd better put it on then.
Go on.
Joe, you should follow
her, make sure she doesn't
signal from the windows
with her bloomers.
- How dare you!
- Sure. I'm doing no harm.
What are these, these skulls?
- I collect them.
- Hello.
So you're Joe Byrne?
The papers say you have the facial
features of a creature born to crime.
I'm the handsome
one in the bunch.
They also said you married
a Spanish housemaid
in Diniliquin with the
exotic name of Madela.
We were just good friends.
Mm. I suppose you have
a lot of good friends.
I'm sure there's no
harm in being friendly.
No, I don't suppose there is.
Oh, you're a beast..
an absolute beast.
She's taking an
awfully long time.
He just fell off the other
side right into a puddle.
You'll never guess who
I ran into last week.
Who?
Danny O'Reilly. He's working
on the new rail line.
He's got a wife and three kids.
Sure. That's grand. I haven't
seen him in at least three years.
That's like one kid every year.
Hey, Ned. Look at this.
Mortgages. One of'em's for
old man Wick's place.
- I recognize a couple of the others too.
- They're of no use to you.
They're the only records I
have of the bank's debtors.
Can I have them back, please?
No.
So I killed their policeman,
and I robbed their bank..
but burning their mortgages.. well,
that was destroying Crown property.
It was like slappin' Queen
Victoria herself across the face.
So they send in Hare,
Superintendent Francis Hare..
late of Cape Town, South Africa.
And wasn't this the challenge of
your whole life, Superintendent?
A feather in your cap.
You can't catch me.
You don't have a hope of catching
me, so you take my friends instead.
Over a hundred men arrested, stuck
in stinkin'cells without trial..
while their crops
perish in the fields.
And guess what. Not one of'em caves
in and tries to claim the reward..
not one of'em.
They loved me just the same and hated
you all the more, didn't they?
Did you really think I was
gonna let 'em all rot?
Two and a half thousand pounds.
There's enough
to pay rent on the
leaseholds for lads in jail.
Thomas, you can take what you need for your
mother to pay off her debt to McTeague.
Thanks, Ned.
And there's some for
McKinleys and Bill Skilling..
whatever he needs for his da.
Have you heard
anything about me ma?
They set a trial at the end of last month.
She's been given three years hard labour.
I'm sorry, Ned.
I say, give me that back.
That blackguard just
stole my watch.
They say the Lord helps
those who help themselves.
Give him back his watch.
- What? - You heard what I said. I
said, give him back his damn watch.
Have you gone simple all of a sudden?
We're robbing the bank.
Listen here, kid. This is
the last time I tell ya..
Give him back his damn watch.
You're not innocent men. You're
a bunch of common criminals.
Did you hear that? If we act like common
thieves, that's just what they'll call us.
My mother is rotting
away in a prison cell..
because of the lies of a
policeman named Fitzpatrick.
She's an innocent woman, and
so are these boys here.
My Irish brethren have been
unlawfully imprisoned..
and blacklisted from
their selections.
How do you expect me to behave other
than to stand up against this treatment?
Any one of you here can take a shot
at me and not be charged for it.
There's me gun.
Any of you feeling brave
enough, go ahead.
No?
That's what I thought.
So if I can beg your patience,
this is my statement..
to the Premier of
Victoria, Graham Berry..
and you here are my witnesses.
Joe, take out a pen and paper.
We'll write ourselves a letter.
Dear Sir..
"Dear Sir..
"I wish to acquaint you with
some of the occurrences..
"of the present,
past and future."
"It will pay government to give
those people who are suffering.."
justice and liberty.
"..justice and liberty.
"I seek revenge for the evil
name given me and my relations.
By the light that shines,
this is my warning."
My brother and
sisters and mother..
have to put up with the brutal and
cowardly conduct of a parcel of..
- "..big, ugly.." ..big,
ugly, fat-necked..
- "..fat-necked.."
- Wombat-headed.
Wombat-headed.
"..wombat-headed, big-bellied.."
Magpie-legged!
Magpie-legged. Thank
you very much, ma'am.
Joe, write that down.
Magpie-legged.
"..narrow-hipped, splaw-footed..
sons of Irish bailiffs.."
Or English landlords better known as what?
Victorian police.
This section here you might find
less amusing, Superintendent.
I give fair warning to all those
who have reason to fear me..
not to attempt to
reside in Victoria.
Neglect this and abide
by the consequences..
which shall be worse than
than the rust in the wheat.
I do not wish to give this order
full force without timely warning..
but I am a widow's
son outlawed..
and my orders must be obeyed.
Hey! Look! It's Ned Kelly.
- Look!
- Oh, my God.
It's Ned Kelly and Joe Byrne.
Can I get a kiss then?
Of course you can.
And a ladies' man, eh?
Where will you go, Ned?
The country belongs to us.
And we'll go wherever we like.
I hear you're planning on getting
married, starting a family.
Well, I'll tell you this, lad.
Lack of cooperation will
make it very hard for me..
to get you out of here and
back to that girl of yours.
I got nothing to tell you.
I don't need to tell you
about the reward out.
It's a lot of money.
You could put it to good use.
You're a friend of Joseph
Byrne, aren't you?
You've known each other
since childhood..
served time together,
isn't that right?
Aaron, it's the Kellys we want.
We don't care about Joe.
If we let this run its course..
he'll be shot down
like the others.
The only chance your
friend will have..
depends on you.
If you'll help me with this..
I'll guarantee his safety.
Ned!
Jesus Christ. Come on.
Let's go.
Sir.
They've poisoned it.
Lying low, living in caves,
you get to learn sometimes.
Eventually, you can read
soils and rocks like books.
I've watched gravel fade.
Dust settle into crust.
I've seen drips of water..
turn to stone that
defied gravity.
I've turned blood
red with cave mud.
I've been a bloody rock.
Aaah! Oh!
Sorry.
Wait.. Please.
Can you help..
to scrub my back?
I can't reach.
Where's your husband?
Out looking for you, like
the rest of the country.
You took a risk coming here.
Well, turn me in so.
You think God'll forgive
us for what we've done, Ned?
I don't know.
I suppose we're all
gonna find out one day.
Just thinking of Ma rottin'
away in that cell.
Where do you think Da
is, heaven or hell?
No. He wouldn't be
in hell, you know.
He wasn't such a bad fella. He..
He was just a dumb paddy who
got picked on his whole life.
And that does something
to your pride, you know?
Can't even picture him.
When I was 10 and they gave
me that green-and-gold sash..
for saving that kid
from drowning..
that was the last
time I remember him.
He was proud of me that day.
We gonna be okay, Ned?
Of course we are, you
little gorn, you.
You're just gonna keep
running, aren't you?
They'll catch you eventually..
or shoot you down.
Did you know they pardoned Frank
Gardiner in New South Wales?
On condition he left the colony.
- He gave himself in.
- He wasn't an Irishman.
Then why don't you just
leave the county now,
try for a new life
somewhere in Queensland?
No. I can't. It's not about me.
You know there's more
to it than that.
What would it take to make
you save yourself, Ned?
Hmm? My husband's best stallion? Take it.
It's yours. Forget the mares.
- More than that. Much more.
- What then?
The red one, too,
would be nice..
with you atop of it, beside me.
For that you'd save yourself,
leave your friends behind?
And you your children.
Look.
You and me had no business with one
another in the first place, did we?
Wasn't that the
whole point of it?
Don't make me grieve for you.
I ain't dead yet.
Rebel!
- Kate. It's all right! It's us!
- Oh.. Oh, you bloody swine!
It's Ned. I know. Come here.
- Oh, my God.
- Now, Gracie, look at you.
You've grown too much.
Give us a cuddle. Come on.
Rebel, come on. Come on.
So..
I saw that rascal Aaron
Sherritt the other night.
Oh, yeah? And what
did you give him?
Nothing, you little scoundrel.
Hmm.
The thing is, I saw him
talking to this fella..
all friendly like
on the way out.
Then the fella comes back here and starts
asking me all sorts of questions about you.
Such as?
When did I see you last
and where you were now..
that sorta thing.
- Is he a copper, do you think?
- I don't know.
Well, it could've been nothing.
I just thought you
ought to know, like.
Thanks, Maggie.
Hello, Aaron.
Joe?
Ned.
So how's things, Aaron?
Not so bad. Well..
not too bad.
I've been reading a
lot about you, Ned.
You're a real terror
altogether, aren't you?
We've been meaning to
talk to you, Aaron.
We were wondering if you'd
consider acting as a scout for us.
We're heading into Beechworth
to rob a bank there.
A scout? Well, I'm flattered you'd
think of me, lads, but, uh..
- You're not interested?
- No. I-I'd love to.
If it was just up to me, I'd be in
there like a shot. You know that.
But I've got the missus
to think about now.
Because between you and me,
lads, she's up the spout.
Ah, she isn't?
- Ah, sure, that's grand.
- Congratulations, Aaron.
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
- How are Dan and Steve?
- They're fine.
Say hello to them
for me, will you?
We will.
Well, I'd best get
back to the party.
Mary will be wondering
where I got to.
Sure. You go on and look
after that girl of yours.
Ahh.
I will indeed.
Sorry I can't help you out.
Good luck with it all anyways.
Aaron, what are you doing?
Some coppers on horses
followed me until Wangaratta..
but I met up with Tom Lloyd and Bill and
we gave 'em the slip easy as you please.
- That's good.
- Here we go.
That's great, Katie.
Yeah, well, I wish I'd
never bloody bothered.
You're all gonna get
yourselves killed.
- We are not.
- You bloody well are!
No, we're not, Katie. We're gonna give 'em
a show like they've never seen before.
There's a certain type
of black tribesman..
that bends in the wind..
blends into the background.
Mostly he employs the
help of the dead..
to destroy other people.
The "Night Dancer,
" they call him.
God, when is someone gonna
give me some proper cards.
Who's in?
Ugh. Fold.
I'm turning in.
I guess all that losin'
would make you tired.
- You in or you out?
- Gimme three.
- You?
- I'm out.
What's happening?
Go back to sleep, love.
Here. I call.
Three to the English queen.
It's blessed you are, Nigel.
Aaron!
- Aaron!
- Who's that?
Who is it?
Another one of your
whores, it looks like.
Just tell her to get lost, unless
she wants her head blown off.
Lizzie, is that you?
Joe.
Why do you think he did it?
Just for the money?
Maybe he started thinking he
was some kind of big shot..
instead of a shit-kicker's
son, like us.
We have received word that
one of our informants..
has been shot dead
by the Kelly gang..
over near Beechworth.
We will entrain immediately
and proceed to Wangaratta.
From there, you'll be
split up into units..
and will fan out
across the country..
encircling the
immediate vicinity.
Stay close to your
troop commanders..
for your orders of march.
I would remind you all..
the men we are hunting have not
only plundered two banks..
kidnapped men, women
and children..
but have murdered three
of your fellow officers.
They have outrun us
before, gentlemen.
Do not allow them
to do so again.
Don't you worry, sir. We'll
show the bloody animals.
We'll blow 'em all
to kingdom come.
These are not
animals, Constable.
These are men who have been glorified
as the leaders of a movement..
a movement that threatens the
stability of an entire country.
Underestimate them, and it will be you
who will be blown to kingdom come.
They say the trouble
with the Irish..
is that they rely too
much on dreams..
and not enough on gunpowder.
Whereas the English were
shy on dreams, as usual..
but had plenty of the other.
Now we had both.
- I suppose you're the Great Orlando.
- That I am.
Well, I'm the Great Ned Kelly, and
this here is the Fabulous Joe Byrne.
We'd like to join your circus.
Ohh.
Mm.
That's right. You're not seeing things.
It's a camel.
I've got a lion and some
ponies back down the road.
And the Great Orlando of course.
If you're here to rob the
train, you're too late.
We're not here to rob the train.
Joe, get this lot inside.
This good-looking fella over
here is me brother, Dan Kelly.
These are my friends:
Joe Byrne at the bar there..
and Steve Hart there
in the back corner.
And I'm Ned.
We're all Irish boys
and selectors'sons.
Had war declared on us..
by Victoria, by New South Wales.
By the crown.
And by the London Times even.
The reward on our heads is the biggest
one yet offered in the world.
It's up to €8,000.
It's a lot of money.
We're the only four lads
in the whole country..
the entire empire, in fact..
that any one of you fine
citizens is allowed to kill..
no questions asked.
No, it's true. The
queen said so herself.
That's right. It's Regina
versus us, the Kelly gang.
So our plans were set.
One. The traitor,
Aaron Sherritt..
dead, as arranged.
Two.
The police special from
Benalla coming to meet us.
The line torn up to send the
train to hell, as arranged.
Three. Superintendent
Hare, if he lives..
easily worth an outlaw's mother.
And four. The townspeople
out of harm's way..
drinks on us, as arranged.
- Here you go.
- Oh, lamb! My favourite.
- Ohh!
Now, cheer up there, Mr Curnow.
You're witness to history.
How many schoolteachers
dream of that?
Come on, Hare. Where
the hell are you?
Were you sleeping?
You thinking of using that?
I'm mulling it over.
Right.
You don't remember me, do you?
You were just a boy then.
You were riding a Palomino
mare with a white blaze.
Jane. Yeah.
Yeah.
Seems like a long
time ago, doesn't it?
A lifetime.
Where's the other fella?
Where's Curnow?
Ned, Curnow's gone!
Come on! Give me a hand here!
Quickly!
Get those horses off!
Knights in shining armour.
- Curnow stopped the train.
- Jesus.
- What does this mean?
- Hare's on his way.
You mean we didn't
get any of'em?
Not a soul.
There'll be a hundred of them..
at least.
You okay, Dan?
Yeah, I'm okay, Ned.
Steve?
Short life, but a merry one.
Joe?
We're gonna give them a
good old fight, aren't we?
Well, that's that then.
All right. Everyone
listen to me!
We're getting you out of here!
Hold your fire!
We've got women and
children coming out.
It's a trick!
Stop your fire! Cease fire!
Hold your fire!
Cease fire!
Get down on the floor!
Keep your heads down!
Stay on the floor!
They fired at us! They shot him!
Keep as low as you
can, you hear?
All right. Let's give it to 'em.
Hit the lights.
Fire!
They have armour
on their bodies!
Aim for their arms and legs!
- Ohhh! Ahhh.
- He's been shot!
- They've shot Hare!
- All right. Get back inside.
Get back inside. Come on.
Oh! Dan, reload me pistols!
I got the bastard that shot me.
Give me that anyways. Rifle!
Bullets. Come on.
Aw. The monkey's been shot!
Poor little bugger!
Ah, dear God.
Oh! Shit.
Somebody help me,
for Christ's sake!
Keep low! Get around
the back of the bar!
Can you find me something
to stop the bleeding?
Get down!
To hell with all you bastards!
Ned! Where the hell
are you going?
Get this lot around the back.
Ned?
Now's your chance. Quickly!
Out that back door there!
Aaah!
Ohhh!
Hands up, the lot of you, or
you'll be shot down like dogs!
Don't shoot!
I got him! I got Dan Kelly!
No, you bloody well haven't.
Jesus Christ, lads.
I think I need a drink.
What I best recall
is riding alone..
with the sun behind me..
seeing me own shadow
cantering ahead..
against the roadside
weeds and willows..
and leaving me
stretched far behind..
galloping to chase it..
Like a centaur in
the picture books.
Well done, Ned.
I wore it seriously..
me hero sash of green and gold.
Proof that I've saved
a life as well.
I'm out of rounds.
Do you have any left?
Only two.
I guess that's all we
need then, isn't it?
We never stood a chance, did we?
No.
Steve.
It's Ned Kelly. Christ
almighty, it's Ned Kelly.
Do you mind if I have this?
Hey! Look! It's Ned Kelly!
Ned! Hey, Ned!
Such is life.
Despite petitions for a pardon that
bore a total of 32,000 signatures..
Ned Kelly was hanged on
11 th of November, 1880.
He was 25 years old.
SubText: MITA.326