Do you know she's...
saving a room for her mother?
Did she tell
you that?
(softly):
Yeah.
Is she strange, that's all?
Is she okay?
If-if you had to take a guess.
That little girl's
the only friend my son ever had.
So she's strange, you bet.
BUNNY:
It crashed!
(kids laughing)
All right.
There you go.
(seagulls calling)
(labored breathing)
Do you know
how he died?
My husband?
It was a calm night
when Herold took the boat out.
There was no sign
of any storm.
Storms can be sudden
around here.
He wasn't the only one
whose boat went down.
It was four years ago...
and it's yesterday.
HERRY:
Look how high
we're up.
BUNNY:
Uh-huh.
Beat you to
the car.
(kids laughing)
Did I blow it
or can you still
be my friend?
Your friend? Sure.
(Bunny humming)
Is this yours?
(yawning):
The ghost brought it.
Then he ran away.
The skinny ghost
with the white dog?
Don't say I dreamt it.
(sighs)
BILLY:
Ah, you're getting
the hang of it.
Now, coax her a wee bit
to starboard.
Attaboy. You're a Quoyle--
there's seawater in your veins.
(groaning)
How are things
with your girl?
Oh, Bunny's just still
adjusting, I think.
Oh, I was talking
about Wavey Prowse.
Sorry... sorry!
Whoa!
Jesus!
Sorry.
I... Wavey and I
are just friends.
Fine. Don't have
to drown me over it.
This is where
I grew up.
That's my poor old
father there.
And that's where
your house stood.
Before they dragged it
across the ice.
Yes, sir.
Before they was driven away.
Driven away by what?
You never knew?
Ah, well.
It's neither
here nor there, right?
The point is, they made
a new place for theirselves.
No, by what?
Driven away by what?
Oh, that's old stuff, boy.
It's in my blood.
You ought to be
able to tell me.
Well, they come to Gaze Island
centuries ago, they did.
The old Quoyles was rackers.
They were, they were pirates,
sort of like.
You see them cairns?
Fires used to burn
in them
to guide
the ships at sea
like lighthouses.
Now, the Quoyles
would move the fires
to fool the ships.
They'd lure them
into the rocks
so the Quoyles could grab
their loot.
Oh, they was a savage lot,
the old Quoyles.
Then they went too far one day,
they... nailed a man to a tree
and they cut
off his nose
to draw the nippers
and the flies
that-that ate him alive.
And that's when the Quoyles was
given their walking papers.
Jesus.
Now, there's still an old Quoyle
down in one of these coves
somewhere.
They say he slept with his wife
after she was dead.
Anything else I should know?
That about covers it.
(buoy bell ringing)
BILLY:
? When the knitting pins,
you is abreast ?
? Hold the tiller
to the west... ?
? Behind the pins
you must steer... ?
? Till the old man's shoe...
does appear. ?
(Celtic drums fade up)
(woman screaming)
(men yelling)
(men shouting indistinctly)
MAN:
Pull, pull!
(shouting angrily)
(drums stop)
(gasps)
AGNIS:
Show me that necklace.
See, if you make
the loops bigger
you don't have
to make so many.
BUNNY:
Okay.
Good morning.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Where's that chair from?
Excuse me?
The chair
that you're sitting in.
Where's it from;
where'd you get it?
It's not from
around here, right?
It's foreign,
it's exotic.
I don't want pirate's loot
in this home.
Billy Pretty told me
all about it.
It's a good thing
somebody finally did.
I don't believe in dwelling
in the past.
No? Then what
are we doing here?
Making a future.
Well, well, well
if it ain't the second coming
of the Quoyles.
Taking a long
and hearty meal break
I can't help but noticing.
Hope you've got a good idea
for your next story, Quoyle.
I'd hate for Jack to think
that it was just
beginner's luck.
Let the man digest, Tert.
Mind you,
if I was the esteemed author
of the "Shipping News" column
I'd pick up
the McGonigle oil field story.
Petro-dollars;
a golden flood of jobs.
You write a story
about that
I'll put it right there
on the front page.
Thank you
for stopping by, Tert.
Yeah, thanks, Tert.
Aw, gee...
What was that
all about?
Oh, uh, he owns Mobil Oil.
Ten shares.
WAVEY:
What about your column?
What about it?
You said you'd
read it to me.
Yeah, I will,
once the game is done.
(horn blowing)
"There's a 1904 photo hung
in the Killick-Claw library...
"eight schooners heading out
to the fishing grounds
"their sails are white
and beautiful.
"But nowadays you're just
as likely to see
"a big black shape
of an oil tanker
"like the rupturedGolden Goose.
"Last week it leaked
14,000 tons of crude
"onto the seabirds, fish
and boats at Cape Despot.
"There will be more
and more tankers.
"They will get old and corroded
and their tanks will split.
"And there will be less fish,
and less fishermen.
"Nobody hangs a picture
of an oil tanker
on their wall, do they?"
What do you think?
I think when Tert Card sees it,
he'll stay up nights
thinking of cheap shots
to pay you back.
I think he won't stop
until you're fired.
I think I haven't been so proud
of a friend...
since I don't know when.
(switch clicks)
(water bubbling)
(door squeaking)
Uh, what do you think?
Pretty impressive, huh?
Like I said, nobody
hangs one of those.
Well... your column's
front page stuff.
Only now it's more
a caption, is all.
"More than 3,000 tankers
proudly ride...
the world's seas."
"Even the biggest
take advantage
of Newfoundland's deep water
ports and refineries."
Spelled it all perfect
so as not to embarrass you.
"Oil and Newfoundland
go together
"like ham and eggs
and like ham and eggs, they'll
nourish us in the coming years."
Even put
your name on it.
"Let's all hang a picture
of an oil tanker on our wall."
Man of your principles...
I understand
the only honorable
course is resignation.
(crumples paper)
And if you're off
to see Jack Buggit
you're going
to have to swim.
For I runs theGammy Bird,
every inch of it--
which he'd have
to do without me.
And if you think he's going
to choose you over fishing
then you're dumber
than a doughnut.
If that's possible.
Jack?
For Christ
sakes, Quoyle
cut your motor!
All right,
what's the emergency?
Can't it wait
till I'm done fishing?
It's about my column.
Card, he printed it
not the way I wrote it.
Well, so?
You disapprove
how Card runs my newspaper
enough to lose your job?
Yes or no?
Yes.
(shortwave radio
playing quietly)
(door opens)
So, this is what
Jack and I think:
we want to run Quoyle's
wrong-headed oil spills story
because controversy sells papers
and papers sells ads.
But the oil tanker picture
stays.
(groans)
(laughter)
You should have seen
Tert's face.
Yeah?
Oh, it was
a beautiful thing.
That's all right,
I've seen it.
(chuckles)
Oh, it's great.
Mm-hmm.
Let's see
what the special is.
How do you feel
about ordering to go?
You ever had that
before?
No, what is it?
Seal-flipper pie.
Yeah, it's made
from, like
the knuckle part
of the flipper.
The slimy cartilage part.
Yeah, it's good, though.
I mean, it's
a good choice
if you like
that sort of thing.
I... you know,
I'm really not
all that hungry.
I just wanted, you know,
to come and sit.
I had a big lunch today.
Yeah.
They say you're not
a real Newfoundlander
till you've had a piece
of seal-flipper pie.
That's what they say?
Yeah, that's right.
Mmm, good.
That's surprising.
(laughs):
I never eat it, myself.
You never eat this?
This is horrible.
Here, I got you some
real food-- look.
(both laughing)
(lilting melody playing)
(engine revs)
(gasps)
(grunting and gasping)
(gasping)
(motor clanks dully)
(yells in pain)
(gasping)
(melancholy music playing)
(music continues)
(buoy bell clangs
in distance)
(motor chugging)
(motor throttles back)
JACK:
Christ.
I knew somebody
was out here.
(groans)
Oh, for Christ's sake.
(shuddering)
He's still burning off
the fever.
Any feeling yet?
Little tingles.
You're lucky.
I'm fine.
I'll be ready to get
right back in that water
in another 20, 30 years.
Do you know how close
you were to dying?
I'll get my uncle, Alvin Yark,
to build you a proper boat
and learn how to use it, okay?
Okay.
Good.
MAVIS:
Were the eyes open or closed?
I don't know.
Just said it was
an disembodied head.
What'd the police have
to say about it?
Still working on it.
A little late to return the head
to its owner, though.
(snorts)
Hello, nephew.
Police bulletin:
"Mrs. Silver Melville
was arrested early today
"in Lanai, Hawaii,
for the murder of her husband
socialite and raconteur
Mr. Bayonet Melville."
'He pushed me once too often,'
Mrs. Melville confessed
'so I finally pushed back.'"
Good for you, my dear.
Well, he probably
deserved it.
Hey.
Don't get your hopes up.
You're the first man
who ever cooked for me.
You got a lot
of leeway.
How are they?
They're both asleep
in Bunny's bed.
Should we trust them?
(laughing)
I can do this.
You just don't think...
Oh, no.
No, I know. Here...
let me do that,
all right?
There you go.
Can you feel that...
Yeah.
through your bandage?
What?
Your husband, he never...
he never cooked you a meal?
Why are we talking
about my husband?
Because I understand.
You said "It's four years
ago and it's yesterday."
(heavy sigh)
I understand that.
My husband's not who
we're talking about, right?
I'll go get Herry.
He wouldn't like
waking up in a strange bed.
(dog barks)
(mysterious theme playing)
(wind whistling eerily)
(rattling and creaking)
(mysterious theme continues)
Hey!
Huh?!
Who are you?
(barking)
(growling)
(muttering)
I tied magic in these knots
to protect you
from the house.
No good ever come
from the old place.
Never, never... never.
You... you have no...
business in the
Quoyle house.
I get you
out of there.
But I am a Quoyle.
A Quoyle?!
I was a Quoyle
before you was anything.
(clearing throat)
Leave the house.
Tell, uh...
Agnis hello from...
Cousin Nolan.
(muttering)
You know why
Agnis come back?
To show she ain't afraid
of the place no more.
'Cause I know what she's done.
I know.
She got rid of the baby
she was carrying.
What could she do? What?
She was only 12
and it was her own brother
that done it to her.
(girl laughing)
(laughs)
No...
No! No! No!
Please! No!
No! Please!
(shrieks)
(kettle whistles)
Does that belong
to you?
Sorry.
There's still hot water
in the kettle
if you want some tea.
I've started looking
for a place for me
and Bunny.
You sure you're going
to be okay at your shop?
I said I would,
didn't I?
I think
Silver Melville was right
to chop her husband's head off.
He probably deserved it.
I think more women
should do what she did.
Maybe some should have done it
to their own brother...
my father.
Cousin Nolan dropped by
last night.
(dishes clatter)
I always thought if anyone
knew, I'd be turned to stone.
Shit!
Here.
Tea's a good drink.
It'll keep you going.
When someone hurts you
that much...
how do you...?
Does it ever go away?
Is it possible?
(sits mug on table)
AGNIS:
Her name was Irene.
The love of my life.
You look happy.
So, yeah, it is possible.
QUOYLE:
Agnis tells me we got to move
for the winter.
It'll be a three-hour drive
from here to the Point.
All the ice...
Me and Bunny,
we're going to
have to find
a room in town somewhere.
I'll have the usual,
please, Annie. Thank you.
Well, if it's a place
to stay you need
you can have
my trailer.
Timing's perfect.
What are you talking about?
My boat's ready.
If I stay here
any longer
I might begin
to like the place.
I'm throwing myself
a farewell party on Saturday.
Departure to
follow Sunday.
The rootless traitor.
Regrets soon after,
no doubt.
(boisterous din)
(bottles breaking)
(laughter)
Quoyle of the North!
Quoyle of the North.
Have you and Wavey
done the dirty yet?
(slurred):
Shh! She's the grieving widow.
Grieving for
Herold Prowse.
Oh, that's a good one.
Let me tell you
something
about old Herold Prowse.
It's like a party game
in town--
to look at babies
and see if they look
like Herold.
Hey...
Hey!
Everyone!
To Nutbeem!
ALL:
We all loves
our fucking Nutbeem, huh?!
(all cheer)
Lets us keep him here then!
Got your chainsaw,
Neddie?
(all cheer)
(chainsaw buzzes)
ALL:
Nutbeem!
Hoh-oh-oh!
(chainsaw buzzing)
(blows echoing)
(woman screaming)
(grunting)
(bird hooting)
(accordion playing
in distance)
(grunts)
(accordion grows louder)
(pounding)
What's wrong?
(slurring):
I'm a Quoyle.
I'm one of the Quoyles
pirates and looters
and murderers.
My father raped
his little sister
and then he taught me
how to swim.
Stop that.
Jesus, you smell
like a brewery.
Stop it.
Go on, Herry. Go on.
(whimpering)
Stop it!
Herry.
Sorry, Herry.
(sobbing gasps)
(voice breaking):
I'm sorry, Petal.
I'm so sorry.
(sniffles)
I meant Wavey.
Good. I feel much better.
When were you going to tell me
about your fucked-up marriage?
?  ?
I'm scrambling eggs.
Are you going
to be able to eat?
No.
Listen, I'm...
Maybe I should just go.
You forget where
the door is?
(door closes)
(pan clattering)
He ran off to Winnipeg
with some little bitch.
She was barely
out of high school.
Is that fucked up enough
for you?
Herold...
my husband,
he didn't die.
Not that he didn't
deserve to.
He left me when I was
eight months pregnant;
no good to him in bed.
So I took his 15-footer
out into the bay
cracked the hull with
a hatchet and sunk her
and pretended
he was drowned
and played the grieving widow
and packed my bags
to leave town.
But then a funny thing happened.
All these folk I grew up with
they put their hearts
around me and Herry
so we wouldn't be alone.
And I just
couldn't leave.
I'm sorry, Wavey.
You're always sorry.
(crying softly)
(footsteps approaching)
You're looking dishy,
Quoyle.
I'm afraid my offer
to let you stay in my trailer
will have to be retracted.
Sorry about that.
And your boat.
I'm some disgusted
with the human race.
I never would have
made it anyway.
Storms would have
blown me to bits.
You boys saved my life,
I imagine.
I've gathered up my savings,
and I'm flying back to Brazil
where the water is
swimming-pool green.
You and Bunny can stay
with the wife and me.
To Brazil.
Brazil.
NUTBEEM:
QUOYLE:
Brazil.
BUNNY:
We can stay with Aunt Agnis
over at her shop.
Barely enough room
there for myself.
You'll like it at
Dennis' house, sweetie.
No, I won't.
Hi, Quoyle. Hi, Bunny.
Welcome, weary travelers.
Our home's your home.
BUNNY:
No, it's not.
Come on in.
QUOYLE:
Bunny...
Come on in, sweetie.
I made a big
seal-flipper pie.
BUNNY:
What's that?
BEETY:
Weather light.
Storm coming.
DENNIS:
Big one.
(distant thunder rumbling)
(thunder rumbling)
The house... the house...
house...
(gasps)
(panting)
(thunder crashing)
(reading softly)
(thunder rumbling)
?  ?
I...
What is it, Quoyle?
What?
(thunder crashes)
(door creaks open)
(closes door)
(thunder crashes)
(thunder rumbling)
?  ?
(Celtic drums)
(wind howling)
It's gone.
What?
The green house is gone.
I didn't dream it.
Don't say I did.
(phone ringing)
Yeah?
Oh, hi, Mom.
Some storm, eh?
What?
Oh.
Yes. Yes, of course.
BUNNY:
What's a wake?
QUOYLE:
It's to say good-bye.
BUNNY:
Mr. Buggit is sleeping
with the angels.
MAN 1:
He was a hard man,
but he was fair.
MAN 2:
Another one
for the Buggit Curse.
QUOYLE:
Dennis...
Yeah, I'm still
looking for my
dad's Navy medal.
I found it.
Don't you worry.
It's going to be
all right.
Thank you.
Mom.
What?
(gasps softly):
Good...
I found it...
in his desk at the office.
Would you write something for
theGammy Birdabout Jack?
Yes, I'll try.
BILLY:
Jack is...
Jack is all right now.
You all know...
we are only passing by.
We walk over these stones
a few times.
Our boats...
sail for a little while
on the waves
and then they have to sink.
Jack knew that
better than anyone.
Right, Jack?
(whispering):
Yes, boy.
(gulps)
(screams)
(others screaming)
(screaming continues)
(screaming)
He's awake!
Jack...
Get a doctor!
Oh, Jack... oh, Jack...
(coughing)
Oh, Jack...
No, no...
JACK:
Come here, son.
I beat the curse.
The fishing license is yours.
(siren chirps)
Sweetheart, you ready?
I want to have a wake for Petal.
Why didn't we have
a wake?
Why didn't we wake her up?
It worked forhim.
Honey, Mr. Buggit
wasn't really...
It's more like
he was in a coma.
From the cold water.
It's like he
was sleeping.
Petal was asleep.
No, honey...
You said she was asleep
with the angels.
I know. Honey, I know
what I said, honey.
You said! You said!
I know, but she's
not sleeping.
You said! You said!
Honey, honey, listen to me.
You said!
I know what I said.
Listen to me.
I just... I was too scared
to tell you the truth.
Petal is dead.
And you know that.
I know you know it.
It's okay.
Is it because of me?
What?
That she drove away.
Well, why would you
say that?
Because...
because I'm boring.
(crying)
Oh...
No, honey, it's not
because of you.
And you are anything
but boring.
Come here.
You just come here.
Hon...
You believe me, don't you?
You still don't
believeme,do you?
About the house.
I told you so.
It's all right.
Worse things have happened.
To both of us.
Maybe one day we'll build
a summerhouse out here.
Summer...
BUNNY:
Do theyhavesummer here?
AGNIS:
Oh, you'll know it's summer when
the partridge berries are out.
WAVEY:
And we can make
partridge berry duff
and sweet berry okie.
Will you show me how?
I will, yeah.
I will.
QUOYLE:
There are still so many things
I don't know.
If a piece of knotted string
can unleash the wind
and if a drowned man
can awaken...
then I believe
a broken man can heal.
Headline:
Deadly Storm Takes House.
Leaves... Excellent View.