Why should the Falls drag me
down here at 5 o'clock in the morning?
To show me how big they are
and how small I am?
To remind me they can
get along without any help?
All right, so they've proved it. But why not?
They've had 10,000 years to get independent.
What's so wonderful about that?
I suppose I could, too,
only it might take a little more time.
Rose?
- Good morning.
- What is your destination in Canada?
- Niagara Falls.
- What's the name of the place?
- The Rainbow Cabins.
- What is your name?
- Mr and Mrs Ray Cutler.
- And where do you live?
- Toledo, Ohio.
- Where were you born?
- Toledo.
- And where were you born?
- Seattle.
Are you bringing in anything
besides personal belongings?
No.
- How long do you plan to be here?
- Three days.
- Honeymooners?
- That's right.
That isn't liquor you have in that case, is it?
Uh, books. I'm going
to catch up on my reading.
Reading?
Fine thing.
I tell him we're on our honeymoon and
you drag out a copy of Winston Churchill.
He must think I'm pretty hot.
You should have told him
we're on a delayed honeymoon.
Delayed or not, we agreed to treat it
like a regular one, didn't we?
I'm game. It'll be just as good
as a regular honeymoon.
Well, it should be better.
I've got my union card now.
- Hi.
- Hi. We're the Cutlers.
- We wired for reservations.
- Oh, yeah.
Let's see now. The Cutlers, huh?
Room overlooking the Falls. Cabin B.
Look, honey. You can see it from here!
- The Falls are that way.
- He means the Shredded Wheat plant.
I work for 'em, but I'm seeing
the joint for the first time,
where breakfast food
became a national institution.
Why don't they have that down
in that book of yours?
- Say, has there been a call for me?
- A call? Nope.
I'd better phone over and tell 'em I'm here.
Have him show you the cabin, honey.
- There's a phone in my office.
- Thank you.
Oh, it's a beautiful view.
- Cabin B is ours?
- The folks in there haven't checked out yet.
Then we can't move in.
Come on. I told them last night.
Hello? I wonder if I could
talk to Mr Kettering, please.
Well, this is Ray Cutler
from the Toledo branch.
No, I'm not speaking from Toledo.
I'm here in Niagara.
Mr Kettering wrote me to get
in touch with him when I arrived.
I'm the guy that won the cash prize for
the most imaginative sales campaign.
- Are you there, Mrs Loomis?
- Shh!
Stop knocking. My husband's asleep.
What is it?
The new folks are here. You were
supposed to be out this morning.
Just a second.
I'm awfully sorry about the cabin, but
my husband hasn't been feeling too well.
Please don't make me move him.
He's finally fallen asleep.
- First good sleep he's had in over a week.
- Is he sick, Mrs Loomis?
Well, he's not quite himself.
He just sits around and...
Last night he got up and wandered around
somewhere at 3 or 4 o'clock. I was frantic.
- Have you seen a doctor?
- Yes. Lately we've seen quite a few.
But I don't want to bore you.
- You're here to have a good time, Mrs... ?
- Mrs Cutler.
We had a good time, too, two years ago
when we were here on our honeymoon.
So I thought it would do him some good
after Letterman. It was a mistake.
I'm sorry, Mrs Loomis,
but this cabin is promised.
That's all right. We'll take another cabin.
You don't care, honey?
We got here the wrong time all around.
No cabin, no Mr Kettering.
- He won't be back till the first of the week.
- It doesn't make a bit of difference.
Thanks for being so nice. I sure appreciate it.
And, Mr Qua, I've got to run down
to the market while George is asleep.
- Would you keep an eye out for him?
- Of course.
Thank you. Thanks.
- It's up to you folks. Cabin K is vacant.
- Does it look down at the Falls?
It looks around at them,
but it gets plenty of sun.
OK. Let's go.
- I'll get the key.
- Thanks.
I'll do it, honey.
She said her husband
was in Letterman. What's that?
It's an army hospital, mostly psycho.
Oh.
Come on aboard. "Maid of
the Mist", the most famous boat in America.
Next tour starts in two minutes.
I'll have two, please.
Two, please.
Thank you.
- What size shoe?
- Ten and a half.
Thank you.
- What size, sir?
- Eight, please.
- Your check, sir.
- Thank you.
You ready, honey?
Get back!
Farther back, honey!
- What's the matter? I was coming down.
- Wasn't Mrs Loomis going shopping?
Yeah. Why?
Well, she sure got herself
an armful of groceries. Come on.
Rose?
Rose? Did you get the cigarettes?
- Didn't I give 'em to you?
- No, you didn't.
They're in my coat pocket, then.
Light me up, too, Georgie.
Mm, that felt good. Dry my back.
Bunch of kids must've checked in.
It's good to hear a laugh for a change.
- And I thought you forgot how to dance.
- There's still some Shredded Wheat in me.
- I'm thirsty.
- You are? Come on.
- Hi, Mr Qua. Having supper?
- No. Fresh figs. Have one.
- Best physic anybody ever had.
- No, thanks. Just a Coke.
Hey. Get out the fire hose.
Why don't you ever get a dress like that?
Listen, for a dress like that you've gotta
start laying plans when you're about 13.
- Would you mind playing this?
- Yeah. Sure thing, lady.
"Kiss. "
Kiss me
Won't you kiss me?
Oh, kiss
Kiss me
Say you miss...
What about it, lady?
Better not.
With heavenly affection
Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo
Hold...
- Plain Cokes or did you spike 'em?
- No, just plain. Would you like one?
No, thanks.
Hold me, hold me...
You kinda like that song,
don't you, Mrs Loomis?
- There isn't any other song.
- With all your heart's protection
This is a moment of
Thrill
Thrill me, thrill me
Mmm
Take me, take me in your arms
And make my life...
Mmm, mmm
Perfection
Take me
Darling, don't forsake me
Kiss me, hold me tight
Love me, love me tonight
Gee, I'm sorry. He was OK before.
I think he cut his hand. If you want,
we have some Mercurochrome.
- I wouldn't dare go in there right now.
- If you don't mind, I'll do it.
Well, thanks.
Your husband doesn't seem to like music.
Depends. He'll get right down and dig,
if you give him a rocking chair
and a corny old tune like "In the Gloaming".
What is it?
I brought you some Mercurochrome
for your hand. I'm Polly Cutler.
I suppose she sent you
to find out if I cut it off.
- Well, tell her I didn't!
- Do you want me to fix it or not?
I...
I guess it was silly, what I did.
But that song...
She didn't tell you about that, I bet.
Of course not.
She didn't say where
she first heard it or with who.
Well, she didn't tell me either.
Hold still, please.
Parading around,
showing herself off in that dress,
cut down so low in front
you can see her kneecaps.
- It's a stunning dress.
- Would you wear it?
Well, I'm not the kneecap type.
She's a pretty girl. Why hide it?
Don't worry about that.
She'd like to wear it where everybody
could see her, in the Yankee Stadium.
She's a tramp!
I tell you now so you won't have to ask.
You love her very much, don't you?
What do you know about it?
You're stuck on her.
Otherwise, you'd walk off and forget her.
I...
I guess so.
That's some confession to make, isn't it?
Here. Let me fasten the end of this.
- What's that?
- It's 8. 30.
Look out the window.
Oh!
- Let's go out with the others.
- I can't see anybody now. I...
I feel goofy after what happened.
Let me tell you something.
You're young. You're in love.
Well, I'll give you a warning.
Don't let it get out of hand
like those Falls out there.
Up above it...
Did you ever see the river up above the Falls?
It's calm and easy.
If you throw in a log itjust floats around.
Let it move further down
and it gets going fast.
It hits some rocks and in a minute
it's in the lower rapids
and nothing in the world, including God
himself, can keep it from going over the edge.
Itjust goes.
Don't worry. I'm one of those logs
thatjust hang around in the calm.
Hi.
Hey, Polly, come on.
You're missing the big show.
- Got myself a ringside table.
- Oh.
Look at those.
Couple of colours I never heard of before.
- This is my husband, Mr Loomis.
- Hello.
- You got yourself quite a girl.
- Well, she'll do for a while.
Hi.
We better be going.
- What's that?
- Oh, it's a 1907 Maxwell.
You make different models from little kits.
Look kind of nice on a mantel...
if you have a mantel.
- It's cute.
- Be all right if I don't foul it up.
I generally foul things up.
- Don't be silly.
- I have lately, anyway.
Everything I touch, ever since Duluth.
I met her in a big beer hall.
She was the most popular waitress they had.
I guess it was the way
she put the beer on the tables.
Until then I ran a good sheep ranch. Then
all of a sudden the sheep went dumb, or I did.
That winter the sheep kept dying.
- Everybody gets a run of bad luck.
- That won't cover it.
I rented it to another rancher. He had
worse winters and made out all right.
She was bored with the ranch. We spent
half our time in town in bars and nightclubs.
After that I fouled up a couple more jobs.
Then Korea. I wentjust to show her
I was young enough.
They sent me home with battle fatigue!
So don't tell me
I can't foul up a 1907 Maxwell!
Didn't do any good to fix that hand.
You like to suffer.
Maybe.
- My wife told you I was neurotic.
- She just said you weren't feeling well.
- She'd like everybody to believe I'm crazy.
- Don't be silly. Why?
I don't know, but she's got a reason.
You can bet on that.
She's got a reason.
Occupational therapy!
Hello? Is this the bus terminal? What time
do the buses leave tomorrow for Ottawa?
No, no, no. You got the wrong number.
This is McGrand's Boarding House.
Why don't you look up the right number
before you dial?
I'm sorry.
Mrs McGrand, that wasn't for me?
Nope. Someone for that bus terminal
again. It's the fourth time in two days.
Must have changed
the number or something.
Hello. You called.
Listen, it's got to be tomorrow.
Do you hear me? Tomorrow.
He just made a big row in front of everyone.
After this, nothing's going
to surprise anyone. It's made to order.
Can you get him there?
There's always a way to handle George.
Be at the place as soon as it opens.
OK, kid. It's a date.
Good luck, darling.
- In Chicago you know what we're gonna do?
- No.
We're going straight to Marshall Field.
I'm gonna buy you the slinkiest, meanest,
laciest evening gown they've got.
- Price no object.
- Yeah?
And when we're all set to step, who'll pull
one of his jealous fits and lock the door?
Oh, no. No more of that stuff.
You wait and see.
I'll take you to any dance place you want
and we'll have fun, the both of us.
You know what I'm gonna do?
Take lessons. Arthur Murray in six hours
can have you doing the rumba, the samba...
Georgie, this is quite a change.
What brought this on?
You know what.
- It's getting late. Hand me my slip.
- I hate to move.
When we have a fight and make up that way,
I never wanna leave your side.
Give me some orange juice, Georgie.
- You know, I'm sorry we're leaving today.
- Just as well.
Wish we'd brought the car.
Driving home, we could take our time
on the road and stop anyplace we please.
- Why are you getting dressed up?
- To pick up the bus tickets.
Pick up the tickets? We'll buy them
when we get to the terminal.
I'm not gonna stand all the way.
I want reservations.
There are no reservations.
We just go early and get aboard early.
You're getting all dressed up
to go out and buy tickets.
Why?
- Where are you going?
- Here we go again.
I'm not going to the bus station.
Do you feel any better?
- You smell cheap. I know what that means.
- Sure. I'm meeting somebody.
Just anybody handy, as long as he's a man.
How about the ticket seller?
I could grab him on my way out.
Or one of the kids with the phonograph.
Anybody suits me. Take your pick.
OK, OK, so I don't know this guy.
This guy you sing to, hum to.
Oh...
Build your Maxwell. I'll be back.
How do you like that?
You know what they say now?
Mr Kettering probably
won't be back till Tuesday.
If I'd only known that bef...
Hold it, kid. The sun's just right.
Now, swing around. We'll get a profile.
Come on, Polly. Profile.
That's it. Now inhale.
You've got nothing to hide. Inhale.
That's right.
What... ?
Oh. Just a minute, please.
Would you mind? Your shadow.
- Sorry, but have you seen my husband?
- No, I haven't.
- Isn't he in the cabin?
- That's just it.
You see, I left for the bus station and when
I got back... Mr Qua hasn't seen him either.
Oh, he probably went across the street
to get a magazine.
He wouldn't do that. We have to be
at the bus station at 11 o'clock.
Well, you've still got 40 minutes.
I shouldn't have left him alone,
especially after last night.
He was so upset and everything.
Well, you saw it.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing to worry about. He's over
on the other side getting one for the road.
I don't know. I think I'd be worried.
All right, now get back
into that same pose again.
OK.
Oh, Sam! Bring in the Missing Persons file.
Right, sir.
- Anything important?
- Might be. What have we got that's recent?
Uh... A Mrs Verna McGuire.
Her daughter has been
missing since yesterday.
She's always missing.
Some fraternity house. What else?
Mm...
A man called George Loomis, a transient.
We got a call at four. People
named Cutler phoned in for his wife.
Call back. Tell them to meet me
at Table Rock House, souvenir shop.
Very well, sir.
- Afternoon. Which of you is Mrs Loomis?
- I am.
I'm Starkey, from the police station.
Where is he? You know
something about my husband?
- You're the Cutlers?
- Yes.
- You've heard something about him?
- Just that he is your husband.
Is there any chance
he could have come here today?
- Here?
- Yes, here.
No, not possibly. He hates the Falls.
- What are we doing here?
- Wasting your time, I hope.
- Hello, Mr Starkey.
- Did you check again?
Yes, sir, I did, and there's still one missing.
And over here...
Let me see 'em.
- Remember anything at all about the man?
- No, sir, I don't.
Ever seen these before?
They're his.
Why is everyone standing around?
Do something! Look for him!
Find him!
Listen, Mrs Loomis, you'd better go home.
Have you got anyone
to take care of you? Any friends?
No. Well, that is, no one except these people.
- No one.
- No one? What about down below...
- Will you people take her home?
- Sure.
Come on.
You've been very kind,
but thanks, I'd rather walk.
Hold on. Wait a minute.
I think we've got him. Yes. On the far side.
It's hard to say.
I imagine he's pretty beat up.
OK, we'll run him down to the morgue.
- Why didn't your friends bring you?
- I'm all right. Where is he?
- Listen, this isn't going to be pleasant.
- I don't expect it to be.
Please wait.
Mrs Loomis, do you identify this body
as that of your husband George Loomis?
Hold her.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
I put in everything I thought she'd need.
No.
Get away.
I wanna get away.
What's all this? I want to talk to her.
Come around in the evening.
She'll be out till then.
Please.
- Business pretty good?
- Booked up for a month ahead.
- How many you accommodate here?
- About 50.
- How's the food?
- It's good.
- Here she is anyway. Hi, Mrs Cutler.
- Hi.
Well, well, well, hello there.
Hey! Cinch to see you belong to the
Shredded Wheat family. I'm Jess Kettering.
- I want you to meet the big boss.
- How do you do?
Sorry we weren't here when you arrived.
We'd have had red carpet over the bridge!
Oh, here's a little spinach for you,
by way of apology.
Hey... Hey, where's that
prize-winning husband of yours?
What a boy!
Turkey stuffed with Shredded Wheat.
Had it right the next day and I loved it!
You better move out of range, dear.
Jess likes to make his point.
Well, this is very sweet of you.
They're just lovely. Thank you.
- Isn't my husband back yet?
- He's been in and out all morning.
We'll take you along in our car. Leave word
for that no-good husband to join us.
Before we're through you'll see the Cave
of the Winds, Goat Island, the Old Fort.
And we're gonna get in the best fishing
you ever did. Just wait till you see our boat...
Now, Kettering, Mrs Cutler
would rather wait for her husband.
Speaking of Niagara, you and I could do with
a shower. We've been driving since six.
The minute Ray gets back, we'll call you.
You bet. Well, toodle-oo for now. Pip-pip!
Come on, mama!
Oh, not that way, Mrs Cutler.
I put your things in Cabin B.
I told your husband I won't charge you
one cent more. You've waited long enough.
Thank you.
The key's in the door.
Mrs Cutler! What is it?
Mrs Cutler!
- What's the matter?
- I don't know. I heard a yell a minute ago.
Polly?
Are you in there, Polly?
Polly!
What's the matter, honey?
What's the screaming about?
Get organised, baby. What's wrong?
- I was half-asleep...
- Yes?
Now, look, darling,
it was probably just a nightmare.
Now calm yourself down.
I'll get you a glass of water.
It's all right. She's OK.
Ray, don't!
- Don't go in there, Ray.
- Honey, wake up.
He's in there. He's alive.
He was standing right here looking at me.
Polly, who was looking at you?
- Mr Loomis.
- Mr Loomis?
- No, Ray...
- No, Polly. I gotta prove it to you.
Well, where is he?
Under the icebox? Under the sink?
Oh, Polly.
Mr Loomis. If I hear that name
once more, I'll start yelling myself.
No wonder it got you. We wait three years
for a honeymoon, then spend it with spooks.
Here. Drink this.
Mr Loomis! From the time we get here
we're patting his hand, burying him.
And her, running around sobbing,
asking if we'll pick out a tombstone.
Why, it's enough to drive anybody nuts!
Well, we're gonna
kiss off this place right now.
Give me a hand
with this stuff, will ya, honey?
Sport clothes! All we needed here
was a couple of shrouds.
Sorry, Winnie.
What's this thing?
Oh, the flowers. The Ketterings brought them.
- The Ketterings?
- Yes. They stopped by.
- Here?
- Yes.
- We're supposed to have dinner with them.
- What do you know? JC Kettering himself?
Yes.
Well, it's out. The way you feel,
the whole idea's silly.
Old JC, king of the VPs.
- He seems to think you're hot stuff, too.
- He does?
Well, that doesn't alter this
one way or the other.
Still, we have to eat somewhere.
Just a bite, maybe.
I'll tell you what, you lie down,
I'll get a shave and we'll decide later, OK?
Now lie down.
Hello. Police Department?
Will you put me through
to Mr Starkey, please?
Well, do you know where
I can reach him? I'm Mrs Cutler.
No, I can't be reached either. We're going
out with some people to see the Falls.
But would you tell Mr Starkey
when he gets back to stay there?
I've gotta talk to him. It's about Mr Loomis.
Yes.
All right. Everybody, listen to me.
That's it. The Cave of the Winds.
At great risk to life and limb,
these bridges were built in 1885.
A world-famous attraction ever since.
Now button up your coats real good
and follow me. Let's go.
It wasn't 1885. It was 1881.
Don't pay attention to him. I'll show you.
Come on, Ray boy. Follow me.
Let them do the mountain climbing.
We're gonna go back and have a smoke.
After all, it's just a lot of water.
I think I'll stay here. You go on ahead.
If you don't mind, I will.
Oh, Polly!
Polly, come on down.
You killed that man.
What was I supposed to do?
He came after me with a wrench.
After that, it was a case of who killed who.
If it was self-defence, go to the police.
In the tunnel I found his claim check.
That meant I could put on his shoes
and walk out of there officially dead.
- For all the good that'll do.
- At least I can go somewhere,
find ajob, get organised, if you'll help me.
- Help you?
- You're the only one who knows I'm alive.
Your wife knows it. They found the body.
When she gets out of the hospital, she'll tell.
Hospital?
Rose won't talk.
She'd have to say to the police
"I had a plan to kill my husband,
but it backfired. "
No, not Rose. She'll go to a new town,
drift up to the right bar stool...
Polly!
What about it? Please.
I'd do the same for you if it meant as much.
Let me stay dead.
Take your hands off me.
- Polly!
- Here I am.
- We got a lot more to see.
Well, kids, sleep well tonight. We've gotta
be out on my boat at the crack of dawn.
Oh, Jess, do we have to get up
before the fish do? Why not 8 or 9 o'clock?
Nonsense. Ray wants all the time
on that river he can get.
- He's a real fisherman. Eh, boy?
- Well, I sure like it a lot.
I hope we're not putting you out.
You've been so nice to us.
Putting us out? Listen, I've been wanting
to meet Ray boy here for quite a while.
OK, 5 o'clock in the morning, right here.
"Olive oil", as the French say!
Thanks a lot.
Bye. Bye, Mrs Kettering.
Sure did have a good time.
Here, honey.
You take this and I'll check on the mail.
- Hello.
I've been using your view.
- Is anything wrong?
- You just stole my question.
My sergeant took a message. You wanted
to see me about the Loomis case.
It was urgent.
The sergeant's exaggerating. It wasn't
that important. Just a silly question.
I hoped maybe that
you had heard from Mrs Loomis.
How could I? She'll be unconscious
for the rest of the day.
Mrs Cutler, the doctor says only panic or
fear could have broken through that drug.
What scared her so much
that she came to and skipped?
- Skipped?
- Yeah, disappeared from the hospital.
No mail, but old...
What is this? If it's another funeral, have
the corpse leave his name at the desk!
Loomis is trying to kill his wife. He's alive.
Polly, you ought to have
your head examined.
She had a nightmare. She thinks
this Loomis is alive, that he was here.
I thought we had this out.
It wasn't a nightmare.
He is alive and his wife knows it, too.
Oh, please, Polly! Mr Starkey, I'm sick
of this thing. Look what it's done to her.
If you've got a problem, take it someplace
else. We're washed up! We're through with it.
Good night. Thank you, sir.
I bought two tickets for Chicago.
Can I have a refund on one?
Sure.
- That's $12. 50.
- Thanks.
Well, are they gonna keep us here all day?
There'll be a delay. The police
are checking up on everybody's ID.
Checking up? Why?
The bus is supposed to leave at 5. 55.
- At this rate, we'll never get home.
- They're looking for some dame.
The bus'll make up for lost time
once we get started.
"Let's visit Niagara Falls. "
I'm sorry I ever mentioned it.
Hop in.
Can you get me to the bus station
on the American side?
If you're not in too much of a hurry.
They've got a roadblock at the bridge.
- Smugglers or something.
- That's no good, then.
And the sidewalk?
Can I get through that way?
Could be. Take that walk over there,
just to the right side of the gate.
Thanks.
The tower is under control
of both countries,
but Americans claim them bells
don't play "The Star-Spangled Banner"
as well as they do "God Save the Queen".
Right over there on June 30th, 1859,
Blondin, a French tightrope walker,
made his famous walk over the Falls.
If you'll follow me, I'll show you
a little better where it happened.
Hello? Hello? Police!
Too bad.
They can't play it for you now, Rose.
Georgie...
I loved you, Rose. You know that.
Ray boy, grab these cans.
You and I will get the gas.
Boss, you run and get some liver.
Polly-O, you run up
and get five or six bottles of beer.
All right now, everybody rush around.
Do yourjob. Jump to it.
Just trying to get things organised.
At home with the kids
he tries to organise pillow fights.
- Come on, honey. Cheer up.
- I'm all right.
Come on, kids. We haven't got all day.
Those fish are dying to get at our bait.
This Canadian town of Chippewa.
Great Revolutionary War battles.
The British whipped us.
All right now. Very nice people.
Polly, get the beer in there, huh?
Boss, you gotta get the liver down here.
- You the one who phoned?
- Yeah. I heard about it on the news later.
There was a fella here seemed a lot like
that Loomis they're looking for. Had a scar.
- How long ago?
- Maybe 10 o'clock.
He come and asked could he rent a boat.
I didn't have nothing till 3 o'clock.
- He's trying to reach the American side.
- Yeah. Notice which way he went?
No, I was working on some tackle. But he
seemed awful anxious to get himself a boat.
Thanks. If he shows up again, phone us.
Right.
Hey! What's wrong over there?
Hey!
Get off this boat!
Get off the boat!
You're insane. You must be insane.
Where do you...
Get off!
Hey!
Hey! Hey, you!
Hello? Give me the police.
No. No, I don't know whose boat it is.
He shoved off toward the river.
There's some girl on the boat.
Yeah. Yeah.
Sorry. You wouldn't get off. Are you all right?
Of course I'm all right.
You turn this boat around.
- Go to the police and give yourself up.
- It's a little late for that now.
Talk to the police.
Tell them it wasn't your fault.
You should've done it two days ago.
Are you afraid to defend yourself?
I can't.
Not any more.
I... killed Rose.
- Any other boat in the inlet?
- No, there's nothing fast enough.
Sorry.
United States River Patrol.
Morris, on United States River Patrol,
where are you? Come in.
River Patrol. Morris speaking.
We're abeam of Navy Island.
Try to intercept a power launch.
She's a 20-footer,
probably on her way to Buffalo.
George Loomis is aboard.
Yes, sir.
He isn't crazy enough
to head downstream, is he?
Where is he trying to go?
I guess he's making a run for Gill Creek.
Mr Starkey, this is Morris
on the launch speaking.
- Something wrong up ahead.
- Starkey here.
Lost headway. Engine trouble or something.
They're in the drift.
There must be some gas on board.
I don't think so.
- They're being pulled into the current.
- A 12-knot drift.
- What does that mean?
- It means they're in real trouble.
You can't. You'll be torn to pieces.
Can't you tell 'em to hurry up
on that police boat? Can't they get there?
Morris, on United States River Patrol,
can you reach them?
No, sir. We're 1,000 yards past
the limit now. We're turning back.
Scuttle it.
If we can take on enough water, she'll ground.
- What's the story?
- Take it easy, fellas. No photographs.
- The car is waiting.
- Here, dear.
Well, goodbye, Mr Starkey.
And thank you.
You've seen enough of the Falls for one trip,
but don't cross us off your list. Goodbye.
Goodbye, and my thanks.
I bet that was the first time anyone
ever used "Scuttle it" as a prayer.
And had it answered.