Presented by KTB Investments
Korean Film Council
and Cheongeoram
Produced by
bom Film Productions
Night and Day
KIM Sung-nam - KIM Youngho
LEE Yu - PARK Eunhye
HAN Sung-in - HWANG Sujung
Mr. Jang - KEE Joobong
JANG Min-sun - KIM Youjin
CHO Hyun-ju - SEO Minjeong
YOON Gyoung-soo - LEE Sunkyun
JUNG Ji-hye - JUNG Jihye
Cinematography: KIM Hoonkwang
Lighting: KIM Sunghoon
Sound Recording: AN Sangho
Editor: HAHM Sungwon
Original Music: JEONG Yongjin
Sound Supervisor: CHANG Chulho
Producer: OH Jungwan
Written and Directed by HONG Sangsoo
During the summer of 2007,
Kim Sung-nam smoked marijuana
with exchange students from the US.
One of the students got arrested
and revealed Kim Sung-nam's name.
Sung-nam's friend, Mr. Baek,
told him about this.
Sung-nam became terrified
and took the next flight to Paris.
August 8
Do you have a light?
A lighter!
August 9
I stayed at the first floor
of the guesthouse.
Over ten people sleep in one room
and it reeks so bad.
I'm here in Paris.
I'm going to clean myself up
and make a new start.
I will.
The air's very fresh for a city.
It has no humidity.
August 11
I finally found an open
cigarette store after four tries.
5 euros and 20 centimes.
Hardly any cigarettes here
because it's the only place open.
Look, there are hardly
any cigarettes here.
They must be sold out.
That's because it's the only store
that's open.
She has a very nice figure.
I don't think I could
fall in love again like them.
August 12
Good morning.
Have a good night's sleep?
Got over the jet lag?
I got some good sleep last night.
- Doing laundry?
- Just folding them up.
It keeps raining.
Yes, it sure is.
See you later.
Do you know how to use the internet?
No, I'm not good at computers.
The wireless doesn't work.
But it's brand new.
Sorry, I don't know much
about computers.
I see.
Do you go to church?
No, I don't.
But you're reading the bible.
Oh, this?
It was just lying around.
It's like a history book to me.
It's fun so I read it sometimes.
Oh, I see.
That book has completely
changed my life.
Oh, really.
Will you be here this afternoon?
We're having a small party.
Really?
Yes, have a drink with us
if you have time.
Sure, I think I'll be here.
How about you?
Sorry, I'm afraid I'll be late.
Okay.
It's the evening and the guy
hosting the party isn't here.
It's inconvenient
smoking out here, isn't it?
No, I'm fine.
It helps me smoke less anyway.
Would you like a cigarette?
So what brought you here this time?
Nothing special.
Although I'm a bit old now,
I thought I should come here
at least once since I'm a painter.
Lots of things to see here.
Nowhere else in the world
like this city.
That's right.
Anyway, you look good.
You would've been a general
if you were born long ago.
You have a nice impression, too.
A very nice impression.
Do you mind if we shake hands?
Of course not.
I have a friend and she's young.
I'll introduce her to you.
She calls me daddy
and she'll be good to you.
She also studies painting.
She can help you out with things
and show you around.
Thank you for your help.
It's the least I can do for you.
I only do the things I like to do.
I see.
Would you like to shake hands again?
Of course.
That was fun!
By the way,
why does the sun set so late here?
It gets dark around ten.
We can't easily tell night from day
during summers here.
Is that so?
August 13
Do you know how I'm living here,
Sung-in?
I miss you.
Me too.
I miss you so much, too.
Honey!
This is so terrible.
Tell me what should I do?
She got no phone call yet
from the police.
I told her to wait a few more days.
We decided that I'd call her
at one every night.
Sung-nam.
I don't have the strength.
I took a nap in the church
at the rotary.
Excuse me.
Excuse me for just a moment.
What?
You're Korean, right?
Do you know me?
You must be kidding me.
Hey, what did you say?
What's wrong with you?
You're really pathetic.
What?
Can't recognize me?
It's me.
You really don't know me?
No, I don't. Who are you?
Wait!
Tell me who you are first!
Stop treating me like this.
All the way here in Paris!
What the hell are you thinking?
Hey!
Wait! Wait!
I'm sorry.
You're Min-sun, right?
What a coincidence!
You're really crazy, you know!
We dated ten years ago
but she seems to be angry with me.
Oh, you remember me now.
You're quick to forget.
What the hell's in your brain?
Sorry, I've been losing
my memory lately.
It's inherited.
You haven't changed at all.
Fortunately, she let up soon
and we went to a cafe.
I'm sorry.
I really couldn't remember you.
August 15
Wow, you're really strong.
Again?
One, two, three!
You're really strong!
You're stronger than you look.
He's too worn out now.
You better not.
I don't think he'll win.
Hold it tight.
One, two, three!
Wow! You're so strong!
When I was young,
I met a cook at a Chinese restaurant.
I arm wrestled him
and his arm was this big.
But I can't beat young guys lately.
They're too strong.
But you beat them all.
To paint,
I need a strong arm and power.
August 16
Now I can start forgiving you.
Remember what you said
while we were in love?
I'm embarrassed that I don't.
Know how many times
I had an abortion because of you?
Six times.
Really?
Six times!
Are you serious?
Why didn't you tell me?
What for?
I must've felt intimidated by you.
I couldn't even tell you about it.
Well, you did try to be
polite around me.
Stop talking about the past.
I'm sick of it.
Dummy.
Sorry.
Give me your hand.
What brings you here?
Do you live around here?
Yeah, I live just over there.
So what are you doing here?
Oh, I have an urgent thing to do.
What is it?
I told you something came up.
It's been a long time.
The rib stew you made was delicious.
Yes, it was.
- Okay, then I'll see you later.
- Bye.
It upsets me to even see her.
Why?
She's too realistic and stingy.
She doesn't care what others say
and keeps talking about herself.
Do you know how cheap
her conversation is?
She shows no reaction
if others say something funny or sad.
She only cares about herself.
And she goes to Beaux-Arts
to be a painter.
She always shows it off
even though it's no big deal.
She really sucks.
I don't like women
who are realistic.
Women don't need to be realistic.
What?
She's stingy.
Do you know her well?
No, I don't.
Can't help knowing her
since few Koreans live around here.
You know how much
she chases after men?
She has no shame.
You know, girls like her
just can't live a second without men.
That's what she is.
Now I see.
That girl made Min-sun feel guilty
about being a married woman.
Oh yeah, the day I met you...
Was it a mistake?
What?
I told my husband about you.
He kept pressing me, so I told him
that I'd meet you today.
Really?
Your husband's French, right?
Yeah, he's a nice man
but he didn't understand me.
He was mad at me even though
I did nothing wrong.
So I just told him the truth.
So, you did.
Doesn't he worry about you?
He knows I'm meeting you anyway.
He'll be okay.
I'll just explain everything later.
Okay, I guess that'll do.
I'm going home later.
I'm a little drunk anyway.
You're too drunk. Go home.
Sounds like you're chasing me away.
How sad.
Don't say that.
I didn't mean that.
You're late so hurry home.
I'm too drunk.
I'll stay out longer.
What's wrong with you?
I have to go now and so should you!
Are you sure you have to go now?
Are you?
Sorry, I have to go. Bye.
I felt like Min-sun's husband
was watching us from somewhere.
My feet were sweating.
August 19
Yes, I'll write you.
I'll write everything
I want to say to you.
That's good.
You can barely talk on the phone
since someone might hear.
How have you been?
What did you do today?
Nothing really.
I bumped into a school friend
by chance a few days ago.
She's married to a French man
and he's a folklorist.
She even has an atelier
in her home.
A woman?
Yes, a woman.
She seemed to be happily married.
And she hasn't given up painting.
If she could help you, ask her to.
You know nobody there,
so ask her about this and that.
It's hard since I haven't
seen her for so long.
People here are different.
They're all too busy to help others.
Really?
I've been talking to your mother.
I persuaded her a little more.
If she helps us out,
we could get a room there in Paris.
Then I could go there to be with you.
She's going to help us out?
It looks likely.
She told the police I'm traveling,
and they hung up the phone.
If it all ends up bad,
I could never return to Korea.
Wait for me. I'll go to you.
Okay, try your best.
I'm so sorry.
August 21
You don't look very good.
No, I'm fine.
You're always saying that.
Get going.
Okay.
Have fun.
- See you later.
- Have a good trip.
Okay, thank you.
Bye.
I went to the Orsay Museum with
the girl Mr. Jang introduced me to.
I decided to be nice to her
since she could help me.
Here it is. It's all Courbet's.
You're right.
Do you like it?
Yes, I do.
I didn't see this here before.
It's a really famous painting.
This is my first time seeing it.
Really? That's great.
Don't you feel embarrassed
while looking at it?
Why?
What's strange about a painting
expressing the origin of humans?
It's the origin of the world.
Oh, sorry.
But shouldn't we feel
some respect for art work?
Well, I care for the painting
not the title.
- What do you think?
- Maybe you're right.
I like the clouds here.
They hang low here.
I paint clouds, you know.
Oh, you do?
Mr. Jang must like you a lot.
Usually, he doesn't ask me a favor
like this since I'm busy.
Yes, he is very nice.
I'm sorry for bothering you.
That's okay.
I also enjoyed the paintings.
So are you studying theory
to be a professor in Seoul later?
I hope so!
Where do you live?
Not far from where you're staying.
About five minutes away?
In an apartment?
No, I live in a one-room flat
with my roommate.
Roommate? A school friend?
No, I just met her as a roommate.
She paints and goes to Beaux-Arts.
By the way,
how much do you pay rent here?
560 euros, excluding the subsidy.
- You got a subsidy, too?
- Yes, about 180 euros.
What subsidizes you?
The government.
As long as the place
isn't so expensive.
Everybody gets it if they apply.
Why does the government subsidize?
Foreign students get it, too?
Anyone who applies gets it.
What a strange country.
Yes, it's great.
From the government?
August 23
Min-sun came over to the guesthouse.
It was my mistake to tell her
I'm staying at the Blue House.
She surprisingly showed up
while I was reading the Bible.
You're so beautiful.
Sit down here.
I've gained a lot of weight, huh?
I'm ashamed of it.
I'm the one who's ashamed.
I'm sorry for bringing you here.
No, it's okay.
Do you want to see this?
I'll read it to you, so listen.
"If your hand commits a sin,
cut it off. "
"You'd rather enter life
without the hand
than enter the flame of hell
with it. "
What is it?
"If your eye does a lewd thing,
fork it out. "
"You'd rather enter God's land
with one eye
than be thrown to the flame of hell
with two eyes. "
We really have to think about this.
We have to overcome temptation.
not to be merely moralistic,
but that it's more practical.
We can gain much more
if we overcome our sins.
We can maintain
peace in our minds forever.
I know.
What it says is how I truly feel.
You're so beautiful.
And you drive me crazy.
Hey, let's get out of here.
I feel that we should go.
It's more 'practical' for us!
Let's not lose 'peace in our minds'!
Not for that damn
one moment of desire!
No.
I'm okay, really.
You don't know.
Nobody knows
what I'm putting up with.
Just once, okay?
Do it once, please.
I know what you're going through.
I feel the same as you.
But why don't we just think
beyond how we see things?
We better fork out these eyes!
They why did you bring me here?
You shouldn't treat me like this.
Why can't you understand
what I'm trying to say to you?
I was amazed about
how that phrase had come to me.
August 24
She's too inconsiderate.
I can't understand her.
How could she do this to her son?
Are you really her son?
If I were her, I'd give my son
all that I have and more.
How could she be like this?
I can't understand her.
She's different from you.
Just forget about it.
Don't let it stress you more.
She's just different from you.
What are you going to do?
You must've run out of money.
I guess I'll find a way somehow.
Shall I go to a restaurant?
Restaurant? Why?
To work there?
I don't like it.
Why do you want to do
that kind of work?
I'm just looking into it.
No, don't do it.
Don't say that to me again!
Okay, don't get upset.
Then what else can I do here
to make money?
No, I don't want to hear it.
Stop it.
Sung-in, I saw a plane
in the afternoon.
This might be funny to you,
but I hated that plane.
I hated it
for dropping me alone here.
I called Mr. Baek today.
He said it could be better
if you give yourself in.
That's bullshit!
He can say that
since he's not in my position!
He calls that advice, damn it?
He's just concerned about you,
so don't be upset.
Anyway, I don't trust anyone.
I trust no one but you.
I'll find a way to live.
I'll find a way for real
starting tomorrow.
August 26
I'm sorry I'm late.
That's all right.
Hello.
This is my roommate.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you for coming out.
Anyhow, the school is closed.
Nobody can go in during break.
I'm sorry.
We can go to the gallery.
It completely shuts down
during the break?
That's strange.
Every other school does the same.
So nobody can go in?
Yes, it's closed.
The school is completely empty.
I see.
- It's great.
- Yeah, it is.
Her roommate goes to Beaux-Arts,
so she came out to show me around.
I think I have to buy them dinner.
Her roommate is the girl
I saw before with Min-sun.
I've seen this name before.
Yes, it's a famous gallery.
But it seems closed.
It's closed until August 28th.
They're probably on vacation.
They're pretty diligent about it.
By the way, don't you think
this memo is cute?
It looks like it's written as,
"I'm right next door. "
Yes, I like how they're casual
about things.
Whether the gallery is famous or not.
Sir, maybe one day you'll exhibit
your paintings in there, too.
What? Me?
I wish I could.
All the best galleries like this
come see the graduates' exhibition.
If they're selected,
they sign contracts on the spot.
That would be so great.
Now I see why so many galleries
are by your school.
Yes, I have to do my best!
Your best!
That's good to hear, but I'd like
for you to not call me 'sir. '
Then how do you want me
to address you?
I just thought
you were quite older than me.
I don't care, actually,
but "sir" doesn't sound appropriate.
It doesn't suit me anyway.
Okay, I understand.
Let's go.
- Please come in.
- Okay.
Promise me you won't use
any of this elsewhere.
Of course.
Here.
I realized while studying here
that painting is basically an idea.
It all starts with an idea.
So can you promise
that you won't use this?
Yes, don't worry.
Be careful.
It's the only one I have.
She cares for it so much.
I'll be careful.
Aren't these clothes?
Yes, they're shirts somebody hung out,
and I loved
the sun's reflection on them.
Those are about figure skating.
The woman is heavy
so the man is suffering.
This is the moment of dependence.
And this is the moment
of connection.
This one looks like a sinner.
Well, everybody commits a sin.
Don't you?
No.
There's no one.
Only the clothes are left.
They're for the artist book.
I wanted to paint the "House of Sand. "
They'll be the characters in it.
How about this one?
That one, too.
A calf with two heads.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Why'd you pretend
that you didn't know me?
Have you seen him before?
We've seen each other, haven't we?
Yes, we did.
I was going to tell you that.
I saw your pictures today, right?
Do you want me to tell you
what I think about your pictures?
I'm curious, too.
No, I'm too drunk now.
It would be better to talk
about others' works when I'm sober.
After taking a shower.
Actually, I'm not too curious
about what you think.
I've never met anyone
who knows more about my work than me.
But you like them, right?
Yes, very much.
Thank you.
Let's toast.
Let me pour you one.
I'm okay.
The food here is terrible.
I think it'll cost
at least 150 euros.
Do you still dream
of becoming a great painter?
Pardon?
You must not want to answer.
I'm sorry.
No, you don't have to be sorry.
I have something
I'd like to hear from you.
Answer me in two answers.
What are they?
What is a painting?
And what is painting to you?
Painting?
Yes, two answers.
Two answers?
August 27
The old hill of golden grass
where I and Maggie were playing
I hear the water mill, Maggie,
with the old dim memory
The hill is covered with the bushes
and the roses are all in full bloom
I hear the water mill, Maggie
Oh, my love Maggie
August 28
Isabelle, ever since Hugo was little,
we've had a lot of important
family events at this restaurant.
I'm so glad to be here with you.
Yes.
I'm happy to be here, too.
You two met at the Lille?
I believe that's what Hugo said.
Yes, we met during the festival
a few months ago.
We're members of the same association.
It's cold today, isn't it?
Especially outside.
Where are you going?
Home.
It's good to see you.
Me, too.
Do you need anything?
Something warm.
And something to eat.
Ham or cheese.
Okay, wait a moment.
Thank you.
See you later, bye.
Did you treat him?
Yes, to a sandwich.
Going home?
Yes.
How are you doing?
Fine.
And you?
Good.
It's nothing but a miracle.
She's a very beautiful person.
What a miracle
from our ordinary lives.
Doesn't this give people
a reason to live?
What's so funny?
Do you like oysters?
People here seem to eat it
very often.
Is it expensive?
They eat it a lot.
It's not so expensive.
It tastes better
if you squeeze lemon on it.
Can I buy some for you?
Oh, thank you.
I also appreciate the dinner before.
But not today, I'm so tired now.
Oh, I just wanted to treat you.
I'm tired from my part-time job.
Part-time job?
I'm working at a restaurant.
It must be very tough for you.
One of the co-workers mocked me
because of my clumsy French.
I had made a small mistake.
No one there but her
laughed at me loudly.
She is so jealous.
You know those girls who always want
to be the prettiest around.
She's so ugly and pathetic.
Yeah, I know those kinds of girls.
So can I leave now?
Yes, of course.
Glad to see you again.
I need some sleep.
Yes, have a good rest.
Buy me oysters later.
Sure.
September 1
Oh, it's you.
It's an old one.
Oh, it's a pine tree.
They're from my exhibition.
Very nice.
You also put clouds
in the pine tree paintings.
You seem to like clouds a lot.
Yes, I like the wind too.
I see.
Very nice.
Since I kept talking about oysters,
Hyun-ju suggested that we buy some
at a seafood store.
I've thought about oysters
for several days.
Yu-jeong, wake up.
Yu-jeong.
She sleeps like a log.
Yes, she really does.
She even slept
during a big party here.
- Really?
- Yes.
Yu-jeong, wake up.
She couldn't sleep in high school
because she studied so much.
So she's been addicted to sleep
every since she came here.
She didn't wake up even when
we splashed water on her.
Are you serious?
Do you want some more?
Yes, thank you.
Just a little.
Need to save some for Yu-jeong.
She doesn't like oysters.
I see.
Her feet are so pretty!
- Please don't see me out.
- No, it's okay.
I drank a lot, didn't I?
Get some rest.
I'm okay.
A lot of people are out here.
You were great in helping me
break the boredom in Paris.
Thank you.
You look pretty when you blush.
Really?
Thank you.
Yu-jeong didn't wake up till I left.
She sleeps too much.
I think I truly love her.
She is such a beautiful woman.
September 3
I read a Korean newspaper.
Then I learned about the South-North
Korean summit in Pyongyang.
I got frustrated with being alone.
So I went by the guesthouse
by foot, not by subway.
I got lost like an idiot.
I used the black building
to find my way.
I was so glad to find
the Alesia Church.
I'm finally home.
September 4
Sung-in, what are you doing?
I was just writing in my diary
in our room.
I see.
I feel so frustrated today.
Anyway, can you do it for me?
What? Do what?
Well, you know...
Can you masturbate for me?
What?
I'm sorry, but please do it.
I'm having a hard time
and I miss your voice so much.
Can you do it on the bed?
Can you do it for me?
Are you serious?
Where are you now?
This is so embarrassing.
I'm sitting alone in the living room.
So I can't do it myself.
I really miss your sound.
It'll be great, really.
Okay.
Wait a second.
I'll go wash my hands.
Okay.
September 6
- Good morning.
- Hello.
Take this medicine.
Thank you.
It'll work well.
- Your forehead.
- Sure.
It's okay. No fever.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
I have to go home.
I will go home.
Oh, hi.
I'm on my way to see something fun.
Do you want to come?
No, I better get some rest.
Why are you so sneaky?
Be a man and act like one.
I'm going to tell your wife
when she comes later.
I swear I will.
I'm sorry. I really am.
Be a man and do it.
I dreamed of her all day long.
September 7
He has a house and a car.
I envy him.
Good morning.
How'd you know where I live?
I came here with you before.
Oh, that's right.
Sorry, I forgot.
I'm sorry.
Where are you going?
I have something urgent to do.
Where are you headed?
Well, just somewhere...
I'm sorry to bother you.
Are you here to see Hyun-ju?
She's not here.
Why don't you come by later?
I thought I could see you any time.
Oh, so you did.
It took me a lot of courage
to come here.
We are very busy people.
I know.
I'm not good
at expressing myself, but...
I'm sorry for telling you this.
I'd rather meet a woman
than a married man.
Sure, I know.
But why do you
have to emphasize that?
When did I ever emphasize it?
Come with Hyun-ju later.
I'm lonely, but it's better
not to meet anybody.
The people here don't know
what circumstances they're in.
Their lives are full of hypocrisy.
They switch to French and Korean
as they please.
They have no shame
in talking bullshit.
They degenerate,
becoming more and more useless.
I'm sure they sometimes feel
uneasy about themselves.
They cry out things like
"Koreans are so prejudiced!"
But they are not logical
and don't know what's really good.
I can tell what they're imitating
with everything they say.
Anyway, all I can do is stay away
from them as far as possible.
Since I'm not sure
what they would do to me.
There are a lot of people like them
here in Paris.
September 8
We visited the studios
where many Korean artists work.
Mr. Jang said that he knows
a famous Korean painting there.
Hello.
The atelier is here.
The hallway is narrow.
First, we met the painter
Hyun-ju knows.
I recently read a book called,
"The Glory of Van Gogh. "
According to the book,
Van Gogh was already known by some.
He also had several exhibitions.
So we can say he was regarded
as a promising painter back then.
But he still cut his ear off.
He died in a mental hospital, right?
Yes, in a mental hospital.
Well, I think that it
actually could've been distorted.
The fact that he had a mental problem
doesn't mean that he became insane
to be an artist, right?
I mean, not everyone needs
to be insane to be a great artist.
Who knows.
It's hard to tell whether insanity
brings about great art,
or if great art
brings about insanity.
Gogh seems like a good person.
He is.
And great, too.
Indeed, he is.
But those images could've been
made up to serve the present's needs.
I think it's time we should
embrace these fabrications
and make use of them.
Who paints better
between you and your husband?
My husband is better.
I can agree to that.
The tea is very nice.
Can I hold your baby?
A friend brought the tea from China.
Oh, really?
He's so cute!
What's his name?
Alexandre.
He's beautiful.
You're the most beautiful thing
in the world.
Thank you.
Korean people here certainly put in
more effort than Europeans.
But we Koreans tend to step
on others to get ahead of them.
I think the natives here
are different in that regards.
They seem to be
more innocent than us.
Considering the difference
in cultures or personalities.
Do you really think
they are that different from us?
Well, since I'm not an expert,
I can't tell you exactly.
But I think the education here
brings about those differences.
But your children
speak Korean perfectly, don't they?
Actually, I beat them if they don't.
That's good.
See you later.
See you soon.
Thank you for inviting us.
It was good meeting you.
Thank you.
Take care.
Shall we go?
Bye.
Do you know how expensive
his paintings are?
No, I don't.
His works are in such high demand.
He is the most popular
Korean painter here.
- Really?
- Yes.
What am I doing here?
He's working so hard
at his paintings every day.
September 10
We are going to Deauville for a day.
Did you find it, Yu-jeong?
Not yet.
Are you looking at the map or not?
I can't look at it,
so you have to at least!
You're driving me crazy!
I'm looking at it.
You can't even do that?
I'm driving, so you're the one
who has to find it.
Can you help me?
You're really unbelievable.
Are we that lost?
Yes, we are.
This is really bad.
I don't know where we are.
I'm so sorry
that I'm no help to you.
That's okay.
Now look at the map and find it!
Hyun-ju rented a car, but Yu-jeong
didn't even want to pay for the gas.
I told Hyun-ju that I'd pay for it
but she didn't take it.
What's wrong?
She's so stingy!
Have you ever been here?
Yes, very often,
when I feel to refresh myself.
So what did you do here?
I just walked around
and ate some oysters.
- I want to eat oysters.
- So do I.
- Do you want to go eat oysters?
- Yes.
Yu-jeong's gone too far.
What shall we do?
I have no idea what to do with her.
She's so selfish
that I can't forgive her.
She's cheap!
It's because you're on a trip.
People traveling tend to be
more sensitive about their own needs.
So they sometimes argue
and fight more.
She's so stingy, though.
I know.
Don't take it too hard.
You're both roommates anyway.
She's too different from us.
Yes, people are all different.
Don't mind her,
and just stay with me.
Yes, okay.
But I'll be back in a minute.
She went out too far.
Yu-jeong!
What are you doing here?
Nothing.
Don't you think that she
was so rude to me today?
She treated me like I'm some beggar.
She's such a nuthead.
I don't know what's in that head of hers.
Take it easy.
It's because you're on a trip.
People usually argue during trips.
Why do people argue when they travel?
Well, people get caught up
in their own feelings.
That's what I call a nuthead.
I bet she's one of the top ten
nutheads in Europe.
I'm very sure of it.
Okay, right.
Don't mind her,
and just stay with me.
How could I not mind?
This is all because of that nuthead.
I have to go to the restroom.
Can you wait for me here?
Sure, I'll just watch the sea.
Or shall I stay with Hyun-ju?
I'll be back in ten minutes,
so just stay here.
Okay.
I have to find my own way to survive.
I can't let these women depress me.
I wanted to gamble, but we couldn't
get in without a passport.
It's tough driving, isn't it?
No, apart from not knowing the roads,
I enjoy driving.
I'm a good driver, so don't worry.
Sure.
Hey, how about we eat oysters here?
You must love oysters.
Yes, I just thought
it would be good for us.
Next time.
She doesn't like oysters.
So I found...
Why don't I like oysters?
You like oysters?
You said you only like meat.
I said I liked meat.
I never said I didn't like oysters.
No, you don't like oysters.
I know for a fact.
You're so ridiculous.
Ridiculous?
Speak for yourself!
What's with you today?
Think about it.
What?
Not finding the way on the map?
Then tell me what I did wrong!
Forget about it.
Please stop.
You're both educated people.
Plus, we're on a trip, okay?
Okay, let's stop here.
Let's go.
Yes, let's go.
What are you doing?
September 12
Sorry, you can't pass this way.
We're shooting.
Mind turning back that way?
Otherwise, you'll have to wait here.
It's only for a moment.
Thank you.
How much is left?
Five minutes.
It feel from above.
September 21
Drinking coke?
Yes.
You're so pretty.
You look very pretty today.
Thank you.
Why didn't you shave?
Are you trying to be stylish?
Well, no need to worry about that.
I don't have to speak
formally to you, right?
What?
What do you mean?
Did I do anything wrong to you?
No, it's not that.
I'm older than you,
so talking formally makes it awkward.
Me talking casually to you
isn't going to hurt, you know.
Why are you being so rude?
Because I want to, you little brat.
This is absurd.
What?
I can sit, right?
Yes, you can,
but don't talk to me like that.
Will you be nice to me
if I talk formally?
Don't kid me around.
Are you crazy?
Yes, I am.
Want a drink, little girl?
I don't drink during the daytime.
I see.
I don't drink much anyway.
How about a drink anyway?
What's wrong with you?
No, well...
I want to sleep with you.
You want to sleep with me?
Well, I see you in my dreams
every night.
I can't believe this.
No one has ever talk to me
like this before.
Don't act like a kid, you little brat.
You better watch your mouth.
No, what I said was wrong.
I was wrong.
Please sit down.
Yes, what you said was wrong.
I don't want to toy with you.
Just that you're so attractive.
Can't you try to understand me?
Are you that busy?
Do you want to drink?
I talk rudely, don't I?
Yeah.
But slightly fun.
Oh, yeah?
Now I can see who you truly are.
Really?
So do you still want to drink?
Of course.
I'll treat. Go ahead.
You should since you're much older.
You're such a little brat.
The clouds here hang very low.
Where did they get all these stones?
Is there a quarry near here?
I don't know.
I think we've walked for miles.
My legs are swelling up.
I think I like legs like yours
more than thin ones.
They're very pretty
and so are your feet.
Thank you, but can you let go now?
Why? Worried people will see?
Yes, there are too many Koreans here.
I feel awkward about us.
Hey, I've been there.
Isn't that the Orsay Museum?
Yes, the sandwiches sold
on the roof cafe is so delicious.
Is that right?
Who did you go with?
Hyun-ju took me there
when I first saw her.
Oh, with Hyun-ju.
The day Mr. Jang from the guesthouse
introduced me to her.
We saw only Courbet's works.
Which one?
I like "The Stone-Breakers,"
but it wasn't there.
I know that painting.
But I haven't actually seen it.
They must've been rich for ages
having brought all these stones here.
Do you want to hear
what Hyun-ju told me?
What's so funny?
We were drinking
and she suddenly said,
"I want to date him
while he's staying in Paris. "
She did?
Yes!
That's so funny.
So when are you leaving for Seoul?
I don't know.
You just tell me when.
What are you doing?
I'm so drunk.
You must be really tired.
What shall we do?
Can I lie on your lap?
You're cold, aren't you?
I don't have anything
to cover you with.
That's okay.
Do you feel like vomiting?
I'll be fine if I don't move.
I feel terrible.
So do I.
We walked and drank too much.
Stay here just for a minute
and go home to rest, okay?
I'm fine.
September 23
Oh no, is it serious?
No, I just walked too much.
And I just feel cold.
You should take care of your body.
But keep going out
to those nice places.
It'll be good for you.
Don't stay inside all the time.
I know.
While sitting at a park bench
a French guy on a bike passed by.
He was riding under the sunset.
I suddenly felt so envious of him.
I bet he has a house
a job, friends, a car.
Or maybe just a bike.
Anyway, I even envied
an ordinary guy like him.
He seemed to be so settled here.
Everything here seemed
to belong to him.
I'm sorry, Sung-nam.
I've been busy thinking about
other things instead of you.
I've been shopping alone
and watching TV.
I'm so sorry.
That's okay. Don't cry.
September 24
The line is good, as you know.
So I think you could do anything.
Your choice of subject matter
is excellent.
You're not imitating some art works
that moved you.
But you rather get ideas
from your real, everyday life.
You also have the strength
to finish a work.
I think you're truly talented.
But people don't know that.
That's the problem.
No, just keep going.
A lot of people with no talent
are persistent to the end.
And they occupy all positions,
screwing up the world.
Those kinds of people
can only repeat clichs.
Eventually those clichs
become poisonous to people.
People like you need to survive.
I usually don't like to say this,
but I think you're very talented.
You can trust me on that.
Thanks, you're very encouraging.
Really?
Wait.
Stop, you're married.
Right.
I'm sorry.
I've been through this before.
It's a waste.
You're right.
I know.
Please stop this.
I know this feels good
but please let's stop.
I don't want to, okay?
I'll hold back.
Why don't you have a smoke?
You may smoke in here.
Okay.
Thanks for the kiss, anyway.
I won't forget it.
It was so beautiful.
Tell me about the paintings.
I like to hear those things.
About my painting?
Yours? Mine?
About yours.
I've painted for a long time,
but people don't seem to like them.
Really?
I'm holding back well, aren't I?
Of course, you have no choice.
Since I don't want to.
You little brat.
I must be crazy, crazy, crazy...
September 26
Oh, you've done a lot as an artist.
Do you have a working permit?
No, I don't.
You can't work if you don't have one.
Immigration laws got stricter,
so we can't hire non-permit holders.
But I heard that people work nights
since they don't inspect at night.
I'm not going to take any risks.
Sir, I'm desperate for money.
I understand
the hard circumstance you're in.
Then how about working for movers
or being a janitor?
I can introduce you to some people
I know if you want.
Oh, thank you.
Then leave your resume with me
and I'll call you.
Thank you so much.
I returned to the restaurant
and took my resume back.
I hated that my resume was
in his hands.
October 1
Mr. Jang invited me to join
a party his friend is having.
Excuse me, whose painting is that?
Oh, it's my cousin's.
Really?
Yes, why are you surprised?
Oh, I'm not surprised.
Who is your cousin?
That girl from Seoul
you saw just a minute ago.
Oh, the student who just arrived?
Is this her work?
Yes, it is.
Oh, so she's a painter.
Yes, she just entered
the Beaux-Arts school.
Ah, the Beaux-Arts.
It's a very good school.
Yes, they say it is.
Hello.
I heard you go to Beaux-Arts.
Yes, how did you know that?
Your cousin told me.
You're a painter, right?
I saw the picture on the wall.
What's it about?
It's nothing special.
It looks like some character.
Yes, you're right.
I've been preparing now
for some time.
It's for a large picture
called "The House on the Sand. "
Oh, "The House on the Sand. "
Yes, there will be
many characters in it.
I see.
Do you know Yu-jeong?
Yu-jeong?
Lee Yu-jeong?
Yes, that's right.
I know her.
How do you know her?
We went to the same school in Korea.
I heard that she goes
to Beaux-Arts, too.
Yes, but she just quit school
because of some trouble.
When?
The beginning of last semester,
I think.
I see.
I don't like to say stuff like this,
but she plagiarized my paintings
onto her portfolio.
Really?
After I got into Beaux-Arts,
I got called into the dean's office.
Then I saw her portfolio there
which looked identical to mine.
I see.
You must've been surprised.
No, I was angry with her.
We knew she wasn't a good painter
back in Korea.
Actually, we all ignored her.
One day I called her
to talk about what happened.
She begged me to keep it a secret.
She looked so pathetic.
I see.
The school became suspicious
of all Korean students because of her.
I understand.
I didn't by anything.
They're going to get mad at me.
It's okay. I bought two bottles.
They're going to get upset.
Ji-hye,
you're not asking a question?
Then I'll do it.
Come on.
Who do you think
is the manliest here?
Okay! Scan!
Isn't it too easy?
Why?
You're too handsome.
She's so funny.
Let me give you a drink.
What's so funny?
It sounds much better than ugly.
Excuse me, but are you from Yanbian?
No, I'm Yoon Gyoung-su,
a student from North Korea.
You're from North Korea?
Yes, I'm from Pyongyang.
Then you should've told me
that before.
Well, I'm telling you now.
I was wondering about your accent.
Now can we continue the game?
Who do you think is the manliest?
Scan...
Sorry, I have one more question.
To me?
What do you think of Kim Il-sung?
Pardon?
You should speak more politely.
Do you call out
your grandfather's name like that?
Then how should I call him?
Should I call him
by General or something?
Hey, he is our great father,
so you should at least be respectful.
Is Kim Il-sung that great? Is he?
This is absurd.
Okay, we better stop here.
Mr. Jang, I have to leave.
I will see you later.
He's such a bourgeois.
Why don't you have a drink?
Don't get mad.
Where were we?
I met a North Korean.
What should I do?
Do I have to give myself in?
Or call the embassy?
October 3
I don't believe this.
Min-sun seems to have
committed suicide.
The paper says
that it was a 'Mrs. Jang. '
It says she has a French husband
who is a folklorist.
The dead woman is a painter.
It's definitely Min-sun.
Painter Mrs. Jang Commits Suicide
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be sorry to me.
We all understand you.
Is there any problem at home?
Sir, I've done wrong.
I've looked down on people so much.
Everybody does in their lifetime.
Nothing good can come from it, right?
Sir, I've been so bad.
I pretended to be strong
since I was afraid.
And I treated everyone in contempt.
Anyway, I'm glad that you're crying.
It means that you're getting better.
I'm so sorry.
I'll be nice to people.
Yes, we are all the same.
Try to cheer yourself up.
Hyun-ju is inside.
Why are you here?
I just came by to see you.
I'm on my way out.
You are?
Let's go out together.
A cup of coffee on the way?
Sure.
Let's go.
Did you cry today?
No.
I want to lie with you in my arms.
You need to be slapped on the cheek.
Go ahead.
Are you sure?
Yeah, go ahead.
Okay, then.
Don't be like this.
You don't have to pretend with me.
Slap me.
This isn't working.
I really want to lie with you today.
Why?
I love you.
Really?
Yu-jeong.
What?
Want to go to Deauville with me?
Yeah, I do.
When?
What about today?
I can't today.
Really?
The day after tomorrow.
Are you serious?
Look in my eyes.
Okay, I got it.
October 5
- Is this it?
- Yes.
Hello, are you cleaning up?
I wish I could help you.
- Good-bye.
Her perfume is too strong.
October 6
Doesn't that look like candy?
Why is it there?
I don't know.
It's hard walking on the sand.
Your legs hurt?
Shall I lift you up?
No, thanks.
I'll lift you up.
I'm okay.
Feel comfortable?
But you don't look comfortable.
I'm so happy to be with you.
Why?
What makes you so happy?
Because you're so pretty.
Very, very pretty.
You're a real man.
I am?
Take this for a second.
How'd we win so much money?
I can't believe this.
We really won a lot, didn't we?
Yes, I've never seen anyone
win so much money like this.
Really?
How much did we win?
About 900 euros?
No, not 900.
A little more than 800.
Wow, that's great!
We're rich.
Do you want half of this?
Are you sure?
You'll really give me half?
Why not?
Thank you!
One sec.
Let me count it first.
One, two, three.
What should I do with this?
Whatever you want.
Thank you.
Me, too.
We devoured oysters
with the money we won.
I can't have sex today.
Why not?
Today is risky.
Are you sure?
I see.
But it's still okay.
It's not okay!
Today is really risky.
This is torture.
So what do we do?
Don't you have any condoms?
Condoms?
No.
No?
Do you really need it?
Yes, I told you that today
is really risky.
What shall we do?
Why don't you go buy condoms?
Let's just do it.
This is our first time together.
Don't talk nonsense.
Hurry and go get some condoms.
Where can I buy them?
Can't we just do it without it?
Can't you do that at least?
Put in the effort.
Go get some, now!
Go! Go! Go!
Do something!
I'll be back.
I found a drugstore
but I couldn't buy any condoms.
I don't speak any French
and there were too many women.
Yu-jeong, are you sleeping?
No.
Can't we just hug?
But hugging is so nice
and comfortable.
I know.
Do you really want to just hug?
Yu-jeong.
What?
I love you.
I want to suck your whole body.
I want to suck every single part.
I mean it.
Why are you nice to me like this?
Why are you so nice to me?
It was nothing much...
I love you.
I love you, too.
Thank you.
October 9
What are you going to do today?
Today?
I have no idea.
I'll just wait for you
till you come back.
Wait.
I've made up my mind now.
For what?
I will love you as much as I want.
Really?
I will too.
What you've been doing to me
is so touching.
But sometimes I can't trust you
and it's hard on me.
I'm tired of not being decisive
about my feelings.
So I really made up my mind
to love you.
I will love you as long as I can.
Feel burdened?
No.
You're very, very pretty.
I don't know who I am.
Me neither.
But I know my feelings
have become clear.
And it's enough to encourage me.
Okay, I'll be brave too.
I trust you.
And everything you said to me.
I don't know anything.
The more I see you,
the more I love you.
I just feel like you're on my side
and you're so pure.
Thank you for loving me.
See you after school.
I'll be waiting.
I'll be back as soon as possible.
Okay.
Hello.
Oh, how are you?
I'm sorry for what I did last time.
Well, we both got too emotional
to think reasonably then.
I thought you could be that way
since youre an artist.
I'm sorry.
Anyway, do you really hate me?
Take it easy.
- We great up in different societies.
- I'm not talking about that.
Do you really hate me that much?
I was wondering.
I have no reason to hate you.
I don't know much about you.
It's because I wasn't brave.
Okay, I understand.
How about a cup of coffee?
Sure.
How about arm-wrestling with me?
- Arm wrestling?
- Yes.
I don't think I can beat you.
Let's try. It would be fun.
What do you mean by fun?
We can touch hands.
I just want to arm wrestle.
Okay, why not?
Let's give it a try.
This is no match of any kind.
I'm just glad to meet you.
You trust me, right?
What's there to trust?
We're just playing.
Playing?
I'll count to three.
One, two, three!
Wow, you're very strong.
You're pretty strong, too.
Anyway, did we have to do this?
It's just for fun
but did I upset you?
No, not at all.
What about the left hand?
Left hand?
Sure.
Here we go.
I'll count to three.
One, two, three.
Are you okay?
Hello.
- What's wrong with your eyes?
- A bug flew into it.
You should wash it out with tears.
I've already shed lots of tears.
Then it will come out soon.
Oh, your wife called you from Seoul.
She wanted you to call her back.
Oh, yes.
Why did she call?
Okay, thank you.
It's because of the bug.
- It'll come out.
- Okay.
- Hello?
- It's me.
Did you call?
Yes, hours ago.
- Are you all right, honey?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Anything wrong?
Hello?
Sung-in!
Can I be pregnant?
What are you talking about?
What shall I do?
But I can't go there now.
You're pregnant?
Yes, it's been two months already.
I found out yesterday.
The doctor told me.
Is it true?
Of course, why would I lie?
Hold on.
Okay.
Hello?
Yes, I'm here.
Look, don't worry.
It's already been two months.
It was probably when we had sex
before you left.
I'll leave here tomorrow.
What?
I'll try to get the first ticket
out of here tomorrow.
- Really?
- Yes, I will.
What about the police?
What will you do?
- What about airport inspection?
- Don't worry.
I have to go no matter what.
You're having a baby.
Is it going to be all right?
I'll do whatever it takes to go.
Stop crying, honey.
I'm not.
October 10
You're exercising?
No, I got this pain in my waist.
- Your waist hurts?
- Yeah.
What kind of exercise is that?
I made it on my own.
It's good for the waist and legs.
I see.
I might be pregnant.
Who says?
I saw the doctor for the pill.
He said that it could be
less effective after 24 hours.
That day was so risky
and I might've taken it too late.
But you took the pill, right?
It could be dangerous
since I took it a day late.
So what do we do?
The only thing we can do is wait.
Anyway, I'm relieved you're smiling.
You're 'relieved'?
What'll we do if I'm pregnant?
I should have
controlled myself.
It's not your fault.
I see.
I have to go to the washroom.
Fortunately, it's not cold.
I'm cold.
Do you have a headache?
Yeah, a little.
I have some medicine at home.
I'm fine. Thanks.
You don't have to go to the airport.
I want to go.
Let me go there with you.
But you have to come back.
Are you grateful?
How bad is your mother?
I have to go and find out.
I have to look into things
for her hospitalization.
She collapsed
so it could be serious.
You must be very worried.
Aren't you?
I'll remember everything.
What?
Everything we've done together.
I must be really unlucky.
What do you mean by that?
I think that's just who I am.
Please stop it.
What time is it?
I have to leave in thirty minutes.
I'm sorry.
You're going through more than me.
What I did was foolish.
Wait a minute.
October 12
Sung-in, how could you?
What?
How could you lie so well like that?
I can't believe this.
I really believed you.
Yeah, it was really smart of me.
I totally tricked you, didn't I?
You absolutely did.
At first,
I had no intention to do that.
But I suddenly felt that
I had to bring you back.
You were too scared
to come back on your own.
So when I got your call
the idea just hit me.
The strange thing was
that I was lying so easily.
Isn't that funny?
How could you lie to me
that you were pregnant?
You cried for real, too.
I was really sad.
I felt sad about our circumstances.
I think you bring good luck.
The police treated you nice.
They were kind, weren't they?
Come on, don't worry.
All you'll get
is a short detention or fine.
I believe what they said, don't you?
- Yeah, I hope it turns out okay.
- You said that's what he told you.
But we should wait till tomorrow.
We'll know then.
Get a hair cut
before you go to the police station.
Okay, I'll shave and clean myself up.
I'm going to iron your shirt,
so put it on tomorrow.
Okay.
When is Mom coming?
I don't know.
She seems to be late.
Okay.
Come here.
Why?
Let's go inside
so we can be together.
Okay, wait a second.
- After I go to the washroom.
- Okay, hurry back.
I wanted to make love to you so much.
I wanted to as well.
You smell good.
I haven't showered yet.
Is that okay?
Sure, I like it so much.
I love you.
You're my angel.
I love everything about you.
Every single thing.
You're so beautiful.
I'll be nice to you.
Believe me I will.
I love you.
I wish we would have a baby today.
I'm sorry for lying.
That's okay.
I'll do my best for us.
You're so precious to me,
so I promise to do my best.
You're a wonderful man.
I have nobody but you.
All I think about is you.
If you don't believe that,
I'll go nuts.
Is that right?
I love you, Sung-nam.
I love you, too.
I love you very, very much.
The kimchi soup smells so good.
It's done, so come and eat.
Okay.
Come closer.
If we're understanding,
we can overcome anything.
It's only us and the world.
Aren't you eating?
Go ahead.
I don't feel like eating breakfast.
Is it good?
I'll tell you after I try it.
It's good.
Really? I didn't even taste it.
Wow, it's really good.
I better eat some, too.
- Yeah, eat.
- No, you go ahead first.
By the way, I'm getting a perm.
My long hair feels uncomfortable.
Can I, huh?
Why do you always talk
about your hair?
Don't lay a hand on your hair.
Don't touch it until you die,
understand?
You never let me do my hair.
Just eat.
Ji-hye, come here.
Why?
Sit down.
I'm going to ask you something,
so be honest.
Can you go see her with me?
Who?
Sung-in, my ex-wife.
Why?
She's sick.
And she can't stand
living alone sick.
She called me.
Okay.
Are you sure?
Ji-hye, what's important
is how you feel.
Okay, I'd like to see her
for old times' sake.
Are you going today?
Today? Today will be better.
Okay then, let's go today.
Where are you going?
To the public bath.
But do you really want to?
It's not that I want to.
I just feel that the time has come.
Okay.
Ji-hye.
Yes?
I was thinking about giving her this.
That?
Yeah, she'll like it.
Of course she will.
It's a good one.
Ji-hye.
I love you.
I know.
Oh no!
What are you doing?
It's broken, honey.
What shall we do?
Damn it! Back off!
I'm sorry.
It just feel by itself.
I didn't drop it.
How could it fall by itself?
I really didn't do it.
- You did it on purpose, didn't you?
- I'm sorry. I don't know what to do.
It's broken into big pieces,
so let's try to fix it.
Don't touch it!
Just leave it!
Sung-nam, but we have to go.
She's waiting for us.
Let's just get her
something else next time.
Come on, let's go.
Why do you keep clinging on to me?
Who are you to screw this up?
Who the hell do you think you are?
Sung-nam, what's wrong?
Shut up, damn it!
You crazy bitch!
I hate you!
Stop it, please.
This is all because of one porcelain?
What's the matter with you?
You're so ridiculous!
You're such a bitch!
A worthless bitch!
Get the hell away from me!
Just leave it, damn it!
Come back here!
Come back!
Ji-hye!
Wake up, Sung-nam.
Wake up.
What's wrong?
Come on! Wake up!
What's the matter?
Who is she?
What are you talking about?
Who are you calling out?
Who is she?
I can't believe what I heard.
What was your dream about?
Did I do that in my dream?
That's strange.
What are you hiding from me?
I wish I hadn't known.
I bet you had a hard time
deceiving me.
Who is she? Tell me!
How should I know?
It happened in my dream.
Dream or not,
it still upsets me!
And it wasn't just a dream!
You're right.
It would make you upset.
You're not some sex-addict, are you?
I'm sorry for having a weird dream.
But it was only a dream.
It wasn't just a dream!
Was it a dream?
Sure, it was a dream.
- Are you sure it was a silly dream?
- Yes, it was. I'm sure of it.
Come on.
Get some sleep.
I don't feel like sleeping.
Then let me hug you for a minute.
Okay.
I swear that I'll be good to you.
I love you.
Never leave me alone again.
And don't have a silly dream again.
It upsets me a lot.
I promise that I won't go anywhere.
Don't leave me alone.
I promise.
I'm sorry.
That's okay.