Not again!
Stop taking pictures of your
pretty mom like a paparazzi.
Blame it on your beauty, mom.
I know, but...
I'm starving.
- Say, "please."
- Please, Mom. $10?
Am I your bank, kiddo?
I'll be late today.
Buy yourself dinner with this.
Again?
To prepare for the housing exams.
I'm sleepy already.
Are you Jealous?
You like him that much?
You said he was so-so.
Is love a guy's dick
turning big or small?
Jeez, Mom...!
Hey, JuJu! Let's go.
Hey, Gigi!
Didn't I tell you to stop calling
my precious son 'JuJu'?
Ditto that.
But you keep calling me Gigi.
"Gigi" and Guitar, big difference!
I can call him whatever I like.
What? Stay right there.
I'm going after you!
See you later, Mom!
I'll let you go today, cutie.
Thank you, ma'am.
See you later, Mom!
Eat properly!
Don't eat ramen noodles!
Wait for me!
I'll go nuts.
- Mama says report.
- Wow, scary.
Damn.
How will I survive
the next semester?
- Won't there be a war?
- One's in my stomach.
How about ramen noodles?
Fish balls, 70, topokki, 280,
dumplings, 400.
And ramen is 800 kcal,
you kind bastard.
And why'd I eat ramen with you?
How about a tteok ramen then?
The break is almost over.
Will you...
come to school?
Your phone number's...
changed.
Tteok ramen, please.
No, dumpling ramen.
- Stop hogging chocolates, Porky.
- Stop that, JuJu!
The meaning in this sentence is...
I talk, you sleep.
You're in class, huh?
At least have your books open.
Saved by the bell.
Don't get all excited
cuz it's new semester.
One-on-one about your scores
start next week.
Be prepared.
Why is the student director
so into that?
Will this really help sexually?
- Heard he takes eel extracts, too.
- Really?
It only gives me cramps.
Guys would think
you don't have lunch money.
Get lost. I'm on a diet.
Like hell you'll lose weight.
Reading that again?
Boring bastards like you
wouldn't know the world of otaku.
The final episode is out next week.
I need to read it over again
10 times until then.
That fun?
Like hell.
Gaia, the main character,
completely lost control.
She's about to wipe them out.
Cheap bastard!
Wanna go to the Silkworm Isle
even if it's Just us?
No one within 300m as usual.
See?
Just us two from my school
and yours.
Who would dare to turn on
the gay app at school?
We met through this, remember?
I've kept it on for 6 months,
and there's Just us.
There might be more.
Who else is there?
It's Just us.
Know what?
They say when you lie,
your nose gets warm.
You have a crush
on someone, right?
Get lost.
Go and study.
Smoking insolently
in front of a senior.
You're only a year older.
Move, you asshole.
Here! Quick, fuck!
- Hey! Hey!
- Buzz off!
You fucking bastard!
Stop right there!
Hey!
Stop!
Get him!
Hurry up!
Han Gi-woong!
Where the hell did he go?
Come out, you shit!
Hey!
Han Gi-woong!
Where are you hiding like a rat?
Come on out!
Come out!
Give it back.
I'll shout.
Damn you freaking shit.
Damn thief.
Does it hurt?
Hurts, huh?
You took it,
but I'm taking it back.
Gi-woong!
Han Gi-woong!
Where is it?
Where is it, I say!
Give me my bike or I'll report
this hires minors.
What did you Just say, asshole?
You little!
I'll get going.
Hey, you shithead!
Who's that small fry?
You prick!
Told you not to smoke
in front of the shop.
He's not at the
cheap dorms, either?
Ow, that stings.
Freaking mosquitos.
See you later, boss.
Take your flip-flop,
you idiots.
Yes, sir!
Why are you looking for him?
Said he was released 3 months ago.
Just...
Just, my ass.
It's all out of your wage.
Who the hell is he?
You nailed lip bastard.
Just wait a few more days.
Fuck, get the phone!
I made breakfast,
so eat before you go.
You should attend school.
We're moving next month.
These idiots tried to lynch
Gi-woong on Saturday.
Heard one of them went to ER
scalded by ramen.
If I had my hands
on those shitheads.
Stupid assholes,
bandaged like a freaking mummy.
Hey, punching machine!
Guten Morgen!
Good morning!
Good morning, you shit.
Good morning.
Wanna smoke?
You paid for it.
Then again, you shouldn't.
We don't want you broken.
You know, Yong-Ju here
was looking around for you.
Yeah, I sold off his bike.
What? He had an expensive one.
How much did you get?
Wash it clean, you bastard!
Wasn't Gi-woong...
Just a dickhead in Junior high?
His dad...
You know what they mean by
a punching machine?
How the fuck would I know?
Hey, Yong-Ju!
Answer your goddamn phone!
One-on-one! It's your turn.
Yong-Ju.
You're in grade tier 1, but your
recent scores are a bit risky.
You know we're creating an
honors class next week, right?
To focus on English and Math,
so let's raise your scores a bit.
Sir.
Why? You have something
to say?
Haven't had lunch?
A friend is...
being bullied.
There's no time for friends now.
Just study.
Get back.
Why are you taking pictures?
Did I mention that this
used to be a gay bar?
It got reported coz it's
near a school.
Why did they build it in
such a high place?
Have you...
met a straight before?
Why?
Just curious...
How would the bitches know
if they are straight?
Coz they have girlfriends.
How would they know until
they've slept with me?
Do they know how I taste?
A taste of me?
So, there really is someone...
Did you confess?
Don't ever confess if he'd puke.
Having crushes on a straight is
Iike taking rat poison.
Get it?
You know how much it was?
It was $225 with VAT..
Shit, you know your IQ drops
when you get hit?
Goes down by 1.6!
And adolescence is an important time.
It's Just you now.
I'm not scared.
Give it!
Hey! Give it!
Give me my bike back.
Or I'll report you're working against
the Juvenile Protection law.
I know your phone number now.
Give it back!
I will not go
until you return it.
Hey!
And give me 50 cents.
You haven't paid back.
Did you...
really sell it?
Did you sell it off?
The place looks expensive.
Did you really sell it here?
Isn't this it?
No.
Fuck, choose whatever!
Who's there?
Stop there!
Who is it?
Wait for me!
You look old now.
You didn't smoke in Junior high.
Still make gliders?
Was it summer?
You borrowed 50 cents from me
to buy glue for its wings.
Said you'd pay back
after the mid-terms.
You have a cut on your arm...
From the bike shop, I guess.
What?
Wait up!
What about my bike?
Be responsible.
We didn't get to steal one.
Why do you keep following me?
You stole my bike.
No... why do you keep
sneaking at me?
Since Junior high,
why do you keep
sneaking at me?
Don't tell... anyone.
Get up when I ask you nicely.
Can I take a day off?
I'm sick.
No, you're not.
You were like this yesterday!
Get up.
Get up!
Are you becoming defiant
coz of me?
What now?
Are you Jealous of the man
I'm seeing?
It's not even the first time.
Did you know that IQ drops
when you get hit?
- And where is your bike?
- Lent it to Gi-taek.
You lend it out for 2 weeks,
while you walk?
Told you, it broke.
My God!
Is this like a voodoo thing?
It must hurt.
Is this from school violence
on TV these days?
It's not!
Then why are you like this?
Hardly talking...
Just leave me alone!
Acting like a refugee in winter!
Your kid is your worst enemy.
Hey, refugee!
He bought it for you.
It's brand-new.
Hey, kiddo!
Aren't you gonna wish me luck
for my exam today?
You kind bastard!
Come grab some cake later.
Social mobility means individuals
or groups in social position...
Minus 2 points, you shit.
In lightspeed, huh?
To minus infinity and beyond?
Look at this bastard...!
Get out! Get out!
Get out of my class!
Get your ass in the teachers' room
after class!
Just because of the fuss on
Student Rights Ordinance,
you all think I won't hit you?
What are human
rights to students?
Isn't studying what matters?
I'll say this again.
Students in grade tiers 1-3
will end up ordering chicken,
Repeat after me! Order...!
Order!
Those in tiers 4-6...
...will fry the chicken!
Those in tiers 7-9...
...will deliver the chicken!
Your scores went up, didn't it?
Shit, mine went
down by 5 points.
Don't hang around with that
fat bitch friend of yours.
You show your weakness at school
and you're dead.
He's not on our level.
And don't mess with Gi-woong, either.
You'll get hurt.
You won't find that bike.
What if I do?
I'll piggyback you every day,
fucking bastard.
Guess you don't know shit
about Gi-woong...
Man, you OK?
Fuck, the student director
going berserk in the morning.
The son of a bitch!
Must be true he can't
get his dick up.
He was doing this shit again.
Always sucking on eel extracts.
I saw him piss in the bathroom.
His dick is this small.
Thought it was a mosquito dick.
Come here.
Run over,
you freaking bastard.
You asshole, I told you not to wear
high heeled shoes.
Hey, want a cig?
No.
Fuck you, god damn
punching machine, try one.
Just get lost, dickhead.
Who's a dickhead?
Crazy bastard!
Just fuck off.
Who cried in the schoolyard?
Shut up!
Get out, you assholes!
Gi-taek!
- Gi-taek!
- Get out!
Get that camera!
Gi-taek!
Shut the door.
Shut the door, I say!
See Seong-Jin's mom
herding others like a pig?
They call her, "Pig Mom."
Teachers and parents obey her coz
she has connections to elite universities.
Gi-taek is the victim since
everyone will Just cover this up.
Even his own mom.
Seong-Jin will probably Just get
community service again.
Damn bastard! How many points?
75 points.
What? You can't feel
the impact coz of the fat?
Shit. I'll tell Grandma on you...!
What's my score?
85 points.
Fuck.
Only 85 points? It won't get
Seong-Jin in Seoul University.
You bastard, I need 95 to be
in grade tier 1.
Let's send Seong-Jin
to college, you bastard.
These Jerks don't remember
unless it hurts.
He needs more beating.
How dare you rat on me.
How many points?
What's he doing here?
- Hey, you!
- Who told you to come here?
What are you doing here?
Freaking bastard, you wanna die?
Let go!
You think you're something, huh?
Leave him alone.
Told you not to
hang around here!
You want to be the
punching machine too?
Shut up and get lost, all of you!
Can't hear me?
Fuck, get out, everyone!
Let's go.
Hit me!
Hit me with this.
I'll give you 100 points.
Hit me with the real thing!
We're... friends, aren't we?
- Remember we used to...
- Shut up!
The kid who died last year...
Before Jumping off the roof,
he was in the elevator like this.
I told mom about him,
and you know what she said?
"Did he get good grades? "
The final episode of Gaia.
It wasn't a happy ending.
The main character dies like a fool.
If the world is this shitty,
shouldn't the ending be happy?
What have we done so wrong...
that we can't even laugh at the end?
It means at least we should laugh
because the world is shitty.
Bad guys don't laugh.
So we should.
Shouldn't we, fatso?
Stop crying.
Stop.
It's alright.
!
Hush!
Did you call the boys?
It's another kid from Ilsin High.
The kid we've been asked to
protect is Gyeong-sik.
His parents are
really concerned.
The police must be lousy
since we get all these Jobs.
Keep it as your wage, kid.
Right?
You'll find him soon,
since the boys are out searching.
Your life is pretty shitty, too.
See you, sir.
Talk to him nicely.
Smile.
Smile, you shit!
You need to keep that smile
on your ugly faces.
If you so much
as touch Gyeong-sik,
I'll kill you...
If you go near him,
I'll kill you.
If you report to the police.
I'll stab your mother.
Sophomore at Ilsin High.
Kim Jin-seok.
Don't pick on your friends...
- Aren't you going to answer me?
- Yes.
Let's never meet again...
Beat it!
Live right, you bastards.
See you tomorrow.
See ya.
You'll definitely pass.
I think I made it.
But Just barely.
Congratulations.
Delivery.
Delivery!
The money is inside.
Or you can go if you want.
Do you know
how late you are?
I should make a complaint.
My wallet's inside.
What a shitty service.
Is that how you're trained?
Eat.
I'll pay you then.
Eat up the crusts too.
I got your name...
back then.
I'm Shin Yong-Ju.
Han Gi-woong.
Don't know about the others,
but you don't scare me.
I still have this.
Don't worry.
Have them on digital files...
You like me?
Crazy bastard.
Don't you come near me.
I'll kill you.
Han Gi-woong.
Take this.
Just like old days.
Just like then.
Know what?
When Mongolians
like someone, they say,
"Let's go to the
mountain together."
And Eskimos say,
"Let's laugh together."
It's corny.
But, isn't it nice and short?
But then, you don't even know
how to smile.
Thanks...
for coming with me.
That girl...
is she your girlfriend?
Gi-woong!
Han Gi-woong!
Okay, I'll call you back.
I will!
Why are you so late?
Why didn't you turn on
the light?
- Don't turn it on.
- Why not?
Just leave it and get out!
Why are you yelling?
Your words
are thorny these days.
What is the matter with you?
Talk, for goodness' sake.
My situation is enough of
a thriller as it is.
Do you tell me everything?
You live the way you want.
What did I say?
You can live your life
the way you want it.
You must be going through
puberty again.
That's shitty.
Better than menopause.
What would you know...
You think flowers
only bloom in spring?
They bloom in autumn, too.
Han Gi-woong.
Absent again?
It's the fourth day already.
Class president.
Yes, sir.
Contact him. One more absence
and he's expelled.
Absence counts as 2 points.
Don't miss school.
Just bear it for 3 more months.
You all know about the honors class
that starts today, huh?
Those of you in the honors,
go to classroom 2.
It's based on your grades.
You think it's unfair?
Then study.
OK, get moving.
It's like an exodus.
Is this a wrecked ship?
- Aren't you going?
- I'm coming.
What are you doing here?
I'm busy. You go ahead.
He should help since he got me into
school service as punishment.
Hey, pick it up.
Pick it up, quick!
You do that on the next exams,
then you write your will that day.
You shithead! I fell one grade tier
because of you!
Must feel good
about your grades.
Have you grown taller too?
Where did you get your bike?
Was it Gi-woong?
Why should I tell you!
Aren't you going?
This is better...
It's not like that bastard will
die of stomach ulcers...
You go ahead.
What's with that Jerk now?
What's the matter?
Jeez!
You really wanna do it?
Told you not to take
rat poison.
Think I don't have any pride?
So, did the bastard...
puke when you confessed?
Don't do it
if you're not confident.
Watch out for rumors.
Am I some toy to you?
I'm transferring...
Mom says she'll die of shame.
Wants me to transfer far away.
My teacher ratted on me to Mom.
Damn.
I can't even take part
in the school festival now.
Then again, it's not the first time.
Huh?
The power's back.
So pretty...!
Been here for 3 months
and never seen it so lively.
NIGHT FLIGHT
Guess it'll be hard to visit here.
Hard to see you.
Wanna go... take a shit?
Let's Just go.
What if we get caught?
So what?
I'm through with this school now.
This will surprise them.
Homeroom teacher, the eunuch.
Have eunuch bastards for
generations to come.
You think... you're the
only one with a mouth?
Who's there!
Hey!
HERE TOO
- Stop right there!
- Don't follow.
Stop right there!
Run, honey!
Run like hell!
Run, run!
Be careful...
Right here.
Oh, my back...!
Haven't used it for too long.
See you over the break.
Jun-woo.
Song Jun-woo!
Don't you do it.
Don't you turn your back on me.
Was seen there yesterday.
But that's all.
Good luck.
My only weak point is,
I'm too soft.
Where are you off to now?
Wait for me.
Why? You're gonna run off again?
Fuck, what's the matter
with you these days?
Tell that small fry bastard,
that I'll kill him!
- Come. Let's go.
- Let go, let go.
Where the hell have you been?
The school will kick you out
if you don't come and write a pledge.
You know how much I looked for you?
You'll come to school, right?
I get nervous without you.
The bastards act up like shit.
Can't focus on my studies, either...
Who would I trust except you?
Am I your mom?
REHIRE LAID-OFF WORKERS
IMMEDIATELY
Where did Han Sang-gi go?
Where is he?
You must know, you were his friend.
Let go, damn.
You would know where he is!
I said, let go!
Why do you pretend you don't know.
He was your leader!
Where is he?!
Not talking?
I know he was here.
- Stop it!
- Don't pretend you don't know!
- We don't know, either!
- Bring him now!
- We can't do anything here!
- I'm not going, fuck!
Bring him here!
Bring him now!
Please calm down!
Bring back the son of a bitch!
Bring Han Sang-gi! Now!
Hey, Han Gi-woong!
Coming and going as you please.
Go see the student director
right now.
Now!
Shin Yong-Ju...
Yes, sir?
Write the pledge if you
don't want to be kicked out.
Am I a Joke to you?
I was in the Marine Corp.
Start writing!
Are you getting
fresh with me now?
Think I haven't seen
bastards like you before?
Why don't you Just drop out?
Instead of ruining the
academic atmosphere.
Mr. Yi, must be tough
with these idiots.
Come see me at the
teachers' office later.
Come here.
Sit down.
Don't you have
something to tell me?
You're wearing glasses, sir.
You feel like Joking at a
time like this?
This came from the other school.
The teachers'
office is in an uproar.
What are you going to do?
Are you...
a gay, too?
Just promise me one thing.
Get into Seoul University.
Nothing else matters.
Go back to class.
In extreme cases,
sexual assaults or murder.
They say they followed
what they saw on film or TV.
Who's fault is it?
Adolescents follow stars and trends.
Clothes, bags, shoes that stars wear
on TV become sold out.
Why are you still on page 69?
Everyone else is on page 70.
You like 69, don't you?
He watches porn every day.
"I'm coming! " "I'm coming! "
Be quiet!
Should you be watching porn
and Jerking off?
Just go to college.
Then no one will care
whatever you do.
Bastards.
You know what?
I heard a bastard at our school
is a homo...
Heard he's in this class.
Who is it?
How disgusting...!
Guess someone will end up
with a male daughter-in-law.
Cut the shit and Just
study hard, got it?
Yes, sir.
And go to church on weekends
and pray hard, got that?
Yes, sir.
Attention, salute the teacher.
Thank you, sir.
t's you right.
It's okay, you're my pal.
He's been fishy.
- Is it you?
- No, way!
- No!
Which bastard is it?
What if he has AIDS?
Run away with me.
I'm so scared.
Know where the southernmost
train station is?
It's Yeosu.
I thought it was Busan.
The last train leaves
at 8 o'clock.
They say if it leaves four trails...
it's an airliner.
If it leaves two,
it's a fighter Jet.
Damn, this is shitty.
Don't you...
get lonely?
Han Gi-woong!
Heard they'll tear down this place
next week.
Should we leave it on?
Turning your back to me
even to the end.
Go away.
What are you... to me?
Can't you...
Just smile for me?
So stupid.
Yeah.
So I'll never look at you again,
never call your name again,
never remember a bastard
like you,
not even for a second.
Guess I'll find someone again.
This world is over
without a friend.
Although you'll never know.
My son.
Who never answers
the goddamn phone.
Perhaps you might know
the taste of alcohol by now.
Is this our first time?
Did you fail the exam?
Kiddo, your mom's a genius.
You think I'd fail something like
the housing exams?
I passed the second round, too.
Then why are you drinking alone?
That's why I called you.
Another glass here, please.
Yes.
Is something wrong?
The hot news is, your mom's been
dumped again.
It's not the first time,
either, anyway!
Drink up, JuJu.
It's okay with your Mom.
Any bastard who says 'Love is...
two people standing side by side
Iooking in the same direction'
are all freaking crooks.
Then drivers rushing on the highway
all fall in love?
What a laugh.
Love is...
Iooking at different directions.
The bastard couldn't accept
this professional life of mine.
Is love a guy's dick?
Turning big or small?
Fuck.
Hey!
A glass here!
Mom.
What?
Do you know...
everything about me?
How would I know, you bastard.
Did you kill someone?
I've learned one thing,
by raising a son as
a single unwed mother at 26.
There's nothing stupid as
minding what the world thinks of you.
I got no end of scorn and temptation
for being a single mom, you know?
I only want you to live
without hurting other people.
Don't care about studies and all.
That's all I want.
Even if...
I'm different from other people?
Shin Yong-Ju!
Who gave birth to you?
Does that fact change,
even if you grow
goblin horns on your head?
When are you packing?
He's doing well?
What does it matter?
He can't come home because of
police surveillance.
Not embarrassed that labor union
bastards gave him the cold shoulder?
Criminal bastard.
You're here early.
Good morning.
Hi.
'Good Neighbor policy' was taken for
Southeast Asian countries.
Underline 'Good Neighbor policy'
it's frequently asked in the tests.
When Japanese pirates become rampant
at the end of Koryo until early Chosun,
Chosun reinforced its naval forces,
and built mass warships.
And the gunpowder weapons were
developed by...?
Choe Museon. How many times
did I tell you?
Hey, homo!
Where're you going?
I heard you're the gay king?
I really like gays, too.
Get out.
Get out!
Get lost. Fucking bastards!
Get out now,
before I bash your skulls!
I hear you're a pro
at this, Yong-Ju.
Suck mine, too.
You homo bastard!
Fuck.
It was like a hidden picture puzzle.
Wondered who it was...
in our class.
Does your grandma know, too?
Who says so?
This friend here...
No?
No... Jerks.
Where do you think you're going?
Suck mine, too,
you fucking bastard!
Stay still, you dirty asshole.
You like that?
Stay still.
Hey, get the fuck out.
Told you to stay still.
Heard Gi-taek
witnessed yesterday.
I wonder what this is.
You know what schwul
in German means?
Schwul.
Ho, mo, sex, ual.
I even like the sound of it.
Homo Schwul bastard.
Let him go.
Get up.
Yong-Ju.
Friends wouldn't spread rumors
or anything, right?
And...
Iower yourself a bit
when you talk to people.
Fucking bastard.
Because this is your eye level.
Hey, let's go.
See you tomorrow, homo.
You're the one
who betrayed first!
What betrayal?
Disgusting.
You and Gi-woong both!
Gi-taek!
Hey, Han Gi-woong!
Why so cold?
I'm beginning to forget your face.
Gi-taek's our friend now.
It's about time.
You and Yong-Ju aren't
like that, huh?
There's been such a rumor.
Our leader shouldn't be
like that, right?
Of course you aren't, right?
I have a question.
This guy set a factory on fire
and went to Jail several years ago.
Someone you know?
No, right?
Can't have the school look bad
with low-income classes.
Don't come near me!
It's your freaking dad!
You cried after getting beaten
by kids in Junior high.
Didn't you?
Teachers didn't like you either,
so they spread a rumor at school!
What did I do so wrong?
That you all bully me?
Do you deliver chicken, too?
Bring some here if you have time.
You're coming to school tomorrow?
Fuck, hit me!
Hit me, you son of a bitch!
You betrayed me first!
I was never... your friend.
Let go! Fuck...
Excuse me.
How did you find me?
Why did you come out?
To set this place on fire?
You know how
Mom and I've been living?
Why did you do it? Why?
You know how I've been living
all because of your high horse?
Damn, why did you do it?
You've grown a lot.
Should've bought a razor.
Gi-woong!
Han Gi-woong!
Fuck, let go!
I'm sorry.
Thought you were dead.
Don't die on us.
Nothing but a dickhead.
Out of my way!
Gi-woong, you okay?
Gi-woong.
Fuck off.
Gi-woong!
Han Gi-woong!
Aren't you packing?
We aren't moving anyway.
I made breakfast.
Let's eat.
Hey, stop right there!
Son of a bitch, stop!
Hey, stop right there bitch!
Come here.
Thanks for the damn
morning exercise.
Damn bitch,
think you can run away?
Seong-Jin!
- Come down you asshole.
- Let go!
Careful with that taser!
Didn't I tell you not to
challenge me?
Bring the bastard's camera!
Relax, you shit.
Gi-taek!
Shut up, you bitch.
Shoot it nice and quick.
I'll put it up on Youtube.
Like it?
Like it?!
Hey, you bitch!
Like it? Huh?
Han Gi-woong!
Yong-Ju...
Yong-Ju!
Shin Yong-Ju!
They even took the memory chip.
This cost $100 without VAT....
Don't you...
come near me, either.
Fuck off.
We'll learn about
radical root today.
First question. Sigma kay...
That bastard always comes
in the middle of class.
Take your seat now!
Sit down now!
Where is it?
- What is?
- Bastard, late and all...
Stop it!
Sit!
- Sit down!
- Where is it, bastard!
Stop it!
Let go, son of a bitch!
Give it back!
You shit!
Han Gi-woong!
You fucking bastard!
Where is it?
Where the hell is it!
I have nothing...
What's this?
What are you doing in
the honors class? Get out!
Give it back.
Give what?
Fuck, give it!
Get out you crazy shit!
You bastard!
Give it back,
you son of a bitch!
Fuck...!
Son of bitch...!
Fuck, give it back,
dammit!
Fuck!
Fucking bastard...
Think you can still run away?
Han Gi-woong!
Bastard!
What the hell are you doing?
Fuck!
Stop it!
Stop!
No!
Gi-woong!
Call an ambulance,
an ambulance!
Call an ambulance.
What are you going to do now?
Are you transferring?
Dropping out.
Why didn't you report earlier?
How would that help?
What is he doing?
Is he nuts or something?
- Must be crazy...
- Isn't he the one...?
You crazy bastard!
Get down now!
Hey! You son of a bitch!
Get down, get down!
Get down, I say!
Get down, you bastard!
What the hell are you doing
to the school building?
You wacko.
Erase it all before you go.
Crazy bastard.
Go up and erase it.
Erase it, hurry!
A GAY LIVES HERE TOO
Go bring a teacher.
Even if they settle...
you'd have to do time
for about 5 months.
I'm sorry.
For not coming sooner.
It's in my pants pocket.
Look it's so freaking gross.
I dropped out today.
I'm going to an alternative school
in the provinces.
It's a school in a mountain.
Gandhi School.
They have dorms...
Don't go.
It's so hard...
I think I'll break down.
- Never again...
- Never again.
Please...
I'm fucking lonely.