SUBTITLES BY LUIS-SUBS
(CHILDREN LAUGHING, SHOUTING)
(DOG BARKING)
Can you tell me if
Delmar Barry lives here?
Right up there.
Excuse me. Can you tell me,
is this where Delmar Barry lives?
He ain't here.
Go on inside, baby.
He's a friend of mine.
As a matter of fact,
he wrote this address down.
Right here.
There. As you can see,
that's Delmar's writing.
I sure had a hard time
finding this place.
That's his writing.
Like I said, he's a friend.
My name is John Rambo. We served
on the same team together in 'Nam.
I don't know if he ever
talked about me.
I've got a picture of
us together,
somewhere.
This junk in my pocket.
Here it is.
That's me.
That's Danforth and Westmore,
Bronson, Ortega, and there's
Delmar right in the back.
We had to put him in the back
'cause he's so big.
If we didn't,
he'd take up the whole picture.
Look how big he is.
Delmar's gone.
What time will he be back?
He died.
What?
He died last summer.
Died. How?
Cancer.
Brought it back from 'Nam.
All that orange stuff
they spreaded around.
Cut him down to nothing.
I could lift him off the sheet.
I'm very sorry.
Morning, Annie.
How you doing, girls?
Great. Thanks.
You all right this morning?
Andy!
Howdy, Will.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Morning, Dave.
Hi, Sheriff.
Gonna take a bath this week?
Morning.
You, uh, you visiting
somebody around here?
No.
You know, wearing that flag
on that jacket,
looking the way you do,
you're asking for trouble
around here, friend.
Headed north or south?
North.
Ah, jump in.
I'll make sure you're heading
the right direction, hmm?
Where you headed?
Portland.
Portland is south.
You said you were headed north.
You got someplace
I can eat around here?
There's a diner about 30
miles up the highway.
Is there any law against
me getting something here?
Yeah. Me.
Why are you pushing me?
What did you say?
I said, why are you pushing me?
I haven't done anything to you.
First of all, you don't ask
the questions around here, I do.
You understand?
Secondly,
(SIGHS)
we don't want guys
like you in this town.
Drifters.
First thing you know,
we got a whole bunch of guys like
you in this town. That's why.
Besides,
you wouldn't like it here.
This is, this is a quiet,
little town.
In fact,
you might say it's boring.
But that's the way we like it.
And I get paid
to keep it that way.
Boring.
Portland, straight ahead.
Now if you want
some friendly advice,
get a haircut and take a bath.
You wouldn't get
hassled so much.
Hope this ride helped you out.
You have a nice day, hmm?
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
Where the hell do you
think you're going?
Hey, I'm talking
to you, goddamn...
Let me see some I.D.
Damn it!
All right. You're under arrest.
You hear me?
Put your hands on the car.
Now you put your hands
on the car and you spread 'em.
Now you're gonna put your
hands on that car.
How you do it, you decide.
Right now!
Get your legs back.
Get 'em back!
You know, you try to be nice
to some people.
Well, what do
we have here, huh?
Why would you be carrying
a knife like this?
Hunting.
Don't be a wise guy.
What do you hunt with a knife?
Name it.
Hi, Will.
Lester.
Buzz us in, will ya?
Talk about your
sorry-looking humanity.
Just another
smart-ass drifter.
Good morning, Arthur.
Morning, Will.
What do ya got?
I want you to book this
gentleman for vagrancy,
resisting arrest,
carrying a concealed weapon.
He says he uses it for hunting.
Hunting? What do you hunt?
Elephants?
Why don't you see if you can
clean him up a little bit.
He smells like an animal.
Hey, Mitch? Mitch?
Yo.
Escort this young man
downstairs, would ya?
Yes, sir.
Right this way, partner.
Right here. That's it.
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
Okay.
Here we go.
You know, it looks like
it's going to take ol' Leroy...
about ten years
to paint this hall.
Why don't you paint it your damn self?
Leroy, sling that paint, boy
Mr. Ward?
Hm-mm?
Would you take this for me, please?
Thank you.
Yeah.
(KEYS CLACKING)
Name?
Your name?
(MEN SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
(YELLING)
Name?
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, if you're looking
for trouble,
you came to the right place,
buddy.
Wait a second.
Hey, you got three seconds
before I break your face in.
He means it.
Yeah. I do.
(CHUCKLES)
What do you know about that?
Ol' Harry here's a soldier.
"Rambo." John J.?
You gonna talk to me.
I promise you're gonna
talk to me, soldier.
I'm starting to dislike you...
...a lot!
I'm gonna run a make on him.
Put his name in the teletype.
Now just roll it across.
Roll it.
Roll it across.
Push it.
It won't work that way. It'll only smear.
Now roll it across!
Look, you son of a bitch,
if you don't put your
goddamn hand down there,
I'm going to break it off.
Now, put it down, goddamn it!
Art, what the hell
is going on down here?
Oh, nothing I can't handle.
He won't let us
print him, Will.
Leave the ink on the hand!
Just what is your problem, huh?
Now, listen, hard ass,
as things stand right now,
you're facing the ass end of a 90-day
incarceration, plus a $250 fine,
which you don't look to me
like you can pay.
At 10:00 tomorrow morning, you're
going up in front of that judge.
And you think we're tough.
Now we're going to make
you a little bit more presentable
for your courtroom appearance.
And between now and then, you can
just impress the hell out of me...
by doing exactly
as you're told.
Now clean him up.
ARTHUR:
All right, Preston,
I want you to go over there
and get that hose ready.
All right?
Holy shit!
Look at this.
What the hell's he been into?
Who gives a shit?
All right, put your hands on top
of your head and turn around.
Oh, Christ!
We should report this to Teasle, Galt.
Look at that.
You just do what I tell ya.
(GROANS)
Galt, what the fuck was that?
Well, the man said
clean 'em up.
(KICK)
(RAMBO GROANS)
Clean him up.
(LAUGHING)
Hey, Preston,
don't forget to get him
behind the ears!
How do you like that, huh?
What's the matter, Mitch?
Don't you like water sports?
Hurry it up.
It's time for my coffee break.
Sit down.
Easy. Sit down.
All right. Sit on the stool.
Come on.
Damn! Damn, this boy's
hard to get ahold of.
Ward, don't worry about
the soap. He's tough.
Just shave him, dry.
All right.
How blind are you?
Can't you see this guy's crazy?
Can't you see I don't give a shit?
Yeah, I can see that.
Good, that's better.
See there, I knew he knew
what was good for him.
MITCH:
Just gonna shave you, partner.
Take it easy.
Take this, Mitch.
(YELLING)
Don't move.
I don't want you
to cut your own throat.
(SCREAMS)
Hey! Hey!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
You son of a bitch!
Come on!
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(MUFFLED)
Get him off of me!
(GROANS)
What the hell is...
Art? Art?
(GROANS, GUNSHOT)
What was that?
(YELLS)
Hey, you can't...
(GROANS)
Hey, hey,
wait a minute...
(MOANING)
(GRUNTS)
Hey!
(MAN YELLING, HORNS HONKING)
I'm gonna get that son of a bitch!
Art, don't shoot!
(GUNSHOT)
Goddamn it! Don't shoot.
There's people down there.
Get help.
I'll go after him.
Move! Look out!
(SCREAMS)
Get out of the way!
(SIREN BLARING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Aaah!
(HORN HONKS)
Son of a bitch!
Lester, this is Will.
I'm right on his tail.
He's just east of Smith's farm,
headed towards Chapman Creek.
(SIREN BLARING)
(HORN BLARING)
(DISGUSTED GROAN)
(GROANS)
TEASLE:
I know you can hear me!
You're finished!
You've gone as far
as you're gonna go!
TEASLE:
You hear me?
(PANTING)
Mitch! Lester!
He's up there, beyond the draw.
Mitch, get Orval on the radio.
Tell him to get out here
with his damn dogs right away.
And tell him to bring
the Dobermans.
It's gonna rain. We'll need
dogs that can hunt on sight.
MITCH: Right!
Lester, tell Galt to get
out to the lumber camp.
Tell him to get the helicopter up here.
Right.
If they give him any shit,
tell him to cite them for
obstruction right on the spot!
We'll get him.
No problem.
MAN: Come on, Duke, Thunder.
Let's get him.
Come on, sweethearts.
That's it, babies.
Let's go get him!
We'll be done
in a couple of hours.
It won't be long before you have this
one stuffed and mounted, huh, Will?
Didn't we go deer hunting here last year?
Yeah. I got a couple bucks.
I'll shoot anything.
Hey, Mitch, up the hill.
(DOGS BARKING)
Keep those dogs
away from me, Orval.
I don't trust those bastards.
Keep moving, 'cause my dogs...
can eat and run
at the same time.
He's heading straight
for the top.
Is this guy supposed to be dangerous?
He's just dumb.
Hey, Walt, you're spoiling
the scent.
Let my babies do the job.
Go ahead.
I'm trailing you here.
This is no good.
Why?
There were three of us
on him in the cell block.
He went through us
like we weren't even there.
Aw, come on.
(DOGS BARKING)
(GRUNTS)
ORVAL: Let's go, babies.
Come on, Duke.
Hey, hey.
Okay, Thunder.
(DOGS BARKING)
Come on, Duke.
We got him cornered.
Art, this is Teasle.
He's headed for Chapman Gorge.
TEASLE: (ON RADIO)
Chapman Gorge. Head him off.
Oh!
God! No!
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
There he is!
On the cliff!
Son of a bitch!
(GUNSHOT)
What the hell's going on?
What are you doing?
We're just supposed to spot him.
GALT:
Hold it steady.
PILOT: I can't!
We're in a thermal draft.
Galt, he's stuck there.
He can't go anyplace.
If you don't fly
this thing right,
I swear to God,
I'm gonna kill you.
TEASLE: (ON RADIO)
Sheriff to Galt. Come in Galt.
(GUNSHOT)
(GROANS)
Hold it steady,
you son of a bitch!
Galt, come in, goddamn it!
GALT: Get in closer,
and hold it steady.
TEASLE: Galt, talk to me. I want
to know what's going on!
(GUNSHOT RICOCHETS)
I got him.
Easy. Easy.
Ow! Jesus!
(SCREAMING)
(MOANS)
There he is!
GALT: He's over there, dummy.
Come on!
Go on!
Hey, soldier boy!
(GUNSHOT)
Move it, move it down the side.
Hold it steady!
Come on!
TEASLE: Galt, get on this radio!
What's going on up there?
(GUNSHOT)
I don't want him dead, Galt!
I want him alive. You hear me?
Art, come in!
PILOT:
Watch out!
(SCREAMING)
(DOGS BARKING)
Art Galt, come in.
Helicopter, come in, goddamn it!
Jesus Christ!
Look!
Jesus Christ.
Give me the binoculars, hurry.
Oh, no, no, no.
Shit!
Jesus Christ.
(GROANING)
I can't figure it.
How'd he fall out?
Does it matter?
Let's nail this sucker's ass.
He can't be far.
Will!
Looks like he wants
to turn himself in.
There's one man dead!
It's not my fault!
I don't want any more hurt!
TEASLE:
Freeze!
Stand right where you are!
Give yourself up!
But I didn't do anything!
I'm warning you boy, don't make
a move! I'll blow your head off!
I didn't do anything!
(GUNSHOTS)
Ow!
TEASLE: Cease fire!
Cease fire!
Ward, goddamn it, cease fire!
I think we hit him.
Let's get down there.
Move!
(ZIPS UP PANTS)
TEASLE: (ON RADIO)
Sheriff to base. Come in.
Go ahead, Will.
Lester, we're down
in the gorge.
Galt's dead all right. Where the
hell is that goddamn chopper?
He won't come, Will. Says there's
a storm headed your way.
I don't give a goddamn what's on its way!
I want that chopper back here right now!
I don't want Galt's body
out here all night.
I'll do what I can.
Listen Will, you sure picked one hell
of a guy to mess around with.
This came over the teletype a few minutes
ago, John Rambo is a Vietnam vet.
He's a Green Beret. Congressional
Medal of Honor. Guy's a war hero.
Jesus, that freak?
I knew there was something
about that guy.
I double-checked it, Will.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to do what I told you
to do, goddamn it!
Get that chopper back
here now! Out!
Green Beret.
War hero.
That's great. That's just great.
Why don't you shut your mouth?
Now what the hell's
the matter with you guys?
He's one man.
He's wounded.
Those Green Berets,
they're real bad asses.
Why don't you let
the state police handle this?
Come here, boy.
Come here, goddamn it!
Look, look at him, look at him!
It's Art Galt, boy.
He and I were friends when your
mama was still wiping your nose!
Now he's dead. He's dead because
of that psycho out there!
Now you listen to me good, boy.
I'm gonna get that son of a bitch.
And I'm gonna pin that Congressional
Medal of Honor to his liver.
And I'm gonna do it with you
or without you.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
OFFICER:
Dang! Twisted my ankle!
(OFFICER GROANING)
ORVAL: We're closing in.
The scent's getting stronger.
TEASLE:
All right, keep your eyes open.
ORVAL:
Come on, baby.
It's gonna storm.
That's all we need now.
Will, let's get out of here
before it gets too dark.
What's the matter?
Are you afraid of the bogeyman?
You goddamn pansy.
Ward, put your gun down.
I'll show you who the pansy is.
Okay, come on down!
TEASLE:
Hey, guys, knock it off!
Ward, move on!
The fight is out there!
He's out there waiting for you!
Mitch, get on your feet
and move!
Let's go find this guy,
for Christ's sake!
Come on!
Keep your eyes open!
Come on there, Duke!
I'll see you later, Ward!
Shut up, Mitch!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Let's go, girl. Come on.
There he is!
TEASLE: Turn them loose!
Turn those dogs loose, Orval!
ORVAL: Go get 'em, sweethearts!
There's your dinner!
(GUNSHOTS, DOGS YELPING)
(MOANS)
Cease fire! Cease fire!
(YELLING)
I'm hit!
Goddamn it, I'm hit!
Jesus.
He's got a gun.
(ORVAL MOANING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's not him!
It's a goddamn scarecrow!
It was no scarecrow that shot Orval!
He's close, he's real close!
Kill 'im! Kill 'im!
Go get 'im!
Go get 'im, Maggie!
(THUMPING)
(DOG YELPING)
Mitch!
Mitch, Ward, come here.
Shingleton, you cover us.
Look at his leg.
Mitch, get your belt.
Get a tourniquet around that.
We gotta get this guy to a doctor!
Goddamn it! Get your belt on there fast!
Where's the first aid kit?
I left it in the car.
Shit!
Where'd he get the gun?
It's got to be Art Galt's gun.
He's out of ammo.
How do you know that?
Because whatever killed
that last dog was no bullet!
That's how.
Hurry up!
Orval, listen to me. Now listen,
You got to stay awake, all right?
You got to release that
tourniquet every 15 minutes.
We'll be right back!
Shh.
We got to get him now.
He's out of ammo.
Hurry up! Move!
He had no right to shoot my babies.
Get the son of a bitch! Go get him!
Come on! Let's go!
All right. All right.
Now, listen up.
We're right on top of him. We're gonna
form a skirmish line 50 feet apart.
And keep moving. There's no way
out of here except through us.
Okay.
Let's do some hunting.
Hunting?
We ain't hunting him.
He's hunting us.
Spread out!
Spread out, damn it!
I said 50 feet!
(PANTING)
Ow! Damn! Ow!
God, I hate this!
(SCREAMS)
Huh?
Ow! God!
Will, it's Mitch!
MITCH: Oh, shit, Will!
Oh, God!
Will!
Who is it?
(FOOTSTEPS NEARBY)
(MITCH SCREAMING)
Mitch?
What the hell's going on?
Shut up!
Oh! Will!
He's got Ward.
All right, spread out.
I'll go this way.
Will!
Will! Oh! Oh! Will!
Over here!
Will!
He's over here!
Who fired?
Who the hell is firing?
I got him! I got him!
Shingleton, follow me!
I got him!
Somebody help me!
Help me, Will!
Will!
Balford?
Balford, where the hell are ya?
Will!
(GROANS)
Help!
Help me!
Balford?
(MOANING)
Shingleton, over here!
God.
Jesus.
Easy. Easy. All right. Hold it.
Get me out of here.
(SCREAMS)
(SOBBING)
Jesus Christ!
Shingleton,
where the hell are ya?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Shingleton?
Will!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus...
(YELLS)
I could've killed them all.
I could have killed you.
In town, you're the law.
Out here, it's me.
Don't push it!
Don't push it, or I'll give
you a war you won't believe.
(GAGGING)
Let it go!
(CHATTERING)
All right. Coming in.
(HORN HONKING)
Come on. Get back.
Move back, you guys. Move back.
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
Captain, can we have a
comment on what's happening?
How bad is the situation?
Captain, we need some...
Only good thing to come
out of this mess...
is the business
we're doing in town.
Reporters are drinking
the place dry.
You look like you're ready
to keel over, Will.
Why don't you go home?
It's my problem now.
Your problem?
Listen, Dave,
don't give me any of your horseshit about
jurisdiction on this one, you understand?
Would you like me to step outside?
Just finish up what you're doing.
REPORTER: Somewhere in this
rugged mountain countryside,
possibly above the snow line,
shrouded in mist,
the fugitive John Rambo
is hiding.
Units of the state police, along with
local members of the National Guard...
are now being mobilized.
What still remains unexplained
by local authorities...
is just how and where
the former Green Beret...
came into possession
of the weapons with which...
he allegedly killed
one deputy sheriff...
and tried to kill six others.
Only their skilled training in police
enforcement techniques saved their lives.
And word now is that the fugitive will
be in custody in a matter of hours.
Here's the maps, Will.
Will, there's something
I think you ought to know.
Talk to you later.
Okay?
What is it, Lester? What is it?
For chrissake's! Spit it out!
Well, I was,
I was just talking to Mitch,
and he was saying that Galt
and a couple deputies...
were, uh, a little hard
on the guy.
Assholes!
Doesn't make one goddamn
bit of difference, Dave,
and you know it!
Look, if one of my deputies...
gets out of line
with a prisoner,
then the prisoner
comes to me with it!
If I find out it's like he says,
I kick the deputy's ass!
Me! The law! That's
the way it's got to be!
People start fuckin' around
with the law...
and all hell breaks loose!
Whatever possessed God in heaven
to make a man like Rambo?
MAN:
God didn't make Rambo.
I made him.
Who the hell are you?
Sam Trautman.
Colonel Samuel Trautman.
We're a little busy this morning,
Colonel. What can I do for you?
I've come to get my boy.
Your boy?
I recruited him.
I trained him.
I commanded him in Vietnam
for three years.
I'd say that makes him mine.
I wonder why the Pentagon would send a
full-bird colonel down here to handle this.
The Army thought
I might be able to help.
I don't know in what way. Rambo's
a civilian now. He's my problem.
I don't think you understand.
I didn't come here
to rescue Rambo from you.
I came here
to rescue you from him.
Well, we all appreciate
your concern, Colonel.
I will try to be extra careful.
I'm just amazed that he allowed
any of your posse to live.
Is that right?
Strictly speaking, he slipped up.
You're lucky to be breathing.
That's just great!
Colonel, you came out here
to find out...
why one of your machines
blew a gasket.
You don't seem to want
to accept the fact...
that you're dealing with an
expert in guerrilla warfare.
With a man who's the best...
with guns, with knives,
with his bare hands.
A man who's been trained
to ignore pain,
ignore weather,
to live off the land,
to eat things that would
make a billy goat puke.
In Vietnam, his job was
to dispose of enemy personnel.
To kill. Period.
Win by attrition.
Well, Rambo was the best.
(ANIMAL GRUNTING)
(PIG SQUEALS)
Okay, Colonel, you got us all
scared to death.
What do you and the Special
Forces think I ought to do...
about your psycho out there?
Let him go.
Do what?
For now.
Diffuse the whole situation.
Diffuse him.
Provide a little gap
and let him slip through it.
Then put out
a nationwide A.P.B.
In a couple of weeks,
you'll pick him up...
in Seattle or someplace,
working in a car wash.
There'll be no fight.
Nobody else will get hurt.
I do my own work.
I don't figure the best way
to do that is to close...
my eyes and then hope he gets
picked up in Seattle.
If you send your people in there
after him, they'll get killed.
You know, we're just a small, hick town
sheriff's department, Colonel
but we're expected
to do our duty...
just like our heroes
in the Special Forces.
In Special Forces, we teach our people
to stay alive in the line of duty.
No shit! I never thought of that.
You want a war you can't win?
Are you telling me that 200 men against
your boy is a no-win situation for us?
You send that many,
don't forget one thing.
What?
A good supply of body bags.
Trautman!
I don't know which side
you're on, Trautman.
I still think you came out
here just to cover your ass.
But if you're serious about taking
Rambo out clean, follow me.
MAN: (ON RADIO) State Police
calling John Rambo. Acknowledge.
State Police calling
John Rambo.
Come in, please.
Acknowledge.
If you're listening, Rambo,
here is your situation.
You are surrounded.
Every possible exit
has been blocked.
Every highway, every road,
every firebreak.
You have our word that your
services to your country...
will be taken
into consideration,
and you will receive
fair treatment.
Just respond. We can work
everything out. Over.
Anything?
He took a radio off
of one of my deputies.
Then he has to be listening.
If I was in his position,
I'd try to pick up information.
Maybe catch some cross talk.
Of course he's listening.
But he's not gonna break radio silence.
No. Not for us.
But he might do it
for you, Colonel.
He's your boy, isn't he?
Maybe you can talk him into...
sparing all our lives
by giving himself up.
I can try.
At least, we'll get
a radio fix on his position,
if you don't mind
setting him up for us.
Setting him up for you? That's like
bringing the pigeons to the cat.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, Don, thanks for
bringing your people out.
Any time, Will.
Come on, Bobby put the magazine away,
will ya? Pay attention.
We may only get
one crack at this.
TRAUTMAN: (ON RADIO) Covey Leader
calling Raven. Come on, Raven.
Covey Leader calling Raven.
Covey Leader to Raven.
Talk to me, Johnny.
Covey Leader
to identify Baker Team.
Rambo, Messner,
Ortega, Coletta,
Jorgensen, Danforth,
Barry, Krackauer.
Confirm.
This is Col. Trautman.
Talk to me, Johnny.
RAMBO:
They're all gone, sir.
It's him. It's him.
Get on it.
Rambo, are you
all right? Over.
Baker Team,
they're all dead, sir.
TRAUTMAN: Not Delmar Barry.
He made it.
Barry's gone too, sir.
How?
Got himself killed in 'Nam.
Didn't even know it.
Cancer ate him
down to the bone.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
I'm the last one, sir.
It's good to hear your voice, Johnny.
It's been a long time.
Look, John, you've
done some damage here,
That's it. Northwest.
but they don't want any more trouble.
TEASLE:
He's northwest.
That's why I've come.
I'm gonna come in there
and fly you the hell out.
Just you and me. We'll work
this thing out together.
Is that fair enough?
Where'd you come from, sir?
Bragg.
I tried to get in touch
with you,
but the guys at Bragg never
knew where to find you.
I haven't been spending
much time there lately.
They've got me down in D.C.
I'm shining a seat with my ass.
I wish I was back at Bragg now.
We'll talk about that
when you come in.
I can't do that, sir.
Well, look, John, we can't have
you runnin' around out there...
wastin' friendly civilians.
There are no friendly civilians.
I'm your friend, Johnny.
I was there with you knee-deep
in all that blood and guts.
I covered your ass
more than once.
Seems like bailin' you out of trouble
is gettin' to be a lifetime job for me.
There wouldn't be no trouble
except for that king-shit cop.
All I wanted
was something to eat,
but the man kept pushing, sir.
You did some pushing
of your own, John.
They drew first blood, not me.
Look, Johnny, let me come in and
get you the hell out of there.
They drew first blood.
Rambo, are you
still reading me?
Covey Leader to Raven.
Rambo, acknowledge.
He's all finished, Colonel.
We've got a real good
fix on him, though.
Come first light, I'm gonna put
every man I got up on that ridge.
Then we'll get him my way.
All right, look down. I want you
to stretch the skirmish line...
right across this ridge.
Goddamn it.
Come on. Let's go.
Over here.
Come on!
Move it!
Let's go.
Hey, this guy got a gun?
Watch it.
It's slippery.
Come on.
Watch your step.
What was that?
To the left or the right?
Which way did he go?
Toss it across.
Toss it.
Which way?
Pa! Pa! Pa!
There's a guy over there!
What happened, son?
I see him! Over there!
I'll get him! I'll get him!
Don't shoot! Cool down!
This way! Let's go!
GUARDSMAN:
There he is! Come on!
(GUNFIRE)
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Whoo!
(GUNFIRE, BULLET RICOCHETTING)
Now we got him!
Yes. Yes, I know exactly where it is.
Listen to me very carefully.
Surround the area with every man
you've got, but don't move in.
I repeat, don't move in. In fact,
don't do anything 'til I get there.
And no shooting. I don't want
him dead. I want him alive.
Get down!
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
GUARDSMAN:
Keep firin'!
Come on, guys.
Shoot!
Come on!
Oh, you guys are great.
All right, Steve?
Yo?
I want you and Bruce, head around these
trees, go to the front of that mine.
Screw that, Clinton.
I ain't goin' up there.
No way.
Raymond?
What?
I want you to go into that mine.
Oh, not me.
What do you mean, "not me"?
Look, I do this part-time.
I didn't come here to get killed. He's
probably in there just waitin' for us.
What's wrong with you, Clinton?
All right, Rambo? This is
Lieutenant Clinton Morgen,
National Guard Leader.
Now, I'm giving you just
three-zero seconds to come on out!
Who's got the rocket launcher?
I do.
Come here, Earl.
MORGEN:
Great.
Rambo, this is your last
chance to come out.
Maybe we should wait.
Earl, this creep is a killer.
Besides, I'm in charge,
and I say we blow it up.
Now fire that thing.
Just let me
get out of the way first.
EARL: Whoo!
Yeah!
(MEN HOOTING)
Give that man a cigar!
Bull's-eye!
Where the hell are they?
Up the hill about 500 yards.
MORGEN: Move in a little
closer, just like Iwo Jima.
(MEN LAUGHING)
I don't believe it.
Idiots!
Steady. Got it.
All right, Nick.
One more for Soldier of Fortune.
Soldier of Fortune?
Damn it! What the hell do you
think this is? Some kind of a circus?
Get the hell out of here!
Clinton,
Jesus...
Didn't you get the word, Clinton? I told
you people to wait until I got up here!
He was shootin' at us, Will. Come
on, I wasn't takin' any chances.
Christ, what a mess.
We're gonna have to dig his
body out of there right away.
You can't get a dozer up here.
You're going to have to find
somebody to dig him out.
It's your mess, Clinton. You clean it up.
Will, come on!
I gotta be back at the
drugstore tomorrow.
Then you better get started
right away, Clinton!
Shit!
(RIPPING SOUND)
Buried in a hole by a bunch
of goddamn weekend warriors.
I thought you said he was
the best you ever trained.
However he may have ended up, there
was a time when he was very special.
Special, my ass. He's just another
drifter that broke the law.
Vagrancy, wasn't it?
That's gonna look real good...
on his gravestone at Arlington.
"Here lies John Rambo, winner of
the Congressional Medal of Honor,
"survivor of countless
incursions behind enemy lines,
killed for vagrancy
in Jerkwater, U.S.A."
Now don't give me
any of that crap, Trautman.
You think Rambo was the only guy
who had a tough time in Vietnam?
He killed a police officer,
for Christ sake!
You're goddamn lucky
he didn't kill all of ya.
This character, he comes waltzing in
here, full of all kinds of good advice.
And wished we'd let the goddamn maniac
go loose so we can save our own asses!
Well, we saved our asses, Colonel,
and we didn't let him go loose!
The best man lost!
And he doesn't like it!
(PANTING)
GUARDSMAN: That Rambo...
Digging trenches in hell.
Why did we follow him up here?
This is so damn stupid.
I wanna get outta here.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
How ya doin', Will?
Hold my calls.
(RATS SQUEAKING, RAMBO SCREAMING)
(RATS SQUEAKING)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Colonel?
Have a seat.
Oh, miss, would you
do this again, please?
Hi, Sheriff.
And for my friend.
Give me a shooter.
Wild Turkey.
Look, if I was
out of line before,
I... I just want
to apologize.
None of that makes much
difference now, does it?
Nah, I guess not.
I suppose...
I don't know.
I just feel...
Like you were cheated
out of your chance.
I wanted to kill that kid.
I wanted to kill him
so bad I could taste it.
Doesn't sit well
with that badge, hmm?
It can get confusing sometimes.
In Vietnam, you can bet that
Rambo and I got pretty confused.
But we had orders.
When in doubt, kill.
What the hell,
you're a civilian.
You can go home to your wife and your
house and your little flower garden.
You're under no pressure
to figure all this out.
What about you, Colonel? What did you
figure out from all of this, huh?
What would you have done
with him if he came in?
Would you wrap your arms around
him, give him a big, sloppy kiss?
Or would you have
blown his brains out?
I couldn't answer that
until I met him face-to-face.
Yeah.
Well, there it is.
It's just as well we never
got a chance to find out.
Hmm.
(SIGHS)
Drive.
Don't look at me,
look at the road.
That's how accidents happen.
What's your name?
Ca... Cathcart, Robert A.
All right, what do ya got
in the back, Robert A.?
M60.
(UNLATCHES DOOR)
Okay, Robert A., get outta the truck.
Oh, please, I got no beef with you. No!
Go on! Move! Go!
(GROANS)
(HORN HONKING)
Whoa!
TROOPER: (ON RADIO) S.P. Car 1,
Charlie 5 to Central.
Want to turn that up?
(PHONE RINGING)
Are we still on that three-way hookup?
WOMAN: Sheriff Teasle's office.
He's not taking any calls.
Roger. Still working.
What's your story, Steamboat?
Looks like somebody
pulled the plug too soon.
That Rambo guy...
is on the loose again.
Shit.
Roger, Steamboat. This is Trapper.
We're setting up roadblocks
on Highway 26.
Hey, Will, it's Rambo.
He's still around.
(SIREN WAILING)
(SIREN APPROACHING)
(SIREN CONTINUES)
(GUNSHOTS)
(TROOPERS SHOOTING)
Heads up!
Get out of the way!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Holy fuck!
All right, get out there right away.
Move!
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
(APPROACHING SIRENS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
What the hell is goin' on?
Watch yourself!
They're all gonna blow!
Attention all civilians.
For your own safety,
please evacuate
the streets immediately.
Remain indoors until you
receive further instructions.
I repeat, this is a
police emergency.
Please evacuate the
streets immediately.
We found Rambo's body.
As a matter of fact,
it stole an army truck,
blew up a gas station
on the other side of town.
The kid is resilient.
Why don't forget what you're thinkin'
and clear out while you can?
Get the fuck outta here, Trautman
and you take your advice with you.
When I talked to you
earlier this afternoon,
you knew he was still alive,
didn't you?
I suspected.
Yeah, sure.
Sure. That's why you stuck around.
You trained him.
You taught him how to get out
of places like that cave.
But he's not gonna
get out of this place.
Teasle, you and all your men
couldn't handle him before.
What makes you think
you can handle him now?
Because God knows what
damage he's prepared to do.
You're gonna die, Teasle.
Everybody dies.
There's only one man in this
room that's got half a chance.
That's not because
I'm better than he is.
It's because he trusts me.
See, I'm the closest thing
to family he has left.
And that may be
all the edge I need.
Jesus Christ, where
do you people come from?
Now this is my job, Trautman.
This is my town.
And I'm not giving it up to you
or to Rambo or to anybody else.
Now, you just stay
the hell out of my way.
Get a little closer!
I can't! It's too goddamn hot!
Will, this is Lester.
Do you copy? Over.
(EXPLOSION)
Come on, let's go!
Will, this is Lester.
Do you copy? Over.
Listen, Will,
we got some serious problems.
The highway's been cut off. The truck's
out here, but we couldn't find the body.
I repeat, no body.
It's totally burned out.
Preston, get those
people outta here!
PRESTON: Hey!
Move 'em back to the south side.
Move back! Move back!
Listen, Will, we don't know how many...
gasoline reservoirs there are
under those gas pumps.
(LESTER CONTINUES, INDISTINCT)
Do you copy? Over.
We got a reporter here.
Preston, push them back!
I don't care who he is!
LESTER: Move them around!
Get the trucks to the other side!
Come on!
Let's go!
Will, do you copy?
Over.
(SIRENS WAILING,
LESTER CONTINUES ON RADIO)
(GUNFIRE)
(SHELLS EXPLODING)
(SHELLS EXPLODING IN FIRE)
Come on, damn it.
Goddamn it!
(EXPLOSION, GLASS SHATTERING)
(METAL CREAKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(SCREAMING, GROANING)
(GRUNTING, GROANING)
(GASPING)
Go ahead.
Go ahead, you crazy son of a bitch!
Finish me!
Rambo!
Rambo, don't do it!
Listen to me, Rambo.
You have no chance.
So drop your weapon.
I'm gonna order the chopper in
to fly you back to Bragg.
(GUNFIRE)
Hold your fire!
Kern! Hold your fire.
Yes?
KERN: (ON MEGAPHONE)
Hold your fire. Hold your fire!
Think about what you're doing.
The building's perimeter
is covered. No exits.
There are nearly 200 men
out there and a lot of M16s.
You did everything to make
this private war happen.
You've done enough damage!
This mission is over, Rambo.
Do you understand me?
(SLAMS DOWN RIFLE)
This mission is over!
Look at 'em out there.
Look at 'em!
If you don't end this now,
they're gonna kill you.
Is that what you want?
KERN: Back it up.
Watch yourselves.
TRAUTMAN:
It's over, Johnny.
It's over!
Nothing is over! Nothing!
You just don't turn it off!
It wasn't my war!
You asked me, I didn't ask you!
And I did what
I had to do to win!
But somebody
wouldn't let us win!
Then I come back to the world, and I
see all those maggots at the airport...
protestin' me, spittin'. Callin' me
"Baby Killer" and all kinds of vile crap!
Who are they
to protest me, huh?
Who are they, unless they've
been me and been there
and know what the hell
they're yelling about!
It was a bad time for everyone,
Rambo. It's all in the past now.
For you! For me,
civilian life is nothing!
In the field,
we had a code of honor:
You watch my back,
I watch yours.
Back here there's nothing!
You're the last of an elite group.
Don't end it like this.
Back there I could fly a
gunship, I could drive a tank.
I was in charge of
million-dollar equipment!
Back here I can't even
hold a job parking cars!
(GLASS SHATTERING, RAMBO SHOUTS)
(SOBBING)
Fuck it. Oh.
Geez.
Oh, God.
Where is everybody?
(PANTING)
I had a friend,
it was Danforth.
I had all these guys, man.
Back there I had all these fuckin'
guys... who were my friends
'Cause back here
there's nothing.
Remember Danforth?
He wore this black headband. I took
one of his magic markers and it said,
"If found, mail us to Las Vegas" 'cause
we were always talkin' about Vegas.
And his fuckin' car,
this red '58 Chevy convertible.
He was talkin' about this car.
He said we were gonna
cruise 'til the tires fall off.
(PANTING)
We go in this bar in Saigon,
and this kid comes up...
this kid's carrying
a shoe shine box.
And he says,
"Shine, please. Shine."
I said no. He kept askin'
yeah and Joey said yeah.
And I went to get
a couple of beers.
And the box is wired.
And he opened up the box.
Fuckin' blew his body
all over the place.
And he's layin' there.
He's fuckin' screamin'.
There's pieces of him all over me.
Just... like this.
And I'm tryin' to pull him off, you know?
And this is my friend that's all over me!
I've got blood and everything.
I'm tryin' to hold him together.
I'm puttin' him together.
His fuckin' insides keep comin' out!
And nobody would help!
Nobody would help!
He's sayin', "I wanna go home,
I wanna go home."
He keeps callin' my name. "I wanna go
home, Johnny. I wanna drive my Chevy."
I said, "Why?
I can't find your fuckin' legs.
I can't find your legs."
I can't get it out of my head.
I dream it seven years.
Every day I have this.
Sometimes I wake up,
I don't know where I am.
I don't talk to anybody.
Sometimes a day,
sometimes a week.
I can't put it out of my mind.
Fuck it.
(SOBBING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO TRANSMISSIONS)
Let's get him inside.
♪ It's a long road
♪ When you're on your own
♪ And it hurts when
♪ They tear your dreams apart
♪ And every new town
♪ Just seems to bring you down
♪ Trying to find peace of mind
♪ Can break your heart
♪ It's a real war
♪ Right outside your front door ♪
♪ I tell ya
♪ Out where they'll kill ya
♪ You could use a friend
♪ Where the road is
♪ That's the place for me
♪ Where I'm me in my own space
♪ Where I'm free
That's the place ♪
♪ I wanna be
♪ 'Cause the road is long
Yeah ♪
♪ Each step is only the beginning ♪
♪ No breaks, just heartaches
♪ Oh, man, is anybody winning
♪ It's a long road
♪ And it's hard as hell
♪ Tell me what do you do
♪ To survive
♪ When they draw first blood
♪ That's just the start of it
♪ Day and night you gotta fight ♪
♪ To keep alive
♪ It's a real war
♪ Right outside your front door ♪
♪ I tell ya
♪ Out where they'll kill ya
♪ You could use a friend
♪ 'Cause the road is long
Yeah ♪
♪ Each step is only the beginning ♪
♪ No breaks, just heartaches
♪ Oh, man, is anybody winning
♪ The road is long, yeah
♪ Each step is only the beginning ♪
♪ No breaks, just heartaches
♪ Oh, man, is anybody winning
♪ It's a long road
♪ It's a long road...