No End
This call is monitored
The time is 7.12 a.m.
I died...
...four days ago
I got the car out, as usual
I waited in it for Ula and Jacek
The engine ticked over.
The radio forecast a low
I felt a stab of fear.
My heart, I thought
But the pain never came.
All I felt was fear
I took a deep breath
And that was that
I wondered if the meIons on the
baIcony wouId ever sprout
By now UIa had emerged with Jacek
She waIked towards the car
but I moved away
I saw her having troubIe
with the car door
But it was Iike Iooking down
That seemed strange
After aII, I was sitting
at the wheeI
I feIt good. Everything
was so peacefuI...
...and quiet
Though UIa seemed to be shouting
I didn't feeI dizzy after
my first cigarette
I couIdn't feeI the keys
in my pocket
It struck me I couId come back
to myseIf if I wanted to...
...and drive Jacek to schooI
But I feIt better as I was,
much better
I watched the coffin being cIosed
It was then that Jacek understood,
because he began to cry
His hands were frozen
But he was ashamed to put them
in his pockets
I went back home.
It was stiII empty
Darek's dossier was Iying
on the desk
I wished I couId be with him
in court
I onIy saw UIa and Jacek
after they got back
They feII asIeep together
on his bed
He cIung to her for a Iong time
She woke up in the night and
moved to her own bed
Ula? Tomek here
-l'm in Warsaw, just landed
- Where?
At Okecie. l hope l'm in time
to catch the Counsellor
- He's not here
-At 7.30? You two split up?
ls that the alarm?
How's that for timing?
Antek is dead
The funeraI was yesterday.
CaII me Iater
- Don't taIk about it at schooI
- I won't
I'II come straight home
You'II be here, won't you?
We'II see each other
ls that Mrs Zyro?
l have to see you,
about my husband
Hello? l said l need to see you
- Who are you?
-l'm Darek's wife
Your husband was his lawyer.
You must know that
lt's a political case.
l must see you
CaII the office
I'm not a Iawyer. I'm sending them
aII the fiIes
That's the point
It's about Thursday's bioIogy.
You asked me to...
The Iine is crossed. HeIIo?
You must have Darek's file.
Hello?
Waiting for me?
I caIIed this morning.
Wake up, SyIwia
- I took some miIk
- AII right, come in
How can I heIp you?
- As I said, I need that fiIe
- What fiIe?
My husband's case
I can't give it to you
Why won't you heIp me?
It beIongs to the new Iawyer
Those are the ruIes.
Don't you know?
FiIes get Iost. No one knows how
But you don't care
Come on, SyIwia
Madam, you said it was
a poIiticaI case
That's right
I shouIdn't, but if the fiIe
is here...
...I'II Iet you see it
Is she thirsty? Bored?
No, she Iikes Iistening
to grown-ups' taIk
- Nothing here
- ShouId there be?
I wouIdn't know. No, nothing
- What did he do?
- A strike. He organised a strike
Who'II take the case now?
Maybe someone Iike your husband?
I can't think of anyone.
Wait, though...
There's this oId Iawyer
Antek trained under
- OId?
- Yes
He was at the funeraI.
His name is Labrador
Maybe he's stiII in the
Iawyers' directory
Go to Dept.4. They'II teII you
I'd Iike to know who the judge is.
'Bye, thank you
Sorry to keep you.
How can I heIp you?
Mrs Zyro toId me you've rescued Iots
of peopIe. That you couId heIp me
Those were different cases
My Iast poIiticaI case was
in 1952
He got death
After that, I quit
Now I do petty crime
That woman won't be testifying.
She's stiII abroad
TeII our cIient to remain siIent
Take a taxi. I'II pay you back
SmuggIing offences.
I'm strong on those
I steer cIear of poIitics
Have you heard of this case?
A hot potato, Iike aII of them
You're making an oId man
face a hard choice
Not me, the times
I'm quite aware of
the present time
But what to do about it?
Got the time?
A quarter past one
Damn it, my watch!
It's stopped. Know how I got it?
A present from Antek when
he was caIIed to the bar
Let me sIeep on this
CaII me tomorrow
- Heard the news?
- What news?
They've done it. The scrap-heap
at 70
It's gone through?
It wiII. You can bet on it
We're finished
What can we do?
Guess what? We've been given
our marching orders
Come January and we're out!
So I've heard
But this charade... how
about that for an ending?
A kind of swan song
PeopIe sometimes go crazy,
madam
You needn't caII me
I'II take the case. Are you
free tomorrow at 4?
Who are you caIIing, mum?
No one. I was going to,
but I forgot who
- Looking for something?
- No
Just sorting things out
A man caIIed earIier
Funny name. GibraItar...
That's right. He asked
about some fiIe
I know. I'II turn out your Iight
when I go to bed
- Jacek? Good night
- Good night, mum
Antek!
He was in the car, waiting.
I'd been on the phone
Maybe if I hadn't been Iate
- A heart is a heart
- But it can't be a coincidence
- You couIdn't have heIped
- I'd have been there
Don't think about it
What can I think about?
You're stiII young. You've a nice kid.
You're a good transIator
UIka, you and Antek weren't
very cIose IateIy
That's true. But now it seems
we were
Does that make sense?
He's gone
Tomek... ten years ago
you were cIose friends
Later, too
I know, but when we first met...
Did you know about certain
photographs of me?
In the nude? He toId me
- Showed you?
- Of course not
- How did he find out?
- A ''weII-wisher'' sent them
I found them yesterday.
He'd cut out my face
He knew I'd been a guide,
and hard up for money
I couId have expIained
Why didn't he say anything?
Why did he cut out my face?
- Did he have many such cases?
- RecentIy, yes
- What's this?
- A note
That's what his wife must
have been Iooking for
''I'm gIad you're defending me
''You're young and you understand.
The first in a month
''You're right about having
to return to society...
''...but with honour
''I'II do as you say
''No poIitics. But I'II admit
to being a strike Ieader
''They trusted me though I
hadn't been in SoIidarity
''I wanted to settIe grievances,
not to wreck the machinery
''I'm worried about my famiIy
''TeII Joanna not to take
SyIwia to dad
''Best wishes from me and
my ceIImates. Darek
''I'm gIad you don't want me
to act insane''
Who'II take this?
I've been away too Iong.
Otherwise I might myseIf
- I put her on to Labrador
- He won't take it
He aIready has
What's this?
The question mark. Is it yours?
By Labrador's name
You poked around in daddy's things
- No. When?
- Yesterday
You scrawIed something...
...with a feIt-tip. Don't Iie!
You're Iying
You know I'm not Iying
I'm going to Praga.
Want to come?
No. Give me the keys.
I'II stay at home
Wait a second
It's Antek's wife
- What did they take?
- Guess!
Contraband books. You had some
Iying around
Yes, I was reading Brandys
- Notebooks?
- Yes
Any cassettes?
They took them aII. PIus
a typewriter, Ietters...
- From Maciek
- Did you have any notes?
Some EngIish notes
I bet you didn't get a receipt
- I was too scared to ask
- Show me
''I hereby request the return...
''...of the property confiscated
in the search...''
Search?
Requisition. They hate
the word 'search'
And 'request'? What are
you requesting? Right?
- Won't it be impoIite?
- Why shouIdn't it be?
Give me some paper. I'II do it
- What's happened?
- I... my car broke down
Remember this? I showed it to you
The Iist of Iawyers
- It wasn't torn then
- What eIse?
- That wasn't there
- Of course it wasn't
Maybe the boy...
- It couIdn't have been him
- Then who?
It's Antek warning me off
Labrador
So what now? No, that's stupid
I must go. I may not get a taxi
- I'II go with you
- I can drop you, sir
- I have a car
- No one says ''sir'' here
The Institute. Is that OK?
I'II get ready
What Institute?
For cancer research.
Radiotherapy
You Iooked through that fiIe
I didn't know you. I was afraid
There was a message.
Something about...
...not taking the chiId to see dad.
I don't get it
I do
What shaII I teII Darek?
I'm due back soon
AII you know. But remember,
everything here is fine
No probIems
BIackbeard!
For you
Thanks
- Drop by sometime
- I wiII
''I'm worried about my famiIy
''TeII Joanna not to take SyIwia...''
You'II ruin your eyesight
Zyro did a good job on
our cIient, didn't he?
Go away
Like some tea? At this
time of day, it's...
Today? What time?
Shit!
I'II be there
Run aIong
Make sure the door is shut
Maybe you know what you want?
To make things better?
Fairer, right?
But where?
- In PoIand
- Which PoIand?
You don't want to taIk to me?
Am I being too bIunt with you?
WeII then, which PoIand?
- Ours. There is no other
- ExactIy
SociaIist PoIand?
Can you imagine a different
PoIand?
- Not reaIIy
- There you are, then
The onIy PoIand you want to make
better is a SociaIist PoIand
And that's what you have to say
Never mind what you think
You're pending triaI
Ever been in a courtroom?
Judges are a fixture
They respect their job
They may be tired, but they're
weII aware history is Iike a wheeI
Let's give them a chance
- Know what that means?
- Yes. A seII-out
There's aIways some Ieeway between
seIIing out and compromising, son
There is. But you have to find it
The evidence against you is thin
They're onIy interested in Ieaders.
Don't make it seem...
...the strike was your idea
- It was everyone's idea
- Sure, but it won't Iook that way
But I was eIected. I had the Iist
Suit yourseIf
There's no evidence, no
committee, no Ieader
- Is that right?
- Right
Not quite, but near enough
I toId you, there's aIways
some Ieeway
Now, have you ever been
to a demonstration?
Once
Why onIy once? I'II teII you why
The opposition were wearing the
same uniform you wore in the army
You wanted to take part,
but couIdn't
Psychiatrists caII that...
Zyro was against pIeading
insanity
He was a wonderfuI man, Antek
But I'm 40 years oIder,
and I can't do it his way
Maybe I'm past it, or Iess gifted
He was my pupiI. ProbabIy
better than me
He was, you might say,
an artist
His way shouIdn't have worked,
but it did
My way is to take a scaIpeI
and hack
You two must have hit it off
Pretty weII
Evidence was beneath him
So were poIitics
He'd appeaI to peopIe's consciences,
even their emotions
But I can't take chances.
I've onIy one objective
To get you out of here
Is there anything you need?
We're thinking of a hunger strike
What for?
Whose hands do you think
you'II be pIaying into?
Got any better suggestions?
No, I've never been any good
at these things
Forgive me, but it's warmer
in here
I had a cake but I ate it
No coffee either. Tea?
No, thank you. What's this?
Antek's notes on that kid's case
Can you decipher them?
The odd word
''The Iaw demands...
''The Iaw demands too much
of peopIe today
''It kiIIs what is...
''It kiIIs what is most precious
in human reIationships''
This is underIined
''If the Iaw is against IoyaIty
and trust, then it is immoraI
''No government shouId be...
''...shouId be interested in ruIing
over a divided nation''
Is it a question or
an excIamation mark?
I never couId read his writing
He wouIdn't want me...
...to take this case
He wanted that boy to go free
Do you miss him?
Very much. I miss him very much
What's that?
''It's coming. It's going to erupt...''
- Want some?
- No, thanks. We're Iistening
I took the parceI yesterday
- It's awfuI there
- Poor oId granny
First she wouIdn't Iet me in.
Then she cried
Did that girI get her things back?
- Have you got your things back?
- Not yet
She took in one of the bIokes.
Hence the search
But they missed him
Antek put someone up once
who was out after curfew
He hid him from me.
Later he was afraid
- What of?
- I don't know
Someone's asking for you.
He won't come in
Meet each other
- Marta Duraj
- UrszuIa Zyro
Are you reIated to the Iawyer
Antoni Zyro?
Antek? I'm his wife
I knew him years ago
How is he?
He died...
...a month ago
- Cigarette?
- Thanks
You knew him?
When he was a student.
He came round one night
A girI and I were sharing
a cabin by the beach
We'd gone to bed
He'd been swimming and
his tent had been stoIen
He was stiII dripping
He sat on the bed, soaking wet
Afterwards... he stood there...
- Scrawny, bandy-Iegged
- He wasn't bandy-Iegged
- He was then
- Then what?
He wanted to be a judge.
He was into Camus
The penitent judge...
I read it Iater. Was he a judge?
No, a Iawyer. That's what
he aIways wanted to be
Remember anything eIse?
- I don't think so
- Anything at aII?
He Ieft soon after,
to do a course
That was that. Were you
married Iong?
11 years
A Iong time. Was it a heart attack?
Yes. How did you know?
He mentioned his heart
at the time
Everything OK?
Everything's fine
They're on hunger strike
Labrador said Antek
was his own man
We'd aII Iike to be
But Antek reaIIy was
No one toId him what to do
He wrote things were
getting harder
But his Ietters were marked
'Censored'. What's this?
A photograph. I've just found it.
Ring a beII?
Summer of '67
How skinny he was!
Who are the girIs?
I've forgotten
He fancied this one
- Brunette? Named Marta?
- No, bIonde and thin
Rather Iike you
We aIways feII for the same girIs
IncIuding you
I'm stiII carrying the torch
UIa, I want you to know that...
What are you Iooking at?
His hands are Iike Antek's
- You didn't hear. I said...
- Don't say it
Forget I said it, then
Oh, my God!
That's my car!
Rush round to the pound.
Got money?
Yes. WiII you wait?
No, I'II get the bus.
Off you go!
My husband died 36 days ago
There one moment... gone the next
I assumed I loved him,
on and off at any rate
The house, my work...
I had everything
But I didn't reaIise
I can hardIy beIieve there were
bad times, that I hated him
It's onIy now I reaIise I was happy.
I can't accept it
I can't
I keep seeing him.
I can't forget him
You seemed to have hands Iike him
You wouIdn't understand.
It's my probIem
Sit down a moment
Goodbye
I've bought a pair of trainers
for SyIwia
They were avaiIabIe
Who was he?
My father
Daddy!
- Where's SyIwia?
- With a neighbour
I can't take it any more
Darek on one side,
my father on the other
He brings me newspapers,
with articIes exposing them
PeopIe Iike Darek and me
I can't go on
Fuck the Iot of them!
I'm scared, UIa
What of?
Some of them go abroad.
Others die
But Darek...
He'II go to jaiI
- And I'II be on my own
- Who has died?
BIackbeard
Two days ago
I've transIated the OrweII.
He wanted to read it
You don't care, do you?
You see aII these tragedies,
but onIy yours matters
Yes, you're right
Yesterday I did something bad
Very bad. I was unfaithfuI
to Antek
But he's dead
I don't know why I did that to him,
when I can stiII feeI his touch
I wish I couId heIp. I have
this address, at JeIonki
It's this young feIIow.
He heIped Marta
You met her here
She was terribIy hung up,
and it did her good
- Want to try?
- What?
To forget
That's bad news
I want him to get out,
not to starve
You'd better teII him
to start eating
To take some soup at dinner,
and to be the first
I'II arrange a visit
I can go, but not to teII him that
Why not?
He'd kiII me
Do you want him free?
But I won't teII him that.
I'm his wife, can't you see?
Do you think it'II get to anyone?
CertainIy not to those
that matter
Human torches, but no water...
We've been there
Don't be stubborn.
This wiII harm him
OK, I'II teII him. And you can
go on pIaying the siIent wife
Someone toId me to show you this
Who?
They've formed a new union
at the factory
- Do you know these peopIe?
- One of them. A friend of Darek's
They grew up together
Can you spare me a moment?
A cIient of mine's been hit with a
tax cIaim. He bought a car abroad
What do you mean, bought?
A cIient of yours?
It was a gift. That's tax-free
I'm onIy a trainee. But
I know how you feeI
Is there any way I can heIp?
How are you off for money?
I forgot that's why I came.
I've brought your money
Keep it. I onIy wondered
how you were managing
We couId fix something
Thank you, I'm aII right.
Better than before
CouId you Iend me the paper?
Give it to me?
HeIIo, Judge
We'II soon be meeting
professionaIIy
- That's right. How do you know?
- I was toId
But first I have some business
with you
Not much
AIways at your service
If you're interested, I'm hearing
a fascinating case
Here's what you'II do
Go to that factory and ask
that feIIow if the new union...
...wouId be prepared to show they
care about workers, even strikers...
...by standing baiI for Darek
- Do you have a name?
- Of course
Damn it! Where's that paper?
It was here a minute ago
It can't have vanished
- Buy another one
- Newspapers now cost 5 zIotys
- Even the Party's?
- AII of them
Lie down, Iie down
I haven't done this before
But it is possibIe
- Is this man aIive?
- Yes
But he can't be with you?
- And he never wiII?
- Never
Good
I shaII now put you to sIeep...
...and try to erase him
from your memory
PIease, Iie down
FIat, reIaxed...
...eyes open
Now Iook at me, and Iet
your whoIe body go Iimp
Legs, arms, stomach, face...
Every muscIe reIaxed
Now Iower your eyeIids,
gentIy cIose your eyes
You feeI Iight, your muscIes are
reIaxed, your eyeIids refuse to open
Now raise your arm. It's Iight...
It takes no effort.
You're asIeep
Now Iower your arm
GentIy
You can't feeI your arms, your Iegs,
or any part of your body
Your mind is bIank
No Ionger thinking of him
AIive or dead, he's gone,
no Ionger there
You won't want to be with him...
...see him or taIk to him
You don't want to be with him
When you wake, you wiII have
forgotten his voice, his face...
You won't want to think about him
Now I'II wake you
You're beginning to feeI
your body
To feeI heavy
You're waking
When I count to zero,
you'II wake
Five... four... three...
...two... one... zero
You've woken
We may have to repeat this.
PIease, come again
Do you feeI aII right?
A gIass of water?
Did it heIp?
Yes
Mummy!
What happened, Jacek?
Had a bad dream?
A nightmare?
Come on, teII mummy
- Don't you want to teII me?
- I do
You and daddy
That's nice
I've never toId you this
I woke up one night
The Iight was on in your bedroom
Daddy was on top of you.
You were both naked
That's what I dreamt now
What were you doing?
Making Iove
Yes, Iove
You were born because
daddy used to cuddIe me
Now you Iove me.
You're cuddIing me
HeIIo, CounseIIor
- Are you with someone? The coffee
- It's for you
I thought you'd be more
responsive
Suppose I spring a IittIe
surprise on you
Like baiI for Darek...
...from the new, IegaI,
respectabIe union
WouId you reIease him?
- So the new union wouId... ?
- They wouId
What about him? That's the rub,
isn't it?
I'II taIk to him, if I think
there's a chance
I don't decide aIone
You think it'II be oiI on
troubIed waters?
Not at aII. Just a good
oId Iawyer's trick
- Know my answer?
- Yes
Screw it
ExactIy
I'II be seeing you
Get yourseIf a coffee.
The judge drank yours
You know I joined you
to wait things out?
NaturaIIy. I'm not bIind
CriminaI cases, divorces...
that was fine
But the way you're handIing this...
Listen, no one's forcing you
I'II give you good references,
anyway
Look what your wife gave me
She did?
The way of the worId...
Know any of these peopIe?
Yes
My friend from chiIdhood
- He joined the strike
- PreciseIy
I'm pIanning to see him
What for?
To stand baiI for you, to vouch
you'II be a good boy
I won't
You shouIdn't Iook a gift horse
in the mouth
Seize your opportunity.
He's your friend, isn't he?
He was
AII right. But his baiI can
get you out of here
Then you won't be facing
a summary proceeding...
...or more than one suspended
sentence. Can't you see?
You can't win now.
Pretend you're passive...
...if you want to stay in the game
I've never begged a prisoner...
...to agree to be reIeased
Don't start now
- Not eating?
- No
Think it'II change anything?
Damn it! I can't watch you
kiII yourseIf
I can't aIIow...
Then don't. Shout it
from the rooftops
Go ahead, die! Jump
out of the window
No way
It's barred
PreciseIy
You aII decided to Iive,
didn't you?
- Who?
- You... the others
Your kind
Your response to martiaI Iaw was:
survive!
You didn't charge the tanks
Was that wrong?
No. But you have to be IogicaI
If you decide to Iive...
...you must Iearn to endure
Point 5: consequences
and concIusions
Antek's dead. He can't save
both his skin and his honour
My way's unacceptabIe.
That Ieaves one option
We IeveI with him
Let him decide himseIf
You shouIdn't have taken
this case
I had to, my boy.
I admire that man
I toId him he had to survive...
...not waste time on gestures
His kind of integrity
is important...
...not just to him
PeopIe want to be brave.
They need exampIes
- What are we in the end?
- Defenders
Yeah, you can say that again
Murderers, thieves,
beg to be sprung
An innocent man refuses
After 45 years at the bar,
he makes me ask myseIf:
Whom do we reaIIy defend?
Against whom? Against what?
- Noticed we have the same name?
- AII the time
At Ieast we can teII him that
his famiIy's being taken care of
That they're provided for
He needn't worry
Who'II teII him?
You, of course, Mietek
But I'II aIso teII him
what I think
What's this?
An underground tape. Know it?
Look what I've got
- What is it?
- A canister
Tear gas
Where did you get it?
Where have you been?
Constitution Square
Stay away from pIaces Iike that
Promise?
It stiII stinks
You're aII I've got Ieft.
Promise me
PIease!
Labrador is wiIIing, but tired
He has his methods, but
you're too much for him
That's good. The crunch is coming.
You have to shout
Never mind those bars.
You'II be heard
PIead guiIty. Say yes,
I organised the strike
I want to fight
I onIy regret I reaIised so Iate
The strike was a pretext
for something bigger
The men supported you because they
wanted to fight too, but didn't dare
You showed them the way,
and you don't regret it
It'II Iook just Iike another triaI
We'II invite observers
With Iuck, they won't be admitted
And both sides wiII think
something's afoot
The whoIe of Warsaw wiII be taIking.
Know what they caII that in Cracow?
They have a speciaI word for it
Here's what CounseI wiII say:
''I do not ask the court
for speciaI treatment
''The accused is a nobody.
Nobodies are Iegion
''But this nobody is aIso
a brave man
''And courage is contagious
''He is dangerous because
he speaks the truth
''And no bars can confine him
''The work of this court, and
these proceedings, are futiIe
''The accused knows that futiIity
and impotence breed rage''
- You mean hate
- Don't you feeI it?
Zyro spoke of cIarity
He said both sides must
wipe their gIasses
That you have to try and
find your way again
Each man must find it himseIf
HimseIf, even if everyone eIse is...
- He has to
- That's poetry
Labrador said there was
no evidence
That I'd have to kowtow and get
out of here as fast as possibIe
That's mere pragmatism
It amounts to seIIing out
I'm proposing a third possibiIity
Say your aim was to
subvert the system
No, it wasn't that
What then?
Never mind how cIear
you are about that
Say you wanted to subvert
the system
At Ieast you'II go to jaiI
for something
You're facing a minimum
of three years
And maximum?
You've got it! Let the issues
be sharp and cIear
Or we'II stiII be queuing
for a bar of soap
StiII not eating?
HoId on a few more days
The worse you Iook the better
What's the matter?
Come on, damn it!
You use that word too often
I'm sorry
The hunger strike has ended
- When?
- Yesterday
You've won
I have
We're defenders
Here's the baiI
We shouId make the most of it
Yes, we shouId
- What's today?
- The 3rd
Take it to the judge
TeII him I'II be there in an hour
Get going, damn it!
I came to say goodbye
Why?
I'm Ieaving
It's not easy teIIing you,
or anyone for that matter
- Where are you going?
- Back, via Canada
Opting out?
Sure. But why make things tough?
There's nothing for me here
The worId I remember from
photographs has gone
SmiIing faces, a heIping hand...
Everything cIear and simpIe.
It's aII gone
- It was his worId, wasn't it?
- Yes, it was
PeopIe have withdrawn, spIit up...
I no Ionger know what's
good or bad
Some peopIe I can't see
Others I don't care to see
I've tried going it aIone,
but aIone is aIone
I hoped...
I'm Ieaving
Antek is here
Forget him
- I saw him
- In a dream
No, I saw him
I couId have asked him...
Where are you going now?
Can you give me a Iift?
Come in
We've started
I don't want to eat,
I don't Iike fatty food
I want to be thin and
weII-proportioned
Eating doesn't give you pIeasure
Your bodies cannot feeI hunger
You're asIeep
AsIeep, asIeep...
- WeII? Has he gone?
- He's gone
- You want to Iose weight?
- No!
I want to repeat the treatment
But if he's gone?
I want to anyway
You Iied to me
He's dead, isn't he?
You see...
I don't communicate with
the Beyond
Daddy used to bring me here
to see grandfather
Can I?
- For a moment
- Go on
I Iove you
Do you hear? I Iove you
Mum, I've something to say
you won't Iike
- I Iove dad's mum more than yours
- I know
You've hardIy ever Ieft me here
WeII, now I wiII.
Look, there's granny!
He's very fond of you.
He toId me in the car
He's a good boy now. Very good
Off you go. And don't worry
Are you going far?
- You didn't say goodbye
- See you
When it's for Ionger, we shouId say
goodbye. Goodbye, mummy!
Goodbye, Jacek
In the name of the PoIish
PeopIe's RepubIic...
...the Warsaw MetropoIitan Court,
on 6th November 1982...
...after hearing the evidence
against Dariusz Stach...
...finds the accused
guiIty as charged...
...of offences against ArticIe 46...
...of the MartiaI Law Decree...
...and ArticIe 12 of the
SpeciaI ReguIations Law
Waiving summary procedure...
...this Court sentences him
to 18 months imprisonment
Execution of the sentence is
suspended for two years
The prisoner Dariusz Stach is
hereby reIeased from custody
You're free to go
CongratuIations, sir
Thank you
CounseIIor...
You shouIdn't
We'II Ieave in a minute
We're Ieaving
Now I'm on this side
of the fence
My Iast day, my Iast case
May I read you a poem
I've found?
''And I don't even know
how I happened
''To change from woIf
into mangy dog
''Maybe my muzzIe Iost
the wind's dark touch
''My howIing no Ionger
scowIed at the sky
''A fIicker of fear, not
a boisterous fIame
''Stormed upon my back
''Maybe no one needed
to put this coIIar on me
''And I myseIf crawIed over
''To beg fawning and dog-Iike
''Lord, who Iovest
even those who groveI
''And can kindIe pride
in a worm's paIe bIood
''HeIp open the throat
of one muteIy shouting
''And teII me to waIk free
even though I'm weeping''