"No Regrets For Our Youth"
The Manchau Revolution created
an excuse for the warlords.
To expand their imperialism.
In order to unite the thought of
the people.
They suppressed the opponents.
An example is
"the Jingto University Case".
The roles in this film are
virtually created.
"Jingto".
Hun.
Teacher.
Father.
Smell of the soil is so refreshing.
The sky is so beautiful too.
The wind is so soft.
This makes people feel relaxing.
Here we can see the University.
The freedom is the Jingto University.
You are a free, prosperous place
for pursuing knowlege.
Now it's time to freely
pursue knowledge.
The Manchau Revolution
created Fascism.
Wild has begun to teach again.
Sze, is there any rehersals?
I saw some soldiers.
I like to listen this music best.
The rhythm makes people comfortable.
How's that?
Any camels?
So tired.
Since you walked too fast.
"Year 8".
Freedom in the school is collapsing.
The problematic Prof. Pak is fired.
Professors feel angry to the Minister.
We must protect the school
even we have to withdraw.
Jingto Uni Student Association.
The Japanese warlords are
supported by the rich.
To make the Manchau in China
become a semi-colony.
By using the warrior way.
To solve the thought problem.
That I believe is the real problem.
You say is always the same.
Talk all about the Manchau
Revolution, warlords and the rich.
I hate the leftists.
Since it's a chain relationship.
To realise the warrior idea.
To compulsively unite all
the different thoughts.
My dad is a man of freedom,
not an opponent.
Person against warrior idea is said
to be an opponent.
My dad is absolutely right.
The right-minded must win.
You dad had said the same.
And the professors resigned to
beg the Minister to self-exam.
But the Minister is the leader of
the powerful party.
It is normal for him to cooperate
with warlords and suppress thoughts.
It's stupid to ask him to regret.
So what do you think good?
To say the cause of this case.
Caused by the militarism.
So it's right to fight against
the militarism.
We can't convince the teacher.
The final loser is the University.
You look happy to wait
for the result.
I said that for I hope they win.
However the teachers can't see that.
Only use the childish thought
for failure.
Please stop this embarrassing
conversation.
Never thought the world of
many problems.
It should have a happy side.
Sze, I tell you some good news.
Please follow me.
This is your pitfall.
Why don't you seriously listen
to the others?
So you can see your
beautiful world.
Full of caring.
Never try to fall, never grow up.
Though your criticism makes me
feel hard.
But the frank say is the most
beautiful words.
Or it's a bubble.
Sze, give me the book.
- Wanna go home?
- Yes.
Please send my regards to teacher.
He's coming, let's have dinner?
I have something to do.
Really?
- Are you back?
- Wanna go back?
Don't say that again.
Do you know the Minister is
proud of himself?
Even no regrets to cancel
all the degrees?
You are so great.
The professors at the North-east
University would be in danger.
Perhaps the teacher would not agree.
Anyway I'd stay firm.
The brave deserves admiration.
But it should not conflict with
the role of students.
How?
Need to smoke?
Is it OK?
Sze, please sit down.
And apologise to me.
Apologise for what?
Just to what I said.
Please.
Hurry up?
What are you doing?
Don't do that, forget it.
Don't be angry with Wild.
He's rude to everyone.
He just tells the truths.
If it were you, you'd not say.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm also a follower of
academic freedom.
How can we keep silent now?
No energy to fight if you're hungry.
He's something good.
I like this guy.
If I were a girl, I ought to
be with him.
"Student Associations united".
"The truth is of academic freedom".
"To protect academic freedom".
"Don't let the friends at Jingto
University be teased".
"To firmly protect the school".
"Student must be united for the
freedom of speech".
"Detest the firm policies of Arts".
"lnitiate collapse of prof.-ship".
"Some profs must resign".
"Make use of the name of reborn
to fight against".
"To firmly protect the school".
"Object the Fascism".
"Minister is talking to the Force".
"Strang [Joint Conference]".
"Arts intends to suppress students".
"Police plan to catch protesters".
"ls academic freedom promised".
"The Head has decide yet".
"The Jingto problem is unclear".
"The Jingto problem is finished".
"Teachers and students are
coming back to school".
How's Wild?
How's Wild now?
We must be stronger.
Don't be tired.
Treat the failure as victory.
Everybody.
Wish you'd think carefully.
We have lost this time.
However everybody.
The justice must win.
Though the flowers wilted this year.
To blossom in the righ time.
No matter what the difficulties.
Most important to learn a lesson.
We fight against the counter party.
In the hard time.
To have the precious experience.
Is what we can't forget.
It's so far from Tokyo.
Even in this far Tokyo.
Under the shine of Fancism.
Self-regulation and freedom
can't stand.
Of course it needs to
avoid self-abandon.
Self-abandon can't solve problems.
We won't be that.
Teacher, we have decided to
fight until we die.
Even we are asked to withdraw.
We have no regrets to a
school without freedom.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot for the support.
But I can't agree with you.
Teacher, why?
Your parents may not allow.
To withdraw before graduation.
What a griving thing.
You're looked after by your sister.
You'd also think about your sister.
Teacher, so what?
Tough I understand you.
Isn't it the band of seven?
Only five left today.
It is rare.
And the absent are the key men.
How are Sze and Wild?
Went to the University.
For three years, for two years.
Although you do not care.
Mum is reckoning.
Finally it's the last year.
But dad can't see it.
Now it's useless to dream.
The assets he left to us.
Frankly we almost finish the savings.
It's good if Wild is here.
Sze is unacceptable.
That guy is always like that
at the critical moment.
How's Sze?
He is a liar.
- Liar?
- No.
Everything is not clear.
What he said today clearly tell us.
How about Wild?
Wild is not coming back again.
Why?
He disappeared one week ago.
Caught by the police?
Released if he's released.
He's not satisfied only
to do activities.
He's a man of perfect.
- Good night.
I am so worried.
Those are the goodness of students.
I mean Hun.
She and Wild...
I feel that she's good to Wlld.
Do they only querrel?
When she's heard of the
leftist activities run by Wild.
You mean Wild?
I am so worried.
I am worried about her.
Has everyone come?
All gone.
What have they decided?
About what?
To bet for studies or activities.
My dad objects seriously.
Great.
So no other objection.
It's so great.
You won't be said of a liar.
I am willing to be a liar.
By doing so I also have some reasons.
You won't understand.
It's so far from Tokyo here.
Even in this far away Jingto Uni.
Under the shine of Fancism.
Self-regulation and freedom
can't stand.
Pain was over yesterday.
"Year 1 3".
Brave to victory.
Promise to go abroad.
How can we die before fighting?
Every time we hear the horn.
The flags are showed like waves.
This is good looking.
Pak's art is outstanding.
This is not possible.
Miss Pak.
How is that?
Teacher said.
Flower art should show
the true side of oneself.
Just follow your thought.
How's that?
Nothing.
Mum.
Perhaps I'll marry Sze.
Just joking.
Hun, I know he's out.
"Please enter this way".
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thanks for worrying about me.
- How much is it?
- The fees.
"Free legal aids".
Anything wrong with the job?
Anything wrong to work for
the public?
I don't mean that.
Teacher was a key man in
the Jingto University case.
Maybe the others discriminate it.
This is lnspector Sze's viewpoint.
Please don't be angry.
No, I may have said too much.
Nothing happened?
Mr. Sze.
What do you think the Sze's work?
It's amazing.
Never think of her outstanding work.
Your way of admiration is special.
She's a girl but like a boy.
The games in primary school.
were all planes, cars etc.
Yes,I'll bring a man here next time.
It may make the family surprised.
Is Wild.
Mum, give me if you don't eat that.
Is Wild good?
He has changed a lot.
I send you to the main door.
Where is teacher?
Academics always leave the guests.
Sorry to bother you.
- Yes, Mr.Sze.
- What?
- About the coming of Mr. Wild.
- Yes.
Is it true?
What do you mean?
I am OK here.
However I think...
- Please don't be that.
- What?
Don't bring Wild here.
Why?
Because l.
Feel scared.
Scared of what?
Wild.
Why?
Foe instance.
The days I follow you are stable.
But it is sorry.
I think the living style
is too simple.
If it's Wild?
If it's with Wild.
I feel the bright shine.
Living would release sharp shine.
Tough it's scary but attractive.
Today's Wild is different.
Five-year made a man changed.
You also changed to be
more matured.
Also the five-year period of Wild.
Is the special period in prison.
It's lucky to be caught.
Recalling makes me sweating.
But it's a good chance
to learn in prison.
Can study pilosophy and arts.
When were you released?
Just a year ago.
Had replacement sentence last winter.
It's hard to be released if
nothing is changed.
This is not wrong.
Sze helps me a lot in lnspection.
To guarantee my lD and
give me a job.
Human are small and weak.
It's unlike the former Wild.
He used to stand higher than I was.
The shine behind me would hurt you.
Hun.
Hun, how's that?
We need to go.
Wild'll go to China and he's
not coming back shortly.
Please come again.
I should not have come.
How's that?
Hun said she's leaving.
Is she leaving?
She's not a child of temper.
Honestly what's happening?
She said she wanted to
live alone in Tokyo.
Why did she say that?
Have you perceived?
Today when she saw Wild leaving?
She finally...
- I know her very well.
- However.
She does the opposite to her thought.
I think Hun loves Wild.
Do you really want to match them?
But Sze hasn't decided when
to take the appointment.
Hun is 25 years old.
Do you think Wlld is serious?
I think it's clear.
This is most important.
I am not interested in this.
So why did you ask if
Wild was serious?
Where is Hun?
She's in the room.
I'm pleased to see her learn
flower arts.
You wait for me here.
- Are you leaving this family?
- Yes.
Now you still haven't decided
like a homeless.
Sit down.
Are you confident to live alone?
I learned foreign languages
and typing.
Maybe I can find a job in business.
It should be OK.
So it can be done in Jingto.
You should think about your mum.
I hate everything now.
I must forget everything.
To find my own way.
This world.
Is unlike what you think to live.
I know.
I only feel meaningless to live now.
At least I wish to know.
What is living?
I must prove it personally.
I have nothing to say for that.
To personally develop my own way.
Indeed it's a important thing.
But Hun.
You must be responsible
for your decision.
It must pass through
fighting for freedom.
And take the responsibility behind.
This point can't be forgotten.
"Year 16".
Left the lecturing room for 8 years.
And I met the prof. again.
It's amazing.
My wife has a flu.
That's no good.
It's not too bad.
Since the leaving of the daughter.
I obviously like to annoy.
How's your daughter?
Did she finally go to Tokyo?
She has been working for the firm.
But the business isn't good enough.
And said wishing to go to China.
To China?
She's also unhappy.
But I see the feeling.
"Tokyo".
Hun, is it Hun?
Good to see you here.
- Haven't seen you for a long time.
- Neither Have l.
I heard you came to Tokyo.
How about you?
I was sent to here.
Are you in a hurry?
No.
Have dinner together?
I wish to talk to you.
I am married.
Going to be daddy.
Congratulations.
This is a way to thank parents.
We have separated for a long time.
Remember the trip to Hill Gut?
That's also long time ago.
I will come by myself.
We were young.
Please not make a mistake.
And don't mind.
It's unforgettable.
Honestly speaking.
"Proposal on Sino-Chinese Problems".
Did you see Wild then?
He's now in Tokyo.
You know nothing about that?
There's a sign in Chuk.
"OPEC Study".
Very obvious.
He's the speakman for the Problems.
And trusted by the financial sector.
It's hard to tell.
You are clever to follow him.
His living style makes
people jealous.
Since he likes to climb hills.
Three of us used to play and talk.
But I was a companion only.
Please.
A guest.
Did not say the name.
Was a girl.
Where is the guest?
Did your parents let you do it?
When was it?
- Leaving home?
- Yes.
The day you visited my home.
Which day?
It was three years ago.
And I changed three jobs.
Anyway it's for the living.
I really wish it comes true.
Do somthings that make me take part.
My dad told me before I left home.
At the back of the beautiful freedom.
Is to take the painful responsibility.
I wish to have a job like this.
This is a difficult question.
Can a man come across it in life?
Same as whether luck enough
to see the Fortune Bird.
Wild.
Do you have any secrets in heart?
Please tell me.
I really want to know.
For I know that must be a good thing.
You look different.
How would you imagine my business?
Don't scold me again.
I was like this before.
No matter what I'd imagine for it.
But now...
I am stupid.
Suddenly shout for the secrets.
I am very embarrassing.
Treated as I said nothing.
- But Sze is so worried.
- Sze?
Perhaps it's nothing.
Just you work here.
Don't know if it's OK.
What do you mean?
Not necessary to know.
Really?
I don't quite understand.
My work here is under monitor.
I am afraid that I need to use
the tunnel to quit.
Now it is not as easy as before.
What does he want to do to you?
Not being good.
Perhaps this moment is coming soon.
So I must try to do.
Hun...
I am afraid the day is coming.
The road ahead is rough.
Don't worry.
I am not scared.
Why do you come?
I have said it clearly.
Useless.
To me.
Must save every minute every second.
Save the time to be with you.
How?
To sew this cloth.
Don't know whether you have
a chance to dress.
Return?
Have you written to dad?
Why?
Don't know what to write.
Tell him I have a happy family?
I feel sorry to him.
And the Mrs. Master and you.
Why?
Recall the living with no regrets.
Are these our words?
No matter how painful.
The present living makes
me feel worthy.
I just feel difficult to write.
Look at the cloud.
Still remember?
Is it Hill Gut?
That time we were young.
To protect the freedom in school.
What?
That little worm.
Very beautiful.
The little spots are fantastic.
Finished one important thing.
I really feel happy.
Let's celebrate.
That's good.
Although I don't know what's that.
But I am also happy.
That's not relevant.
You don't need to know why.
Just to support me.
Thanks.
What we are doing now in 1 0 years.
Will be appreciated by Japanese.
Do you understand?
How?
What is it?
This thing?
This is my weakness.
Weakness?
My heart is the weakest.
Inconvenient to let me know?
You have the right to know.
Is about my parents.
We haven't seen for ten years.
It should be said that we can't see.
In the childhood I was scared of dad.
And scared of mum to make cry.
Really thought myself so pity.
These problems with
parents and children.
Give me some hints to my current job.
Indeed what I want to have.
Is the living with no regrets.
I need to go abroad once.
Return before dinner time?
Certainly.
Let me buy you a gift.
I also prepare a great dinner
for you.
I'll be back soon.
Return?
If you want to go home early,
just tell us the truth.
Anyway we have the evidence.
When did you go with Wild?
When to become the lady of Wild?
Open the mouth to speak.
Have enough time for you.
Disguisting.
As stubborn as Wild.
Do you want to see him?
But what he is planning is a revenge.
Have you given up? Right?
He's been the spy.
It may be hard for him.
Wild used to be great.
You may be interested in what I said.
Special News.
Navy Army Headquarter
8/1 2 announcement.
The Army at the West
Pacific Ocean in the morning on 8th.
Ready to fight with British and USA.
"Year 1 6 December 8 Monday".
Pak Hun, come out.
Hun.
"A revenge of international spys".
"The Head is the researcher Wild".
"Tokyo Regional lnspection".
Sorry to make you worried.
My wife sends you regards.
No, I am afraid I can't help you.
I am the defending man for Wild.
Wild?
The detials are similar to your say.
Why all Wild does is said spying.
Sze, I have left the lecture room
for ten years.
What have you done?
I wanted to guide the hot bloody.
- I want to help Wild...
- Teacher.
I must do this way.
- Although I am not young.
- Teacher.
I've decided to be
his defending lawyer.
Wild was suddenly dead in the prison.
Hun...
Hun.
Can you listen to dad?
Don't say anything.
- But Hun.
- Stop saying.
Stupid.
Aren't you Wild's wife?
Think about the meaning
of Wild's fight.
Also in order to save Japan to
give up himself.
You'd be proud of your companion.
WHen you left home.
Weren't you prepared?
To take responsibility for freedom.
What do you plan to do?
- We need to go to Wild's home.
- Wild's home.
But Hun...
Now only his parents are left.
But they won't come back
for the cropse.
So I need to go Wild's home.
Do you need to go now?
Hun, calm down.
I am Wild's wife.
What have I done wrong?
To deserve this punishment.
This being revenged son.
How can I see the relatives?
But that's a good thing.
Give me, there's nothing we can do.
You stay here.
We'll come back soon.
All the windows are knocked by dad.
Our living is like in the hell.
"Home of spys".
Just to let me stay.
I'll do everything.
No matter what it is.
- Don't say that.
- No.
However our living style.
Is totally different from you.
You mean I can't do it?
It's OK if you teaches.
Just let me try.
Although it is.
I am prepared.
Although we want to do, we can't.
Do you know what the
neighbours talk about my family?
We are treated as a spy.
Please let me stay.
I am Wild's wife.
Please.
I won't go back.
Won't go back.
This being revenged son.
I am Wild's wife.
What are you doing?
Dad asks where are you going?
If I don't wait until night.
I'll be teased.
Hun.
Spy...
Mum.
What?
To recall the living with no regrets.
Don't forget the
responsibility for freedom.
What we are doing now in ten years.
Will be appreciated by Japanese.
Do you understand?
To recall the living with no regrets.
Hun.
Today I need to wake up
early to farm.
How about you?
Don't do it if you are sick.
Nothing.
Morning.
Your head is combed like hot water.
I don't care.
Look.
We have farmed a lot.
Hun...
Don't keep quiet whole day.
Just talk to her.
Talk about some minor things.
She works so hard for us.
This rich wife does not blame.
To farm for us.
Why do you pretend blind?
Lung is also...
Why would it be that?
Who did it?
Did the neighbours destroy our farms?
Why were the neighbours so angry?
Where is Hun?
Where are you going?
Hun.
"Spy can go in".
Old dad.
Animals.
Disguisting.
That's the result from our country.
Hun.
Excuse me.
Is Wild's home nearby?
The surname is Wild.
Shocking.
Really shocking.
In fact auntie asked me to come.
I disagree you are put in the farm.
Wild is unfortunate to go
the wrong way.
But you don't need to follow.
I can't win you.
It can be said that passion.
That strong life makes me shamed.
I always talk to uncle and auntie.
To worry you is the stupid.
Please tell me where
the Wild's grave is.
I decided to wipe his grave
by the way.
Not necessary.
Maybe normal people would thank you.
But I won't.
Even Wild wouldn't feel happy.
Perhaps in the eye of lnspector Sze.
Only is a unfortunate guy.
Which is the right way?
Time will give me a judgment.
"Lost Freedom reborn day".
I wish he'd see the scene today.
Fight for the freedom in school.
Fight for the peace and
blessing for Japanese.
The brave heros.
He's the pride of our school.
That Mr.Wild has passed away.
But the great spirit of Wild.
Would be with us forever.
I expect there'll be many Wilds.
So I decided to step on the
lecture room again.
Very quiet.
How many years like this?
The things happened over
last ten years are like a dream.
The current things are the same
as the previous things.
Today dad is also going to school.
If you want to stay.
Everything at home is
the same as before.
Anyway do you need to go?
If Wild's parents all understand.
Is your target fulfilled?
I have set up a home there.
Mum, please look.
The hands putting on the piano
doesn't match.
And the work at village is plenty.
The living of farmers
especially the girls.
Is especially hard.
I hope I can help to improve.
That's my value to live.
I am a village culture supervisor.
You really were born to work hard.
Why?
I never think about it.
- However.
- No.
Don't feel pity to lose.
That's what Wild used to say.
To recall the living with no regrets.
Is what I feel happy.
The red flowers on the hill.
The Summer scene at two sides.
Don't tell the flowers in the city.
The Hill Gut under the shadow
of the moon.
END