All together towards victory
We're going to say NO
For life and for peace
Chile
Happiness is coming
Good morning, Mr. Aníbal.
Two bread rolls, please.
Of course, Ms. Yolita.
Here you go.
Anything else?
Some tea.
Of course.
Two bags?
Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Just one.
We all have a reason to vote NO.
No more poverty.
This man wants peace.
This man is Chilean.
This man fights for what he believes.
They have the right to live in peace
and work for what they believe in.
Our nation will be great
when no Chilean is afraid
of any other Chilean.
Chile will be great
when everyone has a place
in our homeland.
So this never happens again.
In war, everyone is afraid.
Peace is achieved in democracy.
This is a voting paper.
With it, you will be able to express
your decision, freely and in secret
on October 5th.
Don't miss this event.
Go and vote.
Without hatred, without violence,
and without fear.
No more.
Vote NO.
Now the YES option will use
its 15 legal minutes.
This is the most important part.
What's going on?
A horizon of hope
Born from an unforgotten September
Made us masters of this legacy
That we promised to defend
A voice that flows like wind
Makes the YES in our consciences grow
We have a country
A winning country
YES! In democracy and freedom
The people and you
Pinochet!
Makes this hope possible
Today, victory has a name
President Pinochet!
YES!
We want
every worker
to achieve their maximum
to be always respected
to become a homeowner
and never again a proletariat.
This is my commitment.
Did you know that on average,
Chilean children
are today taller and heavier?
A winning country
YES!
On July 3 1986,
I was coming home from work,
when they announced
a peaceful protest.
The bus I was traveling in
was attacked by terrorists.
Many innocent people were injured.
I suffered burns
on my face and on my hands.
We could say many things
after watching these horrifying images.
But we will only say one:
think.
In the country of the NO,
there's no respect,
neither for your possessions,
nor for your future,
nor your security.
When you vote,
think about everything you could lose.
Think about what you cherish the most,
your loved ones.
A winning country
YES!
Our campaign is a piece of garbage.
It's appalling.
We're throwing our money away.
I don't think it's that bad.
It's more serious than the others'.
My General was very offended.
They attacked him personally.
It's a mockery.
How can we stop this humiliation?
It would be a scandal.
It would legitimize us
internationally.
That's what the referendum is for.
I don't understand
what the problem is.
The strategy's driving force
was its economic achievement.
It has nothing to do with that.
We can't fight universal principles
like joy or that dumb campaign,
a rainbow,
with a film about fruit exports.
We have strictly followed
the client's guidelines.
The two premises were:
that no-one would see the campaign,
and the president couldn't lose.
Minister, you said
the campaign didn't matter.
The president is going to win anyway.
Let's cut the bullshit.
For fuck's sake.
Guzman will from now
be in charge of the campaign.
It's an honor, Minister.
We'll deal with those bastards later.
Don't worry, Sir.
The NO film'll run out of steam
in a couple of days.
These people are using
advertising tricks, you see?
We have to work on one axis:
who is capable of governing,
and who isn't.
We must carry out an audit immediately.
I'm sorry, Guzman, but...
what do you mean by that?
That we're going to screw them.
Excuse me?
We're going to screw them.
Our Father, Holy God
today we bless Your name...
The fraternal, progressive climate
created by Pinochet's government
has meant
that in April 1987,
Pope John Paul II
will finally visit
our country.
Do not be afraid to look at Him!
Your campaign is a copy.
Love always conquers!
A copy of the copy of the copy
of the copy
of the copy of the copy.
Fine.
We didn't copy.
You mixed rainbows, pretty people,
blonde children skipping,
celebrating I-don't-know-what.
A tall man who's 15 feet tall.
Where did you find him?
Denmark?
Who is that guy?
Us Chileans are small.
Who are all these people laughing,
celebrating? Celebrating what?
Us getting screwed
in the referendum?
I don't know where you think you are.
We should do something.
I don't want to fuck.
After, you'll make a scene.
Don't say that!
We've done nothing for years.
You've got a bad memory.
What?
Last time, you didn't want to do it.
Simon was there.
He was sleeping.
This is a normal scene
in the life of this man.
At sunrise or sunset.
He always works tirelessly.
His time, his energy,
the sacrifice of incomprehension,
he gives it all to his initial cause.
In his words:
"For Chile, everything."
Don't get up.
Shit, I've got to go.
Why don't you stay?
I can't.
Simon needs you.
I fell asleep, that's all.
Don't get confused.
Go on.
Stay.
What for?
Did you pay the school?
Yes.
With my Allende Foundation grant.
Stop it.
Bye.
Stay.
We're pulling Pinochet off the screen.
You agree?
Let's protect him.
Too many soldiers.
Too many tacky women.
Tacky?
Too tacky, too fat.
Too many colonels' wives.
You don't have enough material.
Let's talk about them.
About the politicians?
No, them.
Their campaign is very funny.
It's amusing.
Shall we add a little humor?
Say YES!
Dear NO supporters,
don't waste your time with lies
and fantasies
as you have up until now.
To us,
it is a duty
to expose to the country
some of the NO camp's lies.
THE LIE
"Mrs. Yolita" ad.
THE TRUTH
The protagonist was paid.
She has 3 houses,
and one business property.
God, how awful!
We're not going to respond.
Who is doing this?
OK?
I'm going.
All right, good luck.
Call me when you get home, OK?
It's really annoying.
What happened?
They followed me.
Everybody calm down.
They're just trying to scare us.
It's too dangerous.
Do we have any empty boxes?
Or tapes?
Yes, we do.
Here.
We'll leave with this,
all at the same time.
Let me go out first.
Hand me the original.
You're sure?
The National TV Council?
Come in.
This is the NO campaign.
Sign the form.
Here?
Yes.
And I'll give you...
a receipt.
Receipt.
Very well.
Sir...?
René Saavedra.
Thank you.
Tomorrow's.
TORTURE IN CHILE
THE TV IS SILENT
Those who have appeared
number more than 50.
All of them tortured by the CNI.
These people have endured
endless torture sessions,
lasting days at a time
and into the night,
until 3 or 4 in the morning.
They are then thrown,
like useless pieces of trash,
onto the cot in their cells.
They rest for a few hours
only to start all over again.
Without hatred.
Without violence.
Without fear.
No more.
There's a call from the CANT.
What is it concerning?
Good.
Don't worry.
Goodbye and thank you.
Tomorrow's program can't be aired.
The judge's section
breaks the law.
The judge?
You put the judge in?
We're changing nothing.
This is censorship.
We have to go on air.
Or people will get scared.
Let's hold a press conference,
and denounce it...
I'm sick of your fucking denouncements!
We must be more creative
and turn this around.
NO CENSORSHIP
Chile
Happiness is coming
Hello.
Through these programs,
we have realized
that it's important
to say things how they are.
Expressing oneself
and talking is a good thing.
Censorship is pointless.
Why censor?
But for 15 years,
a large part of this country
was prevented from
doing what we've done
on this show.
NO-EWS
Public opinion
has unanimously condemned
the censorship
of the opposition's television program.
During last Monday's NO campaign,
a judge was prevented from appearing
who confirmed the CNI's involvement
in over 50 cases of torture.
It was wrong.
Why?
Because they are hiding
what really happened.
It's very frustrating. Very.
You realize everything is fake.
It's an outrage,
a daily outrage.
The government
is afraid of us knowing the truth.
They wanted to stop the NO show.
It's unfair.
It is bad.
They just do what they want.
Yet another injustice.
It doesn't suit them
for the truth to be known.
Why don't we have the right to see
what has been going on in this country?
Democratically, we have the right
to be freely informed.
That's what I think.
How are you, Saavedra?
How's Simon?
I like your little train.
Simon?
Are you ok?
Yes.
Hi, darling.
Hi, Mommy.
Hello.
How are you?
Here.
Be a good boy.
OK.
Listen to your mother.
Don't go out by yourself,
you hear me?
They're doing this
because you hit the old man hard.
I love you, sweetie.
It's all good. Congratulations.
Hello.
Did you have breakfast?
No.
Would you like some?
No, thanks.
If you need anything, just let me know.
You work with the YES camp?
No.
No, it's...
it's just advisory.
Did you see it?
There's a change
in the conceptual strategy.
Did you like it?
It's bad.
Real bad.
It's awful, Lucho.
It's a huge pile of shit.
It's the copy of the copy
of the copy of the copy of the copy.
It's all mixed together there.
How will people remember this campaign?
The employees made the NO campaign,
and you bosses made the YES one.
That's how it's going to be.
We're going to screw you.
So shut up, asshole,
and look after your son.
Don't threaten me.
I'm just saying.
If they want cash, let me talk.
Hello.
Hello René.
How are you?
Shall we go?
How's it going, Pedro?
"Beautiful"
in a classic, powerful font.
And "Bold" in something youthful,
more playful.
Most viewers
will watch this soap opera.
What we want to do
is produce a marketing event
to present the soap opera
Beautiful and Bold
on the Santa Maria tower.
We want to avoid
a typical soap opera ad
filmed with crappy lighting.
It makes it look cheap and ugly.
We want to create a news story,
and insert it under camouflage,
into the evening news program.
Perfect!
The girls will be on the terrace,
on the heliport.
All the actresses,
dressed in their best clothes,
doing a photo shoot.
We can reuse
the pics from the shoot.
We can use them twice.
We'll also have the soap's heartthrobs,
the actors, dressed like...
James Bond.
But with more of an "action" feel
and more modern.
We'll have
the models and the actresses
showing off their best features.
And a helicopter
flying around the tower
with the soap opera's main heartthrob
leaning right out with
a bunch of roses for the girls.
Wave to them!
No, the election is under control.
Don't worry, Guzman.
But they're making noise.
They could hinder any measures you take.
They'll happen anyway.
Ensure their name is mud,
expose those clowns for what they are.
This will upset the NO camp.
Who are all these people?
We couldn't find any artists.
They're all with them.
This is all that's left.
The bottom of the barrel.
That's enough. I'm leaving.
The idea is that,
no matter what your option is,
or who you vote for,
ou pour qui vous votez,
the important thing is what you feel
through these TV programs.
The lady
will ask questions
and the idea is to build a debate.
The NO camp seem too serious,
too strange.
They talk about problems
that concern old people.
Matilde,
tell us about the YES campaign.
I thought it was too violent
and underhand.
Underhand...
What is your name?
We need more testimonials.
No, more humor.
Did you like the NO campaign?
To make it more fun and more inclusive.
Be careful with that letter!
Turn off that light!
Pay attention for a moment!
Thank you all for coming.
We're very happy.
The soldiers will be proud
to see their musicians, actors,
and artists committed to the NOs.
We can shoot.
24 frames per second
with a 2.8 lens.
Closer, Marco Antonio, please.
Let's do it.
We must put on a good show.
OK? Show me happiness.
Sound?
Rolling.
Camera?
Speed.
36, take one!
Mark.
Action!
Chile, happiness is coming!
This land
was not a propitious place
for warlords and strikes.
The new democracy...
Is it OK?
Or not?
No.
It's no good.
He abandons his uniform
for regular clothes.
After so much hatred and threats,
he now offers peace.
He is alone.
He alone speaks.
What would you say to a dictator?
15 years ago,
the dictatorship began here,
and we've had it up to here!
But it ends now.
My love, say yes.
No.
Say it for me.
Come on, say yes! Please.
All right then, NO!
If the YES camp triumph,
everything will be much better,
according to the results
of the latest polls.
What were the results?
YES wins.
A winning country.
YES!
Comrade
Happiness is coming!
Destroy everything
For life and for peace!
Have you seen the time?
We had stuff to do.
...with the power of my voice
We're going to say NO
I sing it without fear
Together victorious
Tous ensemble pour gagner
We're going to say NO
For life and for peace
A Marxist dressed in velvet
is still a Marxist!
Chile
Happiness is coming!
Today, huge rallies
closed the electoral campaigns.
The YES camp
held huge celebrations
for the arrival
of President Pinochet.
There's a carnival-like atmosphere.
You can feel the joy
on Bernardo O'Higgens Boulevard.
Thousands of people
have come together to say YES.
They support Pinochet
and will return a big majority
on October 5th.
Foreigners
have refused to film
these scenes of joy.
They refuse to show
Pinochet's thousands of supporters.
Meanwhile,
the NO supporters marched today
to where the freeway
meets the road in Santiago.
The main speaker there
was the spokesman
for the NO coalition
and Christian Democrat leader,
Patricio Aylwin.
I've said it clearly:
if the referendum is held
under the correct conditions,
we will accept the result,
whatever it is.
NO to hunger!
NO to exile!
NO to violence!
NO to suicide!
We will dance together for this NO
We will dance together for this NO!
We ask the authorities
to not attack us!
Fuck, my car!
Remain calm!
Here! Give me your hand!
No violence!
Please!
We ask the authorities...
Come! Close your eyes!
What's happening, Daddy?
Murderers! Murderers!
What are you doing?
Why are you there?
Go home!
Hold on tight!
Come on! Let's go!
Daddy!
Give me your hand!
Get in! And stay here!
And Mommy?
Did you hear me? Stay here!
Take Simon home!
Where are you going?
Where are you going, Saavedra?
She's my wife!
Go home.
Hello.
The officer in charge?
Yes, Colonel.
She's here, they told me.
Thanks, Lucho.
Don't worry,
I'd have done it for any of my people.
Happiness, huh?
My congratulations.
Unbeatable.
Thank you very much.
It's quite alright.
Hello. This is our last program.
For the last 27 days, I've been here
showing you the whole of Chile.
This morning, we'd like to say
while you stay at home and rest,
NO to hatred,
NO to violence.
And in this message, we are not alone.
Remember that the ballot is secret
and the future of your country
is in your hands.
The pain of Chile over these long years
has been the pain of all of us.
We'll be with you in our hearts
on October 5.
NO-EWS
Which flags do you sell most of?
YES or NO ones?
NO ones mostly.
Do the YES ones sell?
A little. Not much.
How many badges sold today?
1,500 NO badges.
And 50 YES ones.
More NO ones.
That's why I've only got NO things here.
That's what sells best.
This program is coming to an end.
We've run out of time.
From now on,
you will only hear the official opinion.
Freedom for Chile and its TV coverage
now depends on you.
Happiness is in your hands.
See you soon.
THE YES CAMP WILL USE
ITS 15 LEGAL MINUTES
My love,
say YES.
Honey, it's NO.
Tell me YES.
Come over here.
YES!
In the other campaign,
this ends with a NO.
In this campaign,
it ends with a YES.
You choose!
Consider that this country
has a great future ahead of it!
Great expectations!
Don't throw it all away.
I don't recommend myself.
You judge.
If I did wrong, forgive me.
But if you do the math,
it adds up pretty positively.
A winning country...
YES!
In compliance...
with the laws
governing the electoral process,
the TV channels have been integrated
into the state channel.
From now on,
retransmissions can continue
separately.
Long live Chile and Pinochet!
Of course.
You have a call.
Excuse me.
Go right ahead.
Don't worry.
Everything's fine.
Where will you celebrate?
With the family...
and friends.
Are you confident?
The little campaign's over.
It's now a matter of state.
Let them dance a while.
Are you celebrating?
Yes.
Are you going to eat?
From north to south,
the best team.
All the news and information
from where it happens,
across the entire country.
Televisión Nacional of Chile.
Across the capital
and the rest of the country,
voting booths were set up
early in the morning.
The public,
following official recommendations,
began arriving to vote
from first light,
causing some traffic jams
in certain areas.
A few minutes before 11am,
the President exercised
his right as a citizen,
voting at table number 1.
The images show the Head of State
completing each stage of the process.
Patricio Aylwin Azocar voted
at table number 16.
91, 92, 93,
94, 95, 96...
The Undersecretary of the Interior
is on the podium.
I shall now read
the third official count
by the Ministry of the Interior
which is currently announcing
a 57.36% YES vote,
and a 40.54% NO vote.
He can't give those results.
Of course they want to win,
but they can't.
They can't, right?
I don't think so.
Easy, now.
I didn't want to say it out loud,
but apparently, the old fucker
refuses to accept the results.
The cops are leaving.
I don't understand.
Maybe Ricardo knows...
They've all gone?
Simon!
Come.
It's a self-coup!
Get out the torches.
They want to screw us!
We have to back up the computers.
What's the procedure?
For those counting votes by hand,
you are each responsible.
They're robbing us!
There's foreign journalists everywhere.
So?
It'll be OK.
Will the foreigners help?
We need help!
Let's call some journalists!
International help or we're screwed!
This is critical.
We cannot lose.
José Tomás!
Listen!
Our parallel count shows that we won.
This can't go on.
They're trying to buy some time.
This may keep happening
more and more frequently.
We don't know anything either.
Fucking military!
The TV, please!
...outside the Moneda Palace,
where all the generals are arriving.
They've been summoned
to an emergency meeting
by President Pinochet.
General Matthei!
Does the government have the results?
To me, it really looks like
the NO vote has won.
It seems pretty clear to me now.
That was the General of the Air Force,
Fernando Matthei...
The generals are abandoning Pinochet.
They're forcing him
to recognize the victory.
So that means...
this thing is over.
Shit, we won!
We won!
Really?
Yes! We won!
The YES vote won
43.04%.
The NO vote won
54.68%.
Today, a new Chile is born.
Fairer and more unified,
with no privileges;
we all have the right
to think different...
Bravo!
Where we all have
the same opportunities.
Because after this long day,
without a single drop of blood shed,
we have overthrown this dictatorship
simply by saying, loud and clear, NO!
Therefore...
long live Chile!
Chile
Happiness is coming!
Did you see that?
Up there!
Thank you.
We are happy. Chile wins.
It's a triumph,
a personal triumph
that represents
a choice, I would say...
We don't have to impose our opinions.
People are taking to the streets
to celebrate the NO vote winning
over 54% of the total vote.
Thousands of people are there.
Who doesn't jump for joy? Pinochet!
I'm going to leave you with René.
He will present the piece.
René is one of the main creators
of the successful NO campaign.
Thank you, Lucho.
Well...
First of all,
I'd like to say
that what you're about to see
fits with the current social context.
We believe the country is ready
for communication like this.
Absolutely.
Let's be honest:
Today,
Chile is thinking about its future.
Alright?
Shall we?
Santa Maria tower's heliport
welcomed
10 women in formal gowns
and 5 men who admired their beauty.
Suddenly,
the soap opera's hero, Estéban Greve,
played by Osvaldo Silva,
appeared in a helicopter
offering a bunch of flowers
to these Beautiful and Bold women.
These James Bond-style images
will be used to promote
the state channel's new soap opera.
My name is Kiki Blanche.
I have 5 children,
I own a hair salon,
and I was a dancer
at the Bim Bam Boum.