Listen. Um,
I had a great time sitting
next to you on the plane.
Silver Lake, right?
Every morning, as I drive away,
I am reaching back for you.
It is a helpless feeling,
this wishing, this wanting,
this knowing you will arrive...
just minutes after I have gone.
Well, I thought that
was really freakin' good.
All right. All in favor
of including this piece...
in our spring issue,
raise your hand.
Nearly unanimous.
And our author, Kolt.
Sylvia Plath would be proud.
Congratulations.
Thanks, dude.
Hi.
Hey.
- Um, hello. I'm Martine.
- Hello.
Hey. Hi.
I'm Peter.
Let me grab this for you.
Come on in.
Thanks.
Julie can't wait to meet you.
What's making you feel
so powerless?
I'm way too afraid
to even approach a woman...
that might be on
my intellectual level.
I know what you're gonna say.
It's not 'cause
I'm afraid she'll reject me.
I'm afraid I'll reject her.
Okay.
Why is that?
You know, a lot of smart women
think too much to look good...
and talk too much to fuck well.
I feel like such an asshole
saying these things to a woman.
I do get what
you're saying, actually.
'Cause the movie
comes out this week.
Everyone's acting like I'm supposed
to be excited, but I fucking hate it.
And I wish I could say it looks nothing
like the script I handed them,
but they didn't change
a goddamn line.
I just wrote something
that isn't very good.
We're gonna need to stop.
Don't do this to me, Julie.
I will see you on Wednesday.
There's a lot of life that'll come
out with the sound. There's...
You know,
like the bug's footsteps,
or maybe his breath.
You know, what would it sound like if
you could hear the bug's heart beat?
Or, like, heartache.
What would that sound like?
You know?
Yeah. All right.
I think this'll be fun.
Yeah.
I'm really excited.
Thank you so much for putting
aside time to do this with me.
Absolutely.
So you're working on, like,
a big studio movie right now?
I am, yeah.
They're not picture-locked yet.
So you're in luck.
Hey, Peter, is this a
take-from-the-fruit-bowl night?
Martine, this is Kolt.
Kolt, Martine.
Hi.
Hey.
What is a
take-from-the-fruit-bowl night?
Oh, it just means that everyone's
on their own for dinner.
Nobody's taken responsibility
as of yet.
That's a maybe?
Hey, David.
Oh, hey, Kolt.
Hey.
I'm just getting out of here.
Crazy plans?
Just finishing up
some things for Peter.
How about you?
Lots of homework?
Not really. I already did this
history thing that's due Friday.
Well, it's good
not to procrastinate.
Yeah.
I do anyway sometimes though.
Procrastinate.
Oh, yeah. Of course. I'm giving
you advice I can't take, so...
Eating bark in a tree.
Slow or fast?
Fast.
Wind, and also sand
blowing in the wind.
Sounds that only ants hear.
Ah, need to be more specific. You know what?
We'll come back to it.
Okay, gasping.
Sticky stuff.
Bowling pins.
Blood on pavement.
- Got it.
- Really?
Hey, come on.
An old train.
Okay. Um, bodies rubbing
up against each other.
Okay.
So people having sex?
Yes. But not like, "Uh, uh, uh."
Okay.
Good to know.
Hi, Dad.
Hey, bud.
Hey.
Hi.
Is she coming to eat?
Where is she?
Jet lag.
Is it gonna work out?
I think so, yeah.
She's really sweet.
Good.
I think
she's really talented too.
Hey, who is in the pool house?
Her name is Martine,
and she is a friend
of my friend Miriam's,
and she needed Daddy's help.
- Hey, guess what.
- What?
My poem got into lit mag.
Sweetness, that's fantastic.
- Did you call your dad?
- Not yet.
Well, you know, he wrote poems
before he wrote songs.
And maybe one day, he will
publish some of those poems,
and he can buy us a hot tub.
Wanna get that?
Mm-mmm. No.
- You sure?
- Yeah. One of the kids will get it.
No, they won't.
They always let it
go to the machine.
And you never
check the machine.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
Hello?
Hey, Avi.
No, I don't know where Sea Horse is.
Hold on. Let me check.
Kolt!
It's Avi on line one.
I don't want
to talk to Avi, Peter.
Okay. Why don't you
tell him that yourself?
Firm hand of a parent.
Oh, so good.
Nailed it.
Get the arm in there.
I gotta wash my face.
What?
I have to wash my face.
All right,
the TV's going back on.
Them's the rules.
Hey, where you going?
Class is that way.
Oh, I'm not going.
You want a section? I don't read
Science, Finance or Sports.
Yeah, I'll take Science.
So, um, how's it going
with David?
Hmm?
Oh. Um, it's complicated.
I mean, there's definitely
chemistry, you know,
but the age difference.
And he works for Peter, so...
I think we're both just...
a little afraid of where
it could go, you know?
Well, it's good to be cautious.
You have plenty of time. We're
only, you know, 16.
I hate it when people say that.
I don't know.
What do you think?
Look, sir, we don't need a pool cleaning.
The pool is clean.
I'm looking at it right now.
David.
No, you know what?
Just forget it.
You're crooks anyway.
My assistant.
He's a good guy.
Dusty's been upset
about this dead lizard...
that's been clogging
the drain for like a week now,
and I don't think
the issue's worth $600.
This is our guest, Martine.
She's the bug auteur.
It's nice to meet you.
Excuse me.
Love that guy.
Every time we don't have
a big job going on,
he just tries to fix
what's broken in life.
My life.
Okay, what's next?
Chimes?
And that is the power
of directional microphones.
They're kind of like
magic wands.
Here, come on.
I want to show you something.
All right,
just lay down right here.
Keep the headphones on.
Close your eyes.
You tell me,
what do you think
you're hearing?
All right?
Okay.
I don't know.
It sounds like...
a concert, but far away.
It's the highway.
With those mountains
in the back,
it echoes through
the entire canyon.
- Wanna do another one?
- Yeah.
Close your eyes.
Okay, what about this one?
That sounds like wind
going through trees.
I'll buy that.
Okay.
Tell me what you hear...
now.
But what kind?
I'm tired.
Hey, buddy.
Hey!
Ah, you looking to brawl?
You're Julie.
Wow! Can I hug you?
Yeah, let's hug.
I'm pro-hug.
I can't believe it.
I'm meeting you.
One of the original members of
Miriam's postfeminist wolf pack.
I've seen pictures
of you guys, like,
sitting around swimming pools
looking focused.
It-It seems like
it was an amazing time.
I don't know.
Buonasera.
Ciao, guys.
- Hey, Kolt.
- Hi.
Hi.
Hi. I really
like your jeans.
Thanks.
Do they have zippers on them?
Um, yeah, they...
they do.
Hey, you want to take off?
Uh, yeah, we should.
Um, he's taking me to
my friend's art opening.
Yeah, I... I can't drive.
I'm a New Yorker.
I'm clinging
to that as my excuse.
- Can you drive?
- No.
No, not yet. But we will
be practicing very soon.
Yes, we will.
Okay.
Yeah.
- You hungry, Sea Horse?
- Not really.
Hey, remember. 9:00 a.m.
tomorrow. Actors.
Yes.
I will be there.
And, Julie, I'm sorry that we
didn't get a chance to talk.
- Oh, we will.
- Okay.
Julie, is it possible
to get my check?
Yes. I'm so sorry.
I'll be right back.
There is a
mammal that lays eggs.
Platypus, Avi!
Platypus.
I gotta go.
Thank you for coming
with me tonight.
No, thank you for bringing me.
Um...
I don't think...
that I should
do this right now.
Okay.
I just...
I just got here.
And I'm here to work.
And I think it's smarter
to forgo this type of...
Anyway, this was really nice.
Really nice.
Ah!
Ah.
Mmm.
Martine, you're alive.
Doug. Hey.
Am I waking you up?
Um... God, no.
I've been awake
for a couple hours already.
Everything going all right?
Yeah, it's going great.
Um, I haven't seen it yet.
Um, but as soon as
I get my Internet,
I'm gonna...
No. No, no, no, no.
Yeah, we'll definitely
finish on time.
Okay. All right.
Talk to you later.
Okay.
Ugh.
Hi. I'm...
I'm sorry I'm late.
I, um... I couldn't find the
dialogue that I wrote.
That's okay.
Let's, uh, make
a couple copies of this.
Hi. I'm Martine.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Thanks for coming, guys.
Sure.
Whoo. Okay.
So the reviews are in.
Some great, some good. A few
really hostile ones, of course.
How are the reviews
making you feel?
I don't want to talk
about the reviews.
Okay.
I had a dream last night.
Another one about
your grandmother?
No.
It was about you.
All right.
Am I allowed
to tell you about it?
Of course.
Um, I was on set,
in the house that we shot in...
that weird glass box
in the Valley...
and David Strathairn was eating
cereal out of a megaphone.
I had a break. Something drew
me to one of the bedrooms.
I opened the door...
You were lying on the carpet,
and, um, you were all dressed up
in full lingerie.
You know, lacy bra,
thong, stockings.
Those things that you use to clip
your stockings to your panties.
- I don't remember what they're called.
- Garters.
I was excited.
I walked over,
started to touch you,
softly at first,
and then... more.
You were just ignoring me. You were all
dressed up like you wanted to fuck,
but you were
totally unresponsive.
So I started talking to you.
What were you saying?
I just said,
"Hey, baby. I'm here.
We're not done shooting, but they
don't need me. Do you need me?"
You still didn't respond.
I started to get upset.
I was begging.
Which is not really my style.
I took my pants off. Because I just... I
just needed you to know that I was hard.
And I looked at you
and I said, "I love you."
And then we were fucking.
It was that easy.
Psst. Come over here.
What?
I found it.
Where?
Right here.
On the ground.
- Is it safe?
- It's sticky.
Okay.
Um, I liked that.
Um... Uh...
Ken.
Ken. Yes.
Um, I'm sorry.
Um, I want something
a little harder, I think.
Like you're
a protective husband, um,
but you're a little bit scared.
You're talking about
when I'm asking the question?
Yes.
Um, you're still
soft and scared.
Um, a little less blatant.
Um, like... like... like you're
really asking the question.
But I'm asking the question
because I'm scared?
Right. Um,
but you're not, like,
sitting in your fear.
Um, I just mean, like, um,
y-your fear, um,
it doesn't hinder you.
Like, you fear, yet you're
motivated by your fear.
This is what happened
in the other scene.
We did eight takes
of that, and...
I have no idea what the
difference is between any of 'em.
Well, I think it's good
to just take adjustments.
I'm not an actor who minds
taking adjustments,
as long as a director
is actually saying something.
I mean, have you ever
worked with actors before?
'Cause it seems like
your thing's bugs.
She used to take naked
photos of her boyfriend.
I googled you. I think
they're really beautiful.
Listen. We really
appreciate the help.
All right, you're gettin' paid.
Why don't you do what she says?
You're barely covering my gas.
And she's not
telling me to do anything.
I'm sorry about that.
I'm sorry.
You all right?
Okay, I'm not even
that upset right now.
It's just, like...
I'm sorry, Peter.
I really didn't want
that to happen.
What are you talking about?
You didn't do anything wrong.
That guy just didn't get it.
Ugh.
Hey. Hey.
Are you all right?
Is there something else
goin' on?
Don't be so hard on yourself.
Thank you.
I heard something.
Did you hear something?
I think someone's outside.
It's David.
Okay. Um, I should...
I should go.
- I'm sorry.
- No. No, no, no. It's no trouble.
I don't even know why you're
wasting your time on this.
I want to help.
It's, uh...
I think you're really someone
who's, uh, worth helping, so...
Okay.
Hey, brother.
Hey, man.
Hey.
Are you a free set of hands?
Um, yeah.
I'm a terrible cook though.
That's all right. Just chop
this parsley real quick,
Okay.
and then you can
get back to work.
Getting into it?
What?
Are you getting
a lot of work done?
Oh, yeah. Totally.
Completely.
So much work, yeah.
You know, I just realized
I saw your work once.
At Miriam's.
You were staying there, I think.
Oh, yeah.
She let me keep my, um,
stuff there during the lawsuit.
The lawsuit because your boyfriend
didn't want to be photographed?
Um, well, I guess he felt...
that I manipulated him
into posing naked.
Ouch.
Yeah.
It was not awesome, no.
Um, but I learned a lot.
We don't have to
talk about this.
So, you used to live
in New York?
I did, yeah.
Where do you live?
I used to live in Hell's Kitchen
with my ex-boyfriend,
um, but I'm in Brooklyn now
with roommates.
Two roommates.
What are you, 23?
Yeah.
Twenty-three.
I was going to CalArts.
Sort of.
Why sort of?
Because my main gig
was being a girlfriend.
To Leroy,
who you will meet tonight.
It's not a career
I'd recommend.
It only took me,
I don't know, 20 years
to get my life together.
Just keep doing
what you're doing.
Mmm.
All right, flee.
You're free.
No, this looks good.
Are you sure
you don't need more help?
I'll see you at 7:00.
Okay.
When did you find out
you were gluten intolerant?
I was with, uh, Rod Stewart.
He was, like, having a
dinner party or something.
He was talking about, you know,
this whole gluten thing.
I was like, "Well, tell me,
you know, what is gluten?"
'Cause nobody really knows
what gluten...
Some... I don't know.
I know what it is.
I don't know. Okay, I'm
in the bathroom, right?
And this was, like...
Do you even know
who Peter Frampton is?
These guys don't even know
who Peter Frampton is.
- You know Peter Frampton.
- I know who Peter Frampton is.
Well, he doesn't know. You
never heard of Peter Frampton.
No, I've never
heard of Peter Frampton.
But enough... enough about me.
It's not about me tonight.
To Julie.
For giving me something...
No. For giving me something
like home.
Thank you.
Do you still live in a bus?
Sometimes, dude.
But hopefully not again this year.
I'm so sick of the road.
I'd like to say
thank you to Julie and Peter as well.
- I feel very lucky.
- Oh, it's our pleasure.
You're very welcome.
- Julie, you look beautiful.
- Mmm.
No, seriously. I mean, you look
about the same age as our daughter.
I don't, but thank you.
But you got this big guy over here, huh?
Mr. Handsome.
So, Peter, um,
I hear that your mixing board is
where my practice space used to be?
- Is that right?
- Well, the room was already soundproofed.
I'm glad someone's getting
some use out of it.
- Peter just got a huge studio movie.
- You're kidding.
So he's gonna be
working down in Hollywood.
- Is that right?
- Amazing. That's great, man. That's totally great.
So, Martine,
what do you make?
- What's the inquisition?
- I just want to know. What do you make?
Right now, it's, um...
it's images of bugs.
- Bugs?
- A film, actually.
Peter is helping me
with the sound.
When's your movie come out?
It... It actually
doesn't really come out.
Well, it's gonna be running on
a loop on her first solo show.
A loop?
Which is at a gallery.
It's a big deal.
I don't know about big, but it's
some kind of deal, I guess.
Come on.
Give him the spiel.
It's so much fun to hear you
talk about it. Come on.
Oh, I don't know.
You've got a great thesis statement.
Leroy would appreciate it.
It's basically, uh,
humans versus nature,
and, uh,
the personal versus the...
sort of intricate complexities
of community.
Listen. At the end of it,
what you take away from it is...
What is that e.e. cummings line?
"You can understand a poem
without knowing what it means."
You shouldn't talk
about work around the table anyway.
I learned that the hard way.
Uh, excuse me for a second.
So, baby girl,
your mom tells me that, uh,
you had a poem accepted
to a literary magazine.
Two actually, yeah.
Wow.
Beautiful and smart, huh?
Excuse me.
Tell me. Tell me.
It's amazing.
Yeah. I don't know. I didn't
think they were gonna like both of them.
Just a second.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You don't sound fine.
I remember once I was opening for
Wilco, and I couldn't remember a line.
I sang, like, three songs...
I was just making up the words.
I swear to God, it was awful.
- Yeah.
- She's okay.
What happened? I thought maybe
I offended you or something.
No. I'm sorry.
Um, I'm impossible to offend.
I just, uh...
Um, the tempeh was so good, I...
I forgot I'm allergic to it.
Well, good.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Hey, I have a question.
Mm-hmm.
Is Leroy ever gonna stop wearing
flannel shirts and Doc Martens?
I mean, the guy's like
a cartoon character.
Or like an Amish person.
One outfit? Really?
I mean,
he does have the money...
to get, like,
a variety of apparel.
I think the only reason
why I'm asking is...
I think I was legitimately confused
at dinner as to what year it was.
So you wanna talk about dinner?
What?
You wanna talk about your
little crush on our houseguest?
Excuse me?
What?
Did you not hear me?
No, I definitely heard you.
What are you talking about?
What do you have an issue with?
I don't have an issue...
when you bring your ex-husband over and
make googly-eyes at him all night.
-Give me a break. We have a child together.
-What difference does that make?
I understand
you're attracted to her.
She's attractive.
I'm fucking attracted to her.
Okay. What...
What are we talking about?
Just don't embarrass me.
It just sounds really canned.
Canned?
Yeah, like flat.
Ear fatigue.
It's an actual phenomenon.
Afflicts many.
I think your ears are tired.
I think it's the echo.
Can we just take it out?
I think we need a break.
I think we need to
finish this scene.
Honestly, I think if we come back to
it with fresh ears, it'll be better.
Peter, we really need to,
like, get through this.
Come on.
Okay.
- Listen. About, um...
- Yeah.
the other day
in the pool house...
Look. I'm really sorry.
I...
No, no. I, um...
I find you
incredibly charming...
and intelligent and beautiful.
I respect what you do.
It makes me excited
about what I do.
And I think I just got, uh...
just carried away in that
mix of, uh, feelings.
Peter, it doesn't
have to be a big deal.
We can just pretend
it never happened and...
Marriage is complicated.
I think we should just keep
working on this right now.
Yeah.
Yeah. You're right.
I'm sorry. Your physical presence
this close to me is actually painful.
This house is, like, um,
full of people.
Don't worry about it. This room
is completely soundproofed.
Vroom!
Panino?
Mmm.
I don't know how to say it.
Hmm.
It's called a slip.
You ready for bed?
Where's my cookie?
What cookie?
You ate the last cookie?
No. There are no cookies left.
You suck.
Are you coming to bed,
or are you gonna keep reading?
I'm gonna keep reading.
All right.
My breath just happens to
smell like chocolate...
chip cookies.
Mmm.
Oh, have more.
Do you like Avi?
Well, yeah.
I do.
I think he's really sweet.
Do you like Avi?
I don't know.
I mean, he's certainly not like
my fantasy boyfriend or anything.
Yeah.
Wow. Your dad...
seemed like
the fantasy boyfriend.
But he wasn't.
No. He wasn't.
So then, how do you know when
you've found the right guy?
I don't know that you do know.
I think you're just...
you're ready,
and you pick one.
That's...
really depressing, Mom.
No, I... I don't think
it's depressing. I-I...
I think... I think
people change and, uh...
and you keep changing and...
you make a decision
to change together, or...
you split up.
Um...
See you in the morning.
Good night.
Sleep well.
Hi.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Can I swim with you?
I think you need to have a...
a grown-up as a lifeguard.
You're a grown-up.
Um, well, that's a good point.
I'm just... I'm not very...
Anyway, let's get you
back to bed, okay?
I won't splash anymore.
I promise.
Can you take me back
to my room?
- Um...
- It's dark.
I... I don't want to
wake your parents up.
We can walk
on tippy-toes.
Okay.
Man. These stickers...
I had stickers like that
when I was your age,
except I also had, like,
birds and bees and stuff.
They only had outer space stuff
at the Creativity Store.
Well, it's looking good
in here.
Mmm.
Okay.
Okay. Good night.
So, we can listen to what
he's doing on the synth...
with the ambient sounds
already in if you want.
Yeah, that would be
super helpful.
Seems like he wants to play on the synth
more than actually work on the film.
We'll make it good.
Don't worry.
Hey, David, do you
want to run to the store...
and pick up that squishy food
for the Foley?
I just want to finish
before the party tonight.
Uh, you don't want to
finish this first?
That's okay. I think
Martine can run the board.
Copy that.
Uh, back in 20.
I don't know
how to work the board.
It'll be fine. Just hit space bar,
come back here and watch it with me.
Okay.
Ready?
I think I want synth
in the whole movie.
Okay. David,
you can take Martine.
The kids can ride together.
Great.
Oh. Okay.
You know where you're going?
Yeah.
There you go. Get some more.
No.
No, that's all part of it.
It works better when you cough.
You guys don't know that?
It's the inevitable run-in.
Inevitable?
Well, it's a small town... at least
the parts of it that we inhabit.
Gosh. You look amazing.
Thank you.
It's good to see you.
Are you a friend of Rosa's?
You're not allowed to say?
Hmm.
Can we go somewhere and talk?
Ha, ha. Very funny.
Mm-mmm.
I want to be alone with you.
Um...
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Are you sure?
You look like you might.
- Might what?
- Want to... be alone with me.
Where have you been?
I've been looking for you.
My mom is stoned.
It's hilarious.
Let's get out of here.
I need to tell you something.
Take a walk with me.
I can't. I'll see you on Monday.
You don't know how crazy
you make me.
Well, then I guess I'm
not doing my job, am I?
You're too witty to...
be a professional listener.
I have to go find my daughter.
Mm-mmm. Just give me
a minute of your time.
This has already gone too far.
Drop your glass.
If you moved here,
you could live on the West Side.
You can walk on the West Side.
I don't like the beach.
Hey.
Hey. What's up?
I gotta get out of here.
- Let's-Let's go.
- Okay.
Oh. I forgot my bag.
All right.
I'll see you inside.
Yeah. I'll...
I'll see you soon.
Hey, Peter.
I gotta go.
Hey.
What the fuck are you doing?
What?
You want to fuck me up? Fine.
You were doing a pretty damn good job of
it before you had to go fuck my assistant.
Okay. Whoa.
I'm not trying
to fuck with you.
I'm... I didn't mean
for this to happen.
This whole time I was...
I was feeling something.
I was feeling like there was some
sort of connection between us.
But that was all bullshit.
I'm taking all my time,
and I'm doing this for you.
And you go and you betrayed me.
Betrayed you?
But, dude, you're married.
That's right. I'm married!
With a family!
And now I have to go figure out
a way to fix this.
I'm just here trying to work,
and you're all over me,
and I'm just doing what I have
to do to get my shit done.
Take your files and figure out
a way to fix your own movie.
Fuck!
I want to learn to say
some more practical words.
I don't know.
What's the word for "suitcase"?
Suitcase?
Yeah. What's the word
for "suitcase"?
I'm not a poet.
Some poems.
Ah!
No.
Angry poems.
In English.
"Sometimes there's a person
who you know looks right.
Their skin is fine,
like a linen cloth,
and their hair
is the color of night.
And they walk.
And when they walk,
that walk makes ladies turn
to their window and admire.
All the ladies in the town,
with their secret things
that they want.
You were this man...
in the town
from which you came,
but this...
this is not your town.
And when you speak,
your words are snakes
I swat at with swords.
They crawl into parts of me,
and I kill them
with kindness I can't afford.
I see you...
with the accurate eyes
of the sun.
You think you're imprinting
yourself in my memory,
a man with the power to teach.
You will never have anything
or anyone you want,
least of all...
me.
If I were to tell my mother
and the others,
we would laugh at you,
louder than we have
all along."
I don't understand.
You don't understand?
Basta!
- Who the fuck is this? - iVamos!
iVoy a llamar a la polica! iAhora!
That's Spanish. I'm Italian.
I don't give a shit.
Get out.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I don't know
about that plant though.
I just don't want to
have to explain it.
We can get that cleaned up
before anyone sees it.
My mom's gonna be so mad
I don't have a tutor anymore.
I provoked him...
with my angry poem.
Maybe he provoked you
into writing an angry poem.
I'm supposed to take
the Italian S.A.T. too.
I didn't think there was
anyone in the house.
Yeah. I was just coming back
from a long walk.
A walk where?
I got down to Hyperion,
and then I turned around and...
Someone pulled over because they
thought I was a prostitute.
Maybe they just thought
you were hot.
Well, not the way that Italian
fellow thinks you're hot.
He throws things,
he gets so excited.
I want Martine gone
by tomorrow.
I'm sure you understand
why we need to terminate.
Terminate?
I have a list of names,
qualified colleagues.
Oh, God.
What happened between us...
was an incredible breach
of professionalism...
and is not the way
I want to conduct myself.
Really? Not even a little bit?
Kolt, come in. The water's hot.
I don't really feel
like getting wet.
Mom just blew up the purple raft.
You can go in that and not get wet.
Kolt. We can do a somersault.
Let's do them at the same time.
One,
two, three.
Smells good in here.
It's Dusty's favorite.
I'm leaving.
I'll call you a cab.
No, there's one
on the way already.
Oh.
I'll send your files
in a few days.
I'm thinking
of adding more synth.
I think it'll be good.
Thank you.
All right, all right.
Oh. Let's...
Who wants it?
Grilled cheese!
Oh, I didn't know
you wanted one.
No, these are for me
and Sea Horse. No, no, no.
- Grilled cheese! Grilled cheese!
- No, no, no. Those aren't yours.
This isn't yours.
You go in here.
Grilled cheese! Grilled cheese!
All right, fine.
You can have one.
This is mine.
I want this one.
How's the water?
It's good. It's nice actually.
Ooh. It's cold.
It's not that bad.
After all that hard work?
Thanks for lunch, by the way.
Hey.
I'm, uh...
I'm heading out.
Back to New York?
Yeah. Back tonight.
Thank you again
so much for everything.
You have a really amazing home.
Okay.
And if you ever
come to New York, or...
if Kolt is interested
in RISD...
This is probably the last you'll be
hearing from anybody in this family.
Good luck with your film.