Andersson.
- Is not he coming?
- He is not invited.
Why not?
Is not sin?
It's your father.
- Hello my girl!
- Look, it's Daddy!
Hello! Hey, hey.
- Kalvesylten, did you remember it?
- Damn! The I forgot.
Then we go. - What the hell, I'm just
a little happy. The You're allowed to be?
- Press.
- What?
- At your fingertips.
- Why?
Because I have fought against the dragon
today. Pressure.
Harder. Put everything in you.
Both hands. Pressure.
Press. That's it.
Now I feel like a tiger again.
- Do you think Santa will be here tomorrow?
- Mm.
You know that it's just grandpa,
who disguised themselves?
Or so we shit on the whole
and stay home. Just the three of us.
- We go there as agreed.
- It is no maximum on your wish list.
- So dangerous is it any?
- No. It's worse.
We should abolish Christmas.
We can begin tomorrow.
- No.
- We can eliminate my siblings too.
- Now we eat.
- Tighten the muscles.
Are you ready? Press to.
Ha! It was the tin.
Helan yesterday
sing hoppfaderallan lallan rent
Och it as integral Helan tar,
he nor interest halvan sheep
Helan go!
Sing hoppfaderallan rent!
- Need some more brandy?
- Can I get some meatballs?
I saw you in the Great Square.
The Upside of Anger heard all the way in Tempo.
- What were you against?
- For.
- What?
- Equal pay for equal work.
- Were you indeed?
- I work.
- It was a Saturday.
- She joined the newspaper.
Should I talk politics?
I will just fall out.
- I have no quarrel.
- Do you have what you need?
I'm just saying that it is.
The labor movement split of women.
- Is there a bubble in alcohol?
- No. This is soda.
- Cheers!
Kalle have not gotten anything
since the First World War.
Second World War.
And the gender struggle, what is it?
Two-sex fight? A pussy and a cock?
- Stop, Rolf!
- What's he saying?
Little Brother, it is a soft package this year.
Velour Pants, extra small.
- How sweet! May he inherit your?
- Were you might ask.
- Are you sitting and laughing, you devil ?!
- Stop, boys!
- Do something!
- No, I will not give a shit.
- They have to fend for yourself.
- Now I smoke out!
- Both of you! Head first!
- No, now keep in!
- It's Christmas Eve, dammit!
- Now you'll wise up!
- Get it together!
- Think of the children.
Splitter Throughout the house at ?!
See what mom says.
- Hello. Well. So, yes.
You did well.
Oh, to not believe you're the betting.
Katja
No... No, I will not. La 'be.
I will not. Stop now.
You can get into.
- Hey, what do you have there?
- Pippi Longstocking.
Katja! My brother bought a used
plate, the stingy bastard.
Katja! Come ska 'you hear!
- Off. Turn off, I said!
- It's fucking funny bro.
Turn! Turn the
Where's Mom?
She soon.
Fuck out and play a little.
- When's mother?
- I do not know, I say.
She has no socks.
Levelling...
Nothing about pancakes.
- What should we do?
- Mother must make them.
Yeah, she is.
Where have you been?
You can not just disappear like that.
What is...?
What are you doing?
Mother's gone mad.
Stop that. I talk to her.
What are you doing?
Did I do something?
Say what it is.
Can not we talk about it?
You...
I have to go again.
See you soon.
Wait a minute.
What time is it?
Come. Come on.
- Satan's shit... When opening the nursery?
- I do not know.
Jump up.
- Sit properly. Are you?
- Yes.
Hold.
- Where is the nursery?
- The road.
The Way?
- This is the right way, right?
- Yes.
Go so.
Wait. Take it off.
Hello. A father passes.
Fun! Will you also?
Yes. So fun it will be neither.
- Mommy will get you. Goodbye.
- Coming mom?
- Yes. Have a good time. Goodbye.
- Mom would pick me up.
- I know.
- You promised.
She's not home.
Mph.
Did it? Of course it rings.
- Andersson.
- Am I interrupting?
- Not at all.
- Safe?
No, no. We just came...
We just got home.
- How are you?
- Good. Is she there?
What are you doing? Where are you?
I called everywhere.
Your sister and mother and...
What's going on?
We miss you.
I miss you.
- What should I do?
- Nothing.
I can act and wash up and...
There is another.
Do not cry.
- Sorry.
- No, no...
Do not say anything to her.
I will tell it yourself.
- Of course. It's fine. Hey.
- Hello.
Father?
Father!
Did she say why?
- Did you hit her?
- No.
How the hell did this for?
- Losing his woman - done!
- She'll be back.
They have so many ideas for the moment.
La 'not do that.
- She is good in many ways.
- Have you told her?
Do not throw it all over the tables,
if you want a chance.
- The girl we take care of for so long.
- Father!
Honey. Come on.
- You... Wait. Come on.
- No.
Become  'here. You...
You... Wait.
Wait.
I will never leave you.
Ever.
We must put it here.
Do you understand? Good.
What are you doing?
Yes... So it tomorrow.
Do you know what it is today?
It's Saturday.
The boat Saturday.
Coming mom?
No, not today.
Some of the legs.
Hello.
So. Down with you.
- How nice!
- This one? A stupid plastic tub.
True with soft seating and
flag in the ass, but it's no boat.
This... It's a real boat.
I have restored her completely even.
I started when you were born.
Oak from Blekinge. The finest
kind. Feel how she breathes?
- She?
- Yes. She.
Man she says of both.
This one is special. Listen.
She says her name.
Gold lump. After you!
Mom thought it was a good idea.
How was it then.
And then she said that the first trip, the
we must do together.
- Must mother?
- Yes.
- My Mother?
- Yes. It must be three on board.
A captain, a sailor and a ship's cook.
It's mother.
- I can feel it.
- Yes. We must make her ready.
You and me. Together.
There is coffee! There is enough for you too.
To each his æggemad. And a little juice.
No thanks, we do not have anything.
Girl eating at the restaurant.
Come.
Come on.
Sausage and french fries - is it good enough?
Thirteen crowns! Are you crazy?
You? Can you stay,
until we get home?
Safe?
How.
- What do you want? Milk? Soda?
- I can not drink soda.
- What kind of sandwiches?
- Do you really know?
Yes.
- Two egg sandwiches so?
- A. One is enough. Thank you.
Father?
Are we poor?
We are workers.
Workers are at. definition poor.
Poverty is doing
differences between individuals.
It's such a class society arises:
When someone takes to make money on
the work of others.
- Is not it unfair?
- Yes, it's damn unfair.
I work eight hours a day. Sheep
paid for four. The rest takes Wallenberg.
But there is a country
which has eradicated poverty.
There. There you have Cuba.
- So small.
- Yes, but big here.
Communism, you see,
is the most beautiful thing there is.
Not the terrible Stalin kind. No.
, as it was thought at the outset.
Money does not exist.
One exchange things with each other.
Maybe a mat...
a pair of shoes.
Missing you specified or
- they just go into the store
and take it simply.
This one does. Not too much, not
in abundance. It should be enough for everyone.
So. Come on.
And then from the farms...
... is well-laid tables.
Man turns to make ædelsen
and then you sit and eat together.
No need to feel lonely.
And you talk with each other.
About important things. Not a lot of shit
as platform shoes and Swedish top...
... but about things that matter.
Chile, Greece.
About how you want
it must be on Earth.
So, after dinner,
'll take you to the beach.
Watching the sunset.
Winter does not exist.
It has been abolished.
It's summer all the time.
- There I will go.
- Osse me.
I think we should take 'the boat there.
- But what's up with mom?
- Mother? Mother to be with.
Is there anyone who will
classless society, it's her.
Clear the mother to be with.
Father?
Are we communists?
Yes, we are.
But do not tell anyone.
And then we both
best friends and companions.
Did you know?
And you? Spark not so much in the night.
I have such a hard time sleeping.
- Good night, best friend.
- Good night, best buddy.
Can I see - look up.
So. It's fine.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Come on. How nice you are.
- Thank you.
Never mind. We slips immediately.
Anybody here?
Hello.
- Come on, honey.
- No!
- Sweet came.
- So. Come on.
You? Grandmother has been in the Soviet Union.
She might have bought something for you.
You need to meet someone today.
How I've missed you.
- I've got a boat.
- Lump of gold?
- Father and I make her ready.
- How fun!
Then you have enough to do.
But you will not sail without me.
- Coffee is set over.
- Thank you.
- When did you come?
- Three days ago.
- I guess it was cold in Moscow?
- Icy.
What do you think of this for me?
- Beautiful!
- Can you squeeze it together?
That? Yes...
They are tougher than you think.
- How!
- Nothing to boast about.
- Okay, I am the rock not proletarians.
- What is a proletarian?
- It's... well...
- Your father is.
- Proletarians are the best.
- What's Eating Me?
- Where are you going?
- Home.
But you gotta sleep here! With me.
- Bye, honey.
- Goodbye.
- How are you?
- Good.
He SKUs use two hands, the fool?
- He talks the most.
- Well? He is not the first?
- Not just that.
- Oh...
- I do not think he's best at something.
- Do not you think?
We're out for a walk.
To work. We must meet the dragon.
There, yes. Good.
No, wait.
When it switches to six gives it more.
Change so.
Hell machine!
- It's come to a halt.
- Huh?
Time do they open?
I have to go back. I'm late.
This will surely anyone yet?
Do not you think?
What should I do?
They have just me.
And do not tell anyone,
that you were with Dad at work.
Then just
a lot of gossip.
Wait here, so there will be none.
Okay?
Hello.
He came up to me one day,
the pointy-nosed asshole, and said:
"Look Kalle"... No, so he said:
"Karl Andersson."
"You are the coolest man on the floor.
We did not do without you."
Yes, so he said.
You know what I said?
"Look, Marcus Wallenberg,
you are the coolest capitalist" -
- "and without you,
we are doing absolutely excellent!"
Then he was silent.
Do not you believe me, slut?
Eat properly,
so you get some food.
- He is hot.
- He may well throw the jacket?
Jo... How are things going at home?
The horseradish was dismal.
It should feel like two spears in the nose.
- It's time for a new woman.
- But Kalle...!
There is something wrong with your mother,
but she should be here now.
- It was nice...
- Come on.
Yes. The girl must have her popsicle first.
- Is he all right?
- Mm.
- And at work?
This is good.
It's good he has you.
- Do you have a few bucks?
- Has the money gone already?
- Hell, I'm quite alone with the girl.
- Where to gangs.
Sorry. I need to rent.
Is he the right place?
The city's first free restaurant.
- What's he saying?
- Hi, Mom. No, I eat at home.
Ann-Marie had to do something with
banana.
- Sell the boat instead.
- No way.
I pay well.
It's coming yet never in the lake.
Obtain a little humor, dammit.
What the hell is wrong with him?
Father? What is proletarian?
Uh...
It is one that is struggling.
As living from hand to mouth.
As do not own anything.
I and my husband
Noppe von Bavianrøv visited...
- What's the stupid place?
- Embassy District.
- Have you been there?
- No.
Do woman man never visited
the finest bydel-
i all our great capital?
- Father?
- Wait.
Here are both Hitler's bathtub,
husneger and banquet dwarf.
All have space in my kingdom.
- Ska 'we do not go now?
- We'll take one more, huh?
- Uh...
- It's on the house.
- Should she stay with us now?
- She may. Not so.
I was a promising football player sometime.
Tough but fair midterbak.
Girls sat close as birds on the battens.
Someone
I was not able to 'be wise to.
But I got her in the end.
Mother.
Capitalism is a disgrace, but
sometimes it's nice to ha 'money.
Now we take a taxi.
So. Skip down and check it,
then we will see.
Come.
- You know what I think it looks like?
- No.
Door no. 24 in the Advent calendar.
Think then bitch are coming
and looking up.
So they think: "Up there
lives a skillfully womenfolk."
- Do you think?
- You think? I know.
They never looked lovelier
curtains and sconces.
Damn, they are amazed
More than that here do not live a woman.
We live Sweden's best iron mold.
- Mother?
- Hello!
Hello.
- Did you do it?
- We made it. Do you enjoy it?
Yes. It's fine.
- Are you coming up?
- Yes.
- New curtains?
I heard that you were foreman.
- What did you find out more?
- That it goes well with you.
- What's the foreman?
- I'll tell you later.
Hoof. Caution. Not on your stomach.
You must have a sibling.
Father?
Tighten the muscles, Dad.
It's nerves.
They go as long wires in the body.
Tighten the muscles.
Admission? Hi, Grandpa.
Yes, we are awake.
Yes. It's good. Mm.
He eats breakfast.
Mm. Yes, we do.
You too. Hey.
Father?
Time to wake up.
- Wake up.
- Yes. Yes, yes...
Hello! Thank you.
- Mor'n, mor'n.
- Hey, hey.
- Who is it?
- She's new. She is from Norway.
Spring up.
- What stuff!
- Yes.
- It's boat-Saturday soon.
- Yes, you did.
- Hi.
- Hello again.
- Should we look at the plates?
- I can not.
You promised you so. I dare not without you.
- I need to check something.
- It's what you said last time.
- I've cigars. Three pieces.
- I may come back.
- Goodbye!
- Hey, hey!
- Hello! Are you here?
- Yes.
- How fun!
- You look happy.
I'm happy! I am a happy shit.
Spring up. Spring is now up.
Look at me. Look at me!
Breathe. Breathe!
- The potatoes are ready.
- I'm not talking to you.
- How long has this been going on?
- Leave her alone.
- Not a penny more.
- Can not we just eat?
Did you hear it too?
Not a penny more!
You hear hardly by grandpa?
He never pushed one Wallenberg
against the wall. It's just talk.
I go in and...
- What do you think?
- Fine.
You should perhaps... The fly.
Nah...
- Well...
- Boo!
- Hello!
- Would you like something to drink?
- No, I must go immediately.
- You just got here.
- Yes...
Now it became tiresome.
- We greeted, or what?
- Jo.
What are we talking about?
- You are a hairdresser?
- Yes. Absolutely. And you are...?
- I go to school.
- Yes.
- In sixth.
- The sixth? Fine.
Sixth is fine.
- Nicaragua?
- Huh? What is it?
- No... Yes. Something with Olof Palme.
I hate Olof Palme. Oh, to cram
a bomb in his mouth on him and just...
Sweden has become so communist.
No one should be happy.
All must be equal.
But I think about you.
I've seen you a few times in the area.
Quite often, actually.
're Good people.
You're such a little... Tarzan...
Tarzan-like.
- You think so?
- Yes.
Hello?
Hello!
- Hello!
- I thought to sleep here if it is okay.
- Of course! Cosy.
One night only.
- Hey, girly girl! Good to see you.
- Is that fine?
- Yes.
I is shown by the working class!
I have abandoned my family.
I'm not ashamed
appreciate workers!
We know what it means.
Social Democrats just leads to total
passivation of the working class.
- A holiday week extra, what is it?
- Filled stomachs.
Capital mislead the working class
with socialakrobaternes help.
They are being exploited.
Father plungers 07:03
and stops 16.06.
He works eight hours, get paid
four. The rest takes Wallenberg.
That's it.
You?
- Are you good at home?
- Yes.
- Safe?
You look like your father sometimes.
Dad says I look like you.
Good night.
What do you think?
She has done well in winter.
Only a coat of varnish.
No, no. Sonja.
- What do you think about Sonja?
- She is fun.
Thee so?
- Stop...
- I have not said anything.
- We begin with Pettersson.
- Damn. Come on!
- It is not free to stand here.
- What SKUs we here?
- Hello! Are you there?
- I do not think he's here.
Are you coming, or what?
Your bike is here.
- Sad I under...
- Yes, below!
You too?
So I have not had the boat in the water?
Vasa?
- What do you say?
- You did not get the boat on the water?
- What's she saying?
- It's all right!
- Do you have stereo?
- Mm.
- Wow...
- Take more crayfish.
My favorite!
Relax a little.
- I just wanna live.
- Huh?
- I want to live!
- What do you say?
I just want to live.
You're healthy now.
It's just...
Excuse me...
Well, it's these pills...
Sorry.
- So your father has girlfriend now?
- Yes. She stilettos.
Here. Here is my girlfriend.
Him in the middle.
Now ska 'you hear.
- This is somewhat good?
- Yes.
There is a toilet.
- There is no towel.
- Wipe up here. It's fine.
- Thank you. Do you have ice cream at home?
- No. Come on.
- My mother feel sorry for you.
- Why?
- Because you have no mother.
- But you have no father.
It's not the same.
- Are best friends and companions, then?
- What do you mean?
If you were, you'd know it.
By the way, my mother
a new family now.
But what's up you?
- What was that?
- Huh?
Hey, my girl
Is this you?
- I thought I heard voices.
- She SKUs ready to go.
We should welcome anyway.
Hello, is it perhaps
Miss Hottentot?
Or Countess Bavianrøv?
Sweet Miss, you have possibly seen
my company dwarf?
Father...
I have to call the house Negro. Hello?
- We usually play bridge.
What did I? What my answer is?
Here is my answer:
That's it. And a PS. Hey, hey.
- Goodbye. See you tomorrow.
- Goodbye.
- Why were you at home yesterday?
- How?
Middle of the day?
Yes, nay... It was the dragon.
- Why?
- It was hard yesterday.
Why? Is this an interrogation?
I have a sore back.
Did the heat treatment and the whole thing.
Do you have a...
So...
I'll take a goldfish so.
Yes.
- Come on.
- No.
Who do I talk to, then?
There's just drønnerter here. Come on.
- No!
- What would you do?
Okay.
- Hi. What have you bought? A fish?
- Yes.
How nice. Settle down.
- Thank you, Sonya.
- You were really nice. So we'll see.
Now we see...
No, it is too red.
But this... Do we see.
Laugh not. So.
Do you want to run with us?
We have a boat, dad and me.
We thought ta 'to Cuba,
but I do not think we get that far.
- Cuba is not for me.
- We ka 'to go' anywhere they go.
I need to travel.
For Mallorca.
Once a year, the
Viva España for all the money.
Did you tell dad?
I have something for you.
I just used it once.
It gets fine for you.
Do spit in it.
And then...
And then drag it over the eyelashes.
Your father sitting up there.
It stinks of piss all over the entryway.
- Get out!
- See for yourself.
Listen now! You can not sit.
You ska 'go now. I am here.
You ska 'go!
Do you hear bad, or what?
- Will you not Sonja?
- Take off your shoes.
- Where is Sonja?
- She's leaving tomorrow.
Intl. Do you understand?
She does not want you.
- Where is she going, then?
- She does not like you so much!
Charter? What?
- Sit.
She... she must be careful.
Lying among flabby Germans shouting Sieg Heil
to their children.
She must be careful
she does not get a shit in your mouth.
Come and dance with the Swedish
remaining in the endowment.
- No, no, no...
- Stop. Get off me.
- Stand on my feet.
- No.
Stand on your feet.
Father, stop. Stop! Slip.
Stop. I will not!
Father, let me go. Then go though!
Daddy, stop!
Release! Let me go!
Can not you just die damned old fool!
I think it's nerves.
They are long strands of body
and sometimes filter the contract.
So is he fucking bad.
My mother's sister disappeared.
Drowned.
None grasped something.
And they said it was nerves.
I have to go.
Father? Time to wake up.
Father?
I made breakfast.
- I acted while you were sleeping.
- I guess there's not open yet?
Greek is on the corner is open.
- What do you want? Cheese?
- I would like to have a roll.
- You want juice?
- Yes.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
"Best magistrates.
I am writing to you on the occasion" -
- "the systematic
oppression of the workers" -
- "going on in this country...
and so on and so forth . "
Everything entitled
"Twenty times in twenty society."
- She has nothing to apologize for.
- Red propaganda is not on the table.
But what about black propaganda
kristendomsundervisning-
guide organ tramp in the morning?
- Companion you hang out with...?
- It was my idea.
I need to talk to her.
Why are you defending her? Vouch for
your belief something must change!
It was exactly this i...
She is your daughter!
- Sorry.
- No.
- I thought it was funny.
- That was it. Damn funny.
It was fucking right in the eye.
You may just be a little careful.
Otherwise it gives problems.
Do you understand?
Socialakrobaterne driver hound
on us communists.
They have always done.
You can be an "unreliable element"
and ports in a labor camp in Norrland.
Lump of gold.
With you is to become something else.
You with your good head.
You may be exactly what you want.
Remember.
Now we go home.
No, not here.
"Unpaid bill per 25"
- What's the date?
- The tenth.
So operate the TV either.
- What should we do?
- Yes... We must pull a trump.
- With the bill?
- Yes.
- Are you turned the light on?
- Mm.
- Where are the matches?
- They are there somewhere.
No, I find them.
Yes...
That was it.
It was probably good enough.
We did not fit particularly well together.
To vote on threesome government
once ka 'acceptable, but two!
There is the limit fucking.
- I thought of her.
- Yeah, who the hell did not do it.
Hello. It's me.
Hi there. It's okay.
Thanks ska 'You want.
This is fucking last time.
Do you hear?
You see how annoying you look like?
- Have you seen anything worse?
- Leave him alone.
Vomiting you in the car, do I kill you.
Father?
Meet at the boat later.
After the demonstration.
- So we make it last finished.
- Lump of gold...
Now we do so. It's going well.
Sorry.
Arise, wretched of the earth,
get up, you hunger slave army
In the court's crater rumbling thunder,
is now the last eruption near.
Break only tender ancient wall in pieces.
- Yes?
- Where's our boat? Nugget.
It is sold long ago.
- I know what you want to say!
- I know you did not! He is dead!
The ambulance was here.
They were more. He was fucking heavy!
Drink for a epileptiskt attack!
How the hell do you do it?
Have you had a tanker with hose
right into your trap ?! Fy dammit!
- But Kalle...
- Damn fool, equal not just that!
- You can of course lose the girl!
- Damn it, do not worry.
Say something!
Where is she?
- Has anyone talked to her?
- Have not thought about the girl?
Ska 'it come from you?
Do not sit at home
and wait for something to happen.
No, hang out with me tonight,
you will always find something.
We are going out somewhere
and drink a bottle of wine.
Maybe stop somewhere
and listening to a band.
But then, when everything is over.
What have I gotten out of it?
But I know that it is something.
You only live once
and the time is now.
There is only one who by
how to live - that's you.
You only live once
and the time is now.
nugget?
Lump of gold?
"Shuffle the cards and place them in a pile
with instructions down."
- "Each participant selects one piece."
- I'm blue.
- You want green? Or red?
- Red.
"Game can begin.
The youngest player begins the letter A."
Ask your piece there.
Then you must strike first.
- It's your father.
- Where?
In the hall. He has a Christmas present with.
- Jo.
- No. No!
- Hi.
- Hello.
Can you... give her that.
- It's just a little...
- Yes.
- Will not you come in?
- No, I gotta go.
- Okay... Merry Christmas, so.
- Good July
- This is a table... of Beauty.
- The white?
- Yes. As you got from your father.
- Who stood in the bedroom?
Do I...
Can I move it?
Is it here yet?
- Hello.
- Will not you come in?
- No, I just wanted to drop...
Yes, maybe you...
Thank you.
Why do not you sit here.
Just need cleaning up.
Cleanup is not the girls' strong point.
So. Here you go.
Have a good time.
I close the door behind me.
It is an academic achievement,
outstanding performance. Or what?
Yes.
And you know why?
You have a unique perspective.
As a PhD at the same institution
gets, I have to ask:
How the hell did you do?
Cheers!
I'm so proud of you.
Your father too, you know.
What you got there?
Why had not I
keep up with tonight?
Would you since?
I felt so sorry for him,
I gave him the finest I have had.
Andersson.
Hello. It's me.
Is this you?
- Thank you for the money.
- Here you go, it was so little.
- It was a long time ago.
- Yes. That was it.
... girly girl,
has not gone well?
- Jo. Very well.
- Yeah, so...
So everything is as it should be.
When you become a doctor, you should be happy.
- Promise me one thing.
- Yes?
Be zealous against professors
during deserten.
Yes.
- There I was quick.
- Yes.
Hello. Come on.
- No, I can...
- Yes, I'll take it.
So. I have low coffee.
- Do you drink coffee?
- Certainly.
- Sugar, do you use it?
- No.
No, that's good.
One should be careful with sugar.
- Is it new?
- Yes. Lord, how I saved.
There is very new.
The renovated last.
But it took a damn long time.
I was getting fired.
Yes, I heard it.
The best as ku 'happen to me.
I ended completely with drinking.
- Do you have milk?
- Did not I tell you about...? No.
Do you remember that?
You said that there are dolphins in Cuba.
Of course it was always pitch black
when we woke up?
Of course, we were always alone
when we drove to kindergarten?
And you picked me up every day.
I will always remember.
It was dark and cold.
It was a decent game,
it with Katya.
I was not ready.
I did the best I could.
And you did good.
Although you kicked as hell at night.
They had the difficulty sleeping.
But... It was not bad for me.
I got the you.
We got each other.
I live in Uppsala now.
I know.
- Do you want my phone number?
- I already have it.
You must be grandfather. A girl.
Give her and that we must be
best friends and companions.
Love you.
Translated from the Swedish by
Muntra via nikse.dk