P
PE
PEN
PENE
PENER
PENERJ
PENERJE
PENERJEM
PENERJEMA
PENERJEMAH
PENERJEMAH:
PENERJEMAH: H
PENERJEMAH: Ha
PENERJEMAH: Har
PENERJEMAH: Harf
PENERJEMAH: Harfl
PENERJEMAH: Harfly
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Z
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zo
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zon
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
h
ht
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
htt
http
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http:
http:/
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://
http://h
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://ha
http://har
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harf
http://harfl
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly
http://harfly.
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.b
http://harfly.bl
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blo
http://harfly.blog
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogs
http://harfly.blogsp
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspo
http://harfly.blogspot
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspot.
http://harfly.blogspot.c
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspot.co
http://harfly.blogspot.com
PENERJEMAH: Harfly Zone
♪ "Spesialis Penerjemah Film Horor." ♪
10, 9, 8,
7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1.
New Beginning.
Melissa, how far does
it say we have to go?
Hold on a second, hon.
I'm almost there.
I like this neighborhood.
It's really cute.
Yeah, okay.
The turn is coming up here,
on the left pretty soon.
Isn't this exciting?
You're gonna have so much
more space in your new room.
You're gonna love it.
Just think of all the new
friends you're gonna make.
He's gonna have a hard
time making new friends
if he's not talking, huh, kiddo?
This is a real adventure, Nat.
Maybe we could even think
about finally getting a dog.
Maybe.
This house is perfect.
It's got a great yard.
He'd love it.
What do you say, Nat?
Nat?
Honey, he can still hear.
- I know, Melissa, but if he's ever...
- Jack, watch out!
Honey, what did you hit?
I don't know.
- Stay here.
- Okay.
It's all right, honey.
Do you see anything?
Nothing.
Must have just grazed it.
Looked like a cat.
I think it was a possum.
You didn't even see it.
You okay back there, bud?
Talk about your adventure.
We haven't even unpacked yet,
and we already hit a possum-cat.
Scared me to death.
A possum-cat? Really?
Yeah. It's a ferocious little
beast indigenous to this area.
Okay, Mr. Professor.
Just don't hit any more
indigenous beasts, okay?
Okay.
You all right
back there, buddy?
Oh, look.
There she is.
Pretty great. huh, Nat?
Looking good, Janice.
Thanks, Marie.
Five pounds.
You made it.
Oh, Professor vales, I'm Janice
from university housing.
Nice to meet you.
Of course. Hi.
This is my wife Melissa.
Oh, great to finally meet you.
And this is Nathan.
Hi.
He's kind of having a little bit
of trouble with the move.
Well, I understand.
I hate to move.
That's why I've been
in this town forever.
Well, now you're here, too.
Come on.
Let's go inside.
Here we go.
11.
Yeah, it adds up to 11.
Good job.
Mittens! Mittens!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
You didn't see a little
orange tabby, did you?
No, I can't say that we did.
Just ignore her.
No! No!
I need to find her.
She doesn't leave the porch.
She never leaves the yard.
I'm sorry. We didn't see it.
We're just moving in.
New neighbors?
I don't want new neighbors.
Annie.
I miss Professor Hampton.
We will let you know
if we see your little cat.
Now turn around and go home.
I'm sure she's playing in your
garage like she always does.
Like always?
I'll stop by when I'm done here.
Go.
All right, let's go inside.
Come on. Here we go!
I am so sorry about that.
Ever since she lost her husband,
things have been.. well.
Oh, yeah.
You know, she was essentially
raised on campus.
Her parents taught there
and her brother, Son of a gun.
We're having a little
raccoon trouble lately.
Probably her cat.
Yeah! Yeah!
I'll have someone out
to fix that right away.
These houses are historical, you know.
They're nationally registered,
five of them on this block alone.
Let me show you the upstairs.
Come on.
Here we go.
Nat, this is gonna be your room.
Nice, huh?
Oh, beautiful boy.
I bet all the girls in school,
will take a shine to him..
Actually, he's home schooled.
Oh, well. That's good news.
We've been going through a lot of budget
cuts lately with the elementary school.
Horrible...
Really horrible.
Let's move on. Here we go.
Look at that big back yard.
I bet you'll get into
lots of trouble back there.
What do you think?
Look at that! It's amazing.
Mmm..
It's nice.
Let me show you the rest of the house.
Okay.
Thank you so much,
Janice, for everything.
Oh, that's what neighbors are for.
A pleasure to meet you, Melissa.
Nathan. Aw!
Can't blame a gal for trying, huh?
Professor, I'll probably see you
on campus in a couple of days.
I just hope I can fill
Professor Hampton's shoes.
Oh, don't you worry about him.
He was with us forever.
Between you and me,
it was time for him to go.
All right. I'll have the painter here.
First thing tomorrow morning.
I'm almost done here.
No hurry.
Here. These must have been left
here by Professor Hampton.
Did you know him?
Profesor Hampton?
Sure, I had to clean up
after his going away party.
Oh, big party?
I wasn't invited.
Oh!
Oh, my goodness.
Must be the painter.
We're the welcoming committee.
WELCOME.
Hi.
I'm Chris demms.
This is my wife Sarah.
We live right across the street
in that blue house there.
Oh. This is Nathan and I'm Melissa.
So great to meet you.
Here. These are from our garden.
Oh, how thoughtful.
I'll have to unpack a vase
and put 'em in some water.
I made you some molasses cookies.
My grandmother's recipe.
Oh!
Fresh from the oven.
Mmm..
KWould you like one, Nathan?
No, he'll have one later. I don't
want him to have sugar this early.
But, thank you.
We got you this.
It's a pre-birthday gift.
It's so nice to have a child
in the neighborhood again.
Yeah. Are you gonna
say thank you?
He's a little shy.
The strong silent type, huh?
How did you know it was
his birthday coming up?
Oh, Janice told us.
So, where's your husband?
Oh, he's at the school.
He's working on
his first class.
Well, we'll let you
get back to unpacking.
No hurry in getting
that plate back.
Thanks.
All right, bye.
Bye.
Trust me. You
don't want one.
Oh, God.
Oh, look at that.
Have you seen a little
yellow tabby cat?
Oh, boy. He is such a rascal
Are you 11?
Are you turning 11?
I am so old.
I can't even remember
what it's like to be 11.
When's your birthday?
Is it Friday?
Goodness. You're going
to be 11 on 11/11/11.
That is something, isn't it?
Do you gamble?
Good. You save your money.
Do you like trains?
Yeah. My husband
was crazy about 'em.
I have a whole set
down in my garage.
You should see it.
There's little trees
and there's Bridges.
Come on. Come on.
I'll show you.
- Come on.
- Nat!
Hi, Hi. Oh, I'm Annie.
I live next door.
I was just asking your little son here,
if he'd seen my cat mittens.
I mean, she's a rascally one.
No, we haven't..
Oh. Well. If you should see
a little orange tabby, that's mine.
My door's always open.
My name's Melissa, by the way.
Oh, I know.
Mittens!
Let's go inside.
Mittens.. Aw, mittens.
Mittens.
Just a minute.
Hei, Amigo. I'm here
to fix the wall.
Nat?
Is he all right?
Somebody call 911.
Did anyone see
the car that hit him?
No. I just heard
a loud crash,
and then saw
him laying here.
What did he do?
Go home, Mick.
There's been a hit and run.
What did he do?
He screw up?
Go home, Mick.
Nat?
Oh, honey, are you okay?
Did you see the car accident?
Mommy, I don't
want a baby brother.
What?
Oh! no, honey
Mommy's not pregnant.
Oh, God.
God.
One minute I hear
the doorbell ring,
and the next minute
I hear this car crash,
and the guy is laying
dead in the street.
It happened so fast.
Did anyone else see it happen?
By the time I got there,
the entire neighborhood was there.
Did Nat see it?
I don't know.
By the time I got there,
He was already up here, and
he was mumbling to himself.
What?
I don't know, Jack.
This is really bad,
I don't like it.
I know. You had a hard day.
You just need to relax, okay?
Okay.
I'm gonna go take a bath.
That's a good idea.
Okay.
I picked up some
wasp spray today.
Take care of that
in the morning.
You didn't drown in there, did you?
Melissa?
Aah!
Jesus!
Jack! Jack!
Oh, God.
Pregnant?
About three weeks now.
Was your prior pregnancy
a difficult one?
Yes, he was premature.
How early?
Two months.
Yes.
Excuse me, Mr. And Mrs. Vales.
Dad, the pedersens are here.
Thanks, honey. Tell them
I'll just be a moment.
So due to your previous
problems with pregnancy,
the unexpected
loss of blood,
Not to mention the pain that
you've been experiencing,
Thee are all signs
of preeclampsia.
It's a serious condition and
it could lead to miscarriage.
I'm going to insist on
immediate bed rest.
For how long?
That's hard to say.
I need you completely immobilized.
Could be one month,
could be several...
Several? But I have
to look after Nat.
We've been home schooling Nat.
Would she still be
able to do that?
I wouldn't recommend it.
As little activity and stress as
possible is really the best medicine.
Don't worry about it.
Your insurance covers everything, including
a nurse for you and a nanny for your son.
Great. So we'll see you
Thursday at 4:00.
Okay. All right. Bye-bye.
What happened?
Good God.
What now?
Don't look, Nat.
Hey.
You know Chris and Sarah over there?
Sure. I met them yesterday.
Seems they had an
accident in their house.
That guy Chris was cleaning the gutters
on the second story of his house.
He's not really a tall guy, you see.
And I guess he reached too far.
And the next thing, you know?
He toppled off his ladder.
Is he okay?
Well, he was impaled
to death on the fence.
So I'd say no.
Oh, excuse me.
Honey.
Oh, 11-11-11.
What's that?
11-11-11.
That's when it all goes down.
That's when..
That's when what goes down?
How much more of this
are we supposed to take?
Relax, honey.
Two people have died, Jack.
Melissa, don't stress out.
It's not good for the baby.
I met Chris, all right?
He was a really nice guy.
Stop it.
Now, you need to get into bed.
You don't want to miscarry, do you?
Come here.
Let's look at it this way...
At least now we got all our
bad luck out of the way.
I suppose that's supposed
to be good luck, too.
You must be Professor vales.
I'm Kyle othman.
Professor othman, you're
in the office next door.
I'm new here, too.
We're really glad you
could start so soon.
Do you know what happened
to Professor Hampton?
Well, they said he retired,
but he was gone so suddenly.
I haven't heard from him since.
Listen, forget I said anything.
You better not be causing trouble.
No.
Sorry if I sounded rude earlier.
I was worried about mittens.
So you still haven't seen her?
Is Nat home?
Yeah, he's upstairs
taking a nap.
I'm Annie. I live right there.
Yeah.
I've had trouble keeping
it up since Neal died.
Neal. Neal was..?
My husband.
He took his own life.
I'm sorry.
We had our disagreements.
And the old fool decided to
take things into his own hands.
Now I know how he felt.
Sometimes you have to take
things in your own hands.
Better the devil you know,
than the devil you don't know.
Jesus.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
Dr. Bolger prescribed a mild
sedative to keep her anxiety low.
A sedative?
She's pregnant.
Be assured the doctor would never prescribe a medication
that could result in an embryocidal outcome.
Oh, is that right?
I'm calling Dr. Bolger.
Go right ahead.
Dr. Bolger, I don't understand.
Why does she have to be sedated?
It's only for a week or so.
Starting next week,
we'll lower the dosage.
I understand your concern, but
this is a common procedure.
Hello, Nat.
You didn't expect
to see me, did you?
Wanna see something?
It's simply a precautionary
measure, nothing more.
Don't worry.
The fetus won't be affected.
Come on.
Don't worry, Jack.
All right. Well, if you're sure.
Thank you, doctor.
That's something, isn't it?
Nat!
Nat, stay in the yard.
Nat, your dad won't mind
if you come in for a minute.
I'll show you my
husband's train set.
You can't avoid
your fate forever.
So, Rhonda. How long
have you been a nanny?
I've been a nanny
for the last six years.
These are my references.
I like to get the kids
outside in the sun.
Sometimes we have class out there.
That's nice.
Yeah.
Kids seem to respond better when
they feel like you're one of them.
It seems to help them
open up more easily.
Well, Nat needs that.
And kids love me.
They call me fond o' Rhonda.
Fond o 'Rhonda.
I can see why.
Yeah.
Call any time.
I always keep my phone on.
In case of emergencies.
Bye. Will do.
Bye. Thanks.
What do you want?
That must be the next girl.
I'm Denise.
Your new nanny.
So how long have
you been a nanny?
On and off for a couple of years.
What else have you done?
In college, I mastered
in comparative religions,
and now I work part
time at a butcher shop.
What's her problem?
She's on a new medication.
We'll be in touch.
So which girl
did you like best?
I'm definitely fond o' Rhonda.
Good.
Me, too.
Get some rest, okay?
Okay.
Hello?
Hey, Rhonda, this is Jack vales.
My wife and I would like to
offer you the nanny position.
I'm sorry, Mr. Vales.
I'm no longer interested.
What..
Hello? Great.
I'll start tomorrow.
This is Professor vales.
Did you get my fax?
Who is this?
Numbers are not merely
symbols, Mr. Vales.
They hold great power.
And they have that power
because we give it to them.
When the numbers align,
his fate is sealed.
Who the hell is this?
Your son must die
before his birthday.
And if you don't
kill him, I will.
Milda, it's Jack.
Put me through to Dr.
Othman's office, will you?
Oh, Jack. Didn't you hear?
Professor othman is on sabbatical.
What? I thought he just started.
Sorry. That's all
they told me.
Okay.
What the hell are they doing?
Okay, I think we
should talk to him.
Let's go.
Come on.
We only have three days left, Mike.
What the hell do you think you're doing?
He did not.
He had a big mouth.
Sarah.
What, Janice?
I think I have a right to be furious.
He was my husband.
Well, he screwed up.
You weren't there.
Even if he did, you can't just take
matters into your own hands.
Brian's right. You
were out of line.
We can't afford to make mistakes,
Mike. Not this late in the game.
Chris meant a lot to me.
What is she supposed to do now?
Right. What, now.
I'm the grieving widow?
You messed up.
I did what I had to do.
Go to hell.
Don't do that.
And that should do it.
Make sure that you reset the alarm before you
go to bed and whenever you leave the house.
Sign right here.
You're all set?
Have a good day.
You, too.
Thanks so much.
Jesus.
Scared you?
Can I help you?
You're new here.
Thought we could be friends.
I could use some new friends.
People around here can be mean.
I'm sorry.
Finally got around to
filling in those cracks?
These?
Yep. This whole town is kind of
cockeyed, if you know what I mean.
Stuff like this here
happens all the time.
Really?
As they say, you gotta build
the gate before you can open it.
But you gotta have
the key to unlock it.
Is that what they say?
Sure. You know, there was a big mass
murder/suicide here, like, a year ago.
Is that right?
Uh-huh. Crazy
stuff around here.
You think 9/11
was an inside job?
What?
11. The first plane that hit
the first tower was flight 11.
Okay.
11 is the first number which
can't be counted on fingers.
Well, not human fingers.
Hey, Mick.
Don't overstay your welcome.
Well, I'll stop by. And say
hi again tomorrow, friend.
Filling it in won't help.
It'll just come back.
What did I do wrong?
I'm sorry.
I won't do it again.
I didn't know.
Go for it.
Oh! What the hell?
Come on, Brian. Let's get you
home. Put some ice on that.
Is that all you
want to do?
Dig in the dirt?
Boring.
I gotta get your
dinner ready.
Whoa! You gonna eat that?
You know, sometimes
when you cut a worm in half,
you get two live worms.
And sometimes you
get a dead worm.
Oh, I brought you some lemonade.
Tastes funny, but it's really good.
Come on!
I've got a birthday present for you.
I know it's two more
days till your birthday.
But by then the whole
world could be over.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on..
It's okay. Come on.
Come on.
Nat!
Dinner.
I'll give you the present tomorrow, Nat.
I promise. You'll see.
No. Just get away.
No..
Shh, Shh, Shh, Shh, Shh.
Shh, Shh.
Gotcha.
Aah! No! No!
Nat?
Is something wrong?
Do you need something?
Nat.
Nat!
What has gotten
into you lately?
Oh, buddy.
I'm not mad at you, okay?
This move has been
hard on all of us.
Hold on!
We'll have a proper birthday for you
tomorrow, but I wanted to give you this.
Mom and I love you.
Hold on.
Don't open it yet.
Good morning, Denise.
Hey, good morning.
Beautiful day.
Nat?
Buddy?
Hey, Nat.
Jesus!
Damn it! What the
hell are you doing?
I have to go to work.
Watch him!
♪ No! ♪
No.
On may 11, 1311,
54 members of the Knights Templar,
are burned at the stake in France,
for being heretics.
I thought I got rid of this.
My God, honey.
You're burning up.
She's burning up.
Can you hear me?
Jack..
Relax, honey.
They were all here.
They? They who?
All of them.
Dr. Bolger..
Janice..
They were here?
Yes.
And Nat..
They made him..
What? What did
they do to Nat, huh?
He killed..
He killed a girl.
What?
He..
He slit her throat.
Hey, hey, hey.
You just stay down.
Just relax, honey.
Relax.
They were all here.
They were around our bed.
Sofie, get in here.
They were here.
Shh. Sofie's going to
give you something.
Give her something.
Jack.. No.
Just relax. It's
gonna be okay.
Jack..
No.
Who was here?
Nobody, Mr. Vales.
No..
Honey..
There were 92 passengers on flight 11.
9 + 2 = 11.
Flight 77 had 65 passengers.
6 + 5 = 11.
Jesus.
What did I tell you
about this book?
Stop filling his head
with these nightmares.
Nat.
Nat!
Nat, hey.
Daddy.
Oh, buddy.
You hungry? Huh?
Let's go. Come on.
Tomorrow's your birthday, big guy.
11.
You wanna do something
special for the big day?
I know things have been a little
crazy. With mom being sick and all.
But I need you to let
her get her rest, okay?
Jesus.
I'm havin' an aneurysm.
Nat?
Nat! Jesus! Nat!
Jesus.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
What are you doing?
Be a good girl and
take your medicine.
Shh. Shh.
No.
Happy Birthday, Nat.
What the hell?
I actually think it went
smoothly. Powerful, even.
How do you think
Dr. Bolger took it?
Well?
You don't think she'll remember?
Sofie made sure, she
was heavily sedated.
She won't remember a thing.
And Sofie covered our tracks?
She's no amateur.
I hope the girl
was actually intact.
Are you kidding me?
Mike, her father is a doctor.
I think he would know.
Everything's on course.
Everybody remain calm.
Stay focused. Remember..
Normal.
After tomorrow, none
of this will matter.
Nat?
Denise?
Sofie!
Nat, what are you
doing in here again?
I told you to leave mom alone.
Come on.
Nat!
Why does mommy have to die?
What?
No! No! No!
Mom's gonna be fine.
No, daddy.
Aah!
Oh, my God.
What are you doing?
Sofie, get in here.
What the hell are you doing?
It's a superficial wound, Mr. Vales.
She's going to be fine.
911. What's your emergency?
My wife. I need an ambulance. My..
My wife stabbed herself.
All right, sir. Stay calm.
We'll send someone right away.
Hello. Dr. Bolger's office.
Yeah, Miranda. Put Dr. Bolger on. It's an emergency.
I'm sorry, this isn't Miranda. And
the doctor's not available right now.
What do you mean he's not available?
My wife's been stabbed.
Put Miranda on.
They slit her throat.
I'm really sorry, sir.
But Miranda didn't
show up for work today.
Should I tell the
doctor you called?
Never mind.
It's okay.
Sofie, did we stop..
Did we stop this bleeding?
Your wife will be fine.
It was a superficial wound.
The baby was never in any harm.
Okay. Thanks for getting
here so quickly.
No problem.
Oh, my God.
Hey, Nat. Who did
this to you, huh?
Who did this to you?
Did Denise do
this to you?
God. Damn her.
Hello, 911. What is
your emergency?
I need you to send an officer
over here right away.
Our nanny has
attacked my son.
Well, sir. Do you have any proof
that this young lady's responsible?
Proof? I need proof?
She was his nanny.
We trusted her.
Ma'am, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to take
you down to the precinct for questioning.
Please turn around and place
your hands behind your back.
Aah! Aah!
I didn't do anything wrong.
You're making a huge mistake.
This way, ma'am.
Settle down.
Get her out of my house.
Watch your head.
You're not from around here.
I can tell.
I pretty much know
everybody in this town.
Where're you from?
That's okay.
You don't have
to talk to me.
I can have a nice conversation all by myself.
Wouldn't be the first time.
You're gonna regret this.
Aah!
What the hell was that?
It sounded like that
police car crashed.
Jesus.
Stay focused.
It sounds like a bomb
just went off.
Forgive me if I'm finding it
a little difficult to focus.
Quiet!
Nat?
Where do you think
you're going?
Nat.
Stay in bed.
Who.. who are you?
I am here to
protect him.
From who?
From you.
I'll be good.
I'll be..
I'm sorry.
Before the almighty and
ineffable God Lucifer,
And in the presence
of all demons of hell,
The true and original gods.
I, Dr. James bolger..
I, Brian Miles..
I, Sarah blight..
I, Michael hein..
I, Marie Miles..
I, Janice karpinski..
Renounce any and
all past allegiances.
I renounce the false Judeo-Christian God jehovah.
I renounce his vile and
worthless son Jesus Christ.
I renounce his foul
and odious holy spirit.
I proclaim Lucifer Satan
my one and only God.
I promise to recognize
and honor him in all things,
Without reservation,
Desiring in return
his manifold assistance,
In the successful
completion of my endeavors.
So mote it be.
Hail Satan.
Now stay there.
Sofie..
What?
I'm sorry. I can't understand
a word you're saying.
Aah.
No.
Aah!
T
Tr
Tra
Tran
Trans
Transl
Transla
Translat
Translate
Translated
Translated B
Translated By
Translated By:
Translated By: H
Translated By: Ha
Translated By: Har
Translated By: Harf
Translated By: Harfl
Translated By: Harfly
Translated By: Harfly Z
Translated By: Harfly Zo
Translated By: Harfly Zon
Translated By: Harfly Zone
h
ht
Translated By: Harfly Zone
htt
http
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http:
http:/
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://
http://h
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://ha
http://har
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harf
http://harfl
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly
http://harfly.
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.b
http://harfly.bl
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blo
http://harfly.blog
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogs
http://harfly.blogsp
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspo
http://harfly.blogspot
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspot.
http://harfly.blogspot.c
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspot.co
http://harfly.blogspot.com
Translated By: Harfly Zone
♪ "Spesialis Penerjemah Film Horor." ♪
Nat.
If I can't kill you,
I am going to save you.
Nat!
Aah!
Open this damn door.
Now is the time.
Jack, it's now.
Somebody's
got to stop them.
And if you won't, I will.
Give me my son.
This town is the gate.
Your son is the key.
I'm calling the cops.
It won't do any good.
They're all in on it, Jack.
She's got my son.
In a thousand years, Satan will
be released from his prison.
And we must cast
him into the abyss.
And fire will come down
from the heavens from God.
And devour him.
And I will bring calamity upon them..
and they will not escape,
and they will cry for mercy,
and I will not listen to their cries.
Jeremiah 11:11.
11.
Jack, don't you get it?
11 is the devil's number.
Satan in his arrogance
added 1 to 10.
10 is God's
perfect number.
1 + 0 = 1.
Jack, all one with God.
11 is Satan claiming superiority.
Oh, you've got to kill him.
You're crazy.
Who the hell are you?
Before the transformation
for the sake of humanity.
Shut your God damn mouth.
Come on.
Daddy.
Daddy!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Shh.. You're okay.
You just had a nightmare,
okay? Go back to sleep.
I'll be right back, all right?
Where's Melissa?
Where the hell is my wife?
Aah!
Melissa?
No! No!
No! Aah! Aah!
No.
Aah! Aah!
What do you..
No.
Oh, God.
What did you do?
What did you do? What..
Get away from my son.
He's no longer your son.
He’ll  be fine
without you.
Get away from my son.
It's too late, Jack.
Jack, it's too late.
Who the fuck are you?
Aah!
Get back!
Stay back!
11:08
Aah!
Come on.
I'll be good, daddy.
Stay back! Get back!
or I'll kill him.
You gonna kill
your own son, Jack?
He's not my son anymore.
He lies to evil.
Aag!..
No.. No..
No..
Translated By: Harfly Zone
http://harfly.blogspot.com
♪ "Spesialis Penerjemah Film Horor." ♪