Monday Tuesday Wednesday
Thursday Everyday
My name is Kenji.
This could be me
three hours from now.
Why do I want to kill myself?
I don't know.
I wouldn't kill myself for the same
reasons as other suicidal people.
Money problems.
Broken heart.
Hopelessness.
No, not me.
Many books say death is relaxing.
Did you know that?
No need to follow the latest trends.
No need to keep pace
with the rest of the world.
No more e-mail.
No more telephone.
It will be like taking a nap.
Before waking up refreshed
and ready to begin your next life.
That's what they say.
This is bliss
Surprise!
Present.
But don't open it. It's mine.
Nice place. Big.
Not bad.
Sorry I didn't warn you I was coming.
I had a bit of an emergency.
Got any ice?
You don't have a TV?
How can you live without a TV?
You can't just read.
You'll go crazy.
I can buy you a TV,
and DVD too.
It's fucking hot!
Is Bangkok traffic always this bad?
Took me almost two hours
to get here.
Can't believe you don't have a TV.
Suicide again?
Hanging yourself this time?
It's too hot!
I need a shower.
This heat can kill you.
Why bother with suicide?
Black Lizard, by Yukio Mishima.
"Out jogging.
Don't answer the phone."
This is bliss
Kenji.
Tea is getting cold.
Got to find a way
to go back to Japan.
If not Japan, maybe Brazil.
Japan is better.
Fuck overseas.
But here you have a brother.
Yeah, the crazy one.
He reads too much.
You can't go back to Japan.
The boss will kill you.
But I've been with him a long time.
He's just in a bad mood.
A bad mood?
You fucked his daughter!
If you fucked my daughter,
I'd cut your dick off
and stuff it in your mouth!
Really?
You've seen too many
Yakuza movies.
Kenji, ready to go home?
Yes.
Kenji...
This is the form for the public.
This one is for staff.
Sorry.
Kenji.
I'm making sushi at home tonight.
Are you free?
I'm allergic to fish.
Sorry.
Nid?
Have you seen Nid?
She's somewhere here.
Nid!
What?
Let's go home.
I can't.
My client's still here.
I have to talk to you.
About?
The Last Lizard.
Are you Japanese?
Are you from Japan?
Japan...
Japanese... speak?
Stop fucking with the radio.
Nid, stop.
Are you crazy?
Take your headphones off.
What the fuck?
Did you fuck Jon?
Who told you that?
Did you fuck him?
Jon told me everything today.
What?
What did that dickhead tell you?
He's a dickhead. He's shit!
So why did you have to go fuck
a shit like that?
You couldn't leave him alone
because he's my shit, right?
Jon's such a dickhead. Don't know
why you care so much about him.
I know...
...Japanese.
I...
Japanese...
Getting off here?
Listen, Jon started it, not me.
That's not the point.
The point is you're my sister.
He's probably got his dick in some
other bitch's pussy right now.
Get out.
Out!
The lizard wakes up and finds
he's the last lizard alive.
His family and friends are all gone.
Those he didn't like,
those who picked on him in school,
are also gone.
The lizard is all alone.
He misses his family and friends.
Even his enemies.
It's better being with your enemies
than being alone.
That's what he thought.
Staring at the sunset, he thinks:
"What is the point in living
if I don't have anyone to talk to?"
But even that thought
doesn't mean anything
when you're the last lizard.
Nid!
Your car is
in the parking lot out front.
You know my crazy brother.
Make yourself at home.
We have a lot
to catch up on, Buddy.
Ice, ice, ice!
Is this a house or a library?
Damn, no ashtray.
Cool place.
You moved here for girls?
Or boys?
Thanks.
I'll wait until it's cold.
Kenji, aren't you going home?
Kenji, are you coming?
You go first.
You can speak Thai?
Want some pizza?
I know.
I saw the name card in your bag.
Thank you.
What are you staring at?
Are you washing dishes?
Don't.
Do you want to go home?
I can drop you off.
Don't burn my house down.
Nothing.
I am home.
Who the fuck are you?
What are you doing there?
Get Noi on the phone!
Noi! Noi!
What are you doing?
How dare you come in here?
Get out.
Get the fuck out!
Why did you leave me, Nid?
I'm scared.
I don't want to be alone.
Hey, did you see a Japanese guy?
What are you doing?
I bought you some sushi.
Fucking expensive.
Okay, I know you're sorry.
Thank you.
Good luck.
I don't want...
Thank you.
I thought you didn't want any more.
Too expensive.
I'm full.
Then stop eating.
Never mind.
No problem.
One, two, three, four, five...five.
You are very pretty.
Thank you.
I'm studying Japanese.
Really?
I'm going to Japan.
Where in Japan?
Osaka.
When?
Soon. Monday.
This Monday?
Really?
Nothing.
Just a friend. Friend, understand?
No, don't come. I'm going out.
Why do I have to tell you
everything? This is my life!
If you want to talk shit,
don't call anymore!
You want to stay, stay.
Go to hell!
1,375 baht.
Why am I cleaning the house
when I'm leaving in a few days?
I knew it.
The bitch blew me off this morning.
Now, go back down and blow.
Watch your teeth!
Did you fart?
You fart?
Not me!
That hurts.
Let's go home.
Hey, Jap boy!
Are you upstairs?
Jap boy!
Nid, I'm sorry.
Thank you for cleaning the house.
You're welcome.
Tomorrow we'll do the laundry.
That jerk!
Shut up, old man!
Hey, come sit here.
what?
Hey!
You need a woman.
What do you want?
You had Japanese
for dinner last night?
Are you fucking him right now?
Fuck your mother!
Come on, I miss you.
I don't miss you.
But what if I miss you?
Go fuck yourself, then.
Come on, don't be rude, darling.
Go to hell, asshole.
Let's go together then.
I told you!
Don't be rude!
This will teach you some manners.
So, this is your new fuck?
You'll be sorry!
Fucking Jap!
Bon Appétit.
It doesn't look like you.
Good-bye, Nid.
You need it.
When?
One day.
Kansai lnternational Airport, Osaka
Just one bag, sir?
Yeah.
We are only going there
to kill someone.
Then coming right back.
Hope you're not hijacking the plane.
Don't worry. We're not Arabs.
Here are your boarding passes.
Your gate number is 69.
Have a pleasant flight, sir.
Mr. Tajima, you're very funny.
Hey, young lady,
you have some seaweed
stuck in your teeth.
Are you Kenji?
Good day, sir.
Good day.
What the fuck?
Are you Kenji?
Get me a beer. I'm thirsty.
Excuse me.
Freeze!
Kenji?
This is bliss
Noi, someone's here to see you.
Separate subtitles extracted from
idx+sub by Officina verborum