♪ Fixed & Synced by
bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick ♪
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
Soz, it wasn't me. It were him.
Do you want that, then?
- I'll have it.
- Get lost!
Come on.
My mum locked us out and
l've had nothing all day.
- Go on.
- (DOG BARKING)
Why are you hopping?
I broke my leg. l got run over.
(SIGHS) Jesus, all right.
Cheers!
(BELL DINGING)
(SHAKING PAINT CAN)
(PAINT SPRAYING)
(COUGHING)
Well, what's up?
IT smells nice. IT
smells of pear drops.
You better open the window or we'll
both be on our bloody backs.
MUM: The careers officer was seeing
parents at school last week and...
Well, we've missed it.
That arrived this morning
asking where we were.
I've been down there this afternoon
and had a word with Mr Banks.
Are you refusing
to get Involved?
I was proper shown up
at that school today.
DAD: Well, l've not
encouraged any of it.
MUM: He's becoming a weirdo!
A recluse at his age.
Recluse is a bit of a
strong word, isn't it?
MUM: You stay out of this, Dad.
I want to hold my
head up in this town.
What about that youth club?
Oh, Mum, l'm not going.
Your cousin Lee's not
scared of going there.
I'm not scared!
What's your problem, then?
JOHN: Two steps.
Yeah, you're OK.
Grab the doorframe.
(SIGHS)
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Bloody hell, what's this?
You do what you want with this.
I can't take that.
You take it. They'll only
bloody nick it off me in here.
(CHUCKLES) They're not
that bad, are they?
Gotta share with the
bastards on the night shift.
(LAUGHS)
- OK.
- All right.
I'll see you Saturday
morning, then.
OK.
- You'll be all right.
- Yeah.
So, with your curriculum vitae,
uh, that's Latin, by the way, you
don't need to know that...
But your CSEs, metalwork, maths,
science, if you pass them,
- where do they go?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- You're late again, Clark!
- Been doctor's, sir.
You all right?
Wait a minute!
I'll not have sexual
molestation in my class.
And it'll only ever be molestation
with a face like yours, Clark!
- (ALL LAUGHING) -Book
out, mallet head.
And while you're about it,
do your top buttons up,
we don't want to see
your wispy bum fluff!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
You cretin!
You want to be a bit
more like your cousin.
He's a bit docile, but
he knows his place.
Clark! You bird brain.
Let's have it. Come on.
Come on. Let's get it over with.
What have we got here?
Oh, it's a poem.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- "l've got the blues for you.
- (ALL LAUGH)
"l'll never get used to that
feeling that you're gone.
"l'll never get used to
knowing l'm not the one."
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's bobbins, that is, Clark.
Who's the unlucky girl?
Sir, he fancies a
nurse on the bus!
Oh, yeah?
They're quite good
in bed, nurses.
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's not what we
are here to discuss.
IT's not going to get
you a job, is it?
All right, sit down.
I told your mother last week
you'd never amount to anything.
And that goes for rest of you,
you bunch of mallet heads!
- (SCHOOL BELL RINGING) -Now,
single file on the left!
LEE: Bruiser, l got it! l
got the queer notebook!
JOHN: Hey! Give it me back!
Nice poems, you little poof.
What do you know about birds?
You don't even go out.
You want it, you little spaz?
Too busy wanking. Wanking
over that nurse.
(TAUNTING)
Come on, then.
(ALL GRUNTING)
Get him, get him. Go on, Bruise.
Have him, have him!
JOHN: Fuck off! LEE: Hey! Hey!
- Fuck off, you twat!
- Ponce!
LEE: Fuck off! (LAUGHS)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (KLAXON SOUNDS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON TV)
(SNIFFING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
l didn't know you
were here, love.
DAD: Have you thought any
more about the youth club?
It'll be on tomorrow.
All right, l'll go once.
Good lad to you.
Well, l bet once you've been,
you'll want to go again.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR OPENING)
MATT: You little fez.
TERRY: Are you all right?
MATT: Yeah, not bad. l got a couple
of sixties things in my bag.
Maybe we could stick
them on at the end.
TERRY: What have l told you?
Look, no old stuff.
MATT: What? TERRY: Shite, l've
gotta change the record!
Hey, look, it's up to you.
You're the DJ.
TERRY: Look, l'm not playing
to an empty dance floor.
IT's all about the charts.
Do you still want to be a DJ?
- Yeah, but l'll convert them.
- (SCOFFS)
MATT: Give me a go. One record.
I reckon it will fill the floor.
Just one.
I'll make sure Linda
is out of the way.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, for fuck's sake,
not this shite again.
(INDISTINCT)
TERRY: All right, kids,
that's it for tonight.
I'll see you all
againlN a month.
Ta-ra!
Oi, knobhead! Fat twat!
LEE: Fucking have him!
Go on, Bruiser!
BRUISER: Come on, then!
LEE: Get him down, Bruise.
Come on.
Fucking have him! Wanker!
Come on, then!
(BRUISER GRUNTING)
JOHN: Come on, Bruiser.
Fuck him up now, you twat!
BRUISER: Hey! Come on,
then, you fucking wankers!
(ALL SHOUTING)
LINDA: Oi, you're banned!
- Get out!
- WOMAN: Linda!
You little sod, get out! Go on.
I see you around here again, l'll
kick your fucking teethlN!
LINDA: Go on! Move!
Move! Move!
(PANTING)
(LINDA SHOUTINGINDISTINCTLY)
Thanks for that, mate.
- What's your name?
- IT's, uh, John.
I'm Matt.
Hey, are you into Northern Soul?
Uh...
Yeah.
MATT: l've got tons of Northern
records, me. l've got all the labels.
IT were brilliant, that one.
JOHN: l've never heard
of any of it before.
MATT: l could tell. You look
like you're stuck in the '50s.
JOHN: Oh, and that
dancing you were doing,
it was like watching Bruce Lee.
MATT: Look. Step like me.
That's it.
Then l twist each foot.
Just like that.
That's it.
- You're doing it.
- (JOHN LAUGHS)
That's the basic fucking step.
Bruce bastard Lee, eh?
(GRUNTS)
See that.
"Burnsworth is a shithole."
Whoever did that was
absolutely spot-on.
- Every day l look at that and...
- l did that.
- You what?
- L did that.
What, you wrote that?
- JOHN: Yeah.
- (MATT LAUGHS)
You're a fucking
terrorist, ain't you?
JOHN: They knock
about together.
Really? How do you know him?
I don't, really.
Oh, good.
Where's your mum and dad?
Dad's dead. Mum left us.
Come on.
Hey, l'll tell you what,
you'll like that Edwin Starr.
- Got a fucking great record for you.
- (BOTTLES CLANKING)
l got his tape, right.
- Taped live at Blackpool.
- (THUDDING)
IT's our Paul's, but l can lend
it to you, if you like it.
"Den of Iniquity?
"Thousands of teenagers
dance the night away.
"High on amphetamines."
Wigan Casino, as soon as l look old
enough, l'm gonna go down there
and watch a Henderson set.
Be careful with this.
(LAUGHS)
- Paul taped it live at Blackpool.
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
- Yeah?
- IT's Ray Henderson's set.
PAUL: Hello, hello.
Did someone mention amphetamines?
Eh?
MATT: This is John. He
just helped me in a scrap.
Some big bastard from his
school started on me.
He waded in.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
- PAUL: Wow!
Well done, pal.
MATT: You know that graffiti
on the end of Newbold Street?
PAUL: Yeah. MATT:
"Burnsworth is a shithole."
- PAUL Yeah.
- IT was him. He did it.
What, you wrote that?
JOHN: Um...
Just the shithole bit.
Spot-on, pal.
He must be one of us.
Full of pond life, Burnsworth.
All anyone looks forward
to is going down local.
Not us though, eh, brother?
We're off to the
States next year.
The States?
PAUL: Tell him.
America.
We're going to get records.
They've got warehouses and
basements full of them.
You're joking?
He's got contacts in
Detroit and Chicago.
I'm gonna get tons of
stuff no one's heard.
I'll have everyone
begging me to DJ.
Yeah. Can't even get a
spot at youth club.
You watch, l'm working on Tez.
He'll give me a go.
We'll see about that,
you useless bastard.
Hey, are you giving
us some or what?
PAUL: All right.
Got four each, that's your lot.
There you go, pal.
Think you've earned these.
Get 'em down your neck.
What'll happen?
PAUL: "What'll happen?"
IN 45 minutes you'll
be Into next week.
Well, don't worry. They're made
for fatties to lose weight.
There you go.
MATT: l'm going record-hunting
tomorrowlN Manchester.
- Do you wanna come?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
See you about 2:00, then.
- All right.
- Yeah.
- Ta-ra.
- See you later.
Oi, knock on back.
(MUSIC PLAYING TH
ROUGH EARPHONES)
Fucking hell!
Fuck.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, let us in.
MAN: Visiting time is over!
JOHN: IT's not even
dinner time yet!
MAN: l said it's over!
Fucking hell!
(DOG BARKING)
(MUSIC PLAYING FAINTLY)
Hey up, cocker.
Hey, l wanna buy that record. You know,
the first one on Ray Henderson's tape.
IT says here, "Cover-Up".
Is that the title?
No, it's a cover-up.
I'll come down.
IT's a cover-up, it's
been covered up.
Cover-up's where the
DJ's hidden the title.
He gets a piece of paper
and it covers up the label,
so no-one else can find it.
Shit! How do l...
lf l wanted to go and buy
one, how would l...
How would l know
what to ask for.
You wouldn't. Why do you
think l wanna go to America?
IT's the only place you can go and find
a record that nobody's heard already.
You're all fired up, aren't you?
How was your night?
I just... l didn't even sleep.
I just...
- l get these...
- Tingles.
- Yeah, tingles, down the back of my neck.
- MATT: Brilliant.
See these lyrics, right?
I wrote them all down.
They just jumped out at me.
Really grabbed me.
- Tobi Legend?
- Yeah, they really meant something.
Does that sound daft?
- Bloody hell, you have been busy.
- Yeah.
"Life is just one precious minute.
Open up your eyes and see it.
"Give yourself a better chance
because time will pass you..."
- Do you know what l mean?
- L do.
Fucking great.
MATT: That's like the great
thing about soul music.
You listen to the lyrics on all
them records and they talk to you.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Detroit, '68, Ric-Tic label.
Like my neck.
WOMAN: Oh, dick.
Hey, Bazz, stick this
on for us, will you?
MATT: Put both booths on.
Hey, come on.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Fucking hell, those trumpets!
Hey! Come on, there's
tons of stuff.
Cameo-Parkway.
Philadelphia, a mean sound.
MATT: And Wand label
from New York.
Bloody hell, l'm having that.
That is a great magazine.
IT tells you all about soul records
and like, singers and that.
MATT: Have a look in back, a
fella called John Anderson.
He owns Soul Bowl Records.
All the top DJs buy from him.
You know, like Ray Henderson.
Move away from this section.
Thank you.
Hey, you, fuck off!
MATT: We're buying
serious stuff here.
You're not the only one
that likes "serious" music.
MATT: What're you doing,
three weeks Friday?
Piss off, dickhead!
I'm playing soul
at the youth club.
BETTY: Youth club? Have
you heard this, Ange?
Hey, l know you. The bus?
- Yeah.
- He always gives up his seat for me.
- L wouldn't sit where he's fucking been.
- Aw!
IT's always nice and warm.
Come on, Ange. We're not hanging
here with these kiddy-winks.
Who's the black bird?
I see her on the bus every morning.
She's a nurse.
A nurse, eh? Hey, maybe she could see
to this weird swelling l keep getting.
- (MATT LAUGHS) -She wouldn't
be interested in me anyway.
No, not when your mum's
dressing you in that clobber!
(CARS HONKING)
MATT: They got them. Brilliant!
Solatios. Fucking best!
I can't pay you back in full.
Don't worry about it.
Hey, come on.
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISTLING)
JOHN: Hi, is this
Soul Bowl Records?
Hi. Um, do you have a record by a Lou
Pride, I'm Com'un HomelN The Morn'un?
(YELLING)
Nice kit! Have you won pools?
Who the fuck are you? You
look nearly as good as me.
Do l look all right?
50% Bruce Lee!
Hey, l got this from Soul
Bowl Records, Lou Pride.
IT's on the tape, from the
all-nighter, Ray Henderson's set.
I heard the first ten
seconds or so of it.
Now l've heard the whole thing.
IT's great!
Do you want it?
Fucking hell, no. You keep it.
- Take it.
- All right.
IT's a fucking great record.
Hey.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on, we're going for it.
LINDA: Oi, oi, oi!
Tez's car's broke down.
Oh, yeah? How long will he be?
I don't know. About half hour.
I'll get things going.
You got any charts?
No, l've got loads of soul.
Just wait here, you
two, all right?
- (LINDA SHOUTINGIN
DISTINCTLY) -l'm on.
Are you gonna get
on the dance floor?
Hey, this is our chance.
Just give me five minutes.
I've got an idea!
All right, sunshine. Let's have a little
bit of this, shall we, while we wait.
Hey.
Hey, come to the youth club.
Hey, can you dance?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, where've you been?
Been rounding
people up to dance.
Rounding people up to dance.
What? Who are they?
I'll tell youlN a minute. You
get some soul on or what?
- I'm flying. Come on!
- (MUSIC STOPS)
Now, it's time for
some real music.
IT's the moment you've
all been waiting for.
Let's see you on that floor!
IT's Frankie Valli's The Night.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
You getting on the
floor or what?
(LAUGHING)
Hey, mate! You're
fucking brilliant!
BOY: What a night! What a night!
Did you see some of those moves? Those
Bruce Lee kicks and that! Yeah.
(MATT GRUNTING)
(JOHN GRUNTS)
Have you asked your Paul about
me coming to America with you?
- You better get saving up.
- Are you...
Are you serious? l
can come with you?
(IMITATING BRUCE LEE)
Listen, Terrorist!
If l say we make good team,
l mean we make good team.
I say the three of us,
we could go to States.
Come back with enough unknowns
to give Ray Henderson,
or any man,
a good run for his money!
So, we're... We're going?
Yeah. Let's do it.
- Let's go to America! Let's do it.
- (LAUGHING)
We're going to America!
Come on!
Hey. Easy.
(GRUNTING)
MATT: (OVER SPEAKER) Forget the
top ten, it's all propaganda.
This is underground, but
it's gonna be massive.
This is...
Shit. What're you doing?
Get on with it. You don't have
to be Jimmy fucking Savile.
This is Lou Pride and l'm
Com'un HomelN The Morn'un
(MUSIC PLAYING)
MUM: Keep these curtains closed.
Everyone in the
street can see you.
And keep the noise down!
All right!
Fucking hell!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
DAD: Well, thanks for
letting us know.
- (YAWNING)
- Bye, now.
(DOOR SHUTS)
What's going on?
MUM: He's gone.
He's passed away in his sleep.
What? Who?
MUM: Your granddad.
DAD: They said he had a stroke.
MUM: He's in a peaceful
place now, love.
(MUSIC PLAYING LOUDLY)
DAD: IT's 5:00 in the
bloody morning!
(MUSIC STOPS)
What are you doing dressed?
You didn't want him
here, did you?
I'll take you to see him if you like.
Before the funeral.
What's going on?
You've got your way now.
DAD: There's some tea there.
John, what do you
think you're doing?
Just calm down.
He's dead
and neither of you give a fuck!
Don't use language
like that in here!
You're a grown man now, you should
be able to control yourself.
Now come on.
Here.
Just drink your tea
and calm down.
No, l'm not fucking having it!
- DAD: John!
- Look at him!
This is what he does!
He fucking hated
that fucking home!
And it's your fucking fault!
Do something!
(DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS)
All right. You have two hours.
Please turn over your
paper and begin.
(COUGHING)
Oi, blockhead. Eyes
on your paper.
Do you not hear me, Clark?
Right, sit down. Now!
- Are you deaf? l said...
- (WHISPERS) Fuck off.
- (ALL GASPING) -What
did you say, lad?
(YELLING) l said fuck off!
That's a fire door!
You'll regret this, Clark!
(ALL MURMURING)
(KLD'S CHEERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
BAN KS: Someone let me back in.
(BELL DINGING)
Here you go, love.
Oi! Oi!
Fucking look at him.
Look at him.
MATT: (OVER SPEAKER) ls
that the best you can do?
Come on, you fucking bastards!
LINDA: Right, enough of that.
No more of that language, son.
Fuck off!
(LAUGHING)
Matt, there's a letter here.
- MATT: You all right, Ben?
- Matt.
They're not letting us in.
IT's that Linda.
She's not putting you on.
MATT: What's going on, Linda?
I'm bringing Terry
back on tonight.
Why?
I'm not having you on
them decks any more.
All that swearing.
I've been coming here every
fucking month and doing it!
What are you on about?
I've had enough of
your antics on that mic
and that music of yours
is just bloody trouble!
Most people came for our music.
Tell her, Terry. You know
they all fucking like it.
I think it were much better when
l was playing charts myself.
What do you know? You
haven't got a fucking clue!
Listen here, you
cheeky little girl,
the only reason you're on them decks
is because you let my car tyres down!
- L didn't touch your crappy car!
- GLRL: Yeah, you did!
- You told me you did.
- See!
- Showing off!
- Fuck off, you cretin!
Calm down and you go home now, or
l'll get someone to make you go.
Piss off, you lesbian!
- (BOYS LAUGHING)
- You shit!
- MATT: Fuck off!
- What are you doing?
(ALL SHOUTING)
l'm calling the police!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
BOY: Hey, come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
BOY: Fucking have it!
MATT: That fucking nasty bitch
don't know a thing about music!
(IMITATES LINDA) l'm
bringing Terry back on.
I'm gonna torch that shithole.
Who's helping me?
- (ALL AGREEING) -We'll
start our own club.
No more diva's on the dance
floor, we can DJ all night long
and play what the fuck we want.
Yeah, but it costs loads of
money to buy a night club.
Bollocks! You rent it.
Get people to pay in.
That pays for it.
Yeah, and the money we make,
we put towards America.
Brilliant!
You're not in on it, pal.
I know. Me and Bruiser
are going on our own.
Well, pipe down. l
were on a roll then.
- Sorry, man.
- (BOYS LAUGHING)
Yes! Now you're talking!
Our Paul knows of a club with
an ace wooden dance floor.
That's what we want, none of
this shitty concrete crap.
- Yeah, a proper dance floor.
- Yeah.
Yeah. Fucking yeah!
(ALL LAUGHING)
All right, l'll just go and get him. He's
outlN the back making a phone call.
Are you two promoters?
- Yeah.
- How old are you?
I'm 1 8, he's 1 8.
OK, l'll go and get him.
IT's a great dance floor.
I can see myself up here.
Dance floor full of fit birds.
Lou Pride playing top blast!
- JOHN: (LOW VOLCE) Get down, you dick.
- The queue a mile long outside!
"Matty, Matty, Julie and Tracy are
at the door. They can't getlN.
"Can you come and let them in?
Please?"
Oh, shit.
All right?
Where's your fucking dad?
Who are you, Baby Face Nelson?
Sorry, girls.
Come back when your
balls have dropped.
BOTH: We're 1 8!
1 8? IT's 21 you have to be!
My brother's 21, he's
doing it with us.
- So where is he, then?
- He's coming in a bit.
(FRED SCOFFS)
Don't waste my fucking time, eh?
Rita! Where's that
fucking delivery?
RITA: All right, l've been on the phone.
Don't worry.
(DOOR SHUTS)
JOHN: Well, why didn't you find
out the age thing was 21 first?
MATT: l didn't think about it.
IT's all right. Our Paul
will sort it, you'll see.
PAUL: Get off me! Ah,
you fucking bastards!
Get off...
Paul!
Paul, what's happening?
What's going on?
Paul?
- I'll get you out.
- (SLRENS WALLING)
He might not get out for months.
What are we gonna do?
We need more records before
we start our own club anyway.
Jesus! When did you decide that?
- (ALARM BLARING) -Fucking hell,
you're doing it again, you dick!
All right, you!
Twice in one day!
Follow me, the pair of you!
No bloody gumption.
Too busy thinking about
going out every night!
What this country needs is another
bloody war to shape you lot.
Come on!
You! You're on deliveries!
And you! You're in oven room.
With my little friend.
(MACHIN E RUMBLING)
SEAN: Who are you?
I've been sent down
here by Yarwood.
He wants me to work in here.
(BUZZER RINGING)
Don't open the fucking door!
- L thought...
- Sit!
Jesus fucking Christ!
Fancy a fucking go, do you?
No. No, look.
(LAUGHTER)
(BOTH MOCK SINGING)
Oi! Oi, oi, Matt, Matt,
Matt, this is Sean!
He's one of us! Hey,
check out his tat.
- Hey. You want a pint?
- I'm fine, thanks.
SEAN: Stay here, mate,
l'll get themlN.
(SEAN LAUGHING)
SEAN: So what's your
name, then, sweetheart?
What you doing with
that crazy bastard?
He bit a bloke's
ear off last year.
What would you do if some bloke
came at you with a fucking shovel?
- You drunk?
- No.
- (BU RPS) -What's a
cockney doing up here?
He moved for the music.
The lads upstairs say
he's on the run.
- Doing someone in.
- (JOHN BU RPS)
He changed his name
and everything.
He's going to Wigan. Wigan!
- Tonight!
- Yeah.
Ray fucking Henderson's gonna be playing.
He said we could go with him.
You do what you like, l'm off.
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
What?
He can help us get
our club going.
He's well fucking old.
Our Paul's out soon!
Fuck off. Fuck off.
- Matt!
- The fucking tits on that, mate.
Get them down you.
Do you fancy coming back to
ours and play a few records
- before heading out?
- Yeah, why not, mate.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
- Here you go, mate.
- Thanks.
Here you go, mate.
You can have them for now.
- Thanks.
- Them will last you a couple of weeks.
Don't do more than four
tonight, they're pretty strong.
And listen, a word of advice.
Don't go on the needle. Once you get
into that, there's no coming back.
- The needle?
- Injecting.
It's for fucking divs.
All right, cheers, l'll go easy.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADLO)
This is gonna be a
great night, boys!
MATT: We're fucking going!
Finally!
This tape's fucking ace.
Who made it?
We did, it's our
set, me and John.
We double deck together.
We're Invincible, aren't we?
Who bought this one, then?
Exus Trek?
- He did. Matt.
- Put it there, mate.
Look? This is in my top three.
Fucking hell!
Oh, bollocks!
- What's up?
- We need petrol.
There's a station
in about a mile.
Hang on. l'm going
to pulllN here.
Siphon some petrol from that
poxy fucking van back there.
(SEAN LAUGHING)
MATT: Hey. Under le' Well.
What a fucking name.
Where the fuck are we?
(MATT LAUGHING)
JOHN: Hey.
MATT: Who needs talcum
powder on your soles,
when you've got this
much fucking rain.
- JOHN: IT's slippery.
- (MATT LAUGHS)
JOHN: Hey, check
out this spin.
MAN: Who are you
fucking looking at?
Come to do ballet dancing
at the Casino, have we?
Fucking queers!
I could punch your
fucking lights out,
while kicking the crap
out of lanky here.
Same fucking time...
SEAN: Twat!
Prick!
Come on! Get in!
Come on, then, you
fucking bastards!
- Dickhead!
- (CAR ENGIN E STARTING)
SEAN: Get in the fucking car!
(SEAN YELLING)
Fucking In-breds!
MATT: Bastards!
Oh, fuck me, they
were some moves.
Did you see him,
the scary bastard?
- Never underestimate anyone in a fight.
- Yeah.
Get in first, bang them
as hard as you can.
IT all happened so fast. l
didn't have any time to react.
Speed makes you fast.
Just have some more,
you've had fuck all.
I've already had a couple.
SEAN: Four more won't
do you any harm.
Go on, the one's you've had
already would have kicked in
by now if they were any good.
MATT: Go on, have a few more.
Take these.
IT feels fucking great!
- Go on!
- MATT: Hey, watch the road, you.
SEAN: All right! MATT:
John, this is it.
We're finally going to
go see Ray Henderson!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
SEAN: (SINGING) Truly lonely..
She's here!
The nurse, Angela! Look!
MATT: She's got a bloke.
Ugly fucking lump.
Wait till we get in there.
Ten-a-penny birds like her.
Falling over to get
themselves a lad like you.
SEAN: Shut up, you
queer bastards.
(SEAN LAUGHING)
- Hey! (LAUGHING)
- (THUMPING ON CAR)
SEAN: Yes, boys, Frank and Phil.
(LAUGHING)
All right! What time do you call this?
What's happening?
SEAN: Keep your hair on. Just
sorted out some right Herberts!
Looks like you fucking
brought them with you!
SEAN: Don't be rude.
That's Matt and John.
Well into the scene they are.
Be nice. Don't bite.
SEAN: Frank...
(ALL LAUGHING)
FRANK: Are you all right?
PHLL: You all right?
Wait.
Hurry up...
JOHN: What are they doing?
SEAN: Speed. They're
going in on a needle.
Come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
SEAN: Are you fucking
ready for this?
Are you fucking ready?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Yeah!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Back up!
Get in!
(CROWD TAUNTING)
What? What are you going to do?
Yes, yes. Calm down.
DOORMAN: He's got tickets!
MAN: (OVER PA) The
crown of Detroit soul.
This is Mr Duke Browner.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL CLAP)
(ALL CLAPPING)
(SHOUTING)
SEAN: What's up with him?
Don't know. He's got a
bonk-on over the records.
He's got a bit of a problem.
Sweet baby Jesus!
Have you seen him?
Dances like a diva!
I need to go to the
bogs for water.
Can you not wait? Bloody hell,
you're covered in sweat!
I'll be back. IN a
minute, l'll be back.
RAY: (OVER SPEAKER) You look like
a willing dance floor to me!
You've got me, Ray Henderson,
for the next hour!
(ALL CHEERING)
Let's start as we mean to go on.
Gwen Owens, Wanted (AND NEEDED)!
(WHLSTLES)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(RHYTHMIC CLAPPING)
- Have you seen John?
- Yes, mate, fucking brilliant!
MATT: Get off him!
John! You OK?
John!
You've got to help
John, he's dying.
- ANGELA: What? Where is he?
- John's dying!
ANGELA: Can you hear me? MATT:
He had a few pills before.
How much? A lot?
I don't know. A few.
Go to entrance and get them
to call an ambulance! Now!
(WHISPERS') Fucking hell!
My friend's collapsed
in the bogs.
- What?
- My friend's collapsed in the bogs.
All right, l'll sort it.
But l want him out.
What's going on? Where is he?
Relax, look over there.
He's dancing.
- John!
- What a fucking night!
I thought you were dying.
I've never felT
so fucking alive!
RAY HENDERSON: (OVER SPEAKER) This is
the country's top sound right now!
So all you bootleggers
can back off!
No prisoners tonight.
The cover-up!
This bloke is fucking brilliant!
JOHN: Bombers,
green-and-clears, riccas.
MATT: Get on, you twat!
SEAN: Come on, get it
together, if you want a lift.
We're going to the
Stoke all-dayer!
MATT: Give us some of that
gear before it wears off!
Amphet, come on, anything. Sean's
got loads of it in the back.
Come on.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
SEAN: Will you keep your gob
shut about taking gear?
MATT: Sorry, pal.
IT were a joke.
We weren't thinking.
SEAN: See him? MATT: Who?
SEAN: He's Old Bill.
He never buys gear, never
dances, never buys records.
His tattoo on his hand, see it?
MATT: Yeah.
I'm certain when Frank
sold him gear last week,
that Lancashire rose, it was
stronger-looking with thicker lines.
MATT: Why did he sell him the gear?
SEAN: Well, he looked spot-on.
Then we all noticed he wasn't
in a hurry to neck his gear,
so now, l've been
watching him ever since.
Hey, get in Frank, Phil.
Come on, knees up, make
room for two little-uns.
FRANK: What are we waiting for?
Going to Stoke, aren't we?
PHLL: You two again? Hanging
around full-time now?
Hey, l'd watch him.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHS)
MATT: Fuck!
How much will you
give me for it?
Breaking my heart with this one.
A pound.
MAN: Oi, lads!
- (WOMEN LAUGHING) -Hey,
l've got some stuff
right up your street.
Straight from the States, like.
Hey, hang on. Take that.
MATT: We're going to lose the girls.
Come on.
I've got plenty more where they
came from, and on that same label.
Well, l'm in the Navy, aren't l? So
l pick them up and stuff, you know.
The name's Tezza,
this is my address.
If you want to come back and get some
more, you know where to find me, yeah?
Thanks.
Give us all of it. Sixty quid.
MATT: OK.
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
MATT: She's eying
you up again, pal.
Go on.
Get in. The place is crawling
with plain-clothed coppers.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
What's wrong?
IT's that black girl, ain't it?
Nice old girl, l'd bang her one.
(KNOCKS)
Just won the dance competition!
Dance competition?
Didn't know they even had them.
Listen, mate, l don't know who you
are, but do yourself a favor,
put that away,
it's embarrassing.
(LAUGHS)
Jesus! Who's organizing
fucking dance competitions?
(LAUGHS) His face.
We might as well go
to fucking Butlins!
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
- (ENGINE STARTS)
Hey, look what Angela gave us.
IT gives a description
of every drug.
Bombers, green-and-clears...
IT's written by doctors,
pharmacists, and that.
Why did she give you that?
I think it was meant for you.
So you don't go and take the
wrong thing, collapsing again.
What's up with you anyway?
Right, if you did a
less fucking pharmacy,
we might be able to
get our club going.
I know you've been
injecting as well.
What's it to you if
l've beenlNjecting?
IT's no different having pills.
(SEAN LAUGHS)
- We're in at the Polish Club?
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
Hey, he's been down
and done the deal.
Our Paul's out in a few
weeks, he's doing it with us.
What's that?
Fucking MIMS?
I told you to keep it quiet.
Fucking idiot!
Oh!
Fuck!
- (BANGS METAL) -Jesus!
Did you see that?
Well, yeah, you've pissed
him right off now.
We can't wait for Paul.
You've been stalling anyway.
Paul could be months.
We start in a fucking week.
This is what we've been working towards.
IT's our fucking time!
What's the matter with you?
- (CELL DOOR CLOSES)
- (KEYS JANGLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
l've been sitting here an
hour now, with no visitor.
You're making me look
like a fucking mick!
(EXHALES)
What the fuck is that you're in?
- A coat.
- Yeah, l know it's a coat.
IT's my fucking coat.
Borrowed it.
Have you?
Well, you look after it.
Genuine Italian is that.
How's that mate
of yours, anyway?
Eh?
- What's that supposed to be?
- Terror-wrist.
Terrorist. IT's a fucking joke.
Fucking hell...
- What are you "fucking hell" for?
- L shouldn't have to explain it, should l?
Cheer up, will you?
IT should be me that's
pissed off, not you.
I hope you haven't been
getting in any trouble.
I can't help you in here, can l?
(DOOR CLOSES)
- (KEYS JANGLING)
- Where you been?
Just met with that sailor kid.
I bought everything
he had for a fiver.
I'm probably going to
sell most of it, though.
You know what?
Take a couple.
Sell them and put them towards
your money for America.
- You sure, eh?
- Yeah, l'm nearly there now.
Thanks, pal.
MATT: Fucking hell.
How much have you got saved?
MATT: l don't know,
it'll help, though.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
JOHN: Matt!
- Matt, come here!
- Fucking cover-up!
You got it, John!
What's it called?
IT's The Salvadors and Stick
By Me, Baby We've got it!
Yes, we've got it. We got
the fucking cover-up!
Ray Henderson!
- We've caught you!
- We fucking got it!
JOHN: Fucking hell!
MATT: Roll up, come on.
Polish Club!
Next Friday, ninth of October.
Ray Henderson's cover-up
will be revealed.
Go on. IN you get. Doubles
for you, sweetheart.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
BETTY: Fucking hell, Ange.
You're dropping them.
ANGELA: IT's not my fault!
BETTY: Shit! Just fucking pick
them up, put your hand out...
Come on out, this
is the management!
- Shit!
- Shit.
BETTY: Shit, fucking hell!
I knew this would happen.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
How about a couple
of them for me?
BETTY: Oh, you fucking dick!
(ALL CLAMOURING)
l'll deal with youlN a minute.
Angie, listen, l need
to speak to you.
- You know my mate, John?
- Yeah.
- He's got a bit of a soft spot for you.
- Oh, Angie!
(WOMEN SQUEALING)
Hey, shut up, you.
This is serious.
He can't even dance
when you're around.
Ever since you and that
ugly bastard split,
he's been trying to work up the
courage up to talk to you.
Well, that "ugly bastard" and
me are still good friends,
so you better watch your mouth.
Yeah, you better watch your
fucking mouth, curly top!
Lanky twat!
Your mate's quite cute and
he's an all right dancer.
But there's something not
quite right about him.
- Well, what's that, then?
- L know what it is.
IT's you. IT's the fact that
you hang around with him.
- You're right, that's exactly what it is.
- BETTY: Have a shit!
You'll never guess.
The girls are coming back to
our house for a party after.
- What, Angela?
- Yeah.
You winding me up?
No, l'm not.
He's here, by the door.
Put it on now!
Listen, bastards,
we're gonna play a record you've all
heard Ray Henderson play before,
and so far there's
only one copy.
By next week, every fucker
will be chasing a copy!
So stay on the floor, bog
trotters, or fuck off home now!
- (CROWD BOOING) -This is a record
on Wise World and it's by...
CROWD: Come on! (BOOING)
Wait for it...
(BOOING AND CLAMOURING)
IT's by...
The Salvadors and
Stick By Me, Baby.
(CROWD CHEERING)
MATT: We're on fucking fire, us!
Untouchable!
He's leaving.
JOHN: Hey, Ray!
Hi. l'm John.
Thanks for coming down.
Hey up, you.
You got me. Well done.
So where did you find it?
IT was an accident. IT
was just a job lot.
An accident?
I've seen you knocking
about, selling your stuff.
You obviously know
your audience.
Now compared to you.
I don't suppose there's a chance of
getting a spot at your do, is there?
You cheeky, young fucker.
You've not been DJ-ing
more than two minutes.
Fuck off!
- We could do you a tape.
- Who's "we"?
Me and Matt, we double up.
MATT: (OVER SPEAKER) This is Billy
Butler and The Right Track.
So stay on the floor, bastards!
He's great! He gets
the floor going.
RAY: All that heckling
and swearing on the mic.
Who's he think he is?
Bernard fucking Manning?
If l were you, mate,
l'd lose him.
I'll tell you what, John.
I'll see about letting you do
the first half hour next week.
And l don't want any of
that shit on the mic.
We'll take it from there.
The warm-up?
That would be great.
Thanks!
- See you later, then.
- Thanks!
BOY: l'm trying to get
my hands on some gear...
- You what?
- You got pills, haven't you?
I spoke to Ray. He's
giving me the warm-up!
No, mate, can't help you.
BOY: There was a tall lad
out there with curly hair.
He said you have bombers,
l could do with some.
You know anyone selling, do you?
- No, not in here.
- Well, lad...
lf you do know anyone,
do let me know.
No problem. What's
your name, mate?
Uh, Ben.
All right, Ben.
That's squad.
Plain clothes?
IT's the first fucking night.
I've just had himlN here
with Mr Lancashire Rose.
IT's that daft twat,
he's told everyone in
fucking Manchester.
He might as well announce
it on the bastard mic.
Hey, Sean says last record.
We can play at least three more.
JOHN: Hey, come on,
don't piss him off.
All right, whatever he says!
MATT: (OVER SPEAKER) We're leaving
you with Frankie Valli's The Night,
but we don't want it
to be the last record,
and neither do you.
So we're carrying on
at 1 2 Alfred Street!
- (ALL CHEERING) -Run
back to our house.
Don't fucking announce
your address on the mic.
The filth are going to be crawling
all over you from now on!
IT's too late now, pal!
Is he paranoid or what?
He might have a point.
Don't talk shit.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
John! Sorry, mate.
The girls are in the
kitchen on their own.
Oh, God.
Get in there.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oi!
Get off those undies!
You touch my undies again,
l'll sort you right out.
I'll touch your undies
whenever l like.
Will you?
All right. You, out!
Come on, trouble,
you're helping me DJ.
Did you plan that?
(SCOFFS)
No, it was him. He's just...
He's daft, isn't he?
- Come here.
- What?
Come here. l want
you to look at me.
- Betty reckons you fancy me.
- (SCOFFS)
How does she know that?
Why do you keep
winking at me, then?
I've just had somethinglN my
eye all night, that's all.
All right, l might
like you a bit.
You hardly know me.
I don't know any girls like you.
Oh, what, black?
No, neither do l.
What, you don't know
any lads like me?
No, you twit.
I don't know anyone black.
Well, apart from a few faces
here and there in the crowd.
Are you adopted?
No, my dad's American, he
went back before l were born.
American? l'm going
to America soon.
Maybe you could go get
him and bring him back.
He's living in Chicago now.
Came over in the forces, they fell in...
Well, lust,
had me, then he
buggered off and left.
I don't know why anyone
would want to leave you?
Oh, l don't know,
maybe because my mum
can be a bit of a cow.
(SIGHS)
What's your favorite record?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
All right, Matt, you gonna get
coupled with that, are you?
(SEAN LAUGHING)
MAN: Angela!
- Ls AngelalN here?
- No.
MATT: Get out my house!
- Oi, Angela!
- What the fuck are you doing here?
- She's with him now.
- Move out the fucking way!
MATT: She doesn't even want you.
Stop it. Stop it! Leave him alone.
Jesus fucking Christ!
- Fucking div.
- What are you doing?
What?
- I'll fucking do you, dickhead!
- MATT: Get out!
Fuck off!
- MATT: John! John!
- Jesus!
- (THUDDING) -There's someone
trying to break in.
There's someone's
IT's me, you fucking simpletons.
Fuck.
SEAN: l'm checking for
the escape routes.
- What the fuck is he on?
- SEAN: lf anyone comes,
we get out through the roof.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
l've beenlN a fucking
shed all night.
The squad's watching my place.
They're closing in on everyone.
Fucking bastards!
I need to stay here for a while.
OK.
Hey, there's a strange-looking
car outside the house.
IT's mine, l borrowed it.
MATT: Look, l'm fucking shattered.
I'm going to bed.
Yeah, me, too.
Do you need anything?
No, mate, cheers.
You go to bed.
(MUFFLED COUGHING)
(SEAN COUGHING)
(SEAN VOMITING)
Are you all right?
Frank's dead!
What?
The police ambushed
us last night.
Got me, Phil and Frank
trapped in the front room.
Smashed the windows. Came
through, dogs and all.
Frank's been fucked
in the head a while,
he'd just jacked up,
grabbed the gun,
and shot himself in the mouth,
like they do in the films.
While the Old Bill were
panicking, l managed to get out.
Oh, my God...
(SIGHS)
Don't tell him.
And don't tell anyone l'm here.
No, you're safe.
Fuck!
SEAN: How long till this
trip to the States, then?
JOHN: A couple of months.
I'm just waiting for him.
I need a few months.
Well, how short are you?
I want to go travel
agents this week.
Can't you wait?
Well, how long do you need?
If you are in that much of a
fucking hurry, go on your own.
I knew it! You've
saved fuck all.
IT's all right,
l'll go on my own.
SEAN: l'll come with you.
I'm gonna off-load the big stufflN the
next week and get the fuck out of here
before the squad get me.
- Yeah?
- SEAN: Yes, mate.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Marvin Gaye?
Yeah, l got it off
that sailor kid.
You've had some fucking gear.
How else am l gonna
have a good time?
Look at these fucking lumps, not one
of them can dance to save their lives.
JOHN: For fuck's sake!
Look at him!
JOHN: He's having a fucking go!
MATT: Bollocks to them,
they're not worthy!
Where's your rhythm?
What are you doing?
An lrish fucking jig?
(CROWD BOOING)
l'll leave you with my mate here to
play you the kind of stuff you like.
- Tried and tested crap.
- (FAINT CHEERING)
Fuck off!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
What're you thinking
bringing him on, eh?
What did l tell you, lad? l don't
want any of that shit on the mic!
This is your break. You asked me
for a break. l'm giving it to you.
You've got one shot, lad.
What's going on, boy?
- L haven't...
- What he saying?
- You're off.
- We're a partnership.
Tell him.
Listen, you!
This is Northern Soul,
not Northern Arsehole!
John, you've got ten
minutes to fix it.
And you, you've got ten seconds
to leave this building.
You gonna let him speak
to us like that?
Us?
I'm the one that plays tried
and tested crap, remember.
You played Marvin fucking Gaye!
Who fucking cares?
They loved it and they've never
fucking heard it before.
Them? They know fuck all.
I don't know whether
you've noticed,
but we're fucking playing for them!
We're not playing for you!
You'll never get anywhere
crowd-pleasing, you dickhead.
(MUSIC STOPS)
- What's he playing at?
- L don't know.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISPERS') Fucking hell.
What a mess.
Sorry, mate, missed it.
Had to sit here for a bit.
Clear my head.
- Hey.
Yeah, l know the whole
thing were a disaster.
No!
No, l was just gonna say l
thought you were all right.
I was surprised.
- Really?
- Hmm.
Thanks.
JOHN: l'm just going
to go see Ray.
SEAN: Get in there.
Oi, where do you
think you're going?
Hi, l'm Matt.
Used to be your partner.
Yeah, used to be.
You got one big record that
someone else discovered.
You think you can
get me out now?
At least l've got one!
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean?
You're a shit DJ.
You've got a load
of shit records!
Even if you did have a good one,
you wouldn't fucking know it!
Fucking wanker!
(JOHN COUGHING)
RAY: Hey!
See that skinny twat,
get him out of there!
- Come on, posh twat!
- MAN: Hey!
- You're nothing without me, John!
- MAN: Come on.
- Fuck off!
- JOHN: You're a fucking asshole!
- Come on, John!
- Fucking asshole.
If l see you fucking again,
l'll break your fucking legs.
Now, fuck off!
SEAN: Look at the
state of that lot.
I'm worried about the
rest of my records.
Gonna try and get back
before him and grab them.
Good plan. Come on.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
SEAN: There's someone in there.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
That's them! Come
on, get after them!
(SLRENS WALLING)
SEAN: lf they find this lot,
we'll both get ten years!
A gun! What the fuck!
Go on, get out! Just lie
low for a few days.
Just come with me, just leave it all here.
Leave everything.
No, mate, l wanna make
some money on this lot.
We'll be in the States
before you know it.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, mate, now go while you can!
(SLRENS WALLING)
Fuck. Fucking drive!
OFFLCER: Come on, move it!
I fucking knew it.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(JOHN SHUSHING)
- (TRUCK HONKING)
- (CRASHING)
(GROANING)
Jesus, Sean...
Fuck.
(JOHN GROANS)
Oh, Sean...
Come on.
Sean, come on!
Get up!
(PANTING)
(SOBBING) Sean. No, please...
(SOBBING) Please don't die.
Please don't die.
TRUCK DRLVER: Are you
all right, mate?
Hey!
Where you going? Oi!
(SLRENS WALLINGINDLSTANCE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
You're still in shock, youth.
Get that down your neck.
STEE: You all right, John?
I didn't see you over there.
STEE: This is
horrible, isn't it?
JOHN: l'll have a rum and pep.
A pint of bitter.
BARMAN: Here's your rum and pep.
MATT: l'll get these.
BARMAN: And there's
your pint of bitter.
Is that it? A quid?
What do you want?
Well?
You know, it wasn't paranoia.
Coppers were all over
him, thanks to you.
You just
couldn't stop
bragging, could you?
Cos that's what killed him.
Your gob.
That was James Fountain's
Seven Day Lover.
And as we lost our close friend,
this was Sean's favorite record.
Luther Ingram Orchestra
and Exus Trek.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
There he is. You
all right, Matt?
You all right, mate?
Matt?
Fuck!
(SHOUTING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Do you want a lift somewhere?
Come on.
This is gonna be a
great night, boys!
I want you to come back with me.
I'll just take you
back, then, shall l?
JOHN: Yeah.
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(ANGELA MOANING)
- Lf you want...
- Yeah.
Are you all right?
(BOTH MOANING)
(WHISPERS') Hey,
wake up, gorgeous.
You all right?
I was dreaming that you
were still kissing me.
IT was really nice.
- What?
- What? (LAUGHS)
Your hair smells, what is it?
IT's nit shampoo.
I've been staying at Stee's. His
whole family got head lice.
- Fucking hundreds of them.
- Oh.
God, you scum ball, get away.
- JOHN: A few nits.
- No! (LAUGHING)
Get off!
Get off me.
You knob head, get away.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Yeah, come in.
Come on. (KLAXON SOUNDS)
ANGELA: l saw Matt yesterday
He started a new job
working on roads.
- (SIGHS) -You and him
were best mates.
And when things were good,
you were dynamite together.
You should get him to
go America with you.
America?
IT was always the
plan, wasn't it?
(INHALING)
Just smelling your hair.
See if it still smell
of that nit shampoo.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
JOHN: Hey, Matt.
I'm busy.
I need to talk to you.
Fuck off.
DAZ: What a bastard night!
Lad, am l boring you again?
You've gone back to sleep?
MATT: No, Daz.
IT's not you, lad.
Hey.
Faster! Step on it.
Eh?
- Just fucking step on it!
- What the fuck's got Into you, lad?
Well, what you looking
at there, mate?
You're bananas!
My own fucking
terrorist bastard!
Selfish bastard!
Oh, l can't believe it!
(LAUGHING)
You're freaking me out, mate.
Come on, now, calm down.
MATT: There he is!
Just drop me here.
Bloody hell, what's
Charlie gonna say?
MATT: l'm sorry, pal.
- DAZ: There you go, lad.
- Sorry, Daz.
Do you know what
you're doing, lad?
Yeah!
(VEHLCLE DRLVING AWAY)
MATT: Bit risky in daylight.
Still a fucking terrorist, then?
Could have picked a less
slushy record, couldn't you?
Thought the lyrics might tempt
you out of this shithole.
I was just getting used to it.
I got a new record,
if you wanna come check it out.
Come on, then.
What is it?
JOHN: You have to wait
and see, won't you?
MATT: Cheeky bastard.
You trying to do
cover-ups on me?
JOHN: l might be.
MATT: IT's gotta be shit,
then, if you discovered it.
(MUSIC PLAYING) (BOTH LAUGHING)
[ENGLISH - UK - SDH - BOZXPHD]