Coldblood
Heartless
Chaser
Iron Hand
Hero of the Wind: Zhang Han
Subtitles brought to you by the Deputies@viki
♫ The desolate wind hurts with its blowing.Who is it that is stirring? ♫
♫ The long night. The floating lanterns.Who is singing the praises of the light? ♫
♫ The Heartless person with deep emotions.♫ The Iron Hand that breaks the sky. ♫
♫ The Chaser who moves like the wind.The Cold blooded sword that cuts the sky. ♫
♫ As the heaven and the earth rise up with the clouds.I hope to stay with you always. ♫
♫ Love and hate are illusions. So please take care of yourself. ♫
♫ The wounds blown by the wind still hurt.The pain and tears are hidden in the heart. ♫
♫ Like a rainbow, vast spirits and aspirations passionately honor the heroes. ♫
♫ Honor the heroes. ♫
The FOUR-(Shao Nian Si Da Ming Bu)
Episode 44.
I want to avenge for my father!
You dare to betray me?
I dream about this for many years.
It is finally in my hands!
Devil Relics,
The Rare Book of Teacherous Spirit, the world's treasures.
You need to help me to change the world!
Let this world be mine alone!
Yao Hua!
I hate myself
for not killing An Shi Geng completely.
My father's revenge
is still left not avenged.
Your heart is hurting again, is it?
The me now
is it very ugly?
You are still the past Yao Hua.
Don't think about these already.
You need to learn to control your own feelings, understand?
I don't care about these now.
The only thing that I can't let go
is my father's revenge.
This is what upset me the most.
Brother Leng promise you.
I will definitely help you complete this revenge.
Between Heavens and Earth,
An Shi Geng and I,
only have one person surviving.
When I was at Divine Deputy Bureau,
I did many bad things.
Enough,
don't think about these already.
I am only afraid
that I would leave first.
I am afraid..
No, you don't Yao Hua.
Do you remember the Wolf Teeth I gave you?
It will protect you.
With me around,
you'l be alright.
Today, the weather is really good.
The wind cools a cup of tea. ♫
It is just like the day we met.
From now on,
you are officially deputies of the Divine Deputy Bureau.
From now onwards,
you must get rid of evil
and serve the Court.
Give it your everything,
until your dying day.
You can go down and prepare.,
Yes!
Brother Leng,
I am called Ji Yao Hua.
Lord Zhuge sent me and you to work together to investigate.
Why would Uncle send a female deputy to work on a case with me?
What's wrong with a female deputies?
A female deputy has a female deputy's advantages.
Think about it, if your clothes is torn, I can sew it back for you.
-If you are hungry, I can make food for you.-Enough.
Didn't you hear what Uncle said?
As a deputy, the most important thing is to get rid of evil.
For the sake of assisting the Imperial Court, give it your everything
until your dying day.
I remember.
Say it once more.
What is your name?
I am called Ji Yao Hua.
Have a great teamwork.
Ji Yao Hua, this name
from that day onwards, was remembered in my heart.
Coldblood, this word
is Divine Deputy Bureau's most powerful character.
Before I become a deputy,
I had long admired you.
Yes.
When we worked together that time,
we were so happy.
I really want to return to that time.
I want to return to Divine Deputy Bureau to take a look.
Lord Zhuge,
Butterfly,
Hai Tang,
each grass, each wood.
I never forget.
Don't worry.
I will definitely bring you back,
return to our Divine Deputy Bureau,
return to your Crane Division.
I remember that time,
every 15th
your Wolf Poison would be activated.
Whenever it starts up,
you are more cruel than a wolf.
Many people got injured,
there are also people who nearly lost their lives.
After that, your Wolf Poison was cured,
from a cruel wolf,
you become a human again.
And I
ate Replenish My Heartstrings,
and becomes heartless,
and without love,
lost my humanity.
I am like a wild beast.
Thinking about it,
you had Wolf Poison
and is forced,
while I
chose from a human to become a wild beast.
I really
deserved it
Don't worry.
See,
Didn't Li Mo cure my Wolf Poison?
She can definitely cure you.
Without Replenish My Heartstrings,
my pulse would end sooner or later.
No one can save me.
Brother Leng,
I suddenly feel very thirsty.
Can you find some water for me, alright?
I still have a lot of words to say to you.
Go.
You must wait for me to be back.
♫ I love you. Let me let [this] love go. ♫
♫ I'll forget you. Let me let [this] love go. ♫
Why is it that after so long, your hand is still so cool?
Sacred Lady has been sealed in ice for sixteen years,
the ice poison cannot be removed in one day.
In the future, I will warm you everday.
Foolish child.
I only need to see you,
my heart is warm.
As long as Sacred Lady come back to Holy Moon Sect,
use Western Dessert's warm sand, it can get rid of the Cold Poison.
An Qi Na, you are still like the past,
trying so hard to do your part and duty
and searched for me for so many year, it has been tough on you.
Searching for Sacred Lady is my duty.
Today, I am able to find you
is Heaven's care.
These toughness was not in vain.
These ten plus year, An Qi Na lead us
from the Western Territories to Central, searching all corners.
Efforts does pay off.
Yes. We not only found Sacred Lady, we also found Sacred Girl.
Our Holy Moon Sect is really double the happiness!
Yes.
Heavens arranged us to meet here.
Only we don't know
if this will be the last meeting.
Mother is worried that An Shi Geng will harm us?
An Shi Geng plotted to kill Wolf Clan,
harmed us, Art of Mind Reading family.
His aim was to gain the two treasures in the tomb.
If he really masters the Divine Martials Arts,
the people will be plunged into misery.
Then, we protect Sacred Lady and Sacred Girl and leave this place.
Mother, I am not going. I am not going.
Yes, we cannot go now.
We must think of a way to stop An Shi Geng.
We cannot let him harm the world.
It is so quiet inside.
Did he die from that injury?
He wouldn't die so easily.
I am just afraid that he suck the relic's power
and master The Rare Book of Teacherous Spirit, his martial arts would greatly improve.
An Shi Geng's martial art is sucking others' blood
and internal force to strengthen himself. This time is no exception too.
Once he master such martial arts,
it would be harder to deal with him.
Yao Hua!
Forget the past. It's too late for regrets.
We will not meet again. Do not look for me.
Bear in mind.
Brother Leng,
why are you alone? What about Miss Ji?
Why did it turn out like this?
She still cannot forgive herself in the end.
She is really too foolish.
Even though Ji Yao Hua did evil, she still in time of crisis,
injured An Shi Geng and helped us.
Yes, or else we would have died in there long ago.
It seems like she is seeking death and have negative thoughts.
It must be because of her eating Replenish My Heartstrings and cannot allow herself be shaken by feelings.
Rather than being heartless and no feelings, being a living corpse, why not...
She can only blame herself for walking down into the path.
You can't blame her, it is An Shi Geng making her to do that!
Coldblood, An Shi Geng has not appeared for a long time,
I'm afraid that he'll master the divine skill inside and escape this cave.
If An Shi Geng breaks free of this cave,
The four of us will use all that we have learned in our lives,
and fight to the death with him.
Yes, we'll bury them here!
You are making this too simple.
The two devil relics are the world's divine skills.
It can make the dead come back to life and the user immune to weapons.
Or else An Shi Geng would not have spent sixteen years looking for it.
If An Shi Geng masters this skill, there is no limit to his power!
Then even if we all combine our strengths, we wouldn't be his match.
I think we should think of safety first and hurry and leave.
If An Shi Geng breaks free of this cave,
the people harmed will not be limited to us.
It will also include the entire world's population.
We should make use of this time to think of a way to stop An Shi Geng,
not hurry and leave.
Mother is right.
I will stay and fight with you.
Ying Xue, you don't know martial arts.
You will just be sacrificed for nothing here.
That's right. Leave this place to us.
Li Mo, you should hurry and leave first with Ah Qi Na and Xing Yue.
Leave An Shi Geng to us. You all leave.
Li Mo.
I hope that you can leave here.
Sacred girl,
you have to think about the Holy Moon Sect.
Why are you all being like this? I don't care,
I will definitely stay here and be with you all!
An Shi Geng must have found the two devil relics!
Or else there would not be so much movement!
If he masters the skill and escapes this cave,
we'll all die here!
We must stop him from mastering the divine skills.
Open this Fantasy Feather door.
Coldblood, Ying Xue. I have to use both of your blood,
to see if I can try and open this door.
Let's go in!
-Let's go!-Let's go!
You four brats!
You've come just in time!
There is movement from inside! There is a terrible battle going on!
Mother, I have to go find Brother Leng!
Sacred girl! It's dangerous inside!
-Don't stop me!-Sacred girl, Mr. Leng has already said so,
for safety's sake, you cannot go in.
An Shi Ge is sinister and cunning. Now his power has grown.
I'm afraid that the Infamous Four will-!
You don't know martial arts! Going in would just be to your death.
Sacred girl, you just reunited with the Sacred lady.
You need not shed tears over this troubled waters.
I don't care! Let me go in!
-Don't block me! Let me go in!-Let go of her.
A mother and daughter are united in their hearts.
I can feel that in her heart,
she has gone into the room long ago. No one can stop her.
But the sacred girl doesn't know martial arts. Going in is to her death!
She cannot help the Infamous Four Deputies either.
Ying Xue,
if you want to go in,
then you must have the item to stop An Shi Geng.
Item?
What item is it? Hurry and tell me Mother!
The sacred girl doesn't even know martial arts, what mystical item can be useful?
The highest level of of the Mind Reading Skill,
can enter a person's innermost heart.
Thereby finding a person's strength
and weakness.
What Mother is saying is,
If I can enter An Shi Geng's innermost heart,
and find his weakness, then I can beat him!
That's right. The highest level of the Mind Reading Skill,
can become someone else.
As long as you enter the deepest parts of someone's heart,
You can become his parents,
His lover.
Ying Xue, I believe
that you can definitely find his weakness and beat him.
I understand.
Sacred lady you are intending to teach this method to the Sacred girl?
That won't work. You are so injured already, you cannot use your power again.
If everyone dies here,
isn't the ending the same?
Ying Xue,
Sit down.
You four brats!
You think you could harm me?
I have already mastered the world's absolute divine skill!
Black Dragon in the Sky!
An Shi Geng!
Get out!
You brat, you want to use the Mind Reading Skill?
Then we'll have to see if you have the ability!
Then let's give it a try!
Chu Li Mo!
Your Mind Reading Skill,
isn't strong enough yet!
Then have a taste of my Evil Spirit Deity Palm!
Royal Lord,
I am Butterfly Dance.
You've done so many bad things,
that's why Butterfly Dance left you!
You are creating a rift between us! Have a look at how I deal with you!
Do you want to kill me with one blow?
Butterfly Dance, how could I kill you?
Let me tell you. You simply aren't a match for the Infamous Four Deputies.
Royal Lord, you have done too many evil things.
I am asking you to stop.
See? Even Butterfly Dance is telling you to stop.
You were the one who made her die!
Royal Lord, everything you did was because of me.
You didn't harm me.
But I did die because of you.
Everything you did has harmed the human realm!
To get revenge,
you have added to my guilt.
You were the one who personally pushed the blame onto Butterfly Dance!
Royal Lord,
I hate you.
I hate you for life!
Do you hear that?
Even the Butterfly Dance you so loved hates you! She won't even take a step back for you!
It's your fault! (x3)
Don't say it!-It's you!
-Don't say it!-It's your fault!
Don't say it anymore!
Don't say it! (x3)
Li Mo!
-Sacred lady.-Sacred lady.
Wait! Don't go!
The way to stop him now,
is to break those two dragons!
Let's go!
♫ The sighing world is like a dream. I wake up to the lonely city you have left. ♫
♫ We laugh at the affection of children, as we are buried under ridiculous worldly attachments. ♫
♫ Used a lifetime in exchange for a kiss.Your dance steps is like nature itself. ♫
♫ The love is hard to forget, but the hate is too deep. These fireworks will eventually turn into dust. ♫
-I didn't think that after An Shi Geng did so many things in his lifetime, -♫ I hated that this world is so heartless. I do not deserve the spirit of your dancing. ♫
-It was all just for one woman he loved.-♫ My hair turns ♫
-Butterfly Dance.-♫ white through the pattering rain during the night. ♫
♫ My love is full of these flourishing memories. Even though fate is cruel, I have your red lips. ♫
♫ Why must we bring up these things after all this time. ♫
♫ As tears fall down like dead leaves,we yearn for each other as we are divided. ♫
♫ We yearn for each other as we are divided. ♫
-Greetings Uncle.-Greetings Uncle.
I'm very happy that you all could come back safely.
Everyone has worked hard for this bloody battle.
Uncle, we have already destroyed An Shi Geng.
The unjust are doomed for destruction.
That you could destroy An Shi Geng,
it really is a great thing for the world's people.
Even though An Shi Geng was able to get the Two Devil Relics and the Rare Book of Treacherous Spirits,
but he died inside that room without mastering the skill.
The bad cannot triumph over evil. An Shi Geng worked hard for so many years,
but even with all his planning it was difficult for him to avoid death.
With his death, the world is at peace!
An Shi Geng spent his life attached to his love.
In the end, he was still swallowed up by his own hate in the end.
Fortunately we managed to stop his revenge plan in the end.
Or else if he had succeeded,
Where's Li Mo?
Senior Uncle, I'm here!
Li Mo, you've returned?
I brought two sacred girls from the Holy Moon Sect
and my Mother as well to come see you.
Junior sister?
Junior sister Bian, it really is you!
It's me, Senior brother.
When we last parted in Capital City,
I thought I would see you again very soon.
I never thought that over ten years would pass with one parting.
Yes. We really haven't seen each other for over ten years.
But Junior Sister Bian you haven't changed at all.
Mother was frozen for sixteen years by An Shi Geng,
of course she hasn't changed!
This time when we went to the Fantasy Feather Rock Cave, besides getting rid of An Shi Geng,
the happiest thing is saving my mother!
Junior Sister Bian, what plans do you have for the future?
This time, after I have brought Ying Xue and these two girls of the Holy Moon Sect
to thank Senior Brother, I plan to return to the Western Territory's Holy Moon Sect.
I will resume the position of the Sacred lady.
Junior sister, you won't blame me for letting Li Mo learn the Mind Reading Skill, will you?
Why would I?
If Ying Xue didn't know that skill,
it wouldn't have been that easy to get rid of An Shi Geng.
This is all fate mandated by the heavens.
Everything has already been decided on since early times.
Yes. Jianghu is full of dangerous possibilities.
This time I plan to let Ying Xue come back to the Western Territories with me.
We've been separated for sixteen years. I want to make up for the lost days.
At the same time, I want to let Ying Xue
help spread the Mind Reading Skill everywhere.
Okay.
If Chu Li Mo goes to the Western Territories, then what about Brother Leng?
Yes. Coldblood already has an engagement, it is hard to refuse a royal order.
The Divine Deputy Bureau got rid of An Shi Geng.
King Father was very happy when he found out.
So he has already dissolved my engagement with Brother Leng.
He isn't my consort anymore.
That's great. It really is the world's best news.
-Then it depends on how you act.-What act?
Come a bit closer!
Marry me.
What did you say?
I said I want to make you my wife.
Elder,
I know my father had failed you in the past,
but I don't wish for such lifelong regret
to happen to Li Mo and I.
I will use my life to protect her, defend her,
and truly love her.
We've been through so much together.
We've experienced life and death.
You may choose for yourself.
Ying Xue,
Decide for yourself.
Mother,
I'm not filial.
I don't wish to go to Western Territories.
I'm very glad.
For the sake of love, you've made a proper decision.
Compared to your father, you are more receptive to love.
Ying Xue...
I'll leave her up to you.
Don't worry, Aunt.
Ah Qi Na.
Alright, runny-nosed.
Oh, right.
You said you wanted to stay.
That means you want to marry me.
Which one of your ears heard that I wanted to marry you?
Do you not? Hey! Aunt!-Ah!
Marrying me or not?
We're going home to the bridal chamber!
Heartless is alone again.
Ru Yan is gone. Mu Xue is gone too. He's now alone.
He's very lonely.
Look at the cow herder star and the weaver girl star.
They can only meet once a year. I think...
we're more fortunate than them.
Meeting just once a year.
Let me ask you this. If we could only meet once a year...
What would you do?
Then I would surely think of you every day.
Really?
I have a present to give you.
What present?
Here!
Isn't this the present I gave you on your birthday?
It was also the first present. Why are you returning it to me?
I'm not returning it to you. This jade is an exact replica. Look.
These two jade pendants really look exactly alike.
It took me a long time to find one that was exactly alike.an
They look naturally like a pair.
So...we are now a couple.
Here.
Chaser.-Hmm?
Everyone says that if you love someone, you could pick a star from the sky for them.
Would you give me the stars in the sky?
Whatever star you want, I'll pluck it for you.
I don't want it. I'm just teasing you.
I don't want anything.
I just want you by my side.
Eat some fruits.
What about this?
Its color isn't good.
Lychees, then
Bad texture.
This one, then! Its alkaline.
I've not been acidic recently.
Then, grapes.
Grapes are too sour.
Then what do you want to eat?!
Actually, I can eat anything.
It's sweet, right?-It's really sweet!
I love you!
Look at the stars.
Come look! The stars tonight are really pretty.
If we see a shooting star, we can make a wish. What would you wish for?
Silly. You can't say it out.
If you say it out, it won't come true.
That's true.
What did you wish for?
Me? I wish that we'll be together forever.
Naughty!
But...you can't wish the same thing as I did.
Why not?
You always have to order me around. You're even commanding me on this!
If we wish different things, we get two wishes.
That is true.
Then..what should we wish?
You should wish...you should wish that we'll bear...
We'll bear a whole group of children! They'll be running all over the Divine Deputy Bureau.
They will drive Uncle mad.
Who said they will bear you children?
Do you not agree?
Then what shall we name them?
Their surnames will definitely be Leng (Cold). So I should choose their names.
Their father is called Leng Xue (Coldblood).
I'm called Chu Li Mo. So...
it'll be Leng Mo.-Huh?
Leng Mo? It sounds really discordant.
Nope. I think it's good.
This name resembles his father.
As soon as one hears that they'll know that the father is a heartless animal.
-A shooting star!-Hurry and make a wish!
Thanks for watching!Brought to you by: The Deputies Team @viki
♫ The sighing world is like a dream. I wake up to the lonely city you have left. ♫
♫ We laugh at the affection of children, as we are buried under ridiculous worldly attachments. ♫
♫ Used a lifetime in exchange for a kiss.Your dance steps is like nature itself. ♫
♫ The love is hard to forget, but the hate is too deep. These fireworks will eventually turn into dust. ♫
♫ I hated that this world is so heartless. I do not deserve the spirit of your dancing. ♫
♫ My hair turns white through the pattering rain during the night. ♫
♫ My love is full of these flourishing memories. Even though fate is cruel, I have your red lips. ♫
♫ Why must we bring up these things after all this time. ♫
♫ I hated that this world is so heartless. I do not deserve the spirit of your dancing. ♫
♫ My hair turns white through the pattering rain during the night. ♫
♫ My love is full of these flourishing memories. Even though fate is cruel, I have your red lips. ♫
♫ Why must we bring up these things after all this time. ♫
♫ As tears fall down like dead leaves,we yearn for each other as we are divided. ♫
♫ We yearn for each other as we are divided. ♫