I'm here
to present an opportunity.
An interview with Carlos Mora
in Mexico.
You know him as "El Toro."
El Toro wants me
to interview him.
The biggest narco trafficker
since Escobar?
He's just gonna use Louise
to drum up support.
It's the opportunity
of a lifetime.
Julia, I really think
this is a bad idea.
I'm gonna be fine.
And then you will executive
produce your first show.
Más rapido.
Más rapido!
Julia, let's go.
I don't know
how long she's been gone.
Have you called
the Embassy?
Yes.
They have a legal attaché
to coordinate the investigation
from the U. S. side,
but we ‐‐
Don't worry.
We're experienced in handling
missing people.
No, she's not missing.
She was taken!
There's blood
in her room.
She's an American
journalist.
So you came here
to cover a story?
Wait a minute.
You were in the cantina
last night.
‐No, you are mistaken.
‐No, I'm not.
What was a federal doing here
last night?
Preserving peace
and order.
You were tipped off.
You knew we were here
to meet El Toro.
Señora.
If El Toro's
people saw you here,
they would've assumed
we said something.
You're the reason
Julia got kidnapped.
You came to my country
to interview
the most wanted man
in Mexico,
the leader
of a drug cartel responsible
for thousands of murders.
You're the one responsible
for whatever happens
to your friend, not me.
I killed Johnny Weston
because he was a predator.
He was sleeping with me
and my daughter
at the same time...
Megan, I'm sorry,
excuse me.
Why are you playing me
last night's show?
I was here.
I will call you
right back.
Dana's on‐air confession is
the country's top story.
I want you to come on tonight
and share your perspective.
‐I don't think so.
‐Come on, Jake.
It's only my second show
executive producing,
and I'd feel
a lot more comfortable
if you were
in the interview chair.
Megan, I represent Maya,
not her mother.
Coming on your show is
not going to help my client.
Is Maya still
in the psych ward?
She gets out
this afternoon.
Avery.
Avery Whitsell,
Jake Gregorian.
Avery just joined WCN
from our Vermont affiliate.
Tonight,
she's subbing for Louise.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to me you.
Congratulations.
‐Thank you.
‐I was hoping Jake would be
your guest tonight,
but he's playing hard to get.
‐Ooh.
Work your magic,
please.
So, uh, how do you
like L. A. so far?
Hello?
Louise, what's wrong?
Sunshine, palm trees...
And there wasn't a note
or a ransom demand, nothing?
No, I reached out
to the Embassy,
but I'm getting
the runaround.
Call my contact at State
until she answers,
the Under Secretary
for Civilian Security.
See what she knows.
‐Of course.
I'll keep you posted.
So, Mr. Gregorian, how can
I convince you to be my guest?
Uh...
Excuse me, Jake, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Yes, you can.
One moment.
Sure.
What is it?
Julia and Louise went
to Mexico last night
to interview El Toro.
Apparently,
the federales were tipped off,
and Julia was taken.
‐What do you mean "taken"?
‐She was kidnapped.
iRaúl!
iAquí estamos!
Stop fighting,
or this will get a lot worse.
Go on in.
Who are you?
Take the tape off, Raúl.
Aah.
My name is
Julia George.
Louise Herrick and I are here
in Mexico at your invitation.
Your men approached us.
‐Davíd!
I'm not your enemy.
I'm a journalist.
Come here.
What happened?
This is not Louise.
I did as you said.
I watched the lobby,
and you were right.
There were some federales
in the bar,
so we went upstairs
to room 3.
No. Louise wanted my room,
so we switched.
I can fix this.
Raúl.
Please.
Carlos, please,
I can fix this.
Davíd, hey.
You don't have
to do this.
I have been wanting
to talk to Louise Herrick
ever since her interview with
the Prime Minister of Canada.
I remember she flirted
with him just enough
to make him feel
comfortable,
and then...she pounced.
He gave it
right back to her,
and they both looked
brilliant.
I think she may have won him
the election.
I agree.
I produced that episode.
I know you want Louise
to interview you,
but I can do it.
No.
The world doesn't recognize
your face.
You cannot help me.
You're staying until I decide
what to do with you.
Come.
Let's go.
Come back! At least ‐‐
At least talk to me!
Save your breath.
Sorry, I didn't mean
to startle you.
I'm not one of them.
You're Ignacio Enriquez
from Las Noticias.
Yeah.
And you are?
‐I'm Julia George.
I'm a producer
from "Louise Herrick Live."
We thought you were dead.
Not quite yet.
Corporate called
a meeting upstairs.
Savannah Barbour, our C. E. O.,
arrived a few minutes ago.
Good. What about
the State Department?
The U. S. embassy
in Mexico
and Mexican Secretariat
of Foreign Affairs are aware
of the situation.
They're doing due diligence ‐‐
whatever that means.
Yeah, it means
everyone's scared to act.
No one wants
an international incident.
Darin, any news?
No.
Heading up
to that briefing.
K&amp;R team's already here.
‐What's K&amp;R?
‐Kidnap and ransom.
Corporations have
insurance policies for
situations like this.
The K&amp;R guys will do whatever it
takes to get the victim back.
I just don't believe
the richest drug lord
in North America would kidnap
Julia for the ransom money.
You're not coming
to this meeting.
The hell I'm not.
K&amp;R has directed corporate
to wait for the kidnapper
to claim responsibility,
provide proof of life,
or demand a ransom.
Now, obviously,
our primary concern is
Julia's life, but our K&amp;R
insurance policy will
be invalidated if we don't abide
by their directive.
We cannot let that happen.
Uh, Mr. Gregorian,
this is a private meeting.
Are you sure
about that, Savannah?
See, I represent
Julia George's interests,
so I should be here.
But last I checked, the
district attorney was not
an employee of your company.
My contact in Mexico called me
when Julia went missing.
It was me
that informed the network.
Your contact in Mexico ‐‐
You knew Julia was going
to Mexico.
You had federales
follow her, Max?
She was hell‐bent on going,
so I put some security in place.
Great idea.
All due respect, Savannah,
K&amp;R orders
of operation notwithstanding,
we do not have time
to wait.
We're dealing with Carlos Mora.
There man is a terrorist.
Julia will be dead
before K&amp;R lifts a finger.
We're doing this
by the book!
Per K&amp;R directive,
I'm calling for a media blackout
on Julia's disappearance.
And let's reconvene
after two hours.
If anybody finds anything out,
my office is always open.
‐How did you get here?
I mean, everyone heard
rumors that you were
interviewing El Toro,
and then nothing.
A few months ago,
a guy showed up
at my apartment.
He showed me a photo
of Carlos Mora reading my paper.
And then, he offered me
an exclusive with Carlos.
As soon as I started talking
about how his Robin Hood act
was a sham,
how he has done more
to harm the poor communities
in Mexico than help them,
he shut me down.
All he wanted was to use
the most respected paper
in Mexico to shout
his insane ideas
about revolution.
That's probably why he wanted
Louise to interview him.
People in my country are
desperate for change.
If I allowed El Toro
to shout nonsense
under my byline,
it would end with violence.
So, I refused,
and he threw me
in here,
where I get to be
his guest until I give him
the interview he wants.
I admire your principles,
but what good are they doing you
if everyone thinks
you're dead?
We have to get out of here ‐‐
whatever it takes.
No, no, no, no, no,
not if it means
legitimizing a madman.
The people want change.
If you give El Toro
a platform,
some people will listen
to him,
and there will be blood
in the streets.
I refuse to participate
in that,
even if it kills me.
I hope
you will do the same.
Here's what we know ‐‐
WCN has K&amp;R on the case,
but they're waiting on El Toro
to make the first move.
And, unofficially,
the federales are waiting
to take their cue from
the Embassy's legal attaché.
That explains why the federales
aren't breaking down any doors.
No one wants
to poke the bull.
Darin, can you get me
an affiliate crew?
We need to tell the world
what's going on.
Savannah called
a news blackout.
When Laura Ling and Euna Lee
were kidnapped by North Korea,
their families relied
on the news
to appeal to their captors.
We know El Toro watches
my show.
He likes me.
I'll make a direct appeal.
I just need a crew.
All right.
I'll do what I can.
In the meantime,
I'll pursue another option.
It's a long shot,
but Carlos Mora's nephew is
in custody.
Maybe we can make a deal.
‐What kind of deal?
Two years ago,
the Cuban government released
an American civilian
on the same day
that we released three
of their intelligence officers.
Now, the feds said
it was a coincidence,
but that's a hell
of a coincidence.
It's an avenue
worth pursuing.
Let's stay in touch.
Even if you pry them off,
the windows are boarded
from the outside, as well.
What do you know about
this place? I mean, how
far are we from help?
Not a lot of coming
and going ‐‐
Carlos keeps a small group
so they can move quickly.
He's got safe houses
across the country.
I've heard the guards talking
about moving soon.
The guards talk
in front of you?
Well, they speak
Zapoteca.
They don't know
I understand them,
so they don't watch
their words around me.
Right now,
they're pretty nervous.
Apparently, there was
a recent raid
in one of his compounds
in Saltillo.
He's convinced
one of them sold him out.
You should eat.
I want to talk
to Mr. Mora.
I have a theory
about the raid in Saltillo.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to get
an audience with El Toro.
It's our way out.
El Toro's brother is
Raúl Mora.
Raúl's son is Emilio.
Emilio immigrated
to the U. S. last year.
Four months ago,
he was pulled over
for running a red light.
When local P. D. realized
who they had,
they called the FBI.
The Justice Department threw
the book at this kid ‐‐
I mean, RICO charges,
money laundering, conspiracy.
So does he work
for the cartel?
Unclear.
El Toro tried and failed
to break Emilio out
a couple months ago.
He doesn't have
any sons.
I'm assuming he loves Emilio
and wants him back.
So El Toro might be open
to a trade.
Maybe, if we can convince
the U. S. Attorney
to even consider it.
100 grand.
‐Thank you, Ella.
‐What's that about?
You remember our old client
Graham Barrett?
Well, he still lives
in Mexico, Bradley,
and he has a contact
who can get me to El Toro ‐‐
his mistress, Maria Alvarez.
Wait, Graham is
a money launderer
a‐and a bail jumper.
I mean,
you can't trust him.
Jake, I know you want
to get Julia back,
but this is too dangerous.
I have a private plane waiting
for me, Bradley.
I will check in with you
when I land.
Hi. I'm Louise Herrick.
Thanks for coming.
How quickly
can you set up?
Uh, we'll uplink
to your control room,
and then we'll be all set.
‐The sooner the better.
‐Get yourself wired up, please.
Annie, we go
that uplink yet?
No, nothing yet.
You talk to Rita in New York?
They know we're preempting them?
Yes. I didn't say why.
I just said it was authorized.
Good.
Show me Louise and preview 4.
Got it.
Avery, prompter's loaded
with your copy,
then you'll throw to Louise.
Got it.
How's it going
in here, everybody?
‐Great.
‐Uplink is live.
Okay, we've got picture.
Louise, it's Megan.
I can see you.
Do you copy?
Loud and clear.
Louise.
Louise!
Get the signal back!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Louise, what happened?
Are you okay?
Yeah, we're fine,
but the van is toast.
Without a satellite
or a high‐quality phone,
I'm no use to you.
Okay, please,
go somewhere safe now.
Megan, you need to use
my show to break the news.
The kidnappers have
to understand
how important Julia is.
And if we make noise,
we can pressure
the diplomatic community
to help secure her release.
You've got two hours
to put it together.
Okay.
Get me a copy of Julia's
contact list from her computer.
Find footage
of Julia in WCN B‐roll ‐‐
photos, too.
‐Yes, ma'am.
Megan, we got
to keep this quiet.
I know.
Otherwise,
Savannah will shut us down.
I've been calling my contact
at the State Department
about the possible swap,
but I haven't heard
anything back.
I'm not getting anywhere
with the U. S. Attorney, either.
They don't want to talk
about Emilio Mora.
‐How would you know that?
‐'Cause I know you've tried.
Bradley put in a call
to his attorney this morning.
She called me thinking
there were new charges pending
against her client.
It wasn't hard to put
two and two together.
You're trying to use Emilio
to swap for Julia.
So what if we are?
I want to help.
Like how you helped
Jake get indicted for murder?
Look, I understand
why you don't trust me,
but I care about Julia,
and I'm gonna do
anything I can to help her.
I have some information
that might persuade
the government to act.
‐I'm listening.
‐The case against Emilio relies
upon a confession
he made to his cellmate,
Antonio de Silva.
Now, the problem is de Silva
isn't just some random guy.
The FBI placed him in Emilio's
cell to act as their agent.
Shouldn't that invalidate
the confession
and therefore the entire case
against Emilio?
Absolutely, and if you look
into de Silva's history,
he snitched
on three other cellmates.
If his involvement in
Emilio's case became public,
it would call those verdicts
into question, too.
The FBI would do
just about anything
to avoid that level
of embarrassment.
Right, not to mention
three possible retrials.
Assuming we can orchestrate
the swap,
we need to make sure
Emilio will cooperate.
Can you get us
on the approved‐visitor list?
I'll see what I can do.
♪♪
How do you not
go crazy in here?
I mean, six hours, and I
already feel like I'm losing it.
It helps to stick
to a routine.
Sun comes up ‐‐
I meditate.
I pace the room 500 times
for exercise.
And I've never stopped
reporting.
What do you mean?
I listen.
I watch.
I file away everything
that seems important.
‐What have you heard?
‐Raúl is picking up ammo
next Tuesday in Jalisco
from a man called Vicente.
The guards have mentioned fights
between the two brothers.
They think Vicente
might attack Raúl.
You, come with me.
So, tell me ‐‐
What do you know about Saltillo?
Nothing.
That is not
what my brother says.
I lied to him
so I could talk to you.
And here I am.
Your boss, Louise, is not
one to be trusted.
Clearly,
neither are you.
Louise isn't my boss.
I'm her boss.
I'm the one
behind the curtain ‐‐
just like you.
‐Should that impress me?
You come from a town so small
it doesn't even have a name.
You were raised
by your grandmother.
Your mother,
Graciela, taught you
how to turn poppies
into morphine
and morphine into heroin.
You think America's
War on Drugs is a joke.
It's not a radical position,
but I have a feeling
a man
of your intelligence has
an interesting take
on the subject.
What is your point?
Let me do the interview ‐‐
one hour.
You can say
whatever you want,
and I will broadcast it
on "LHL,"
which airs
in 130 countries.
You will ask
only the questions I give you,
and you will air
the footage unedited.
In exchange,
you will release Ignacio and me.
Do we have a deal?
Raúl, get the camera ready
in the other room.
I have to get ready.
You can wear the clothes
I bought for Louise.
Raúl, show her
where they are.
I should have known
you'd show up.
I'm just here
for some fresh air...
and to meet
an old friend.
Graham,
thanks for coming.
Well, I, uh ‐‐ I still owe you
about 10 grand, technically,
so it's my pleasure.
"Technically," huh?
This is Louise.
Louise,
this is Graham Barrett.
I was his lawyer
before he jumped bail
and headed to this side
of the border.
You're gonna help Jake
find El Toro?
Well, I can get you close.
His mistress has
a reputation of doing
just about anything
for a price.
I've got that covered.
Let's go.
All right.
I'd rather you be armed
than sorry.
Hey, hold on.
Your plan is
to just walk up to El Toro
and pay him
to hand over Julia?
No, Louise, I'm here
100% off the record
strictly to negotiate
a prisoner swap ‐‐
Julia for El Toro's
nephew Emilio.
I'm going with you.
If anything happens to her, I ‐‐
I understand.
Come on, let's go.
Good evening. I'm
Avery Whitsell filling
in for Louise Herrick.
We have breaking news.
Julia George,
the executive producer of "LHL,"
has been abducted in Mexico.
It is believed
that drug kingpin Carlos Mora,
A. K. A. "El Toro," is
behind the kidnapping.
We are devoting tonight's show
to her story as we make
a united appeal for her quick
and safe release.
With us tonight is
Dr. Sanjay Gupta,
Julia's friend
and colleague.
Dr. Gupta, how long
have you known Julia?
I guess it's been
about five years now.
We first met while covering
Hurricane Sandy.
And what was that like?
Well, you know,
I should start off
by telling you
that Julia was supposed
to be on vacation
that week in New York,
but then the storm hit.
And, of course, no surprise,
she came in to work.
And after Julia finished
producing her piece,
she started packing up
hospital supplies
and loading patients
into ambulances...
What the hell is going on?!
...for transport
to other hospitals.
And nobody asked her to do that.
I know it's early,
but cut to commercial.
She just saw the need.
Julia is
a pretty remarkable woman.
Thank you, Sanjay.
We'll be right back.
We're clear.
When we get back
from commercial,
air a repeat ‐‐
something upbeat.
No one talks
about Julia.
Savannah, I understand
there's protocol,
but we can't just sit
on our hands.
Every other station will cover
Julia's kidnapping.
If we bury this story now,
the network loses
all credibility.
Which I'm guessing was
your plan all along.
You're only keeping quiet
so we don't void
our insurance policy.
Darin, you're fired.
The story's out.
We don't have a choice now.
Finish the show.
What are you
still doing here?
All right,
let's keep going.
We're back in 10.
Dad.
Dad!
This isn't fair.
Savannah's just doing
her job, son.
I got in her way.
She fired me.
That's how it works.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm gonna be fine.
Don't you worry about me.
Dad.
I'll come by
for Sunday dinner.
I'd really like that.
I'm, uh, ready to begin.
I'm Julia George,
and I'm here with Carlos Mora,
the man known to millions
as El Toro.
This interview is being recorded
in an undisclosed location
in a safe house owned
by Mr. Mora.
Uh, please,
call me Carlos.
I'd like to begin
the interview by discussing
the alarming number
of drug‐related deaths
in our two countries ‐‐
by some accounts
750,000 deaths
in the U. S. and Mexico
in the last 15 years.
That is far too many.
I am aware
of the propaganda being told
by the newspapers
and the politicians ‐‐
that I am a terrorist,
that somehow I am the one
to blame for the violence.
But this blood is not
on my hands.
It's on the hands
of the government ‐‐
yours and mine.
What's your solution?
People will use
these drugs regardless.
Why not legalize them,
tax them, and use the money
to support the working people
of my country?
So, you're advocating drugs
as a way to save the poor,
including Schedule I
narcotics?
And to fund
the revolution.
There should be bombs
on every corner
until the state represents
the will and needs
of the people,
including the poor.
In a revolution, won't
more families get killed
than institutional
oppressors?
How does that serve
the poor?
Raúl, cut the camera.
Cut the camera.
Do you want to end up
like Ignacio?
You will keep your ignorant
commentary to yourself.
You understand?
‐Yes.
The world has to see
that you support my agenda.
Okay.
Let's try again.
Who are you?
I'm Bradley Gregorian,
and this is my colleague,
Ella Benjamin.
We're here to broker
your release.
My lawyer hasn't said
anything about anything.
Your Uncle Carlos kidnapped
an American journalist.
Our associate is
on his way right now
to negotiate
the exchange.
My uncle hasn't made
an honest deal in his life.
I don't want
to be part of this.
Your uncle tried to break
you out of jail six weeks ago.
No, the media got it wrong.
My uncle didn't try to free me.
He tried to have me killed.
And if I walk out of here
as part of some exchange,
he'll try it again.
Well, if that's true,
what makes you think you're
safer in here than outside?
Our associate is meeting
with his mistress,
Maria Alvarez.
‐It's a trap.
Maria is gonna demand money
and send him off to be murdered.
She'll never betray Carlos.
Do you know
where Carlos is?
Emilio, please, help us.
The clock is ticking.
We'll do whatever we can
to get you out of here
and keep you safe.
Please.
Where is your friend
meeting Maria?
Um, northern Mexico,
in Sonora.
My uncle has one safe house
in that territory.
I can tell you where.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, stay here.
I want to go bring Maria out.
We should do this
in the open.
What if Maria won't talk?
What if she can't help us?
This will work.
I trust Graham.
A criminal who ran off
without paying you?
He's the only option,
Louise.
Hey. What's going on?
I've got intel on Maria Alvarez.
Do not trust her.
Also, I got
a possible location.
Okay, thanks.
Got to go.
All right,
let's make us a deal.
Maria says she has the
directions to Carlos' compound.
Not to fast.
As you Americans say,
show me the money.
Nice to meet you,
too, Maria.
Hmm.
Carlos is staying in a farm
10 miles outside of Galeana.
There's an unmarked road
after the highway ends.
You can't miss it.
‐Let me guess ‐‐
Is that where
your friends take our truck
and leave us for dead?
That's crazy.
I would never do s‐‐
I just got the real coordinates
to the safe house.
Keep eyes on her
for the rest of the day.
Make sure she talks
to no one.
You got that, boss.
I'll be taking your car.
Consider your debt paid.
Thanks.
Let's go.
Although people think
of Julia and me as competitors,
I call her a friend.
We keep each other
on our toes.
We push each other
to work even harder.
And I beg the captors
to treat this amazing woman
with dignity and respect.
Thank you so much
for your time.
That was news anchor
Greta Van Susteren,
and we'll be back
after commercial.
And we're clear.
We're out of guests.
What do you mean?
We had at least
two other remotes lined up.
No, Anderson Cooper is
on a plane.
Katie Couric's interview with
Princess Kate is running long.
Who's up next, Megan?
Stand by.
Okay, we have 15 minutes.
We need to find someone
who knows Julia well,
someone who can make
an emotional plea on her behalf.
I hate to point out the obvious,
but that's you.
No, I have to run
the show.
‐We're running out of options.
‐I can cover for you.
Let's go.
Megan, you're on.
Just to wrap up the interview,
we have a few more questions.
Where do you see yourself
post‐revolution?
I'm only concerned
with the people in my country.
Do you see yourself
in a leadership role?
If my people ask me to lead,
I will lead.
It would be an honor.
Thank you, Ms. George.
Okay, uh...
Okay.
We should celebrate.
Um, champagne?
Uh, no, thank you.
Carlos, get in here!
They're talking
about Julia on TV.
Come on.
Oh, oh, sí.
I'm here with "LHL"
senior associate producer
Megan Byrd, Julia George's
second‐in‐command.
Megan, how is
your team holding up?
We're all scared
and worried, but we just ‐‐
We want to do right
by our boss.
We want her to be proud
when she comes home.
So, Megan,
what can you tell me
about Julia George
that no one knows?
Why does she inspire
such a fierce loyalty?
A couple months into
this job, I made a mistake.
I had drinks with a colleague
from another network,
and I let something slip.
The network brass wanted
to fire me,
but Julia defended me.
She said that if I go,
then she goes.
I owe her everything.
And when I think about what
might be happening to her ‐‐
I just want her
to come home.
Nice.
Let's cut to commercial.
We'll be right back.
Look at that.
Your return is gonna be
a huge story,
and the interview is
gonna be well‐received ‐‐
perhaps your
best ratings ever.
I actually agree
with you on that.
Megan, you have
to see this.
All right, everyone,
we're back in 20 seconds.
Louise took photos
of Julia's room.
She put up
a hell of a fight.
‐We have to air these.
‐No! Absolutely not.
We made a decision to talk
about Julia's character,
not about the crime
or the kidnappers.
Yeah, but this is part
of the story.
Avery, not the one
we're telling.
And we're back
in 5... 4... 3... 2...
It's been almost 24 hours since
Julia George was kidnapped.
We're speaking today with
her friends and loved ones.
But the question
on everyone's mind ‐‐
Why hasn't the kidnapper
made a demand?
I'm speaking directly
to El Toro right now.
What do you want?
Avery,
get back on point.
You want money?
We have people ‐‐
a whole corporation.
Make a demand.
Only a coward would kidnap
a journalist
who was invited
to conduct an interview ‐‐
a coward and a liar.
‐Avery ‐‐
‐You are pathetic.
‐Cut.
‐You are not to be trusted.
‐Cut!
‐You are a weak man...
Go to commercial, dude.
It's only been a minute.
... Carlos Mora...
Who cares? Do it.
... and the full force
of the U. S. government
will make you pay
for what you have done.
Your crimes will not go
unpunished.
Cut!
Avery, go
to commercial now.
We'll be right back.
You.
You're gonna pay for this.
What the hell was that?!
I'm sorry. Just
after seeing those photos ‐‐
You're sorry?!
After seeing
the photos, I...
Carlos, please.
Your people have insulted me
in front of 130 countries.
I had nothing
to do with that.
Here's what's
gonna happen ‐‐
You will go back
to America.
You will air
our interview tomorrow ‐‐
no edits,
no commentary.
And Ignacio stays here
another 30 days.
No, that was not our deal.
It is now!!
And if you do anything
to disgrace me,
I will kill him myself.
Then, I'll come
after you.
Emilio gave us
El Toro's location.
The feds have been trying
to get him to talk
ever since his arrest.
Yeah, they'd assumed
he was an enemy of the state,
but the truth is he doesn't want
to leave this country.
I told him we'd do our best,
but no promises.
Well, I've got bad news.
The U. S. Attorney won't
even entertain a deal.
He thinks that releasing Emilio
would set a dangerous precedent.
And letting
an American die wouldn't?
Bradley, at this point,
Jake has no leverage
with El Toro.
He's on a suicide mission.
You have to call him off.
According
to Bradley's coordinates,
we're practically
on top of the safe house.
I don't see anything.
Damn it.
Jake. Jake!
What now?
‐Go with them. Go.
‐Okay.
Easy, easy.
‐Money? Where's the money?
Okay, okay.
Julia.
Are you okay?
‐What are you doing here?
‐Carlos!
Hello, Louise.
So pleased
to finally meet you.
Who are you?
I'm Jake Gregorian.
I'm a lawyer here
to negotiate Julia's release.
I don't need your money.
I have something
that money can't buy, Carlos ‐‐
your nephew's freedom.
Emilio?
You can free my son?
My team is finalizing
a deal for his freedom ‐‐
if you release Julia.
So, that is
how you found me?
‐Emilio gave you my location?
This could be good.
Emilio made
a gentleman's agreement
so we could bring
this deal to you.
It was off the record.
No one else knows, I swear.
If he's told you,
he's told others.
No, Emilio
wouldn't do that.
He's my son.
He's family!
We have to leave here.
We're no longer safe.
We have to go.
Pack everything.
We're leaving.
Sí, jefe.
Take Julia
back to her room.
Kill the lawyer.
Okay.
‐Did they hurt you?
‐I'm fine.
It's you I'm worried about.
‐Shut up, both of you.
Raúl, why not convince Carlos
to take this deal, hmm?
Why not save your son?
We will get justice
for Emilio when it's time.
You have a meeting with
a weapons dealer on Tuesday.
His name is Vicente.
Isn't that true?
‐How would you know that?
‐There's not gonna be any deal.
Carlos paid him to kill you.
If you want
to live past Tuesday,
if you ever want
to see Emilio again,
you've got to trust us.
Get inside.
Move.
Please, make yourself
at home.
So, do I call you Carlos
or El Toro?
Whatever you like is fine.
What happens now?
You will travel with me
and report on my operations
exclusively.
You like
something to drink?
I hope you like wine?
I prefer red.
Red it is.
You got to be the most famous
journalist in the world.
We'd have to figure out
an arrangement.
I don't work for free.
Money is not a problem.
Only a very wealthy man
would be so uninterested
in a bag of money.
What can I say?
It's just
a drop in the ocean.
Mind if I take a look?
Go ahead.
Are you looking
for something?
I'm not an idiot, Louise.
Jake.
He could not be trusted.
Now, sit.
Sit!
Perhaps...
I will grow
to trust you later.
Not just yet.
‐It's done.
‐Good.
Louise will be joining us.
We'll come back and get her
when everything is ready.
Carlos, stop!
What are you doing?
You set me up.
You paid Vicente to kill me.
Why would I do that?
You're my brother.
You had a chance
to let Emilio go free.
My son wasting away in jail
because of your crimes!
Raúl, put the gun down.
Be reasonable.
I'm done taking orders
from you.
You're a dad man!
No!
Please, don't hurt me.
The keys are
in the S. U. V.
Your friends will meet you
by the back door.
‐They're alive?
‐Yes.
‐Now, listen to me ‐‐
I want you to go back
to America.
You get my son out of jail.
You understand?
Now, go.
Come on, get in!
I couldn't see where I was going
the whole way to the safe house.
I had the bag
over my head.
And then, he killed a man
like it was nothing.
Why?
Because he took me
and not you.
I'm so sorry, Julia.
It's ‐‐ I'm fine.
I'm glad
they didn't take you.
You would have hated
the food.
I really thought,
at any moment...
he might kill me.
Good evening.
Everyone here
at "Louise Herrick Live" is
grateful for the safe return
of our executive producer,
Julia George,
kidnapped two nights ago
by member
of Carlos Mora's cartel.
Mora, known as El Toro, was
found dead in Mexico yesterday.
His brother Raúl Mora is
the suspect in El Toro's murder,
and he is still at large.
In a separate
but related story...
Cue the photo.
...El Toro's nephew Emilio Mora,
who was being held in California
on conspiracy charges, is
in the process
of being released
after Assistant U. S. Attorney
Gerald Lee dropped
all charges against him.
I don't buy
that coincidence.
With Carlos Mora dead,
the feds don't need Emilio
for leverage anymore.
Emilio Mora moved
to America several years ago...
Well, maybe I shouldn't have
said that.
... and he graduated
magna cum laude...
I take it you and Ella are
still doing well.
Yeah. Sorry.
Oh, never apologize
for having a good source...
or being happy.
I'm honored to have a
special guest with us tonight ‐‐
Ignacio Enriquez,
the journalist
from Mexico's
Las Noticias newspaper,
held by Carlos Mora
for three months.
Ignacio, it's good to see you.
How are you doing?
I am good.
Thank you.
I have been granted
an emergency refugee visa,
and I have just accepted
a job covering cartel operations
north of the border
for the L. A. Times.
I have no plans
to back down from my work.
And, of course, I am so thankful
to Julia George.
She, uh ‐‐
She saved my life.
Tell us what kind of work
you'd like to do
now that you've gained
your freedom.
‐Megan, can you take this?
‐Of course.
Hey, what's up
with the 911 text?
I'm in the middle
of a show.
Julia,
I have some bad news.
I got a call from a detective
friend of mine in the LAPD.
He knows I represent
Maya Hartman.
Her car was found abandoned
on the Broadway Bridge.
She left her keys,
a wallet.
They think
she might have jumped.
She left a note
on the windshield.
What does it say?
"I'm sorry, Julia.
Please help my mom."
We're gonna get
through this together.
You believe me, right?
Yeah.
I got to go.