My wife's going to pay
at the association tomorrow.
These 50 are for you.
You sing just like him.
If you need anything ask the waiters.
Bocha, get something to eat.
I have an important show
next Friday.
We've been rehearsing a lot.
Do you want to come?
I'm playing "Unchained
Melody", alone on the piano.
I'll talk to your mom
if you like.
We're here.
Lisa! Lisa,
come here.
Remember to keep
a level head.
Bye beautiful.
Hey, Gutierrez!
Gutierrez!
You're listening
to concerts all day long.
2 hours at a burner, man.
Get on with it. Come on!
I'm yours, baby!
Dollars, right?
How much does Business cost?
Hi there!
Economy then.
What time does it depart?
August 14th.
Perfect.
Elvis.
- Great to see you.
- Freddie.
Come in and have a drink.
- Britney! Hi.
- Hi.
- Which one's ham and cheese?
- No idea.
The son of a bitch is making it
by the barrel. Look at this house.
They don't call me anymore.
You're lucky,
you're back again.
I invented rock and roll.
I was never gone.
You want me to blow you?
Why are you like that?
Like what?
Like the guy on the TV.
'Cos God gave me his voice.
I just had to accept it.
Listen to what he says.
Amazing, isn't it?
I don't know English.
He says women've scratched
and bitten him.
But he knows they don't
want to hurt him.
They just want a piece of me.
Guys.
No I don't think so.
OK. Bye.
Yes, can I help you?
- I'm here to get paid.
- Name?
What's your name?
- I'm under Carlos Gutierrez.
- Gutierrez...
Julio... Maria...
Carlos, here you are. 700 pesos.
They owe me shows for
the last 4 months.
That's what I have.
700...
Your lunch ticket.
Who is it?
Elvis.
- Hi
Mom!
I'm coming.
I brought you this.
Thank you.
Are you coming in?
Okay
What's that?
It' s for Lisa.
Lisa!
- Do you want to eat?
- Okay.
You're getting fat.
I'm trying to put on weight.
- What's that?
- How about "Hello"?
Hello
It's for you.
It's black.
Didn't they have
another colour?
See what it does.
- It doesn't do anything.
- Wait.
It doesn't do anything.
ELVIS.
I taught it.
Take it off the table,
I'm going to set the plates.
Lisa got chosen
for the school choir.
Yeah, Lorena too.
We're going to sing
at the school concert.
I don't know...
...the world of music
is very tough.
It's the school choir, Carlos,
she's not going on tour.
I'm just saying that
it's a tough business.
Do you want to go
or not, love?
Yes, I want to be with the girls.
Well, we 'll talk later.
Lisa...
If music is what you want,
I will help you, OK?
ELVIS.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
Many young artists
can't take the pressure.
What pressure?
- You'll understand me one day.
- Lower your voice!
You take her to school once,
and you think you're a hero.
And then you bring
that fucking bird.
Who' s going to buy
the food for the birdy?
It's a mate for Lisa.
Don't get jealous.
Damn the night I met you.
Can't you act like a father,
for once?
Priscilla, you'll always
love me.
Get off Carlos!
What are you doing?
- Don't call me Carlos?
- What's your name, then?
Sometimes I think
you want to drive her nuts.
Get out. Just get out.
- What is it?
- Get out of here.
Go!
Carlos, can I borrow
some deodorant?
Thank you.
To Sarah, please
Come on Sarah.
Do you hear me, ma?
I'm about to do something big,
what I always dreamed of.
I want you to know that
it's thanks to you and dad.
You will be proud of me.
You're going to see me
make it.
Lydia
Here.
This is for a few months.
I don' t want her
needing anything. Bye.
What is it, Gutierrez?
Here. Keep these.
- They'll be worth millions.
- What?
Where are you going?
He spoke in English.
Did you hear that?
Can you give me the eyeliner?
This one is OK, it works.
- Spray? You have some?
- No, I have mousse.
It works for you?
It's really cold in here.
Yeah, I'm shivering.
How many people came?
Not much.
But they usually come late.
Have you ever felt that
you've done everything,
that you've reached
your goals?
No.
Still, I got a promotion
at the supermarket.
I don't think you're good for her,
Carlos.
Lisa needs somebody who talks
to her, who understands her.
- Not your silly songs.
- What do you mean silly songs?
Wait. Listen to me.
A  friend at work got me a lawyer
and I'm asking for custody.
It'll all be easier.
You can visit her  for Christmas
and birthdays and stuff.
I think it's best for Lisa.
We can't take this anymore.
I'm fed up.
Good. Watch the chorus,
the song has to be perfect.
- This show is very important.
- Hello. Just a moment.
It has to be like the last one.
I want to sing Unchained Melody.
- Elvis.
- Not now, I'm rehearsing.
It's for you.
They say it's important.
Hello.
What?
I'm looking for my wife
and daughter.
Excuse me, excuse me!
My wife and daughter had an accident.
They told me to come here.
Name and surname?
Alejandra Olemberg,
Lisa Marie Gutierrez.
No, I can't.
I said no!
I can't play.
Who's with Alejandra Olemberg?
Your wife had an accident.
She suffered cranial trauma
and she's unconscious.
We're running a brain scan to
see if there is any damage.
- Are you sure it's my wife?
- Alejandra Olemberg.
And my daughter?
The girl is fine.
Doctors are assessing her condition
in the emergency ward.
- Where's that?
- Down the hall.
She is ready.
Lisa...
...shall we go?
Where?
You're coming with me.
Isn't mom coming?
No. She's staying
in the hospital for a while.
Let's go get the blackbird?
We gave it to a neighbor.
- What are they?
- Banana and peanut butter.
- I don't like it. It tastes funny.
- Lisa Marie loved them.
Is there anything else on?
I have another concert
if you like.
It hurts.
The doctor said to give me
the medicine every 4 hours.
It's been 7 already.
- Where are they?
- In my backpack.
It's in your room.
Where?
Look around. But
don't mess up my stuff.
Dad.
I can't sleep.
What is it?
Is mom going to die?
What?
I don't know.
I'm scared.
Me too.
It' s been 48 hours. She's stable,
but still not responding.
There's no toilet,
but I peed anyway.
What did the doctor say?
They don't know yet.
Can you play pool?
- Yes. Can you?
- No.
D'you want me to teach you?
Sure.
Lean on this, and you guide it
with these 2 fingers.
You have to hit the ball
into these holes.
The colored or striped one.
Now move, I'm starting.
Hit it with all your
strength. There.
Now you do it.
You've got to aim
at the white one,
and make the cue stick
go straight for the hole.
No, no.
- How?
- Watch me do it.
Great.
755.
7-5-5.
Anyone has that number?
You must participate to win.
959.
Stay here.
I'm going to play.
I can't hear a thing.
- This damn sound, this damn club.
- Come on Sandro!
What's your problem?
You come up here and sing.
Lady, what are you laughing at?
Fuck you lady and your
fucking hairdo.
And fuck this damn club!
Shit.
Open the door!
What's the matter? Are you nuts?
Don't do this.
Come on, chubs.
Listen. They're all waiting
out there. Come on.
Come on, asshole.
They're waiting for you.
What's wrong with you?
Who do you think you are?
Come on,
open the door.
Do you hear me?
Come out!
Take it easy guys.
The show must go on.
Fucking hell!
Where were you?
I had something to do.
- I thought you'd gone.
- No.
Why did you get mad?
I didn't get mad.
Yes honey bun, all yours.
Yes, all yours.
Sure, for you of course,
I've got to go. Bye.
I need to get paid.
It's 7 shows.
We don't make payments here.
You got to stand in line,
like everyone else.
You have to pay me now.
We haven't been paying
in the last 20 days...
...cos we're fixing
the building.
I have my daughter, and
Priscilla in hospital.
You have to pay me.
I'm sorry. You'll have to wait
like everyone else.
Call before coming out here.
Talk to the girls first.
You have the number, don't you?
- Do you know who I am?
- No. Who are you?
- I'm Elvis.
- Elvis, from where?
From Memphis, asshole.
I'm going to have this place
burned down.
Get out. You know how many
Elvises like you I have?
- Which do you want?
- This one.
- You want an olive?
- Yeah.
Stay here for a while,
I have something to do.
- And when will you be back?
- Before the show.
Please. I need my job back.
What happened?
You left me a message.
Your wife came to and
she's stable.
We're keeping her here
for another 24 hours,
and if she's okay,
we're moving her to a ward.
- Will she be all right?
- Yes.
Can I see her?
In a bit. She has to rest
for a while longer.
It hurts.
Don't worry Priscilla.
They said you're going to be fine.
Do you know how long
you have to stay?
No. I don't.
- How's Lisa?
- She's fine.
I took her home a few days.
Now she's with my mom.
With your mom?
I was passing a corner.
And I just can't remember
what happened.
I didn't put her safety
belt on.
I didn't put it on.
I'm sorry.
Tell Lisa I'm sorry.
That I miss her.
And I love her very much.
- And when will she be back?
- In a few days.
But now she's better.
She says she misses you.
Don't you want to come, Lydia?
I'm wearing the blue suit.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
You can sleep a little more
if you like. It's early.
I have a present for you.
What is it?
And this?
Where did you get it?
A friend at school
gave it to me.
His dad had it.
Thanks, beautiful.
We leave it here.
They made me quite
thin, don't you think?
How's the choir doing?
I don't go anymore.
I got bored.
Don't worry Lisa,
you'll find something that you like.
You were bom with a gift,
like me.
You just have to find it.
- Does mom have a gift too?
- No, not everyone has it.
I don't think she can stay here.
- Please, I couldn' t stay yesterday.
- Okay, just for a bit.
- Can you fetch her later?
- Right.
What happened with the car?
I almost had to pay for them
to keep it.
That's enough.
I have to sleep.
You should have benefits
for artists.
Some VIP room.
I was out there waiting
for an hour.
Can I go to the show tonight?
Now your mother's out,
you have to stay with her.
Why did you sell the TV?
'Cos I'm going on tour
in a few days.
It's very important for me.
- But, when will you be back?
- I don't know.
But you'll be fine, baby.
I'll miss you.
Me too.
When you really believe
in something
you have to pursue it
'til the end.
Those who don't
are unhappy.
I want you to be proud
of your father.
My boss told me they're going
to pay me the months I couldn't work.
Great.
Ma, can we make
some banana sandwiches?
Gross!
Bye, precious
Bye.
Let's go honey.
I want to hire a limo.
White.
For tomorrow.
Elvis...
Presley.