Quiet, please.
Excuse me.
You know, if you haven't learned
your lines by now...
...probably too late.
Thanks. Real encouraging.
Nice outfit.
- So you nervous?
- Yes.
So where are you sitting?
Front row, center balcony
with Alanna.
Oh, I didn't know she was coming.
Yeah, are you kidding?
We wouldn't miss it.
Got your tickets, got your tickets,
got your programs.
Programs, $5.
- Hey, hey.
- Programs, $5.
- Oh, hey, sweetie.
- Hey.
- I'm sorry I'm late. I got your text.
- Yeah?
I had to do a knee replacement.
Three hours. Can you fix this?
They need to quit treating you
like a resident.
- They think I am. Tickets?
- I don't. Thought you did.
May I please see
your tickets, quick?
Let's check them out.
Make sure these babies are legit.
You're bronze package.
- Problem?
- Minor.
I can bump you guys up
to platinum package.
It's a small fee, $22. Basically
better A/C in the building...
...better seats and the proceeds
go to a charity, a really cool one.
- You're Truman.
- Am I German?
Daughter's in the play.
- Yes, I am Truman.
- She's told us all about you.
All right, thanks for buying
the platinum package.
Excuse me. Hey.
- Hey, how are you?
- I'm good.
- Did you get a program?
- No, I didn't. I'll just look off yours.
So that took a while.
Yeah. I went to see a friend.
How is she?
She's nervous.
Well, I guess I would be too.
Thank you for joining us tonight...
- Excuse us.
- ...for our production.
Special welcome to our alumni
and guests. Good to have you.
We are proud
of our spring production...
...one of our enduring traditions
at the university.
But this year, we are featuring
some fresh new faces.
So join me, as we welcome
to the stage our cast...
...as they perform an original play
written by yours truly.
Thank you. Thank you.
So without further ado,
I present to you Annabella.
Annabella?
- Is that you, Desmond?
- Hello, Annabella.
You can dispense
with the pleasantries, Desmond.
It's a bit trifle, don't you think?
If you'd just let me explain,
I'm confident we would agree.
You need to know that my family has,
well, certain standards for me.
Standards in which I do not meet?
Admit it, Desmond. Please.
- I've realized...
- I've...
I've realized...
...that I have certain standards
that you do not meet.
- That's not right.
- I'll set sail on my own.
It's time I discovered the life
I've always dreamed of...
...but thought impossible.
Get it together, Hannah.
I'm leaving, Desmond.
Leaving?
Where, Annabella?
I'm...
What?
Hannah!
Excuse me.
Hannah.
Hannah. Hannah.
Get her inhaler. In the brown bag!
Get her inhaler!
- We need Hannah's bag.
- Hannah. No, no, Hannah.
No, listen to me. Hannah! Hannah!
Hannah. No.
Dr. Jacob Lawson, is he in surgery?
Thanks.
Yeah, but what I'd like to do
is maybe give her the tests.
- Yeah.
- Just to make sure.
Hi, sweetie.
I was looking for you. They said you'd
be here. What was that about?
Does he know what happened?
No, no, no.
The full test results
won't be in for another couple days.
But your PTF levels were fine
when you stayed here overnight.
So Dr. Stewart thinks
it's good for us all to go home.
Is that not what you think?
Yeah, no-- No, I do. I agree.
I agree with Dr. Stewart. He's a
specialist. We need to do what he says.
All right, well,
I'm gonna go get changed, I guess.
Okay.
"lf you just let me explain,
I'm confident we would agree.
You need to know that my family,
they have certain standards for me."
Standards in which I do not meet?
Admit it, Desmond, please.
It's time I discovered the life I've always
dreamed of but thought impossible.
Predictions?
Is there something
you're not telling me, Dad?
I was thinking about
asking you the same thing.
- Jacob.
- Hi.
Hey, Grace.
- Hannah.
- Hi.
It's good to see you all again.
Although, I wish it was under
better circumstances.
So how have you felt this week?
Any new symptoms or problems?
No, I feel fine.
Well, I've looked
at your EEG and MRI...
...and it looks like
we need to reconsider...
...our current management
of the epilepsy.
Stress, sleep deprivation and alcohol
can increase your risk of seizures.
Since you haven't had a seizure since
childhood I just have to ask--
I don't do drugs. I don't drink.
I don't smoke, I don't...
If that's what you mean.
Oh, I see.
BPD, acute asthma, seizures,
multiple hip surgeries.
Most when you were too young
to remember.
I remember some.
Hannah, I believe that
everything you suffered from...
...is related.
Why am I sick?
You were born very prematurely,
24 weeks.
Premature birth
or low birth weight...
...and a traumatic delivery
can be associated with this condition.
I was premature?
And that's why I'm sick?
Hannah,
we're concerned about you...
...because of the physical and
emotional symptoms that you're having.
What do you mean "emotional"?
Your father e-mailed me this.
"l feel dead inside.
No, something worse than death.
I am still a child.
A child trying to find a place
in this world.
I have many unanswered questions.
Questions I feel
but can't even begin to speak...
...because there are no words
to express them.
Something is missing.
Why, God, do I feel...?
Do I feel unwanted?
Why do I feel I have
no right to exist?
Why do I spend more time
wanting to end my life than live it?"
You--? You read my journal?
Hannah, I believe
that what you're feeling is normal...
...and is even expected.
What is--? What is this about?
What? What?
Hannah, we're not
your biological parents.
Hang on.
That's not how I wanted to tell you.
Why didn't you tell me
I was adopted?
Okay.
You were born premature...
...because you were the survivor
of a failed abortion.
Your physical, and, I believe,
your emotional symptoms...
...can be traced to this
as they have in other cases.
I can only speak
to your physical symptoms...
...but I'm suggesting
that you begin treatment...
...for your psychological symptoms
as well, immediately.
Now, I'm prescribing a new medication
to help control your seizures...
...and you have to continue
to take your current medication.
- Hannah.
- No, I have to go.
- Hey, I don't think that's a good idea.
- Don't touch me.
Hello?
- Hi.
- Hey, I can't hear you.
I have set your iron on fire.
Can I call you back?
Jason, the iron's on fire.
It's in my hand.
It's really loud in here.
Can I call you back?
The iron's on fire.
Sure, it's fine, whatever.
Call me back.
Bye.
We didn't even talk about
the e-mail.
What am I supposed to do?
My daughter is contemplating suicide,
I'm supposed to do nothing?
- I don't think so.
- It's not like that.
Hannah, sweetheart, please sit down.
We need to talk to you.
You've had 19 years to talk to me.
I can understand
why you'd feel that way...
...but, please, I would like
to talk to you now. So sit.
I don't wanna sit down.
I don't wanna talk.
- What do you want?
- I wanna see my birth certificate.
- Why?
- Because I wanna know who I am.
This is who you are, Hannah.
Okay, well, I wanna know
who my birth mother is.
I wanna know how I can find her.
- I can't do that.
- Why?
Because I can't. I can't...
I can't because I have no idea
who your birth mother is.
- I have no idea where she is. She--
- Here, it's your birth certificate.
Thank you.
Hel--
Who's there?
Hello?
It's me.
- You can put down the pepper spray.
- Great.
- How did you know I was here?
- You are way too predictable.
- I am not.
- Can I come in?
- No, I'm mad at you.
- What are you doing?
- I am taking off my shoes.
- Why are you taking off your shoes?
- Because I'm sorry.
And I don't like
when people are mad at me...
...especially you.
So are you doing all right?
No.
You wanna talk about it?
My whole life is a lie.
Why do you say that?
The hip surgeries...
...the nightmares...
...the asthma...
...the seizures...
...all of it's connected.
My parents aren't my parents.
They adopted me.
They adopted me because my
birth mother tried to abort me.
I guess I wasn't supposed
to survive.
And I barely did.
All I know, or all they will let me know
is that I was born in a hospital...
...in Mobile, Alabama,
which is 12 hours away.
And I don't know
how I would get there.
Or if I did go, what I would do.
I just-- I want answers.
I want answers to all these questions.
I wanna be able to get on with my life,
you know?
Because right now, I just feel stuck.
Like there's--
Like there's no way out.
I'm stuck in this place that I hate.
I told you I didn't wanna
talk about it.
Hannah, l-- I'm sorry.
I don't know what else to say.
I imagine things
are pretty terrible right now...
...but they'll get better.
That's really optimistic.
Look, things are gonna
work out, okay? I promise.
You'll know what to do.
What makes you so sure?
I know you.
I don't even know me.
- Who's that?
- Alanna. I'll just call her back.
No, no, no. You can answer it.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I mean, you should.
Hello.
Hey.
No, no, just hanging out.
What's up?
Yeah, yeah, sure,
I guess you can come.
Look can l...?
Actually, can I call you back?
Yeah. No, I promise.
All right, thanks. See you.
I am officially the worst
at planning road trips.
Three days before we leave...
...and we have no idea
where we're going. Awesome.
Look, get in my car,
I'll take you home.
We both have exams tomorrow.
That's the last thing
on my mind now, Jason.
I know, but we need to st--
I need to study.
Come on.
Just agree, reluctantly, please.
Okay, you stalker.
Behold.
- What a piece of junk.
- It's vintage classic.
It's vintage junk. Look at it.
- It's dead.
- It's not dead.
- This is your cousin's?
- Yes.
What does he look like?
Not nearly as good as the van.
By the way, I think I know
where we're going.
- You have a wild side, Hannah.
- What?
I know you've got one
deep down in there somewhere.
Don't you ever wanna just go crazy?
No, I don't.
I need you to have a wild side,
Hannah.
- Can I hear you say "Mardi Gras"?
- No, you can't.
And are you aware
that you're in a library right now?
- So did Truman tell you?
- Tell me what?
Well, spring break.
We finally decided on New Orleans.
And we want you to come.
Come on, Hannah.
NOLA, Mardi Gras.
You know, Mardi Gras
didn't actually start in New Orleans.
Yeah, it began in Mobile, Alabama,
which is on our way.
So I figured if we got some time...
...we can swing by there
and check it out.
- It's a pretty cool place.
- Thank you for the history lesson.
I'm just saying I don't want anyone
to feel like they're stuck on this trip.
You know, like, if someone wants
to go somewhere, they should go.
I was doing just fine
before you came over.
Do you think I'm ready
for a trip like that?
- I think it's now or never.
- It's now or never!
Come on!
I can't believe this.
Sir, this is a library.
- Jason.
- Hey, Mr. Lawson.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Thanks for getting back to me.
- Yeah.
- Let me guess. You're Truman, right?
- Yup. Yeah.
The charity
you were telling me about?
What is going on?
I thought I fixed that.
This is the classic upon which
we'll be taking our voyage.
Our Millennium Falcon, if you will.
Her name is Evelyn.
Hey, who's the old dude, man?
- You remember Hannah?
- Yeah, the spaz?
- Yeah, that's her dad.
- Oh, hey, dude.
- Who are you?
- Bmac, his cousin.
And I'm driving them to their thing
because this is my baby, you know?
I'm sorry, what did you say
your name was?
Bmac.
No, your name.
Your real name. Your actual name.
I go by Bmac.
I mean, seriously, why...?
I came to talk to Jason.
You mind a little privacy?
Absolutely, you should do that.
- Whatever, man.
- I'm sorry.
What can I do for you?
Hannah's sick, you know that.
So why did you invite her?
- What's that guy's problem?
- You look like the Unabomber.
Whatever, man.
I don't know.
I figured she might have some fun.
- Fun?
- Yeah.
- I was just trying to help.
- You're not helping, Jason.
You're not helping at all. In fact, you've
made my position very uncomfortable.
I'm sorry.
Look, Hannah's not listening to me
right now and l--
- I can't get in the middle of this.
- You're in the middle of this.
You are smack dab in the middle.
And I got stuff going on
at my house you have no idea about.
So I would appreciate it if you would
just take my side on this thing, okay?
Fine.
Yeah.
I wouldn't go 10 feet in that thing
if I were you.
She can hear you!
I didn't know that sticks and stones
could break your beard.
Here on the John Walter's show,
Revocation Radio, your true...
The sun is up and you're still here?
Yup. I gotta go to the clinic today.
Although,
I wish I was going in scrubs.
I had a really good talk
with Hannah.
- About?
- About the trip.
Told her I didn't think she should go,
be better if she stayed here.
I don't necessarily think
she agreed with me...
...but I do think she understood.
So she's not going?
I told her that we trusted her
to make the right decision.
So I think we're good.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna get some coffee.
- You want some coffee?
- Sure.
No, don't put in your headphones,
Diego.
Attention. Diego doesn't
wanna talk about our problems.
This is really a surprise.
Everyone wishes
they had headphones at this point.
- Fat Man's Burgers. Best.
- You do not know about burgers.
Meat is actually meat fillers which are
yellow pellets in a cardboard box.
Like, seriously,
when you cook a burger...
- ...all the bad stuff drains into the grill.
- It's in your body. It's in your arteries.
I'm not listening to you.
You're making me really angry.
That's the meaning of life
That's the meaning of love
That's the meaning of everything
And that's all you need to know
about everything
Yeah
You're really good.
Thanks.
That was supposed to be a jingle...
...for a barbeque company,
but they thought it was too deep.
You should go
on one of those reality shows.
I don't think so.
Those things are rigged, I think.
Sometimes I write songs
based on dreams...
...I imagine other people have.
Tow truck.
- Are you with the tow truck?
- Sir, step away from the vehicle.
- You been drinking?
- Of course not.
Why does everybody
always think I've been drinking?
- Explain this to me.
- Oh, what?
You can't drive on the beach.
They do it on TV. Also running, it's--
Curly Top, do you see
hotels on this beach?
- Yes. No.
- Any restaurants or bars?
- No.
- It's because it's a land preserve.
- For?
- Set aside for endangered turtle eggs.
Turtle eggs.
Dude, seriously are you...?
Am I being punk'd? Like what's--?
No. That's... No.
- Five thousand dollars?
- He's the owner and the driver.
No, Truman! You're the one
who told me to drive here.
I don't know your name.
I don't have time for this.
I need to impound this car.
I ask all of you
to pick up your belongings...
...and make your way to the curb.
- I'm gonna also need your names.
- Our real names?
- Excuse me?
- Sir, can I just say something?
This is my first trip like this, okay? I've
never done anything like this before.
And the only reason
that I came is...
...I'm trying to get
to Mobile, Alabama--
I don't have time for this.
I'm gonna have to ask you--
No, just listen.
I promise,
I have a really good excuse.
See, I'm trying to get to Mobile...
...because I just found out I'm adopted,
like, last week.
And this is my only chance
to find out who I really am.
I mean, to find my mother.
And, well, I think she lives there.
At least I hope.
We probably deserve everything
that you're trying to say, but really, l...
I've got $93.50,
no, 40, if this will help.
Ma'am...
- ...I'm not gonna take your money.
- Just take it.
Seriously, that was in--
I've complete--
- Thanks for letting us off the hook.
- Don't talk to me.
- Take care of this?
- Yeah.
Let's push it, y'all.
Come on, push, push, push.
Come on, Evelyn.
You can do it, Evelyn.
I know it's painful.
- Truman's not doing anything.
- I'm--
- Truman, I've been doing all of this.
- I hurt in my legs right now.
You did it.
Hey, Hannah.
I think-- I just wanted you to know
it's really brave what you're doing.
You know, like, the whole,
you know, thing with your mom.
I hope you find
what it is you're looking for...
...because, you know, it's important.
So I really shouldn't eat burgers?
I guess it's just so hard for me
to think about eating healthy food.
I mean, like, it just weirds me out.
Like-- And tofu?
I mean, who came up with the idea
to take a bean...
...and turn it into a sandwich that
tastes like a hamburger, remotely?
Vegans always try to tell you that,
like, tofu tastes like real beef.
That is untrue.
Know a guy named Jo-Jo?
I've never even heard
of a guy named Jo-Jo.
This is literally the worst hotel
I've ever seen.
It looked better on the Internet.
Where? At normanbateshotel.com?
Hotelmonkey.biz.
I'm sleeping in the car.
Hannah, you will be rooming
with Alanna.
There another option?
No, Danielle paid double
for her own room.
I'm sleeping here in the van,
so you can have my room.
That won't work
because you're staying with me...
...and neither Hannah nor Alanna would
wanna stay with me, would you?
Get away from me, Truman.
Respect Evelyn!
That's a lot of pills.
Yeah, it's ridiculous, huh?
You know what I think?
I think you just like to use this stuff.
That way, people have
to be nice to you, you know?
Like, poor little Hannah,
so wounded.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean--
Okay, you never mean to do anything.
But that's the point. You still do.
Why did you even
come on this trip anyway?
Jason invited me.
We didn't want you to.
He's just...
...too nice to say it.
I usually get up early,
but I can set an alarm if you want.
Hannah, just go to sleep.
What is wrong with you?
- What's going on?
- It's just me.
- What are you doing?
- Getting some stuff. Go back to sleep.
Hannah?
- Hannah, what's going on?
- I'm leaving.
It's the middle of the night.
Can we talk?
I don't wanna talk.
I'm leaving and you're staying here
with your girlfriend.
I realized that I am a problem
and that I never should have come...
...so you can just go to New Orleans
with everybody else in your posse...
...and just have fun or whatever.
I don't even care anymore.
You're not making sense.
What is wrong?
Apparently, I'm what's wrong.
Look, I'm leaving.
Don't follow me.
Dude, her dad's gonna kill you, man.
He's scary, man.
Sorry it took me so long.
The only rental place that was open
was by the airport, so it took a while.
- I don't need your charity, Jason.
- Yeah, you do.
What, so we're just gonna go
to Mobile together, or what?
Beats walking.
- What would Alanna think?
- It doesn't matter what she thinks.
This was my decision, all right?
She knows that.
Now, get in.
I don't have time for this.
- Why do you care?
- I care about you, all right?
You know, I'm not the kind of girl
who gets in a car with anybody.
Right, but you will hitchhike
by yourself.
- I wasn't hitchhiking, I was walking.
- Okay. No, that's equally smart.
I would have been fine.
Do you remember
when we were 9, I think?
When you were 9,
I was 8 and a half.
Yes. Thank you
for that unnecessary correction.
I was 9, you were 8 and a half...
...and we would go
with the Thompson kids.
- Remember, and we'd--
- Race to the water?
Yeah.
This all just reminded me of it.
- Hi.
I have $90 and change...
...or something like that and a phone
that doesn't work. The ocean broke it.
The ocean broke it?
- Do you have a towel?
- The cheapest we have is 110.
Unless you are AAA.
- Yeah, we are. We have all three As.
- Yeah.
- We need separate rooms too.
- Yes, because...
- ...we're not together like that.
- No.
AAA is 99.
Only one room available at that rate.
The only other room I have
is the luxury suite.
Two-ninety-nine.
That sounds great. We just need
the regular room, though.
- The very regular room.
- Yeah, standard.
Maybe next time.
I don't know. I don't know. I mean--
Easy.
Well, this is awkward.
Yeah. Definitely only one bed.
Yeah.
Are you asleep?
- I literally just laid down.
- Oh, yeah, sorry.
Are you okay down there?
Well, you know, I usually prefer
the king-size floor...
...but this is all they had
so I'll make do.
That's funny. You're funny.
Do you think I'm being weird
about all this?
Why are we whispering?
I don't know, I mean, you're like,
the popular college guy.
Girls...
...they find you attractive
and enjoy your company.
Would you think
it was weird if I said...
...I never been
with anybody before?
Physically speaking.
Which is purely
a hypothetical statement, of course.
Oh-- Sorry. I didn't--
I didn't mean to get into that.
- Good night.
I can feel you down there judging me.
You think this is totally ridiculous.
Like I'm some Christian
home-schooling freak.
- I'm a Christ--
- You thought it.
- I did?
- I thought so.
- No, that was a question.
- Look, here's the thing.
What's wrong
not having a wild side?
I mean, I'm glad about the fact
that I haven't done these things with...
And-- And-- l-- I have a wild side.
You've seen me play Scrabble.
I'm wild.
What are you thinking?
- I think--
- You know what?
I can't do this.
- No matter what the circumstances--
- Hannah, where are you going?
Stop judging me.
Go away.
Hello?
You're not a freak, Hannah.
Well, good night.
Was there a problem with the room?
No, no. No, the room was fine.
Because there's no refund.
No matter where you sleep.
Hannah, I'm-- I'm sorry.
I do have a wild side.
- I can't believe you broke in.
- I didn't. The door was open.
It was the back door
and you pried it open.
I used to wander into the old OR
at my dad's hospital.
The cool thing is, all the files
and all the equipment, it's still there.
Hello, I'm home.
Oh, scrubs.
- You got your wish.
- Yeah.
Have you talked to Hannah today?
I tried to call her a couple of times.
Her cell phone not working?
I don't think
that girl's ever gonna grow up.
I remember the first time
I held her in my arms...
...I couldn't believe something so small
could have such a power over me.
And I did see him smile.
I wonder if she's ever
gonna be able to...
...see things from our perspective?
I think we should tell her.
Tell her what?
Everything.
No, she couldn't handle it.
I think she could.
No, she couldn't. Trust me.
And I think we need to trust
our daughter.
- All right, turn.
- You know we can't see you.
Breaking and entering. Do you...?
Do you understand
the consequences?
You do?
Yeah. No. Not really.
All right, lookit.
Why were you there?
Alanna, don't freak out.
Something happened.
And long story short,
me and Hannah are in jail.
Yeah, well,
it's not like we planned it.
You've got yourself into this,
get yourself out.
Alanna, pl--
We've gone so far
and the hospital was all I had.
It's the only place that I had left.
It was a dead end.
You know, if you're gonna put me
in jail, please, just get it over with...
...because my dad's gonna kill me.
"Owen's Free Clinic."
Oh, my Dad's gonna kill me.
He's gonna kill you too.
This...
What are the odds?
I had some dealings with this clinic.
There were some bomb threats,
death threats and whatnot.
I dealt with a doctor and two nurses
and the reason I recall this was...
...one of this nurses was just,
well, she was very kind to me.
Here you go.
This is one of her statements.
The signatures are the same.
Why would she sign
my birth certificate?
No idea.
Her name is Mary. Mary Rutledge.
The phone is unlisted.
There's just an address...
...and it hasn't been verified
in quite a while.
Good luck.
- Wait, what about all the...?
- Don't worry about it.
Look, I'm very sorry for this
misunderstanding, all right?
I hope you won't think badly of our city
and you'll come back again.
- So we're free to go?
- Yeah.
Jackie out there
will get your stuff and check you out.
Oh, you know what, wait a minute.
What will you say?
I mean, if you find your mother?
What will you say? I'm just curious.
I don't know.
Well, my wife
has this thing she says:
"To be human
is to be beautifully flawed."
And, well, she's five months pregnant
with our fourth...
...so I think I understand
what you're going through...
...and how hard it must be.
So, you know,
life isn't always black and white.
So hate the crime, not the criminal.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Do you want me to go with you?
Yes? Can I help you?
- Are you Mary?
- Yes.
I don't know how else to...
Why did you sign this?
How did you find me?
A police officer
recognized your signature.
Sergeant Dodd.
You do favor her.
She was a pretty girl.
Barely 18.
I wasn't much older...
...but I was older.
The girls that came there...
...they really knew what they wanted,
you know, they were sure of it.
But your mother...
...she was conflicted.
I'm the one that took her in back
and prepped her for the procedure.
- The abortion?
- Yes, the abortion.
She tried to convince me that she was
making the right decision.
But, you know, she was really trying
to convince herself.
She told me
she didn't even know the fella...
...didn't know his name,
met him at a bar...
...and had a night together
and then he was gone.
I listened.
Listened to her
like I did a hundred girls before her.
Nodded, told her I understood.
For some of those girls,
I was their only friend.
Halfway through...
...well, something
must have gone wrong.
I wish I knew what.
But when I went to see your mother,
she was just awakening...
...and the doctor was telling her
that it had been a failed attempt.
Was that a normal...?
For him.
There were things
that happened there...
...terrible things,
things they had me do.
When you hear something
enough times...
...somehow you start to believe it.
It was tissue,
that's what they told us.
It was tissue that couldn't survive,
non-viable tissue.
Your mother came back
the next day.
She said she wanted to finish
the procedure...
...that she had to go to school,
have a career.
And she knew she couldn't do that
with the baby so this was the only way.
I took one look at her
and I knew she was in labor...
...and too young
and naive to know it.
I had two choices.
I chose to take her to the hospital.
When we got there,
she was ready to deliver.
She begged me to stay.
I was really the only one she had,
so I did.
- Your brother came first, I'll always--
- Brother?
I'm sorry,
what are you talking about?
Hannah, your mother
was carrying twins.
And your brother came first...
...and I always remember him.
He was so teeny.
He was less than a pound.
And he was damaged.
His arm was missing,
completely gone...
...torn off during the failed attempt.
And he was just...
I saw him shaking there.
I saw the pain.
And I didn't see no tissue.
I just saw the face of a child.
But you were the big surprise.
Nobody knew about you,
not even your mother.
And you came out, big eyes...
...just beautiful.
I never went back to that clinic.
And I never nursed again.
Was this mine?
Your mother's.
She gave it to me
when she left the hospital.
And then she just left.
They looked for her, but she changed
her name and she was long gone.
My brother, how long did...?
- How long before he--?
- Your parents...
...adopted both of you.
I would come by now and then
and see you in the NICU...
...they were always there.
They sat right by the incubators
and would read passages of the Bible.
They were praying people,
I remember.
And he fought hard.
He never did leave the hospital.
He died four months
after you all were born.
I know where your birth mother is.
I saw her not long ago.
And she did get that education
and she does have that career.
Her name is Cindy Hastings.
Now she works at a law firm in town.
Finally home after all that running.
I've needed to have my say.
Thank you.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Are you gonna go see her?
Yeah, I have to.
You know, I'm starting to think...
...that I shouldn't have found out
about all of this.
Because...
...deep down...
...there's always just been this...
...feeling.
Nothing that's happened
is your fault.
Come in.
Hey.
You gonna be okay?
All right, well, I'm gonna go sleep
in the ice machine or something.
How are you paying for this?
I saved a few bucks for this trip.
Don't worry, I'll bill you later.
Hey, Jason?
You know what the last thing...
...was that I remember
before I blacked out?
The last thing
that went through my mind?
Falling.
Falling into perfect blue water...
...holding your hand.
Why have you
always been there for me?
Good night.
Can I help you?
I'm here to see Cindy Hastings.
Oh, she's out at the moment.
Would you like to wait?
Do you have a restroom I could use?
Thanks.
Conwell and Hastings,
Attorney at Law. How may I help you?
Yeah, she's really booked up
for the day, though.
Monday?
Hi, can I help you?
I-- I'm sorry, Stacey didn't tell me
that I had another appointment.
I'm sorry that I'm just, like,
in your office like this.
I'm Hannah. I'm Hannah Lawson.
Are you one of the new interns?
You know, I would love to talk
but I have a lunch appointment.
I was...
I was born October the seventh, 1991...
...at Mobile General Hospital.
I guess I came here because I hoped
that that meant something to you.
Stacey, could you
please cancel my lunch...
...and hold all my calls.
I don't know what you wanted.
Hey, honey, you ready? We gotta go.
Lilly's waiting for us in the lobby.
Oh, I'm sorry. Who's this?
I...
I have-- I have no idea.
I don't know.
I'm Hannah.
Hi, Hannah.
I don't know where you got your
information from but it's not correct.
I don't know what you're referring to.
I can't take
any more cases right now...
...but Raymond down the hallway,
perhaps he can.
He can help you
with your civil dispute.
I'm sorry.
Hannah! Hey.
Look, I'm really sorry.
Yeah, she just--
- She didn't even say anything--
- No.
- It wasn't me. I swear.
- What are you, following me now?
- In the car. I'm taking you home.
- No.
I'm not going.
How do you even know where we are?
His girlfriend called me to tell me
and that you had been arrested.
I can't believe you would lie.
- You can't believe I would lie to you?
- In the car.
- We're going home, now. Come on.
- No.
- Get in the car now.
- Fine.
Fine.
- Mr. Lawson.
- Stay out of this, Jason.
- Mr. Lawson, look--
- I said, stay out of it!
- I know how you must feel.
- You have no idea how I must feel...
...and you can't know until you have a
daughter of your own. So stay out of it!
She's not your daughter.
And she has every right
to find out who she is.
I'm gonna make this very simple.
You stay away from my daughter.
You make no contact whatsoever.
Do you understand me?
You lied to me, Jason.
I expected much more from you.
Look at me.
Are we going to talk about this
or what?
Until we get this straightened
I don't think you should go to school.
I see no reason why I should
continue funding this sort of behavior.
- What happened down there anyway?
- Why do you care?
Why do I care? I care
because I'm your father. I love you.
If you love me,
you would have told me.
If you want to know the truth,
I'll tell you. It was three months--
Three months after we adopted you,
we find out...
...the medical bills
are not going to be covered.
We lose the house.
We have to file for bankruptcy.
I am one year, one year away
from finishing med school.
So tell me, how does that
make me the bad guy?
I'm sorry I was such a burden.
- That is not what I said.
- It's what you meant.
Hannah, stop. Stop!
- What was his name?
- What was whose name?
My brother.
I found...
I found my mom.
Sweetheart, I always meant
to tell you about that.
Right.
Jonathan.
Your brother's name was Jonathan.
Hey, guys.
- Oh, look, the prodigal returns.
- Hey.
- Where's Alanna?
- Good to see you too buddy.
You know, if you had been here...
...maybe I wouldn't
have had the audacity...
...to drink something called
a hand grenade.
That would've been a good thing,
because three sips in...
...you don't know
who you are anymore.
When I say I have
no recollection of those events...
...I mean I don't remember anything.
Nothing.
Not the argument, not the fight...
...not this guy, just a little shiner.
Oh, and look, it comes with a court
date, for free, disorderly conduct.
I have a criminal record, Jason.
I'd like to go home.
Oh, I got your luggage,
it's in my room.
Thanks, buddy.
I wanted to say that...
...I went too far and I'm sorry.
- Where are you going?
- Home.
We're going home tomorrow.
I'm going home tonight.
Dr. Lawson, it's Jason.
I wanted to say that I was wrong...
...and I won't be seeing
Hannah anymore.
I'm sorry.
- Hey, can I come in?
- Yeah, sure.
What's all this?
It's financial aid stuff.
Honey, he's not going
to take you out of school.
He's just upset.
I wanna try to explain.
This is you?
Yes.
You look so pretty in this picture.
You look pregnant.
I was. 20 weeks in that picture.
Twins.
You were pregnant with twins?
What happened?
We...
We lost them.
I started volunteering
at this pregnancy crisis center...
...and there was this beautiful
cathedral around the corner...
...and I would go there
to pray at lunch.
And I'll never forget...
...October 17th...
...I went back to work...
...and I saw a bulletin...
...and it said:
"Twins, abandoned...
...twenty-four weeks."
And we knew...
...you and your brother
would have been the same age.
Hannah, you are our miracle.
And that's why it's so hard
to let you go, honey.
You mean so much to us.
I know.
Which cathedral?
It was beautiful.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry,
but we need to close for the evening.
Oh, I didn't know.
I've never been here before.
I'm Hannah.
Hello.
We have services daily,
if you'd like to come back.
I'm actually a-- I'm Baptist.
I guess you should know that.
And why did you come?
I don't know, really.
I guess I'm trying to figure out
how to let go of things.
Things?
I can't figure out how to let go...
...of the fact that I feel hatred
for myself and others.
There, I said it.
What is it that you want to say?
Just say what you feel.
Well, three weeks ago I found out
that my entire life is a lie.
So I went on a trip.
I thought if I went that I would get
all these answers...
...and somehow when I got back
I would feel different.
But I don't.
My parents aren't really my parents.
And my real parents
tried to abort me.
And I have a brother...
Well, I had a brother.
He died shortly after the...
I'm angry at my parents
for not telling me sooner...
...and making me think
that I was just like everybody else.
I'm angry at my real mom...
...for not wanting me.
Why didn't she want me?
What's so wrong with me?
I found her.
And she still doesn't want me.
And I feel guilty.
Part of me feels like...
...he should be alive and I shouldn't.
I wonder if he would have been
a better person than me.
What he would have been like.
It's just l...
I just hate myself
for feeling this way.
I see.
This cathedral...
...was built in 1893...
...named for St. Paul the Apostle.
It's magnificent.
He wrote a letter to the Church
at Colossae and said:
"Because we have been
forgiven by God...
...we should forgive each other."
In Christ you are forgiven...
...and because you are forgiven,
you have the power to forgive.
To choose to forgive.
Let it go.
Hatred is a burden...
...you no longer need to carry.
Only in forgiveness
can you be free, Hannah.
A forgiveness that is well beyond
your grasp or mine.
A forgiveness that...
...you can't find on a trip...
...or even in this cathedral.
But if the Son shall set you free...
...you will be free indeed.
Well, I guess you'd better
close up then, huh?
What was your brother's name?
His name was Jonathan.
Jonathan wants you
to live your life, Hannah.
Live it to the full.
Come in.
I've been giving this
a lot of thought...
...and I wanted to tell you that...
...I am sorry.
I'm sorry that I overreacted.
So you're still enrolled in school.
Thanks, Dad.
And I think
you should probably pack.
What for?
What's this?
I know that you need to finish this...
...but with your permission...
...I'd like to be there when you do.
But there is this one place
I would like to take you...
...on the way, if it's okay with you.
Sure.
The doctor said
there wasn't much brain activity...
...but I saw him smile.
We truly believed
that God would heal him.
We were so young we didn't know what
to tell ourselves so we never told you.
Days became years,
years became decades...
...and you still didn't know.
After he died,
I remember holding you.
I would hold you for hours,
I would not let you out of my sight...
...because I was afraid
that if I lost you too...
So I would just hold you
because I couldn't let go.
And, sweetheart, I still haven't.
And I'm sorry, Hannah.
I'm sorry for the journal.
I'm sorry for keeping so much from
you, for how controlling I've been.
Sweetheart, it's not because
I don't trust you...
...it's because I'm trying honestly
to learn how to trust God again.
So please...
...don't...
Dad.
Yeah?
I...
I love you and it's okay.
Yeah?
Thank you for bringing me here.
You're sure
this is how you want to do it?
Stacey, can...?
- Hello?
- Jason, it's Dr. Lawson.
Yeah, listen, I wanted to say
that I assumed the worst about you...
...but Hannah talked to me.
She told me how you treated her
with respect.
How much you cared...
...and I think you should call her.
I...
Yeah, listen, I'm not saying
that I think you have to call her...
...but I just think that you should.
And I'm not trying to pry.
I just want to know what your
intentions are about my daughter.
I love her.
- You need to call her.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Yeah, I definitely will.
- Thanks.
- Stupid--
- Hey, baby.
- Hi.
Hello?
What, a date?
Like, me and you?
What about my Dad?
Yeah, I mean, I do. I mean, I will.
You sure?
Bye.
- This is stupid.
- You're stupid.
- You want to ruin the surprise?
- Yes.
I dressed for dinner.
- Five times, actually.
- Five times?
- I don't go on a lot of dates, obviously.
- Yeah.
- I'm good.
- Are you good?
- My dad is scary.
- Yeah, I know that. Okay, ready?
Three, two, one, open them.
I thought you should finish.
- Finish what?
- Your play.
- What do you think?
- I think we need actors.
Don't worry,
I was in a play once. Kindergarten.
- Okay.
- I was Sheep Number 5.
Hello, Desmond, you can dispense
with the pleasantries...
...a bit trifle, don't you think?
I think...
- They ex-- Have high...
- "Standards for me."
Standards for me.
- I'm pretty terrible.
- Yes.
Yeah. Well, look,
when I was Sheep Number 5...
...I didn't have lines.
I just-- I wore a sweaty wool suit.
I did not just say that.
That is ridiculous.
"l don't suppose
you're talking to family."
Okay, I think this is the last of it.
Call us, all right?
Let us know who your roommate is.
Try not to pick anybody too weird.
- I'll be fine, Dad, I promise.
- Okay.
I've got to go.
- Bye, Dad.
- Bye.
Mr. Lawson.
Thank you.
- For what?
- For wanting me.
- I gotta go.
- You gotta go.
I love you, baby.
Well, initially, Jon called me.
He said,
"We think that you would play...
...the birth mother in this film."
Jon e-mailed me the script...
...and I was so excited
I think I sat down that very night.
I got to the point
of the birth mother...
...and I was so overwhelmed
I started crying over it...
...because the story actually
had been truly written for me...
...and Jon and Andy
didn't even know my back-story at all.
And she read it...
...and literally called me back...
...just weeping
about the script and said:
"How did you know?"
And we said,
"What are you talking about?"
And she said:
"20 years ago
I was working in a law firm."
Which is very similar to the story.
She said she was in a relationship...
...she found out she was pregnant
and she decided to have an abortion.
It was easier to get rid of the child...
...to not be questioned again...
...rather than to have a child...
...and be looked upon at that time
like another failure.
And...
So many times...
...I think
especially as young women...
...we carry that burden...
...that we're going to look like a failure.
That it's shameful.
And, you know,
you can hide a secret...
...for a long time of abortion
unless you verbally speak about it.
"Nobody knows. Nobody knows
except my husband, my therapist...
...and some people like that."
We were blown away.
Said, "l feel like this is God
telling me it's time for me to share."
And I remember hearing Jon on the
other line going, "Wow." Like, "Wow."
From the post-abortive mother, it
was important to be sensitive to that...
...for this to be
a healing movie for them...
...and so having Shari's voice
and having her play the role was just...
...phenomenal to make sure that came
across authentic and very sensitive.
I think as we went forward...
...and filmed her scene,
she wasn't acting.
It was as real as you could get.
It was one of the more moving things
I've ever seen.
We went into it
and I remember the cameras rolling...
...and I just,
right as I walked into the room...
...I just knew that...
I just knew
that the Lord was with me.
And that it was just complete
healing in the moment...
...that I slide down that door
and that I'm crying and I'm feeling...
...that wasn't acting,
that was my moment with God...
...and him with me, to say,
"It's okay, it's over...
...and you've been forgiven."