CTB FILM COMPANY
SOYUZKINO
PRESENT
SERGEI MAKOVETSKY
VIKTOR SUKHORUKOV
LIKA NEVOLINA
DINARA DRUKAROVA
ALYOSHA DE and
CHINGIZ TSYDENDAMBAYEV
IN THE NEW DRAMA
OF FREAKS AND MEN
Johann passes through
Immigration Control
and enters the town.
Dr. Stasov adopts
the Siamese twins.
Engineer Radlov and his wife
photograph their daughter Leeza.
Years went by.
After the death
of his wife,
Radlov lived with his daughter
Leeza, and their maid, Grunya.
You can't bring
Mama back, Leeza.
They're leaving...
We'll go as well.
To the West?
I promised, didn't I?
Yes, Papa.
That'll be
the records.
Good day.
Have you come
to see Papa?
I'll call him.
Papa, there's someone
to see you.
Ah, Johann.
Have you brought it?
No.
But...then?
I've come
to see Grunya.
Grunya?
Grunya was
Johann's sister,
but she kept this
a secret.
She knew all about
her brother's occupation.
That's all.
Hello.
So that's what you do here,
Mr. Kohl.
You won't
fool me anymore!
I saw everything!
Everything!
I won't permit it!
I simply won't!
I didn't rent the studio
to you for that!
There are respectable
people living here!
There's no room
for your kind here!
Wait...
Putilov,
have you brought it?
What?
Leave the camera.
Viktor Ivanovich
sold the photographs
that were taken
in Johann's studio.
What do you want?
Don't come here.
What is it?
Who's in there?
Daria, who's there?
It's for me.
Go away.
What are you doing?
And the money?
Later.
You’ll get your money.
Go away!
Daria!
Yes.
Who was it?
It was for me, a relative
from my village...
But why come
to the front door?
Yekaterina Kirillovna,
it won't happen again.
Kolya, you sing the lead.
What's that?
A relative from
my village came.
Right, from the beginning,
with the introduction.
Kolya,
pay more attention,
you keep cutting in
on the Lead.
Boys, have you seen
my stethoscope?
Andrei, can't you see
that we're busy?
Katenka, forgive me,
but I have to go
on my rounds,
and I've no stethoscope.
You're going out?
I'll be back for supper.
Yekaterina Kirillovna
did not love her husband.
She carried on only
for the adopted twins.
Again,
from the beginning...
As the bell rings
monotonously
The road get dusty
and through the field
The coachman
sings his song
There is so much
feeling in his song
That my heart
burns up
in my cold chest...
Excuse me, have you
come to see us?
No.
Leeza.
Hello, Leeza.
Is papa home?
Yes, in the study.
Thank you.
Leeza,
Nikolai Nikolayevich
is waiting for you.
Leeza, meet Putilov.
Undoubtedly the cinema
is the thing,
no doubt about that,
my friend!
The cinema may become
a real art form,
an art form accessible to
the people of whom you speak.
Not painting, not literature,
not photography,
but the cinema will
reveal truth to the common folk.
You yourself
saw what effect
moving pictures have
on common people.
So your photography
will die out.
Shortly you'll see how
everything will change.
We're on the verge of
something major, something new.
The cinema is only
the beginning.
Excuse me.
It's all right, Grunya.
It won't be long now.
Leeza is already
grown up...
Grunya.
What was that?
They're fueling
the steam engines.
Do you like photography?
That must be the records.
Is that me?
Ah, you've brought it.
It's my gift to you
on this special occasion.
It's turned out well.
It's a present.
Take it, take it.
It's me at age five.
To become a photographer,
Putilov got himself into debt.
So he became dependent
on Johann.
Putilov, you should be
on your way.
It's already late.
Yes, yes.
Could I, perhaps,
photograph you?
Leave me alone.
Take the boys
to the cinema.
Johann readied himself to make
a wedding proposal.
Is Leeza home?
Leeza?
Grunya,
who's there?
It's Johann.
But why through
the front door?
Hello.
Never, never set foot
in this house again...
Scum!
Don't let him in again!
In this village...
In this village, my father
your grandfather, was born.
Whereas I was born
in a town...
right here.
Where was Mama born?
Mama?
Mama,
Mama...
Andrei, it's for you.
Excuse me,
I won't be long.
Speaking.
Yes...
Yes, Grunya, of course.
When?
Take a look.
No, don't do anything.
Do you have any ice?
It's disgusting.
Order some ice.
Have you got any more?
There are more.
Yes, yes.
Where's Leeza?
Do you want to touch?
Go on.
So, Mama...
Mama was born here...
in this town.
Boys, engineer Radlov's
heart is acting up.
I must go.
Leeza! Wait!
Putilov, what an odor!
Thank you,
Semyon Markovich.
Excuse me
for having troubled you.
We'll have to clarify
certain points.
I'll phone you.
I'm sure you'll be able
to manage without me.
However, I disagree
with your decision.
Why did you get up?
The doctor said
you mustn't.
I've made a few changes
in my will.
It will be
a surprise for you.
It's a bit early for you
to be worrying about a will.
What'll you think of next!
I think you should
take a look at the photographs
I found in Leeza's things...
Photographs?
Come on then, come on.
Viktor Ivanovich couldn't get
the twins off his mind.
I told you not
to come here!
Quickly!
Is the master home?
He's not here.
But the mistress is home.
Go on, get out.
Where are you going?
Go away!
Go!
If she sees you...
I'll be punished.
What are you doing?
Go away, go away.
Where are the freaks?
What freaks?
Daria...
Have you run a bath?
Daria?
Who's here?
Viktor Ivanovich.
Viktor Ivanovich?
Turn around.
Mama?!
What do you want?
Viktor Ivanovich.
Yekaterina Kirillovna had fallen
in love for the first time.
The addition from
the 17th of May of this year.
The heretofore mentioned
Elizaveta NikoIayevna Radlova
will receive the benefits
of her inheritance
upon her entry into lawful
wedlock with such person as she,
Elizaveta Nikolayevna Radlova,
of her own free will
shall deem fit.
Until such time,
all heretofore mentioned assets,
monies, stocks and shares,
and the like,
will be administered
by an appointed trustee,
Gardena Spiridonovna Bosykh,
who shall act on my behalf
to safeguard the heretofore
mentioned properties.
Established on the 17th
of may of this year
in sound mind
and good health.
The engineer wanted Grunya to
replace Leeza's deceased mother.
Leeza, I will save you.
Putilov, you should be off.
It's already Late.
Yes, yes.
Leeza!
Hello.
This way, that's it.
Nanny!
What? What do you want?
This is my nanny!
Leave me alone!
Go away!
Hello, Leeza.
Putilov, you should be
on your way.
Yes, yes.
Behind Johann's back,
Viktor Ivanovich
began his business.
Ready?
Hello.
A cinema!
May I use it
to photograph?
Some film.
I need a dark room.
What?
Yes, it's me.
We won't marry.
Grunya!
Make sure it's the same
as in the pictures.
Go on!
Nanny!
Why have you done such
naughty things?
Don't you know
that it's bad?
As it's your first time,
I won't punish you too severely.
There, my dear...
Let that be
a lesson to you.
Leeza...
I'll save you!
It's too late, Putilov.
Leeza, I'll save you.
And so Leeza became a woman
for the first time.
Where are they?
Tell me! Tell me!
It's Dr. Stasov.
Are you hiding something?
Viktor Ivanovich hated
and feared Johann.
They sing.
Go on!
Make the bald one leave.
What?
As the bell rings
monotonously
The road get dusty
and through the field
The coachman
sings his song
There is so much
Feeling in his song
That my heart
burns up
In my cold chest
As I remember
those nights
Those fields
and those forests
A tear comes to my eyes
That have been
dry for so long
That have been dry
for so long
As the bell rings
monotonously
I can hear it
from far away
My coachman
has stopped singing
My coachman has
stopped singing
My freaks will live here
for the time being.
Here?
What is it?
Drink it.
I won't.
Drink it, freak.
Find Putilov.
Forgive us, please.
Tolya isn't like that really.
Tolya?
And who are you?
I'm Kolya.
What's your name?
Leeza.
Nanny!
What's that?
The snow is shining
In the moonlight
A team of horses
Is rushing
through the night
Ding, ding, ding
ding, ding, ding
A little bell rings
And talks to me
At early Spring
The moon is shining
In the field
A friend will stop
Your young voice
That sounds
like a bell
Ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding
Sweetly sings
about love...
I hate this town.
Months went by.
Leeza lived in one room
with the twins.
Kolya was hopelessly
in love with her.
Tolya drank on the sly.
If you keep traveling toward
the West, the sun never sets.
Must you travel fast?
We'll travel East.
That's where papa was born.
He'll find us.
Check.
I've brought you some wine.
Where's mama?
She left with the doctor.
That's not true!
Well, go on then!
Tolya, don't drink it.
Just a drop.
What?
Leeza.
So, freaks!
Let's go.
Nanny!
Why have you done such
naughty things?
Don't you know
that it's bad?
Viktor Ivanovich?
Viktor Ivanovich,
Viktor Ivanovich...
Let's go then.
Come on, come on.
Viktor Ivanovich?
Let's go.
Where?
Who's here?
It's okay,
it won't take long.
That's it. Stand here.
Viktor Ivanovich.
Go on.
Get on your knees.
Nanny!
I hate him.
I hate this dead town.
I hate carrots
with sour cream.
Leeza!
I'm sorry.
Do you also
think I'm a freak?
Of course not!
You're very handsome.
I disgust you, I know.
It's because of Tolya,
isn't it?
Because we're
always together.
But I'm normal.
I saw papa's books.
It doesn't happen like that.
To love a woman,
you don't have to whip her.
I know how, I'll show you.
Leeza, try, please!
Tolya's asleep.
Just once!
He won't hear a thing.
Try!
You may never
have another chance!
I love you.
And so Leeza became a woman
for the second time.
Putilov!
Leeza.
My nanny's died.
Nanny!
So, freaks?
It's all over.
The twins left
for the East.
Are you coming?
I'm heading toward the West.
Cast off.
We'll come to see you.
We'll find Papa
and then come.
Forward.
I'll be waiting!
The famous doctor
and physician,
Andrei Fyodorovich Stasov,
was born in this house.
Papa.
Gentlemen!
After a short interval,
as promised,
the singing freaks
will appear before you.
Tolya, just a little further.
What did you have to drink?
Just a minute.
How are you?
Better?
Can you sing?
Quickly, open up!
Tolya, wake up.
Tolya, get up!
Get up, Tolya.
We gotta go.
Get up, Tolya, come on.
Open up now, freak!
Get up!
Tolya, get up!
Tolya!
Leeza traveled to the West.
Would you like some music?
I recommend it.
Putilov!
Look, it's Putilov!
Johann visited
the cinema.
F. PUTILOV
PUNISHMENT FOR A CRIME
A REAL LIFE DRAMA
Why have you done
such naughty things?
Don't you know
that it's bad?
As it's your first time,
I won't punish you too severely.
There, my dear...
Let that be a lesson to you.
THE END
The snow
is shining
In the moonlight
A team
of horses
Is rushing
through the night
Ding, ding, ding
ding, ding, ding
A little
bell rings
And talks to me
At early Spring
The moon
is shining
In the field
A friend will stop
Your young voice
That sounds
like a bell
Ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding
Sweetly sings
about love
The snow
is shining
In the moonlight
A team
of horses
Is rushing
through the night
Ding, ding, ding
ding, ding, ding
A little bell rings
And talks to me
Johann
Sergei Makovetsky
Leeza
Dinara Drukarova
Yekaterina Kirillovna
Lika Nevolina
Viktor Ivanovich
Viktor Sukhorukov
Kolya
Alyosha De
Tolya
Chingiz Tsydendambayev
Putilov
Vadim Prokhorov
Doctor Stasov
AIexander Mezenstev
Engineer Radlov
Igor Chibonov
Grunya
Daria Lesnikova
Daria
Tatiana Polonskaya
Producers
Sergei Selyanov Oleg Botogov
Director and Scriptwriter
Alexei Balabanov
Director of Photography
Sergei Astakhov
Designer
Vera Zelinskaya
Sound
Maxim Belovolov
Editing
Marina Lipartia
Costumes
Nadezhda Vassilieva
Make up
Tamara Frid
Executive Producer
Maxim Volodin