I said, "You are gods,
sons of the Most High.
But you shall die like men
and fall like princes."
OF GODS AND MEN
Lord, open my lips
And my mouth will proclaim your praise
Aspirin...
And cough syrup.
There's hot tea.
Help me, Papa.
- Brother Luc.
- Nouredine, labesse??
And you?
Saturday is Jamel's "khtana" (circumcision).
Will there be a party?
You're all invited.
- Will you come?
- I'd love to.
See you later. Take care.
Yes, you too.
Little brat! You're here?
Not at school today?
Good.
It's almost dry.
Stop with the bandages.
Be sure to keep her out of the sun.
That would be dangerous. Forbidden.
Otherwise, all's well.
Little kiss.
What else?
I see.
It's serious.
Be right back.
Asleep, brother?
Here.
Guide us in the straight path,
the path of those
whom Thou hast blessed,
not those against
whom Thou art wrathful,
nor those who are astray.
Amen.
The Messenger believes
in what was sent down to him
from his Lord, and the believers:
each one believes in God,
His angels, His Books
and His Messengers.
We make no division
between any one of His Messengers.
They say, "We hear and obey."
"Lord, grant us Thy forgiveness."
"Unto Thee is the homecoming."
God charges
no soul save to its capacity.
It will be rewarded for good it has done
and punished for evil it has done.
Lord, take us not to task
if we forget or make mistake.
Lord, charge us not with a load
such as Thou didst lay
upon those before us.
Lord, do not burden us beyond
what we have the strength to bear.
And pardon us, and forgive us
and have mercy on us.
Thou art our Protector.
And help us against the people
of the unbelievers.
How do you know
when you're in love?
There's...
...something inside you
that comes alive.
The presence of someone.
It's irrepressible and makes your heart
beat faster, usually.
It's an attraction, a desire...
It's very beautiful.
No use asking too many questions.
It just happens.
Things are as usual, then suddenly...
...happiness arrives, or the hope of it.
it's lots of things.
But you're in turmoil.
Great turmoil.
Especially the first time.
Your father spoke to me about Khaled.
My father speaks too much.
I don't want that.
I feel none of the things you mentioned
when I see Khaled.
That means it's not very serious.
My father wants it, not me.
That's another problem.
Ever been in love?
Several times, yes.
And then I encountered another love,
even greater.
And I answered that love.
It's been a while now.
Over 60 years.
Here,
you have to put your son's address.
He's no longer at home?
He lives far away now.
Abdallah...
Taroudi.
13 Rue d'Etretat.
Le Havre.
And here they ask for two photos.
Do you have photos?
Listen, Tuesday
we're going to the market.
We can take you along.
And have photos taken.
Okay?
My cousin from Mostaganem...
They killed her granddaughter.
This afternoon.
She's 18. Samira.
They stabbed her on the bus.
Right in the heart.
Those dogs.
They threw her out like a dog.
And for a veil!
She didn't wear the hijab.
What's the problem with these people?
it's beyond me.
Is that normal?
God says in the Koran,
"You kill your brother, you go to hell."
They say they're religious.
They've never read the Koran.
In the Koran, it's written down.
Does it make sense to you?
Look at France.
Schoolgirls make an uproar
about wearing a veil.
The world's gone mad, Christian.
True.
They're killing imams too.
Yesterday they killed an imam
in the street.
Where are we going?
I don't know who these people are.
Only God knows.
This is new. No one understands.
Who's killing who?
We'll pray for Samira and her family.
May she go to Heaven.
It's not mine.
- Whose then?
- The haji's.
Get lost!
Kill him!
Beat it!
Are you stupid?
Christian!
They killed the Croatians!
Our friends, the workers.
Throats slashed, all of them.
You need military protection.
That is not an option.
How can you say that?
Those men were killed nearby!
The atrocities will continue.
The Walt's offer deserves
to be discussed.
There are families here.
Think of them.
I made my decision. I refuse.
Let's speak inside.
We'll lock the gate at 7:30
and take no night calls.
Do you think that's enough?
You don't know them.
Try to make him see reason.
Is your phone working?
We can't complain.
Call us before it's too late.
Because he is with us
in this time of violence
Let us not dream
that he is everywhere
Other than where we die
Let us make haste
Let us draw patience from him
Let us turn to the Man of Sorrows
Who beckons us from the cross
Because he is with us
as on Easter morn
Let us not forget
The blood he shed
Let us break the bread
Let as drink
from the chalice of passage
Let us greet the one
who sacrificed himself
By loving us until the end
Through Him, with Him and in Him,
You shall receive, Almighty Father,
in the unity of the Holy Spirit,
all glory and honor,
forever and ever.
How could you decide this
without consulting us?
All our lives are at stake.
What would you have done?
I'd have let everyone speak
and listened to each position.
To answer what, in the end?
The answer doesn't matter.
The very principle of community
is compromised by your attitude.
Who wants the army
present in the monastery?
You refuse to understand
what we're saying.
I do understand!
None of us chose to live here,
to be protected
by a corrupt government.
Christian,
we didn't elect you
to decide on your own.
And if they come here?
We lie down and die?
It's a risk.
We were called to live here.
In this country, with these people,
who are also afraid.
We'll live with this unknown, yes.
I didn't come here
to commit collective suicide.
Maybe we can try to figure out
what each of us could do,
if they came here.
What's there to do?
Look at the Croatians.
Play hide-and-seek.
Cough.
Once more.
You'll outlive us all.
Hello, haji.
Still got your head?
I don't care.
They can have my head.
- May I?
- Sure. Be my guest.
The roads are blocked.
I won't go to Meznir today.
Not after what happened.
We don't need anything.
I'll let you know.
Christmas is in a week.
You know it's important
for us to be here together.
Thanks again.
Talk to you soon.
"Accepting our powerlessness
and our extreme poverty
is an invitation,
an urgent appeal to create with others
relationships not based on power."
"Recognizing my weaknesses,
I accept those of others."
"I can bear them,
make them mine
in imitation of Christ."
"Such an attitude transforms us
for our mission."
"Weakness in itself is not a virtue,
but the expression
of a fundamental reality
which must constantly
be refashioned by faith,
hope and love."
"The apostle's weakness
is like Christ's,
rooted in the mystery of Easter
and the strength of the spirit."
"It is neither passivity
nor resignation."
"It requires great courage
and incites one
to defend justice and truth
and to denounce the temptation
of force and power."
End of article.
New article.
By Carlo Carretto,
"The God Who is Coming".
"Often throughout my life
I've wondered
how God could act so strangely."
"Why does he stay silent so long?"
"Why is faith so bitter?"
And nothing exists except love
Except love which now begins
By separating sand from water
God has prepared earth like a cradle
Far his coming from above
This is the night
Happy night in Palestine
And nothing exists except the Child
Except the Child of life divine
What do you want?
Are you the Pope?
Where's the Pope?
There's no Pope here.
Your leader.
His name!
Brother Christian.
Who are you?
Ali.
Here he is.
This is Christian.
What do you want?
This is a house of peace.
Are you Christian?
No weapons allowed here.
If you wish to speak,
you must leave them outside.
Please.
I never part with mine.
Follow me. We'll talk outside.
I need the doc.
He has to come with us.
Impossible.
I have three men wounded
an hour away.
He can't leave here. He's sick.
He's old and asthmatic.
Brother Luc sees patients at the clinic.
He tends to everyone
who needs his help.
Their identity is not an issue
and never will be.
That's all.
So you can give us medicine.
We're short on supplies.
We see 100 villagers a day.
Enough!
You have no choice!
Yes.
I do.
We can't give what we don't have.
Ask your brothers in the village.
We live modestly.
With products we grow.
You know the Koran?
"Those nearest in love
to the believers
are those who say,
'We are Christians'"
"Among them are priests and monks."
"Priest and monks
and they wax not proud."
That's why
we're close to our neighbors.
Come on, let's go.
Tonight is different from other nights.
Why?
It's Christmas.
We celebrate the birth
of the Prince of peace.
The Prince of peace?
Sidna-Aissa.
Jesus.
I'm sorry, then.
I didn't know.
Christophe?
Michel?
Come out now.
They're gone.
We're fine. We made it.
Hold this down gently.
You can let go.
You'll be fine. Don't worry.
This is the night
The immense night of origins
And nothing exists except love
Except love which now begins
By separating sand from water
Gad has prepared the earth like a cradle
Far his coming from above
This is the night
The happy night of Palestine
And nothing exists except the Child
Except the Child of life divine
By taking flesh of our flesh
God our desert did refresh
And made a land of boundless spring
This is the night
The long night in which we grope
And nothing exists except this place
Except this place of ruined hope
By stopping in our abode
God, as with the bush, did forebode
The world on which fire would fall
Why...
...not give them medicine?
We have enough.
If you have medicine,
I'd like to know about it.
We can't start negotiating.
Every day they'll ask for more.
I agree with Luc.
Don't forget, I was held at gunpoint.
If we stay,
our lives would be at risk every day.
I became a monk to live.
Not to sit back
and have my throat slit.
You're right, Celestin.
We shouldn't be seeking martyrdom.
Maybe we should leave.
Or at least
take refuge in a safer place.
I think that Celestin
is asking a good question.
They've come once.
They'll be back sooner than we think.
The fact that
you refused all their demands
could be taken as a declaration of war.
Look what they did to the Croatians.
If they'd wanted to kill us,
we'd be dead already.
Maybe Fayattia
isn't the only one who decides.
Maybe others will come back tomorrow.
There's another solution.
Leave for good.
We should each decide
according to his own conscience.
Go back to France
or to another,
safer monastery in Africa.
To leave is to run away.
And to leave the village
to the terrorists.
We'd do it gradually,
so the villagers won't worry.
That won't change a thing.
The Good Shepherd doesn't
abandon his flock to the wolves.
We should each express our opinion
about leaving.
Jean-Pierre?
We stay.
Since when do we yield to arms?
Paul?
I think we should leave.
Gradually.
Celestin?
I'm ill. I want to leave.
Luc?
To leave is to die.
I'm staying.
Michel?
I have no one else, anywhere.
I'll stay.
Amédée?
I don't know yet.
We need to think...
...and pray together.
I think we should leave.
And you, Christian?
I agree with Amédée.
it's too early to decide.
Help will come from the Lord.
Who made heaven and earth.
We do not know your mystery
Infinite love
But you do have a heart
For you seek the prodigal son
And hold against your breast
This troublesome child
Which is the world of mortals
We do not see your face
Infinite love
But you do have eyes
For you weep through the oppressed
And look upon us
With a shining gaze
That reveals your forgiveness
I fear for the fate of this country.
Yesterday two women teachers
were found murdered.
For telling teenagers
falling in love is normal,
that they're allowed to.
It's a 15-year-old girl
who tipped off the extremists.
We're as sad as you are.
What do you know?
This is my country.
Besides being sad,
I'm tired of not seeing it grow up.
And despite what you think,
I blame French colonization.
That organized plundering.
For you.
MINISTRY OF THE INTERIOR
They mean business.
They're giving you orders.
No one other than ourselves
can decide that we must leave.
I'd have been surprised.
Really surprised.
Your stubbornness is getting dangerous.
Look at all these people.
They're at home here.
They're terrorized.
They all wish they could leave.
They have no choice, no money.
It's not cowardly to want to leave.
It's about being free.
TERROR STRIKES DJELFA
Sooner or later, it'll be you.
No one can control
what's going on these days.
You'll end up
becoming just another pawn.
Your sacrifice
will eventually be exploited.
I've known you for years.
I have respect for you.
And for what your community has done.
Please, go back to France.
Did your car break down?
Is any of you a mechanic?
If you know how to fix it, be my guest.
Should I try?
- Should I try?
- Is it in neutral?
You're in neutral? Go on, try.
Will the village
need the army to protect it?
Because they'll be back someday.
Forget the army!
It's a disaster.
The army won't come.
The protection is you.
This village grew up
with the monastery.
Who was that priest, before?
A while back, before the war.
Brother Bernard?
Another one. Old.
Brother Daniel.
That's him.
He told my mother not to stay here.
Move to a city.
There was no more work here.
She made him swear
to say nothing to my father.
Because my mother,
she feels good living here.
Comfortable.
We may be leaving.
Why are you leaving?
We're like birds on a branch.
We don't know if we'll leave.
We're the birds.
You're the branch.
If you go, we lose our footing.
Forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us,
and lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from evil.
Let us bless the Lord
We render thanks unto Him
So you want to leave?
I was thinking that.
I wonder what my life would be.
Your family, in France?
They're worried?
I'm not sure they realize
what's going on here.
I haven't said anything.
The last time I saw them,
it was strange.
What do you mean?
We celebrated my mum's 80th birthday
at a restaurant.
I saw everyone.
My sisters were there,
nephews, nieces, my goddaughter.
Everyone was talking, telling stories.
Taking pictures.
They know that's not my thing.
I was there, listening. I was happy.
They put me next to my mum.
And at the same time...
...I was totally out of it.
I was thinking...
...if I stopped everything, if...
I could move back home.
Get back to work, plumbing.
Town council,
ire department, chorus.
Then I thought,
"No, that's not possible."
My life's over there.
Here. With you.
Christian's teaching today
was interesting.
Don't you think?
Did you understand anything?
Fuck off!
Okay.
Just tired. Not his fault.
"There was a time
when a French toe-punt was crummy
and its Irish equivalent
a mere display of folklore."
"When these damned men didn't know
what to do with their ten digits,
but were great at bending the rules
to piss everyone off."
Is that all?
"Even though we agree
with Mr Break-Neck
that our amiable guests
never closed the game out,
we still wonder whether they prefer,
deep down,
the dervish-like scrums
and bleak brawls of yesteryear."
"Back when players
still cared about not being
naughty old men."
A little more.
Help me, help me.
Don't abandon me.
Don't abandon me. Please.
Help me.
Not very pretty. It got infected.
Tell him I'll be giving him two shots.
An antibiotic and a tetanus shot.
He's in pain. He needs medicine.
I'll give him a tranquilizer.
Let's clean this up.
You'll be fine.
Glory be to the Father,
and the Son and the Holy Spirit
World without end
Save us, Lord
Whilst we watch
Keep us, Lord
Whilst we sleep
And we shall watch with Christ
And we shall rest in peace
I'm worn out.
Does Amédée help out?
Fortunately. I don't know
how I'd manage otherwise.
I've never had so many visits.
I'm up to 150 a day.
Can you imagine?
People come from everywhere around.
I'm dealing with new pathologies.
Lots of hypertension.
They're stressed.
Some are in a state of shock.
Not to mention the effect
on the kids.
The villagers may talk
about these men we help.
Be careful.
Throughout my career I've met
all sorts of different people.
Including Nazis.
And even the devil.
I'm not scared of terrorists,
even less of the army.
And I'm not scared of death.
I'm a free man.
Let the free man through!
My men tied him to a truck,
dragged him through the city.
People jumped for joy.
Lucky for him he was dead.
Why didn't you stop them?
Stop them?
Lots of people in the crowd
were victims of his atrocities.
Family.
Friends who died.
Many innocent people.
Disgraceful.
No one should be treated this way.
Want to know his favorite torture?
Fayattia and others like him
deserve no compassion.
You're very indulgent
with the terrorists.
Overindulgent.
Rumor has it
he was shielding the monastery.
Did you ever treat them?
Where did you ind him?
Two days ago,
the Walt's car was ambushed.
Near Tikrit.
The terrorists got away.
We found a wounded man
on the ground.
His friends ditched him.
He talked about his mother.
Said his name was Fayattia.
My men let him suffer.
He died
before we could make him our trophy.
How can you be sure it's him?
Why do you think I asked you here?
So?
It's him.
Get out. Go on.
Outside.
I sleep badly.
The slightest noise wakes me.
I think over my life.
My choices.
As a kid I wanted to be a missionary.
Dying for my faith
shouldn't keep me up nights.
Dying here,
here and now,
does it serve a purpose?
I don't know.
I feel like I'm going mad.
It's true that staying here...
...is as mad as becoming a monk.
Remember.
You've already given your life.
You gave it by following Christ.
When you decided to leave everything.
Your life,
your family, your country.
The family you could have raised.
I don't know if it's true anymore.
I pray.
And I hear nothing.
I don't get it.
Why be martyrs?
For God?
To be heroes?
To prove we're the best?
We're martyrs out of love,
out of fidelity.
If death...
...overtakes us, despite ourselves,
because up to the end,
up to the end we'll try to avoid it,
our mission here
is to be brothers to all.
Remember that love
is eternal hope.
Love endures everything.
I'm sorry.
Like patched earth
I stand before you, Lord
O Lord, hear my prayer
Listen to my cry for mercy
In your faithfulness, answer me
Enter not into judgment
with your servant
For no man living
is righteous before you
The enemy persecutes my soul
He has smitten my life to the ground
He has made me dwell in darkness
With those long dead
My spirit grows faint within me
My heart within me, dismayed
Answer me quickly, O Lord
My spirit fails
Do not hide your face from me
Lest I be like them
who fall into the pit
We've received so many letters recently.
People are worried.
I can't answer them all.
There's that French journalist
who wants to meet us.
I don't know what to tell her.
We shouldn't expose ourselves further
by doing publicity.
Of course, but...
...it's a way of making
people understand our choices.
To show that
amid all this drama,
for people here,
there's reason for hope.
You know,
hope is not what interests journalists.
It doesn't mobilize them.
Exactly.
Maybe we should mobilize them.
I suggest we take a vote.
To see if we're all of one mind.
Who wants to leave?
I've already told you
my position on this matter
and my calling is to be here,
with everyone.
I don't see myself leaving.
Leaving would lead nowhere.
I'm not ready to leave myself.
Last night I thought about leaving.
I'm not comfortable with it.
Not at peace.
Deciding to run off like that
makes no sense.
We didn't come here
for our own personal interest.
I still think that our mission here
is not finished.
I'm staying.
I prayed all morning
while I was cooking.
The disciple
is not above his master.
This is no time for me to stray.
Let God set the table here.
For everyone.
Friends and enemies.
And you, Christian?
Wildflowers don't move
to ind the sun's rays.
God makes them fecund
wherever they are.
Who prefers to stay?
You.
You envelop me, hold me,
surround me.
You embrace me.
And I love you.
- Where do you live?
- In town.
- ID.
- I don't have it on me.
- Where do you live?
- Just nearby.
- ID.
- I don't have them.
- Where do you live?
- The village.
Stop this nonsense!
These women and children
are here to be treated.
This is not a police station!
Enough!
Unbelievable.
Sit down.
Follow me.
I recently read
this pensee of Pascal's,
"Men never do evil
so completely and cheerfully
as when they do it
from religious conviction."
Here it is mayhem
and violence.
We are in a high-risk situation,
but we persist in our faith
and our confidence in God.
It is through poverty, failure and death
that we advance towards him.
Heavy devastating downpours
have put no damper
on the spread of violence.
Two opponents,
one clutching onto power,
the other out to seize it.
They'll fight to the bitter end.
I don't know when or how it will end.
In the meantime, I do my duty...
Caring for the poor and the sick,
awaiting the day I close my eyes.
Dear friend,
pray for me, that my leaving this world
will in the peace and joy of Jesus.
O Father
Of light
Eternal light!
And source of all light
You illuminate us,
at the threshold of night
With the radiance of your face
The shadows, for you
Are not shadows
For you, night
ls as clear as day
May our prayers before you
Rise like incense
And our hands like the evening offering
Welcome, Bruno.
Celestin.
Christophe.
Hello, Luc.
Jean-Pierre.
Amédée.
- Hosts.
- For me.
For us.
For us all.
Medicine.
For Luc.
Lots of medicine.
- You found it?
- I found your book.
Is it the right one?
"The Chosen".
Cheese!
Any news of Brother Didier?
Of course he said to say hello.
And I have a letter for you.
So how was your trip?
How long was it?
It took a while
to come from the diocese.
At least three hours.
There were three checkpoints!
Between the last two checkpoints
there was a bus burning
on the roadside.
Smoke coming out of it.
And we didn't know
if the checkpoints were real or fake.
On the way here,
as we got closer,
there were fewer vehicles.
Many soldiers?
Yes, near the checkpoints.
They were all very tense.
Out of the question
to speak to them.
- How do we stand?
- However we want.
Short ones up front.
Squeeze in closer.
Ready?
Set...
Let's take another.
Smile a little.
I've often thought of that time.
That time...
...when Ali Fayattia and his men left.
Once they were gone...
...all we had left to do was to live.
And the first thing we did was...
...two hours later.
We celebrated
the Christmas Vigil and Mass.
It's what we had to do.
It's what we did.
And we sang the Mass.
We welcomed that child
who was born for us...
...absolutely helpless and...
...and already so threatened.
Afterwards,
we found salvation
in undertaking our daily tasks.
The kitchen, the garden,
the prayers, the bells.
Day after day.
We had to resist the violence.
And day after day, I...
I think each of us discovered
that to which Jesus Christ
beckons us.
It's...
...to be born.
Our identities as men
go from one birth to another.
And from birth to birth,
we'll each end up
bringing to the world
the child of God that we are.
The Incarnation, for us,
is to allow the filial reality of Jesus
to embody itself in our humanity.
The mystery of Incarnation remains...
...what we are going to live.
In this way
what we've already lived here takes root
as well as what we're going to live
in the future.
"Whoever tries to save his life
shall lose it,
and whoever shall lose it,
preserves it."
"I tell you, on that night,
two people shall be in one bed."
"One shall be taken, the other left."
"Two women shall
be grinding grain together."
"One shall be taken, the other left.
"The disciples asked him,
'Where, Lord?'"
"He answered,
'Where there is a body,
'there too the vultures shall gather.'"
The Gospel of the Lord.
Praise to you, Lord Jesus Christ.
The body of Christ.
Lord, blessed art thou for this meal
which unites us as brothers
now and...
...world without end.
Hurry up!
Move!
Hurry, faster!
Hurry, get dressed.
I just got here.
I can't.
I said don't push!
Careful with that medicine.
it's for the children, not you.
It's very precious.
Stop pushing me! That's enough!
Calm down!
I am Brother Paul.
A monk at the Monastere de l'Atlas.
And I'm in good health.
I am Brother Celestin.
I'm 63.
A monk at the Monastere de l'Atlas.
I'm in good health.
Your turn, Luc.
My name is Brother Luc.
From the Monastere de l'Atlas.
I heard what they're saying
on the news.
I've been taken hostage
with my colleagues by the Jama...
- What's it called?
- Islamiyya.
Jama Islamiyya, that's it.
Your turn, Christian.
In the early hours of Friday morning,
the Mujahideen read us the bayan
of the Jama Islamiyya Musalaha.
- It says...
- Signed by?
Signed by Abu Abderrahmane Amine.
It says we're being held hostage and
demands that the French government
free hostages belonging to their group
in exchange for our liberation.
This exchange is non-negotiable.
Did you hear?
Should it ever befall me,
and it could happen today,
to be a victim of the terrorism
swallowing up all foreigners here,
I would like my community,
my church, my family,
to remember that my life was given
to God and to this country.
That the Unique Master of all life
was no stranger
to this brutal departure.
And that my death is the same as
so many other violent ones,
consigned to the apathy of oblivion.
I've lived enough to know
I am complicit in the evil that, alas,
prevails over the world
and the evil that will smite me blindly.
I could never desire such a death.
I could never feel gladdened
that these people I love
be accused randomly of my murder.
I know the contempt
felt for the people here,
indiscriminately.
And I know how Islam is distorted
by a certain Islamism.
This country, and Islam, for me
are something different.
They're a body and a soul.
My death, of course,
will quickly vindicate
those who called me naive or idealistic,
but they must know that I will be freed
of a burning curiosity
and, God willing,
will immerse my gaze in the Father's
and contemplate with him
his children of Islam as he sees them.
This thank-you
which encompasses my entire life
includes you, of course,
friends of yesterday and today,
and you too,
friend of the last minute,
who knew not what you were doing.
Yes, to you as well
I address this thank-you
and this farewell
which you envisaged.
May we meet again,
happy thieves in Paradise,
if it pleases God,
the Father of us both.
Amen.
Inchallah.
Christian, Luc, Christophe,
Celestin, Paul, Michel and Bruno
were killed on May 21, 1996.
The identity of their murderers
and the circumstances of their deaths
remain a mystery.
Amédée died on July 27, 2008.
Jean-Pierre is still alive.
He is now 86.