KNOCKSArretez au coin, s'il vous plait.
Monsieur Foine. Yes, monsieur?
Could I speak to you for a moment?
Well, I've been studying painting
with you for some time now.
Do you think it's worth my whileWhy do you ask?
There's no sense in staying
unless I have talent.
If you are not certain about
your talent, why stay till now?
Because all this
is so beautiful to me.
In my youth,
it was also beautiful to me.
But now,
it is the city of lost illusions.
Is your studio very far?
No. Not very.
Let us go there. You will show me
what you have done. Yes.
Have you any money?A little. Not enough to live on.
Then, I must tell you.
There is no talent here, merely
industry and intelligence. You will
never be anything but mediocre.
And it is very cruel
to discover one's mediocrity only
when it is too late. I know.
That name does not belong there.
It belongs somewhere else.
Take your courage in both your hands
and make something of your life.
Have you anything in mind?
Well, you see...
..I have my limitations. I've always
been interested in medicine.
If one can't be great, at least
one can be of some use to people.
WOMAN COUGHS
I don't know why I should 'ave such
a thing. Upon my word, I don't!
I've never had a day's illness
in my life.
It's a winter cough.
Many middle-aged women have it.
Well, I never! No-one's
ever called me middle-aged before.
It's time you got used to it.
All the same.
You're a nice one, deerie.
I can't say the same for you.
Good day, madam.
The rest of you come back tomorrow.
Get him ready.
All right, sir.
Are you the boy's father? Yes, sir.
What's the matter with you now?
You see what the matter is.
The boy has a club foot.
Carey, you'd better take this case.
It's a subject
you ought to know something about.
It's only for the looks of the
thing. I don't find it no trouble.
That's wonderful. I did. That's cos
you let them go on at you.
You're a little slow, Carey.
I'll instruct the class.
There are many varieties of
club feet. This is less interesting.
Yours would prove more interesting.Yes. I believe so.
Mind taking off your sock, Carey?
No. Not at all.
Keeps his feet nice and clean,
doesn't he?
Hm, yes. Talipes equinovarus -
malformation requiring you to walk
on the outside of the foot.
A very interesting example,
I must say!
Do you mind if I have a look?
Congenital club foot.
In simple language, a foot twisted
inward. The cause is not clear.
Hereditary influence plays a part.
Dr Little traces recurring deformity
through four generations.
When you've quite finished...
I say, old man, I like that!
French, isn't she?
Yes. She was a model in Paris.
I can't, for the life of me,
understand why you gave up painting.
I'd rather look at that all day
long, than at this! Woman, you know!
You can tell by the, er, pelvis.I like 'em with a little more...
LAUGHTER
There's life in the old girl yet!
Don't inhale, deerie!
I say! I've got to be getting along!
A little matter of a barmaid
at the Crown & Anchor.
Very nice, too! Cheerie-o!
Funny fellow, isn't he?
It must have been wonderfulIt was.
You really knew all thoseSome of them.
I wonder if you couldn't help me.In what way?
There's a girl
and I can't get anywhere with her.
You've been to Paris and all that.
I'm sure you can give me a starter.
I'd ask Griffiths, only he couldn't
remember whom he was doing it for.
You know,
say something to make her laugh.
LAUGHS
MAN: What? You don't believe it?
You are too suspicious!
I say, she's marvellous, isn't she?No. She's anaemic.
You don't suppose she likesOf course.
Now's your chance. Say something.
Well, I see your friend's going.
I don't know what you mean.
The nobleman
with the sandy moustache.
Has he left you for another?
Some people would do better
to mind their own business.
Why?
You have a very nice back. Am I
on speaking terms with your back?
Woman, you know.
You can tell by the pelvis.
And that...calls himself
a gentleman!
I apologise. What for?I promised you something charming.
She's turned out
to be ill-natured and contemptible.
You don't suppose I care what
an anaemic waitress says to me?
Well, I do. I must be going.
Coming along?
No, I think I'll have some more tea.
Anything you want?Yes, if you don't mind.
I'd like to talk to you.
Filthy weather, isn't it?
Makes no difference to me.
I have to be here all day.
Oh, I only wanted to sayWell, say it.
You know, you have a lovely smile.
You should use it more often.
Now, don't go spoofing me.
A girl that works hard all day
don't have much reason to smile.
Perhaps I could find a reason.
Will you let me try?
I don't know whether I will
or whether I won't.
I hope you'll decide you will.
Huh!
RAIN FALLS
KLAXON BLARES
Like that, unt that, like so!
BOTH LAUGH
That is a nice little hand.
GLASS CHIMES
Excuse me, won't you? Ja ja.
THEY GIGGLE
How do you do?You seem in a great hurry.
I've been waiting ten minutes.
I didn't know you could draw!Didn't you?
That meant to be me? Looks like you.
If you look at it that way. Tea?
You are a strange sort.
I say, will you dine with me
some time? We'll go to the theatre?
I don't mind. When will you come?
I'm off Thursdays.All right, Thursday,
seven o'clock Victoria Station?
RINGING
All right. I'll meet you at Victoria
in the second class waiting room.
All tickets, please!
Show your tickets.
STEAM ENGINE FIRES UP
All tickets, please!
Show your tickets.
Boat train, platform 19!
All tickets, please...!
I thought you were never coming.I like that!
After keeping ME waiting.
I almost went home.
I was in the second class
waiting room.
Is it likely I'd sit in the second
class when I could sit in the first?
For a gentleman of brains,
you don't use 'em!
Perhaps not. Anyway, you're here,
so it's all right, isn't it?
You certainly do make a girl
feel important.
VIOLINS PLAY
I love that music.
Whenever I hear it, I think of you.
How pale you are.
How strange, how cold.
CORK POPS
You ARE going it!
Do you always order champagne?
No. Why did you do it now?
I was hoping it would make you
more friendly.
Do you think it will? Well,
there's one thing I can say for you.
Gentleman,
in every sense of the word.
May I see you again?
I don't mind. Doesn't it make
any difference to you?
No. If you don't take me out,
someone else will.
I'll say good night here.
Won't you stay for a moment? No.Why not?
People would think
I don't know what.
I love that music.
Whenever I hear it, I think of you.
Whenever I hear it, I think of us.
I've never danced with anyone
who danced like you.
I've been looking for you
all my life.
You don't have much to do with
your time. I should be studying.
Then why don't you?Well, I'd rather see you.
Any of the girls noticeI don't know.
What difference does it make?
They all laugh at you. Do they?
Why? Say you're in love with me.
SHE LAUGHS
May I call you Mildred?
I don't mind.
Look here, don't say that any more,
will you? Why not?
Well, I'll call you Mildred
and you call me Philip, will you?
I'll think on it.
I, um...I'm a little awkward at this
but will you kiss me good night?
No.
Oh, Mildred. Will you come
to the theatre with me on Saturday?
I don't mind.
You're sure they're for Saturday?Certainly.
My name is Miller, Emile Miller.
We should know each other.
Why? Well, we are both interestedThing?
My dear young man, you are so...
so... er...
artistic.
You, you should be more...
Like so!
Thanks. Thanks very much.
That's all right.
Keep the change.
What time shall I see you?
I forgot to tell you, Philip.
I can't go. W... Why not?
Me aunt's ill.
Oh.
Well!
What's the sense in that? You don't
suppose I want to go by myself?
I only got them for your sake.Well you needn't go on about it.
WOMAN: Violets! Sweet violets!
Sweet violets, tuppence a bunch.
Violets! Sweet violets...
You're spying on me.
I thought you was a gentleman,
in every sense of the word.
Are you going out with Miller? No.
Well, what if I am? I can go out
with him if I want to, can't I?
He's keeping you waiting, isn't he?
I'd rather wait for him
than have you waiting for me.
Won't you change your mind?
I'll get some more tickets... No.
You keep looking for him
the way I look for you.
If you don't come out with me
tonight you'll never see me again.
Good riddance to bad rubbish.
PIANO, LAUGHTER, VOICES
Oh, drink?
Desire?
PIANO PLAYS JOLLY TUNE, LAUGHTER
WOMAN'S LAUGHTER
CLEARS THROAT
Sorry, old boy.
How about a nice large beer, huh?
Wouldn't help? What would?
Oh, Phil. Leave it.
Why? What for?Shows the waiter who you are.
He knows who YOU are.
And so do I. What do you mean?
I'm sorry. I...didn't mean.
You're a bit too superior for me,
my fine young friend.
Mildred!
Of course you don't like me.
I'm a cripple.
No, Phil. It isn't that.I've felt it all along.
Foolish.
Mind my hat, silly!
You ARE clumsy!
WHISTLES A TUNE
Off your nut! What practice can you
expect with a wife like that?
I don't know. Let me ask you.
Why do you want to marry this girl?
Because I'm so in love with her.Aah!
That ring with a little design
is very popular, sir.
We sell a great many of them.
They're 30 shillings.
Thank you, sir.
Philip, were you surprised when
I asked you to take me to dinner?
I was delighted.Were you? Yeah. Why?
You've been so sweet to me all day
and I've got something to ask you.
It makes it so much easier for me.Makes it easier for me, too.
I've something to tell you.No, no. Let me tell you first.
There it is.
I want you to marry me.
I'm so sorry, Philip.
That's what I was about to tell you.
You shouldn't have waited so long.
The fact is,
I'm going to be married.
Are you?
To whom?
A man I know.
He earns very good money.
Yes, I'm...I'm sure of it.
Now, you won't go on about it,
will you, Philip?
All right.
I'm getting on.
I'm 24. Time I settled down.
This gentleman earns £7 a week.
He's got good prospects.
Well, this is goodbye.
I hate to eat and run, Philip.
I'm going to the theatre with the
gentleman that I'm going to marry.
MAN: All the latest films
of the day...!
Taxi.
Have you seen her since?
No. London is the largest city
in the world and you know the cure
for ONE woman.
Another. Ha ha! Right, ho!
Norah, you don't read such junk,
do you?
No. I write it. What?
That's how I earn my living.
I didn't know.
Successful? Very. I have an immense
popularity amongst kitchen maids.
They think me so refined.
Let's not talk about that.
Let's talk about us.
Norah, y-you're not really
fond of me, are you?
For a clever boy,
you ask such foolish questions.
Oh, my dear. It never struck mePleased?
Delighted. And so proud
and so happy and so...
So grateful.
I wish you hadn't been in love
with... What was her name?
Mildred.
Because if she hadn't treated you
so abominably
it wouldn't have taken you so long
to understand how I feel.
I saw you! I wasn't very quick!
Let's go out and play.
Not until you've passed that exam.
Tell me, darling.
What do you get out of this?
You'll never know.
I'm afraid you don't get much fun
with me.
I wish...
If only I could take you dancing.
I know how you love it.
Philip, it's very silly to be
so sensitive about your foot.
Other people don't think about it
as much as you.
They notice it when they first
see you then forget about it.
You know, I only speak of it
because I love you.
I don't want it to make you unhappy.
Now, will you please stay here
and go on cramming for that exam?
There's a lady to see you, sir.
I shouldn't have let her in
but she was that upset...
Norah!
What do you want?
I didn't think
I'd ever see you again.
What's the matter?
He's left me. Emile.
Oh, has he?
Yes.
Cos I'm going to have a baby.
Why don't you sit down?
I suppose you want him back.He'll never come back.
Why not? He just won't, that's all.
You're his wife.
He has to provide for you.
He won't give me anything.
Even if he did, I wouldn't take it.Why not?
No matter what's happened,
I've got me pride.
That's something, isn't it(?)
Have you got any money?
No.
You'd better get yourself
a place to live.
After that,
we'll see what can be done.
Philip, you were always so good
to me. I knew I could come to you.
Look here, Mr Miller.I?
What you expect me to do?Take care of her. You married her.
I? I married Mildred? Ach!
I married...
This one.
I'd still like to know
what you intend to do.
Me? I can do nothing.
One man cannot solution the problem
of the unmarried mother.
Why didn't you tell me?
I just couldn't.
Well, brace up.
Everything will be all right.
Philip...
Do you still...like me?
Really?
Strange as it may seem,
I always have.
I suppose I always shall.
I did everything I could
to make you love me.
I thought you were incapable
of loving anybody.
It's horrible to think
that you were willing to sacrifice
everything for that man.
I'm awfully sorry, Philip.
I shall never forget
you wanted to marry me.
Philip? Yes?
You've been so nice to me...
..I'll do anything you want.
Will you? Why?
Why, I owe it to you.
Oh. Do you?
You're not angry.
No.
Then you'll stay and haveYes, if you want me to.
Of course, Philip.
Nothing could delight me more.
Just a moment
and I'll have everything ready.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Come in.
Hello, darling.
Norah!
How did you happen to come?
Just passing by.
I wanted to rub my nose
against your door.
Philip,
why haven't I heard from you?
I was just going to write.
Why haven't you come to see me?
Well, I...I've been busy.
Why so silent?
Well, you see...
Norah, I've got something strange
to tell you.
You've been so good to me,
it only makes it harder.
Philip, what's wrong?
I'm sorry. It's just over.
You mean you don't care for me
any more?
I'm afraid so. What have I done?
Nothing.
You've been wonderful to me.
It's just that I...
Of course, I knew you never loved me
as much as I loved you.
Yes, I'm afraid
that's usually the case.
There's usually one who loves
and one who is loved.
Oh, it's always the same.
You want a man to be nice to you,
you have to be rotten to him.
If you treat a man honestly, you...
Philip, there's someone else.
Yes.
Who is she?
Mildred.
She's come back.
After all she's done.
How could you?
That's what I'd like to know.
It's just as though
you're bound to her in some way.
Yes.
As I am to you.
And she was to Miller.
As every human being is
to something or other.
Funny looking little thing,
isn't it? I can't believe it's mine.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
So glad it's over, darling.
You've been so good to me, Philip.
From now on,
things will be different.
Now, you will take good care of her,
won't you?
That I will, ma'am.
Good day. Good day.
I know you don't like it, Philip.
I can't do anything elseI suppose not.
Be sure and go over on Sundays
and see the baby's taken care of.
I will.
What are we going to do
this afternoon?
I asked Griffiths to come over.
Oh, did you?
Why? I know you find him amusing
and I'm always afraid of boring you.
Hello, hello, hello.
Sorry I'm late.
Had to get rid of a girl.
Why didn't you bring her?I'm not interested in MY girl.
I'm interested in other men's girls.
D'you like me?
LAUGHS
Really, I'm too hungry to know.
I think I like you lots.
I'd like you more if he took us out
to dinner. I'd tell you stories.
You'll have a wonderful time.
What would he do?
Ooh, pay the bill.
BOTH LAUGH
GRIFFITHS AND MILDRED LAUGH
I said, "What's that? Your missus?
I thought it was your sister!"
Oh, allez-up!
Allez-up!
"Thought it was your sister!"
POLITELY: Good night, Philip.
FLIRTATIOUSLY: Good night.
Just a moment.
Are you in love with Mildred?
I?
LAUGHS
That's what you've been
so funny about! My dear old boy...
Look here. It doesn't matter to you,
Harry. You've got so many women.
Don't take Mildred away from me.My dear old boy!
She's nothing to me at all!
Nothing at all!
CHUCKLES
Do you like it, Philip? Very much.
So nice of you to give it to me.
What are you thinking about?
You were having quite a flirtationI was.
Matter of fact, well...
I'm sort of in love with him.
I'm not surprised!
What do you mean? He's good looking,
says the things that make you laugh.
I'll thank you not to make funI wasn't making fun of you.
You don't act as if it's serious.
I don't think it is. Why not?
Griffiths isn't in love with you.
How do you know? I asked him.
Would you like to read a letter
I got from him this morning?
"I've been up all night
thinking about you.
"I have just sent for a messenger
to take this to you in the dawn.
"You've no notion of the time
I had with your friend last night.
"He kept asking me if I love you
and of course what could I say?
"He'll doubtless tell you all this,
"so I'm making sure that you..."
Well?
Can't help it if I love him, can I?
No. I suppose not. Then whatNothing.
Only I was fool enough to thinkI do, Philip.
As a friend.
Not in any other way.
But you do care for Griffiths
in the other way.
But you're cold. That sort of thing
doesn't mean anything to you.
That's what YOU think.
It's no use going on about it,
Philip.
You said yourself that I couldn't
help it if I'm in love with him.
If there's anything else to be said,
say it.
That's a nice dress you have on,
Mildred.
I couldn't afford it,
but I paid for it.
You have a nice apartment.
I couldn't afford it but I...
If you were a gentleman, would you
throw what you've done in my face?
Do you think it matters to me
whether I'm a gentleman or not?
If I were, you don't suppose
I'd care for a cheap vulgar...
I'm sorry, Philip.
I didn't want to end this way.
Harry's waiting for me.What do you intend to do?
We're going to Paris.
Get out.
Get out!
RIPPING
SOBBING
I've moved three times and each time
this woman's hounded me down.
I don't like to do this but...
All right, sir. I'll move her on.
Come on, young lady.
You can't stay here. Come on, now.
SOBBING
Look here, Carey. Mildred and I
are all washed up... Too bad.
BELL RINGS
Excuse me. I'm due in the ward.
Anything interesting, Carey?
What an unusual name you have.
An old Yorkshire name. Once took
a day's riding across our estates.
And here I am in a charity hospital
because my father loved fast women
and slow horses.
How the mighty are fallen!
Hello! Hello, Father.
Carey, this is my daughter,
christened Maria del Sol.
Her mother called her Sally.
This young man is a student here.
He's been nice to me. With some
inducement, he might be nice to YOU.
Now, Father. Father's particular
genius is saying the wrong thing.
He thinks it's fun to embarrass me.
It is. Try it some time, Carey.
ALTHERNY CHUCKLES
I will, if I get the chance.You shall have it!
You're coming to see us
the first Sunday I am home.
Oh, yes. Please do.ALTHERNY CHUCKLES
CHILDREN CHATTER AND LAUGH
KNIFE SHARPENING
What a quaint house!
Yes, but it's not very sanitary.Sanitation be hanged! Give me art!
I've got nine children
and they thrive on bad drains.
Look at that, now.I am, with great admiration.
Shall I bring the ale, Father?
Right, m'girl.
The sooner the better.
I hope you didn't have the table
here on my account.
I'd be happy to have dinner
with the children.
Oh, no. I take meals by myself.
I like these antique customs.
I don't think women ought
to sit down at table with men.
CHUCKLING: Why not?It ruins conversation.
It's bad for them. Puts ideas
in their heads! Women are never
at ease when they have ideas.
You sound like the voiceI am, sir.
This fine Yorkshire pudding
gives me strength to carry on.
Stop getting up and down
every time she comes in.
She doesn't want you to make a fuss.
She won't think it rude if
you sit still. She don't care a hang
for chivalry, do you, Sally?
No, Father.
You speak quietly while eyeing
the young man so boldly.
Yes, Father.
You know what I'm talking about?
How could I, darling?
You're so clever.
Don't stand behind me
in order to make eyes at him.
Better get Philip some more ale.
EXHALES LOUDLY
SLURPS, EXHALES
My word! Is there anything better
than English ale?
Let us thank God
for simple pleasures -
a good appetite,
roast beef and beer.
I was married to a lady once.
Good heavens! Never marry a lady,
my boy! Oh, really? Why?
Because a lady has a point of view,
a personality and an individuality
to devil you with.
You want a wife who can cook dinner
and look after your children.
Don't you think so, Sally?
I think you'd talk the hind legIt's clean fun.
Now, Sally, I'll wait on you.
Take my chair while I fetch you
and the young man some cheese.
Thank you, Father.
What do you think of us?
You don't know what this means to
me. I practically never had family.
This is the only place I've known
that's had the quality of...home.
Don't you think us a little queer?
Everyone's queer but me and thee.
And sometimes
thee is a little queer.
Thank you, Father.
It's no use mooning over her, Carey.
Sally never kisses a gentleman
until he's been here twice.
Well, you must ask me again,
some time.
Do it yourself!
Why don't you come next Sunday?
May I walk to the station with you?
No. Why not?
It's too late and you're a child.I'm 20.
Let's talk it over when you're 30.
Did you hear what I said, old man?
Yes, I heard. Sorry if I brought
up a painful subject.
I thought you'd be interested to
hear about Mildred. Sorry she's hadI gave her all I could.
But you know me, always stony broke.
I thought perhaps you'd want to...
I can't do anything.Go on.
I don't blame you.
I wouldn't have told you. She asked
me to give you her address.
Gave me a jolt, seeing her with that
baby, asking for something to eat.
She had the baby with her? Yes.
Not difficult to imagine
her next step.
Baby all right?
I'm very grateful to you, Philip.
If I could afford it, I'd have given
you a place of your own.
You're welcome to my room.
I don't know what would become
of me and...baby...
if you hadn't taken us in.
You'd have got on, I expect.
You've always been much nicer
to me than I deserved. I'm beginning
to realise how silly I've been.
You couldn't help how you felt.
Let's not talk about it, shall we?
I don't feel like that now.
Look here, Mildred. Let's have no
misunderstanding about this.
The reason you're here is... I know.
Because you once liked me enough
to want to marry me.
Yes.
Well, at least I can cook for you
and keep your flat clean.
Maybe some day you'll...
you'll feel better about me
and things will be like
they used to be.
Oh, thanks. I'll smoke it later.
Well, er... Good night.
Good night.
Landlady came upstairs
a little while ago.
She said, "Mrs Carey," she said.
"How can you stand it?"
What's the matter with them? They're
indecent. Disgusting, I calls it.
To have drawings
of naked people about.
If you want to know what I think,
I've half a mind to take them down.
You'll do nothing of the kind.
I love those pictures, Mildred.
I love them for what
they were meant to be.
JAUNTY TUNE BEGINS
What happened to it?
Hm? What?
The way you used to love me.
Oh, I don't know.
I was disappointed so often
and hurt so much.
What difference does it make?
Nothing. Only, remember how you got
when I was so cold to you?
You're getting me that way
cos you're so cold to me.
No-one else, is there?
He's not in love with anybody.
Where were you?
Altherneys'.
What are you doing up?
I couldn't sleep.
Hadn't you better put on
something warmer?
Oh, I'll be all right.
Just let me stay here.
Phil...
Phil, I love you so.
Oh, nonsense. T'isn't.
I can't live without you.
Please get up. You're making a fool
of yourself and a fool of me.
Oh, Phil. Please.
I can't go on like this.
Nonsense. You haven't anywhere
to go. Stay as long as you like.
But with the definite
understanding...
You disgust me.
Me?
I disgust YOU?
You.
You!
You're too fine!
You won't have me but you sit here
looking at your naked females!
Mildred. You cad!
You dirty swine!
I never cared for you, not once.
I was always making a fool of you.
You bored me stiff.
It made me sick when I let you kiss
me. I did it because you begged me.
You drove me crazy!
And after you kissed me,
I always use to wipe my mouth!
Well, I made up for it.
For every kiss, we laughed at you.
Miller and me, and Griffiths and me.
We laughed at you.
You were such a mug, a mug, a mug!
You gippy-legged monster!
You're a cripple! A cripple!
You love these things.
You love what they were meant to be.
Well, here's what
they were meant to be!
You want to be a doctor!
This will take care
of your medical school.
You're leaving? ..Why?
My money's gone.What do you intend to do?
Oh... Anything.
Before you go out into the world,
don't you think we ought
to do something about that foot?
Think it'll do any good?
I'll know better tomorrow.
How are you, Philip?I'm all right, Sally.
How's your foot? Well...
Let's try it, shall we?
All right.
Careful now.
No openings...
Sorry, nothing today...
All situations filled...
No experience? Can't use you...
Nothing today...
Sorry, no vacancies...
No openings...
Nothing...
Nothing... Nothing... Nothing...
Nothing... Nothing...
TURNS KEY AND PUSHES DOOR
Why haven't you been to see us?Oh, I don't know.
I've had things to do.
You've been putting on weight.I'm sure you haven't!
Why do you say that? The wayOh! That's only my look!
It's more than that. I sent you
a note and when you didn't answer
I went to your room.
Your landlady said
she had to put you out.
Hello, Philip!
My dear fellow, by pre-arranged
signal, my daughter communicated to
me confirmation of our suspicions.
As you know, I've been on the beach
most of my life.
In Tahiti, I was President
of the Beachcombers' Union!
I would like to enquire
into your amateur standing.
Where have you been staying?
Oh...anywhere.Why didn't you come here?
False modesty, I suppose.
Now, stop being an Englishman.
When a man's on his uppers,
it's time he came down to Earth.
We want you here with us. Well, I...
Thanks very much, but... You're
to stay until you get your bearings.
I want no more fine talk about it.
It's all arranged.
Well...
Well, here goes my amateur standing.
I-I really have no place to go.
It's awfully good of you. Nonsense!
The house is completely unsanitary.
You'll wind up with some
foul disease! Let him alone, Father.
I want to talk to him.I suppose youth must be served.
But I'm sick and tired
of serving it. Nine of them!
Will that do?
Looks as if it might.
Wouldn't be a nice night to be out.
Not really. No. It's going to be
jolly having you here.
I hope I shan't have to stay
very long. Why?
I can't go on like this, you know.
I need a job.
Father and I discussed that.There isn't much you've overlooked.
I'll have to sew that on, too.
And Father has a job for you.
Has he? Where? Where he works.
You're walking all right now.
I saw you in the window.
I never thought you'd come to that.
COUGHS SHARPLY
You're very hoarse. Throat sore?
You haven't forgotten
your doctoring, have you? No.
Because...that's what I want
to see you about.
Why not go to a doctor?
There's the Free Hospital.All them students staring at me?
COUGHS
What seems to be the trouble?Well, I cough all the time.
Let's have a look at your throat.
Phil.
It's not...me lungs, is it?
SOBS GENTLY
Where's the baby?
She died last summer.
Oh.
You might say you're sorry.I'm not. I'm very glad.
I'm afraid I can't help you much.
Don't leave me, Philip.
I know I've treated you shocking.
But don't leave me. Not yet, please.
There's no-one I can go to.
You're the only one that treated me
like I was human.
You're a gentleman, Philip.
The only one I've ever met.
COUGHS
Some things you'll need.
Our last day.
Why, Sally!
Darling.
I was so determined
not to let you see.
Well, that's sweet of you
to care because I'm going away.
I suppose I'm a fool to care,
but it doesn't mean you have to do
anything about it.
You can't help it because someone
loves you and you don't love back.
Sally, look at me.
Darling, do you think you'll always
feel like this about me?
Yes.
I've known it since the first time
you came to our house.
I thought at first that
I meant something to you, too.
Oh, but you did.
You do.
When I come back, if you feel the
same, will you marry me, darling?
Don't you mean if YOU feel the same?
VOICES SHOUT AND ARGUE OUTSIDE
This is what you might call
the irony of fate.
Come on now. Be quick.
Get her out of here.
I don't want the likes of her
on me hands.
I understand there's an interestingDon't go in there.
Why not?
If you please... It's no use.
Philip, I'm sorry I'm late.
You're not. I'm not going.
What's that?
My wedding present to my wife.
When do you intend to marry me?
Right away.
Thank you, Philip.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
You don't seem very pleased.
Well, I am and I'm not.
Why? I'm afraid
it's only a noble gesture.
That's not enough for marriage.No, Sally. It isn't just that.
I like you far too much
to stand in your way.
WHISTLE BLOWS
HORNS BLOW
CACOPHONY DROWNS OUT CONVERSATION
WHISTLE BLOWS, HORNS STOP
Philip, you're free. Yes,
but suddenly there's nowhere to go.
Taxi, sir? No, thanks.
I had to be free to realise that,
free to understand that all those
years I dreamed of escape was
because I was limping through life.
Taxi, sir? No, thank you!
And because I was bound up with
a person who was incredible to me.
That's all over.
I'm not limping any more. My life's
all right. Then why don't you go?
Because everything that's beautiful
to me is right here.
Won't you please marry me, Sally?
If you like. But don't you want to?
Well, there's no-one else I'd marry.
< How about a taxi, sir?
What? How about a taxi?
Yes.
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd