[ ball hitting mitt ]
[ umpire ]
strike two!
[ crowd shouting, heckling ]
[ man ]
let's go, baby!
[ crowd whistling, applauding ]
[ exhales ]
[ woman ]
we're with you, Dave. Come on.
[ crowd continues
shouting, heckling ]
[ man ]
come on, Dave!
Stay in the zone, Dave!
Stay in the zone!
You got what it takes.
You struck out 10 batters
already this game.
You need one more!
[ whispering ]
don't fuck up. Don't fuck up.
Don't fuck up.
[ cheering, applauding,
shouting continue ]
[ whispers ]
that's it.
[ man ]
put it down the middle, Dave!
Full count! Come on!
[ whispers, indistinct ]
[ exhales ]
[ ball hits mitt ]
- Ball four.
- [ crowd shouting, jeering ]
[ crowd continues
shouting, jeering ]
You're blind, ump!
What, are you drunk?
Our boys are
out of the play-offs
because of you.
You know
I don't pick favorites.
Oh, yeah? Yeah?
Screw you!
[ boys shouting ]
[ mutters ]
fuck 'em all.
[ guitar ]
%%  honey, love ya
honey, little honey-bunny %%
%%  Sunday morning
love ya more funny
love in the skyline, baby %%
%%  ice cream, 'scuse me
I seen you looking good
the other evening %%
%%  oh, you dig it
had to smile
just an hour or so  %%
%%  are we in love
like I think we be %%
%%  it ain't a long rhyme
it took ages to think of %%
%%  I think I'll lull it
in the water, baby %%
%%  honey, love ya
honey, little honey-bunny  %%
%%  Sunday morning
love you more funny
love in the skyline, baby %%
%%  ice cream, 'scuse me
I seen you looking good
the other evening %%
[ ends ]
[ sighs ]
Hell of a game tonight.
The pitcher from Cedar Springs
walked in the winning run.
It was a tough call.
I'm gonna have to wear
a hat and shades
when I go in town.
The parents-- oh, boy.
They wanted blood.
I didn't know
what the heck-- he--
[ mutters ]
fuck.
[ grunting ]
shit.
Crap.
Hell of a game tonight.
The pitcher
for Cedar Springs
walked in the winning run.
Tough call. I'm gonna have
to wear a hat and shades
when I go in town.
[ play-by-play announcer ]
the 371 Mark in right field.
David Wright with
his 16th home run of the year!
And the brewer lead
is cut to 7-5.
[ trash scattering ]
[ glass shatters ]
Get your goddamn monkey-ass
away from my car!
[ whispering ]
oh, shit. Fuck.
Hold it right there.
[ yells ]
hold it.
Don't make a move.
There's no telling
what I'm liable to do.
The gun's loaded.
Don't shoot!
Are you holding the gun?
No, I don't think so.
I'm holding the gun.
Right?
All right, get up.
Okay, you're gonna walk over
to my front door.
Okay.
You're gonna open it
and you're gonna
go inside.
I'm gonna have my gun
sticking in your kidneys
the whole time.
Just don't shoot.
Sit in the chair!
[ coughs ]
sit still
while I call the cops.
Oh, boy,
they're gonna love this--
2:30 in the morning.
All right,
take off the mask.
I said, take off
the goddamn mask!
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You? What the hell
are you doin'?
What's your father
gonna say? Huh?
What are you
thinkin' about?
I'm sorry.
It wasn't even my idea.
Why do I care?
Grow up, boy!
Take some responsibility
for your actions.
Well, after you
cost us the game--
Oh, I cost you
the game, did I?
I cost you the game?
You were pitching,
and your teammates
let in two runs on errors.
So you think
I cost you the game?
Sloppy play.
That's what cost you the game.
So don't put it
on my ass.
Okay.
[ mutters ]
oh, man.
- What?
- Nothing.
Shit.
I don't know
what I'm gonna do with you.
[ sighs ]
all right, listen,
I'm not gonna call the cops...
If you deal with that yard
and you take care
of the broken window.
And I already know it was
Paul Michaels and Todd Hunter
that was with ya.
If it was up to me, I'd
rat those little S.O.B.'s out
the first Chance I got.
But it doesn't matter to me...
Whether you deal
with the yard yourself
or have your friends help ya,
So long as it gets done.
Okay?
Yeah.
Thank you.
I know you're doing me
a huge favor--
Don't start kissing my ass.
I already know
I'm doing you a favor.
Listen.
I'm gonna go and
get me and Kelly Dawn a beer.
You want a soda or somethin'?
Wait, Kel--
your dog has a last name?
[ panting ]
no.
It's not hyphenated,
damn it.
It's one word.
Kelly Dawn!
Oh.
Kelly Dawn drinks beer.
Yeah, she drinks
a little bit of beer.
She doesn't get plastered
or nothin'.
No dog of mine's
gonna teetotal.
Know what I'm sayin'?
[ chuckles ]
this little bitch here,
she's a little Queen.
She eats a steak
every night of the week.
Leftovers,
things like that?
No, I don't feed her leftovers.
I make it just for her.
I can't eat meat anymore.
Wow.
Sure I can't
get you nothin'?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- Uh, raisins?
Uh, no,
I'm-- I'm good.
[ sighs ]
That's it.
Dave!
Dave, what happened?
What happened?
You okay, man?
Did he try
to mess with you?
Dude, two more minutes,
I woulda gone in there.
I was gonna break his legs.
He's just a crazy old man.
Let's just forget about it.
Yeah.
[ sighs ]
[ girl ]
David!
David James Tibbel,
time to get up.
[ groans ]
Just five more--
hey, loser, up. You have
to drive me to school.
- Remember?
- [ groaning continues ]
[ coughing ]
[ imitates groan ]
get up.
[ mock snarl ]
[ giggles ]
Dad.
Uh, you have
a button missing.
Oh.
Yeah.
I didn't notice.
I'll fix it for you.
No, that's all right.
I'll fix it.
Okay.
Thanks.
I'll put it on your bed.
- You gonna be ready to go
in, like, five minutes?
- Sure.
Thank you.
Oh, you're welcome.
Hey, ash?
You know you got weeds
around your neck, right?
Think it looks nice?
Yep.
Yeah, I think so too.
Oh, shit.
[ groans ]
[ grunts ]
[ invitation crumples ]
[ motor running ]
I'm sorry. You can probably
see this pile of change
sitting on my dresser.
[ clerk ]
you don't have 75 cents?
No.
I don't think--
look, is it all right if I
give you the money tomorrow?
D-do you need 75 cents?
I have it right here.
Uh, you're a pitcher,
aren't you?
Uh, yeah, actually.
That's right.
Um--
Okay. Fine.
Here, just--
Just-- just take it.
Don't even worry about it.
No, I'll pay you back.
I don't take money.
Scout's honor.
Here you go.
Sorry about that.
Hey, no worries.
Thanks.
Uh, sure.
Hey.
How's it goin'?
W-where you coming from?
Day job.
Something you have
to look forward to
when you graduate.
It's a responsibility.
It's part of being an adult.
A lot of kids
can't handle responsibility.
You know what I mean?
Hey,
get the top. Too.
[ coughs ]
and just so you know,
It's not
that I'm embarrassed.
It's an eyesore...
For me.
The neighbors
can suck it.
So get it down.
Well, how do you suppose
I do that?
It's not my problem.
Figure what you did
to get it up there,
And then do it
in reverse.
Hey, David.
[ chuckling ]
There's a tall ladder
round in back.
You can use it
if you want to.
Thanks.
Yeah.
[ TV: Announcer ]
a solid major leaguer.
[ TV: Announcer continues,
indistinct ]
Son of a bitch.
[ TV: Play-by-play announcer ]
two strikes, the count.
2-2 pitch.
The pitch is lifted
in the air towards center
and then crossing--
[ TV: Sound mutes ]
[ grunts ]
Shit. Piss. Corruption.
Yeah, here you go.
Take that.
David.
[ chuckles ]
Go home.
I'm, uh, not finished yet.
Well, you're not
gonna finish today.
So go on home
and come back tomorrow.
Well, why?
Why?
Because
you've worked enough today.
So go home and suck
on your mama's titties.
[ chuckles ]
all right.
My mom doesn't live with us.
That's too bad.
Hey!
Tomorrow,
same place, same time.
[ truck door opens ]
Okay.
[ truck door
closes ]
[ truck engine starts ]
Strike...
Three!
You're out!
[ exhales ]
Beautiful, isn't it,
At night?
And I get to work here.
[ exhales ]
They just cut the grass.
[ inhales ]
And I swear, that smell
is as sweet as it was...
50 years ago...
When my father took me
to my first game.
I'm a lucky man.
I'm a very lucky man.
[ water running ]
[ water stops ]
hey, dad.
You sure been making
a lot of photos lately.
Yeah.
Better be careful.
Stay down there too long,
you become a mole.
Mole. Don't have eyes.
Can't see a thing.
Hmm.
[ chuckles ]
You can always
take care of me.
[ chuckles ]
Yeah.
Do you ever
think about mom?
No, n-n-not really.
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
Why did you let her go?
What?
Why did she leave?
Your mother loved you--
love-- loves you.
I-I don't see her here
right now.
[ sighs ]
look, it's, um--
It's not that simple.
Your mother,
Um, wasn't the woman...
That... All of us
thought she was.
What?
She wasn't happy.
A lot of people
aren't happy, dad.
No, she wasn't happy
for a very long time.
Wh-- what the hell
does that mean?
Look, you want
to discuss your mother?
Yes.
Okay, well,
we'll talk about it sometime.
We're talking about it now.
Well, now's
not a good time.
Look, I'm beat.
Uh-huh.
I'm just--
I'm beat.
[ water running ]
[ man ]
Ray, you should go home.
You got some
big decisions to make.
It's not a question of
do we perform surgery?
It's
where do we start?
You understand me?
I'm not gettin' cut.
Hey.
You ump--
Umpire?
Yeah, I'm an umpire.
I-I-I thought
I recognized you.
My, uh-- my son
used to play ball...
Till he graduated
six years ago.
What was the name?
Travis. Varlie?
Oh, Varlie.
Do you remember him?
Yeah, sure, I remember.
Number seven.
[ laughs ]
that's right.
Yeah. Played third base.
He had
a real strong arm.
I remember him pulling off
some surprising as hell plays
for a high schooler.
What's he doing?
Uh, well, uh,
Travis, uh, lives
in Arbortown now.
He got married last may,
and his firstborn's
on the way.
[ chuckles ]
if you can
believe that.
They grow up fast now,
don't they?
Yeah, they sure do.
They never
told me that.
Yeah, well, congratulations
on being a grandpa.
Oh, uh, thank you.
[ scraping ]
How's it goin'?
Fine.
Good.
Don't you have
a game to ump today?
Ah, it doesn't start
for a couple hours.
How much money do you have?
I-- I--
How do you plan to pay
for my broken car window?
Well, how much
were you thinking--
A few hundred.
I mean, I haven't had it
priced out yet, but--
You got
a few hundred?
No.
But your father
would loan it to you if you
told him why you needed it.
Is that right?
Huh?
I got a proposition.
Why don't you
come inside with me.
[ bottles clinking ]
[ exhales ]
You want one?
Nah, just kiddin'.
You're too young
to have one. Right?
Uh, right.
[ sighs ]
whew. Are you happy?
Uh, what? I--
are you happy, kid?
I don't know.
Yeah, I guess.
Well, which one is it?
"yeah" or "I guess"?
I-I don't know.
Um, I'm assuming that
you want me to say "yes,"
so I'll just say "yes."
Good.
That's good.
You should be happy, David,
[ snorts ]
inside and out.
You think I'm happy?
I... Don't know.
I don't know you that well.
Can you try and answer?
As-as happy
as anybody else, I suppose.
You're just
avoiding the question.
Say what you mean,
you little pussy.
Yes or no?
No. No. I-- no.
You're-- I don't think
that you're happy at all.
Good.
Uh, you're right, David.
No, I am not happy.
But I wear it well.
[ exhales ]
I'm miserable, in fact.
I'm 57.
That makes me
three times you.
There's not much in life
that makes it exciting for me.
There's not much out there.
And, on top of it all,
I got my high school reunion.
You know what that means.
Do you have any idea
why people go to reunions?
To see
all their old friends?
[ chuckles ]
No, to tally up
who they're beatin'.
They can't help it.
They just gotta find out
who's worse off than they are.
[ laughs ]
that sucks, doesn't it?
Yeah.
But you wanna know
what's gonna happen this time?
I'm gonna go
for the first time.
I'm gonna go to my reunion.
And if anybody says
anything to me, they're gonna
have to say it to my face.
Okay.
[ chuckles ]
and you know what else?
I'm gonna win.
And you're gonna help me.
I-- I am?
Toad Ramsey.
He was an alcoholic.
Irish cat.
Died when he was 41.
Ah.
He was a pitcher too.
One day he was
laying them bricks, you know?
Split one, cut that tendon
right there in his hand.
He had to find a new way
to grip ahold of the ball.
And you know
what he come up with?
The knuckleball.
Can you believe that?
[ laughs ] you know?
That's, uh-- yeah.
That's --
I-I don't really see where
you're going with that, but--
The knuckleball moves all over.
You don't know
where it's gonna go.
Sometimes in life you gotta
roll with the punches and just,
You know, make things up.
I can't go to my reunion alone,
so you're gonna
have to go with me.
What?
And you know what else?
We're gonna be blood.
W-wait! I don't see
what the problem is.
You don't?
You just asked me to go
to your high school reunion.
No, no, no! I asked you
to pretend to be my son
at my high school reunion.
That's pretty
screwed up.
No, it isn't.
- I don't even look like you.
- Says you.
Whatever!
You look like me.
I feel for you.
It's just weird--
please don't get any closer.
Weird? What does that mean?
What about my broken car window?
Oh, no, you don't!
What about that,
you little turd?
Do you hear me?
Do you hear what I said?
Maybe.
[ engine starts ]
[ truck pulls away rapidly ]
[ grunts ]
[ mutters ]
[ Ashley ]
you okay?
Fine.
You know, dad didn't go
to work yesterday.
Or the day before.
What are you talking about?
[ grunts ]
yeah, that's it.
Ray!
Yeah?
Um--
Whoa.
Jesus Christ.
What the hell
happened to you?
You look like a worm
set up shop in your colon.
Well, I'm fine, so--
are you sure?
Yeah, yeah,
I'm fine.
Really?
Yeah. I wanted to talk
to you about what you--
you asked me about before.
Yeah?
Um--
Uh-huh?
And, I don't know,
I guess I've just been--
I thought about it
a little bit-- do you
need one of these?
Yeah.
And, um--
I'll do it.
I'll-- I'll go
to your reunion.
Are you serious?
Really?
Yeah. Yeah.
As long as
we're on the same page
about what I'm doing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. Shoot.
I go to your reunion,
I do the dog-and-pony show--
that's it. I'm done. Gone.
Right. Now, you positive
you wanna do this?
Yeah, I wanna help you.
All right.
So--
And once that's over,
the slate's clean, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fresh as a Daisy.
Fresh as a gravestone.
All that stuff.
Okay. It's set.
Okay, just a--
I got this.
Okay. Here.
Here, David.
There you go.
[ chuckles ]
"no hippie hair"?
No.
[ lighter flint strikes ]
[ man ] what we're gonna do
is take our tape and feed it
through a tape timer...
And attach it to
the back of our vehicle.
[ man continues, faint ]
[ play-by-play announcer ]
one ball, one strike.
First year with the patriots.
24-year-old
out of palm beach--
Want one?
Uh, thought I was too young.
Remember?
Whatever, whatever.
But I'm offering.
Right there it is.
[ groans ]
[ cap releases ]
Shit. Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Tastes good,
doesn't it?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah. You know,
I was a lot younger than you
when I was drinkin' beer.
I've had beer before.
Sorry, old-timer.
I didn't mean
to ruffle your feathers.
[ Dave ]
that's all right.
If you drink that beer
like a man,
I'll let you have another one.
But you're gonna have to go out
back and get it from the fridge,
where I keep my fishing beer.
Your fishing beers?
You fish?
Yeah.
Fishing.
Didn't your old man
ever take you fishing?
I don't think
I've ever been fishing.
Oh, Jesus.
Then you don't know
anything about women, do ya?
Uh--
[ chuckles ]
Uh, no. No, I don't.
You'll have to come with me
sometime then.
Yeah, right.
Why don't we
just start with beer.
Consider it done.
Good.
I'll be right back.
[ laughs ]
[ Ray groans ]
[ Dave ] man, you okay?
[ Ray ] no. I just
tried to take a piss.
It hurt like a bitch.
[ exhales ]
Should probably
get that checked out.
I have.
Nothing you can do about it.
It's just age.
Remember that the next time
you try to write your name
in the snow with your pee.
Got you your beer.
Oh, great.
Whew.
Ah.
You gonna come
to the state play-offs?
I'm umpin'.
- I might do that.
- What do you mean, you might?
You should.
I mean, you're gonna play
one of these teams next year.
- That's if I play next year.
- "if" you're still playin'?
I don't know
what I'm gonna do next year
or the year after that.
All right. You got a career
you wanna pursue?
Well, I like the idea
of being an archaeologist.
You know?
I mean,
digging up pottery
and, uh--
And, uh, like, arrowheads
and things like that.
Actually,
I have a pretty good
collection already.
My mom gave me her collection,
she got from her grandfather
when she was a little kid.
That's really nice.
I mean,
if you think about it,
how realistic is that?
How realistic is
me becoming an archaeologist?
I sort of feel clueless.
Well, you're not alone.
Stick with baseball.
How long
is that gonna last?
That's a good question.
It doesn't
really make me happy.
That's too bad.
[ Ashley ]
you okay?
[ Dave ] I'm fine.
Well, I'm doing fine too, Dave.
Thank you for asking.
What?
Exactly.
You're not the only one
who has bad days, you know.
What am I supposed to ask you?
Are you having a bad day?
No. Just ask me what's going
on in my life sometimes.
All right, what's going on
in your life sometimes?
Do you even care?
Yes! Why would I ask
if I didn't care?
I have to sing a song
by myself for chorus.
I'm sorta nervous.
Really?
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Like, really
you have to sing?
In front of
the whole school?
Well, sing it.
I'm not
a trained monkey,
you know.
You have to sing in front of the
whole school. You're not gonna
sing in front of your brother?
They talked to us
about peer pressure,
like, literally, last week.
Oh. Really?
I think you're afraid.
No. No.
I think
you're a scaredy cat.
No.
Then sing it.
Do it!
No. No!
As your older brother,
do it now!
What, you want me
to just sing it right here?
Please.
Light she was
and like a fairy
And her shoes
were number nine
Herring boxes
without topses
Sandals were
for Clementine
Oh, my darlin'
Clementine
You are lost
and gone forever
Dreadful sorry
Clementine
In my dreams
she doth haunt me
Robed in garments
soaked in brine
Though in life
I used to hug her
Now she's dead
I draw the line
Want to, uh, call it a day?
We haven't gotten any bites
all day.
You're a real whiner.
You know that?
No, I just--
Do you know
who Henry Schmidt was?
This fella was a pitcher.
He was from Texas.
In his rookie year
he played for the dodgers.
He won 20 games.
You know what he did
for his second year?
You tell me.
He sent in
his second-season contract
unsigned...
With a note
attached to it saying,
"I do not like
to live in the east,
And I won't report."
He never played
another game in the majors.
Why?
Because Henry Schmidt...
Knew he had to walk away.
Because some voice...
Deep inside of him...
Was telling him...
It was time.
Maybe you have a voice
deep inside of you that's
telling you it's time?
Not like that, no.
So why don't we do
what I said
when we first got here.
Just shut up and wait.
And if that doesn't work,
what did I say to do?
Wait some more.
Yeah.
[ chattering ]
Yo!
Dave? Hello. Hey!
What's up, man?
What's goin' on,
buddy?
How's it goin', guys?
What's up, bro?
Wanna check out a movie
with us tonight?
Uh, I think I gotta get
some stuff done tonight, so--
Okay.
All right.
Well, I'm just curious, man.
What happened the other day?
You bailed on us.
You know, I'm sorry.
I had some errands to do.
[ Todd ]
no, 'cause we drove by
the ump's house.
Funniest thing.
We saw your truck
out front.
[ wheezing chuckle ]
I was out there to apologize.
You sure that's all?
What else would I
being doing, Todd?
We have no idea.
But toddy here was thinkin'
that might not be the first
time you've been over there.
- Is that so?
- Are you hangin' out
with the ump?
Do you wanna hang out with that
wack job? I'm taking care of
shit so you two don't have to.
You guys should be
thanking me.
Thank you.
Are you sure you're not
lettin' him suck your dick?
[ ship horn sounding ]
[ Dave ]
where'd you learn
how to shoot?
[ Ray ]
military.
Did you get drafted?
No, I volunteered.
They sent me over to Germany
for a year and a half.
[ chuckles ]
it was boring as hell,
So I asked them to move me.
Did you go back
to the U.S.?
'nam. I did two tours
in 'nam before I got back.
You asked
to go to Vietnam?
What did you do there?
I flew.
- I flew c-123s.
- Well, did you drop bombs?
Yeah, we dropped bombs.
No, you idiot.
Not everybody that flew
dropped bombs and blew shit up.
Well, then, did you...
Fly people back and forth?
No, no.
I did herbicide
spray missions.
What is that?
You know when people
are out in their yard
spraying weeds and insects?
Yeah.
That's what I did,
Only on a much
grander scale.
[ crowd chattering,
applauding ]
Your buddy from the mall...
Said you have a crush on me.
He's-- he's an asshole.
Does that mean
you don't?
No. No.
It just--
[ ball hitting bat ]
It just means
he's an asshole.
So how do you know Ray?
Um--
Um, we--
I-I play baseball.
So--
I mean, I also
vandalized his house.
[ chuckles ]
[ woman ]
yeah, Ray's been
umping forever.
You know, I played softball
in high school.
Really?
Fast pitch.
Yeah, I was pretty good too.
I'm Debra,
by the way.
Dave.
[ Ray's voice ]
it was nice of the two of you
to come to the game.
You practically
begged me to come.
Oh, I begged you?
That's the way
it goes now, huh?
Hey, what are these?
Those?
They're moonflowers.
They only blossom at night.
Debra's got an obsession
about 'em.
They're more like
diamonds to her.
Note taken.
You want a pad
to write it down?
No, I'm okay.
All right.
Hey, listen.
Why don't you go in there...
And help her with
the dishes or something?
Okay. And you're gonna
sit here and look
at the moonflowers?
Yeah.
Okay.
There's nothing sissyish
about looking at Flora.
You know what
I'm saying?
What?
[ chuckles ]
nothing.
All right.
Whoa!
What?
Um--
- Is that--
- a syringe? Yeah.
- No, I mean, is it--
- what, you never saw
a junkie before?
Let me ask you another question.
Have you ever known
a diabetic before?
[ whispering ]
oh, I know. I know.
Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I try not to take my insulin
in front of other people.
It kind of freaks them out.
But Malcolm doesn't mind,
do you? No, you don't.
You're used to seeing mommy
shoot up, aren't you?
Oh, I know.
You're my perfect little man.
Don't ever grow up.
- I noticed you have
lots of books.
- Yeah.
[ chuckles ]
what, you thought
I was illiterate?
No, I--
oh, come on.
No. I-- you have
lots of books. It's just
there's a lot of 'em.
I'm just giving you
a hard time.
Yeah.
Yeah, you are.
Um, jerk.
It's a nice night.
[ sighs ]
Makes you want the sun
to never come up.
[ train approaching ]
Mr. Tibbel?
How you doing today?
Fine.
Good. Good.
That's good to hear.
I'm Ray.
I'm a friend of David's.
[ grunts ]
Thank you.
Dave!
[ Dave ]
one minute!
He'll, uh--
he'll be right down.
You like baseball.
I hear
you're a photographer.
That's right.
Yeah.
Oh.
I have my own lab.
How's that work?
People bring me their photos,
and then they come back
and give me the slip,
And I give them
their photos back.
It's really that simple.
Dave!
Funny thing, though, people--
I'll tell you.
You'd think they'd get their
photos and that they'd take it
to the car, bring it home.
But no, they look at them
right in front of me,
show them to me.
I mean, have you ever seen
someone eat a tub of yogurt...
In front of the cashier
who just sold it to them?
[ chuckles ]
no.
That's--
that's what I'm saying.
[ footfalls on stairs ]
Ah, here he is now.
Dave, uh,
what's going on?
I'm going to a dance.
What the hell
you got in your hair?
- The gel... Under the sink.
- Oh.
Is this okay?
Yeah. You look great.
Good.
[ Dave ]
I didn't know what you meant.
Is that my suit?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
Is that okay?
Sure.
Hey, we'll-- we'll talk later.
Um, okay.
Okay, let's take
your car, son.
Wait. First, are you gonna
call me "son" all day?
Why? You want me to
call you something else?
Well, Dave.
Dave would work, I think.
No. I like "son."
all right.
Oh. Can I drive your car?
Um-- um, yeah.
Uh, here you go.
Bye, Mr. Tibbel.
All right.
Listen, I gotta make
a quick stop before
we hit the reunion.
All right. Where?
[ radio: Soul ]
No, Ray.
This isn't right. Okay?
I don't think--
no, no. Dave.
Dave. Dave. Dave.
Listen to me.
I don't think there's any
possibility that you can judge
whether this is right or wrong.
Well, I am. This is wrong.
I will go to hell
for doing this.
You will not go to hell.
There is no hell.
That's a myth.
And what you're going to do
is you're going to get some
practice for this reunion.
Pat, do you understand what
Alzheimers disease is?
Yes, ma'am.
All right.
I just want you
to be prepared...
Because it can be really hard
on the patient's loved ones.
And I want you to know
even if your grandfather
doesn't recognize you,
It has nothing to do
with how much he loves you.
Hey, pop.
Who's pop?
You are.
I'm not pop.
Who are you?
Why are you all
dressed up?
I'm your son.
My son?
Mmm.
And I brought your grandson
to see ya.
He's right over there.
Well, well.
Look who's come to visit.
Come here, you!
Hey.
You remind me of myself
when I was your age.
- Yeah?
- You wanna be a ballplayer?
Uh, I-I don't know.
You look like a ballplayer.
Did you play any baseball
when you were a kid?
I-- yeah.
I-I-- I played second base.
And I used to be able
to field a grounder,
And then turn
a double play...
Without even wearing my glove.
Hey.
You remind me of myself
when I was your age.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You-- you like baseball?
I sure do.
I love baseball.
I used to take my son to all
the games when he was little.
Those were some
of my... Best memories.
- Do you like that channel?
- Um--
I really can't say that
I've watched it that much.
Do they always sell knives
on this channel?
Oh, no.
They sell lots of things--
you know, sweaters,
And baseball cards and--
and fake diamonds and--
But, uh, knives
are my favorite.
Yeah.
Do you like TV?
- Not really.
- Well, why do you watch it?
Because it's there.
What I really like is...
Talking to people.
It's unbelievable.
It's just unbelievable.
Well, you remember
what the nurse said.
Just because he doesn't
remember you doesn't mean
he doesn't love you.
[ scoffs ]
yeah, but he remembered you!
Don't take it
too personally.
But he's never even
seen you before.
I make a good
first impression.
Bullshit.
[ folk music ]
You want me to bullshit to these
people, or do you have anything
specific you want me to say?
I don't keep up
with any of these people.
Say whatever you want.
Anything?
[ laughs ]
no.
Your name is pat.
You like me
and our life is good.
[ chattering, laughter ]
Don't worry about it.
I'm all right.
I won't embarrass you
tonight.
[ laughing ]
no, no.
Thanks.
You guys have
a terrific time. Hello.
Can we help you?
Um, is your-- is your wife
part of the class of '66?
No, I am.
I'm sorry, but--
Who are you?
Oh.
Ray cook.
Raymond Leroy cook.
Ray?
Yeah.
[ sighs ]
we all thought
you'd passed away.
I'm not dead, am I, son?
No. No, dad.
Good. Yeah.
[ chuckles ]
yeah!
Welcome.
What a handsome son you have.
So glad you came.
Thank you.
[ rock and roll ]
[ chattering, laughter ]
Ow!
[ continues ]
Ray cook.
Hey, Jonas.
[ laughing ]
Terrific.
I can't believe it.
Yeah. Me either.
Wow!
And, pat, I swear,
you're the spitting image
of your father.
Oh, really?
Shit, yeah.
I can see it in the eyes.
They're the windows
to the soul, you know.
That's right.
What are doing
with the soul stick?
I took me on a third leg here.
It was necessary.
When you get older, you know?
Oh, yeah?
I know. Things fall apart,
don't they?
They sure do, quickly.
Your dad was crazy
back in high school.
- Can you believe that?
- Oh, I believe it.
Ray? Ray cook?
Ray!
Marianne.
Ray! Oh!
Who's this?
It's Marianne Reynolds.
Ray's girlfriend
from senior year.
How have you been?
Hey, listen. I have somebody
I want you to meet.
This is, uh, pat,
my son.
Your son?
Yeah, my son.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
He looks just like you.
Yeah.
Ah. Oh, isn't this nice?
Oh, Ray.
[ slow music ]
[ man ]
I gotta be honest.
Your father is the last person
I thought I'd see
at one of these things.
It's like he wanted to fall off
the face of the earth.
[ man chuckling ]
[ Dave ] well, you know.
[ Jonas ] everybody wondered
what happened to him.
For the first 25 years
people would always ask,
"you seen Ray cook?"
Then after that,
the occasional rumor
would pop up--
"Ray's a C.I.A. Operative."
[ Dave chuckles ]
"Ray's a hermit
up in Alaska."
[ all laughing ]
And, "Ray's living in a commune
down in south America."
[ woman ] oh, yeah.
He practically
became a myth.
[ man ] you could say that.
With all the sightings,
you know, and
the weird theories,
Ray was sort of
like a goddamn sasquatch.
[ man #2 ]
what's that?
Sasquatch is like bigfoot.
Bigfoot.
Yeah, yeah.
Ray's sort of like bigfoot.
[ woman laughs ]
oh, Ray cook.
[ barking ]
[ men laughing ]
You know all the girls
were crazy for him
back in school.
We were!
I don't think I've ever seen
someone bark for my dad before.
[ woman ]
everybody thought...
He would be
this big baseball star.
And look at him.
He's still moving like
he's in his twenties.
Jesus, you know, you think
time changes everything.
And then you realize
that it doesn't much
really change anything.
What?
[ man ]
you got me, baby.
Oh.
You know what?
My dad's a hard Guy
to get to know.
It's hard for him
to express anything.
You wouldn't know it
by looking at him,
but he's got...
A heart filled with...
Love and pain.
And I think, slowly,
through the years,
It's just been...
Bleeding.
You broke my heart
40 years ago.
You know, I can't remember
that far back.
I can't even remember
how I got here.
Oh, Ray, I bet you broke
a lot of hearts.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I broke hearts.
I broke my own too.
Oh.
Good for you.
[ laughing ]
So what'd he do
after high school?
Air force.
Air force guy, huh?
Yeah. Was.
So, what's he doing now?
Well, after he returned
to a civilian life,
He went to wall street.
Yeah.
Huge millionaire.
God, we're rolling in it.
You know?
Just tons of money.
But the weird thing was
that he gave it all away.
I mean, not all of it
'cause he saved just enough
to travel the world.
But he gave most of it
away to Charity.
Are you serious?
Just one.
I'm tired.
Just one. That's all.
That's a cute kid.
[ woman ]
don't let him fool you.
- He can act like a demon.
- [ man chuckles ]
- So, uh, who are you here with?
- Oh, Ray cook.
Huh. So he, uh-- he finally
came out of the woodwork?
Yeah.
Wow.
Son of a gun. I'd sure
like to talk to him.
Hey.
How's he doing?
He's doing good. Yeah.
I'm glad to hear that.
So, what relation
are you to him?
I'm his son.
Well, there you are.
[ chuckles ]
That's good of your mom
to let you fly out here
for this thing.
Sorry. Huh?
Oh, I got a buddy, a lawyer.
He represented your mom when
your folks were splitting up.
Geez, you were just a little pup
when all that happened.
Yeah.
That's a tough
situation to be in.
Ray must have made
one hell of a plea...
To get your mother
to let you come out
for his reunion.
[ laughs ]
huh?
Yeah. He sure did,
didn't he?
How do you feel?
I feel...
[ chuckles ]
good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
[ sighs ]
I--
I don't know.
It's been a long time
since I felt--
What?
I don't know.
Anything.
Mmm.
Oh, Ray.
Yeah.
Everybody loved you.
You were the perfect son.
- Did you have a good time?
- I had a great time.
We sure fooled them, huh?
Yeah, we sure did.
Sure did.
[ radio: Soft rock ]
I heard a rumor
about you.
Uh-oh.
Let me have it.
Do you already
have a son?
I didn't mention that,
did I?
No, you didn't.
Is he okay?
Yeah, yeah, sure, sure.
He's fine.
Yeah.
I mean,
as far as I know.
You see,
My son and I have a--
We don't get along.
I mean, I try, but...
He, uh--
He doesn't want to have
anything to do with me.
And...
So I make these videotapes
of myself...
And I send them to him.
Those ones?
Yeah, those.
You didn't see those, did you?
Well, I didn't watch them,
if that's what you mean.
That's what I mean.
What do you do
on the videotapes?
No, I don't do anything
on the videotapes.
Nothing funny.
I talk to him, basically.
I tell him about myself,
how I feel.
Pretty much before I met you,
that's the only talking I did.
Does he ever reply?
No.
No. They all get
returned unopened.
Almost all of 'em.
That's the problem--
every now and then...
They don't come back.
So, that keeps me
making 'em.
- I had a lot of fun
at your reunion.
- You did?
Yeah. Yeah. I said
some shit about you.
Oh, yeah?
And everyone could tell
that I was your son.
[ chuckles ]
You see, that's why
it's a better part to play
than the real gig.
As a father,
I'm a real shit, you know.
- I doubt that.
- No, it's true.
I'm a weakling.
I'm just, you know--
I never... Paid attention.
I was never there.
That's probably why
he doesn't call me.
You know,
he doesn't know me.
And my ex-wife,
boy, oh, boy,
I'm sure she's filled
his head full of--
full of lies.
You know, but--
Well,
[ grunts ]
Maybe not lies.
But, uh, she's probably
telling him...
Only the bad stories.
He's never gonna know
in this life...
How much
I really love him.
How about your father?
My father ain't so good.
What'd he do?
He didn't buy you that stereo
you wanted for your truck?
I'm serious.
What'd he do?
Nothing.
He hit you?
No.
He's a cripple.
Just a cripple.
Ever since my mom left
about two years ago,
He's just been a cripple.
She left all of us.
Me and my sister
get birthday cards
and Christmas cards from her.
But... She just took off.
Was she a good mom
before she left?
She was an amazing mother.
Divorce is a real bitch.
You see all these houses
around here? All around?
I don't know a single person
in any of 'em.
And no one knows me either.
The older I get,
The more I know
that I don't know anyone.
You know me.
[ chuckles ]
yeah.
Maybe.
But I think right now
you should go home.
I don't have to go home yet.
I don't have a curfew.
You've done everything.
It's all square.
- What?
- You've repaid me.
It's over.
[ slams bottle down ]
So, is that just it with us?
Are you serious?
Fine.
Hey, David. David.
You're a really good kid.
And any man would be lucky
to have you as a son.
[ zips up zipper ]
[ crowd cheering,
applauding ]
[ cheering,
applauding continue ]
[ rattles doorknob ]
Ray?
[ knocking ]
Ray, you home?
Ray!
Who died?
[ whispering ]
This is how
it's always gonna be?
Everyone just goes away?
No.
Not everyone.
He left something
I'm supposed to give you.
[ knocking ]
hold on.
[ stops videotape ]
Come in.
Are you all right or--
What's wrong?
Spit it out.
Everything's gonna
be okay, right?
I--
I-I sure hope so.
It has to, right?
If you want to talk
to me, I'll listen.
[ knocking ]
Hey, guys.
What's going on?
Nothing.
Um, you watch the game?
I must have missed it.
Okay, well,
You kids, uh,
you stay out of trouble.
[ Dave laughing ]
We will.
What if tomorrow, when
we're driving to school,
we just keep driving?
Huh?
What if tomorrow,
when me and Ashley
are driving to school,
We just keep driving,
we don't come back?
Like mom.
I would miss you both
very much.
Good night, dad.
Good night.
[ Ray ]
oh, hell of a game tonight.
The pitcher from Cedar Springs
walked in the winning run.
Tough call.
I'm gonna have to
wear a hat and shades
when I'm in town.
The parents--
[ chuckles ]
Boy, they wanted blood
after the game.
I didn't know
what the heck to do.
So I hid out in the car
until they left through
the other exit.
Not a fun day
to be an umpire.
Those kids on the field,
they don't know
how good they have it.
And that pitcher, Tibbel,
he threw a solid game.
Just a lot of bad breaks.
But he's got a good future
if he sticks with it.
To be honest,
for a second there,
I wasn't sure whether
to call that last pitch...
A ball or a strike.
It was just barely
off the black.
[ folk music ]
[ man ]
%%  well, if I needed you %%
%%  would you come to me %%
%%  and ease my pain %%
%%  if you needed me %%
%%  I would come to you %%
%%  I would swim the seas %%
%%  for to ease your pain %%
%%  well, in the night forlorn %%
%%  oh, the morning's born %%
%%  and the morning shines %%
%%  with the lights of love %%
%%  and you will miss sunrise %%
%%  if you close your eyes %%
%%  and that would break %%
%%  my heart in two %%
%%  a lady's with me now %%
%%  since I showed her how %%
%%  to lay her Lily hand %%
%%  in mine %%
%%  Loop and Lil agree %%
%%  she's a sight to see %%
%%  a treasure for %%
%%  the poor to find %%
%%  if I needed you %%
%%  would you come to me %%
%%  and ease my pain %%
%%  if you needed me %%
%%  I would come to you %%
%%  I would swim the seas %%
%%  for to ease your pain %%
[ music fades ]
}}