- Afternoon, Mrs. Abbott.
- How do you do?
- Hiya, Preston.
- Hello, Charlie.
Say, these things really travel, don't they?
You need any help?
- Thanks.
- How's the building business?
- Fine, if I ever get back to it.
- Here, don't forget this.
Say, my paper wants to get
a photograph of Katherine Marlowe...
- and I was told Millie might have one.
- Dozens of them.
- They're old friends, I hear.
- Millie says so.
And I understand she gonna stay
with you folks.
- You're telling me?
- And they say she's something.
There's a big story in the paper about it,
and every seat in Town Hall has been sold.
Everybody's talking about it.
Now, for goodness sakes, Kit,
don't miss the train.
Remember, you're a celebrity.
- Is that Miss Marlowe?
- Oh, Kit, it's going to be wonderful...
seeing you again.
I'm having a big party for you.
- What train is she taking?
- What train are you taking?
- The 11:05.
- 11:05.
Everybody's coming. And darling,
do you realize how long it's been?
It's been years.
And, oh, Kit, I've something wonderful
to tell you, about me.
Just a moment, darling.
What is it, Charlie?
If that's Miss Marlowe, I wanna talk to her.
Kit, there's a reporter here
from The Daily Journal...
who wants to speak to you.
Just a moment.
Hello, Miss Marlowe.
What about your next book? Any news?
Anything special you'd like to have us say?
$1.50 a minute? Oh, it's long distance.
Oh, I'm sorry, excuse me,
I didn't know. Goodbye.
Wait. Kit, what I wanted to tell you was,
I'm going to have a baby.
Kit. Hello? Hello? Kit.
Oh, she's hung up.
- Charlie.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Say, how about a picture of her, Millie?
Can you spare one?
Oh, of course. I've lots of them.
I knew you'd want it,
so I got it all picked out.
- Well, haven't you got one of her alone?
- I don't think so.
What about this...
Well, I looked all through,
but I couldn't find a single one.
You see, all through school and afterward,
until she moved to New York...
we were absolutely inseparable.
From the first day we met,
our lives, our thoughts, our feelings were...
- Inseparable.
- That's it.
- The book's dedicated to me, you know?
- Yeah, I know.
Well, thanks, Millie.
I'll cook up a real story.
- Fine.
- Where do you want these, Millie?
Just a moment, dear. Will you be at
the station in the morning, Charlie?
- Oh, sure.
- Don't forget, the 5:11.
- No, 11:05.
- Oh, yes.
Oh, I hope she didn't miss the train.
- Why should she miss it?
- You don't know Kit Marlowe.
There you are, sir.
She did miss it. Oh, Charlie, what'll I do?
I could kill her.
Well, let's have a look. You take this coach
and I'll take that one. Come on, Frank.
- All aboard!
- I knew this would happen.
Excuse me.
Kit!
- Kit! Kit! You're here.
- Oh, are we?
Well, come on.
- Oh, Kit, how like you.
- We're leaving!
It's a good thing I came in here.
You'd have slept right through
your own hometown.
- Home.
- Oh, Kit.
Hello, Millie.
- Well.
- Where's the rest of your luggage?
- That's all there is.
Toothbrush, pajamas and a clean pair of...
Oh, hello, Charlie. This is Charlie Archer.
He's on the paper.
- He came down to meet you.
- Oh, has he? How very nice.
Remember me? $1.50 a minute?
- Long distance?
- Of course.
We'd like to get a picture, Miss Marlowe.
Do you mind?
- Not at all.
- Not from the back, Frank. That's Frank.
- Hello, Frank.
- Come on, jump right up here on this cart.
- Oh, not that, Charlie.
- Why not? She's gonna look swell.
Now, just kind of lean on that box there.
Get the Brownie ready, Frank.
Now, give a smile for the folks. That's it.
Hold it.
Hey! Where you going with that?
Wait a minute. Hold it!
- There she is!
- There she is, girls!
Excuse me, lady.
Are you Katherine Marlowe?
- Yes.
- I'm Margaret Kemp.
How do you do?
We represent a newly formed
Katherine Marlowe Club at the college.
You know, your book
has caused something of a stir among us.
- Oh, has it?
- Oh, it certainly has.
Now, we're gonna have a debate today
for an hour, after your lecture.
- You've got to be there to defend it.
- Defend what?
Well, never mind.
We'll tell her all about it at lunch.
- Yes, but...
- But you can't. Luncheon's at my home.
- Don't be silly, lady.
- Oh! Don't you do that!
Put her down! Kit! Kit!
You can't do this. Get down from there.
You're my guest.
Millie, join the Katherine Marlowe Club.
- Did you do this?
- No, but I got a good story.
- Did you get her?
- I got her.
- No, I mean Miss Marlowe.
- Kit! Kit, you come right back here!
- Bye!
- I can't!
- What? Oh, how do you keep your job?
- Oh, get off my car! Get away from me!
- Why don't you go back to school?
- I ain't got a shot... I only got a shot...
- Oh! My chickens! This is the milk!
- What do you mean? It's all your fault.
What's the matter with you?
You ought to be driving a wheelbarrow...
- that's what you ought to do!
- I'll call the police and have you arrested!
Get your filthy finger out of my face!
Don't let us down on that debate now,
or you're a dead bunny.
- I'll be there with bells on. Bye.
- Bye.
Hello. You're Preston.
- Kit?
- What's left of me. Look.
- Is there a hammer in the house?
- Sure.
Oh, go right in.
Have a seat.
Well, we've been...
- Oh, yeah.
- You better take that off.
I'll get you one of Millie's slippers.
Thanks.
I'll put this in your room.
- All right.
- Where is Millie?
There was a riot at the station.
She got lost in the shuffle.
What happened?
- I was kidnapped.
- Kidnapped?
By young America.
It seems my literary honor was at stake.
They wanted me to defend it.
- Did you?
- I got out of it.
Here you are.
- Oh, they're pretty.
- Yeah, they were a Christmas present.
- I'll have your shoe fixed after lunch.
- Thanks.
How about a drink?
Oh, no, not for me. Puts me to sleep,
and I have a lecture to give.
Oh, it'll do you good.
I wonder why Millie's not here yet.
Last time I saw her,
she was getting into her car.
- Millie certainly looks well.
- Yes, she does.
Oh, did she tell you?
We've got a little something on the way.
- No, what? A baby?
- Well, why not?
Why not.
Ever since I've known Millie,
the good things of life...
seemed to make their way carefully to her.
- Does that include me?
- You look all right.
- Thanks, so do you.
- Thank you, Preston.
Not quite what I expected.
- Here, come on, I can't drink alone.
- Well, maybe one.
- To the next generation.
- Thanks.
You must have a good bootlegger.
Millie dug him up.
I think it's the best bathtub gin in town.
It certainly hits the spot.
Three of them guaranteed
to make you go blind.
Why, there's Millie now.
I wonder why she's walking.
- Anything happen to the car?
- Not that I know of.
Wait.
You know, she's going to be pretty sore
she wasn't here to welcome you.
Maybe you ought to make a new entrance.
- Oh, what an idea.
- No, really, it will make her laugh.
I'll tell you what,
you slip out through the garden...
and when she comes in here, pop in again.
- All right.
- Well, come on, hurry.
Oh! My shoes.
Oh, thanks.
- Hello, where's your guest?
- I don't know, and I don't care.
I've never been so humiliated in all my life.
- Where is the car?
- At the depot.
- We owe $40.
- $40? For what?
- Milk.
- Milk? That's an awful lot of milk.
- How do you know she drinks milk?
- Who?
Your girlfriend. $40 for milk?
Are you crazy?
Oh, leave me alone!
Now, calm yourself, Millie,
and don't shout.
I will shout. I'm fighting mad!
I've never seen such a display
of bad manners in all my life.
Why, you don't even treat a stranger
like that, let alone your best friend.
She could have gotten away
perfectly well, but no...
she had to go running off
with those silly college girls.
She left me standing there, like a...
Like a...
- Oh, so you saw her?
- Yes, I saw her.
She looked like someone
who was selling something.
I'm sure if she'd been a man,
she wouldn't have shaved.
No hat, no luggage. Just sprawled out
in the day coach, sleeping peacefully.
What are you shushing me for?
Now, honey, you know the doctor said
you shouldn't excite yourself.
That's true.
I mustn't.
But after I'd gone to all this trouble.
Look.
- These cost 60 cents.
- Oh, well, Millie, that's...
That's terrible.
What's that?
She's here!
You... You...
Now, Millie.
- You!
- Millie! Millie, Millie.
Millie, Millie, wait a minute. Wait!
Oh, where's your sense of humor?
Oh. Never a dull moment.
Same old Millie.
Where are you going?
Oh, I'm sorry things didn't work out.
I still think it was a good idea.
- What happened to you?
- To tell you the truth, I was scared.
I don't blame you.
What did she mean,
I look as if I didn't shave?
Well, don't let that worry you.
I like girls who don't shave.
- She sounded as if she meant it.
- Yeah, I'm afraid she did.
I never thought she'd take it that way.
What do you think we ought to do?
Well, I guess we'd better think
of the next generation.
- Shall I go up?
- Oh, please do. I'd appreciate it.
Of course.
Oh, Kit, I'll have Bertha
put the food on the table.
Will you tell Millie
her man, Drake, is serving?
Very well, Drake.
- Be sure the port is at room temperature.
- Very good, madam.
Millie.
Millie, remember you're a hostess,
and you have a guest.
We just thought you'd like to be the
first one to welcome me to your house.
It was only a joke.
Millie.
Millie, have a heart. Let me in.
You never used to mind.
- I can go to a hotel.
- Perhaps you should.
You certainly didn't act
as though you wanted to see me.
Oh, Millie, what could I do?
I couldn't get away from those Amazons.
Everything's gone wrong
from the moment I got up.
I know, Millie, but don't worry about it.
I like your husband.
You were quite right
when you said he was easy on the eyes.
- He's all right, I suppose.
- And you have a lovely home.
It'll do.
And it was awfully nice of you
to go to so much trouble for my visit.
Come on, Millie, give me a little smile.
And it's so wonderful
you're going to have a baby.
Oh!
Oh, I suppose I couldn't even
tell you that myself.
What does it matter, Millie,
as long as it's true and I know?
Well, it matters to me.
But why? What possible difference
can it make who told me?
You don't know what it's like
to plan to do things a certain way...
and then have them
all go exactly the opposite.
- But, of course, I do.
- Oh, I'm really trembling.
It's so unimportant, Millie.
You have so much to be grateful for.
You should be very happy.
Oh, naturally, I'm happy.
You know, Millie, you're a very lucky girl.
I'm not so sure
that I don't envy you just a little.
Kit, I'm really glad you're here.
- I shouldn't have acted so badly.
- Oh, I understand, darling.
And now, your husband
has told me to tell you...
that your butler, Drake,
is waiting to serve lunch.
- Come on, I'm starved.
- Yes, let's go.
Oh, Kit, I've arranged a little party for you,
not too many...
just the people I thought
you'd like to see again.
They're really nice people.
Charlie?
- Hey, what are you doing here?
- Oh, this stuff is delicious.
Now you've had enough.
I'm gonna take you home.
I don't wanna go home.
It's getting late
and you're the last one to leave.
That's right, pal. You're absolutely right.
It's time to go.
- Which way you live?
- I'm taking you home.
No, I'm taking you home.
- Charlie, you're drunk.
- Confidentially, so am I.
- Good night, Kit, old pal.
- Good night, Charlie.
- I gotta get Pres home. See you later, huh?
- You do that.
- Kit, you look tired.
- I've had a busy day.
Only a couple of stuffed shirts left.
- Why don't you turn in?
- Oh, thanks.
Preston.
Preston, please get Charlie home.
He's so loud.
After all, we have neighbors.
Oh!
- Kit, I'm so sorry. I hate drunkenness.
- Oh, Charlie's a lot of fun.
Oh, don't bother about any of this.
Preston will be home in a minute.
He'll attend to things, he always does.
Come on, let's just go to bed.
All right.
Oh, I could stand a little sleep myself.
My feet are just killing me.
I don't think I've been off them
for about two days.
Well, I hope everyone had a good time.
They certainly ate enough, didn't they?
Oh, my.
It must be nice, having a nice man coming
home in a few minutes to see to things.
Yes, a husband can be
a great comfort at times.
What are you going to do about that, Kit?
Well, right now,
I'm concentrating on a book.
Oh, I know that, but what are you
gonna do about your life outside of books?
About men, I mean.
- Is there anyone?
- I haven't noticed anyone.
- You're not engaged or anything?
- What do you mean by "or anything"?
- But you're not?
- No.
- Oh, I'm rather surprised.
- So am I.
You know, Kit, I had a real pang of envy
when I read all about your success.
But then, afterward, I got to thinking that
being just a woman and a housewife...
- has its compensations.
- Oh, I'm sure they have.
Of course, there are people
who can have both.
- Both what?
- Well, a career and a life.
- What are you getting at?
- Just what I was saying, just now.
It's possible to have the two things,
I'm sure of it.
Millie...
you're holding out on me.
What have you been up to?
Yes, there is something.
I was going to keep it for a while,
but now I'll tell you.
Oh, Kit, promise me you won't breathe
a word to a soul, not even to Preston.
It's been my secret for months.
- And, Kit, please don't laugh.
- I won't.
Well. Well, when your book came,
with your name on it...
and my name printed inside,
something happened to me.
Oh, it wasn't jealousy.
I'm above jealousy, you know that.
But I just said to myself, "Here's Kit.
"Can sit and write a sad, almost sordid
analysis of two people's lives...
"and get marvelous write-ups,
and become a notable overnight.
"And here am I, little Millie Drake,
sitting at home...
"just bubbling over with a message
of quite another sort."
- Then you didn't like my book?
- Oh, I didn't say I didn't like it.
But I don't think
it's really what people want.
Well, as a matter of fact, Millie,
you're probably perfectly right...
because in spite of the reviews,
it's not selling.
- Oh, isn't it, really?
- No.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
But you see, that's what I mean.
Millie, what are you trying to tell me?
That you've written a book?
Well, why not?
Kit, you aren't the only one
who can write a book.
- Well, Millie, darling, I know...
- Wait.
Your eyes will be the first, other than
mine, to look down upon my first novel.
Why, Millie.
Oh, it's about a boy named Lionel,
and a girl, a wonderful girl.
I've called her Deirdre.
I think it's a beautiful name.
The kind of a girl I would have been
if I'd been born in vast spaces.
- Tall and willowy.
- Windblown, you mean?
In a way, yes.
Oh, Kit, will you read it, and if you like it,
take it to the publishers?
- Why, Millie, of course I'll read it.
- Honest?
Cross my heart.
It's good and long, isn't it?
Why, I could have gone on
for twice that length.
Only I have another one all dreamed out.
Oh, it's about a girl called Fern.
Look, Millie, you better stick
to one at a time.
Yes, of course.
Kit, if there's anything in beauty...
then the beauty-loving world
has got to know this book.
It simply laughs and cries with people.
- I hope people laugh and cry with it, Millie.
- They will.
Oh, I'm sure, they will.
I don't mean to seem egotistical
or overconfident...
but, you know, Kit, I've read a great deal...
and I really think I know
what appeals to most people.
- How'd you think it all up?
- It just came to me.
Kit, I really believe I was born to it.
Writing, I mean.
Once I start, the words just seem
to pour out without my knowing it.
It's like I was in a trance.
Millie, you're marvelous.
It took me two years
to write my one book...
and it's taken me 11 months
to even sketch out the second.
Well, it could be that I'm more prolific.
Could be.
Millie, after you've written
all these books...
what are you gonna do with the money?
Do you think they'll make money?
That kind of a book, if they click at all,
usually make a fortune.
- Kit, do you really think so?
- That tender-young-love stuff always does.
Oh, I know exactly what I'd do.
I'd buy the old Crimpton house,
over at the back of Ferndale.
It's such a lovely place.
No neighbors, all those grounds.
I'd have a secretary, two cars...
and when my baby comes,
I'd have an English nanny for it...
and later, a French governess,
that is if it's a girl.
You've got everything all planned out,
haven't you, Millie?
Oh, of course, it's only a dream,
but it's a lovely dream.
Success is thrilling, isn't it, Kit?
I guess so, Millie.
But it's funny how soon you get used to it.
I never should.
I'd always want more and more.
Don't you want to go on to bigger things?
Oh, I don't know about bigger things.
Other things, perhaps.
- Such as?
- I don't know.
- I'd like to write a play.
- A play?
Yes. An opening night must be thrilling.
All the people calling, "Author, author."
But you know, Kit,
I think I'll just stick to my books.
- What's so funny?
- Millie, you're so wonderful.
- Where are your pajama pants?
- Oh, I never use them.
- No?
- No.
- Oh.
- Oh, I'm dead.
Oh, Kit, it's like old times, isn't it?
Late at night, long talks.
All we need is Mama saying,
"Now, don't you two girls talk all night."
Yes, and knocking on the wall
to tell us to stop.
Yes.
Millie, remember,
whenever we were in the dumps...
your mother used to say...
"Don't worry, girls.
There's always what's left of the icing."
I remember.
- Good night, Kit.
- Good night, Millie.
Oh, Kit, won't it be marvelous?
Two friends, both writers
both such successes?
Oh, Millie.
Well, I'll leave you, then,
to Deirdre and Lionel.
- Hey!
- Oh!
Preston, will you please lock the door?
Remember, we have a guest.
I'm sorry.
- Hey!
- Oh, I am sorry.
Preston.
- Good night, darling.
- Good night, Millie.
Yes, what is it?
Come in.
- Where's Millie?
- I guess she went to her room.
Oh.
- Is everything all right?
- Oh, fine, thanks.
I put some ice water in there
this afternoon.
- I just had a drink, thanks.
- Good.
- Good night.
- Oh, thanks about this morning.
- Oh, that was nothing.
- Good night.
- It's fun having you here, Kit.
- Well, it's fun being here.
- Breakfast at 10:00.
- All right.
- Good night.
"Married in June,
by Mildred Watson Drake."
As a matter of fact...
I knew nothing of my wife's first book
until the day it was published.
Our little girl was born
in the middle of the night...
and the following morning,
on my breakfast table...
there was Millie's book
in a very gay cover.
Now, that's charming.
That's very charming.
And that was how long ago?
Well, Deirdre will be eight next month,
so it must be almost eight years ago.
The first child and the first book
came together.
That's right, and there were
seven more afterwards.
One a year?
Not bad.
Books, not children. Only one child.
The books keep Millie pretty busy,
you know?
I should think so.
And they've all been such great successes.
Yes, they've been
a dream come true for Millie.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
She has the house that she wanted,
servants. All the things that women like.
You must be very proud of her.
Yes, I suppose I am.
- Does she discuss her books with you?
- Me? Oh, no.
I'm afraid I wouldn't be much use to her.
Then you're completely detached
from Mrs. Drake's work.
No more than she is detached from mine.
Oh. Do you work, too?
Well, I'm a sort of
a combination architect and engineer.
Oh, now, that's very interesting.
Now, please, don't put anything
down there about me. Leave me out of it.
In fact, I think you ought to let her
tell you the story.
She'd do it beautifully.
- She really is an amazing woman.
- I'm sure she is.
She'll be back soon. Out shopping.
- We don't often come to New York.
- I see.
Well, then you must be here for the
opening of Miss Marlowe's play tonight.
- That's it.
- It's her first, isn't it?
Yes, and nothing would keep us away.
Kit's one of the family.
She's a darling, really.
You say that
as though you really meant it.
Quite frankly, I do.
Hello.
No, I'm afraid Miss Marlowe is not here.
Oh, you are leaving the theater. Yes, I see.
It'll be a pleasure.
Miss Broadbank. Butterfield, 8-4-6.
Certainly.
- Miss Broadbank?
- Yes, indeed.
- And who is she when she's at home?
- She's starring in Miss Marlowe's play.
We've certainly got to see her.
- Deedy, Deedy, you're too fast for me.
- Well, hello, hello!
- Give me a big kiss!
- Hello, Daddy.
- Hello, Preston.
- Hello, Kit.
You just missed Miss Broadbank.
Was she here?
No, but she nearly jumped through
that telephone. You better call her.
I will.
Oh, this is Miss Belle Carter,
The News Post.
- Oh, hello, Miss Carter.
- How do you do, Miss Marlowe?
- This is Miss Deirdre Drake.
- How do you do, Miss Drake?
How do you like
your daughter's new outfit?
Now, that is something. Well.
The very latest thing in winter fashions.
It's lovely, Kit,
but you shouldn't have done it.
- Why not? I enjoyed it.
- You know, this kind of thing...
has been going on between these two
ever since she was born.
Well, she's really partly mine, anyway.
I was at the hospital when she was born.
As a matter of fact,
she gave me her first smile.
Her mother said it was gas.
- That wasn't true, was it, Deedy?
- No.
Well, young lady,
where have you two been today?
- Oh, we went to the zoo and to the stores.
- We went everywhere, Pres.
Are you very excited
about the opening of your play tonight?
Well, I've been trying to forget it all day.
Every time I think about it,
I get butterflies in my stomach.
Come on, Deedy.
We'll see if Mademoiselle
has your supper ready.
- Excuse us, Miss Carter.
- I'm not hungry.
Now, you go and eat, and drink your milk.
That must be Mrs. Drake.
I'll tell her you're here, Miss Carter.
She'll be right out.
- Hello, Millie.
- Hello.
- Oh, what's the matter?
- Who's out there?
Oh, Kit, your daughter,
and a lady of the press, why?
I'm desperately tired.
You knew I would be.
Too much shopping?
I didn't get half the things done
I planned to do.
Just wait till you see Deedy,
and you'll forget all about being tired.
You haven't been calling the child
that silly name...
in front of a reporter, have you?
I wish you wouldn't.
Very good, madam.
But wait till you see her anyway.
Kit's bought her a new outfit.
They've just come in.
Why does she keep her out so late?
Upsets her whole routine.
They've had a marvelous time.
Been on a bender,
both of them completely cockeyed.
Preston, I'm in no mood
for your silly jokes.
Now, Millie, you're tired.
Let me fix you a nice, big drink.
- How many have you had?
- Fourteen or fifteen.
Oh, stop being funny.
Preston, you know I don't like you
to drink in the daytime.
- It's as good a time as any.
- Oh, Preston.
Millie, you better see that press lady.
I told her as much as I could.
- What did you tell her?
- Oh, how brilliant and capable you are...
and how we regard life
from our pinnacle of success.
But, Preston, I've asked you
a thousand times...
- to let me handle my own interviews.
- I had to be polite.
Well, next time,
please talk about something else.
Millie, I...
- Millie, you look like the Queen of Sheba.
- Oh, thanks.
But, I had my hair done this afternoon.
New girl, dreadful.
She just chatted at me all the time.
I thought she'd never stop talking.
Millie, Miss Carter asked me to tell you
she can't wait very much longer.
Yes, I know. I'm going.
Pres tell you I stole your daughter
this afternoon? We went shopping.
He told me. Time you had one of your own.
Oh, how do you do, Miss Carter?
Well, I'd better call that Broadbank wench.
- Where did she say she'd be?
- She was just leaving the theater.
She must be home then.
- Kit, will you tell me something?
- Yes, what?
I've been wanting to ask you for years.
- Why are you and Millie such friends?
- Oh, Pres, what a thing to ask.
I mean it. It can't just be
because you were girls together.
Well, that counts
for more than you'd think.
Hello? Miss Julia Broadbank.
Miss Marlowe calling.
Thank you.
Millie remembers the same things I do.
That's important.
For instance,
I think she's the only one I know...
who remembers
when I used to be called Chunky.
I shouldn't think
you'd want anyone to remember that.
I know, but one does.
It's funny, but one does.
What? Well...
All right, I'll wait.
Besides that, I owe Millie a great deal.
On my very first day at school...
she took me by the hand
and brought me home...
and said to her mother very solemnly...
"Mama, this is Katherine Marlowe
who's going to my very best friend."
What? No, she called me.
And then, when my aunt died,
her home was the only real home I had.
Her mother and father couldn't have been
nicer to me if I'd been their own daughter.
Millie's really all right, Pres.
Kit, you're just what I always thought
you were, a pretty nice person.
Oh, pooh.
I don't know what I'd have done
if you hadn't been around all these years.
Just to look at you...
I know, my...
My fatal beauty drives men mad.
I don't have to tell you, do I?
Miss Broadbank, I was told you called.
Well, I'm returning your call.
My dear Miss Broadbank,
that is not what I said at all.
I love you so much.
Pres, I've begged you not
to ever say that to me.
No. No, I did not go to the theater
this afternoon.
Because I'm sick and tired of arguing.
I don't care what you wear
in the second act.
What?
You can wear spangles if you want to.
Kit. Kit, Mommy wants me to go to bed!
Do I have to?
You should save your voice for tonight.
Goodbye.
Kit, can't I stay up until you leave?
I don't wanna go to bed yet.
- Aren't you sleepy, old lady?
- No.
I don't wanna go yet.
Deedy, you and I are in the doghouse.
Now, if you really want to help...
you'll go to bed quickly
and go right to sleep.
Because if you don't, your mother'll
never let us go out together again.
Do you hear?
- Good night, angel.
- Good night.
- Go on.
- Daddy, give me a piggyback.
- You're too fat.
- I am not.
Giddyup.
Kit, I meant every word I said.
Take me out again tomorrow, Kit?
- I'll try.
- Okay, good night.
- Giddyup.
- I'm galloping already.
You are not. Giddyup.
- Thank you so much, Mrs. Drake.
- I've enjoyed it.
Oh, Kit, I'm glad you've come in.
Miss Carter wanted
to say goodbye to you.
It's been an honor and a pleasure,
Miss Marlowe.
I wish I could do a story on you sometime.
She always says she hates publicity.
Well, some other time, perhaps.
It's been so nice.
Tell me, how is your new book
coming along?
Well, I write, and I rewrite,
and I still don't like it.
But at least, when you do turn one out,
it's a gem.
None of this
grinding them out like sausage...
- I suppose I could cut my throat.
- There's a knife on the table.
Miss Carter, I'm sure you'll excuse us.
We have a million things to do.
- Good luck for tonight, Miss Marlowe.
- Thank you. Bye.
Thank heavens I don't have to write
for literary snobs like that one.
What difference does it make
what she said?
At least, I don't labor over my writing,
and I'm proud of it.
If I have more facility than others,
that's my good luck.
And you can take comfort
in the knowledge...
that your books sell and mine don't.
Well, I deliberately write
for the great, broad public.
- Of course, and I wish I knew the secret.
- I wish you did, too.
I'd be much happier if you were
more successful financially, Kit.
Well, I'm willing. What do you suggest?
Well, there are a lot of things.
For instance...
is it laziness or affectation that you
don't like to see your name in print?
Why, there are posters all over the place
about your play...
and your name isn't any size.
It's all Julia Broadbank.
Her name will bring in
more people than mine.
But you're the author, you wrote the play.
Why should you be
pushed off the mat by actors?
Well, to tell you the truth, Millie,
I'm not so sure the play's any good.
Oh, you make me furious.
Now, supposing I started one of my books
with the attitude I wasn't sure about it.
- Where would I be?
- Where I am, probably.
But you must remember, Millie...
you've never not been sure
about anything.
- You mean I'm too sure?
- I didn't say that.
But you must admit,
you're a very certain little woman.
Perhaps, I am. But I certainly
couldn't see myself at our age...
waving in the breeze
like a piece of limp rag.
You don't seem to know, or care...
what's gonna happen to you
from one minute to the next.
Now, when I make up my mind
I want something, I work until I get it.
Then I hold onto it
like a bulldog with his teeth.
There are some things
you will hold on to too tightly, Millie.
Especially people.
Oh, people are a nuisance.
The only people I need are in my books.
Outside of Preston and my baby,
no one means anything.
Me, too?
You go without saying,
but you do make me mad.
Oh, Kit, hasn't there ever been anything
in your life that you've really wanted?
Well, coming right at this moment,
that's a hard question to answer.
But you keep holding on, darling,
and I'll keep wondering whether I should.
And I may wave around
like that limp rag...
but there is a certain ecstasy
in wanting things you know you can't get.
Well, you might be
a very lonely old lady one day.
Something I'll never be. I took care of that.
When you married Preston
and had Deirdre...
and that put money in the bank.
What better insurance could I have?
Millie...
- now, I want to ask you something.
- Go ahead.
Why aren't you more considerate of Pres?
- What do you mean?
- Just that.
What are you talking about?
Certainly, you can see
how miserable he is.
Miserable!
Why, haven't I been a good wife to him?
I've given him everything.
A house, grounds, servants.
Why, I make him a definite department
in my life, as I do my child.
How can you say he's miserable?
Millie, do you know anything at all
about men?
Do you?
Well, I know there are a lot of little things
that a man expects from a woman...
that I think you, in your success,
have forgotten all about.
What little things?
Oh, little things, like humor
and charm and tenderness.
Oh, should I be charming,
humorous and tender...
when a man consumes nearly
a bottle of whisky in an afternoon?
- People drink for escape, Millie.
- But escape from what?
Well, our offspring is in the hay.
Drinking again, my love?
No, but I'll pour one for you if you want it.
- Do you really think I should?
- Why not? We only live once.
Say when.
- Hey, when.
- There you are.
- And some ice?
- Thanks.
There. Oh, Preston,
I bought you two dinner-jacket ties.
They're the new kind from Paris,
with the single end.
Oh, that's very nice of you, Millie.
Hey, what's going on with you two?
What's the joke?
Oh, our Kit's in a very
rambunctious mood today.
I think I must write a play sometime,
and see if I can feel rambunctious.
I'm sure you will, Millie.
I really must go.
Oh, no, I've something for you, too.
Something for my very best friend...
to commemorate
the first night of her first play.
I'll only be a moment.
They're on the little table in here
by the chaise longue.
I separated them from the other things.
The sun seems to be shining.
Yes.
I wonder what caused it.
Well, now, here they are.
- This is for my husband.
- Thank you, Millie.
And this is for my best friend.
This is just a little thing
I picked up for myself.
I think when you open it, darling,
you'll find it's quite charming.
Thank you, Millie.
Millie, you can't give me things like this.
Well, why not? I think it's very beautiful.
It's almost too beautiful to wear.
It must have cost a fortune.
Well, I'm a very successful woman
and very rich.
- Do you really like it, darling?
- I don't know what to say.
Here. Put it on your coat.
Oh, it looks very smart. There.
- What did you get for yourself?
- Just these.
And very nice, too.
- Do you like them, Preston?
- They're very handsome.
I wish I could afford
to have given them to you.
They're lovely, Millie.
- Do you resent my having them?
- Of course not, Millie.
I don't resent your having anything.
I said they were very handsome.
What's the matter, Millie?
We both said they were very nice...
and you suddenly look like a volcano
that's about to erupt.
- You can't make a joke of it.
- Make a joke of what?
You wish you could've afforded
to buy them for me.
- If that isn't a sneer...
- It was not a sneer.
Millie.
Millie, let me put them on you.
- Be good.
- Oh.
Anyone would think I was...
I'll do without them!
I'll do without everything!
I'll give up writing!
We'll go back and pig it on Cameo Street,
the way we used to.
- Is that what you want?
- Millie, will you stop this, please?
No, Millie, we'd better stay just as we are.
You can buy me a nice uniform...
and on the cap and collar
you can put M-W-D...
the property of Mildred Watson Drake,
in diamonds.
Pres.
Here.
I'm really partly to blame.
I had just given Millie
a sort of bawling out before you came in.
Go in there and apologize.
And no more of that uniform business.
It wasn't kind.
I'll leave your tickets at the box office.
See you later.
Kit's gone.
I'm sorry, Millie. Here are the clips.
You can throw them in the wastebasket.
You didn't pay for them.
All right then.
What do you think you're doing?
"'The time has come,' the Walrus said,
'to talk of many things:
"'Of socks and shirts and dressing gowns,
and whether pigs have wings."'
You're drunk.
Oh, no, Millie, I'm not,
but I am very happy.
Is this your nail file, or mine?
I never knew.
Preston, will you stop playing the fool,
and get dressed for tonight?
I am dressed for my night.
But you have to wear your dinner jacket.
I won't need my dinner jacket.
Oh, we went into all that
before we left home.
I had the new silk facings put on.
New silk facings! Thoughtful little Millie.
Preston, I don't know what this
is all about, but it's no time to go into it.
We've got to get dressed,
and go and see Kit's play.
I am sorry about one thing,
I hate leaving that baby.
- What did you say?
- I said, I hated leaving my daughter.
Preston. Preston, you're mad.
I was mad not to have done this years ago.
You don't need a husband.
What you need is... Oh, why go into it?
Just where are you going?
As far away as I can get
from you, my dear.
You don't know what you're talking about.
- Oh, yes, I do.
- You've been drinking all that whisky.
- It's not the whisky.
- You can't do this to me.
- You can't just walk...
- Stop it, Millie! No more scenes.
I never was much good at them.
As you would say in one of your books...
"And so ended this chapter in their life."
- Good luck, my dear.
- Preston.
Preston!
- Preston!
- Down.
Preston!
- Good evening.
- Good evening. Mr. Preston Drake, please.
- Are you Miss Marlowe?
- Yes.
Oh, yes, he's been trying to reach you.
He was around here a minute ago.
- I think you'll find him in the lounge.
- Oh, thank you.
Pres.
- Hello, Kit.
- Hello.
- Don't bother.
- How'd the play go? I bet it was great.
- It was all right, I guess.
- Good.
Pres, I've just seen Millie.
She's very upset.
- She'll get over it.
- What do you mean, "She'll get over it"?
Pres, you're hardly a child.
How a grown man
can be hiding away here...
just for the fun of torturing his wife,
is beyond me.
- I'm sorry, Kit, but it's over.
- Don't be ridiculous.
You can save your breath, Kit. I'm through.
Have you got a cigarette?
Thank you.
Pres, this is very serious.
Kit, I couldn't stand it any longer.
It's been building up for a long time.
And today, something clicked
and said, "Now." And now it was.
Well, something chose
a peach of a time to say it...
on my opening night.
I'm sorry if you were bothered.
I didn't mean to involve you.
But Harriet said you called three times.
What I had to say to you
was not about Millie.
Pres, you simply must not do this.
It's nothing that can't be straightened out.
You two wouldn't
have lived together happily...
It wasn't happy.
Well, you two wouldn't
have lived together, then, for nine years...
if there hadn't been strong ties
between you.
Kit, when I married Millie, she was
a sweet, pretty little girl. It was fun.
But, Pres...
But our marriage has been headed for the
rocks ever since Millie started to write.
I don't have to tell you.
When Deedy was so sick that time
it was you who took care of her.
Millie was in Mexico.
I get a chance of a big contract
in Philadelphia...
I can't leave, Millie's in California.
But, Pres, whatever may have happened
to Millie is only superficial.
If you just look at Millie's activities
as a confession of weakness...
an admission that there's something
essentially lacking in her nature...
you'd find it a little touching,
and love her for it.
- You sound like one of Millie's books.
- Do I?
That's rather a joke on me, isn't it?
That seems to be that, then.
It's not so serious. It happens every day.
Kit, there's something I've got to ask you.
It has nothing to do
with my leaving Millie.
Miss Marlowe,
you're wanted on the phone.
Oh, thank you.
You can take it in here.
Thank you.
- Hiya, bub.
- Hello.
- Great weather we're having.
- Yeah.
You the guy?
- What guy?
- The guy that wanted Scotch.
- You've got Scotch?
- No, I got gin.
- How much?
- $10.
Okay.
Hey, bub.
You don't have to worry about that stuff.
I make it myself. Here's my card.
That was my apartment.
I'm having a party.
It was my opening night, remember?
I'm a hostess.
Kit, I told you I wanted
to ask you something.
I know you did,
but this is no time to talk about us.
Pres, you know that. Now I really must go.
It means such a lot to me.
Kit, you must listen.
Please, sit down. Just for a minute.
Kit, you mean everything to me.
The thought of you,
the mention of your name.
Kit, I am really in love with you,
deeply in love with you.
Look me straight me in the eyes
and tell me you don't feel as I do.
I'm never going back to Millie.
So, don't let that make any difference
in what you say, but tell me.
Tell me the truth.
Pres, I haven't let myself
even think about it.
Why not?
Because there are things you just don't do.
There are things...
that a woman just can't do
and this is one of them.
Kit, this is our chance for a happy life.
That might be, Pres,
if things were different.
It's the only chance.
There's no such thing as an only chance.
Life goes on.
Pres, Millie would always be between us...
spoiling any chance of happiness
that we might find.
There are things that you just don't do...
if you want to live decently
with yourself afterwards.
Do you mean to stand there and tell me
that your friendship for Millie...
would mean more to you
than your love for me?
Pres, I know it's hard
for a man to understand.
All I know is that it's something
I just couldn't do...
whether it was Millie, or any other woman
who is a friend of mine.
I guess it wasn't meant to be, Pres.
That was Millie on the phone.
She's on her way here now.
I told her to come.
Pres, talk to her, give her a chance.
Don't just throw away nine years
without at least talking to her.
Kit, you know I'd do anything for you.
Anything but that.
Oh, Pres, don't be stubborn.
Please, for my sake, see her.
I'm sorry, Kit,
but that's one thing I won't do.
Well, I guess that's goodbye then.
I guess it is.
May I kiss you goodbye?
No, Pres.
Goodbye, Kit.
Pres...
come here.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Kit.
Will you keep an eye on Deirdre for me?
I'd kind of like her to grow up like you.
Of course.
If anyone asks for me, anyone at all,
I don't want to be disturbed. Understand?
Very good, Mr. Drake.
Hello, Millie.
- Where is he, Kit?
- He's gone to his room. He won't see you.
He won't see me? But why not?
Let's not talk about it here. Let's go home.
Wait.
- I want to see Mr. Preston Drake, please.
- Mr. Drake does not wish to be disturbed.
Well, then let me speak to him
on the telephone.
But I've just told you,
he doesn't wish to be disturbed.
But he's my husband.
I'm Mrs. Drake. Don't you understand?
Lady, I don't care if you're Admiral Drake,
those are my orders.
Where's the manager?
I want to speak to the manager!
I am the night manager.
Millie, come in here a minute.
There's nothing you can do about it.
But how can he do this to me?
We were always so happy together.
Nine years of bliss...
and now he's in that room up there
and he won't even see me.
Millie, be quiet.
Oh, he's ruined my life,
that's what he's done.
I've nothing left to live for. Nothing.
I should have thrown myself
out the window like I planned.
Millie, don't talk nonsense.
Oh, how can I face people?
How can I tell them that he's left me?
Everybody envied me so.
They thought I had everything, and I did.
A husband and a home,
and a baby and a career.
Well, Millie you still have your home
and your baby and your career.
- No, I'll never write another line!
- Don't say such silly things, Millie.
In a few months,
you'll be in the middle of a new book...
and will have forgotten all about this.
Oh, they say you can lose yourself
in your work. I wish I could believe that.
- Do you think it's true, Kit?
- That's what they say, Millie.
Perhaps, I can.
Perhaps, it'll even be good for my work.
Oh, I'm going to try.
I'm going to make
a whole new life for myself.
Oh, I know I can, with you to help me.
- You will help me, won't you, Kit?
- Of course, Millie.
It'll be like old times.
Making plans,
and talking things over for the future.
Oh, Kit, we'll always be friends, won't we?
Nothing will ever happen to us, will it?
Nothing will ever come between us?
Millie, we'll probably end up two deaf,
old ladies sharing the same ear trumpet.
Oh, Kit.
I don't know what I'd do
without you to turn to.
Cheer up, Millie. Cheer up.
There's always what's left of the icing.
Mr. Chairman,
members of the Red Cross...
ladies and gentleman
of the radio audience.
Our country and its allies
are engaged in a fierce and terrible war.
It is doubtful whether we shall realize
how vast and terrible it is...
until long after it is over.
Nevertheless, we have dedicated our lives
and our resources...
to the complete and final destruction
of the enemy.
We know, too, that in God's good time,
we shall win.
In the same way, I think,
we should be proud of the Red Cross.
For more than 75 years...
it has been a beacon of mercy
a symbol of humanity.
It assists in your local neighborhood...
safeguarding the lives and health
of the civilian population.
It operates with the army in the fields,
and goes to distant outposts.
It accompanies the navy
to outlying naval stations.
It is with the men in hospitals,
wherever general hospitals are located.
And through its staff
and military stations...
it provides
the important link of communication...
between the service man...
- Excuse me, I'll be right back.
- Surely.
... and his family back home.
And the only creed it knows,
is the creed of humanity.
It is always there
wherever people need help.
And the reason this can be done...
is a matter of simple trust,
an act of simple faith.
Faith in you and in me.
Faith that we will supply them
with the funds necessary...
for carrying on their great work.
And now the need for money
is greater than ever before.
I think we cannot do less
than justify this faith and confidence.
What else, indeed, are we fighting for?
Thank you.
Thank you, Miss Marlowe.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we urge you to send contributions...
to your local chapter
of the American Red Cross.
Thank you and good night.
Excellent, Miss Marlowe,
and thank you again.
Not at all. I'm only too glad
to have been able to help.
- Wonderful, Miss Marlowe.
- Very kind of you, Admiral.
Congratulations, Miss Marlowe.
You were splendid.
- Splendid talk, Miss Marlowe.
- Thank you, Commander.
Kit, I know you never like to hear it,
but you were wonderful.
Oh, pooh.
- Tell me, have you seen Deirdre?
- No, I haven't.
- She's very naughty.
- Miss Marlowe.
- Yes.
- There's a call for you.
- You may take it in the control room.
- Do you know who it is?
- No. I'm sorry.
- Oh. Excuse me, darling.
Hello? Kit?
Yes, this is Kit. Who is this?
- Preston.
- Who?
Preston. Preston Drake.
Preston Drake.
Well, I don't believe it.
I just heard your broadcast,
and couldn't resist calling you.
Kit, you were great.
Well, thank you.
Where on earth did you spring from?
I'm stationed in Washington these days,
in the Army.
Really? How wonderful.
Say, Kit, what's the chance of seeing you?
Let's meet later on for a drink.
Well, I'd love it, Preston.
- Would you mind if I brought a beau along?
- Of course not.
I'll tell you what, let's all meet
at the Garden Center in an hour.
Well, make it an hour and a half, will you?
I've got to get out of my uniform.
An hour and a half?
All right, 10:30 at the Garden Center.
All right. Goodbye.
That was Preston Drake, Rudd.
Deirdre's father.
He asked us to join him
for a drink at the Garden Center...
and I said we would.
- Do you mind?
- Do we have to?
Look, Kit, we haven't had an evening alone
since I can remember.
I know, darling,
but there wasn't much I could do.
He's a very old friend,
and I haven't seen him for years.
- All right.
- Tell you what you do.
You drop me off at my apartment,
and I'll change...
and then you go on and pick up Deirdre.
She's probably at the Swing Club.
That's where Lucien plays.
Look, I'm getting tired
of playing nursemaid to Deirdre.
Just this once. I want to surprise Preston.
And if she refuses to come with you,
tell her I want to see her.
- Good evening, madame.
- Oh, good evening.
I'm looking for a Mr. Drake.
- You mean Major Drake?
- Oh, that's right.
- Right this way, please.
- Thank you.
- Kit.
- Preston.
- Preston, it's not true.
- Well, well.
- You're looking wonderful.
- Thank you. So do you.
Oh, I like that gray streak.
It's very attractive.
Oh, it's a frightful giveaway.
Where's your beau?
Oh, he was delayed.
He should be along in a minute.
- Thank you.
- Fine.
- It's good to see you, Kit.
- It's good to see you.
What'll you have to drink?
Well, I think I'll have
a champagne cocktail.
- They don't put you to sleep anymore?
- Oh, what a memory.
Waiter.
- How long have you been in the service?
- A couple of years.
- A champagne cocktail.
- Yes, sir.
We kept up with you for a while
and then we lost track of you.
Where on earth have you been?
Oh, I drifted around Mexico
and South America, in various jobs.
Oh, did you?
Tell me about Deedy.
How's she turned out?
Well, I... I think you'll be proud of her.
And Millie?
I suppose you two are still friends?
- Oh, of course.
- How's she wearing?
Well, Millie was guaranteed for 80 years
when she was delivered.
She eats, sleeps, and writes,
all three very heartily.
She has a home in Pelham...
but this winter
has taken an apartment in New York.
As a matter of fact,
your old rooms at the Chelton.
Why don't you call her up, Preston?
I know she'd love to hear from you.
- All right, I will.
- Good.
But tell me more about you.
Well, Kit, the last time I saw you,
you told me that life goes on. Remember?
Yes, I do.
And I said, it was our only chance
for happiness.
Yes.
And you said it wasn't true.
- Well, you were right. I've found someone.
- I'm so happy for you, Preston.
Thanks, Kit. I knew you would be.
Kit, I am curious about this beau of yours.
Is he something important in your life?
Yes, he is.
- But there's a catch in it.
- Oh?
A matter of years. Ten years, to be exact.
- Older?
- No, younger.
You might know there'd be something.
Leave it to me.
All right, come on.
Listen, if this is a trick or a lie,
I'll never forgive you.
Look, I've got more to do than
play tricks on you. I'm doing this for Kit.
- But what does she want me for?
- I told you you'd find out.
I don't believe you.
Drive me back to the Swing Club.
- Doll, come here, will you? Stop being...
- Let go of my hand. You hurt me.
Oh, you're a tender little morsel,
aren't you? Now, come on.
- Well, you don't have to push me around.
- Oh, shut up.
Why don't you relax for a change?
You're gonna run yourself to a frazzle...
then wonder later on
why you're old before your time.
And to hear you, anyone would think
you were pleased about it.
Look, I've told you a dozen times,
you don't mean a thing in my life.
I'm doing this for Kit.
I don't know why
she should be so concerned about me.
Neither do I, but she is.
Look, why don't you get
some sense in your head?
Don't you know
Lucien Grant's no good for you?
And what's more Kit doesn't like him,
and you ought to respect her judgment.
- Who says I don't?
- I do.
- Good evening, sir.
- Oh, hello.
We're joining Miss Marlowe and a friend.
- Oh, yes. Right this way, please.
- Now behave yourself.
- Hello, Kit.
- Oh, here you are.
- Hello, Deedy.
Deedy?
Deedy, may I introduce you to your father?
My father?
Well, I...
Darling, you might at least give him a kiss.
After all, he was the first love of your life.
Deedy, come here.
Preston, this is Rudd Kendall.
Mr. Kendall, Major Drake.
- How do you do?
Darling, let's you and I have a dance.
And let them say
all the sentimental things to each other...
they've stored up for years.
Thank you, Kit. Deedy, sit down.
- Well, Deedy, 10 years is a long time.
- Yes, it is.
Believe it or not, I used to take you
on my knee, put you to bed...
kiss you good night,
even give you your piggyback rides.
I'll give you two pennies for your thoughts.
- Not enough. Cost you a quarter.
- All right, I feel like splurging.
Come on, Kit, tell me.
What are you thinking?
- Oh, lots of things.
- About us, maybe?
- To tell you the truth, no.
- Oh.
I was sort of hoping that maybe
you were thinking about my proposal.
- What proposal?
Remember, I'm the guy
that wants to marry you?
- Oh, yes, of course. I'd forgotten.
- You'd forgotten, huh?
- You know, you're very encouraging.
- And you're very charming.
This afternoon I was sweet,
tonight I'm charming...
and they both mean no, huh?
You said that every woman
has a ghost in her life.
Is the Major your ghost?
That, my dear, will cost you
more than a quarter.
Good morning.
Good morning, Harriet.
It's 10:00. I thought maybe
you'd want to get up.
- I suppose maybe I should.
- How do you feel this morning?
I feel very lonely and very old
this morning, Harriet.
- Do you ever feel that way?
- Not lonely, but kind of old sometimes.
Your picture's in the paper.
- Is it a good one?
- I don't like it.
You're much better looking than that.
Oh, thank you, Harriet.
I heard your speech last night, too.
It was just fine.
You're such a little thing,
nobody'd think, to look at you...
you had that much brains.
I hope someday
to be able to figure you out, Harriet.
What for?
There are times when you show signs
of genuine sentiment.
- Is Miss Drake up yet?
- Not yet.
But Mrs. Drake called up to say
she'd be a few minutes late for breakfast.
That means she'll be twice as hungry.
What have we for breakfast?
Well, I managed to pick up
a little piece of liver.
You can give that to Mrs. Drake.
Well, you could do
with a few vitamins yourself.
I loathe vitamins, except eggs.
One, lightly boiled, would be heavenly.
- By the way, how is the egg situation?
- I could only get pullet eggs.
Well, I suppose
we should be grateful for that.
When Miss Drake wakes up,
tell her to come up if she wants to.
Are we running a hotel
for the Drake family?
Well, it would seem that way,
wouldn't it, Harriet?
If there was no system,
there'd be no point having any.
- Well!
- Good morning, Harriet.
Oh, good morning.
- Where is she?
- She's upstairs.
- Is she awake?
- Having her coffee.
- Good.
- Well, what's all the rush about?
Tell you later. Oh.
Better knock on the door.
Come in.
- Good morning, darling.
- Rudd. So early.
Yeah, I just had to see you.
Take a look, darling.
It's my commission,
just arrived from Washington.
See, I leave in five days.
- What about some coffee?
- No, thanks.
Kit, marry me, will you? This morning.
- Rudd, this is so sudden.
- Well, these are sudden times.
- Well, I know that, but...
- Will you, please?
- Rudd, I...
- I can't take you out to sea...
and keep asking you every day,
I couldn't keep my mind on my work.
Rudd. Let me get my breath.
All you've got to do is make up your mind.
- Well...
- Now, don't start analyzing again.
Rudd, I'm not any younger
than I was yesterday when you asked me.
Oh, Kit, please, let's not go into that again.
But that is the important part of it.
I've thought a lot about this
since yesterday.
Rudd, come here, sit down.
You should marry some young girl.
Someone with whom
you can have children.
Someone with whom you can settle down.
I'm not gonna marry some sappy girl,
and raise a bunch of sappy kids.
- That isn't what I want, Kit. I want you.
- Rudd.
Rudd, listen to me calmly
for just a minute.
You're leaving in five days,
and heaven knows when you'll be back.
But when this war is over...
let's hope there'll be a wonderful world
waiting for young men like you...
to take hold of, and make happy lives
for yourselves and everyone else.
And that does not make sense
with a woman 10 years older than you are.
Perhaps it wouldn't make
so much difference now...
but think of 10 years from now.
Kit, no matter what you say,
I know what I want.
I want to marry you.
Rudd, you make it so difficult for me.
No, Kit. You make it difficult for yourself.
Hello.
Yes.
Oh, put him on.
It's Mr. Mallory.
Good morning, Mr. Mallory.
I meant to call you. I'm sorry.
Kit, ask him to call back later.
Mr. Mallory, would you hold on
for just a minute, please?
Rudd, give me a few days
to think this over by myself...
without your distracting presence.
- So, I'm distracting, huh?
- Very, I find.
At least that's something.
Yes, Mr. Mallory.
Well, I'll try to get it to you
by the end of the week.
Yes, I think I can.
Mr. Mallory, would you hold on
for just one more moment, please?
Rudd, don't act like this.
I'm only thinking of you.
Darling, call me in few days.
I promise to give you my answer
before you go.
All right, Kit, if that's the way you want it.
Oh. Oh, Mr. Mallory,
I'm so sorry to have kept you waiting.
Good morning.
Hello.
Well, you look like I feel.
- Anything wrong?
- No, no.
I suppose I ought to apologize
about last night.
If you had told me
I was going to meet my father...
I wouldn't have caused you
so much trouble.
Oh, it's all right. Forget it.
- Where are you going?
- Oh, no place in particular.
I'm going for a walk.
Harriet says, a nice long walk
is good for a mood.
- Yeah?
- Would you like to come along?
- Might be good for you, too.
- Sure, why not?
Good. Harriet.
Yes.
I'm going now.
Tell Mother I'll see her
at the apartment later.
- All right.
- Thanks.
Goodbye.
Bye.
- Harriet, is Miss Drake up yet?
- Yes.
She went out for a walk.
Mr. Kendall went with her.
Oh.
Good.
Harriet, our nice Mr. Kendall
is leaving us in a few days.
- He's going into the Navy.
- Well, that's fine.
Now you'll get some rest
and you certainly need it.
Should I marry him?
- Harriet.
- Yes, ma'am.
Should I marry him?
Did he ask you?
Well, I certainly didn't ask him.
Well, if he asked me, I certainly would.
- Oh, you would?
- Yes, I would.
- These are all rumbas.
- Oh, thank you.
- I think I'll take these and these I have.
- Very good.
A rumba or two
might liven up the apartment.
It might be good for Mother
to learn to rumba.
I need a fresh needle.
You know, there's a war on.
Uncle Sam needs needles.
- You do think of things, don't you?
- Oh, sure I do.
I'm terrific. Haven't you heard?
I really think you think you are.
- Come on, let's dance.
- No, no. No, I had too much lunch.
- It's good for the lunch. Please come on.
- No.
- Rudd.
- But I don't feel like dancing.
Look.
Where you grabbed me last night.
- Well, you had it coming to you.
- I did not!
Hey, take it easy, will you?
You're giving me the jitters.
Can't you sit down
and listen to the music?
- No, I like to dance.
- Oh, sit down, will you?
Every time I feel like laughing...
or behaving like
any normal human being...
someone comes along and says...
"Don't feel like that,"
or, "Sit down," or, "Be quiet."
Hey, you are in a bad way.
Here.
What's the matter with you, anyway?
Oh, don't mind me. I'm just all mixed up.
- Yeah, you are a little nuts.
- Thanks.
- But you got a very odd sort of attraction.
- Really?
What you'll grow up into, I don't know.
I don't think I'll grow up into anything.
You know the old proverbial ship
without a rudder?
Well, I think I was born without a rudder.
You mean, you're at the disposal
of the weather?
Yeah, that's it. Sums me up completely.
Well, I'm sorry if I was rude just now.
I was a little sore about something.
- I shouldn't have taken it out on you.
- It doesn't matter.
Oh, I wish I were 30.
Then I wouldn't have any problems.
That's what you think.
Well, at least you know
what you want, by then.
No, I'm not so sure.
You don't mean to say it's going to go on
being as bad as this always?
- Well, I don't know how bad this is.
- It's bad enough.
Hey, look, you're not thinking
of doing anything drastic, are you?
- Supposing I am?
- Well, don't.
You're not in love with Lucien Grant.
- How do you know?
- Well, you're not, are you?
- Well...
- Come on, come on, tell me the truth.
No. It doesn't feel the way
I thought being in love would feel like.
Then you wait until it does feel like that.
Why are you telling me this?
Well, I don't want to see you get hurt.
You know, it's funny,
but quite suddenly I can talk to you.
Last night you were so angry,
but now you've changed.
Maybe you had something to do with that.
Thank you.
- Why is it that...
- Why is what?
Oh, I don't know.
Just now, you said I was nuts.
Well, there are certain things you can't be
immediately articulate about.
What are you trying to say?
Well, quite suddenly
I seem to be able to talk to you.
You've changed.
Well, maybe you had something
to do with that.
You're very charming, Deirdre.
Are you contemplating
making love to me?
Is there any reason why I shouldn't?
No.
Hello. Hello.
Oh, hello. This is Mrs. Drake.
I'm expecting Mr. Drake in a few minutes.
As soon as he arrives,
will you send him right up?
Thank you so much.
Come in!
Hello, Millie.
Oh, it's you.
Who did you think I was going to be?
Well, to tell you the truth,
I'm expecting someone.
- Oh, then perhaps I'm intruding.
- Oh, no, not at all.
- Millie, your apartment looks very nice.
- Thanks.
You might be interested to know
who I'm expecting.
- Yes, who?
- Preston.
- That explains the music, then.
- Yes.
He telephoned this morning
and he said he wanted to talk to me.
- And he was extremely pleasant.
- That's wonderful.
Kit, why should he suddenly want
to see me, after all these years?
Well, I don't know.
I should think perhaps
he wants to talk to you about Deirdre.
I think it's something else.
Kit, do you think I should take him back?
What?
I said, do you think
I should take him back?
But, Millie, surely Preston has told you
that he's engaged?
Oh, yes, but that doesn't mean anything.
He's probably lonely, just like I am.
Well, Millie, far be it from me
to disappoint you...
but I believe
he's very much in love with this girl.
But what have they in common?
After all, we were together for so long.
It's a great satisfaction to know
that in the end...
a man does turn back to his wife.
Well, Millie...
I wouldn't count on it, if I were you.
Oh, you couldn't understand.
I know Preston. I was married to him.
Just the sound of his voice today.
Kit, I want something more out of life...
than just books
and a discontented daughter.
We aren't getting any younger, you know.
Yes, Millie, I'm quite aware of that.
Millie, what would you say if I told you
I thought I might be going to get married?
Who to? Not that young Kendall?
Yes. Do you think I'd be crazy?
I should have thought
you could have done better for yourself.
- That's not the point.
- Well, what is, then?
The point is, I'm in love with him.
I didn't see him all day yesterday,
or the day before, and I...
I find I miss him. Miss him terribly.
Well, it's all very romantic.
But what would he be like as a husband?
He'd be devoted and enchanting...
while it lasted.
But you think he's too young for me,
don't you?
And you think I'd really be crazy
to marry him.
Yes, I think I do, really.
So do I. But I'm going to, all the same.
Goodness, I didn't realize
how late it was getting.
I have an appointment with Mallory
to pick up my galleys.
- Bye, darling.
- Goodbye.
Look, stop in on your way back.
I may have
some very interesting news for you.
I will if I can.
I'll see if I can get an extra set
of my galleys and leave them by for you.
Good.
- Millie, you look very pretty today.
- Same to you, dear.
Oh, isn't it marvelous
what it does for one?
- Goodbye, darling.
- Bye.
- Hello, Deedy.
- Hello, Kit.
- Is Mother in?
- Yes.
What's more, she's expecting someone.
- Who?
- Well, as a matter of fact, it's your father.
- You don't tell me.
- Yes. Hear the Brahms?
Deedy, you're looking very gay today.
Thanks, darling, I feel gay. So do you.
Thank you. Goodbye, darling.
- Bye. See you later.
- Yes.
Oh.
- Hello, Mother.
- Hello.
- I hear we're going to have a visitor.
- Yes.
And when I'm worried about you...
when I want to know where you are
you're strangely absent.
Now, this is one time I could do
without you and here you are.
All right, I'll go. I can take a hint.
- I like your hat.
- Thanks.
Give my love to Father.
By the way, how did you ever let anyone
as nice as that get away from you?
Coming!
- Hello. Come on in.
- Hello, Millie.
My, how handsome we look
in our new uniform.
Thanks.
- Here, let me take your things.
- Thank you.
Well, it's been a long time, hasn't it?
Yes, it has.
- Oh, won't you sit down?
- Thanks.
- Same old rooms.
- Yes, the same old rooms.
- Looks nice.
- I'm glad you like it.
- Can I make you a drink?
- I'd love one.
Good.
- Any Scotch?
- Of course, silly.
Your special brand.
That's fine.
- Where's Deedy?
- Oh, she isn't here.
I can see that. Will she be in?
Well, she may come in later.
- There. Here you are.
- Thanks.
You're looking well, Millie.
- Do you think so?
- Very well.
Oh, it's just vitamins.
- Here, will you have a cigarette?
- No, thanks.
All right.
- Here's looking at you.
- Thank you.
Well, Millie, I suppose you're wondering
why I've come to see you.
I think I can guess.
- Yes?
- Yes.
You see, I know a great deal
about men, Preston.
Especially when they're behaving
according to their finer instincts.
Oh. Yes. Yes, of course.
Millie, now that I'm getting married,
I'll have a home...
and I thought perhaps you might
be willing to share Deedy with me.
I know that Laurel's a bit young to be
a stepmother, in the ordinary sense...
but I see no reason why she and Deedy
shouldn't be very good friends.
Oh, no, of course not.
- That's what you wanted to see me about?
- That's right.
Why, yes, of course.
Well, Preston...
how long have you known this young girl?
A year or two. Why do you ask that?
Well, naturally, I'm concerned about you.
After all, we were together for so long
and we had a child and...
Well, you just disappeared into the blue.
- Not a word.
- I know.
- People have feelings, Preston.
- That's true.
But I thought it best
to make a clean break.
I'm rather one of the old,
sentimental sort...
and I knew if I saw Deedy again,
it might upset the apple cart.
So I decided
to put her clean out of my mind.
All of you. Kit, too.
Kit?
Yes, Kit.
Why... Well, what had Kit to do with it?
Well, I really don't see
why I shouldn't tell you about it now.
Millie, I was in love with Kit.
- In love with her?
- Yes.
When was that?
Oh, it began a year or two
before we separated.
Did you ever tell her that you loved her?
I did. Many times.
- And while you were married to me?
- Yes.
Oh, the snake in the grass!
And all the time pretending
she was my best friend.
But she was. She still is.
She's been a better friend to you
than you've ever realized.
I'd be married to Kit now
if it hadn't been for you.
I was desperately in love with her
and I think she felt the same toward me.
- Did she tell you so?
- Yes.
She'd have married me
but you were the reason she didn't.
Her best friend. She said
that's something you just don't do.
I don't believe it.
I don't believe a word of it.
- You're just making this up.
- I'm not.
Oh, Millie, you can't mind about this now.
- What happened between you?
- Nothing.
Oh, don't let's go into it.
It's over and done with.
We certainly will go into it.
I want to know what happened.
Nothing at all. She kissed me goodbye
and sent me away.
- Oh, she sent you away.
- Yes, she did!
- You're just trying to protect her!
- Millie.
Preston, I'd like you to go, please.
I'm very glad to know
what you've just told me...
but I'd like you to go.
I must say, Millie,
you're as unpredictable as ever.
I'm terribly sorry this has happened.
I really didn't mean to upset you.
Goodbye.
Mother, what's happened?
You do let yourself go.
You asked me a while ago...
how I happened to let anything
like your father get away from me.
Well, I'll tell you.
He was taken away from me. Filched.
- Filched?
- Oh, well, stolen, then.
And who by, do you think?
By the woman I thought
was my best friend, your sainted Kit.
Mother, have you gone quite mad?
All these years I've asked myself
what I'd done to drive him away from me.
I've searched my conduct.
And all the while
the truth was lurking in the shadows.
It was that Judas
that calls herself my friend.
Look, Mother, this isn't one of your books.
This is real life.
You're talking about Father and Kit.
I know who I'm talking about.
Your father's just confessed
the whole thing.
Oh, that she would have the nerve
to criticize me...
for the way I was treating him.
Why... Why, it was in this very room.
I was sitting there on the couch...
and she was standing back here,
by the piano...
when she accused me
of making your father's life miserable.
No. No, she walked away from the piano...
and she stood right over me
and told me that.
And all the while she was carrying on
with him like some Jezebel.
Well.
Well, I can wish her no worse fate
than that for which she is heading now.
What do you mean by that?
Oh, she's embarking
on a little cradle-snatching.
That silly young boy
she's been carrying on with...
has been called into the Navy.
And she must immediately become
a young sailor's bride of 42.
Who are you talking about?
- Mother, you can't mean Rudd?
- Who else?
She was here just a few minutes ago
driveling about marrying him.
I think she sees herself at the point...
where she can't be
so sure of men anymore...
whether they're
other women's husbands, or not.
- Are you sure of this?
- Yes.
Apparently Rudd is still infatuated
and anxious for marriage...
in spite of the closeness
of their relationship.
- Just what do you mean by that?
- Just what you think I mean.
Well...
this is quite a surprise.
Oh, the longer you know Kit...
the more you'll find
she's full of hidden surprises.
- Mother, are you telling me the truth?
- Of course. Why should I lie?
Why, it's time you knew
what was going on around you.
It's time you came out
of your illusions about Kit.
I think it's about time
I came out of a lot of illusions.
Why... Why, Deirdre.
Well.
Thank you.
- Hello, Kit.
- Hello.
I'm sorry, I have to rush.
- Congratulations.
- What about?
You and Rudd. I'm so glad.
Heaps of love to you both.
- Deedy, where are you off to?
- I have a date, with Lucien.
Come in.
- Hello, Millie.
- Hello.
What's been going on?
I just ran into Deirdre in the hall
and she was almost hysterical.
I don't know what you mean.
Millie...
what did you tell Deirdre
about Rudd and me?
I told her that you were
going to be married. Why?
What did you tell her that for?
Since I haven't even told him myself yet...
I should have thought
it was a little premature.
But that certainly couldn't have upset her.
It must have been something else.
What was it?
You set yourself up
as a paragon of virtue to that girl...
and it was my duty, as her mother,
to open her eyes.
So that's what you told her.
Millie, why did you do that?
Why should you?
Why shouldn't I?
Haven't you done enough to me?
What have I done to you?
- Don't you remember?
- Remember what?
You, my so-called best friend
and Preston, my husband.
Surely you remember that?
I do, distinctly.
Then you don't pretend that you've
forgotten taking him away from me?
Millie, where did you hear such nonsense?
Never mind. You didn't think
I'd ever find out, did you?
There's nothing to find out, Millie.
Don't try to squirm out of it.
Why, there hasn't been a man yet
you haven't carried on with...
if you've had half a chance.
- Millie, have you gone stark staring mad?
- No.
You took my life and broke it.
You were at the bottom
of this whole thing and I hate you for it.
Millie, if that weren't so stupid,
it would be funny.
You don't really believe these things,
I know you don't.
How could I have been so blind?
You've coveted everything
that I've ever had, always.
All right, Millie.
You've been asking for this for years.
I'm going to have to tell you something
that I hoped I'd never have to tell you.
You don't care at all
about having lost Preston.
If it had been any other woman...
you never would have given it
a second's thought.
You only cared because it was me,
because you're jealous of me.
You've always been jealous of me.
You've been jealous of my career,
of the kind of life that I lead.
You're even jealous
of Deirdre's affection for me.
That's why you told her
about Rudd and me today.
Millie, you've done some
pretty bad things in your life...
but this is the worst yet.
Even if you didn't care
how much you hurt me...
you might at least have given a thought...
to what it would mean to Deirdre
to have her faith in me shaken.
I'd better get out of here, Millie,
before I do something I'll be very sorry for.
Yes, go! Go!
And if you think I want you
to come back again, ever, you're wrong!
You need have no worries on that score.
And as you've taken everything else
I've ever cared for in my life...
you might as well take Deirdre, too,
since she's so fond of you.
And don't think I couldn't have,
many times.
All right, go ahead and leave me alone,
all of you.
But you can't take my work
away from me.
That, at least, is inviolate.
Well, why don't you go?
In just a minute.
Sorry.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Hello.
Yes, Major Drake.
Well, she's not here right now
but I expect her any minute.
Yes, sir.
I'll tell her as soon as she arrives.
All right. Goodbye.
- Well, at last.
- Hello, Harriet.
- Was that Mr. Kendall?
- No, it was Major Drake.
His fianc is in town...
and he's giving a party tonight
at the Park Avenue Hotel...
and he wants you to come.
Says he'll call back.
Did Mr. Kendall call?
I've been trying to reach him all afternoon.
Yes, three or four times.
He says he'll be here at 8:00.
Oh, what is it now? Oh, 7:00.
Everybody in New York's been calling you.
I've written it all down.
Oh. Thank you.
But where on earth have you been?
I thought you were lost.
I've been walking for blocks.
Harriet, I did something today
that I've wanted to do for years...
and I feel perfectly marvelous.
Well, that's fine.
Harriet, would you say I was a woman
who knew her own mind?
Yes, I would.
Well, I've made up my mind
to marry Mr. Kendall.
Well, congratulations.
Thank you, Harriet.
Did a dress arrive for me from Jerdan's?
Oh, that explains it.
I thought it was something
you bought for Miss Deirdre.
Well, I felt very young when I bought it.
As a matter of fact,
this is my second blooming.
Life has been very good to me.
Oh, I would look like a hag of 90
when I want to look like Shirley Temple.
Harriet, have the little florist on the corner
send up some roses...
and put on that table by the fire.
I'll take it.
And put some champagne on ice.
- And be sure and wear your black uniform.
- All right.
- Good evening, Mr. Kendall.
- Hello, Harriet.
Let me take your things.
- Well, that's very becoming.
- Thank you, Harriet.
Miss Marlowe is upstairs.
I'll tell her you're here.
- She'll be down in a minute.
- All right.
- Have a seat.
- Thank you, Harriet.
Hello, darling.
Hello, Kit.
You look very handsome
in your uniform, Lieutenant.
I should think it was a nice feeling.
Yes, it is.
You look beautiful tonight, Kit.
That's what I was waiting for.
Now I can come down.
Are you sure
I don't look haggard and worn...
with what the critics call, my genius?
No, I've never seen you look so lovely.
Why, Rudd, I'm overcome.
Darling.
I had Harriet put some champagne on ice,
to celebrate.
I think it's about the last bottle we have.
Well, darling,
aren't you going to do the honors?
Oh, of course.
It seems ages since I've seen you...
and yet it's only been a few days.
Here you are.
Thank you, darling.
Well, here's to you, Kit.
Here's to...
To you, Rudd.
Darling, I must have seemed very abrupt
with you the other morning.
- I'm sorry.
- No. No, you were being honest, Kit.
And you were perfectly right.
- You mean, about us?
- Yes.
Now, I suppose a woman's intuition
is better than a man's, after all.
Then you mean that
you agree with me now, is that it?
Yes, I do.
I must admit, I felt pretty awful
about the other morning...
but now I'm sure you were right.
But, Rudd...
It's funny, isn't it,
how things work themselves out?
- Funny?
- Yes, the whole business.
Rudd, what are you trying to tell me?
Well, something's happened, Kit...
which can't be any more of a surprise
to you than it was to me.
Darling, nothing could surprise me today.
What is it?
Well, I've fallen in love with Deirdre.
- With Deirdre?
- Yes. Can you believe it?
Why, yes.
Yes, of course I can believe it.
It began the other morning
when I left you...
feeling so hopeless
because you wouldn't marry me.
Deirdre was feeling rather blue
about something, too...
and, well, we went for a walk.
Then we had lunch at the Colony and...
Kit, this couldn't mean anything to you,
could it?
Why, Rudd, of course not.
I'm delighted for you both.
Oh, I'm glad to hear you say that.
I do feel rather funny
about telling you this.
Oh, but you mustn't.
If I'm acting peculiarly,
it's only because it's been such a shock.
I just never had thought
of you and Deirdre.
That's what I meant
the other morning when I said...
you should marry some nice young girl
and settle down.
And I think Deirdre's
a very nice young girl.
And I've always wanted the best for her.
And now I'm sure she'll have it.
Thanks, Kit.
It's sort of a protective sense, I guess.
She's such a kid.
I want to slap her if she does wrong
yet I'd kill anyone who'd touch her.
Do you know what I mean?
Of course I know what you mean.
Have you told her that you love her?
Yes, we told each other.
I asked her to marry me.
Weren't you planning
to see her this evening?
Well, her father's giving a party
at this hotel.
I'm supposed to meet her there.
Well, you'd better be going, Rudd.
She'll be wondering where you are.
Well, if you don't mind, Kit,
I guess I should.
Oh, no, of course not.
Rudd, have you heard
where you're going to be stationed?
Well, no, I haven't yet.
You must be sure and let me know
where you'll be.
I will, Kit.
Thanks.
- Goodbye, darling.
- Goodbye, Kit.
Kit...
just to have known you,
I'll always be grateful.
It's been an enchanted patch
we've had, Rudd.
Like a spell of perfect weather.
It's been like that to me, too, Kit.
Goodbye.
- Harriet.
- Yes, ma'am.
Harriet, bring down
my Persian lamb coat, will you?
- And call a cab, immediately.
- All right.
Harriet, call Major Drake
at the Park Avenue Hotel...
and tell him not to let Mr. Kendall leave
under any circumstances...
until Miss Drake arrives.
- And you needn't wait up for me.
- Well, where is Mr. Kendall?
Harriet, you're looking
at the biggest fool that ever lived.
Oh, Miss Marlowe, don't.
- Mr. Grant?
- Yes.
I'm Katherine Marlowe.
Did the man at the desk
tell you I was on my way up?
Yeah, he did.
Would you mind very much if I came in?
Not at all. Come in.
Charming. Typical bachelor's lair.
- So you're the Katherine Marlowe.
- I've often been referred to as that.
- I've heard a great deal about you.
- Have you?
- Oh, that's the bedroom.
- Really?
- Would you like a drink?
- No, thank you very much.
- I will have a cigarette, though.
- Why, certainly.
Thank you.
- Do you mind if I sit down?
- Please do.
This will be quite comfortable, thank you.
I presume there is no need
for me to tell you why I'm here.
I've come for Deirdre.
- Oh, the little Drake number.
- Yes.
- What would she be doing here?
- Well, that's what I've come to find out.
Look, Miss Marlowe, I don't know
where you got the weird idea...
- but if you think that I...
- You're far from convincing, Mr. Grant.
- Now, really.
- Deirdre!
- Come out from behind that screen.
- Now look, Miss Marlowe, I...
Deirdre, are you coming out by yourself
or shall I come over and drag you out?
How did you know I was there?
My dear, I was hiding behind screens
before you were born.
Well, I won't be treated like this.
I won't be followed about like a child.
Mr. Grant, would you get
Deirdre's hat and coat, please?
I'm old enough to take care of myself
and to lead my own life.
Mr. Grant, would you get
Deirdre's hat and coat, please?
Gladly.
Oh, why don't you let me alone?
Deirdre...
I gave you credit
for more intelligence than this.
If you insist
upon throwing yourself away...
for heaven's sake,
do it with a little originality.
This is definitely old hat.
- That goes for the way you're dressed, too.
- What are you doing to me?
What's the matter
with the way I'm dressed?
You're a fine one to criticize anything I do.
Deirdre, I have never made a practice
of slapping people...
but I'm dangerously close
to slapping you right now.
Here you are.
Thank you.
- Come on, Deirdre.
- I'm not going.
Deirdre, I want no more nonsense.
Come on.
By the way, Miss Marlowe...
if there's anyone else you know
in my little black book...
I'll be only too glad
to cross them out right now.
I know practically
everyone in New York, Mr. Grant.
- Shall I call a taxi?
- No, thank you, I had mine wait.
I'm sick and tired
of everyone interfering with me.
- Good night, Mr. Grant.
- Good night, Miss Marlowe.
You went to Lucien's tonight...
because of what you heard
about Rudd and me, didn't you?
- Well, I...
- Didn't you?
- Well, yes.
- I thought so.
- And you're in love with Rudd, aren't you?
- That has nothing to do with it.
- I don't see why you don't marry him.
- Because he doesn't want to marry me.
And, well, no nice woman wants to marry
a man who doesn't want to marry her.
- But Rudd's in love with you, isn't he?
- He was, Deirdre.
- He isn't anymore.
- You mean he just stopped suddenly?
You can't say
when you stop loving somebody, Deirdre.
All you know is that you have stopped.
But you haven't stopped loving him,
have you?
To be quite honest with you, no, not yet.
But I shan't go on loving him forever.
Anyway, the thing has happened...
and, well, thank God it's happened now
and not a year from now.
I don't think I could have taken it then.
Well, here we are.
Deirdre, you think over everything
I've said and you'll realize I'm right.
Kit, if I'd only known,
this never would've happened.
But if it hadn't been you, darling,
it might have been someone else.
And I'm happy it was you.
You're so right for each other.
Now, come on. Rudd's waiting for you.
Kit...
tell me something.
Was my father ever in love with you?
Yes, he was, once.
Kit, I can't tell you...
You're just about
the most wonderful person I know.
Oh, nonsense.
I'm not at all.
Darling, it's late...
and I'm very, very tired
of youth and love and self-sacrifice.
Now come on.
- Good night, Kit.
- Good luck, darling.
Now you be happy.
That's what I want most in the world,
for you to be happy.
Where to now, lady?
Oh.
Well, I really don't know.
Drive me around for a while, will you?
I'm sorry. I can't cruise around these days.
Gas rationing.
That's right.
Well, I guess
you'd better take me back home.
Yes, ma'am.
Well, Millie, imagine finding you here.
Kit, it's hard for me to apologize.
Anything I may have said today...
I didn't mean it.
Forget it, Millie.
I've been a fool.
I... I know you must hate me...
but if you could find it in your heart
to forgive me.
Of course I forgive you, Millie.
I'm not even angry anymore.
Thank you, Kit.
Millie, how about a glass
of nice, flat champagne?
- Do you think I should?
- Oh, come on. It'll be good for both of us.
Well, I never have, but all right.
There comes a time
in every woman's life...
when the only thing that helps
is a glass of champagne.
It's been a strange sort of day,
hasn't it, Kit?
That's putting it mildly.
I didn't expect you back so soon.
I thought you'd be out
celebrating with Rudd.
Millie, brace yourself.
I've something to tell you.
Yes?
Rudd is getting married, but not to me.
Oh.
Thank you.
Well, if he's not going to marry you,
who is he going to marry?
Deirdre.
Deirdre?
Are you joking?
No, Millie. Far from it.
Deirdre and Rudd.
But they don't even know each other,
do they, or more than casually?
Apparently they knew each other
well enough for that.
I can't believe it.
Don't be upset, Millie.
Deirdre was bound to marry someday.
And Rudd couldn't be nicer.
As a matter of fact, aside from Preston...
Rudd is the only other man
I ever wanted to marry.
And I'm just conceited enough
to think that that means something.
But it wouldn't have worked out, Kit.
You know that.
You're probably right.
Oh, my goodness.
- Millie, what is it?
- This changes everything.
Changes what?
My new book,
the one I told you I was writing.
You see, it's about two women friends.
They're practically brought up together.
They have their ups and downs,
and finally...
You mean, like us?
Oh, the characters are all imaginary but...
In a way, yes.
Millie, you never cease to amaze me.
No, really.
It's your not marrying Rudd
and both of us finding ourselves lonely.
If I finish it that way,
well, of all my books...
it'll be the first sad ending
I've ever written.
Well, Millie, you've always said
you wanted to write...
what you call "an artistic flop."
Maybe this will be it.
No, Kit. The public doesn't expect
a sad ending from me.
Two women left all alone like this.
- What you going to call it?
- Well, I'm not sure.
I've had several ideas.
What do you think of Auld Lang Syne?
Well, if it's about us,
why not Old Acquaintance?
Old Acquaintance.
Old Acquaintance. Of course, Kit.
Let's drink to that, Millie.