Leave a message,
we'll call you back.
Hey, it's Kurt! I am calling you.
I'm in town. Just
hoping you're around.
I don't know if you're
there or what...
Pick it up, man. You
will not regret it.
Hey, Kurt...
So you're here?
Where're you stayin'?
Yeah, thanks. The rumours are true.
Nah, we didn't wanna know.
Oh yeah? What've
you got? Lay it on me.
Sure... I could be into that.
I could use some time in
the woods, absolutely.
Yeah... I think that could be cool.
Let me just run it by Tania.
I'll call you in ten... Right on.
What?
Don't ask my permission...
I said I'd run it by you.
He wants to check out some hot springs
near Estacada, camp out tonight.
Get an early start tomorrow,
be home by... noon I'd say.
Look, if it's gonna be a problem I'll just
call him back and tell him I can't go.
Hey... you should come too.
You're totally welcome.
You know that, it'd be fun.
I'm not exactly up for camping.
It's probably gonna rain anyway.
Could rain all day.
Look, you're just waiting
for me to tell you to go...
We know you're going so I don't know
why we have to go through this thing
of me letting you off the hook.
I'm not gonna enjoy myself if
you're... miserable about it.
Go in, Lucy, go in!
that'd be Eleven Nine.
Hugh, how are you?
- Very good. How are you today?
- Good, thanks!
I'm callin' in... I never could
understand why Lyndon Johnson
became the champion of the
Civil Rights Movement.
are you talking about? I mean the
Voting Rights Act was a great thing.
- Oh yes...
- It was the...
It was the beginning, literally the
beginning of American democracy.
- I grew up in a state...
- It also became the foundation of the...
- Southern Strategy.
- He said we've delivered the South to the
Republican Party for a long
time when he signed the Act.
- I mean is that what you're talking about?
- Yeah.
You said it with regret...
These were all wedge issues.
When Reagan talked about...
He's for State's rights.
All it was, it was just a veiled
way of saying: "He's a racist."
When Nixon talked about "Law and Order",
that's what he was talking about!
He was talking about the...
Think about this. You had... Lee Atwater
kickin' around when all these guys were
devising the Southern
Strategy. Including...
Including Karl Rove, he's taken the
Southern Strategy to the next step,
and that's to divide
us by way of religion.
So, I don't think you're insane.
I mean, I was joking when
I said you're insane...
Not really.
I'll tell you... I'll tell you this.
I agree with the fact that...
- May I interject here?
- Yeah.
I didn't call up and assert that Lyndon
Johnson did this, I asked a question.
But Bobby reacted as
if I was asserting it.
And then he starts calling names.
- Let me go back...
- It was a bad question.
Listen Bobby, there's no such
thing as a bad question...
Kurt!
Hello?
Hello!
Hey man!
Hey, Kurt!
I brought a cooler.
Take it. And a wagon. And a TV.
- You're looking good.
- Really? I wish!
He hasn't sold the house yet?
No, not yet. But my
days are numbered here.
I'm really glad you could come.
I didn't know if you could
make it on such short notice,
everyone's so busy now.
You know I had a dream about you
the other night? Where you're...
in, like, a hospital or something.
It was really weird.
But you were the best
thing about it by far.
That's cool...
- How's Ashland?
- Ashland? Amazing!
Transformative.
I'm at a whole new
place now really.
Wow, you've really
got it all goin' on.
Hell yeah!
- Where's your shit?
- It's in the car. I've got the dog too.
Really? Why don't we take
your ride. What do you think?
Cause this thing is just
a slug in the mountains.
Erm... sure! I can drive.
Alright! Let's load it up!
The Democrats are sitting on their damn
hands. What do you make of that?
First of all, the Democrats in Congress
have made a tragic mistake, and that is...
they seem to think that they're
part of the Government...
- Yeah. Yeah, that's a good point.
- Rather than going to the people.
Opportunity is not just knocking at
the door, it's pounding at the door.
There's the Democratic donkey, you know,
sittin' there sipping tea sayin':
"I don't know! I don't know if I should
get up and answer the door or not."
It is there. You know
we saw the same thing
in last year's presidential election
when our party's nominee did not...
- It'll just take two seconds.
- ...the corporate crooks.
- Hope that's all?
- ...the fight is not
about them. It's not
a fight for them.
- It's a fight to hold on to the very solid...
- Yo, you got ten bucks?
by the Exxon, by the Coors, by the
Murdochs, by Richard Mellon Scaife.
It's a fight, we can't win by removing
ourselves, standing on the sidelines...
Some people say we
need a third party,
I wish we had a second one.
And I'm gonna fight for that
to be the Democratic Party.
But I certainly
understand people...
- Hey, what's up?
- What's goin on?
- 30 dollars?
- 30 dollars...
- ...and other folks, because...
- Take it easy.
And if we do not stand
up for working folks...
The one good thing about the... he
is trying to flip the party back
to the grassroots level.
In last month...
This thing go back any further?
How's your dad?
He's alright, you know.
All things considered.
Last I heard he was
living in... a new place.
Yeah, right.
For some reason he
decided at age 70,
that he didn't want to be married
anymore. So he moved out.
Yeah, that's what I heard.
Then he ended up with these...
fuckin' blood clots on his brain.
Oh, fuck.
And they just showed
up, out of nowhere.
He was really weak for a
while, nobody knew what to do.
Then they... dissolved.
Just went away.
That's heavy.
Really put my mom
through the wringer.
Yeah, I bet. I bet.
It's kind of like when an old
Eskimo goes off to die alone.
Who knows?
You still have this.
- Didn't this use to be Noah's?
- Yeah.
Found it behind Krugers, there's
crumbs in there where you can add it.
And then, it was mine for a while.
Man... Mark, you really
hold on to shit.
Not that I should talk.
I've still got crates of
records in the garage,
stuff that I haven't even
listened to in... ten years.
I'm gonna have to take the whole load down
to Syd's I think. See what I can get for it.
- Syd's just gone man.
- No way!
The rent got to be too heavy,
now it's a... smoothie place.
- Rejuicenation.
- No!
Syd sells on eBay, now.
Oh that makes sense.
I should be doing that.
Tania went by on the last day, said
the only records left in the bins
were our friends'.
No more Syd's.
End of an era.
Come on!
That was amazing! Were
you catching that?
- That young soldier got a raw deal...
- And everybody that was there...
- Do you know where we're goin'?
- Oh yeah!
Cruisy... Downtown!
Now you take this.
No, you take this one.
You take this one.
These aren't even funny.
Back to you, Lucy.
Sunshine!
This is a great spot, man!
You're gonna love it!
I was here...
two summers ago.
Totally private. No one around.
And most of all...
It has this otherworldly
peacefulness about it.
You can really... think.
Sounds awesome.
'Cause you can't... you can't
get real quiet anymore.
I visited this hot spring
in Arizona last summer.
Where no one is allowed to
talk at all. Total silence.
It's fuckin' amazing.
They want me to come back
and work as a chef sometime.
I've got a whole menu
worked out for 'em.
Right, I think I read about
that place in a magazine.
You remember Yogi?
Sure, he stiffed us on the
rent when he left town.
Really? I forgot about that.
Well, I ran into him
in Big Sur last month.
We had the most incredible
night together.
We were out under the stars,
dancing to these drums.
Everybody was jumping
over these huge bonfires.
I'd never seen anything like it.
Everyone there... was just
so joyful that night.
Beautiful women...
singing and dancing.
I don't know, just a really,
really amazing group of people.
- No shit.
- Yeah. You should've been there.
I think Yogi got laid.
Slow down...
Slow down, you wanna go left.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Trust me Mark.
Okay!
I'm in your hands.
I remember that.
I think we're somewhere...
in this area.
I need a little space.
- It's the mother of your child.
- Thank you.
I have no idea...
No it's fine...
Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
What was that?
No... I mean, we are
looking for it.
I can't hear you.
We're gonna have to go.
I'll call you when
I have reception.
I love you.
The sign up there
is literally blank.
- We've entered a whole other zone.
- Far out.
- Up or down?
- Up!
Getting dark...
What do you think, Kurt?
I spotted a turn-off where
we can camp for the night.
Just a few miles back
down that road we passed.
We can camp there... And find
the river in the morning.
You know how to get there?
Yeah, I know how to get there,
but you gotta turn around.
Well. That's close to
here I guess, right?
Still get a good start
in the morning.
Looks fine to me.
Lucy, stay here.
It's good to get out of the city.
Forget all this is
out here sometimes.
No shit.
It's not like there's any big difference
between the forest and the city though.
Know what I mean?
It's all one huge thing, now. There's trees
in the city, and garbage in the forest.
What's the big
difference, you know?
I see what you mean.
So you lookin' forward
to fatherhood?
Yeah.
Sure, I mean...
We're both stretched so thin with work,
it's almost impossible to imagine, but...
It'll have to work itself out.
We'll just... find another rhythm.
Do it is whatever people do.
So... fuckin' brave, man.
I've never gotten myself into anything
that I couldn't get myself out of.
It's just... Having a kid
is so fuckin' for real.
Watch out Ham's cans!
- Did you... are you pumpin' these for me?
- I pumped it.
It's easier to aim with one
hand than with two hands.
Really?
Why do you think on TV
they do it with two hands?
Everything is about looking cool.
But I look pretty cool
with one hand, right?
Yeah...
Two hands is the responsible shooting.
One hand is renegade shooting.
Yeah, renegade...
I'll try leftie.
Switch, switch.
Switch Hitch shooting.
I think one more shot...
Let me take one more shot.
You know I was gonna
sleep out, but...
Is it... cool to sleep in?
- Sleep in the tent with you?
- Fine.
- So you're gonna sleep in the tent?
- It's a two men tent.
Two men and a doggie.
- That's cool.
- Two men and a doggie tent.
That's pretty cool.
Sleeping with the dogs.
Pretty cool. She's a girl.
Keeps you warm.
- I took some night classes.
- Anything good?
It was alright. Some
physics classes...
But here's the thing about that,
It's that I knew more than they did.
All this quark and superstring
shit, I know all about that.
It makes sense.
And don't get me wrong.
I understand it. But that's
not the final answer.
- Wow, you think you understand it?
- Basically...
It's like this see...
Sometimes things look like
they don't have any order,
and then, from a different level,
you realise that it
does have order.
It's like climbing a mountain.
Look around, you see trees and rocks
and bushes, pressing around you.
And then you get above the tree line, you
see everything you just went through
and it all like comes together. You know,
you see that it has a shape, after all.
Sometimes it takes a long time to get high
enough to see it, but it's there, it's...
It's all about space
and time and how it...
How they change the
rules sometimes.
Makes perfect sense to me.
It's like... two mirrors.
Moving through space.
There's a single atom
moving between them.
Fuck. I forget...
Whatever...
But I... I... The thing is: I get it.
I get it on a fundamental level.
The thing is... Is that
I have my own theory.
Ah yeah?
It's that the universe
is falling, man.
That's what explains it all.
The entire universe is in the shape of a
falling tear. Dropping down through space.
I'm telling you man. I don't
know how it happened,
but that's just the
way that it works.
This tear, it's been dropping down
for ever, just doesn't stop...
So did you tell them that? Your theory
about the tear-shaped universe?
Did I tell them?
Who the hell am I?
They don't care about my theory,
doesn't mean shit to them...
I don't have any numbers for it.
God...
I miss you, Mark.
I miss you really, really bad.
I want us to be real friends again.
There's something... between us, and I
don't like it. I want it to go away.
Man, what are you talking
about? We're fine.
Are you serious?
Do you really think that?
Of course!
Course I do, we're fine.
We're totally fine.
I don't know...
My God!
God, I'm sorry.
I'm just being crazy.
I'm sorry.
I know...
Don't pay any attention
to me, okay?
We're fine...
Everything's totally fine.
Feel a lot better now.
- Your dog's in distress.
- Yeah...
Tania calls it "separation anxiety".
It hates to be left out.
Hi!
Thanks.
How far are we from
Bagby Hot Springs?
Oh, you're real close. I think.
I've never been there, but...
it's around here somewhere.
Maybe 10 miles... away.
We might have a little
map printout in the back.
- I'll check for ya.
- Great.
And I'll bring you some coffee
while you're looking at the menus?
This is better anyway. Now we won't be
rushed, we can take our sweet time...
- Need more time?
- Nope.
Alright.
Hey, hang on a sec.
Could I get... two scrambled
eggs, dry toast and sausage.
Before my call comes. Could I get
the same as my friend please?
Except, bacon instead of
sausage, and no dry toast.
Wet toast please.
Very good.
Not too wet, just make it damp.
I know... I know, I'm sorry.
Well, he thought he knew
where it was, but...
Remember who we're dealing with.
I don't know. Apparently
we're... closing in on it.
Did you do anything last night?
She's fine.
We're super close.
I never doubted you, man.
This is where we're goin'.
- This is where we are?
- Awesome.
Yo, yo, yo yo yo...
There! On the tree.
I don't know how we
could've missed that?
I'm tellin' you man. This
is a very special place.
If you can't see the little arrows
at night, you can't get in.
- Grew pickles?
- Yes.
So they grew pickles?
It's only like a half-sour.
It was... I guess
it's called half-sour
where they're sort of salty and
don't have a lot of flavour.
- How are you feeling?
- Good.
I feel good. How about you?
Feel good too.
I see sticks!
Yeah, over here!
My God, Lucy, look!
Go catch it!
It's only one day a week but,
really pulls me out of myself.
The kids are cool.
They're really into it.
And it's fun thinking about
carpentry and woodworking...
in a way I haven't for a long time.
Makes you realise how
long ago sixteen was.
So now this... it was
basically a dumping ground...
is this really happening
community garden.
I'm so proud of you, Mark.
I'm serious.
You've really done something.
You've really given something
back to the community.
I don't know...
No, really. I'm serious.
It's really something.
It's not that big a deal... It's not
that... much time out of my life.
It's nothing you couldn't do if you
felt like it too.
Not that you don't give to the community,
I mean...
Just a... different community.
This is it, Mark.
- Cool, this looks fantastic!
- I hope you like it.
Awesome.
Alright. Let's start these flowing.
Plug it up, and then...
Let's grab it.
Come on.
Fill up here.
And then... just make the tubs
cool enough to get our bodies in.
Just dump it in.
- Whole thing?
- Yeah!
Probably wanna refill.
Look at that water.
Man...
Yesterday...
Wanted to get a notebook.
For my journal.
So I borrowed Pete's bike, and
first when I took off riding,
and where I was on the sidewalk, there
was this old man on the sidewalk too.
And... you know he was walkin', walkin'
walkin', so I thought: "Oh, I'm clear."
And I took off to the left, around him,
and just then he stepped to the left,
and I didn't ring the
bell or anything.
When I got past him, he yelled at me. He
was like: "Hey! Thanks for the warning!"
And I just felt so... bad.
All of a sudden I felt so guilty.
But it was fine, you know. Never
gonna see this guy again.
But I realise I forgot something
at the house. So I rode back.
Had to ride back by him. Just looked
at his face, like, I felt like:
"Oh, he's so angry at me.
Totally hates me."
Whatever. Can forget him again.
So, then I wanna go, you know...
Get something to drink.
And I go into a little
store, stop the bike.
When I come back out, I get
on the bike, I'm riding,
I'm riding down the same street, cause
it's a hill. And I pass the guy again.
And again, I'm just like, feeling
more and more tense, like...
Then I've got a stretch, you know,
before I get to the notebook store.
So I'm like: "Okay! I can finally move
on with my life, not have this guy!"
Go down to the notebook store, look
for my notebook. It's like 20 blocks.
Look for my notebook. Come
up to the cash register.
I'm buyin' the notebook, and the
automatic doors open, and I look up
and the guy is like, walking right
into the store, right, in front of me.
And I'm just... can't believe it!
And then the cashier woman, I hear
her talk to me all of a sudden,
She's like: "Superstar."
What?
And I look at her.
And she's this Indian woman, maybe
like 50 year-old Indian woman,
with glasses and a dot on
her forehead. And I was like:
"What?" She said: "Jesus
Christ Superstar!"
"You said 'Jesus Christ!"'
I was like: "No! I didn't
say 'Jesus Christ."'
You know? I looked at the bagging guy.
Asked like: "Did I say 'Jesus Christ'?"
He's like, just, shrugs.
And she's like:
"It's okay! It's okay!"
felt like, I feel like I would've known
if I'd said "Jesus Christ", you know?
I would've heard my voice in my
memory, like: "Jesus Christ."
"Jesus Christ", Kurt
said, "Jesus Christ."
So, I was still shaking my head, I was
like, I feel like I'm going crazy.
And I'm still sorta tense and everything.
"I feel like I'm going crazy!"
She's like: "It's okay! You're
not crazy. It's okay."
She was really nice.
And right when she said that, I...
This dream that I'd had just,
just yesterday morning,
just flashed on me,
because, the same lady,
the cashier lady was in the dream,
doing the same thing, basically.
I mean, it wasn't in a store...
But I was really upset about something.
Totally depressed about something.
And she just... put her
arms around me and said...
"It's okay! You're okay."
"Sorrow is nothing
but worn-out joy."
I see all kinds of
shit out there, man.
Most people don't see
it, they don't want to.
Hey, what's goin' on?
Just relax, man.
- Just... settle in.
- Alright.
Lucy, come!
- All righty!
- Yep.
That was... that was awesome, Kurt.
I'll call you soon, man.
Hold on a sec.
See ya.
See ya, Kurt.
take care of the new people
who come along every year
to join the labour force
or to re-join them.
And it doesn't take care of the
sharply higher cost of necessities.
It's one thing to say inflation appears
under control of the aggregate.
But when you notice
that housing costs,
healthcare costs and
energy costs are exploding
you're talking about things that
make up the overwhelming share
of the budget of an
ordinary family.
And so the combination of
uncertainty about the future
and the pressures on the present
create this mood. Now the White
House is well aware of this.
You hear the word
"recovery" all the time,
because they don't dare use
the word "prosperity".
You also see things like these...
photo opportunities this week
from the... uh... so-called...
'working vacation' in Texas.
Think you can help me
out with a little change?
Ahhh... I'm sorry, man.
- Hey man.
- Right on, thanks.
- Have a good night.
- You too.