A Daiei production
Older brother, younger sister
Based on a novel by MUROO Saisei
Script : MIZUKI Yoko
Cinematography : MINE Shigeyoshi
Art Direction : NAKA Mikio
Music : SAITO Ichiro
Cast
KYO Machiko
MORI Masayuki
KUGA Yoshiko
FUNAKOSHI Eiji
URABE Kumeko
Directed by NARUSE Mikio
How are you Kizo?
Not very well, Because of this work
We don’t work anymore as we used to
of course not.
With you, it was good.
We worked hard,
carrying heavy stones
Those are good memories
Kizo, let’s have a drink together after work
With pleasure
Life has turned hard for him
Nowadays, he doesn’t have a work anymore
since the river banks have been
built in concrete.
He used to have 7 boats
and 70 employees
Everyone knew the name AKAZA
Again your stories with
good-hearted hero
They don’t understand
careful
Hey, do you know what is Môn doing ?
Is she still sleeping ?
Is Ino back at home ?
Daddy
next stop is “Tsujiya factory”
you have a day-off today?
Yes
I’ll see you at your place later today
What’s the matter ?
Your sister is at your home.
My sister ? since when?
- since five days
- really ? that’s strange.
Good day madam.
What are you doing here?
If the neighbours see you...
Stop playing with men
or you end up like your sister.
be careful,
Good day Sir,
Good day,
Taichi, hurry up.
Anyway, you’ll hear about it very soon
TSUJIYA
NOODLE FACTORY
- San
- hello
Today is off?
You’ll see Ino today?
He didn’t come to work?
As soon as he gets some money,
He disappears
But I need him for a job
Please apologise. I’ll tell him
Yes please.
Her sister, Môn,
pays for her nurse school
with the money she took from men
then, she has been fired
from her first job
I don’t want you to get involved with Sân
Môn has the nerve
to come back to this village
If you let go
I hang myself here.
Taiichi, be reasonable, OK ?
She looks like an innocent girl,
but Sân is just like her sister
Look at her,
her mother was a hair-dresser...
Those two girls are only
smooth talk and nice touch !
- Welcome.
- Good day.
It’s hot today, isn’it ?
Would you like some cold drink ?
How is the business going ?
Slowly.
It would be better
if there wasn’t shoplifters
shoplifters ?
The last time,
It was six cakes.
children ?
No, your father and your brother.
But they don’t like cake
Your father steels cake,
not for him
but for his former employees.
Ino steels money from the cashdesk
So much trouble on our family...
it’s tragic.
How is he, papa?
He is fine, but complaining a lot as usual.
Môn is back ?
holidays ?
No she left her job
She resigned ?
What has she done?
Nothing
At the factory
they told me that...
What did they tell you?
That I should not play with men
like Môn does
with men ?
Is that true ?
Do you really believe that Môn does it?
Here you are. Eat this
People say that this old Tokiko
is loosing her head.
That is why she is telling stories.
Have this drink, It taste good with this
Thanks
Someone gave it to me,
but it is too loud.
Was it Môn?
Me too, I have a present.
Here you are.
What is it?
Bamboo sandals.
It’s ideal for summer.
It’s very good quality
With nice ribbon...
It must be expensive.
You told me you would like that model.
with your small pay… Thank you.
Can you keep the store ?
Of course
I’ll go shopping.
This really looks worn-out...
Of course. It belonged to your brother
Your sister, and you.
Just stay there… If a customer comes
Come on, let’s have a drink
Stop it, it is too early
I have something to ask you.
Hell.
What’s the matter?
Are you hiding a girlfriend from me?
shut-up.
Dad, do you want to try ?
fool !
Go back home !
What a temper!
You’re disgusting.
What ?
I don’t want to see Môn at home!
Still dragging yourself...
She is dreaming of a romance stroll
in the moonlight... ridiculous.
How can you appeal to men
with this face ?
Finally, you come back pregnant
and then, you complain you ache all over
You just sleep here all day, like a log.
As we don’t know
what egg you are going to lay
you’d better not keep it
I hate baby cry at night.
Your boyfriend is clever than you.
after having a good fun,
he drops you.
you don’t even have his address.
and you, despite all,
you still love that bastard.
What a fool !
Still being in love...
You will see, your baby will get bigger
and when he is born,
you’ll be rejected from the society.
Then you’ll have to go to Tokyo
and you’ll die with the baby !
Let that be a lesson to you !
Really, because of my sister
you are not allowed to speak to me ?
Yes, it’s because of the grand-ma
My father has also been adopted by her
She has nothing in life but work
The word "love" makes her sick
To them, Love is bad
because it misleads young people.
They lost a son during the last war.
If I leave with a woman,
it would be a disaster
It is not only
because of your sister
Anyway
if we get along well
there would be no trouble
wouldn’t it
Taiichi, can’t you go back
to your real family ?
No, they have seven sons….impossible
I don’t want them to argue
You are all old-fashioned
My sister is taking care of herself
It is not your business
We are in the country here.
Tokyo is on the other side of the river.
Sân, you have already seen other places,
but here, there are people
who have never travelled to Tokyo
In Tokyo, one has much
more freedom than here
It is not far though,
just on the other side.
hey, Kizo...
What do you think..?
Me… in my all life
I have never surrender...
I would never accept
to become a looser !
You are damned right.
Listen to me,
I’m born here, and since then,
I have always lived with this river!
- Who is the old man ?
- stop it.
in the old times, we used to stick together
Nowadays,
young workers are too hard,
they don’t show respect anymore
at work
Hey boss, do you remember...
on new year’s day,
Us, all 70 of your workers,
we stand in line in your garden
receiving greetings,
and drinking Saké together.
it was wonderful.
When it comes to organise party,
you were,
always the best.
OK, I’ll do it again this year.
for new year’s day
I hate stinginess.
Boss. You remain trustworthy.
Tell me, boss...
me too,
I came here at seven,
at 15, I started looking up for stones,
until 20
when I became on my own,
I’ve learned that job,
hurting my back everyday
carrying heavy baskets.
I was not the kind that stay by
the river looking helpless
under the scorching sun.
You are damned right
every year, during the rainy season
the water level could raise
and even when it last long,
our baskets remain
at the bottom of the river
with the stones that we had found.
It would stay there
until the end of the rain.
But nowadays...
they just cover the banks with concrete !
Yes, that’s true...
- Please, More sake
- right away
have another drink
Don’t worry,
This is the only place which is giving me credit.
I don’t think I can live other places.
I am staying here. I am not moving
of course not
I don’t even want you to pick up
stones like us
More drinks please.
what’s the matter ?
what is happening?
Sân has just come here, you know ?
forget it.
She can not control herself.
But she is my daughter.
Your daughter that you spoiled
Look at her now.
Môn, where are you going?
Where are you going ?
Go wherever you want.
Ino, be nicer to her.
You don’t have the right to speak to me like that
you neither. You’re just a lazy sloth.
You have to choose the right time
to get angry
Just now, this is not the right
time for Môn
anyway
this is your father’s job
As he doesn’t tell her anything,
we too, should leave her alone
Thanks, but I am bothering
everyone here
Yes, you are a pain
Sân will not be able to find
an husband like any other girl
Ino, Môn has worked
to pay for my studies...
she gave me a chance.
What ? Shut up brat
Môn, wait !
Leave me,
I’ve decided to go.
But what are you going to do
with your baby ?
I’ll go and ask the hospital.
No, wait !
I am not an animal
I want to make up for it
but you treat me like a slut
now it’s enough!
Ino, you are not the one who feeds me,
I live on my own.
What ?
stop it, please.
I will raise my child by myself.
He is already alive !
Men can not feel this.
I will never abandon him.
Don’t worry anymore, it’s over.
Daddy told me
to take my responsibilities
and that he doesn’t want to see
his disgraced daughter anymore
Don’t play the elder brother,
you are giving me headache, that’s all.
I am a big girl,
I know how to defend myself
I won’t bother anyone
Sân
Môn
The future bride?
Yes, presumably
It taste good
thank you very much
Good day
Welcome
It smells good.
Look, I bought this cooking pot
with your money
but it was so few.
I paid some of it myself
I wanted to have it before you come
Any news from Môn ?
She came once for new year’s holidays
Do you want to eat something ?
Help yourself.
- Hello.
I would like to know...
where does M. AKAZA like
Here is his store.
My name is OBATA
I come to see Môn.
Môn...
Well...
I came to talk with you
About her.
Môn is not living here anymore,
She is in Tokyo.
Could you please wait for a moment ?
Yes.
Sân, take him home.
I am going to find Dad.
Come with me.
Mika, Can you keep the store?
I’ll give you something later
Excuse me
Are you her sister?
Could you please wait here.
Daddy !
He is here, the father !
What ?
He is at home.
Môn’s boyfriend...
He is a young student
Be reasonable, no violence.
Maybe he wants to discuss
about the baby with Môn
Does he look dishonest?
No, he seems to be well-mannered
Please, have some tea.
Sân
Can you keep the store?
Don’t stay there. Please get in
What do you want?
I haven’t introduce myself,
My name is OBATA
I shouldn’t be here right now.
My father locked me in,
I couldn’t get out.
Please forgive me for giving you
so much trouble.
I came here today
to give Môn a compensation...
I thought about it all the time...
Did she have an abortion?
Did you come here
just to put your mind at ease ?
Do you thing that everything is over ?
Well, it’s not !
Do you thing we’ll forgive you
if you give us money...?
No, but I’d like to help
as much as I can...
The child is still-born.
Since that day,
Môn is not the same anymore.
Where is she currently living?
I’d like to see her
to explain my behaviour and to apologise
I can’t stay like this.
I have no idea. We tried in vain
to hold her back here.
Now, she doesn’t give us her address.
Madam.
This is from Sân for your guest.
Really? Thank you.
Even if you genuinely apologise,
I doubt Môn would see you again...
You should better go back home.
M. OBATA,
Don’t you ever do such stupid thing again
This time,
You’re the one who won...
Don’t worry,
my husband is always like that.
If you can,
Please stay for dinner with us…
No, thanks.
Madam,
I have to leave,
Thank you very much.
Please.
If Môn comes here one day,
I’ll tell her that you came.
Please ask for her address.
and also
Please accept this.
It’s not a lot.
What is this ?
some money, a very small amount.
No, I can’t accept this.
Please... you may need it…
There is no reason I should accept.
Please, I beg you.
This is the only thing
I will ask you
This is not a lot
but if you feel pity for me,
accept it, please...
I should go
Wait
How do you call this ?
This is boxwood flower
It is really beautiful.
I don’t know if you’ll like it
with pleasure. Thank you very much.
How old are you ?
I just got 24.
So, just one year of difference with Môn.
This is my address.
Could you pass it to Môn ?
OK, next time she visits us.
Apparently, she often changes location.
each time, we ask for her address.
but she never tells us.
Well, if you see her...
Wait !
I am Môn’s brother,
I have things to discuss with you,
follow me,
Have you seen Môn since then?
No never.
Really ? never ?
Listen to me,
You are the one who abused my sister
and torment my family
how dare you coming here ?
When we were small, Môn and I
were sleeping in the same bed
When she needed to take a pee,
I would go to the toilet with her
I would carry her on my back...
I preferred playing with her
than with my friends.
Until she gets 17
there was no boundaries
between us
we were always together on table
We got along better than
brother and sister
When she came back pregnant with your child...
I shout at her, treating
her like a slut on purpose.
They then started hating me
And got softer on Môn
I don’t regret it
If I hadn’t done it,
Môn couldn’t cope...
But you,
I knew that you’ll come one day...
I was waiting
for that moment where I could
tell you about Môn and me.
The daughter of a worker
can not be wit a neat
student like you ?
One can forgive but
I am not like my father
who don’t give a damn about anything
I won’t let you leave like this!
Did you come here only to apologise ?
But there is nothing else I can do
what about Môn ?
If I see her, we’ll speak about it
Are you going to marry her ?
I don’t know. Perhaps.
Liar !
Don’t hit me !
What ?
You, bastard, may very
well forget everything...
Môn has suffered much more than that !
She is not like she used to be.
She doesn’t want to live with you.
She is worse than before
but she is more confident,
She has lost that innocence
that you loved
She has nothing left in life...
Because of you.
If you hadn’t touch her...
she wouldn’t be what she is now
Don’t you ever come back !
and promise me that
you will never make her cry again.
It was my fault
You are right.
I am her brother.
If you were in my position,
you would understand me.
Go home,
there is a bus stop further in that direction
- Did you find him ?
- No
Moron... what is he doing ?
San.
Let’s go live together in Tokyo.
later, it would be too late.
The date of my marriage has come.
I am completely stuck,
I must leave
But I am not ready yet...
Never mind, we’ll sort it out.
but...
We’ll take time to consider
in Tokyo, not here.
I took my decision.
but...
San, You are the one
who wanted to go to Tokyo...
We can’t leave like that, without a word.
I’ll be waiting at the bus stop.
Will you be there ?
Is it OK ?
I’ll be waiting. See you in a minute.
I am sorry.
Are you hungry ?
- Did you have something to eat ?
- Yes.
Someone was here ?
Can you stay until this evening ?
Yes.
What is the matter ?
Tell me. That man, OBATA...
why did he come...?
To apologise
That’s it
He is so sorry, the poor boy.
Are you going home ?
Mom, I have to leave.
Really, so soon?
Are you so much busy?
Yes. But I was pleased to see you.
Me too. Well,
I won’t insist.
- See you next time
- Take care.
- Good bye.
- Two tickets to the station.
- OK.
Thank you very much.
They must be looking for me.
Thank you very much
Do you know him ?
Wait for me
We shouldn’t be seen together
The tickets ?
I go and buy them.
It’s done
The train will leave soon
What is the matter ?
Taiichi, I am going back to Tokyo alone.
Why ?
Don’t get angry
If we leave together to Tokyo
What can we do there with no future
Even if we find a room in a hotel,
we can not live there
Moreover, if the police is after us
It would be terrible
What on earth are you talking about?
Let’s go now !
Please, think about it.
No, I don’t want to.
Listen, if we get along well
it would come naturally.
I am sure we can manage.
but not now.
It is too early. We are not
there yet. We can not make it work
Let’s wait until we
are sure about ourselves
You don’t love me anymore ?
Why don’t you understand ?
Think about it again
I’ve already thought a lot about it. Let’s go !
No. the only solution you have
is to run away
Why can not you just tell them
that you love me ?
It is hopeless
You are just a big lump
Sân
If you love me, you should tell your family
that you don’t want that marriage
that you would leave the house
to live with me
Tell them, or you are not a man
I am going
Sân
No, leave me alone !
During his life, this student never
had to take a commitment
A honest, decent and boring life.
I’ve never been like him !
I have just nothing in common
wiht those people.
I can have my own opinion,
right ?
right.
Boss.
Thank you very much.
Good day.
Good day
Taiichi.
here, Take over me.
Good day.
Some lemonade please
Hello
Sân, you took an unusual path
Did you stop at the store ?
Mum was there ?
No. Daddy was sleeping.
Daddy is keeping the store. That’s nice
It has been such a long time
Don’t you look thinner?
Especially in the face.
Yes, maybe a little bit.
- You are a grown-up now
- Do yo think so ?
Nothing to be ashamed of.
let’s call her
Hello
Hello !
She can not hear us.
Mummy
Dear mother
OK, I hear you. Get in.
She aged so much
Is she not happy to see us ?
- Hello.
- Please forgive me for not answering.
You are welcome.
I was sure that you would
come for the holidays.
Since yesterday, I am cooking cakes.
really?
Don’t Sân come often ?
No, very rarely.
Before, she was very close
to her family.
She told me she has to study a lot
to become a mid-wife
That’s a good reason.
Good luck then.
Ahh It is so hot
Is it hot outside?
Where did you meet Môn ?
- just outside
- really ?
I have seen the new bride
at the noodle factory.
At the wedding ceremony, everybody
was wearing autumn kimonos
They didn’t wait for the end of summer
The old lady just couldn’t wait
The kimono of the bride
seemed very heavy.
The old Tokiko was wearing
a lined kimono...
After that, because of heat rash,
she could’nt take a bath
for one month.
You talk nonsense
As usual...
you know me well.
Mister OBATA came here.
OBATA ?
Really? When?
It was maybe three months ago...
Wasn’t it Sân ?
yes.
Why did he come here ?
Here is his address.
He came to apologise
- Did he talk with dad ?
- Yes
What did he say ?
Your father ? nothing special.
wasn’t he too harsh on him ?
No, he kept cool
It’s rather rare for him.
He even called him “Mister OBATA"
But I was scared
your father might become violent
fortunately, he was very polite.
I am sorry to give you so much trouble.
He didn’t have to come
- Did Ino meet him ?
- No
That’s better !
He makes a whole lot of fuss,
he could go over the top.
He was not here
He is an handsome guy
Isn’t he?
Who ?
him.
You fool ! You still love
The one who dropped you ?
Stop it. That’s enough.
Here you are Mum
- This is for me ?
- And here is my present.
- Here you are
- What is it ?
- Some Yukatas
- Really
There are 3 of them
yes for San,
she prefers western style
Present for me too ?
here you are
You don’t have to give present to all of us
Would like some tea ?
No, thanks.
I prefer water from our well.
It is the best water of the world
Really ?
Have as much as you want
You can change clothes,
there is my old summer kimono
With this, you could make a cute robe
cute ?
Why not ?
I don’t dress
like a little girl anymore
Really? You have a boyfriend, right ?
Not at all. That is too much...
I don’t have men on my mind
Marriage is not all in life.
I need to get a job.
Ahhh!
Life is what matters, right ?
Life...
Yes... it’s hard.
According to my experience,
men are all bastards
a women of low reputation like me
can easily be liked by men
by playing with them as they expect to...
That’s the tactic...
they taught us
I don’t count how many times
I believed them...
At the end, they are just all the same.
Now, I don’t care.
Môn, what did you like in OBATA
What a question
I am sure you can find
someone better
Maybe there is someone
It’s a big world
I met a couple of nice guys, but
the handsome ones were too pretentious
and those who had money
were too violent
He is the only one
who is balanced
But if he comes to pick me up
I won’t go with him
I still love him in my mind...
But, now he is too lukewarm for me.
Here you are. Nice and cool
I’ll give some good and fresh
watermelon.
Here you are
I should take advantage of
all soul’s day.
have a good work.
Same to you,
rich man
That’s a good one
You can go and have lunch
hey boss...please
It is tough to work on holiday
Without extra money
again ?
She has really fallen.asleep
Let her sleep...
She can rest.
She looks tired.
She probably doesn’t sleep a lot...
- Yoo too, be careful
- to what ?
the other day,
Someone saw you at the station.
It is better for this adopted son
To marry someone else
They were in such a hurry
for the wedding !
For you, it is too early,
isn’t it ?
I thought his love was genuine...
Unhappy in Love ?
Were you awake ?
You should not regret it
You can have any men you want
I’ll find someone nice for you
Mum, I’ve seen OBATA in the bus
going to the station
He was eating the cakes.
The cakes I gave him ?
He is like a little boy
Good day, Ino
Do you work today ?
theres is no holiday for me !
You are there ?
Don’t lie down like a dead person
We’ll have some cake for lunch, OK ?
and I’ll make some nice dishes
for this evening
Môn, come here
You should better go home early
to have fun with your customers
here is a good-mannered household
I don’t want you to bring mess into it.
Ino !
Anyway, she doesn’t care,
even if I shout at her.
That’s enough.
Ino stop it.
We don’t see each other very often any more...
There is no use to be nice
with her.
Look, Môn brought very nice presents.
I’ll buy you tons of it
No, it’s for you.
I don’t want to wear what she bought
with dirty money.
I want her to come back here only when
she has a decent job
Shut-up….let’s eat
Môn, come and eat.
This is intermission, understand ?
Intermission ,
It’s a break during a play. The curtain comes
down between two acts.
Now it is time for intermission,
we stop the show.
Some green tea
already finished ?
Do you want something else ?
I don’t, because of somebody here
Stop turning the past over
The past is still going on
This guy didn’t have the right to come here
but he took advantage of your good nature
Did you see M OBATA ?
- Yes
- Where ?
I followed him after he left the house.
And then ?
What have you done to him ?
I beat him up
He didn’t fight back. I scared him a lot
It was fun
Come on, tell me that again.
I beat him up
Bastard
How dare you
Who ask you about it ?
Why are you such a coward ?
What is it between you and him ? nothing ?
I gave myself to him
but that is not your business !
What ?
Stop it !
Who asked you to beat the living
daylights out of him?
You are a coward, a swine !
crazy bitch !
stop it Ino
stay out of it
What a stupid bastard...
Ino stop it !
You don’t get it
here I am, kill me, kill me !
Kill me you bastard !
Again...
stop it Ino !
You ! I know that you just go with sluts
but I don’t go along with your game
According to you,
I am a druken whore
A dissolute woman who can not marry anymore
and who doesn’t give her address
to her parents
Exactly
But… someone
who has already offered his apologies...
How can someone dare to take advantage
Of his weakness ?
I hate those people !
Tomb engraver !
Are you a man ?
What a shame to show him
that Mon’s brother is such a coward !
Moron !
keep it down,
the neighbours can hear you.
Leave me alone, mum.
I can’t believe
my brother be like this.
I can’t stand him anymore
Would you like some more...
Go on, keep hitting me !
Stop it !
bastard !
Do you think I’ll change my mind
Because of your blows
?
Those are just for little girls
From here, you can not understand
what I am doing in town
Again !
That’s enough now!
You are both the same...
Hit me !
Get out of here and go back to your place !
You changed... you became a fearsome woman...
Mom
Don’t you worry
I beg you
to live a decent life
like any well-mannered lady
Earlier, I thought you were
even worse than your brother
I am not as bas as
you think.
but...
it’s too late for me.
- Have an eye on the house,
- OK.
Don’t drink too much.
See you later, Môn.
Shall we go this way ?
Ok, let’s go.
and the spoon !
It is too hot to take the bus !
...because ...
I have to work very hard
and for a long time.
long...
When will you come back ?
I don’t know.
When I wish to see Dad and mum...
and to see Ino too
who is neither nice nor fine
but I’ll come to see him though.
Môn, take care.