Prepare to surface.
- Depth: 58 feet.
- Depth: 58 feet, Sir.
Sonar,
any contacts topside?
No contact, Sir.
Tank center ready to
surface, Sir. Very well.
Vents shut.
Ready to surface, Sir.
Depth: 58 feet, Sir.
Very well.
Up periscope.
Point Lonsdale bearing,
mark.
013, Sir.
Cape Schanck bearing, mark. 125, Sir.
How's the tide, bob? High tide, Sir.
Controls rigged
for surfacing, Sir.
Surface.
Surface,
surface, surface.
Blow main ballast.
Main ballast blown.
Depth: 45 feet, Sir.
Secure the air.
Open main induction.
Main induction open, Sir.
Our scientists disagree...
as to when radiation
will reach Australia.
The atomic war has ended, but
the prime minister reports...
no proof of survival of human
life anywhere except here.
Navy department.
Congratulations.
Tea, dear.
I said, "tea, dear."
Got a bit of a burn yesterday
at the beach after all.
You'd better put some
calamine stuff on it.
You did give Jennifer
her bottle?
I laid out your white uniform.
Was that right?
I almost forgot
I have to dash.
Peter?
Mm-hmm?
They must be giving you
a ship of your own.
No, darling. They don't
give ships to lieutenants.
Then why would it be
Admiral Bridie himself?
If you were just to replace
someone who's ill or something,
that wouldn't mean seeing
Admiral Bridie, would it?
I don't know. You don't quite
know what to expect these days.
I'll pick up jenny's milk on
the way home from the station.
Why do you have to pick it up?
They just won't be delivering
it anymore, I understand.
Oh.
It's a beautiful day,
peter.
If I wheel Jennifer down
to the club after lunch,
could you meet me there
for a swim?
Peter?
They just decided that
yesterday.
If you're going to be in Melbourne
by 11:00, you'd better hurry.
So long, Charlie.
Hosgood?
Hosgood!
Yes, Sir?
Have you seen this from
that idiot Attenborough,
that great correlator
of statistics? Yes, Sir.
It's finally seeped down to him
that most of the oil in the world...
comes from the northern
hemisphere.
Attenborough says so.
It's now official.
We will carefully conserve the remaining
supplies of petrol in the depot.
Yes, Sir.
Hosgood!
Lieutenant Holmes
is here, Sir.
Ah, yes.
Come in, come in.
Sit down.
Thanks, Sir.
I have an assignment
for you.
Do you care for some of this
miserable muck that passes for coffee?
No, thank you, Sir.
It's a reasonably important
appointment, as things go these days.
That's getting to be quite a
phrase, isn't it? "These days."
You find yourself using it?
Yes, Sir. I'm afraid I do.
I'm sorry it can't be
one of our own ships.
It's seagoing though and better
than sitting around on your bottom.
Liaison officer aboard the
American submarine Sawfish.
She just docked.
Nuclear-powered, of course.
You know about her? Yes,
Sir. I read the report.
She's at our disposal
for a cruise:
Reconnaissance or whatever
you care to call it.
You'll sail soon, but just when or
where or for how long I can't tell you,
not until the government
and a pack of these
longhaired scientists
sort themselves out.
She's moored across the dock from
the carrier Melbourne in Williamstown.
You'll report
to the Captain, Towers.
That will be all,
Holmes.
Sir, would it be possible to discuss
the duration of this appointment?
No.
But I can give you
a review in four months.
Thanks very much, Sir, because I’d
like to be home if possible when...
is there any official estimate
as to how much longer?
The beaker-heads, the
finger-in-the-wind boys say,
calculating the rate of drift
or what have you...
about five months
before it gets here.
That's why I say
four for review.
There's transport leaving for
Williamstown, if you care to take that.
Yes, Sir.
Hosgood, where is this
coffee coming from?
Supply says it's the best
they can do these days, Sir.
Shall I query them again?
No, no, no. It doesn't matter.
You have anything important to
do, Hosgood? No, Sir. What is it?
Oh, nothing. I just thought you might
like to take yourself off till Monday.
A fine weekend.
Boyfriend or whatever.
No, I...
I guess not.
I'll be here, Sir.
All watches of seamen
fall in on the deck.
Rob... lieutenant Holmes
will be coming aboard...
Monday and off and on
until we sail.
Have Benson issue him what
clothing he'll need. Yes, Sir.
I'll see you Monday, lieutenant. Thanks.
It's funny. Somehow I get the feeling...
they're putting her in moth balls. Sir?
I'm afraid I’ll have to bunk
you with this scientist fellow...
who's coming aboard
from the C. S. I. R.
Sorry. I don't know
who he'll be just yet.
That's all right, Sir.
I'll manage.
Care for a drink
before lunch?
Yes, Sir,
if it's all right.
It's Australian country
in the flattop...
I’ll have to stick to coke.
You have whatever you like.
I'm a bit puzzled
about this cruise, Sir.
Our destination, I mean.
Admiral Bridie seems...
a bit indefinite.
Of course, if there's some
reason I shouldn't know...
no, there's no reason
why you shouldn't know.
But outside of the fact
that it's reconnaissance,
I don't know any more
about it than you do.
Of course, the crew
has it all down pat.
We're sailing the end
of next week.
We're going north, and
we'll be back in two months.
But I’ll let you know...
as soon as I hear
anything more official.
Do you live
in Melbourne?
Just outside, actually,
in Frankston.
That's three-quarters
of an hour by electric train.
You make out all right?
Any serious shortages yet?
Yes, a few. Petrol
mainly, but we manage.
Say, uh...
I’ve been sticking
pretty close here lately.
Think I’m due
for some shore food.
You know of a place where
we might get a good steak?
Yes, I suppose so.
The Admiral fixed me up
with a temporary card...
for something called
the pastoral club.
What's that like? It's a
mahogany- and-polished-brass place.
Some people used to claim it was the
stuffiest club in the commonwealth.
I suppose there's
no argument about that now.
Would they have any scotch
left? Yes, if anyone does.
My wife's uncle lives there; mostly
at the bar these days, I understand.
I would think they would have
some scotch, yes.
Sounds good.
Let's give it a try.
I'll be with you
in five minutes.
Sometimes I think that child
could float a battleship.
That's what
I told the Admiral.
Peter, how could you?
I don't know, really. I just
held the towel like this and...
very funny.
You're starting to get your
figure back, aren't you, Charlie?
You know,
after Jennifer and all.
A little here,
a little there.
By the way, I invited Captain
Towers for the weekend.
Oh, peter, you didn't. I had to, really.
We had lunch together, and he started
asking questions about how we live and all.
Mary, I would have looked an
awful clod not to have asked him.
He'll be all right, I think.
Was he married, do you know?
Two kids.
And they're gone?
Yes, they were in America.
Nappies flying in the breeze, pablum
everywhere... they're bound to remind him.
We'll just try to get them
out of sight, that's all.
He'll get sodden and weep.
I can't stand that again.
He doesn't look
the type to me.
Your R. A. F. Chum didn't
either. Now, Mary...
what are we going to do
with him for two days?
For one thing, I thought a party on
Saturday night. Ten or twelve people.
We haven't done that for a
while. Would you like that?
Well, as long as they all understand how
I feel about those morbid discussions.
We would have to get
someone for him, though.
What about Moira? Why not?
If she's sober this weekend.
Julian said
she'd given it up.
No, darling, you didn't listen. Julian
said she'd given up gin... for brandy.
She says she can drink
more brandy.
Moira's not a bad notion,
in point of fact.
She'd keep him occupied,
at least.
But she'd have to stop over, and
we can't just put him on a cot.
Put Moira on a cot
on the veranda.
She claims she's not slept in her
own bed the last three months anyway.
That's not entirely fair.
It's all on the surface.
I'll ring her up tonight
and give her the drill.
I wonder what he's like
when he gets a skinful?
Peter...
what?
You do understand how I feel
about people talking? Sure.
And you do love me?
Of course I do.
Then why don't you
ever say so?
Give her what for, mate.
You're looking for me.
Am I?
Mm-hmm. I'm Moira
Davidson. M-O-I-R-A.
It was a very fashionable
name in bad novels
when my mother was
young and impressionable.
I'm a throwback.
Where's Holmes? Oh, he's
decking the halls with holly.
He sent me for better or
worse. Better, I’d say.
I'm your date
or whatever you call it.
How'd you recognize me?
I love Americans.
They're so naive.
This way, Commander.
A new model.
Only one horsepower,
but she does a good eight
miles an hour on the flat.
Quite a buggy.
Over 70 years old.
Dad said she was made in
America. I wouldn't be surprised.
Give me your toothbrush. Take Amelia’s head
while I see if we can get us out of here.
She's still a wee bit
sticky in reverse.
All right, boy.
Here we go.
Is there a place we might stop
where I could get a little breakfast?
What?
"A little breakfast."
Do you mean that in
addition to everything else,
I have to watch you eat bacon
and eggs and all that muck?
I was on a party last night, and I got
up at 8:00 in the morning to meet you.
I, uh... oh, never mind. Hop in.
But you have to buy me a
couple drinks to get me started.
Oh, incidentally, they didn't
tell me what to call you.
What's the protocol? My name
is Towers, Dwight Lionel Towers.
Really?
Really. Hang on, Dwight Lionel.
As a matter of fact, we've only
been in port for three days.
It's called the Sawfish. My
second husband was an American.
We traveled
all over the world,
and everywhere we went
he would say to people,
"I am an American.
I am an American."
They finally shot him in one
of those eastern countries.
Oh.
Well, I’m sorry.
I was too. He was such a
nice man while he lasted.
Is he yours, Moira?
Oh, on loan.
Oh.
Weli... toodle.
Toodle.
He just drinks and drinks
and nothing happens.
At least he hasn't burst into
tears. Keep up the good work.
amen!
That's sheer balderdash!
I never heard so much
nonsense in my life.
You mean to tell me,
this whole war was an accident?
No, it wasn't an accident.
I didn't say that.
It was carefully planned, down to the
tiniest mechanical and emotional detail.
But it was a mistake,
it was a beaut.
In the end, somehow granted
the time for examination,
we shall find that our so-called
civilization was gloriously destroyed...
by a handful
of vacuum tubes and transistors.
Probably faulty.
There you are, Julian.
Now we know
where the blame lies.
Oh, no, you don't.
No. No.
Maybe we were the blind
mechanics of disaster,
but you don't pin the guilt
on the scientists that easily.
You might as well
pin it on... motherhood.
It should be pinned
on somebody.
You scientists are the likely
ones as far as I can see.
You built the bomb. You experimented
with it, tested it and exploded it.
Just a moment, Morgan. Thanks to you
chaps, a moment is about all we have.
Every man who ever worked on this
thing told you what would happen.
The scientists signed petition
after petition, Julian, please.
But nobody listened.
There was a choice. It was
build the bombs and use them...
or risk the united states, the
soviet union and the rest of us...
would find some way
to go on living.
That's wishful thinking,
if ever I heard it.
I'm not against
wishful thinking, not now.
They pushed us too far.
They didn't think we'd fight,
no matter what they did.
And they were wrong.
We fought. We expunged them!
We didn't do such a bad job
on ourselves.
With the interesting result that
the background level of radiation...
in this room is nine times
what it was a year ago.
Julian.
Don't you know that?
Nine times!
We're all doomed, you know.
The whole silly, drunken,
pathetic lot of us.
Doomed by the air
we're about to breathe.
We haven't got a chance! Stop it!
I won't have it, Julian!
I won't.
There is hope.
There has to be hope.
There's always hope.
We just can't
go on like this.
We can't.
We... we...
I shouldn't drink,
you know.
I inevitably say
something brilliant.
Sorry.
I...
I can't help it, peter.
I'm sorry.
I just can't.
Everybody's gone to bed.
You like that?
Settles the stomach.
I had a lot to drink.
Julian had
a lot to drink.
Julian and I
are the town drunks.
What are you trying
to forget?
It's a damn silly question
if I ever heard one.
Yeah, you're right.
It's just an expression.
You know... somebody should
have given me a copy...
of the local ground rules.
I might have opened
my big mouth.
Danger struck
from the wrong quarter.
The people of the city
watch the wrong mouse hole.
Come again?
But then who would know you were
so tough and drank straight milk?
Where are you from?
Which state?
I'm from Idaho.
Idaho?
I know better
than that.
There's no navy in Idaho
because it's too hilly.
Well, I was born in Idaho.
I live in Connecticut now.
Near new London,
where I’m based.
Where were you during
all the watchamacallit?
Oh, no. I didn't mean
to ask you that.
Peter said not to.
You don't have to answer.
I can't decide if I’m more
objectionable drunk or sober.
It's perfectly all right.
We were at sea...
between Kiska and Midway,
when it began.
We got orders to go
to the west pacific,
and when we put our nose up
north of Iwo Jima...
the air was filled
with radioactive dust.
So we ducked.
Later on, took a look at
manila... through the periscope.
It was still too hot to surface, so
we came down the coast of Australia...
and ended up here.
There wasn't much
of anyplace else to go.
You look married.
Oh, I am.
My wife's name is Sharon.
I have a couple of kids:
Richard, eight;
Helen, five.
Dick is the real sailor
of the family.
He is going to Annapolis.
Oh, that's to be expected.
He'll probably
change his mind.
Why is it taking so long?
Can you
explain it to me?
Nobody can
explain it to me.
And don't tell me about
those damn winds again.
How the northern hemisphere
and the southern hemisphere...
get all mixed up
and overlap.
I don't want to hear
about that anymore.
All I want to know is...
if everybody was so smart,
why didn't they know
what would happen?
They did.
Well, I...
I can't take it.
I...
Oh, yes, I can take it.
But it's unfair.
It's unfair because
I didn't do anything...
and nobody I know
did anything.
Maybe I’m stupid.
I had to take algebra twice.
The only thing I could
understand was geography.
I like geography.
You know what
I always wanted to do?
I wanted to walk down
the Rue de Rivoli.
Have you ever been to
the Rue de Rivoli? Yes.
I wanted to walk down
the Rue de Rivoli,
and I wanted to buy gloves.
I know the French word
for gloves...
No, you've got it all
backwards. What's that?
I was supposed to comfort you,
and you're comforting me.
I'm crying.
Everybody was so afraid
that you might cry.
They were?
Isn't that funny?
No.
Sometimes I do.
You better go to bed.
Mm-hmm.
But you're in my bedroom.
Oh.
Weli... I’ll clear out.
Dwight.
Even if you don't like me,
would you please hold onto me
just for a moment longer?
This fellow Julian...
I take it that he's English and
here on some kind of scientific job.
What's he do, exactly?
I think professor Jorgenson
should outline his plan...
before we make a decision.
Simply stated, our view,
our strong opinion, is this:
During the last winter
in the northern hemisphere,
rain and snow may have
washed the air, so to speak,
causing the radioactive elements to fall
to the ground more
quickly than anticipated.
But the transfer
of radioactivity to us...
would be progressively
decreased,
and human life could go on here
or, at least, in Antarctica...
that's clear enough,
professor Jorgenson.
It's a hope.
We agree and the government agrees that
it's worth trying to find out, anyhow.
How far north
could a vessel proceed?
Our recommendation is that
the submarine should go...
as far north in the pacific
as possible,
to point barrow, and make the
necessary radioactivity readings.
The prime minister's
instruction, incidentally,
is the Sawfish be exposed
to as few dangers as possible.
Commander,
how about ice that far north?
She's no icebreaker.
We can feel our way.
I make it over 13,000 miles
round trip.
Enough power in your reactor
for that, Commander?
I understand there's a considerable
stockpile of uranium here.
Enough for ten trips
like this.
Wish we had something
we could use it in.
You might try using it
in my car.
Get a load
of the Charlie wheeler.
May I be of assistance? Yes,
I’m looking for Captain Towers.
I'll try to locate him for you.
Paulson, show the lady to Captain
Towers' cabin on the Melbourne.
Thank you very much.
It's a pleasure.
Right this way,
please.
Relax.
Captain.
There's, uh...
somebody to see you.
I asked her to wait
in your stateroom.
Oh.
Hello.
A very nice man
asked me to wait here.
I don't think
he knew what to do with me.
That's debatable.
Did you... did you ask me to
visit your submarine one day?
Hmm... no.
Oh, I couldn't remember.
Oh, in the meantime,
I’ve been snooping.
Regular fish,
these kids.
I'll have to get them a boat
of their own one of these days.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Here, have a cigarette.
I'm glad you came.
Oh...
I just bet you are.
No, I am.
Really.
And I’ll just bet that my crew
didn't mind too much either.
Yes, I have a sneaking suspicion
they didn't mind at all.
Come in.
I see they found you.
Oh, Mr. Chrysler.
See if you can find miss
Davidson something she can wear...
to go down in the Sawfish. Yes, Sir.
I, uh...
I take it
you put me to bed.
Yes. I arrived at that by deduction.
I asked peter and Mary,
and they didn't.
I'm afraid I was
a bit of a mess.
You drank too much brandy.
You passed out.
Yes, I’ve been drinking quite a
bit recently. That's no big secret.
But, you know, I...
I’ve never had it happen
quite like that before.
My obvious job
was to seduce you.
So I suppose
my pride is hurt.
I ought to feel ashamed.
Why did you bother
about me?
There's a regulation
in here somewhere.
It's under "shore duty."
I'll read it to you.
No, tell me.
It says when a young
lady has had so much
to drink, she doesn't
know what she's doing,
you put her to bed...
and go back to the ship.
That's what it says?
That's what it says.
Yes?
Well, this requires quite a comprehensive
change. Are you sure about this?
You can't go down in a submarine
in that ballet costume.
I'll give you five minutes.
Unpack that one next, please.
That one.
Everything under control,
Mr. Osborne? Oh, I guess so.
Blasted idiots sent me
two wrong components.
I'll have to get them
replaced this afternoon.
As long as they're right when
we sail. What is he doing here?
Mr. Osborne's been assigned
by the C. S. I. R...
to look after our health
on the trip. "Health"?
It's your submarine.
Captain...
may I see you a minute, Sir?
Half a second.
Very becoming outfit.
You know, Julian,
they don't allow drinking
on American submarines.
I can't imagine what else
you'd do. Thanks very much.
What are you going to do? Oh, keep an
eye on the weather. Check on radiation.
I guess I’m sort
of a scientific cruise director.
Then it can be
dangerous?
I wouldn't know, really.
A relative question
at best, isn't it?
It seems that everybody
I know is going.
I feel left out.
I can sing and dance.
You'll have to excuse me. The
Admiral is up top. Don't you go away.
It's the damnedest thing.
Started the day before yesterday.
Came on again
ten minutes ago, Sir.
Starts and stops. We've
monitored 60 hours so far.
It's weird. You're sure
it's from San Diego?
Within a 100-mile radius.
It's as close as we're able to
pinpoint it, without triangulation.
Could it be a kid, somebody
who doesn't know morse?
We've made two words, Sir:
"Water" and "connect."
You know the old story about
an infinite number of monkeys...
and an infinite number
of typewriters.
One of them has to end up
writing "King Lear."
I may be cracking up under the
strain, like everybody else,
but this interests me.
It's more than Jorgenson's
theory. It's a fact.
It's impossible,
but it's a fact.
A radio signal is coming from around
san Diego, and they shouldn't be.
There shouldn't even be
any power for transmission.
Hydroelectric?
Yes, possibly.
There has to be an explanation,
and I’d like to know what it is.
Not that I’ll live
any longer for knowing.
How would you like
to track it down?
I'd like it, Sir.
Very well, then.
I've been on
to our electronic wizards.
They tell us you have radio direction
equipment that can be
used from periscope depth.
Is that correct? Yes. It hasn't been
used much. We'll have to run some tests.
I'd like it
to be in the pink.
Perhaps you can amuse yourself
around here a little longer...
until you're ready
to leave.
Hey!
What did you do that for?
We could have won.
They've had it.
Are they all right?
They're all right,
but they're out of the race.
It's like looking
at a French movie.
Dr. Fletcher?
What about these pills
they've got,
whatever they are?
They'll be available from the
chemists' shops on the free list...
when the time comes.
I understand that they
have got them already...
at port Moresby and Darwin.
Apparently.
What's the effect?
Lethargy, then some
euphoria, coma,
then nothing.
In fairly rapid order.
You, uh...
you don't suppose you could
get me a couple?
And... wh-whatever
it is for children?
Not a chance...
until
the time comes.
Sorry, peter.
I'm beginning to twitch
when I hear the word "time."
If for some reason... I’m not
talking about now, I’m just talking...
if there's one thing
you could do...
no.
No, I know what I mean.
When the dentist is drilling your
tooth, what do you think about?
The nicest thing?
Sex? Or what?
Fishing.
Trout fishing in a clean
mountain stream. You would.
Why not go then,
when you come back?
The season doesn't open until September.
I've asked. You think I can't fix that?
You think I don't know
important people,
that I spend all my time
with this moldy suburban set?
You can't mean me. She never bottled
like that before. What happened?
She bottled us.
I was trying to win.
Taking the race too seriously,
not paying enough attention to her.
Truth is,
he made a pass at me.
I had to go overboard in
self-defense. Well, if that...
I like to see the young folks
enjoying themselves.
What?
You never wrestle with me
anymore. What does that mean?
I mean exactly what I say. You
never wrestle with me anymore.
All right.
Peter, really.
You said I never wrestle.
Never mind... for now.
Now, tell them the truth.
But I told them the truth.
Sharon is the most
terrible liar that...
I think it's absolutely
preposterous.
How much of this Gould Campbell
have we got left, Stevens?
Better than
400 bottles, Sir.
And in its prime.
Shocking. Shocking!
Four-hundred bottles of
vintage port in the cellars...
and barely
five months to go.
Five months, mark you! If what
these scientist chaps say is right.
I think it needs
another year, actually.
I blame the wine committee
very much.
Very much, indeed.
Should have had
more foresight.
How can the members be expected to
get through 400 bottles of port...
in five months' time?
Bad planning, I say.
Ridiculous.
I'll take another bottle home
with me today, Stevens. Yes, Sir.
Sir Douglas Froude
is expecting me.
I believe he's in the
bar, Sir. Thank you.
Yes, I’ve heard
about those pills.
This cruise is developing into
something bigger than I thought.
I may not be here
when it happens.
I understand, but if dr.
Fletcher can't get them for you...
I’m not certain I can.
I've tried everything else.
You're my last hope.
You're convinced you want Mary
to have them now?
I've thought about it a great
deal. Yes, Sir. Yes, I do.
Hmm. I'm not certain
you're right...
but considering Mary...
I don't know how much weight I carry
with the government in my old age.
There's a lot of bureaucracy
still, you know? Even in death.
But take this around anyway
and see what happens.
Thank you.
The wine committee is mad,
absolutely mad.
Four hundred bottles
of vintage port.
Too late.
Sorry, Dykers.
Good show. Carry on.
As a matter of fact, the whole
thing is due to the wine committee...
having failed to conserve
their supplies properly.
If they'd only regulated
their...
oh, how nice.
Have you noticed Moira isn't
drinking so much? I wonder why?
No, I hadn't noticed.
Peter?
Mm-hmm?
Could we afford an
electric mower for the lawn?
A very little one I could
start myself while you're away?
Doris Haymes has one.
She does?
Well, she's cut the cord three times
and nearly electrocuted herself.
Besides, darling,
I doubt there's any left.
What's that?
Sit down.
This is something I want you
to know about before I go.
You're going to be serious?
I wish you wouldn't.
I wish
I didn't have to be.
Now, darling, this is
a big cruise we're going on.
There will be mines
and ice to contend with.
Peter, I knew when I married you that
you were going to be a naval officer.
My father died at sea.
You know that.
We just don't have to
discuss it, do we?
We have to discuss this, Mary, because
there isn't any tradition for this.
Peter... you're going to listen
whether you like it or not.
Now, this is
a special kind of...
sleeping pill.
I had a devil of a time
getting them,
but I wanted you
to have them on hand...
and make sure you knew
how to use them.
What happens with the
radiation is that you get ill.
You start feeling sick,
and then you are sick...
and you go on
being sick.
You can't
keep anything down.
You may feel better for a
while, but it always comes back.
You get weaker.
And this cures it?
Darling, you know
nothing cures it.
This ends it.
But, peter...
however ill I was,
I couldn't do that.
Who'd look after Jennifer?
Jenny will get it too.
You're not trying to tell me
you want me to kill Jennifer?
Mary, don't be an idiot!
Supposing you get it first?
What are you going to do? Struggle
by yourself until you drop?
Jenny might live for days and be helpless
in her crib with you dead on the floor!
Don't you see that?
Don't you see it?
Darling...
I’m sorry.
I can't believe it myself half the time.
Let's not discuss it
any more right now, peter.
Anyway, Mrs. Hildreth's husband was
talking to someone the other day...
who said it isn't
coming here after all.
He says it's slowing... for god's
sake, Hildreth's a damn fool!
???? [continues
let's go.
Would you like
another drink?
No, let's go
for a walk.
All right.
You know, I think I’ve
discovered why you fascinate me.
Shall I tell you?
Uh-huh.
Because you take me
for granted.
I know women aren't supposed to like
that sort of thing, but somehow I do.
I've been treated
in every other way...
like a child...
and sometimes like...
like things
I’ve probably deserved...
but I’ve never been pushed
around in such a nice way...
and treated
something like a wife.
I suppose what I mean is...
like an American wife.
Moira, this isn't going to
do us any... no, hear me out.
I was hurt at first when I realized
you were mixing me up with Sharon.
And then I realized that it was one of
the nicest things that could happen to me.
I wouldn't really mind if you
could forget entirely who I am.
I don't like myself
very much anyway.
Wouldn't you like to try?
No.
It seemed
like a good idea.
I suppose it wasn't.
There's a train leaving
at 10:50.
I think I’ll take it.
You see, in the navy,
during the war,
I got used to the idea that something
might happen to me, I might not make it.
I also got used
to the idea...
of my wife and children...
safe at home.
They'd be all right,
no matter what.
What I didn't reckon with
was that in this...
this kind of a monstrous war...
something might happen
to them...
and not to me.
Well, it did...
and I can't...
I can't cope with it.
My kids...
all the planning since
the day they were born.
Sharon...
Sharon and I, we...
weli...
see, we were the sort
of people who...
we would have been happy
to grow old together.
I-I can't accept it.
I can't...
does that make any sense?
Do you understand?
Yes.
It makes sense.
I understand.
Good night.
I am sorry
to see this.
And you were doing
so much better too.
I would like to come in,
whatever this is.
An opium den
more than likely.
How on earth
did you find me?
What is it?
It's a Ferrari.
Does it run?
"Does it run?"
She won the grand prix
last year.
Bought it from Simonelli's widow.
Gave her a hundred quid for it.
What are you going to do
with it? Race it, of course.
You? Me. You needn't
sound so pessimistic.
I've always wanted to,
just never could afford it.
Sixth of august, if the
Commander gets me back in time.
You're going
to kill yourself.
It's possible.
Julian?
Hmm?
When was it you were
in love with me and I...
and you were so stupid
about it?
And I was so stupid
about it.
You should have grabbed me.
I'm about to be extinct.
I came here tonight, Julian,
because I want to know...
are you stili...
I’m serious.
In a normal world, I think I
would still be in love with you.
Yes or no, Julian?
But lately,
with so little time left,
my sense of values
seem to have changed.
No, then?
I'm such a fake, such a lot
of meaningless talk.
Now, now, don't say
that. Yes, it's true.
There have been men,
lots of men.
Every time one fell out,
there was always a replacement.
But not one of them
meant anything to me.
I can't pretend
any longer, Julian.
I'm afraid.
I have nobody,
and I’m afraid.
What about Dwight?
He's married.
He's married
to a girl named Sharon,
and they have two children.
Mm-hmm, I know.
But if things were different,
if she were alive,
I’d do anything...
any mean trick I know
to get him.
Even if I could make him forget,
there isn't time.
No time to love...
and nothing to remember.
Nothing worth remembering.
I can't go home tonight,
Julian.
May I stay here with you?
It's late, and I have to pick
up some things before we leave.
Leave...
you're leaving?
At 6:00 this morning.
He didn't tell you.
Come on.
I'll take you home.
Depth: 56 feet, Sir.
I recommend course 045,
Captain.
Right rudder,
new course: 045.
right rudder, new course:
045, Sir. Check sonar.
Fogerty,
how's it look topside?
All clear for about a mile,
scattered icebergs.
Well, this looks
like the spot.
All stop.
Up periscope.
Okay.
I got point barrow.
Bearing:
130 relative.
Distance: About seven
miles. Aye, aye, Sir.
All right, Mr. Osborne. You
can take your readings now.
Chief, raise the E. C. M. Aye, aye, Sir.
E. C. M. Fully extended, Sir.
It's hot,
isn't it?
It's hotter than it is
in mid-pacific,
at least 30 points
in the red.
That takes care
of Jorgenson’s theory.