Cinema Service
and Unikorea presents
in association with
MBC Production
a Miracin Korea production
THE TURNING GATE
Kyungsoo receives
a phone call from Sungwoo
Hello?
Is this Kim Kyungsoo?
Yes, who's this?
It's me.
Sungwoo,
How are you?
Oh, Sungwoo?
How long has it been!
You're hard to reach!
Guess you've been busy?
Good to hear from you.
Where are you, in Seoul?
I'm in Chuncheon.
I finally saw your film today!
Nice job!
You did?
Are you still writing?
Yeah.
My writer friends
and I saw your film on video.
They say you're great!
Few have seen my film.
I'm sitting next
to a big fan of yours!
A dance instructor!
Want to talk to her?.
Stop it...
Yeah.
Thanks... for calling.
Come visit me in Chuncheon.
We share some great memories.
I'll take good care of you.
So just come, okay?
Okay... Thanks.
I will go next time.
Really.
I'm not kidding.
We have great people here
in Chuncheon!
Kyungsoo goes to the film company
and has a quarrel with the director
Hello?
It's me.
Why did you just leave?
I waited.
You came back out?
After how long?
I have... something
to apologize for.
We can't cast you in
my film this time.
So, it's final?
Yeah, I think so.
The company's already been
working on the casting.
Star quality is
important, after all.
They blame you
for the last film's failure.
I'm sorry for keeping you
waiting for so long.
It's okay.
I didn't expect much.
I didn't feel you were
doing your best.
Anyway, can I shave now?
Shave?
Yes, of course.
Shave, as you wish.
Sorry about that.
Here.
Thanks.
I'm only getting my share.
What a sum to lose face over!
Aren't you aware
of the company's losses?
The company and staff are all
making sacrifices for my sake.
How could you take
a running guarantee?
I'm appalled.
How could you be
so thoughtless?
I'm suffering as much as you!
Who cares about the company!
They'll continue working with you!
I'm the one who's in a rut!
You're in no position to speak.
I'm going away.
See you later.
Kyungsoo...
Even though it's difficult
to be a human being.
let's not turn into
monsters, okay?
Who do you think you are,
a film director?!
Kim Kyungsoo!
Sungwoo.
Amazing how quickly
you rushed over here.
Great to see you, too.
You've put on
so much weight!
Yeah?
Did you have lunch?
Yeah, it's been so long.
Brings back memories.
You haven't changed.
How can you be the same?
What's there to change...?
Shouldn't you be busy?
I always get stage parts...
But I'm waiting
for something better.
It's film I really want to get into.
Let's go.
We'll talk on the way.
You've put on so much weight!
I'm trying to slim down,
but nothing seems to work.
Was I drunk
when I called yesterday?
No, I had something
on my mind.
I really wanted to see you.
Really?
Of course.
Tired?
Who are you living with?
Living alone?
No, with my cousin,
her husband and
their daughter.
The farm's my cousin's.
So, it isn't yours?
My cousin's been running it
since my father's death.
So, who owns the place?
It's mine...
but, it's really my cousin's.
I see.
That man, walking
in front of us...
Who?
Who is he?
My cousin's husband.
I see.
Tired?
No.
I feel great.
Good?
This is really good.
It's not your everyday
chicken gruel.
It's got everything in it.
I love chicken gruel,
but this is really good.
It's not any ordinary
chicken gruel.
Anyway, tomorrow morning,
you'll see.
Huh?
Wait and see.
Everything's in it.
What?
Guaranteed erection.
Sungwoo.
Finished eating?
Where's your husband?
We need a ride.
Do you need it now?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I really enjoyed your cooking...
I'd like to pay you for it.
Don't bother.
But it's from your diner...
Besides, I really enjoyed it.
Really, it's okay.
Sungwoo, tell him to drop it
okay?
What?
I just wanted to pay
for the meal.
Come in now.
This place is colder
than Seoul.
Yeah?
Not that much.
I'm dragging you out, huh?
Don't say that.
The air here is clearly
different from Seoul's.
Let's play!
Rock! Paper! Scissors!
Okay! You!
It's your turn!
Hey!
Drink up, or take it off.
Stop drinking. Let's play!
Drink up!
Goddamn it!
Wait.
New bottles coming!
Give me, whatever.
Give him a bottle!
You're such a sissy!
You damn alcoholic!
Why do you sway so much!
Can't you see I'm naked?
I've got to quit now, I'm serious.
Take your pants off!
Let's tickle him.
Let's take them off for him.
Get off of me!
Take off your pants!
Asshole!
Get off of me.
Why do you fucking
sway like that?
Game's over, now!
Get up!
Move.
Isn't that what
you want us to do?
Fuck!
Is this Kim Kyungsoo...?
Yes.
What's wrong?
Why didn't you answer?.
Where are you?
Why did you pay the bill?
I'm leaving for Seoul.
Seoul?
Why?
Where the hell are you?
You can't go
to Seoul at this hour!
How the hell will you get there?!
You asshole!
Do you realize
how happy I was to see you!
Kim Kyungsoo!
What's wrong with you!
Come here.
Come here!
Even though it's difficult
to be a human being,
let's not turn into monsters.
Myungsuk tells Kyungsoo
that she loves him
His name is Daengchil.
Daengchil?
Yes.
What's your name?
Choi Heerah.
Who named you?
My grandfather did.
Who do you prefer,
your mommy or your daddy?
Both, mommy and daddy.
Come over here.
Is this a duck?
No, it's a goose.
-A goose?
-Yes.
A big goose, isn't it?
Let's go!
My God!
Are you all right?
Is she hurt?
It's okay.
She jammed her finger
Is it serious?
Don't cry.
Open the door!
I think she's really in pain.
Can you bear it?
It'll be okay.
You used to be
a playboy, right?
Never!
You meet this girl
who's far from your type,
and suddenly she becomes
a woman to you.
That girl's too young for you.
That's not what I mean.
Just that I once liked
a girl like that.
She looks like
a college freshman.
She seems to be
on her own.
Yeah, it appears so.
The water level
used to be much higher.
Hello.
What a surprise
to meet you here.
Why, hello.
How have you been?
What a coincidence.
Here sightseeing?
Are you going
to Chungpyung Temple?
Yes, and you?
Yes.
What a coincidence.
How do you do?
So does the Turning Gate
really turn?
No, it's just like any old gate,
there's not much to see.
Then why are we going there?
Just for the ferry ride.
Who are they?
Another time...
I'll tell you about the Turning Gate.
You know the
Chinese Emperor Taejong?
He had a daughter.
There was a young commoner
who became lovesick over her.
Enraged, the king beheaded
the commoner.
But this commoner
reincarnated into a snake.
which wrapped its body
around the princess.
She was on the verge
of death.
A Taoist priest told her
to seek Chungpyung
Temple in Korea.
She went there
and in front of the Chungpyung
Temple, she told the snake:
"I'll return with some food,
so wait for me here."
The princess went inside
and never came out.
So the snake went after her.
Suddenly, there was rain,
lightning and thunder.
Terrified, it ran away.
The gate from which the snake
turned back from was called
the Turning Gate.
Excuse me!
We're not going
to the temple.
See you another time.
I see, goodbye then.
Good day.
Who are they?
I'm not comfortable
with them.
They run a bag factory.
We've missed the Turning Gate.
You wanted to see it?
There's nothing much to see.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, I was just joking.
Too many drinks last night.
I'm not feeling well anyway.
Me neither.
It's the Turning Gate
that's turning us back.
Myungsuk.
Why, hello.
How have you been?
But we met the other day.
Are you coming
from Lake Soyang?
Hello.
Did you have lunch?
Not yet. What about you?
I'm on a diet.
I've put on so much weight.
You look fine to me.
No, I have a fat tummy.
Where is the studio?
It's shabby, but my teacher
is attached to this place.
Coffee?
I'd love some.
How about you?
Yes, please.
Would you like
to see me dance?
I'd love to.
Yes.
I'll show you then.
I really should be wearing a skirt.
This is modern dance.
This is traditional dance.
This is salsa.
Done?
That was great.
You're a good dancer.
Thank you.
Do you have a boyfriend?
A boyfriend?
It's been 5 years
since we broke up.
No one else since?
He...
I guess it was too hard for me.
At first, his innocence
attracted me.
But gradually I saw
my father in him.
Your father?
Yes.
My father was quite liberal,
just not to family and women.
I'm okay now. Because...
I realized that life isn't easy
for everyone else either.
Since then, I've been trying
to live life to the fullest.
What is it you want to do?
She's dancing, isn't she?
Me?
You know.
People who tumble in the air.
That's what.
Really?
Yes, I really will someday!
Can I borrow your lighter?
Lighter?
Here.
Thank you, I appreciate it.
Wonderful.
Try a Korean song.
You're truly wonderful.
Stop worrying about driving,
and drink up.
No, I'll pass today.
I have to drive.
No drivers-for-hire here.
Don't overdo yourself too.
No drivers-for-hire here?
No.
Excuse me.
No drivers-for-hire here?
You're a strong drinker.
I drink because I like the taste.
I see...
Why don't we...
Let's kiss to break the ice.
Sleep well.
I'll bring your car
tomorrow morning.
Aren't you getting out?
What?
Then Sungwoo, good night.
What do we do?
He'll be back later, I guess.
I think he misunderstood.
Care for another drink?
No, I had too much already.
Chuncheon is colder.
Are you worried?
What are you thinking
about now?
Now?
Since this afternoon.
Since we met?
I was so happy
when I heard you were here.
Really? Thank you.
I even prayed for it, really.
To meet you.
I love the expression on your face!
Can you see it?
Yes.
Want to go home?
We've come too far.
From now on, no more lies.
Okay.
Here.
What's wrong?
Don't you want to
show your face?
Yes.
Kyungsoo waits for
Sungwoo all day long
You don't have one?
Yes, but it's a bit funny.
What is it?
Supergirl.
Supergirl?
I'm strong.
I don't get tired easily.
Strong?
It seems to run in my family.
And my uncle can even carry
80kgs of rice using one hand.
Really?
You're so cute.
I hate that word.
Why?
I hate it.
Can't you find a better one?
Like what...?
You don't love me, do you?
Love?
To me, love is just liking a lot.
You don't love me.
Come here.
Come.
Stop it.
You don't love me anyway.
lf it only leaves bad memories, then stop.
Let go.
It really hurts!
Really?
Ah, that feels good...
You're so great.
You could please any woman
if you do this...
lf you're not going home,
how about a hot meal?
Okay.
Why don't we go to the farm
and get Sungwoo.
Okay.
It is a bit of a walk
from the taxi.
Yes, it is.
Let's tell him we talked
all night at a street bar.
Do as you wish.
That tree looks like
it was struck by lightening.
You don't eat meat at all, do you?
It tastes okay for hotel food.
Yeah? I'm glad.
Get some rest.
Are you okay?
How about you?
I think he really trusts you.
You think so?
Yes.
Get some rest.
The same with you.
Scott Nearing's
"The Making of a Radical"
Come out for lunch.
Yes, thank you.
Over there, at our place.
Okay.
Sungwoo's not in yet, is he?
He's still out.
I don't get it,
abandoning his guest like this...
Hello?
It's me, Myungsuk.
Yes, hello.
I'm at the dance studio.
I see...
Wait a moment.
I can talk now.
I can't do anything.
It's so hard to practice dancing,
I can't focus.
What should I do?
Really?
When do you finish, today?
Today?
I can't meet you today.
I have an appointment.
We'll go drinking.
I see.
It's a writers' gathering, you see.
We'll probably have drinks.
We should make it another day.
I'm leaving tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow morning?
I'll call you another time.
We can meet
in Seoul or something.
If you don't tell me you love me,
I'll never see you again!
Say something...
What should I say?
Say anything.
So I can hear your voice.
What should I say...
Tell me you love me.
You don't want to, do you?
No.
I'm hanging up.
Okay.
Hello?
It's me, Myungsuk.
Yes.
Life is a challenge!
What?
Do you know where I am?
No.
I'm in a motel.
A man's in the shower.
I see.
What should I do?
I called to ask you.
Follow your own judgment.
That's not it.
Want to know whom I'm with?
Is it Sungwoo?
Yes, you're right.
What should I do?
Is he taking a shower?
Yes, I told him to.
We haven't even kissed yet.
Even though it's difficult
to be a human being,
let's not turn into monsters.
Okay.
I'm hanging up!
Yes...
I'm sorry.
Bitch!
What a bitch!
Fucking bitch!
Kyungsoo meets
Sunyoung on the train
Take it.
Thanks.
I'm sorry.
You spent a lot the other night.
Is this enough?
Of course.
I'm going home anyway.
The Wonju-Busan train
only runs twice a day.
So off the bus,
go straight to the station.
I know.
Thanks for the T-shirt.
Are you sure about
giving this to me?
Yes.
The color suits you.
Yeah?
You're here.
What time's your bus?
I have 1 5 min. left.
Why are you
wearing sunglasses?
Last night, I cried too much.
My eyes are really swollen.
Are you okay?
Take them off.
But, they're so swollen...
Leave them off. You're fine.
It's better with them on.
I have a present for you.
I had no time to shop,
so I brought something
from home.
It's cologne I bought in Shanghai.
This is a photo of me.
Thank you.
Your phone's not working,
have you checked my message?
No, yesterday it got
wet in the rain.
It needs to be fixed.
I see...
You can't fix a wet
phone, can you?
Check my message later.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Let's really talk next time
Okay.
What's that on your neck?
What?
You should have told me...
about your relationship with her.
You didn't say anything.
Did you ask Myungsuk to come?
No, I only mentioned
I am leaving this morning.
But here she is.
It bothers you, doesn't it?
Kyungsoo.
Don't ask for more than
a man can take!
Yeah.
I know.
This is enough.
Let's say our goodbyes here
Goodbye.
But, l...
It's really okay.
I need to talk to Sungwoo.
So just stay here.
Goodbye.
Are you an artist?
No, why do you ask?
No, you just seem like one.
I see.
Are you good at Go?
Not really. Just a bit.
How about a game?
No, I can't play.
She's beautiful.
Is that your girlfriend?
I don't have one yet.
Then why do you
carry that photo?
She's a real beauty.
Would you like to have it?
What for?
It was given to me.
It's not mine.
You can have it.
Then, who is this woman?
There's a name on the back.
Wishing eternal happiness
and good health to you.
Keeping the precious memories
we've shared.
You in me. Me in you.
So precious to me.
Myungsuk.
Hello.
What? Hello.
So nice to meet you.
Yes.
Where's your stop?
Kyungju.
Kyungju...
Are you traveling alone?
Yes, I'm going home.
Where do you live?
I live in Seoul,
but my parents are in Busan.
Busan?
I'm getting off at Kyungju...
Do you know me?
Yes!
I've seen you perform
on stage, Kyungsoo.
How do you know my name?
I'm quite flattered.
I think you are a good actor.
I guess you've seen my plays.
Yes, I have.
You were great in some.
But I shouldn't flatter
you so much.
Of course not.
Kyungsoo!
You're really into that book.
Have you read it?
Yes.
They say the author lived
to be 1 00,
but took his own life
by starving himself.
That book changed
the life of someone I know.
I see...
You're so absorbed in it...
There's a bar inside the game cart.
Will you join me for a beer?
No, thank you.
Then...
I just wanted to say goodbye.
Good luck with your acting.
Stay as passionate as you were
when you first started out.
I really appreciate it.
Now I've embarrassed myself.
Goodbye.
Mom, Sunyoung!
Open the door!
Mom, it's Sunyoung!
I like your garden.
It's not much.
How long are you staying?
Well...
I'm not sure yet.
I'll be here today
and tomorrow.
I'll let you know later.
Whatever you want.
Where can I wash my face?
Wash up? Over there.
Was it that hard...
to call from Seoul?
I was busy... with school.
You do understand?
So, you couldn't even spare
1 0 min. to call me?
That happens when you're busy...
Drink up.
Don't think too much of it.
Excuse me.
Hey, you...
What's your problem?
Can't you see her sitting there?
I'm sorry.
Wait.
What are you doing?
What were you looking at?
Nothing...
Asshole, where's your
fucking manners?
I wasn't staring at anything.
Stop it!
Take it easy.
Just sit and drink up, asshole!
Sit!
What about your college degree?
You've come this far...
It's just for self-satisfaction...
Excuse me.
That picture.
where can I find one like that?
Like that, I don't know.
I see...
Kyungsoo recognizes Sunyoung
as an old acquaintance
Excuse me!
Who are you?
Is this where Sunyoung lives?
Yes, she does.
Can I help you?
Can I see her for a moment?
She's here...
but who are you?
I'm Kim Kyungsoo.
- Kim Kyungsoo?
- Yes.
Okay. Wait here...
What brings you here?
How did you find me?
You're home.
Yes.
I've come too early...
Who are you?
I've come to see Sunyoung.
What for?
Do you know him?
Yes.
We've met, before...
He's an actor.
Actor?
What kind of actor?
You left this book on the train.
He's a friend
You can go now mother.
You're returning her book?
This book's yours?
Yes.
What kind of book is it?
It's yours?
Can I talk to you for a moment?
Talk about what?
Can we go somewhere else to talk?
About what?
Talk right here!
I'm listening.
Mother, go inside.
It won't take long,
What is there to talk about?
Please.
It really won't take very long...
Sunyoung, shall we go over there?
Where?
It's so strange...
Why don't you talk inside?
Yes, talk inside the house.
Be quiet!
I'll talk to him.
It won't take long.
Have I imposed on you?
Yes, you have.
Really, I've never done anything
like this before.
Is that so?
Never!
I'm sorry, but mother's waiting.
I'll be straight with you.
After meeting you,
I wanted to tell you
how beautiful you are.
I'm not beautiful, Kyungsoo.
Sunyoung, you are to me!
I'm flattered to hear this
from a handsome man.
What?
It doesn't matter how...
I want to see you again.
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
They'll get the wrong idea.
About what?
Go now.
Can I have your mobile number?
It's 01 7-204-1 61 7.
01 7-204-1 61 7?
Yes.
You're going home now,
aren't you?
Goodbye.
Don't rush!
You're here.
Hello.
What time is your train?
I'm leaving soon.
How soon?
In about 1 5 min.
Were you going somewhere?
Just to get some cosmetics.
I didn't know what time
you were leaving...
I hope you didn't feel
insulted by my mother.
No.
She's like a child.
Yes.
I see you were sucking
on these flowers.
You saw me?
Yes.
I did the same thing
in kindergarten.
There were so many
in the front yard.
What are they called?
Salvia
Right.
Thank you.
They're all withered, not too many left.
Here's one.
Want to try?
Thank you.
How much are these?
3,000 won.
Shall we go that way?
That way?
Would you like to hear an old story?
An old story?
Have you ever been
to Taeneung?
Taeneung? The one in Seoul?
I may have, many years ago.
What for?
I just used to go there,
but not recently...
And the Chinese restaurant there?
Chinese restaurant?
Don't you remember?
Chinese restaurant...
What Chinese restaurant?
Then...
the day at the pool on a rainy day?
Where, in Taeneung?
The outdoor pool
near the National athlete's pool.
I remember the place.
So, you saw me there?
You're not lying, are you?
Why would I lie to you?
We met there!
You saved me from the bullies,
posing as my friend.
You were in middle school.
Then your friends and mine
all had Chinese food together.
We did?
The next morning
you came to my house.
Your house?
Yes, in Seoul!
You did the exact same thing!
Like you came looking for me
this morning!
Don't you remember?
Yes...
I remember...
I do recall something like that.
You're saying that was you?
You remember now?
Yes, I think so.
But your face...
I'm amazed.
That's why I said it was strange.
That's why I've been
seeing your plays.
I see.
But I just don't recognize your face.
I'm so sorry...
It happens,
that was more than 1 5 years ago.
Anyway, I'm amazed.
Isn't it amazing?
By the way, this place
seems quite empty, doesn't it?
Yes.
It's strange,
whenever I enter
an empty restaurant,
it soon fills up with customers.
How about you?
The same happens with taxis.
A cabbie once told me,
"Hey, you seem to attract people."
I tried to tell you earlier,
that I'm married.
What? I had no idea...
My husband's a professor
at Andong University.
When he was young,
they called him a genius.
Life became difficult
with his involvement
in political activism.
Times have changed,
now he is respected for his past.
Strange, isn't it?
I see.
Is it your fault?
No.
Watch your fingers.
Okay.
Move!
Why do you sway so much?
It calms me.
It also helps me stay sober.
When I am down.
I do it back and forth.
You've got such thin ankles.
How did you notice?
They are a bit thin.
They're so pretty.
I have to wear the
right length skirts.
lf not, I look very awkward,
because I'm a bit heavy on top.
I remember now.
You remember, now?
Yes.
You moved your hand like that
at that Chinese restaurant.
Probably so, it's a habit of mine.
Now, I remember!
I really remember your face.
This is great!
It makes you that happy?
Yes, your hand motion
brings back everything.
You must really remember now.
I'm glad.
Drink up, to celebrate.
I'll drink from the bottle.
I wish we could be alone.
I won't lay a finger on you.
I promise.
I won't, okay?
Take us to a decent motel, please?
Which one do you mean?
Concord Hotel, please.
Concord Hotel?
Yes.
Your signature please.
Have a pleasant stay.
Gently, or with force?
Which do you prefer?
Either way.
How do you like this move?
You lied to me, Kyungsoo.
Yes.
Please don't ejaculate inside me.
No, of course not.
How do you like my moves?
I don't want to get pregnant.
Of course.
Don't worry.
I love you.
Me too.
Kyungsoo is reminded
of the Turning Gate's snake
Where are you going?
You're awake?
I have to attend my cousin's
wedding with my mother.
I have a headache!
A headache?
Then get some medicine.
Yes.
I'll be back before noon.
Will you wait?
I will.
Get some sleep.
Wait.
Come over here.
Can I take them off?
It doesn't matter.
Those things are everywhere.
Nature always seems
indifferent to us.
But the sight of you sleeping
and the fresh vigor of the morning
overwhelms me
with the wholeness of the world.
Me in you! You in me!
Nobody home?
Everyone's inside.
Can I help you?
Excuse me!
What are you doing?
Can you speak English?
Catch!
Here's string for you.
Thank you.
What's this for?
Yes, thank you.
What's the persimmon for?
I'm trying to punish a fraud,
but I just might be
wasting my time.
"I hereby charge you
"with hypocrisy, deception,
and cowardliness..."
Real persimmon/Word "persimmon"
"Your wife, suspecting
the lack of truthfulness
in your name,
in your occupation
and your façade,
has written a note
to another man which
I've attached."
Nature always seems
indifferent to us.
Go now.
Drive safely.
Bye.
I'll call you.
Okay.
Take care.
Yes, go now.
Can I see you for a moment?
What is it you want?
You weren't answering your phone.
Should I just give up?
Wait here. I'll check inside.
I'll wait here.
I forgot to bring my wallet.
It's okay.
It's so funny.
This has never happened
to me before.
It's because you drink too much.
Alcohol does this?
Does your husband
work in Chuncheon?
No.
I think I've seen him there.
What?
When I was in Chuncheon.
I saw him with a woman
in a duck paddle boat.
My husband?
How do you know him?
I think I met him this morning.
Why did you meet him?
I just did by chance.
No, I think I'm wrong.
Koreans all look alike.
Could you stop talking about him?
He's not like us.
He has something
that most people lack.
He truly lives for others.
I'm sorry, but I don't
believe in that.
Stop it.
I could have been mistaken.
I went to Chuncheon
when I was in university.
They tell you to travel alone
when you're a freshman.
Have you been to Lake Soyang?
Yes.
Nice there, isn't it?
I remember it so vividly.
Everything stirred me
like a newborn child.
A little frightening as well.
I skipped the ferry
after hesitating for a while.
I took that ferry.
You did?
Two men followed me.
I think one of them was nice.
I skipped the ferry because of him.
Sunyoung, I love you.
Really?
There's nothing more
I can wish from a woman.
Do you like my breasts?
Yes, a lot.
You want me to help you?
It's okay.
Want to die together?
Why?
I don't want sex anymore,
just die, pure and innocent.
Nice, isn't it.
Hello.
Do you read fortunes?
Yes, why do you ask?
How much do you charge?
Why?
Why do you want it read?
No need for it...
How much do you charge?
As much as you'd like.
You don't seem to need it.
Would you like to try?
Come in...
Age 30.
Born in 72, May 9th, Lunar year.
Luck opens up for you
from this year.
Next year, all four gates will open.
Fame and fortune will grow
as you wish.
All people of the secular world
will look up to you.
From next year,
your wishes will be your command.
Are you married?
Yes, I am.
What does your husband do?
He teaches at a national university,
a kind of public officer.
You've met a good person.
His age?
Date of birth?
June 23rd , Lunar year.
Your husband also foresees good luck.
Your husband's luck begins
this year, for a 3-yr peak.
Great luck it is.
He will acquire high dignity
which commands over people.
I see great fortune awaiting him.
Both of you were destined
to experience early hardship.
You have passed that.
Now is the beginning.
From now on you will enjoy
his good fortune.
Support him well as a good wife.
Good fortune is coming your way.
What about him?
I've already read his, haven't l?
His fate is like a Buddhist priest.
Destined to turn his back
to the secular world,
he has bad ties with others,
and foresees 3 years of bad luck.
September and October
are his dark month.
I see a knife touching his body.
He should be very careful
for the next 2 months.
Anyway, take good care
of your husband
and luck will come your way.
Fortune hovers over
your household.
It takes a decade to find
a fortune like this.
Goodbye.
Aren't you coming?
What's wrong?
Where are you going?
Then, I'm leaving.
Will you wait for me?
I'll return with some money.
Will you?
Wait for me here.
Cast :
KlM Sangkyung
CHU Sangmi
YEA Jiwon
KlM Haksun
Crew :
Executive Producer :
AHN Byungjoo, CHOI lngee
Production Executive : KlM Junjong
Producer : Hanna LEE
Written and directed by :
HONG Sangsoo
Camera : CHOI Youngtaek
Lighting : CHOI Sugjea
Recording : AHN Sangho
Editor : HAM Sungwon
Sound Supervisor : OH Wonchul
Assistant Directors :
KlM Jaehan, JANG Kisoo
Line Producer : PARK Kyungduk
Script supervisor : KlM Nary