Joe?
Are you in there?
Dammit!
- Hi.
- Hi!
- Oh, they're so pretty...
- Thank you!
Hi!
Rob, have you seen Joe?
- Joe? No!
No, no...
God!
You look all right!
You are beautiful!
You're glowing.
You're the one
that's glowing!
Just look at you!
I'm just so dressed up.
You walk like...
You're wearing your soul
like something inside out today!
- Yeah!
- Fuck you and don't fuck you!
- Oh Tony!
- Hi, Mom!
Is dad here?
Did you see him at all?
No, no. I have no idea
where daddy might be.
Hi!
Joe?
The baby is crying.
Joe!
What are you doing?
I'm down in my car, Marilyn!
Come on in here!
It's nothing.
Hello, Joe.
Your booby prize!
You're not goin' to wear it?
No, you are!
Something borrowed, something blue,
something new...
Hey!
Something small, something cheap,
something plastic...
Stop that!
You know you guys are next.
Oh, who gives a shit!
I'm having an affair...
You are not!
Oh yeah!
I don't believe you.
Oh God!
I'm not listening to this!
With a mutual friend!
Maaa!
- Shut up, will you!
- Maaa!
Wait, you're getting
married in one second!
Please! I'm not goin'
to see him anymore...
- Maaa!
- After I'm married. Besides...
If you were having an affair,
if you'd know it's great!
- It's Jim, is't it?
- Okay honey, are you ready?
Shit!
Mom!
It is not time yet,
there's not...
I mean, it's really on...
it's really...
Really, really, going to be...
Honey, if you don't want to do this,
you don't have to!
And you haven't to be
embarrassed or anything...
I'll just go down there
and tell them!
- Ma!
Okay.
I just wanted to make sure.
Let's go, then!
- Good going.
- I will.
- Bye.
I love you, daddy.
I love you, sweetheart.
Peter, will you...
Tony...
What odd kind of shoes
are those?
Now, by the powers
vested in me...
By the state of Massachusetts...
I now pronounce you
man and wife.
And you may kiss your bride!
Thank you!
- Peter!
- I did it!
Okay, here we go!
That counts!  That counts!
It's the real thing!
You want to be smart?
Get that boyfriend
of yours over here...
Pour champagne, and set
the date right now!
Shall I...?
Crazy ritual, uh?
Renata!
You are lovely!
You must really be getting it today
being the only unmarried Bella.
But let me tell you...
There's still time!
- That's great, aunt!
- Sis!
Joe!
I'm sorry about this.
It's not a problem,
no problem.
Why don't you look at me?
Look at you?
I'm looking!
At you,
right at you!
- Can I get something to drink?
- Of course!
Hoy Rob!
Take a little advice
from me, will you?
You...
You would thrive
in marriage.
Am I right, Joe?
- That's right!
- All right...
Pressured, uh?
As if I'm not being pressured?
What?
Everybody is not stupid,
you know?
You gave me that sapphire necklace
as an engagement ring...
- You said it yourself!
- Yeah!
And I noticed
Jan is wearing it now.
It really makes me feel much closer
to her, now I know...
She's wearing it.
I don't care one way or another,
if we get married or not.
But you should know
you look like a worm.
A spineless worm!
A worm? Hey!
- I am being as sociable here as...
- Hello! Excuse me everyone!
Could I get your attention,
for a second please?
I 'm not going to take
too much time up here.
I just wanted to say, uh...
Before I say anything else,
I just wanted to say...
If my mother
were alive today...
She'd be happy...
Very proud.
I miss Ma!
What the hell...
Hey, Rob.
How is it going, buddy?
I am a worm.
I am a spineless worm.
So am I
Jan, baby...
I'm going to sing
a song just for you.
Whenever you're down...
And there's going to be times
when  you're down...
I want you to remember
your our old man...
And this song.
You've got to give a little...
Take a little...
And let your poor heart
break a little...
That's the story of...
That's the glory of love...
You've got to laugh a little...
Cry a little...
Before the clouds
roll by a little...
That's the story of...
That's the glory of love...
As long as there's
the two of us...
We've got the world
and all of it's charms...
And when this world
is through with us...
We've got each other's arms...
You've got to win a little...
Lose a little...
And always have
the blues a little...
That's the story of...
That's the glory of...
Love...
I...
Saw a good job
in the newspaper.
I'm starving!
You go to St. Maarten...
And get trained to sell
condos to people in Boston.
You could make a of money
with that, Rob!
Do you want anything?
Huh?
Ren?
What's the matter?
Stop crying!
I just want a house...
And a big, important job.
And I want you to...
Fall on your knees
and beg me to marry you.
I want you to say:
"You're the woman
who will change my life."
I could, you know?
I think my life is pretty good!
Is that sapphire...
An engagement promise?
That's what you said it was...
There is no question about it.
Are you ever...
Happy about...
No, listen to me.
Listen to me.
Do you intend
to ever marry me?
Tell me.
Tell me!
- Oh, baby!
- Oh, baby.
Tell me, tell me!
Sweetheart!
I want to hear the exact words
you choose.
I do not ever intend
to marry you, Ren.
I love to dance with you, Joe.
You're my favorite
dance partner.
So you see, Renata...
It's bigger than
all of us honey.
You can't guess it!
I was crazy about a girl.
Before I met your mother,
of course.
But crazy!
You know...
I do not remember
her name!
Do you believe the same
will happen to you?
Do you?
Attagirl!
The son of a bitch  had
the best years of her life.
The thing is, he really
never even knew you.
That's right!
He had no idea
that you're exceptional.
An exceptional person,
you always were!
- Isn't that right, Jan?
- Absolutely mom, he...
He says I am not intellectual.
Who gives a shit?
You're lucky!
He is a pig!
I wish I could
take you with me.
Don't get nervous, all right?
- Adios!
- Okay! Bye!
You're gonna love the flight, honey!
Don't get nervous!
Goodbye!
I'll go up and see
if I can see them.
Dad!
Oh, you just missed them!
It's honeymoon your sister
goes on, and you miss it!
Oh, come on, you guys,
cut it up!
- Where is your wife?
- Oh, it's a madhouse!
Yes yes,
forget about it!
Sorry to point this, but you missed her
going on her honeymoon!
Get rid of the beard.
You look like a goddamn terrorist.
Honey!
Let's get going!
We're going to be late for work!
It's their plane!
D'you know what
surprises me, Tony?
Why, how you got through security,
that's what surprises me...
Right over there...
Ma? Dad?
Honey!
It's anything the matter?
Can I sleep
with you and daddy?
- Sure!
- What's going on?
Nothing, nothing, Joe.
It's just Renata wants
to sleep with us.
Why don't you get your pillow
honey, and come back.
Joe, don't cram me in
will you?
Could you spare me
a little room to breathe?
I feel sick.
You're going to be
just fine, honey.
Just fine.
Goodnight sweethearts.
- Good night, Joe.
- Good night, daddy.
Good night, Ma.
Good night, sugar.
I found a job.
Selling condominiums in St. Maarten
to people in Boston.
Now you talk.
Let's talk... talk of it.
That's terrific.
You got to take it.
Really?
Just sleep...
You've been
a waitress long enough!
Just sleep.
Just don't think
about anything.
Sleep now.
Hi!
I'm Brigitte Larson.
I'd like to welcome all you
cold weather Bostonians...
In paradise!
Right now we are heading
towards the fabulous...
Pelican Resort and Casino
timeshare complex.
You'll find 300 timeshare units...
152 with extraordinary
ocean views.
All of the luggage
with red tag...
Will be staying in
the Terrace Room, ocean side...
Blue tag, in the new building,
right behind us.
There are two things
you need to make a deal...
One is money...
The other is attitude.
Their money...
Your attitude.
If you don't have a
positive attitude...
Get out now!
So now tell me...
How do you feel?
Great!
- How do you feel?
- Great!
That's what I want to hear!
You'll fill that board
if you have that attitude!
You'll sell every condo we have...
I don't care whether it outlooks
onto the parking lot...
You'll sell it!
Hello, everybody!
Welcome, all you beautiful people!
Boy, I got a treat for you!
I'd like to introduce you to
our very top salesman...
My idol...
Mister Sam Sharpe!
Thank you very much!
Thank you.
Thank you!  Thank you!
Thank you very much!
Is that a banana in your pocket,
or you're just happy to see me?
What did the man say,
who had five penises?
What?
My pants fit me like a glove!
That's sick!
Thank you, thank you.
Welcome...
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
all you guys and gals...
To the Pelican Condo family...
You're a great looking bunch
of trainees, as a matter of fact...
There are some
of you here today...
Who are simply stunning.
I want to hear you
give yourself...
A big round of applause!
Ready?
One, two, three, go!
That's it!
Let me hear it!
Now...
For those of you...
Who don't know me,
my name is Sam Sharpe.
And I guess you could say that
I've sold a few of these babies...
Myself.
Sam Sharpe...
Has sold...
2.575 shares....
Now you're acting
like a salesperson...
Thanks a lot!
And last year,
in commission alone...
I made...
Earned a lot of money.
A lot of money!
Now you must be asking
yourselves, by now...
Who is this guy?
You know, who is this...
Hugely successful salesperson...
Who is this...
Incredibly well-dressed...
Yeah!
Incredibly well hung guy, well...
I, uh...
I am descended...
From a long line...
Of Lithuanian generals...
My family, God bless
each and everyone of them...
Came over here to this...
Fabulously wonderful country...
When I was...
Just a little fellow in shorts.
And now...
Take a look
at what I'm wearing.
That's America!
Everyone of you can do just as well,
you know what I'm talking about...
This place sells itself.
Thank you very much,
"bon appétit".
A cheer for Sam Sharpe!
That was nice!
Thank you!
Thank you very much!
- It's time for the Pierrot, Pepe.
- I love that wine!
Not many people
know that wine.
I used to work
in the food industry.
Really?
So did I!
- Hi everybody, I'm Joyce.
- Hello!
Hi, Joyce.
Well, cheers!
- May I?
- Oh! Thank you!
Red is a beautiful color!
It's my favorite color!
- Your suit is gorgeous!
- Do you really like it?
Oh yes, I love it!
It's wonderful!
Thank you!
- I got it in Japan.
- No!
- Yes!
- Wow!
Tokyo.
Tokyo...
is a wild ploy.
Ohoh, yeah!
I can imagine...
You can't believe the dresses
they can make in Tokyo.
I would like to buy you
a dress from Tokyo...
Wow!
My dad uses to sing that song
for my mother.
"Fly me to the moon"!
I, of course, was born
in the forties.
When they wrote
incredible songs.
Thats why I have such
intense passions.
I believe that
a hundred percent!
I mean...
I know all those songs
because of my dad.
Hell...
Men of my own generation
have never understood me at all!
I mean, if you know...
"Fly me to the moon...
"And let me play
among the stars...
"Let me see
what spring is like...
"On Jupiter and Mars...
"In otherwords...
"Hold my hand...
- Baby...
- Darling...
"Kiss me"
- What's your name?
- Renata.
- Yes.
It's a lovely...
Lovely name.
You are the second most beautiful
woman I've ever seen.
- Your mother.
- You got it!
I don't believe you!
You know...
There's an old
Caribbean custom...
That says when a man
kisses a woman on a roof...
On the very first night,
that they meet...
That she has to
believe everything...
He ever tells her.
And that...
Is a fact.
- I shouldn't have done that.
- Why not?
You're wearing
a wedding ring.
I'm... I'm divorced.
No!
In business...
In business it's
better to be married!
Renata, my divorce
was final September 2nd.
- No!
- Yes!
Christ!
That's my birthday!
- No!
- Yes!
Renata, you have to come
to New York with me...
Just for a weekend, please!
I'm immeasurably flattered,
I mean...
A weekend is just two days, but...
but I can't...
- I have my family to go back to...
- "Fly you to the moon..."
"And let us play
among the stars..."
"Let us see
what spring is like..."
"On Jupiter and Mars..."
"In other words..."
"Old my hand..."
"Darling kiss me... "
Sam...
When you brought me back
to my room last night...
And you wouldn't
let me in you tease...
I wanted to tell
you something...
You drive me wild...
I was afraid to excite you...
- Any more then I did already.
- You old-fashioned...
Baddy, daddy's sex goddess...
Sam!
What?
Tell me, what?
You know Sam...
When I saw you for the
very first time...
You were standing and you
looked down at the ocean...
Yeah!
And the moment I saw you...
A voice inside me, said...
"I'm going to kiss this guy
in front of an altar...
With God as a witness."
Yes.
That voice inside me...
- Yeah?
- I've never heard it, ever...
Untill I saw you.
I can't believe this.
I can't believe
you're driving me here.
Why, is only logical!
You wouldn't let me feed you
baby shrimp in New York.
Renata!
Daddy!
Oh God,
I'm so happy!
Daddy, um...
Let me shake the hand
of the first man...
That my little
rosebud ever loved.
A word, a word, it's not
going to be a second!
- Come on, it will be interesting to you!
- My hands are dirty, I...
- I don't want to go in...
- Get in! Get in!
Get in!
I got mud on my boots!
Okay, Sonny, let's go!
You can go
around the rotary...
At high speed without
ever hitting your brakes.
I think I have the record
in Massachusetts.
What suspension!
This is an automobile!
Hey, what's it, Sonny?
Sonny!
You can crank her up
ten more miles per hour!
What ten, thirty miles
an hour, come on!
Okay!
This baby really
hugs the road!
There's even champagne
in that refrigerator.
No, no!
No thanks!
No thanks,
I get headache!
Have one daddy!
- Marilyn!
- Hi honey, what...
What're you doing up there?
Get down!
Renata!
- Mom!
- Do you want to kill yourself?
How many times do I
have to tell you all...
Aaah! Help!
- Are you gonna shame us...
- Mommy, mommy, how are you!
- I am so happy to see you!
- I din't think you'd be back so early!
Sam, this is my mother.
Mom, this is Sam.
- Hello!
- Hello, how are you?
Isn't she beautiful?
How do you explain a rose...
To someone, who has never
seen a rose before.
Welcome!
So, uh...
He detoured Renata
to New York City...
Just so he could drive her
back to Boston.
How nice!
If I had my way, I would've driven
her all the way to California.
Well!
How did you like the job?
Did you love it?
I learned I wouldn't be good
at selling condos...
She'd be sensational!
It just wasn't the right place for her.
Really!
So uh...
You're back to where
you started?
Well...
Not really, dad.
Not really, dad!
What's that supposed
to mean?
- Hi, Tony
- Tony!
Come on, come here!
Hi, Tony!
Hey, Renata!
You're home early!
How's the condo biz?
This is Sam.
This is my brother Tony.
Tony!
Sam, nice to meet you!
Nice limo!
Why don't you come up and have
something to eat with Renata and, um...
- Sam.
- Sam!
No, I have to go to work.
Well, this came in
real handy, thanks.
But it's Saturday!
Got to go!
I got a work, see?
You could take a day off
once in a while.
Listen, I got a plumber here...
He robs me blind as soon as I
turn around for a minute!
- Bye Tony.
- Bye, donna.
Tony!
You're going to get plenty of chances
if you get to know me.
Joe, come on and have
something to eat with the kids!
Hey, Sonny!
Bring the champagne!
No, no, no, no, no!
No thank you!
Just leave it in the car.
Tony, don't forget it's
dad's birthday tomorrow.
Marilyn, Marilyn, please!
Please honey,
no celebration....
No cake....
Nothing!
Sure, sure, sure!
Come here! Come here!
Come here!
Now I've got you!
Was that just regular vodka
we were drinking?
It's two clock in the morning,
for chrissakes!
I mean, we don't even know
this guy, really!
I think she should go
to her own goddamned room...
I mean, it's close to 2:30!
You know Joe...
I think if this works out...
It could be the best thing
that could ever happen.
I think he's crazy about her.
That's it!
- Where are you going?
- That's it!
Don't go down there!
Oh, darling! Oh, darling!
Kiss me!
Oh, Joe!
Joe, she's so funny!
She was just telling me how
her horse Horny used to...
- Shoni.
- Shoni!
Shoni used to walk in the rain
through the rain.
- With all the water falling...
- We woke you?
What the hell is the matter
with you Renata?
Your mother can't sleep.
Oh, yes?
For chrissakes,
it's three in the morning!
Okay, fine, I'm going to bed!
What's with that attitude?
All of a sudden
I'm the bad guy?
Because it's 3:30
in the morning...
And I want you to go
to bed for chrissakes...
Allright!
Your mother wants
her goddamned sleep.
Renata...
Don't let him
go away angry.
Come on.
Sweeten him up!
Buttercup...
Dad!
Don't worry, sweetheart.
You're forgiven!
Let's go to sleep now.
Wait a minute.
What's the matter?
What's going on?
Are you okay?
Am I okay?
If I told you how wrong everything
has been since Rob, I...
If, if, if...
If I told you the truth, you...
you'd problably call the cops on me!
Or... a priest, or Jan,
or a medical doctor...
I'm coaching for dear life
in here, okay?
How?
I have been...
Spit down the middle!
Spit down the
fucking middle!
I've been...
Flung into this wasteland...
Trying to figure out how can
two plus two make five.
And at the same, I feel like
I'm getting in...
A tall white flame,
that suddenly goes "pfft"...
Disintegrate!
And you ask me,
if I'm okay?
That's not the point!
That's just not the point!
The point is, I don't want
to be told when to go to bed.
Alright, stay up late.
No problem.
You bet that I'm staying
up late if I want.
Okay, Mom?
Okay! Sure, you stay up
as late as you want.
And then again I just
might go right to bed.
- That's okay too!
- Sure, absolutely!
What was that?
Do you hear that?
I don't hear anything.
Brrr, shut the window,
I'm freezing my ass off.
"Fly me to the moon...
"Let me play
among the stars...
"Let me see
what spring is like...
"On Jupiter and Mars...
"In other words...
"Hold my hand...
"Baby... Kiss me...
"Fill my heart with song...
"And let me sing
for ever more...
Let me me see it again!
Look at those shoes and dress...
Look at this neckline!
No, no, no, no!
Leave your coat open!
You stare at me.
Oh God, I'm busted up inside...
I swear the adrenaline
inside me is like....
- I'm  kicking ass.
- Why?
Do I look okay?
Because I'm going crazy!
Oh my... God!
Let go!
You awakened Sam Sharpe!
Don't move!
Not if you care at all for
this minutes, this car, for me at all!
- Dont move your hand!
- I don't think I can!
I can't do this!
I want you to live
with me in New York.
No!
- That's impossible!
- Nothing is impossible!
- Come on, say yes to me!
- I live here!
Come on!
Leaving my family is like...
Is like...
Renouncing my citizenship, or...
Or moving to Russia!
Or becoming Protestant!
No!
Sonny stop the car!
Stop the car!
Sam, what are you doing?
Get out of the car!
- Please!
- Come on!  Come on!
- We are on a bridge!
- Come on!
- Where are we going?
- Trust me.
- It's cold out here!
- Renata...
When I was eight years old...
I used to stare at the photo
of my grandfather.
Who was a General
in Lithuania.
What do you talk...?
We were talking about me...
Wait, wait, wait, wait...
I used to say to myself:
Sam...
The blood of this
powerful, viril man...
Is coursing through
your veins.
And I was just so...
I would... I would get...
I would ran out
of the room...
Dieing to do
something decisive...
I would say:
"Mommy, mommy..."
"Did I really suck on your tits,
when I was a little boy?"
Sam!
What are you talking about?
- What am I talking about...
- Oh, I'm freezing!
- Let's go back to the car.
- What am I talking about?
I'm trying to tell you that
from the first minute I ever saw you...
Renata!
Look at you...
Look at you!
Everything you do...
The way you eat
your food...
The way...
The way you put on
your shoes...
The way your eyes are looking
at my mouth when I'm talking...
Renata, you name
anything you do...
The way you hug
your mother....
The way you talk
to your family...
You move me.
Give me the phone!
Sonny?
What are you doing?
I'm dialling
my accountant's number.
I'm going to look at the Charles River
every day for the rest of my life.
When he asks me why
am I moving...
My business from New
York to Boston...
I'll be able to say to him...
This man...
I am in love!
Marilyn, give me those
needle nose again!
Yes, coming up!
He lives in New York City.
I'm glad too.
I'll get it!
Imagine that guy
on a day to day basis...
Oh, my word!
Oh, my goodness,
look at this!
Look at what Sam sent me!
Look at that!
Is he a darling?
Oh, my...
I've never saw so many
flowers in my life!
I don't know why I'm
putting in this fixture.
I am 140 years old today...
You'd think my...
Goddamned son, your
husband would help out.
Oh, he had to go
watch that plumber!
- I don't look that old, do I?
- No, you look great, dear!
- Thanks, honey!
- Wait a minute...
Renata really likes this guy?
Likes him?
She's almost as absurd
as your mother in law!
Ta-ta!
I told you Marilyn...
Don't do anything fancy
for my birthday.
Oh, I suppose you think this
cake is for you, uh?
It's not for you.
Can't you just one time
accept something...
Without spoiling it
with your censorship?
There was never a day I could
or would court you like that.
All I ever wanted to do was...
Sit in the stoop
and hold your hand.
Yeah, me too!
Isn't that funny how
on the one lousy day...
You want to put a gun
in your mouth...
Everybody wants to come
over to celebrate.
Yes, that's because
we love you.
D'you want some coffee, baby?
Renata...
I want you to try the greatest
coffee cake you've ever eaten.
Sam, don't believe anything
that daddy says.
- Can I give you some coffee?
- Thank you very much!
- Where's the bananas?
- Bananas, you got it!
Oh, God!
Tony and Gail!
Stop!
Don't have to eat it yet!
- Don't, don't...
- Okay, okay, okay!
I can get it myself...
Sit down.
Marilyn, where's the cream...
The cream!
You ruined it, you ruined it!
She ate it!
Okay, Sam...
I got it!
Uh, Joe...
- Why don't you answer the doorbell?
- Mum!
Why?
I think it's right that
you answer your doorbel!
What's going on?
Justr do it, dad!
Answer the door!
- Excuse me.
- What's up?
Hello!
You're Mr. Joe Bella?
That's me!
Come on, keep up!
Come on!
Thanks a lot!
Do you hear that?
It sounds Byzantine!
Hear!
Let me put it inside you
right now, you have guessed
Peter...
- Cut it down!
- Come on!
- Let's go in that bush!
- Please!
- Peter!
Come on, just feel it.
Come on,
just give it a touch!
Peter, please!
This is a front
lawn in America.
They're dancing!
They can't be dancing!
Jan!
I was dying for you
to come home!
I'll tell you,
you look gorgeous!
- Jan! Peter!
- Come on!
Peter! Peter!
- Welcome home.
- Who's the naked lady?
Hey Sam!
Sam, Sam, come on!
I want you to meet my kid!
Who is the guy?
My new boyfriend!
No, no, come on,
who is he really?
I'm with him.
My God, who could imagine,
not even sun tanned, uh?
She's probably seeing
museums all day..
Sam, come here!
Sam, this is my sister Jan
and this is her husband Peter.
- How are you?
- Sam Sharpe!
I hope you both have a lifetime
of great sex and joy.
That's what it's all about,
ain't it?
Hey, Miss?
Why don't we have
something to eat?
I'm starving!
Let's all go in the kitchen and sing
Happy Birthday to daddy!
For Christ's sake, I offer the birthday.
No more eating!
Glad you all are here.
Wait for us, okay?
Oh, thank you, I will.
That's sweet!
Bye bye!
Why didn't you ask your friend
to join us for cake?
Oh, no, no, she wouldn't want to stay here
with a bunch of strangers...
She'd rather go home,
you know?
With her tits full of cash!
She's married.
She's dieing to get out of here!
- Joe!
- Yeah!
She said Happy Birthday
in Lithuanian!
So, we'll be in there!
Yes.
Oh, my God!
I saw you came home last night.
Jim!
I was... behind the big tree.
Jim...
Would you...
You should...
I need you!
- God, I need you!
- Jim!
Remember how you...
You needed me
at your wedding, and...
You could explain it?
Yeah!
Yopu really missed me,
didn't you?
I met a woman.
She's phenomenal!
She asked me
to marry her.
I want you there.
Next Thursday.
You have to be there!
How could you meet a
woman, I've been only...
A bar.
- A bar?
- Yes.
And you're going to marry
someone you met in a bar?
For Christ's sake,
look at me, Jim!
Please come to my wedding.
Please!
That was pretty good!
Go, go!
I wish you could have
met my father.
He wasn't a very good skater
but he loved the ice.
I wish I could have met
your father.
Wait till you see what this Olympics
manage to do!
Sam, you shouldn't
have done all this...
Oh, I...
Hey, come on!
I'm all alone out here!
Sonny!
Sonny,
turn up the volume!
It's wonderful out here!
It's wond... come on, Joe!
- Come on, baby, it's you and me!
- What, what, what?
Renata! Come on!
Hey, what is this?
You told me you'd been
a hockey star in high school!
- Field hockey!
- Ohh!
Look at this!
Where did Sam
get all his money?
Sam is an incredible salesman,
haven't you heard?
He's selling real estate
on the moon now!
Hey, Joe!
Are you ready to whizz
the ladies around?
Come on!
Here we come!
Jan!
Are you ready
for a little whipping?
Sam?
God, you can say
anything to anyone!
Oh, come on!
She's your sister!
Come on, Joe!
I'll do it myself now!
Good style, old Joe!
Good style!
This is my imitation of Joe!
Hey, hey, hey!
Watch out!
Come here,
come here you guys!
Marilyn, Marilyn!
Come on,
take it, take it!
That's very good.
Now...
You're going to go
round slow...
Come on!
Now you'll learn,
I'm going to see you really do it.
- Hey, come on, go!
- Go, go!
- Easy!
- Come on!
Jan, come over here!
Yes!
Why do you call me in?
Do you want a drink?
Neat show!
That's good!
Marilyn down!
Marilyn!
First Aid!
Are you alright?
Are you sure?
- Are you alright?
- Yes!
What do you think?
About what?
You haven't told me
what you think.
Well, you used to tack
about having a job, but...
I'm asking how you feel
about Sam, what you think?
I think you should take it slow.
I mean...
I thought you were supposed
to be selling condos by now.
So what are you doing
that's so goddamn important?
At least I'm worried about my future,
not of avoiding it.
Oh, give me a break!
- You're stuck here!
- Me?
Your feet are nailed
to the fucking kitchen floor...
You don't do anything
without daddy's permission.
Or is it Sam's now?
I mean, at least I...
What? Have Peter?
Or is it Jim?
I saw you this morning.
I'm just asking you
give me and Sam...
The same kind of consideration
you give a neighbor.
Come on Renata!
I mean, you hardly know the guy!
I mean, for chrissakes, he ​​puts
money in women's breasts.
Okay!
It's fine!
You can just screw off, okay?
Screw off!
Oh! Yeah!
Right!
You're just pissed off,
I went on my honeymoon...
Instead of staying and taking care
of your stupid broken heart.
You get real creepy, Renata,
This people...
- You're creepy!
- That's right!
He makes her happy....
Can't you see that?
Mum! Come!
Watch me!
We watch you!
Yeh, you're great!
Watch this!
Mum? Dad?
Hey, what's going on?
What's the matter?
I'm sorry to wake you, but...
I can not sleep unless
I say the following....
Then say it, then.
Does anyone care?
That... Renata is spending day and night
with some moron?
Renata doesn't think
he's a moron.
Mum...
We don't know a thing
about this guy, do we?
Dot you, Dad?
No...
No, not really.
He could be a criminal!
No!
I should know
more about him.
We should.
We all should.
And why is he living with us?
He's not living with us!
What do you mean,
he's not living with us...
If he's here, he's here.
- Do I see him in bed or not?
- He's visiting!
Okay, technically he's
not living with us...
But he's here,
he's staying here!
That's what she's asking us...
Is that what you're asking?
Exactly!
He is living with us
for some weird reason!
I think we should
just stay out of it!
Oh no!
No, no, no, no, no.
Marilyn...
I mean, goddamned, he's been
with us long enough!
Enough is enough!
I'm sick and
goddamn tired of...
Of smelling smoke
and drinking vodka!
I'm sick of it!
Sick! Sick!
That's what I am!
Janny, she is awfully happy!
Aw, whiplash!
Come on! Pull over!
Let me see your license!
Come on!
Come on, out!
He's more excited about
this wedding than anyone.
Crazy wedding!
All my instincts tell me
take this kid aside and say:
"What's your rush?"
Sometimes people know,
they just know like that!
He has to be in love!
I'm glad you're so
open minded, Jan.
Peter!
Come on!
Listen, Renata!
Let's forget about
the other day, okay?
I overreacted.
I'm sorry!
I was a real bitch!
I just want you to be happy!
It's none of my business
how you go about to end there.
No. You cared...
And you're right!
No, I understand
your concerns, I do.
I'm going to cool
my jets with Sam.
We have gathered here...
To unite in holy wedlock...
Jim Redstone...
And Honey Beach.
Do you, Jim Redstone...
Take Honey Beach...
For your lawful wedded wife?
To love...
To honor and to cherish
all the days of your life?
I do!
And do you...
Honey Beach...
- Take Jim Redstone...
- I, Sam Sharpe...
- As your lawful...
- Take Renata Bella...
To be my lawful
wedded wife....
To love, honor and look on her...
- Ush, ush!
- All the days of my life...
- That's not funny!
- Say that out!
- Say it, Renata!
- Leave me alone!
I, Jim Redstone...
Take thee, Honey Beach...
To be my lawful
wedded bride...
I...
Renata Bella...
- Take Sam Sharpe...
- Sam!
This is not a fun game!
And... Now you Honey....
Repeat after me...
I, Honey Beach...
- Take Jim Redstone...
- I...
Take Jim Redstone...
- Renata Bella...
- As my lawful wedded husband...
- Take Sam Sharpe...
- To be my lawful wedded husband...
- Lawful wedded husband...
To love, honor and cherish...
All the days of my life!
And may God bless you both!
And I now pronounce you...
Man and wife.
I would like to propose a toast!
A toast!
Those of you who, uh...
Know me even
a little bit by now...
Aren't going to be surprised to hear
that I 'd like to make a toast...
To the...
Consummate happiness
of Jim and Honey,
Jim and Honey!
Jim is
a heck of a guy.
I don't know him
well myself...
But I can tell by the way
Jan is sweet on him that...
He must be one...
One heck of a swell guy.
And Honey...
Well...
I don't need to say
a lot about honey, uh....
We did get a chance to get
acquainted a little bit...
In the men's room a
few minutes ago...
Just kidding!
All right!
All kidding aside...
To Jim and Honey!
- Cheers!
- Jim!
Now, don't finish,
don't finish!
Just leave a little bit.
Inspired by the great happiness
and joy that I see around us...
By the shining example of Mr. Joe Bella
and his lovely wife Marilyn...
But darling Jan,
their daughter, and...
Her lovely husband Peter...
I would like to
take this this opportunity...
To announce the engagement
of Miss Renata Bella...
And Mr. Sam Sharpe IV.
Ohoh, yeah!
There is an old
Lithuanian proverb.
It goes...
Roughly translated, that means...
"Dogs can't make their dreams
come through..."
"So people have to."
And I just did.
Wow!
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Come on!
Once around!
For the bride!
It's a fertility rite.
Eggs, bread...
They are dancing
with genitals.
Oh, come on, Joe,
they are not!
Look at that car!
You can't believe all this.
I mean, look at it...
It's like he's purchasing her.
- How can she do that?
- Dad!
Look, I'm old-fashioned...
And I'm as sexist
as the next guy.
But Christ, I've always
treated your mother as an equal.
Dad, we all got to let Renata
live her own life now, alright?
A lovely ceremony.
- It was beautiful.
- Thanks.
I've been waiting for this dance
for over a quarter of a century.
Oh, oh!
Hello, hello! Hi!
Come on in!
Everybody!
Yeah, come on down at
the front, you little guys...
Got a rocket in your pocket
or are you just happy to see me?
Um... I...
I am overwhelmed.
I... I'm standing here...
In front of this microphone,
and I'm...
I'm overwhelmed, I'm overwhelmed
by my beautiful bride.
And I am overwhelmed by my
beautiful new mother in law...
Marilyn Bella!
And I'm... I'm overwhelmed
by everybody, really....
Every single person in this room is...
I... I...
You are love!
Your are...
Your are love!
Embodied in
great looking outfits.
Give yourselves a big
round of applause...
Come on, really!
Come on!
Everybody!
Yeah!
Oh, ohohoh...
There is one person here...
Who's  Mr. Love...
I'm not talking about
dollars and cents...
When I say that he is
the richest man...
In this room.
He is the richest man
in this room...
Because of what
is in his heart.
You know whom
I'm talking about...
Let's have a big
round of applause...
For the big guy...
Mister...
Joe...
Head of the family...
Bella!
Joe!
Come on up!
Come on!
Joe! Joe! Joe!
Joe, come on!
Joe! Joe! Joe! Joe!
Go, go, go, go, go, go...
Come on, Daddy!
All right, all right...
I'd just like to say that...
Excuse me.
Sorry...
I'd like to
sing this song...
To Renata.
But Sam, you should
listen carefully to it...
Because for some
reason Renata...
After meeting Sam...
You're always humming this song.
I mean, for some reason.
It's been in the air,
since you two met.
"Fly me to the moon...
And let me play
among the stars...
Let me see
what spring is like...
On Jupiter and Mars.
In other words...
Hold my hand...
Baby kiss me...
Fill my heart with song...
And let me sing
forever more...
You are all I long for...
All I worship
and adore...
In other words...
Please be true...
I love you.
Oh, Renata, Renata please,
could you call it off...
Easy Joe, no peeking!
Here we go!
And a drum roll please!
Do you like it?
It's a potter's wheel!
Look at that!
Isn't it great?
Very few on the market!
Hey, hey, you 're getting
to be an expert!
My leg hurt.
Is it a flower?
No it's... it's...
quite off center...
It's kind of an abstract.
- Hey, Dad!
- Yes!
This is for Marilyn.
-  Thank you!
- And now to myself...
- Do you like this?
- Oh, bravo!
-Yeah?
- You look at this!
Oh, you kids got to be bonkers!
Why, we really are, mom!
We gave that crazy mirror...
I'm not sure I want to be
a location salesman...
A lot of money!
More money than you
ever dreamed of earning!
This is a very
generous offer!
Awful!
If you don't even
know what it is...
How can you evaluate
it seriously for one?
Daddy!
What do you think?
Come on!
Why don't you give it at least a try?
Just try it out!
I can quit, right?
Anytime! This is America,
what do you think?
Joe!
Look at this!
People used to have...
- Hi!
- Hi.
- Where, Jan?
- Upstairs, I think.
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
The refrigerator.
It's a lot...
Of cashola!
VCRs...
CD's, Digital TV...
Porsches... Shih-tzus...
Guess, how much?
Wrong! Whatever
you just thought...
It's twice what
you just thought!
He threw me a bonus!
How much of a bonus?
Come on!
Get it with your mouth!
You know you want to!
What!
God, it's getting
hard to separate...
Your boon and
your professional role.
Shit, what the hell was that?
What a threat!
Mom, are you alright?
I want to put a bomb under
your father's chair...
And I'm going to light it.
He just sits there
in that robe.
All day.
- All night!
- Ma, he's resting!
Resting?
Hey!
You want to talk about...
Wha... take a look at this place!
I mean it's making beds,
hanging up clothes...
Dusting, mopping, cooking,
doing windows, and...
What is this supposed to be,
the thrill of my lifetime?
- Shit!
- Ma, calm yourself!
No, no, I'm sick of it!
I'm...
We were going to travel...
We were going to go
deep sea fishing!
I was going to learn Italian!
Well. I've decided what
I really want to do.
I want to build a
boat, paint it...
Put it to sea.
and die on it!
Oh!
Go chase a flying...
What are you doing, sleeping
at twelve o'clock in the afternoon?
Will you tell me that?
I'm trying to daydream...
Marilyn.
Now, why don't you
leave me alone, uh?
Ever since I retired,
you can't take it, can you?
Well...
I'll be at my
pregnant daughter's...
If anyone cares.
Dad!
Nice view, uh?
Oh, yes!
Yeah.
You know, your mother...
She doesn't understand...
I just want
to slow it down.
Do nothing.
Sam could never stop working.
Never!
It worries me.
I... I wish Sam
was more like you.
I wish he could
just relax
You stopped working,
because you wanted to.
Now, when you
were Sam's age...
You worked all hours too.
Of course I worked all hours.
I had you, I had Tony...
My date!
Is my date home?
Throw the turkey in the oven
and spread them!
Hi, Sam.
Oh, youyouyouyou...
Dad!
Hey!
I was just thinking of you.
Got to go.
Oh, don't go!
Hey, Joe,
don't go home yet!
Please, I need your
help on something.
I need your advice, okay?
It takes just a minute.
Come over here,
take a look at this.
Now...
Which do you like better?
The blue or red?
I like the blue.
I do too!
Yeah, this one
is way too provocative.
Now, first off...
You start the thing off
with a goddamn question.
If I was sent a brochure...
Of which I got a shitload
at work every day...
And it started
with a question...
I'd say they're assholes.
They're being provocative
where I want...
Safe.
They're asking questions,
where I want answers.
- Really.
- Fuck them, I'd put it in the basket.
Renata, your father is one
smart cookie.
Well, no one has
to tell me that!
One smart cookie.
What was that word
you just used?
- Provocative?
- Provocative, right.
Mister bull's eye.
- You take the blue, right Joe?
- Yes.
The blue.
Okay, okay.
Im going with the red.
See, I'm going
for the new breed...
I'm going for the people
who want provocative.
Thank you Joe, I really
appreciate very much...
It was very helpful!
Well, if you need
an old fart...
Give me a call.
See you later, Joe.
Old fart!
Daddy, can I...
can I talk to you?
Don't be late for
your grandmother's death memorial.
- Okay.
- Bye, sweetheart.
Why?
What was it you just said?
What?
You trapped him.
I did not!
Why did you talk to him
like that, why did...
Why did you trick him
like that?
I asked his opinion,
because I...
- I value him.
- Oh, Sam!
Can't you be sensitive
to another person?
Don't you notice what
he's going through?
I think you are
underestimating your father.
Jesus, back off a little.
I'm worried on this.
Honey!
I think you'd better
get dressed.
It's getting late.
"Forse...
"Non s'usano più...
"Oh, mamma....
"Ma la canzone mia
più bella sei tu...
"E per la vita non ti lascio...
"Mai più.
Oh, mamma...
"Mamma...
"Mai...
"Più...
Wow!
Allright...
Let us enjoy ourselves.
God!
I really like your father.
It was nice, Dad.
Thank you, Peter.
It was great, Dad.
You know, there's a
song in Lithuanian...
That's like that.
That honours the mother.
Joe, that was magnificent,
that was really...
- Magnificent.
- I don't want to hear that...
But thanks, Sam.
I'm not kidding you,
it was...  it was magnificent.
Sam...
Cut it off!
What the hell is he going to do?
Make a speech now...?
Not appropriate here, Renata.
Hello!
Reading...
Can you hear me?
Can you hear...?
Sam...
What are you doing?
I'm going to sing a Lithuanian song
I know about motherhood.
Oh, I wish you wouldn't.
Uhm... You know...
The thing is...
The Bellas are
a funny group, and...
Well, they are very funny about
the memory of their mothers.
Don't sing, please Sam!
This is a song about a woman...
Who's completely
devoted to her son.
Everything she does,
every action, you know...
All the cooking and cleaning, everything!
Is done for her son,
who is going on a journey...
It's really...
Yes, it sounds like
a wonderful song, but...
We got to hear it sometimes,
just not today. okay?
You listen and you tell me after
if you think I was wrong, okay?
Sam... uh...
I have the microphone in my hand,
because I can't seem to reach you.
And I know it's my fault,
because I probably sound...
As if I'm asking you
not to sing.
But I'm actually doing it, Sam.
As I'm telling you, you can't!
You cannot do it!
Marilyn, I think you saw...
Let me see what's going on daddy,
I want a taxi home.
Give me the microphone
and go to your seat...
And sit next to Renata
were you belong!
Marilyn, I want to sing a song
about mothers!
Over my dead body, okay?
Now, go sit down!
- I know how you feel, I really do...
- Give this to me right now!
Listen, I want to sing
this song...
And I know with my heart
this is the right place!
It is absolutely the wrong place, and you're
the wrong person to sing today!
You have had a free rein over us,
but I'm telling you...
As of this moment, it's over!
I will kill you before I let you sing that song
and upset my husband and his family!
Oh, go ahead, I'll kill you!
- Is that right?
- That's damn right!
Marilyn, I don't believe
that you really mean that!
Oh, I certainly do!
- Wait, wait...
- Stop it!
Wait, I just wanted... I...
- Look...
- Daddy, I want this thing...
Don't worry, I have it, I have it!
Take it easy...
My God!
Damned...
Sam!
You're tearing us all apart.
God.
Renata!
Please forgive me.
I know you want me
to leave you alone.
I know that.
I know you want to watch this,
but I have this....
I have this really bad...
Feeling that...
You know, if I walk out of the room,
you're going to decide not to forgive me.
I keep thinking
that if I just...
You know, don't move and...
Stay where I am, I'll...
Think of something.
You know, I'll...
I'll just...
I'll get another chance with you,
I don't know.
I don't know a shit.
Okay. Okay.
There.
Now you can...
Now you can watch and you
don't have to look up if you don't want.
Is that you?
That's me.
My son is going
to have your spirit.
There's Jan.
And Jan's fire.
Playing with daddy...
Renata, no one
can tear your family apart.
I hope he'll have
my father's goodness.
And my mother's wisdom.
He will.
We're going to have
a beautiful baby.
Aren't we?
It's a girl!
I can't believe it!
Is she okay?
I didn't think
I could make it!
Is she okay?
Yeah...
She's great!
Hi, mom....!
Are you okay?
I'm pretty tired!
I'm so happy to see your mom!
- She's got your eyes!
- Now, really, dad!
Look at her fingers....
Marilyn...
About what happened
at the memorial yesterday...
Oh, no, no, that was my fault!
You were just being enthusiastic.
Sam!
Let's put all that behind us...
We got a good reason
to look ahead.
I hired the band
for just ten minutes...
I thought, what the hell,
you know...
I want to form a ring of love
around the baby.
Ok, Joe? Here!
You put your left
hand on Renata...
That's right, there we go.
Peter, take that hand,
and Jan...
Sorry, that's okay!
Jan, take Peter's hand...
Marilyn, you can take
Tony's hand...
That's it!
Gail...
There you go... That's it, honey...
Thank you very much!
And now Marilyn...
Perfect!
This is the song I wanted
to sing yesterday.
I know, and she was
the same way...
No, no, no, you...
We believe one child
yields me have one option.
- You have enough...
- No, no...
Listen... Listen!
All we have to get...
Excuse me!
All we have to get
is the baptism's date.
Now, we shold be
capable of doing that!
Okay! Okay! Okay!
I want Jan to be godmother...
And I would think
it would be an honor...
I mean, I want Tony
to be godfather.
And I'd like to add,
Sam here is being pretty terrific.
Though he has
friends of his own, okay...
So he's quite happy that
Tony be godfather.
Why do you have to
have the baptism on...
The first day that we are going away
on our very first vacation in 12 years...
You know, my parents
are really not going to understand...
How their granddaughter...
Is born and is not baptized  on a
preordained date.
Sam...
That has been followed
in Lithuanian tradition...
- Sam...
- For all of their lives!
I mean, they're really not
going to be able to understand...
- Sam!
- Why...
Sam, uh, ah...
I don't want to be rude,
but your parents...
- Are dead!
- Exactly!
- That's exactly the point!
- The bottom line is...
That Tony will not give up shit
to be there.
The bottom line is...
That you'd rather follow some
absolutely bullshit...
Uh, uh, tradition...
Rather than thinking about
my happiness, Gail's or Mikey's.
- Okay!
- That's the bottom line...
Fuck you, Tony!
Don't... ever...
- Say that to me again.
- Joe, do something!
There is a baptism
and there's a date...
You're the godmother
and you're the godfather...
I hope you can
fucking attend.
Jan?
You don't certainly have
to leave town, do you?
You're such a selfish bitch...
I can't believe, what a selfish...
I got it!
Hey! Hey!
That's it!
Now, the end, done,
It's finished.
I want everyone out.
Everyone!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
So Tony...
And Gail...
Just go to your
and go home.
You did nothing wrong.
And Jan, Peter...
Go to your room, please.
Joe...
- Maybe this isn't the right time.
- Marilyn, please.
Don't you start...
I know what I'm doing.
Joe, you know, if it's...
A question of financial loss...
I'd be happy to make up
anything that Tony....
Sam!
I don't want
to discuss it further.
Renata, I want you to ask Sam
because he is your husband...
Ask him to wait
in the car for you.
Why are you acting
like this, daddy...
Renata, please!
Okay. Sam, would you please
go wait in the car for me.
What is this, ma...?
Renata...
I'm going to say something
for the first time in my life...
Without consulting your mother...
But I think she's going
to very much agree me.
Renata, Sam is
a wonderful man.
He is a generous
and kind man.
But he is killing us.
He is killing us.
Is it true, Marilyn?
He means so well.
Marilyn, is it true?
Yeah.
How can you...
How can you
say that about Sam?
He has done nothing!
But...
Great, great...
- Renata...
- Things for this family.
Renata look,
I hate to say this...
But I'm more afraid of what
will happen if I don't.
Now, you and the baby...
You're always...
Forever welcome here.
But I do not want
Sam in this house again.
At least, you know,
not untill we all...
Get control of ourselves.
I simply don't know
what else to do.
I'm sorry!
Well. why don't you just get a gun
and blow my head off!
Because if Sam is not welcome here,
I am not welcome here.
In fact...
Why don't you just douse the place
in kerosene and blow it up?
Oh... and do me a favor...
Do not come to baptism.
You are not welcome.
Renata, wait!
No!
You wait!
That man...
I know he's different...
I love that he's different...
I love that he flatters me...
And he flatters mom, and Gail
and Tony and Jan and you.
Hell, Peter copies him!
You are impressed by him.
So what if he gives gifts?
If he is arrogant,
why shouldn't he be?
He is remarkable!
This is my adventure, dad,
my goddamn adventure...
If you don't get it,
well, I'm sorry!
I take it back.
I'm not sorry.
No way!
Once I thought, no,
once I wished...
That my parents would drive
off the road in their car and die.
Because then I 'd be different.
Those are your parents, Renata.
Your irreplaceable parents.
Don't ever talk like that.
Okay, Sam.
- Here, Renata.
- I'm sorry.
Ok, that's all right.
- That's right.
- I'm sorry...
I've got it.
Renata!
We are here!
Get the baby!
Come on!
We should be godparents!
Godmother, or what?
Sam...
Well, isn't that my family....
Jan, Tony!
Tony, Tony!
Tony, Jan...
- I didn't do that!
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Button up your coat!
Button up!
I am pleased to be here.
Remove the cap.
- Yes.
- He'll pour some water on her.
Thank you.
Sam!
My God!
Oh, my God!
Oh, God!
- Peter, get an ambulance!
- Sam...
Sam?
So mom, butter's got
35 milligrams of cholesterol...
What's that, per ounce?
No, that's one tablespoon.
So...
With cholesterol deposits
in the arteries...
That's a no butter for Sam.
Yes, but turkey
is great, isn't it?
Yeah, but dark meat is saturated
with double fat proteins.
Ok, we'll just give Sam
all the white meat.
Right.
You know, maybe we
shouldn't even serve wine
I'm shocked for every
person in this house.
Mom...
It would be better clear a path
to the back.
You know, it would
be longer that way...
And those extreme
slings in temperature...
They can cause a
real shock to the...
The circulatory system of
heart patients...
So, it's safer than to stay
with the front path.
Yeah, I think so.
Wait, you've all gone nuts, I mean,
Sam comes up the front door.
And if he wants to
go out and make...
A fucking snowman, he'll do it!
And if he wants to smoke
a pack of cigarettes...
He'll smoke a pack
of cigarettes!
Dad, he dies if he smokes,
he dies!
- Think of Renata, Joe!
- Yeah!
Under the tree!
Really, dad...
I mean, normally, a guy wants to jump
out of the window, okay...
But this is different, dad.
It's kinder to let the man
be a free man.
Now, just think about that.
Answer the door.
- Hey, doll!
- Hi! He is here!
He's doing fine!
Hi, ma!
Hi darling!
Although his bronchial tube
suddenly restricted...
But his inhaler regulated
him immediately.
My, God!
Merry Christmas!
- Hi Sam!
- Merry, merry!
- Merry Christmas!
Oh, are we glad
to see you!
You look well.
We sure are glad to see you!
- Sam, how are you?
- I'm great, how are you?
Yes, she's right, come on!
Why do you all go
into the house?
Let's go have some dinner,
come on!
Be careful. Tony!
Help your sister.
You're okay, buddy?
In the family paradise.
Okay!
Jan...
Pass that!
Ate that since
she was four years old!
Not Nicole Whitman...
But roasted!
Peter!
Thank you!
Sam, Sam...
- There's really good meat up for you.
- No, no, it's okay...
I tried the white, I think I
want a little bit of the dark .
This is fabulous!
Sam...
They are all on the attack
because you're eating dark meat.
But I say, live your life.
And that doesn't mean
let me live it for you.
Thank you very much,
I just want to...
Try a little bit of Marilyn's
fabulous turkey...
But I'm not going to make
a life habit of it.
Recognize anything?
That's the bowl!
You made it!
The thing!
You did it! I can't believe it!
I'm so proud...
Well, you know, it's
slightly offset...
I think it's fantastic,
look at that!
Realy, it's got...
lines and everything...
It's built like a brick shithouse!
It took me about eight and
a half days to make!
I love it!
It's like...
It has got fruit in there.
It has got utilitarian uses...
And Marilyn, you
did everything like...
Using with fruit, you could
use it with anything, right?
Excuse me.
Ren!
- Renata?
- Oh God!
Renata.
I'm sorry!
I'm afraid
to make love with you!
you'll die in my arms!
- And you are smoking!
- Renata.
No, no, I mean it!
No!
What are you trying to do?
Die?
You appear into my life like a
beautiful flash of light...
And then just as suddenly go pfft!
Sam...
I am not going to die on you, Renata!
I'm living for the first time in my life,
I could kick death in the teeth!
I'd spit in it's
face, Renata, if...
Death had hands,
I'd chop them off!
If death had eyes, I'd burn
them out of their sockets for you.
If death had a liver,
I'd bite it out wit my teeth!
And stamp on it!
- You would, uh?
- I would! I would!
And you know what else?
What else?
Come over here!
Come over here
and sit on my lap.
No!
You come to me.
Okay!
And if death...
Had a cock...
If death had a cock...
You'd kick him in the balls.
And send him off
squealing away...
Here we go!
- I can do it! I can do it!
- Okay.
The baby bleats.
Hey... hey!
Hey, you know we are going to skate
out here together one day?
Yes we are!
I'm going to skate faster
than anyone has ever skated...
In the history...
Of heart patients.
Here!
Here! Here! Here!
Well!
Let's not break any records yet.
- Here we go!
- Here we go.
So what do you want to see?
My figure eights?
My spin? One leg?
Or one legged spin, what?
You see that hole out
there in the ice?
It's like...
like a fishing hole...
- It's like a pile of ice and...
- Ye, ye, ye, I see it!
Go straight out there...
and then...
- Come right back.
- Yeah, sure!
Not bad.
Not bad!
Sam!
Are you crazy?
Let's go back.
I have had enough.
No, no, no!
One more!
The ice bar.
Okay.
You got it!
Hey, you?
Watch me go backwards!
Backwards!
Sam?
Sam!
No!
Oh, no!
God, no!
No!
Jan!
I had the greatest
time of my life.
The greatest time ever.
Time to sleep, little thing.
Are you sleepy, honey?
I used to love watching you sleep
when you were that age.
Why don't you come and lie down
with daddy and me a few minutes?
You're going to need
your strength today.
Hi, doll.
Are you going to lie down?
Come on, baby!
I love you guys.
One for the big guy.
"Fly me to the moon...
"Let me play among the stars...
"Let me see
what spring is like on...
"Jupiter and Mars...
"In other words...
"Hold my hand...
"Baby kiss me...
"Fill my heart with song...
"And let me sing
forever more...
"You are all I long for...
"All I worship and adore...
"In other words...
"Please be true...
"I love you"