ONE TO ANOTHER
Good! That's it!
Stop moving!
It's him!
Nico, stop!
Stay like that,
look at each other.
That's how it was
how youth must be...
No matter what, no matter how often...
The five of us... Pierre and me,
Nicolas and Sebastien Baptiste.
Pierre and me.
And Paul who kept his distance
because of his fragile nature.
Instinct guided us.
We were like magnets, I swear.
It was like this for years.
We grew up together.
One of us always paved the way.
It started with Baptiste
and porn when we were ten years.
He nicked them from his dad
who rented porn on the sly.
On my bulletin board
is a quote I copied from a book:
"Deprived of youth, man becomes
the accomplice to his own death."
It must have been a warning.
I don't like writing, Doctor.
I want to click on "trash".
Bring me there
Take me where
Endless tangled nights,
blackened lights.
And if you think about it.
We could really go far
We keep starting over again.
Stop thinking of the end
Wrap me up
Come on, tear me up
Your stockings are run
Can't resist it's too much fun
Isolated
We are stuck in our nights
Can I be a part of yours?
If not, your loss, life goes on
Isolated
Locked in your head
What I like
is not in a bed.
We said 500 for 1 1/2 hours,
Mr. Sylvaire.
I could only get 300.
Stop calling me Mr. Sylvaire.
You pay more when
I call you Vincent.
Your check will be ready tomorrow.
We said cash, Vincent.
Come by my office tomorrow.
- How am I gonna take you home?
- I'll hold on to you.
- You can't even stand up!
- You're hurting me!
- I have to vomit.
Come on, I'm exhausted!
I wanna ask you something...
What?
Come on, move it!
Nathalie...
She says you fuck better than me.
She is full of shit.
that's why I dumped her.
I warned you.
I would like to see you fuck
to understand.
This is what I wanted to ask.
Haven't we watched enough pornos?
C'mon!
It's not the same thing.
Promise me.
You're a pain in the ass, Baptiste.
I promise. Happy now?
Any gum?
My mouth tastes like shit.
No.
Wait a sec...
I have a strawberry flavored rubber.
It'll have to do.
I can't sleep.
Tell me how beautiful I am.
Again and forever.
You're as beautiful as a god.
You're as beautiful as a truck,
as a shiny new coin.
That's all?
As beautiful as a sunflower.
As beautiful as a fire engine ladder.
As beautiful as a squirrel.
As Holy Communion.
You're as beautiful as a ladybug.
Mom?
What?
When d'you start to feel old?
The first time
you asked me this that question!
I don't want Pierre
to get a motorcycle.
Pierre didn't die in
a motorcycle accident?
No, Lucie.
I don't believe anymore, Doctor.
Last night,
I tried crying but couldn't.
- I felt better when I could cry.
- It'll come back.
You tried to write as I suggested?
Tell me the truth, Doctor...
Is Pierre dead?
All images I have
are from when we were grown.
I don't have any from before.
It must be part of my illness.
Our bodies and faces
as kids are gone.
Our dad died
in a motorcycle accident.
I was 8, Pierre was 7.
One year separates us.
Nicolas Saunier.
Date of birth?
February 6, 1984.
Profession?
Law student, first year.
Address?
My parents or
my apartment near the university?
Your parents'.
Around midnight, after rehearsal.
Did he say where he was going.
No. Home, I think.
And... have you noticed
anything recently?
Anything fishy about him?
Why all these questions?
You were the last to see him.
You're close: studies, the band...
Who else can I count on
to find him?
I'm doing my job.
Did you find his motorbike?
No.
It looks like a runaway,
but his mom and sister don't buy it.
So, I'm investigating
Well?
Tell me!
Go on, Nico, you start.
I'm lighting my cigarette.
What do you feel, Lucie?
He's not here, Mom.
Stop repeating the same thing!
You think he'd just disappear
without telling us?
Without telling you?
We have to be strong as he'd be.
Is he thinking of us at least?
Inevitably.
It's a good sign
the bike has not been found.
What does the inspector know?
He questioned the guys
and that's it!
They are idiots
for not having come.
You have a hard time
being alone with someone.
Nico's the same.
Pierre can deal with it.
What?
It's often just the two of us.
It's like there's always
something missing.
I feel it.
His analyzing is so annoying.
Nicolas warned me.
So why do you love me?
I never said that.
I said "I like you a lot".
Drop it, you're such a liar.
So are you.
You're really
in love with Pierre.
Nico thinks...
Pierre and you...
What, Pierre and me?
He thinks you do it together.
Is this true?
Even if it was true,
you think I'd tell you?
Don't mind us,
We're just going for a dip.
We should write
something about this place.
Yeah, something really sappy.
What do you have against
sappy things?
You could have said hello.
I've seen you with an erection.
What's with your boner, Nicolas?
You never just got a hard-on
for no reason?
Yes, when you guys fought
or when I watch boxing.
I start getting hard for no reason.
Nico, what was the last thing
he said to you?
Why me? The three of us were together.
Don't be a dick.
The last time it was the two of you.
I don't remember.
Don't take it out on us.
We feel the same.
You're not doing anything!
And you?
What are you doing?
Paul!
- Mrs. Gambier!
- He isn't here.
- Use your gift!
- I don't know anything.
At least try!
I don't know...
Pierre and I never said anything
because we like you.
Pierre always said:
"Our images ease his headaches
His innocence protects us."
I'll tell your mother
you're a peeping tom.
- You're not mean!
- Tell me what you know.
No.
Does that mean you know?
You're hurting me.
That day, my professor read us this:
"Each man in his night
goes towards his light."
I convinced myself that if I could
imagine everyone's nights,
I could shine some light
onto their destinies.
- Why won't you admit it?
- Stop!
I'm gonna hurt you!
You're lying
and think I'm stupid!
I'm ready to understand.
This don't bother me.
What irritates me is
you denying it like a jerk.
I don't want to be a jerk!
You want to stop going out,
is that it?
What is that?
It's your strawberry...
the one I love to bite!
Pierre has exactly the same one.
You could have showered.
I like keeping his scent.
Smells like milk.
Don't you think?
Like a baby.
I prefer yours.
You better.
Do you think the others know?
Nicolas would do himself if they knew.
What are we going to become become?
Happy people.
Happy people are boring.
We'll be the first people
happy-not-boring.
We spent hours stuck to each other
like animals in their lair.
I went out with Nicolas
and then with Sebastien.
But never both at the same time.
Leave me alone. I'm exhausted.
Stop thinking about Pierre.
He'll come back.
We've never done it here.
It turns me on.
I said I'm totally out of it.
Everyone wants to connect to my brother.
People radiate towards him.
I knew it from when he was a baby.
When I saw him in his cradle,
I wanted to hold him.
I was too little.
I made up for lost time.
When hold him, I feel like
I'm proving eternity.
Please...
make Pierre appear.
He's my brother.
Please.
I'm ready to know today.
Pierre is dead.
The headline read:
"Body found near La Roquette."
Tomorrow, I can forget again.
Fractured lower jaw,
nose and skull.
Several fractured ribs.
Burst spleen.
Internal hemorrhage.
Brain lesions.
I'm in the reality now.
I hope you're satisfied,
the treatment works.
Sporadically, but it works.
I'm telling as it comes...
Come on, Lucie, I'll get cold.
Don't you get fed up?
You know...
Drinking, eating, pissing, shitting...
Soaping up, rinsing of...
Drying, dressing, undressing...
Looking in the mirror, getting up...
Itching, shaving...
All those repetitions.
Grow a beard! One less thing to do.
Pierre wanted to be burned.
My brother was burning.
The five of us were there
when Pierre went up in smoke.
It was unimaginable.
None of us had ever been to...
a cremation before.
Pierre keeps teaching me things.
It lasts 1 1/2 hours.
We recommend not staying the whole time.
The urn will be available
tomorrow at 9.
Thank you.
Do you know why you're crying?
Yes.
Why?
Because life separates us.
By imposing this sentence?
Life doesn't mean anything.
See, we're not separated.
You're an idiot.
No, I mean, you know the college and...
the band and the girls and guys.
- Before it was just you and me.
- It'll always be.
Really?
You're annoying 'cause you know it.
I just wanted to make sure.
It's beyond my control.
It's my life force.
We have one lead:
A sperm stain on his shirt.
Sperm that's not his.
You call that a lead?
Don't be aggressive,
It's hard enough as it is.
I bet it's Nicolas
and he's innocent.
And his jacket?
Not found.
Finding that would be a lead!
No one said he was wearing it.
It's like the motorbike...
You have no idea
and we we've been counting on you!
I'm going to verify the sperm.
We are here for a test.
Yes, I know.
It's on the third floor.
Thanks.
Here it is.
Can I stay with him?
It's against the rules.
It's okay.
Think of him.
- Think of us.
- It's fine, I'll manage.
It's just a jerk-off.
- You should know if it's yours.
- It's mine,
but that fucked cop
wants it tested.
There's other ways of getting DNA.
He must get off
imagining me wanking.
My brother was bisexual.
So is he.
- We had meetings for
That's what I... - I know the case...
And you?
- I'm fine.
- What do you mean "fine"?
I'm straight.
You're gonna tell me who did it.
You're scaring me, stop!
Did you know he was dead the other day?
Yes.
Come on, concentrate.
Tell me who killed him.
You want money?
How much?
My sadness prevents me from seeing.
You have to believe me.
I'll distract you then.
You're still a virgin?
Come on Paul, try to relax.
I don't know you anymore.
Leave me alone. My head aches!
I'm sorry.
You know what the cops say?
My brother's case is almost closed.
In a month his case will be closed.
"Probably someone from out of town"
That's it.
But I don't believe it.
I thought you could help me.
I don't know anything.
I swear.
- Not another step!
- You scare me.
They don't want us to play.
What's wrong?
We don't like Arab loving fags.
And if you play?
We'll destroy you goddamn snobs!
What's with him?
Forget it.
They're known around here.
Know what I mean?
We could've become just like them.
I bet we all look the same naked.
- Shut up, fag.
- No more fag than you!
Get the hell out!
Next time we come we'll be 50
against these fags.
And that fag
better stay out of my way!
All you can bark is "fag"?
I'll tell you when I'm ready.
For you to open and tell all
Same old bullshit over and over
And your desire for me
always so strong
You take me for a prick
Who gives a shit
We should have put
music on at the cremation.
Some of his favorite songs.
Can't you think of anything else?
Thanks for coming with me.
It is normal
We also want to know.
If I'm not back in an hour
come get me.
Are you sure it's there?
Absolutely.
Hi Romain.
- Hi...
How do you know my name?
Want a drink?
No, I'm fine.
And what do you want?
See if you're a fag.
You like me?
More without this Nazi costume.
You don't know me.
You have a twin inside of you,
and you're lost.
Are you gonna bite my lip again?
Why are you doing this?
You may not be a fag
but you're not hot-to trot.
Would you feel better
in your costume?
No, I'd like to see you again to talk...
I heard about your friend.
- How?
I heard it on the local news.
- You watch the news?
You came to see I was involved.
Where's your fucking violence?
Where does Mr. Nice Guy
hide his hatred?
I saw the hate in your eyes!
He was my brother.
He's clean.
Are you sure?
- Yes, be quiet!
I should have taken
more pictures of him.
I'm missing so many.
What are you talking about?
Lots of his expressions...
I can't stand it, Mom.
It's because you lock yourself up
in your room or in his room.
I need to know what happened.
You must return to life.
What are you hanging on to, Mom?
To you, Lucie.
What are you doing?
- I'm collecting you.
What?
- I'm looking at you, recording you.
And?
It's rare to see you in a state.
It's difficult to capture that.
You get uptight when you clean...
What's the point?
I hate it when you get snotty!
So do it even if you annoy me!
I decide what I collect from you.
Pierre told me everything.
Everything.
I miss Pierre's voice terribly.
His tone was always constant.
He talked about his life.
I just had to imagine...
Will I see you again?
Do you do these this often?
Once a month.
But I meant...
I'd like to see you alone.
Same price?
You name the price.
That should be possible.
I miss your brother very much.
He often spoke of you.
Did you replace him?
Not yet.
You loved him?
I think I DID.
Your love had a price.
That's true.
Pierre wasn't cheap
if that's what you mean.
What he gave me
was totally worth it.
You're not here
to talk about money?
You know, I was married for 5 years.
And my wife surprised me
here with a younger boy.
She asked for a divorce.
It cost me a lot of money.
A few months later,
she moved in with him.
You were tricked?
Actually I was never able
to admit it.
I never knew who was
victim of whom.
What exactly did you come for?
To get to know you better.
You're looking for the killer.
I'd never massacre
such a beautiful young man.
Have an idea?
Pierre told me everything
and nothing.
Mostly nothing.
The body must always be engaged.
You mean desire?
- I'm talking about my body.
To feel alive,
I need to engage it sexually.
Some use it politically
and burst.
They eliminate themselves physically.
Their bodies are their sole power.
No more ideas and words.
They're naive, like our songs.
You like sex, that's all.
It gives me the certainty of living.
Like a kamikaze with a cause...
I'd engage my body.
Yeah...
How's it with Sebastien?
Not bad.
Better than with me?
Never better than with you.
Only a body can know another body.
You come with us.
Julie, do you mind if he joins us?
- No.
Are you turned on at least?
A little, yes.
That's already a lot.
Get undressed.
Pierre, I prefer watching, I swear.
I'm sorry for being late.
I went home to change,
I didn't realize it was so far.
It was to not be seen together.
It's not a problem.
Are you okay?
Call me Damien.
I liked you right when I saw you.
Glad you called back.
I usually don't like normal guys.
Good evening.
What would you like?
- A coffee, please.
You wanna talk about your brother?
I'm not supposed to mix work and...
I said I like you.
I know I don't last long.
But if you would just stay still
like that...
I mean... if we could
keep that intimacy,
we can start again.
Give me a cigarette.
You're really cool.
Most girls don't understand.
They get pissed because I'm quick.
I need your help.
His case was closed too soon.
I swear, we have nothing.
Something could've escaped you.
Reopen the case.
Read it again.
There're lots of unresolved cases.
More than you think.
We're within national stats.
I don't give a shit about stats.
I want to find
my brother's murderer.
Do you understand?
I like when you stroke me.
There must've been
at least two people.
What does your boss say?
First he thought theft:
The bike and jacket are gone.
Out-of-towners who followed him.
It might've been to muddle things up.
Then he thought
it was sex related...
Your brother got around a lot.
Perhaps it was revenge
or some jealous guy...
who got back at him.
I questioned some
gay guys, but no...
Look, I'm getting hard again.
Can I lick you?
I was engaging my body.
Pierre would've been proud of me.
He knew I was going to find
his deranged murderer.
That was my logic.
I wasn't deranged yet...
A girl came to see me after class.
She was Algerian. Pretty.
I thought she was hitting on me...
but she wasn't.
She asked me about Pierre.
That's why she came to see me.
She seemed to be in love.
She saw us at one of our concerts,
but...
she didn't dare talk to him.
This seems very complicated...
What are you saying?
She was with her two brothers
at the concert.
When they saw she fancied Pierre,
they forbid her to ever see him again.
That's why she came to me,
to try to see him.
What's her name?
Where does she live?
I don't know. I told her to piss off
and I never saw her again.
What's the use if I can't
get my hands on her.
Who cares if her brothers
were protecting her?
What are you trying to say?
That he died because
some cultural thing?
Calm down, Lucie!
You always over-react!
No one dares talk to you!
Are you finished?
I'm sorry.
What else?
Hurry! I don't like this moment!
I can't...
Don't look at me!
I miss Pierre.
Will you sing me Dad's song?
No, it'll make you sad.
It's a good sadness.
I do as she says,
I never answer back.
She'd think it treason
Her jealousy gets her out of whack
Beyond good reason
A pretty flower caught my eye,
lovely and fresh.
Prettier than she
A pretty little flower,
one day, was threshed
From her umbrella
I'm like a child
around this doll
That shuts her eyes
when you put her to sleep
I'm like a child
around this little doll
That cries Mama
and then she weeps
Palm readers, gypsies
and magic stones
Make predictions
Her arms will be the cross
of my very own
Crucifixion.
There's always better,
there is always the worse,
But you have to face the drop
Hanging here or there
it's the same old curse.
But you have to face the drop
I'm like a child
around this little doll
That shuts her eyes
when you put her to sleep
I'm like a child
around this little doll
That cries Mama
and then she weeps
I wrote everything down..
It's a bit of a mess..
You were right, it helped.
I haven't finished.
It helps me understand
even if there's nothing to understand,
even if I haven't understand.
You haven't helped me with that.
You don't help me...
I regret not having been able
to clean him at the morgue.
They wouldn't let me.
"That's not done, miss."
Hold me tight, I feel so alone.
You always find a good excuse.
I'm sure you want to know,
Doctor...
What we did with our bodies
was extremely subtle.
We didn't need to make love.
Only a body can know another body.
Only his really knew mine.
We have something to say.
Go on, Sebastien.
We think we know
what happened to Pierre.
A group of gypsies live near Aix.
They steal and resell motorbikes.
I pretended I was interested
in buying one...
- I saw his motorbike.
- When?
Yesterday.
They just changed the plates.
Did you tell the cops?
Cops don't do shit.
They can't be bothered.
After two months,
they should have found this out.
- He's right.
- He's wrong.
It's risky. Especially if you
think they killed him for his bike.
You want to play
cowboys and Indians?
Maybe they just
found the bike.
I'll call the inspector.
So,
what should we do?
Nothing, my mom's is right.
Let's do as planned.
It'll do us good.
What do you want to show me?
I got a strawberry tattoo!
Asshole!
I said no.
He won't even touch you.
He just wants to watch.
How can he ask that?
- Did you fuck him?
- Your jealousy is annoying.
You fuck girls to prove you're a man!
It's different.
I don't care about girls.
He pays well.
- really well...
- I said no.
You know what he wants?
To experience
what he never had before.
I think it's touching.
He wants to see two young
passionate bodies.
That's is what we are.
You're disgusting. It's sick.
It's not sick at all.
It's reality TV at home!
You're ready to sell
our intimacy like that?
I'm selling because he's buying.
It's business.
It's fucked up.
Our bundle is growing, sis.
Over 350.
We should invest it.
And to prove where it came from?
Think!
So when do we spend it?
I've spent some on the band.
The losers are always broke.
You know what?
Some orgy planner
offered me a great gig...
He just wants to watch me have sex.
I talked to Nicolas. He refused.
And he took it badly.
I'm gonna buy a motorbike.
No, Pierre, no motorbikes.
If Dad had died in a train crash,
would you stop taking the train?
I always chased away the image
of you on a motorbike. It's horrible.
I'll be so beautiful.
Traveling on the wings of the wind.
We should get away from here.
If we're gonna live together,
we need a change
I don't want to live with you.
Why not?
They look so young.
You're selfish like your brother,
always using people.
What you did together
was so twisted.
You've been punished.
Don't you ever speak
of Pierre like that!
I'm sorry.
It's all this tension.
Okay, go over there.
Well?
Nothing.
They found
the bike in the countryside.
We questioned them
according to procedure.
They have nothing to do
with the murder.
Gonna sulk all night?
I'm sorry it wasn't them.
It could've raised the statistics.
Can I leave you now?
No, you can't.
As long as we don't have the killer,
you have to do what I want.
I'm joking.
I'm sorry.
I'm an asshole.
Sorry, Lucie.
I really like you.
What can I do for you?
Like shoot your wad in 10 seconds?
You're an asshole.
What are you doing?
You're losing your mind!
- Where are the others?
- Baptiste is coming.
Sebastien is sick.
What's wrong?
Heartbreak.
You dumped him, remember?
- Call him, I have to talk to you all.
- Why here?
You'll understand later.
You have to come.
Lucie insists.
She has something to tell us.
I don't know! Move your ass!
Baptiste is also sick.
What's wrong?
Are you smashed?
What do you want?
I'm waiting for Sebastien.
Why'd you make us come here?
It's sado-maso.
It's like an exorcism,
you'll understand.
- Pierre saw this before he died.
- Enough, Lucie!
Where the hell is he?
It's freaky meeting here.
We're here where Pierre
lost his life...
I've an announcement to make,
I'm pregnant.
It's a boy
and it will be a boy.
I'll call him Pierre.
We're here to ward bad fate.
I wanted to share this with you.
It's yours, Sebastien.
I'm keeping it it even
if we're not together
The baby will belong to all of us.
Even if life separates us...
like Pierre's death is doing.
Life lacks rituals, don't you think?
I write.
My shrink thinks it's healing.
That it puts me into reality.
At first I didn't say anything.
Selective mutism.
And of course, the pills...
I've been here 8 months.
Crazy, huh?
You're in danger here.
I can't live and I can't seem to die.
Know what I was thinking?
That you bring me a knife,
a pretty big knife.
You're the only one I can ask.
You have to live.
You're going to live.
If you say it, Paul.
Who are you watching now?
You, Lucie.
No, I mean outside.
Like you did with us.
No one.
You're mad!
It makes no sense to have this baby!
I don't want to talk about it.
What do you want to talk about?
Hello, Lucie.
They don't know what came over them.
They?
My son...
Sebastien and Baptiste.
I wanted to tell you
before the police.
I caught Nicolas
wearing this jacket.
He confessed everything.
Sorry.
I don't understand.
His mother stayed with him.
I'm going to the police
to deliver the jacket.
I don't know what to do...
He stayed with his mother.
I haven't called...
Baptiste and Sebastien's parents.
The police should.
As soon as I leave here,
I'm going to the police.
I don't know what else to say.
I don't know anything else.
Nothing.
I want to see them!
I keep imaging cop shows!
What'd they say?
Don't be an asshole!
There's nothing to know.
They're being transferred!
Thanks.
I want to talk to you.
Leave us alone, Lucie.
I told you everything last night.
You've been alone with Nicolas.
He must've said something?
Nothing.
We also want to understand!
And the others...
did you speak to their parents?
Briefly...
They're like us, devastated.
Baptiste wasn't involved.
He just watched.
Leave us alone!
It's unbearable!
We're sorry.
You have to understand.
I had an intense dream last night.
Those dreams that seem real.
What was it?
Do you want to tell me?
No.
It was about the abortion.
I think I went mad
to be locked up like them.
Dear Lucie,
This isn't my first letter,
but the first I'll send.
Time passes slowly here.
It's trite.
I have a homosexual buddy.
"By default"
that's what he says.
I'm coming to terms with it...
I call out for Pierre at night.
He doesn't mind.
It's just sexual.
I'm fulfilled without love.
I have to take part
in another reenactment.
Baptiste's lawyer is asking for it.
We'll get to see each other,
and get some air...
I have to play my role like an actor.
I'm not the same.
I've changed. I think.
I feel better about myself...
Barehanded. I swear.
Pierre...
whoever it was,
don't fight back.
Shut up!
Suddenly I thought Pierre
found a way to be a Kamikaze.
Must be the pills
giving me these thoughts.
I never told you what I was doing...
while they were killing Pierre.
I was folding laundry.
Absurd, isn't it?
I was humming, you know,
one of those repetitive songs.
No intuition, no premonition.
No weird feeling.
Nothing.
How cute am I today?
Like a heart.
It's my new shirt for good luck.
- We brought the house down!
- You screwed up...
Fuck, we really did it!
Two encores! Fantastic!
We ran out of songs like jerks.
- We should've repeated one.
- We didn't think of it!
Not bad!
There's lots of fans waiting for you.
What do they want?
I'm condemned to searching
for the unanswerable.
People kill
and we don't know why.
I need to understand that.
You really scared me!
You said that I'd live,
did you forget?
When did you get out?
Yesterday.
What are you doing?
Learning how to die without him.
Don't worry.
Nicolas and Sebastien were sentenced
to 18 years for murder.
Baptiste was sentenced to 5 years:
"Non assistance to a person in danger
and passive complicity."
During the entire hearing,
none expressed their
motives for the murder.
This film was based on
a true story
that took place in France.