I heard you are
doing another program?
Hot, isn't it?
Do you know how to use
a fire extinguisher?
Forget it.
I know how to cheer you up.
Want to have a drink?
-Were you drinking?
-No.
You had a lot.
Why did you drink so much?
I didn't.
You'd better lie down.
Are you okay?
What?
Something's wrong.
Are you really okay?
What's wrong?
Something's wrong.
Don't cry. Don't cry...
Eun-su, come and have some breakfast.
Have some breakfast, Eun-su.
I'm not hungry. I want to sleep more.
I made something good. Get up, okay?
I don't want to.
Come on. Get up.
Leave me alone! Just go away!
How long have you been
singing ''Arirang''?
I started when I was 20...
How long ago is that?
60 years.
60 years?
Ma'am, do you sing
''Arirang'' with him too?
That's a ridiculous question.
Men do not sing with their wives.
Not like these days.
Not even once with her?
Men do not sing with their wives.
Not old man like me.
Are you ready?
Why don't you sing, Ma'am?
I put up a thorn fence
to hold in my youth.
But it slipped away,
leaving me with grey hair.
The sun must set when it's time comes.
I wish my lover
had a good reason to leave.
Arirang...Arirang...Arariyo.
I follow my love up Arirang Hill.
What are you going to do now?
We're almost finished.
What do you mean?
I mean, we're almost finished.
What's finished?
I said we're almost done.
Didn't you hear me?
-What's finished?
-Oh, Jesus.
I just wanted to know...
what you are going to do
after this project? Okay?
I've got to go somewhere.
Come make me some ramen, okay?
Okay?
I have work to do.
What work?
Something I don't know about?
You're going drinking aren't you?
Eun-su.
Do I look like your maid?
Watch your language.
Eun-su, I got you something to eat.
This is FM Music Hall
with Han Eun-su.
Please feel free to share
all your love stories with us.
I loved you with
all my life could bear.
I trusted you with such sincerity.
I know I shouldn't have loved you.
I'd be willing to try it again,
but goodbye...
Hurry up. The producer
is going crazy. Okay?
All right.
Is this the one?
Hello?
Where are you going?
Move!
I'm in the sound studio.
It's been a while.
I have to get back to work.
Are you still angry?
Are you happy that I came?
Did you miss me?
I should go.
Are you asleep?
No.
Sang-Woo, let's not see
each other for a month.
Do you mean you want
to break-up with me?
Would you want to?
I don't know.
Grandma! Grandma!
It's been a long time since
we had dinner together.
Do you normally have your meals
at regular time?
Sang-Woo.
Where is your girlfriend? I thought
I told you to bring her home.
You have a girlfriend?
Marry her, then.
I can't take care of
your family forever.
I am tired.
-I don't have one.
-You don't?
You should get married while
your grandma is still alive.
And I want a grandson too.
You want me to set you up?
I know a nice girl.
Don't bother.
I'm full. Can I be excused?
Where are you going?
You haven't finished yet.
I lost my appetite.
I bought pork belly just
because you are home.
Mother, eat slower, okay?
Come on, mom.
Something's going on, isn't it?
Nothing's going on.
Hang on son.
Hi, it's me. How you doing?
You sound busy.
Okay. Don't want to bother you.
Seems like we are pretty far away.
You scared of me?
Drive faster.
Faster.
Hello?
I said I'd call you. Stop doing this.
What are you doing here?
Hey.
What's up?
I don't think
I can continue working here.
Let's go for a drink after work.
I'll find someone to replace me.
What are you talking about?
What's the matter with you?
You know better than that.
Aw, fuck!
What? Fuck?
I'm sorry.
Stay here...
Come back!
Let me stay here tonight.
Sang-woo.
Eun-su, want to see something funny?
Don't act like this.
You want a ride?
No, thanks!
I didn't do anything wrong, did l?
See you.
Could you stop, please?
I want to break up.
I'll do better.
Let's break up.
Do you love me?
How could love disappear so fast?
Let's break up then.
Grandma, let's go.
Grandma, come on.
I have to wait for your grandfather.
He's gone.
He's passed away, Grandma.
Let's go.
Get a hold of yourself!
-Hey, how've you been?
-You skip dinner again?
I'm eating now.
Want to go to Kang-neung?
Let's have a drink.
Nah. I don't want to drink.
Because if I get drunk,
I will feel like
she's waiting for me again.
Sang-woo, forget about her.
Imagine she's an old woman.
Her hair's all gray,
she's got wrinkles.
That might help you forget.
Just keep that in mind.
Right.
I feel kind of sorry
for an old Eun-su.
But I still miss her.
Let's go.
Stay a little longer.
What are you doing here?
I just wanted to see you.
Are you going somewhere?
Go home. I've got to leave.
Do you want a ride?
Was it hard to find?
Yeah. You got here early?
Yeah, we've been waiting for you.
-My friends.
-How are you?
-You must be tired. Let's get inside.
-OK!
Sang-woo!
Let it out.
Buses and women are all the same.
Once they leave,
they will never stop for you.
-How have you been?
-Very well.
You haven't changed a bit.
Do you remember?
What?
You know...
It's for your grandma.
I heard plants are good for old
people. Take good care of it.
Stay with me today.
What's wrong?
I should go.
Goodbye.
Sang-woo!