(opera starts)
(music stops)
("Un'aura amorosa del nostro tesoro"
from "Così fan tutte")
Del nostro tesoro
Un dolce ristoro
Al cor porgerà
Un'aura amorosa
Del nostro tesoro
Un dolce ristoro
Al cor porgerà
Al cor che nudrito
Da speme, da amore
Da speme, da amore...
I'll bring you back a slice of cake,
(woman) Get away from the window,
Bisogno non ha
Di un'esca migliore
Bisogno non ha...
Punch, you will call me, won't you?
This way, please,
No, no, I'll take them,
Look, Ma, it's gorgeous,
Well, you're very welcome, Christy,
very welcome,
(impaired speech) To your humble abode,
Hm?
Oh, my humble abode, Yes...
Hello, My name is Mary,
I'll be with you till you go on this evening,
I have to take him into the library,
- I'll see you later,
- (Ma) See you later,
Be careful of that fella,
I'll be OK,
I wouldn't be too sure about that,
Well, now, you're all very welcome
to my humble abode,
and to this benefit organized
by my friend Dr Eileen Cole,
Dr Eileen Cole,
(applause on PA)
Now I'm not going to ask you to put
your hands in your pockets, not yet,
because we're going to start
the evening with a little concert.
Do you want to go out and watch?
No,
(piano on PA)
Do you want to see the original?
The original?
Of the book,
It looks good,
Looks can be deceivin',
It's a bit sentimental,
Did you paint this?
Yes,
That's very good,
(baby crying)
(crying stops)
Mr Brown?
Your son was born a couple of hours ago,
There's been some complications,
- Where's the small one?
- A pint and a small one?
- That's what I said,
- So long as you're payin' for it,
Are you gonna put him in a home, Paddy?
He'll go in a coffin before
any son of mine will go in a home,
Ah, Paddy... I believe it's the end of
the road for you in the breedin' stakes,
Who told you that?
Ah, now... What are you goin' to do, huh?
You goin' to tie a knot in it?
Now, Paddy, there was no need for that,
A shut mouth catches no flies,
Where's Tom?
(Ma) Is Tom not up yet?
(Tom) It's all right! I'm up! I'm up ages!
Say goodbye to Christy, Father,
(Paddy) Goodbye, Christy,
(Ma) Good girl, See you later,
See you, Christy,
- See you, Christy,
- Bye, Christy,
Something for the money box, Christy,
Another pound saved, Christy,
Here, Christy,
Good boy, That's it,
I have to go away, Christy,
To hospital,
Don't worry, Sheila's going
to look after you while I'm gone,
Do you understand, Christy?
That's my ma, That's my da,
I was their baby,
It's only for a few days, Christy,
I'd better get this house
organized before I go,
You can't be stickin' to me
like stickin' plaster forever, Christy,
Nearly there, Christy,
Christy, I have to go and make
a phone call, Stay there,
Oh, my God... Nan...
Nan! Nan!
(Ma falls)
(wailing)
(banging)
- But what really happened?
- I heard this bangin' and rushed over,
She was carryin' Christy
down the stairs when she fell,
And there he was,
lyin' at the bottom of the stairs like a moron,
God help her,
He's a terrible cross to the poor woman,
Ah, sure he has the mind
of a three-year-old,
A is for apples,
B is for butter,
C is for carrot,
And D... is for dunce,
Ya poor, unfortunate gobshite,
Enough to feed an army,
God, you'll never go hungry, Christy,
Would you like to come back with me
till your mammy comes home?
(girl) What's 25 percent of a quarter?
(Paddy) 25 percent of a quarter?
Now that's a stupid question,
I mean, 25 percent is a quarter,
You can't have a quarter of a quarter,
You can, Can't you, Christy?
What would he know?
Ma, Ma, Christy picked up the chalk,
Go on, Christy, Go on, make your mark,
(boy) It's a Y.
It's an X.
- What's that, Christy?
- That's only an oul' squiggle,
There's something in that,
Nah, don't be gettin' notions
into your head, woman,
The child's a cripple, Face facts,
It won't do anybody any good
trying to put ideas in his head,
(cheering)
Right, Now come on,
We're gonna put the engine on now,
- You're puttin' an engine in it?
- Yeah, Come on till you see,
Come on, engine,
All he needs now is a license,
It's great,
(cheering)
Take it easy, will ya?
Ah, go on, take it easy,
He'll play in that all day now,
He can go out with the other boys now,
Look at those! They're massive!
- What's that?
- That's her thing,
You put your thing in there
for a half an hour and you get a baby,
If you do it for an hour you get twins,
My cousin's a twin,
- Benny! Brian!
- There's your ma,
Quick, Tom, Here's Ma!
- It's not mine!
- Is Benny in there?
- Hide it!
- Where?
Are you deaf? Come in for your tea!
- Hide it under Christy,
- Are yis all deaf?
I've been calling you for 20 minutes
to come in for your tea,
- It's OK, Mam, we'll take him in,
- Well, take him in now,
It's been on the table
for at least a half an hour,
See?
Why won't he go to bed?
He loves that oul' chariot,
Come on, get him up,
I want to go and have a pint,
Come on, Christy,
It's way past your bedtime,
It's nearly closin' time,
Now, son, you know
you can never get out of hell,
You can get out of purgatory,
but you can never get out of hell,
Do you know that?
Do you?
Mrs Brown?
I don't think you should
bring him to the altar just yet,
You've been very helpful, Father,
Do you know about All Souls' Night?
Did I ever tell you about that?
It's a really special night, Every time
you light a candle on All Souls' Night,
and you have to say five Our Fathers
and five Hail Marys and five Glory Be's,
and then a soul flies up
out of the flames of purgatory
and goes straight up to heaven,
Say some prayers
for the poor souls in purgatory,
Right,
(Christy moans)
- What's wrong with you?
- (continues moaning)
Christy, keep your voice down,
What's wrong with you, son?
What's the matter? What do you want?
Do you want to light another candle,
is that it? Do you? For the poor souls?
Good boy, That's a good boy,
And don't forget, even if we
can't understand you, God can,
See, Christy?
Even God has to lock his house,
Look, Christy, there it is!
There's a soul going up to heaven!
Oh, look! Look, Christy, Oh, look,
- Oh, you'll frighten the life out of him!
- Here, Christy, You're king of the bonfire,
Don't be frightened, Christy,
It's only your brother, Tom,
This way, Christy, This way,
You all right, Christy?
(Ma) What's Christy doin', Sheila?
Is he all right?
He's drawin',
He's drawin' a triangle,
No, Christy, you don't start there,
Here, son,
Now that's a triangle,
That's not a triangle,
That's an A.
- What's up?
- (Paddy) Keep quiet,
- All I said was "What's up?"
- Sit down!
Here, Paddy,
Why don't you go and have a pint?
- What?
- Here,
- What's that?
- It's money,
- Where'd you get it?
- From the fairies,
- Go and have a drink,
- I don't need a drink,
All I need is to be obeyed
in me own house!
Mother,
Sweet Jesus...
Jesus sufferin' Christ...
He's a Brown! He's a Brown, all right,
Christy's a Brown!
- Coat,
- Where are you goin', Paddy?
Where do you think?
This man deserves a jar!
This is Christy Brown,
My son, Genius,
(knocking at door)
Hello,
Is he OK?
- He's grand,
- Good,
It's just that he can be a bit...
- What?
- A bit... a bit like Christy,
No, he's fine, He's asleep now,
Well... I'll leave you alone then,
14,
15, 16...
- Keep your voice down,
- ...17...
Great,
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Christy
Go on, Go on now, me boy,
He's a man now, Father,
Come on, Christy, 17 candles,
- Now take a deep breath, Come on,
- (baby cries)
Will you shut that baby up,
for Christ's sake?
- Take it easy, Christy,
- Go on,
Go on, Christy, Go on,
Go on, Christy,
Go on,
- It's like the bleedin' fire of hell, that one,
- Come on, Christy, Here,
There you are, now, Go on,
That's it, Well done, Don't worry,
you'll get your wheelchair, Christy,
Get the fuckin' ball!
Save it, Christy!
Well saved, Christy!
He bit me! He bit me!
- It's a free out! A free out!
- Right, OK,
- We're takin' it, right?
- OK, come on,
Pass it, will ya?
Stay away from them sheets,
He handled it!
Penno for the Browns, Give us it,
Let Christy take it,
- You can't hold him up!
- Right,
(yelling)
If it stops at Tom, I'll kill ya,
- Nobody,
- No, nobody,
It's pointin' at Christy,
- He's not in the game,
- He is if it's pointin' at him,
I don't think it's pointin' at me,
Sure you're the nicest of the lot,
And you've nice eyes too,
Let's go, Ah, Christy, ya boy, ya!
Chasin' the women!
- See you, Tom,
- See you, Rachel,
See you, Tom,
(laughter)
She's mad about you, Christy!
(woman giggles)
Not here, Brendan, Later,
(Ma) This is a fine time of night
to be comin' in,
- What's wrong, Ma?
- I don't like these late nights, Sheila,
What's this?
Holiday pay, isn't it?
I got laid off,
What about Christy's wheelchair?
Christy will get his wheelchair, OK?
Why did you get laid off?
Don't you question me
in front of the children,
A brick hit the foreman on the head
accidentally on purpose,
(Christy murmurs)
It's Rachel,
- How are ya?
- What?
"Your beautiful eyes are splendid pools
of blue in whose depths I swim regularly,"
It's lovely, isn't it?
He even signed it himself,
Even signed it himself,
CB, That's not Tom Brown,
That's Christy,
Sure he does it with his left foot!
(laughter)
You're in love with a cripple!
She's in love with a cripple!
Rachel, come back!
Could I speak to Christy Brown, please?
Christy! You're wanted,
Did you paint that?
Yeah,
I can't take it,
I'm sorry,
Tell your brother Tom
we were askin' for him,
- What's this?
- (Ma) What does it look like?
But we had porridge for breakfast,
So?
And we had it for dinner,
I'm not eatin' any more,
You get that into ya,
I can't,
Get it into ya,
Go on, more,
(Christy) Who's been eating my porridge?
- What did you say?
- (unclear)
- What did he say, missus?
- He just said the porridge is lovely,
Burst his brain, the barbarian,
Keep quiet!
(sniggering)
Aw, come on, Christy,
Everybody has to go to bed,
I have to do my painting,
I know, but everybody has to go to bed
because there's no coal,
Now, Christy, don't push me nerves
any further, all right?
I'm sorry, Mam,
Yeah, Oh, Christy, someday
you'll have a place of your own,
Right, come on, you lot, come on in,
Mind my paintings,
- (Paddy) Are all those kids in bed?
- (Ma) Right,
(moaning)
- What's up, Christy?
- Coal,
- What?
- Coal!
Coal? It's too early,
- All right, all right!
Mister!
Mister! Me driver abandoned me,
Could you push me out of the way?
- Your plan's not working, Christy,
- Wait till it goes up the hill,
Margaret, hold the baby,
(cheering)
Come on, Christy!
We'll be warm for the whole winter,
Christy!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
What's happened to you?!
It's all right, Ma, It's only coal,
I know where you got that coal,
You know it's a sin to steal,
And you know that God
is looking down on you right now,
And that coal is not coming
into this house!
Come on in here
and sit by the fire, woman,
- Do you want me to wash you, Christy?
- No,
- Good night, Christy,
- Don't you be late,
(moaning)
Ma! There's somethin' wrong
with Christy!
There's somethin' wrong with him,
What's wrong with you, Christy?
The fire,
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
Aagh!
- Ma, what are you trying to do?!
- Get water, quick,
Hurry up,
What's wrong with you? Are you mad?!
What have you got in the box, woman?
Christy's money,
- What?
- Money for Christy's wheelchair,
- Must be £20 in there,
- £28, seven and threepence,
We've been freezin' cold, eatin' porridge
for breakfast, dinner and tea,
and you have £28, seven and threepence
up the fuckin' chimney?!
(raucous laughter continues)
Tom, Brian, everybody, upstairs,
Now,
- Mam, what's going on?
- You too, Christy,
Your daughter's gettin' married,
Oh, that's wonderful news,
- When?
- Friday,
What's the rush?
- She's pregnant,
- That's great news,
I mean, that's wonderful,
That's just what we need,
Who's the father? Or do you know?
Leave me alone, It's not my fault,
And whose fault is it, then? Is it mine?
That's a lovely picture,
The oul' woman that lives in the shoe
and the daughter
that can't keep her knickers on!
Stop it, Stop it!
- (Paddy) Ya dirty sleeveen bitch!
- Stop it! Stop it, Father!
(clattering)
- (Ma) Get out of here, Sheila,
- (Paddy) She should be thrown out!
Her and her swollen belly!
I'll give her fornication!
(Sheila) Get away from me,
- (Paddy) That'll keep your legs shut for ya!
- (Ma) Paddy, leave her!
I'll get hold of you!
I'll break every bone in your fuckin' body!
- I'll fuckin' kill him,
- Oh, Christy, stop,
(Paddy) Jesus Christ! What am
I going to do in this fuckin' house?!
Tom, Benny, stop him,
- For Christ's sake stop, Christy!
- (Christy howls)
Christy, stop!
Christy!
Stop, Christy, stop,
Please, stop!
(yelling)
(baby crying)
(Christy wails)
He's gone now,
Christy,
Come on, Christy,
It's OK,
Christy, I'm going away,
I'll miss you too,
Look after me ma for me,
(baby crying)
(applause on PA)
I need a light,
- What?
- I need a light,
I don't smoke,
I need a light,
I'm not deaf, I can hear ya,
You need a light,
I haven't got any matches, so you'll just
have to wait here while I go and get one,
Don't think I'm your mother
just cos I'm looking after you,
I don't need a fuckin' psychology lesson,
I just need a fuckin' light,
- Light,
- Have you got a cigarette?
I'm just after tellin' ya I don't smoke,
Was there anything else I can do for you?
Glass,
No point in drinkin' out of the bottle, huh?
Hello, Dr Cole, please,
Hello, Eileen,
Yes, Yeah,
Athetoid cerebral palsy,
- He's 19?
- Yes, 19,
Yes, 19,
Yes, that's correct,
Mm, Mm,
I'll get his address,
OK, OK,
Dr Cole thinks that...
this model would be the best for your son,
- Which one?
- This one here,
That is grand,
See that there?
He won a prize for that,
- It's lovely,
- Wait till I show you now...
- What's that there?
- Oh, that's nothing, Isn't that lovely?
And that one,
That got torn, but we put it together again,
Ah, that's his first one he ever did, there,
Christy, there's someone to see ya,
This is Dr Cole,
Hello, Christy,
You're a great painter,
Thanks,
Look, I'm a doctor, like your mother says,
and I specialize in cerebral palsy,
We've just started a clinic here in Dublin
and, I wonder, would you like to attend it?
(unclear)
No, we don't have to pay, Christy,
We don't have to pay,
Well?
(unclear)
- He said "Hope deferred...
- ...maketh the heart sick,"
I understood that,
Ah, come on,
Maybe,
Good,
- Good morning, Christy,
- Good morning,
No!
You have to, What do you
want me to do, tow you behind?
Do you wanna ride up front
with the driver?
Come on, come up the front with me,
- I'm all right,
- He said he's all right,
Eileen,
Eileen, Will you come here?
Come on, relax,
- What?
- I want to go home,
- Are you sure?
- Yeah,
(Ma) The door's been locked
for two days now,
I'll tell him you're here,
- Christy?
- Go away,
Christy, there's somebody
here to see you,
(knocking)
(Eileen) Christy?
I'm not a child,
(Ma) "I'm not a child" he says,
It's only children at the clinic,
(Eileen) Christy, if you like,
we can work here,
Fuck off,
With speech therapy, I could teach you
how to say "fuck off' more clearly,
One, two, three, four, five,
And over again,
One, two...
Just relax with it,
Three, four, five, That's it,
One, two, three, and out,
Breathe,
No, Your lungs are too weak,
Try this instead,
Right, now you have a go,
Blow,
Steady, steady... And one big breath,
That's very good, That's very good,
Now focus the breath,
Breathe slowly, and...
He's been like that for three days, I don't
know what's wrong, he won't talk to me,
Go on up and see him, Go on,
(knocking)
I've brought you a present,
Thanks,
There's a speech in there
I'd love you to look at,
It's "To be, or not to be", Hamlet.
I wish you'd stop
feeling sorry for yourself,
You know, I don't want
to be a failure either,
Will you have a look at it for me?
Maybe,
(Christy) To be...
or not to be...
To be, or not to be,
that is the question,
To be, or not...
(Christy continues, unclear)
Whether 'tis nobler in the mind...
(Christy continues)
To be, or not to be,
that is the question,
Whether 'tis nobler in the mind...
to have to fuckin' suffer listenin' to that...
He's in love with this girl Eileen,
Well, so long as he's gettin' better,
Could get hurt, Paddy,
A broken body's nothin'
to a broken heart,
- (knocking)
- Yeah,
Eileen, How's it goin'?
Very, very well,
- I've got some news for you,
- What?
Well, remember I told you
about Peter and his gallery?
Well, he's offered you
an exhibition of your own,
What do you think about that?
- I think you're brilliant,
- Yeah,
I'm only as brilliant as my patients,
(Christy),,consummation devoutly
to be wish'd, To die, to sleep...
...to sleep, perchance to dream...
- Is that our Christy up there?
- What?
Does that sound like our Christy?
Sounds a lot better,
Not to me, it doesn't,
Are ya mad, woman? You can
understand your child for the first time,
- I always understood him,
- Ah, well, nobody else ever did,
At least he can function now,
There's somethin' in that voice that...
that disturbs me,
What do you mean?
Too much hope in it,
What?
There's too much hope in it,
"...fly to others that we know not of?"
"Thus conscience
doth make cowards of us all..."
- "And thus the native hue..."
- "And thus the native hue of resolution
is sicklied o'er
with the pale cast of thought,
and enterprises of great pitch
and moment with this regard
their currents turn awry
and lose the name of action,"
What do you think about Hamlet?
A cripple, Can't act,
- He did in the end,
- Too late,
Eileen...
I like you very much,
And I like you, Christy,
You've the heart of a poet,
No...
Well...
What?
Nothin',
I'd better go,
Ladies and gentlemen,
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you,
It gives me great pleasure to open this
exhibition of the work of Christy Brown,
A lot of people say that Christy
is a great crippled painter,
- I think that's an insult to Christy,
- That's right,
Christy is simply a great painter, full stop,
He has struggled with his material,
as every painter must do,
to bring it under control,
If you look around the walls today,
you'll see the forces
that shaped Christy Brown,
His mother,
His father, His brothers and sisters,
And the lady who brought him
to public recognition, Dr Eileen Cole,
Yes!
What do you think...
There's only two kinds of painting:
religious and the circus,
(laughter)
Give us a drink,
You know, on each side of the mouth...
There you are,
And you've had enough to drink,
D'you hear me?
I'm all right, I'm goin' for a meal, Ma,
Are you comin'?
No, no, I'm... I'll take your father home,
He's not feeling well,
There's no pints, you mean,
It's good wine, tell him,
Your father never drank anything but pints
in his life, No, I'll take him home,
- You gettin' a taxi?
- Eileen's givin' us a lift,
Right,
- I'll see ya later, Mam,
- I'll see ya later,
I think Mulcahy is a great painter,
Inside, Soul,
You see? I agree with Christy,
No, He's too uncontrolled for me,
Ah, Let Christy try the wine,
Intro ibo ad altare Dei.
- What's he saying?
- The Latin mass,
I thought it was James Joyce,
The wine's A1 ,
- Can you tell us which year it is, Christy?
- I'm not that sophisticated,
Not yet,
I love you, Eileen,
- And I love you, Christy,
- No, I really love you,
I love you all,
- That's good,
- I even love Peter,
(laughter)
Well, I'm glad you like Peter, because
we're going to get married in six months,
Well, Christy, what do you think of that?
(loudly) Con...
Con...
(groans with effort)
gra...
tu...
lations, Peter and Eileen,
on the wonder...
wonderful news,
I'm glad you taught me how to speak...
so I could say that, Eileen,
Thanks, Christy,
Well, where were we then?
- Discussing Mulcahy,
- Mulcahy is empty,
- I thought you said he was full of soul,
- I said he was empty, Whiskey!
Take it easy, Christy,
You're not my mother,
Never forget that,
And you know, I know what age that is,
That's ten-year-old,
Same age as me,
- Don't give him any more,
- Pour,
- Take that whiskey from him, Tony,
- Touch it, and I'll kick you
in the only part of your anatomy
that's animated,
Stop it,
Why did you say you loved me?
- Because I do love you,
- Ah, you mean platonic love,
I've had nothing but platonic love
all me life,
Do you know what I say? Fuck Plato!
Fuck all love that is not
100 percent commitment!
Pour,
- I can't let you go any further,
- Let's discuss nature,
- Christy...
- What are you going to do about it, Peter?
You're a nice man,
What are you going to do about it?
Peter, sit down,
I'm gonna wheel you
out of this restaurant,
Wheel out the cripple! Wheel out...
Stop, Stop it,
Where's the feckin' brake
on this stupid thing?!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it, you bastard, stop it!
Sharon!
Sharon? Come on in
for your tea, will ya?
Sharon, come in now
for your tea, please, Come on,
All right, all right, Ma,
Get up, Christy,
You've got a hangover,
that's all that's wrong with ya,
You get more like your father every day,
All hard on the outside
and putty on the inside,
It's in here battles are won,
Not in the pub, pretending
to be a big fella in front of the lads,
Right, if you've given up, I haven't,
What do you think you're doin', Mam?
Buildin' a room for ya,
Don't be mad,
Maybe if you have a room of your own,
you might start paintin' again,
You have me heart broken, Christy Brown,
Sometimes I think you are me heart,
Look, if I could give you my legs,
I would gladly take yours,
What's wrong with you, Christy?
I'm sorry, Mam,
What in the name of God
is goin' on here?
Christy and me is buildin' a room,
- Yis are buildin' a room?
- Yeah,
Will ya have a look at this?
Ah, Christy, you may be a great painter,
but you'll never be a brickie,
Fair play to ya, missus,
Right, lads, You bring in some
more bricks, mix up a bit of muck,
Bring me in me level, will ya? Brown
and Son contractors are on the job,
Here, you start there, I'll start here, and
by the time you have three courses up
- I'll be finished and havin' me tea,
- Not at all!
Water, More water,
I'm not beaten yet, bejasus!
Listen, Brian, boys, listen to me,
Let your father win, He needs it,
Here, Take it easy, Father, will ya?
(Paddy laughs)
Take it easy!
Sure I was never able to take it easy,
And you, of all people, ought to know that,
Right, lads?
That's her finished,
They've a long way to go
to be a better man than their father,
Well, Christy, that's the nearest
he'll ever come to sayin' he loves you,
I'm parched, I'm going to make a nice
cup of tea, and I have a cherry cake here,
Oh, Christy!
I'll just put the kettle on and get
the cherry log, and we'll be away,
Ah, come on, who's in there?
Those kids, their tomfoolery!
- What's happening?
- Ah, come on, let me in!
What's goin' on?
- Jesus, Mary and Joseph! Christy!
- What?
Your father's lying on the floor
and I can't open the door,
Jesus, Mary and Joseph! Paddy!
Christy, I can't open the door!
- Get out the way, Mam,
- I can't open the door, Oh, Jesus...
Push, Christy, push!
Paddy? Oh, Jesus, Mary and Joseph,
Paddy!
(sobs)
Seven pounds five shillings and sixpence
he owed, missus,
And whenever there was
a bit of a scrimmage
I was the toughest of all
Sure I was the toughest of all
Fair play to ya, Christy,
- Drinks for everyone,
- Take it easy, Christy,
Get some drinks in, Get one
for Sadie, shut the oul' bitch up,
Fair play to ya,
Your oul' fella will never be dead,
How's me ma going to survive?
Don't be worryin' about that,
We'll be all right,
Terry, will ya tell us
about when you and me oul' fella
carried the foreman
up the ladder, will ya?
- Later,
- Yeah...
Give us a song, somebody,
for Jesus' sake! Tom, give us a song,
Christy... Sing Paddy's favorite
for me, would ya?
All right, yeah,
It was down the glen one Easter morn
To a city fair rode I
There armored lines of marching men
In squadrons passed me by
Will somebody shut him up?
No fife did hum
No battle drum did sound its loud tattoo
And the Angelus bell
o'er the Liffey's swell
- You'll have to keep it down a bit, lads,
- Rang out in the foggy dew
- He was singin' that for his father,
- His father was nothin' but a mouth,
Like all the Browns,
All right, lads, take it easy,
In respect for Da,
I don't fight cripples,
Wreck the pub!
Come on!
Somebody get the till!
Get the till, get the money!
Get the till!
Drinks are on the house!
That's great, Christy,
- No, it's not,
- Why not?
It's not there, I've no eye,
- What?
- I'm not a painter,
I think it's brilliant, It's the image of Da,
- Poor Tom, what?
- Yeah,
"All is nothing,
Therefore nothing must end,"
- What's all this, Christy?
- Nothing,
Sorry I asked,
Benny, would you help us?
- Doin' what?
- Writin',
Yeah, Writin' what?
Me own story,
Yeah, Course I will,
Don't worry, Christy, the book is... great,
Well, it's not bad,
Do you know what I was going to call it?
- What?
- The Reminiscences...
Reminiscences?
... of a Mental Defective.
- That's a terrible title,
- It was my blue period,
And you typed all of it with your left foot?
I didn't do it with me nose,
- I really wanted to finish it,
- You'll hear it later,
I have an appointment, I told you,
Is he good-lookin'?
- Who?
- Your appointment,
Yeah, in his own way, he's nice,
Oh, it doesn't matter to me,
You can meet who you like,
But is he, now?
- What?
- Is he good-lookin'?
Yeah,
Are you in love with him?
You're very bloody nosy, Christy Brown,
I was only askin',
Would you like a drink?
- I'm workin', I can't,
- Later,
- I have a date, I told ya,
- Yeah, I forgot,
- You're a fast worker, aren't ya?
- Read your book,
I can't with you starin' at me,
I'll look away,
Oh, God...
- She's very pretty, isn't she?
- Prettier than that bloody picture,
Who's in there?
Ma, are you in?
Go on, then,
Jesus! £800, Christy,
That was scrumptious, Ma, Like you,
I fancy somethin' sweet now,
What have you for dessert, Mam?
- Mam, what have you for dessert?
- Dessert?!
Kids, kids, do you not fancy
a drop of ice cream now?
- Yeah, ice cream, Mam!
- Yeah, Mam, get some ice cream,
Some raspberry ripple,
No, get us some Neapolitan,
All right!
- All right, all right, yeah,
- The pink and green stuff,
But just this once, mind, I've more things
to spend me money on than ice cream,
Jesus, Mary and Joseph, what's this?!
- What's this?
- Christy's money,
Bring it out and count it,
£800,
That's more money than your poor father
ever earned in a whole year,
I can't take it,
It's for you, It's yours,
I can't take it, son,
Da was a bricklayer, Ma, and I'm a writer,
I know it's mad money,
I want you to have it,
What would I do with it?
Well, for a start, get yourself a dress
and a new pair of shoes,
Will ya?
Christy? You have a visitor,
You look well,
- So do you,
- Thank you,
Sit down,
- Look, I won't stay very long,
- Stay as long as you like,
I need to ask you a favor,
What?
A benefit,
- Where?
- Lord Castlewelland's,
Him?! He's mad,
- Posh,
- Filthy rich,
Look, I know you don't like appearing
in public, but... it's for a good cause,
For the cripples,
- For the cripples,
- Yeah, I'll try to behave meself,
- You sure it won't upset you too much?
- So I'll anesthetize meself,
No, Not too much,
How's Peter?
(applause on PA)
(knocking at door)
- We have to get goin', Christy,
- Yeah,
What do you think? Too much self-pity?
No, I think he's a lovely man,
and not in the least sentimental,
Mary, do you really think so?
Yeah,
- And would you go out with him?
- Certainly,
(speaker) Now listen, everyone...
So you'd go out with me?
- (speaker),,Christy Brown,
- I might, Shh, he's talkin' about ya,
I want to introduce you
to one of the brav...
Well, no, no, quite the bravest chap
I've ever come across,
Yes, well, now when
Christy Brown was born
the doctors told his mother
that... just no good...
- Stay with us for a couple of hours,
- (speaker),,a vegetable for all of his life,
But Bridget Brown,
she wouldn't take that, oh, no,
Would you go out with me tonight?
I told you, Christy, I have an appointment,
And so we have with us here tonight...
Are ya in love with him?
What?
I asked ya did ya love him, Mary?
(speaker),,introduce to you
Christy Brown, man of genius,
- Mary,
- Christy,
Mary, I asked you a question, Do ya?
- It's none of your business,
- So you won't answer me?
- Why should I?
- What are you afraid of?
You imagine that people are afraid of ya,
I'm not afraid of ya, OK?
- You're afraid of yourself,
- Aw, come on, Look, just...
- You're afraid of me,
- We can't talk about this now,
Why can't we talk now?
Now is a good enough time for me,
- I'll see you again sometime,
- I've heard that before, Mary,
Why is it always "some fuckin' time"?
Mary, stay,
Stay!
Christy,
We've got to go,
Take me out to the firing squad, so,
(inaudible)
I must say, I'm honored to be asked to
give voice to the words of Christy Brown,
"I was born in the Rotunda Hospital,
on June 5th, 1932,"
"There were 22 children in all,
of which 13 survived,"
"It would not be true to say
that I am no longer lonely. "
"I have made myself articulate
and understood to people
in many parts of the world,
and this is something we all wish to do
whether we're crippled or not. "
"Yet, like everyone else,
I am acutely conscious sometimes
of my own isolation,
even in the midst of people,
and I often give up hope of ever being
able to really communicate with them,"
Sheila, what's the matter with Christy?
"...that every writer or artist must
experience in the creative mood
if he is to create anything at all,"
"It's like a black cloud
sweeping down on me unexpectedly,
cutting me off from others,
a sort of deaf-muteness,"
"I lay back in my chair while my old
left foot beat time to a new rhythm,"
"Now I could relax
and enjoy myself completely,"
"I was at peace,"
"Happy,"
Come on, Ma, stand up,
Mother,
Mother, come here,
Ah, Christy, no, don't,
Give us one of them flowers, Ma,
- Are you not comin' in the car, Christy?
- No,
You're mad, Christy! It's great,
Get in the car before I kick your arse,
Good luck, Christy,
(Ma) Good night, Christy,
Good night, Ma,
Go on, I'm all right,
Will ya get in the car now, Ma? I'm fine,
Good night, Christy,
- Be careful,
- Ah, you're not me Da, Tom,
- You take it easy, Christy,
- Take it easy yourself,
Let's go,
Christy, Now, tuck that under you,
Great stuff,
I hope to see you again,
Yes, I hope to see you again, Christy,
Before closing time,
- I thought I'd lost ya,
- Not at all,
You can just see
Joyce's Tower down there,
And that's where JM Synge was born,
at the foot of the mountains,
What'll we drink to?
Let's drink to Dublin,
To Dublin? Why?
Because Christy Brown was born there,
(cheering)
[Skipped item nr. 890]