This is a story of long, long ago...
...when the world was just beginning.
A young world.
A world early in the morning of time.
A hard, unfriendly world.
Creatures who sit and wait.
Creatures who must kill to live.
And man, superior to the creatures
only in his cunning.
There aren't many men.
A few tribes scattered
across the wilderness.
Never venturing far, unaware
that other tribes exist even.
Too busy with their own lives
to be curious.
Too frightened of the unknown
to wander.
Their laws are simple.
The strong take everything.
This is Akhoba,
leader of the Rock tribe.
Sakana.
And these are his sons,
Sakana and Tumak.
There is no love lost between them.
And that is our story.
Tumak.
Tumak!
Ahot.
Ahot...
...Loana....
Ahot.
Ahot, Loana....
Tumak.
Tumak!
Tumak. Loana?
Loana!
Sakana.
Tumak. Tumak.
Tumak.
Loana!
Loana.
Payto.
- Tumak.
- Tumak?
- Tumak
Loana!
Tumak.
Tumak!
Nupondi.
Akhoba!
Tumak!
Sakana!