The Great Sacrifice
Our member Albrecht Froben
returns from a voyage which has led him
from Hamburg across the Atlantic ocean,
across the old German colonies in Africa
to the Japanese islands.
and which we proudly call
a pioneer enterprise,
undertaken in the service of
the German Colonial Association.
The Hamburg section of
the German Colonial Association
is aware that to Froben,
the Hamburg senator's son,
in whose blood has been
the global traveler since generations....
we couldn't offer a more
appropriate token of our esteem
than the whole world.
This is where I went off the boat
for the first time, Portuguese Guinea,
the Sudan,
our old colonies Togo and Cameroon,
Belgian Congo, Somalia.
The suitcases have arrived,
shall I bring them in?
Yes, bring them in.
Open the big black one,
here, it's the biggest key.
Then on board again,
to Ceylon.
In Ceylon I stayed for four weeks,
because there's our main tea depot.
Then onward, passing Singapore,
the Philippines, Japan.
You've made the first stop
because of me, haven't you?
Not exactly, but I know
your passion for East Asia.
I've brought you something
that will interest you.
I quite liked the way
the gentlemen have honoured me today,
but after all it's no big deal
to undertake such a trip nowadays.
You've accomplished something,
and it has been no small matter.
After all you've renewed connections
which in the last years
had been cut off for Germany.
To conquer something back is more
difficult than to stay put on it.
A Japanese warrior,
of the Ashikaga Shogunate,
around 1500.
You see, I've been there,
but you know much more about it.
But now I'll show you something
that will interest you most.
A beautiful Buddha.
That's not a Buddha, it has
eleven heads. That's a Kwannon.
The eleven-faced Kwannon.
Or a Kwannon, what's the difference.
No, this is something special.
A special goddess.
The Buddhist goddess of mercy.
The eleven-faced.
According to the legend,
a princess who knew how to
defend her virtue against all attacks.
Then she'll suit you.
Allow me to give her
to you as a present.
Albrecht, you don't know
what a pleasure you give me.
I'm just writing a book about East Asia,
about the old Japanese beliefs
up to the cult of Shintoism.
This here isn't probably as interesting
for an art historian and scholar.
A kimono?
for whom?
I'll find someone.
Albrecht, Albrecht...
You're now a dignified
and famous man,
you can't afford such
affairs any longer.
Your position demands it.
(speaks with Hamburg dialect) Oops!
Don't step on your own tie!
The best thing in life is what
has been tested and proven good,
as old Hummel used to say.
And if you imagine that I shall refrain
from taking out a Hamburg girl
for a boating
on the Alster in the evening,
then you're wrong.
Say, isn't that Octavia?
By the way, you'll have to pay a visit
to the uncle, the senator.
How is he?
Still busy with his humanistic studies?
Still reading Horace and Virgil?
I can't imagine how one can give
one's daughter a Latin name nowadays.
Octavia.
What does she do?
She's what she has always been.
The most beautiful thing
the Alster has ever seen.
Where did you get the painting?
She gave it to me.
I say, it doesn't fit
into your Buddhist shop.
It will have to fit.
I see.
Is she already married?
No.
No one dares to, is that it?
Yes, you're right, that's it.
Look at this!
The eleven-faced Kwannon.
The princess who knows how to
defend her virtue against all attacks.
Well, you'll have to visit
their house on the Elbe anyway,
even though she has a Latin name.
Is the family away on a voyage?
No.
Because the blinds are down.
The family doesn't like
glaring sunlight.
But the senator and
the lady of the house have gone out.
Please give my card to the senator
when he comes back.
Shall I announce you
to the young lady?
Miss Octavia is playing the piano?
Yes, please do.
One of these hours will be your last.
Octavia!
A return after three years
of wandering around?
I didn't really think
of returning, Octavia.
It's more like a very short visit.
- Is that a difference, Albrecht?
- Yes, it is.
"Returning", that sounds
as if someone expected you.
Really?
Would you like to come up?
Very pretty.
Much more pleasant than
down there in that old hall.
Here one may enjoy life.
Beautiful.
Very beautiful.
That clock is also nicer
than the one downstairs.
It doesn't remind one
of one's own mortality.
The good old clock.
It goes all the way back
to grandfather.
And great-grandfather probably.
I don't know,
I don't even notice it anymore.
Yes, what one has always seen in one's
childhood, what one grew up with...
that you don't see anymore.
But once you've been away for a while,
then you see it again,
and with new eyes.
Does world-travel
make one so pensive?
No, but one gets to see things
from a distance, Octavia.
Alster boat race.
My consolation prize from last year.
Matthias couldn't do better than that
He's more of a scholar
than a sportsman.
He doesn't risk enough perhaps?
Perhaps the dinghy isn't agile enough.
Constructed in a far too solid way,
is that it?
Old Hamburg.
I've come back to a
completely different kind of life.
I haven't had breakfast.
Will you have a coffee with me?
With pleasure.
Shall I fetch an armchair?
No thanks. I always sit on the floor.
You've played the piano just now.
That's my great passion.
It's my life.
On Sundays, we all sit together
down there, we're playing in a quartet.
The old Sanitätsrat Terboven
plays the first violin,
Matthias the viola, and when papa
has the time, he plays the cello.
- Milk?
- No, black.
I don't have the patience anymore
to listen to a quartet.
That has never been your style.
You need the wind and the waves,
the glare and the lust of the sun...
- Yes.
The wind and the waves,
the glare and the lust of the sun.
No arm's length
must be between us anymore.
One of these hours will be your last
You see Albrecht, this is how
we're sitting here every Sunday morning.
It's so to speak our spiritual
hors d'oeuvre before the Sunday roast.
We've another hour till dinner.
Read us something, papa.
What do you want to hear?
Perhaps a Dionysus Dithyramb
by Nietzsche?
A what?
A Dionysus Dithyramb.
I see.
Albrecht doesn't know that.
Let's listen to it.
The most beautiful one:
"The sun sinks".
That's Nietzsche's
premonition of death,
one of the most profound
poems ever written.
The sun sinks
Not much longer will you thirst,
Burned heart!
A promise is in the air,
Blowing to me from unknown mouths  —
A great coolness comes...
The air passes by strange and pure.
Doesn’t the night cast a furtive
Seductive glance towards me?
Remain strong, my brave heart!
Do not ask: why? —
Serenity, golden, come!
You doomed, more secret,
sweeter anticipation of pleasure! —
Did I run too quickly along my path?
Just now, when my foot becomes weary,
Your glance catches up with me,
Your happiness catches up with me.
Seventh solitude!
I've never felt
Closer to sweet security,
In the warmest glance of the sun. —
Isn’t the ice of my summits
still glowing?
Silvery, light, a fish
My bark now glides away ...
Very beautiful.
Yes, very beautiful.
But I think it's terrible.
What is terrible, the poem?
Nothing against your
recitation, papa, but...
What is it you don't like, Albrecht?
Don't smile in such a
patronizing way, Matthias.
Apparently you think I'm too stupid
to understand the poem.
Albrecht, why are you so irritable?
Don't you want to tell us, Albrecht,
why you find Nietzsche
disgusting all of a sudden?
Go on, I'm ready to listen to reason.
It's been a misunderstanding,
you must excuse me.
I had no intention to
teach you reason, papa.
But why do you
think it terrible, Albrecht?
This is why.
But my boy, open the other blinds too
if you don't like to sit in the dark.
The blinds have
nothing to do with Nietzsche.
But they have!
Unfortunately they have.
Can someone tell me why you're sitting
here every Sunday feeling gloomy?
Nothing against the poem.
But you lower the blinds and say:
"The sun is sinking."
Albrecht, please!
And outside the sun is shining.
Matthias, don't interrupt me for once.
You've asked me
what I think is terrible.
Here you are,
just look outside!
We've been sitting here for three hours,
talking about philosophical matters,
playing nocturnes,
night pieces by Chopin,
reading the thoughts of a genius
written shortly before he went mad.
Is that how a Sunday morning
is supposed to be?
It wasn't only the death premonition,
It was the approaching madness
he felt before his sun sank.
Night night night,
nothing but night.
and death.
And outside the sun is shining.
Say,
don't you think it spooky?
Don't be angry,
but that's beyond me.
I'm sorry.
Poor Octavia.
I'm a tough case.
You won't have it easy with me.
But later we can arrange our life
just like we want to,
or like you want to, but...
There's still another hour till dinner.
Let's run away.
You may, no one will be angry at you.
But I have to stay here,
we have guests.
Look around, row out with the boat,
stretch out on the planks.
There you have your wind and your waves,
and your glare of the sun.
Very well.
Ro vidare!
Go on!
Faster!
Jag ber dig hjärtligt, var god och va' förnäm,
och titta inte för noga på mig!
I beg your pardon?
If you stop rowing, my dress of waves
will become too transparent,
and I shall have to leave you.
Also, the water caresses me better
if you row faster.
Min vänlige släpare!
Just cling to the boat.
I'm not the least bit curious
to resolve this magic.
We're very far out now.
If you aren't a mermaid with a fish's tail,
it'll soon become dangerous.
Can you swim out that far at all?
I'll turn back now,
and you won't follow me.
just like you wouldn't follow
a real mermaid.
Tack så mycket.
She lives over there in the next house
Äls? But that' s not a name?
Älskling. Actually it's Älskling,
but everyone calls her Äls.
Is she Swedish?
I believe she's from Finland,
but I'm not sure.
Anyway, she's from the north.
Her step-father gave her the house
before he died,
but she lives rarely here.
She like a migrating bird,
comes along, settles,
and is off again the next day.
She spends a few months every year
in her homeland,
the land of a thousand lakes,
that's what you call it I guess.
And in the winter
she's somewhere in the south,
in the autumn in Africa,
or somewhere like that.
She has indeed a very...
how shall I put it...
a very unconventional way of living.
You know how people talk.
I don't know the details.
Äls... sounds charming after all.
And it suits her.
And it suits the mermaid
who appeared in your backwash.
I have no use for her.
I never had.
A pity, really.
I think she's a nice person.
Are you on friendly terms
with your neighbors?
Good heavens! First,
she lives there all alone, and then...
You know how we are around here...
Even if someone lives next door,
we don't know each other.
Here every house is a world in itself.
It has always been like that,
and will stay that way forever.
Good morning!
I still owe you thanks
for your pulling-service.
Don't mention it.
Or do you demand payment?
If it's all the same to you,
I'd rather accept payment.
What kind of payment would you like?
For instance...
going out for a ride with you.
My greatest wish would be to
take part in the derby myself.
Thank God that's still men's business.
But it would certainly be beautiful.
I'd place a bet on you immediately,
victory and place.
Place?
That's not very gallant.
If you bet,
then it'll have to be victory only.
Earth's paradise lies on horseback.
You're saying this?
I thought sailing was your passion.
But there you depend
on the wind, Miss...
Well, 'mermaid'.
How may I call you, then?
Just call me Äls,
like everybody else does.
The name is a dear memory to me.
My mother gave it to me.
Äls...
May I accompany you on your rides?
Äls?
Of course, only
until you tire of me.
With that concession, I'll agree.
Well, goodbye.
Tomorrow at six.
But I'll have to be back at seven,
then my day begins.
Get back in there, you tramps!
Heisann.
Good morning.
You've been waiting for me?
You don't say!
Let me check first what your pulse has
to say about that gallop ride.
Don't look so serious, Sanitätsrat.
I feel splendid.
The pulse says no.
Very clearly no.
But I have forbidden you to swim,
to ride, to run around.
Let's sit down.
Why don't you listen to me?
My collegue Wildbrand made
an analysis of your blood.
I must confess it doesn't look good.
You are not as splendid
as you say you are.
Leave that.
I believe the doctors always want
to make you a bit more ill,
that's how they make their money.
Don't be angry, Sanitätsrat.
I tend to keep my worries
a secret from my patients.
because they have to feel healthy first
in order to get well.
But with you I mustn't act like this,
Miss Flodéen,
because you're unreasonable.
I know what's the matter
with me, Sanitätsrat.
I think I know it even
better than yourself.
Really? What do you know then?
How long do I still have
to live, Sanitätsrat?
I wasn't prepared for
such a direct question,
but no one could
seriously answer that.
Anyway, I believe...
that if you're reasonable...
What if I'm unreasonable?
Well, if you're unreasonable...
Do you want to be unreasonable?
I want to live.
I don't want to pine away,
I don't want to think all the time
whether I may do this or not.
I'd rather live a shorter time.
What does it matter if one
dies at 25 or at 26?
But I want to get something
out of those 25 years!
I've seen it for years with my mother,
taking one medicine after another,
always sparing herself.
That was her life,
leaving one sanatorium for the next,
artificially prolonging her life,
and all she got out of it
was a prolonged suffering.
A prolonged torture.
What is that torture
you want to prolong?
Are you in pain?
I am not, that's the point.
And that's why I'm such a bad patient.
You see, nature arranged this
very wisely, pains and all.
Pains protect us from decay,
pains can be the elixir of life.
You don't have that
natural protection, Miss Flodéen,
and you completely forget that fate
has already given you
a clear sign once before.
Do you know my silver
Danish mastiff Peer?
You have so many dogs, how can I...
But I have only one Peer.
I liked him best of all.
But when he got ill
and couldn't enjoy his life any more,
I myself killed him.
My gardener couldn't
bring himself to do it,
and I didn't want to
take him to the veterinary.
He was to be with me.
I was more merciful.
Excuse me, Miss Flodéen,
this is not a conversation for a doctor.
It's my profession to heal people,
and to keep them alive
as long as possible.
And that's why I am telling you:
quit riding.
You know it, first you perspire, then
cool off, then you catch another cold.
And you cannot afford such a cold.
Be merciful with yourself.
Älskling.
Mama's crying.
It's too much for you, Älskling.
In the end, the child
won't sleep again.
Come to me.
Älskling.
Älskling,
you're an unreasonable person.
That's what the doctor has told me
too just now, Gitta.
Do you imagine it's as easy for me
as it is for you to be reasonable?
I live under a different law.
Just like your mother.
Yes, that's how it'll have to be.
But I've always hoped to have
my child with me one day, and...
and that it wouldn't have to grow up
among strangers, like I had to.
Strangers?
Gitta, don't be angry with me.
You've been my nurse,
and I've believed for a long time
that you were my mother,
and you've always been
like a mother to me.
Now you're a mother for Susanne.
So you see.
Only, I often think...
I have my beautiful garden,
my beautiful house.
Why can't my child live with me?
With an ill mother?
We've gone through all this before,
and decided not to try that again.
- The child will suffer most from it.
- Yes.
It wouldn't make sense anyway.
You're hardly here,
you lock up the house again,
move south, or north,
and then it'll have to leave anyway.
Or do you want to take it
with you everywhere?
That's not suitable for a child.
There must be order in its life.
Älskling, let's not talk about
those old things anymore.
You know it's impossible.
Susanne doesn't lack anything, Älskling.
As long as I live,
she won't lack anything.
And you won't get talked about.
That would be unnecessary.
I don't care about that,
But it's nobody's business.
It doesn't have to be.
Then it's best that way, I guess.
But when I'm well again,
we'll build a house by the sea.
Next to the beach, so that
we'll see the sea all the time,
then I'll buy a pony
for Susanne, and...
A pony? Are you mad? A wild animal?
That's just like you.
and I'll have to be afraid again,
like in old times,
when little Älskling
started to gallop off, no.
You see, you'll cry and shout
and we won't listen to you again.
Does it always have to be like that?
Yes, it always has to be like that.
It's always like that...
That you have to fear
losing what you hold most dear.
- A mulled wine?
- That would be best.
- One mulled wine!
- Two, you mean.
Of course, two.
Two mulled wine!
A small adventure makes
life more interesting.
Wipe your face and your hands.
Water doesn't harm a mermaid.
I hoped to meet you yesterday
when I was rowing.
I searched the whole Elbe.
The mermaid is no longer.
Once you know the mermaid's name,
the magic is gone.
But if her name's Äls...
Äls isn't a name.
Nice and warm.
You see, you're cold.
I'm not, but still:
Härligt varm.
Will you be staying longer
in Hamburg this time?
Why?
Miss Froben told me that you're
only passing through here.
No, this time I'll stay longer.
I'm treated by a specialist.
You know him, Sanitätsrat Terboven.
I would have thought you
a model of health.
You see how one can be wrong,
But I'm healthy all right.
Only a remnant from the tropics
is bothering me now and then.
What business do you
have in the tropics?
Haven't you been told yet
that I'm a migrating bird?
I've already heard that
you were a migrating bird.
Bravo!
That was great, Äls!
Shooting from a standing position
is not difficult, Miss Froben,
but from a galloping horse,
that's different.
Bravo!
I'll be back!
Yeah!
Äls!
Not too far into the water!
It gets deep suddenly!
Äls!
Do you imagine my horse cannot swim?
Don't be so reckless!
Otherwise I'll have to follow you!
Out here there are no waves!
Go, Grållen!
You were splendid, Äls.
But you're reckless all the same.
- Why?
- The horse will shy at the surf.
What if it had
thrown you in the water?
You could easily have
gotten under its hoofs.
That's no big deal.
No big deal?
The horse might kill you with its hoofs
if it gets nervous.
Then I'll be dead,
what of it if, Herr Froben?
It's going to happen one day anyway.
I say, how can you talk of death
like this at your age?
What has age got to do with it?
One is always close to death,
and it's a good thing
if you smile at him from time to time,
and tell him: "You're my friend, you'll
come when I can't go on any further."
What are you saying?
I think you still have some time left
before he takes you in his cold arms.
Perhaps...
and perhaps not, one never knows.
You see the rainbow?
The bridge spanning to the beyond.
Who knows how soon
we'll have to cross over.
This is my favorite spot,
here at the lighthouse.
Today it's beautiful here,
but in autumn, when the migrating birds
arrive from my homeland.
then it's sad here.
But why?
Then they fly against the lighthouse
because they think it's the sun,
and in the morning they lie
on the ground with their skulls smashed.
Sometimes whole flocks.
A sad picture.
Terrible.
But Äls,
you're so full of life and happiness.
It doesn't suit you
to think about death,
with the wind and the waves
and the blazing sun around.
You think so?
What am I supposed to think about?
You?
Yes, I only think about him.
Only about Albrecht Froben.
You're the only one
who knows about it, Grållen.
But you won't tell anybody.
You carried me with your soft
and light trot, as you always do,
and I must have said it
aloud very often:
"Albrecht Froben, Albrecht Froben".
I didn't mean it.
Only when I saw you
prick up your ears listening,
then I too heard myself saying it:
"Albrecht Froben, Albrecht Froben".
I didn't want it.
We galloped,
I wanted to cover it all
with the sound of your hoofs,
but it got wilder and wilder,
as the two of us got wilder.
Ah, Grållen, it's good
that you're here,
so that I can tell at least one person
how often I think about him.
And it's so hard to keep silent,
especially if you're a woman.
You're thinking about the other woman,
not about Octavia,
only about the other one.
What makes you think so?
I can tell by your face.
Do you know my face that well?
I hope I do.
That is, at the moment I'm afraid I do.
Albrecht, I have
to tell you something.
I think it's...
impossible.
It's hard to find the right words.
Perhaps I can give you an example
for what I have in mind.
One can pack a Kwannon
or a silk kimono into a suitcase,
but not into a life.
You've put that splendidly.
Kwannon and kimono!
You're a poet!
But you don't know Äls at all.
Be so good as to stop using
that endearing name.
That's ridiculous,
everybody calls her like that.
Her name is Miss Flodéen.
After all she is a registered resident,
not a mythical creature.
But even Octavia calls her like that.
And you object that I call her by a name
which all the world uses.
And I think it's incredible that you
compare her and Octavia
in such a ridiculous manner.
Kwannon and kimono!
One cannot compare the two,
one wouldn't do justice to either of them.
Octavia is just heavenly,
and Äls is...
Earthly, isn't she?
Yes, earthly, if you want.
You don't seem to be
very proud of your abode.
We know very well that
we're closer to earth than to heaven.
We're made out of earth.
You don't have to give up heaven
just because you love the earth.
One doesn't have to,
but one does occasionally.
Even if you find me ridiculous again:
It means something that you faithlessly
gave up your passion for sailing,
excuse the word faithlessly,
and that you've suddenly
become a passionate horseman.
You ought to start working again,
you've had a long enough holiday.
It only gives you silly ideas.
Say, Matthias...
Do you doubt my love for Octavia?
I don't want that,
for Octavia's sake I don't want that.
That's why I tell you as a friend:
don't place yourself in danger.
Even if you don't die doing so.
Think of Octavia.
Does your cousin know
that you're here?
No, nor does my cousin Octavia.
So it's just you
who are worried, Herr Froben?
Yes.
Fortunately, Octavia doesn't seem
to know about that trouble yet.
You speak of such things...
I would be ashamed
to call them by name.
Don't you now that it's very dangerous
to interfere with fate?
You've said something aloud
which was carefully left unspoken
between Herr Froben and myself.
One shouldn't speak of everything.
It might have evil consequences.
At least I thought it my duty
to talk with you about it.
But I didn't hope, Miss Flodéen,
that we would understand each other.
Of course, you cannot share
my feelings for the Froben family.
Why have you turned to me
and not to your cousin Albrecht?
I already did so.
And?
I don't think I have achieved
anything by it.
And you thought you'd achieve more with me?
You're wrong, Herr Froben.
If it were like you suppose it to be,
especially then you should beware
of interfering with such feelings.
You should know that I would
fight for my happiness.
So it's war. Very well.
It all depends on who is the
strongest, Miss Flodéen.
And you must know that
Albrecht loves Octavia,
and she'll be his wife.
The couple will move away from here,
and I hope the distance
will cause you
to separate from
Albrecht emotionally, too.
All of a sudden he
immersed himself in his work
He didn't even want to go
on a honeymoon.
He cancelled everything.
We couldn't move to
Düsseldorf fast enough.
Are you comfortable
in the hotel, Octavia?
I don't think
we'll stay long in this town.
Then Albrecht isn't
looking for a flat?
He sends me out to look for one,
and I've had a look at lots of flats,
but when I think of our
house on the Elbe,
then I can't make up my mind.
That doesn't sound very happy, Octavia.
I am as happy as Albrecht is.
And is Albrecht happy?
Good gracious, he has his work,
and many social engagements.
He has so many obligations.
I could go to a party
or a ball every night.
But you know me.
One cannot overcome one's inhibitions.
That's it I guess.
But I accompany him,
you'll see tonight.
I'm even looking forward to it.
"The slide",
that's what the ball is called.
I've even got a mask.
They won't recognize me.
A mask?
Octavia with a mask?
We do this quite often.
We arrive at different times,
noone knows what the other wears.
and we have to look for
each other on the ball.
But I'll show my mask to you.
Albrecht won't mind
if you stay at my side.
I felt a bit uncomfortable anyway
to go there all alone.
Octavia's mask?
Yes.
Are you terribly shocked?
No, on the contrary.
I think it's wonderful that you join in.
Octavia's mask.
But Octavia, you won't
find him this way.
You've the whole evening before you.
Do you think I might take off
that disgusting thing?
Just keep it on.
I think such a mask is a good thing.
That way you can remain
incognito for a while.
A glass of champagne, please.
I feel that you think of me.
In the night the souls are closer to
each other than during the day.
Or is it just my longing
which lies to me?
I wanted to fight for you,
but I mustn't take you
away from Octavia.
I know how much happiness
I would take away from her.
I hope that I'll have the power
to conceal from you always
how infinitely I love you.
But I may tell you in my diary.
Each of its pages
shall speak of this love,
because this love alone fills my days.
Good night,
my beloved.
You cannot recognize him behind
the mask and the domino,
but you can recognize
his company, can't you?
Come.
Tell me, beautiful mask,
are you looking for something special?
Sure, whether you wear a wedding ring,
or whether you're still free.
Masks will be taken off
only at midnight!
What a pity!
Octavia!
Octavia.
You're wrong, sir.
Have a drink, Octavia.
Are you that sure?
I would recognize you
among thousands, Octavia.
A bit more distance, sir.
Matthias!
Play-acting isn't your
strong point, Octavia.
But whoever you may be,
go down the slide with me just once!
All of life is a slide anyway!
Come along!
Ladies, please!
Albrecht!
I'm surely allowed
to kiss my own wife?
But nobody here
knows that I'm your wife!
Neither do I see that you've blushed
behind your mask, Octavia.
Once a year, at carnival,
we put off all seriousness,
all dignity, and whatever else,
and slip into fools' costumes.
The delicious juice of our native vine
shall wake up the holy ghosts of life,
our native vine
which has been growing for centuries
on the sunny shores of the Rhine!
Here innumerable feasts have been
celebrated in homage to beauty,
and now let's pay our own
tribute to beauty's triumph.
For the most beautiful of our masks
we have the most beautiful thing
which grows on the beautiful shores
of our beautiful Rhine.
A cask of old Rüdesheim wine!
I'll raise a toast with the first glass
of this delicious drink
to the most beautiful mask
to whom the jury has unanimously
awarded the first prize today.
The golden mask in the white dress!
Octavia!
A now His Foolish Highness,
Prince Carnival,
will lift the most beautiful mask
up onto his throne!
There he arrives
in his foolish splendour,
descending to us,
the dust-born!
That is the signal:
the mask is dropped!
Carnival has begun!
Where is she?
She's already in the car,
driving home.
But how will it look, Matthias,
I have a position here.
It's embarassing,
with all those people around.
Why? No one has recognized her.
That's what the masks are for.
Well, I guess you're right.
Say Albrecht, don't you ask
too much of her?
You must admit she
has been splendid tonight,
participating in everything,
even going down the slide with you.
Yes, and she screamed like mad.
You cannot ask more of her.
But don't overdo it!
Octavia!
Yes?
You're already in bed?
Matthias has come with me.
But you were to stay there.
You see, I didn't want that at all.
I didn't want to spoil your fun.
But you haven't spoiled it.
Octavia...
Let's finish celebrating
our carnival in here.
I've ordered champagne.
You don't mind, do you?
I was afraid you were angry with me.
You're so sweet to me.
Now go to Matthias.
I'll be with you soon.
Fine.
Well, will she get up again?
I have a bad conscience, Matthias.
Couldn't do you any harm.
I ought to apologize to you
because I've spoiled your evening
with my lack of humour.
But you haven't, Octavia.
Octavia, I have to tell you something.
- You...
- I don't deserve this.
I don't want to play down my faults,
but I was really angry
when you ran away.
But Matthias gave me
a good talking-to.
He told me that
I was very egoistical.
I didn't say that!
Perhaps you didn't use the word,
but I can read between the lines.
Anyway, you were right.
Cheers.
I wonder what will be
the outcome of this?
The outcome is perfectly clear.
We'll pack and return to
Hamburg with Matthias.
There's nothing which holds us here.
Octavia, I didn't
advise him to do that.
Don't hurry things,
you're always so terribly volatile.
Very well, then in the spring,
but we'll leave as soon as possible.
Over-seas interests me much more
than inland navigation.
Besides, your father offered us
the house for the spring,
they'll be leaving for the manor.
Think of it, Octavia!
The house by the Elbe!
But Octavia, you mustn't cry.
I am so happy, Albrecht.
We'll return home.
I didn't know that she
was still in Hamburg.
She told me at the time
that she was going away.
I don't remember either that she
ever stayed in Hamburg for the winter.
But Sanitätsrat Terboven says
her illness is persistent,
perhaps that's the reason.
Yes, it has to be her old complaint,
a remnant of a tropical disease.
How do you know?
She told me.
Strange that she would talk about it,
since she is so secretive otherwise.
This morning I've sent her our most
beautiful orchids from the hothouse,
with greetings from both of us.
You don't mind, do you?
And now you'll go riding.
I hope you won't find it boring,
being so alone.
I'll take a few more riding lessons,
then I'll accompany you
if you want me to.
I'm not sure whether
it was right to send her flowers.
How now, out of bed?
You're not a good patient.
Will you believe me, Sanitätsrat,
there's no better medicine for me
than to be able to look down
to the garden once again,
look out into the street,
to see a bit of life.
And a horse once again.
It didn't do you any harm,
you look better.
Then I might allow you the walk
to the window after all.
The walk to the window
doesn't make me well either.
I want to be allowed to drive
down to town just once.
But what business could you
have in town these days?
Now, let's listen to your heart.
I have a duty to perform,
an urgent duty, professor.
Yes, very true.
Towards yourself,
towards your health.
Not only that.
I haven't just myself to look after.
Yes I know, Susanne.
But she's fine, isn't she?
She is, but I want to go out.
Back onto the horse, is that it?
That too.
A few days patience,
if the heart helps us along.
Do you think it's the heart?
I don't know what
has helped us so suddenly.
I do.
Wonderful how that
little Lippizan goes!
You like him better than the bay?
I like them both.
Only the bay is lame.
I'll have to send for the veterinary,
or do you know something about it?
Let me have a look!
The back leg?
Yes, the left.
I've made a bandage,
but I think it's better if...
We love each other, my friend,
and it will be terrible.
Terrible.
Why did you ever take me
back to Hamburg, Matthias?
I have?
I beg your pardon?
I have taken you back to Hamburg?
You should have told me
that Äls was still here.
But I didn't know it.
What is she to me?
Ok, you're right.
It's just a subterfuge to accuse you.
I'm accusing myself.
But that's of no use at all.
I don't understand.
- You've told me yourself...
- Told you, rubbish!
You don't have to remind me of
the things I have told you at the time.
The things I'm telling
myself all the time.
But what use is it to tell myself that
Octavia is infinitely more beautiful,
nobler, better.
The sublimity, the grace, the nobility
running in her veins.
What's the use?
- It's of no use to you?
- No, it isn't.
It's of no use at all.
Not a bit.
I can tell myself a hundred times,
but when I'm with Äls, then...
then I'm just happier.
It seems there always remains an arm's
length between Octavia and myself.
That's the way it was on
the day of our engagement,
and that's the way it is today.
But that's terrible, Albrecht.
But I love Octavia.
No, my dear Albrecht,
that's impossible!
You cannot do away with it
that easily.
After all you're a man,
you have willpower!
You couldn't possibly hold
one woman in your arms
and claim to love the other.
But I haven't held her
in my arms, Matthias.
Or as good as, probably.
I shouldn't have
talked to you, Matthias.
No. If you want to make me
your ally against Octavia, no.
I don't understand who you
think I am, Albrecht.
If you don't respect yourself,
at least show some respect for Octavia.
Well, then.
I've always believed friendship
knows no bounds,
but today I realise there are things
one must solve alone.
Is it that difficult?
Go on, answer me.
Octavia.
I was so sincere at the time
when I wooed you.
And now it is to have been a betrayal?
It cannot be all bad,
because it gives you a force,
a joy, a sweeping movement
which I've never
seen in you before.
Am I to love you less because of it?
Octavia.
You're so...
good.
So, so...
Yes, I know.
But it's about you,
not about me.
Octavia...
That is so, so...
superhuman.
Lugna lite, lugna lite.
Jag kommer snart tilbaka. Stanna kvar.
Octavia!
What's the matter?
Where are you going?
I see.
Octavia, what do you want?
How is it going to end?
I don't know.
I want to, I just want to.
Octavia, what do you want, what can
you want out here on the street?
Octavia, I am afraid for you.
I couldn't find any
peace of mind at home.
I had a feeling that you might
need me, that's why I came.
Octavia.
This is not the right way
you're following now.
Octavia, its not like you at all
to follow that woman.
It is.
If you knew how I have
suffered these last days.
Not every narcotic
takes away the pain.
But it's not a narcotic.
Look at this!
The way men gaze after her.
Nobody ever gazes after me
on the street.
Even though everyone
tells me I'm beautiful.
You've told me many times yourself.
Albrecht has told me.
What's the secret?
She's like a magnet.
Yes, indeed.
Octavia, you should be glad that
nobody gazes after you on the street.
You're such a pure person.
No, that's not it.
She is, too.
She's just more powerful that I am.
It's no use pretending.
Octavia, you're beside yourself,
I beg you, come home now.
No. Don't you see,
she's on the way to somewhere.
Dovenfleet [Hamburg harbour area]
Look!
She's about to enter a building.
Hello, Susannchen!
Do you see that?
Does she have a child?
I don't know.
I didn't know.
Say, you're losing your bandages.
Kom til mig, Grållen.
Spring inte ifrån mig.
Stanna her.
Vär rar mot mig, Grållen.
I have to hold my horse.
I can't afford it.
I don't have
your way with animals, Äls.
I love smelling the hay.
That's how I got to know you first.
A picture of abounding health.
When I think about how I greeted you
at your window the first time,
how pale you looked behind
the window panes.
You should never have gone away.
For two months I lay
in that boring room,
and no one was there
to send greetings up to my window,
and to call me back to life.
Was it that dangerous?
The old Sanitätsrat Terboven thinks so.
But now all that is over.
Äls.
You mustn't break.
En gang kommer et ögonblikk
der du glömmer all ting omkring dig.
Min älskling.
What does that mean?
Beloved.
Min älskling.
Älskling, that's what you are.
You, too.
To die like this,
that would be the happiest death.
Äls.
What are you saying?
And when I'm dead, do you hear,
I want my ashes to be
scattered into the sea.
I beg you, Äls...
And when the waves
caress your foot,
Then you shall know
that it is I, your Äls.
Äls, don't talk like that.
You're frightening me.
It was close, Albrecht,
when you were away for so long.
If you hadn't returned,
I think I would never
have overcome my fever.
We're like that,
we're different from you down here.
When we love, then we're like that.
När vi älskar så är vi sånn:
I skillsmissan visnar vi som en bloma utan sol.
That means:
In separation we perish
like the flower without the sun.
Do you love me that much?
Do you know if my husband
has gone out?
Herr Froben has just gone out
for a ride with Miss Flodéen.
I see.
Why do you cry?
I love you.
And you're crying
because of that?
Because there has been
a love in my life before,
without you.
Madam, I've made you a cup of tea.
Have I been asleep for long?
Perhaps an hour.
Has the Sanitätsrat...
hand me my back cushion...
Has the Sanitätsrat been here?
Yes, but he's left now.
He said he couldn't prescribe anything
better than sleep and rest anyway.
I don't feel well.
I think I have a high fever.
Will he return this afternoon?
He didn't know yet.
He has so much to do right now.
There's an epidemic in town, he says.
An epidemic?
That sounds bad.
What is it?
Typhus in the harbour area.
It's in the paper, too.
In the harbour area?
Whereabouts?
Read it to me.
"As we've just learned, in the harbour
area near the Dovenfleet,
alarming illnesses have appeared"
Dovenfleet?
Yes, Dovenfleet.
"which show symptoms of typhus.
Unfortunately there have already
been a few fatal cases.
At the moment it is deliberated whether
stricter police measures are necessary.
Good heavens!
I must get up!
Hand me my clothes and call a taxi.
But Madam, you cannot get up now.
The Sanitätsrat said it's very
dangerous and that you need rest.
Give me my clothes.
But Madam, this will end badly.
I can't take the responsibility.
Please lie down again.
I'm too weak.
My friend!
I mustn't write to you, but I have to.
An epidemic reigns in Dovenfleet,
bearing a terrible name.
A child is in danger, my friend.
A child that I love.
It lives at 22, Dovenfleet,
with Frau Steinkamp.
Take the child.
They will give it to you.
If there's no one left to look after it,
take it wherever you want to,
only away from the danger.
I'll wait for you by the window
at 6 o'clock, till you come.
And when you ride by,
I'll know whether it has been saved.
Hurry! Äls
I arrived just in time.
The mother is ill, you say?
Typhus?
The foster-mother.
The child is healthy.
We'll keep it here for
a few days for observation.
Symptoms of typhus make
themselves felt very clearly.
I'll bring that news gladly.
But it was unwise to fetch the child,
you might have caught the disease.
You leave things like that
to an ambulance.
The mother was worried
about the child.
She waits for the news,
I'll bring it to her.
Do you need anything else, madam?
No, I don't need anything. You may go.
You may go.
It can't be pleasant for a sick woman
to look out at the rainy weather.
If it were the sun...
The sun...
I've seen so much
of the sun in my life.
Go now.
Leave me alone.
You're riding into
the stable, Herr Froben?
You've almost smashed
your head at the gate.
Are you unwell, Herr Froben?
Good gracious!
Herr Froben!
I'll call the lady of the house.
No, it's nothing.
Nothing to my wife.
I don't want her to...
or someone...
Help me.
Octavia.
I hear you, Albrecht.
You mustn't open the glass.
Typhus is very infectious.
Do you want to tell me
something, Albrecht?
No.
But I must tell you.
It weighs on my heart like a stone.
What is it?
I am afraid for Äls.
Don't be afraid.
Fate knows better what
it wants to do with us.
I can see life above you,
and a light and happy future.
Only above myself?
Not above the both of us?
I don't know, Albrecht.
You know it quite well,
don't avoid it, Octavia.
Above you,
and above my love.
Yes.
Wherever you go to be happy,
my love will always accompany you.
In this rain I have greeted Äls
for the last time.
And now she'll be waiting,
and...
And what?
And die.
One doesn't die
that quickly, Albrecht.
You don't know her.
At the time, when we were
away in Düsseldorf,
She couldn't get well again either.
She once said to me:
"In separation we perish,
like the flower without the sun."
That's what she said.
"And no one was there
to send greetings up to my window,
and to call me back to life."
Then I'll conclude the last will.
Yes.
He isn't inside the room yet,
but I can feel him
sneaking round the house.
Who's sneaking around the house?
The friend.
Friend?
Friend Hein.
I see.
Friend Hein. Death.
I think, madam,
you are too gloomy.
You're seeing ghosts, don't you?
Don't say anything.
And the universal heir's
exact address is...?
Dovenfleet 22.
Susanne.
Now it'll come to nothing
with our pony,
with our house by the sea.
Susanne...
I beg your pardon?
Six o'clock.
Notary, please go now.
I must be alone.
I'm expecting someone.
You're expecting a visitor?
And you're talking of dying!
If he doesn't come
I won't survive this day.
Yes, even an embrace can bring death,
even a child's embrace.
So be careful in the future.
This time you've been lucky.
You'll get over it
with your robust health.
Ah, well.
Aren't you glad about it?
I am.
But...
But?
Why don't you tell me how
Miss Flodéen is, Sanitätsrat?
You're her doctor.
You ought to know
how much I long for news of her.
Or do you think that you owe it
to Octavia not to speak of it?
Octavia does not need a sacrifice.
She is making a sacrifice.
Yes.
For her, our marriage has
been a great sacrifice,
One great sacrifice.
Yes, there are people whose
nature is like this, Herr Froben.
and that's why Äls
doesn't have to wait in vain
for you and your greeting.
A rider is standing at the gate,
at Äls' garden gate,
offering her the lover's salute
for which she is waiting every day.
Who?
Who is standing at the gate?
Octavia.
Äls..
I will have to hurt you
very much, Äls.
I know, Albrecht.
I know it.
I know everything.
I am so sad, Albrecht,
even though I see
your figure at my window.
But you're so far away from me.
Your love is so far away from me.
I don't feel it anymore.
Albrecht.
But I'm not at the gate, Äls.
It is Octavia who is greeting you.
It isn't you?
Yes, it's you.
I can see you, Albrecht.
Is it really you?
Who can say what is real?
What do you want here, my darling?
I want to say farewell, Äls.
Do we have to?
Before Octavia's love
everything else must be extinguished
and pass away.
Do you understand this?
Yes.
Forgive me, Äls,
that I am so cruel.
But I must tell you.
I love Octavia.
I know it.
I know.
Beloved.
Farewell,
and be happy.
Äls!
I cannot see you any longer.
Don't call me any longer.
I don't want it anymore.
Listen, Albrecht.
So far away am I,
far away.
The sea
is far away.
Are you going away?
Or...
is it I?
Who is going away?
We...
cannot know.
Step aside, Albrecht.
Stand clear of the gate.
It was her last wish to have
her ashes scattered into the sea.
She has returned.
The wind and the waves
had been her elements.
Now she is in wind and wave.
Subtitles: serdar202 & knappen
Adapted by Tommaso