When a man is abused unjustly
by any form of authority
all men are responsible;
for it is they who, by their silence
permit and condone such oppression.
ORDERS
Why can't I go?
I want you to come home.
But Ginette's a nice girl.
I know, I know.
Then why can't I go?
I don't have time to explain.
Tell me!
I want to know. School can wait.
No, it can't.
Will you
make coffee?
What fell?
- I dunno.
Pick it up.
The water's still hot.
Could you make it?
Mom, tell me why I can't go to Ginette's.
Martine, when you get home
from school I'll tell you.
But by then...
I haven't time to argue with you now
My name's Jean Lapointe
and I play the role of Clermont Boudreau.
I was born on a farm
like my wife, Marie.
I guess our biggest mistake
was coming to the city
I work in a weaving mill.
Our one hope
is the union.
Do you go to church?
Yes.
Are you involved in politics?
Not directly.
I'm active in the union.
Take your bag and put your coat on.
Hurry up, off to school.
Ok, we're going.
You'll be cold...
I'm going to Ginette's anyway!
I want you home straight after school!
My name is Hélène Loiselle.
I play Marie Boudreau.
Clermont's my husband.
I'm a housewife.
It keeps me busy.
But later, maybe, when the girls are older
I'll get a job, work outside the house.
Jeez, it's tough.
With what's going on, I want her here.
That's why I told her to come home.
Bye, dear.
You could've backed me up.
Might've made it worse.
The FLQ kidnaps two political figures.
Federal authorities proclaim the
War Measures Act.
450 citizens are imprisoned.
All are eventually released
without any charges having been laid.
This film is based on interviews
with 50 of them.
I'll be gone for 10 minutes.
Again?
What do you mean, again?
- What for?
I have to look into a grievance.
Goddamn union!
My name is Louise Forestier
and in this film I play
the role of Claudette Dusseault.
I've been a social worker for 4 years.
I'm based in St Henri
and I love my work.
There's so much to be done...
and not only here in St Henri.
I've...
always been
a fighter
sometimes using force...
sometimes
my wits
of social injustice.
I like this work and I believe in it.
Claudette!
They took everything!
- I'll handle it.
The stove, the fridge, the sofa...
Leave this to me.
- Nothing's left.
Put that all back inside!
Mr...? Martineau.
I'm the one who called you yesterday
We had an arrangement.
What's all this?
I said the welfare office
would take care of it.
Not the chairs! How many are you?
Four.
Law says we leave 4 chairs.
Look, I've seen plenty of social workers.
They're nice folks
but they don't pay my bills.
Guys like him make me sick.
What'd you say?
You make me sick!
Clermont!
What?
I'm warning you.
If you leave the floor again
I'll suspend you for 2 days.
Finished.
You know damn well
that union reps can look into grievances.
Grievance or not, I'll suspend you.
Oh yeah?
I'll tell my union boss.
Then I'll suspend you indefinitely.
I'll have you thrown out!
Don't need to hide to drink at your age, Léo.
I have two good seats for tonight's game.
Want to go?
No thanks.
I'm driving a cab.
I'm back to driving a cab.
I was suspended.
Jesus!
Didn't I warn you?
You and your damn union!
The way I see it, Clermont
you ought to hang up your skates.
You've done your share.
Struggling to make ends meet...
Police Launch Wave of Arrests
Anyway...
Hey, listen...
Have you heard
the army's in town?
Yeah, sure!
They're just trying to scare us.
Listen, Clermont...
Your credit's always good here, you know
Thanks.
It worked out because we wanted
to take a week off
to visit his parents in Lac St Jean.
His dad was over 70.
It had been a long time
and we'd just gotten a letter...
It's been 5 years since you last came to visit.
The doctor says
to tell Clermont
that his father will need a little boost
to get through the winter.
But don't let him know I told you.
He's not very well.
She underlined "not very well."
She say why?
It's his old illness.
He's always muttered
about having to slave away
getting up at dawn, working hard all day
Well, he's stopped muttering.
I'm the one slaving away
and I could do with a little boost myself.
Love to you both, Mathilda.
Mom, André's throwing rocks at me.
You punk!
I'll kick you in the pants
and tell your dad!
Where are the cookies?
What?
- The cookies!
In the pantry.
There's a box open.
Where's Clermont going?
- Is he driving a cab again?
He was suspended
cause of that foreman.
Careful! Don't stand in front of a machine gun!
I'll stuff a cork up the barrel!
What are they up to with their army?
It's getting chilly
Grampa!
Getting cold?
So he said: Cost a lot to learn to drink.
Not gonna give it up now.
We only have one life.
Imagine spending it crazy!
I'm cold.
I'm going in.
Ok Grampa, time for bed.
Mr Prime Minister,
The Chief of Police informs us
that assistance from higher
government levels is essential
to protect society
from the sedition and
apprehended insurrection
made evident by the recent kidnappings.
We request all the support
you deem appropriate
to protect our citizens.
- The Mayor
Mom! Who is that?
Call the police.
- What's the number?
Mom, they're on the porch!
Anybody in there?
All right, that's enough.
What's going on?
Do you have a warrant?
Don't need one. There's a new law.
It was just passed.
Did you check the end of the hall?
Look in the cupboards.
I thought they'd gone crazy
We hadn't done anything wrong
and they broke in like thugs.
I was pretty shaken up.
The War Measures Act just now decreed
authorizes the police and army
to arrest without a warrant
those they suspect belong
to an illegal organization
or who declare they are members of such.
Further, the police may search
without a warrant any place
where they suspect members of such an
organization are hidden
or are holding someone illegally.
This has been a special news bulletin.
My name's Claude Gauthier.
In the film I play Richard Lavoie.
I'm unemployed.
I have two children.
I look after them and I really like it.
Richard Lavoie?
No, he lives next door.
Next door?
4058?
Wait a minute.
Police, open up.
What is it?
We've got company, kid.
Where's your wife?
She's at work.
Where?
Waitress, night shift.
Oops, that's dangerous!
Can I see your search warrant?
Don't need one.
Do I have the right to know what's up?
You have no rights.
Look, as far as I know
people always have rights.
This is war.
War? What war?
We've got orders.
What do you think, kid?
If you guys have orders, the grocer's next door
I don't keep my dynamite in the fridge.
Smoked all my pot last week.
My name is Guy Provost
and from now on I am
Dr Jean Marie Beauchemin.
I head a community health clinic
for people with low incomes
and I once ran
as a socialist candidate.
I lost, of course.
We had no rights at all.
But they had the right
to do whatever they wanted.
To them we were
common criminals, maybe worse.
They even watched as I got dressed.
Do you want this coat?
Handcuffs?
Not behind his back!
Call the clinic.
Speak to Demers.
Tell him what happened. This won't take long.
I'll get a lawyer.
Call Jacques.
If Demers isn't in, speak to nurse Parenteau.
Where are you taking him?
- You'll be told.
Unbelievable...
It's outrageous!
Do you know why you were arrested?
I was never told.
I didn't let it show, but I was scared shitless.
And then my shoelace broke.
Not that it matters.
So then...
What'll you do with the kids?
What do you mean?
We're taking you in.
Who're you calling?
- My wife.
To tell her to come?
Yeah.
Ok, let him call.
Sébastien!
What?
Give your little brother some cereal.
He won't eat.
- Sure he will.
He's not hungry.
Ginette, please.
Ok, I'll wait. There's no hurry.
Captain!
They want to talk to you.
That girl wants to go back to bed.
Tell her we're taking her in.
Ginette...
Listen, the cops are here.
I don't know.
Yeah, he's up.
Tell them the baby's sick.
Can we wait till she gets here?
How long?
10 minutes.
Alright.
Ok, we'll wait for you.
I'll tell you later.
Get your coat.
I can't leave the kids. You said we'd wait.
We'll wait.
See, we're not such bad guys.
There's Daddy!
What's that for? Take it off.
Mom!
- I'm not cold!
Are you scared?
- No!
But of course inside I was scared.
I tried not to cry in front of the girls.
With the chill and my nerves, I was shaking.
Besides, I wasn't sure
if they were real policemen.
I wondered who they were.
There was one of them
who didn't look like a gangster
but he didn't look like a cop either
So where's your husband?
I told you, he's working.
Come on.
Where to?
Where to? Jail.
No, Mom, don't leave us!
I can't tell you where he is.
I don't know myself.
Where does he work?
- He's driving a cab.
Ok, come on, get dressed.
We're taking her in.
No, Mom!
You can't go!
That young policeman didn't say a word.
He just stood there with his hands
behind his back.
But I could tell he found it disgusting.
He wasn't proud of being a cop then.
That's her, let's go.
Richard, what's wrong?
The two little ones were crying.
Monique wanted to console me
but didn't know what to say.
She just kept saying:
I love you, Mom. I love you.
I can't leave you alone.
I'll call Mme Thibault.
Stay away from the phone.
What do you mean?
I can't leave them alone.
Louise...
go get Mme Thibault.
Don't cry.
Go with her.
Seeing them cry, I wept too.
I tried to hold it back, for their sake.
Martine...
Don't forget to make lunch.
And go straight to school.
Ready?
Get your coat.
What the hell's going on?
She never hurt anybody...
minds her own business and
takes care of her kids.
Get off me!
Must, be a serious crime
if lugs like you have to come after her
Finished?
Shame on you!
You want us to take you along too?
Yeah!
Just try it!
QPP.
Jesus!
Occupation?
Social worker.
Your name, Sergeant?
No, he didn't arrest me, it was Binette.
Doesn't matter.
Binette arrested me!
Yeah, those three and her are mine.
Lavoie! What are you doing here?
Got a new band.
They sure know how to beat.
Where's Mom?
- Just like Mme Thibault said.
They wanted you, Dad.
They're all mixed up.
They don't know who to arrest next.
Can you get her out?
- I'll do my best.
Mom told us to go to school.
I don't feel like going.
- Me neither.
What did Mom say?
- We have to go.
See?
Do what she said, be good girls.
I want to stay with you.
I wish you could, but Mom said to go to school.
Louise!
You're in charge now.
I'm counting on you.
- Don't worry.
I, was shook up.
Really shook up.
I acted brave, but I knew
the cops would be back.
I'd heard about it on the cab radio.
I knew they'd pick me up.
The worst was
knowing Marie was in jail.
I imagined her sitting in jail, under arrest...
And there was nothing I could do. I felt rotten.
Go on.
Wait here.
They don't tell you anything.
You don't know why you're there,
or what's going to happen to you.
You just have to guess.
None of us had been charged.
We thought they'd let us go.
How much longer?
Wife's name?
Claire.
Her address?
4244 Marlowe.
Take off his cuffs.
Her phone number?
737- 9687
You can take him for his shower.
What's this one's name?
Name?
- Richard Lavoie.
Take your jacketoff.
Your belt too.
Address?
4056 St Christophe street.
Age?
Date of birth?
- January 31, 1939.
Ok, search him.
Where were you born?
Montreal.
Married? Single?
Married.
Got any scars? Scars or tattoos?
Yeah, a tattoo.
They'll check that in the shower
Ever been in jail before?
- No.
5'8, 130 pounds, Lussier.
Ok, fine.
Occupation?
Take your boots off.
What's your occupation?
Unemployed.
Education?
Grade 10.
Eye colour?
Eye colour... Brown?
Brown.
Stand here.
Have you ever been treated
for a venereal disease?
Any children?
Yes, three.
Names?
Louise
Martine
Monique.
Any previous arrests?
Why no!
That's all.
That's all?
How much longer?
- I don't know.
Be right there.
Have you finished?
Open the gate, will you?
On your feet, girls, we'reoff.
We can go? We'll see.
Come on, this way.
Six more.
- Bye, girls!
Hey, don't leave me here.
We all thought they were going to let us go.
There was no reason to mislead us.
When I got in the van...
I didn't want the younger girls to see me cry
but I couldn't hold back any longer
I kept thinking, What's going
to happen to my kids?
It's a shock when you realize
you're going to jail.
I was pretty scared.
I didn't let it show but inside, boy, was I scared.
Ever seen a rabbit that's just been caught?
It can't stop shaking.
Well I was shaking too, and how!
I can still feel the pounding of my heart.
Well?
Later.
Name?
- Boudreau.
Spelled eau?
First name?
Clermont.
Address?
407 4 St Hubert.
Occupation?
I work in a weaving mill.
What do you do there?
I weave, for Chrissake.
Yeah, but what do you do, run a machine?
I weave.
I'll put weaver.
So why ask if you know?
Nationality?
- French Canadian.
Obviously.
Put Québécois if you want.
Don't be smart.
Don't be dumb.
Up till then I'd been hoping they'd let us go...
they'd see it was all a mistake.
But then they gave us those uniforms...
Christ!
Looking down at yourself... brown shirt, grey
pants, boots
you don't recognize yourself.
You've got nothing of your own.
That'll do.
That's when you realize
how important clothes are.
They're who you are.
And then the sheets...
You wonder how long you'll be sleeping there.
A year, two years? You have no way of
knowing.
Next!
Ok, this way.
That's when you realize you're in prison.
And for what? Nothing.
The first thing you know is you're...
stark naked
and there's a dozen guards looking you over
from head to foot.
It's not a question of modesty, but...
Go on, scrub up!
It's humiliating.
They do it just to embarrass you.
Undressing doesn't bother me
but only when I want to.
Gotta respect people's sense of modesty.
Wait here.
Left hand.
That's it.
Sit down.
It hit home. We were really in jail.
Locking up a housewife
who'd spent her life changing diapers
washing up and cleaning house...
who'd never talked politics
except to agree with her husband...
That's hard to take!
What struck me was the colour of the walls.
It drives you crazy.
Ok, stop.
The prison itself was modern, clean, cold.
But with all those doors slamming behind you...
Such a miscarriage of justice!
That's why the colour gets to you.
Though it's pretty ordinary.
Ok, move on.
Sit down there.
Hand in all your personal belongings...
rings, watches
necklaces, handbags.
They'll be returned later.
Mlle Claudette Dusseault, please.
Next.
You're not allowed to shave me.
It's an ampu...
Sit down!
Well, seems I've got no choice.
No, I wasn't scared then.
I don't think the others were either.
The fear came later.
You can't feel much, they
keep moving you around.
They led us from one place to another
Never said, We're taking you to the elevator
Just did it.
And you wait.
You may wait 10 minutes.
Number nine.
It hit me when I got in the cell.
I was in a rage. It wasn't right.
They had to tell me why I was there.
Locking me in that cell
without telling me why...
it just couldn't be.
The worst part is the sense of paralysis.
There's no room to move around.
You're caught, trapped.
Everybody up. 8 o'clock.
Come on, get up.
Get up, it's 8.
C'mon, get up.
They kept us in our cells for five days.
We weren't let out, couldn't wash or shave.
We had to use the water from
the toilet bowl to wash our faces.
For 3 days straight we ate porridge.
Service stinks... I'll change jail!
Porridge.
Cold porridge, like cardboard no milk, no sugar
Where's the spoon?
Swill fit for pigs and even they wouldn't eat it.
Porridge, morning, noon and night.
Goddamn porridge.
I stopped eating tillTuesday,
when they gave us real food.
Knit one
pearl one
knit one...
Look at me, I've always loathed knitting!
I did everything to keep busy
Even tried knitting.
Kept starting over, but I just couldn't get it.
In jail, it's like you're no good at anything.
We smoked, read and knit.
Boring as hell.
When you're in jail, at the beginning
you're given nothing.
It's all calculated.
You have nothing at all.
No cigarettes, no razor
no aspirin, not even salt for your food.
So you ask them for things.
And then, one by one, they start giving you
all those little things that seem so essential.
So the guards become benefactors.
You see what being inside is like.
Everything's upsidedown.
One of the privileges is to wash the floors.
You get so you want to wash the floors.
Hey, could you please change the station?
Yeah, a French station. It's our right!
Hey, wise guy...
Since when do prisoners have rights?
You have no rights.
You're given privileges.
Hey, here comes the canteen.
Time to stuff our faces.
Beaulieu.
Lavoie.
Careful of the floor, guys.
Wipe your socks before you come out.
Plourde.
Sign here.
Boudreau.
Sign this.
It's not that we were mistreated or beaten.
At least I wasn't.
It was knowing that our families
had no news of us.
No one knew where we were
or when we'd come back.
Some had no one to care for their babies.
I kept thinking of my girls and
how they must be crying.
To me it was all very cruel.
Others were worse off.
Now, now, don't cry.
That's ok, dear.
It'll be all right.
This won't last much longer.
It's just a big mistake.
They'll see that.
Don't cry.
Tomorrow you'll be free.
It's not easy when you feel like crying, too.
You don't know what to say.
B2 North, come to the door.
Lucky man, Boudreau!
Lucky Boudreau!
It's your father...
He's dead?
Will they let me out?
We'll see. I'll tell you.
Well...
I guess this business with me didn't help.
Hearing where I was must've killed him.
Somebody's going to pay for this.
What?
Forget it.
They really gave it to Lavoie.
One night they took him
and interrogated him for 3 hours.
They told him he'd be executed in 3 days.
And he believed them.
Awful...
Can you imagine those three days?
What's Beauchemin's number? 5.
Put the lights on in 5.
Get up. A search.
Someone smuggled something in.
Do the back, I'll do the front.
Check the fan too.
That wasn't the first time.
Every night they found new ways to harass us
to humiliate us.
Being so helpless made us furious.
The scars we bear will never heal.
I was worried about my wife.
She was going to have the baby any day
and I'd had no news.
They'd managed to create a psychosis in us.
We were so humiliated,
we didn't even know how to react.
Besides...
You won't believe what I'm going to say
but it's true.
They sentenced me to death.
Not a court, the guards.
They said I'd be shot in 3 days.
And I believed them.
Under those circumstances you can't help it
I think.
I spent those 3 days in a state of utter panic
sick with fear.
I was going to die without even knowing why.
It was absurd, but I was helpless.
I was paralysed.
3 days, 3 nights, alone
lying on my cot, shaking.
It was horrible.
I was scared. I'm not much of a hero
but probably no one could be brave
in a situation like that.
They came to get me the third night.
Come on.
Move!
C'mon!
Where are you taking me?
You know where.
Down to the end.
All the way.
It was just to scare me, the bastards.
They used blanks.
I went into shock, and fell.
I passed out.
When I woke up I was in my cell.
And when you wake up from
an experience like that...
Never been to Lac St Jean?
Lord! How many times must I tell you? No.
Or to Roberval?
No, absolutely not.
My husband's been there, but not me.
And you don't know these names?
All right...
It seems you're not being charged.
You were arrested by mistake.
You're free.
Why'd you do this?
I'm free!
Claudette! I'm free to go!
What? I'm free!
I don't believe it! That's wonderful!
What about us?
Marie is free!
When can we go?
What did they say?
How about us?
They just said I was free.
Doesn't matter. It's a good sign.
First one...
They're going to release us one by one.
Marie's free!
Marie's leaving!
I only heard about his father
when I got home, after six days in jail.
Maybe it doesn't seem long
but six days in jail, tormenting yourself, is long.
Stop that!
What's going on?
What's going on is that common sense
says Boudreau should be allowed to leave
because of his father.
It's the minimum of decency.
Are you listening?
The minimum!
I can't make that decision.
The Minister of Justice
gives the orders. We carry them out.
Who would treat a man that way?
Have you lost your father?
Besides, not one of us has been charged.
Why're we being held?
We still have fundamental rights.
Dr Beauchemin, you know...
Forget the Dr and do something for Clermont.
You know we have to follow our orders.
Orders! From whom?
From heaven?
I'll look into it.
45 minutes I've been waiting...
Yes?
Yes, I'll wait.
It's the Minister!
Yes...
This is Mme Clermont Boudreau.
It's my husband who's in jail.
Yes.
Well...
My husband's father just died and...
I wondered if, I mean...
given the circumstances, and that he's been in
jail 10 days
with no charge...
I thought maybe you could let him out.
I thought that
for humanitarian reasons, you know
under the circumstances...
But this is different.
I know there's a special law but those people...
Exactly.
You'd best pray to God for guidance!
I don't understand
why you can't make that decision yourself.
I'll wait for your call.
Thank you, sir.
We don't weigh heavily on his conscience.
Take Lavoie's name off the board.
You're free.
It's not true!
Get undressed.
What's this?
- Get undressed!
But you said I was free.
Want us to do it for you?
Take it easy.
Goddamn filthy pigs!
Lavoie...
we'll get you yet.
You pig!
Just you try!
Françoise?
Yeah, it's me.
Just walked in the door
when the telephone rang.
They kept me six days, more than enough.
No, they didn't torture me.
You should see my place.
It's incredible.
They came back while I was in jail.
It wasn't this bad when I left.
It's a real mess.
The plants, record player, books.
You should see it.
They didn't even lock the door.
Want me to help clean up?
It's a huge job.
That's ok.
Oh, I meant to tell you.
Be careful on the phone.
They have wire taps.
What?
Yeah, they record your calls.
Well let them!
Tap all you want, see if I care!
My life's an open book. I've nothing to hide.
Are you there?
Go on, give it to'em!
Hello there, police.
Must look stupid with their tape recorders.
I couldn't sleep. First time in my life
I was really scared.
We all get scared
but not damn scared. This time I was.
All night long in the dark I felt it.
I heard every sound.
Like when they came for
Maurice and brought him back.
The least noise, someone breathing
or moaning in his sleep.
I couldn't stop listening, I was too scared.
Maurice!
Clermont...
What is it?
I have to get out of here.
They said they'd kill me.
Get the nurse.
Yeah, but...
everything's closed after 11:00.
Did they beat you up?
Call the priest!
Boudreau, come to the gate.
I was pretty worried about Maurice
but I was even more worried for myself.
I wondered when they'd come for me.
You ok?
- I guess so.
Boudreau!
Clermont, I'm scared.
They're going to shoot me. Listen...
They would've done it by now.
Get some rest and don't be scared.
What's that for?
You're going to see your father.
At this time of night?
Those are our orders.
Unbelievable!
They didn't want us to know they'd given in
so they waited till we were asleep.
They came for him at 3:00 a. M.
To take him to see his father.
St Joseph was pretty far...
but they didn't ease up.
Not allowed to smoke, handcuffs...
Four guards and they kept the cuffs on.
To take him to see his dead father!
This way.
Oh my God!
Didn't stay long.
It was in the month of October
in St Joseph d'Alma.
Although my life is sober
it is coming to an end.
I pack my bags
To the station I go.
Today I'm leaving you
for a long time.
When you come to this world
you feel tall and strong.
And you laugh at yourself
for having feared death.
Hope, is born again...
We must preserve it well.
Cast off your false masters
This is freedom.
To hear him singing, to give himself courage
a song his father sang to him as a boy...
There, was silence.
It made us stop and think.
If he could still sing after all that
our own little problems didn't seem so bad.
But it was getting harder and harder to bear.
Believe, it or not, they
interrogated him that night.
You know how it is.
You're wrong no matter what.
So you won't talk?
I've nothing to say.
You're only hurting yourself.
All your pals talked.
So don't try to pretend.
You'll get 20 years, minimum
unless they decide to shoot you.
In Roberval
did you meet a man named Brochu?
We have ways to take care of people like you.
You have the right to speak,
but not others, huh?
Alright.
That's enough. You can go back now.
Yeah, back to yourcoffin.
They must've given up trying to make me talk
so they let me go.
You're, in no hurry, huh?
Bye, Maurice.
Here, Gaétan.
Good luck, kid.
Bye, Gaétan.
Bye, Maurice.
See you, guys!
Have one for me, a cold one!
Bye, Richard. Bastard!
Won't be long.
You're going to miss us, you'll see.
They kept me locked up another six days.
Waiting was the hardest.
When there's no charge, you can't defend
yourself.
You think you'll never be free again.
When they let me go, after 21 days
I spent a few weeks in a psychiatric ward.
They destroyed a part of me.
I feel like I'm...
older than other people my age.
I've lost my innocence.
What I've told you...
is true, every terrible word of it.
Pierre Bélanger!
Sign there.
Clermont Bourdeau!
It's Boudreau!
Sign the envelope and you can go.
Don't you drive us home?
Forget it.
I think you can find your own way.
Dr Jean-Marie Beauchemin.
See you!
Stuff, your See you!
After what happened here...
I almost died. You won't see me again!
You drag me here like a dog
shut me up in a hole for 16 days.
16 days in a cell, and then
you say it was a mistake!
Mistakes like that...
Next time I'll be ready!
Don't bother, they just follow orders.
Next time there'll be a trial, out in the street!
When we were arrested,
it made all the headlines.
But, when they let us go
do you think that was news? No way!
Outside, it was like
nothing had happened.
Now that it's over, what are you going to do?
Go back to work.
I've got no choice. That's how I was raised.
Just so people learn from this.
Like Marie says...
after the ice jams the rivers flow again.
What happened to us
is nothing really.
But we must realize
it shows something's rotten somewhere.
We mustn't let the sickness spread.
This film is based on the true stories
of the victims of the War Measures Act.
Subtitles: Marcia Coulle & Robert Gray
(Kinograph)