A SHOCHIKU FILM
ORNAMENTAL HAIRPIN
A Film by
HIROSHI SHIMIZU
Based on a Story by
MASUJI IBUSE
Adapted Screenplay by
KIHAN NAGASE
Director of Photography
SUKETARO INOKAI
Music TAKAAKI ASAI
Production Design ISAMU MOTOKI
Edited by
YOSHIYASU HAMAMURA
Produced by
YASUYUKI ARAI
Starring
KINUYO TANAKA
HIROKO KAWASAKI
TATSUO SAITO
CHISHU RYU
SHINICHI HIMORI
HIDEKO MIMURA
KANJI KAWARA
JUN YOKO YAMA, MASAYOSHI OTSUKA
TAKESHI SAKAMOTO
KOJI MATSUMOTO
MUNENOBU YUI
TSUNEO OSUGI, KAYOKO TERADA
It feels so nice
walking in the bright sun.
Yes, it's nice...
but perhaps a little too hot
for pale girls like us.
I'm really perspiring.
I like it. It's washing all
the old powder out of my skin.
Along with the tobacco smoke
and alcohol.
You know, I've been thinking
about something.
What?
One of these days...
Pick up the pace, everyone!
WELCOME, NICHIREN PILGRIMS
Please listen, everyone!
You all asked for masseurs,
but there are only 18
in this whole town.
I was able to get 12 of those,
so come draw lots!
Come on, everyone!
What a racket!
They're so noisy!
They really are loud!
Quite a merry bunch, eh?
Merry?
What do you mean?
Well, I...
Does that sound "merry" to you?
It sounds noisy to me.
Just plain noisy.
Sounds like
they're in high spirits.
High spirits?
You call that "high spirits,"
old man?
It's just noise.
That's what it is.
Is he mad again?
Yes.
It's quite a big show tonight.
Big show?
What do you mean by that?
Does that sound
like a "big show" to you?
They're just noisy!
Too noisy!
See? He's grouchy again.
Hello?
Is this the front desk?
It's really noisy down there.
This is an outrage!
That's no way to behave at an inn.
Tell them!
I can't work.
I need a massage before bed,
so send a masseur.
What? They're all taken?
All of them?
We're ready.
Please do your best.
Who's the professor?
He's been here
since early summer,
reading very
difficult-Iooking books.
Maybe that's why
he says rather difficult things.
What sort of things?
A man was reciting
a Chinese poem in the water.
The professor heard it
and asked if the man
had composed it himself.
The man said no,
it was a famous poem by so-and-so.
The professor said
it was ridiculous
to recite other people's poetry.
That means geisha
shouldn't sing songs,
because they didn't write them.
That's right.
That man hasn't recited
a poem since.
Poor man.
I feel more sorry for the couple
across the hall from him.
Hello?
Where's that masseur?
What! That's ridiculous!
One group
can't monopolize them all!
How can you allow
something so absurd?
Get me the owner!
What?
Gone to bed?
How can the owner
go to bed before his guests?
Wake him up!
I was so angry last night
that I couldn't sleep a wink.
Was there something wrong?
You bet there was.
No masseur ever came.
They were all busy
with that group.
These excursion groups
have no manners
or consideration at all.
Well, they only travel
once or twice a year.
So are you saying...
that means they can behave
however they please?
No, I didn't mean -
I didn't mean
they can do anything.
I'm sorry.
Ethically speaking,
monopolizing all the masseurs
is absolutely inexcusable.
Don't you agree, old man?
Well...
Ouch!
What is it?
I stepped on something.
Did you cut yourself?
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
Call the innkeeper!
Your injury was due
to our negligence.
We sincerely apologize.
The carelessness of the staff
is my responsibility.
I beg your forgiveness.
How's your foot?
Frankly I'm embarrassed
by all the attention.
It's a great dishonor
to have a guest hurt.
We owe all of our guests
a profound apology.
Tell me, sir,
do you mean
you're apologizing to everyone?
Indeed.
Apologizing to all
the guests means
you believe that
the facilities are perfect.
Not at all.
Either that, or you're exploiting
his misfortune for publicity.
Rationalize it how you will,
that's how I see it.
Exploiting this tragedy
is an outrage.
"Tragedy"?
It's just a little wound.
Besides, there's
something almost poetic
about finding
a hairpin in the bath.
Poetic?
It's like the sole of my foot
has been pierced by poetry.
Everything you just said
smacks of decadence.
Why not add vulgarity to it
by hoping that the woman
it belonged to is beautiful too?
There's no need
to read so much into it.
Besides, I was careless too.
That may be so, but -
No, it was all our fault.
We'll see that
it never happens again.
- But the problem remains -
- It's all right.
He's already apologized.
It's really not that serious.
Is that so?
Then am I to presume I'm making
a nuisance of myself here?
Then we'll discuss this
in my room.
Innkeeper, come to my room.
The professor's bored
from being here so long.
Talking relieves his boredom.
You're right.
We're bored too.
His anger relieves our boredom.
I am not bored.
I have a mountain of reading.
If my anger relieves
your boredom -
Well, we'll discuss this later.
If you'll excuse us.
Dear...
you shouldn't have said
the professor was bored.
What if he comes to us
and complains?
That would be awful.
You're right.
What will we do if he comes?
What will we do?
Don't worry.
I'll take care of him.
Really?
Mr. Nanmura called it "poetic."
He said his foot was
"pierced by poetry."
How do you interpret that?
It's got to mean something.
"Dear Sir,
I am one of the pilgrims
who stayed at your inn.
I seem to have lost a hairpin
with a red coral gem.
If you happen to find it,
please let me know.
If so, I will send money
to have it returned to me
by registered mail.
Sincerely yours,
Emi Ota"
Professor, a letter came
from the hairpin owner.
Yes, so it seems.
But that person doesn't know
what her hairpin did
to Mr. Nanmura's foot.
Of course not.
Not unless she's told.
She couldn't know that
Mr. Nanmura felt it was poetic.
Professor, I think
the owner of that hairpin
may in fact be
an older woman,
but my wife thinks
it's a young woman.
You're constantly going on
about what your wife thinks,
but what does her opinion
have to do with any of this?
No... I just meant...
I'm sorry.
Say, old man,
what do you think?
Since it was
an ornamental hairpin,
she's not the kind
to wear Western clothes.
Right. You can't wear
one of those with a perm.
So she must wear a kimono.
Whether she wears a kimono
or whether she's old or young
is of no importance.
I just hope for Mr. Nanmura's sake
that she's beautiful.
For Mr. Nanmura's sake?
That's right.
He felt the hairpin was poetic.
She has to be beautiful
so that his poetic illusion isn't crushed.
I see.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
Very well put, Professor.
So that's how it is?
I see.
You should send it right away.
Of course I will,
but you were hurt by this pin.
She should apologize.
There's no apology needed.
Just leave it be.
Just hurry and send it.
But...
"Sorry about injury.
Coming to apologize. Emi"
Mr. Nanmura?
Telegram, sir!
He's not here?
Where could he be?
A telegram?
From the owner of the hairpin.
She's coming to apologize.
Really?
She's coming?
She sent this en route,
so she must be on the next train.
Where's Mr. Nanmura?
Excuse me.
Well, the owner
of the hairpin is coming.
Think she'll be beautiful?
- Well, my wife says -
- What?
I'm sorry.
I hope she is, for his sake.
But we must consider
the other possibility.
What?
If she's beautiful,
all will be well.
But if she's not,
he'll be disappointed.
We must be prepared
to comfort him.
Comfort him?
Dear, what do you -
- Again?
I'm sorry.
What do you mean?
Poetic illusions are like dreams,
and they're always beautiful.
But reality is quite often ugly.
Dear...
maybe you should
go look for Mr. Nanmura.
All right.
I'll go have a look.
Nanmura,
what are you doing here?
I've been looking all over.
Wait a minute.
How much is that?
Forty sen.
Bring me the change later, kid.
Actually, the hairpin's owner
has come to apologize.
- She came all this way?
- Of course.
She hurt you.
Is she beautiful?
I saw her only briefly
from the back.
"A goddess from the back,
homely from the front."
Listen, there's a chance
she won't be beautiful,
so don't be disappointed
if she's not.
Poetic illusions are like dreams,
and they're always beautiful.
But reality is quite often ugly.
I have no idea
what you're going on about.
What are you trying to say?
What am I saying?
- What are you thinking, dear?
- Oh, right.
Anyway, just stay
calm and collected.
Don't de disappointed
under any circumstances.
She's not the only woman around.
You'll find your poetic beauty,
so don't let yourself get gloomy.
I'm not disappointed
or gloomy.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
You don't want your poetic illusion
to be crushed -
Dear...
we don't even know
what she's like yet.
I only saw her from the back.
You're right.
All right, let's go see.
Let's go together and see.
...and thus, I'm sure
your visit will please him greatly.
Don't you think so?
- Indeed.
So please don't crush
his poetic illusion.
I beg you.
I'll do the best I can.
Ah, welcome.
This young lady owns the hairpin.
She's very sorry.
I'm terribly sorry
for my carelessness.
It's nothing, really.
You needn't have come
all the way here.
It's almost embarrassing
to make such a big deal out of it.
I've told her everything.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Let's go.
Please excuse us.
Thank you.
Professor, I'm so relieved.
Thank goodness she's beautiful.
Don't you think so, dear?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
It would've been a tragedy
if she weren't.
Well, thanks for your help.
No, it was all thanks to you.
No, no.
Come here a minute.
The heat's a bit oppressive,
isn't it?
Is it?
I mean, yes, it is.
Um...
Yes?
It's really very hot.
Yes, you're right.
Maybe I'll soak in the water.
Your towel?
Have you gone for a soak yet?
It might be refreshing.
I will.
Thank you.
You're very considerate
for a scholar.
I'm too old for all that.
That's not so.
You do just fine.
Let's see...
Miss, please bring a mirror.
And bring in the lady's bags.
And we'll close these screens.
I guess that should do.
Really? I guess
I was wrong to ask.
I won't ask again.
All he does is
talk to her all the time.
Hey, what about
your walking practice?
Oh, right.
I lost myself in our conversation.
How far did I get yesterday?
Just past that tree.
You made it
this far yesterday.
I'll try for the next tree today.
One, two, three!
You can do it.
Keep going!
Come on.
A little further.
You can do it.
Keep going.
Just a little further.
Come on!
You can do it!
Careful!
Too bad.
You almost made it.
- It's still a record.
Do you practice
like this every day?
- Will you come watch?
- Yes, absolutely.
Go get my crutches,
would you?
You take them to him, lady.
Jiro, let's go.
You boys!
Come on.
Why don't you take
his crutches to him?
All he does is talk to you.
You take them.
The professor's moved in with us.
We were really cramped last night.
Right, Jiro?
That's right.
And the professor snores!
Even louder than Grandpa.
We can't sleep.
That sounds awful.
I'm sorry.
We'll all sleep
in my room tonight, okay?
Now go take him his crutches.
Come down now.
Careful. Don't fall.
Now go get his crutches.
- He's gone.
- Where could he have gone?
- The crutches are gone too.
- He probably went back.
That was nice of you.
You managed that well.
Listen, let's everyone take turns
singing their favorite song.
It can be any kind of song.
If nobody speaks up,
I'll pick someone.
Another group arrived today.
So it seems.
These groups
lack all consideration.
Oh! I better book
a masseur while I can.
Hello? Front desk?
Since another group's
come in today,
would you book me
a masseur now?
What?
They're all booked?
Surely you can find one!
What? You can't?
All taken?
They didn't lose any time
booking them all.
They sure didn't.
I tell you, these groups
lack all consideration for others.
Hello?
Speaking.
Is this Ume?
Is everything okay?
He got mad?
He came back three times?
You didn't tell him I'm here, did you?
Make sure you don't.
Really?
He'll take my things
if I'm not there next time?
Fine with me.
He can have it all.
It'll be a clean start
for both of us.
And Ume...
when he comes
to take my things,
don't say "see you later"
like always.
Say "farewell."
Understand?
And like I've said before,
you should think about getting
married and changing jobs.
Think it over while I'm gone.
I think it's best for you
to go home and get married.
Anyway, think it over.
By the way, have you seen Okiku?
Was she worried?
I'll write her
and explain everything.
All right, then.
Good-bye.
Don't swallow the seeds.
You'll get appendicitis.
- Aren't you going to eat?
- No.
- What a waste.
- You can have it.
What's the character
for "suddenly"?
"Suddenly"?
Shall I ask the professor?
No, don't bother.
"Dear Okiku, I'm sorry
I left without telling you.
I won't be coming back
for a while.
The reason is because..."
Can we visit you
when we get back to Tokyo?
Yes.
- Will you cook something for us?
- Yes.
- Where do you live in Tokyo?
- You're not listening!
- What?
I asked if we could
visit you in Tokyo,
and if you'd cook us something,
and where you lived.
Sorry. I was thinking
about something.
I may not have a home
when I return to Tokyo.
Then what will you do?
I don't want to go back.
I probably won't.
Then we can't visit you after all.
I'll have to start all over again.
Here we go again.
The professor's the loudest.
Grandpa has to try harder.
- Come on, Grandpa!
- Louder!
- Come on!
- Don't let him win!
Boys, be quiet.
Grandpa's louder now.
I can't stand it
when people snore.
Taro, you've written here
about your summer vacation
as if it's already over.
I wanted to finish
the assignment.
I understand that,
but how can you write about things
that haven't happened yet?
Because every day here
is the same.
I get up, exercise
to the radio, bathe,
eat breakfast, study, play,
have lunch, take a nap,
go for a walk,
help you practice walking,
then have a bath,
eat dinner,
and then...
study a little more, and go to bed.
Every day's the same.
But you have to write
about the special things that happen.
For example,
how a lady came from Tokyo,
how the professor got into fights
with excursion groups.
Different things happen
every day.
Like how the professor moved
into our room when that lady came?
And how we moved
into her room?
- And their snoring contest?
- That's right.
How about another game?
- Another game of Go?
- If you would.
- Again?
- Please.
Really?
This is Grandpa's.
The professor sent his too.
He's got some nerve.
He expects you
to wash his things.
Really?
That's all right.
I'll do them all.
Take your clothes off now
and have a swim until they dry.
Go on, get in.
It's cold!
See? Doesn't it feel nice?
You splashed me!
I'll splash you back!
Don't splash me!
Just go swim.
I'll splash you more!
- Stop that!
- No.
Come on! You can do it!
Come on!
You've broken
your own record!
Keep going!
A little further!
Keep trying!
You can do it!
Don't give up!
You're almost there.
A little further!
You can do it!
You did it!
You made it!
Thanks to all of you.
I'll try a new place tomorrow.
Someplace with obstacles.
Obstacles?
That might be a little tough.
It'll be all right.
Won't it?
Of course.
You made it this far today.
All right. I'll do it.
Now let's go have a soak.
This is almost like
a neighborhood meeting.
That's true.
Why don't we get together
like this regularly?
Next time will be in our room.
Right, dear?
Ah, I'm sorry.
The professor
should be chairman.
- Really?
- Absolutely.
Me?
No question about it.
Very well.
I accept the duties of chairman.
As our first topic, I submit
the service here at the inn.
I'd like to hear your opinions.
Yes, let's talk about that.
In my opinion...
although there are many
shortages these days,
it isn't being too picky
to point out that the food
leaves something to be desired.
Breakfast is miso soup, egg,
seaweed and pickles,
and lunch is noodles -
basically a rice substitute.
That much is fine.
The problem is dinner.
Sashimi followed by grilled fish,
soup, and boiled greens -
always the same,
as if it's written in stone.
They change the presentation,
but never the food.
One look
and I lose all appetite.
I didn't come
to the mountains to eat fish.
There should be
some local specialties.
What do all of you think?
You're absolutely right.
You may be right,
but I get a big discount here,
so I can hardly complain.
Actually,
with the grandkids along
I got a much lower rate too.
Now that you mention it,
I'm paying below
the normal rate too.
So you can't complain.
You're right.
But still...
a bit of variety would be nice.
Some tofu, or squash,
or salmon, or sardines.
I agree.
Some squash would be great.
I love squash.
Or salmon rice with tea.
What about you,
Mr. Hiroyasu?
You haven't said a word.
Do you have no opinion?
Oh, the meals here
are definitely not fancy.
Are they, dear?
Ah, I'm sorry.
They're not fancy,
but we don't feel deprived.
- What do you mean?
- I mean...
from now on we'll have
the same as everyone else.
Won't we dear? Oops!
I'm sorry.
Shall we change
the subject now?
Very well. I'll speak
to the innkeeper about the meals.
Next topic?
Your snoring, Professor.
It's annoying.
She couldn't sleep
a wink last night.
Taro!
You said it was like
sleeping by train tracks.
I don't know what to say!
I'll try to be more careful.
Next topic?
Miss Emi, anything you'd like
to bring up besides train tracks?
Not really.
Since I arrived,
I've been getting up early.
I learned the exercises to the radio,
and I do washing in the river.
I wish I could live
like this forever.
But the boys will leave
when summer's over,
and so will Mr. Nanmura
and the rest of you.
I'll miss you all.
If Mr. Nanmura leaves,
I suppose you'll -
Listen, everyone.
After we all return to Tokyo,
we should keep meeting.
Shouldn't we, dear?
Yes, dear. Good idea.
What do all of you think?
- I'm in favor.
- Let's do that.
- Good idea.
- Yes, indeed.
Will I still be chairman?
Of course!
But Miss Emi may not have
anywhere to go back to.
It's been chaos
since you left.
He said he'd file
a missing person's report.
I didn't know what to do.
I'm sorry about all this.
What did he do then?
He flew into a rage
and took everything.
I think he was just
trying to intimidate me.
I'm glad he took everything.
A nice clean break!
How can you say that?
What would you do
if he found out you're here?
What would I do?
I'm not sure.
I'd slap his face.
You don't seem terribly worried.
What are your plans now?
I'm not sure...
but something will come to me.
I've learned the radio exercises
and how to do laundry.
See how much sun I've gotten?
Okiku, remember
during the pilgrimage,
how we were perspiring?
Miss Emi!
It's time for his walking practice!
Hurry up!
Oh, I forgot.
Why don't you soak in the springs
and then rest awhile?
Here I am.
Here I come!
Get set, go!
Are you all right?
Be careful.
You okay? Careful.
And he's off!
He's walking
on his own two feet!
Miss Emi looks nervous.
Mr. Hiroyasu
is trembling with fear.
Mr. Nanmura's covered 30 feet,
and he's giving it his best.
He's clenching his teeth.
Come on!
Keep going!
Don't give up!
We're all rooting him on.
He's trying with all his might.
He's breaking out
in a sweat.
Come on!
You can do it!
Keep going!
Be careful!
You're halfway!
Careful!
Just relax.
Too bad - he fell!
He almost made it.
- That was tough.
- Are you hurt?
No.
I'll carry you back.
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
That's dangerous.
Be careful!
Careful!
Come on!
You can do it!
Miss Emi, watch your step!
Are you all right?
Please be careful.
Watch your step!
Don't rush!
You're almost there!
Watch your step!
She made it!
Thank you.
What a relief!
Here come the masseurs.
Let's let them by.
Gentlemen, watch your step.
It's rocky there.
Thank you.
Be careful.
The bridge starts right there.
It's narrow.
Be careful.
- Isn't that Mr. Hiroyasu?
- Good day.
- Hello.
It curves there.
Be careful.
You can do it!
We know. Thank you.
You all right?
Come on!
Keep going!
I'm afraid I let you win.
You did no such thing.
Let's try again
after I go for a soak.
Again?
Hello? Front desk?
Listen, I came here
to read my books,
but this old man constantly
makes me play Go with him.
I want a different room.
Send a maid.
What? No rooms?
I have to do something.
I know!
I'll go back to my first room.
Hey. Hey you.
Who are you?
I came to get Miss Emi.
Miss Emi?
Yes.
To take her back?
Yes. Some matters
need her attention.
That's a real shame.
Shouldn't I take her back?
I can't tell you not to,
but it's still a real shame.
Did you already have a soak?
No, it's packed
with new visitors.
Another group?
If you don't mind,
could we play another game?
Really?
Perhaps we can talk more later.
If you'll excuse me.
So the water's packed
with people, is it?
Another group, eh?
The masseurs
are already booked up.
Hello? No, nothing.
So that's how it is, eh?
I'm back.
- Welcome back.
This is my friend Okiku.
Mr. Nanmura.
Nice to meet you.
What about me?
Jiro and Taro.
Hello.
Nice to meet all of you.
How about introducing us too?
Mr. And Mrs. Hiroyasu.
Nice to meet you.
So we have another member.
Yes, and this one
is very poetic too.
I wonder how Mr. Nanmura
will feel about Miss Emi going back.
When I told the professor
I had come to take you back,
he said it was a shame.
Why would he say that?
So you're here to take me back?
Yes.
Aren't you coming?
No, not yet.
No matter what?
That's right.
I don't want to go back
to that gloomy life.
That's no way to live.
I didn't want for money.
I could sleep when I wanted,
get up when I wanted,
wear what I wanted,
eat what I wanted, see what I wanted.
But that's all.
I want more meaning
in my life.
So please don't try
to talk me out of this.
I don't know
what the future holds,
but at least while I'm here
every day in the sunshine,
the sun will show me the way.
So don't try
to talk me out of it.
You know you feel the same way.
- I do?
I suddenly feel like crying.
Please don't stop me.
I came here to lecture you,
but I wound up
getting lectured instead.
Emi, I understand.
If that's how you feel,
I'll settle things with him.
Leave it to me.
Forget about everything,
and let the sun bronze your skin.
Someday I too will -
Miss Emi!
The little boy's coming.
Mr. Nanmura is moving
into Grandpa's room.
Two groups arrived today,
so all the rooms are packed.
I'm very sorry.
We have a group of pilgrims
and one of shopgirls.
- Sorry to intrude.
- Not at all.
With the rates we're paying,
we can't moan.
Sorry to barge in like this.
You and your wife too?
No, my wife will be
in the next room.
Well, then,
I guess it's all right.
Having a couple in here
would be a bit much.
So you're on
a discounted rate now too?
Quiet! Stop that racket!
Emi, could we trade places?
You'll get used to it.
I don't notice it at all anymore.
Are you sure?
This is really something.
I didn't expect this.
Loud, isn't it?
Isn't there anything
we can do?
Well...
we have to startle them.
Shall we try it?
What happened?
Nothing. You called me.
No, I didn't.
Really?
"The day after
those two groups arrived,
the professor got really grumpy
and went back to Tokyo.
Miss Emi's friend left too.
Grandpa seems to miss
his Go partner."
"Mr. Nanmura finally crossed
the log bridge today - hurrah!
Mr. And Mrs. Hiroyasu
have gone too.
We'll be going home
soon as well.
I hope Mr. Nanmura
can make it
to the top of the steps by then."
If I make it to the top,
I can go back to Tokyo
with the rest of you.
Go back to Tokyo?
Ready?
Go!
This will be tough.
If he makes it,
he can go back with us.
Come on!
You can do it!
Keep going!
Come on!
Don't give up!
Come on! Keep going!
10... 11...
12... 13...
Keep going!
18... 19...
You're halfway there!
Come on!
23...
Keep going!
28...
Ten to go! 9...
8...
5...
4...
3...
2... 1!
You made it! Hurrah!
He's going back after all.
I made it.
Now I can go back to Tokyo.
Miss Emi!
What's wrong?
I'm just happy he made it.
These are tears of joy.
You're all leaving me.
I'll be all alone.
"Emi, many thanks
for your help during my stay.
Since my return,
I've started using a cane,
and it's not just for show.
Tonight's our first 'neighborhood meeting.'
We look forward to your return to Tokyo.
Takeshi Nanmura"
THE END
Subtitles by
SUBTEXT SUBTITLING