Gas! I need gas!
Signor Bregana, I need gas!
My truck's engine is busted
and nobody wants to stop and take a look.
Are you in that much of hurry ?
I wake up in the morning and here we are.
The night before, I go to bed--
toot, toot, toot... and now here you are.
And this one ?
Who is he ?
Hey, you, get down!
It must be uncomfortable traveling in the back.
Maybe we should set up a mattress for bums.
Let's go. Hurry up.
You have to be careful.
Those guys could rob you naked.
- What do you want ?
- Fill it up.
Hey, Bregana.
- Hey, Bregana.
- No, not here yet.
Stay ! Sit !
. . .three, four, six, four, six.
Do you serve food here ?
I'm asking if you serve food here.
- Look, I'll pay for it.
- Okay, but in the other room.
Wait, I'll bring it to you in the other room.
it's good.
Do you have anything to do with that potbelly outside ?
He's my husband.
He's lucky to have a woman like you,
one that cooks so well.
You're exaggerating.
I am not a cook.
Wait for me there.
It's hot in here, by the stove.
You're built like a horse.
What's a little heat to you ?
Giovanna ?
We've caught a chicken thief hiding on a truck.
He must still be around here.
You never know what those guys are up to.
Why have you stopped eating ?
He may try something.
You hear so many things these days.
Here, it's even in the paper.
I hope...
Just the one I was looking for.
Who told you could come into the kitchen ?
Are you crazy ?
He could even steal the dishes.
Let's go, boy.
Thank goodness my brain still works.
Well, princess, you do your nails every day
and let my house go.
Don't get mad at me.
You're really smart.
You talk and talk and let him go without paying.
- Without paying ?
- Yes. Without paying.
- Why didn't you say so before ?
- Because--
I'll take care of him.
Hey ! You !
Wait a minute !
I told you, nobody can fool me.
Where you come from, do you eat without paying ?
- What are you saying ?
- Don't play dumb.
You didn't pay. The wife said so.
- Your wife told you that ?
- Yes.
That's a good story.
No need to repeat myself. Go ahead.
Move it. Empty those pockets.
What's this, then ?
- I haven't got a penny left.
- Think I'm gullible ?
You ate and you've got to pay one way or another.
- Then I'll give you my stuff.
- What would I do with it ?
if that's how you feel,
we'll find something else.
What do you want to find ?
Come on. Pay up.
- I heard your truck broke down.
- So, what's that to you ?
- I'm a mechanic.
- So ?
So, let's go take a look.
You think you can cheat me ?
If so, you'll pay for it.
It's written on your face that you're a good man.
What were you doing on that truck ?
Where did you want to go ?
- I'm out of work.
- You're not really a bum, are you ?
I like to travel. Rich people travel by train.
- l get by.
- You get by ?
- Hey, Bregana, you're late today.
- You can see I'm busy.
Then we'll take care of it ourselves.
Here are the chickens.
Always picking at my tires.
You also like working in the dark, don't you ?
Come on.
Let's go. Here it is.
Now let's see what you can do.
We need to run it to hear how it sounds.
Okay, let's do it.
Are you dropping parts as you go ?
No wonder it runs bad.
We need a new rotor.
Is there a place nearby to get it ?
The closest place is in Codigoro.
I could go by myself if l knew my way around here.
Not a chance! I'll call.
It's one hour away by bicycle.
Also, the pump sticks a little.
You know, it's hard getting a mechanic just for that.
- Since you're already here...
- Yes, I'll take care of it.
- Half a day and it will be running.
- Yes ?
Then take the tools and let's go.
- Hey, were you a bersagliere ?
- Sure. in the Sixth Regiment.
Me, too. I spent 18 months as bersagliere.
You too7 What a coincidence.
Sixth Regiment ?
That's the one for the best.
Actually, Riva the Marshal used to say the Fourth was the best.
You mean Sergeant Riva.
You met him too ?
''Study war tactics and you'll reap the reward.''
- Hello, Father Remigio.
- Good morning, Bregana.
Do you want to arm wrestle again ?
No, some other time.
If Santa Lucia guides my aim,
I want to pepper a dozen ducks.
- Hey, Giovanna, I'm off to Codigoro.
- Codigoro ?
Yes. Something urgent.
Hello, hello. . .
Is this the shop ?
I need a rotor.
Could you send it right away ?
To Bregana at the Dogana.
Are you hungry now ?
Then it's impossible for tonight.
Can't you find someone to bring it ?
Yes, but I'm out of money.
I can't pay you.
I understand. That's fine.
Come, Ferruccio, would you like to go
pick up a part for my truck ?
- I'm sorry, I can't go.
- Come with me. We'll go together.
Very well. Give me five minutes.
Giovanna, bring my coat and hat.
It was good of you to drop by.
At least I'll be able to give you news
you'll be interested in.
Is that right ?
Well.
I'll be back in an hour.
- Bring me the bicycle.
- Doesn't he go too ?
He's the mechanic.
He's going to fix the truck.
A mechanic ?
Yes, what's so strange about that ?
He looked and knew right away.
Why do you always
do things your own way ?
It's my house. I'm the boss.
Understand ?
- Good morning, Signora Giovanna.
- Let's go, Father.
- Where are you from ?
- Senigallia.
Ah, Senigallia.
Half saints, half crooks.
In the meantime, work on that pump.
- I'll expect you to be done.
- Don't worry.
- Let's go, Father.
- Let's go.
But you really don't know the news ?
- I'm telling you.
- Come now, l know you.
I'm going to tell you.
Those fellows are serious.
They caught a 10-pound yellow eel.
They will put it in the paper.
Unreal! Why didn't you say so before ?
10 pounds!
- Where did they cast the net ?
- l don't know.
I meant to ask you.
That's why l stopped by at the store.
Let's go first to set things up
for tomorrow morning.
Let's see if there's any good hunting in the marsh.
And the part for the truck ?
I'll pick it up on the way back.
First I want to find out. . .
oh-- here comes the ferry.
Really ? 10 pounds ?
I'll bet you they caught it in the Eden Valley.
When did you notice I liked you ?
Right away.
When I asked for something to eat...
and you didn't answer.
Now you'll never leave me, right ?
Not even to go back on the road ?
No.
Perhaps I was wrong about you.
You'll go boasting to everybody.
Some things I keep inside.
You're the first woman I've been with in a long time.
I didn't have much of a social life in the last few months--
longshoreman in Trieste, mechanic when I found work.
So who could I tell about this ?
I don't know anybody around here.
Then...
We'll get along.
How come he's not back yet ?
He's always like this.
He always says he'll be right back.
Maybe he is with the priest.
Why did you marry the old man ?
You never told me.
I don't even know myself.
I was foolish.
When I met him all proper-looking,
I didn't have a job.
I was letting people ask me out.
People just passing by.
You don't know what it's like being without any money, on the street--
not knowing what to do.
And then... ?
Do you understand ?
It means being asked out by men.
Yes, I understand.
I thought I could be safe with him,
but it's worse than before.
It's impossible, you see ?
To live like this-- dirty, fake.
What do I care about his money,
If I have to work here in the kitchen ?
Do I look like a cook to you ?
You deserve to be a lady.
You understand, don't you ?
With you I don't need to lie.
You're young.
You can't know what it's like with an old man.
No, but I can guess.
No-- you can't understand...
what it's like for a woman...
to live with an old man.
Each time he touches me
with those hands of his...
I would like to scream.
I'm no lady.
I am just miserable.
I can't stand it anymore.
Listen--
What do you say we go away ?
You and me together.
But where ?
Who cares where ?
Wherever we want.
No.
For me it would mean being propositioned again.
For you, it's different,
but for me...
I wish I had at least
a place where I could go and live.
No.
I'll stay here.
I'll continue to take it.
Until...
Until ?
Until I don't know when.
Tell me--
will you love me... always ?
Yes, Giovanna, I believe so.
Enough...
not to want anything else ?
Yes, Giovanna.
Then... something needs to happen...
for us.
But you must love me very much.
Gino.
Gino ?
Hey, Gino.
That was a long time.
Here's the part.
Did you fix the pump ?
Yes. it works.
Now you can fix it ?
Here, it's done.
It runs real well !
You did a good job !
Now where are you going ?
- Listen, Signor Bregana--
- What is it ?
I did the job, now we're even.
But now, I would like to ask for something.
I have no place to go.
If you need something else done. . .
That is, if you could put me up for a few more days.
Huh ! Got tired of wandering around ?
I won't give you any trouble.
Actually, I don't need any help.
But if we don't help each other, between us ex-bersaglieri. . .
hey, I'll give you food and drink, then we'll see what happens.
Okay.
Now, you can borrow my razor and clean up your face.
Giovanna ?
Giovanna.
Oh, you're here.
Why didn't you answer ?
Give me a kiss.
Can't you see someone is looking ?
Don't act like this in front of strangers.
He's not a kid.
He knows what goes on between a man and his wife.
Besides, he's no stranger.
It's Gino.
Didn't I tell you ?
He'll stay here a few days.
With us ?
Yes, with us.
It's a pity for a mechanic like him to wear out his shoes on the road.
Here, Gino.
Go shave yourself.
Go ahead. Help me dry out.
It's hot today.
There is a storm in the air.
It would be good if it rained.
Did you get the chickens inside ?
How hot it is.
Harder.
Good. Scratch there a little bit.
See, Gino ?
These are the pleasures of being married.
There is no other way.
You have to get married.
- You made up your mind a little late.
- A little late, but I'm not sorry.
You only think of yourself-- as if I didn't exist.
Don't worry, I've taken care of you too.
I have a document in here. . .
When the time is right, it will take care of you.
That's all. I know what I'm doing.
A document ?
Who knows what kind of mess you've gotten into.
A "mess", she calls it !
As they say...
"The wise person makes the relatives happy."
Meanwhile, let's make sure everything is ready.
Tomorrow at sunrise I'm going fishing.
Do you want to come along ?
I'd rather stay here.
I don't like fishing.
Your loss !
That cat sounds like it's being tortured.
Because the storm is coming.
It'll break overnight.
Let's hope.
I can't breathe.
Why don't you take off your shirt ?
Because he's here.
Where did he go ?
I don't know.
I'm not watching over him.
So, you're still mad at him.
- It is the heat. it gets to me.
- The heat. That's it.
Gino ?
Gino !
I'm here.
What are you doing ?
Here, get something to eat.
It is going to rain soon.
What have you done ?
There's a ton of pepper in it.
Just what we need with this heat.
You did this on purpose, didn't you ?
Idiot.
You ought to thank God someone is here just now.
Here ! I'm coming !
Look, I'm giving you this charm.
Keep it.
This way, with the three of us here, it can't go on.
You're telling me.
I feel the same.
Listen, Giovanna-- leave, with me.
That was a truck from Rovigo.
The driver was telling me
They killed poor Sarfi.
They say it was of one of his workers.
Because of his wife.
- Did they catch him ?
- No, but they'll find him for sure.
How was he killed ?
Shot from behind.
They just found him there.
Sometimes you can lose your mind.
There go those cats again.
We must close the windows.
The wind will blow everything tonight.
Didn't you hear me ?
It's all right. I'll take care of the cats.
Gino.
Wait a moment.
Wait.
I can't take it anymore.
I can't continue.
You're tired.
We'll wait for a truck that can take us to the train station.
I'm not tired, but I can't continue.
Last night, you made up your mind.
Now we can't go back.
Why can't we go back now ?
He is fishing.
He didn't notice anything.
You're out of your mind.
We have to get to the station.
And then ?
Then ?
Then we get on the train.
No. it's impossible.
I know how these things end up.
I can't tramp around like you.
We'll spend the night in a hotel,
and tomorrow we'll look for work.
Didn't you say that anything would be better than being with him ?
I was wrong.
Giovanna... ?
Come back with me, Gino.
With your husband always around ?
Come back with me, Gino !
Gino !
Gino, think about it.
Tickets ! Your tickets, please.
Tickets, ladies and gentlemen.
Tickets please, gentlemen.
- I don't have a ticket.
- Where are you going ?
I don't have a ticket.
And I have no money.
What do you mean ?
I don't have a ticket or money to buy one with.
If you want, I can get off at the first station coming up.
Don't worry, at the next station I'll get you off this train.
What is this ? Why throw an honest person off the train ?
You stay out of it.
This is none of your business.
Stop being a bully.
Tell me how much it costs.
I'll pay for his ticket.
You'll pay ?
To Ancona, it is over 100 lire, with the fine.
Is that so ?
So it's illegal to pay for a friend ?
As you wish.
it is 120 and 50.
I don't get paid to make distinctions.
Tickets, gentlemen.
Thank you.
Don't worry about it.
We must help each other.
How far is Ancona ?
Four stops... or five.
Ancona has a harbor, doesn't it ?
Do you want to board a ship ?
I don't know.
For now, I'll take a look around.
And you ?
Why are you going ?
I am an artist.
One day here, one there,
wherever I go there is work.
I'm coming from Trieste.
They call me "Spagnolo".
I worked for a long time in Spain.
If you want, you can join me.
Two people can do a lot of things together.
Why not ?
- What are we doing now ?
- Going to look for a room.
Tomorrow we'll look for work.
Heads-- we'll go left toward the harbor.
The room usually costs eight.
With two of you it will be 12.
We'll pay tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow ? No way.
Pay now or no room.
Let's not worry about this.
You're a good man.
What about him ?
Here's your money.
You see, Gino, money can't stand still.
In your pockets it gets moldy.
Instead, you take a piece, pass it on,
and someone else can make a living.
It's the same way all over the country.
Don't leave your shoes on, okay ?
Only dead people wear their shoes to bed.
Don't worry.
We aren't going to ruin your sheets.
Okay, okay.
Are you hungry ?
No. Usually when I travel
I don't get hungry.
Besides, these last few days
I've been eating regularly.
What do you do, sell women's apparel ?
Leave that alone.
Stay out of my business.
Your expression has changed.
- I didn't know you were so involved.
- You talk too much.
I'm not talking too much.
Why did you want to beat me up ?
You're right. I'm sorry.
I've never met a woman like her before.
If you stay with me, I'll show you the streets aren't just for making love.
That would be useless.
I understand what you say--
you have so many ideas--
things I couldn't even repeat.
You say we need to help each other.
You pay the train fare for someone without any money.
l only know that without her...
I'll never be happy.
Why didn't you bring her with you ?
- She didn't want to come.
- That means she doesn't love you.
Yes, she does love me...
but she isn't like us.
What do you mean, "not like us" ?
She has courage, but not enough to leave everything...
her house... and her husband.
She's afraid of being poor.
You've got to get away, Gino.
Go as far as you can.
Leave ?
I need to forget her first.
And yet, I know that I want her...
no matter what it costs.
And if I were to go back,
I could not resist her... as I did before.
Listen to me. Get on a ship.
The sea breeze will clear your mind of these ideas.
You'll feel free again.
Free ?
Free.
Did you miss your boat ?
There will be others.
Shall we go ?
An umbrella turned around like this jumps up and down, flies like a plane.
For 50 cents, I'll tell your fortune.
Green. A nice color.
A strong color, the color of hope.
You're lucky. You'll be a sailor.
50 cents. Only 50 cents.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Not like ones you buy at the store.
It's waterproof.
Look. Take a look. No leaks.
Hold this for me a moment, sir.
Look at the one that you'd buy at the store.
Here is the water test. Pour it in.
You see how it comes through ?
Look at mine, instead.
Made of steel and horn.
And it's yours, not for 50
or even 40, but only 20 lire.
Who doesn't have 20 lire nowadays ?
I'll be damned !
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Look who's here !
What a way to leave us.
If you weren't happy with us, you could have said so.
What are you doing ?
What's this ?
You know, the truck broke down again.
I had to take it apart and call a mechanic from Ferrara.
If you had been there-- tell him, Giovanna.
Tell him what a mess it was.
How are you, Signora Bregana ?
Look at the job you got here in town !
It's tied in the back.
Somebody did a real good job.
I'll help you get it off.
He deserves to leave it on for life.
You were stupid to leave a place
Where you had food to eat and a bed to sleep in to slave away in town.
Wait a minute.
I'll take care of it by myself.
Balloons. Balloons.
...even the old proverb says so...
Please. Take this poster off for a minute.
I need to say hello to a friend.
- A friend ?
- Yes, yes, a friend.
Don't ask questions now.
Hey, wait a minute.
Take this.
50 cents! 50 cents!
50 cents to tell your fortune!
- ...and the store at home.
- We closed for two days.
It did Giovanna some good, too.
She was getting unsettled.
Here we are-- Amici's Bar.
This is where I will sing.
The Best Voice Contest.
I'm going to win.
- Hey you-- where are you going ?
- I'm going to sing.
Hurry up, you're late.
I'm Giuseppe Bregana.
I'm singing an aria from "La Traviata".
Here you go. Hurry up !
You didn't go too far.
If I scared you so much...
Why didn't you go farther away ?
Let's not talk about it, Giovanna.
Tell me--
did you think about me sometimes ?
Why do you want to know ?
Giovanna...
I tried to forget you.
But I couldn't do it.
I can't live without you.
Before, the world looked immense.
Now, there is only your store.
I've been seeing you in my mind
since you sent me away, alone.
I would have never thought it possible to depend so much on someone.
If that's the problem...
soon you'll be free again.
I'll go back home with him.
In time, you'll forget me.
Giovanna !
- You must come with me.
- You know that's impossible.
Then I'll come back to the store.
Is that what you want ?
- Have you seen Gino ?
- No, I haven't see him.
Have you seen Gino ?
He's probably with some woman.
Bravo! Bravo!
It went well, didn't it ?
Be careful. You'll get sick. You're all sweaty.
We have to celebrate your success.
We too are from Ferrara.
Yes, but I have company, my wife and a friend.
Have a drink with us too.
The champagne is very good.
Okay, let's go, let's go.
Cheers !
When there's free food and drinks, Gino's always first.
Remember when he first came and didn't want to pay ?
And those guys, they invited us.
And who paid ?
Bregana !
Someday they'll come to the store and I'll get my money back.
What's important is working, and someone to leave the money to.
Am I right ?
Well, Giovanna, when are we going to have a baby ?
It's something to think about it. And you really have to commit.
Tell her, Gino. But women want to keep their figure.
It would be too bad to lose a voice like mine.  Let's go.
You know what I'm thinking now ?
Try to guess.
Beniamino.
That's what we'll call him.
Like the great tenor, Gigli. Then he'll be famous like him.
That's a good one, isn't it ?
Come on !
- Hurry up !
- I'm coming.
Hurry up. We have a long way to go.
Right away. Understand ?
Right away.
Be careful. What are you doing ?
Don't worry. I have a good grip.
- Let him drive.
- Him ?
Why ?
Oh, boy, I'm sick. Really sick.
Get out, get some air. It'll do you good.
Get behind the wheel-- now!
Are we close to the river7
It's probably 600 yards away.
Well, now I feel better.
What are you doing, getting out ?
He's going to drive. You get some rest.
Let's go.
Signor Bregana had too much to drink. At some point he got sick.
You should have been driving. You're the mechanic, aren't you ?
Yes, but he was saying I didn't know the way.
You had been drinking too ?
We were all together, but he had been drinking the most.
All right, go on.
After stopping because he was feeling sick,
he got back behind the wheel and drove three-quarters of a mile.
Why did you leave the main road to get on the country road ?
He wanted to get home faster. He took a shortcut.
Maybe he didn't know the way well and missed the curve.
He lost control of the car.
I don't know what happened next.
It happened in an instant.
When I opened my eyes I saw a lot of blood.
How do you suppose it was that your boss died instantly ?
Perhaps he was pinned down between the steering wheel and the car.
The impact crushed his head.
And why do you think Signora Bregana was unhurt ?
I told you already, I had no time to look.
She was by the door. Maybe she managed to jump out.
She jumped with her purse and her hat ?
With her purse and hat ?
What do you mean ?
The first truck driver who saw Signora Bregana calling for help
says she was holding onto her purse
without showing any trace of being in an accident.
I found them on the ground.
I took them to clean off the blood.
You jumped from the car before it rolled over ?
Yes. I saw it coming. I opened the door and jumped.
I asked my husband to let him drive, but he didn't want him to.
And he was going faster than usual.
What did you do after that ?
I came back to the truck. I opened the door...
and my husband wasn't answering.
Then he got out.
Didn't he faint ?
Yes. That's why I flagged the truck.
When the drivers arrived, he was already moving on his own.
Had you been with Signor Bregana for a long time ?
The first time, I was there a few days.
But I didn't like being tied down in one place and left.
Then, we met in Ancona and he insisted I come back.
So you were traveling around and decided to settle down ?
Yes, just like that.
- Do you have anything else to say ?
- No.
Let's go sign the report.
"Death by accident", Superintendent ?
"By accident".
Let's write it that way.
Let's go back into town now.
In here is everything he had on him.
These are the papers to release the body from the morgue.
Thank you, Superintendent.
Goodbye, Signora.
We'll need to get a few more details...
before closing the investigation.
We'll let you know.
It's hot. Do you want a drink ?
What is it ? Aren't you happy to be back ?
I had envisioned it differently, coming back here.
We have to get used to it.
When the store opens again
and there are people around, it'll be easier.
- We're reopening the store ?
- Of course.
What are you thinking ?
Nothing.
I'm happy.
I still can't believe I'm here...
alone with you.
Gino--
isn't this what we wanted ?
Yes. This is what we wanted.
When I think back to the days I spent behind this counter--
crying... alone.
I wouldn't want to go back.
Who's talking about going back ?
What's done is done.
We must love each other very much.
Otherwise, it was all for nothing.
Listen, Giovanna, we have to go away.
Why ?
Because as long as we stay here, I'll always see him.
I'll never forget him.
I still see him behind that counter.
I still hear his voice.
Look, Giovanna,
let's sell the store and move away--
away from here.
If you saw how silly you looked,
talking so loudly here in the store.
Somebody will hear you.
Don't drink so much.
- Someone's out there.
- Let them go.
We can't. They saw us come in.
- Then you go.
- I can't, dressed like this.
I'll go upstairs.
You know what to do. The drinks are all there.
Open up !
- Are you closed ?
- No. What do you want ?
I knocked, but didn't see anybody.
I'd like something to drink.
It's hard to work with only one arm.
- Are you the owner ?
- The owner is inside.
I'm sorry. Sometimes I feel like chatting.
I'm new around here and I don't know anybody.
I'm looking for work.
- How much is it ?
- One lira.
That's cheap. In town, they want 50.
Pay me whatever you want.
You must be knew at this.
You're lucky I'm honest.
Who was it ?
Someone looking for work.
He was asking questions.
I don't like people that pry into other people's business.
I don't like people asking questions.
What are you afraid of ?
You're worrying about nothing.
- What were you doing there ?
- Nothing.
- Let me see ?
- What do you care7
- I want to see.
- No.
- Give it to me, Giovanna.
- No, Gino !
Let go of me.
Good shot. And on the fly.
Bregana wouldn't have spent so much money in one evening.
Of course, he wants to be comfortable.
Say what you want, they aren't happy.
Not at all.
There she is, the lady boss, with Father Remigio.
Father Remigio is here.
I stopped to talk with him after mass to ask his opinion,
then I asked him to come by.
it was a long time since he last came by to play bocce.
It wasn't up to me.
I had to give up the game.
Good morning, Costa.
Have you been drinking again ?
I have nothing else to do to pass the time.
Today it's because you have nothing to do.
Tomorrow it'll be because someone invited you.
You always have an excuse to get drunk like this.
Because there is never anything happening.
Calm down, my dear Costa. You know drinking is bad for you.
After what happened to poor Bregana...
It was such a terrible tragedy.
We can't get over it.
Let's not talk about it anymore.
Peace to his soul.
Would you like a Strega, Father ?
No, you don't have to.
But if it helps to break the ice with this good young man...
You see, you should put an end to this arrangement of yours.
That's exactly why I came to see you today.
Cheers.
If we-- how would you say-- resolved this situation right away ?
No, no. Not right away. It would not quiet down the rumors.
We aren't doing anything wrong.
Thank you. People always say that.
But you're hurting yourselves.
My feeling is that he... could find himself another place.
Maybe around here.
I also said from the beginning that it would have been better to go away.
I'm not afraid of rumors.
It's not the rumors, Signora Bregana.
We mustn't forget God and our duties.
Listen to me. Work alone. Maybe only for a while.
Perhaps we shouldn't continue talking about this now.
I'll stop by the church with him in a few days.
As you wish. But don't forget what I've told you.
We have to bring this to an end.
- Good morning.
- Here come the musicians.
- It is the group from Polesella.
- Good, very good.
Take care, then.
Since they are here, I'll go play some bocce.
- Good day, Father.
- Good day.
Good day.
- Would you like a glass of wine ?
- Yes, please.
Who said anything about marriage ?
Do you think l want to spend my entire life here ?
You heard. Even the priest says we have to go away.
Don't talk like this in front of others.
Do you hear what I'm saying ?
I feel like screaming--
telling everybody what's happening, to put an end to it all.
You seem afraid to marry me.
Maybe you don't love me anymore.
It was only last month
when we met in Ancona,
and you were saying you couldn't live without me.
That's true...
but each day I hate this house more.
We cannot leave now. We'd become destitute.
Nobody would ever forgive us. We have to stay.
We have to. Do you understand ?
I know-- you've always feared uncertainty.
But you see...
I was thinking we could sell this place,
take the money and go anywhere we want.
Then we could truly start all over.
Let's wait a while. Not now, I told you.
How could we leave everything like this, all of a sudden ?
But I can't handle it.
I can't get used to it-- sleeping in his bed, eating at his table.
That's silly.
We must face people... without fear.
So that's why you want people here,
and the music, to get attention.
What are you thinking ?
We have to run the business.
Take care of it then, if you like parties.
You've learned how to do so many other jobs, you can learn this one, too.
This is not a job...
keeping guard on a dead man's house.
- Signora Giovanna ?
- I'm coming.
Signora Giovanna ?
- Signora Giovanna.
- I'm coming.
Good day.
What can I get you ?
How did you find me here ?
What a question. Everybody's talking about you.
No. Let's go this way.
What do you do with all your smart ideas ?
l carry them with me. Why ?
You had your chance.
What do you need with them ? You've played your hand.
You're doing pretty well here.
You've lost the taste for travel, haven't you ?
You can't wander around all your life.
You'll see, sooner or later it'll be the same for you.
No.
You should know better. People like me will never stop.
- Why do you say that ?
- You've acted badly, Gino.
What's wrong with loving a woman ?
- it's not about the woman.
- Then l don't know what you mean.
You know, Gino, I'm leaving now.
It's a good time of year.
I came by thinking maybe you would come with me.
If it were like before, you would have said yes.
I wanted to go to Sicily.
Sicily is beautiful, you know.
Then again, lots of places are nice-- Naples, Genoa.
Have you ever been to Genoa ?
In Genoa you can walk for hours by the docks.
It's like a main street. You meet a lot of friends,
because everybody goes to Genoa.
I know they're building a road. It's easy to find work.
You'll spend the day blasting your way through the mountains.
I can't stand it any longer.
I don't like hanging around anymore.
What's become of you ?
I don't like it anymore !
I don't like to travel anymore.
And stop playing like you know everything.
All this talk-- because I don't want to be a bum anymore.
A bum ? You say that in so harshly.
I was wrong. I thought I could talk to you like one of us.
But you don't want to understand. Certain things you pay for.
- Shut up.
- Yes, I'll shut up.
Don't worry, I'm not going to tell on you.
- Don't worry.
- Shut up !
Stay here if you want, with that woman you got by--
Shut up !
Before, you only threatened me. Now you've got more courage.
Can I help you ?
- But you hurt yourself.
- Thank you. I'll take care of myself.
Your temper is too hot, my boy. Punching him right away, even if--
It's our business.
I'll walk with you for awhile.
No, I'll go alone. I don't need anybody.
Go away, boys. Go on.
Spagnolo ?
Spagnolo... ?
Spagnolo !
I'm warning you for your own good.
He has a hot temper. He punches hard.
He could be dangerous.
Signora Giovanna ?
I'm coming.
Hello ?
How do you do ?
Signor Giuseppe, you are known as "Spagnolo" ?
Yes, sir.
Let's go home, it's late.
We made l80 lire today.
It was a good idea to hire the musicians.
Why can't they leave us alone ? It seems everyone knows.
What are you saying ?
This time, one year ago... I was in the Apuane Mountains.
I was working in the mines.
You talk as if I wasn't here.
Aren't you going to eat ?
I'm not hungry.
What are you doing ? Give me my ball of wool.
Thanks.
Are the boys misbehaving ? Are they bothering you ?
No. They just do it for fun.
Ice cream.
Ice cream for you, sir ?
- Here you go.
- Would you like one, too ?
Another one.
Thank you.
Ice cream.
- It's what you need with this heat.
- Why are you smiling ?
No reason, I just feel happy.
That means you don't have any worries.
I have worries, all right. Maybe it was meeting you.
Or maybe it was the ice cream.
You are a big flirt, aren't you ?
It depends, if I like someone.
Then you like me ?
Why are you asking ? Do you have something in mind ?
Maybe.
- Are you from around here ?
- No, I'm leaving soon.
- You're not from Ferrara ?
- No.
Then you'll be going back home.
I can't go back home.
Where are you going, then ?
I'm on tour. I'm a dancer. Next we'll go to Como.
I'm in the company. I'm in the second row, left side.
You can come see me, if you want. At Cinema Teatro Verdi.
You're a great girl.
I'm glad I met you.
Keep me company. I'm due back at the theater for rehearsal.
I can't. I'm waiting for someone.
Thanks for the ice cream. It was very kind of you.
There aren't enough people who are very kind.
Do you like her ?
The dancers all stay at Number 15 in Via Saraceno.
There are even better-looking ones.
Gino ? Gino.
Do you want to know something ?
Bregana had a life insurance policy.
They'll pay me, but they asked a lot of questions.
At times it was worse than being with the police.
But everything went all right.
I'll get 50,000 lire. We can expand the store.
A life insurance policy ?
And you got paid money for it ?
Yes, that's the way these things work.
What good fortune for you!
But Gino, the money is yours too.
What are you thinking ?
I don't want any of it !
Why are you telling me this now ?
How could I have told you before ?
Before I got the letter.
Stop playing with me.
How stupid I was. I didn't understand.
When we met you wanted to get rid of me.
Now I know why you didn't want to come away with me.
It was this money--
No, Gino. You're not thinking straight.
I'm not ?
Now l know that you used me.
You needed someone to help you.
If it had been only for the money, I could have found someone else--
- With more courage than you !
- You don't need any courage.
- I wouldn't do it again.
- Gino!
I'm sick of you.
I can't bear to look at you anymore.
Watch what you say.
Are you going to blackmail me now ?
I'll show you I'm capable of leaving you.
- Gino!
- I don't want to see you.
Is there a girl living here ?
- Her name is Anita.
- Yes. She is out now.
If you want to wait, that's her room.
Thank you.
Now you behave yourself !
First you say yes, then no. What do I do now ?
Go back to Rosina!
I wasn't expecting you to visit me.
I was in the neighborhood and I thought I'd stop by.
Then that means that you like me.
I'm glad you came by.
You're different from other men.
I don't know why I feel this way.
Why did you come here ?
Now I'm going to eat.
Do you want some ?
Are you hungry ?
Listen, let's eat together. I'll go out and get something.
Wait. I'm coming with you.
Where are you going ?
Now I understand why you were so worried about the insurance money.
Come.
Do you think I'm going to leave you with her ?
- After all I did for you ?
- For me ?
We love each other. That's why we did what we did.
Enough. She knows nothing about me.
Are you concerned about her ?
Gino !
Quiet ! Don't say anything.
Listen, Gino, forget about what I said a minute ago.
It wasn't fair. But I'm at the end of my rope.
You wanted me, Gino, and now you don't care about me.
Let's go back home. You'll calm down.
You'll think straight again. You'll stop treating me like this.
No. Leave me alone.
Look out, Gino.
- Look out ? Why ?
- You know.
I only have to speak up and they'll be after you.
Your choice. Come with me or...
Or what ?
I'm sorry about what happened on the street.
I've already eaten, but you can make yourself at home.
I'll tell you who she is.
I don't need to know.
- Why are you acting differently now ?
- It's not important.
Do you realize that your delay could impede justice ?
Superintendent, we have to work.
One day we work here, another day we go elsewhere.
Now you called us and we came. We told you all we knew.
Could you swear you saw both the man and the woman
climb up the levee as the car was rolling down ?
Yes, it made an impression.
I know the road very well and it seemed strange to me.
We were the first to help, but we had to go.
Other people came and we felt we couldn't do much more.
Yes, they already told me they were in a hurry
because they had to be in Milan before noon.
All right. Sign here on the report.
Come over here.
What about that man, Costa ?
Don't worry, Superintendent. We kept an eye on him.
Today he's here in town, but he has a two-way ticket.
Let's stop him before he goes.
I want to question him.
Sure, Superintendent. I'll take care of it.
I keep hearing it.
He tried to get up--
then I saw him...
fall again.
She was looking at me...
looking at me.
Then I acted...
without realizing what I was doing.
She had been so unhappy.
Tell me...
- Do you despise me now ?
- No.
To me you are still the same person.
I'll never be able to be what I was before.
Now I'm bound to her forever.
I'm a police officer.
Coffee.
Now I understand-- that man. . .
has been following me for a month.
He's a policeman. She's reported me.
I must get out of here no matter what, Anita.
What can you do ? Think for a moment.
If you go back to her you'll never be safe again.
You can help me. Go downstairs.
There's a man out there. Come, I'll show you.
Did you see him ?
Would you be able to recognize him ?
Yes.
You must distract him until I get out of here.
Tell him...
you saw him looking up here.
You know who he is looking for.
Tell him I left an hour ago.
Yes, tell him that. "He was here but left an hour ago".
What if he doesn't believe me ?
What else can we say ?
I'll tell him I'm angry with you...
because you didn't pay me.
I'll go now.
Giovanna, open the door.
Open up, Giovanna.
Open the door, Giovanna.
Open up !
Open ! Giovanna !
Open !
Here I am.
Now you can kill me if you like.
You kept your promise, didn't you ?
I don't care about anything anymore.
I know what you're capable of. I'm not afraid.
- You're not afraid, eh ?
- I don't care about anything.
You're not afraid ?
Then why did you report me ?
It was only a threat.
It was only to keep you here.
But now, if you want to go, go.
I'm not afraid to be alone anymore.
I always knew that for you I was the same as any other man.
No, Gino.
Don't you understand ?
Don't make up something else.
You're glad you reported me. They'll catch me,
and you'll have your revenge, isn't that so ?
I didn't report you. I felt like doing it...
when I saw that girl come between us.
Only because of that-- but I controlled myself.
I should've known that sooner or later you'd go.
These last few days I was afraid you'd go.
You can't bear staying in one place too long !
I remember...
the first time you came here.
You didn't even have socks on your feet.
I understand why I loved you so much right away--
and why I hated him so much.
Now I couldn't hurt you even if I wanted to.
Not even to stop you from leaving if that's what you want.
Because...
now I'm having a baby. It's your baby, Gino.
What are you saying ?
Yes. I suspected.
Now I'm sure.
I wanted to tell you about this.
Before, everything was confused,
but now I see clearly.
I've thought about it a lot--
about us, the baby.
We have taken one life away,
we can create another one.
That's why I'm not afraid anymore.
I have no resentment toward you.
l know l love you, Gino,
and I can't hurt you.
But you, how can you stop from taking it out on me ?
Now, if you want, you can do it.
I've told you everything.
I'm here.
Do you think I'm a bad man ?
No.
Gino !
I've looked for you all night.
You're all wet.
- Did you run ?
- Yes, but I don't mind.
Forgive me, Giovanna.
It would have been terrible if I'd hurt you.
This night was liberating for me.
It's like I've become a new man.
Before, something was keeping me away from you.
I had no peace.
Now I feel certain, Giovanna.
But we have to leave--
for good, right away.
We will go away.
It was impossible not to go wrong.
With everything we lived through, we should have left.
From now on, don't listen to me. You were right.
Don't say anything more.
Didn't I say everything has changed now ?
Gino... ?
Gino.
Last night, why did you say I had reported you ?
I don't know. That man...
What man ?
That man at the station. He must still be after me !
Giovanna ?
Lean against me. On my shoulder.
- Are you all right like this ?
- Yes, I'm fine.
You don't know what it's like.
It's not just having the baby, it's what you feel.
Soon I'll have a big belly.
I don't care if I look ugly.
Just the opposite. I want everybody to see.
- This is life, Gino.
- Yes.
This is life, finally.
Far away from that house.
They'll be there by now. They'll search every room.
If they catch us ?
You couldn't be with me anymore, Gino.
Don't worry about it.
You'll see. Everything will be all right.
Good luck will be with us.
It will not abandon the two of us, waiting a baby.
Don't worry. From now on, I'll take care of everything.
Where did the boss go ?
To Scatovari.
Scatovari ?
- Did they take the car ?
- Yes.
Let's go. Let's not waste any time.
We have to take our time behind this truck.
Try to pass. The fumes make me sick.
Close the window.
You know, from now on you'll have to take special care.
I've heard of women that had problems...
because they exerted themselves.
But nothing will happen to me !
Why worry about getting bigger each day ?
Right, Gino ?
Stop !
Bring the car !
Gino Costa...
let's go.