(crashing thunder)
(howling wind)
(men shouting)
(chorus) A sail! A sail!
It's the winged lion!
The lightning reveals it now.
A trumpet blast!
(boom)
The cannon has sounded!
It's the General's ship!
First it sinks down,
then it rears up.
Its prow rises from the waves.
It's hidden in the clouds and the sea,
then appears in the lightning's flash.
Lightning! Thunder! Whirlpools!
Stormy winds and thunderbolts!
(shouting)
The waves quake, the winds quake.
The foundations and pinnacles quake.
A grim, blind, whirling spirit
cleaves the air.
God shakes the white heavens
like a gloomy curtain.
All is smoke! All is fire!
The horrible soot turns to fire
and then dies.
(crashes and booms)
(whistling and explosions)
(massive blast)
The universe writhes,
the phantom north wind
rushes through the passes.
(dramatic trumpet fanfare)
Titanic trumpets blare out in the sky.
God, lightning in the storm!
God, the smile of the shore!
Save the vessel and the flag
of the Venetian destiny!
Thou, who rules the stars and Fate!
Thou, who governs the world and sky!
Grant that the faithful anchor,
rest on the bottom of the calmed sea.
Her mainsail's torn away!
Her prow is hurtling towards the reef!
(crowd) Help! Help!
May the stormy seas be her tomb.
(crowd) He is saved!
He is saved!
Lower the small boats!
All hands to the ropes! Hurry!
Row with all your might! To the shore!
To the landing place! Disembark
Hurrah!
Rejoice!
The infidels are buried
at the bottom of the sea.
Heavens be thanked.
Our weapons and the wrath of the storm
defeated them!
(crowd) Long live Othello!
Long live Othello!
Victory! Victory!
Victory is ours!
Slaughter!
Lost souls, crushed,
buried in horridness,
in horridness,
in horridness.
(cheering and applause)
(excited shouting)
- Rodrigo, what are you thinking of?
- Of drowning myself.
Only fools kill themselves for love.
How can I win her?.
Let time work for you.
The fair Desdemona,
whom you secretly adore,
will soon loathe the embrace
of that repulsive savage.
Although I pretend to be loyal to him,
I hate the Moor!
There is a reason. Here it is.
Look.
You see that foppish captain down there?
He usurped my rank,
earned in a hundred bloody battles.
Such was Othello's will.
And I remain
his lordship,
the Moor's ensign.
Oh, if you listen to me.
(shouting and whooping)
(drumming)
(dancers whooping)
(drum roll)
(cheering)
(cheering whooping and applause)
(cheering and laughter)
- Your cup, Captain.
- No more wine.
- Just another sip.
- No!
Come, today Cyprus is in a frenzy.
It's a joyous night!
No, one cup put my head afire.
But you must drink
to the marriage of Othello and Desdemona.
Her beauty and charm
have won her the hearts of all on the island.
Jago, sing her praises.
Listen to him. I am a mere bystander.
And she is beyond praise.
- Beware of that Cassio!
- Why?
He's a young and sly seducer
who could get in your way.
But if he gets drunk, he is lost.
Get him to drink
Bring more wine!
(cheering)
Drink and be merry
before joy and wine are spent.
This noble wine befuddles the mind.
Let all who have once succumbed
to the wild pleasures of the grapes
drink with me, drink with me!
Drink with me! Drink with me!
Drink!
Drink, drink!. Drink with me!
(crowd) Let all who have once succumbed
to the wild pleasures of the grapes
Drink with me! Drink with me!
- (Jago) Drink, drink!
- Drink with me!
Drink!
Drink! Drink!
Drink with me!
Another sip and he'll be drunk
(Jago) Men who don't drink are cowards.
My heart is an open book
Cowards and deceivers.
- I don't fear the truth.
- Drink, drink!.
I don't fear the truth.
- Drink with me!
- I don't fear the truth.
(crowd) Drink, drink!. Drink with me!
Drink, drink, drink, drink!
- (Jago ) Drink, drink!.
- (crowd) Drink with me!
Drink!
Drink, drink with me!
(hens squawking)
Captain, you must stand guard on the ramparts.
Let's go.
- What do I see?
- Cassio is drinking himself to sleep.
Othello must know.
Let's go.
- (crowd) Ha ha!
- Who's laughing?
I'm laughing at a drunkard.
Mind your words, you scoundrel.
Drunken rascal!
No one can save you now.
Please hold your hand, sir.
I'll split your brains if you interfere.
The words of a drunkard.
Me, a drunkard?
Go to the harbour and cry, ''Mutiny'!"'
Spread confusion, sound the alarm.
Brothers, stop this fighting.
Montano is wounded. Stop, I say!
He can't be stopped.
(panicked shouting)
Sound the alarm! He is possessed!
(swords clashing ferociously)
Put down your swords!
What's happening?
Have you turned into Saracens?
To be fighting amongst yourselves
Like mad dogs?
Honest Jago,
for the love you bear me,
speak!
I don't know.
One moment all friends happy and smiling.
The next, as if some evil star
had bewitched them,
their swords out, fighting with fury.
I wish I had lost the legs
that brought me here to witness it.
Cassio, how could you so forget yourself?
Your lordship, forgive me,
I don't know what to say.
- Montano.
- I am wounded.
Wounded? By heaven, my blood is boiling.
Anger has chased away our guardian angel.
Cassio, you are no longer captain.
Oh, sweet triumph!
Jago, go and restore peace to this troubled city.
Someone help Montano.
Return to your homes.
I shall not move from here
until I see this place cleared.
Already in the deep of night
all tumult has been silenced.
Already my throbbing heart
finds solace in this embrace
and recovers.
Let war engulf the world,
if her endless wrath
comes such boundless love.
My noble warrior!
How many sighs,
how much sorrow,
and how much hope
have led us
to this tender embrace?
How sweet are our whispers!
Do you remember?
(Desdemona voiceover)
When you told of your life in exile,
of daring deeds and many misfortunes,
and I listened with rapture in my soul,
in terror, with ecstasy in my heart?
I told of the clash of arms, fierce battles
and the brave flight into the mortal breach.
The assault,
clinging like ivy to the ramparts,
the target of whistling arrows.
Then you led me to the flaming deserts,
the burning sands of your native land.
You told me of your sufferings,
when you were sold in chains to slavery.
(Othello voiceover)
Your fair face, your sighing lips,
ennobled my story with tears.
Over my dark shadows, glory, heaven
and the stars descended to bless.
(Desdemona voiceover)
I saw the beauty of your noble spirit
beyond the darkness of your brow.
(Othello voiceover)
You loved me for my misfortunes.
And I loved you that you did pity me.
(Desdemona voiceover)
I loved you for the dangers you endured.
You loved me that I did pity you.
- You loved me.
- And you loved me.
- And I loved you that you did pity me.
- That I did pity you.
Let death come and sweep me away
in the ecstasy of this embrace,
the supreme moment.
So complete is my soul's joy
that I fear, I fear never to know again
Such a divine contentment
in the unknown future of my destiny.
(Desdemona voiceover)
May heaven banish all sorrow
and our love endure the passing of years.
(Othello voiceover)
To your prayers,
may the powers above say, ''Amen''.
(Desdemona) May it respond, ''Amen''.
Ah, joy washes over me so fiercely,
I fear I will suffocate.
A kiss.
Othello!
Another kiss.
The stars sink into the sea.
(Desdemona) Night draws to a close.
Come!
- Venus shines on high.
- Othello!
(gentle lapping of the sea)
(men talking)
Listen to me.
You know that Desdemona rules our ruler.
He lives only for her.
Beg that generous soul to plead for you
and you'll surely be pardoned.
But how can I approach her?.
She often strolls here
at about this hour with my wife.
Wait for her.
There lies your path to salvation.
Go.
(birds chirruping)
Go! I see your end already.
Your evil genius drives you on.
And I am your evil genius.
Mine follows me,
implacable God!
I believe in a cruel God,
who created me in his image,
and in my wrath I speak his name.
Born from some vile atom or germ,
vile I am.
I'm evil because I am a man
and I feel within me the primeval slime.
Yes.
This is my creed!
I believe as firmly
as any widow piously saying
her prayers in church,
that all the evil I think and do
was decreed for me by Fate.
I believe that the Righteous man
is just a buffoon
and that everything about him is false:
his tears, his sacrifices, his honour!
I believe man
to be the sport of an unjust destiny
from the germ of the cradle
to the worm of the grave.
After all this futility
comes death.
(voice echoing) And then?
Death and nothingness!
Heaven is an idle tale!
(roars with laughter)
Now to bring Othello here.
Help me, Satan, to achieve my end.
Chance favours me.
There he is. Now, to work!
(Cassio speaking quietly)
This saddens me!
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
I thought I was alone.
Idle words left my lips.
Is that Cassio leaving my wife?
Surely not.
That man fled like a culprit
when he saw you.
I think it was Cassio.
(birdsong)
(door hinges creak )
Beware, my lord, of jealousy!
It is a green-eyed monster, ghastly
and blind,
which poisons itself
with its own venom.
Its breast is ripped
by an ever-open wound.
You plunge me into misery!
But suspicion serves no purpose.
Probe before doubting.
After doubting, prove.
After proof...
..Othello has his own laws.
Away with both jealousy and love!
You make it easier for me to talk
(birdsong women singing happy folk song)
I don't yet talk of proof,
but, generous Othello, be vigilant.
Honest natures like yours
often don't see deceit.
Watch her well.
Listen when she talks.
One word may restore faith,
or confirm suspicion.
Here she comes. Watch her well.
(women singing happily)
(birdsong)
The brightness of the sky,
the scent of flowers...
This song completely captivates me.
If she is unfaithful, heaven mocks itself.
(women and children singing happily)
(singing continues)
I bring a petition from a man,
who has incurred your anger.
- Who is that?
- Cassio.
Were you talking with him just now?
The same.
And his repentance is so sincere,
that it deserves pardon.
For him I plead.
I beg you to forgive him.
Not now.
Don't refuse me.
Forgive him.
Not now!
Why is your voice troubled?
Are you unwell?
My forehead is burning.
The pain will go soon
if I bind it with this soft kerchief.
- I don't need that.
- Oh!
You are angry, my lord.
Leave me!
If I have unwittingly sinned against you,
my husband,
grant me the warm and sweet word
of your forgiveness.
(Othello) Perhaps because I don't stand
for betrayal in love.
- Give me that handkerchief.
- (Desdemona) I am your little one...
- What mischief do I read on your face?
-..humble and constant.
Perhaps I'm growing old.
But your lips sigh...
Perhaps because I'm black...
Look at my face...
(Jago) Give me that handkerchief!
(Desdemona)..see how I love you.
Perhaps I'm growing old.
(Othello) Perhaps because I'm black...
Let me lighten your heart,
Let me relieve your pain.
Grant me the warm and sweet word
of your pardon.
Leave me!
I want to be alone.
For your own good, say nothing.
Understand?
Desdemona unfaithful?.
What a terrible thought!
My poison begins to work
Unfaithful to me? To me!
Suffer and bellow!
Dreadful! Dreadful!
Think no more about it.
You! Out of my sight!
You have crucified me!
Alas!
Nothing is worse than suspicion.
During her stolen hours of lust,
did I feel any ill omens?
No, I was happy.
I still knew nothing.
I could not taste on that divine body
that enchants me, nor on those lying lips...
the burning kisses of Cassio.
And now... and now...
Now and forever farewell,
sacred memories.
Farewell content and tranquil mind.
Farewell brave troops,
great victories,
galloping horses, swift arrows.
(Othello) Farewell triumphant banner
and trumpets sounding reveille.
Farewell shouts and songs of battle.
This is the end of Othello's glory.
This is the end.
- This is the end!
(sword clatters)
My lord.
Find me proof that Desdemona is impure.
Don't run away, It's no use.
I want conclusive proof,
or the thunderbolt of my fury
will end your miserable life.
Heaven protect me!
I resign from your service.
I call the world to witness
the rewards of honesty.
No, stay.
Perhaps you are honest.
I would be better off a swindler.
Don't you see?
I think Desdemona true
and think she is not.
I think you are honest
and think you are not.
I want proof!
I want to know!
What proof do you need?
To see them embraced?.
Death and damnation!
That would not be easy.
Y et, what certainty can there be,
so long as the filthy proof eludes you?
But if reason is guide to truth,
I offer a conjecture,
which can bring you closer to certainty.
Listen.
One night,
Cassio was sleeping
and I lay nearby.
In muttering tones,
he betrayed his most secret thoughts.
His lips moved slowly
in the abandon of his ardent dreams.
And then he murmured, faintly, faintly,
''Sweet Desdemona,
we must hide our love!"'
''Divine ecstasy is drowning me!"'
The dream became more passionate.
Fervently, he seemed
almost to kiss the image of his love.
Then he said,
''Curse the cruel fate
which gave you to the Moor'!"'
- Monstrous crime!
- It was only a dream.
A dream that reflects reality.
A dream that can confirm other clues.
What evidence?
Have you ever seen in Desdemona's hand
a flower-embroidered handkerchief
more delicate than gauze?
The handkerchief I gave her
as first token of my love.
That handkerchief,
I'm sure of it,
I saw it yesterday in Cassio's hand.
Would but God grant him a thousand lives,
for one is not enough to sate my fury.
Jago, my heart is ice.
No more illusions.
I cast away my futile love.
See, it is gone.
The serpent of hate
has trapped me in its coils.
Blood! Blood! Blood!
I swear by the cold heaven,
by the forked lightning,
by death, and the dark devouring sea!
May this hand I now stretch forth
soon be fired,
this hand that I now stretch forth!
Do not rise yet.
I swear by the sun
which gives life to the earth
and the soul of all creation,
that my hand, heart and soul
shall be dedicated to Othello's service
if he also steels himself
to perform the cruel task
I swear by the cold heaven,
by the forked lightning,
may this hand
I now stretch forth.
Eternal God!
God of Vengeance!
(distant trumpet fanfare)
(waves crashing on shore gulls cawing)
(men talking)
The lookout has sighted the Venetian ship
carrying the envoys to Cyprus.
Very well.
May God smile on you, dear husband,
master of my soul.
Thank you, my lady.
Give me your ivory hand.
This hand is moist with soft beauty.
It yet has felt no age, nor known sorrow.
And yet here nests
the noble demon of bad counsel
that the whiteness betrays with its little clutches.
So sweetly it bends to prayer
and to pious abandon.
And yet with this hand
I gave you my heart.
But I must speak to you of Cassio again.
I feel feverish again.
- Bind my forehead.
- Here.
- No, with the handkerchief I gave you.
- I don't have it with me.
Beware if you've lost it!
Beware!
A powerful sorceress wove magic
in its threads.
There is, in its web,
a talisman.
Beware! To lose it or give it away
would bring disaster.
- Is it true?
- Yes, It's true.
- You frighten me!
- Have you lost it?
- Look for it!
- I'll look for it soon.
No, now!
Oh, God!
There is a threat in your voice!
- Raise your eyes.
- The idea!
Look me in the eye. Tell me who you are.
Othello's faithful wife.
Swear it and damn yourself!
- Don't you believe I am faithful?
- I believe you are impure.
- God, help me!
- Run to your damnation.
Say you are pure.
I am pure.
Swear it and damn yourself!
There's a fury in your words.
I hear it,
but cannot understand it.
Look at me.
I reveal my face and soul to you.
Search into my broken heart.
I pray to heaven
for you with my tears.
For you, I weep these hot tears on the ground.
See, the very first tears,
see, the very first tears
that grief ever drew from me.
The very first tears.
If the devil saw you now,
he'd think you an angel
and not lay a hand on you.
God sees my innocence.
No, hell sees it!
I implore you to be just!
Desdemona, be gone, be gone!
Be gone!
What sin have I committed?
Dare you ask?.
The blackest of crimes
is written on your forehead.
Alas!
Are you not a whore?
No, by my faith as a Christian!
Eh?.
I am not the thing
this vile word expresses.
(sobs)
Then give me your white hand.
I ask your pardon.
I took you,
forgive me if I am wrong,
for that cunning whore,
who married Othello!
God,
you could have afflicted me
with poverty,
or with shame.
Make of my triumphal trophies
a heap of rubble,
a meaningless shame.
I would have borne the cruel cross
of anguish and shame
with patience and fortitude,
resigned
to the will
of God.
Oh, grief! Oh, suffering!
I've been robbed of the illusion
which kept
my soul in joyful peace.
Cold is the sun,
the smile,
the radiance which gave me
Life and gladness.
Cold is the sun, the smile,
the radiance which gave me life,
which gave me gladness.
But now, gentle God of mercy,
holy immortal spirit,
cover your face
with the horrible mask of hell.
Oh, damnation!
She must first confess, then die!
Confession! Proof!
Cassio is here!
Oh, joy!
Oh, foul torture!
Calm down and hide.
Come in, no one is in here.
Step inside, Captain.
The word sounds hollow to me.
Your cause is in Such good hands.
Your Victory is certain.
- I hoped to see Desdemona here.
- He spoke her name!
I wanted to speak to her again
to know if I am forgiven.
Wait for her.
And to pass the time,
tell me about the one who is in love with you.
- Who's that?
- Bianca.
He smiles!
Nonsense!
She's determined to ensnare you.
- You make me laugh.
- He who wins, laughs.
Where women are concerned,
he who laughs, wins.
(Jago) Ha ha!
The wretch's gloating is killing me.
God, curb the torment in my heart.
I've already tired of her and her kisses.
Now you make me laugh.
(swords clashing)
You long for another beauty.
Do I hit the mark?. Ha, ha!
The villain mocks me.
Heaven, give me patience!
Yes, you've guessed.
- Listen to me.
- Keep your voice down. I'm listening.
You know, Jago, where I live.
Now he is telling how, where, and when.
I don't know who le it...
I can't hear his words. Yet, I wish I could.
Am I reduced to this?
An embroidered handkerchief.
Look!
A fine piece of work!
Othello is eavesdropping.
Handsome sir, in your abode,
even the angels would lose
their haloes and their veils.
That's the one! That's the one.
It's all over: both love and pain.
No one can stir my soul any more.
(trumpet fanfare)
(cheering and shouting)
(crowd sings anthem)
Long live the Lion of St Mark!
The Doge and the Senate,
greet the triumphant hero of Cyprus.
(fanfare)
I consign into your hands
the Doge's message.
I kiss the symbol...
..of his sovereignty.
(cheering and applause)
I don't see Cassio amongst you.
Othello is angry with him.
I am certain he will soon return to favour.
Are you certain of that?
What are you saying?
He's reading. He is not talking to you.
Maybe he will return to grace.
I hope so.
You know how much affection I have
for Cassio.
Be quiet, devil!
Excuse me, my lord.
Be quiet, you demon!
What my eyes see
cannot be the truth.
Call Cassio.
Watch her when he arrives.
Is this the hero?.
Is this the warrior with the sublime feats?.
He is what he is.
Explain your thoughts.
I better hold my tongue.
Here he is. Search into his soul.
Gentlemen, the Doge...
How well you weep.
..summons me to Venice.
And as my successor in Cyprus,
he appoints Cassio.
- Cassio.
- Hell and damnation!
The Doge's word is our law.
(Othello) I shall obey.
The crew and the troops...
Still weeping?
..the ships and the castle,
I leave in the new leader's hands.
We sail tomorrow.
On your knees...
..and weep!
(crowd murmurs)
On my knees, yes,
in the livid mud,
stricken I lie.
I weep.
The shuddering of my dying spirit
chills me to the bone.
Once on my lips blossomed smiles and kisses.
Now, there's only sorrow on my face
and pain in my heart.
The sun,
serene and bright,
which shines in the sky and on the sea
cannot dry the bitter tears,
the bitter tears of my grief.
- Be gone!
- (crowd shouts)
All of you!
He's lost his senses.
Anyone who stays is my enemy.
(crowd shouts)
My husband!
My beloved!
I curse you!
(shouts of confusion)
I cannot flee from myself.
Vile thoughts!
I see them embrace!
The handkerchief!
The handkerchief! The handkerchief! Aah!
(groans)
(moans softly)
My poison is working.
(crowd) Long live Othello!
The shouts of Victory...
..are his eulogy.
(crowd) Long live Othello!
Who can stop me
from crushing this face under my heel?
(crowd) Long live Othello!
Hail to the Lion of Venice!
Behold the Lion!
(crowd) Long live Othello!
(guffaws)
Emilia, please,
put on the bed my white wedding dress.
Listen,
if I were to die before you,
bury me
in that lace.
Dismiss that thought!
I am so terribly sad.
(wind howling)
(creaking)
Listen! I hear a wailing.
Who's knocking at the door?
It's only the wind.
(creaking and banging)
Farewell, Emilia.
How my eyes burn.
It bodes weeping.
Good night.
Ah, Emilia, farewell!
Farewell, Emilia.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
blessed art thou among women.
Blessed is the fruit of thy womb,
Jesus,
pray for those
who kneel before thee in adoration.
Pray for the sinner
and for the innocent.
Pray for us now.
Pray for us always
and in the hour
of our death.
Pray for us.
Pray.
Ave Maria.
In the hour of our death.
Ave.
Amen.
Othello.
Have you said your prayers?
Why?
Then hurry. I would not kill your soul.
You talk of killing?
Think of your sins.
- My only sin is love.
- For that you die!
You kill me because I love you?
- You love Cassio.
- No, on my soul!
The handkerchief that I gave you,
you gave to him.
- It's not true!
- I saw it in his hand.
- I'm innocent. I swear.
- Beware of perjury.
Help! I don't love Cassio.
Ask him!
He's mute forever.
Heavens!
He's dead?.
Dead.
I'm lost, he was betrayed.
You dare weep for him!
Othello, don't kill me!
You defend yourself in vain.
Have mercy! Let me live!
- Just tonight, another hour, a moment!
- No! No!
- While I say a prayer.
- No! It's too late!
(gasps)
(Othello shudders)
Still
as the grave.
- (Emilia) Open the door! Open the door!
- (knocking)
Who's there?
(Emilia) Open, my lord. I must speak to you.
Open the door!
(banging)
Emilia, what has happened?
A great crime!
Cassio has murdered Rodrigo.
- Cassio lives?
- He lives!
Cassio lives!
(Desdemona) Unjustly...
Unjustly killed.
Who moans here? Horror!
I die innocent.
Oh, dear God. Who has done this?
Nobody.
I, myself.
Commend me
to the Lord.
I die innocent.
Farewell.
She's a liar.
- I killed her!
- Murderer!
- She was Cassio's lover. Ask Jago!
- Ask Jago?
Fool! And you believed him!
Help!
Othello has killed Desdemona!
(exclaiming)
Jago, disprove this vile murderer.
Did you think Desdemona unfaithful?
Speak!
I believed her so.
She gave the handkerchief
I had given her to Cassio.
Oh, heavens!
- Hold your tongue!
- No, I will tell all.
- (Jago) Hold your tongue!
- No!
Jago took the handkerchief from me by force.
And I found it in my room.
Before he died, Rodrigo confessed.
(cries out)
(roars)
(shouts of confusion)
Has heaven no more thunderbolts?.
(shouting)
Have no fear.
Though you see me armed,
this is the end
of my path.
Farewell, Glory!
Othello is no more!
(sword clatters)
And you,
how pale you are
and tired and silent
and how beautiful.
Sweet creature,
born under an evil star.
Cold,
as the chastity of your life.
Already risen to heaven.
Desdemona.
Desdemona...
..is dead, is dead.
Dead.
I have a weapon!
(cries of panic)
Before I killed you,
I kissed you.
Now, before I die,
in the shadow where I lie...
..a kiss.
Another kiss.
One last kiss.
(sobs)
(moans softly)