Essa bola vai rolar
O mundo é um tapete verde
Quando a bola chega lá
Coração fica na rede, na rede, na rede
Hola! Hola!
La la la la la
I dare you
Leggo
Feel how the planet's, Become one
Beats like a drum, To the same rhythm
Hear the whistle, Kick the ball
The entire world, Soars like an eagle
In Rio we play, Like we dance
Only today, There's no tomorrow
Leave all behind, In this place
There's no space, For fear or sorrow
Is it true that you want it
Then act like you mean it
With everyone watching
It's truth or dare can you feel it
La la la la la
I dare you
Leggo
You have arrived, It's the place
No more doubts, The time is coming
Feel how the planet's, Become one
Like a drum, Destiny's calling
German, Colombians, Spanish, and French
Off the bench, You gotta own it
Down here we play, Like we dance
It's Brazil, And now you know it
Is it true that you want it
Then act like you mean it
With everyone watching
It's truth or dare can you feel it
La la la la la
I dare you
Is it true that you want it
Then act like you mean it
The whole world is watching
It's truth or dare can you feel it
Feel it
La la la la la
I dare you
Leggo
www.facebook.com/CaptainFahim