PRODUCED BY JEONWONSA FILM CO.
OUR SUNHI
JUNG YUM
LEE SUNKYUN
KIM SANGJOONG
JUNG JAEYOUNG
YE JI WON
LEE MIN WOO
CINEMATOGRAPHY - PARK HONGYEOL
LIGHTING - YI YUIHEANG
RECORDING - SONG YEAJIN
STILL PHOTOGRAPHY - KIM JINYOUNG
EDITOR - HAHM SUNGWON
MUSIC - JEONG YONG-JUN
SOUND - KIM MIR
PRODUCER - KIM KYOUNGHEE
WRITTEN & DIRECTED
BY HONG SANGSOO
- Sunhi!
- Hi! How've you been?
Hi! It's been so long
since we met.
It has.
I came to meet
Professor Choi Dong-hyun.
- Have you seen him?
- No, I haven't.
He must've stepped out.
His phone's off, too.
Oh! He went on
a business trip abroad.
- I see.
- A few days ago.
When's he coming back?
I'm not sure.
Probably soon.
Let's go. I'll buy you
a cup of coffee.
No, thanks. I'll just go.
I want to ask you something.
Have some coffee, then go.
Ask me what?
I'd better go.
- Don't leave like that.
- I have somewhere to go.
Professor!
- What brings you here?
- Didn't you go abroad?
Me? Why would I?
Sangwoo said you went
on a trip abroad.
- He did?
- Yes.
Why would he?
He was just with me.
Have a seat.
- Anyway, it's good we met.
- I guess.
So, what brings you
out to school?
I was just passing by.
Have you been well?
They said you
went into hiding.
- Who?
- That's what the students say.
Why would I go into hiding?
Because you don't keep
in touch with anyone.
Let's see... 2 years? 1 year?
Has it been a year
since we met?
I did many things.
I've been diligent.
I see.
Actually, I have
a favor to ask.
Could you write me
a reference letter?
- Planning to study abroad?
- Yes, I'm looking into it.
- Where?
- The States.
It'll take at least 3 years
to study abroad.
- You want to go to grad school?
- Yes.
When you come back,
you'll be 31 or 32.
- You want to make films, right?
- Yes, I will eventually.
But now I want to stay
in school more.
I want to study.
Isn't it better to learn from
actually making films?
Though it's hard...
I think you should try
to go all the way.
You think you'll buy time
by going to school and such.
Then, you can make self excuses
not to go all the way.
You find it hard working
with others in productions.
So without results,
you're bound to get weary.
But you can't make films without
working with people, right?
You should keep trying
to work with others.
Come out and
mix with others.
And learn to live along
with them, though it's hard.
Right?
Well, I guess.
But Professor...
It took me long
to decide this
and I've taken
measures already.
It's too late to give up now.
- Really?
- Yes.
Okay. When do
you need it by?
The sooner the better.
Aren't you busy?
No, I'm not busy.
Tomorrow? Tomorrow?
- Come by tomorrow.
- Okay! I can come.
1 o'clock? 2 o'clock?
How about 1 o'clock?
Great. Thank you.
No problem.
But I can't lie.
If you don't like my reference,
you don't have to use it.
I'll just write what I know.
Okay. Thank you very much.
- Hi, Sunhi.
- Why did you lie?
- What?
- Professor Choi went abroad?
Oh, that. Did you meet him?
Why'd you say
he wasn't here?
You're so weird!
I was just joking.
It was for fun.
Why're you yelling?
You think that's funny?
You're weird!
How can you
call that a joke!
I just wanted to
play a joke on you.
I wanted you to laugh.
It's nothing!
How is that nothing!
I was just kidding. Really.
Sunhi, you're so innocent.
I shouldn't joke with you.
I'm not innocent! Stop joking.
No, you are innocent.
The most innocent girl
I've ever seen.
You really are weird.
Just say, you're sorry.
Don't make excuses.
Be honest.
Just apologize to me now!
Fine. I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
May I take your order?
- Just A bottle of beer, please.
- What would You like?
- Anything would be fine.
- Okay.
But we only serve
beer with chicken.
Really?
I'm so full. Can't I
just have the beer?
I'm sorry. You'll have
to order chicken.
Okay, then.
- Taking the subway?
- Yes.
I'm taking the bus.
- Aren't You late for the train?
- Not yet.
- When will You return from Busan?
- Tomorrow night.
Really?
Should I call
even if it's late?
Sure. Let's have
dinner together.
- Yes, sir. Thank you.
- No, I'm the thankful one.
- Have A safe trip.
- Bye.
- Take care.
Bye.
Kim Munsu!
Look! Over here!
Sunhi! What are
you doing there?
Come here!
Come up!
Okay. Sure.
What are you doing?
I got mad over some
crazy guy, so I'm drinking.
It's been so long.
Why'd you come
by the school?
I was Just passing by.
- I saw your film.
- You did?
You shouldn't have.
Didn't you use our
story a bit much?
Is it our story?
- Would You like to order?
- A bottle of Soju.
I'll be right back.
What's with her?
She was really rude
to me before.
What a crazy bitch.
She goes to our school.
Are you drunk?
You didn't drink much.
Are you still in grad school?
Stop studying.
Why're you still there?
I have 1 semester left.
I hate it, too. It seems useless.
You're a director now.
So, why go to school?
Oh, right. With that degree,
you can become a professor.
Maybe.
That's a big maybe.
Why'd you change so much?
Acting so serious after
becoming a director?
Seeing you coming in,
you looked so haughty.
Stop it. It's gross.
No, I'm not.
I looked like that?
It's not the beer talking?
I've never seen a decent man
who changes with little success.
Be yourself.
Don't act so big. Relax.
I didn't become anything.
I made that film with
my money. I spent $10,000.
And hardly anyone
saw my film.
I know.
So, don't change.
People try to
change too much.
What change? When you
don't even know yourself?
So, I want to go somewhere
else after I finish school.
People in film aren't normal.
They're all crazy.
Stop making excuses
and focus on one thing.
Going to school or running away,
they're all excuses.
Keep at it all the way.
Then, you'll know your limits
and find out who you are.
Here you are.
Let's drink together.
Anyway, I'm glad to see you.
When I see you,
I always drink.
You make me want to drink.
I do?
I really missed you.
- We drank too much.
- I really missed you.
You're lucky to see me.
- You saw my film, right?
- Yes. It was okay.
You...
You're the topic of my life.
If I... make films till I die,
they'll all be about you.
All my films are
about you. You know?
Why am I a topic?
Why did we break up?
Tell me. Why did
we break up then?
- Later. I'll tell you later.
- Later? Again?
Why?
You know how hard it's been?
What are you waiting for?
It's hard for me, too.
I'll tell you later
when the time comes.
Sunhi.
Look at me.
I really like you.
Do you know that?
Do you?
Why don't you know that?
Why?
I can't explain my feelings.
- I'm weird, right?
- No.
You're so pretty.
In all my life... you're
the one I like the most.
Really!
I'd better go.
Don't go.
Sorry, I have to go.
Where?
I have to go somewhere.
Don't leave like that!
Oh, the old days of playing
merrily in my hometown
How we whispered love
under the tranquil moonlight
Where have you gone?
Were you only a dream?
In my old hometown,
only the grass has grown green
In the beloved hometown,
you and I were innocent and young
We held hands and promised
to never change
Where have you gone leaving
me unforgettable memories?
In the beloved hometown,
now only the moonlight shines on me
Jaehak!
- What are You doing there?
- Hi!
I just came to see you.
What are you doing?
Just something.
I wanted to see you.
Should I come up?
But I was in the
middle of something.
- You Have to do something?
- Yes.
What? Will it take long?
I'm not sure.
You really came to see me?
Yes, I have something
to ask you.
Can you come out
for a second?
You're noisy.
There are people.
What?
Then...
Wait around. It'll take
me an hour or two.
- You know, 'Arirang'?
- Yes.
- Wait for me there?
- Okay, then.
I'll wait for you!
Annoying fool.
Why's he bothering me! Damn!
CAFE ARIRANG
- Here. Have some.
- Thanks.
What's taking him so long?
- His phone's turned off, too.
- I don't know.
Are you hungry? I know
a great chicken place.
- Really?
- It's very good.
Well, if you want,
you can order it.
- Should I?
- Yes.
- Then, I'll order.
- Sure.
- Hi!
- Waited long?
It's okay. I just wanted
to have a few drinks.
You drank a lot.
Something wrong?
Jaehak!
I really, really missed you!
You know I really
like you, right?
Thanks.
You really know?
Sure you're okay?
Things are hard these days.
What's so hard?
I just have a lot on
my mind these days.
- You came?
- Hi.
- What'll it be? Soju?
- Just A cup.
- We ordered chicken.
- Good idea.
- Wasn't it?
- Yes.
The chicken must
be really good.
It's very fresh.
And very crispy.
And it's less oily.
Are you sick these days?
You don't look well.
Well, sort of. But I
just don't feel right.
I saw Sunhi.
She came to me.
So, I drank today.
Oh, really?
I heard she disappeared
and couldn't be reached.
She came to see you?
She came to the school.
She's still as pretty as ever.
Really?
To me... she is really,
really pretty.
I can't help it.
Here you are.
Soju?
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
- Munsu.
- Yes?
Women shouldn't
be held back.
You think I held her back?
No, I didn't.
I just liked her.
Women are more
realistic than men.
We should respect
their judgment.
Men just fall for anyone.
And too emotional.
But women are different.
Women are far better than men.
Don't try to hold her back.
If she wants to go,
then let her.
That's good for
both of you.
But Sunhi came to me.
That means she is still
thinking about us.
So, just go with
what she decides.
Don't try so hard.
Don't ever overdo it.
But I should try
hard to know!
If I don't do anything, I won't
know what's really good!
I guess.
I have to dig all the way...
I have to dig all the
way to get there.
I have to dig all the way and go
to find out about myself.
- Right?
- Look.
Digging all the
way and going...
- Digging and going...
- I get it.
- No!
- Okay, I get it.
- Listen to me!
- I get it!
- Just listen to me!
You have to dig all
the way to know.
Then, I can go and
know what's important.
I'll realize what's good.
Fine. Digging all the way is good,
but you won't find what you want.
You'll just learn what you can't do.
You'll know your limits.
Then, you'll know
who you are.
Really?
There are a million things
you want. Right?
And it changes every day?
Anyone can imagine
what they can be.
Knowing what You can't do...
that's how you know who you are.
Do you really think that?
Of course I do...
Didn't I tell you this before?
I thought I did.
Didn't I?
I told you this before.
What are you talking about?
Trying to put me down?
No, I'm not. I'm just saying.
Forget it, then.
Don't stare at me.
Yes, don't stare like that.
Don't get angry.
He's trying to give
you advice. Right?
Right.
Be happy drinking.
Are you avoiding
me these days?
No.
Well, you never answer
my calls these days.
And come out late like this.
Before, you used to...
call me often.
But you never call me now!
Why?
I didn't?
You could've felt that way.
I'll tell you later.
See? Even now!
You're saying crazy things
to me, now! To me!
I'll think it over.
Then, I'll tell you later.
Tell me what!
You're making me curious.
It's something important.
I'll think it over more,
then tell you.
Man, I'm so curious.
Really...
What are you
thinking about me?
Later!
I'll tell you.
- How about some music?
- Sure.
I waited 3 hours.
Hey.
I heard this song.
Just before.
Okay, pal.
- I'm serious.
- Okay.
- Hello.
- Hi, Sunhi.
- Sit down.
- Okay.
- I printed 3 reference letters.
- Thank you.
See if it's okay. If you
don't like it, don't use it.
No, I'll use it. Thank you.
- You even signed it?
- Of course.
- You can read English, right?
- Yes.
This is wine.
You didn't have to.
I'll enjoy it.
- I'll try my best.
- That's good. Good luck.
One copy is mine.
Wui Sunhi was a film
student in my courses.
She is reserved and rarely
expresses herself.
So, she had difficulty
getting others
to cooperate in her works.
She seems ambitious, but
lacks courage to take action.
She is smart and has
a great grasp on films.
She has artistic sense.
With chance,
she'll get stronger
and may show
her hidden talents.
I suspect she has some talent,
but I couldn't verify it.
I hope her experience at your
school will be that chance.
She tries to be honest and
has an ideally innocent side.
Thank you for reading this.
Hello?
It's Sunhi.
Are you okay to talk?
Sure. It's fine.
I read your reference letter.
Is it okay to write it like this?
Why? What's wrong?
You don't like it?
It says things like
I'm reserved. Is that okay?
That's better, silly. It seems
more honest and good.
They regard it more
highly like that abroad.
I've written many references.
But it makes me seem
like a weak person.
It doesn't say
what I want to do.
I wrote what I
felt about you.
What do you
want me to do?
Can you spare me a moment?
Can we discuss this in person?
I'd like to ask you
something, too.
Really?
Fine, then.
Come to my room.
I'd like to treat
you to lunch.
How about your
favorite place? 'The Sun'?
Okay, I'll be right there.
Thank you.
KOREAN CUISINE
Professor.
Am I really that reserved?
Yes, You are. But sometimes you
seem odd, and sometimes brave.
- I'm brave?
- Yes, because You are honest.
Then, why'd you say
I can't express myself?
What? Did I?
I told you I wrote
it in 30 minutes.
You said, I lack courage,
but now you say I'm brave!
You remember
everything I wrote?
And... I seem too ambitious?
You have hidden ambitions.
Doesn't everybody?
That's true, but
aren't you different?
I'm not different!
I'm just the same.
Right. But I said
some good things.
I guess.
You said, I was good.
I have artistic sense.
And I'm idealistic.
You do have artistic
sense and you're good.
I'm not good.
Really?
You want me to give
it more thought, right?
Yes. Just 30 minutes
more, please?
Fine. I'll think 1 more hour.
But will that bring
out anything else?
I don't know.
Right. You don't.
You used to like me.
So, I came to you.
But why're you so cold?
Right. You're my
favorite student.
- That's right.
- But you were cold.
Though I liked you,
you never called me.
You never call, do you?
Remember when
you held my hand?
No.
In the winter, we met
outside the library.
You pretended to give me a High 5,
then grabbed my hand.
You don't remember?
You squeezed it
hard like this.
- Don't you remember?
- Oh, right. I did.
Because I liked you.
Did you do that
to the other girls?
No. Just you.
Why?
Because I wanted
to be with you.
Really?
Because I wanted to be
on your side forever.
What a comment.
Want me to be on
your side for life?
Should I?
Yes.
I'd like that.
Thanks.
I'm the thankful one.
Have a drink.
When do you need
the reference letter?
The sooner the better.
Thank you.
Jaehak!
What are you doing here?
Just passing by.
Are you busy?
Not really.
Really? Then,
should I come up?
No.
Wait for me at Cafe Gondry
down the street?
- Cafe Gondry?
- Yes.
Okay, then.
Why didn't you
call beforehand?
Aren't you moving back in?
How long will you live there?
I don't know. They raised the rent,
so I might move to West Village.
- West Village?
- Yes.
That place was really nice.
Isn't the sunrise
beautiful from up there?
Yes, but they want $200 more
from when you lived there.
Why aren't you going home?
Doesn't your wife say anything?
I feel bad, but...
I went there last month.
You did?
I'm sorry to keep asking.
But why'd you leave home?
Let's not talk about that.
I'm curious. Why'd you leave
your lovely wife to live out alone?
Let's just drop it. That's
my business to handle.
Your wife is amazing.
I feel sorry...
But I can't help it.
Still, sometimes I envy you.
You?
- Why would You envy me?
- You live so freely.
I like how you live true
to your feelings.
It's weird to hear you
say that to me.
I'd love to live like you.
Really? You think that?
Of course! I'm a man, too.
I'd love to live freely.
I see.
There's a famous quote...
'Sooner strangle
an infant in its cradle
than nurse unacted love'.
I think it's great how you
live true to your emotions.
You're great.
What's with you today?
I've never heard you
say things like that.
Hey.
Did something happen?
Yes.
I met up with a girl again.
I can't take my mind off her.
Really? Who?
WOW!
This is really amusing.
I don't want to say who it is.
Who is she?
Ordinary and a bit young.
- How young?
- She's Just A lot younger.
This is so shocking!
I can't believe I'm
hearing this from you!
You like seeing me like this?
It's amusing! It's great.
If you like her, it's great.
I'm not dating her yet.
She's just a young
woman I cherish.
- Something like that.
- Really?
Even now, she makes
my heart throb.
As I thought of her this morning,
my heart started pounding.
But I loved that feeling.
I almost forgot how that felt.
It's been so long.
It's a good thing.
- Is it?
- Of course it is.
Tell me more about her.
She's good. She's reserved,
has artistic sense, and is smart.
Sometimes she seems odd.
But she's great.
Great.
- You like someone like that?
- Yes.
I've met a lot of people.
I'm sick of girls who act
innocent and quiet.
But she's brave.
Do you want to get a beer?
I do, but I have to meet
some professors.
I'd love to drink.
Let's have some next time.
Okay. But I need
a beer now.
Hello?
Director!
- Sir!
- Sunhi!
What are you doing there?
- Hello.
- It's been A long time.
Yes, it has.
I stopped for some
good coffee here.
But here you are.
- Well, I live Here.
- Right.
- You've lost weight.
- No, I'm the same.
- You look skinnier.
- I'm the same, too.
- Drinking coffee?
- Yes.
I'll order one, too.
Did you eat?
Yes, I ate. Will You
buy me drinks?
Really? Then, let's go now.
We don't need coffee.
Okay.
You lost so much weight.
- Did You pay for the coffee?
- Yes.
CAFE ARIRANG
Cheers.
Do you like chicken?
I know a good chicken place.
- Want to try it?
- Sure. Thank you.
Sunhi, you're so pretty.
You have a beautiful face.
You look great, too.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I'll order the chicken.
- Okay.
- We're ordering chicken.
- Great! Order it.
- Then, I'll go order.
- Order it.
She loves anything
with chicken in it.
Really?
When I met Munsu here
before, we had chicken, too.
- You met Munsu?
- Yes, he said he met you.
Really? We met by chance.
Really? He said
you came to him.
Crazy fool. That's nonsense.
We met by chance.
Okay, then.
Anyway, it looks like he
is still in love with you.
He said his feelings for you
didn't change at all.
Well, so what?
He's a good guy.
He's manly. And nice.
I'm not going to
date men anymore.
- Really?
- Yes.
I just want to study.
Or else...
I'll give up everything and
just move to the country.
- To your mother?
- Yes.
Then, what?
I just want to be alone.
Should I try farming?
You? Farming?
That's funny.
You can't farm.
Then, what?
What should I do?
Look. I think
they're all excuses.
Studying? That's
all an excuse.
- Really?
- Yes.
- An excuse?
- That's what I think.
Just do what you like doing.
You want to make
films, right?
So, you wrote
scripts and such.
Then, just keep doing
what you like to do.
Dig deep while you can.
Before you get older.
When you have strength.
Keep at it all the way.
To the end.
Dig all the way
to see your limits.
Then, it's comforting.
And you'll find out who
you are. That's the best.
I've heard that before.
You have?
Yes, I have. But I have no
luck when I really need it.
You really know
what I'm saying?
I know.
I used to take in
every word you said.
Now, it goes in one ear
and out the other.
It's no use at all.
People need luck.
- Luck is the best.
- Right.
But you're wrong.
Don't say things like that.
Why' re you so cold to me?
Because I met Munsu?
Why would I be?
You like me seeing Munsu?
No.
I'd rather you don't
meet him. But...
I have no right to
say that. Right?
I don't have to date men.
I don't need them.
The only thing
that's important...
What's really important
is knowing who I am.
You're good.
You're a little reserved.
But you're smart.
You have great artistic sense.
You're a little odd.
But that also means
you're brave. Right?
I'm brave?
Yes.
And you're the prettiest
girl I've ever met.
Really?
Yes.
Believe me.
I want to believe.
You're lovely.
It's good to see you again.
Me, too.
You scare me.
Sometimes you really do.
Though it gets hard...
just don't do anything
to stand in shame.
You're so lovely.
Sometimes you're very lovely.
Lovely.
I feel the same.
So lovely.
Oh, the old days of playing
merrily in my hometown
How we whispered love
under the tranquil moonlight
Where have you gone?
Were you only a dream?
In my old hometown,
only the grass has grown green
Chicken delivery.
Hello. Here you are.
- Thank you. Bye.
- Enjoy.
Thanks. The chicken is here!
Have some.
It looks so good.
It looks delicious!
You want to do it?
Yes.
I'm not really drunk.
Go in.
You sure?
I'll see you go, then leave.
- No, I'll see you off.
- No.
You go in.
Then, take this with you.
I'm going in.
We still have lots of time.
Right.
CHANGGYEONG PALACE
Wui Sunhi's works
in my workshops...
were strong, experimental pieces
far from existing narratives.
They were beautiful pieces
that overcame...
The typical trap of
self-absorbed expressions.
Free from the constraints
of certainty...
there were poetic messages
effectively expressed within.
Seeing her amazing achievements
at a young age...
she made me realize the joy
of teaching as her professor.
She has a calm personality
and a meticulous mind.
She is persistent yet not
fallen to self-assertion.
Although a quiet way
of communicating...
I've witnessed her success
in sharing opinions.
She has innocence and
honesty of the ideal person.
It's hard to imagine
a person of
such integrity and
talents will fail.
I hope the school's
excellent programs
will have great effects on her.
- Hi.
- Busy?
I'm just at a palace.
- Which one?
- No need to know.
- Are you with someone?
- Yes, someone.
Are you at Changgyeong Palace?
How did you know?
Well, I just thought
you'd go there.
Really? Why?
You don't like crowded places.
You're good.
Can we meet?
Sorry, I'm busy.
There's something
I have to tell you.
Tell me now.
Let's have drinks.
I'll tell you then.
I already drank too much.
Really?
- It's because of you.
- Me? Why?
Anyway, I'm not
drinking anymore.
Let's just meet up.
I'll call you in the
evening if I can.
Let's come to our senses.
- Will you help me?
- Of course.
Let's really do it.
I just need to see you.
I don't need anything else.
- Okay. I'd better go.
- Sunhi! I really want to see you.
- Okay. I'm hanging up.
- Call me.
- Jaehak?
- How've you been?
Good. Why did you call?
What are you doing?
Enjoying a taste of autumn.
- Really? Where are you?
- Changgyeong Palace.
Really? What brings you
to a place like that?
I wanted to feel autumn's breeze
before the seasons change.
- Is it nice there?
- Yes. it's quiet and nice.
Really?
Should I go, too?
Ah, no. I'm with
someone right now.
Really? Who?
I'd rather not say.
You really are with someone?
- Is it the girl?
- What?
No need to know.
You're really up to
trouble, aren't you?
I'm not up to any trouble.
What are You up to?
Nothing. We promised to have
drinks. I feel like drinking today.
Really? So early in the day?
Did something bad happen?
Just a little down today.
Let's have drinks.
I'm sorry. I can't
today. I'm sorry.
You really are up to
trouble! Lucky you!
- I'm not up to trouble.
- Must be nice.
Okay, then. Have fun.
I'd better go drink.
Have a drink. I'll call
you later if I can.
- Okay. Call me.
- Okay.
- I feel like drinking.
- Really?
How about a drink?
- I need to pass.
- Really? Not feeling well?
- I overdrank.
- Okay, then.
I read the reference letter.
You wrote about me so well.
You complimented me so
much, I'm embarrassed.
Don't use it if you
don't want to.
I'm sorry you wrote it twice.
No need. I wrote
that in 30 minutes.
I could express you
better by rewriting it.
I rushed the first one.
So, is this similar
to who I really am?
This is the real you.
The more you think,
the more you see.
Right.
I wish I can be
like this forever.
Like what you wrote here.
This is you.
Okay.
I'll believe you, take
courage, and study hard.
Good. Do your best.
If I get to go abroad,
I'm going to dig deep.
Great. Dig deep till
you see the end.
I will.
If I dig deeper,
I'll find out who I am.
Then, I'll feel better no
matter what I find out.
Good. I told you
before to dig deep.
Did you?
Of course, I did.
I said to dig deep.
- Well, maybe you did.
- Silly. I said that to you.
Right. You did.
I know you'll do well.
I believe it.
- I want to believe it.
- Good.
Wow! Do it again.
It bounced back.
Let me try.
- This isn't easy.
- Let me try again.
No, I'll try again.
You try. How can
you throw so well?
One more time.
- I need to use the restroom.
- Really? It's over there.
- I'll be right back.
- Sure.
Hi.
What?
Why'd you come here?
I came because
you said it's nice.
I haven't been
here in a while.
Why didn't you call
before you come?
Are you alone? Why?
You silly fool. You should've
called me before.
I came for sightseeing. I'll go.
- What are You so scared of?
- Why would I be scared?
Jaehak!
- Professor?
- Hi.
- Hi, Munsu.
- What brings You here?
What are you
two doing here?
Why'd you come here?
I just came to see Sunhi.
- Sunhi?
- Yes. Sunhi said she's here.
Sunhi's here? Really?
- You came to see Sunhi?
- Yes. Did you see her by chance?
We didn't see her.
What are you doing
here, Professor?
- You came for the autumn leaves?
- Yes. it seems so.
It's really nice here. I haven't
been here in a while.
- It's nice.
- Yes, it's really nice.
I'm going to the bathroom.
You two stay here.
- I need to go, too.
- I was going to go, too.
- Let's go together.
- Okay.
- Professor? Let's go.
- Sure.
Jaehak and Munsu came.
You go ahead first.
I'll call you later.
- Let's go This way.
- Okay.
I don't see Sunhi around.
- Have you dated Sunhi long?
- Yes.
But she's making
things hard.
Why?
She is kind of reserved,
so she doesn't open up.
We've been together long, but
I don't know how she feels.
- I see.
- Yes.
Why date her
when it's so hard?
But she's also really smart.
I know. She is smart.
She's smart and
has artistic sense.
- You know, too?
- I know her. She's my junior.
Right. She's cute
and a little odd.
She's honest
and really brave.
Right. I think so, too.
I guess people see
things the same.
Right.
But I don't know
what she is thinking.
Really?
Where'd she go?
Try calling her.
I just did, but
her phone is off.
I hope she won't hide again.
- She Just got back.
- Really?
She tends to disappear.
Sometimes she can't
be reached for years.
- She can't do it again.
- I see.
People live the
way they please.
Right. There's nothing
much others can do.
Right.