Our Children
You'll bury them in Morocco?
We'll see what we can do.
You have to tell their father.
You have to tell Mounir.
You have to bury them...
You have to bury them in Morocco.
- I have to get rid of the sand for him.
- Don't worry.
- What?
- I just...
Are you OK?
I want to marry you.
- What did you say?
- You heard.
- You heard me, right?
No, I didn't hear.
I want to spend my life with you.
- There's no bread?
- Bread? Just a second.
After you.
- See you next week.
- Thank you.
Drive safely.
How are you lovebirds?
- Good evening, sir.
- Call me André.
I've heard a lot about you.
How about that?
- You've cooked?
- I asked Mounir what you'd like.
He told you I liked lasagne?
He's too much.
Lasagne is his favourite dish.
You've got a nerve!
- You do like lasagne, though?
- You bet I do.
When it's made with love.
But I just had an urgent call.
I need to see a patient.
- So I can't...
- Can't it wait? We just...
I already had a bite to eat. I'm sorry.
- You won't hold it against me?
- No.
If he's any trouble, call me.
I'm sorry.
Be good.
Mounir, where are the keys?
It's OK, I've got them.
I'm OK, it's just...
- We do all this and he just leaves.
- It doesn't matter.
Next time.
"A crocodile in the city sewers."
- Yes?
- I think that's non-verbal.
That's right.
And how do we modify it?
- "A crocodile is in the city sewers."
- Great, Celine.
Now...
"There has been an earthquake
in France."
A verbal or non-verbal phrase?
Margaux?
- A verbal phrase.
- How do we make it a non-verbal one?
"Earthquake in France."
The concentration is easy.
- It's matter divided by...
- I don't care!
I don't care any more.
I'll never manage it in a week anyway.
You don't want to end up
working at the practice with me.
Why not? Would that bother you?
Right.
I'll do it for you.
But reread it or you'll look stupid.
Surely you expected it?
My internship report was good.
Yes, you did a good internship.
But let's face it,
the skills just aren't there.
It's no big deal.
I'm sick of it. I quit.
- I want to earn a living now.
- Be a youth worker again.
- I'm not baby-sitting all my life!
- You get on so well with kids.
- I'm sure you could do it.
- Not for such crap pay.
My offer still stands anyhow.
What offer?
I've needed someone
at the practice for months.
You mean...
Mounir could work with you?
Part time?
No. Full time.
He can start tomorrow if he wants.
That's great, isn't it?
I don't know about him,
but I'd like that.
I think...
- I think I want to marry her.
- Hold on, Mounir.
No, I'm serious, I swear.
Being in love is no reason
to marry the first girl who blows you.
Stop it, André.
It's not the same thing, there's...
A difference in cultures
is never easy to deal with.
I know. But you and I get along.
It's not the same.
- It is the same.
- Cut it out.
You do like her, don't you?
- Want one?
- No, thanks.
I've never seen Mounir like this.
I know he'd never dare to ask me,
but I get the impression
he'd like you to live with us.
So if you want to move in,
that's fine by me.
But... Didn't he tell you?
No. What?
Mounir's pretty independent.
Besides...
It would make me happy too.
What's up?
- Am I disturbing you?
- Let us have our little secrets.
- Are you OK?
- I'm fine.
Just a second, André.
- We have something to tell you.
- You do?
Shall I?
Alright, André,
we wanted to ask you
if you'd be the witness
at our wedding.
That's wonderful. Excuse me.
Congratulations. Of course.
Have you set a date?
Maybe this summer
but nothing's final yet.
Will you have a little trip?
We talked about it, but we'll wait.
- Not right away.
- Why not?
Because we need to save up for it.
That can be my wedding present,
your honeymoon trip.
- That's too much.
- Why? It's my present, period.
That's quite a present!
- Let's have a drink to celebrate.
- Yes.
I'll be right back.
We accept, but only if you come too.
Where?
- On our honeymoon.
- You're crazy!
Why am I crazy?
- You're kidding.
- Not at all.
We'll only accept if you come too.
In that case, of course I accept.
It'll do you good too.
Here's to the two of you.
To your future.
To us. To everything.
Cheers.
Francoise.
- Francoise!
- Coming.
Well?
- Is my hair OK?
- You look fabulous!
It's pretty cushy here.
- What do you mean by that?
- Nothing.
The doctor coughs up for it?
You have a real problem with that.
It's true.
- Can't I have a laugh any more?
- Cut it out now.
You're jealous, are you?
No one's forcing you to stay, OK?
Nice!
You could've told Mum, at least.
- Thank you, my daughter.
- She's thanking you.
You're beautiful. Very beautiful.
And you'll have
very beautiful children, inch'Allah!
She says you're beautiful
and that you'll have
very beautiful children with Mounir.
She says that about me too.
Don't you, Mum?
You say that about me too.
Of course, my daughter!
I'm the only one left then?
We'll work something out.
My neighbour is afraid.
She's hesitating
and wants more money.
- How much does she want?
- 100,000.
Can you imagine?
For three trips to the town hall.
What are you talking about?
We're looking for someone for Samir.
Enough! Stop talking about it!
Are you serious? It's easy for you.
Don't start.
Cut it out. You're brothers.
Calm down, you!
Samir wants to get married?
Yes and no. He has to find someone
to get his papers.
I was the same.
Without André,
I'd still be stuck back there.
- He helped you?
- Yes, we're married.
But it's hard for Samir now
because people are more wary.
It makes it harder.
It's a little tougher.
For us, it's not just about the papers?
Murielle, it's not the same.
You two are in love.
Excuse me!
Why do you shame me like this?
- It's easy for you.
- Like I told you, be patient.
It's easy for you.
I'll die back in the village.
You and Fatima...
Poor things, you act innocent.
You don't give a damn!
When you're with the doctor,
you always show off.
Why did he take you?
I don't know. I didn't choose!
- Why you and not me?
- I don't know.
He married Fatima,
took you with him and left me.
I don't exist!
Just be patient
and it'll all work out.
Besides, everyone knows.
Knows what?
People talk.
About me?
You and the doctor.
What do they say?
They never stop.
They say, "See what's happening
with that dumb doctor?"
"He took your sister and your brother."
Don't I exist?
I'm sick of it, sick of them!
- And you believe them?
- I'm sick of the village.
Mounir, Samir, what's going on?
- I'll tell you something...
- You're mad today!
You just have to ask for something
and he gives it to you!
That's not the problem!
When he talks about you,
it's like he's talking about his woman!
For God's sake!
- The way you talk! Shut your mouth!
- Mounir, just go!
- Tell him to shut up!
- Samir, cut it out.
- Enough.
- Come on, let's go back.
- My little shark!
- You're the shark.
Dr Pinget's office.
Yes, I'm just filling them out.
They'll be in this evening's mail.
With the certificates, of course.
I'll ask him to call when he gets in.
Very good.
Goodbye, Mr Hénard.
- He was moving all day.
- Moving?
- Come with me.
- I just came to give you a kiss.
Here. Come on...
Put your hand here.
- Shit!
- Did you feel that?
It's crazy!
How's it going, sonny?
It's not necessarily a boy.
- What?
- It might not be a boy.
It's a boy, alright.
See how he moves?
- Feel that?
- Yes.
Don't mind me.
If you put it like this,
you'll hear better.
Well?
When are you seeing Lefévre again?
I have an ultrasound next week.
Mounir... Phone.
- Are you OK?
- Yes.
A little bleeding. Is that normal?
A little brownish?
Don't worry, it'll pass.
He just moved.
- She's cute, isn't she?
- You bet.
Alright.
This calls for a little present.
Thank you.
- You like it?
- Yes! You shouldn't have.
And for your little treasure...
She's sleeping. I won't wake her.
Give it to her later.
- Look at this, baby.
- What is it?
- Look... It's her bracelet.
- That's so cute.
Thank you, André.
With this, her dad
won't be late for work
if he spends too much time with her.
- Thank you, André.
- No.
- The same as yours!
- Don't thank me.
The best gift is her!
- It's beautiful.
- I'll leave you now.
- Goodbye.
- Thank you, André.
See you tonight.
This is a fancy one.
Seen it, sweetheart?
Can you put the necklace on for me?
- Can you manage?
- Lift your hair.
Don't rock her all night,
you'll be exhausted.
- I don't know what's wrong.
- Let me try.
- Is this OK?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- Go on!
- Go on, Jade!
Head up the hill!
- Faster!
- Just a few more metres!
Excellent!
- Coming back?
- Go and see Mum. A kiss first.
Back to Mummy now.
What do you want?
Want to see the baby?
You want to see him?
You won't see him there.
Baby?
Where is he?
- He's here. You saw him?
- Yes.
Really? Come and see!
What's he doing? Is he hiding?
Look, this is Sohane,
your little sister.
Well?
You're already jealous?
You are. It's alright.
Mummy loves you too.
Mummy's with Sohane now.
- Daddy?
- A hen.
- Can you give it to her?
- Sure.
- Let's go.
- No.
Yes.
Mummy's coming back.
That's so good.
One for Daddy.
Get to sleep now, girls.
Murielle!
Coming.
One always wakes the other.
- Wait.
- What?
- The girls.
- They'll go to sleep.
Stop it!
Not here!
Stop it, Mounir!
- Not here!
- Why not?
- Not in André's room.
- Who cares?
Stop it, OK!
Stop it!
Not in André's room!
Can you watch Jade?
I won't be long.
See you later, sweetheart.
Got a kiss for me?
Be good with Daddy. Bye.
See you later.
Mummy!
What's wrong, my baby? What is it?
What happened, my love?
What have you done?
What happened?
What happened, my love?
- It's nothing.
- Go for an X-ray at the hospital.
Go for an X-ray right away.
I'll look after the baby.
- Where are the car keys?
- On the desk, to the left, I think.
- I keep telling you to close the gate.
- I know.
For six months, I've been saying
she could have a fall!
- I know!
- So why don't you close it?
I'm sorry, I thought you...
You thought what? Look at this.
Maybe she's cracked her skull!
- Mummy?
- Yes, sweetheart?
- Daddy?
- I'm sorry.
- Yes.
Daddy's driving
to check everything's OK.
How many steps did she fall?
About ten.
Five or six. Five or six of them.
- How many bumps did you hear?
- At least two.
- Has she been sick? Lost consciousness?
- No.
- How did it happen?
- Here.
Thank you.
I went out
and I forgot to close the gate.
I should have checked.
It's all my fault.
- Oh, sweetheart!
- It happens every day.
It's nothing. She's fine.
I see loads of kids
who've fallen down the stairs.
Even my son fell once. She's fine.
Just keep an eye on her.
If she's sick or loses consciousness
and is apathetic, come back.
But it should be OK.
- Thank you, doctor.
- You're welcome.
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
- Say goodbye.
- Goodbye, Jade.
Forgive me for blowing my top.
I'm sorry.
When I saw her like that...
It's nothing.
It doesn't matter.
- Yes, Helene.
- “Michel lends his book."
"His book", direct object,
"to his neighbour", indirect.
Why? Who can tell me?
- Yes?
- Indirect tells us to whom or to what.
- And the direct who and what.
- Very good.
You can do
the exercises I gave you now.
Ma'am, is your baby a girl or a boy?
I don't know. It's a surprise.
It's time to sleep now, Jade.
Mummy will be back tomorrow
with your little sister.
So have a big sleep now, OK?
- Good night.
- Good night, sweetheart.
You go to sleep too now.
- You left the nightlight on?
- Yes.
Well, then...
To Malika!
What about your office?
- Do you like it?
- It's beautiful.
- I love the colour.
- That's your sister's.
Put it down.
Want to give it to her?
Can you put Malika down?
Put her with her toys.
Look at this!
Gently, girls. So, have you seen?
Can you put Malika down?
I'll give her the toy.
- Careful, she's sleeping.
- Careful with the baby.
Gently.
Put it under her arm.
- We'll put it here for her.
- Gently.
Seen this?
- You three will be fine here.
- Mummy, look.
Have you called Mum?
- You spoke to her?
- What can I tell her?
You're not mad at me?
Are you managing?
I'm doing OK.
- Francoise!
- André.
It's been a while. How are you?
- Would you like a drink?
- I'd love one.
- You know how to live, André.
- I do.
If you want to go out one night,
call me.
You do go out now and then?
You don't just see my sister?
You have affairs?
You don't have any flings?
A man like you, if he wanted...
Excuse me.
- What's got into you?
- Can't we have a laugh any more?
Don't scowl like that!
Mummy, it's not working!
Jade.
What are you doing? Always ask me
to put a tape in for you.
Dad'll mend it. Go and play now.
Don't touch the video player! Stop it!
- Go and draw.
- It's stuck.
I know. You could hurt yourself.
Off you go! Don't touch it again.
I'm coming, my baby.
What's up?
Sohane, not on the table!
Like this.
Put another tape in!
Can you take her?
I don't know why
but the girls are terrible today.
I heard it was pretty busy here.
It's got them wound up.
Your sister turns up unannounced,
smokes in front of them...
If André has something to say,
he can say it to my face.
This is still his home, remember.
I don't want your sister here again!
If you're exhausted, take a break.
Go to Morocco for ten days
to see your mother.
Maybe.
Murielle's really tired.
I swear, André, she's not well.
I can't leave her with the kids.
Murielle's tired, so what?
Tell her your mother's sick
and you need to see her. It's not a lie.
Besides, I'll be here.
Good night.
Look at the little fish here.
- Those are little fish?
- Yes, of course they are.
Don't you recognise them?
Go on, you try.
Show me how to do a little fish.
- Is that it?
- That's the idea.
Going to try something else?
That looks kind of like a boat.
- Here's Mummy.
- We'll do the same again.
We've been very good.
- We've been good, haven't we?
- Yes.
They're not the same.
Mounir called.
He's staying another week.
His mother's still not well.
He sends his love.
- What are you doing?
- I want to take my shoes off.
You've done a drawing?
- Show me.
- No, it's for Godfather.
Thank you.
Very beautiful.
- I didn't sign it.
- She didn't sign it.
I didn't sign there either.
You'll have to sign both of them then.
Look, Daddy's here.
How are you?
You look well.
- What's she crying for?
- I think she's hungry.
Come on, give me a kiss.
Come here, you.
Come here, Sohane.
- They've missed you.
- It doesn't look like it.
Thanks.
- Shit!
- Look, it's broken again.
Jade.
If it's broken,
play with something else instead.
Now let me watch the football, OK?
- It's broken again, Daddy.
- What did I tell you?
If it's broken, pick another toy!
- What's going on?
- She broke her toy.
Why aren't they in bed?
I was seeing to Malika.
Surely you can play with your daughter.
Don't tell me what to do!
- Alright, girls.
- Calm down, will you?
I got here five minutes ago
and my head's already throbbing.
I get back and she nags me
about a pony!
They want to play with you.
They want what?
They have plenty of toys!
It's no good, we're on top
of each other all the time.
With our two salaries, we could...
We could find another place.
Don't you think?
Murielle?
We could live in Morocco.
Why?
For them.
I don't know.
Why not?
You're right. We need to leave.
We'll think of something.
You don't fancy Morocco?
Yes, you bet I do.
- André, can I have a word?
- Of course.
Listen, Murielle and I
keep arguing all the time.
With the kids around,
it's not easy, you understand?
If you think this place is too small,
we'll look for somewhere else.
We were thinking it might
be worth trying to live in Morocco.
Life is cheaper there.
And we'd be out of your way.
You do so much, but you don't have to.
It's getting tough with the girls.
You understand?
Yes, that's great.
Morocco is great.
But don't count on me
for anything ever again, understand?
We're through.
André, wait.
- Don't react like that.
- How should I react?
I bleed myself dry for you for 20 years
and this is the thanks I get?
Don't you think I might be sick of it,
that I'd like to leave too?
That I'm sick of taking care
of you and your tribe?
You have a problem with Murielle
and you solve it by dumping me
and then taking off!
I never talked about dumping you!
You're crazy to think that. Hold on.
I didn't say that!
I have a wife and kids.
I want them to know their grandmother.
- And Morocco is my country too.
- "Morocco is my country."
What has your country done for you?
What has your family done for you?
Your mother was happy
to let me take you away.
My mother was happy but you, too,
were happy to bring me here.
- Leave my mother out of it. Stop it.
- OK, I'll stop!
Get out, all of you. Get out of here!
I don't need anyone.
Are the girls asleep?
Yes, for now.
I've been thinking about Morocco.
Maybe it's not a good idea.
Think of the girls.
It won't be easy for them.
- You told him then?
- Who?
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
I've just been thinking.
Besides, what'll I do there?
I won't find work.
Of course you'll find work.
And we won't need two salaries there.
You yourself said it was better
for the girls!
The thing is, I want my own place
where I can say what I want.
Come on, it's not so bad here.
We don't lack anything.
Yeah, we don't lack anything.
I can't do that to him.
What are you saying?
We can live as a family, can't we?
You wanted space, a garden.
We'll find that.
We'll find that? Who's we?
- We're buying a house with him?
- No.
He's buying a house with us.
But I'm not married to him!
You're my children's father.
I want to live with you.
You'll live with me.
The house will be ours.
He'll just have a room or two.
We've always found a solution.
We'll find one this time.
Surely we can talk?
I'm listening.
- What ideas have you put in his mind?
- Nothing.
I put nothing in Mounir's mind.
If he wants to go back to his family,
ask yourself why.
I'm not asking myself why,
I'm asking how.
How can he live there?
Do you know what Morocco's like?
Do you know how they raise girls?
Is that what you want for them?
Their father's from Morocco
and they're Moroccan too.
Give me a break.
The girls were born here,
grew up here, live here.
They don't lack anything.
You don't either.
- I lack time for myself.
- It's a bit late for that.
You have three kids
and now you want time too?
Just how old are you, Murielle?
If the apartment is too small,
we'll find somewhere bigger.
But one thing is sure.
I won't let you both screw up like that.
Mr Pinget, André, gives this sum
to Mr Moudayeb, Mounir,
for the acquisition and renovation
of a piece of landed property.
Mr Pinget will be your tenant
since the sum represents
15 years' payment in advance
for rental of part
of the said property.
You still don't wish to include
a rescinding clause?
- No, there's no need.
- Alright, let's sign then.
- Go on.
- Initial each page.
- And sign the last one.
- Here?
Over to you.
Look who's here.
I'm not in quarantine any more?
What's wrong?
Nothing, but I'm a bit worried.
I think my period's late.
It is? Come and sit down.
It's a month and a half already.
Why didn't you say so sooner?
I don't know. I didn't have time.
- Any nausea?
- Yes.
Right... We'll do a blood test.
If this is it,
give us a boy this time.
Listen...
I have something to say
but you may not agree.
Why wouldn't I agree?
What is it?
I've wanted to say this
for a while.
But I didn't know if...
It's important.
Go on!
I'm pregnant.
You thought I wouldn't agree?
Are you crazy?
I don't know.
Maybe you wouldn't want to keep it.
You didn't think I'd let you
get an abortion?
Did André mention that?
No, he just said
we needed to think it over.
After all, it's our fourth.
He said that?
No, he congratulated me.
He was really happy.
He told me to bring you here.
It's great.
- You're sure?
- Yes, it's great news.
Everything will be easier
in the new house.
You have ten minutes.
- What?
- Silence!
Cut that out!
- Need a hand, Arthur?
- No.
- Put the book away.
- Which one?
- Don't make fun of me. Put it away.
- Which book, ma'am?
- OK, get out!
- What did I do?
- Take your things!
- Shit, ma'am!
- Watch your mouth! Just get out!
- But, ma'am...
Are you crazy? I pity your kid!
- What?
- I pity your kid.
Take that back right now!
It'll be OK.
I'll give you a certificate
to see a therapist.
You can go on sick leave
and be with the children.
Mounir's going to agree with me.
Don't let those little shits
ruin your health.
Just take one.
I'm having anxiety attacks again.
Especially when I'm alone.
Were you anxious before?
Yes, a little.
What do you think
causes this anxiety?
I don't know.
I'm scared of doing the wrong thing
with the girls.
I'll put you on sick leave
and follow your doctor's treatment.
I think we need to plan
on a lengthy analysis.
An analysis?
Yes, with regular sessions.
To think about all that.
If you want to talk about it, that is.
I think it would be a good idea.
There.
Thank you.
This is perfect.
It will take us through
to your maternity leave.
- She's nice anyway.
- I wanted to talk about that.
You know, De Clerck...
knows I'm your family doctor.
It's best not to tell her
that we live together.
Just in case welfare
runs an investigation and...
It could be a problem.
One other thing...
We could hire a cleaner.
That would help you out.
Do you want to look for someone?
What's wrong with her?
Put your hand here.
Stay in contact with her.
I'll get the ultrasound ready.
I'm here.
It's going to be a caesarean.
- I want to give him a kiss.
- A quick kiss?
Gently then.
No, don't cry, son.
This is my son alright.
He has my eyes, huh?
He has my eyes.
This is fun, huh?
- Like this?
- Yes, my girl.
Well done, Murielle.
Here you go.
Tell me, Murielle...
ls Francoise divorced?
- Does she still need money?
- Yes.
Do you think she'd marry Samir?
I don't know.
He can't take it here any more.
He needs papers.
Maybe I can ask her.
Thanks.
I've found a tiny stone.
A white one too.
It's not a stone.
- One more, Sohane.
- I fancy a dip. Can you watch her?
In Morocco,
I felt really good.
Some days,
I didn't even take my pills.
It was really great there.
My sister has even agreed
to marry Mounir's brother
so he can get his papers.
You mean a sham marriage?
Yes.
A sham marriage
can be a source of stress.
No, it's...
You know,
Fatima, Mounir's sister,
has been married to Andre for years.
Her name's Pinget but they don't live
together and there's never any problem.
You mean Dr Pinget is this André
you often mention?
Dr Pinget, your family doctor?
Yes.
You live with your family doctor?
No. Well, yes.
Well, not exactly.
I'm sorry, Murielle,
but there's a problem.
But...
I know you and he talk, but...
I trust him
and we get on well.
I realise that, but I can't work
with a colleague who shares your life.
I don't live with him,
he just shares our house.
Your family doctor sends you here,
you're living with him...
...under the same roof, OK?
You go on holiday with him.
He's your husband's adoptive father
and your sister-in-law's husband.
And he bought the house
where he continues to live with you.
Yes.
And he's bought a house in Morocco too.
I can't work with Dr Pinget any more.
So we have to end my therapy?
But I need to see you.
I don't want to stop.
Don't worry,
I'm not saying we're going to stop.
I'm just saying I can't work
with him any more.
- André?
- Yes.
Actually, my shrink told me
we don't need any more sessions.
Really? Why?
It's just...
she doesn't think it's necessary.
We've made good progress.
And she says I'm doing better.
That's good news.
You're going back to work?
I don't know about that.
How'll we manage with the kids?
I don't know.
I'll do you another sick note.
Yes.
You want more eyeshade?
Look how beautiful Jade is.
Want some more, Sohane?
Let me see.
Some pink on your cheeks?
- Can we help you?
- No, you'll dirty yourself.
- Hold on.
- Don't get my ring dirty.
Bravo, sweetheart.
I'm proud of you, honey!
- Are you OK?
- A little stomach ache.
- You took your medicine?
- No, I forgot.
Hold on, I have some.
You realise what the children feel,
seeing you like this?
Take that and we'll wait for you
in the car.
With the treatment,
it'll soon pass. Drive safely.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
See you soon.
Can I have a quick word?
I've done the transfer
but go easy with the account.
Sure.
Why say that? I'm careful.
I don't know.
Tell her to be careful too.
I'm not made of money, OK?
- Girls, we're home!
- Shit!
Shit!
Did you do anything nice today?
- What did you do?
- How are my princesses?
- Where's Mum?
- She's asleep.
I'm here.
I fell asleep. Dinner isn't ready.
And you left them all alone?
I'll get some pizzas.
Does pizza suit everybody?
Shall we buy pizzas?
- Leave it, André, I'll go.
- It's OK.
- Come on, girls, before they close.
- Here's your card.
Thank you. Come on, hurry!
What were you doing with his card?
Doesn't he give us enough money?
How does that make me look?
- I'm sorry I fell asleep. I was tired.
- Don't tell me you're sorry!
He pays for everything
and now he has to buy dinner too?
You could've gone.
You're pissing us off!
He doesn't have to do all this!
Show him some respect!
It's just a fly.
- It was a fly.
- A fly's nothing.
What are you doing?
If there are bees in the house,
they sting, so don't touch them.
There are no bees.
That's too much.
It's too much.
The contracting parties deposited
their wedding contract on May 22, 2005,
with Mr Rémy, a notary in Brussels.
The contract foresees
division of property.
Witnessed by Mounir Moudayeb,
brother of the groom,
aged 26, resident of Brussels,
and Murielle Moudayeb,
sister of the bride, aged 27,
resident of Brussels.
This marriage act was drawn up
in their presence
and signed
by the couple and their witnesses.
By the powers vested in me,
I declare you husband and wife.
You may kiss.
Praise God, I'm happy for my children.
I'll never forget
what the doctor has done.
She says she's proud
of her children and her grandchildren
and will never forget
what the doctor has done for us.
You're a good mother.
May God preserve you.
She says you're a great mother.
Here. A present for you.
Try it on.
You have to try it on.
Thank you.
André!
- What's wrong?
- She fell.
I want to go home.
I don't know what's wrong.
- I can't breathe.
- What was that?
- She wants to go home. She's in pain.
- Where?
- Where does it hurt, Mum?
- I don't know.
I was alone in the bathroom.
I thought I was dying.
- I saw my own death.
- She was in the bathroom.
She says she saw death.
She wants to go home.
- Lie her down. I have to examine her.
- She can't get up.
- Help me, my son, please.
- Come on.
We'll go home tomorrow.
Take care.
You take care.
Try to rest, my daughter.
- She can't understand, Mum.
- Look after the children.
May God protect you, my daughter.
- You gave her the medicine?
- Yes.
You're sure?
So difficult at times
When every single wound
Seems to last forever
Women, I love you
I know no simple ones
I only know fragile ones
And difficult ones
Yes, difficult ones
Sometimes so funny
With a look over the shoulder
Yes, but so funny
With a sidelong glance...
Come on, girls, it's time!
When will Granny be better?
- What?
- When will Granny be better?
You know,
when people get very, very old,
they're much more fragile.
But with the good Moroccan air...
Come on, let's go, girls.
You should change, you look ridiculous.
Hello, Dr De Clerck.
It's Murielle.
Murielle Moudayeb.
I...
I'm sorry, it's a bit early.
I wanted to talk to you...
These last few weeks...
...I haven't been doing so well.
I have gloomy thoughts.
I imagine things...
And I...
I'm scared for the children.
I'm not very well.
I'm tired.
And I can't see a way out.
I feel... walled up here.
Mounir is away.
I don't even know
if I should tell Mounir about it.
And then there's Pinget.
And the children.
I'm sorry to take up your time, doctor.
If you want,
you can call me at home.
Godfather, does it hurt
when you have a verruca removed?
No, it doesn't.
What can really hurt, though,
is if you don't have it removed.
- You're sure?
- Yes. Don't worry about it.
I'll be there with you, sweetheart.
Stay near her. Please.
Let me work, madam, please.
Take her hand.
There, like that.
You'll see. You'll hardly feel a thing.
Count to three.
One...
Two...
Madam?
Sit down.
- You're having a dizzy turn.
- I'm OK.
Come and sit down.
- Come on.
- I'm OK.
Jade“.
- Are you OK? It didn't hurt?
- Are you OK too?
I'm OK, sweetheart.
Jade, your mummy just felt dizzy.
It's nothing serious.
Murielle, can I have a word? Sit down.
- I'm going to fetch the children.
- Sit down!
Do you know who called me earlier?
No, I don't.
You don't?
Why are you lying?
Why didn't you say
you were still seeing De Clerck?
I didn't lie.
She told me it had to stay between us.
It's her fault then?
What are you doing, Murielle?
Why are you lying?
I'm not lying.
Who do you think you are?
What have we done to you?
- Nothing.
- What have we done?
Nothing.
I'll go and fetch the children.
Hello.
Will that be all?
That's 38 euros 60, please.
Thank you.
Here you go.
I want strawberry.
- That one's my cake.
- There.
Want some, Malika?
Can the rabbit have some?
The rabbit can have some cake too.
Malika, honey, come here.
Malika.
Come here, sweetheart.
Come on.
Sohane!
Come on, sweetheart.
I'm coming.
Jade, honey?
I've done something really bad.
I've killed my children.
I wanted to kill myself, but I can't.
But I want to die!
Yes...
My four children.
18...
...Rue des Vosges...
English text: Ian Burley