Is anybody there?
(HORN HONKS)
-Woohoo! Yeah!
-Daryl has to work!
-Daryl has to work! (LAUGHTER)
Let me tell you something.
This damn farm's done pretty
well by you and that boy.
-I want to sell the place.
-Well just who in the hell
is going to buy it?
I don't care.
You don't want Daryl to go to
Los Angeles, do you?
Hell no, I need him to
work the farm!
You didn't want Tommy to leave
either. You wanted him to
waste his life here
just like we did.
This farm has fed and raised
them two boys and Tommy up
and left
and you want Daryl to do the
same thing.
I want Daryl to have
a better life than we did.
-I don't want him to go.
-I don't care what you want.
I care about the boy's future.
We have used our life's
savings trying to keep
this place going.
Now I am sick of you, I'm sick
of this place and I'm getting
out before
I'm too old to start over.
I know it's me you're really
sick of. Well by God, that
goes two ways.
Tommy's gone, Daryl's leaving
and so are you.
By God, it doesn't leave me
much choice.
I'm getting the hell out, too.
Honey, I want you
to write down this number.
-Where is it?
-Missouri. I'm going there
for a while.
Write down this number.
Area code 816
555-3002.
Daryl.
In case you get hungry
along the way.
Whatever happens,
I'll always love you.
-Where are you going, Dad?
-Camping.
-For how long?
-A little while.
-You, uh,
you got enough money, son?
-Yeah, I got money.
You know
sometimes things don't work
out the way you want them to.
-God knows, I wish they did.
-Yeah.
Would passenger Daryl Cage
please identify himself to
the flight attendant
in the forward cabin.
-Mr. Cage?
-Yeah.
Why don't you come with me?
I want you so bad.
We've landed.
Must have been some wild
dream. What was it about?
Come on, you can tell me.
I mean, I have really strange
dreams all the time.
I have a reoccurring nun
dream. These nuns are chasing
me through a tunnel
and when we come out the other
side, they're penguins.
You're quiet. That's okay.
I don't like people who
talk all the time.
-I'm an actress.
-Mmm?
Mmm. Did you ever see
Massacre in Blood City ?
-No.
-No?
Cycle Sluts from Hell ?
-No, Ma'am.
-No, Ma'am?
-Where are you from?
Iowa.
-Life's a bitch, ain't it?
-Sometimes.
I can't tell you what a great
experience it has been
talking to you.
-Yeah, you too.
-See you later! Bye!
-Uh, hey, you uh...
-Oh thanks! Jeez.
Hey! Hey! There's $50 missing!
No, I'm joking! Lighten up.
So look, um, if you get bored
while you're here, why don't
you drop in and see me?
-I work at the Beanery.
-Uh, what's your name,
by the way?
-It's Dizz.
-Hey
I'm going to be here in
Los Angeles all summer.
Oh, you are? Could turn out
to be a real hot one.
Hi.
-Daryl!
-Hey, man.
-It's good to see you.
-Thanks.
-This is my wife, Crys.
-Hi, how are you?
Good to see you.
-Hi! Tommy talks about you
all the time.
-Oh, does he?
-Yeah, you've grown up.
-What can I do, man?
I used to sling this kid
over my shoulder. (LAUGHTER)
-Did you have a good flight?
-Uh, yeah, it was okay.
-You look great.
-Thanks.
-Do you have anything else?
-That one.
Great. All right, let's
get out of here.
-Okay, you're okay.
-Thanks.
Sir, your stubs don't match.
Hey, slow down, man!
There it is. The dream house.
I built it from scratch.
So, uh, what do you think?
I built this for you.
Ta-da!
It's your own private place.
You can't even see it
from the street.
You two go ahead.
You have a lot of catching up
to do.
-Good night.
-See you later.
Come on. Get in there.
-How'd De Witt do this year?
-Three and eight.
-That's not bad.
-Yeah it is.
-You never lost one, though,
did you?
-No.
-Badass.
Still wearing the ring?
-Yeah, I am.
You never missed a game,
did you?
No.
-How are things at home?
-Pretty bad.
Mom left. Dad went away.
-Well, I guess it was just
a matter of time, huh?
-I guess.
-How come you left, man?
-I left for a lot of reasons.
I wanted you to come here
and live with us,
after we got married.
-But Mom and Dad said no.
-They never told me that.
I guess they were afraid to
lose their last son.
Tom
I want to tell you
some things.
Nothing bad, just...
Hey, it's okay.
I guess we could talk about it
in the morning.
We're just glad you're
here with us.
Holy shit.
Oh, my God.
Hey Tommy! Tommy!
Some weird stuff's happened.
There's some crazy stuff
in my bag. Where are you?
Hey, Crys!
Tommy?
Hey, Cage! Your septic
tank's overflowing.
I didn't do it!
(GUNSHOT)
(CAR HORN)
Hey, what are you doing?
187 at 439 Valleyheart.
Male Caucasian 18 to 20
light hair blue jacket
fled the scene on foot.
Considered armed
and dangerous.
(CAR HORNS)
-Operator.
-Yes, police, this is
an emergency.
(PHONE RINGS)
-Police emergency.
Where are you calling from?
-I don't know.
(SQUEALING TIRES)
Go on, get out of here!
-Freeze!
-Put your hands over
your head.
-Look out! He's got a gun!
-No!
(GUNFIRE)
-Get the hell out of here!
-Sure!
(SIRENS AND SQUEALING TIRES)
No!
I'm sorry about that gun.
It's just something
I had to do.
Hey, I'm really lost here,
man. Do you think I should
go to the police?
Are you out of
your fucking skull?
They almost blew you away.
-They think you did it.
-I didn't do it. I didn't do
anything, man.
-Don't you know
anybody else in LA?
-No.
I don't know anybody.
That's what's crazy.
I've never even been here.
-I can't believe this.
-Wait a minute.
I do know a girl.
I met a girl on the airplane
coming here.
Her name is Dizz or something.
Anyway, she said she works at
a place called the Beanery.
Do you know where that is?
Yeah, I know where it is.
Hey, kid!
Don't be messing with that!
The suspect, a white male 18
to 20, was seen fleeing the
premises carrying a red bag.
Police refuse to speculate on
any motive other than robbery.
A neighbor who was wounded
was temporarily hospitalized,
but has been released.
Reporting from the
Hollywood Hills,
this is Bill Press.
Back to you in the studio.
So, here we go.
Rock'n'roll chili and
an Elvis Presley shake.
-It's about time.
-And a Chuck Berry burger
with fries.
-I had the Buddy Holly
burger with onion rings.
-You did?
Trust me, baby, I know
what I ordered.
I must've written it
down wrong.
I would get a jet pilot
when I'm in a rush.
Oh, cut me a break, okay?
I'm an actress, I'm not
a waitress.
Oh. Well, try acting like a
waitress and bringing
me my order.
Mmm. Right away.
-So busy...
-Dizz.
Hi! You sure got bored fast.
Toast, I need it toasted.
-Listen, listen.
-What?
-I need your help.
Right now? Not right now.
-Dizz, I'm in a lot
of very serious trouble.
-Well so am I.
These orders are piled up
and I don't know
where they go.
Hey, hey, listen to me.
I'm seriously in a situation,
and it's life-or-death.
I'm not playing any games.
I need your help.
And I need for us to leave
here now.
-You need me?
-Yes I do.
-Let's go.
Would you take my station?
-Yeah, okay.
Hey, brain trust!
Where's my Buddy Holly burger?
Buddy ate it.
Whoa.
Oh boy, you are in deep shit.
-Listen to me.
They think I did this murder.
-What do you want with me?
You're the only person I know
in Los Angeles, Dizz. Look,
I wouldn't have come to you
if I didn't need your help.
My brother's dead.
-Think we ought to
make a move?
-No, not until we're sure.
(KNOCKING)
Hi, baby.
Didn't hear me knocking, huh?
Aren't you going to
open the door?
I've got some magic dust
for you.
Playful, isn't he?
The little guy bit me.
It's okay, fella.
I'm not going to hurt you.
There's a kid out there
on the street
with 10 keys of heroin
that belong to me.
You talk to your friends, and
find out if anyone's seen or
heard from this guy.
You can do that for me,
can't you?
Good girl.
Cute little fella.
Ugh!
(BUZZ)
Hey, Dizz, it's Mark Gerchick
director of Teenage
Bloodsuckers.
Are you busy tonight?
I thought we'd make some
sparks, huh?
What a troll! Oh, yeah.
One call.
(WHISTLES)
Sweetie-pie, you keep an eye
on him.
What a mess.
(BEEP) We're sorry. Your call
cannot be completed as dialed.
Please check the number,
and try your call again.
The suspect is armed,
and considered
extremely dangerous.
Police have just released this
composite drawing. He is
believed to be at large now
in the Los Feliz area.
-Operator, is 816 the correct
area code in Missouri?
-If you have any information,
please contact the Los Angeles
Police Department.
Sir, that number is no longer
in service. Hello?
-Hey!
-Hey, what are you doing?
-I saw your picture on the TV.
You killed them!
-What do you mean
you saw my picture on TV?
What's that supposed to mean?
Well if that's not how it
happened and you're so
innocent, then why don't you
just go to the police
and leave me alone?
Look,
I already tried that once
and they blew me out of
a phone booth, practically,
okay?
-Oh, right.
-Hey, you don't believe me?
-No I don't. Why should I?
-Because I'm telling you
the truth.
Look, I hardly know you.
I mean, there are a lot of
freaks in this world.
Yeah, I'm learning that.
You take care, huh?
Hey, Iowa!
Where are you going?
Come on, get in and
I'll give you a ride.
Come on.
(SQUEALS TIRES)
-On TV they said it was
a robbery.
-No.
No, I was at the airport and
I got the wrong bag and it was
full of drugs.
-That's what happened.
-Well what did you do with it?
-It's safe.
-That's good. Don't you think
you should call the police
and let them know
where the bag is?
They don't want a bag.
They want me.
Well, at least you've got to
call them, okay?
(PHONE RINGS)
Homicide. Lieutenant?
Lieutenant Delgado.
Yeah, look.
My name is Daryl Cage.
My father is Harlan Cage.
My brother Tommy and his wife
Crys picked me up at the
airport. He grabbed
the wrong bag off the thing.
We got back to his house and
when I woke up
there were drugs in the bag,
and they were dead.
That is the truth.
-Where are you?
-Let's forget about that,
all right?
Look, if you want me to help
you, you've got to help me.
Come on in, tell me the story.
Yeah, look, I think we tried
that once and I got shot at,
okay?
When the officers told you to
freeze, you pulled a gun.
I found that gun. When I
pulled it out, I was trying to
give it to them.
If you're innocent, you've got
nothing to be afraid of.
-Yeah, I want to
talk to you alone.
-Where?
-Daryl!
-Police! Freeze!
Daryl?
Move it, move it!
Come on, let's go!
-Are you all right?
-I don't know. All this stuff
is just happening too fast.
When I talked to Tommy,
I never...
I never got to finish
what I wanted to say.
He told me he always wanted me
to be with him.
Then he got taken away.
My mother, my father,
I can't go to them.
They don't even
matter anymore.
Look, you don't need the cops
to help you find who killed
Tommy. We can do it.
All we've got to do is get the
word out on the street that
we've got their smack
and they're going
to be finding us.
How do you get that
word around?
There's a whole network of
people that can help us. We've
got to connect with them.
People like this guy Marshall
that I know. But Daryl, if
we're going to pull this off
you're going to have to
change a little bit.
If we're going to find them
you're going to have to play
the game by their rules.
Can you handle that?
I want to find them,
wherever they are,
and wherever they're going.
Well, we can lose the scarf.
That's, that's good.
That's better.  Tres chic.
It's classic. Let's go.
Hey! Come here.
-Do you know why there's a
crosswalk on that corner?
-Yes, officer.
-We were just in a hurry.
-Haven't I seen you before?
-No.
-Take the shades off.
-What?
-I said, take the shades off.
-Don't let me catch you
jaywalking again.
-Yes, sir.
So far, so good.
So, if you hear of anybody
looking to score big,
here's my number.
-Yeah, rad.
-Take care, now. If you hear
anything, shoot us a call.
You got it.
-"Shoot us a call"?
-Yeah, I heard it on TV.
Look, if we're ever going to
pull this thing off
you'd better just let me do
all the talking.
Hey blondie, why don't you
come with me, huh?
I couldn't find Marshall.
Come on.
¶ Water was running
Children were running
¶ You were running out of time
¶ Under the mountain
A golden fountain
¶ Were you praying
at the Lares shrine
¶ But oh
¶ Your city lies in dust
¶ My friend ¶
So listen, if you hear
anything or you see anything
would you let me know?
-You got it.
-All right. Let's go.
-So, how's he doing?
-Who?
-Cage.
-Oh you? Yeah, you're not
doing bad for a farm boy.
¶ Your city lies in dust
¶ My Friend
¶ Oh
¶ Your city lies in dust
¶ My friend ¶
-Hey, baby, what's happening?
-Yo, Marshall!
Dizz, what's happening?
You're looking so sleek this
evening, girl! How you been?
Whoa, check it out,
baby, what's happening?
Stone fox, what do you...
-I hear you know some people.
-Now who the fuck are you,
man?
Hey, I got 10 keys of smack.
It doesn't matter who the fuck
I am. Who the fuck are you?
I know just the dude that you
need to be speaking with,
my man. Now, I want you
to check me out at the
Stardust Club. You make it
after midnight, okay?
And I'm going to
take care of you, okay?
Now you be cool.
-There you go. Take care.
Be cool.
-Later.
Later, baby, you take care.
Yeah.
You find anything new?
We've been through the house
a second time. The foreign
prints we found on the
neighbor's shirt match the
prints we found on
the dead woman
and the ones in the hallway
and in the bedroom.
-And there's still only one
set of foreign prints.
-Mm hmm.
Then the kid is the only one
we can place in this house.
-Did you locate a Harlan Cage?
-I talked to a sheriff
in De Witt.
There's a Cage family there,
but he can't locate them.
Maybe the kid's telling
the truth. Maybe his brother
did pick up the wrong bag.
Maybe. Maybe he picked up the
right bag, and the kid killed
his brother in cold blood.
¶ Well I can hear you
¶ I can see you
¶ But I can't feel you
¶ Touching me, yeah
¶ Oh, it's obvious there's
¶ No one you can trust
¶ To tell your tales of love
¶ Goodbyes ¶
Do you think maybe you could
buy me a mouse, because he
broke my mouse's neck?
That's him!
-Marshall.
-Dizzy. Tonight is your lucky
night, dude.
-Why's that?
-Money talks, man.
Bullshit walks.
Where is he?
(GUNSHOT)
(GUNSHOTS)
Whoa! What's that?
Hey! Gaddis!
(LAUGHING) That was intense!
What are you, mental? Huh?
-What do you think this is, a
fucking video?
-No, now we know who they are!
No, Dizz, now they
know you we are.
So what are we going to do?
Hey look, I really appreciate
your help and all, okay?
Hooking me up with all
these people. I couldn't
have done this without you.
But it's just too sick and it
is too serious, and I have
to do this alone.
What, you're just going
to blow me off now?
I mean, I've only driven you
all over Los Angeles.
I even lost my job because of
you. And now you're just going
to blow me off.
Oh, that's great. Figures.
My brother's gone, okay?
And I'm here alone.
And if we make another mistake
they're going to nail me.
And you know what else?
They're going to nail you.
That's serious.
Well, then we gotta make real
sure that we don't make
any mistakes.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(DRIVING AWAY)
Hey!
You crazy son of a bitch!
(DRUNKEN SINGING)
What's happening? How you
doing there today?
Very nice to see you.
In a hurry?
Marshall?
-No.
-Relax, man.
We're all friends here.
Yeah. Get in the car.
Listen.
If it's about that kid...
I want him.
I don't know where he is.
I swear.
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
(SCREAMING)
I'll find him! I'll find him!
-I like you, Marshall.
-Yeah?
-(SCREAMS)
-Just don't get on my
bad side.
Don't ever get on my bad side.
Okay!
This is definitely heroin!
I think.
How much is it worth?
Ten of these? I don't know,
a million! Maybe more.
Okay, so what are we going
to do now?
We gotta get to a wide open
space. You know, somewhere not
near here at all.
We gotta get away from here.
Oh, I got it. I know exactly
where we can go.
We can go to San Pedro.
The docks down there?
It'll be ideal.
(PHONE RINGS)
Yeah.
This is Marshall.
Yeah, we got a message
to call you.
Listen to me,
you little prick.
Nobody fucks me over.
I want my shit back tonight.
Well look, I don't want any
more trouble with you or the
cops anyway, okay?
If you can just give me
a couple grand
so I can get the
hell out of here
I'll be fine.
Sure, kid.
No sweat.
See how easy I can be?
Lead rain, Lemar.
Lead motherfucking rain.
Okay, it's San Pedro.
By the docks.
Pier E.
Pier E, I got it.
What took you so long
to tip us?
I did that so you wouldn't
scare him off.
If what you're saying is true
you're way out of bounds.
One careless move and he'll
blow your ass to pieces.
And anyone else who
gets in his way.
Daryl?
Go home, okay?
I don't want to go home
and just leave you
here by yourself.
Look, I don't want to see
you get hurt.
Get the hell out of here.
Go on.
Get the windshield for you?
You'd better just be reaching
for your dick, Lemar.
Hey! Hey!
Where's Gaddis?
He's looking for some kid!
Made off with our smack!
(SCREAMS)
He didn't get it.
There's the kid!
Dizz, get out of here!
Police! Freeze!
Come on, move it! Move it!
(GUN CLICKS EMPTY)
(PHONE RINGS)
Hi, it's Dizz. You know what
to do so do it after the beep.
(PHONE RINGS)
Delgado.
No, you blew it, Daryl.
-Hey why don't you believe me?
-Doesn't fucking matter
whether I believe you or not.
Two of my men are dead!
That makes you an accessory to
murder one.
Now you listen to me.
You better start playing ball
with me, boy.
Or else I'm going to nail
your fucking ass to the wall.
Hey man, I'm telling you
everything I know.
Bullshit! You've been
short-stroking me from the
very beginning.
Now I want to know, who are
those two other guys, huh?
The one we found toasted
in the car and the one who
cut down my men.
Look, those are the dudes who
killed my brother. I never saw
them before last night, man.
What about the girl?
She has nothing to do with it.
She's only helped me while
I've been here.
Okay, now you listen to me.
You listen to me good.
We only found one set
of foreign prints at the
murder scene.
If they turn out to be yours,
then there's no evidence that
there was anyone else
in that house, but you.
Daryl? Daryl?
Scare you, Gil?
Jesus, Roy.
I'm your worst fucking
nightmare, right?
You look like shit.
You got any painkillers?
There's a few percs in the
medicine cabinet.
You still too wasted to fly?
Going to be making a run to
Mexico real soon.
Go ahead, Gil.
Use it!
Doesn't look like any
sign of him.
Or your smack.
What about the girl?
I got her address.
You're cute.
-You know that?
-Mm-hmm.
Hey, Dizz, it's Mark Gerchick.
(SCREAMS) (PHONE RINGS)
Look, she works over
at the Beanery.
Sometimes she eats here.
You seen her?
-Hey.
-Yeah?
-You know a gal named Dizz?
-Yeah, I know her.
-Where's she at?
-I don't know.
-Where's Marshall?
-There's a lot of Marshalls
in Hollywood.
Hey!
-I'm looking for him, man.
-Walk down to Bates
and Lakeford.
It's the corner house.
It's the kid from last night.
If he's got the stuff,
this could be it.
(GUN COCKING)
That was a real stupid
stunt last night.
Now, I want my shit!
Where is it?
Where's Dizz?
Lieutenant? She identified the
Cage kid leaving the house.
Well, make sure you get her
name. We'll want to talk to
her later.
Yes, sir.
I'm looking for a kid.
He's got a lot of smack?
And some girl named Dizz.
You seen them?
You know where they are?
-Be back here in half an hour.
-I wanna go home...
-Do it now!
Oh, Dizz.
DIZZ: I was so afraid.
I thought I'd never see
you again.
Now I gotta get a new
set of wheels.
No, now they have the stuff.
Life's a bitch, ain't it?
How'd I do?
Not bad.
For a city girl.
Sunset Towers,
across from Party's.
I come up here sometimes
by myself.
I'm really sorry that
you had to become
involved in all this.
'Cause this, man, this...
This has gotten crazy.
I'm not sorry.
Don't apologize.
I bet compared to the girls
back home I must seem
really strange.
I hadn't known that many.
Come on, you must have a
girlfriend back home.
Well, actually, these is this
girl I actually have been
kind of seeing.
She's kind of an actress type.
She's kind of wild.
Daryl, there's something I've
really gotta tell you.
I haven't been straight
with you.
I'm not really an actress.
I'm not.
I mean, I didn't get any of
those parts that I went
out for.
I didn't get that part in
Massacre in Blood City
or anything. I made it all up.
I know you probably think
I got lots of friends here and
I know a lot of people
but they don't know me.
I mean, my name is not even
Dizz. It's not, really,
it's Darlene.
I really couldn't give a shit
about those things.
Any of that stuff.
Daryl, I've been alone
for a long time.
(SOUND OF SOMETHING MOVING)
Don't move.
Out with the gun.
Slowly.
Drop it.
Kick it over here.
You want me to blow her away?
Where is it?
-It's in the bag.
-Get it.
Get it!
Toss it over here.
Nice and easy.
Pick it up.
Get over there.
Move, you little motherfucker.
Turn around.
Bye, kid.
Easy, kid.
No, wait.
Ed Hurley, Drug Enforcement,
Daryl!
Don't hurt him, he's a cop!
My partner and I have been
dogging Gaddis since
New Orleans.
Fuck you, okay?
Because you've been using
me as bait the whole time.
Kid, I didn't even know you
existed until yesterday.
I still don't know who the
fuck you are!
I think you're talking
a lot of shit!
He's getting away. If you're
going to shoot me, go ahead.
-Get Delgado!
-Be careful!
-Yeah.
-We're going to Mexico.
(POLICE RADIO NOISE)
Stop the car, stop the car!
You've got to help me!
You've got to help us!
Just called Drug Enforcement
New Orleans.
About Morano's death?
Turns out he and Hurley have
been on suspension for the
past two months.
Boys down there think
they're dirty.
That means that kid's out
there all alone.
They're coming for me.
Where is he?
Resnick just brought a second
set of prints from Tommy
Cage's house.
I put them through
the computer.
They belong to him.
Good.
Lieutenant!
Hurley and the kid were seen
headed West towards Venice.
They got the girl downstairs.
They're bringing her up now.
You recognize him?
Yeah, that's him!
Okay, you come with me!
In the car, come on! Let's go.
Let's go!
Get out of here! Go!
Shit!
Give it up, Gaddis!
You have any idea what
this stuff is worth?
Sorry it's gotta
be this way, kid.
I was really beginning
to like you.
It's just business.
Go for it, kid.
Maybe you'll be quicker
than your brother was.
A knife?
Life's a bitch, ain't it?
There's two dead
bodies inside.
That's what we were all
running around about.
Now you got it.
Are you going to be all right?
Yeah. What about you?
Okay.
Guess you're going to
go back to Iowa now?
Well actually, I was kind of
hoping I could stay here
with you for a while.
I would really like that.