Previously on Outsiders...
Evening, Foster.
What's the matter? You scared?
You scared to die?
Will you be my queen, G'winveer?
I accept.
You took everything from me.
So finish what you started
the day I was born.
Foster!
It's not worth it. It's not worth it.
What's it like up there?
Well, it's beautiful.
There's more stars than you can count.
I'm not sleeping down here
like some homeless person.
Hasil Farrell?
Pleasure, miss.
I say we buy us four,
five jugs of kerosene,
go up there and burn their asses!
Yeah! Yeah!
- Caught one of 'em.
- On the lives of my kids,
I swear you'll never see me again!
Guaranteed, I won't see you again.
A Farrell killed Breece.
I'm gonna find the guy who did it.
We're ready.
You're good to me, and
I love you for that.
Your tea's gonna get cold.
Is this what you were looking for?
This is witches' glove.
You killing him, G'win?
Oh, God. What the hell
are you doing here?
I am the one returned.
The prophecy of lady Ray told it so.
You're up to something, right?
You're up to something?
- I can't figure it out.
- I ain't up to nothing.
All right, now, you, your
time's come to an end.
I warn you, be careful.
Because if we're caught,
it could mean banishment,
or even worse.
Help me.
You sure are poorly.
Oh, no. No.
I'm worse than poorly.
I can't hardly raise my bones.
It's best you stay settled in bed, then.
No, I can't. Can't, can't, can't.
No. No, I gotta get Asa dead.
I got dark premonitions
about that devil.
I know, sir. I appreciate
that it's late notice.
Honestly, it's however
many men you can spare.
Yeah, that's great.
No, sir. That's... that's...
that's great.
I'll have someone call you,
but we're planning on heading
up the mountain on Thursday.
All right. Thank you, sir.
Okay, that's two men
from Christianville.
How are you doing?
Well, we got one from Marston's Mills,
- one guy from miner.
- So where's that put us now?
Well, with the 2 you just
got, that makes... 11.
That's just nowhere near enough.
We're gonna need at least 20.
I mean, we just got no idea
what we're walking into.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
No, I was...
I was just thinking about sheriff Weineke
and... your brother-in-law.
A lot of people aren't coming
back down that mountain alive.
Yeah, well, I mean...
You're scared,
and... I don't blame you.
But someone's gotta do somethin'.
When we take on this job,
we take on a responsibility.
At a time like this, if we don't do
something, people gonna die.
Outsiders 1x12 - All Hell
Are you certain this is how
you wanna deal with him?
Don't go soft on me, lady.
It's gotta be done.
I'm concerned about
what people will think
when they see you hunting
a man down like a dog.
I'm trying to people your
relationship with your people.
Sounds more like you're
trying to protect him.
Well, then you're not hearing me right.
I don't give a feather if
cousin Asa lives or dies.
That's cold talk, woman.
But it warms me up fine.
I'm gonna talk to the
boys, get his ass found.
- Morning, Krake.
- Morning.
Good morning, G'win.
Morning.
I have apologies to give to you.
For what?
For the man that I
was, the man I become.
I should be the one apologizing to you.
I done terrible things...
I'm not talking about recent.
I'm talking about years past.
All that time wasted in weakness and...
running after his
respect, long hours fr...
fretting about losing your love.
It's all gone now.
When I think about it, it's like
I'm contemplating a stranger.
So you've changed?
Listen, I just come here to tell you,
no matter what happens,
you can always trust me.
Your secrets are safe with me.
Is there anything you want to tell me?
McGintuk,
Shay,
Farrell,
welcome here to celebrate
this last dawn of summer,
and to honor our home,
as our ancestors have done
for so many years before us.
Summer is done.
The harvest comes, followed soon after
by the cold, quiet, death of winter.
Through it all, we are
sustained by our mother,
our mountain.
So let us give her all praise and glory.
For life, for sustenance, for balance,
we honor the mountain.
A-myrr waigh myrr.
For blessings, for riches,
for your great, quiet majesty.
A-myrr waigh myrr.
For now...
for then...
for always.
Our land gives us great strength,
but that strength alone
cannot sustain us.
It is our strength as a community
that allows us to survive.
Please turn now to the family
members nearest to you
and offer them words or gestures
of fellowship and love.
Asa wants a meeting.
All right.
A meeting at fuzzy Shay's old place.
Let the others know.
You better get out of here.
He's gonna grab you when this is over,
and he's gonna kill you.
Let us prepare now for
the chill of winter.
A-waigh clan,
a good harvest to us all.
Ged-gedyah!
Take him.
- Shit.
- You see where he went?
Split off. We'll find him. Go.
You're idiots.
He was right under your noses.
It's a miracle any of you can piss
seeing as you gotta
find your dick first.
Do you wanna wait until he
slits my throat in the night?
I want him gone.
Split up. Search everywhere.
Every holler... check
the damn shit pile.
Now you.
And you, too, you... you come with me.
Hey, sheriff.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm just coming to see you.
That guy who killed Breece, you got him?
Nope, not yet.
Right, but you told us
he'd be in custody by now.
Did I? Yeah, well, I was wrong.
Taking a little longer than we thought.
So you don't got him?
No.
That's all we needed to know.
You think you done
enough damage already?
You stay out of our way.
You let us handle it.
You okay?
I have no bars.
Well, we got us a bar up in the barn.
You want something to drink?
Never mind.
I am thirsty, though.
All right, well, I'll head on up there.
- I'll get you somethin'.
- Okay, I'll go with you.
Hey, no, no, no. Hey, hey, hey.
Let me go. I'll take care of you.
You my guest, right?
I wanna look around.
And I'm tired of waiting for
that Krake guy to come back.
What? You're saying you're bored?
Is that it?
No. I'm not bored.
I just wanna take a walk.
- Well, you can't.
- Why not?
'Cause I told you there's
things going on up here.
Look, you ain't from here.
Right? I gotta get a lot
of folks used to the idea
of a stranger being around.
And I'll do it, but I need you
to give me a little bit of time.
- Come on.
- Okay.
But I didn't come up here
to live under a tree.
Hasil. Are you listening to me?
I need you to get underneath
that blanket and be quiet.
- Why?
- Just...
Hasil.
All this time, Krake, you've
been telling us to trust Asa.
He said Big Foster would never get guns.
Now he's got more fire than
he knows what to do with.
Oh. He'll figure out
what to do with them,
believe you me.
How are we supposed to
fight big Foster now?
Can we just wait for Asa, please?
Asa's our leader. I'm sure
he'll have an answer.
Asa's your leader?
Is that true?
Well, it seems my
premonitions were correct.
I thought I was your leader.
What was it you said, Shurn?
"How are we supposed
to fight Big Foster?"
You heard me.
Asa's your leader.
So here you all are.
Your minds poisoned by Asa.
All in defiance of your Bren'in.
Take 'em to the barn.
Keep a guard on 'em.
Any of them try to escape,
you shoot them dead.
Especially this one.
Go. Come on.
I need your help.
He's got men all over the mountain.
There's a man two stones' throw
from here hidden up in a tree.
I'm not sure there's
much I can do for you.
But you will help me?
You saved my life.
The fact that you done that
when most people here wouldn't
even look me in the eye?
That won't soon be forgotten, cousin.
All right.
So what do we do?
The way that I figure it, you
got two options right now.
You gotta get off this mountain or die.
He's sick. Could be dying.
He's got it set in his head that
he ain't going to his grave
until you go to yours.
I thought I could beat him.
You know, like I was so
much smarter than him.
Like it was gonna be so easy.
I had destiny on my side, right?
My destiny's exactly what you say it is.
Either I go or I die.
Then let's find you some safe
passage off this mountain.
How do I know you're not gonna
run straight to your father
and hand me over to him?
Maybe you didn't hear
what I said before.
Are you giving me up?
That'd go a long way to
mending your relationship.
That man is dead to me.
There ain't no mending that.
Foster.
You're a good man.
Bren'in! Got you somethin'.
Well, come. You got me Asa?
Not Asa.
Well, well, well.
Look who we found at last.
- Yeah, come here...
- Get off of me!
He had that bitch hid away.
- Shut up.
- Hey, hey, oh.
Doesn't seem like to me,
this is the place for you
to be talking large.
No! Leave him alone!
Yeah, so you tell your
friend about the last time
you and I made acquaintance?
You remember that?
When I was all chained up in a box.
And you come to burn me alive.
You remember that?
- You're hurting him! Hey!
- Wait, wait, wait...
It's okay. It's all right.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Just simmer down, okay?
You're a guest in my home, okay?
Don't you go pushing me.
That ain't polite.
Oh... oh, get him up.
You are something else, boy.
And by that, I mean, you are
the king of the dumb shits.
First, you got caught stealing from us,
now you got caught
bringing in an outsider.
She's a good person. She
don't mean nobody...
she don't mean no... she
don't mean nobody no harm.
Last outsider come up here said
the same thing, didn't he?
Right. We all know what happened to him.
- Wait, what? Wait, what?
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Wait, what?
- Get 'em out of here.
- Hasil. Hasil.
- Lock 'em up with the others.
Hasil! Hasil!
Hell...
this keeps up...
...won't likely be anybody
left walking around here free.
Yeah, last time we talked
to that damn sheriff,
he said he was gonna
have the man in custody.
And, of course, he has not done it.
Yeah, that's right. I
just talked to him.
We can't sit on this no longer.
It's an insult to Breece's memory.
Doing nothing and letting them
get away with killing him?
We got us a big group together now.
Ain't gonna be just the three of us.
Tomorrow, at 5 in the afternoon,
we're gonna be meeting
and head up that trail
by eno white's place.
Could you please close the door?
Okay, go ahead.
Okay, we got weapons, but
we need ammo, kerosene.
We need money.
Gentlemen, what you're suggesting here
is highly illegal.
If I was involved in any way,
even if people knew I was a
party to this conversation,
it could be extremely
damaging for my career.
So I am going to forget
that you came here.
And I'm going to leave my office.
And I'm going to ask
that you please not look
in the top left-hand drawer of my desk
where there's an envelope
containing $1,000 in petty cash.
You have a great day.
I mean, we're supposed to
take the money, right?
Idiot.
On your feet, all of you.
Your Bren'in is here.
Here they are.
You believe me now?
I gotta say...
I'm hurt.
'Cause some of ya, I
knowed since we was kids.
I laughed with some of you,
I cried with some of you.
Your queen talks to
me about many things,
including forgiveness.
So I'm gonna heed her word
and I'm going to forgive you all.
But in order to earn my mercy,
y'all gotta do
one simple thing.
Tell me where he is.
Nobody?
Well, I know somebody here knows.
Our world ain't that big.
So I'm gonna ask you one more time...
where is Asa?
We were expecting him at the meeting.
He never showed himself.
Well, that don't answer my question.
But I ain't gonna get angry
and I ain't gonna yell.
I'm gonna give you a whole
day to think on it,
and then I'm gonna come back
and I'm gonna ask you again.
And I still don't get an answer...
then I'm gonna have to kill one of you.
And, Krake, it's gonna be you.
Dinner's up. You gonna come eat?
No, I'm good.
Well, apart from being pretty salty,
I think it might actually be quite good.
I mean, the kids thought
it sucked, but...
Since when do you drink beer?
It's one of Breece's.
Didn't wanna throw it away.
That didn't seem right.
Yeah, sure.
I don't know, Wade.
Feel like I wasted a lot
of years at that church.
All that praying and
thinking about the almighty.
And then... when I need him,
he's nowhere to be found.
I mean, I stopped doing the
church thing after dad,
so I'm about the worst
person in the world
- to talk to about that.
- Damn it!
Okay.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's not okay.
It's gonna take time, you know.
It's gonna take a lot of time.
I know.
I know that.
We're getting close to
the guy who did it.
- Really?
- Yeah. It might not help,
but it's gonna be something
in the face of not being able
to do a goddamn thing.
I'm sorry.
- I'm okay.
- It's okay. I know.
- I'm fine.
- It's okay.
- I mean, I'm not fine.
- I know.
Okay, come on. Let's go eat.
I'm gonna stay out here
and wait for somebody
to run over that bottle and get a flat.
I can't be the only one
suffering like this.
All right, well, I'm gonna
go in and get a plate
and come join you and watch.
Foster?
Foster, you there?
Well, hey there.
I hope you're going to
suppress the urge to run back
to your husband and tell him where I am.
I'll try.
I know you're killing him.
At first, I didn't believe it.
But then, it all made sense.
You marrying him, giving
yourself up to him.
It wasn't for power.
It was for the good of the clan.
I mean, you love this place.
These people.
I thought I could change him.
Soften him.
And now, this choice that I made, well,
half the time I feel
like I'm the one dying.
I forced you to make that choice.
How?
By coming back.
I mean, everything was fine and
peaceful before I showed up.
Well, what's done is done, Asa.
And I have to worry about now.
About our survival, about the prisoners.
Say what now? What you
mean, "prisoners"?
Your group.
The people plotting against Foster.
He captured them. He's
holding them in the barn.
He threatened to kill Krake
unless you're found.
Oh, my God.
Goodbye, Asa.
Haylie Grimes, yeah.
- Haylie, Donoushee.
- Hello, Don.
To what do I owe the
pleasure, Mr. Boss man?
Well, congratulations, lady.
What wonderful thing have I done today?
You got your cop friend
off his bony ass.
The sheriff over in
Sherwood's a pal of mine.
He got a call today from your
sheriff there in Blackburg
looking for men to go up the mountain
and get those hillbilly assholes down.
Oh, right. I was just about to
call and tell you the good news.
Going up day after tomorrow.
It's a win/win for us either way.
- How do you mean?
- Well, either the cops
get the freaks off the
mountain and we win,
or the freaks shoot and
kill one of the cops
and it turns into a situation
for the Feds, and we win.
Sweet?
That's damn sweet, Don.
Your father's holding prisoners.
I have to help them.
First things first, cousin.
We gotta talk other plans.
Oh, get me something, woman.
Can't you see I'm in pain here?
Don't rush me, Foster.
I gotta do this right.
I could make you sicker than you are.
I can't be sicker than I am.
What... what is wrong with me?
I'm just... I'm just surrounded
by vipers and thieves and liars.
When all I'm trying to do is guide them
from darkness into the light.
Okay. Okay, here. Sit up.
You're gonna drink this.
You're gonna drink it quickly.
It's gonna taste awful, but
it's gonna get the job done.
- Believe you me.
- Oh... Just give it to me.
Fa!
Are you... are you out of your mind?
- I got him.
- Storming here like that.
I got him! The lostie.
He's in my tent right now. Come on.
- All... all right.
- He's tied up. Let's go.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
Just get my boys, all right?
You get them a gun.
Okay.
Let's go.
Come on, Fa. Go on. He's
in there, go on. Inside.
- He ain't here.
- He's gone.
What the hell is going on, boy?
I don't know, Fa. He was in there.
I had him tied up.
I don't see no ropes.
Yeah, well, maybe he took them with him.
I want that demon. I want him...
Hey, all right, hey.
Go get G'win. Get G'win, go on!
Thank you, cousin.
I thought you might do
something like that.
We need to get you out of here
and get you somewhere safe.
There ain't nowhere
safe on this mountain
until that lunatic's out of here.
Where's Krake?
They took him to the box.
Foster's gonna kill him.
Shit.
Take this, and you take them
a half a mile beyond Chalk Falls,
and there's a little mine.
I want you to hide there and
wait for my all clear, okay?
Go, go. You four, you stay with me.
Enoch's got himself a bum leg.
Why don't you let me take them?
No, Hasil, I need you and
these four men, okay?
Look, I gotta go get Krake.
I'll explain it to you on the way.
Come on, let's go.
Hey. Hey, you go on with them.
It's all right.
Hey, Sally-Ann. Hey. Hey!
Hey.
Where you going? You're
going the wrong way.
- I'm going home.
- You can't... What are you...?
You can't walk down the
mountain by yourself
in the middle of the night.
You're gonna fall and break your neck.
- I'll take my chances.
- Listen, hey. Hey!
- You lied to me!
- Hasil! Hasil.
Just...
you told me it was beautiful up here.
You said that it was
all skies and stars.
It was. It was that way.
But it's just going crazy
on account of big.
I'm begging you, please, go with them.
Goodbye, Hasil.
No, you can't.
If you don't know where you're going,
you're going to get yourself killed.
Come with me then.
Come with me.
My family needs me.
Damn it, Krake.
I'll get it. I just gotta
find the right rock.
Trust me, cousin, you've been
at it since the dark of night.
That thing won't never yield.
You sound pretty sure about that.
I built this box.
I'm a good man at the still,
but my ironwork's where I really shine,
as you're finding out.
I wanna hold the first brief at 9 A.M.
A few of the guys can't
get here till then,
so that's when it's gonna be.
Knock, knock.
Yeah, what can I do for you?
Could I speak to you in private?
No. Sit down.
Anything you wanna say to me,
you say in front of him.
I'm sorry to interrupt you boys.
I know you have big plans for tomorrow.
How'd you know about that?
I know all sorts of things.
But I'm here today, sheriff,
as a concerned citizen.
It came to my attention
that a group of local men
are planning to start some trouble
up on the mountain today.
Now I know for a fact
they're gathering at 5:00,
and they're gonna go up a trail
behind eno somebody's place.
Do you know where that might be?
So how do you know this?
Told you, sheriff, I know
all sorts of things.
You know, I mean, I know
all sorts of things, too.
I'm sure you do.
I know who each of these men are.
And... I know they
were all in a meeting
in your office yesterday.
Are you having me followed?
No, I'm having them watched.
But everywhere they go,
you keep popping up.
You're under arrest.
Are you kidding me?
Nope.
I'm under arrest?
Yeah.
Okay, well, tell me, Barney
Fife, what's the charge?
That's good. I like that joke.
I haven't decided on which charge yet.
I got a few to choose from, though...
I got accessory, I got conspiracy,
I got inciting a riot, but
I think I'm gonna go with
unlawful possession of a narcotic.
What in the hell are you talking about?
You dropped me off a little
gift basket a little while ago?
Had some oxycontin in it.
I mean, if you got a
prescription for that,
then you got nothing to worry about.
But I'm guessing you don't.
So stand up, turn around,
put your hands behind your back.
Dope fiend hick son of a bitch.
That's right.
I'm a regular triple threat.
You can take her away to the cells.
I'm gonna get started on
this goddamn paperwork.
Shit.
Your time of judgment has come, Krake.
- You said it'd be a full day.
- Get up!
Well, your fellow jackals...
they escaped and run off last night.
And my urge to punish is
too strong to contain.
Get him out of there.
- I ain't gonna beg you none!
- Wouldn't help anyhow.
Yeah, on your knees, scoundrel.
Not gonna spend my last moments
on this beautiful earth
trying to reach the heart
of a man who don't got one.
Foster, please, you
ain't thinking right.
Don't you talk against me.
I am thinking clear as day.
Get off me.
I'm fine. Fine.
Bren'in, you want us to shoot him?
No.
No, damn it.
I can do it.
Foster?
No.
No, get him...
get him back in the box.
But, Bren'in...
Do as I say.
How are you doing it?
How'd you get out of there
leaving the ground undisturbed?
Tell me.
You hateful,
dried-up...
whore bitch.
I put you in there.
I know...
I put you...
- Foster.
- I put you...
Foster, Foster, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
G'win. Oh, G'win.
What is it?
Oh, I'm lost. I'm lost,
I'm lost to this world.
She's after me... after me,
to join her in hell for what I done.
What have you done?
If I speak the words...
My shame will consume me.
Look at me. Look at me.
I'm here. I'm right here.
I'm right here.
- G'win, G'win...
- I'm right here.
You can tell me.
I won't judge you.
I love you.
You love me?
I killed her.
My mother.
I killed her... dead.
I'm sorry.
I forgive you.
Now there's a heartwarming sight.
What are you doing here?
You want me dead, old man?
Well, there's a lot of other
people involved in that now.
So why don't we just
make it simple, Foster?
You and me.
Right here, right now.
Get ready to die.
Hey there, folks.
What in the heck are y'all doing here?
Caught y'all bird watching?
We-we're just bird watching, too.
You know what we're doing here, sheriff.
- You ain't stopping us.
- I think I am, pat.
All of y'all turn around and
go back home right now.
Hey! Hey!
All right! Any one of you fire
at me again, I will open up!
Drop your weapons now!
I will unload on you!
Goddamn it, you bunch of morons!
You're all under arrest!
Everybody put your weapons down now!
Weapons down on the ground!
What? You're gonna shoot me?
You're gonna shoot an unarmed man?
You fear me that much, Foster? Really?
This ain't right. He's... he's not well.
I could be...
...half-hour dead,
and I'd still kill you.
Guess we'll find out in half an hour.
Go ahead. Finish me.
As you wish.
No. Let him be.
He's dead.
No, he don't belong here.
Help me, G'win.
Okay.
It's done.
Everything will be better now.