- There. You have just
entered the painting.
You would think time has stopped,
but it is not so.
Everyone is in their place
and holding their breath.
The castle over there,
is occupied by the Toupins
(Tout peint = totally painted).
At this moment, things
are going their way.
They think they're in paradise.
Lower down, in the shadow,
at the foot of the blue tree,
lovers are locked in a tender embrace.
Do you see them?
They believe in their love.
But they have to hide
for Ramo is a Toupin,
and my friend Claire,
a Pafini (Pas fini= Unfinished),
like me.
I await her,
and I'm starting to have
pins and needles in my legs.
I almost forgot to tell you about
the Reufs (Rough Sketches).
They are even worse.
It's said
that they believe in nothing!!
Oh yes! Here, everybody
sees the world in their own way.
Well, I must leave you.
I, too, have role to play
in this story.
(Frenzied music)
- Over here!
- You see him?
- He's going to escape us!
He's over there!
He's going towards the lake.
- Bastard!
What do we do?
- We won't see him in these thickets.
- Leave him.
We'll find another one.
(They laugh)
(He gasps for breath)
(Confused discussions)
- Did they catch him?
- No, they're coming back without him!
- It's true we don't see them easily.
- They are just doodles!
- How do you call them again?
- The Reufs.
- Oh yes, the Reufs.
They disgust me!
How did the painter let it happen?
- They were his first sketches.
- He should have erased them!
- As long as they don't
come close to the castle...
- Well, our young Toupins
need to amuse themselves!
- Say, it's beautiful!
You see all those lights?
What happened to you?
Oh, clever! What are we
gonna do now? The stairs...
are on the other side.
- Those colors, so wonderful!
- This color looks great on you, dear.
- You're not so bad either.
- Look! Over there!
That Pafini!
- She got...
no self-respect!
- Surely they won't let her come up!
- Please, I implore you!
I'm almost completed...
- Go away!
Don't you understand?
To be a Toupin, you
need to be completed.
- Yes, but...
- Go away! Shoo!
- Ah, the Pafinis! They don't understand
that they have no place here.
- The garden is big enough.
They have all the space they need!
- There is only one way to make them
understand and I hope it's tonight!
(Sweet and sad music)
- Did you hear them?
Hatred, always with the hatred!
- To what lengths will they go?
- I'm afraid.
- They won't dare hurt you.
- I don't fear for myself.
I fear our love won't last any longer
in this cold shadow.
During the day, I wait for night
and when night comes, I have to hide!
- I can barely see your face!
- I see yours, Claire.
- Tell me then.
I don't know my own face.
- It's very beautiful,
elegantly simple.
Your eyes are like blue almonds
marvelously drawn.
Your cheeks are golden sunset.
And your lips have
the color of this flower here,
rosy, with a touch of crimson.
- My lips are colored?
- Of course!
- Ramo, hold me tight, please!
Lie to me again.
Tell me we could...
love each other freely.
- They are not lies!
I feel that the painter will come back.
Even if he didn't,
I'd go look for him
at the end of the world.
And he'll finish the painting.
- Lola is right, we can't stay here.
I'll see you at the lake tonight.
- Come with us!
- I want to know what's happening.
And you know the Pafinis don't like me.
- Claire!
- I'll tell you what I'll have learned.
For now, go with them.
I love you.
(Sweet melody)
(evening atmosphere,
loud discussions)
- There he is.
Look!
- Hush!
- My friends, my dear friends!
You have chosen me to proudly
wear our colors.
And maybe also...
to voice out loud what everyone
is thinking.
The painter will never come back!
- Finally, someone with the courage
to speak the truth.
- We must recognize this fact:
Such was his decision.
And if he has made of us, The Toupins,
the only perfectly drawn
beings of his works...
it's because such was his intention!
(The audience applauds)
And naturally...
that means it falls to us now to
put the castle in order.
- The Pafini have no business here!
- We must chase them away...
once and for all!
- You're no doubt right, our castle
is not infinite.
Can we find place for all the
sketches from the painting?
- They must go!
- In the Forest...
- Yes!
- Exactly!
Who could blame us?
- Me!
- Who is that?
- Young Ramo.
The one who... with that girl...
- How exactly are the Toupins
superior to the Pafinis?
- Isn't it obvious? The painter
wanted it that way, young man.
- What would you know of it?
Are you speaking in his name, now?
Listen to me!
We don't know why
the painter disappeared.
But he can come back any day,
and finish his work.
- Shut up!
- He's talking absolute nonsense!
- You are proud of your looks.
Me, I feel ashamed every time
I hear you talk.
To feel superior just because you're
wearing sparkling costumes!
- Better than a rough sketch!!
- Or a barely outlined girl!
- My friends, my friends!
Our young Ramo is only trying
to defend his liaison
with a young Pafini.
We must understand,
it's typical of his young age.
But understanding doesn't mean
we just accept everything.
Blissfully happy idealism
belong to the past.
Equality, freedom,
the castle for everyone! Hah!
For the Pafinis?
Why not...
for the Reufs?
- Let go off me! Don't you see
he only wants power!
Don't be duped!
- The Painter will be back!
- Yes, yes, he'll be back, he'll back...
No, my friends, believe me.
You don't have to be ashamed
for being the betters,
the most beautiful!
My dear little hearts,
you're the light of this castle!
- Bravo!
- Vive The Great Chandelier!!
(dramatic music)
- Look!
- A Reuf!
- What horror!
He slipped into the castle!
- Stop!
Are you mad?
- This boy is dangerous.
Don't you think, Mr. Grey?
- We can take care of
it, Great Chandelier.
- Do you hear them?
- I don't like this song!
- They're getting each other
worked up, like the devils.
- If only you knew how
they treated me!
- Then why do you want to join them!
- Because it's unfair.
Me too, I want to dance, to have fun.
- The only dancing we're gonna do
is to try and dodge their blows.
- You know what he told me?
That my lips were colored!
I adore him!
I even almost believed him!
- You're lucky.
But if he loves you,
why does he lie to you?
- They are beautiful white lies.
Life is so sad here.
- We only have to keep
quiet, like they asked...
It's the Reufs they are after.
They slip everywhere.
- It's hard to see them.
They risk nothing.
- Listen to them, they
all want to be Toupins.
Me too, I admit.
- Not me. I'm happy like this.
- You say that 'cause you have no lover.
When you love,
you're not alone in the world.
There is him, and me.
There is our love.
He wants to live large...
to be accepted by everyone.
- It's true I've never had a lover.
- But I'd go find my lover elsewhere.
- Elsewhere?
And where would you go, petite Lola?
There is no elsewhere.
There is the castle, the garden,
And then, nothing else.
Excepted the damned Forest.
- The Forest... We
know nothing about it.
No one has ever gone in there.
What are you doing?
- I'm going to see him.
You know he's waiting for me.
- Hey you,
where do you think you're going?
- Let me pass.
- She's going to see her lover!
- Come on, it's none of your business!
- Lola is right.
Let her go.
- No! She will tell them where we are!
- Her Ramo...
is a Toupin.
- No, he is not like the others.
- He will be worried.
- Relax.
Wait a little bit.
They will let me pass.
- Gom!
(Ominous music)
Oh, no!
What have they done to you?
The monsters!
Poor,
poor idiot.
No!
(Dramatic music)
- Ramo? Is it you?
I can't help you,
I'm waiting for someone.
- But I didn't ask you anything.
- Where's Claire?
- The Pafinis didn't want to let her go.
- Everybody is against us!
Let's go get her.
- What is he doing here, this Reuf?
- He, too, is hiding.
- There they are!
- Yes, I see them!
- Where are you going?
- I don't know!
- This is not the way!
The current is carrying us away!
- Current?
This lake has no current!
- What are you doing?
We are going towards the...
- The Forest!
- The Flowers of Death!
- Oh, no! It's horrible!
The flowers will devour them.
It makes my blood run cold.
(Dramatic music)
(Ominous music)
- So, Silouet?
- What have you seen?
- The Toupins pursued
them to the Forest.
- And then?
- Well...
- Did they escape?
- They went into the Forest and
the giant flowers ate them.
There were three of them:
Lola, a Reuf, and...
- And the young Toupin,
- No!
That's not true!
Why are you lying?
(Sad music)
- We passed!
I can't believe it!
- They didn't...
eat us.
- Do you see now?
Our people talk nonsense!!
- The real nonsense was that I got
in your pirogue in the first place!
How are we gonna find Claire now?
- It's not my fault.
I did what I could.
Are you ok?
Nothing broken?
- Leave me alone!
And him, there,
I don't want him to come close.
- He won't hurt you.
- Don't touch it!
- Ok, calm down!
(He sighs)
- Claire is over there,
with those maniacs.
And me, stuck here with this imp and
this Reuf who won't stop whining.
If only the Painter could see this!
- We just have to go find him.
- If you want my opinion,
he doesn't care about us.
Why not? I've been thinking
about it for sometimes.
- We can always
go tell him about all this.
- He will finish the Pasfinis.
- And the Reufs!
- Naturally!
- Hmm!
- He'll just have to work a little
harder, that's all.
Where to find him?
You know that? You who are so smart?
- This forest is not so dreadful.
Why not continue on?
- In which direction?
Everything is so dark.
- I'd go over there.
- Or there!
- You're not helping.
- Enough!
We turn our back on the castle...
and go straight ahead.
- Hey! Can't you see me?
I am...
- He is caught in the vines again!
- Why doesn't he ever
complete his sentences?
- Maybe because he is a Reuf.
- It's annoying.
- I understand him well enough.
But you must have trouble doing so.
- Yes, I know.
I'm slowing you down, eh?
I just can't stop
getting all tangled up.
Aie!
Watch the head!
Well. Just leave me here. Leave me!
- Oh, all right!
Stay here, then, if it suits you.
- And if you...
see him, tell him that...
Hey! Don't you think that...
- He is right. We went this way
three times already.
We're going round and round in circles.
- Nonsense!
- It's true, I tell you.
- Stay together!
- It's funny,
I feel so light... Like a feather!
Look!
- Lola!
Lola!
Wait for us, I don't see you anymore!
I can't hear her!
- I'm here... hanging!
- You see her?
- Yes, way down there. She is...
- Ramo!
- Yes, I see you!
All right?
- All right.
- Don't move.
We're coming.
- What happened?
Return to your positions.
- What's happening?
In line!
Who is that?
Catch that...
girl.
- Girl?
- There. In the tree!
- Plume!
I need more rope.
Oh no, you came down, too!
- So what? I was afraid,
all alone up there.
You can't blame me.
- Hang on!
- Damned little spy!
The Green sent you, didn't they?
- The Green?
No, I come from another painting...
hung just above yours.
The rope broke.
- A painting?
What rubbish!
- Well, I see that I bothered you.
My apologies.
- By my mustache, she is mocking us!
- But it's the truth, I swear!
You're in a painting. A painting of war.
- War is a serious matter, kid.
You will see tomorrow,
when we execute you,
that your blood is not watercolour.
- You are even worse than
the Toupins.
- Captain!
The Green are...
prepared for battle.
- Well, they certainly
didn't waste any time.
Magenta, Solférino!
Keep an eye on this little hussy.
- We have never seen you before.
- It's useless to tell,
nobody will believe me.
- Try me.
- She is a liar, don't listen to her.
- You are...
in a painting depicting a battle.
And I mean to get the hell out.
- Drummer Magenta,
prepare to sound the charge!!
- The charge...
I've had...
enough of this war!
My place is not here.
You sure we can get out of here?
- Of course, I got in, didn't I?
Cut me loose.
- Maybe she is right, Solférino.
- Don't listen to her!
What are you doing?
You won't get out...
of here!
- Where were you?
And him, where did he come from?
- It's Magenta. He helped me,
he is a brave boy.
He is with us now.
Oh, pardon!
What have I done?
- Go ahead!
Don't be shy, I'm used to it!
- Plume is very fragile.
- Forgive me, Plume.
True, it's not...
very solid, your nose!
- Well, I wonder
what are we doing here?
- It all seems abandoned.
Maybe he...
has gone far away.
- What if he is here,
listening to us right now?
- Let him show himself then!
We aren't going to spend the night...
talking about someone who
is not even here!
- That one sure is grumpy!
- Oh, life is so beautiful!
The paint is of the highest
quality every where.
Harmony, tolerance...
And down here, it's the big empty!
- Lola?
- Yes?
- When you meet him,
what will you ask him?
- Ramo thinks he hasn't finished
painting us.
- Me, I'll ask him...
why he painted a battle.
He should have painted the sea.
I've always dreamt of
standing on a seashore.
And you, what will you ask him?
- Me?
I don't know yet.
There are so many things
I'd like to understand!
Why are we sometimes
happy or unhappy...
- Claire!
- What's with him?
- He is in love.
- Oh yeah? And the painter
will fix that, too?
- Grand Chandelier.
When she came out of the forest,
she had blissful smile on her face.
I think our young Ramo is not dead.
- The Flowers of Death didn't
find him to their taste?
Odd.
Unless...
- You think something protects them?
- Love, mr. Grey!
- Love?
- Yes, love.
You know what you need to do?
- Your wishes are my commands,
Grand Chandelier.
- They are so fragile!
- Who spoke?
Did you hear?
- No.
- I tell you, somebody spoke.
It came from that big sheet over there!
- Ssshhh!
- Hello.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Ma'am!
Call me Garance.
And who are you?
- Go ahead, Lola.
- Er... well...
I'm sure you will believe us.
We fell out of our painting
and we are looking for the painter.
- Odd, that he left you like that.
I thought he always
finished his works...
to the least detail.
Take my dress, for example.
- But you're naked!
- Oh yes, it's true!
What was I thinking?
- I think we woke...
Orange of Mars.
- Hey, there!
Did you come play with me?
- We're looking for the painter.
- And you don't know...
where he is... what he looks like..
Is he tall? Short?...
If you meet him,
you won't even know it...
because you...
don't know him at all!
- And you, young man,
do you know him?
- Young man?
I am a Harlequin.
And the painter, I know him well.
He is not far.
Yes, yes. Behind you, on the easel.
- It's him?
- It's the painter?
- No, unfortunately.
It's just a self-portrait.
- Are you happy now?
You woke everyone up.
Where do you think you are?
A train station?
- We're in the painter's studio.
We are sorry to have...
bothered you.
- He abandoned you, eh?
I'm not surprised. He is
arrogant and contemptuous!
And you, you chase after him
like a bunch of idiots!
- Why are you saying...
that?
- Are you upset with us?
- I'm always upset!
I can't help it.
Don't expect me to ever be happy.
I just can't.
True, when He painted me,
he was in a good mood.
And so were I, consequently.
And then, I don't know
what happened to him.
Or rather, I know it well.
You don't know what
she has made us go through!
Look at her.
Madame is still in love!
You will notice the way
she looks at me.
- Hold on! I know full well
you're not the painter!
- They can't see themselves
in painting.
- I don't look like him.
- Not true, you're his...
spitting image!
- We have to find him!
- I hate him.
Meaning I hate myself, too, in a way.
If only you knew how painful it is
to have feelings...
not your own!!
I just want to be myself, that's all.
It's not too much to ask!
- Oh, you are so pretty!
He must have been pleased!
- Heu... I'm not sure...
- You forgot?
Come here, Lola.
Me, I could never forget him.
He was please with me, too, you know.
He loved me! He didn't say it but,
I could feel it.
One day, he...
soaked his brush in his coffee,
and drank from the
flake of castor oil!
He didn't even realize it!
I wasn't afraid.
His look was sweet.
First, he outlined me with
vigorous strokes.
Then he chose the colors of my eyes
my skin, my hair...
without neglecting the least detail
of my body.
Then he adorned me with
fine lace lingerie.
And to finish, an admirable dress.
The painter sure had style, I tell you!
- What happened to your dress?
- I thought he was done.
But then...
one day,
he picked up his paintbrushes,
and removed one after the other
all my clothes.
- Oh! Là, là!
And you said nothing?
- No.
It was a pleasant sensation.
- You're very beautiful this way.
- Oh yes? You think?
- I would like to...
meet him.
Where did he go? You should know.
- Maybe he returned to Venice.
Venice was for him...
a real passion.
- Venice is another woman?
- Venice is a city!
A dream.
Men love women, Lola. But
they love their dreams even better.
- And how do we get there?
- Easy.
- Oh no!
Lola!
Where are you going?
- Wait for us!
- Plume? Are you there?
- Yes, as you can well see!
- No. I see nothing.
- The paint..paint...
The painting!
- Who could have...
done this?
- Him, of course!
The painter!
- He can destroy us?
- At least, this means,
he really exists.
- Lola has gone to find him.
Quick, we must warn them!
- Oops!
I am out of breath.
- You dance like that
all day?
- Yes. Tomorrow, we start again.
Every day the same.
It's not funny, but that's how it is.
It's the carnival.
You're not from here!
- Hey!
What are you doing?
- You're not the painter.
- What do you mean I am not the painter?
And that, what is that then?
- Dead paint.
- Dead paint!
Why you little...
wait till I...
- You don't look like him.
He is way more handsome.
Impudent child! You know
nothing. Everyone
wears a mask here.
It's required.
- I didn't know that.
- You don't seem to know much.
- Take it off then,
your mask.
- Hey! No! Wait!
Don't leave!
- Look at this crowd?
We'll never find them!
- Nonsense!
They must be warned!
- Maybe he already erased them...
- Hey, you!
What have you all got
against this painting?
- Is it your work?
- I could have finished it,
but she vanished.
A real beauty.
But I couldn't make her stay!
You like paintings?
- It's unfinished.
- I'll give you a discount.
I can do even better.
As a rule, I don't paint from memory.
But you'll soon see...
It'll be done quickly.
I'm not so bad with colors,
if I dare say so.
It's capturing motions that
gives me trouble.
- And this girl, where is she?
- Gone.
Vanished, I told you!
So, don't you want it?
Oh well, too bad!
I'm giving up painting.
People just won't stop moving!
- Ramo!
- Well, mr. Grey,
how is she behaving?
- She cries, she calls for him.
Her cries are painful to hear,
Grand Chandelier.
- Of course, Mr. Grey!
Of course.
They say love is blind
though it can hear.
Ramo will soon re-appear.
Prepare our little ceremony.
- Lola!
- Follow me!
The painter!
He is over there!
- Don't go there!
It's dangerous!
- What?
I can't hear you!
- Follow...
that gondola.
Where are...
you...
- Here we are, miss.
There is your painter.
- Oh, no!
Look,
there are at least 350!
- They come here every evening,
for the sunset.
- No!
I don't believe you.
He couldn't have done that!
- It's true. There were
dozens of them, ripped open, burnt...
- Cut up!
- It's not possible!
Look how beautiful this is!
The sun descending into the sea,
green reflection on red water.
- A sunset, it's tasteless.
He should stop painting rubbish.
- It's not rubbish!
It's called feelings!
When he is sad, he paints sadness.
And when he is in love,
he paints Garance.
Even if it's not her he is in love with,
he still paints Garance.
- Then he cuts her up in pieces.
- I have no desire to meet him.
- Anyway, you won't
meet him any time soon.
- Why?
- The painter is not here.
We are in one of his paintings.
He can't be inside and outside
of his paintings at the same time.
- What about them?
- Imitators who paint
what he painted.
- I don't get it.
- Let me tell you something:
We don't need him.
Hmm, where did I put it?
- Oh! My dress!
- Look at that! You've
been sitting on my idea!
- What is it?
- Paint? So what?
- Oh, yes!
You think we could?
- We need some more.
A little practice and then...
- Say, will it pain you to
complete your sentences?
- Bah!
You've got some nerve!
- Well, well, here are
our friends again!
- Who gave you permission to enter
my home? Get out!
What is this...
horror?
- Yellow.
Plenty of it on my dress.
You should fix that.
It's awful.
- Ah, that's clever!
- There we go!
- Magnificent!
- You think?
- You can paint!
- It's funny,
I've never tried it before!
Yes, it's not so bad!
- You're no longer upset then?
- I still am, alas.
It's in my nature.
Even though I'd like to help you.
- Teach us how to paint!
- Yes! If you have his bad mood,
maybe you also have his talent!
- To complete his work?
It won't displease me.
I need more colors. Orange,
red ochers,
- There are some on the table.
- Indigo...
- On top of the piano.
- Veronese.
- In the opened drawer.
- No! You first, Plume.
- No!
I can wait.
Him first.
- Oh!
- What will I do...
with this doodle?
- Doodle?
He is my friend!
- What was he like, your friend?
- He was...
very kind!
- To paint...
kindness!
How will you do it?
- He... was a little plump.
Yes, but not like that.
No flabbiness.
Yes, that's it..
Delicate, sensitive.
A good guy, you know!
- What am I doing here?
- Plume!
- Dear old pal,
you've come back from afar!
- Silouet, have you got news?
Why...
all those noises?
- The Toupins are cooking up
something.
They caught...
all the Reufs and make them work.
- These Reufs are incompetent.
It's like they're doing it on purpose.
- Get out of there,
you!
We need able bodies.
Pafinis or Reufs,
all the same!
- Out!
- Faster!
You, too!
- We'll stay under the trees,
to the right of the camp.
- You come with us, Magenta.
- Wait. I have an idea.
- Come on! Hurry up!
- Go on ahead.
We'll join you later.
- There we go again!
- I'll see if the way is clear.
Wait for me here.
And don't touch anything
before I come back.
- Toupin!
Are you looking for Claire?
- What happened?
Where are they? Where is she?
- Come, I'll show you.
- I understand.
Count on me.
Don't forget anyone!
- Ramo? Is it you?
- Oh, my poor love!
- Where were you?
- Far, far away.
No more worry.
Everything will be all right now.
- Ramo! No!
Stop!
Don't hurt him!
Let go off him!
You have no right!
- Come on, advance!
There they are.
- But it's...
Plume and Gom!
- No, it's not them!
- Yes, look!
- Unbelievable!
- They are magnificent!
- It's not possible!
Are you sure it's them?
- Come closer.
You have here everything you need.
All the colors, all the brushes.
And most of all, the freedom
to paint yourselves!!
Take a pastel tone,
a lively tone, or a bleaker tone...
Look at me. I am sure
you don't recognize me!
- It's true he has changed a lot.
- He speaks well, now!
- I'll show you.
There. You need
good strokes and dexterity.
Follow the curves,
like this.
You see, it's not that hard.
- Yes, but I don't want this color.
- You don't like it? It's pretty!
- Gimme that!
- Do it yourself then, but...
- You said we could paint!
- Like that?
- Calm down!
There is enough for everyone.
- It's very beautiful.
- Mommy, I want purple!
Why is there no purple?
- Let go off me!
Let go!
- There you are, finally!
- Look at them. What a mess!
- A rotten mess!
- Sorry.
We did what we could.
- Oh, there you are!
- Please don't bother.
- What is the program?
- How are you doing, dear friend?
- He loves mysteries.
- I hope we'll have fun.
- I'm here!
- They are so young!
- Here are our young pigeons,
reunited, as they desired.
Aren't they cute?
But what am I seeing?
They don't look happy!
Look how pale they are!
They say nothing anymore.
So, young man?
Where are your fine speeches?
Has the painter returned?
Did you meet him?
Will he, according to your wishes...
What has he said already?
Ah yes!
Abolish differences.
To abolish differences!
You couldn't ask for anything more!
We shall no more be distinguished
one from the other!
Executioner,
black execution!
- Look at those colors!
- It's wonderful.
- Who are they?
- Toupins?
- Let's go take a closer look.
- It's absolutely magnificent!
- Fresher,
more Parisian.
- Don't talk to them!
I forbid you!
- A lot of colors are available.
- My dear, you are gorgeous.
- Change yourself!
- Your colors are glistening.
- We have paintbrushes, colors...
- Change the Great Chandelier, too!
- Bring up the colors!
- He is running away!
- Yes, yes, of course. There are
other paintings.
- We can go from one to another
without difficulty.
Well, almost. There are some
differences in colors.
Some paintings are greener,
some redder...
- Don't make a drama out of it!
- So, Lola?
How do you find me?
But... Your dress!
You can't stay that way!
- We can even abandon
ourselves to frenzied
farandoles (farandole=a
lively French dance)
- Exactly! Just ask Lola.
Heh, Lola?
- No.
You.
- Come on, Miro. Quiet!
Don't be afraid, he won't bite.
He can't see clearly anymore.
Say, I know you.
You left...
your painting!
- Yes. Are you angry?
And I'm not the only one, you know.
But rest assured, they won't...
bother you.
They are busy painting...
The Pafinis, The Reufs...
- Painting?
But who taught you to paint?
- Your self-portrait.
- Oh no, not him!
He came out, too?
- No, no.
He is sleeping again.
You know, back in our painting,
people thought you abandoned them.
- Abandoned?
What are you saying?
I didn't abandon them,
I gave them the basic essentials.
A simple drawing...
can be more beautiful than
an elaborate painting.
So, they completed themselves, eh?
Well, it's all right then!
It's all very good!
But you?
You are not like the others.
Why did you come here?
- You still paint?
- Yes, but only landscapes.
It's less tiring.
- What do you think?
- I like it.
The clouds look like they're dancing.
Can I take a walk...
in your garden?
- You can go anywhere you want.
There is no barrier.
You can even go to the sea.
Over that way,
on the other side of the dunes.
But you didn't answer my question.
What did you want?
- Oh, nothing!
I just wanted to meet you,
that's all.
And now...
- And now what?
- I'd love to know who painted you!