Yes.
I see.
When did it happen?
OK. All right.
Thank you very much.
Nesrin?
What is it?
Did something happen to Murat?
No. Not Murat.
My mother is missing.
Nesrin?
I just landed.
What?
When was this?
I'm on my way to
the newspaper office.
Okay, I'm coming.
Bye.
I'm coming.
- We're going to the village.
- Where?
Mom disappeared.
Nesrin is waiting in the car.
Get rid of that cigarette!
This early in the morning!
How did the local police know?
The villagers told them.
Where on earth could she be?
I have no idea.
Is he back?
All right.
I'll call you later. Bye.
C'mon Nesrin, let him be!
He's destroying his life and mine!
It's crap,
just to get our attention.
Watch your tongue!
She knows the mountains inside out.
- Who are you talking about?
- Mom.
You're so cruel!
You forget how hard she was on me.
But you were so stubborn.
You still blame me. I was a kid!
If you'd only listened to her.
I'm not you.
You forget what she went through.
She chased dad away.
- No! He disappeared in the mountains.
- Come on. He ran from mom's temper.
What's she talking about?
Dad took her to that village
and then abandoned her.
The road is blocked.
What luck!
Hello!
- What's wrong?
- The road is blocked.
What will we do?
It'll be cleared tomorrow.
There's a roadside inn, we can go there.
Hey, what kind of service is this?
Go on, move your butt!
Butt? Mine's an ass!
You guys are beginning
to get on my nerves!
Don't flirt with me when you're drunk.
- What're you gonna do?
- I'll kick your ass out!
Don't get Nezahat upset.
The road is closed.
Come on! Have a drink with us.
Okay.
- Are you going over?
- Yeah.
They left their car like us.
They're our guests tonight.
Enjoy your meal!
Thanks! Welcome.
Excuse us, we're truckers
with no manners.
No problem, I don't mind.
- Do you want a glass of raki?
- Sure.
...we were so drunk
when we got there...
We're not bothering you?
Not at all.
Thank you.
Don't eat that.
It'll make you sick.
- You're not eating?
- I have some crackers.
Thank you.
Enjoy it. Some raki?
No, thanks.
Dad left mom for just such a woman.
Don't cry, my love
Don't cry, my dear
Don't cry, mama
Bravo, bravo!
I'm giving you a discount of ten liras.
- Give it to me.
- Give it back!
- Messages to him!
- Give me!
I'll have an accident!
Right! Give me!
- Break up with this guy!
- It's none of your business.
That asshole's screwing with you.
That's enough!
- There's no connection.
- Of course not!
Shut up! Stop the car.
Why?
I have to talk to him.
Do what she says, Nesrin.
Will you stop?
All right!
Well, then I'll have a smoke.
It's too cold.
I'm getting a backache.
Stop smoking.
- You want one?
- No.
Leave it.
Clean your eye. It's disgusting.
Thanks.
- Hurry up, it's cold.
- I'm coming.
There's no connection.
Oh, it's too cold!
I'm freezing.
Finish up, I'm getting back in.
Mehmet.
The car won't start.
- What's wrong with it?
- I have no idea.
The fuel gauge is lit.
- What'll we do?
- We'll push it.
Don't be stupid, it's out of gas.
Didn't we fill it?
I don't know.
I have to take care of everything.
Mom, Murat, the gas,
I just forgot.
There he is.
I hope he figured something out.
He's not carrying anything.
Who knows!
- So?
- I found a tractor.
He'll bring us some gas.
You didn't go along?
Should I have left you alone?
I hope he comes soon.
When he comes, pay him ten liras more.
I didn't have enough.
You already paid him?
Yeah, so? He's not going to run away
with the money.
Of course he will, stupid!
- What?
- Open the door.
Do you think that everyone is like you?
Stop it!
Why? He was supposed to run off
with the money, right?
You can't even pay your own rent!
Don't teach me lessons.
At least I don't kiss
people's asses right and left.
Whose ass am I kissing?
Those bastards you used to fight.
Don't be cruel.
- Stop!
- You stop giving orders!
I am not!
Yes, you are!
To me, your husband, Murat.
Can Murat do anything without me?
Why? He'll end up like me?
I'd rather die than see him become
a parasite like you.
Pull over!
How can you talk to me like that?
Where are you going?
Mehmet, come back!
What if he doesn't come back?
How do I know?
She left the key in the lock.
Mom?
Mehmet?
Where did you go, you silly goat?
Mehmet. Where have you been?
Auntie Nusret...
Oh mom!
I found her prayer beads.
I hope nothing happened to her.
I'll never forget this house,
no matter what.
Where is the emergency room?
- Right there.
- Thanks.
We gave her a thorough examination.
And we didn't find anything unusual.
Her EKG and lab tests are okay.
There are no traces of toxins.
Don't worry too much.
It may have something to do
with her age.
It might be neurological.
What do you mean?
A neurological disorder.
I'm prescribing some medicine.
When will she wake up?
In a couple of hours.
Then you can take her home.
Come on, mom.
I'll get the bags and meet you
at the elevator.
Are you all right?
Come on, mom.
Go in there
and help her get comfortable.
Go get some slippers.
Sit down, mom.
Are you comfortable?
Let me put on your slippers.
Mom,
give me your foot
so I can put on your slipper.
No, not that one, the other one.
Okay, this one, then.
Fine.
This one, mom.
No, this one again.
Where should I put this bag?
Put it in the small room.
We just arrived
at Nesrin's.
I can't go to the office today.
I'll try tomorrow.
I couldn't call earlier.
We'll talk later.
What about Murat?
He was at Ozan's last night.
He stayed at Ozan's?
You didn't tell me before?
- When could I?
- I haven't slept in days.
I'm not supposed to worry?
See you tonight.
Mom, what are you doing?
What did you do, mom?
Stop laughing you two!
Can't you sleep?
Come on, let's go to sleep, mom.
- Like this?
- Yes, nice and easy.
What's all this stuff, mom?
Give me the handkerchief!
Goodnight.
You can't sleep either?
I couldn't fall asleep.
Did you make tea?
Have some, if you want.
My shoulder hurts so much.
Mom has gotten very strange.
Especially in the bathroom.
She got mad, started shouting.
She wouldn't let me touch her.
Her hands stuck between her legs.
- She has no hair down there.
- Really?
We'll end up like that.
Nonsense.
How are things with Faruk?
The usual.
Nothing changed.
Haven't you solved your problems?
No.
I still freeze up when he touches me.
Didn't you see a therapist?
I did.
So?
He said the secret is to learn
to touch one another.
I don't know how to touch,
so I don't know how to make love.
At this age, you become like siblings.
Why are you saying that?
- What should I say?
- Just try.
Good morning.
Don't call.
I'll call you tonlght.
Who is this?
- Who, mom?
- Murat.
Your grandson.
Then, why is he...
Why didn't he come pay his respects?
He will. I'm going to get him.
Let's put this back.
Come sit here.
Go on, sit down.
I'm going to his school to find him.
Stay seated like that.
Don't go anywhere, okay?
OK.
Here's the phone.
I am writing down my number.
Call me if anything happens.
Go, go on.
OK. I'm leaving.
Can you read it?
Yes. Go! Leave!
I'll turn on the TV.
This Is one of the biggest
demonstrations ever seen.
Even the boats are covered
with the Turkish flag.
- Where are you from?
- Izmlr.
My feet hurt, so I'm In the café.
Long live democracy!
We'll save the Republic, Inshallah!
- You're selling it?
- Yes.
How much?
I bought it for 200 liras.
How much do you want?
Give me 100 liras.
It's not worth it.
How much?
50-60 liras max.
Okay, 60 liras then.
But it's cracked. I'll give you 50.
You said 60.
No, I said around 50-60. It's cracked.
Okay, it's a deal.
Good morning.
Thanks.
- Can I see that walkman?
- Of course.
The red one.
- Will you give me the SIM card?
- Sure.
- Is there a passcode?
- No, no problem.
The battery works?
Of course.
Check if you want.
How much is this?
30 liras.
You trying to die, man?!
If you don't have any balls,
why did you follow me?
Don't make me mad when my feet hurt.
Take off your shoes, asshole!
- Hello, Ozan!
- Hello, Mrs. Nesrin.
I'm looking for Murat.
I haven't seen him lately.
Are you sure?
- He didn't stay with you last night?
- Yes, but he left in the morning.
Come on, Ozan. Tell me.
I don't know anything.
I have class now.
I know what dirty business you're into.
I swear I'm calling the police.
I really don't know anything.
I have to go.
Where were you for the past few days?
We went and got your grandmother.
So, it's true, then!
You didn't know about it?
Damn. I thought my mother
was trying to trick me.
No.
What's wrong with her?
She had disappeared.
How come?
- She just disappeared.
- Where to?
Just left home and disappeared.
Why?
I don't know. We looked for her
and brought her here.
Where's she now?
At your parents' place.
What is she doing there?
She's pissing on the rug.
Wow. Right on.
I'll piss on that rug, too.
Me, I'm gonna shit on it.
You're lucky you're still alive, bro.
Why the fuck did I run after him?
It wasn't worth it.
He grabbed me
and pulled me into an alley.
He put a knife to my neck, like this.
There was nobody around.
He could have cut me to pieces.
I couldn't breathe.
He said some shit to me. Look at this.
- What the fuck?
- He took my shoes.
I froze up.
You should have seen his dark eyes.
As dark as the bottom of a well.
For the first time in my life,
I felt my feet, my hands,
the blood in my veins.
I've never felt
anything like that before.
So it gave you a real high, huh?
Yeah.
HH: I've run out? Got a spliff?
Phantom: Go to the Infidel.
HH: He got busted.
Phantom: Then go to Tarlabasi, nr. 58.
Nesrin?
Yes?
What are you doing?
I'm finding out who
he's hanging around with.
Has it come to this?
What do you mean?
You pay so much tuition,
and he doesn't even take the exams.
Wait a minute, mom.
Come here, mom.
Don't move from this spot, mom.
I will be right back, OK?
Mom!
Mom, I brought you something...
I brought meatballs
in yogurt sauce for you.
Come in.
Everything going well?
Yes. I'm finishing my dissertation
when I have time.
And your mother?
She just got out of the hospital.
And Murat? How is he?
Fine. He's sleeping right now.
- Alonso's with the Red Bull team.
- Yeah?
Get me out of here!
Mom!
Come here!
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Blue, falcon, tulip.
Very good. Remember those words,
I'm going to ask for them again.
Can you count down from one hundred
subtracting seven at a time?
Can you count down from there
What were the three words from before?
- Blue.
- What else?
God! What other disasters
will befall us?
When will they let her out?
I don't know who to deal with first,
Murat or mom.
Very good. Now try to whistle.
Does it feels the same on one side,
as it does on the other side?
Does it feel the same
on both sides when I touch you?
Very good!
Now try to pull your arm towards you.
Very good.
Only I take responsibility?
Now you take care of mom.
I have to look for my son.
I don't have
a regular schedule, you know.
Fine. So it's my fault for having
a regular schedule.
Your mother is suffering
from Alzheimer's Disease.
The illness is in an advanced stage.
You have to expect
all sorts of difficulties.
For example,
your mother will no longer
be able to perform
many of her daily activities.
Possibly she won't be able
to wash herself
or go to the toilet alone,
or even dress herself.
You have to help her
and teach her routines
over and over again.
She should never be alone.
She lives with whom?
With me.
She may have some nervous spells
and act very irritably.
You will have to calm her
and stay calm yourself at those times,
because just the illness is to blame,
not her.
Do you have any questions?
You can call me
if there is any problem.
Thank you.
Mom, calm down, please.
You're going to fall down!
Mom, calm down!
Please, calm down.
Please, let me do it.
Is the water too hot?
It's hot!
Please, mom!
Look, mom, this is the toilet.
If you have to pee or shit,
you do it here.
You sit here like this.
Don't do it on the carpet, okay?
- Mom, pee and shit.
- This isn't working.
How else can I explain it?
Mom, here is the toilet,
don't do it on the carpet.
Nesrin, don't push her.
Let's put her in a hospital.
They'll say we didn't take care
of our mother!
- Who's going to say that?
- What?
I can't explain it to her?
You're exaggerating.
Enough!
- I'm going home!
- That's out of the question.
I'm going home.
Tonight?
After work?
Let me think.
Okay.
Let's meet in front of the newspaper.
Bye. Kiss.
Take us to Galata, please.
This way, mom.
You stay here tonight.
I'll pick you up tomorrow.
Mom, please!
Fine, we'll wash your hands inside.
Murat! What are you doing here?
None of your business.
Your mom is looking for you.
Why haven't you called her?
Who is this?
Your grandmother.
Mom, look.
This is your grandson, Murat.
- She's staying here tonight.
- How come?
I've lots to do at work.
Let her stay tonight.
I'll come get her tomorrow.
- Where's Mehmet?
- He should be here soon.
- When does he get home?
- Do I know?
Mom, Mehmet will be here soon.
I'll come and get you tomorrow. OK?
- What should I do?
- Here's her stuff.
I'll give you some money.
150. Is that enough?
Give her these pills.
One in the evening,
and one in the morning, after meals.
And one of these, too,
every three hours. Don't forget.
- What's wrong with her?
- Alzheimer's.
- What's that?
She forgets everything except the past.
Keep an eye on her.
Tomorrow I'll be back
and you go home, agreed?
- I'm talking to you!
- Yes, go.
See you tomorrow, mom.
Grandma,
let's go inside.
Where's my mountain?
Güzin? I couldn't find you at home.
Where are you?
Don't worry. We're on our way.
What? Where did you go?
I had to stop by the paper.
Don't worry, we're going home.
Why did you take mom? Is she all right?
Stop worrying, Nesrin. She's fine.
Call me when you get home.
Okay, I'll call you.
- How are you, darling?
- Fine and you?
- I got rid of my mother.
- What's she doing here?
Since when do you care?
What do you mean?
Let's go to your place.
I don't want to.
Let's go talk somewhere.
I don't have a lot of time.
You won't stay overnight?
Can't we ever wake up together?
Güzin, please. I have so much work.
- That's enough!
- Why so upset?
I work too, but I make time for you.
I make time for you too!
I don't want your time!
Stop the car!
What a damn callous world!
What a fucking senseless life!
Will grandma get mad if we smoke pot?
No, she's cool.
Does she know what it is?
She's been using tatula plant for ages.
- What's that?
- You don't know?
No, what is it?
They collect tatula in the mountains.
They boil it then drink it.
To get high?
Stoned. But they fool us
saying it cures asthma.
Roll the joint, you'll see.
The smell will get her excited.
- I'm going to light up, then.
- Go right ahead.
You see how she likes it?
What's your name?
Murat, grandma.
Grandma?
Are you one of mine?
Yes, mom.
It was you that named him,
after my father!
Murat.
I should go now.
The road will get blocked.
Where are you going, mom?
Where, grandma?
The roads will be blocked.
It will snow!
No, it's not the season for that.
Don't worry, I'll take you tomorrow.
Okay?
Stay, Grandma.
That's right, mom. Relax.
She must be remembering
my father's death. Goddamn.
How did grandpa die?
In the mountains.
No, not in the mountains.
He abandoned you.
He always did whatever he wanted.
Like you.
I never abandoned anybody, mom.
Whether you've abandoned me
or yourself,
it's the same thing to me.
Come on!
Grandma, wait!
No, the other one.
Wait.
What's your name?
Murat, grandma.
What are you doing?
I have to pee.
Okay, but not here.
Over there, maybe.
No, grandma, come on.
Don't you have a family?
No.
Who brought me here?
Your children.
Who?
My mom, my aunt, my uncle.
I don't remember anything.
Well, don't remember.
It's better that way.
Kidnap me. Take me to my village.
Güzin?
Güzin? What's the matter?
Come on, say something! Are you okay?
Come on, get up! Tell me what's wrong!
Güzin? What's the matter?
Did something happen to mom?!
Where is she?
Tell me!
I left her with Murat.
With Murat?
Where did you see him?
At Mehmet's place.
What? Why didn't you tell me?
Enough! Stop irritating everybody.
Who do I irritate?
- You pester everyone!
- I do not!
Enough!
- I'm worried about my son!
- Leave me alone!
Come on, Grandma.
Just a few more steps.
What are you doing, man?
And where were you two?
You were snoring
when we left this morning.
What is all this?
I'm privatizing my electricity.
Why?
Because they cut mine off today.
So what is this thing?
You like it?
Look.
- Are we going to die?
- No, don't worry.
Hold that up, Murat.
- You are nuts.
- OK, ready?
Lights!
Damn, that's incredible!
What are you doing there?
What are you up to?
- Mom? What are you doing here?
- Why not?
You enjoy making me suffer?
- Why are you here?
- Why do this to me?
- What's gotten into you?
- How so?
- You want to end up like him?
- Hey!
- You bring mom to this place?
- Stop!
Just a minute.
Mom is fine here. As if you care.
He's a good boy.
- Don't yell at him.
- Mom, you stay out of this.
- Come, we're going home.
- What home?
You never ask me what I want to do.
You never asked me even once.
What do you mean? That's your home!
- Not in this dump!
- Fuck off!
It's you I don't want to be like.
For once just look what's in your hands.
I always wondered
if you ever really loved me.
Look at you.
You are empty...
as empty as the glass behind you.
The funny thing is, I'm just like you.
Now we are both the same.
Why are you calling me?
There's nothing to apologize for.
Mom?
Don't call me again.
I don't want to see you anymore.
Mom?
Güzin.
Giving birth to you was so hard.
You stuck to me.
And now you want everyone
to stick to you.
I might as well leave, I'd say.
But who will play with my toys?
And who'll caress
my hands and fingers
the way my mommy does
five times a day?
I might as well leave, I'd say...
Don't be like me.
Open yourself up.
Why did they shut her up in there?
How could they?
That's life, man.
You give in to it
sooner or later.
Are you going to leave me too?
Don't worry.
Even if I wanted to, I couldn't.
I wouldn't know how to live
without you.
That's even worse.
Let go of Murat.
Grandma, I can't light the fire.
Grandma!
How can I light the wood?
It's all wet.
Come and help me!
How do I get it to start?
What to do?
Standing here?
What should I do now?
Never mind, grandma.
Go back and lie down.
Uhff. Grandma.
Grandma,
what are you doing here?
They told me to walk.
Who?
Who said that, Grandma?
Never mind.
Now they're telling you to sit down.
Let me go to my mountain.
Or else I'll forget that too.